News time, 4:31.
I'm Gail Reissmeyer,
bringing you traffic and
the weather on the ones.
Rain all over Chicagoland today.
The rain continues
to come down...
Nice.
Causing flooding on I-94
and other expressways.
The WMAQ weather
calls for the rain to continue
into tonight
and it stays in our
forecast through tomorrow.
Bring your umbrella,
your raincoat, and your...
Son of a bitch.
Son of a bitch!
Please leave a
message at the tone.
Mark?
Mark, if you're there,
it's Kerry Weaver.
Could you pick up?
We got a little problem here.
Neal Hansen's on tonight
but his mother-in-law died,
so Morgenstern...
The answer is no, Kerry.
I am not coming in.
I don't really care if his
mother-in-law died, okay?
I've been on three
nights in a row.
Well, tell Morgenstern
that I can't,
and give the shift to Doug Ross.
He can use the money.
What do you mean, whiplash?
No evidence of fracture
or dislocation.
Vertebral bodies are
in good alignment.
There is, however,
reversal of cervical lordosis,
suggesting the possibility
of acute cervical
ligamentous injury.
My headache just tripled
during that dissertation.
Does the name Evelyn
Wood mean anything to you?
You know, Doug,
I like you in that collar.
It's a good look.
Bold yet spiritual.
No, I'm stopped,
stopped dead at the stoplight
and this Pakistani cab driver
plows into me.
I get out.
He doesn't speak
a word of English.
I look at his photo ID
and it's some sandy-haired
guy named Kroopf.
Kroopf?
Isn't that kind of
a German name?
Can I have your shoes?
What?
Mine are sopping wet.
Sure, Mark. Absolutely.
You know, I'll just walk home
barefoot in the rain.
Just so you know, I'm sorry.
I would have taken that shift.
No problem at all, Doug.
I've only worked graveyard
the last three nights,
got off at 8:00 this morning,
drove to Milwaukee
to spend the day with Rachel,
only to have Jennifer tell me
that she got the dates mixed up.
See, Rachel, it turns out,
is on some Brownie
troop camping trip,
so I drove back,
three and a half hours this time
because of the heavy
rain and flooding on I-94,
and here I am
refreshed
and full of enthusiasm
for my work.
You on tonight?
Uh-huh.
Go with God.
Susan, why are
all these patients
in the hallway?
No beds. Oh, great.
You're on tonight,
right? No, wrong.
I have dinner with
my lawyer at 7:00.
Dr. Lewis, a Peter
Kreidman called.
Can't make dinner till 7:30.
Oh. 7:30.
Listen, Susan, can you
change that to tomorrow night?
Hansen's out,
Doug has got whiplash,
Benton's in some
marathon surgery
and Kerry and I,
we're gonna be a
little shorthanded.
No, Mark. I'm sorry. I can't.
You know, I think
Chloe's gonna try
and fight this
adoption, you know?
I can't miss this.
Mark. You made good
time. I was afraid I'd miss you.
You're leaving too?
I've been on 14 hours.
I've been on for
the last three nights.
Look, I'd stay, but
Morgenstern wants me
to present our QA at
the JCAH in the morning.
Whoever's been handling
it kind of dropped the ball.
I'll be up all night
pulling it together.
It's a real mess.
Yeah, I was handling it.
Oh. Well, I'll walk
you through it
once I get it straightened out.
Shall we make rounds?
Mr. PCP, sleeping it off.
Probably need another six hours.
Second-degree burns, both hands.
Taking out her pot
roast, forgot the hot pads.
Gangbanger in a fistfight.
Fistfight? That's quaint.
Waiting on x-rays.
38 years old, AIDS.
Hand and foot
spasms, CMV retinitis,
PCP pneumonia, GI lymphoma,
waiting on ICU.
Rule-out MI.
Waiting on a Cardiology consult.
Calls himself Bobby Darin,
claims he got a shark bite
while swimming in the pool
at the Four Seasons
Hotel. Waiting on Psych.
Ten-centimeter laceration
sustained while
sliding into second.
Needs sutures.
Abdominal pain,
probably food poisoning,
but Surgery's
ruling out an appy.
Presented with
severe shoulder pain
and nosebleed.
Platelet count, 15,000.
Waiting on Hematology.
TPA patient on dopamine.
Pulmonary edema.
Intubated on a nitro drip.
Waiting on ICU.
Bicycle versus postal truck.
Multiple rib fractures.
Bilateral hemopneumothoraces.
Critical but stable.
Let me guess. ICU?
Uh-huh.
Anaphylactic shock,
and...
septic shock.
I think that's about it.
How are things in Glocca Morra?
Unbelievable, huh?
It's been like this
since the rain started.
Who else is on besides me?
A few Residents, a Psych intern,
and maybe Carter.
Good night.
LOL with burned hands,
admitted to burn service,
films on that gang
kid were negative,
sent him home,
and the rule-out appy was
ruled out and discharged.
Excellent, Haleh, you
get three gold stars.
Carter?
I have sutured the leg lac in 4,
the knee lac in
3, the arm lac in 2,
and the head
lac in 1. That's it?
All right. we have
seven waiting for ICU.
No. Make it eight.
Bounce-back hip replacement
with DVT and PE.
Okay. We have 33 in the
ER and 41 in the waiting room.
Make that 42.
Paramedics pulling
in with an altered LOC.
So your mission,
should you choose to accept it,
which you will, because
you have no choice,
is to move these folks out
so we can move
these folks in, okay?
I want quick turnover.
No big workups.
No unnecessary labs,
x-rays, or consults...
But, Mark...
And no comments.
Carol, Carter, let's
go meet the incoming.
Randi, I want a
turkey sandwich, okay,
from the cafeteria,
because Jerry,
he's not here yet.
Sorry. I'm late,
and I can't be responsible
for him, Dr. Greene.
But, but... Randi...
Get me out of here!
Hi, Chuny, you're late.
I'm on at 8:00.
Yeah, well, it's 8:04.
What do we got?
Omar Gandera, 15.
Strolling down by The
Loop, drunk out of his mind.
Vitals are stable, BP 120/80.
Fell on his knees. He's
gonna need some stitches.
You guys got a
party going on here?
Don't start with me, Doris.
How much did you drink, Omar?
Don't touch me! Get out of here!
Can I give Mrs. Layton
another 50 of Demerol?
How long's it been? Three hours.
All right, well, if you
help with this kid.
All right, on my count.
One, two, three...
Put me down!
Buckle him up tight.
He got out of ours.
Party on.
Let me out of here!
Sinus tach at 110.
All right, Carter, what
do you want to do?
BP's still 120/80.
CBC, Chem-7, blood
alcohol, tox screen,
ABG and saline. Wide open.
Carter, she said tie him tight.
I did!
Labs are back on
that kid with the fever.
Yeah? Any films? Uh, not yet.
All right, well, go
sit on Radiology,
and don't bug me
until you got everything.
Carter,
get the labs going,
and I'll be back.
Oh, yeah, we're
having some fun now.
There are non-displaced
oblique fractures
of the third and fourth
metatarsal shafts
with no significant
angulation or comminution.
The foot's busted, okay?
Splint him and ship him out.
Chuny, what are you
doing with this guy?
Gonna fix his feet.
Uh-huh. What'd he do?
Stick them in a blender?
No more mixed drinks.
Put him on the back burner.
We've got people who
are a lot worse than he is.
Excuse me, doctor.
Could you just come
and look at my mother?
In a minute.
What a mess, huh?
It's not helped by the
fact that you were late.
Are you the doctor in
charge? The one and only.
I'm Ruth Huggins. My son
has a horrible cut on his hand.
We're gonna get to
him. I'll bring him in.
Jerry, can you take Mrs.
Huggins to the waiting room?
Sure. But, please,
it's bleeding.
We've been waiting
out there... Come on.
Jerry, don't let people
sneak in like that, okay?
Whoever's out there
has been triaged.
We'll see them
as soon as we can,
but no one gets in
here without a chart
unless they're dying. Right.
Malik?
Mrs. Votey,
you're having weakness
in your right arm?
Yesterday and again today.
Everything's sort
of out of focus.
At one point today,
she couldn't even speak.
Scared my students
half to death.
My mother teaches self-defense.
To seniors.
Squeeze.
Maybe I could just wait
here for my regular doctor.
Dr. Randall. Jack Randall.
I know him.
Mrs. Votey, you
might be experiencing
what we call TIAs,
transient ischemic attacks.
They can be a warning
sign of impending stroke.
I'll call Dr. Randall,
but in the meantime, I'm
going to admit you upstairs,
where they can work you up.
Start her on heparin,
800 an hour, call Randall
and get her
admitted to Medicine.
You want a CT first?
Let them do it.
We need the room.
I don't get it.
He's still altered, but
his tox screen's negative.
I have to pee. Ethanol?
None detected.
PH? 7.30.
Omar, what'd you drink?
I gotta pee. Omar!
Gotta pee.
Go ahead and pee, Omar.
There's a tube in your bladder.
Paramedics five minutes out.
Drive-by shooting.
Who's on call for Trauma?
Benton. You want me to
call him? No. Call Thoracic.
Thoracic? You heard me.
Call Morgenstern,
tell him that we are
closing the Trauma now.
Lytes?
Not back yet.
What the hell's wrong
with the lab tonight?
Same thing that's wrong with
us. There's just too many patients.
Okay.
Let's say he has a gap.
Methanol, uremia,
DKA.
Ethylene glycol?
You think he drank antifreeze?
Well, gotta rule it out.
All right. Get a Woods lamp.
Really jammed in there.
What?
I said, it's really
jammed in there.
Carter, what are you doing?
Foreign body in the canal.
Have him lie down.
Do you know what it is, sir?
What?
A bead.
So Carter,
you having fun paying
your penance in the ER?
Ha.
I'm off Surgical Service.
I'm working nights in the ER.
What's not to be happy about?
Still, it is better
than not graduating.
I thought Dr. Hicks
might suspend me.
Believe me, she
would if she could have.
I can't believe I
was that stupid,
sneaking off and
drinking on call.
I can. You're a medical student.
Hmm.
Superglue?
Yes.
Just touch the bead.
Hit the skin, you're in trouble.
Don't move! Don't move!
Dr. Greene?
Paramedics are here.
Got it.
How old is she? 18 months.
Two gunshots to the right
upper leg, through and through.
Hypotensive. Can't get a line.
It's okay, baby. We're here.
Cops got the boy who did it.
Black kid, 14 years old.
Shot him dead.
Can't say I'm sorry.
Yeah, cops never mind
shooting a black kid.
And he didn't much mind
shooting this one, did he?
CBC, type and cross for two.
Get a unit of O-neg.
Right foot's cold. No pulse.
That's the femoral artery.
I'll call for x-rays.
Sixteen-gauge Jamshidi.
One percent with epi.
Faint pulse.
Dynamap's not reading.
120 of saline.
Okay. Fill these tubes.
Haleh, page Netzley.
Malik, you're gonna take her
up to O.R. You got it.
Dr. Greene, about
closing the Trauma,
Morgenstern gave the big "N-O."
Yeah? Well, get him
on the phone for me.
He went back up to Surgery.
All right, well, I'll find him.
Mark, bingo on Omar.
You got it?
Mommy.
Daddy.
Ethylene glycol it is.
What's that?
Antifreeze. Get
Renal down here stat.
Let's give him IV ethanol.
We don't have any.
What?
I checked.
Pharmacy's out.
St. Luke's is sending us some,
but it won't be here
for another hour.
There's a bottle of bourbon
out in that shopping
cart in the hall.
Bourbon?
120 cc oral loading dose.
Thirty cc's POQ one hour.
Otherwise,
he's got brain damage
and renal failure.
Bourbon shooters it is.
E labs are finally back
on that coma in 2. It's DKA.
Start an insulin drip,
0.1 per kilo per hour.
Mrs. Votey... Who?
The karate lady.
She had another TIA.
She's supposed to be
admitted to Medicine.
Yeah, but Dr. Randall
said to discharge her.
Discharge her? What, is he nuts?
Page him 911
and tell him to
get in here, now.
Here you go. Whoa!
Who let this dog in here?
Try and take it
away and it bites you.
That puker in 4 is still at it.
Give him 10 of Compazine
and a liter of saline.
Mr. Nathan in 5...
Morgenstern made
it. He's up at the front.
The turkey sandwich?
Sorry, I forgot.
I can get it almost immediately.
Who are we talking about?
Mr. Nathan in 5,
high white count,
temp's 101, Thanks.
Still has left
lower-quadrant pain.
Probably diverticulitis.
Make him NPO.
Give him amp, gent, Flagyl,
and get an abdominal series.
That's right. Bring him in.
Answering the phones?
I'm here to help. Yeah?
Well, then why don't
you close up the Trauma?
Sorry, Mark. No can do.
County's only
looking for excuses
to put us out of business.
Well, it's 10:30.
We've got enough
business to last a year.
32 in the ER,
49 in the waiting room.
Look, Mark, I'm sorry...
Mark, got a little Benton
fracas going on in Trauma 2.
Board of Commissioners
wants to close a county ER,
save 80 million a year.
Every time we close,
we're sending a message
that we're not
capable of providing.
Yeah, well, we're not.
I now have nine ICU
patients draining my staff,
we've no monitored beds.
Here are the films on Robinson.
I have... I can't even
help half the patients here.
It's insane.
Look, I've talked to the
critical care coordinators.
We can move six patients
from ICU to Telemetry,
but we're staying open.
So what? He's oxygenating well.
The tube heads medially,
striking the mediastinum.
Peter, Shelley, what's going on?
Why didn't you page
me when this came in?
Shelley's handling it.
I'm on call for Trauma.
We didn't need you. If
you don't want my help...
Gentlemen, please. Ladies...
I don't hear anybody
helping anybody here.
Now, what's going on?
Third-year Surgical
Resident Leung
placed the chest
tube anteriorly.
Which has relieved
the pneumothorax.
But which will in no way
drain the hemothorax.
Which can be repositioned
when we prep for a lap.
Excellent idea.
Let's all scrub in.
Come on, folks.
Let's go.
Mark, hang in there.
If you need anything,
give me a call.
How about a turkey sandwich?
Too late. Cafeteria
closes at 10 now.
County cutbacks.
It's called a growth plate.
It's a piece of cartilage
that doesn't turn to bone
until you're grown up.
Dr. Greene.
Carter. Chloe.
Hi, Mark. I, uh... came
here to see Susie,
but John says
she's not on tonight.
No, she isn't.
Chloe was curious
about how to read an x-ray.
I guess the interest in medicine
must run in the family, huh?
Yeah, right.
Junior gymnast in
5. Fractured patella.
Time to break the bad news.
Man, that hand is so little.
Look at that.
Yeah, it's probably
four or five years old.
Little Susie's hand's
about that big, right?
So Susie probably told
you what's going on with us.
Yeah, she mentioned some things.
I understand
why she's upset with me.
I never thought I could change.
Why should she?
I just want her to see that
things are different now,
that I'm different now.
She tell you that I'm engaged?
No, she didn't.
He's a great guy.
Steady.
He's as smart as Susie is.
He's the only person
I've known, besides Susie,
who's ever taken
the time with me,
to get to know
me, you know, to...
That thought that there
was something in me
worth finding out. I don't know.
It's really busy out there.
I gotta get back to work.
Hey, Mark. Um, the
thing is, I really miss her.
I'm sure you do,
and I know it's hard,
but as far as babies go,
Little Susie's doing great.
Yeah, I miss her too.
Jerry? Uh-huh?
Put out a page on Steve Flint.
How's our score?
Bleak, bleaker, bleakest.
No, wait, we can
mark this one off.
Omar Gandera.
Renal finally got here.
They're gonna take him upstairs.
Did you call Psych for him?
Yeah. They said to
call back in a week.
Oh, great.
Kid OD'd on antifreeze
and Psych can't
quite fit him in.
Exam 2's open.
Good work, Chuny.
Somebody help me, please!
All right, Chuny, park that
guy. Jerry, clear Trauma 2.
Get a doctor here, please!
What happened? I
don't know. It's his chest.
What's your name? Corky.
You all right? Yeah.
It's just my dad.
He's sick. He's really sick.
Was he vomiting blood?
You got some on your
shirt. No, I just cut myself.
What do we got? Possible MI.
What's your father's name?
Louis. Louis Etheridge.
Louis? Louis? Mr. Etheridge?
Is he on any medications?
I don't know. Maybe.
Louis?
Need air...
Tachy at 120. BP, 160 palp.
EKG, portable chest.
ABG, first-day CCU labs.
Fifteen liters O-2, four of MS,
titrate a nitroglycerine drip.
O-2 sat's 100.
Are you nauseous, Mr. Etheridge?
Yes. Yes. Please, help me.
Inferior MI?
Has he had any heart trouble?
No, that's not it.
What is it, Corky?
It's okay to tell us.
Dr. Greene, what
the hell are you doing
pulling me down here in
the middle of the night?
Wait outside,
please, Dr. Randall.
Corky, what's wrong
with your father?
I need to talk to
you. In a minute!
Corky?
I don't know. He's just sick!
Double lumen
IVs. Get a TPA tray.
Let me know when
the 12-lead's done.
You got me out
of bed at midnight
for absolutely no reason.
Your patient's just
around the corner.
Why don't we step this way?
I gave the order to have
her discharged hours ago.
Yeah, well, she's had three
TIAs in the last two days.
She needs to be admitted.
Stroke Council, AHA,
1995 recommendations:
Hospitalize for
four or more TIAs
in a two-week period.
Or for findings suggesting
a worsening course.
I know the paper.
Her HMO will not
authorize her admission.
There we go. She's one
of your HMO patients.
They're the only ones
who have patients anymore,
in case you haven't noticed.
So we're supposed to
wait until she strokes out
so they can keep
their costs down?
You don't have to wait
for anything, Dr. Greene.
She is discharged.
That bounce-back migraine
in 4 is still complaining of pain.
Try a milligram of
DHE and 10 of Reglan.
What's the story?
His father's an alcoholic. Yeah?
Corky says his mother's
been putting Antabuse
in his father's coffee.
While he's still
drinking? Uh-huh.
And not telling him?
Right, so he's still drinking
and now he's having
an Antabuse reaction.
That could've been fatal.
The kid knew all along?
Hey, Corky! Mark,
the kid's scared enough, okay?
Yeah, well, he should be.
His father could have died.
Call the mother
and get her in here.
Excuse me, doctor. I
know you said to wait,
but my son's hand,
it really is a bad cut.
Mrs. Huggins, your son
has been triaged
as a minor injury.
There are much more urgent cases
ahead of you.
You have to wait
in the waiting room.
Jerry, I asked you to keep
these people out of here.
Now, I am running over to Doc's
to pick up my sandwich, okay?
I'll be back in two minutes.
Get this dead guy out of here.
Hey, give me that, give me that!
Call for help,
okay? Call for help.
Okay!
You all right?
Hang on in there!
We're gonna get you out.
Hang on! We'll get you out!
We're getting help!
Hang on!
Leita, try and crawl out.
If you just crawl
out the window,
we can get you out.
Anything?
We're still waiting
for the other unit
to show up with the
extrication equipment.
I can't get the mother
or daughter out.
The mother's unconscious.
All right, well, tell
her to grab your hand.
You can pull her out.
Over here!
I got it.
Her leg is stuck.
She can't move.
All right, I'll try to get in.
One, two, three.
Come over to this side!
All right, hold
it. I'll be back.
Let me in. Let me in.
Let me get in.
I can't reach her.
Let me get in. Let me get in.
Grab my hand. Come
on, grab my hand.
Grab my hand. I can
get her out of there.
I can grab ahold of
her. Let me get in there.
I almost got her hand.
I can get her out of there.
Move!
Let me get her out, okay?
We'll bring her in.
Why don't you go
dry off, all right?
Get the Trauma rooms ready.
Jerry.
I wouldn't ask if I were you.
Jerry?
Folding chairs for
the waiting room.
Maintenance ordered
them four hours ago.
Oh, God.
All right, let me know
when those accident
victims get in, okay?
I'm gonna go grab some coffee
and dry scrubs,
and clear those Trauma rooms.
Hey, you don't have
any coffee filters in there,
do you?
Are you kidding?
No. And we can't even do
the folded paper towel trick.
Mr. Carter, you are in luck.
Now, if we had a hair dryer,
it'd really be our lucky day.
How do you do this?
Well, you got to get
the coffee grounds out
without ripping the paper.
No, I mean this.
Patients stacked up everywhere
and no end in sight.
It's like the O'Hare
of emergency rooms
in there.
It was a lot easier
when I was younger.
I was newly married.
I'd just had a baby.
Jennifer used to come down
in the middle of the night
with chicken sandwiches.
She'd have Rachel
in the car seat
and we'd picnic between
the waiting-to-be-sutured
and the bounced-back migraines.
Yeah, I guess it
helped, having a family.
Yeah. Yeah, it did.
What are you gonna do?
That is really bad.
I'm gonna go change.
That's a lovely little pup
you got there, Mrs., uh...
Excuse me. Ms. Decksley.
Absolutely charming.
Hey, Stinky,
want a few little stitches?
Shut that yappy
little mouth of yours.
You're not a dog lover,
huh? This is not a dog.
This is a small, furry
object suitable for punting.
Mm-hmm.
I bet you can't get him
over that desk back there.
Don't tempt me.
But tempting, that's
what I do for a living.
I'm a lap dancer.
Okay.
So I hooked up
with this polyester guy tonight
and I slipped right
off his knee and bam!
Sliced my butt on his spurs.
I mean, why would you wear
cowboy boots with polyester?
I don't think I would.
Are you gonna stitch me up next?
Because this
cut, it really stings.
You want something for the pain?
Drugs? Sure.
Any word from outside?
Yeah. They radioed over.
Probably be about
another 10 minutes.
Jerry, call ICU.
This ventilator guy has
been down here for days.
Okay. Uh, do you
want me to page Benton
for that rule-out appy in 4?
No, I'll check it out.
Lydia, get those
labs on Cromley.
I thought you were trying
to get that girl out.
So did I, but I can't
even get the lab
to get a CBC in
under three hours,
I can't get an x-ray
shot in under two,
and I can't get any ICU beds
to open up.
Mark, Jennifer's on the phone.
Jen, what's up?
They brought Rachel
home. She's not feeling well.
It's 1 in the morning and they
drove her back from the lake?
Yeah, because her stomach hurts.
Stomachache and
what else? She threw up.
Well, does she
have a temperature?
Maybe it's altitude sickness.
Well, how do I know
where the lake is?
You didn't even tell me she
was going on a camping trip.
Jen, I don't want
to fight right now.
Listen, just put Rachel in bed,
keep her on clear fluids,
and I'll call you
in the morning.
Well, what do you want
me to do from down here?
Well, I'm sorry you called too.
Jerry, get Carter in here.
She's gonna be okay.
Get this out of here.
You want me to page Benton?
Yeah, might as well.
The ankle's deformed.
No cap refill or pulses.
BP's 80 palp. Pulse, 110.
Hey, Doc, listen.
Fracture dislocation.
We need to reduce.
Let's sedate her.
Prep 35 migs
Ketamine, 0.3 atropine.
I was just trying to
get her out of there.
Start another line. Hang
half a gram of Ancef.
Bolus 20 per kilo? Yes.
CBC, chem seven,
UA, portable chest,
and get an ankle.
We got her out, damn it.
Let's hear it.
Pulse, 140. BP, 90/60.
Probable flail chest
but good bilateral
breath sounds.
Fractured left femur.
Abdomen's rigid,
x-ray's on the way.
O-2 sat, 90. Blood ordered?
Two units O-neg are up,
type and crossed for eight.
Heart rate's 30.
Atropine, now.
Good work, Carter.
Prep for a lavage.
You okay with that?
I'm okay with that, yeah.
Shooting.
Clear!
Grab a C-spine
and a post-intubation
chest next door.
Ketamine's onboard. She's out.
You wanna wait for the films?
No. Let's do it.
Countertraction.
That's it. Back in.
She's coding!
Where the hell is Benton?
Page him stat.
All right, everybody off! Off!
Okay, sinus brady.
Mig of atropine.
Mix up dopamine.
I paged him 911.
Muffled heart sounds,
neck vein distention.
I don't have a pulse.
Thoracotomy tray.
Chuny, do compression.
Tamponade?
Yeah. It could be a
cardiac laceration.
10 blade.
Did you page him? Twice.
Rib spreader.
O-neg's here. Four more units.
Throw them on the infuser.
Oh, yeah.
Sac's tense with blood.
Metz!
She's bleeding out.
Rib punctured the heart.
Keep your finger over the hole
and do compressions.
Should we wait for Benton?
Let's try a 16
Foley, 30 cc balloon.
Foley?
Yeah. Clamp the
end. And saline, not air.
Last thing she needs
is an air embolism.
She's in fib!
All right, internal paddles.
One second.
Carter, pay attention.
There we go.
The catheter is going
into the hole in the heart.
Okay. Now fill the balloon.
Two units O-neg in.
Excellent.
All right. Now, traction.
What do we got?
Charging.
Charge 20.
Zapping.
Sinus.
Got a pulse.
Let's get her up to the O.R.
Where the hell have you been?
We have a double trauma
and you don't even respond?
I was closing on a
mesenteric infarction.
Yeah, with how
many other Residents
who could have closed for you?
Well, it was my
surgery. I was busy.
No, no, Peter.
Down here is busy.
In there is busy.
In there is where we
ignore everything else.
I ignore my
patients for in there.
I ignore my child for in there,
my marriage for in there.
Don't ever pull this again!
Ybe the rain will
keep the people home.
I thought it stopped raining.
Nope.
Going...
Gone.
Is there a problem? 2:00.
The bars are closing.
They're getting in their cars.
Going too fast.
Swerving.
Crashing.
Paramedics are rolling out.
Scooping them up.
And dropping them
off on our doorstep.
Dr. Greene,
that was a 911 call
from our waiting room.
It's a jungle out there.
I know.
Doctors Lewis, Ross,
Weaver, and Treloggen
will be on in four
hours and 58 minutes.
They will not be pleased.
And by the way, Jerry,
that light bulb's out.
Carter, did you discharge
that ankle sprain?
About an hour ago.
Rule-out MI in 4?
Uh, Cardiology took him up.
What about that Huggins kid,
the one with the cut hand?
The one with the mother?
Yeah.
No. He's still in
the Suture room.
There's a metallic foreign body
of 14 millimeters
located one centimeter medial
to the distal femoral condyle.
Morning, Harry.
Labs back on that OD in 6.
Excellent. Stick
them on the chart.
Films are back on
that busted collarbone.
Excellent. Stick
them on the chart.
Mrs. Huggins.
This is my son, Danny.
Hello, Danny.
Hi.
Mark, I need to
see you a minute.
Can't it wait?
No, I don't think so.
Excuse me.
Why Trauma 1?
She's not doing so well,
and there's no exam rooms.
Is her son with her?
Yeah.
Carol, why don't you
take Corky outside?
You drink coffee yet?
He's not supposed
to, but he does.
Me too. Come on.
Let's go get a cup.
Mrs. Etheridge, I'm Dr. Greene.
Corky didn't tell
you about his father
because I told him not to.
I told him not to tell anybody.
His condition tonight
was very serious.
Antabuse is a
deterrent to alcohol.
Mixing them can be fatal.
It's not that I want him to die.
It's just that when he drinks,
it can get pretty bad.
There's blood on Corky's shirt.
Does your husband
beat him as well?
No. Corky got in the middle.
I think it's from my nose.
There are places you can go,
Mrs. Etheridge.
Shelters
where you and
your son can be safe.
I know.
In cases of domestic violence
I'm legally obligated
to inform the police.
I know that too.
Jerry, call the police.
Domestic violence case.
Sure.
Carol,
order a facial series and
clean up the abrasions.
Okay.
Did he want to talk
about it, say anything?
No. Not a word.
Bend your finger.
He was helping me hang a mirror.
It weighed a ton.
Needless to say, we dropped it.
Seven years of bad luck.
Nah. I don't
believe in that stuff.
It's a fairly deep cut,
but I don't see any
tendon damage.
See? That's good luck.
What time did it happen?
After dinner.
After Hard Copy, Mom.
Unfortunately, I
can't stitch it up.
What?
After six hours,
the risk of
infection is too high.
We've been sitting
here half the night,
and now you can't
even do anything?
I'll put him on antibiotics
and you can bring
him back in three days
for delayed closure.
Do we have to wait again?
Carol,
did they admit that
bowel obstruction in 5?
Yeah. He's under
the knife as we speak.
The room's free. Good work.
Whoever's got
gastrointestinal distress,
rise and shine.
Mm.
Loretta.
Hi, Dr. Greene.
Wow. These gurneys aren't bad.
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I mean, no. You
know, of course, I'm not.
But it's Jimmy.
He's got a fever.
He's been throwing up.
Come on, baby. Wake up. Come on.
Swing your feet over there.
How you doing there, fella?
I puked twice in
the waiting room.
He's kind of embarrassed.
There were six other men
in line for the bathroom.
Yeah. It's a little
crowded out there.
Sorry.
So your stomach feels okay?
Open your mouth.
There you go.
Tongue down. Ah...
Yeah, I don't think
it's anything serious.
Your garden-variety
24-hour virus.
Nothing by mouth for six hours.
Then, sips of clear liquids,
and if he keeps those down,
you can try a little
toast and applesauce
for dinner.
Okay. Thanks, Dr. Greene.
I'm sorry you had
to wait so long.
Oh, it wasn't so bad.
We got in before a
lot of the others did.
Chuny,
you want to help
me grab some stuff?
Sure. What do you need?
Uh, gauze, syringes, Ace wraps,
saline, suture sets,
eye patches.
4-0 nylon.
Check.
Skin staplers.
Tetanus boosters.
Double-check.
Haleh, Lydia, what are you doing
for the next couple of hours?
He's kidding, right?
Can we treat them
without a chart?
How's the hospital
going to bill them?
Does that metal detector work?
You aren't going to make
an announcement or anything,
are you?
And start a stampede?
These are some of
the more minor cases.
Explain to them
what we are doing.
No labs or x-rays
without a chart.
Richard Tomco?
Anderson?
Mark, we know this guy.
What do you want
this time, Ricky?
Percocet? Demerol?
No, no, I'm telling you,
this time, it really hurts.
Yeah. Yeah, it's abscessed.
Pretty nasty in there.
Five cc's Marcaine,
27-gauge needle.
Do you have any allergies?
Uh-uh.
Open up.
Okay.
You're going to be
numb for about six hours.
Dental clinic's on
the second floor.
Opens at 9.
Do I need stitches?
No, I don't think so.
When was your last tetanus shot?
Probably high school.
Okay. We're gonna
give you one now,
but I want you to come back
if there's any redness or
swelling or red streaks, okay?
Impetigo. Write him for Keflex.
Uticaria,
0.2 Susphrine sub-Q.
Subungual hematoma. Drain it.
Do you think he's, you know,
lost his grip on reality?
No. I think he's having fun.
Vaginal bleeding.
Haleh, do you think
we can do a pelvic
in the waiting room?
Just kidding.
Take her back, spin a crit,
dip a urine and do an ICON.
Sudden-onset blindness.
Woke up this morning,
couldn't see a thing.
Carter?
Differential includes
retinal detachment,
central retinal artery
occlusion, CVA.
Diabetic retinopathy, retinitis,
macular degeneration.
She's too calm.
I think it's psychogenic.
Lydia,
try and find that
opticokinetic drum.
If the eyes move
when the drum spins,
she's faking.
Brought you some coffee.
Molly and Sarah
were roughhousing...
Don't ever buy bunk beds...
And then Molly got
pulled off the top.
Okay. Your arm hurts, Molly?
Did you hit your
head or anything else?
Do you want me
to order an x-ray?
No, we don't need it. Ms.
Taylor, one of the ligaments
in Molly's elbow
slipped out of place.
I'm gonna fix it.
She's gonna cry,
but it'll only hurt
for a second.
Ow!
Jeffrey fed his brother
a couple of those
little button batteries.
You sure?
Yeah. I saw the second
one go down myself.
Why'd you do that, Jeffrey?
Because he likes
them. He likes them.
Well, he's gonna
need some x-rays,
Mr. Alexander.
If they're stuck
in his esophagus,
there's potential
for a perforation.
Carter? Carter,
hold on for a second.
Can I borrow this?
Try that.
What do you know?
It's below the diaphragm.
No need to worry.
Check his stool.
They'll probably
pass in a day or two.
That's great. Thank you.
You're welcome.
He was right.
Psychogenic.
Lois,
I'm gonna give you
some eye drops.
I think they're gonna help you
with your vision, okay?
So just lean your head back.
Always give the patient
a way out.
One more.
Okay. That ought to do it.
Oh, wow, yeah.
Yeah?
I can see everything.
It's still a little
blurry, though.
Yeah, well, uh,
by the time you get home,
everything should be fine.
Mark, Mrs. Lipshultz, 83,
flushed, headachy.
Oh, and nauseous.
Sorry.
That's all right.
They're Doug's shoes.
Uh, give her 10
of Compazine, I.M.
What's bothering
you, Mr. Buchanan?
Where does it hurt?
Here.
How you doing, Mr. Buchanan?
It's my back.
It's killing me.
Not your shoulder?
No, no, no. My back.
BP, both arms.
Don't worry, Mr. Buchanan,
We're gonna take
care of everything.
Where can I get one
of these things, huh?
Her arm feels absolutely fine.
What do you say?
Thank you.
You're very welcome.
We still have an eye pain,
a neck pain, an abdominal pain,
and a boil that
needs to be lanced.
Be there in a minute.
I know it's early,
but I knew you'd be up.
How did you know?
Because Bananas
in Pajamas is on.
No, no. Don't
turn it up, Rachel.
You'll wake up Mommy.
Listen, I'm glad you're
feeling better, sweetie.
I'll see you next weekend?
Okay.
Love you.
Love you too.
Hey, breakfast?
Thanks.
Breakfast?
Thank you.
Mm.
Be careful. It's ugly out there.
Not as ugly as
it's been in here.
Good night. Good night.
Oh, what a night.
Hey. You ever have to sleep
in one of these things?
Listen, Doug,
I'm gonna put your shoes
by your locker, okay?
Because mine are
probably dry by now.
Thanks for the
great work, Carol.
Hey, that's why they
pay me the big bucks.
Hey, Peter,
we're gonna have to find
some way to work together.
Yeah. I guess we are.
So how was dinner?
I fired him.
What?
I have to find a new
lawyer this morning.
The guy was a lightweight.
He said Chloe could
possibly have a case
if, in fact, she
does have a job,
yadda, yadda, yadda.
What do you think?
I've seen her go through
hundreds of jobs, Mark.
What am I supposed to think?
Hey, Kerry.
Oh, hi, Mark.
I think I finally made
sense of that QA Review
but I know you're
on your way out.
We can go over it later.
Thank you. I appreciate that.
Good night.
Thought it would've
stopped by now.
Yeah.
Tonight was great.
The waiting room.
When I started med school,
that's what I thought
it was gonna be like.
Really helping people.
At least, that's what I
thought it was supposed to be.
That is what it's
supposed to be.
What are you gonna
do today, Carter?
I don't know.
What are you gonna do?