.
- Oh, my God.
Is this why you ended things
with me?
- Ended things with you?
Did you go out
with my daughter?
- There are several tumors.
- Is it malignant?
- We'll send the tissue
for pathology.
- Is that your wedding ring?
- The Chief of ED
at Andrew's hospital
is retiring.
Andrew wants
to put me up for the job.
- It's been nice, you know,
having my old rival back.
But, uh, you gotta do
what's right for you.
- Is my 5:30 Thursday
still available?
- I'm trying to lighten
my patient load.
- I deserve a little more
of an explanation.
After 20 years, I don't--
I don't make the cut?
- I have developed feelings
for you, Daniel.
- Thank you.
- Oh, hi.
- Hey, there.
- I was just on my--
- What are you doing?
You go.
- I'm on my way up
to Medical Records.
Need to sign a few charts.
- Nice to see you.
- Have a good day.
- Hey. Hey, Lonnie?
Look, I accept the fact
that you can't
treat me anymore,
and I--I respect that.
But, I--it's also--
it's important
for me to tell you
that--that the--
the work we did together?
Um, you really helped me.
A lot.
And I wanted
to thank you for it.
- I appreciate that, Dan.
Okay, take care.
- Hey.
Daniel?
- You seeing her
in person again, huh?
- No, you know,
she, um--she dumped me.
- She's been your therapist
for years.
What happened?
- She developed feelings
for me.
- Feelings?
- Yeah, romantic feelings, man.
- She give you a referral?
- Well, sure, but I mean,
you know,
changing shrinks is not
exactly like changing sneakers.
You know?
- True, true.
Are you okay?
-  Yeah.
How're you doing?
- You know, I think
I left my phone in the car.
Look, I'm going
to be here all day,
so if you want
to talk some more...
- I'm fine.
But thank you,
and I'll see you around.
- All right.
- You're going to T2.
Thank you.
- Hey, biopsy results
come back yet?
- Not yet,
but the lab promises
that sometime today.
- You know there's
a good chance it's benign.
- I'm not so sure.
I had cancer before.
- Oh.
- It's just--
- You're afraid
your cancer's come back.
- breathing shakily]
- Chest sounds good.
X-rays, a lot better.
As long as he continues
to improve,
I don't see any reason why
we can't discharge him.
- Oh.
- It still hurts.
- Yeah, well, pneumonia's
no joke, D-man.
Look, I'ma give your mom
some medicine
to make you feel better, okay?
Due to his pneumonia,
it'll be a couple weeks
before he can
go back on chemo.
- Okay.
- Any word from Terrell?
- No.
And he's never stayed away
this long.
This isn't like him.
- Thank you.
- Sure.
- Morning, Ms. Goodwin.
- Dr. Shentu.
- Seems like the Med staff
is adapting well
to our new guidelines.
- Yournew guidelines.
And you really think so?
- In any case,
I appreciate the cooperation.
- My God, look out!
Please, help me!
- We got you.
It's okay, it's okay.
- I need a 911
and the emergency response team
out front, main entrance.
Single vehicle crash,
driver responsive.
The patient's car
hit a concrete barrier.
The airbag deployed,
but no visible signs of injury.
Heart rate's steady.
- Having a lot
of generalized pain.
- Okay, everyone,
let's get ready.
Got it? On my count.
One, two, three.
Okay, let's get a cannula
and IV in.
Let's put her up on a monitor,
draw trauma labs.
We need x-rays stat.
- Yup.
- Dr. Shentu.
- BP 95/65.
- Heart rate and sats
not picking up.
Cycle it again.
- Clear.
- Chest is okay.
No hemo or pneumothorax.
Mediastinum is normal.
Ultrasound? Thank you.
Fast is negative.
- Got an ID.
Name's Gia Lindahl.
- I can see
if there's a history.
- She's too distracted
to clear her C-spine.
Let's keep
the collar on for now.
- Dr. Shentu, pupils?
- Yeah. Spare penlight?
Pupils equal and reactive.
Little sluggish.
- Ms. Lindahl,
can you hear me?
- Ms. Lindahl?
GCS 12.
- She is a patient here.
One of the first
we treated for COVID.
Been back a few times
with long-haul symptoms.
- Give her 50 mics
of fentanyl.
Let's get a pelvis x-ray,
and let's send her up to CT
for a pan scan,
and make sure we add
a tox to her blood and urine.
- Yep.
- Dr. Shentu, why don't
you see this through?
- Uh, certainly.
- And Dr. Taylor,
you run point.
Doris, let's get the doctor
a pair of scrubs.
- Okay.
- Did you just assign
the compliance officer
to a medical case?
- He's a critical care doctor
who's credentialed at Med.
- He's a bureaucrat.
A suit.
- Nevertheless, I know
you'll be accommodating.
- Yeah, do me a favor,
keep me briefed
on Dr. Shentu's
performance today.
- Sure.
♪
.
Oh, God.
Why does my body
feel like it's on fire?
- Given everything we've seen,
we think you have a condition
called fibromyalgia.
Let's give her
another 50 of fentanyl.
Fibromyalgia?
- We've seen it
in long-haul COVID patients
like yourself; there's
even a name, "Fibro-COVID."
- What causes it?
- We think it's due
to a problem in the way
that the spinal cord
and the brain
process pain signals.
It's not life-threatening,
but it is--
- It's terrible.
- We need
a rheumatology consult,
but for right now,
we're giving you
more pain meds
so you can get some rest,
all right?
- The good news, Gia?
According to your scans,
there were no serious injuries
with your crash.
- Oh, I'm so sorry.
I should have never
driven myself.
- Dr. Taylor and I are
just happy you're safe
and getting
the treatment you need.
- Fibromyalgia.
- That's tough.
- Yeah.
So how are you thinking
of treating her?
- There's data on patients
responding very well
to Xyrem.
- Xyrem?
As I recall, it's not
FDA-approved for fibromyalgia.
- Right.
- Yeah, it's only approved
for cataplexy and narcolepsy.
We'd be using it off-label.
And per your new mandates,
our doctors can't prescribe
off-label meds
without the patient's consent.
- And she's sedated now,
so she can't.
- Well, then as soon
as she wakes,
we'll, uh, explain
the situation
and ask for consent.
- Yeah, seems like
your only option.
- Dr. Scott!
I understand we're doing
a transplant
on a patient of yours.
- Yeah, yeah.
I was glad you and Dr. Blake
got the case, man.
- Well, we're gonna take
good care of her, all right?
- Thank you.
- Dylan, I could use
an extra set of hands in here.
- 30-something male. GCS 10.
He was found passed out
in the street, inebriated.
Right arm swollen
and discolored.
- Terrell.
- You know him?
- Yeah, since we were kids.
His son's a patient upstairs.
- Paramedics gave Narcan
in the field,
but zero response.
Still hypothermic.
- Terrell, you hear me?
♪
- Get away from me.
- Look, I'm just trying
to help, man.
- Not you.
- All right, he's rousable.
Let's get this board
out of here.
All right, on three.
One, two, three.
- Temp's 93.
- All right,
let's swap this out
for one of our warmer blankets.
And get him a liter
of NS on the warmer.
Right arm's pretty tight.
Hand's cold.
Can't feel distal, ulnar,
or radial pulse.
- Compartment syndrome.
Heart's a little tachy.
- Foley output.
5cc's of dark urine.
- Dead muscle's
causing him to go into rhabdo.
- Could be disaster
for his kidneys.
- He needs a fasciotomy.
Call Dr. Archer.
- On it.
♪
- Hey.
Any history you can share?
Help us treat him?
- Terrell's kind of a mystery.
When we were kids,
he was funny, smart.
Then he drops out,
starts hanging
with the wrong crowd.
After that,
things went downhill.
- It's tough to see
a life fall apart.
- He's been MIA for a while.
I'm gonna go tell
his wife he's here.
- Yeah.
- All right, thanks.
- Morning.
- Hey.
- Here you go.
I hear that Stevie's
going back to Michigan
to be with her husband?
- Yeah, so?
Don't start with me.
Where is Trini?
- They're short-staffed
at the ICU.
She's covering.
- Well, I need her.
She's supposed to make
a house call with me.
- Oh. I'll go.
- Trini knows the patient,
you don't.
- What?
Am I not the nurse
with more experience
than anyone else down here?
- Sorry, Nurse Lockwood.
I'm sure you've seen it all.
I'm grateful
for your assistance.
- Huh.
Charge Nurse Lockwood.
You're in a good mood.
- So are you.
- Mm-hmm.
- Dr. Hammer.
Good news, huh?
- What's that?
- Your mom.
I was just up
in the Psych Ward.
I saw
that they're discharging her.
- Oh, right. Yeah.
Kind of put them
in their separate corners,
but other than that--
- My mother's here?
Why didn't you tell me?
- I couldn't.
- Why?
- Because she gave me
express orders not to.
- Well, this doesn't
make any sense.
Did you commit her?
- I'm sorry, I can't
discuss that with you.
- She's my mother!
- Doesn't matter, Stevie.
She's a patient here,
and she has rights.
- Okay, where is she?
- Stevie--
- This is ridiculous.
- Come on.
Are you really gonna
make me call security?
♪
- Terri, good morning.
Um.
So Stevie found out
that you're here.
- How is she?
- She's a little confused.
Right? She's--she's angry.
She's--she's hurt.
But, um...
how would you like
to handle this?
What--what would you like
me to tell her?
- Wait here, please.
- What's up?
- Nothing.
Nice.
- Patient's
a financial planner.
He's, uh, done well.
- Mm.
- Dr. Halstead.
- Hey, Lenny.
This is Maggie Lockwood,
our charge nurse.
- Hey.
Ellis is ready.
- Ellis, hi.
- Hey.
Thank you for coming.
- Of course.
I want you to meet my friend,
Maggie Lockwood.
- My pleasure, Maggie.
- Hi.
♪
.
- When I was bathing him
this morning, he looked paler.
- I normally have
a healthy glow.
- Okay.
Well, we're gonna need
to open the box
so I can take a look.
- Can't be for long.
- Polio paralyzed
Ellis's diaphragm
and intercostal muscles,
so without the respirator,
every breath requires
conscious effort.
- Polio.
- Contracted it
when he was five,
a month
before the vaccine came out.
- Good timing, eh?
- Turning it off.
♪
- Those were my ward mates.
- Ellis has been
in the iron lung
for 60 years.
- 63.
But who's counting?
- He's also instructed me
more than once
never to refer to him
as a polio victim.
- Life threw me a curveball,
that's all.
I got lots to be thankful for.
Found some friends,
work I enjoy,
good docs like Halstead.
Hey, how's your love life, huh?
Last time we talked,
it wasn't so good.
- Hasn't gotten any better.
- Mm, I'm all ears.
- Nothing to tell.
Ellis, I'm seeing
peripheral cyanosis
and you're skin is cold.
Maggie, pulse, please.
- Bradycardia.
His HR's in the 50s.
- We need an EKG.
I brought one.
You good
for a few more minutes?
- Oh, yeah.
I need the exercise.
- So, um, your mom
has given me permission
to share her medical history
with you.
- Well, that's big of her.
- Have a seat, please.
- I'm okay.
- So you're mom
admitted herself.
She was very depressed
and, uh, was worried
about self-harm.
- Oh, my God.
- She has been diagnosed
with bipolar disorder.
All right?
Which has, of course,
been exacerbated
by her alcohol abuse.
But admitting herself
to the hospital,
seeking help--
really good sign.
And I have to say,
with, uh--
with treatment, right?
With therapy,
with medication, she's--
- I've been trying
to reach her for weeks.
No answer.
She just hasn't returned
any of my calls.
I'm, um--
I'm moving back to Michigan,
but I didn't know
if I should.
- You know, Stevie,
I'm so sorry that you've had
to go through this.
- Yet you were just fine
keeping me in the dark.
- Look, if it's
any consolation,
you're mom?
She's doing very well.
- Yeah, okay.
But did it have to mean
cutting me out of her life?
♪
- So Doc, am I gonna live?
- Well, our heart rate's
hovering around 49,
not quite the picture
of heart health.
- Any more good news?
- EKG also shows low voltage,
and I wish your BP was higher.
However, these alone don't
point to anything specific.
- Blood work?
- Yeah.
So Ellis, we gotta place a line
so we can collect your samples.
Unfortunately, you know,
the only place
we have access to
is your neck.
- Gets better and better.
- Mr. Turner, I'm gonna
ask you to remain
as still as possible.
- Uh-huh. And shut up.
I--I get it.
- And we're in.
I know a private lab nearby.
I'll have them run the tests.
We'll get a quick turnaround.
- Should I be worried?
- Hey, whatever's causing
your symptoms,
we'll deal with it.
- Okay.
- Sorry about before.
I shouldn't have made that
crack about your love life.
- What's going on with you?
- I'll talk to you
about it later.
You need to get to the lab.
- We won't know the size
of the recipient's
abdominal cavity
until we open her up.
So we'll resect
the donor liver then
according
to the body weight ratio.
- Right, get as close
a match as possible.
- Good morning.
How's everyone doing?
- We're all a little nervous.
- Her most of all.
- Yeah.
So how you feeling?
- Good. Ready to go.
- And how's our recipient?
- Stable, lightly sedated,
but no reason not to proceed.
- They're gonna make you
all well, honey.
- The techs are gonna
be in shortly
to take your daughter
and you, Mr. Byers, to pre-op.
- I love you.
♪
- So we'll see you guys
on the other side, yeah?
You all right?
All right, I'll see you.
Hey, Pamela? Pamela.
Hey, look, I spoke with Avery,
and I made it clear
you had no idea
we'd gone out.
- You mean, so she
wouldn't think
that her mom
was snaking her boyfriend?
- What a mess.
- I know, come on.
I want to make things right.
I want to make things right
between you and me.
Look, I also told Avery
I had--I had feelings for you.
- Okay, stop.
Stop, stop, stop.
I never should have let
myself get involved.
You're a surgeon.
You're on my team.
That's all.
♪
.
- Dr. Taylor, Dr. Shentu,
need you.
O2 started dropping.
I put her on a mask
at 10 liters.
- Need a chest x-ray.
- I'm hearing a rub.
Okay, clear.
- Her heart shadow
looks a little fuzzy.
- Ultrasound?
- Yeah.
- It's gonna be okay, Gia.
- Okay.
Pericardial effusion.
- Why didn't your morning
work up catch it?
- Wasn't on CT,
but things change.
Could be a blunt cardiac injury
from the crash.
We need to perform
pericardiocentesis.
- Dr. Shentu, it's not
indicated at this time.
She's not in tamponade.
- She's protecting her airway,
her condition is not emergent.
- And with a non-emergent
invasive procedure,
we need Gia's permission
before we can perform it.
- Like the Xyrem?
Yes.
Another new guideline.
- Well, let's hope she regains
consciousness soon.
♪
- Resected the left lateral
segment.
- Graft-to-recipient
weight ratio is 4.2%.
- All right,
resection complete.
Go ahead and put that on ice
for Lily's transplant.
Let's get ready to close.
- You're heart rate's
not getting any better.
Same as your BP.
- What are you not telling him?
- What?
- Halstead.
What are you not telling him?
Come on, come on.
I'm in an iron lung.
I'm allowed to be nosy.
- I had a biopsy.
- Cancer, maybe?
And why didn't you tell him?
- I don't want
people worrying about me.
- Yeah, I get that.
I'm not much
for pity parties, myself.
- No.
- So what are you going to do
if it's positive?
- I don't know.
♪
Depends on how serious it is.
Chemo, radiation, surgery.
I'd have to stop working.
- So how are you set
for retirement?
I don't know.
I haven't thought about that.
- Yeah, but you should.
So you want me to take a look
at your financials with you?
- I can't ask you to do that.
- Why not?
- Because you're my patient.
- Get your phone.
Pull up your accounts
and email them to me,
and we'll go over them
together.
- Now?
- Yeah.
- I don't believe
in putting things off.
- Hi, Terrell.
Hi, I am Dr. Archer,
this is Dr. Hammer.
I was the surgeon who performed
a procedure on your forearm.
What happened?
- You were found
near Washington Park.
You were passed out
and laying on your arm,
which lead to a condition
which needed
to be treated surgically.
- You're lucky Dr. Archer
was able to operate so quickly.
It could have been
very serious.
- Does my wife know?
- Yeah, uh, she's here
in the PICU with your son.
- Yeah, she must be so mad.
- Do you want me
to have her come see you?
- No.
No, please.
Not like this.
Can I go home today?
- Well, I wouldn't
recommend it,
but, uh, if you insist--
- I do.
And, um--
and then after I'm dressed,
I'll--I'll see her.
- All right, well,
you rest,
and we'll make sure
you get out of here.
- Living arrangements all set.
And a van is on the way
to pick you up.
- Thank you, Dr. Charles.
- You know, Terri,
there's something
that I've been curious about.
- Yeah?
- When you checked yourself
into a hospital
where you knew
that Stevie worked,
you had to think
that eventually
she was gonna find out
that you were here.
- I did.
I--I wanted to be
near her,
and I thought
eventually I would want
to see her.
- But...
- The better I got,
the more I felt I was
turning my life around,
the less I wanted to see her.
Does that sound terrible?
- No.
- I love my daughter.
I--I do,
but she can be negative.
Even if she doesn't say it,
Stevie always thinks I'll fail.
I know I've given her
plenty of reasons
to think that, but--
- Not necessarily something
you need right now.
- No.
- Ah, Dr. Shentu.
You know, I heard
about your inability
to treat your patient.
But hey,
you stand by your rules.
Somebody's gotta set
an example.
- Dr. Shentu?
Dr. Taylor needs you.
- I decided
to scan her heart again
just to be sure, and look.
You can see
the beginning stages of--
- Diastolic collapse
of the right ventricle.
- It's a sign of impending
cardiac tamponade.
- Congratulations,
her condition is now emergent.
We can perform
the pericardiocentesis
without consent.
Doris, bolus fluids.
Add 125 milligrams
of solumedrol,
and set up a pericardial tap.
- Heart rate 145,
BP 88/48.
- She's tanking.
♪
What do you think?
Maybe this could
have been avoided?
.
- You mind?
- Come on in.
- Um, my mom...
was, uh, was she bipolar
her whole life?
- The disorder does tend
to be genetic,
but it doesn't usually present
till late teens, early 20s.
- And the drinking? The drugs?
- Most likely an attempt
to self-medicate her condition.
You know, problem is,
it just invariably
makes it worse.
- I used to get
so angry at her.
I thought she was
a drug addict.
- Happens all the time.
You know, a, uh,
a psychiatric illness
goes undiagnosed,
people just assume
that it's an addiction issue.
- I thought the drinking,
drugs, were the cause,
not the other way around.
- I mean, situations like that,
they can, in a strange way,
turn into kind of a--
a self-fulfilling prophecy.
- Yeah, I'm always just, uh,
waiting for her
to fall apart again.
- Well, of course you are,
because that's what she did
over and over again
your entire life.
Stevie, you gotta try
and take it easy on yourself.
I think you should be
giving yourself credit for...
Recognizing the importance
of seeing
somebody that you love
in a new way.
♪
- Okay, um, so if you do
have to stop working,
you'll want
a risk-averse portfolio.
So I'd--I'd get you
out of the mutual funds
and put you in dividend stocks,
and, uh, maybe an annuity.
- It's my doctor.
- Go ahead.
- Hello?
Yeah.
Thank you.
- Your biopsy?
- Yeah.
- Negative?
Well, that's good news.
Why aren't you jumping
up and down?
- This isn't
my first go-around.
I've had cancer before.
And I guess the--
the possibility
of it coming back,
it just--
- It will always be a worry.
Can I give you a little advice?
Okay.
- We all live
on a razor's edge.
Everybody.
Just some of us know it
more than others.
In a way, we're the lucky ones.
We have the good sense to...
Cherish every moment.
- So it looks like we'll
keep you in the mutual funds.
- Okay.
- All right,
making the chevron incision.
- Ready?
- So now you'll stay
in the ICU for observation,
and tomorrow you'll be
transferred to Rheumatology.
There they'll work up a plan
to address your fibromyalgia.
- Thank you, Dr. Shentu.
- Okay.
Ms. Goodwin,
about the, uh, directives
that I recently implemented,
I think some of them
might be too stringent,
given the frenzied nature
of an ED.
I will adjust them accordingly.
- If you think that's best.
- Ah, well played, Ms. Goodwin.
Well played.
I'm assuming that was
the precise outcome
you were hoping for
when you assigned
Dr. Shentu to the case?
- Dr. Archer,
you have a devious mind.
- Maybe not as devious
as yours.
- What kind of person
even becomes
a compliance officer, anyway?
- He's a good guy.
And a good doctor.
- Well.
Look at you.
Dr. Shentu?
- Yes?
- I was wondering
if you'd like
to go to a concert
with me tonight?
Durand Jones.
I've got an extra ticket.
If you think it's appropriate.
- Huh.
You mean, uh,
within my guidelines?
Um, yes.
I would love to go.
- Wow, this is great.
I didn't think
there was anywhere
you could still make 5%.
- Ellis?
Ellis, talk to me.
Ellis?
He just lost consciousness.
- I got his labs back.
Thyroid function's
in the toilet.
I'm hoping this levothyroxine
will do the trick.
- Poor guy, everything
he's been through...
- Hey, if anybody
can beat this, it's Ellis.
♪
- Terrell, how you feeling?
- Uh, okay.
Now when can I get out of here?
- Well, your vitals are good.
I just need you to sign
discharge forms.
- Where?
- Oh, just your signature here.
And then just check the box
that says that you agree
to the terms and conditions.
- There's two boxes?
- Oh, the one that says
"I agree."
- Yeah, uh--
- That one.
- No, yeah, right.
Right, right, right, right.
- You know, you're probably
gonna be here for a bit.
Why don't you order yourself
some food?
- Yeah, so what's good?
- Uh, nothing.
But, uh, if I was you,
I'd probably get
the roast beef.
- Yeah, the roast beef...
- Roast beef.
- Yeah, roast beef.
- Great.
I'll let the nurses know.
I'll get this in the works.
♪
Hey.
Terrell.
I'm pretty sure he can't read.
- Can't read?
- People can be
really good at hiding it.
You had no idea?
- No.
- He had trouble
with the discharge forms.
He couldn't read the menu.
- I mean, he dropped out
of high school at 17,
be he knew how to read by then.
- Unless that's why
he dropped out.
- You know,
come to think of it,
he did always have trouble
telling left from right.
We'd make jokes about it.
And he'd mix up words.
You know, I've seen
kids like that.
Stevie, don't discharge him
yet, all right?
- Yeah.
- All right.
.
- Damn, you again, huh?
- Since you lost consciousness,
we need to do
a brief neuro exam.
Standard--
- Where's Dr. Hammer?
- You know, I'm sorry,
but she had an emergency.
- Well, you're not
doing it.
- Aw, come on, T.
Just let me do this,
and then you can
get out of here.
- All right.
All right, let's just
get it over with.
- Okay, so without
moving your head,
follow my finger.
Good. All right.
Now, I'ma say
four things to you,
and I need you
to repeat them back to me
in the order
that I say them, okay?
- Whatever.
- All right.
Cow, pig, duck, horse.
Cow.
Pig.
Duck.
Horse.
- Horse.
Pig, duck, cow.
- All right.
Now, with your good hand,
I need you to touch
your nose, ear, and chin.
- Come on, man, what was that?
- Nose, ear, chin.
- All right,
let's get you processed.
- Hurry up.
- Okay, all bile ducts
reattached.
Finished up the hepatic artery.
Removing clamps.
- Yeah, not hearing
any systemic circulation.
- Yeah, liver's
not pinking up either.
- Looks like hepatic artery
thrombosis.
We're gonna need
to remove that clot.
Get me a small Fogarty balloon
and 500 units of heparin,
Betty.
- Reopening the hepatic
arterial anastomosis.
- Sats down to 91.
- Inflate.
- The balloon's too small.
Next size catheter, right?
- The patient's
not even a year old.
Any wider and we risk
perforating the vessel.
- Well, I don't see
as we have any other choice.
- Reset. One size up.
♪
Oh, this one feels too tight.
I do not want
to rupture this artery.
- Sats are still lowering.
86. 84.
- We might have to go back
to the smaller catheter.
- Why don't you let me try?
I might have a better angle.
- Here.
♪
Crockett.
- Give me a sec.
Now.
Here's the clot.
- Sats climbing.
88, 93.
96 and holding.
- Moment of truth.
- Yeah.
Looks like an adequate flow.
- A quick turnaround, Ellis.
I'm impressed.
- Quality medical care.
- I'm gonna send over
an endocrinologist,
make sure this doesn't
happen again.
- Thank you, Doc.
- Hey, take care.
♪
- You gonna be okay?
- I should be asking you that.
- Nice meeting you,
Nurse Lockwood.
- You too.
both: Bye.
- Can I give you a kiss?
Sure.
♪
- Here.
So you asked what was going on.
I had a biopsy.
- Oh, Maggie.
- No, no, no, no.
It's benign.
I'm okay.
- That's great news.
- Yeah, it is.
- Well, long as
we're coming clean,
I wish Stevie was staying.
But like Ellis says,
life can throw you a curveball.
♪
- Terrell, honey,
let him speak.
It's important.
- You need to be tested
by a specialist,
but I believe you have
a neurological condition
called dyslexia.
Something you were born with.
- Dyslexia?
- It affects how the brain
processes information.
You know how you've
always had trouble
with left and right,
and how you mix up words.
- Everybody does that.
- It's, uh...
It's why you never learned
to read.
- Dude, who says I can't read?
- Terrell, come on.
Listen, it's not your fault.
And it doesn't mean
that you're not smart.
- No, no. Not at all.
- It's a learning disability.
It has nothing to do
with intelligence.
You should have been
diagnosed as a kid
and helped,
but, psh, let's face it,
our school?
They didn't have the funding
for that kind of thing.
- I thought I was stupid.
- No. No, baby. No.
- It's not too late
to change things, bro.
Dyslexia is not
all that uncommon,
and there's plenty
that can be done for you.
♪
- His life could have been
so different if he'd known.
- That was great work today,
Dr. Marcel.
- Thank you. You too.
- Okay, well, good night.
- Good night.
- Oh, God, Crockett...
It's better this way.
- Is it?
Not the way I see it.
♪
- Dan--
- Lonnie, just hear me out.
- No, there's something
I gotta say to you.
A colleague of mine
had this pretty...
remarkable breakthrough today
where they--
they were able see somebody
who had been in their life
for a long, long time,
in a completely
different light.
And it--it kind of
got me thinking,
um, you know, I've been, um,
I've kind of been at sea
since you told me that you
couldn't be
my therapist anymore.
And I thought
that that was because
what I missed was
the work that we did together.
But now what I'm thinking,
is maybe...
Maybe what I really miss
is you.
♪
- Hi, honey.
- Come on in.
- Thanks for seeing me.
- Sure.
It's my own space.
I feel safe.
- It's really nice, Mom.
- There's a rec room,
showers...
- And we're self-governed.
No one tells us what to do.
- Oh, honey,
I wasn't talking about you.
- It's okay, Mom.
- Would you like some tea?
- Yeah, that'd be great.
♪
Listen, Mom...
Are you gonna be okay
with me leaving?
- I'll be fine, Stevie.
And...
I'm really going
to make it this time.
- I know you are.
- I love you.
♪