Elmira. CARTER: Mexico?
Upstate New York. Chloe stayed
in a motel there for two weeks.
- The cops told you?
- It showed up on Joe's credit-card bill.
- Who's Joe?
- Her husband. Or ex-husband.
- He's driving up there.
- Can you hold that?
- Is it numb, Mr. Cannillo?
- My whole face is numb.
Maybe I should too. God knows what
she's doing. Suzy needs to be in school.
- Ow!
- Got it.
Okay, watch that back
cast next time, Mr. Cannillo.
Chloe could lose her in a heartbeat,
and we might not be so lucky again.
- I need the Wooly Bugger back.
- On the tray.
You could have her
declared an unfit mother.
- Then Joe gets Suzy.
- If he wants her.
I don't know. TOBY: Hey, lady!
Where in the hell's my leg?
- I believe it was amputated.
- Not the real one, moron. My prosthetic.
- You had one when you came in, Toby?
- Yes. She took it. Give it back.
- Why would I want your leg?
- You tell me, pervert.
Can you describe the leg?
Looks just like this
one, only it's plastic.
We'll see if we can get you one.
Haleh, fly fisher needs a tetanus shot.
Check central supply, see if
we have extra orthopedic legs.
- Somebody stole Toby's leg again.
- Uh-huh.
- Thanks for defending me.
- The guy needs a free leg.
You got both of yours.
- Is the server down again?
- Half-hour. We're loading new software.
Did we get the LP
results back on Jessup?
- You know where the fax machine is?
- Frank, did a match letter come?
- Do I look like the postmaster?
- Match letters are at the dean's office.
I know that, genius. I forgot to
pick it up. They said they sent it here.
- You forgot to pick it up?
- I had a date.
Hey, when did this come in?
- What?
This letter. Dr. Greene.
Stick it in his box.
I'll mail it to his home.
- No, it's from Dr. Greene.
- To who?
- Everyone, I guess.
- What's it say?
- It says, "Dear ER gang..."
- We're a gang now?
- Got a secret handshake and everything.
- While you were in Phoenix.
- Go on, Carter.
- "Dear ER gang:
So here I am out on the
beach at 5:30 in the evening.
Elizabeth is sitting with me drinking
juice, but I'm all about the mai tais."
- What's he reading?
- Dr. Greene's letter.
"The sun is going down. Rachel
is dipping Ella's toes in the ocean...
as they head off on a quest
for the perfect seashell."
- "Wish you were here" would've done it.
- He doesn't have to rub it in.
"would make this moment complete?
Some jogger dropping to the sand...
short of breath, so I can swoop
in with a piece of bamboo...
- to perform a nice, clean intubation...
- What's this?
- Mark.
- Fix the guy up and send him off...
with a good simple dispo."
The day I start fantasizing about
critical procedures is the day I leave too.
"Which is my way of saying that I
miss you all and that dingy place."
- Want another five
of...? KOVAC: Dr. Greene.
"Lots of times, I thought I should
have chosen a different career...
or gone into private practice. Something
easier, less grinding, more lucrative.
But since I've been gone, I realize
outside of what I'm doing right now...
sitting on this beach
with my family...
staying at County all those years
doing what we do on a daily basis...
was the best choice I ever made.
I know what you're thinking. Trust me, it's
not hard to appreciate once it's over."
I think that's the
mai tais talking.
Shut up. Keep reading.
"As much as part of me would like to
believe the ER can't go on without me...
the smarter part realizes that you're an
incredible group of doctors and nurses...
who approach every day with such
skill, compassion and thoroughness.
And when it comes to patient care, I
know my absence will hardly be felt."
I'm not so sure of that.
"As for friendship and camaraderie,
well, that's another matter.
In order to leave, I
had to go the way I did.
But I wouldn't want any of you to think
that meant I didn't value each of you...
and the years that
we worked together...
or that I didn't have things of
a more personal nature to say.
Most of you, I think, have an
idea of what those things might be...
without me writing
them down. But still..."
Go on.
There's just a
couple dots and then:
"Ella is laughing and waving
for me. Rachel's found her shell."
Nothing else?
Probably jammed. Damn
machine's been on the fritz all week.
Is there a transmission report?
- So he faxes the letter...
so he doesn't have to
send the macadamia nuts.
What? What is it?
This is from Dr. Corday.
"Mark died this morning...
at 6:04 a.m.
The sun was rising...
his favorite time of day.
I sent this on so that you might
know he was thinking of you all...
and that...
he appre...
He appreciated knowing
you would remember him well."
Post it on the floor, Frank.
That last part?
The whole thing.
It ain't my heart.
Cold, that's all.
And I need some of
that breathing stuff.
BP's 100/76.
Sally bolus?
Sally?
Bolus normal saline,
start an insulin drip.
- Work him up first.
- Where's my cart?
- CBC, lytes, BUN, creatinine.
- Wait, he's a brittle diabetic in DKA.
- We need to lower his sugar.
- You don't know his sugar.
- Get Dr. Greene. He knows what to do.
- Mr. Ervin, he's not here today.
- Then I'll come back later.
- No. You might have fluid in your lungs.
- And you have a high fever.
- Fever?
I'm colder than that hawk
out there on a windy day.
- DKA, I'm telling you.
- Send up LFTs.
- You want his bank statements also?
- Last time someone stole my dictionary.
Bet 20 he's over 400.
Dr. Carter?
- What?
- Twenty bucks says glucose is over 400.
Just plug him in.
Dr. Weaver?
Ahem, Dr. Weaver?
When did this get...?
You were at lunch.
And you felt the need to
post it on the bulletin board?
Well, he wrote it to the ER.
- Do you want us to take it down?
- No.
- Double MVA coming. Father, daughter.
- Carter and Lewis.
- And George cut himself again.
- In a minute.
Auto versus cement truck. 10-year-old,
unrestrained back-seat passenger...
- flew to the front, hit deployed air bag.
- I'm Dr. Lewis. What's your name?
- Melissa.
- Melissa, were you knocked out?
- No.
- Does it hurt?
- My chest.
- Dan Rue...
36-year-old restrained driver.
Throat to steering wheel, knee to
dashboard, with hip and pelvis pain.
- LOC?
- No. GCS, 13.
- Can you tell me where it hurts most?
- Right leg and my throat.
All right. Page Surgery. Tell RT to get
the heliox. Has his voice changed much?
- Maybe a little.
- Is my daughter here?
- Tachy at 108. LEWIS:
Full trauma panel.
Follow the light with your eyes.
BP? HALEH: Cycling.
- Melissa, did you hurt your neck at all?
- No.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
It's okay, sweetie. It's okay.
We're gonna take care of you.
- Where's my dad?
- Another doctor's helping him.
Okay, I'm gonna take this
off. I need you to be really still.
- Okay.
- Like a statue.
- Yes.
- Okay, here we go.
Oh, good girl. Lateral
C-spine, chest and pelvis.
Pressure's 100/70.
- Is the fiberoptic in here?
- Back counter.
What's his pressure?
- Ninety-five.
Dad! LEWIS: Head still.
- Is that my dad?
- Tender at the left axilla.
- Might be a rib fracture.
- HemoCue times three and a Foley.
Pupils 5 millimeters and reactive.
- Abby.
- Sorry.
- Hang two units O-neg. I need a crit.
- Sats are falling, 92.
- Got the scope.
Okay, we gotta crike him.
Get me some cervical
traction and oral airway.
Sinus tach on the
monitor. No ectopy.
Oh, God. CARTER: What?
Large hematoma in
front of the trachea.
- You got to be kidding me.
- Can you cut through that?
No. I won't be able to see
anything through all that blood.
Pulse ox is not corresponding.
- I can't feel the landmarks.
- We need an airway.
- Damn it.
- What do you want to do?
Give me the scope.
- First HemoCue, 13.4.
- What are we talking about?
- Give me some cricoid pressure.
- On what?
- Dial up the source all the way.
- Anybody home?
Swollen airway. Expanding
hematoma blocking trach access.
- How long's he been down?
- Two minutes.
- Crike him.
- Too many vessels.
- 11 blade now.
- No. Just wait, I can't see as it is.
- Trousseau dilater.
- Pulse ox, 84.
- Bradying down.
- Wait, I'm almost underneath it.
- Cutting.
- No, wait. Wait! I said, wait.
His heart rate's 60. Most
chief residents know he'll arrest.
We don't have an
airway. So mg of atropine.
- Dropping to 50.
- Trauma shears.
What are you doing?
- Just clamp. ABBY:
BP's 80 systolic.
No. You're gonna
hit the internal carotid.
Tracheostomy.
- Field airway. JARVIK:
Sats are climbing.
Dr. Lewis? JARVIK: Next door.
Call RT for a vent. AC 12, 750 cc tidal
on a 100%. Less whining, more action...
- next time, Dr. Carter. LEWIS:
No deformity. No step-off.
- Dr. Lewis? LEWIS:
How about here?
- A little.
- Five-by-seven mass over the scapula.
- Let's have Surgery take a look at this.
- Susan, it's your sister.
- What?
- She's on the phone.
No. Chloe, you disappear with
Suzy after almost killing yourself.
You don't call for three
weeks. Yeah, well, I hope so.
Are you in an
outpatient program?
Where's Suzy gonna stay?
He took you back?
Oh, damn it.
No. No, not you, Chloe.
You know what? Fine. Fine, fine,
fine. Just give me the number, okay?
Yeah, Chloe, listen.
Yeah, I have to go.
Chloe, I have to go.
Yes, I love you too.
CT's ready. Urine is
dip negative for blood.
Forget the Foley.
Page Pedes, Oncology.
Calcified mass
in the lung field.
She has cancer?
- Keep your ankle cocked.
- You promised...
not to use the knife.
A.J. called in sick.
I tried to be careful.
Don't touch it.
- That was too long.
- It's fine.
- It's too long. It will itch.
- Okay, I'm done.
- Who's picking you up?
- I took the train.
- I'll get you a cab voucher. Keep it dry.
- Plastic bag like before.
Come back in 10 days.
I did this last time. I saw on
TV, those cutters where you put...
the bun in a covered white thing
and press down on the handle...
and it slices without
using the knife.
I asked Lance to
get one of those.
But he said those guys are
crooks and it would break right away.
- What are you doing?
- This one's too long.
Stop it. Stop it. George.
I told you not to touch
it. Damn it, George.
- I'm sorry.
- I don't care if you're sorry.
I don't care if you're stupid. If
you don't listen, it'll never heal.
Kerry, I'll do it.
You should go home.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry,
George. I'm sorry.
- Casper's Foley bag is full.
- I know.
I don't know why I bought hoops.
- They were cute.
- Yeah.
The 3-year-old in
4 thought so too.
Did you think it was
gonna happen so soon?
He stopped treatment.
Yeah, I know. But still, I
mean, he was just here working.
I keep expecting to see him
walk around a corner or something.
He was 38 years old.
Too soon by any calculation.
Yeah.
Hey, when are you off?
Now. Just don't
feel like going home.
What do you say we
go out and get plastered?
- I'd say that's an appropriate response.
- Susan, I have to go.
Bohan is an IUP, 12
weeks and spotting.
Ultrasound's otherwise negative.
Okay. Carter's on for
another couple hours.
I'm waiting on a parent to
transfer a girl to Oncology.
Okay.
I'm sorry about Mark.
Yeah.
Hey, Kerry.
Hey, Kerry, we're going out
for drinks. You want to come?
- Thanks. I'd like to, but I can't.
- Yeah, sure you can.
- The Lava Lounge on Damen.
- I have other plans.
- But thanks anyway.
- Okay.
- Good night.
- Bye.
- The Lava Lounge?
- Yeah, you kind of have to see it.
Dr. Romano needs you.
Tell him I'm icing my ear.
He's putting a chest
tube in your patient.
- What?
- He came down for a consult.
I canceled that consult.
28 French on a vascular
clamp. Hang in there, Melissa.
- What are you doing?
- Where's her CT?
Oncology has it. - Oncology?
Incidental finding. Likely
Rhabdomyosarcoma.
- Did she have a hemopneumo?
- No.
- She does now.
- What is it?
We're gonna put a tube in
your chest to help you breathe.
I'm in. Thoraseal. Probably
outgrew its blood supply...
bled into her chest cavity.
Come on. My dog fetches faster.
- Is my mom here yet?
- Yeah, she's on her way.
Call the O.R. Tell them we
have a red blanket. Get consent.
Her father's in the SICU.
You criked him, remember?
Melissa, you need an operation.
- What?
We're gonna take care of you.
200 cc's already.
Second signature. Let's go.
Don't worry.
- We'll blow it off, go some other night.
- No. You changed your shift.
Kerry, the guy died. You
should be with your staff tonight.
- They were being polite.
- They're your friends.
They're people I work with.
One of our guys goes down, the
company gets together and we get drunk.
It's more for the unit
than the guy who's gone.
I'm not a firefighter.
Basically the same job,
isn't it? You put out fires.
Mark and I always butted heads.
I was always trying
to maneuver him...
gain some kind of edge
like it had to be a competition.
He just wanted to do
his job well and go home.
I've known this was coming for
a while, and I never imagined...
that I would feel like this.
You've lost a friend.
I think I have.
All I got out of him was, they put him on
dialysis for three days once. He hated it.
Then he passed out.
- As in vagalled?
- As in old.
- Find his old chart?
- Still pulling it. I need a forklift.
His temp's down, but he's
altered. He called me "son" once.
Glucose is over 400.
You owe me 20 bucks.
Started that insulin drip.
And he could be uremic.
You know, your basic "MMP."
- MMP?
- Multiple medical problems.
You just make this stuff up?
What? Multiple medical
problems? M-M-P, MMP.
All right, start with a urogram
and do a repeat Chem-20.
- I did it twice already.
- Just CT his belly and his pelvis...
- and call Nephrology.
- They won't take him. He's septic.
Well, then we'll dialyze down
here until we can admit to the unit.
Or we could turf him to
Medicine and let them figure it out.
Right now he belongs to us.
I'm gonna write this down now. Sure
you're not gonna change your mind again?
- Pratt, your letter.
- Where was it?
Filed N for "ne'er-do-well."
- What's your first choice?
- I ain't saying.
See you at the Lava
Lounge, Dr. Carter?
- What?
- Couple people going out for drinks.
- Don't feel like doing much else.
- Who?
Dr. Kovac, Dr. Lewis,
Abby, Haleh.
Maybe. I don't know. I got
some dictations I need to finish.
Okay. If you change your mind...
Good night.
Bad news?
- Yeah, you could say that.
- Second choice?
Last choice.
Someone's got to get their
last choice. Where is it?
- Here.
- Oh.
Good for us.
You know, I better be
getting my damn locker.
Well, that was fast.
- What?
- You haven't even had a drink yet...
- you already got somebody's number?
- Oh, my God. What is that?
- Two Sacrificial Virgins.
- How much alcohol is in there?
Enough to make you forget
you're being thrown into a volcano.
I get it.
- I think.
- Do you need some help?
Yeah. Can I start a tab?
Sure, Susan.
Oh, my God. Those
are our drinks?
- Too tacky?
- No, not for this place.
- I'm just bummed I forgot my grass skirt.
- Yeah.
I was gonna wear my
coconut bra, but it itches.
- How did you know about this place?
- Mark had a birthday here once.
It seemed appropriate.
Thanks. ABBY: Haleh.
Martini.
- Coke.
- Yeah. How did they find all this stuff?
It's kind of creepy. I keep
expecting Vincent Price to show up.
So should we toast or something?
Good idea.
Me?
You knew him the longest.
I'm not very good under
pressure. Someone else go first.
What the hell,
I'll drink to that.
Looks like we're going public.
Hey, Kerry.
Hey.
Well-encapsulated discreet mass.
No extension to
the visceral pleura.
Pickups.
Did you talk to Dr. Corday?
Yeah, Shirley, I'm
at the top of her list.
Right after the funeral home.
Aah! SHIRLEY: What?
Penetrated the rib cage. We
are gonna be here all night.
At least you caught it.
Amazing how the human body...
can turn on itself.
The very process we need to grow
in the womb to regenerate ourselves...
systematically eating us alive.
And no one's sacred.
Little girls. Fathers
with little girls.
Cancer. Brain cancer,
liver cancer, breast cancer.
It's the same traitor,
the same merciless...
unrelenting predator.
Like time itself.
I hope you're not driving. - No.
You're not on call, are you?
What are you, some
sort of Nazi bartender?
I prefer to think of
myself as magnanimous.
Hey. LEWIS: Hey, Carter.
- We thought you were gonna blow us off.
- Did you pick this place?
- She's outside.
- Who?
John Carter makes an appearance.
Abigail Lockhart sits alone.
- It's a nice jacket. Is it new?
- What, do you have ESP?
No, your car's right there.
I saw you circle
the building twice.
Thanks for yelling
out directions.
Didn't wanna encourage you. I don't
think you should be hanging around in bars.
You got me there.
Great letter, though.
I especially enjoyed
the surprise ending.
I didn't write it.
Well, that's the last time
we let you read out loud then.
Suddenly antisocial?
No, you just missed
my table dance.
- Hula?
- Oh, yeah.
Well, I'll have to stick
around for the second show.
How many lives do you think?
What?
How many lives do
you think he saved?
It's hard to say.
One a shift on average, I guess.
Five shifts a week for 10 years.
- Two or three thousand people.
- Damn.
Forget Superman,
I'll take Mark Greene.
Well, if I knew you felt that way, I would
have shaved my head a long time ago.
Are you okay?
Come on.
- Come on what?
- Let's get out of here.
- And ditch our friends?
- I think that they'll get over it.
Okay.
- You know, I have a tiki mask in there.
- I'll buy you another one.
Where are we going?
I know a place on Franklin.
- The titty bar?
- No.
Well...
- Oh, the tattoo parlor.
- No.
No. Where are we going?
Bill's place.
No.
- No, thank you.
- Come on. There's a meeting at 1.
- Great. Go. I'll catch up.
- When's the last time you went?
What's it gonna hurt?
- It'll kill my buzz for starters.
- Come on, one step at a time.
I sponsored you. Remember? Save
the dogma. Besides, you screwed it up.
- I'm screwing it up?
- Yes. Would you say that I'm drunk?
- Yeah.
- You can't go to meetings drunk.
- They'll overlook it.
- And the program is voluntary.
- Then get in the car voluntarily.
- Come on, out of my way.
You are going, even
if I have to carry you.
- Thanks for caring, but not tonight.
- Yeah, tonight.
- No. Slow down, tough guy.
- Get in the car.
- No.
- No, no.
- Hey.
- Hey, no. John! Stop.
- You're going.
Stop it. Help! Help!
- Aah! Son of a bitch! You bit me?
- You dropped me.
- I can't believe you bit me.
- I told you to put me down.
- I think that might be bleeding.
- Good.
Everything okay out here?
- Yeah.
I'm sorry. I just... I can't...
I can't go to a meeting
tonight. I won't do it.
Let's go get something to eat.
Come on. A cup of coffee.
Thank you.
We gotta stop at a pharmacy. I'll
get some gauze and bandage that.
A crate?
- Four feet by two feet.
- Greene gets a crate of live lobsters...
- for a pericardiocentesis?
- Every Memorial Day.
I gave a Heimlich to a kid at the
zoo once, didn't even get a thank-you.
I've been working
up to a fruit basket.
Wait. Is this the surf and
turf we had on the roof?
Yeah.
That was good.
- We can't tell him.
- Tell him what?
That he's dead.
We have to keep it coming.
That's a survivor talking.
We're starting breakfast.
You want anything?
- Yeah. Two mimosas, please.
- Excuse me?
No, we're fine.
It started on my birthday.
What?
I didn't start drinking when Brian
hit me. I started drinking before that.
And I probably wouldn't have been stupid
enough to open the door if I hadn't been.
Self-pity excuse.
Well, it's one of
my better ones.
What time is it?
Oh, God. It's almost 6:00. Oh,
my God. I have to work tonight.
- You sober?
- Unfortunately.
Good. Then I have got just enough
time to drop you off at a meeting.
No. I have to go to bed.
- Let's go.
- Nope.
But if you quit bugging
me, I promise I'll go later.
When?
Before my shift.
Good, you're here. I was gonna page
you, but Jerry said you were on at 7.
- You're on at 7?
- Yeah. I've done it before.
- What is it?
- It's your homeless guy.
- Six-beat run of ectopy.
- How long has that been going on?
Almost an hour. I
needed to start lido...
but I couldn't get a directive in
his chart, and he won't tell me.
She don't listen.
70 milligrams IV load and then
start a drip at two per minute.
- Wait. So he's full code?
- There he goes again.
I don't know. He was Greene's
private patient or something.
- Yeah, we lost his pressure.
- Mr. Ervin?
- No pulse.
- Okay, starting CPR.
- You sure?
- No.
- Slow PEA.
- Mg of epi. Prep an amp of atropine.
Well, guess that clears
it up. Intubation tray.
I'll do it. 7.5 ET
and a 3 Mac blade.
V-fib. CARTER: Okay,
charge paddles to 200.
No pressure, no pulse.
And clear.
All right, charge again to 300.
Back to sinus.
I've got a pulse.
Tough old bird. Okay, 20
of etomidate, eight of Pav.
Wait, wait, wait. Carter,
I think he's trying to talk.
Dr. Greene.
- No.
- What?
No tubes.
No shocks.
What did he say?
He said no more.
- Thanks for destroying my night.
- Did you get it?
She bled like stink. Control was
nearly impossible around the rib cage.
I was inside and outside
the chest simultaneously.
- Did you get it?
- Yeah, I got it.
Resected fully.
Margins are clear.
- How's Daddy?
- Breathing over the vent.
Reflexes fully intact. Should
be extubated by this afternoon.
It was lucky they got
plowed by that cement truck.
These suckers rate 50%
mortality once they break out.
I'll tell Mom. You should get
some sleep. You look like crap.
Dr. Romano, are
you sure you got it?
I got it.
The only thing he's been consistent
about is not wanting any treatment.
If he discussed this with Dr. Greene,
then there should be a note in the charts.
- Maybe Dr. Greene expected to be here.
- Fine. He's your patient.
I have no idea what
you're saying. I'm sorry.
- Should someone save him?
- No.
I don't understand.
- What's the problem, Pratt?
- I don't speak Portuguese.
- That's Italian.
- That either.
Grandma was babysitting,
and he woke up with this rash.
She can't tell me if he's got any
allergies, and I can't find the parents.
Strawberry.
- What?
- Strawberry. Jelly, jam, maybe cereal.
Probably eating it
before he went to sleep.
Hey, you know anybody
at Northwestern?
- Yeah, I know a few.
- Could you do me a favor?
Tell them they made a mistake,
that they should take me.
- No. I'd have to believe that.
- Come on, you know I'm good.
- Too good to be wasted at County?
- I didn't say that.
Look, we're an under-serviced
community, and we need doctors.
For better or for
worse, we drew you.
Blood sugar over
400. Good pick-up.
Yeah, thanks.
I shouldn't have sat down.
If I don't sit down, I won't cry.
- Well, you have to sit down eventually.
- Yeah.
Can't I just pretend he moved to the
South Pacific and lived happily ever after?
In a way, he did.
A girl and her father...
are hit by a cement truck
on the way to ballet class.
A malignant tumor invades her
chest, and we find it by happenstance.
She'll walk out of here in a
week with not a care in the world.
Mark walked the halls of a hospital every
day and didn't know about his tumor...
till he presented with symptoms.
Well, we save who we can, right?
It has to make more
sense than that.
You're looking for a reason?
I miss him already.
- Me too.
- I went away for five years.
I thought of him on occasion.
Talked to him sporadically.
But I miss him. I thought
he'd always, always be here.
Well, it's good to miss him.
It's missing him
that keeps him here.
Yeah.
Hey.
You should write for Hallmark.
I have hidden talents.
- I'm sorry.
- No, no. It's okay.
I have to get back to work.
I have a pilonidal cyst
in 5 waiting to be lanced.
Give it to Pratt. He
needs the humility.
That will be cathartic.
- Where did you get that?
- What?
- Combination.
- Personnel.
Pratt matched at County.
Yes, I know.
He keeps bitching about it.
He needs a locker.
Thought I'd spare
Elizabeth the chore.
Heard you had some trouble
with Romano yesterday.
He was right.
- I took too long making a decision.
- You don't have that luxury anymore.
I never really thought I did.
Mark's gone.
That means you've been here
longer than any other doctor.
People will look to you
to step in and fill the void.
Big void.
Yes, it is.
I can't do this.
Will you do this?
Thank you.
Shotgun to the face.
This is gonna be fun, huh?
Cheaper than plastic surgery.
How's the bite?
I'm not howling at the moon.
There is no moon.
- How did it go?
- What?
The meeting.
It was boring.
You went?
Yeah. I just said it
was boring, didn't I?
Sorry, they didn't
give me a card.
You went for you or because
you promised me you would?
Is this guy gonna
look like hamburger?
More like ground chuck.
I went for you.
- You're gonna need some more people.
- Why?
Come on, hard restraints!
- No IV?
- 20 of morphine before he pulled out.
- Sir, we need you to hold still.
- Come on, Gallant, keep him on the table.
- 100 of fent, two of Ativan.
- Page Surgery, Plastics, Head and Neck.
- Could be PCP.
- Or the gunshot wound.
Sir, we're gonna help you.
But you gotta hold still...
- while we get the morphine into you.
- Okay, pressure 100/80. Pulse, 150.
Get access. We
need to sedate him.
- Get a 7.5 ET tube.
- You won't be able to use it.
- Break open lap pads and a crike tray.
- Gallant, hold down his arm.
Seven sterile... - Gallant.
And an 11 blade. Drape his neck.
- All right, fent's in.
Get some O-2 in him. 100% by mask.
- I'm pushing meds.
- Gallant. Gallant.
- Okay, okay, okay.
He's settling down. Betadine.
- 20 of etomidate.
- Wait, are we tubing him or criking him?
- Criking. Look at his face.
- Just taking a peek.
- All right, bradying down.
- Yeah, he aspirated too much blood.
- Open the crash cart.
- Gallant, unroof his jaw...
and hold it out of the way.
I need to see the epiglottis.
Mg of atropine.
Susan, hook your
finger under his tongue.
I can't do it.
Don't move. Abduct the mandible.
- I need to sit down.
- Don't move.
V-tach. CARTER: All
right, I'm in. Let go, Gallant.
- Charge is 200.
- Hyperventilating.
Sats are 90. LEWIS: Clear.
- Sinus rhythm.
- Okay, full trauma panel.
C-spine, chest and pelvis. Gallant,
why don't you go get yourself some air?
Want a facial CT?
Yeah, good idea. Why don't we get a full
head series? Call RT. Let's get a vent.
Give him four of
Ativan, seven of Pav.
Nice work, John.
Bet that was a new one.
Yeah. Yeah.
Look, I'm sorry.
I just thought I
was gonna be sick.
It's better if you
keep your head down.
It'll be okay. It just caught
me by surprise, you know?
Relax. Take a minute.
You know, sometimes I
don't think I can do this.
You know, there's
two kinds of doctors.
There's the kind that
get rid of their feelings...
and the kind that
hold on to them.
If you're gonna hold on to your feelings,
you're gonna get sick once in a while.
It's part of it.
You know, people come in here...
and they're sick...
and they're bleeding...
sometimes they're dying...
and they need our help.
And helping them is more
important than how we feel.
Hell, I've been doing this
eight years. I still get sick.
Take another minute.
- Did he go up?
- OMFS, ENT and Plastics all in.
Both carotids and IJ's intact. He must
have turned right when the blast hit him.
- Good.
- How's he doing?
Oh, he'll be all
right. How are you?
Ask me tomorrow.
- Good night.
He might need some fluids soon.
No. Morphine boluses of 10.
I heard you were gone.
No, I'm still here.
Good.
You know I don't like
nobody else helping me.
I know.
You've always
treated me like a man.
Just try and relax.
What is that?
That monitor's just a
little sensitive, that's all.
I'm scared.
There's no reason to be.
Everything's okay.
I could have been
a better person.
I could have done more.
You did enough.
Stay with me.
It won't be much longer.
I'll stay right here.
- Let me see.
- I think I singed my eyebrow.
I need to see. You thought it was a good
idea to put kerosene in your barbecue?
- I thought it was lighter fluid.
- It doesn't look burnt.
I'll check for corneal burns
with an ultraviolet light.
I need everything
documented. Worker's comp.
- You're a chef?
- It was my summer office party.
Oh, I don't think that counts.
Any word on the
air conditioning?
Yeah. They think
it'll be fixed by winter.
I can't work like this.
- You want a Big Stick?
- No.
- Why did I buy these shoes?
- Because they were cute.
- Some help here.
- Yeah, what is it?
Car rammed into a picnic at Lincoln
Park. I got three rigs behind me.
- John?
- Yeah, I got it.
Intubated, regular
pulse, good sats.
Get Neurosurgery.
Warn CT they'll get busy.
12-year-old boy,
dislocated shoulder...
multiple lacerations.
BP, 100/60. Pulse, 120.
Hey, I'm Dr. Carter.
What's your name?
What's that? Okay, we're
gonna take care of you.
Set me up...