Shaun, did you undress me?
Except your underpants.
- How long have you been here?
- All night.
- You should be at work.
- I'm taking the day off.
No, you should be at work.
You're sick all the
time, not just after hours.
Shaun, you shouldn't
give up your life.
You have my number,
you check in with me.
I have 15 paid vacation days
and 10 sick days per year.
But I can only take sick days
when I'm sick, not when you are,
so this is a vacation.
The plan is to align your eyes
using what's called
distraction osteogenesis.
We cut the bone and implant posts
on either side of your eye orbits.
Then, we slowly
expand that distance,
allowing for new bone
to grow in the gaps.
Will it hurt?
Mmm... For mere mortals, it
would, but with your pain tolerance?
It'll tickle.
You up for this?
So, I'll have
perfectly aligned eyes,
but still look like a
wad of chewing gum.
Molly...
You lost an awful lot of bone
and soft tissue in the accident,
and in terms of
facial reconstruction,
we've actually come a long
way in the past two years.
And after 12 surgeries, you get
your own personalized coffee mug.
I forgot about that. Okay,
when can we get prepped?
Is now too soon?
Car accident. Karin Tindle, 14.
She was sleeping in the back.
Trucker in the
oncoming lane fell asleep.
She wasn't wearing a seat belt.
Head trauma, non-responsive,
GCS of five with decorticate posturing.
Sounds like a
bleed in the brain.
And she has a 25-point difference
in blood pressures between her arms.
- Possible aortic dissection.
- Head and heart.
Page Dr. Melendez, have
him meet us in the OR.
- Have you contacted Karin's father?
- He passed away three years ago.
Let's go.
Why isn't she waking up?
We're gonna take
good care of her.
- CT confirmed an aortic dissection.
- She needs a thoracotomy.
Aorta hasn't ruptured yet. And
she has a pseudoaneurysm.
We need to get after
her head trauma first.
I don't see any major brain bleeds,
and we can monitor pressures.
In this case, the
heart trumps the head.
Okay.
I have two major symptoms,
nausea and boredom.
I didn't know boredom was
a symptom of chemotherapy.
It's a symptom of
sitting on my ass all day.
I used to run a 700-bed
hospital, with a staff of thousands.
Now all I have to think about
is how I keep my food down
and how many bowel
movements I've had all week.
Four.
And I don't have
to think about that.
You know what I need? My meds.
Will you do me a favor,
and run and pick these up?
When I come back,
we can do Mad Libs.
Unclamp.
- Graft is holding.
- That's one fire out. Drill.
Pupils are blown.
ICPs are spiking way up,
brain perfusion CPP is down.
She needs a hemicraniectomy.
Let's sit her up.
- It's marijuana.
- Yes, it is.
- Medicinal marijuana. Hold on.
One for the boredom.
One for the nausea.
Can I try one?
I met someone who said cannabidiol
improved his ASD symptoms.
A person? You met a person once?
Shaun, have you heard
of the scientific method?
I'd like to perform a practical,
albeit anecdotal, experiment.
Since you're on vacation.
And we can keep an
eye out on each other...
One. One... Whoa! One. Take one.
Cruciate wide
incision of the dura.
- Brain edema.
- She's bradycardic.
Push another 50 grams of
mannitol and ventilate down her CO2.
- No corneal reflex.
- No overbreathing vent.
No brain stem reflexes.
She's brain-dead.
Fore!
You broke my house.
You gotta club down.
It's just 12 yards,
just a little dog-leg.
Here, watch this.
- It's in the cup.
- Nice shot, Glassy.
You're gonna call me Glassy?
All right, I'm gonna call you Smurf.
Smurf. This is very interesting.
I find that very
funny, but it's not.
- It's not. Am I high?
- I think you're pretty high, yeah.
Am I acting more normal?
No, you're acting high.
- Smurf. Smurf. Why is Smurf funny?
- I don't know.
You take the first
letter of the first name
and you attach it to the first
syllable of your last name.
See? S-Murph. Smurf.
We did it all the
time in high school.
So, your name was A-Glass?
Yeah, no, it didn't work for me.
Okay, serious now.
Where's the next hole?
Right there. Careful of
the hazard right behind it.
- Okay, Sam Snead.
- Dr. Glassman.
Let's see what you got.
How's Lea?
Lee-Ya.
Lee-Ya. There should
be a Y in her name.
Lee-Ya. Is she still into Jack?
No.
She is into Jake.
Who the hell is Jake?
Jake is the guy Lea is into.
Are you okay with that?
I don't think you're
okay with that.
I think that's why you're here.
I'm here to help
you through chemo.
When a guy is stoned,
he can tell another guy
anything that's in his heart.
You know, all the messy,
scary, embarrassing stuff
that you would otherwise
never, ever, ever tell anyone.
So, what do you think?
A dog pooped on your lawn.
Oh...
You were right to insist that we
deal with the aorta before the brain.
I appreciate you saying that.
Don't let guilt make you
second-guess yourself.
Why would I have guilt?
You shouldn't. That's my point.
Good.
- I'm hungry. Are you hungry?
- I think I am.
When a man's hungry, you
know what a man wants...
There's an open can of
chickpeas in the fridge.
- Mallomars.
- What are... What is the Mallomar?
Pure chocolate, fluffy marshmallows,
on a crispy bed of graham goodness.
Get us an Uber.
The next few days are going to be
filled with many difficult decisions.
Decisions no parent
should ever have to make.
We've kept your daughter
on life support because we...
You...
want to ask about
organ donation.
Yes.
And you want her,
what? Her heart?
Unfortunately, her heart
was injured by the trauma,
as were several other organs.
We have a 16-year-old girl
who had a tragic accident
a couple of years ago
that destroyed her face.
And we were hoping
that you might...
You want to take my daughter's
face and put it on someone else?
This young girl's life
has been devastated,
and you have a chance...
No.
I'm sorry, Dr. Andrews.
Okay, how about this one?
The ugly can be
beautiful, the pretty, never.
- Seems a little judge-y.
- Yeah, well, it was Oscar Wilde.
Fair enough.
So, I'm guessing you didn't
see the Quakes last night.
The San Jose Earthquakes?
Your home team?
Yeah, I know who the
Quakes are. I recorded it.
No, you didn't.
Don't worry. I watch enough
soccer for the both of us.
They won three
to two, by the way.
Beautiful goal in extra time.
They didn't have any either.
Well, that's all the major
chains. We're oh for four.
Our next place is on Thornwood Drive,
just west of Santa Teresa Boulevard.
- That's in Alamitos.
- Yes.
There are still 28 stores in
the greater San Jose area
that we can try,
and I've devised a
route starting in the south,
working counterclockwise
around the city to best avoid traffic.
We'll buy you a box, I promise.
Okay. Guys, I like a big fare
as much as the next driver,
but racking up hundreds of
dollars on a munchie quest
is starting to
feel exploitative.
What do you say I
order ahead for pizza,
and then we just pick
it up on the way home?
- I don't want pizza.
- What take-out food do you like?
- I like pancakes.
I don't want pancakes.
I don't want to go home.
We're paying you to drive us.
You want these cookies?
What is the real reason?
- You'll laugh.
- What's the funny reason?
I had a crush on a girl.
Robin Demayne.
Senior year in high school.
Her favorite snack.
- Okay.
- Are we going to get Mallomars?
Nope.
You have been harboring feelings
for this girl for over 40 years.
That is a worthy quest.
How do you spell Demayne?
D-E...
You're the same sex,
race, approximate age,
share compatible blood
types and antigens,
and a whole bunch of other things
that make you the perfect match.
And we just received
permission from her next of kin.
Yeah.
Our donor's on life support
but her heart is compromised,
so we are very
much on the clock.
Cancel all elective
surgeries, all personal plans
and all hopes of sleep.
This is your home
for the next two days.
Let's give Molly a new face.
There is another Robin
Demayne living in San Mateo.
That's less than half
an hour from here.
Ooh! I found one in
Los Gatos. Even closer.
You realize how
stupid this is, right?
This is a quest. A
quest is never stupid.
A quest is by definition
almost always stupid.
Why would I want to see Robin
Demayne after all these years?
To tell her you love her?
I just want a cookie.
I wasn't in love with her.
I was a teenager.
I was infatuated.
And whenever you thought
about her, it made you happy.
And you thought
about her all the time.
And every time you saw her,
you felt a rush, light-headed.
Is that how you
know you're in love?
That's how it starts.
And when you're
not with that person,
you miss them so much,
you're willing to drive to 32 stores
to find a sensory reminder that
might bring back those memories.
I'm all right today
You gonna find a way to
cross and you gonna get there
I'm gonna leave it
all out there to dry
I'm gonna leave it all out there
I'm gonna leave it
all out there to dry up
I'm gonna leave it all out there
Ah, but you worry me
You worry me
And you worry me
Ride home's on me.
Flake. Flake's a guy
from my high school.
He knew everyone, he
kept track of everyone,
and I guarantee you,
he never left Livermore.
We need to go to Livermore
and ask Flake about Robin.
We're going to Livermore.
Every lab and imaging
test that comes back
just reinforces the fact that this
really is a one-in-a-million match.
Nice.
Yeah, it is.
It's also very scary.
And natural to be
having second thoughts.
I just...
I don't know how to
accept a gift like this.
Someone else's face,
someone else's identity.
But the face is just
a mask. It's what's...
Underneath that counts?
Really?
Those lame quotes we've been
mocking, you're gonna use them on me?
Yeah.
Molly, right now, your face
is the only thing anyone sees.
This operation will change that.
It will let the world
see, not your new face,
but what has always
been behind it.
Will it count towards
the coffee mug?
Flake lives at your
old high school?
He was the janitor back
then, he's the janitor now.
He'll probably be the janitor when
this planet crashes into the sun.
- Flake.
- Findlay Lake was his name.
- Hey, Flakey.
- Hey, yourself, Glaaron Assman.
Your name was Glaaron Assman!
His name was Glaaron Assman!
1973 State Championship.
He threw for 460 yards,
and if you squint hard enough,
you'll see who was named MVP.
You said you had
something to show us.
Oh... Yeah. Wait right here.
Shannon?
I keep thinking
she's just sleeping.
How can I say goodbye?
We call it the Walk of Honor.
To thank your daughter
for her sacrifice.
You remember a guy
named Bobby Juarez?
Tall kid but too
clumsy to play hoops?
He told me that Robin
married a dentist named Scaplin
and moved out of state.
You couldn't tell me
that when I called?
I wanted to see you.
I found her. Robin Scaplin
is in Portland, Oregon.
It's an 11-hour and
27-minute drive.
Fill up the tank, I guess.
We're going to Portland.
Ten blade.
Proximal facial nerve
isolated and dissected.
Okay, let's start
the heavy lifting.
Clamping the left and right
common carotid arteries
and jugular veins. Cutting
the carotids and jugulars.
Let's do it.
It's a long way to go to
visit a married woman
you haven't seen since high
school, who may not even be home.
She's home. I
called at the last stop.
- What did she say?
- "Hello."
- What did you say?
- Nothing. He hung up.
When you sober up, you are gonna
want to turn around and go home.
Probably.
As rehearsed.
Veins, arteries, nerves, in that
order, from the chin up, yes?
Can I get the osteosynthetic
plates and screws, please?
Damn it. I tore part
of the donor's artery.
- I need more interrupted sutures.
- Let's keep our focus, people.
Dr. Browne, Molly's parents would
like to see you on your next break.
Take it now.
You too.
Dr. Park.
I had a huge crush
on Robin Demayne.
Thoroughly unrequited crush
that slowly turned into a grudge.
Last day of school, and kids were
passing around their yearbooks,
and I signed in hers something
that was born out of anger
and resentment and pettiness.
It was designed to be
somewhat humorous,
but it was really
just mostly hurtful.
Later that day, at
the award ceremony,
I was skimming through my
yearbook, and saw what she wrote me.
"I have only two regrets.
My haircut in junior year,
"and that you never
asked me out."
And just then, I looked out
in the crowd and saw her.
Her eyes were red, obviously
crying and obviously very hurt.
And at that exact moment,
I was awarded my trophy.
I looked for her after
but never saw her again.
Is that all the scary,
messy, embarrassing stuff
that guys never,
ever tell anyone?
Pretty much.
Dean and Lori, this is Shannon.
Thank you for meeting with us.
And for everything.
If you don't mind, we have
so many questions for you,
about your daughter.
We'd like to know
what she was like,
what she liked to do.
Molly wants to know too.
Her name was Karin.
And I killed her.
I'm supposed to tell
you to get back in.
- Don't let him get to you.
- It's not him, it's you.
Your advice that I shouldn't
be second-guessing myself
is making me think you must
be second-guessing yourself.
About what?
You're the one who insisted we
deal with the heart before the brain.
And you didn't
fight me. Why not?
- Because you were right.
- I was right.
But you have never thought
anyone other than yourself
was right in an OR since
you first stepped foot in one.
You backed off 'cause
we're sleeping together.
The car accident was my fault.
It was my idea
to leave so early.
It was my idea to let
her sleep in the back.
It was up to me to make sure
she was wearing her seat belt.
None of which would've mattered
if the truck driver
hadn't fallen asleep.
It's natural to feel guilt,
but you have to understand,
this wasn't your fault.
It doesn't work that
way, Dr. Browne.
It was my handgun
that hurt Molly.
And you can say that
it was a freak accident
or that Molly knew she
wasn't supposed to touch it,
or some other BS,
but it was my fault.
I had one job and that
was to protect my family.
I didn't do my job.
You can try to make sense
of it, try to find something,
some pleasure
somewhere, some meaning,
but there just isn't.
And then, your daughter
does this for us.
Hi, Robin.
Aaron?
He had a huge crush on you.
Yeah. Uh...
That's not why I'm here though.
I'm here to apologize,
for what I wrote
in your yearbook.
Yearbook?
Yeah. Uh...
I wrote something, um...
hurtful and untrue
and really stupid.
And then I read what
you wrote in mine.
What did I write?
She had a bad
haircut in junior year.
I certainly remember that.
Yeah, well, it was
a long time ago.
Anyway, I just... I
wanted to say I'm sorry.
Well, apology accepted.
Thank you.
Mallomars.
Robin's favorite snack.
Right side donor to recipient
vessels are anastomosed.
Ditto on the left.
Let's see how our plumbing
works. Unclamp them, please.
She's pinking up.
Moving on. Motor and
sensory neurorrhaphies.
How's our girl doing?
She's just waking up now.
Hi, Molly.
- How are you feeling?
- Terrible.
Then we're right on target.
You want to have a look?
No.
No rush.
It is going to look surreal.
Like you're looking
at a stranger.
But it won't always.
Because nobody laughs,
or holds their head,
or looks someone in the
eye exactly the way you do.
Okay.
I apologize for telling you
how to react to losing a patient.
Thank you.
When I accused you of
second-guessing yourself,
that's because I'm doing it too.
Our relationship has me
questioning everything I do,
and everything you do.
You're making this way more
complicated than it has to be...
It is complicated.
The fact that we're
seeing each other
changes the context
of all of our interactions.
I guess that's why
there are rules against it.
I think I can keep being
a jerk to you at work,
if that's what you want.
You think we should end it?
No.
See you tomorrow.
So, once you're feeling
a little less woozy,
we'll set you up with a
whole bunch of therapists.
Speech, occupational, physical.
Shannon.
Please come in.
I'm Karin's mom.
Hi.
I brought something for you.
She was beautiful.
Thank you.
And thank you for timing
that elevator ride so perfectly.
Can I ask you for a favor?
I'd like to say goodbye.
Yeah, we'll clean up tomorrow.
And buy a new vase.
Yeah, buying a new vase is easy.
Vacuuming up my
grandmother's ashes, not so easy.
Are you glad you apologized?
Yeah.
Do you still feel guilty?
Guilt must be a bad thing,
if it makes people feel badly
about something they can never fix.
Or maybe it's a deterrent, so
we do the right thing the next time.
You loved Robin but
could never be with her.
Do you wish you'd never met her?
Not for one second.
I'm not okay that
Lea is into Jake.
Good night, Smurf.
Night, Glassy.