Coming up to 50 feet.
Roger that.
We're light on fuel.
Two minutes to bingo.
Come on, Fisher, we got
places to go, people to see.
Working on it!
So I've heard.
What's taking so long?
Let go of the suitcase!
You're gonna have
to hold on to me!
Sir, whatever it
is, it's not worth it!
We're at bingo fuel, sir.
You hear that, Fisher? Bingo!
Either reel him in or we're
leaving them both here!
Okay, sir.
Ditch the damn luggage!
Marina.
Marina! Marina!
Tell him if he was so worried
about his wife's clothes,
he should have stayed in Cuba!
He says it wasn't her clothes,
it was her medical records.
Says she's sick and
needs to go home.
No home, House! I
need to see Dr. House!
You don't answer
your phone anymore.
I'm world-famous now.
Press won't leave me alone.
It's Cuddy. I know.
If it was the press,
I'd be answering.
And since you're not
taking her calls, I am.
Your patient's been
waiting for hours.
She didn't book an appointment.
No, she risked her life.
If you don't reach terra firma,
you don't get any milk or honey.
The woman has 10 different
things wrong with her,
including pains
all over her body.
Admittedly, not as interesting
as staring uselessly at Foreman.
You know why I find a
goodbye party fascinating?
I think it's kind of insulting to
celebrate when someone leaves you.
What are you gonna
do to keep him? Nothing.
He really is gonna leave.
You know that, right?
Yeah. So what are you gonna do?
Nothing I can do.
He doesn't want more money,
better working conditions,
doesn't even want a better job.
He wants to not be me.
Because he thinks you're
a cold-hearted bastard
without any regard
for anyone but yourself.
He's right.
You need to show him
that you really do care.
Don't!
Foreman's not the only
chocolate-covered cherry in the box.
House, you play a guitar
you got in ninth grade.
Eighth.
You're living in the same
apartment for 15 years,
you drive a 10 year-old car,
you are not good with change.
That used to be
true, but I changed.
He's not afraid to be you, he's
afraid to be who he thinks you are.
Rheumatic fever would
explain the skin rash.
But not the double
vision or bloody urine.
They were lost at
sea for three days.
Severe dehydration
causes kidney problems.
And the double vision?
Concussion during the shipwreck.
It all fits as long as each symptom
started when you think it started.
This would be a lot easier if
we had her medical records.
Any of you certified
deep-sea divers?
She's from a dirt-poor
country in the tropics.
Infectious disease and
parasites are the most likely cause
of unexplained pain, fever and skin
rash. We might as well start there.
If there's one
thing Castro knows,
it's how to look great in green.
And if there are two
things Castro knows,
it's how to look great in
green and train doctors.
Even without the
medical records,
we can assume she
was drowned in antibiotics
before she risked
drowning to see me.
So what doesn't Castro know?
How to lay his hands on
high-tech scanning equipment.
Pain, double vision
point us toward the head.
Cameron, get an MRI.
See what's cooking
in the old cabeza.
Chase, check out the husband.
Why? He hasn't
complained of any pain.
Basic math. Take all of her
symptoms, subtract his sea symptoms,
the remainder equals
her original symptoms.
Are you in any pain?
No, I'm just sunburned.
Any blurred vision?
No.
So my wife, she
is with Dr. House?
She's with another doctor
who is part of Dr. House's team.
No, she's supposed
to see Dr. House.
We have permission.
That's the way it
works with Dr. House.
I came 1,000 miles to see him!
He doesn't care.
I'm sorry, but that's who he is,
that's who you
risked your life to see.
And you made the right choice.
Any other metal?
Must have been
difficult on the boat.
When the storm
came, yes, very much.
I pray while my husband, he...
With the paddles?
You were on a boat
without a motor?
No, no, we start with a motor,
but it break on the first night.
My husband, he can fix anything.
A washing machine,
a car, a computer.
But that is stupid motor.
And me.
These two he cannot fix.
He got you to us.
He never gave up.
No matter what happen,
he kept saying to
me, "Don't worry,
"we will make it.
"I'll take care of you."
That's Esteban.
He refuses to worry or pray.
He believe if you
don't have one,
that you don't need the other.
Husband has a pulled
muscle in his shoulder,
but no other pains
or double vision.
He does have a fever, fungal
rash, cough, and elevated bilirubin.
Foreman's not going anywhere.
He said that to you?
He doesn't really wanna leave.
And you don't
really wanna let him.
You'll cave, just like
you did with Cameron.
Foreman's not as
easy as Cameron.
But, of course, who is?
I'm in the room.
He may not want a date,
but he does want something.
Well, maybe it's
something I can't offer.
Then you'll just lie.
He'd see through it. Maybe.
Or maybe he'll just see
what he wants to see.
She has MS.
Explains the pain, fatigue,
double vision, kidney problems.
The kidney problems
aren't connected.
Her husband has the same issues.
It is possible for
two people to have
the same symptom for
two different reasons.
If we're gonna
take that approach,
then we may as
well just throw out
everything we got from
the husband and start over.
We could do that, or we
could do something productive.
Start her on
Interferon for the MS,
see if she improves.
I do like being productive.
Well done. Do it.
"Well done"? Is that what you
think he wants, a pat on the head?
Go do your job.
She does not have MS.
I know it's not a pleasant
diagnosis to hear...
But, no! The doctors in
Cuba would have found MS.
What's that?
It's all right. Her
pulse ox just came off.
Marina, you can't...
But it hurts.
Her pain is getting worse!
Your treatment isn't
working because it's not MS.
Does this hurt?
Wow! Well, either Foreman's way
stronger than he thinks he is or...
Seriously. Or?
She's too young for
osteoporosis that severe.
And too old for
osteogenesis imperfecta.
Which leaves bone cancer.
Cancer's a long shot. - Why?
Because metastatic tumors
don't explain the abnormal MRI,
kidney damage, cotton
mouth, double vision.
Oh, wait, they do!
Infection could
do all that, too.
It's not an infection.
Because you know the
nonexistent medical records confirm
that the brilliant doctors in
Cuba treated her for infection,
or because you're trying
to kiss up to Foreman?
Because an infection
would cause a fever,
and the brilliant doctors
who work in my office
have already crossed that off
the list because the husband...
You're the one who said
it's possible for two people
to have the same symptom
for two different reasons.
And you're the one
who said if we do that,
we might as well throw out
everything we got from the husband.
Right, and then you said we
should do something productive
like breaking her arm?
Foreman didn't break her arm.
Of course he didn't. Cancer did.
Put her in a PET scan,
see what else it's breaking.
This isn't gonna
work! He's not a moron!
You can't just agree with
everything he says for two days
and hope he forgets the last three
years and how much he hates you!
Anything else?
When you get the results of
the PET scan, let me know.
I don't really care if
Foreman stays or goes, but...
You're fired.
What, because I yelled at you?
Because you've
been here the longest,
learned all you can or you
haven't learned anything at all.
Either way, it's
time for a change.
Fine.
No tumors in her arm.
Synovial membrane
is working fine.
No hot spots, no bone cancer.
Maybe we should be
looking for something else.
Is it raining out?
House fired me. What?
Because you yelled at him?
"Time for a change" was
the official explanation.
It makes no sense.
Since when does
House make sense?
He always makes sense.
He's angry.
Yes, it's all about
you, Foreman.
He's upset you're
leaving, so he fires Chase.
Excuse me.
On the humerus,
she's got a hot spot.
Why'd you fire Chase?
Sure thing.
First you tell me the
results of the PET scan.
Did you fire him for me?
Would you stay if I did?
You asked him to fire Chase?
No! Yes!
You're frustrated with Foreman
so you lash out, kick the dog?
He's not gone five minutes
and the name-calling starts.
What's on the PET scan?
Why'd you fire Chase?
Do you know what's
on the PET scan?
You two, out.
Wait! What's on the PET scan?
You can't dump your
entire department
just because you don't know
how to deal with an issue.
Yes, they are all irreplaceable.
If only in this country
we'd figure out a way
to somehow teach people
to interpret PET scans.
What the hell's wrong
with you? You fired Chase?
I don't suppose you know
what's on my patient's PET scan.
I told you to show
Foreman you have a heart.
How does that translate
into you being a bastard?
So that's a no.
Pick up the phone and tell
Chase you made a mistake.
Un-fire him.
Chase, if you know what's
on the PET scan, call me back.
Cut the crap.
Chase is a good doctor.
Sorry, you're in the wrong room.
My name on the door,
my team, my decisions.
My building, my
floor, my people.
Hold that reprimand. House.
Dr. Chase! How are you?
Thank you. You
are indispensable.
You're still fired. Sorry.
Wow, that was awkward.
PET scan revealed a blood
clot in my patient's arm.
Which means goodbye.
Still got two people
working for me,
gotta get one of
them to do my job.
A clot means a heart problem.
We have to do an
emergency angiogram.
But you're not sure
it's a blood clot?
PET scan can't determine
that with certainty.
So you have no better idea what's
wrong with her than when we first got here?
We've ruled out MS. I
told you it wasn't MS.
Where is Dr. House?
Dr. House has
left for the night.
He'll be here in the
morning to review the results,
if you sign the consent.
But, you know, you
could call him at home.
He doesn't always
pick up, so keep calling.
Thank you.
Dr. House, it's Esteban
Hernandez again.
As soon as you get home,
it's very important you call me.
Hello, yes, Dr. House,
it's Esteban Hernandez.
As soon as you get home,
if can you please call me?
The catheter is in
her femoral artery.
Why are you telling me that?
Because you're assisting.
Do I look like I'm assisting?
I had nothing to do
with Chase's termination.
Is everything okay?
You're doing fine, Marina.
The dye will take a minute to
work its way through your system.
Why would you tell House
you're leaving because he's a jerk?
Because it's the truth.
Did you give an angry
Cuban my home number?
Why would you do that?
You're not turning into
House, you're worse than him.
Let me get this straight.
Instead of picking up the phone
and talking to a
patient for five minutes,
you gave up on sleep
and drove in here.
My chest!
She's in V-Tach.
What did you do? Nothing!
Must have hit something.
You nick an artery?
She has no pulse.
It hurts.
She has no pulse,
but she's talking.
Cough! Cough
again! Keep coughing!
It'll push blood into your
head, keep you conscious.
Push one milligram Epinephrine.
Will that help?
No. But it is amazingly cool.
We need to get her on bypass!
We need to keep her here.
If this was a clot,
the force of bypass
will blow it into
her brain, kill her.
If we continue CPR,
she'll lose blood flow,
which will cause brain damage.
What caused the heart to stop?
Let's assume it
wasn't human error.
I didn't nick an
artery, it just stopped.
I said let's assume.
The only other option
is electrical instability.
No ST segment changes.
We need to tell the husband.
Tell him what? We have
no idea what happened.
House?
Keep going until
I figure this out.
House!
Jeez.
At 47, I hope my colon
looks better than this guy's.
Isolating the
first transverse...
Help! I'm trapped
inside a monitor!
Not a good time, House.
My patient lost her heartbeat during
routine cardiac catheterization, so...
Human error.
It's not human error.
Electrical instability?
Pre-procedure EKG
was normal, no syncope.
Ischemia?
Foreman said no
ST segment changes.
Human error is the
only other possible...
It's not human error.
Of course it's human error!
You don't want Foreman
to have made a mistake
because then you'd
have to mock him.
And that would put a crimp in
your brilliant plan of keeping him
by having a breakdown
and firing Chase.
Did you just spit
on the monitor?
You know I can't see you.
Human error would not
explain her symptoms.
You mean her heart stopping?
I mean her foot
pain, her back pain.
House! I'm busy!
You have a team,
run your differential with them.
Foreman and Cameron
are doing CPR.
Then you shouldn't
have fired Chase.
Change is fun, huh?
Five, six, seven, eight!
Go!
Someone's gotta
talk to the husband.
He thought this whole thing
was gonna last 45 minutes!
A half hour more of
this, nothing to talk about,
we won't be able to bring her
back. We gotta get her on bypass.
House still isn't
answering his phone.
You, get in here.
Go!
Excuse me, my wife was
supposed to be back an hour ago...
As soon as we know
anything, we'll call you.
Thank you.
Human Behavior
finals will also get into
clinical presentations of mania,
and we'll touch on Stanislas
Dehaene's PET scans.
Excuse me, Professor.
House, when we're
done with our rounds...
My patient has no heartbeat.
Stopped when we inserted a
catheter during a routine angiogram.
Anyone tells me
why her heart stopped
gets an A in Dr. Cuddy's class.
Anyone?
Human error?
Yeah. I'm polling
first-year medical students
because I hadn't
considered human error.
Marfan's Syndrome?
Structural abnormalities
would show up on the echo.
You get a C. Yeah?
Botox injections.
F.
If the injection was tainted
with live botulism, it'd fit.
B-plus.
Unfortunately, she missed
her last Botox appointment
due to a boating accident,
but send me your résumé.
House, time's up.
Good Lord, you
smell like musk ox.
Either our patient goes on
bypass, or I call time of death.
Your patient isn't
already on bypass?
I was worried about a clot.
How long? Three hours.
House. Bypass, now!
Clear the hall!
Out of the way, please!
Let's go! Excuse us!
Dr. Foreman! My wife!
What has happened?
Her heart stopped. We
have to get her on bypass.
He needs to wait outside.
Got it?
Dr. House.
You can vacuum later.
I am not the janitor, I
am Esteban Hernandez.
What happened to my wife?
Her heart stopped.
Why did her heart stop?
Well, if I knew that,
I'd be coming to you.
Tell me where you take her.
Tell me what is happen to her?
"Happening." It's
a present participle.
Not a particularly
interesting form of speech.
Kind of like this conversation.
But I risk my life to see you.
I looked you up. You fix people.
When everyone else
gives up, you don't!
And now you insult me?
Ignore my wife?
Helps my process.
You do not ignore my wife, okay?
She is everything to me.
Well, then you do
not ignore your wife.
You just sit here! You
don't talk to people.
How do you fix something
if you don't look at it?
Turn on bypass, please.
Good. Good distal flow.
Need to look at the heart.
Why?
I can't find my wallet.
Pick it up. Turn it over.
I don't see anything
physically wrong with her heart.
Hearts don't stop for no reason.
Okay. Take your look.
You see anything wrong?
Give her a jump-start.
Clear. Clear.
Clear.
And again.
Clear! Clear! Clear!
Again.
Yeah, seventh time
is the charm. Sorry.
I'll keep her on bypass until the
husband has a chance to say goodbye.
I'm not telling the
husband anything
until I can tell him why his...
It doesn't matter.
Her heart can't
start. She's dead.
I got you something.
I'll miss you.
I know you won't miss me, but...
I just thought it would be
nice for you to have that.
I will miss you.
Can I have a hug, too?
The surgeon found nothing.
He can't start her heart.
What a thoughtful gift.
Nice reminder of
intellectual theft
to hang at your new
place of employment.
You two can go. Say
hi to Chase for me.
You're wearing lipstick.
We can stay. We can
run another differential.
You two have no theories
about why the heart stopped,
which means I
don't need you. Go.
It's too late for theories.
We need to tell the husband.
Tell him what? That it's over.
Why? Because
her heart won't start!
How can we tell
him there's no hope
if we don't know
why there's no hope?
He's not gonna pull
the plug on his wife.
He risked his life
to get her to me.
If he pulls the plug,
it means he's failed.
If he pulls the plug, it
means you've failed.
And you're okay with that?
Go.
Hey. Hey.
You look great.
You know House firing you
has nothing to do with you.
The why doesn't matter.
Foreman will end up
staying, House will call you,
probably yell at you
for not showing up.
It's okay.
He's right. It's
time for a change.
You were right, too.
The whole "It's Tuesday,
I like you." It was silly.
Oh, don't give me that look.
Don't feel sorry for me.
Getting this job was the best
thing that has ever happened to me.
Everything about
it. And losing it?
Well, I think it's
gonna be good, too.
I'll miss you.
Have you got time for
a drink or something?
I think I should go.
Yeah.
How's it going?
The way the security
light hits your legs,
looks good.
Thank you.
If you're here to
yell at me about
the Foreman-Chase
situation, it can wait.
When do you plan
on telling the husband
it's time to say
goodbye to his wife?
Haven't put a clock on it.
Other than your curiosity, do you
have any reason to keep her on bypass?
Patient's husband
prefers her not dead.
Or you want a storybook ending
for the young man who
crossed the ocean for his wife.
This is not an act.
I don't care.
Then pull the plug!
What if I can fix it, but
I just don't know it yet?
I know you care.
I don't care!
I really don't care.
My motives are pure.
If we do an autopsy
and we see, "Oops,
"if I'd thought of that crazy
idea, we could have saved her,"
then the husband might be upset.
You've done all you can do.
It's time to let go.
I was told you
didn't believe in God.
I don't.
I promise my wife I'll do
everything I can to fix her.
If I don't pray, then I
don't do everything.
It's not working.
She's not coming back.
If you want to say goodbye,
you can come down to the ICU,
and then I'll take
her off bypass.
I'm sorry. I should have...
Marina, I am so sorry.
When you turn the
machine off, that's it?
Yeah.
Right now, is her brain working?
Probably. Just not her heart.
She seems like
she's just sleeping.
She's not sleeping.
We double-checked.
Her heart? It beat?
No, it's residual
flow from the bypass.
No, I can feel it. Look!
That is her heart, no?
P wave, Q, R, S, T wave.
That's a normal normal.
Esteban?
Marina!
Holy crap.
Is this heaven?
No, it's New Jersey.
God sent you back to me.
It's a miracle.
It's impossible.
Apparently not.
Live hearts don't
stop for no reason.
Dead hearts don't
start for no reason.
Apparently they do.
She's three hours off
bypass and still stable.
And the pain is gone.
No, it's not.
You think she's lying
about feeling better?
Just because it's not there
now doesn't mean it's gone.
Just because it was there before
doesn't mean it's coming back.
Chase was probably right.
She had some sort
of tropical infection
that cleared when we put her
on antibiotics during the bypass.
Antibiotics did not
bring her back to life.
Other than a miracle,
it's the only explanation
for her symptoms.
How come God gets credit
whenever something good happens?
Where was he when
her heart stopped?
What if it wasn't human error?
What if it was God's error?
A congenital defect in an artery
making it susceptible to inflammation.
We need to do another angiogram.
We've looked at her heart 100
different ways. There was no evidence...
The one time we
looked inside her heart,
we stopped before
we could see anything.
Because it stopped.
Good news.
I think we know
what the problem is.
You mean "was."
Hey, it's my first
language, not yours.
If she wants to outlive
Castro, we need to fix her heart.
In case no one's filled you in,
today is Monday, which means
you've been dead for a day.
If that kind of symptom
comes back, it can get serious.
I need to do another angiogram.
Wait. Wasn't that what
caused her heart to stop before?
No, God caused that.
He's all-powerful, you know.
He was watching
over us in the ocean
and he's watching over us now.
Your rescuers didn't have
wings, they had a helicopter.
Esteban prayed.
Do you know how many little
boys are praying for jetpacks?
How many priests
are praying for...
Well, that one actually works.
You didn't bring me back to him.
And I'm not gonna
take you away from him,
but if we don't do
this test, God will.
You said there was no
chance, no hope, which means...
Which means I was wrong.
But I'm wrong all the time.
My mistakes don't
prove there's a God.
You came a long way to see me.
You gonna put her life in
God's hands or in mine?
Ready?
I better not see you praying.
I don't want to have to
fight for credit on this.
Exiting the femoral,
entering the aortic arch.
This is where...
Where we stopped to
have a picnic last week.
Her blood pressure's rising!
Mine's rising, too. Of course,
I am doing battle with a deity.
In the heart.
Injecting the dye.
Right coronary
flow is unobstructed.
Left coronary flow looks normal.
Looks like you're wrong.
Either I'm right or this
test is about to go very bad.
What's that?
She has one,
two, a third ostium!
How many is she
supposed to have? Dos.
All the third one's doing is causing
inflammation, throwing off clots,
getting in the way
of the angiogram.
No human would
screw up that big.
Don't worry.
Just one more
surgery, it'll be fine.
Thank God!
Don't make me slap you!
Hi.
It's Tuesday.
No, it's Monday.
I know, I just...
I didn't feel like waiting.
I hear you got another
satisfied customer.
One more and I get
a set of steak knives.
Well, this is it.
I appreciate the
opportunity you gave me.
Didn't do it for you.
Thought you were
the best guy for the job.
Thanks, I guess.
Which is why I want you to stay.
You're an important
part of the team.
I need you.
I know. But I don't need you.
And I definitely
don't wanna be you.
You're miserable.
I just solved a
case by predicting
a never-before-seen
heart defect.
A case you couldn't solve.
A case you gave up on.
I couldn't be happier.
For two minutes, maybe.
Until the next case comes along.
Until you're jonesing
for your next fix.
This woman talks
while in full cardiac arrest
and you're more excited about
the talking than the heart dying!
The two were connected.
I don't wanna solve cases.
I wanna save lives.
Do you think she cares?
Do you think the husband cares?
You think the children
she can now have
because of me are gonna
care why I saved her?
I care. About yourself!
About your own ego! House.
You're the selfish
bastard, not me,
which is why you took so
much pleasure in drawing out
this little goodbye of yours
for the last three weeks.
It wasn't for me, it
wasn't for anyone!
It sure as hell
didn't help anyone!
Nice try.
Nice tries are worthless.
You now have a
bigger office than I do.
Why don't you go enjoy it?
Better be naked pictures.
My resignation letter.
I've gotten all I
can from this job.
What do you expect me to do?
Break down and apologize?
Beg Chase to come back?
No.
I expect you to do
what you always do.
I expect you to make
a joke and go on.
I expect you to be just fine.
I'll miss you.
Genuine American cigars.
You guys can't get them in Cuba.
100% healthy.
Shouldn't you go home?
Patient follow-up.
Very important.
She looks great. I
think she's sleeping.
She is sleeping, I double-check.
So, they all quit?
Two of them quit.
I fired the third.
It must be very hard
to lose your people.
You must be very upset.
Yeah, I must be.
But you're not?
I don't think I am.
I think I'm okay.
What are you going to do?
God only knows.