Previously on The Good Doctor...
You've always taken after your father.
- Why is that a bad thing?
- It isn't.
He was driven, and he was brilliant.
I wish that he had been able
to ask for help.
And insert the tube into the vacutainer.
And you've just passed phlebotomy 101.
Oh, God.
Stop talking. You're distracting me.
I wanted to impress you.
It's a top journal...
Get out of OR!
Charlie Lukaitis
won't listen to me.
I cannot work with her anymore.
Apparently, she can't
work with you, either.
She filed a complaint against you.
- What's going on?
- I've asked them to leave.
He's a Jew, too.
A gay one, in fact.
And I'm calling the cops.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah. Now go get engaged.
Are you okay?
Yes.
I am meeting with HR
to discuss Charlie's
complaint this afternoon.
Okay.
It's just been three days
and you've barely mentioned Asher.
I've read that grief reactions
are delayed in people with autism.
When a loss finally hits,
it can be really intense,
sometimes even overwhelming.
If that happens, find me anytime.
Okay.
Asher and I came from different worlds.
I am a devout Christian from Oakland,
and he was an Orthodox Jew
turned atheist from Brooklyn.
But when we met at St. Bons,
he became my closest friend.
Asher had a way of making you feel like
he saw the best version of you,
but he still loved you at your worst.
He was also one of the most
courageous people I knew.
Brave enough to leave behind
the people he loved
to be the person he knew he was inside.
He was stubborn and opinionated,
had a strange
affinity for grandpa sweaters,
made a crazy-good margarita,
and he was just so, so much fun.
I've made breakfast.
I'm not hungry.
You're barely eating.
I know. I'm exhausted.
I couldn't sleep last night.
I know.
I've heard you up every night since...
Isn't your friend's funeral today?
Yeah. I-I think I'm coming
down with something.
I'm gonna do a swab at work.
I don't think you're sick.
You should talk to a therapist.
I just need sleep.
I have to tell you something
about your father.
And I should have told you this
years ago,
but I promised him that I...
Mom, I cannot do this right now.
You idolized him,
and he never wanted you
to see him vulnerable.
You won't listen to me,
but you will answer a text?
Well, it could be work.
- Honey, your father...
- Ma, I gotta go.
He was one of the most
considerate people I knew
and a damn good doctor.
He knew what the patient wanted,
so he fought for it.
He made it happen.
But that was Asher...
standing up for his beliefs.
Even if it cost him his family,
even if it got him in trouble,
Asher always did
what he thought was right.
And now he's gone...
...because of a couple of
ignorant, hateful monsters.
They knew one thing about Asher.
One thing. And they killed him for it.
Left him lying there
bleeding on the pavement.
And those animals, they get to live.
And now he's dead.
And I hate them.
I hate them for taking my friend.
Have to go. We all do.
Excuse me.
A guy drove his car through a
crowd at San Jose SpringFest.
- Accident?
- Doesn't look that way.
How badly are we outnumbered?
Still early intel,
but it looks pretty bad.
Activate Mass Casualty Event Protocol.
Alerts are out. ORs are up.
- Elective patients are canceled.
- Good.
We have eight surgeons away
at the Cleveland Conference.
I need a surgeon.
Severe head injury,
hypoxia, and seizures.
Skull fracture,
brain herniation with CSF leak.
I'll take him up.
Call Dixon. He's the backup Team Leader.
He's in Cleveland, too.
- Put Murphy in charge until I get back.
- You sure?
Today's gonna be messy,
especially after losing Asher.
You'll help him.
Shaun won't let emotions get in the way.
Synced & corrected by -robtor-
www.addic7ed.com
Dispatch said we're getting
over 25 patients,
many critical. First wave just arrived.
Lim's gonna be in the OR for a while.
SpringFest was
six blocks from our house.
You were gonna take Eden.
I know it's horrible,
but these things are pretty rare.
Are they? Look at Asher.
Are you okay?
You seemed pretty angry at the funeral.
Seems pretty reasonable.
Watch your backs.
Do you need me to slap you?
I hope not.
You gonna have a problem
working with Dr. Murphy?
I hope not.
Okay.
Doctors Park, Kalu, and Allen,
you'll be treating Red Tag patients.
Dr. Reznick, you're with the ER
physicians on Yellow Tag patients.
Dom, you're on Green Tags
in the waiting room.
Green Tags?
Red Tags are urgent surgical patients.
Yellow, urgent non-surgical.
And Green, minor injuries.
Minor injuries. I can do that.
What about me?
You're on Black Tags.
But they're already dead.
Yes, every Black Tag patient
needs a pronouncement checklist
completed before they can be
moved to the morgue.
Those bodies are taking up
valuable space.
It feels like you're punishing me
for filing an HR complaint against you.
I am not. Not working with you
is an unintended benefit.
That's not how you're gonna
get her to drop the complaint.
And you're gonna need
all the help you can get today.
Yes, and I need more surgeons. Like you.
I'm not available. Remember?
You have experience,
and I am very short-staffed.
You're short-staffed
everywhere you look.
Give me Yellow Tags.
Bay six.
I'm taking her for an Ex-lap.
Jordan needs you.
I've got a red tag. I need a surgeon.
Flora, blunt abdominal trauma,
40 weeks pregnant.
This is Ken, massive flail chest.
I need a surgeon now.
There are only two of us.
Move them to adjoining bays.
She is critically hypoxic.
My patient's bleeding out.
My guy's here because of him.
Ken jumped in front of the car,
saved a little girl.
- This the driver?
- Yeah. His leg's a mess.
Femoral artery's lacerated.
Tourniquet there.
Pressure's critically low.
She must be bleeding into her abdomen.
FAST ultrasound.
What do you see, Dr. Allen?
Massive cardiac contusions,
pulmonary artery trunk tear,
lung lacs...
Okay, those are terminal injuries.
This patient needs a cut down
to clamp his common femoral artery.
I can cross clamp Ken's aorta.
That won't fix his heart.
He is a Black Tag.
He risked his life to save a kid.
That is very heroic.
He will be dead soon.
You can still save the driver.
We should try to do everything we can.
You have. Move on.
She's in cardiopulmonary failure.
She's... dying. I can't save her,
but I can save the baby.
Prep trauma one for a C-section.
Dr. Allen, the leg. Now.
Crash cart!
Melissa.
They're unhurt, but their dad
was just brought in.
Can you check on the status?
I don't know where to start.
Start with the patients
on the left side of the room
and work your way over to the right.
Hi. I'm Dom. How can I help?
There's a uterine rupture here.
Fetal decels are critical.
Baby looks good.
Dr. Murphy, we can take it from here.
Get a Black Tag for the mom.
I need a thoracotomy tray.
I might be able to save the mother, too.
That's two more units of O neg.
His pressure's stabilizing.
That's the last bleeder. Bipolar.
There's just so much vascular damage.
I think I have good profusion.
Let's close the dura.
Cerebral pressure is spiking.
His brain's herniating.
I need to remove half his skull.
Blood pressure dropping.
She's minutes from anoxic brain injury.
There. In the pulmonary trunk...
Dr. Murphy, four more Red Tag
patients just came in.
There it is.
Amniotic fluid entered her bloodstream.
The clump of hair got stuck,
blocked her circulation.
Mom and baby will be fine. Yes?
While you've been in here,
four Red Tags arrived,
two nurses need central lines,
and Kalu's asking for you.
We have incoming
ambulances with multiple casualties.
The damage to your husband's
brain was too severe.
He didn't survive.
I'm so sorry.
Shaun needs you to take
another patient to the OR.
It's STAT.
I need to relocate your ankle
to restore blood flow.
Can you hold this over your wound?
Maybe you should call your supervisor.
Maybe.
- Ah!
- Got it.
A new patient just walked in.
She can't wait.
Pediatric alert, bay seven.
Can you tell me what happened?
Car came through my stand.
Everything went flying.
Something hit me in the eye.
Cast-iron skillet, I think.
Let me take a look.
Dr. Reznick!
I think I can save his leg
with microvascular anastomosis.
No, you need to amputate below the knee.
Limb salvage is tricky,
but I really think I...
That is a six-hour surgery
with a less than 5% chance of success.
We could save six patients in that time.
Okay. Clamping bone two.
Huh. The last time I was in this room,
Asher and I were doing a colectomy.
You need a minute?
I am faster at limb amputation than you.
See the Red Tag in the corridor.
We're out of treatment rooms.
Convert the storage
room into a trauma bay.
Can't. Charlie's still
processing the Black Tags.
I need to head home to Steve.
You want to come with?
I could make you a sandwich,
loan you a baby for an hour.
Steve's cuddles can be very soothing.
Thank you.
I'm just gonna sit here a little longer.
Yeah.
Call me anytime.
The nurse says you're my son's doctor?
- He's in a lot of pain.
- Who's your son?
Riley Larson. He's over there.
The driver. I know who he is.
Can you give him something stronger?
He had the standard dose
of morphine 30 minutes ago.
He's still hurting.
That's a shame.
There's a lot of people
hurting right now.
It takes some time
for the meds to kick in,
but he should feel some relief soon.
Move, move, move.
Tell the OR to prep for bypass.
It's okay, Amy. I'm here.
Look, I tried to get to her, but...
Please just save her.
We're on our honeymoon.
These bodies need to go to the morgue.
His pupils are fixed,
but I don't think they're dilated.
Apparently pupillary dilation
is very subjective.
I'll finish this.
"The Principles of Neurology"...
Mm.
You can't check the pupil box
because this patient is still alive!
Starting ACLS protocol.
Cardiac arrest from a tension pneumo.
- Ethan needs this.
- No, that doesn't matter.
- He was a Black Tag?
- Lazarus effect.
When the paramedics did CPR,
air compressed his heart
until it stopped.
- I saved his life.
- No, I did.
- Heart's too fast. Amnio.
- On it.
Inserting a central line.
I was right about the pupil.
You were listening to a book
while he was dying.
I gotta get his pressure up.
I was learning.
You can't learn if you don't listen.
Asher was excellent at
receiving constructive criticism.
That's not a fair comparison. Asher...
You know what?
It doesn't matter who saved him.
Let's just keep him safe. Okay?
Central line is in.
All right, the pressure's good.
It's good.
Charlie, can you get us
a cardiac monitor, please?
She's not gonna be at her best,
nor anyone else,
if you continue to argue
over every stupid little thing.
She is not helpful.
She's helpful to me.
Then you take her
for the rest of the day.
She's bleeding everywhere. Hanging FFP.
I'll do an ACP to
divert all blood to her brain.
Ophtho is expecting her.
Hey, I'm sorry. I just...
I don't think I can
make it through this day.
Then quit.
Tomorrow. Right now, I need you
to deal with that guy in the corner.
The EMT thought it was cardiac,
but it's just a panic attack.
Take him somewhere quiet
and calm him down.
He knew that you were gonna propose.
He was so happy.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
They asked me to tell you
that they need the room.
My apartment is so empty.
His family took him to New York.
There isn't even a grave I can visit.
My mom used to take me
to the library on Olive.
Sometimes when I miss her,
I go back there
and take out her favorite book
and just get lost in it.
Stabilize the plate.
I'll place the lag screws in.
You were pretty
dismissive of your patient's mother.
Forgive me if I'm not all
broken up about that man's pain.
Riley didn't kill Asher.
And it's not your job to punish him.
I'm not.
But shouldn't people feel the
consequences of their actions?
Maybe,
but Riley's mother is feeling
the consequences, too.
Her son did this.
She should feel terrible.
Your anger is totally justified.
But is it helping you? Or anything?
If those monsters
hurt like we're hurting,
maybe something will change.
I did everything I could for your wife,
but her chest injury was just too...
No.
Excuse me. Doctor.
You need to look at this.
I've been waiting two hours.
S-Someone will get to you soon.
After my arm gets infected.
We're doing the best we can.
Then get more doctors.
Hey, look around you. People are dying.
Sit down and wait your damn turn.
You have a new patient.
20-year-old, shattered pelvis.
Charlie, I need that thing.
Sorry. I was reading Ethan's EKG.
Hook up the drain now.
Good. Start suction.
You're doing great.
Dr. Murphy doesn't think so.
He's still evaluating me.
That's why I filed the HR complaint.
We'll deal with that
when the time is right.
A bad evaluation will stop me
from getting into a surgical residency.
No matter what I do,
Dr. Murphy will
find something to criticize.
Why is he like that?
Dr. Murphy has been held
to a higher standard.
He's doing the same thing to you.
That's not fair.
Nevertheless,
he wants you to be perfect,
so you do the best you can.
I need you to treat a complex
liver laceration, Dr. Glassman.
I'm not operating. I told you that.
It can't wait.
Well, Dr. Lee should be finished by now.
I just gave him an open hip fracture.
Well, then transfer the patient to SFG.
They are on diversion.
For crying out loud, Shaun,
you know the last time
I was in an operating room,
and a liver lac?
Yes, it is a complicated,
multi-step surgery.
Exactly. I might kill the patient.
He's already dying.
You are my only option.
So it's me or the janitor?
The janitor is cleaning trauma two.
He is very bright but is...
Okay. Okay. Okay.
Just give me Nurse V.
At least she'll keep me honest.
Nurse Villanueva
is running the ER with me.
Nurse Paikin, then.
Assisting Dr. Lee.
Nurse Lashelle,
she is very experienced and available.
Okay, fine.
Keep an eye on Mr. Newton's
hemoglobin and Ethan's EKG.
My son's pain medication
still hasn't kicked in.
I'm on my way to surgery.
It's been two hours. Please!
Then he's likely maxed out
for the next couple hours.
I know what you think of me.
I can't even argue with you.
He left me a letter.
He didn't think he'd still be alive.
He wanted to die doing this.
For as long as I can remember,
I've been trying to help him.
We tried everything.
Pills, therapy,
inpatient, outpatient.
Seemed like he was making progress.
Maybe that's just what I hoped.
I'm angry, too, at him.
How could he have done this?
And I'm angry at myself for not
knowing what he was capable of.
I wish you would help him.
He's down a liter.
Give me two units.
Okay, here we go
into the triangle of death.
So many things can go wrong.
You want to talk it out?
Clamp the porta hepatis.
Ligate the left hepatic
to control the bleeding.
Remove the left lobe...
- Dr. Glassman?
- Yes.
I need you to look
at Ethan's rhythm strip.
Is it urgent?
He's in sinus rhythm,
but I noticed a run of PVCs.
Well, keep him monitored.
I'll check it when I'm done.
But a half hour ago, he had another run.
Didn't I tell
you to check every 45 minutes?
I'm being thorough.
PVCs are fairly common.
Can I do a 12 lead and electrolytes?
That's a good idea, Charlie.
Run it past Dr. Paxton in cardiology.
Mm.
Okay.
Clamp the porta hepatis.
Ligate the left hepatic
to control the bleeding.
I need threaded
pins here to stabilize the pelvis.
What is it?
He looks a lot like Asher.
Maybe a little.
Blood pressure's dropping.
There's bleeding
in the pelvis. Vascular clips.
Okay, your pressure's pretty high.
I still feel my heart racing.
That sounds normal.
Maybe that doctor lady
should do another EKG.
I learned about mindfulness-based
meditation last semester
in psych class.
I think that could help you.
I'm here for medical care, not yoga.
- Is that bad?
- It's just a little nosebleed.
Pinch hard.
I've never had a nosebleed like this.
I need a doctor in here. Hello?
Why is it not stopping?
Okay, 500cc bolus.
Get her to OR three with Dr. Lee.
I need to hand off to a doctor.
One minute.
Morgan can close this when she's free.
Two more Red Tags in the corridor.
- Have Jared take them.
- Dr. Kalu's still in the OR.
Then get Asher.
Asher?
Oh. He's dead.
One of the Red Tags
has a chest impalement.
He could go south soon.
Doc, my crew has an urgent pick-up.
Dr. Quao needs an anesthesiologist,
but they're all tied up.
I need you to look at Ethan's EKG.
There are some unusual patterns.
Dr. Glassman is supervising you.
He's busy. He sent me to Dr. Paxton.
He thinks this is normal,
but I think Ethan is gonna die again.
Okay.
Dr. Paxton was right and I am very busy.
If you compare them over the two hours,
you'll see the clusters.
- Sorry.
- Quao really needs an answer.
And that Red Tag needs a surgeon.
Okay.
- Look, two hours ago...
- Okay.
Dr. Murphy?
Dr. Murphy, Quao really needs an answer.
Doctor, we have an urgent pick-up.
- Find Dr. Park.
- We need a new Team Leader.
Wait.
Dr. Murphy, I see
you're covering your ears.
I think you're feeling very overwhelmed.
I would be, too,
with people coming up to me,
bombarding me with questions.
But maybe it would help
if you broke it down...
...step by step,
issue by issue.
We can't wait any longer.
Go find Dr. Park.
Get the plastics resident to
close for Dr. Park in OR one.
and send Dr. Park
to the corridor patient.
EMT can hand off to Dr. Steffy
in the procedure room.
And the anesthesiologist in trauma five
should be finishing soon.
Come with me now.
We are going to save
your patient's life.
He has a ventricular aneurysm.
His heart's going to rupture.
There's no empty OR and this can't wait.
- I will have to operate.
- Here?
- It's not sterile.
- I can treat an infection.
I can't do anything for him
if he's dead.
Okay. You have to help me.
It seems like it's slowing down.
This is a posterior epistaxis.
A what?
An artery ruptured
in the back of your nose.
You're bleeding out. I need help!
Look, I gotta go find you a doctor.
Uh, I don't feel so...
Help! I need help, somebody!
Somebody help!
Inflate the balloon...
I got the DeBakeys.
There are no Dacron sutures in the ER,
but I think the Teflon should
be a suitable replacement.
Yes, it is.
- I need a surgeon!
- Is that the aneurysm?
Yes, and we're too late.
It's already ruptured.
Give me your finger.
You need to plug this.
Don't move.
Clear.
Push another milligram of epi.
Charge to 50 joules.
Heart monitor's showing asystole.
It's an unshockable rhythm, Audrey.
Time of death, 4:50 p.m.
Somebody heard yell...
What the hell happened?
TachoComb sheet is in place.
Give me the...
Final closure.
I need to run mattress sutures
to secure it.
Any error, I will destroy
the blood supply
to his entire left ventricle.
- That sounds really bad.
- It would be catastrophic.
Can I help?
You must do exactly what I tell you
- exactly when I tell you.
- Okay.
Teflon sutures.
Cut here. Exactly here.
Very good.
Hold this forceps at a 30-degree angle.
You see that felt strip edge?
Press it down gently.
I couldn't watch the news anymore.
So I made cookies.
It's stupid.
What else can I do?
Nothing, Mom.
- You can't bring Asher back.
- I know.
I am so sorry.
Yeah.
Oh.
What were you gonna tell me
earlier today about Dad?
He was an amazing man.
Love of my life, really.
And he had clinical depression.
What?
He traveled for work,
but some of those trips,
they were hospital stays.
And he never wanted you to know.
- Why?
- Because...
he loved being your hero.
He loved being a success,
being immersed in his work.
But when those things
weren't propping him up...
he would get lost.
And I know that I am far from exciting.
No, you weren't all wrong about me.
More than anything,
I have found fulfillment
from the small connections
that I share with people...
like making cookies for my daughter.
He would have been so mad
that I told you,
but I realized that
I couldn't keep telling you
that I was worried about you
without telling the truth about why.
I loved your dad,
almost as much as I love you.
I am so proud of who you have become.
And I don't want you to end up like him.
Okay.
This will help him
sleep through the night.
I promise I'll keep
your son comfortable.
Thank you.
Simon. Kerry.
You ready to see your dad?
Go see your dad.
I saved Ethan's life twice today.
You just saved him once.
The first time I did.
I may have been wrong about you.
You might make
an adequate surgeon one day.
The corridor is clear,
and there are four empty bays
for walk-ins.
Thank you, Shaun.
You did a great job.
It was a lot to ask, especially today.
I am a good leader.
Let's take a look at that arm.
I'm sorry about earlier.
You were right.
Compared to what these people
are dealing with, this is...
You don't need to apologize.
It's just that my wife's
been home alone all day.
She has MS.
I have to lift her.
That sounds tough.
Not really.
She's an amazing woman.
An amazing architect.
What's her name?
I've sat there
every day since it happened.
I came to empty his locker.
I just can't.
Pre-gaming before Beyonce.
I'll help you.
Go home.
Rhino Rocket.
I could've stopped the bleeding
with a Rhino Rocket,
but I did everything wrong.
You were right.
I can't handle this job.
I should quit.
Don't be an idiot.
You saved a man's life
with a urinary catheter.
That's some kickass MacGyver medicine.
You still got game, Dr. Glassman.
Ha. Even MJ knew when to call it quits.
This felt like an old-timers game.
Well, nice to go out on a win, though.
Ah, thank you.
How's Ethan's heart?
It exploded. But we fixed it.
Oh, and I'm withdrawing the
HR complaint against Dr. Murphy.
For now.
I figured you guys
would need something to eat.
Oh, bless you.
I hear you're leaving town tomorrow.
Yes.
It's been a memorable trip.
Sorry about earlier. We, um...
Please sit. You've been
on your feet all day.
Come join us. I have extra sandwiches.
I, uh...
I found some things that I thought...
you might want.
Asher was waiting for the right moment
to slip that onto your desk.
A rep was handing these out
at a medical convention
that Asher and I went to.
I was going to toss it, but...
Asher stuffed it into his backpack.
I... already knew about
this articulating dissector.
It is very promising.
Oh...
I will miss Asher.
He was a good friend.
He was.
I'll miss him, too.
We all will.
I want to apologize for earlier...
going off-script in my eulogy.
I made it about my anger.
And if you knew Asher,
you'd know he would have plenty to say
about not being the center
of attention at his own funeral.
- This photo.
- Oh, yeah.