Hold on!
All right!
Coming.
Sorry. Did I wake you?
Uh, yeah, kind of.
Dr. Kovac ordered breakfast.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Have a good day. You too.
Sorry. I... I told him
to leave it outside.
That's okay. I had to get up.
Have some if you want.
No, thanks.
You want to take a
shower? I'm almost done.
Nah.
I have to stop home.
You working today?
Yeah.
Are you?
No, no.
Okay.
See you later, then.
Morning.
How was your night?
What's all this?
Mmm. I borrowed the
sewing machine from Marge.
Who's Marge?
Marge is your neighbor in 2A.
An adorable woman.
I'll introduce you to her.
Divorced.
Coffee's fresh.
Thanks.
You been up all night?
No. I got up early
just to finish this.
I have a big interview today.
Where'd you get all that fabric?
Sale at the yardage
store. Big sale.
And then I talked them
into a bit more of a discount.
Honey, I'm sorry.
I used the money you
gave me for bus fare.
I know it wasn't my money.
I will pay you back just
as soon as I get this job.
It's a fabulous place.
Fabulous. Very high-end.
Big commissions.
I'll buy us all-new furniture.
There. Finished. Tell
me what you think.
I copied it from something
I saw in a magazine.
You know, the
skirt and everything.
I shortened the
jacket. I changed...
You don't like it.
No, I do.
Do you? Heh-heh.
Oh, you know what I got you?
Something great.
Knit-jersey fabric.
I love the jersey. Where is it?
I'm gonna make you something.
Make that Euro-doctor
stand up and take notice.
Euro-doctor?
I've been here long enough
to know what's happening.
As far as I'm concerned
he's very handsome
but too old to be
playing hard to get.
Well, I thought I had him.
You do. You just
don't know you do.
When you're not looking,
he stares at you all the time.
Ah! Here it is. Come here.
Come here. Come here. Come here.
We're gonna make one of
those wraparound dresses
with a plunging neckline.
There we go.
He stares at me?
All the time.
I'm gonna take
some measurements.
Oh, no, no. I have to shower.
I have to work this morning.
Uh, honey, my... My
interview isn't until noon.
Maybe we could have
breakfast? Okay. If there's time.
Well, hurry up.
Honey, have you got any...?
What are you doing?
Counting your pills.
Why?
Just checking.
I told you I'd
take them. I know.
Did I pass inspection?
You taking any Prozac?
I'm normal. I'm normal.
I'm a little nervous
about this interview, but...
Prozac. Zoloft. Effexor.
I gave them to you.
Did you get more? How?
Mom.
Look, I told you.
I promised you.
You don't believe me?
Can you do me a favor?
Anything. Come to
the hospital with me.
What for? A blood test.
A blood test? Yes.
Would you do that for me?
Sure. Sure, I'd do
anything for you.
There was no epidural.
I was the only one
remotely close to the dura.
Answer the questions
honestly. You'll do fine.
I had to have punctured it.
It's a known risk. It does
not constitute negligence.
Mark, missing a leak does.
I don't even remember looking
before I removed the endoscope.
You've done 100 of these.
You know the procedure.
There was a bad outcome.
They're looking for
someone to blame.
It doesn't mean you
did anything wrong.
Do you want me to
ride with you there?
No, go to work.
You sure? Mm-hm.
Hey. Don't go jogging
into any more street signs.
Hard as a rock. Apparently not.
How long do these
depositions usually last?
Call me if it goes
past midnight.
What?
I'm just kidding.
I hate to go on an interview
with a big Band-Aid on my arm.
What will they think?
You have a suit jacket.
Yeah. Yeah, well, hope
I don't have to take it off
if the room gets
warm or something.
Tell them you gave blood.
Yes. I don't wanna
be late, though.
Rule number one is, do
not be late for an interview.
This will just take a
minute. I'd like to be early.
What if I go and come back?
Then if you want to do this...
Okay. Hold still.
I... I just don't
understand, Abby.
I mean, you've let
me in your home.
We're getting along so
well. This is an absolute gift.
I mean, what will taking
my blood accomplish?
Nothing, hopefully.
Wait, stop. Stop. Stop.
Listen to me, honey. Listen.
When this test comes
back negative or positive
or whatever it's supposed to be,
then you're gonna feel
foolish and I'm gonna be hurt.
And then you're gonna feel bad.
You can't touch the
vein after I've cleaned it.
That can't be what
you want! It's not.
Then, honey, let's
just not do this!
Need some help in here?
No, we're fine.
Hi, Dave.
Hey. Hello, Mrs. Lockhart.
Oh, it's Wyczenski.
Right. Right. Are
you not feeling well?
No. Why, do I look sick?
No, no.
Actually, you look great.
Oh, thank you.
You look good too.
Thank you.
Uh, what's the draw for?
I'm giving blood.
What? That's what
you told me to say.
Go. Just go. Go ahead.
What? Go. I don't
want you to be late.
Really? Yes.
Honestly? Yes.
Sweetie, I love you.
Okay. Thank you.
Bye, Dave. It's good
to see you, Miss W.
Miss W. Oh, I like that. Miss W.
I'll call you,
let you know how it goes.
Mwah, mwah, mwah. Bye.
Must be nice having
such good genes.
Knowing that you're gonna
grow up looking like that.
You got a...
Is this about a patient? No.
Bye, Randi. Hi, Maggie.
Oh, love that top! Oh, thanks.
He's supposed to be working.
Abby, have you seen Dr. Malucci?
He's around here somewhere.
Just tell him
Stephanie stopped by.
Your last name? He
knows my last name.
Uh-huh.
I don't get it. He had another
girl looking for him yesterday.
You fire enough shots,
eventually you hit something.
Or catch something.
Don't knock it till you try it.
What?
Abby! Abby! A girl out here
needs help! She's bleeding!
Some kids, they just
threw her from a car.
Honey, honey, here
you are. Take this.
What happened? They
hardly stopped the car.
I'm okay.
No, you're not. Mom, step back.
Okay. Let's sit down.
Come on. Careful.
Oh! Oh! Okay, okay.
What's your name? Kynesha.
Okay, Kynesha. Lean
back. Let me take a look.
Did someone beat you up?
I fell. Nonsense.
Honey, who did this?
Mom, go to your
interview. I'm trying to help.
We don't need your help. Go.
Did you lose consciousness?
No, no... Ah! Any
trouble breathing?
Get a gurney and page X-ray.
Abby? Yeah.
Mr. Resnik called
from the garage.
He's on his way up now.
Thank you.
We'll wait another five
minutes, and then we'll leave.
I can stay. I've taken
the whole day off.
No. We shouldn't have to
play these kind of games.
Gordy, good to see you.
Bruce. Sorry to
keep you waiting.
There was a pileup on the
expressway. A real mess.
I'm sure. You
must be Dr. Corday.
Yes. Bruce Resnik. A pleasure.
They didn't tell me
you were so stunning.
That's okay. You
don't have to respond.
Has the court
reporter set up, Fran?
In the library.
Well, let's get going.
After you.
Hey, Irene. How
are you this morning?
Fine, Mr. Resnik. Yourself?
Can't complain.
Hey, how are you?
Fine, thank you.
Please, have a seat.
Ignore the camera.
Thank you.
Everyone was rubbernecking
past this accident.
I waited my turn. So,
of course, I take a look.
You know, human nature.
And these firemen are using
one of those big
steel, um, things to cut.
What do you call
them? Uh, Jaws of Life.
Jaws of Life! Right.
I mean, it looked
pretty dangerous to me.
You ever use one?
No, not personally.
It was cutting into the
car like a can opener.
Anyway, shall we start?
Certainly.
Please raise your right hand.
Sit down.
There's no Bible? No.
Do you swear to tell the truth
in this matter, so help you God?
Yes. RESNIK: We
are on the record
in a deposition on the behalf
of the plaintiff, Al Patterson.
His attorney's Bruce Resnik.
Gordon Price for the defense.
Doctor, state and spell
your name for the record.
Elizabeth Corday. C-O-R-D-A-Y.
Doctor, how long have
you been a surgeon?
Including Residency? Yes.
Ten years.
Have you ever had a...?
A deposition taken before?
No, this is the first.
After 10 years,
that's pretty good.
Well, only three
have been in America.
Touché.
Extraocular
movements are intact.
Okay, Kynesha.
We need to remove your pants
so I can check
for injuries, okay?
It's just my face.
I know, but we
still need to check.
I'll be right back.
Hey, Peter.
Hey.
There's an inguinal
hernia in Curtain 3.
Could you take a look? Yeah.
After the assault
victim. We've got it.
Probably a facial fracture.
Well, I'll clear the belly.
She's stable.
There's blood in her underwear.
She says it's her period.
Get a rape kit.
Peter, wait.
You shouldn't take this one.
Why?
It's Jesse's girlfriend.
I can take care of her.
I'm gonna come in close
and check the back of your eyes.
Let's take a look
in your ears now.
Peter.
Good. No hemotympanum.
And what's that?
That means you
didn't crack your skull.
I'm Dr. Benton. I know.
Anyone you want us to call?
Mother, father?
She won't be home.
The re-enhancing lesion
and central necrosis on
MRI was, uh, suspicious.
The biopsy confirms it.
Another pathologist
should take a look.
Could be an astrocytoma.
Two neuro specialists reviewed
the slides independently.
They concur.
It's a GBM.
What's the survival rate?
Untreated, eight weeks.
But with radiation therapy,
the average increases
six to nine months.
You need to go see a
radiation oncologist today.
Wait... Wha...?
What about surgery?
Uh, I'm afraid the
tumor is inoperable.
Why?
It looks like it
invaded Broca's area.
The speech arrest
you were experiencing
was probably the
result of a focal seizure.
Even if we removed
the entire tumor,
you'd most likely be
left with the inability
to speak and
understand language.
Communication. More
than communication.
You'd... You'd lose all
ability to comprehend,
interact with the
world around you.
Essentially, what
makes you human.
Even if you consented,
I wouldn't even
consider operating.
We'll keep you on Dilantin,
uh, 300 milligrams daily.
Do you have
disability insurance?
Dr. Greene?
Yeah.
What's going on, Carter?
Why are we so backed up?
Uh, I... I just got here.
Weaver's not on till tonight.
This happens when she's off.
Hey, what happened to your head?
Oh, uh, jogging. I
ran into a street sign.
She left you a note.
Take the shoulder
pain and the vertigo.
Dr. Greene, guy
with palpitations.
Tachycardic at 300. BP is
100/70. Normal mentation.
Uh, six of adenosine.
I'll be right there.
Whoa, did you say
heart rate was 300?
Yeah.
If it's Wolff-Parkinson-White,
adenosine could
put him into V-fib.
Oh, yeah, right. 100
milligrams procainamide.
IV every 10 minutes.
Thanks, Carter. Sure. You okay?
Yeah. It's just, uh...
It's been a long morning.
Listen, we have to do a
blood and urine test on you.
It's your three-month mark.
Right now?
Sometime in the next
six hours. Whenever.
Listen, if you want
privacy, I'll do the stick.
Otherwise, you can ask a nurse.
Um, yeah, I'll ask Abby. Okay.
Randi, what's open?
Exam 1. Meet you there.
Liver and spleen are good.
No peritoneal free fluid.
No lacerations or contusions.
Kynesha, when's the last
time you had intercourse?
I don't remember.
Woods lamp.
I'll get the lights.
What's that do?
Hold on.
There's no semen.
What? BENTON: We got abrasions,
but no stridor.
I need to do a pelvic
exam, Kynesha.
Do you know what that is?
No. I'm on my
period. I told you.
I still need to check.
Hey, hey. Whoa, whoa.
Let me go! Come
on. Hey, calm down.
Kynesha, it's important
we give you an exam.
Not down there.
Just fix my face.
Look, we know it's hard, but if
someone sexually assaulted you,
we have to check.
I didn't get raped. I
got beat up. That's all.
Who beat you up?
I got jumped out. No big thing.
Of a gang? I did okay.
Some girls get real messed up.
I did okay.
So you concede
Mr. Patterson's surgery
started at 5:17 p.m.
According to the chart, yes.
And you sent Mr. Patterson
to Pre-Op at 2:15 p.m.?
Approximately, yes.
Expecting to operate
within the hour?
Expecting to
operate immediately.
But you didn't.
You didn't start the operation
for another three
hours, did you?
No. Why not?
I'm on emergency call.
A life-threatening gunshot wound
to a 14-year-old boy came in.
I had to respond.
And were you able
to save this boy?
No.
And this Jesse Robbins...
uh, did you know him?
By association, yes.
And that association was through
a colleague, Dr. Peter Benton?
He was Dr. Benton's nephew.
And Dr. Benton is
your former lover?
Don't answer that.
Was the young boy
you weren't able to save
the nephew of your former lover?
Move it along, Bruce.
That has no probative value,
and she's not answering it.
Are you refusing to answer...?
She's not answering
the question.
Fine. She'll answer
in front of the judge.
So the death of his
nephew was upsetting to you.
Of course.
How long did it upset you?
I'm not sure.
Well, losing a young
boy, a boy you knew,
a boy close to someone
you cared about,
it must have been
quite overwhelming.
Is that a question?
Was it overwhelming?
At that moment.
So overwhelming
and tragic, in fact,
that it was still on your mind
while you operated on my client.
Wasn't it, Dr. Corday?
Guess I should have had
that blood transfusion
this morning, huh?
Come on. That was funny.
This is kind of
ironic, isn't it?
Check my cholesterol
while you're at it?
Hey, you! You're supposed to
be watching this. You better watch.
You think I want to
be doing this, Carter?
I don't have
better things to do?
Okay. What should
I do with this?
Give it to me. We done?
Yeah.
Abby, paramedics
called. Your mom's hurt.
She's asking for
you. What happened?
I don't know. She's outside a
clothing store on Oak Street.
If she wants to give
names, I'll check it out.
She's afraid. She's
not going to give names.
Dr. Benton?
She wants to talk to you.
She changes her
mind, give me a call.
Peter, I said I'd
take care of her.
I got it.
Looks like you broke
your cheekbone.
Gonna have to do a
CAT scan of your face.
So you're really gonna protect
the girls who did this to you?
Protecting myself.
They find out I said
something, they gonna kill me.
Like they did Jesse?
You don't know that.
I know he wasn't a gang
member and you are.
Was.
I know that the only reason
he was in that neighborhood
is because of you.
He only came there twice.
Said he didn't like me banging.
Kept telling me that I
was better than all that.
That he loved me.
He was gonna get me out.
You're telling me that's
why they killed him?
He ditched school.
Tried to get me to come over.
Told me that his mom
was gonna figure things out.
We had a fight.
I was walking away
when it happened.
You...? You saw who shot him?
That's why I don't want
to be a part of it no more.
I loved him too.
Who shot him, Kynesha?
You just said you loved him.
You'll tell the
cops if I told you.
No. Why you asking?
Because I gotta know.
You swear you ain't
gonna say nothing?
Kynesha...
Who murdered my nephew?
- Hold still.
- My daughter is a doctor.
I don't need you to do
any of this. Don't touch me.
She's a doctor. She will
be here. She can do this.
Abby, this wasn't my fault.
This... This man came after me.
You her daughter? I didn't
even know who he was.
She was shoplifting.
I was not shoplifting!
Why would I
shoplift a $10 scarf?
It's a $300 scarf.
Well, it looks like a
$10 scarf, I'll tell you!
She ran straight into my door.
Shattered glass everywhere.
You don't want to arrest her.
It's not worth it. I'm a nurse...
What's wrong with her?
Nothing's wrong with me!
What's wrong with you?
She has a mood disorder.
She was stealing.
She wasn't stealing.
She was confused.
You weren't there.
She walked into the
store, demanded a job.
I explained... Let me
tell you something,
I have better retail skills than
you do any day of the week!
Be quiet, Mom!
Common courtesy and
politeness being two of them!
Can I just give you
my phone number,
and then I... I'll
pay for the glass?
Is that cool with you?
What if she comes back? I
mean, I have customers in there.
She... She's not
gonna come back.
You'll take care of
it? Yes, I promise.
All right. Fine! Just...
Just get her out of here!
Up to 5 of Haldol, p.r.n.
You got it? Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
What? Huh?
You wanted to see me? Yeah.
Carter, your naltrexone
level was nondetectable.
My naltrexone level?
The blood test. You're
supposed to be on 50 mgs a day.
I just thought it
was a drug screen.
I didn't know you
were screening for that.
It's in your contract.
Well, my prescription ran out,
and I haven't
had time to refill it.
You know that it's
part of the agreement.
And I'm taking it.
I don't need it,
and I'm taking it.
What? You're not the only one
with something at
stake here, Carter.
We put ourselves on the
line to give you a fresh start.
In any other circumstance,
you'd either be dead or in jail.
Fresh start, huh?
You think this has
been a fresh start? Yeah.
I think that I've done
absolutely everything
that you've asked of me.
And I've done it
without complaint.
I think that I've obeyed
all these arbitrary
and arcane rules and regulations
about what patients I can
treat and what patients I can't,
when I can treat
them and when I can't.
I think I've peed into cups. I
think you've taken my blood.
And I think at some point,
it's gonna have to be enough.
I think at some point, you're
actually gonna have to trust me.
Hey, Mark!
Hey, I need some help in here!
Chuny, get me some Ativan!
Oh, my God! What happened?
Get the Ativan. How much?
Four milligrams. Now.
Did he hit his head?
No. Does he have a fever?
I don't know. He
just started seizing.
Hold him still.
All right. Start him on...
Start him on 15 liters of O-2.
Get a line going.
And then I need a pulse
ox and a set of vitals.
Get a tox screen.
Finger stick of glucose.
What do you want for labs?
CBC and a Chem-20.
Carter?
Dr. Greene? Hey, hey,
Mark! Can you hear me?
Squeeze my
hands. Right and left.
What happened?
You had a seizure.
Your vitals have been stable
and you didn't drop your sats.
We're gonna take
you for a head CT.
See if you can follow
my finger with your eyes.
Come on, Mark. Just lay back.
No. We need to work this up.
I don't want to work it up.
Neuro is coming
down for a consult.
It's not necessary.
Yes, it is. You had
a new onset seizure.
I just need a Dilantin level. I
can go to the outpatient lab.
Sit down and relax. Come on.
I called Kovac in to cover.
You've got a
Hep-Lock on your arm.
I'll handle it. I'll
handle it! Mark. Mark...
Dr. Greene, are you okay?
I'm fine.
Hey, boss, what are you
doing? I heard you had a seizure.
Yeah? You heard wrong.
But Mr. Patterson's condition
needed immediate
surgical attention, did it not?
It depends on what you
mean by "immediate."
You had to operate that day.
Within the next 24 hours.
And the endoscopic surgery
is certainly the fastest
procedure, correct?
Among other benefits.
So it was more
convenient for you.
I base my surgical opinions
on what I perceive to be
in the best interests
of the patient.
The recovery, how...
Let me try again.
Perhaps you didn't
hear the question.
The endoscopic surgery
was faster and therefore easier
on your schedule than the
alternate open procedure.
Of course, but... Thank you.
How long does the
endoscopic procedure take?
My schedule had
nothing whatsoever
to do with my advice
to Mr. Patterson.
Please strike that
as nonresponsive.
Dr. Corday, how long does
the endoscopic procedure
take to perform?
About an hour.
But you performed
Mr. Patterson's
endoscopic discectomy
in 42 minutes.
Correct? I don't know.
I'd have to check
the operative report.
Well, if the operative report
stated that you were in the O.R.
with Mr. Patterson
less than 43 minutes,
would you say that's
correct? It could be.
Do you have any reason to
doubt the veracity of the report?
No.
Would it surprise you
that of the 87 endoscopic
discectomies you performed
before November 16,
your fastest time
was 54 minutes?
Twelve minutes slower
than Mr. Patterson.
Objection. You're
testifying, Bruce.
It's a question. She can count.
Would that surprise you?
Let's move on. Did you know
that the fastest you had
ever performed this procedure
was 12 minutes slower
than Mr. Patterson's surgery?
I do now.
You don't time yourself?
It's not a race.
Then why did the circulating
nurse remind you it was 10 to 6?
Objection. Assumes
facts not in evidence.
Do you recall the circulating
nurse reminding you
that it was 10 to 6 while you
were operating on Mr. Patterson?
Yes.
Why did you need to be reminded?
To keep me on schedule.
And what did you have scheduled
after Mr. Patterson's surgery?
I had an engagement.
Someplace more
important that you had to be?
No, and I resent the inference.
What inference is that?
That I rushed
Mr. Patterson's surgery
in order to satisfy a
personal obligation.
Okay, that's it.
We're taking a break.
Did you? Did you
rush? Don't answer that.
Were you reminded of the time
because you needed to leave?
Yes. PRICE: We're
taking a break.
Did you get that? No.
We're off the record.
Stop typing.
Now, I said we're
taking a break.
Let's go.
All I wanted to do
was talk to the owner.
If I could just talk to
him, he'd want to hire me.
What happened?
I don't know.
Dr. Greene had a seizure? Yeah.
I've never understood people
who make themselves feel big
by making other
people feel small.
Let me tell you something.
I've got plenty of experience.
Plenty. You know what? Sit down.
She was threatened,
is what she was.
She knew I could
outsell her. She knew it.
And so she... She sent
that Neanderthal in on me.
Know why? She was threatened.
Did you even have an interview?
Of course I had an interview.
Until she chased
me into the window.
Ow! Ow!
Oh, God. This is
bad! This is bad.
You need stitches.
Here. Sit down.
I'll get an x-ray and make
sure there's no glass in it.
Ow! All right. Keep
some pressure on it.
I'll be right back. Abby. Abby.
What? You're mad at me.
No, Mom, I'm not mad at you.
I thought you would be mad.
Sit down.
I have plenty of experience.
Plenty of experience.
Do you think I'm
gonna put up with that?
Well, I'm not.
I'm not. I'm not
gonna put up with that.
See if I don't.
I hate people like that.
I have so much more
experience than you.
I don't think she's
gonna say anything.
She wouldn't have told if she
didn't want us to get this girl.
I gave you the name. Why
don't you go pick the girl up?
We have to get it
from the witness.
What if she doesn't
say anything?
Depends. We can bring
in the DA, maybe a judge.
There's, uh, fluid in
the maxillary sinus.
But no depressed fracture.
Good. Good.
Kynesha, there are a
couple of guys out here
that need to talk to you.
No! No way!
I told you I don't know nothing!
Looks like you're
feeling better.
Yeah.
Hey, I got my
prescription refilled.
Do you want to see me take it?
No.
Thanks for helping me out.
Sure. You want to tell
me what happened?
Not particularly.
You know, I did treat you.
Technically, I am your doctor.
Anything you tell
me is confidential.
Okay, doctor.
It's quite simple.
I have a brain tumor.
What? Glioblastoma multiforme.
Bummer, huh?
Gets better.
I found out that
it's inoperable.
Oh, Mark. I'm sorry.
Yeah. Well...
You're up.
What are you gonna do?
Die, I guess.
After today, I probably won't
be able to work anymore, so...
Did you get a second opinion?
They double-checked the biopsy.
No, by another neurosurgeon.
There's gotta be a clinical
trial going on someplace, right?
Yeah. Looking into it.
Oh, looks like they need you.
Are you gonna be okay?
Stupid question, Carter.
Do me a favor.
Try and keep the rumors
from spreading around here
before I get a chance
to talk to Elizabeth.
Sure.
Do you know what time it is?
Uh, 2:47.
Correct, but it's
not the right answer.
It's not?
No, the right answer
is "yes" or "no."
Yes or no when
possible. Don't elaborate.
Not all questions have
a yes or no answer.
I understand. Yes or no
when possible. Don't elaborate.
We don't win
cases in deposition,
but we can lose them.
At best, this is a
stain that follows you
for the rest of your career.
At worst, you lose your license.
We're not here to
win an argument.
This is about information.
He's looking to gain information
to use against you in court.
We're looking to
limit that information.
You mean hide the truth.
I didn't say that.
How many do you think? Stitches?
Uh, four. Five.
Five?
You're so good at this.
You're so gentle.
Thank you.
It's hard to believe
'cause you have such
great big, masculine hands.
Oh...! Oh!
Sit still. Don't move.
Don't move. Don't move.
Eyelash. See?
Okay, now you have to
make a wish and blow.
That's all right.
Okay. I'll blow for you.
What did you wish for?
Don't tell me. Don't tell me.
I'm sorry.
You're sorry for what?
It's, uh, part of the disease.
Oh!
Oh, yes. We're going
to now apologize
for your diseased
mother, are we?
Are we?
She's always misbehaving.
You know, Abby never
wanted me around her friends.
She was always ashamed. Stop it.
Ashamed and embarrassed.
You think I don't know?
Let him finish your hand.
You would walk by me
and pretend you didn't know
me. You'd pretend I didn't exist.
Let him finish your
hand and shut up!
Don't sass me! I'm your
mother! Not by choice.
Okay. Okay. Okay. All right.
Okay! Do you want
a 5 of Haldol? No!
Abby, I'm sorry!
Do you want 5 of
Haldol? I'm sorry!
I don't want Haldol!
Sit still and behave
and we won't give you anything.
Don't! You let me go! Okay.
I'm leaving! I'm leaving!
I'm leaving!
I am leaving!
No! No! No!
No! No! No! No!
You want a 5 of Haldol?
Get restraints, stat!
No! No! Start an IV!
Abby! Abby!
Abby, no! Don't let
them do this to me! Abby!
Abby, don't let them...
Starting a line with saline.
Here! Arm restraints!
Okay, call Psych.
Put her on the monitor.
Please!
Please don't let
them do this, Abby!
Come on, Maggie. Calm down.
No!
Maggie! Maggie!
Maggie. MAGGIE: Don't!
Don't!
You... You're my
daughter, you little bitch!
Make them stop!
No! No! No!
They're ready to start again.
You okay? You
look a little peaked.
Oh, I'm fine.
Look, we're getting to
the critical stage, here.
So if you don't feel like you
can maintain your composure...
No. No, I want to
get this over with.
Okay.
What's he doing here?
It's his deposition.
He has a right to be here,
just like you have a right
to be at any of our depositions.
Don't they have to tell us?
He's been brought
in to rattle you.
Just stay calm.
Pretend he's not there.
Don't let it affect you.
Are we ready to start?
Yes. Okay?
You removed the restraints?
I can admit her voluntarily,
but she doesn't meet
the criteria for a hold.
Ran through a
plate-glass window.
An accident. She's
not gravely disabled.
She's not a danger
to herself or others.
That's debatable.
She's rapid-cycling.
Probably experiencing
a drug-induced mania.
Blood alcohol's 0.092.
Well, that'll do it.
So do you want me to admit her?
I don't care.
Okay, I'll do it.
She wants to talk to
you. She's remorseful.
She wants to apologize.
No, thank you.
Okay.
Abby, I'm sorry.
Hey, Maggie... I'll
go in the hospital.
I'll get better. Go
back inside the room.
Go back to bed. I'll get better.
It's all right.
I'll get better.
Get some frozen peas.
Reuse them every four hours
on your face for 20 minutes.
You can take some
ibuprofen for the pain.
I want you to come
back for a recheck.
Hey, he was my nephew. You
knew I had to do something.
LOL, complains of weakness...
Yeah. Good luck.
While under a hair dryer.
Ma'am, were you having any
chest pain or shortness of breath?
No, dear. The dryer
was just set too high.
Okay. EKG, CBC,
Chem-7, and get a chest.
I'll be right with
you, Mrs. Fruhman.
Thank you, dear.
They think they're
gonna find the shooters.
The ones who killed Jesse.
Good. I hope it helps.
Yeah. Cleo...
I got angry, you know?
And I got you angry.
You're the only thing in my
life that makes sense right now.
You know what I'm trying to say,
I'm, you know, sorry.
Buy me some dinner.
I'll consider your apology.
Well, then in your
medical opinion,
what caused the meningocele
that cut off the blood supply
to Mr. Patterson's spinal cord?
A leak of CSF,
cerebrospinal
fluid from the dura
which covers the spinal canal.
Which means you must have
punctured the dura
during the procedure.
That seems evident now, yes.
It wasn't evident
during the procedure?
No.
It was apparently evident
to the anesthesiologist.
Objection. Argumentative.
According to the
operative report,
Dr. Babcock, the
anesthesiologist,
drew your attention
to spinal fluid
in the surgical
field at 10 to 6.
Correct?
No.
The note says
10 to 6, doesn't it?
Yes.
The report is wrong?
No. He did draw
my attention to fluid.
Fluid we now know
to be spinal fluid.
No.
What could it have been, doctor?
Saline.
But you understood that the
anesthesiologist was concerned
it might be spinal fluid?
Yes.
And how did you satisfy
yourself that it wasn't?
I suctioned the
irrigation saline
and did not see
any persistent CSF.
Did you look?
I can't operate without looking.
Well, given that it was 10 to 6,
that you were in a hurry,
the nurse simultaneously
reminding you of your date...
Objection.
Can we get to a question, Bruce?
Did you perform a complete
and competent inspection
of the field to ensure
there were no CSF leaks?
Sometimes leaks are so small
you cannot detect them visually.
Nevertheless, did you
perform a thorough inspection?
That's procedure. And
you followed procedure
by performing a
thorough inspection?
Objection. Asked and answered.
It's been asked. It has
not been answered.
What was the question?
Did you perform a thorough
and competent inspection
specifically looking
for possible CSF leaks
before you closed?
Yes.
Hey.
Hey. Where did you go?
I was looking all over for you.
Took a walk. Got
a cup of coffee.
You didn't get my page?
I knew what it was about.
Yeah. Legaspi was trying
to find a bed for your mom,
and, uh, she just took off.
I figured. Thanks.
Maybe you want to
check your apartment...
She's not there.
You checked?
No. Uh, this is the
end of the cycle.
Our cycle. She disappears.
And then for months, I
don't know where she is
or what she's doing
or if she's alive.
And then eventually,
she'll turn up somewhere,
and I'll have to deal with it.
I'm sorry.
Don't be.
I knew how it would
end when she showed up.
It's the dance we do.
You get lost in
it for a little while,
but it always ends the same.
Do you...? You ready?
Yeah.
Carter, I forgot to tell Weaver
enzymes are pending
on Mr. Albe in 4.
I'll tell her. Thanks.
Good night, Carter.
You coming in?
I don't want to intrude.
They're probably
just eating. Come on.
Jackie always makes
so much food anyway.
They need some
time to themselves.
I'll wait for an invitation.
All right. I'll just grab
some stuff for tomorrow.
I'll be right back.
Dr. Benton.
What are you doing here?
I went to the
store, like you said.
Jackie see you? No.
You can't be here.
The cops was there
hooking up the cousins.
- They gonna think it was me!
- Have you been home yet?
No. They're gonna
kill me! I'm dead!
Shh! Come on. Get in the car.
I talked to the cops.
I can't go home.
I told you this was
gonna happen.
All right, just get in the
car. I'll figure out something.
Mark?
I'm up here.
What are you doing?
Just thinking.
How'd it go?
Terribly.
What happened?
W-what? W-what is it?
I lied.
The fact is, I rushed.
I rushed through
and didn't inspect
the entire surgical field.
That man will never walk again
because I wanted to get
out early for the weekend.
And I... I couldn't even
claim responsibility.
I sat there, and I...
I swore to God, and
I lied to save myself.
God owes us one.
I think you're allowed
to be selfish for a while.
I didn't run into a street sign.
I had a biopsy.
Those, uh, headaches
weren't from hockey.