After a trauma,
your body is at its
most vulnerable.
Response time is critical.
So you're suddenly
surrounded by people.
- Doctors, nurses...
-  Focus, focus.
- Specialists, technicians.
-  You got it, you got it!
- Go!
- Surgery is a team sport.
A little more!
A little bit more!
Everyone pushing
for the finish line.
- Yes!
- Yay, fingers!
Yeah. Yeah.
Putting you back together again.
It's OK, you're
retraining your brain.
Getting your fingers straight
was the goal for today.
Little goals, remember?
All right, let me in there
to check her incision.
Morning. Baby report.
- Boom!
- I'm gonna go see her.
- Hey. You're awesome.
- Gimme, gimme, gimme.
See? She's moving her
arm like she's waving.
She still hasn't opened her eyes,
but she only stopped breathing once
last night and, get this, her
brain bleed's still grade one.
Good girl! She looks bigger.
Is she bigger?
All right, some of
us are still working.
- Let me get in there, please.
- OK. I have a consult. I have to go.
How are you?
I... almost got
my hand straight.
- That's great!
- Yeah.
But surgery is a
trauma in and of itself.
So today? I can see her today?
And once it's over,
the real healing begins.
- We call it recovery.
- I'm sorry...
- No. No!
- But until you can be mobilized
and your infections are completely
gone, you cannot see her.
And she cannot leave the NICU.
Now, you know I would if I
could. You know that. Right...
Recovery is not a team sport.
- Yang, tell her I would.
- Mm-hm? Mm-hm.
She would, if she could.
It's a solitary distance run.
- Are you giving me the finger?
- Yes, I am.
Good job.
It's long, it's exhausting...
and it's lonely as hell.
Mrs. Pulcher, you're gonna
have to stop the smoking.
- Your infections
are getting worse.
- Your infections, you mean.
I didn't have them before
you two idiots operated,
and you didn't
even do that right.
Again, I'm sorry,
but your lung cancer
- had spread to the point...
- Please. Useless.
I can afford any
hospital in the world,
and I come to this third-rate crap
factory. When am I getting out of here?
I've been here for three
weeks. This is not Guantanamo.
Discharge her.
Please. I'll pay you.
There's not much more that we can
do unless you're willing to help yourself.
- Now, the smoking...
- If I wanted a lecture
on smoking,
I'd dig up my dead husband. Now, get
me outta here before I sue your balls off.
Well, we'll run some tests.
And if your white blood cell count
- is up to an acceptable
level...
- How high does it have to be?
- Give me a number.
- It's at a point-eight now.
- I'd like it to be above a two.
- One.
- This is not a negotiation.
- Everything is. One-point-five.
One-point-five and
you let me outta here.
Now, get me a wheelchair. 'Cause
if I have to wait around this hellhole,
- I'm gonna smoke.
- OK.
Oh! I smoothed out some bumps in
the NICU surgery protocol if you want to...
stop acting like a child.
You crushed his heart, April,
and none of us thought he had one.
- So that's impressive.
- It's inconvenient.
I need him to sign this.
- Uh... morning.
- Oh. Good morning.
- Another Alzheimer's
trial patient?
- Yes, sir.
Good, good.
How's your islet cell trial going?
Have you found a resident to assist you?
- Yeah. Avery's gonna
help me out today.
- Great. Good.
And Mrs. Webber?
How is she feeling?
She's doing all
right. Thank you.
Oh, sir...
You...
Wow, that kid looks screwed.
He is. He has five different
cardiac and abdominal defects.
I'm supposed to operate
on him next week.
That's awesome. Can I scrub in?
Yeah, if you can
get us to Africa.
I was supposed to go
back there next week, but
now I have a very
sick little girl of my own
- and a fiancee in the ICU.
- Fly him out here.
Yeah, I've tried. But you can't
imagine the red tape and the money.
And there's a dozen more like him
that I want to do the same thing for.
I'm trying to find someone
to help him out over there.
I just... I made a
promise, that's all.
It's healing pretty well.
Maybe in a couple of days
you can try sitting up by yourself.
- Let's try now.
- You can't rush it.
Why did I get you? Why aren't
you cutting out hearts somewhere?
Well, Altman and
I had a falling out,
over your ventricular
septal defect, actually.
I'm just giving her some
space. OK, you're good.
- You need anything?
- I need to see my baby.
She's mostly tubes and wires.
And she looks more like
a chicken than a baby.
Like a featherless, beakless
chicken. You want to wait...
- until she's cuter.
- You are the worst godmother
ever.
You picked me.
She opened her eyes. Sofia!
She looked right at me! I
saw her sweet, little eyes!
They're beautiful.
They look just like yours!
Oh, my God, I should
have taken pictures!
Why didn't I do that?!
Oh, no! Oh, no! Oh,
God, no! I'm so sorry...
Go, go, go, go! Go get the
pictures! Go get the pictures!
Callie. Callie.
No, don't. Callie! Callie, stop
it. Stop it, stop it, stop it! Callie!
- You'll rupture your sutures.
- I'm missing her! I am missing her.
- I know, honey. I know.
- She could die and I'll
never...
- I could miss her whole life!
- OK, OK.
Easy, easy, relax.
Lie back down.
- Pulse is 102.
- Are you nervous, Ed?
Yeah, it's kinda like going
to the dentist, only worse.
This is gonna be over
before you even know it starts.
Dr. Grey is gonna do the drill now.
You're not gonna feel anything, though.
- Ed. Try and relax, OK?
- I can't.
All right, stop.
Stop. Just pull back.
Let's get the halo
off, he's having an MI.
OK. Flatline!
What the hell happened?!
- His EKG was fine?
- He never complained
of chest pain.
I did the work-up, there
was nothing in his history.
It wasn't your fault.
It was a massive MI.
After we inform
Mr. Beckert's family,
I will call the FDA
and file a formal report.
Is there a chance they
could shut down the trial?
It doesn't matter.
I'm gonna shut it down,
pending the autopsy.
I want to know why
we didn't see it coming.
I thought Dr. Bailey said
Torres can't be moved yet.
Yes, sir, but since she has
had no contact with the baby,
- I was wondering
how soon we might...
- Bring the baby to Torres?
I think it'll do the
both of them good.
- If I could at least
tell Dr. Torres...
- When the baby is off the vent.
When she has an immune system
and can withstand the onslaught
of deadly infections Dr. Torres
would threaten her with. That's when.
I mean, come on! I'm all
for mother-baby bonding,
but not when
it'll kill the baby.
Why do you even
ask me these things?
I thought you were a doctor.
Ouch.
I need your help with something.
Oh, wait! I have
patient 122's trial packet.
It was never opened, so it
needs to go back into the lot.
OK, one sec.
I heard about your patient.
- I'm sorry.
- Thank you.
- Have a good night.
- You, too.
Henry, will you
just open the door?
I'm sorry, the place is... You
were just supposed to tell me
if this is normal or if I need
to... if I need to go to the hospital.
Will you just sit
down and be quiet?
Did you check your blood sugar?
Fifty-six. But I
don't have any juice.
- I just have
half a can of diet soda.
- OK, OK.
- Damn it. Look at you.
- What?
You look amazing. You
were on a date, weren't you?
I made you come here
in the middle of a date.
No, you know what?
Actually, you saved me
from the longest date
with the most tedious man.
The only good thing that came
out of the date were these cannolis.
Which, as it turns out, is
exactly what someone needs
when they're having a
hypoglycemic episode.
- You still shouldn't have come.
- You know what? You'll stop saying that
once you try this.
Mm!
- Yeah. OK.
- Good.
- Tell me about this date.
- Well...
Mm. His name is Erwin.
- Ooh.
- Mm.
OK, so strike one.
No!
Give me that.
So am I leaving?
What's my number?
It's not good.
Not your opinion,
stupid. Number.
Point-six.
It's gone down.
I'm sorry the results
weren't better.
You should be, you worthless
bastard. It's all your fault.
Get out of my sight. I can't stand
looking at your stupid face! Go!
- How'd she take it, Karev?
- Bitchy. 'Cause she's a bitch.
She's also dying. She's alone.
She hasn't had any family or visitors
- since she got here.
- Well, maybe that's 'cause...
Let's keep our
assessments to ourselves.
Karev, what's your
plan for chief resident?
- My plan?
- Mm.
Besides badmouthing patients.
All your colleagues are showing
some kind of leadership potential.
Grey and Avery,
they're on clinical trials,
Kepner's overhauling the surgical
checklists. They have a plan.
- I was just wondering if you...
- African kids!
- Sorry?
- I'm gonna bring over about
a dozen kids from Africa
and get them surgeries.
Badly needed surgeries.
- Hm. Sounds pretty ambitious.
- I'm an ambitious guy.
It also sounds like you just
pulled that outta your butt.
Oh, no, sir. It's
a... It's a plan
that I've been... planning.
OK. Well, good. Let
me know if I can help.
- Right outta your butt.
- Shut up.
Are you guys
ready? Let's do this.
Wake up.
Just lay still and relax. Let us
do everything. Can you do that?
Tell him that cholie
moved to 8:30 tomorrow.
Back, back, back.
OK.
Dr. Bailey.
- Can I ask you something?
- What is it?
- How's your day going?
- How's my day going?
My day should have
ended three hours ago.
I'm tired, it's late,
and I still have six more
things to do before it's over,
and now I have you in my face
asking me how my day is going.
OK, OK, OK, OK.
We'll give you some privacy.
Oh.
Hi.
Hi, baby.
Don't worry.
See? I'm...
I'm a little messed up, too.
But we're gonna be fine, OK?
We're gonna be just fine.
- Hey.
- Hey. How is Mr. Beckert's wife?
- Her kids took her home. I can't believe they lied to us.
- They didn't lie.
They just left out the history of his heart
problems because they needed this trial.
While we're waiting for the FDA
to respond, I wanna re-screen
all the applicants
with a fine-tooth comb.
- Is that what you're doing now?
- No. As morbid as it sounds,
I'm trying to find a
replacement for Mr. Beckert.
- A new Patient 122?
- We'll need to have one ready.
- OK. So, what about Adele
Webber?
- Meredith. You know I want to,
but she's just not far enough along.
Her disease has not progressed enough
for her to be eligible for
this trial. You know that.
Well, this fell off of Richard's
sweater this morning.
Breathe.
- Breathe.
- No!
She can't talk to me like
that! I'm a trained professional.
- She's an uncooperative,
insulting...
- Fiancee of mine.
- So let's just... let's watch it.
- He's a wuss! Let him go!
Good luck.
That's the third one this month.
- They don't push me
hard enough.
- It's a traumatic brain injury.
- It's not boot camp.
- We're getting married.
- You want me walking down the
aisle, not rolling, right?
- I want you healed.
It's OK. The wedding can...
Sorry! I'm sorry.
The baby won't wait.
You can pick her up.
You can hold the baby. Mark can
hold the baby. I can't hold my baby!
Don't tell me it's OK!
I'm sorry.
Then bring me
those balls, please.
I've got eight patients lined
up from three African countries,
all through the Namboze
Clinic. There's a... Wait.
Here. A cardiac defect, a brain
tumor, an idiopathic gangrene case.
When do we get to see
that, right? What else?
Oh, and Hunt, he got me in touch with
a military guy about ground transport.
And he also volunteered
to operate, pro bono.
So I've got him and Robbins,
Bailey, Sloan, Shepherd...
Stop.
How are you gonna
pay for all this?
Well, that's why
I'm talking to you.
You're the chief
of Peds surgery.
I mean, they're
incredible surgeries.
- On kids.
- OK. This is coming
out of my budget?
I'm saying, if I do
all the logistical crap,
it's a project the hospital
should fund, right?
- It's worth...
- Nothing. That's what it's
worth. No.
I'm sorry.
Right. I should have
known what you'd say.
No. You don't get to do that.
You don't get to ask me to
fund a plan this half-assed,
and then paint me as somebody who wants
to deny health care to Third World kids.
Come on.
I mean, there are people
that can do this sort of thing,
but you're not one of 'em.
- Mrs. Pulcher.
- Ooh.
Is it two hours already? Ow.
Seems like I saw your
slack jaw a minute ago.
I feel like I just saw
your blistery old butt.
Don't... You can't
speak to me like that.
You can't speak to me like that.
I should sue you ten grand
for every bedsore on my ass.
I'll die before I ever see
any of that money, but I'll...
- But you'll die rich.
- Richer, thanks to you
dumbasses.
Or you could do something
good with the money.
Donate it to a good
cause. Help someone out.
Or put it to getting
you a medical degree?
Mrs. Pulcher, I have a plan to
bring some African kids over here
for some really cool...
I mean, desperately
needed surgeries.
You asking me for money?
I need at least a hundred grand
- to get things started.
- Oh, my God!
Take it somewhere else, Sally
Struthers. And get out of my face!
Overall, Adele scored a
23, which is a marked decline
from the last time we
tested her, which was 27.
So she's definitely a lot
worse than we thought.
Well, the upside is
she gets in the trial.
- But she's declining so fast.
- I know.
Why can't we just give her the
medicine on the side, outside of the trial?
- Who would know?
- No.
The FDA is going to be
on us harder than ever.
Anything we do that taints
the results would ruin the trial,
and not to mention
our careers along with it.
Don't think I haven't
thought about it.
She's in heart failure. She's
gotta go back on the vent.
- She needs surgery now?
- As soon as possible.
Her ductus arteriosus
hasn't closed.
Fletcher's a no-go.
I'm gonna try Terry
Lennox at Seattle Pres.
I know I'm not high on your
list, but your baby's out of time.
You know it can't be you. I've
performed the procedure before.
- So... you're stuck with me.
- I understand.
Although you're not
technically related to the baby...
- I'm sorry, what?
- The hospital would have no
ethical objection if I let
you be in the OR with me.
If you'd like to look
over my shoulder.
You know, make
you feel any better.
- Thank you.
- OK.
We'll page you when we're ready.
- Thanks.
- I'll go tell Callie.
- So should I get her prepped?
- Looks like I'm stuck with you,
too.
- You ready to go back?
- Mm-mm. One more lap.
- Did you lose a bet?
- She's my new physical
therapist.
- Because she does
what I tell her to.
- Whose charts are those?
Altman's. She's
being ridiculous.
I haven't seen a cardio
surgery in a month.
- So you stole her charts?
- Yes, I stole her charts
so I will be prepared when
she comes crawling back.
Grey, sit, I need
the resistance.
So I re-tested Adele Webber.
She's worse than we thought.
But at least she's
gonna get in the trial.
OK, see? See, I
should be on this!
How do I even have a shot at chief
resident if I can't do what I'm good at?
Alex, you didn't!
You're gonna be fired!
- I'm gonna be chief resident.
- Not if you don't work here
anymore.
- He solicited
a patient for money.
- You're hooking now?
- For my African kid thing.
- It's against so many rules!
Who cares?! The old hag
could die leaving her money
to save dying children, but instead
she'll probably leave it to her cats,
who probably hate her, too.
Are you going to Radiology?
Hey, everybody off now.
- Callie.
- I did four laps today.
Sofia needs surgery.
- What?
- Today. Now. She has weakness
in her left ventricle, she
needs a PDA ligation.
- Oh, God.
- She's gonna be fine.
I'm gonna be there.
- Ow!
- What?
- Callie!
- Oh, God.
Oh...
Oh, my... Help!
Somebody help!
Abdominal wound dehiscence
with a small evisceration.
She's worked
herself into a rupture.
I should have seen this coming. I
should have forced her to stop walking.
I checked that wound
three times a day.
- She never complained of pain.
- Yang, I've been telling Torres
to slow down for weeks.
The woman doesn't listen.
So stop kicking yourself
and just help me fix it.
- Bovie.
- How bad does it look?
- How is she?
- They're just starting now.
- BP's 39 over 20.
- That's way too low.
No. For a kid
this small, it's fine.
The talking is a
little distracting.
I'm sorry. I have to hang up.
I didn't say hang up. Just
keep it down, please. Potts?
You're dumber than you look!
I'm gonna have your job.
Nurse!
- "Help me, Mrs. Pulcher."
- Nurse!
- I'm gonna call your
supervisors!
- "You're my only hope."
- I'm gonna have you fired.
- "I need your help."
- Then I'm gonna sue
this hospital.
- "Please."
- Then I'm gonna sue you!
- "Please!"
Get out!
I don't ever wanna see
your face here again!
He's just getting
ready to clip the PDA.
- Three-0 Vicryl.
- She's closing now.
No leaks, no bleeders,
no sepsis, BP's good.
So we're home.
- What's happening?
- The PDA ripped.
Suction! Six-0 Prolene!
Now, damn it, now!
What's happening?
What's going on, Robbins?
- What happened?!
- I'm sorry.
If she...
I'm sorry.
You need to be in here.
You missed the good
part, Dr. Robbins.
She tried to bleed out,
but I wouldn't let her.
And the lung is up.
And it is beautiful.
All right. Five-0
Vicryl, please?
And everybody's fine.
- OK.
- Don't touch me!
- She's been asking for you.
- Get in here!
This ham-fisted twit
doesn't know how to roll me.
- You asked me not to come back.
- Just shut your hole
and get in here
before this idiot
breaks my spine.
One hundred grand.
- What?
- Alex! Don't.
Give me a hundred
grand, and I'll come in.
Mrs. Pulcher, he's joking.
He doesn't mean that.
- Fifty.
- One hundred.
- Seventy-five.
- One hundred grand. Final offer.
- You don't know
how to negotiate.
- I'm not negotiating.
Don't pretend to be smart,
you crooked little bastard.
Don't pretend you're
poor, you evil old bitch.
One hundred grand!
Done. One hundred grand,
and get in here
and roll me over.
Wait. He made you pay
for parking, too? Smooth.
Yeah, and that was
all before dinner.
You gotta try this
pasta, it's ridiculous.
I'm in.
Did I tell you that his hair
was longer than mine?
No. No...
It's funny, I don't know why
his online photo didn't feature
his very, very long ponytail.
- I love this guy.
- Mm!
- So good.
- Meet us at Joe's. I'm buying.
- What's up?
A hundred thousand
dollars is what's up,
courtesy of the dragon
lady in room 1022.
- Alex!
- You know what happens
when you break the rules, Mer?
You get a hundred thousand
bucks. Drinks are on me.
I can't, I'm on call.
No. No, no!
- No!
- Time of death, 21:44.
- No! Shut up! No!
- She had an arrhythmia.
- Get her back! I need her! I had it!
- Alex!
- I had it! No!
- I'm sorry!
I had it! I had it!
You bitch.
Mrs. Webber? What are
you doing here so late?
You know, Richard is
finishing up, and I'm just waiting.
He doesn't like to
see me go home alone.
May I sit with you?
I'm surprised to see you here.
- You're on call tonight?
- Mm-hm.
- So how are you feeling?
- You really want
to ask me that?
It's hard, I know.
- You think so?
- I only know from my side of
it,
- from my experience.
- Excuse me,
but I have no use
for your side of it.
I thought I could
handle it, thought
I could live with it, it was only
temporary, that it was gonna go away.
But clearly I was wrong.
It's just getting worse.
- I'm sorry.
- Are you?
Are you really?
Then stop. Please, just stop.
Are you in love with him?
If you're in love with him, I don't
know what you should do, but I think...
God help me, Ellis, I
think he's in love with you.
And if you're not, please,
give him back.
Adele, it's Meredith.
Not Ellis.
It's Meredith. I'm her daughter.
Ellis is gone. She died.
Please give me back my husband.
Please, give me back my husband.
He's... He's yours.
He's all yours.
Good morning!
Oh, yeah! Look at you!
Look at how big you are!
Hey, I was just
coming to see you.
Not you, her. Good
morning, beautiful.
Are you gonna tell me to get
back in bed, 'cause I just got here.
I am not. I was coming
to tell you to go home.
- Don't drop that baby.
- To what? To what?
- Go home.
- When?
Now.
Look, your vitals are
stable. Your balance is good,
and you obviously are strong
enough to carry this one around. So go.
Get out!
Did you hear that?
We're going home.
Wait.
I'm going home.
It's 500 bucks to
get it out of impound.
- Come on!
- Should have paid the tickets.
Have a nice day.
I will see you as
soon as you are done.
Meredith, make him
stop fussing over me.
I'll be right there.
So she's going into surgery
right after the MRI, so don't worry.
Meredith.
- Thank you for everything
you've done.
- I didn't really do anything.
- The circumstances changed.
- You did. You caught it first.
And the minute you
did, you looked after her,
you did everything you
could to take care of her.
I've made a lot of mistakes,
and it's taken me a lot of years
to finally realize that all I
want to do is be with her.
You've given us the best
chance that we can get.
You've done everything.
- What's this?
- What's this? It's your kid.
- Your African kid.
- That's happening?
- Today?
- Tonight!
The first group
gets here tonight.
I've been telling
you this all week!
Look, each of you
gets your own kid.
Some of them will be
traveling with family,
a few of them are orphans, so
you are in charge of your kid, right?
You're like their ambassador. Wait.
You can't have her. You'd be awful to her.
Him. No. Yes, him.
- He's melting down.
- Train wreck.
Evil Spawn is now Mother Teresa.
Don't forget, they
get here tonight!
Karev! They're here! They
just touched down in D.C.
and they're gonna change planes
and have dinner and then they'll be here!
You did it! You know, I
never thought you would,
I didn't think you
could, but you did.
- Hm.
- Well done, Karev.
See?
I am in so much trouble.
Oh, my... Oh, my God! How...
- How did you let this happen?
- It just happened.
I asked for things, and
people started saying yes
and I paid for it myself at first,
but then I maxed out my cards.
But the ball was rolling
and planes were reserved
and a freaking military transport!
What am I supposed to say?
"Sorry! Never mind! Lack of funds!
Keep your dying kids where they are!"
- Well, yeah.
- No!
You say, "I'll pay you
when you get here.
Keep the receipts!
Send me the bill!"
And now, I'm... Oh, God.
Right now they're eating eight-dollar
airport hamburgers I can't pay for!
Alex, this... I
mean, this is fraud.
- You've actually
grifted people!
- I can't do this.
You have to now. I
mean, you already did it!
You could go to
jail for th... this!
Ah! There you are. Here's
your kid. They're coming tonight.
- OK. Hold it for me.
- Just take it.
He's a five-year-old with optic
glioma. What are you doing?
I'm working.
No. What are you doing?
- Alex, this is from a lawyer.
- Ah!
- No, take it!
- No, I don't wanna see it.
Look, they're gonna get here tonight,
Lexie. They'll get their surgeries,
I'll go to jail. I don't
even care anymore!
No, no, don't! It's a check.
It's a check for $200,000 from
the Estate of Gladys Pulcher.
It's from the dragon lady.
That bitch.
OK, Adele, I need you to take a
couple deep breaths for me, OK?
- Are you OK?
- I'm fine.
Good.
All right.
OK, I'm gonna
make the injection.
And you shouldn't feel this.
There it is.
Hi.
I really don't want to go home
until she goes, you know?
And clearly, she's
not ready to go,
- so...
- Shh, shh!
- She can go.
- What?
- - With most parents, I'd say no.
But she has three doctors at home.
So if she passes the infant carrier test...
- What test?
- She has to sit
in an infant carrier
for an hour with no
apnea or bradycardia.
She'll nail that.
I'll go get it.
- Thank you.
- Oh. Yeah, it's OK.
I mean, if she passes
the test, it's OK.
People are talking about you.
Kindly. They're
saying you're kind.
Funny. Compassionate.
And Dr. Robbins has a lot of
nice things to say about you.
I'm just glad, you know?
I'm glad that people
are getting to know
the Robert that I
got to know, and like.
You deserve for
people to like you.
It's Dr. Stark.
- How did it go?
- Actually,
it's still kind of going.
- What? What do you mean?
- Well, it's this guy
that I met before
and now he's back in
town and it's kind of great.
Oh, and they had that pasta
that you love, and I didn't want to...
- So... here.
- You didn't have to... Thank you.
Yeah.
So... I'm sorry I can't stay.
No, no, this is
great! You should go!
- Yeah?
- Yeah, go.
OK, all right. I'll call you.
- All right.
- OK, good.
- How's your friend?
- Good.
Thanks. It was good
that we stopped.
Glad to do it.
So... what's next?
Am I taking you home?
Or I might be taking you home.
The length of your
recovery is determined
- by the extent
of your injuries.
- Five more seconds.
Five, four, three, two, one!
That's one hour.
You did it, big girl!
- I can't believe she's leaving.
- Yeah.
Yeah, she's cute, isn't she?
No, Callie. She was
my last cardio patient.
- Does Teddy even talk about me?
- It's a cute baby, right?
Its small features and oversized eyes
trigger a hormonal response in humans.
It's autonomic. It's what
keeps us from eating them.
And it's not always successful.
For the grad wall!
- Yay!
- OK, let's roll.
Wait, wait, wait, put her down.
I have got the apnea
monitor, the O2.
Callie, steal some of
those NICU blankets,
- they're the best.
- OK, everybody stop! Stop, stop!
No matter how
hard we work at it...
She's not ready.
No, she can't leave.
She's been watched by
doctors 24 hours a day.
- She still will.
- Well, her lungs. She could get RSV.
- Any kid can get RSV.
- She's not getting in a car!
- It's not safe!
- Some wounds might
never fully heal.
- Callie.
- It's not safe!
The last time she was in a car,
she nearly died! We both nearly died!
Get her out of that thing! Give
her to me, Mark! I'm not kidding!
Get her out of that thing!
Callie. Callie.
OK, OK. You're right,
you are absolutely right.
Cars are not safe for children.
Neither are
bookcases or squirrels
or strong winds or
people who sneeze.
They're all gonna get your baby.
But honey, you don't feel this way
because you were in an accident.
You feel this way
because you are a parent.
Mm.
It'll pass, mostly.
Some of it never will.
You might have to adjust
to a whole new way of living.
Things may have
changed too radically...
I wish I could tell him.
- What?
- Richard.
I wish I could tell him his
Adele got the medicine.
I just hate keeping it from him.
To ever go back
to what they were.
Me, too.
I need a wheelchair.
Lexie. Avery.
You might not even
recognize yourself.
It's like you haven't
recovered anything at all.
You're a whole new person...
with a whole new life.