♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
♪ Bah bah bah, yeah ♪
Hey.
♪ Oh, oh ♪
So Pete must be happy.
♪ Oh, it's a shame,
we used to be so tight ♪
What?
Custody of Lucas.
Oh.
Yeah, yeah, I think so.
I mean...
I guess.
Well, he won, right?
Yeah.
He won.
Sam...
You coming to bed?
♪ ...without it,
there's no gain, only pain ♪
Yeah. I, um...
I'll be in in a minute.
♪ ...on the shelf ♪
♪ I'll give my love
to someone else ♪
♪ if you see me walking by ♪
♪ hand in hand
with another guy ♪
♪ know that it's true ♪
♪ ooh, ooh ♪
♪ it could've been you ♪
My god.
We were
supposed to just have dinner
like normal people.
We ate.
I ate.
Cooper.
Do you...
Do you think we should
talk about what this means?
You think it means something?
Do you?
You want
to just do it again?
Okay.
Mm.
♪ Oh ♪
♪ don't wanna wait ♪
Hey. I thought you had
the day off today.
Uh, yeah. Uh, Maya's got
a history exam tomorrow,
so I'm doing
her ultrasound today.
Oh, you're so sweet.
I just got
some really good news.
Oh, god. Oh, no.
What?
The bitch is back.
The woman who threw the cup
of coffee at my head?
Yeah.
She's here?
She's waiting for me
in my office
with her husband right now.
God. Why they'd even bother
to do marriage counseling again
after last year...
You know she calls that
poor sweet man the weasel?
Violet, she threw
a coffee cup at my head.
I have a scar.
She's got anger issues.
Yeah.
You know, I mean, deep,
unresolved anger issues.
Oh! Look at you.
I know. Crazy, huh?
Your mom's on her way up.
You ready?
Oh, you were gonna
tell me something?
I'll tell you later.
Are you still, uh,
not talking to me?
Okay. I had sex
with Charlotte last night.
It was supposed
to be just dinner,
but it became dinner with sex.
I don't know what to do.
I had to do it, Violet.
I couldn't lie on the stand.
Come on, really?
I need to talk to you.
Talk to somebody else.
H-Hello?
Dr. Turner?
It is so good
to see you. Mm.
Oh. It's great
to see you, too, Claire.
Um...
Yeah.
She's happy.
Yes, I can see that.
No, I mean, really happy.
Irwin thinks
I have dementia.
Sweetie,
I don't think that.
It's just, you're usually
not a happy person,
and you changed,
just overnight.
Something's wrong.
Oh, just say it, irwin.
Come on, say it.
I was a bitch.
Right, Dr. Turner?
It's okay.
I was a huge bitch.
Right?
But I am not anymore.
I'm feeling better.
And I'm doing charity work.
That's--that's wonderful.
She gave away
all of our money...
Uh-huh.
To a church.
Didn't need it.
And now she's--well, we're
having a lot of sex now.
You think he'd be thrilled.
I am, I am. I...
It's not her.
You know my wife.
Well, uh, c-Claire,
how would you explain
this, uh, t-transformation?
I can feel him in my soul...
Inside me.
God.
I have found god.
I have been touched
by the hand of god.
Stop staring at me
like I'm about to keel over.
I'm fine.
I just--i just wish
you wouldn't be so stubborn.
You know,
you need to be resting.
I'll rest later.
Hey, guys.
Pete.
William, good to see you.
How you feeling?
Oh, let's just say
I'm glad to be home.
Uh... if you'll excuse me,
I have some work to do
in my office.
Okay.
The flight from Switzerland
really took
a lot out of him.
Is there anything I can do?
Uh, I'm consulting with
some a-list specialists,
see if there's something else
that we can try.
He has to keep fighting.
I can't let him give up,
not now.
Well, that's what you want.
What about what he wants?
I think
he's come back to die.
Thank you. Hello.
I'm Dr. Montgomery.
Hi, I'm George Walters.
This is my daughter Kim.
Hi, Kim. The E.R. doctor
says you're having
a lot of back pain.
It started
a few days ago.
It says here
you're at 30 weeks.
You haven't had
any prenatal care?
We live on a farm.
It's difficult for us
to get into the city.
Okay.
Uh, well, let's take
a look here.
Is my baby okay?
She's the appropriate size
for her dates.
She?
It's a girl?
Oh, y-yes.
I'm sorry. I--
I'd appreciate it if you could
make it as quick as possible.
I'd like to take
my daughter home.
Okay.
Weird how?
I don't know. Just weird.
You'll see.
Hi, I'm Dr. Bennett.
I'm a cardiothoracic
specialist.
I'd like to speak with you
about your scans.
Uh, if you'd like, your father
can wait in the lounge.
I'm fine here.
Okay. Well...
Uh, what you have
is an aortic aneurysm.
Uh, it's an abnormal widening
of the large artery
in your abdomen.
We're going to need
to do surgery.
We're hoping to avoid it
until the baby's further along,
but we will need to keep you
here under observation.
How long?
I don't know. Uh, we've ordered
some repeat ultrasounds.
And we're going to need
to review
your family medical history--
mother, father, siblings.
My mother's dead.
Why do you need all that?
It's standard.
A medical history helps point us
in the right direction
when we're trying
to evaluate a problem.
You and I can talk further
while your daughter's
undergoing the test.
No, I'm going with her.
Didn't your mother teach you,
it's not polite to stare?
Gabriel...
I know you're upset
with the way we left things.
But William needed me.
Hey. I get it.
Any woman in your position
would've made the same choice.
In this corner--
angry, sarcastic guy
in a wheelchair,
who,
obviously a dynamo in bed,
can't exactly
sweep you off your feet.
And in this corner,
you got old moneybags,
who, if you marry real quick,
well, let's just say,
you'd make for
an extremely attractive,
not to mention
wealthy widow.
I want you to try
the a.L.S. Protocol on William.
The one that still needs
f.D.A. Approval?
The one that would be completely
delegitimized if we use it?
Yes. Will you do it?
Wow. Amazing.
Little miss moral compass
is suddenly willing to blow off
everything she believes in.
Gabriel... I'm asking you
to think about it.
Okay?
Just think about it.
Hey.
So, uh, based on Kim's
repeat scan,
I recommend surgery now.
Oh, but the fetus
is only 30 weeks.
It's too risky.
Yeah, well, blowing
the aneurysm could be riskier.
Kim tested positive
for the gene
associated
with fibrillin disease?
Yeah, it explains
the aneurysm.
But it's
an autosomal dominant disease.
I mean, it's inherited from
the father. Is she adopted?
Well, George never mentioned it
in his family history.
He doesn't have the disease.
He's not her father.
He can't be.
Well, then who is he?
She says she feels god,
and it changed her.
Just like that,
she changed?
Just like that.
People don't change.
Of course they do.
They modify. They adjust.
But underneath,
we are who we are.
That's not true.
I-I know it's not true.
My entire career is based on
helping people
become who they can be.
People do change.
I've seen it.
People just get better
at covering up their flaws.
There.
What is that?
That... is Claire's god.
Don't you guys have
your own cereal downstairs?
Naomi doesn't let us
buy the kind
with marshmallows in it.
Hey. How do you get
someone to talk to you
that won't talk to you?
Charlotte?
Uh, no, not this time.
Actually, we're doing okay.
It's Violet.
She's being...
I don't know, mean to me.
She's being mean to me,
and she's never mean to me.
And I said I was sorry.
Well, just, uh,
keep on keeping on.
Is that the best you can do?
'Cause I can get that
from a bumper sticker.
She's hurt, Cooper.
You can't expect her
to come around
as soon
as you apologize to her.
Because even if she understands
your explanation intellectually,
she, uh, still has to
accept it... emotionally.
And that takes time.
So keep on keepin' on.
Exactly.
Okay.
Hey, uh, you want to hear
something pretty cool,
something I haven't told
anybody else?
I got into
u.C.L.A. Medical school.
- Oh, my god!
- Oh, oh, oh, okay.
That's fantastic.
Congratulations.
Yeah, I have no idea
how I'd pay for it, but--
hey.
Oh, I'm sorry I'm late.
I hope I didn't miss
all the fun.
No, we're
just getting started.
Hey, mom.
Hey. Thanks for
having me here, hon.
Wow. Three weeks to go.
Yeah.
Everything looks great.
Heart rate is strong.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Oh, I remember
my last month with you.
I was so nervous,
kept looking up
every possible obstetric
complication in the book.
I was driving your dad crazy.
It can be a little scary,
you know?
So do you have
any questions?
I'm fine.
You have a plan?
I've got it all worked out--
totally natural birth...
Dell's doing
the delivery here.
Uh-huh.
I do my squatting exercises
in the morning,
my relaxation techniques
in the afternoon.
That's so I won't need
an epidural.
Um, my bag is packed,
and dink made a mix cd
for my birthing music.
I'm so ready.
Wow.
Wow. You've just--
you've thought of everything.
You don't have to worry
about me, mom.
You not being around
actually helped.
It gave me a chance
to grow up,
figure things out
on my own.
Thanks for doing
the consult, Sheldon.
Ordinarily, I'd ask Violet,
but things have been
a little weird
since the tri--
Sheldon?
I know, stopping elevators
is your thing,
but today, I...
I need to change things up
a little.
Wait. You need help...
From me?
Sheldon, you sent me a bill
last time.
When I asked for
elevator advice, you charged me.
All right. Well, I'm gonna send
you a bill, and I'm expensive.
I have many
board certifications.
Only eight people in the world
do what I do.
I can give you a pap smear,
operate on your uterus
and perform surgery on your baby
before and after he's born.
Are you gonna listen to me
or not?
All right. Spill it.
It's about Charlotte.
I've been giving her advice
on how to get back together
with Cooper, but the thing is,
I think about her, Addison.
When she's not around, I think
about the way she smiles,
the way she looks at me.
I-I...
My god, I spend half my day
coming up with lame reasons
to go up and visit her.
D-Do you know how many times
I've borrowed stamps from her?
I don't even use stamps.
I pay my bills electronically.
Listen to me, Sheldon.
You want her? Go get her.
You have to try.
If not, you're gonna spend
the rest of your life
kicking yourself
and wondering why you didn't
man up and go for it.
Thank you.
Do you have
the test results?
Can we go home now?
Actually, the results
were inconclusive.
We're gonna need her
for one more test.
You can stay here.
Why? I want to be with her.
We need her for radiology,
some x-rays.
You're not allowed
in the room.
It's all right.
She'll be right back.
I'll be waiting
for you here, Kim.
Appreciate it.
God is in a brain tumor?
I'm sorry.
That sounds ridiculous.
Well, it's actually
a well-known phenomena.
The temporal lobe
contains the emotional engine
of our brains.
It's the center
of all of our feelings.
So anything--rage, lust,
anger, passion, bliss--
anything that stimulates
that part of the brain
can elicit those feelings.
But they're not real.
They're just misdirected
neural impulses.
They're...
Random short circuits.
You're wrong.
They are real.
I can feel it.
It's happiness.
I've never felt it before,
but...
It's like I-I had this giant
weight on my shoulders
and--and now
the weight is lifted.
That doesn't just happen,
that's not just...
Chemical reactions
in my brain.
And you know what?
If it takes a magic bullet
in my head to do god's work,
then that's his plan.
It's a slow-growing tumor.
With surgery, your chance
of recovery is excellent.
But without it...
What, you're saying this tumor's
gonna kill my wife?
Without the surgery,
you will die.
I spent three years
in intensive therapy
with Dr. Turner,
and I didn't have
a happy bone in my body.
Now I've found god.
He's in me.
If dying is god's plan,
then so be it.
I thought we were going
to radiology.
Uh, we are.
I just wanted you to consult
with one more doctor, Kim,
before we do your test.
Hi, Kim.
I'm Dr. Wallace.
Nothing?
Nothing? Did you--did you
check with n.I.H.?
Yeah, I know, I know.
I knew it was a long shot.
Thank you for trying,
Dr. Klein.
Okay.
What do I have to do,
Gabriel?
Do I have to beg?
Okay, I will beg.
What you're asking
is unethical and illegal.
The protocol is not approved.
If I give it to William,
it will never be.
And I am still asking.
No.
If you don't help him,
he is going to die.
Well, then I guess
he's going to die.
She's rational and oriented.
There's no evidence
of delusional thinking.
She's entirely capable
of making decisions
about her own treatment, so--
she can't decide.
She thinks she has
a personal pipeline to god.
This woman was miserable
her entire life until now.
And you are telling her
to accept a treatment
that would bring
all that pain back,
to just live with it.
I-I may not agree
with her decision,
but I certainly understand
her refusal
to let you do that to her.
Why would anyone choose
to feel worse?
Because without the surgery,
she will die.
And Claire understands that.
She believes
it's part of god's plan.
If god
is not gonna do his job,
I guess I'll have to do it
for him.
So you don't remember
your mother at all?
No.
Well, how old were you
when she died?
I'm not sure.
You keep looking at the door.
Are you afraid
your father's gonna come in?
Or hoping he'll come in?
Do you have plans
for your future?
Do you want
to go to college or...
My dad doesn't think
I need it.
Well, the two of you,
you're very close.
We have
a special relationship.
How so?
When's my dad gonna be back?
Soon.
Kim,
this abnormality you have,
it's a condition
you inherit from a father--
only from a father--
and George doesn't have it.
My dad says
doctors don't know
what they're talking about
half the time.
Well, your father...
He seems to know everything.
Of course he does.
He's my dad.
Her answers felt rehearsed,
you know, and planned.
And she's been
extremely isolated.
She doesn't watch TV
or use the Internet.
She can't even remember
the last time she left the farm.
I think we should call
the police.
The police?
I'm not 100% sure, but I think
we may be witnessing
a kidnapped girl
and her abductor.
What?
We're leaving.
Kim, get out of bed.
Get your stuff.
We're going home.
No, George.
You can't leave.
No, George. Whoa.
This is my family,
and we are leaving.
George. G-George.
All right. No. George.
You're not going anywhere.
What are you doing?!
Get back into bed, Kim. Kim.
Let him go!
Kim!
Yes, I need security.
3-0-1 east.
You're hurting my father.
I love you.
Please.
You're going to hurt him.
We're family.
You have to get back into bed.
Sam! Sam, a little help here.
- She's unconscious.
- Okay.
She's bottoming out.
Call the O.R. we got
a triple-a that's bleeding out.
Okay. Easy.
Are we gonna
talk about this?
Huh.
I guess we're not
gonna talk about this.
There's gotta be
something else.
Naomi...
We've been through this.
Whatever time I have left,
I want to spend it with you...
I...
Enjoying each other...
Not chasing
some impossible cure.
There's nothing left to do.
♪ Now I'm feeling different ♪
You can't leave.
What?
I've made my decision.
Irwin and I are going home.
But you--
please don't try
to convince me.
I'm happy.
I'm finally happy,
and I don't wanna go back.
I understand how you feel.
No, you couldn't possibly.
My father was murdered.
My brother and I were there
when it happened.
I-I was just a kid
at the time. I...
But the bottom fell out...
Of my whole world.
I-I was...
♪ ...time ♪
There was a dark place,
and I was in it.
Until one day, this friend
gave me a pill.
And... I took it,
and all of a sudden...
I felt okay,
better than okay.
I felt good.
And so I kept taking them.
And I felt...
Great.
And when people would try
to get me to stop
and tell me that it wasn't real,
I would just laugh,
because it was real.
How I felt--it was better.
It was better...
Than being miserable.
But it almost killed me.
I was dead for three minutes.
And let me tell you, when you
are lying on a stretcher,
gasping for what you think
are your last breaths,
you don't think that dying happy
is better than living sad.
Dying... sucks.
♪ 50 crying all the times ♪
It hurts...
In a way
that I can't describe to you.
And, no...
I don't believe
that people can change.
that you'll change.
But maybe I'm wrong.
And, hell, maybe you will
wake up from that surgery
and you will be happy.
But if you're dead,
if you are rotting in the ground
from some tumor
that ate your brain,
you don't get a chance
to find that out.
♪ Is it gone? Is it gone?
Or is it floating... ♪
And one more thing,
and then I will go.
I'm...
I'm not a religious person.
I... don't believe in god.
But if I did...
I wouldn't believe in a god
that wanted you to die
the horrible, painful death
that you will experience
from a giant tumor that will
take away your ability to speak
and see and go to the bathroom
and breathe on your own.
That can't be god.
♪ ...a little more delicate ♪
Okay.
Wait a minute.
Claire.
No, no,
it's too dangerous...
And god is telling you--
see, maybe she's right.
Maybe this is what god wants.
All right?
I'll do it.
I'll do the surgery.
♪♪♪
♪ oh, no, where did all... ♪
We're losing her, Sam.
All right.
Hang another 4 units
on the infuser. Suction.
She's bleeding out.
Cross-clamp the aorta.
There's too much blood
in the field.
I can't see a thing.
Give me your hand.
♪ That was handed to... ♪
Okay, you feel that?
Right there. You feel it?
No.
Move closer.
♪ ...make sense ♪
Okay, now push down.
Right there. Don't stop.
♪ Is trying to find a way
to let you know ♪
Okay, more suction.
All right.
2 centimeters to the left.
Got it.
There we go.
Debakey clamp.
♪ Can't it just be over? ♪
Pressure's coming up.
♪ Cry until it's all gone ♪
Okay.
Oh, it's okay.
♪ Time for us to... ♪
So Claire is in pre-op.
She said I'd find you here.
♪ I'm tired of trying
to find a reason why ♪
You know, Dr. Shepherd
is an excellent surgeon.
It'll be okay.
No, it won't.
No, you were there.
You were in therapy with us.
It was hell
living with her.
♪ ...thinking 'bout my life ♪
You know, suddenly, I find
the woman
I've always dreamed of,
and in a few hours,
she might be gone.
I'm not sure
I have it in me
to love
the old Claire anymore.
See, I love her
the way she is now...
With that damn tumor
in her head.
♪ ...yesterday ♪
♪ but the hardest part... ♪
I don't know
what's gonna happen
after the surgery.
But we've seen Claire
for who she can be.
And I do believe
the joy she feels now
comes from a deeper place
than a lesion in her head.
Somewhere inside of her...
That part must exist.
Do you really believe that?
♪ And we'll just cry ♪
♪ cry, cry
until it's all gone ♪
♪ been holding
on for too long ♪
You may be smart and insightful
and some kind of super shrink,
but I know Cooper,
and I shouldn't have listened.
Charlotte--
he is who he is. He's funny,
neurotic in that way
my mama warned me
wouldn't be cute after a while
and a freak between the sheets,
but he's not any more than that,
and he isn't gonna be.
♪ Cry ♪
Well, I will be...
More to you.
I... I will be.
You're right.
You should expect more.
And from the man in your life,
you should expect everything--
trust and emotional support
and intellectual stimulation.
And you should expect
that he'll be there for you
unconditionally,
no matter what you do,
no matter
what life brings you,
and--and sex, too--great sex--
plus a great recipe for haggis.
I mean,
you should get everything.
I'll give you everything,
the whole package, right down
to the picket fence.
I'll give it to you.
Sheldon Wallace.
I'm throwing my hat
in the ring.
Have dinner with me...
Tonight.
♪ ...a reason why ♪
You were great.
I was great.
Yeah, we did good.
Good?
We saved two lives today--
two for the price of one.
I mean, how often
do you get to say that?
I mean, can you imagine
dropping that at a dinner party?
We saved two lives today.
I mean, who's gonna top that?
Yeah.
We're always good together.
When it's just us...
We're great together.
But we live
in the real world,
and it's taken me a while,
but i'm--I'm okay with it.
We'll be friends.
We'll be neighbors.
But we can never
be more than that.
Naomi told me that you're
refusing to give William
your a.L.S. Protocol.
Protecting my research.
One day, when this drug
is approved by the f.D.A.
And saving thousands of lives,
Naomi will realize
it was more important
than the life of just one man.
Really?
That's your reason?
Because if it is, that's good.
If you're saying no because
you want to get Naomi...
Mind your own business.
Does she know
that you're in love with her?
Oh, screw you.
You're pathetic.
Oh, coming from the guy who
dragged Violet through a trial?
I didn't drag Violet through
a trial. She dragged me.
You turned her friends
against her.
Are you kidding me?
And now you're keeping her
away from her child?
You're gonna call me pathetic?
Go on, hit me.
You think I can't take
a punch in the face?
You're not worth it.
You know what? I am so sick
of being the guy in the chair.
The guy in the chair
never gets the girl.
And this time,
I am getting the girl.
So screw the chair.
Come on. Hit me.
Who's the bigger man now, Pete?
Come on.
Hit me.
You're letting William die
so you can have Naomi.
The chair is not
what makes you the smaller man.
Get out.
Not until you listen
to what I have to say.
Okay, then I'll get out.
Okay, when you sent Sam
into my office
the first weeks that we
worked here to fake fire me
for looking at adult web sites
on my computer, I forgave you.
Oh, Cooper. Are you kid--
when you told Annie mersel,
who I'm pretty sure
I was falling in love with,
that I wasn't
the marrying kind because
you couldn't picture us together
in 20 years, I forgave you.
Cooper--
puking in my new car,
puking in my old bed
or using the 1910 silver dollar
my grandfather gave me
for my bar mitzvah
to pay the pizza guy...
But that's what friends do.
They screw up,
and sometimes,
they hurt each other...
And you forgive them.
That's what friendship is.
That's what love is.
I'm going to leave you now.
But I leave you with this...
You once told a woman
I had just started dating
that I have
a very small nightstick,
which was unforgivable
and also...
A lie.
And I let it slide.
Mm.
What... what happened?
Your aneurysm ruptured,
but we were able
to repair it.
My baby?
She's doing great.
Kim, we spoke with the FBI.
They're trying to track down
your biological parents.
Where's George?
He can't hurt you.
We have a police officer
stationed at the door.
You are safe here.
No.
You don't understand.
I need to see him.
I love him.
The procedure went well.
I'll probably send Claire home
in a few days.
And the rest?
We'll see.
Where the hell
are they--the damn doctors?
I am tired of waiting.
I'm sorry.
I can't.
Claire.
You lied to me, you bitch.
You pushed me to do this.
Now I have nothing. Nothing!
You shoulda
let me die happy.
He kidnapped her,
assaulted her
and kept her
away from her real family,
and she still
wants to see him?
The police said George
held her captive for 15 years.
He's been the only person
in her life,
putting clothes on her back
and feeding her
and making all the decisions
in her life.
To her,
he is her real family.
It's the only love
she knows.
Oh, it's just too perverse
to comprehend.
Well, all Kim sees
is that he took care of her,
protected her.
Have they located her family,
her parents?
I mean,
maybe when she sees them--
she's been totally
cut off from the world.
And over time,
that old love she knew
became vague, faded memories.
And eventually,
in order to survive,
his beliefs become her belief
and his reality
becomes her reality.
♪ ...Sense of loss ♪
♪ I'm the memory you can't get ♪
♪ out your head ♪
Was there something
you wanted?
♪ But if I leave you now ♪
♪ you'll wish you were... ♪
I want to ask you
to forgive me.
I mean--i mean, not now.
I mean, I don't expect you to
forgive me right now, but...
I ran out on you...
When I should've leaned in.
I gave you my baby
and... I ran.
And part of it's not my fault.
Part of it's
what happened to me,
but there's this--
there's this other piece,
and...
You loved me.
You loved me...
And I should've
leaned into that.
I should've let you
take care of me.
But I didn't...
Because...
Because I don't know how.
You know, I'm that person.
I'm a shrink.
I take care of other people,
but--
and I should've let you
take care of me...
But I didn't.
So when I asked you
to share Lucas with me,
of course you said no.
I-I shouldn't have been hurt.
I shouldn't have taken you
to court.
I lost my happiness,
and I didn't ask for help.
I didn't lean in.
So how could I possibly
expect you
to lean into me...
To... to trust me...
To believe in me?
♪ ...out of your hair ♪
And so I...
♪ God help me, baby ♪
I'm sorry.
♪ I'm lost inside ♪
And I understand.
You did what you thought
was right.
But I hope that someday...
You can forgive me.
♪♪♪
♪ yes ♪
We could start
with overnight visits
for Lucas...
♪♪♪
Until...
He gets used to it--
until I get used to it--
if that's okay.
♪ I'm the babe that sleeps ♪
♪ through the blitz ♪
♪ I am a sudden and... ♪
♪ Quite unexpected twist ♪
♪ I am your one true love ♪
♪ who sleeps with someone else ♪
I wish I had said no to you
for the right reasons.
Instead, I said no
for the wrong ones.
♪ ...life itself ♪
I'm in love with you.
And even if I work
the--the poor
crippled guy angle,
I can't compete
with a dying man.
So I said no so that
he would just die already
and be out of the picture.
But the thing is,
I'm in love with you,
and William dying
would hurt you.
And I can't hurt you.
I can't.
If you want something,
I want to give it to you...
Because you deserve
to be happy.
Because even if I hate William,
I can't be happy
unless you're happy.
Gabriel...
I'm having
the protocol prepared.
It'll be here within the hour
to administer to William.
I'm so very sorry...
About your research
and the... compromise
I'm asking you to make.
I had a choice to make.
I made it
and now I gotta live with it.
I hope
you can live with yours.
♪♪♪
I used to watch cartoons.
I'd get up early
on Saturday mornings
and sneak into the living room.
I kept the volume low
so I wouldn't wake anyone up.
It was the only day
my mom and dad got to sleep in.
I forgot about cartoons.
Well... in time, I'm sure
there'll be lots of things
that you'll remember.
He loves me, you know?
But sometimes people confuse
other things for love,
like...
Not wanting to be lonely
or... afraid or hurt.
We're having a baby together.
I know. And you're
going to love that baby.
But not with George,
because you don't want
your daughter
to go through
what you went through,
because you don't want him
to do to your daughter
what he did to you.
Because that's not love.
What do you want?
Just checking up on you.
I thought maybe we could talk.
I wasted three years
of my life talking to you.
I'm not wasting anymore.
You're unhappy.
I can help you.
I am just so tired
of you helping me.
Where has it gotten me,
huh? Look at me.
I'm here alone
in a hospital room
with a--with a hole
in my head.
You don't have to be alone.
You have had
a rare experience, Claire.
You got to look through a door
to the other side of your soul.
And now you're afraid.
You're afraid that door
is closed forever.
But it isn't.
It's--it's there
waiting for you.
You just have to find a way
to walk through it.
How do you suggest
I do that?
We can try new things,
alternative therapies.
And we'd do it together.
I'm afraid.
I know.
Hey.
What took you so long?
I called an hour ago.
I came as soon as you called.
Where's dink?
Band practice.
He can't hear his cell.
Corinne?
She went to San Francisco
to visit a sick aunt.
She left you here alone?
My due date's
not for three weeks.
She didn't think i'd--
oh, my god. That hurts.
Well, you're definitely
in labor.
Okay, I'll take you
to the birthing suite.
I want to go to the hospital.
That's not a part of the plan.
Screw the plan.
Maya--
I'm not waiting here!
I want to go to the hospital
like a normal person
where they have doctors
and pain medicine.
So get your keys
and let's go now.
Okay?
Lainey?
L--
You think she'll ever
get over something like that?
How could she?
I mean, right or wrong,
she just lost
the only person she loves.
Hey, Dell.
What--hold on.
She wants me to deliver...
Oh, okay.
How--how far apart
are her contractions?
Is that--is it m--
okay.
Uh, yeah, t-tell her that
we will meet her at the E.R.
And, um, and t-tell her
that we love her, Dell.
Okay. Yeah.
Drive safely.
Bye.
So it's, uh, it's happening.
This is happening. Oh.
Uh, I have to go deliver
your grandchild.
Yes. Yes, you do.
Ow! Oh.
We're almost there.
Oh, ow!
Hey, w--
hey.
What's so important?
I have... macaroni and cheese
with sugar on top,
eggplant parm, extra spicy,
straight from tana's,
I have pumpkin pie,
which is actually
incredibly hard to get
this time of year,
and I have that
sweet sugar cane stuff
that we drank
in the San Jose airport
that we didn't know was alcohol
but made us incredibly dizzy.
Guaro!
Okay.
Now...
Talk to me about Charlotte.
You know what?
Can we just eat?
I saw her leaving
with Sheldon.
She was dressed up.
Hmm.
Do you love her?
Then go get her.
Now, Cooper.
I mean go get her now.
Oh!
Oh.
All right.
Okay.
♪♪♪
Naomi will be here soon.
That's good.
48-year-old male
involved in a head-on collision
sustained a deep 6-centimeter
laceration to the left chest.
Vitals--b.p., 95 over 60,
pulse 120.
We've got a possible
subclavian artery injury.
We could use your help here,
Dr. Bennett.
Yeah.
You're the cardiac surgeon on call?
Yeah, I am.
Uh, what about Maya?
I will be with her
the whole time.
You'll be done before she's
even close to delivering.
Okay.
Uh, updates every half-hour?
I promise.
All right. Thank you.
♪ A series of portraits ♪
Let's go!
Hey. What's going on?
They're airlifting people
from the other car.
♪ On and on and on ♪
♪ and on ♪
♪ on and on ♪
♪♪♪
♪ in my dreams, you are alive ♪
♪ ...and breathing ♪
♪ standing at my door ♪
♪ not speaking ♪
♪ I just can't break this ♪
♪ it seems ♪
♪ in my dreams ♪