We are three weeks
into IVF.
You know what they say,
you blink and the kids
are grown.
Dr. Hannah Asher,
Gynecology.
You shouldn't
even be working.
You OD'd. For all I know,
you're high right now.
How about you and I
keep our distance
from one another?
Just as soon as you
stop treating patients
and seek treatment
for your addiction.
If I go down, so do you.
So does the site.
Dr. Asher.
Could you say that any louder?
Not sure
everybody heard you.
Sorry.
I wasn't trying
to blow your spot.
Yeah, well, remember.
You tell on me,
I tell on you.
Thanks for the reminder.
Hmm.
Why are you here?
Hey, hey. Wait.
Let's start over.
Okay, can we talk?
About options
to get clean?
Yeah, like I appreciate
you wanting to help,
but I'm not really
in the mood
for a lecture right now.
Hannah.
You're a doctor.
You know what
you're doing
to your body.
Yeah, so, I know
that this can't
last forever.
Okay, then
why don't you want
to do something about it?
I can get you an intake
at a rehab facility.
I can't just
go to rehab.
Okay? I have a job.
I have responsibilities.
Okay,
Narcotics Anonymous then.
You can drop
in and out.
There's a meeting
at the church
right around the corner
from the hospital.
8:00 a.m. tomorrow.
One hour of your time.
You won't even
be late to work.
Okay.
Yeah?
I'll go.
All right.
Thank you.
Hey.
Hi.
So,
wonder if
it's gonna snow today.
Crockett, it's okay.
What happened
is in the past.
Can't remember what it was.
Desmond, what do we got?
Rick Tyler, 40, passenger
in a motor vehicle collision.
Intubated in the field.
BP 88 over 57,
heart rate's 70,
GCS six.
What happened?
Wife was driving the car
and ran a red light.
She's in the ambo behind us.
CFD had to use
the Jaws of Life
to pry them
from the wreckage.
Ouch. Need a hand?
Yep.
All right, we're gonna
transfer on my count.
Ready? One, two, three.
Need an X-ray in here.
Right leg's badly mangled.
Lost a lot of blood.
Hang two units of O-neg.
Trigger the MTP.
Breath sounds are clear.
Chest and pelvis.
BP's low.
We need to FAST him.
X-ray's ready.
Everyone stand back.
Chest is clear.
There's blood in the belly.
Dr. Manning.
Yeah.
His wife's coming
into Trauma 2.
I got him.
You get the missus.
Okay.
Hey, Mike.
Shoot the pelvis.
Then we're taking him
to the OR.
All right,
let's transfer on my count.
Ready? One, two, three.
Her name's Kim.
BP 115 over 75.
Heart rate's 90. GCS 15.
Hi, Kim. I'm Dr. Manning.
I didn't see the light change.
All I care about is
your well-being.
All right, I'm gonna
check your neck, okay?
Okay.
All right, let's see.
Okay, can you touch
your chin to your chest?
How does that feel?
Any pain?
I'm okay.
All right.
Help me roll her over
so I can check her spine.
We're gonna do it
on my count.
All right,
one, two, three.
You're doing great.
All right. Let's see.
Mmm-hmm. Mmm-hmm.
Kim, were you in an accident
prior to this one?
You have significant bruises
all down your lower back.
Must be from the crash.
It couldn't be
from the crash.
Bruises take a while
to turn yellow like this.
Yeah, I fell last week.
On the stairs.
I forgot.
All right.
Kim? I have to ask.
Did someone do this to you?
No.
Because if someone did...
No, I fell.
Okay.
But there's a goose egg
on her forehead.
I'd like to get a head CT.
My husband Rick...
Is he...
He's headed into surgery now.
Okay.
Dr. Manning?
Yeah.
Those bruises...
She was abused, right?
Come on, everyone.
Meeting's starting.
Hey. You free
for an intake?
Yeah. Your sister called.
Vincent's transitioning
to a toddler bed,
and she asked
if we want his crib.
He's getting so big.
And it's kind of early
for that,
but we're gonna need a crib
at some point, right?
I mean, yeah.
It is one less thing
to worry about.
I can pick it up tonight.
Hey.
I'm Dr. Choi.
This is Nurse Sexton.
Hi.
Nina. This is Harlan,
my husband.
Aw, I love it
when you call me that.
Newlyweds?
A month ago.
But we're still working
our way through the cake.
Ooh, but it's delicious.
So, what brings you in?
This awful rash.
It goes all the way
up my neck.
It's all over my legs.
My gynecologist prescribed me
fluconazole last week
for a yeast infection.
Could that be related?
Maybe.
What about something
in my apartment, maybe?
Nina just moved in.
Hadn't been cleaned
since 2015.
Okay.
Well, you're definitely
allergic to something.
We're gonna order some labs,
and get an antihistamine
for you,
then come back
for a full allergen history.
We'll get this rash
under control.
Aw, but I love you
all red and puffy.
Oh, come here, you.
No, you come here.
Missed you at the meeting.
So, you're stalking me now.
Do you do this
with all the women
that leave the injection site,
or am I special?
I'm just concerned.
Yeah, okay, if I had known
going to a safe injection site
would result in
you hounding me,
I never would've gone
in the first place.
Hi, I'm Dr. Lanik,
this is Ms. Curry,
fourth year medical student.
Hi, I'm Vanessa,
Xavier's mom.
And this is
my boyfriend, Alvin.
So, I see Xavier was diagnosed
as being in a persistent
vegetative state
at Norris Memorial
after a bike accident?
Yeah, about five months ago,
he hit his head.
So, what brings you in today?
I was changing Xavier's
clothes this morning,
and I noticed
a sore on his hip.
Maybe I left him
on his side too long?
I'm just worried
it's infected.
Let's roll him.
Okay.
We call that
a pressure ulcer.
Yeah, it does
look infected.
Have you been managing
Xavier's care at home?
Since he was discharged
from the hospital
about four months ago.
See the granulation
in the center?
We'll go ahead and clean
and dress the wound.
Okay.
So, it should never
get to this point.
We try to
turn him regularly.
Well, there's actually
an air mattress
that can help with that.
We'll send you home today
with some antibiotics,
but why don't you come
with me, and we can
go over a handout
about how to
prevent bed sores?
Keep this from
happening again.
Talk to me, Marty.
BP's better.
He's gotten a lot of blood.
Packed his liver crack
pretty well.
Bleeding should no longer
be an issue.
I'm worried.
There's only 10 CCs
of urine in his Foley.
Dark and brown.
I sent a sample for labs.
Could mean
he's in rhabdo.
Let's remove
the drape please.
Nice and easy.
Yeah. Leg's not looking good.
Muscle is dying
and dumping off
into the bloodstream.
Lab report?
CPK levels are high.
25,000.
Whoa!
That does indicate rhabdo.
Leg's gotta come off
or it's gonna kill him.
Gotta talk to his wife.
So, based on your scans
and neuro exam,
we can safely rule out
a traumatic brain injury.
Yeah.
But I do want to
ask you again
about the bruising...
I told you. I fell.
Hi, Mrs. Tyler?
I'm Dr. Marcel.
I'm the surgeon who operated
on your husband, Rick.
How is he?
He had a bad liver injury
and he's still pretty sick.
So, is he going to live?
Well, we got
the bleeding
under control,
but my main concern
is his right leg.
The muscle is dying,
and it's poisoning
his blood,
which in turn
is hurting his kidneys,
putting him
in renal failure...
What does all that mean?
Rick's leg is
making him very sick.
It will kill him.
And I need your consent
to amputate.
He has to lose a leg?
Isn't there something else
you can do?
I'm sorry.
He'll be so upset.
Kim, I know this is
a lot to deal with.
I...
I'm not...
I'm not sure
what Rick would want.
He might rather be dead
than have only one leg, he...
You sure there's nothing else
you can do?
Not that I'd advise.
Please, tell me.
We could move him
to the ICU
and do the best we can
to keep him alive.
That might give us
some time
for him to wake up
and make the decision
himself.
Okay.
Let's do that.
Every second we wait
increases the risk
of him dying
of multi-organ failure.
I understand, but...
He should
be the one to decide.
Okay.
I'll be back in a moment.
Hey.
Yeah?
I am not
comfortable with this.
That woman was abused
by her husband.
You sure about that?
Yes.
And in my opinion, she should
not be making this decision.
What are the chances
Mr. Tyler does wake up
on his own
to make this call?
Slim.
Rick needs
to have his leg
amputated.
And I don't think it's right
to have Kim decide
if he's been abusing her.
Why not?
Because it's
a life or death call.
And she's not
in the right frame
of mind to make it.
She's too vulnerable,
and it's a decision
she'll have to live with
for the rest of her life.
So, let me get this straight.
We're gonna take away
the legal rights
of an abuse victim
because she was abused.
No, it's more
complex than that.
I mean, considering
the emotional
and psychological burden
that Kim's been under,
I really feel like
the hospital
should step in.
She's his wife.
She's entitled to make
this decision.
Then, you're in favor of him
not having the surgery?
I'm in favor
of respecting the rights
of the next of kin
to decide...
Even if it goes against
what's best surgically.
All right, I'll convene
an ethics committee.
Until then,
do everything you can
to keep Mr. Tyler alive.
Strange, isn't it?
Mmm-hmm.
Is this consistent
with a vegetative state?
No, it is not.
You know what?
Send me his chart.
Okay?
As soon as you can.
Okay.
What was Dr. Charles
doing in here?
Um, I thought he might
have some insights
into Xavier's condition.
Have you guys noticed
that his legs can stay up
like this?
We thought that was
part of his condition.
Ms. Curry? A word.
Excuse me.
Ms. Curry, you had no right
to consult another department
without clearing it
with me first.
You were busy
and I had a concern.
I mean, how do you
explain Xavier's leg
staying up on its own?
Probably just spasticity,
which is common
in a vegetative state.
Well, I've never heard of
muscle stiffness causing
that presentation.
Look, this kid was brought in
for a pressure ulcer,
so that is what
we're treating him for.
Okay.
Nina, you ready
for a scratch test?
I will give you two a minute.
The couple in Treatment 3
is having sex.
I don't get it.
The ED
is about the last place
I'd ever wanna have sex.
I know.
You know what?
God bless the couple
that can't keep
their hands off each other
even in this place.
Yeah.
What's going on?
Dr. Lanik is
sending them home.
Oh.
I'm Dr. Charles
with psychiatry.
I have been reviewing
Xavier's medical records.
And I think that
there's a very good chance
that he was
misdiagnosed there.
Misdiagnosed?
Yeah, I don't think your son
is in a vegetative state.
Do you know how his joints,
they stay in the same position
after they've been moved?
Mmm-hmm.
That's something called
waxy flexibility.
It is indicative
of only one condition.
Catatonia.
Catatonia?
Yeah, it's
a neuropsychiatric disorder
that can lead to paralysis,
but it's treatable.
And this was caused
by the head injury?
I'm suggesting that
this has nothing to do
with your son
hitting his head.
What's going on?
He's saying our son
might be catatonic.
Xavier was
fully evaluated
before being diagnosed
as being in a PVS.
Catatonia's a pretty
rare condition,
so without
a psychiatrist
weighing in,
it's possible that the doctors
at Norris weren't even
looking for it.
Yeah, but Xavier fell
off his bike.
He hit his head.
Yeah, but the scans were
inconclusive,
meaning that there was
no clear brain injury.
Look.
I think that
I can help your son.
But in order for me
to do that,
he needs to stay here.
Look, I'm just trying
to spare you
a bunch of tests
your son doesn't need,
so you don't wind up
right back where you are.
Wait.
We're staying.
All right, well, he is
discharged from my service,
so, Dan, if you wanna
admit him to yours,
be my guest.
Put him back
in his room please.
Somebody help! Please!
Babe, no, no, no.
Wake up.
Her rash suddenly
just flared up
and she just passed out.
Nina? Nina,
can you hear me?
She's not moving any air.
Pulse is thready.
Code blue, Treatment 3!
What's happening?
She's in
anaphylactic shock.
We need to intubate.
Bolus her a liter of NS,
and 0.3 milligrams
of epi IM, stat.
Nina? Nina!
Heart rate's in the 40s.
BP 70 over 33.
Atropine?
Yeah, push a mil IV.
Baby, baby,
come on, come on.
No, no, no, no, no.
I'm in.
Stats are coming up.
Pressure's still soft.
All right,
keep the fluids running.
Fifty of Benadryl IV,
start racemic epi,
and give her another dose
of epinephrine IM.
What caused this?
Catatonia only freezes
the voluntary muscle groups,
not the involuntary ones
like those that
help us breathe.
So if I'm right,
and Xavier is
indeed catatonic,
he does not need
the ventilator to breathe,
and we can disconnect it.
Wait.
But isn't that dangerous?
The doctor said
he'd die without it.
They said he wasn't...
What's the expression?
Protecting his airway.
He has a trach.
Which means that we can
always reconnect the vent
if he needs it.
Do, uh, do we have
your permission?
Yes.
Okay.
Ms. Curry?
Okay, SATS are dropping. 92.
Ninety.
Isn't that bad?
Not necessarily.
As carbon dioxide builds up,
it should kick
his respiratory system
into drive.
Eighty-five.
Dr. Charles.
He's not breathing!
Wait, wait, wait.
Oh, my God.
Xavier?
My little boy!
What does this mean?
What do we do now?
Well,
probably not a bad idea
to try and figure out
what put him
into a catatonic state
in the first place.
So the first doctor
to explain catatonia
about 150 years ago,
Dr. Kahlbaum, described it as
"immobility induced
by severe mental shock,"
like an emotional trauma.
Well, I mean it's like a...
Like a deer caught
in the headlights.
But instead of bounding
into the forest,
they stay there, frozen.
What, like PTSD?
I'm a cop.
I've seen PTSD.
It doesn't look
anything like this.
And there's been no trauma.
Xavier was always
a happy kid.
Okay, you mind telling me
a little bit more about...
About your home life?
It was good...
Before this happened.
I mean, there have been
some rough patches.
My ex, Xavier's father,
left us high and dry
when Xavier was
a little boy,
but we got through it.
And then Alvin came
into the picture.
Yeah, we started dating
five years ago.
We've been living together
for the past three years.
How about school?
Xavier's always been
a good student.
Loved reading.
Friends?
Lots.
I used to take them all
to White Sox games.
He did watch this movie
Poltergeist,
which gave him nightmares.
But that was a few years ago.
Unlikely that one movie is
gonna induce catatonia.
I have to take this.
I'm working a task force
with the DEA.
Sorry.
Alvin here. Yeah.
How did Xavier feel
about Alvin's work?
Alvin's always been good
about not bringing it home
with him.
He took all the precautions.
Keeps his gun in a safe.
But still, did he ever
talk to you about
how he felt about
the fact that Alvin
was a police officer?
Xavier's a 10-year-old boy.
Alvin being a cop is like
having a superhero
sleeping down the hall.
Hmm.
Why would you ask that?
Just trying to get
some background.
Alvin's the best father figure
Xavier could ever have.
You don't have to
worry about that.
Hey, why did you stop?
It seemed like
you were on to something.
I think we're getting
to a sensitive area here.
So I just like to,
you know, take a pause
before we push forward,
but Alvin's work life
is absolutely something
that we want to look into.
Nina's stable for now.
It doesn't make sense.
The antihistamine
was working.
So she must have been
re-exposed to the allergen.
I guess we can move her
to a clean room.
But she had the rash before
she even came to the hospital.
Yeah, I just wish we could've
gotten that scratch test.
I tried,
but they were indisposed.
Before I could get
back in there, she crashed.
Indisposed?
What do you mean,
"indisposed?"
Were they having sex?
Yeah.
We need to talk
to Harlan.
Harlan, I'm not here
to judge you,
but I gather you and Nina
had sex in the hospital.
Uh, I'm sorry
you had to walk in on that.
Did you finish?
Jeez, man.
It's pertinent, Harlan.
We need to know.
Did you ejaculate?
I did, yes.
I'm gonna write her an order.
You need to go to the lab.
Maggie.
Yeah.
What's the story
with the patient in 5?
Uh, second trimester
with preeclampsia.
Dr. Asher's seeing her now.
You all right?
Yeah, just have to do
something I don't want to do.
Well, in my experience,
better to not hesitate.
Just rip the Band-Aid off.
Thanks.
So after reviewing
the details
of Rick Tyler's case,
the ethics committee
has decided to take away
decision-making rights
from Kim.
Wow.
Kim's choice to wait
on amputating Rick's leg
puts his life
at unnecessary risk
and the committee
believes that Kim,
whatever her circumstances,
doesn't appreciate that risk.
Okay.
So you can take
Mr. Tyler to surgery.
All right.
I have to go tell Kim now.
Why don't I come with you?
Thanks.
Yeah?
Dr. Charles?
Come on in.
I called over to CPD,
and I found out some
pretty interesting things
about Detective James.
Without asking him?
Why?
Because you said
you didn't want
to bother them?
Until they were
ready to talk again.
What about
their privacy, Elsa?
Alvin's not the patient.
I mean, it's not like
I violated
anyone's HIPAA rights.
Well, that is,
in fact, debatable,
but you definitely
violated their trust.
This family's in a very
delicate place, Elsa.
They... They need to feel
like we're on their side,
or they could just
walk out the door.
Okay.
Do you wanna see what
I found out or not?
What's going on?
This is Sharon Goodwin.
She's the Executive Director
of Patient Services.
What's going on?
We're moving forward
with your husband's
amputation.
But I said
I wanted to wait!
The hospital believes
it's in your husband's
best interest
to take control
of his medical decisions.
Why?
Kim, I saw
signs of abuse.
We don't think you should
have to be responsible
for someone who might
be hurting you.
Kim? Hey, Kim.
Whatever your situation is,
it does not have to
stay that way.
You can talk to us.
When he wakes up,
and he remembers
I was driving the car...
It is my fault
he lost his leg!
There are shelters that can
provide you a safe haven.
You'll be taken to
a secret location where
no visitors are allowed.
Please, Kim.
Let us help you.
Okay.
I'll think about it.
Detective James,
I want to apologize.
I called CPD
to ask about you.
My thought was that
I might learn something
that could be helpful,
but I... I overstepped,
and I'm sorry.
Xavier's your patient.
Why would you be
checking up on me?
Ms. Curry
made a mistake.
A serious mistake.
I just hope that you'd
appreciate that
what she was trying to do was
gain a better understanding
of Xavier's situation
so that
we can give him
the best possible care.
And I hope she learned
what a good man...
What a good cop Alvin is.
Matter of fact,
she did.
You have an outstanding
record, Detective.
You took out the Southside
Ministers gang on your own?
I had a lot of help.
Sounds intense.
I mean, they put
a hit out on you.
They blew up your car.
What does this
have to do with anything?
Well, it just sounds like
a pretty monumental event.
Do you think that
there's any chance that
Xavier could've
been aware of it?
I don't think so.
The car was parked
around the corner.
So, he didn't witness
any of it?
I mean, he may have seen
the wreckage towed away.
There's no way he could've
understood what happened.
But I'm sure you were
probably pretty upset,
Vanessa.
You think that he could've
picked up on that?
Alvin moved out after that.
He stayed away while there was
an active threat against him.
Just out of curiosity,
when did you move back in?
It was about a week
before Xavier became
catatonic.
Alvin would never let
anything happen to us.
He didn't do anything wrong.
I'm not suggesting
that he did.
Then what are you suggesting?
I'm suggesting
that Alvin works
in a very scary world
and that, on some level,
Xavier very much
understands that.
And his fear about
the possible consequences
could very well
have triggered
his catatonic state.
So what does this mean?
That Alvin needs to leave us?
Look, honey, it's just...
No, you are the best thing
that's ever happened to me
and Xavier.
We've heard enough.
Hey, Sean.
Will.
I have you on schedule
for tomorrow night.
Right. Thing is...
It's not such a good idea
for me to be involved
with the site right now.
Wait, we're really starting
to make a difference
with these people,
in large part
'cause of you.
Appreciate that.
But I want what's best
for the site,
and that means
I have to go.
I'm sorry.
Are we at risk here?
I think my leaving
will protect you.
Thanks.
Think you're ready
to have this out.
Take a deep breath.
All right,
hard exhale.
There we go.
What happened?
You had another
allergic reaction.
Yeah, I'm...
I'm the problem, honey.
It's me.
What are you talking about?
We ran tests
on Harlan's semen,
and it turns out
you're allergic to it.
What?
No...
It was never an issue before
because you used condoms,
which you stopped
once you started trying
to get pregnant.
His semen? Come on.
Oh, my God.
So what are you saying?
We can't have sex anymore?
Yeah, what about kids?
There are options.
We'll get you to
a fertility specialist.
There are multiple
procedures you could do.
We'll also set you up
with an allergist.
There might be some methods to
help you build up a tolerance.
With treatment,
your sensitivity may lessen.
Meanwhile, you can go back
to having sex with condoms.
Hey, you two obviously
love one another.
You'll work this out.
Just keep an EpiPen
on your nightstand.
You know, walking in
on them like that
got me thinking, um...
Ever since
we started IVF,
I feel like
the only time
you touch me
is when you're injecting me
with hormones.
You're right.
How about
we have a date
tonight?
And stay home?
I'd like that.
Come in.
I'm sorry. I didn't
mean to intrude.
You got a minute?
Of course.
Um...
You were right.
My job.
I do bring
my work home with me
whether I want to or not.
And Xavier knows that.
"Do the bad guys know
where we live?"
He asked me that once.
And I told him
that they didn't.
But the fact
that he had to ask...
I mean, it
kind of says it all.
Doesn't it?
Yeah.
My job is
to protect people.
And if I can protect my...
My son
just by stepping aside,
then that's what I'm gonna do.
Look. Alvin.
If you feel you need
to get a little space
while Xavier's coming out
of this,
while he's recovering
his faculties,
maybe that's
not a bad idea.
But
as soon as he's ready
to start the therapy
that he needs
to process his fear,
you need to be right there
next to him,
so you can heal together.
And move forward.
Like as a family?
Yeah.
Is he going to
wake up now?
Well, after the surgery,
and all the drugs,
it'll be a while
before he does.
Okay.
This might
sound crazy, but...
I think he really
does love me.
That's not crazy.
A social worker
will be by shortly
to talk to you
about your options.
Thanks, Dr. Manning.
Dr. Manning.
You remember
our social worker,
Arlene Baker?
Yes, hi.
How's Ms. Tyler doing?
She's anxious.
Understandable.
I think I can
allay some of her fears.
No pulse. He's in PEA.
Starting compressions.
Milligram of epi.
Why's his ventilator off?
I did it.
How is this happening
so fast?
He's in multi-system
organ failure.
He had no reserve.
Still no pulse.
Another milligram of epi.
Asystole.
Time of death,
18:08.
I don't understand.
She had options.
I imagine she couldn't
stomach the idea
of looking over her shoulder
the rest of her life
waiting for her husband
to get even.
I thought we'd reached her.
Considering
what just happened,
Kim might have
run that red light
this morning on purpose.
And if she was willing
to sacrifice herself
to stop
her husband's abuse?
I doubt there was any way
to reach her.
Dr. Charles!
Look, he's moving.
Xavier, honey?
Can you hear me?
What do you want, baby?
You thirsty?
I can go get him
some ice chips.
Mommy's here.
I'm here, baby.
Did he wake up?
Yeah.
Looks like
he's coming out of it.
That's my boy.
Um...
Will you
send Vanessa out here
when the time is right?
Absolutely.
Hey, you good?
I heard what happened.
It was awful.
A lot of fine surgical work
went to waste.
Really? That's all
you have to say?
No, actually,
I'd like to add
that if we just let it be,
he would've died on his own.
Hey, you can't
kill someone
who's already dead.
Can't even be tempted.
Is that why
you were so adamant
about having Kim decide?
Let me put it like this.
A victim of abuse
is being hauled off
to jail.
And in my opinion,
that's a lousy outcome.
I'll see you tomorrow,
Natalie.
That was a good catch
today, Ms. Curry.
Yeah, right.
"Yeah, right"?
Look, if it
wasn't for you,
Xavier might be back home
on a vent for
who knows how long.
Really good thing that
you piped up when you did.
Good work. Well done.
Asking a junkie
to meet you in a bar.
Not exactly sensitive.
I guess not.
Just a water for me.
Sit.
Look, I'm sorry
about this morning.
I may have
overreacted a bit.
That's okay.
Hannah,
I can't let this go on.
If you won't
turn yourself in...
Look, I thought we had
an understanding.
I quit
the injection site.
I thought that it meant
so much to you?
Not more than this.
I never would've
turned you in.
I just... I got...
Desperate and scared.
But you can't...
You can't possibly know
what it's like.
Every day I say
I'm gonna quit and yet...
Hannah.
You don't have to
do this alone.
I'll be there.
I'll help you.
What?
You care
about me.
I do.
I do care.
I will turn myself in.
First thing in the morning.
I can go with you.
Yeah.
Yeah, I'd like that.
Okay.
Come to my place?
Hey.
Check it out.
Looks good.
Now we just have
to set up the nursery.
But in the meantime...
How about that date?
Hey.
Everything okay?
Yes.
Come here.