Every patient who gets bad
news wants to be the exception.
The one in a
million. The miracle.
But surgeons don't
believe in miracles.
We have to make them happen.
- Are you okay?
- He has all the power now.
It's wrong. I'm his boss.
But I asked him out, and his
"No" is always going to be there
like a bloated corpse.
I've ruined work.
I've ruined it.
No. No, I'm not okay.
- I was asking Alex.
- Alex?
Alex is fine. He's
lucky he still has a job.
Well, this is not his
job. He's a surgeon.
He's still a doctor.
In the clinic,
where he doesn't have to look all
of his stupid mistakes in the face.
- Maybe let him answer.
- I'm fine.
- See?
- I mean, it sucks, but I'm fine.
If you get any
cardio consults today,
I mean, even the slightest
palpitation, you page Riggs.
I'm his boss. I give
you my blessing.
I'm not doing that.
Maggie, this isn't a real
problem. You're making it one.
- There she is.
- Hey!
- Hey, how was New York?
- Oh, my gosh. It was amazing!
Callie's got this great
place near the park,
and Sofia's got this
huge room all to herself.
- She loves her new school. It's good.
- Very good.
- Hey,
when did you get in?
- This... morning.
Welcome back, Robbin.
Cool. Well, the gas bill
came while you were away,
so I went ahead and
paid that. Thank you.
And the bathroom sink, it
just needed a new washer,
so don't call your guy.
It's better than it looks.
And at least my
eyesight's all the way back.
Good. That's good. I'm glad.
- I got to go.
- Yeah.
Marriage is like a bed and
breakfast in Vermont, with sex.
Until you have kids.
When I want sex, I don't
have to get out of bed
and drive to the sex.
I just roll right over.
- Can you stop it?
- Why would I stop it?
Married sex is dirtier
than I expected.
Not the sex, the bragging.
You're flashing your money
after going to the ATM. We get it.
You're sex-rich. It
is not polite to brag
in front of people
who are sex-poor.
Some of us are barely
making ends meet.
Multiple MVCs
coming into the ER.
Hey, Pierce, I got a valve
replacement. You good in the ER?
- Yep, I can cover the pit.
- Got it.
Shepherd. Grey.
- Was that normal?
- Why wouldn't it be normal?
No reason.
I mean, you were
a tad deferential...
- Amelia, don't.
- Damn it.
Come on, I move out, and I'm
dead to you now? You just cut me off?
I asked Riggs out. He said no.
- Wait, Riggs?
- Yeah.
I'm trying not to be
weird about it at work,
and you said I wasn't
weird, so there. Not weird.
Except for the part where
you keep talking about it.
Nathan Riggs?
Uh, you're not busy, right?
Nah, I'm just carrying
19 pounds of lac trays,
so I have something
to do with my hands.
Uh, can you get
Tuck from school?
- What, is he sick?
- No, he's not sick.
- Well, then,
why am I picking him up?
- There was an incident.
- What? Is he okay?
- No, he's fine. Are you busy?
Yes, there's a seven-car
pile-up in the pit.
I know! That's why I
need you to pick him up.
Coming through!
Oh, come on. This
is too good to miss.
Look, someone ran
into a funeral procession
just before it reached the
cemetery. A funeral procession!
Limos hitting
limos hitting limos.
And then all limos
smashed into the hearse.
Doors cracked open, casket
went airborne. A flying corpse!
All right, this, this
is all one family.
All right, it's, it's... It's art,
Miranda. It's a hot mess of art.
And, if you really need
me, I will go pick up Tuck.
But if you don't,
come on, this is...
this is too good
to miss. This is...
Someone hit a funeral,
and you want popcorn
and a front row
seat. Shame on you.
Just for that, you have
to go pick up Tuck.
- I had to pick up Tuck anyway.
- Just go.
I can't... I can't get air.
I know, but you have to
put the oxygen mask on
so it will actually help.
Where's my... Where's
my brother? Where's Julian?
Um, I don't know, but
I can find out for you.
I'm right here, Morgan, just
like I was two minutes ago.
Follow the light. Again.
Can you give her
something to calm her down?
Sir, I really need
you to look this way.
My sister gets panic attacks.
It's not even her first one today.
I'd like to rule out any
injury to her heart and lungs,
- but thank you for the heads-up.
- It was just out of nowhere.
We were to the cemetery
when this jerk just came
speeding out of nowhere.
The car just plowed into us!
And there was, like, a
chain reaction like dominoes.
Was it a drunk driver, or...
I don't know. When I figure
it out, I will sue his ass.
It's what dad would want.
Julian, that's the last
thing dad would want!
This funeral wasn't cheap. I
ordered orchids for the grave site.
Okay, tell me if this
feels dull or sharp.
Films are back, Dr. Shepherd.
- And your scans are up.
- Thanks.
Is my arm broken?
It's broken, isn't it?
In two places.
I'm making a list of everyone
in the family's injuries.
We're not paying
for any of this!
Dr. Keller, extension 2219.
Excuse me. I need to find out where
Barb is. Do you know if she's okay?
- Well, if you...
- Barb is my sister.
She's dressed in
black. Oh, that's no help.
She's a little shorter than I
am. Blond hair. Barbara Davis.
Okay, um...
She is in a procedure room.
She is getting a few stitches
on her forearm.
Looks fine otherwise.
Thank goodness. Thank you.
And those two over there,
they're my children. Are they okay?
Morgan and Julian Fisher.
Morgan, they are making sure
that her heart and lungs are okay.
Julian has a broken arm
and a cut on his forehead,
but I made sure he's okay, so...
And Carl ruptured his
spleen. Gene broke some ribs.
Michelle mostly has
broken glass in her hair.
Lynne has whiplash. Only
Pete came through unscathed.
- Pete is...
- Pete is my husband.
He's dead. This
was Pete's funeral.
- Oh, God, ma'am.
- Georgia.
Georgia, I'm so
sorry. You shouldn't...
Someone should be taking care
of you. We have a waiting area...
You know, right now, I really feel
like I need to be doing something.
But if you could find
out where they took him?
You got it. Yeah.
Edwards!
- Sir, I know...
- The patient in this bed
is deceased.
- I know.
- Not just deceased, embalmed.
The deceased, Peter,
it was his funeral.
The hearse and
the coffin got totaled,
the EMTs couldn't
leave him in the streets.
- Call the morgue.
- I did,
but they're taking
their sweet time.
There's not a lot of
urgency in that job, I think.
Then call them again. And
find someplace else for Mr...
- Peter.
- This is a room
for healing the sick.
- Yes, sir.
- Corpse in the emergency
department.
It's just creepy is what it is.
Kara, I need you to try and
slow your breathing, okay?
Oh, God, is he alive? I
can't even feel his little kicks.
He may be less active from the
pain meds we gave you, okay?
- Please, just tell me, is
he... Oh, Kara, you hear that?
That's a strong, stable
heartbeat. He's okay.
- Films are back.
- Yeah. good.
Hey, do we know where
the deceased guy was put?
What? Who else is hurt?
Is everyone hurt?
Did I kill anyone?
You were the driver?
I was late for the funeral.
I came around the corner,
and there they were,
the whole procession. I ran
right into them. It was me.
Kara, it was an accident.
I'm sure they'll understand.
Not my family. They've
never understood me.
I haven't even seen any of
them for almost ten years.
Dad maybe, but mom...
Julian, and Morgan.
God, I never should
have come back.
I just wanted to tell
my dad that I love him.
It's okay, it's
okay. It's all right.
Kara, your pelvis is fractured,
and there may be bleeding.
- We need to do a CT scan...
- What?
To check for bleeding
and other injuries, all right?
- CT? Is that safe for him?
- It's minimal risk for the baby,
but we need to know how
badly you're bleeding, okay?
Yeah, just... Just page
me when she's in CT.
The clinic is supplied for crap.
You didn't pick up my
calls or answer my texts.
- Arizona...
- I was worried about you.
- No, you were mad at me.
- Damn right I was mad. I'm still mad.
- You beat up my roommate.
- So, that's why you're mad?
Some guy you barely know
who pays you rent got beat up?
- What the hell
is wrong with you?
- Look, let's not do this.
I've had enough lectures. I'm
not in the mood for another one.
Your job is to take
care of children.
- Look, Arizona...
- Your job... is to take care
of children.
You want to throw your
life away? Or your career?
The career that I helped
you build? I trained you.
I had your back, and I
always pushed for you,
- no matter what anybody said.
- I know!
- Alex!
- I know all of this.
You can't tell me
anything I haven't heard
from Bailey or Mer or Jo... or
frankly, the State of Washington.
And hearing it one more
time isn't gonna help anything
or change anything or
fix me or turn back time,
so just shut up and
back off, please.
Excuse me.
What do you got?
Possible mesenteric tear.
Hmm. Hemothorax here.
- Is Pierce okay?
- She's in the pit, I think.
No, I mean with me.
Oh, don't flatter
yourself. She'll live.
All right, all right.
For what it's worth,
I feel bad about it.
She's my sister. You
think I like telling her
she can't have the good thing?
Then let's just come
clean, tell her why.
We'll feel better.
It'll feel really good.
Why don't you just focus on
your patient's Hemothorax?
All right.
"The good thing."
- Excuse me.
- You called me a good thing.
- Forget I said it.
- You ain't the boss of me.
Actually, I own a big
chunk of this hospital,
so technically, I am.
- Well, then, after you.
- Damn right.
Dr. Kadano to dialysis.
- Hey.
- Hey, what are you doing here?
So, I've been prescribed
movement, since my incision's healed.
I'm supposed to get up,
get out. I can walk now.
I should walk, actually, you
know, to get better. So, walking.
You can walk around
the block, you know?
In the neighborhood. It's
nice, you should check it out.
Yeah, I know, it's totally...
It's super nice. So is the house.
But I figured... I, I figured
you'd want to see the baby.
You know what? That's
really sweet of you.
I did just see her,
like, an hour ago.
I know, but look at this one.
You can't get enough
of this little nugget.
No, I guess you can't.
Okay, we are gonna go
down to the ER for a minute,
check out what's going on
there. I hear there's a big MVC.
- Really?
- So...
- What?
- You're gonna take her down
to ER
a newborn with all the blood,
germs, and dying people?
Right. Not a good idea.
No. I'll walk you out.
- Who wants to see Daddy?
- No, that...
- Hey, sweetheart. Yeah.
- Oh, there you go.
- Daddy's so good. Okay.
- Okay.
Bring her back
when she's hungry.
Hey...
I picked up Tuck,
and you know what?
- Tuck's teacher said
he got in a fight.
- Oh!
They said that he
pushed another child
- and that he started it.
- Who said that?
They also said they told you
all of this already over the phone.
- How's that, now?
- Miranda.
I must have... misheard.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Aren't you gonna go in there and
bring down the hammer on him?
I'm gonna let him sweat it out.
But he knows what's coming.
The hammer will fall.
Your husband has been
moved to a private room,
and the funeral home
has been notified.
Okay. Okay, thank you.
I'm afraid I have some bad news.
- What's wrong?
- Your daughter was injured.
She is okay, and
the baby is okay.
- Thirty-five weeks, almost time.
- What?
But I'm afraid your daughter was
the one who caused the accident.
No, I think you're confused.
Morgan was in the car
with me when we got hit.
I'm so sorry. Your
other daughter, Kara.
Kara?
Like I said, she and
the baby are both stable.
Kara's here? Kara's
having a baby?
- Kara?
- What?
She is. She
fractured her pelvis.
- Kara's here?
- Wait. Kara was driving the car?
- She's pregnant?
- You have got to be kidding me!
- She had the nerve to show up!
- Kara did this to us?
- She said it was an accident.
- Of course, she did.
- Classic.
- Julian.
Drugs again, right? Has to be.
I hope not. They
said she's knocked up.
Good Lord, what's next?
What Pete and Georgia did
to be saddled with that mess!
You said my husband was
here. Can I see him, please?
I'm sorry. This was the best
place we could find for him.
The morgue guys were
supposed to come and get him,
they said he was
dead when he got here,
so he's not their problem.
He's the funeral home's problem.
And it's just become
this big thing...
Edwards.
Take all the time you need.
Always thought I'd go first.
Actually, no.
If I pictured it, I thought
we'd go together.
Holding each other's hands.
Honey... Kara's back.
It's a miracle.
Kara came home.
Our baby came home.
Dr. Phelps, 2277.
- A felony?
- I know.
I mean, he did beat
him up really bad.
- Yeah, he did.
- You could punch
a cardio surgeon in a hospital
hallway, and nobody says a word.
Wait, apples and oranges.
And yet, Alex is charged
with a felony assault.
Apples and oranges.
Riggs and I, it was personal.
No, just apples.
It was about Wilson. It was about
a girl. How is that not personal?
- Shepherd just paged. The mom's okay.
- Oh, good.
Kara, we just got word that
your mom is fine. She wasn't hurt.
Okay, thanks. Does
she know I'm here?
- Yeah,
I think that they told her.
- Oh, God.
Then she knows. She
knows that it was me.
Maybe that wasn't a great idea.
But, I mean, I thought
she should know.
They haven't seen each
other in, like, ten years.
Kara, I am, I'm so sorry,
but the machine cannot get a clear
read, unless you're very, very still.
Okay. Okay, sorry.
It's okay. It's okay.
Take your time.
It's so sad.
I mean, can you imagine
saying goodbye to somebody
you've woken up next
to every day for 40 years?
So, Riggs, huh?
It's nothing. I mean...
It's nothing now.
It's stilted conversations
and avoiding eye contact.
- And he said no?
- Oh, yeah.
- To you?
- Right? Thank you.
- Yeah.
- We don't have to talk about it.
I've been trying to talk
about it, but Mer won't listen.
She thinks I should just forget
the whole thing happened.
They're here for Mr. Fisher.
Mrs. Fisher?
Georgia, the men from
the funeral home are here.
Oh... okay.
Why is someone with him?
She has had a rough day.
Georgia, I'm sorry,
but it... it really is time.
No, no, no! Dr. Pierce! Georgia!
Out of the way! Move!
- She's in V-fib.
- Continuing CPR.
Edwards, ready?
Charge to 120.
- Set up an intubation tray.
- Clear.
Charge to 150. Clear.
It's your husband's day,
Georgia. Don't steal the show.
Push one of epi.
What... Whatcha doin'?
I, uh, I asked you a question.
Sorry. I'm leveling up.
- Well, what did your mom say?
- About what?
- What do you mean "About what"?
- I haven't seen her.
- What are we waiting for?
- Sorry?
Tuck is just hanging in your
office, playing on his phone.
No hammer has fallen.
What are we waiting for?
- "We."
- What?
We are not waiting for anything.
He is my child. I will handle it.
Well, right now, you're
not doing anything.
You think I don't know that?
Look, I have to bring down
the hammer at work every day
it seems like lately, so excuse me if
I'm not jumping to do it at home, too.
Now, I have to explain to my
son why not to pick on other kids?
It's exhausting! I'm exhausted.
And right now, you're exhausting.
Edwards, ready?
- What's going on in there?
- They're running a code.
Clear!
- I just froze off a wart.
- Continuing CPR.
- I just wiped a butt.
- I did that, too.
Well, my body is making
food for another human.
That's something, I guess.
- Charge to 270.
- Well, you got me beat there.
Clear.
Charge again.
The force of your fracture
tore some vessels in your pelvis,
but your scan showed that
there's no active bleeding.
And since the baby's
stable and you're stable,
- we'd like to avoid surgery.
- I'll be monitoring you
very closely.
You know, I thought coming
home was the right thing to do.
You leave and so much time
goes by, you just get used to it.
And then one day, you get a
phone call that your dad died,
and you just see how
much you've missed.
And I didn't... I didn't want that
to happen with anybody else.
I didn't want that for my baby.
Kara, we can get someone from
your family, your mom, maybe?
What, no! No. I can't
face her. Not right now.
Thank you, though.
Kara, she'll forgive you.
Your mom will always forgive
you no matter how bad it gets.
You should try.
- Hey.
I need to find Georgia Fisher,
the mom of all those funeral people.
Look, do... Do I need to move?
- Do you what?
- I just... I understand.
All right? Karev is your friend.
He's your... He's your guy.
Things are gonna be
awkward enough at work.
Can we just say three weeks?
It's just that my medical bills have
been eating up a lot of my savings.
- I just need some time...
- Stop, stop, stop, stop.
I don't... That's not...
No, I don't want that.
- You don't?
- No. Why?
Everyone's just so pissed at me.
They don't say it, but I can feel it.
You just seem pissed, too.
- I got to find this lady.
- All right.
- Hey, is this Georgia?
- Yeah, yeah,
sudden cardiac arrest.
- No.
- We're getting her back. We have to.
- Well, how long has it been?
- Forty-two minutes.
- What are you doing?
- We have to call it.
No, she's not... They
can't have another funeral.
Amelia, she's gone.
- Damn it.
- Time of death, 14:02.
- You need something?
- No.
What the hell? Georgia was fine.
Your mother went
into cardiac arrest.
We tried to revive
her for almost an hour.
But despite our
best efforts, she died.
Why? Was it the crash?
We won't know exactly what
happened until we do an autopsy.
Of course it was the crash.
Has anyone told Kara?
I can't even look
at her right now.
Where is she? Where's my sister?
- Kara, I have some bad news.
- What? What is it?
- Why did you come back?
- No.
- Julian?
- Mom's dead.
- No...
- Dead?
No, no, they said she was fine.
- No.
- You told me she was...
- She, she had a heart attack...
- From all the stress you caused.
Sir, I understand you're
upset, but I need your sister
to keep calm right now, okay?
- Mom's dead? Oh, my...
- What the hell, Kara?
- Wilson.
- Why did you even come here?
- Okay! All right! Leave.
- You need to go.
- I am so sorry.
- She can't be. She can't...
Oh, God. I killed her.
Baby's heartbeat is down.
He's been having
decels, never this long.
What's wrong? What's going on?
I'm sorry, Kara, but we're gonna
take your baby out right now.
- Book an OR, let's page Hunt.
- No. No, no, no.
Let's move.
Dr. Alberts to the ICU.
- It's possible to hate you,
you know?
- What?
You're easy to hate. I
hated you when we met.
- And now?
- Well, now you're just...
A bloated corpse.
That's it. Maybe you
should go out with Maggie.
- Excuse me?
- Go back.
Tell her you changed your
mind and just be terrible.
You know, be rude to
waiters, no eye contact,
bad breath, close
her foot in the door.
Just turn off all that.
I'm not... I'm not sure
what all that means.
Just go out with her
and be someone else.
- Don't be you.
- Be a jerk?
- Yes.
- With bad breath?
Exactly.
- Because being myself
would be too...
- Ugh, forget it.
- Hold one moment. Of course.
- Thank you.
Oh.
You're not a single parent.
Oh, you think Tucker
Jones is gonna punish him.
'Cause he's Mr. Fun Dad.
Mr. Ice Cream and camping
trips and video games.
I'm the one who has to
dole out all the punishment.
No, look, I mean that
Tuck has three parents.
I love him. And I'm
pissed at him, too.
I know you feel like
you have to do it all.
No, I'm going to do it.
But you don't have to.
I'm right here. Let me!
Look, put me in, Chief. You
need a bad cop. Deputize me.
What does Mer say exactly
when you talk about Riggs?
She just...
So, the morgue
is on its way, uh,
They said, since she
died in the hospital,
they are happy to come.
Tell them to wait, and keep your
voice down. Show some respect.
Respect?
Uh, we're having a funeral?
That's allowed?
- It's fine.
- Okay. I'll let the morgue know.
You were saying?
- No.
- What?
It's like she doesn't
want to hear it.
At all. Like I'm annoying her.
Which, maybe I am,
but be a sister, sister.
I mean, if it was
her and she was...
craving something
that she couldn't have,
I would commiserate.
I would at least listen.
I'll listen to you. Any time.
I don't think that
now is the best time.
I'm not listening.
Then how would you know to
say that if you weren't listening?
If Dr. Webber finds out,
I'm gonna be in trouble.
I told you it's fine.
Nobody needs the room.
This family was
primed for a funeral.
Not hers.
I wish I was as good as
Mer at forgetting things.
My life would be
a lot easier if I was.
Okay, she does
not forget things.
She buries them. She
thinks they're gone,
but trust me, they are not gone.
They're gonna come back.
They always come back.
See, this is the problem
with me moving out.
With three, there was
balance. Now, it's chaos.
She squeezed my hand.
She squeezed my hand!
- She what?
- No, she squeezed it!
I was holding her hand,
and she squeezed it!
- I'm telling you!
- Morgan, I am sure that you...
- did feel something.
- No, I don't think
she's dead.
The body can experience
residual reflexes.
Yes, muscles can spasm,
and then they stiffen.
There are a lot of reasons
for slight movements.
This wasn't slight!
Okay, I promise you it does
not mean that she is actually...
No, that woman is alive!
I love my job.
- She was dead?
- Yes.
- And now she's no longer dead.
- Also, yes.
We saw her flatline,
and she's not dead.
Lazarus Syndrome.
Spontaneous
return of circulation
after failed attempts
at resuscitation.
Or a miracle.
You can't rule it out.
Well, when we tell a
family a patient is dead,
I prefer we be correct!
It's a low, low bar
for a physician.
How is she, besides undead?
We won't know about neuro
deficits until after the cardiac workup.
I did detect a slight murmur.
I'm going to run a TEE to make
sure there aren't any abnormalities.
- Edwards,
will you check on that?
- Hell, yeah.
Yeah. Yeah, yes.
Yes, Dr. Pierce.
We got her back. Don't blow it. Do
not lose this woman a second time.
- Understood.
- Got it.
Jesus wept.
Let's continue with
chest compressions.
What's going on in there?
A guy came in, fell three stories
off his building into the alley.
Oh, dumpster dive.
Guys, don't mess around
with intubation. Just crike him.
What are you waiting for?
There's too much swelling.
- Just cut him already.
- Come on, you guys!
- There it is.
- Okay, they got it.
God, I miss this. I
miss the pace of it.
- Yeah.
- I can't wait to get back here.
I cannot wait. Can't you?
Well, you know
you're coming back.
- I'm sorry.
- I should get going.
- Go ahead with it.
- Guys, just push more epi.
Sorry. You're doing great.
Good... Good work, everyone.
See, now, this is
where his eye should be,
but instead it's trapped
in the broken bone.
- Jeez.
- Yeah,
- that's what can happen
when you punch people, Tuck.
- Mm-hmm.
- Who is that?
- Doesn't matter.
I'll tell you who it used
to be. He was a surgeon.
- That's right.
- But now he may never be one.
- 'Cause he's blind in one eye.
- What?
And the guy who
hit him? He's in jail.
Probably for a long time.
- Want to go to jail, young man?
- No, sir.
Well, that's where fighting
gets you. Prison or... Dr. Avery.
Yeah, yeah, and
that's his collarbone.
God!
Lazarus Syndrome has only
been reported 38 times since 1982.
Advance the probe, please.
She could have had
impaired venous return
due to dynamic
hyperinflation of the lungs,
which caused delayed action of
the drugs we gave her during CPR.
Or a transient myocardial
stunning or electrolyte imbalance.
No one knows for
sure why this happens.
Or she missed her
daughter. Wasn't ready.
I'm just glad we were there.
Oh God, because what if
she'd woken up in the morgue?
She could still be there
for all we know, just...
crying out for
somebody, no one's there.
Banging on the wall
of her metal drawer.
Bonk, bonk, bonk, bonk, bonk.
I have to concentrate on this.
Oh, yeah, sorry.
'Cause if we lost her a
second time, that poor family.
- Could you ever count
on anything again?
- No.
I mean, it'd be like we were
throwing away a second chance.
And not just
Georgia's, but ours,
'cause we'll never
see this again.
- Statistically speaking...
- Edwards.
All this woman wanted to do was
die, holding her husband's hand,
and she did that. She
got to die holding his hand.
And then she came back to life.
Sorry if I'm too amazed.
Wait. Georgia's not
dead? Curved mayos.
Not according to Shepherd.
Incredible.
So this little guy's gonna get
to meet his grandma after all.
Take him to the
NICU and page Karev.
Uh, Karev's in the clinic.
Oh, right. Just take
him to the NICU.
- Yeah.
- You don't know that.
- Know what?
- If Kara's mom'd ever
forgive her.
- You've no idea.
- Of course, she will. It's her mom.
Well, not every
family is like that.
It's really dangerous to
get someone's hopes up.
That's not the kind of
thing that you can promise.
Jeez, Wilson,
have a little faith.
- BP's dropping. We're losing her.
- There's major hemorrhaging.
- Let's get some laps. Start packing.
- Yes, doctor.
You hear about the
miracle lady in the ER?
M.I. coded her for 40 minutes,
dead for 20 more, then she sat up.
- Shut up.
- Yeah. Awake and alive.
She's got to be gorked.
You can't be down for
that long without deficits.
Well, we'll see. Pierce is doing
a cardiac assessment now.
- Could be a miracle.
- She's gorked.
You ever have that dream?
- What dream?
- The miracle dream.
I'd roll over in bed, and there she
was, asking me to go make coffee.
So real.
Then I'd wake up.
No, never had that dream.
- A knock at the door.
- Sorry?
He knocks at the door,
says he forgot his keys,
and he's sorry for
being gone so long.
She's gorked.
Pupils reactive, reflexes intact.
I'm seeing no neurological deficits.
We're gonna keep an eye on her
heart, but for now, she looks good.
- Do you hear that, mom? You're okay.
- How are you feeling?
Tired.
How about Kara? Is she okay?
I'm sure she's fine.
Yeah, she always walks
away from the wreck.
Oh, please. She is your sister.
And maybe you have had
your problems in the past,
maybe she is a train wreck.
Maybe, she is a walking demolition
crew, but she came back to you.
- She came back to her family.
- Yeah, and she killed
our mother!
And your mother came back,
too! Do you know how rare that is?
Since 1982, that
has been recorded...
- Edwards?
- Thirty-eight times.
Which might as well be
never. And now mom is fine,
and you're both fine, and
you should all be celebrating.
And instead, you're
just whining and fighting
when your sister came back!
And your mom came back!
Do you really want
to throw that away?
Is that what your father
would have wanted?
You two deserved that.
I would have thought you would
have... both been gone by now.
You know how it is with a
baby. Everybody wants a turn.
Uh, pretty bad Le Fort
fracture in OR Three.
I saw that.
Should have seen the
intake. It was gnarly.
How gnarly?
- About eight, nine.
- Nice.
You are bored out
of your freaking mind.
Oh, my God, I'm so bored.
And I can't move as much as I
want to, so we just sit and stare
and stare and stare.
And I love Harriet.
I do, obviously. I
mean, she's a miracle.
She'll make a little face
or a little sound at me,
and I'm just like dumbstruck
with gratitude and joy.
Just, like, delighted
and amazed.
Yeah.
But then the delight and
amazement fades a little
when she goes back to sleep.
And I stare.
I did not know a miracle
could be so boring.
Why don't you go check
out the Le Fort for yourself?
Really?
Has everyone had their turn?
'Cause Daddy would like one.
- Thank you. Hey, sweetheart.
- So sweet.
Kara, he's right here.
- Hi. He's okay?
- Yeah.
- I didn't screw him up?
- He's great.
You're here. Hi, you.
You both did great.
I hear we have a nephew.
They... they said it was
okay if... if we're family.
We just wanted to
see if you were all right.
- If you needed anything or...
- I'm so sorry.
- Hey. Hey.
- It was an accident.
- Everyone's okay. It's okay.
- No, not mom. Mom's not okay.
- Mom's fine.
- What?
Yeah, mom's good.
I mean, you killed her,
but she's really good now.
- See? They forgave her.
- Yeah. You got really lucky.
And how long do
I hold onto this?
One...
Two weeks.
- What else?
- And I'm gonna talk to Marcus.
To the kid. I'm gonna apologize.
- And?
- And I'll never do this again.
I don't want to go to jail.
- I'm sorry, mom.
- How's that?
- I'm sorry.
- All right.
You can wait in the car.
- What is wrong with us?
- Wrong?
That we waited so
long to deputize you.
She's awake.
The dead lady. No
deficits, fully ungorked.
- That's great.
- A miracle.
Just sayin'. Anything
can happen, Dr. Grey.
- She needs her good sister.
- Amelia, what are you doing?
Not having dirty married sex
because I'm worried about you two.
So here is how it's gonna go.
Maggie, you are gonna talk to
Mer about whatever you want,
whenever you want, period.
And, Mer, you are gonna
listen, whether you want to or not!
Because that is what
a sister does! Period!
I'm gonna walk away now.
Don't make me move back in.
I'm listening. What do
you want to talk about?
Riggs? Work?
You know, all I've been doing
today is listening to siblings
talk and complain
and talk and complain,
and all I really want to do
is to get something to eat.
I'm good with that.
What about you? I can't
be the only one talking.
Sisterhood is a two-way street.
Is there anything you
want to get off your chest?
- Any guy you're into?
- No!
Miracles aren't always huge.
The fever breaks. The
stitch holds. The bone heals.
That's why they
can be hard to spot.
And why they can be
such a pain in the ass.
You're not supposed to be here.
I heard you did an
emergency C-section.
Yeah. I almost lost
the mom and the baby.
- You're pissed.
- Yeah!
Yeah, I'm pissed.
That baby deserved the
best peds surgeon we have,
and we didn't have him
because you screwed up.
Yeah.
Today I froze a wart,
diagnosed three sinus infections,
gave someone a laxative
and waited until they pooped.
I wanted to quit every
five minutes today.
I wanted to walk out the
damn door and never look back.
- Yeah, so now
you're gonna complain?
- That's the point. I'm not.
I'm gonna do my time, work
in the clinic, and help people.
I want to come back, and
I'm gonna do whatever it takes,
and I'm not quitting.
And that's the guy
you trained and raised
and whatever, so... Okay?
I missed you today.
But I'm still really,
really mad at you.
I know. Me too.
Don't get me wrong.
Tiny miracles are great.
A little miracle is a miracle.
It just may not be
enough to save us.