- Who's there?
I've already called the police!
- Mr. Sullivan, you were
sentenced to three years
for a class IV felony
aggravated battery
of one Pawel Wapniarski.
We're here to consider
a compassionate release
based on a new diagnosis?
- My client's physician,
Dr. Mitchell Ripley,
would like to address
the board.
- Dr. Ripley?
- Mr. Sullivan's
latest PET scan
indicates that his cancer
has metastasized
to his lymph nodes
and adrenal glands.
- Given this new diagnosis,
how much time does
Mr. Sullivan have,
in your opinion?
- Less than three months.
- Thank you, Dr. Ripley.
- Mr. Sullivan
has a new family.
This is his girlfriend, Lynne,
and his son, Nate,
who he's barely
got a chance to hold.
I've known Mr. Sullivan
most of my life.
He's not perfect.
Far from it.
But he's a good man, and...
I believe his son
would be better off
knowing his father
during the short amount
of time he has left.
Thank you.
- Thanks, man.
- Ta-da.
My first attempt at Ma's
sweet potato pie recipe.
- I'm sure you nailed it.
Mmm.
- Well, you can be
the judge tomorrow.
- Yeah.
- Hey. Sorry.
Uh, where's Hannah?
Got two cans of cranberry sauce
with her name on it.
- She's decorating the doctor's
lounge for Friendsgiving.
You remembered the potluck.
- Best thing about a demotion
is the freedom to do
grocery store errands.
- Is that self-pity I hear?
- On the contrary,
it's just a more well-rested,
more relaxed disposition.
- Hmm.
- Your sister call you back?
- Nope.
- Sorry.
- No, you know,
I made a peace offering.
Ball's in her court now.
- Yeah.
- Good morning, Dr. Archer.
- Good morning, Dr. Lenox.
I promise not to
make this awkward.
- I'm glad to hear that.
I know a change like this
could be difficult to process.
- It's good, actually.
It feels like a huge
weight's been lifted.
- You sound like you mean that.
- That's because I do.
You're the boss,
and I respect that.
And I'm gonna make sure
that everybody else
around here does too.
I appreciate that. Thank you.
- Overdose just pulling up
in five, Dr. Lenox.
- On it.
- Oh, no, no, no.
No worries. I got this.
I just gotta change first.
- Is he really okay?
- He thinks he is.
Just go with it.
- Hey.
- Hi.
The board rejected Sully's
compassionate release request.
- I'm so sorry, Mitch.
I'm so sorry.
- The chairwoman said that
if he was well enough
to commit battery,
he was well enough
to serve out his sentence.
He should be with
Lynne and Nate.
I know.
- Sully screwed up. I--he did.
But he doesn't deserve
to die alone in jail.
- Hey. Come here.
- Going to treatment five.
Talk to me, Corey.
- Ariel Sparkman, 24-year-old
female, possible drug overdose.
Heart rate 122, BP 130/70.
Her roommate found her
passed out on the floor
next to a nearly empty
bottle of pills.
- What did she take
and how much?
- Antidepressants.
Ariel probably took
around 10 to 15 pills,
but she's only supposed
to take one per day.
I called her psychiatrist.
She's on her way.
- All right, on my count.
One, two, three.
- Struggling to breathe.
Okay.
- Heart rate is
climbing at 165.
- You experience chest pain?
Let's bolus her a liter of LR
and get her an EKG
and a tox order set
for a possible overdose.
- You got it.
- Morning, Dean.
I have the bullet points,
but do we know what she took?
- Antidepressants,
but her heart rate's
just shot through the roof.
This is her roommate.
- Savannah.
- Hi, Savannah.
Do you happen to know the name
of the antidepressant
she's been taking?
- No.
We left so fast. I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
- Her breathing is worsening.
- Ariel, how are you doing?
I'm Dr. Charles.
I want you to do me a favor.
Take a deep breath with me, okay?
Ready?
In through the nose...
And out through the mouth.
Beautiful. One more time.
In through the nose
and out through the mouth.
Excellent.
- Ariel's not overdosing.
She's having a panic attack.
- Sarah?
- Hello, Dr. Charles.
It's nice to see you.
- And you are?
- I'm Ariel's psychiatrist,
Dr. Reese.
I used to work here.
- Tachycardia is improving.
Should I still run those labs?
- No need, Doris.
- You still have privileges
at Gaffney, Dr. Reese?
- I don't, but I was hoping
Dr. Charles might grant them
while Ariel's here.
- Of course.
- Cancel those labs, Doris.
- Mm-hmm.
- I promise this
physical reaction
was not brought on
by the drug itself.
It was fear, your fear.
And now you are
taking back control.
Deep breaths.
Good.
I'm gonna go call
your parents, Ariel, okay?
I'll be right back.
- Thank you, Dr. Reese.
- Hey, Daniel.
Some history there?
- Yeah, Sarah interned
under me when she was here.
Can't say we parted
under the best of terms.
It was complicated.
But let me tell you something.
She's so talented.
I haven't seen her
in six years.
- A May-December thing?
- No, Dean.
It was a people thing.
- Okay.
- Dr. Archer, aren't you
joining the festivities?
- Oh, you bet.
I can't miss out on
Doris's Jell-O salad.
It's even better
than her cookies.
How about you?
- Well, I wish I could,
but I'm meeting Dennis in--
oh, jeez.
I forgot to charge my watch.
Anyway, I'm gonna grab
some things from my office,
and then I'm out.
- Oh, sounds lovely.
- How are you holding up?
Letting go of the reins
isn't always easy.
- Mm, I got in my head
about it at first,
but frankly,
it's been liberating
to focus on just
being a doctor again.
Feels good.
- I'm glad.
You're an excellent doctor.
- Oh, don't blow smoke
up my lab coat, please.
- Oh, no smoke,
just simple fact.
- All right.
- Happy Thanksgiving.
- You too.
- Hey, Catie?
- Kip.
- Can we talk?
Oh, why don't you
close the blinds too?
Hide me from your
terrified minions, right?
- I told you never
to come here.
- Why?
Are you afraid I'll tell them
you're not actually scary?
What do you want, Kip?
- I can't go tonight.
- What? Well, why not?
- Something came up.
- I don't believe you.
- Kudos to
the human lie detector.
Nothing came up.
I just simply don't wanna go.
- What happened to your face?
Looks like--
Nothing.
Just fell.
- Oh, you fell?
'Cause it looks like
you got punched.
- Right again, Catie.
I got into a bar fight
because I was drunk.
It was a night
of irresponsible choices.
- Are you ever gonna grow up?
- Oh, God.
You know, Mom would hate
the way that you treat me.
- Mom overindulged you.
- Well, that's why
I am the way I am.
- You know, if you're
really gonna bail tonight,
you obviously don't care about
Mom as much as you claim to.
- All right.
- Have a good day, Catie.
- I gotta tell you.
It really is--
I don't know.
It's a nice surprise.
- Good to see you, too,
Dr. Charles.
- How long have you been back?
- I finished Baylor
four years ago.
- Four years?
- Sorry, just,
the time got away from me.
- I totally get it.
I really do.
What--are you in--
in private practice now?
- Yeah, I joined the
Ananke Center last year.
- Really?
So Ananke, Greek,
mother of fate?
- And necessity.
I focus on a holistic,
by-any-means-necessary approach.
- Well, anyway,
hear it's a really cool place.
- Thank you for extending me
temporary privileges
so I can care for Ariel.
- Of course.
Are you kidding me?
Oh, by the way,
speaking of Ariel,
how were you so sure that
she wasn't overdosing
on an antidepressant?
- Because she's not taking one.
She's on a placebo.
- Oh, so she's in, like,
a double-blind clinical trial?
- No, no, no.
She thinks she's taking an
antidepressant, citalopram.
- She's unaware?
- She thinks she needs
the citalopram
to manage her depression,
but I see it as
an unnecessary crutch.
There will come a time,
however,
where I disclose that truth
to illustrate that point.
- Well, good,
because I mean,
there is the ethical piece, right?
- What do you mean?
- I guess I mean the
ethics of prescribing
a placebo to somebody
who's suicidally depressed.
- This wasn't a suicide
attempt, Dr. Charles.
I'd actually appreciate it
if you'd discharge her.
- Of course.
I mean, I'd feel
a little more comfortable
if I could just get--
- You know, I totally understand
your cause for concern.
But I want to assure you, I do
actually know what I'm doing.
I had an excellent teacher.
- Oh, okay.
Very good.
- Aaron Decembly, 36,
traffic accident.
Passenger side got
T-boned by a huge SUV.
Seat belt was on.
Heart rate 95, BP 123/82.
Facial airbag contusions,
also complained of neck pain
at the scene.
- Wipe that goofy grin
off your face.
- Why? I'm the happiest guy
in the world.
But you are,
and I say this with love,
a remarkably bad driver.
- That car did come out of
nowhere, but I'm so sorry.
- Are you his girlfriend?
- I don't know, Krista,
are you my girlfriend?
- I--yeah, I think I am.
Finally.
- All right, carefully
on my count, one, two, three.
- Normal respirations.
Lungs are clear.
- Thanks.
- I'm getting first date vibes.
- Yeah, you're right.
We've secretly been in love
with each other for 18 years.
- We met in our college dorm.
- We were never single
at the same time
or geographically compatible--
both: Until now.
- Well, there's no sign
of free fluid.
CT's backed up.
Let's do a lateral
C-spine X-ray.
- My company just
transferred me to Chicago.
Krista literally just picked
me up from the airport,
and this happens.
- X-ray up.
- Spine's been torn in half.
- It's hanging by a thread.
One wrong move
from paralysis or death.
- I mean, how did he even
survive the accident?
- Luck.
That neck brace is the only
thing keeping him alive.
We have to get him to surgery.
- Scream, and I'll
cut your damn throat.
- Where's your phone?
- In my car.
I just ran up here to grab
that bottle of whiskey.
- Stand up. Empty your pockets.
- What?
What can I help you with?
- Just sit back down.
I already cut the line.
- Look.
You should know my friend
is waiting for me in my car.
And if I don't show up soon,
he's gonna come looking for me.
- Nice try,
but I watched you park
and walk in today, alone.
- Do we know each other?
- I don't know.
Do we?
- Were you a patient?
- You'll figure it out.
- Wait. My spine is severed?
- It's fractured and dislocated
between the C2
and C3 vertebrae.
- Miraculously, your spinal cord
is still functioning.
But any sudden movement
or trauma could change that
and leave you a quadriplegic.
- And surgery could fix him?
- Surgery is our best chance
to fix it,
but it's still
a very risky procedure.
- Why is this surgery
so dangerous?
- Well, his CTA showed that
both vertebral arteries
are occluded, blocked.
- Usually, all four arteries
supply blood to your brain.
But right now,
your carotid arteries
are shouldering
the entire burden.
So we need to restore
regular blood flow
back to your brain stem.
- Until then,
any dip in blood pressure
could cause a massive stroke.
- So it's a ticking time bomb.
- We need to get you
upstairs ASAP.
- With your permission.
One of the best neurosurgeons
in the country
is on his way here now.
Are you game?
- Damn right, I'm game.
Krista and I have
a life to live together.
Let's do this.
- Okay.
- Savannah?
- Hi.
Just getting some chips
for Ariel.
- How's she doing?
- Good.
She's definitely ready
to go home.
- Oh, I bet.
You know that, um,
Sarah was probably the most
emotionally intuitive resident
I've ever worked with, ever.
- She's made a huge
difference for Ariel.
- Oh, clearly.
Do you happen to know
how they--
how they found each other?
- Ariel and I have been
roommates for two years.
The first year was epic.
We became like sisters.
But that all changed last year.
Ariel began to withdraw.
She stopped taking care
of herself,
never wanted to go out.
Some days, she wouldn't
even get out of bed.
- Was there, like, a, um,
I don't know,
a specific event,
like a trigger?
- No.
That's what made it so weird.
- Sometimes depression
will come out of nowhere.
- She tried
a ton of therapists
who prescribed
a ton of antidepressants,
but nothing worked.
But then she found Dr. Reese.
And within a month,
Ariel was her old self again.
I didn't have to live in fear.
- How do you mean,
live in fear?
- Ariel swallowed up
a bottle of--of aspirin
around eight months ago.
We took her to
Jackson Monroe ED,
and they pumped her stomach.
- Of course, I mean,
Dr. Reese knows all this?
- Yeah, that's why
Ariel started
seeing her a few weeks later.
- Right.
- Look, I don't know
what your plans are,
but you haven't done anything
that can't be undone.
So why don't you just
put the knife down,
and then you can go home
to your family.
- But that's the thing.
I don't have a family
anymore because of you.
- Okay, I get that
you're angry with me.
But if I don't know why,
I can't very well
apologize for it.
Can I?
- My name is Cassidy.
- Okay.
- And do you wanna know why
you don't remember me?
Because I don't matter to you.
My wife certainly
did not matter to you.
- Your wife?
- Wendy.
We were on the ship
that capsized.
And you let her die.
You let her die.
- Okay. Okay.
- The NCI depleted
our supply of O-neg.
These are the last five units.
Your wife was
Dr. Lenox's patient.
She needed blood, and it was
given to another patient.
- No, you gave it
to another patient,
to the man who caused
the entire accident,
who is the reason
Wendy got crushed under debris.
- It was an impossible choice
to make.
- You know what I can't
stop thinking about?
That blood would have
saved her.
It was no long shot.
If you would have chosen Wendy,
she would be here right now.
You knew it was
a death sentence.
- Cassidy--
- Don't.
- All right.
I regret that Wendy died.
I followed a protocol that
saves more lives than it loses.
It's not perfect,
but it tries to be fair.
- Fair?
Fair?
- Look, I totally
understand how you feel--
- You understand nothing!
Please. Please.
- What's his neuro exam?
- He's still intact,
with full motor strength
and normal sensation
in both arms and legs.
- Great.
Dr. Abrams should be here soon,
and we'll get you up to the OR.
- Look,
you said earlier that
the surgery was dangerous.
But how dangerous?
I wanna know.
- It's not a very
common procedure,
so there's not a lot of data.
But in my experience,
more than half don't make it.
- Well, that certainly
puts things in perspective.
Wow.
You know, for a couple that
specializes in bad timing,
this really takes the cake.
This morning,
I was the happiest
I'd ever been in my life.
- No one knows
what's gonna happen.
- Yeah, well, fate certainly
seems to be against me.
- When did you plan on
asking her?
- Today.
- So what's stopping you?
- Are you serious?
- Any of us could die today.
Some of us know it's coming.
Some of us don't.
But fate is boring.
Live your life.
- Good for you.
- He is nice to look at.
- But?
- I don't know.
Loren's great,
but I feel like I'm 15,
you know,
and everything's going great.
I get bored.
Maybe I just need to grow up
and accept it's not all
butterflies and fireworks.
- You're not bored.
You just don't feel it.
Those are two entirely
different things.
- You think?
- I know.
- Butterflies and fireworks
are worth waiting for.
- Oh, so you found
someone special?
- Mm, not yet,
but I'm a patient woman.
And I gotta be honest.
You should be too.
- "I gotta be honest"?
Do you know who you sound like?
How dare you.
- Speaking of which,
can we see if he's finally
discharged Ariel Sparkman?
- Ariel still hasn't
been discharged.
- Um, please.
Can you grab me
an orange juice?
- What?
- I'm diabetic, and my
blood sugar's crashing.
- It doesn't matter.
- Well, it should matter
to you.
This--
This glucose monitor
is programmed
to notify my children
of my location
the moment my blood sugar
falls below 70.
They'll know
something is wrong.
- Okay. Okay. Where are they?
- In the fridge.
They're in the bottom drawer.
Well, I had to sit up to drink.
Thank you.
It's harder than
you thought, huh?
- What?
- Trying to kill
another person.
You never pictured yourself
doing something like this.
But would Wendy want--
- Don't say her name.
- But if she were here
right now,
would she want to see you
throw your entire life away?
No.
She was a better person.
- And if she were here,
what would she tell you
right now?
- What was that?
- You lying bitch.
- Sharon.
Yeah, just calling
with a quick question,
but you're probably already out
celebrating with the family.
So don't worry about
calling me back.
I'll sort it out.
Hey, it looks like
somebody said yes.
- Uh-huh.
Rumor has it that
Dr. Lenox here
talked Aaron into
proposing today.
- Oh, you going soft on us?
- I've read several studies
that indicate
a patient's odds for survival
rise exponentially
when they have hope,
so happiness heals.
- That sounds on brand.
- Sorry to disappoint.
- I have an idea.
- Hey, listen,
I looked into it,
and we can still appeal
the parole board's decision.
- No, man. It's done.
I'm done.
- The board never gave you
a chance today.
- Sure, they did.
They just decided
I didn't deserve one.
Can't say I blame them.
- What?
- I've had a lot of time
to reflect in here.
I make bad choices even
when I know they're bad,
because I somehow
thought it made me tough.
Turns out, I'm not.
No point in lying to myself
anymore, right?
- Don't talk like that.
Lynne and the baby need you,
whatever time you have left.
- I need them.
I just don't know how much
more fight I have in me.
- You got one more fight
in you?
- Do you want
more orange juice?
No, I'm good.
A doctor would be nice.
- I can't do that.
- Yeah, I figured.
- Why aren't you scared?
- Scared of what? Dying?
- Yeah.
- Well, I was a nurse.
I saw death every day.
I--I don't want to die,
but I don't regret
one moment of my life.
I have known love.
I have three amazing children.
I'm a grandmother,
and I have lived
a life of purpose.
- What do you think happens
when you die?
- I hope that I'm reunited
with the people that I've lost.
And that my children
carry just a little piece
of me as they move on.
- I don't know how to
move on from Wendy.
I--I can't.
- Well, that's because
you're letting
your love for her
tear you apart.
I know.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
Everything's actually perfect.
- Okay, is that
the pain meds talking?
Wait.
Is this what I think it is?
- Are you okay with that?
- I'm more than okay.
This all seems
strangely appropriate,
given our history together.
- Look behind you, sweetie.
- Uh, I was recently
ordained online.
- About 15 minutes ago.
- Yeah, not by choice.
- Shh.
- We are gathered here today
for reasons
not entirely clear to me
to witness the joining
of two lives.
Do you, Aaron, take Krista
to be your partner in life,
to love and to cherish,
for better or for worse,
for richer, for poorer,
in sickness and in health,
from this day forward
until death do you part?
- I do.
- And do you, Krista,
take Aaron to be
your partner in life,
to love and to cherish,
for better or for worse,
for richer, for poorer,
in sickness and in health,
from this day forward,
until death do you part?
- I do.
- You people do
have rings, right?
By the power vested in me
by some random website,
I now pronounce you married.
Now, kiss, and let's get
Aaron up to surgery.
- We're gonna spend more
years together than we wasted.
You hear me?
- You bet we will.
- It's time.
- You having a moment?
- Yeah.
- I'm sorry, Dr. Charles,
I'm just curious why you
haven't discharged Ariel yet?
- So I can fully assess her.
- Uh-huh.
Why would you need to do that?
- Because it's become
pretty clear to me, anyway,
that when she took
those pills this morning,
it was a second
suicide attempt.
- Oh, you spoke to Savannah?
- I don't understand why you'd
withhold that detail from me.
- You wanna know why
I chose not to tell you?
It's because I know you.
You analyze.
You second guess. You judge.
And here you are again,
right on time.
- Sarah, do you not realize
how serious this is?
- Ariel did not try
to kill herself today.
- All I can say is,
you're damn lucky
they were just sugar pills.
- It was an accident.
- Why do you keep saying that?
- I want her discharged now.
- Well, it's not happening
'cause she's on a 72-hour hold.
- Dr. Charles, you are wrong.
- How is it humanly possible
that someone could take
12 pills by accident?
- I'm still figuring it out.
- Okay, great.
So you want me to just
discharge a patient
who is a clear suicide risk
to your disturbingly
questionable care
so you can figure it out?
- You arrogant son of a bitch.
- I don't know, but you got too
close to your patient again,
lost all objectivity, again.
Let's face it--
been an issue before, Sarah.
- Call me Dr. Reese.
And this isn't about Ariel.
This is about you
and how you could never fathom
that you might possibly
be wrong.
And you know
just as well as I do
that that was
the reason I left.
- Okay, well, guess what,
Dr. Reese?
You're about to leave again.
Get the hell out of my unit.
Dr. Ripley, incoming.
- Robert Sullivan, 36,
BP 120/80, O2 97.
Involved in an altercation.
They did a chest X-ray
at the jail.
Ribs 7 and 8 are broken,
but no pneumothorax.
- Sully.
- Gentle, Rip.
I'm very delicate.
- What happened exactly?
- Genius picked a fight
with someone twice his size.
- He was smack talking
the Bulls.
I couldn't just let that slide.
- Okay, let's get him
upstairs for a CT,
and I'll need his
cuffs off for that.
- Yes, sir.
- Hey, you missed
the festivities.
Look. I snagged the wishbone.
- Ah, yes, the beloved
tearing of the furcula
holiday tradition.
- I gotta say, Dean,
I'm proud of you.
- Oh, yeah? Why is that?
- This positive attitude.
- Ah.
- You know, I thought
your first day back
was gonna be
all doom and gloom.
- About that.
- What's this?
- It's a resignation letter.
I'm gonna slip it
under Goodwin's door.
- Wait. Are you serious?
- Yes, I am.
- You said you were relieved
to not have
the extra responsibility.
- I tried
to believe that today.
I really did.
But with Sean leaving Chicago
and Margo and I ending things,
why stay?
- Are you really
saying that to me?
- Of course,
you're a reason to stay.
But Goodwin's right.
Lenox is the future of the ED,
and it's time for me
to move on.
I don't wanna let anything
get in the way of that.
- Okay. Let's make a deal.
You win, you get to
slip this little letter
under Goodwin's door.
I win, there's a
24-hour cooldown period
where you need to reconsider.
Deal?
- Yeah, deal. Yeah.
- Three, two, one, pull.
- Oh.
Cheater.
- Sore loser.
Better start reconsidering.
- It's not exactly
wedding cake,
but it is homemade.
- Thanks.
I'm way too anxious to eat.
- Yeah. Okay.
- Thank you for today.
Dr. Asher said that you were
a secret wedding planner.
- Guilty.
And it was my pleasure.
- Thank you so much
for creating that
special memory for us.
- You and your husband
have a lifetime
of memories to make together.
- My husband.
I like the sound of that.
- She's here.
- Oh, my gosh.
- I'm right here, okay?
- Dr. Abrams is
just finishing up,
but you should start
planning that honeymoon.
- Thank you.
- Hey, buddy.
How you feeling?
- I'm a fan of the Percocet.
I haven't slept that good
in weeks.
I'll enjoy it while I can.
Well, that's what I need
to talk to you about.
- Uh-oh.
- Your spleen has
been lacerated.
- That doesn't sound good.
- Could be worse.
We'll need to keep an eye
on your hemoglobin levels.
But also, your
white blood cell count is low.
So I can't in good conscience
release you back into
police custody anytime soon.
- Hmm.
So this is a bad news,
good news scenario.
- Actually,
it's a bad news, good news,
more good news scenario.
- Lynne.
- No visitors.
- Come on, man.
Let him see his kid.
- No can do.
- It's Thanksgiving.
- Make it quick.
- Hi.
Hey.
There you go. Watch his head.
Oh, he missed his dad.
- Oh, yeah.
There he is.
There's my man.
- Hey, buddy.
- Whoa.
Thank you, Rip.
This is a gift.
- Hey.
- Why do you give him flowers?
You know he doesn't deserve it.
- You wanna do it?
I miss her.
- I know.
You loved her so much.
- Yeah.
I just wish he loved us
that much.
- Kip.
I just wish you
could forgive him.
- I can't.
It's not even a choice.
I just...
I--I can't.
I'm glad I came, Catie.
- Me too.
- Hey.
Wake up.
I'm sorry.
I'm--I'm so sorry.
Ugh!
- No, no. Please wait!
Wait, please!
Wait, wait!