Previously on The Resident...
I'm Dr. AJ Austin in the flesh.
One of the most gifted
cardiothoracic surgeons
is meeting with me today.
I still plan to cut.
Why bother?
Keep Austin away
from conscious patients.
York, what did you shove
up your rectum this time?
It was the first time that...
That you had extracted
an object from the
colon of an adult male?
- Yes.
- I like working for Hunter.
She likes everyone who
works for her to be discreet.
Sorry, I didn't
mean to startle you.
I'm just delivering
your groceries.
I think someone's following me.
I'm just starting to realize
how far Lane's willing to go.
Hey!
6-5-4-U-H-V-F.
6-5-4...
U-H-V-F.
Claudia!
Claudia, wait!
Somebody, he... Get her!
Seriously? Are you...
Really? Thanks.
- And then he said...
- "No,
Bob's actually your uncle."
See, that's funny
because it's...
Never mind.
"Incoming"?
Whoa!
Oh!
Claudia?
- Get back! Get back!
- Hey! Hey!
- Stop. Claudia.
- Claudia.
- Get back! Get back.
- Claudia, let us help you.
- Hey.
- You're hallucinating.
No! Please!
Oh, my God.
Just come with us.
Claudia!
♪ ♪
- Incoming.
- Okay, let's go to Trauma One.
Major trauma, page Surgery.
It's your sis. Do you
want me to pick up?
I can't do Jessie before coffee.
Well...
I got his license plate.
And you were gonna
keep that to yourself?
- What?
- And do what?
Track him down, catch up
to him this time, kick his ass?
Oh, well, maybe you can track
him down and slash his tires,
throw a trash can
through his window.
Whatever.
How about I call the cops?
They can finally nail
this creepy son of a bitch.
Yeah, that sounds
like a good plan.
Think this is when
you go help someone
in that big, shiny hospital.
I'm fine.
She was hit by an ambulance?
Yeah, she was admitted
with a severe headache,
high temperature,
nausea, somnolence, and
she started hallucinating
- and she charged out.
- Yeah. Hip fracture
from impact with
the ambulance, and...
looks like loops of
bowel in her chest?
The impact ruptured
her diaphragm.
I'll prep for surgery.
Yeah, I'd like to pull
in Dr. Austin for this,
if you could check his schedule?
He treated you like a
child at Bradley's surgery.
He's the best thoracic
surgeon I've ever seen.
He'll probably save her life.
Dr. Nolan,
I called you a cretin
after our last
surgical experience.
Is there anything
you'd like to say to me?
Yes, there is.
Let's have a good surgery.
I love that.
Yes, let's do that.
Dr. Okafor, proceed with
the time out, s'il vous plaît.
Claudia Clare Webb.
Yes, correct.
A pair of ruptured
diaphragms, status: post-MVA,
versus pedestrian...
Well, this is a special treat.
Just here to observe.
Dr. Bell said,
"I will still cut."
I said, "Why bother?"
Dr. Bell said,
"Love, passion, discipline."
A rare opportunity
for the both of us.
- And after that,
we can take you to see her...
- Damn it, lady!
You keep giving
me the runaround.
I need you to tell me...
Sir, you need to calm down.
I need you to tell me
where I can find Claudia.
- Now. My...
- Hey. Dr. Conrad Hawkins.
- Claudia's my patient. What's your name?
- Felix.
- Are you taking me to see her?
- Soon.
Trust me, she's in good hands.
I trust nobody.
Nobody.
Now, somebody, tell me
where I can see Claudia,
or get out of my face now.
I'll take you to see her as soon
- as she's in recovery.
- I don't believe you.
I got to make sure
that Claudia's getting
the best treatment.
People like you
lie to people like
me all the time.
I need to see Claudia now!
Are you done? Are you
ready to listen to the person
who's trying to save her life?
Hmm?
So, Claudia's your mom?
She's more of a mother
to me than anyone else.
She gave me a job
when no one else would.
We have to run some tests
when she's out of surgery
and figure out what's going on.
Yeah, I know, I know, but...
She spreads herself
thin, you know?
She's got a lot
of mouths to feed.
Looks like a traumatic
splenic laceration
from the accident.
Do you need a
trauma surgeon or...?
No. Lap. Suction.
Hmm.
"Not seeing things
can be a blessing."
Someone famous said that.
August Strindberg.
Ah, look at the
big brain on Albert.
But that quote doesn't
really apply in surgery.
Seeing is saving.
Wouldn't you agree, Dr. Bell?
Dr. Bell?
Well, I've never met a
bleeder I couldn't catch.
All right, Captain,
I think it's my turn.
Stay where you are, keep
your quotes to yourself.
2-0 silk.
Imagine you can
handle it from here.
Nice.
Yes, Officer, the guy
has been following me,
he confronted me at my house.
I just... I don't feel safe.
Okay. You'll look into it when?
Thanks.
For nothing.
- Allie, listen.
- What are you doing here?
Look, I'm worried Lane's
gonna hurt someone else.
I just need Lily's
original blood work.
- I know you're scared...
- Uh, yes.
I'm scared.
I have a child, bills.
If I lose this job...
I can't lose this job.
Stay away from me.
All right, the
surgery went well.
- Toxicology results?
- Negative.
- No drugs, no alcohol.
- Well, we still have
to figure out
what's causing
her erratic behavior.
Sounds like
bacterial meningitis.
She needs a spinal tap.
Start her on empiric
antibiotics after that.
Ah, Pravesh.
Your favorite frequent
flyer just arrived.
Go.
No, no, no, no. No, no, no.
Don't tell me he put another
condiment in his colon!
It's nice to see
you again, York.
- And this must be...
- My beloved mother, Yvonne.
Yorkie has told me so
much about Chastain.
Thank you for your care of him.
Don't mention it.
I have the same
problem, you know.
A day without asthma
is a day I long for.
Well,
we are so glad
that we could help.
With his asthma.
And Conrad is where?
Urgent case.
So, Ms. Evans, what
brings you in today?
Well, I took a tumble.
Yorkie and I were out for a
walk on the BeltLine, and...
Can we stop for a second?
Do you have any
heart-related issues?
Mm, no, not that I know of.
- Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- It hurts, yeah.
I'm gonna order an
echocardiogram and expedite
an X-ray on your foot, okay?
- Fine by me.
- All right.
Wait.
- Wait, where you going?
- Just one sec.
My mother is my entire
life. Do you understand?
She seems like a
very sweet lady, York.
She is a bulldog.
My dad left us.
Did she wallow in self-pity? No.
She grabbed life by the balls.
Kung fu grip,
- started squeezing...
- Okay.
Just try not to worry, York.
I assure you, she is going
to get the very best care.
She better.
♪ ♪
Jessie?
- I screwed up, Nicky.
- Look at me, what did you take?
I tried to call you,
I tried to call you.
Oxy?
- Yeah. I'm...
- Okay.
- I'm sorry.
- Hold on, okay?
911. What's your emergency?
Oxy overdose, 79 Fairview Drive.
I have Narcan.
I'm giving it to her now.
Stay with me, Jessie.
Come here.
Come on.
Come on, come on, come on.
Come on, come on.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I never
want to do this to you again.
I don't care. I don't care
about that, Jess, okay?
- Let's just get you better.
- Trauma Bay Two.
- What's going on?
- My sister. She OD'd on oxy.
- I gave her two doses of Narcan.
- You had it around?
After the last time, I had to.
Just keep an eye on her, okay?
You know I will.
Vitals, full blood work, EKG.
Let's have Narcan standing by.
I want updates every five
minutes. Keep this one quiet.
Of course.
I told her to call
me before she...
I didn't pick up earlier. I
should have answered.
She's here now. She's safe.
- She could have died.
- Do not do this to yourself.
I should've picked
up the phone. I...
Any word on
Claudia's blood test?
Elevated white count,
otherwise normal.
We'll need more tests to
figure out what's going on.
My head's killing me!
- My head is killing me!
- Look at me. Deep breaths.
Deep breaths, Claudia. Claudia.
Tell me what's wrong
with me, please.
- Stay focused. Shh...
- What's going on? What do we got?
Her head CT was normal, but with
these symptoms, I think we need a repeat.
Claudia.
We're gonna get you
something for the pain.
Claudia's visitor,
Felix, in a gang.
Last time one of their
members showed up,
a rival tried to take him
out, this place was chaos.
She's also uninsured,
so we have to diagnose and
treat Claudia before Bell turfs her.
Huh.
Excuse me, Doctor. I'm
looking for Claudia Webb.
- She's in recovery right
now and can't be seen. Yo!
Felix.
Go back to the waiting area.
- Hell no. He's cool.
- Wait, who's cool?
This cat right here.
- Thanks for coming.
- How are you?
Man, I'm freaking out,
man. I still haven't seen her.
Do Claudia proud,
keep it together.
For her, okay?
I used to arrest this
guy every six months
until Claudia took him in.
Felix is one of many ex-cons
she's hired at her
catering company.
Claudia's an important
part of the Atlanta PD family.
- Take special care of her.
- Don't worry.
I got your word on that, homie?
Yeah, you got my word.
Appreciate it.
Come on.
Thank you for coming.
You have a fifth metatarsal
fracture in your foot.
But the good news
is it's-it's nonsurgical.
Oh!
Yeah, but that
echocardiogram is not so good.
Let's keep this train moving.
Ms. Evans, your aortic valve
has calcified and thickened,
resulting in critical
aortic stenosis.
It's in urgent need
of replacement.
How urgent?
D-Does it require
general anesthesia?
It does.
A close friend of
mine went under
and when he woke,
he was a different man.
He couldn't even
recognize his own family.
Yeah, she's right.
General anesthesia can trigger
dementia in the Cocoon crowd.
Now, there is another option.
It's, uh, nonsurgical.
- You interested?
- Yes.
Don't have the surgery and die.
Hey. You... watch it, buddy.
Dr. Austin is just being
honest, but I would rather die
than go through life being
demented and confused.
- Mom!
- I still got to go
to my belly dancing classes.
I like this lady. Pravesh.
- Hallway, sidebar, now.
- York.
Emergency, sorry, bye.
It's Claudia.
She started seizing and
her sats are dropping.
Let's get her to the ICU.
Push two of lorazepam
and prep a gram of
phenytoin on standby.
Okay, ready?
Let's go. One...
two... three.
- Not now.
- Easy. I come in peace.
I-I heard about
your sister. I'm sorry.
- I trust she's doing better?
- Yeah.
I have a troubled loved
one in my family as well.
Believe me, I understand
what you're going through.
He's doing great now.
He was part of the
program over at Crossroads.
Hasn't had a relapse
since. Four years clean.
If you'd like,
I can help get Jessie into
the program free of charge.
Are you crazy?
You are the last person I
want help from right now.
Why don't you let me
take care of my family.
Hmm.
What's wrong with me?
The seizures have
been continuing
and we're trying
to figure out why.
I have so many people,
they're like family to me.
- They depend on me.
- I know. I've met some of them.
I don't know what
happens to everyone
if I'm not okay, you know?
Look who it is.
You look great.
You're gonna be okay.
I know.
Whatever happens...
look how far you've come.
I am so proud of you.
Don't talk like that.
Everything's gonna be fine.
I love you. We all love you.
I know you do.
Dr. Austin, where are you going?
To see a movie. I Feel Pretty.
Centers on an ordinary woman
who struggles with feelings
of inadequacy and
insecurity on a daily basis.
Amy Schumer. She makes me laugh.
What do you want?
I wasn't comfortable
mentioning this earlier,
but I can do a transcatheter
aortic valve replacement.
So Yvonne can have
moderate sedation.
- I need an attending.
- I'm not really a fan
of awake surgeries.
A risk we have to
take. You in or out?
Great.
I already bought my damn ticket!
Are those Claudia's CSF results?
Negative for
bacterial meningitis.
So we're still nowhere
closer to figuring out
- what's wrong with her.
- We're looking for a zebra.
- But we've run every test.
- Yeah, now you know the drill.
You talk.
- To whom?
- Felix, Mambo, and Raq.
Figure out everything
about Claudia.
Habits, hobbies, favorite food.
Hope we get closer
to a diagnosis.
Awake? What do you mean awake?
Awake, meaning not sleep...
Don't you do that.
It just... scares me.
- When I had surgery...
- Surgery?
For what, Yorkie?
Mom, it wasn't a big deal.
- Is it safe?
- Yes. And just regional anesthesia.
- I'm in.
- Mama.
I'm in.
But you listen to
me, mister man.
I'm sure you are
God's gift to medicine,
but you mind your
Ps and Qs in the OR.
If I hear anything
to the contrary,
I will wield my pen like a
mighty sword. Ask Pravesh.
I was thinking about something
else when you were talking.
But don't bother repeating
it. I really don't care.
I am going to save
your mother's life.
You're welcome.
So you've got the valve issue,
asthma, varicose veins,
a recent cataract surgery.
Any other medical history
we should know about?
- Nope, that is everything.
- Uh...
Yorkie, honey, give us a minute.
- But we don't have secrets,
Mother.
- No, no, honey.
I... Just one moment, sweetie.
Okay?
Close the door.
I have, um...
the little "C."
The little "C"?
You mean big "C."
- Cancer.
- No. Chlamydia.
We call it the little "C" in
my retirement community.
Yeah, you do.
She likes European movies.
- At least I can tell you
that much.
- European movies...
Mambo, not European movies,
she hates European movies.
- She loves the outdoors.
- She does.
- She does like the outdoors.
- She loves music.
It doesn't matter
what kind of music.
As long as she can groove to it,
- she digs it.
- Loves food.
Oh, she loves to cook...
- The Hot Pocket things, the...
- The little Hot Pocket things.
- She cooks a good meatloaf.
- She likes hiking, biking.
She's at the water
park, she's always in...
she was in the
water the whole day...
- Yeah.
- It was nice. I mean, we do it every year.
Wait.
Wait, back up. What
did you just say?
Uh, we did an event
for the Boys & Girls Club.
- I know, but, uh...
- We-we always do
an event for them.
Wh-Where was it, again?
- It was, uh, Running Rapids.
- Running Rapids.
- Yeah, yeah, Running Rapids.
- Right?
- Yeah.
- Yo, why are you asking
all these questions?
Did Claudia get in the water?
- Yeah, man, lazy river.
- Obviously.
- Slides.
- You know what,
uh, I'll be right back.
Hey! Yo! I got it!
Conrad, I got it.
Get this.
Claudia was at Running Rapids.
- Warm, stagnant water.
- So what are we thinking?
Naegleria fowleri.
98% fatal. I don't
like those odds.
Yeah, but the signs
and the symptoms,
they-they-they all line up.
The CSF didn't show an amoeba.
Because it was Gram
stained. I took a seminar
on brain-eating
amoebas in med school.
If they don't use
the Wright-Giemsa,
it's almost
impossible to detect it.
Tell the lab to rerun
the held sample
with the Wright-Giemsa. Now.
You need anything?
Yes, go to work. I know
you got a million things to do.
We're good.
Nice to see you two
are happening again.
Nothing's happening again.
Well, it should be.
- Nice to have you back, Jess.
- Conrad.
When's the last time
you had a simple carb?
It's been a minute.
Eight months clean.
Happiest I've been in forever.
Just like that, I
threw it all away.
Saddest part is, I
can't even tell you why.
It happened. It's done.
Now I just need to get you
into a treatment program.
Too expensive.
I'll do outpatient again.
I'll go to meetings.
No, Jess, we got to get
you better for good this time.
Whatever it takes.
I'm such a liability.
Thank you. Let me talk to her.
You've saved me
so many times, Nicky.
I can't keep doing this.
- You don't deserve this.
- I'm not going anywhere.
And don't you dare call
yourself a liability again.
We all have our demons.
You never judged me for mine.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
I really do think you might need
to make Conrad some pasta.
He won't eat it.
Dr. Okafor.
- What are you doing here?
- Well, one of your patients
made it into my space, so
now I'm coming into yours.
- York.
- He's very insistent.
He also writes medical reviews
on every major
website known to man.
An awake surgery on his
mother with the Raptor?
Whose grand idea was that?
Well, now you'll have to
control his uncontrollable mouth.
Isn't that your expertise?
It's way below my pay grade.
You put this plan into motion.
This surgery falls on your head.
I'm sorry. I don't get it.
What are we doing here?
I'm the patient, wide
awake on the table.
I'm trying to prevent
you from giving Yvonne
a heart attack during
surgery. This isn't about me.
Well, this certainly
isn't about me.
Is that what you thought
was-was happening here?
You were gonna train me?
You're gonna groom
me, huh? Come on, girl.
I don't want this
old lady to die
because you can't
keep your mouth shut.
Maybe this will help you
understand me better.
My daddy looks like Chow Yun-Fat
and my mother is the
spitting image of Mary J. Blige.
Now, you're probably
thinking at least one of them
served in the armed
forces, right? Wrong.
They met at Vassar.
A decade later they
adopted my left-for-dead ass.
They were fantastic parents.
My childhood was
amazing, but guess what.
That didn't matter 'cause
I was still mad as hell
because the people
who actually made me
tossed me away like trash.
That's all I ever thought about.
Why are you telling me this?
Because I was just
like you, princess.
Closed off, tied and,
and twisted all up inside,
until I learned to use
that emotion as fuel.
See, you think my
behavior is a weakness. No.
It's my superpower.
I walk into the OR with nothing
but a clear mind
and steady hands.
The only thing that stands
between life and death in an OR
are these, and the very thing
that you were trying
to breed out of me
is why mine are better
than anyone else's.
Now...
you tell me something
real and make me believe it.
I...
do not need your superpower.
Then you will make
a great surgeon.
But you will never
be the best surgeon.
That's too damn bad.
Whoa. There it was.
Naegleria fowleri confirmed.
Brain-eating amoeba.
So we administer miltefosine.
Spoken like a true rookie.
It's the only
chance for a patient
with primary amebic
meningoencephalitis to survive.
It's also incredibly expensive
with a short shelf life.
So I'll give you one guess
who doesn't stock this drug.
Chastain.
And Claudia doesn't have the
money for a drug we don't have.
Okay, so we fix this.
I mean, there's got to be
something that we could...
Yeah. Yeah, there is.
We need the Glacial Sun.
That's for inducing hypothermia
in cardiac arrest patients.
If we can lower her
body temperature
to below what the
amoeba can survive
and administer the miltefosine,
we might have a shot.
We also might
freeze her to death.
It's possible. Call the CDC,
and then call whoever
the CDC tells you to call
and do not stop until you
get a dose of miltefosine.
What do we do about the money?
We do whatever it
takes. And keep this quiet.
We don't want this
popping up on Bell's radar.
- Hello?
- Hey, uh,
I've been thinking
about what you said.
Nic, if it's true,
I couldn't live with myself.
Can you meet me at
the clinic at 4:00 a.m.,
before the staff arrives?
Of course.
And listen, Allie, I
know this is hard,
but it's the right thing to do.
You don't deserve
to go down with her.
I will get you Lily's files.
Okay, see you then. Thank you.
Gotta go, bye.
Ms. Evans, would you
care for some music?
Yes. How nice. Tom Jones?
I love Tom Jones.
Dr. Okafor, time out, please.
- Yvonne Aurora Evans.
- Correct.
- Actually, that's "Aurr-rrora."
- Dr. Chu.
You got to roll the middle "R."
It's Spanish.
- I'm not Spanish,
but my mother loved...
- Date of birth.
April 4, 1942.
My boyfriend thinks
I was born in '47.
He was born in '45,
but you know men.
They prefer younger women.
Am I gonna feel much? I mean,
I know I'm not gonna feel pain,
- but...
- You know what you are going
to feel, Ms. Evans?
♪ She's a lady... ♪
As good as new, when
this surgery is complete.
How does that sound?
That sounds wonderful.
Just wonderful.
♪ That little lady ♪
♪ And the lady is mine. ♪
Were you aiming at something?
Sorry, I'm just-just frustrated.
Claudia was
diagnosed with P.A.M.
I know. I heard.
And the CDC sent me to
the only company in the U.S.
that supplies miltefosine.
They're in Florida and
of course they're closed.
I've been calling the
owner's cell phone
and I keep getting
his voice mail.
She's gonna die, man.
I'm sorry, am I boring you
with this devastating news?
It's late; he's sleeping.
Yeah, awesome.
Super helpful. Thanks.
What's the number?
We'll tag-team him
until we get him,
even if it takes all night.
Oh, I remember visiting
my grandmother in the '60s.
It was awful.
I never imagined I'd be one
for a retirement communities.
Oh, I remember...
But these days,
they're like mini resorts.
Mmm, I couldn't imagine
I'd be one for a
retirement community.
Is everything okay?
Ms. Evans, best to stay quiet
as we thread the
catheter through.
Okey-dokey.
♪ I'll be your comfort ♪
♪ And you can meet my needs ♪
♪ First-class mystery ♪
♪ And you've been
giving this for free ♪
♪ It's atypical ♪
♪ What you've been doing to me ♪
♪ Now I see you are ♪
♪ Some kind of miracle. ♪
This is Kevin.
Kevin? It's you.
It's Dr. Devon Pravesh,
Chastain Park, Atlanta.
We left you, like...
39 messages, yeah.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
It's just urgent.
I have a patient with primary
amebic meningoencephalitis,
and we need miltefosine
as soon as possible.
Patient insured?
No.
It's $48,000.
It's not a problem.
How fast can you get it here?
Uh, the time it takes me to
pull on my pants and drive there.
I'll see you in
about four hours.
We need a lot of money.
From where?
48 Gs?
Yes.
- Brain-eating amoeba?
- Unfortunately.
So, we get this money for
Claudia and she'll be good?
It gives us a fighting
chance to save her life.
Yes.
But there could be
some permanent damage.
We'll get the money.
Yeah.
Good luck.
♪ Oh, whoa, whoa, she's a lady ♪
♪ Talking about... ♪
Sorry, I'm sorry. OR 3 ran over.
This one's a doozy, huh?
My gram-gram had chlamydia.
- Uh, Jess.
- And I think... Hey, Chu.
Yeah, estrogen and, uh, Viagra,
they're helping gomers
hump like rabbits.
The patient's awake.
Are you blind,
illiterate, or both?
The sign on the window says,
"Awake surgery in progress."
- She made a mistake. Move on.
- You giving orders now?
I'm giving advice.
I don't feel well.
What's happening?
Abnormal rhythm.
- What's happening to...? Oh!
- Put her under.
You sure?
I said put her under.
Geez, this looks like my
eighth grade science project.
If she dies, it's on me.
My call, my ass.
So do me a favor, relax.
So, lowering Claudia's body
temp freezes the amoeba?
It slows its progress,
which hopefully can limit
the damage to her brain, it's...
It'll buy us time until
the miltefosine arrives.
Get me that miltefosine.
We can't keep her cold for long.
Pads. We need to cardiovert her.
Push diltiazem.
♪ She knows just what to do... ♪
Get Dr. Nolan in here.
Why? He's a trauma surgeon.
I have my reasons.
Clear.
Sinus rhythm.
We do not need a trauma
surgeon when there is no trauma.
I'm here. What's going
on? What do we got?
♪ And the lady is mine... ♪
Is this Tom Jones?
You know this is Tom Jones.
Uh, a-am I needed
for this surgery?
No, you are not needed
for this surgery, Dr. Nolan,
but your colleagues
need to lay eyes on
someone who gets it,
someone who listens, who
learns and who understands...
What it's like to let your
emotions get the best of you?
Just shut your mouth.
This is unfortunate.
I believe it was Nietzsche
who said that many
are stubborn in...
You've served your
purpose. Now get out.
♪ Whoa-whoa-whoa, she's a lady ♪
♪ Yeah-yeah-yeah,
she's a lady. ♪
Oh, man, thank you. Thank you.
Thanks.
♪ Uh, yeah ♪
♪ You don't want this
problem, uh, yeah ♪
♪ It's whatever you want ♪
♪ You see that Benz ride slow? ♪
♪ That's me on
the hunt, I'm a jerk ♪
♪ Might creep with
your girl in the front ♪
♪ Just so you know... ♪
Hey, how's Jessie?
- She's better.
- Huh.
Uh, what exactly
is going on here?
Fund-raiser.
Reformed criminals
doing a legal drug deal
with more cash
than I've ever seen.
While my sister is
detoxing from legal drugs
bought illegally.
Hey, you.
Uh, look, Mambo, this...
Ooh... Uh, yep.
- Nurse Nevin, right?
- Yeah.
Yeah, you took care of my
Uncle Deebo a few years back.
Deebo. Oh, I love him.
- He's a big teddy bear.
- Yeah.
He always would brag about
how good you were to him.
I think he had a little
crush, to tell you the truth.
Oh, how's he doing?
He's dead as hell.
Well, diabetes
finally took him out.
- Sorry.
- Yeah.
But, anyway, I
never got a chance
to say thank you in person.
- Hey, just doing my job.
- Yeah?
Well, you ever need
me to return the favor,
you just holler.
Hey, Mambo.
Actually, there...
there is a situation I
could use a little help with.
You are quickly becoming a
lost cause to me, Dr. Okafor.
Your behavior in the OR...
In general... is unacceptable.
Well, I inspire and
transform those around me
in order to breed the best.
I do not compromise.
- You're delusional.
- Yeah?
Well, when you win a
three-peat JAMA publication
and an ASA Medallion in
the same year, then, maybe,
I'll consider your diagnosis.
But until then, if
you're in my OR,
you either exit or evolve.
That's funny.
I didn't peg you for a doctor
who cared about accolades.
Well, I do.
I am who I am.
That will never change.
What's up, man?
Can I help you with something?
Yeah. My little sister Nic
wanted me to return the favor.
Thanks for coming
all this way, Kevin.
Ah, it wasn't so bad.
I once drove to Kentucky
to deliver a dose.
Did that patient make it?
Ah, afraid not.
Never would have imagined
a pharma CEO to
hand-deliver medication.
Yeah.
Well, I worked in Big
Pharma for 20 years.
Couldn't take it anymore.
Believe it or not, I put
people before profit.
Wait, so you only
supply miltefosine?
Big Pharma refuses.
Not enough people
contract Naegleria.
No patients, no money.
How do you profit?
I don't. 48 grand a pop's
what I need to keep the
lights on and the drug stocked.
Speaking of which, my daughter
is getting married tomorrow.
I should probably
get back on the road.
Uh, who should I, uh... invoice?
Yeah, uh...
Hey, pay that man his...
- Uh...
- So you're the guy?
Drove all the way from Florida
to deliver Claudia's medicine?
It's all there.
For your records.
- No records.
Thank you, Kevin.
I really hope this trip
was worth it for you.
It certainly will be
if Claudia survives.
Let me know, okay?
Will do.
You've reached Allie.
Please leave a message.
Hi, Allie, it's Nic.
I'm pulling up now.
Allie?
- Tell me about this man
that you're very close to.
- No.
- You met him.
- Oh, there he is.
Bring it in for the real thing.
Oh.
- All right, big guy.
- Thank you.
- You're all right by me.
- Thank you, York.
Now, let's get you
guys home, yeah?
- Yeah.
- All right.
- Just get my flowers,
don't forget.
- Yeah.
It's clear you've chosen the
right profession, young man.
Thank you.
Yorkie, why is there a
syrup bottle up your butt?
You pulled up
the wrong "Y. Evans."
I'm so sorry.
It's okay.
I have chlamydia.
Those... look...
good.
How we feeling?
Can you tell us your name?
Yo, Felix.
Hey, what's up?
What?
Oh, what's up?
She okay?
She's awake?
This one's all you.
Yeah.
She's awake.
And she's okay.
In fact, she's doing great.
And she can't wait
to see all you guys.
Hey, man.
You did good, man.
You did real good.
Oh!
I love you, D.
Oh, God.
Man, not again.
You know, only four
people in the U.S. have
ever survived Naegleria fowleri.
You just saved the fifth.
It would not have been
great if you'd frozen Claudia
to death, but you didn't.
No, today you gambled
on unorthodox
medicine and you won.
Had you not won...
you'd be walking
out of this hospital
for the last time,
to join the ranks
of the unemployed
along with Nurse Nevin.
This is my hospital.
It's not your casino.
Enjoy your drinks.
Ah.
Wait, wait.
What just... what just happened?
He said you're amazing.
And he can fire you
whenever he wants.
Hello.
They set me up.
Who set you up?
Where are you?
Atlanta Detention Center.
I'm on my way.
No, Conrad, listen to me.
There's nothing you
can do for me right now.
There's something
else I need help with.
There you are.
I was just about to call you.
I tried Nic, like,
a hundred times.
She's not answering.
Where you going, Jessie?
Inman Park. Gonna
meet up with some friends,
just clear my head.
It'll be good for me.
Thanks for everything yesterday.
Sit down, Jessie.
Yeah, I'm good.
Did Nic send you?
Is that why she's not
answering my calls?
You know, I don't
need this right now.
And I've been discharged.
Dr. Whatever said I could go.
Uh, Nic got you a
place at Crossroads;
it's a three-week program.
- Crossroads.
- Mm-hmm.
Nice.
See, this is what happens.
People make
decisions about my life,
- and that's not okay.
- We'll do this together.
Yeah, I said I'll do
the outpatient stuff,
I'll go to meetings...
You tried it last time,
and it didn't work.
I'm leaving.
Move, Conrad.
You almost died last night.
Would you have come
to my funeral if I did?
You care now?
We're family?
Please.
You're still just
passing through.
Well, I'm here right now, and
I'm not leaving without you.
Where the hell is my sister?
Your sister's going through
a hard time right now...
- Is she okay?
- She will be.
Your sister loves you very much.
She loves more than anything.
If you don't want to do
it for you, do it for her.
I wasn't always the
one screwing up.
Oh.
I guess you don't know Nic
as well as you think you do.
I'll be waiting outside.
We'll leave when you're ready.
♪ There's no need ♪
♪ To argue anymore ♪
♪ I gave all I could ♪
♪ But it left me ♪
♪ So sore ♪
♪ There's no need ♪
♪ To argue ♪
♪ No need to argue anymore ♪
♪ There's no need ♪
♪ To argue anymore. ♪
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH