Previously on
"Grey's Anatomy"...
- Ollie.
- Hi, Richard.
You got me sober, Ollie.
You walked me through it,
and I'm gonna walk you
through this.
I have my polymer,
and I have your science.
The mini livers will be known
as the Cerone method.
♪ Hello, good morning, how ya doing? ♪
Life doesn't owe us a thing.
It just is.
♪ OJ with a champagne tune up ♪
♪ Hell yeah, it's a new hallelujah ♪
♪ Popping like the top off a bottle ♪
♪ And I ain't stopping, yeah ♪
♪ Baby, it's a brand-new day ♪
♪ Ain't no clouds hanging over me ♪
♪ Something doesn't feel the same ♪
♪ The rest of my life gonna start today ♪
♪ Good morning ♪
♪ Na-na-na-na-na ♪
Like a river,
it goes where it goes.
♪ Calling out the ocean,
this is evolution, can I ♪
♪ Grow into another animal?
A next level ♪
♪ I'm spreading wings
- ♪ and I just wanna sing ♪
- I got a present for you.
What?
A present? What for?
♪ In the future,
now the past can't harm me ♪
♪ Forget about yesterday,
Paul McCartney ♪ - Oh, my God.
- ♪ I'm feeling like a Beatle on stage ♪
- What is this?
♪ And the whole wide world's
gonna know my name ♪
- Baby, it's a brand-new day
- It's for your...
your heart pills,
your statins, all that.
Now you can take them anywhere
and no one needs to know.
♪ The rest of my life gonna start today ♪
♪ Good morning ♪
♪ Na-na-na-na-na ♪
- ♪ Na-na-na-na-na ♪
- You can try
- ♪ The rest of my life gonna start today ♪
- to fight against the current...
♪ Ladies and gentlemen,
this part right here is very simple ♪
♪ It goes like this ♪
- ♪ I've been up ♪
- ♪ Been up ♪
- I've been down
- Been down
♪ But I got the feeling right now ♪
- ♪ 've been up ♪
- ♪ Been up ♪
Or you can learn to ride it.>
♪ But I got the feeling right now ♪
♪ Na-na-na-na-na ♪
As surgeons,
we dedicate ourselves
to an endless fight
against the current.
Jimi Hendrix died.
No!
That happened
kind of a while ago.
No, Jimi Hendrix
is a liverless mouse.
Hmm. I thought
he was a guitar genius.
We're trying the seven different
polymers that I found
to see if any of them can be
used instead of Cerone's.
And we named the mice.
It's easier than numbers.
And now Jimi Hendrix is dead
and Elvis is...
Has left the building.
Anyway, Hellmouth is watching them
now.
You have the next shift. I mean,
we really have to come up with something
- if we're gonna...
- Beat Marie Cerone!
No. Save lives!
If we're going to save lives,
Wilson.
You can't give up that easily.
It's been four days.
You can call her.
It isn't easy, and Teddy doesn't
want to hear from me.
Can't you just trust
my judgment on this?
What are you...
No, no, no, no, no!
Dr. Altman!
Amelia Shepherd,
did I catch you at a good...
Great.
So I'm standing here
with Owen and...
Uh-huh.
Totally. I would just like to add...
Yeah, good talking to you.
- Yeah, that's not happening. Sorry.
- Hmm.
Hey! Oh, my God,
I never got to ask you
- how it went with Teddy.
- It went great!
Well, at least it didn't go badly.
Okay.
I'm gonna let the ER know.
Hey, lookin' good, Warren!
- Feelin' good, Dr. Webber!
- Uh-huh.
67-year-old female,
collapsed at an AA meeting.
We bagged her,
got her breathing again.
Then discovered her DNR bracelet.
- Uh-oh.
- Yeah, she was not happy.
Anyway, she asked for you...
said you were her personal physician.
Hey, Richard, don't worry,
I haven't been drinking.
Cross my heart and
hope to die.
Ollie?
So, just to be clear, these
ultrasound waves,
they go right through the skull
and everything?
You don't cut him open
at all?
Exactly, right.
The waves meet directly on
Noah's tumor.
All the energy is focused there.
Imagine it
like using a magnifying glass
to burn a hole in a leaf.
Okay. And the risk?
I mean, I know
I keep asking, but...
Well, there's always a risk,
but since
the procedure's
completely non-invasive...
It's very dangerous.
It's difficult to control
the heat that is generated,
so the procedure is
slow and risky.
But it's also
his one real chance.
In the next few weeks,
the laughing fits are
going to increase
as the tumor presses
against his brain stem.
In better news,
we are excellent at what we do.
And we want this to work
almost as badly as you do.
That was harsh.
And I was thinking
it wasn't harsh enough.
I didn't tell her that her son
is basically a guinea pig.
Well, I'm gonna tell
Kimmie it's on.
- Don't oversell it!
- Wait, is that a yes?
- We're on.
- Okay, you know, important decision...
what are we calling this?
I'm thinking
"The Koracick Method,
featuring Amelia Shepherd."
You're distastefully cheerful.
Uh, because
this is the frontier!
I could scoop out brain tumors
like I'm balling melons,
which is my second favorite
kind of balling.
Look, we're so far out
on the edge of medicine,
no one's ever been there
before.
Aren't you... pumped?
This is like crack for you.
Or... melon balling for me.
Wait, where's, uh,
Bello and Blandrew? I gotta...
So, this is good news?
It's amazing news.
I mean, look, I-I don't want to
get anyone's hopes up too high,
but this procedure today
is a really big step
towards getting Kimmie back out
there and singing her face off.
Won't I just be back in here
in nine months with a new tumor?
I mean,
it's not a cure, right?
You know what, let's take this
one step at a time, Kimmie.
I'm... I'm so sick
of hospitals.
I just want to go back to
school, see my friends.
Do the spring musical.
Oh, sweetie.
Kimmie, I need you to...
Did I tell you
my friend invited me
to go with her family
to New York this summer?
They're getting
"Dear Evan Hansen" tickets.
I mean, maybe
I could last that long...
Isn't this below your pay grade?
I hope you're not
giving me special treatment
because I'm your sponsor.
Okay, here's the deal...
my liver has survived much
longer than it ever should have.
There are multiple options
for combating liver failure.
Did you see
my nice fat ankles, Richard?
And my lovely ghostlike
complexion?
Surely you heard it in my heart.
I have cardiomyopathy.
My dying liver is killing
my heart
and my heart is killing me.
I have reached
my expiration date.
When did you decide on
the DNR?
Eight months ago,
along with an advance directive.
- No intervention.
- Eight months!
We talk three times a week.
Sometimes three times a day!
How could you not tell me this?
I wanted to,
many times.
But you know
how this works...
something goes bad for you,
you call me.
Something goes bad for me
and I call my sponsor.
And here I thought
we were friends.
Give me a break.
You're acting
like a pouting teenager.
We're more than friends,
Richard.
I...
I didn't know how to sponsor you
through my death.
Good news...
you're not gonna have to.
Because I'm not gonna
let you die.
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 14   Episode 18
Episode Title: "Hold Back The River"
Maintenance
to 4 West nurses' station.
Peggy, Dayna, hi!
Oh, hey, Dr. Robbins. Hi.
Hey, what's going on?
Is the baby okay?
Oh, yeah, she's fine.
That one, not so much.
Oh, I'm a mess.
Peggy was driving and Dayna...
She puked all over me.
Like power-puked.
And then I swerved and...
You hit a tree
at 30 miles an hour.
All the airbags went off
except for Dayna's.
Ouch.
Did you hit your head?
No. My ribs feel a little sore.
It's okay.
It's very common to have
a release of emotion
after an accident.
Especially once the body knows
it's out of harm's way.
"Out of harm's way."
Babe.
I have stage 2 breast cancer
and I just had
my second round of chemo.
That's why I got sick.
So, the harm is most definitely
still in the way.
Uh, yes.
Uh, are you sure
this is your stop?
Well, maybe not.
Maybe not, huh?
Sorry I haven't been able to get free.
Harriet's, uh, teething
and, you know, April's still...
Please do not apologize
for taking care of the people you love.
Thank you very much.
Okay.
Have you talked to her yet?
I'm gonna try again today.
Koracick.
April. Please, we had sex.
Call me Dr. Koracick.
Um... Um, can I talk to you?
I'm... I need to say something to you,
and it is not easy for me.
Oh. Well, l-let's make it easy.
Just picture me naked.
Tom, I, um... what I was trying to say
is that I was horrible to you.
And you were kind, and you were
vulnerable and I was...
Just using me for sex?
Yes, I was just using you
for sex. And I am sorry.
I am sorry for that.
Look, no. I love being used
for sex, Dr. Kepner.
You can use me for sex,
uh, any time you...
No, I didn't... I... No.
Oh, you... you made up with God?
Well, for whatever it's worth,
uh, I'm almost certain
God approves of you
using me for sex.
I don't know why I'm so upset.
Dr. Hanson told me
I'd be nauseous.
Remember what else
Dr. Hanson said...
stay positive, because
you're gonna get through it.
He promised.
Promised, did he?
Yeah, he has
the proof to back it up.
His success rates are
amazing.
He cured my friend Lucille
without surgery.
You must know him...
Dr. Scott Hanson... Ow!
- Sore there?
- Ohh.
Uh, afraid I don't know him.
Oh, my God, you need to be
sending people to him!
He sounds amazing.
Let's get Dayna up for a CT.
And, Peggy, we have a waiting room
for you to relax
with the baby, okay?
Okay.
If I ever hear you
use the word "cure"
and "promise" when
speaking with a cancer patient,
your medical career will be
as short as you are.
- Yes, sir.
- Call Dr. Hanson's office,
get me her medical records,
okay?
So we monitor from
inside the room with him?
- Mm-hmm.
- This is so cool.
We're at the edge of
the cutting edge.
And hopefully we don't
melt Noah's brain stem.
This is exciting.
It's incredibly exciting.
It's why we do this, right?
Come on! You...
You know I love doing that, too.
"Important" isn't quite
a big enough word.
But, I mean, normally,
I would take care of this personally,
but, uh...
she's more like family to me.
- We get it.
- Of course.
Hey, you!
Yeah, you, the old one.
Get in here.
Uh, give me a minute, will you?
Uh, how you feeling?
I need your advice
on something.
When your physician
refuses to honor your request
for "no medical intervention,"
what's the protocol?
Do I ask to speak to
his superior?
Well, I'm married to
the head of the hospital.
And I mentored the chief,
so good luck with that.
Okay, so I guess I'll have to
resort to more extreme measures.
Mm-hmm.
And what might those be?
How does "recovering drunk"
go over in the medical community?
Good?
Because I will
break your anonymity
to any doctor
you send in here.
Uh, this is Dr. Meredith Grey,
and this is Dr. Maggie Pierce.
- So nice to meet you.
- The famous Meredith and Maggie.
I can't tell you what it means
to meet you both.
I've asked them both
to come up with
every possible option
to take care of you.
And like you,
I trust and respect
these two women completely.
So, anything you have
to share with them,
you have my complete blessing.
Are those sound wave readouts?
They're microphones
inside the helmet
listening for popping sounds.
What would popping sounds
mean?
They would mean that
his brain is boiling.
It's getting hotter. Hold off.
- How long?
- Until it stops getting hotter!
Okay, we're getting awfully
close to a cavitation event.
If we go much longer,
he will develop hyperemia.
Yeah, but if we don't separate
the tumor from the brain stem,
- he may never wake up again.
- Well, what... what should we...
Stop! Stop! It's too hot!
Okay.
All right, th-there's nowhere
for the h-heat to disperse.
This... This could take a while.
Schmitt, when I ask you
to get Dayna's medical records,
it means come back
with her medical records!
I'm not sure what to do.
They just said
- they couldn't release them...
- Just... Just call... call again,
and make sure
they know it's emergent,
and also make sure
they know it's Grey-Sloan.
Ah.
Don't take it out
on the poor interns, Owen.
- Wait, what?
- I talked to Teddy.
Look at this scan.
I can't believe you.
What were you thinking?
You double dipped within 24 hours of...
- Would you just look, please?!
- Ugh!
There's no broken ribs,
and I don't see any internal injuries.
What else don't you see?
Wait, what?
Exactly.
Well, show me
the sagittal views.
Now, I will bet my license
this woman does not have cancer.
You know, when a person's
been sober a long time,
and they lose their sponsor,
it's hard...
it's hard to get a new one.
It's hard on the ego
to even have to ask.
And recovering drunks, as a rule,
we're not all that fond of change.
But Richard will need a new sponsor.
Let's not get ahead of ourselves.
All right, we still have
a few more tests to run.
Don't give up hope just yet.
Oh, honey, I'm all hope.
Hope of moving out of this old,
broken shell of a body,
into whatever comes next.
Hope of feeling like I did
when I first got sober.
"Happy, joyous, and free."
I don't need hope.
I need acceptance.
From Richard.
I need to know that
he's gonna get through this
without a bottle.
Can you work that up for me?
Dr. Midvad to Cardiology.
Owen.
Hey. I saw you admitted
my rule-out appy...
I'm sorry.
Why? What happened?
I, um...
Owen, I want to apologize
for my behavior lately.
At trauma cert day,
and actually a lot of days.
I was, uh... I was going through a thing.
And I-I'm really sorry
that I worried you.
Hmm.
Well, I forgive you. Completely.
Because you're a good person,
April, a very good person,
and you don't deserve to be
crucified for one bad move.
Great. Thank you.
- Sure.
- Thank you so much.
My pleasure.
- Hey, April, you got a sec...
- No, I'm sorry! Busy!
You've got to be kidding me.
They said their systems are down.
All medical records unavailable.
Okay. All right.
I'll take it from here. Thank you.
Dr. Ryan to the ER.
Dr. Harry Ryan to the ER.
Hey. I talked to Dayna.
She was referred by a friend
in the exact same situation...
inconclusive mammogram,
and then she needed
a second opinion.
And did you tell her
that she is cancer free?
No. No. We have one scan
and we don't have
any of her prior records.
Two chemo treatments?
That really would be
a miracle cure.
This guy... there's something
really wrong here.
Well, maybe
she was just misdiagnosed.
Sometimes good doctors make
mistakes.
- Why are you defending this guy?
- Why are you attacking this guy?
You have been so angry
all day long.
Maybe it has something to do
with the fact...
American Society of Clinical Oncology.
Yeah?
Guess who is not a member?
I am tore up
from the floor up.
I mean beat up
from the feet up.
- Come here.
- Ohh.
I don't think I'm even gonna
put anything on.
Oh, here, let me get the light.
Oh, yeah.
Okay.
Uh, here, maybe I can, um...
help sooth some of your tore up...?
Ben?
Uh...
Vitals?
Stable, but the skull
temperature is spiking again.
We're approaching
the upper limit.
Okay, that's it.
We're done.
No.
I want to let it cool off again
and then do another round,
- make sure the tumor's all gone.
- We have to stop now
before we turn the inside of
Noah's head into stew.
- No, one more round.
- Dr. Shepherd, let it go!
♪ Time, it takes some time ♪
♪ But when that's all you got, it eats ♪
♪ At the corners of your mind ♪
- ♪ Words ♪
- But we might have saved him, right?
Well, we'll know
as soon as the kid wakes up.
♪ Spoken low ♪
If he wakes up.
♪ Whispered quietly as if ♪
Welcome to the frontier of medicine.
♪ They're in a language
only you and I could know ♪
We have reviewed
every option.
And, um, there are some things
that we could try,
- but honestly, Richard, Ollie doesn't...
- Ollie has had enough for today.
So, I think what we should do
is,
let's get her hydrated overnight,
and we can run some more tests
in the morning.
Um, okay. Right.
Uh, I'm gonna
keep an eye on her,
and don't you two go far,
either, okay?
Nope.
We'll be right here.
Tell me you see
what's happening here.
We cannot go against
Ollie's wishes,
even if it upsets Richard.
The last time
he fell off the wagon,
he nearly lost everything...
his career, his marriage.
Um,
I can't even picture him drunk.
Trust me,
you don't want to see it.
- Where's Catherine?
- In Boston.
Maybe we can get her back
by the morning.
Can you get on that, please?
Jerry Garcia needs me.
♪ Won't let go of me ♪
Jerry?
We have three left.
And big companies like Cerone's
always move slowly,
- so...
- For the last time,
this isn't about Cerone!
It's about Olive Warner.
And all the other Ollies
that we could save
if we could just work faster.
Damn it.
You two should go home.
I have to stay here tonight anyway.
No, no, no.
I'm staying if you're staying.
Me, too.
♪ Deep in the ground ♪
♪ Can't bury it down ♪
♪ I let it go but it won't let go of me ♪
♪ Won't let go of me ♪
Nothing?
No change.
What did we do to him?
Come on, kid.
Noah?
He's still not awake.
Damn it.
You just assume,
since you're working with
the great Amelia Shepherd,
it's all gonna work out.
Hey,
there's still time, okay?
Ohh. We spent the night here.
Gross.
I don't know.
It's not so bad.
Oh, my God.
What?
I've... I've never
been to your place.
You... You...
You never talk about your place.
Uh, well, what...
No, no, no!
What are you doing?
No, no, no.
Sam, stop! Stop!
What the hell, Andrew?
Okay, you got me. I'm in between
places, that's all.
I was staying
with Dr. Robbins,
and then she started
sleeping with my sister.
So then I moved in
with Dr. Hunt, but then...
he started
sleeping with my sister.
Now you're laughing at me.
Great.
You're living in
the on-call room.
Yes.
Move in with me.
A-Are you serious?
- Hi.
Hi. Arizona Hunt.
This is my husband, O-Otis.
Um,
I called this morning?
Fill this out and we'll call you
when Dr. Hanson is ready.
- Great. Awesome.
- Thanks.
Suddenly we're a married couple?
With an appointment?
What happened to
"good doctors make mistakes"?
His Yelp reviews
are all five stars.
Well, that sounds like
a good thing.
No, it's too good to be true.
People go to Yelp to complain.
Nobody gets five stars.
I don't get five stars.
You sure don't.
So now this is your idea
and it all makes sense to you.
You... You really are
like my other wives.
I figure if he doesn't know
that we're doctors,
he's likely to
give more away.
Hmm.
Nicely done, Mrs. Hunt.
You know, I'm just gonna...
You get
three and a half stars.
- What?
- Same as my dry cleaner.
Wow.
Dr. Teller, extension 2219.
Hey, you okay?
I just spoke to Catherine,
and she wanted me to...
Oh, so Catherine's
asking you about me.
You'd like it if
Ben asked me about you?
Ben Warren
can stick it in his pill box.
I've spoken to Ollie nearly
every day for the past 20 years.
More than I've spoken
to anyone else in my life.
More than my parents,
Adele, Catherine.
She's the keeper
of my secrets.
She's...
She's how I feel
God's presence.
You've got an awfully big
village of people here.
You know that.
Yeah, I know I do.
Dr. Kepner?
Can I place an art line
in Trauma 4?
- Yes.
- Thanks.
Also, I am sorry.
What?
Um, I was not entirely fair
to you on trauma cert day.
Your work was
particularly impressive,
and I may not have made that
clear on the day in question.
Thank you.
I just... I just thought
you might be, you know...
I might be what?
Um, you know, like,
having a nervous breakdown?
Oh.
Oh, uh,
I didn't take it personally.
Good. Great. Great.
Thanks for that.
- And we will not speak of this again.
- Right.
Schmitt.
I'm sorry!
What? For what? What?
I... I don't know.
I'm just really sorry.
Uh...
apology accepted.
The truth is
we don't have any good options.
We could put you on
liver dialysis,
but that would cause
a real strain on your heart.
Mm-hmm.
We could try an LVAD,
but the long-term prognosis
is very poor.
Who saw this coming?
Hey, it's better to have
a chance at a good result
than a guarantee
of a bad one.
By whose definition?
Do you think that
when I found out I was dying,
I was just, "Oh, well,
that's life for you"?
Coming to terms with this
was the second hardest thing
I have ever done in my life,
and now I'm at peace.
Or at least I was.
The one thing...
The only thing...
Stopping me from moving on
to whatever comes next
is one childish, stubborn,
nagging problem.
You are driving me to drink,
Richard Webber,
and I'll be damned if
I don't leave this world sober!
Well, if I'm the only thing
that's keeping you alive,
then I guess
I'm doing my job!
Please tell me
you have good news for me.
My mom's Boston patient
had post-op complications,
so she had to stay back
and see it through.
Dr. Ryan, call the psych unit.
I'm the one who's gonna have to
tell him, aren't I?
How do you tell somebody something
that they already know?
I mean, this isn't... rational,
it's just pure emotion.
Hmm.
How can I...
What can I say that would
possibly change his mind?
Believe it or not,
I know exactly how that feels.
You do?
Mm-hmm.
That's how I felt
when your mother was dying.
Look, I can go with you.
Be there with you
when you tell him.
Let me help.
You helped.
I have to say
how refreshing it is
to have a couple
come in together.
You'd be surprised
how many husbands
don't even want to
come into the office,
much less the exam room.
- Hmm.
- Yeah, yeah.
It's just we're... we're really
close. Right, honey?
- Mm-mm-hmm.
- Mm-hmm.
Well, right breast
looks nice and healthy.
- It's not...
- Oh, okay.
Any problem there at all.
Yeah,
more often than not,
these inconclusive mammograms
turn out to be nothing.
But, you know,
better safe than s...
Yeah, this looks
slightly less than good.
Unfortunately, I am seeing a
solid lesion in the left breast.
Hmm. So, I...
I definitely
have breast cancer, huh?
Hey, uh, can you show us
what that looks like
on that machine there, Doc?
Yeah.
You see this area
right here?
And that's the lesion.
And then there's a small one
right there.
That's...
That is really there.
I have breast cancer?!
Let's go.
- Hey. Oh, I've been looking for you.
- I think I owe you...
Come with us. Right now.
Did she page you, too?
Is it bad?
You're showing up clean.
You're 100% sure?
Look, they look totally clean!
See for yourself.
Um, she's like...
Oh, we're way past that.
You're okay.
I'm okay.
He fakes
the ultrasounds.
He is poisoning
completely healthy women,
probably just to charge them
for the chemo.
- No.
- What he does to these women,
what he puts these families
through...
- We need to stop him.
- No. We need to destroy him.
Owen...
You told me not to take it out
on the interns.
You figured out a way
to get Ollie more time?
Otherwise,
it's just...
You know who
you remind me of?
Don't care.
Me.
When my mom was dying.
I worked so hard,
looking for anything that would
give her more time.
And I didn't even
think about it.
I just instinctively knew
it was what I had to do.
Yeah,
but she was your family.
More than blood.
She shaped me.
More than anyone else,
she made me who I am.
How could it be wrong
to do everything in my power
to save her?
♪ For fifty-one reasons
not to lose our souls? ♪
Because you weren't
doing it for her.
♪ And it's not that
you're not the one ♪
I'd give anything for
another chance
- ♪ And it's not that you're not the one ♪
- to do it again.
Just to be there with her
and then give her
the ending that she wanted.
♪ Do you feel a little broken? ♪
That experimental protocol
that I made her do...
- ♪ Do you feel a little broken? ♪
- All that suffering...
putting her through
all that pain
when all she wanted
was peace...
♪ Do you feel a little broken? ♪
And to know
that I would be okay.
♪ Do you feel a little broken? ♪
It's my only regret.
♪ Tell me where
we're going so fast ♪
♪ Never used to run
when we were young ♪
Hey.
I, uh, assumed
I was still getting her.
- ♪ And I'm running out of words ♪
- Yeah, I, um...
I would really like to...
if that's okay.
I... I...
I'd really like to.
- How you doing?
- You okay?
Yes, I am...
I am totally fine to take her.
I promise.
- I'm good.
- You? You, though?
You okay?
Um...
♪ And leave behind ♪
- ♪ What you don't want no more ♪
- Ah, I lost God.
I-I lost
Matthew's Taylor's wife.
I lost her
in childbirth.
And then this little boy died
for no earthly reason, and...
God was nowhere to be found.
I lost Him.
And that's never happened to me
before, and I got scared...
and, uh, really angry.
And all during our marriage,
I just...
I wanted you to know God
the way that I did,
and you never wanted to.
And so, when I lost him,
it felt like, I don't know,
you've won or something.
And...
- ♪ Do you feel a little broken? ♪
- ..I hated that.
I hated you.
Yeah, well,
I was just trying to help.
I know, I know, I got it.
You did.
Oh, my God, you did.
Things got...
really rough,
and I just...
I needed to be sure
that Harriet was okay.
And of course she was
because... of you.
And I'm... I'm good now.
I, uh... I found Him again.
He and I are, like,
tighter than ever.
So you know.
But I realize that even when
it felt like He wasn't there...
♪ Do you feel a little broken? ♪
You were.
So thank you.
♪ Do you feel a little broken? ♪
Thank you.
I'm really sorry.
♪ Do you feel a little broken? ♪
Give Kimmie a standard
course of chemo and radiation.
Shrink the tumor enough
to get her to summer.
That could work.
By then, I'll be able to
take the three,
maybe four weeks of
vacation time I'm due,
and then I'll just take Kimmie
and her grandmother to New York
and we'll hit every
Broadway show we can.
What's going on?
Alex...
Noah made it.
He's good.
Noah is doing okay,
but I cannot tell you why.
That procedure was like skiing
down a mountain blindfolded.
We should have crashed
a thousand time.
- All right, hold on, hold on. Amelia?
- No, he's... he's right.
We ran into a dozen things
that we never even saw coming.
And this was supposed to be
the easy one.
I mean, Kimmie's tumor
is much more dangerous.
Yeah, with a lot more tests,
a lot more practice,
we'll be able to save
more kids with Noah's tumor,
but Kimmie's procedure
is years away.
- Kimmie doesn't have years.
- I know.
No, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
I do not accept this, because
you saved Noah, so you can...
I will do everything I can
to make sure
that Kimmie treasures
the time she has left,
but I will not perform
that procedure on this girl.
All right, fine. Um,
Dr. Shepherd can do it
without you.
- Alex, I... I'm not gonna be able to
- No, no. No. No, listen to me.
- Listen to me, okay? Listen.
- The technology is not there.
Kimmie has only one chance
to live,
and you are the only doctors
that can do this in the world!
- We're not gonna do...
- I'm asking you as... as a colleague,
- as a friend...
- Do you have children, Karev?
- Please, please, please.
- I will not, I cannot
- Alex! No, Alex! - At my hands!
- Watch her die on my table...
Do what you got to do.
I'm okay?
I'm really okay?
Yes.
Your scans came back clear.
Dayna,
you do not have cancer.
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God, babe.
Oh, my God.
Oh, this is a miracle.
I have to tell Dr. Hanson.
Uh, actually Dr. Hunt
is telling Dr. Hanson right now.
Oh, my God.
Hey, Doc.
You got a minute?
Mr. Hunt, um, actually,
we're closed,
if you don't mind
coming back tomorrow.
You know, I have heard such
amazing things about your chemo,
like it's smoother
and milder.
Almost
makes it sound good.
What's the secret, Doc?
You know,
it's no secret.
It's just, uh, finding ways
to make it less... painful.
You know?
Do I know?
I guess I don't know.
So, walk me through it.
When you give a patient
chemotherapy,
what's the process?
- Uh, I mean, I...
- Let's see.
So,
it comes through here.
Right?
No, no, no,
wait, wait, wait, wait.
Wait, first...
First...
No.
No. Ah.
Here we go.
You know... Doc...
I think
I'm getting the hang of this.
Mr. Hunt, this is making me
very uncomfortable.
I bet it does.
You as uncomfortable as your
patients and their families?
What's next?
What is next?
Oh, I know.
This is the fun part.
- What are you...
- Roll up your sleeve.
You're not serious?
Roll up your sleeve.
I'm not doing that.
Why not, hmm?
Why not?
Because you're not sick.
Hmm?
'Cause only a psychotic
would pump that poison
in a completely healthy person
just to make
a few extra bucks?
Come on, Doc.
That's never stopped you
before.
Don't worry.
They're with me.
What's on your mind,
Shepherd?
What I really need is to get
as far away from my mind
right now as possible.
I got to admit, I'm feeling
that need pretty bad.
♪ Oh, oh, oh-oh-oh ♪
- ♪ Oh, oh, oh-oh-oh ♪
- Come on.
♪ Oh, oh, oh-oh-oh ♪
Really?
You brought another doctor?
No, Ollie.
I brought you a meeting.
♪ I'm not over you ♪
What?
♪ I'm not ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Whatever I say ♪
- I'm Amelia.
- Nice to meet you.
- ♪ My heart has hit a wall ♪
- Um...
And if it's okay with you,
I'd like to open the meeting
with the Serenity Prayer.
- ♪ Now my armor's broke ♪
- Thank you.
♪ Bleeding everything
that I fear ♪
God...
God, grant me the serenity
to accept the things
I cannot change, the courage
to change the things I can't,
and the wisdom
to know the difference.
♪ 'Cause this fight was rigged
from the beginning ♪
♪ All the tears I've cried ♪
All day, every day,
we fight against the current.
Sometimes we lose.
♪ Oh, oh, oh-oh-oh ♪
Here.
Here, here, look.
♪ Oh, oh, oh-oh-oh ♪
It's growing.
Okay.
It's growing a liver.
A new liver that is
60% of normal size.
So, this is Janis, right...
- Janis Joplin?
- No, no, no, she didn't make it.
This is David Bowie.
No, no, Bowie is the one that we
injected straight into
without the polymer,
so it can't possibly be Bowie,
because...
Yeah, exactly.
The liver cells migrated
completely by themselves.
We never needed
the polymer.
Are you serious?
Mm-hmm.
That means...
We're gonna save
a lot of lives.
We are gonna beat
Marie freakin' Cerone!
Yes!
Okay, stop all that.
Sometimes we win.
Oh. Oh, no.
You said it was urgent.
I thought I was gonna find you
lying on the floor.
God, Miranda, you can't say
it's urgent if it's not urgent.
Now, you listen to me,
Ben Warren, and you listen good.
I know I gave you a real scare,
but you have been scared
long enough.
I am not dying.
My heart is strong and powerful
just like me.
I'm very much alive,
and so are you.
And it is urgent.
It... is... urgent
that we celebrate
being alive right here,
right now, naked.
♪ So, you've taken
it all from me ♪
♪ Will you sell me back my world
and leave me be? ♪
♪ Strange ♪
Sometimes the current carries
us exactly where we need to go.
Oh, crap,
I left my keys.
Um,
I'll be right back.
Okay.
♪ I bet you thought that I ♪
♪ Would lose my reflection
in the sea ♪
♪ You let me drown ♪
Hey.
Uh, I have been apologizing
for the last two days,
and I finally
got the hang of it.
So,
if you'll let me, I just...
I want to tell you
how sorry I am.
Sorry for what?
I was so awful to you
at your game-night thing.
Like, so awful.
And I'm really sorry.
No, please, please,
you were the least of
my problems at that party.
Clive was married.
I was sleeping with
a married man.
Even though I didn't know,
I still can't shake
the shame of that.
Oh, my God, no.
I so relate.
I slept with an intern...
The douchey one.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
And then I slept with
Tom Koracick.
What?
And then I jumped my ex-husband
in a closet,
so, you know, I was just,
like, a total mess.
Anyway, I got to... I got to
get this little girl home.
But, um, I'm sorry.
And thank you.
Mmhmm, yeah.
Sorry.
Let's go, let's go.
♪ Won't get no tears from me ♪
Oh, God.
Ready?
And sometimes it slams us
right into the rocks.
Sync corrections  by  srjanapala