No, no, no, no...
Hi, I'm looking for Carl
Ferris. He's not in his room.
How much longer?
Trudy!
Where's the damn ambulance?!
They're on their way.
What's the problem?
Oh, nothing you need
concern yourself with, sir.
I'm a doctor. Then get in here!
I think this guy's
having a heart attack!
Make way! Doctor coming
in! Bernice, shake a leg.
Mr. Ferris? Are you
having pain in your chest?
Well, he says yes. It's like
someone's squeezing his heart.
No, no, no. It's more like...
Like he's been
punched in the chest.
When did it start?
A few hours ago.
Give me your stethoscope.
Let's sit him up. Here we go.
Easy.
He needs oxygen.
We're board and care.
We don't have any.
Jerry, I need your oxygen.
Get your hands off that!
Hey, that's mine!
How am I supposed
to breathe now?
Ah, he's in CHF.
Oh, CHF.
What's that?
Congestive heart failure.
I just take blood
pressures. I know CPR.
Dr. Benton?
Good. He's in rapid A-fib.
Let's start a line.
Oh, my God. Look at this.
We can't take your orders
unless you stay with us.
All right. Five liters
O-2 on a nasal cannula.
Let's get him on the gurney.
Hang in there, Carl!
Yeah, you're gonna be fine.
His lungs are wet. We
need to treat as failure.
Another nitro spray
in five minutes.
Forty of Lasix and titrate
up to 10 of morphine.
Keep his pressure above 100.
Lasix and MS. What's happening?
You've got fluid in your lungs.
Ten of morphine.
This might make you
a little drowsy, okay?
Pressure holding at
110. Pulse down to 100.
Am I gonna make it?
You're doing just
fine. You're gonna be...
Anybody hurt?
No, I don't think so.
Are you okay? Yes.
What happened? He
came out of nowhere.
Sir, does your neck hurt?
- A little.
He pulled out
right in front of me.
I didn't see you.
Don't move your head.
I had my lights and sirens on.
I'll go call another rig.
No, we'll take him with us.
I don't wash my hair. I
never wash my hair. It helps.
You shouldn't wash
your hair every day.
It gets rid of the natural oils.
Hi, Mom.
Abby. What are you doing here?
I'm on a break.
If you comb it too much,
you'll damage the ends.
How are you feeling?
Better.
Now it's full of
static electricity.
Winona, your hair
looks fine. Really.
I don't think she
knows where she is.
Time for your meds, Maggie.
I think Winona needs
to go to the bathroom.
She gets agitated
when she has to pee.
Thanks.
You need to use the
bathroom, Winona?
I need to fix my hair.
Okay. I'll be right back.
Uh...
You're gonna have to
stay here for a little while.
They're keeping you on
a 90-day hold. I'm sorry.
No.
No, it's me.
I should never have put
you through all of that.
It's me.
I'm sorry.
Trauma panel, C-spine, chest
and pelvis. Prep the left chest.
Where does it hurt?
My chest and stomach.
Any headache or neck pain? No.
No loss of consciousness.
Is there someone you'd
like us to call? My mom.
Let's infiltrate with
lidocaine, Malucci.
Where you going?
I'll be right back.
CBC, chem panel,
cardiac enzymes,
12-lead EKG and
a portable chest.
He was in A-fib with a
rapid ventricular response.
Heart rate's 88, irregular.
He's in CHF. How
about some Lasix?
We gave him 40. How
you doing, Mr. Ferris?
You tell me.
Don't worry. You'll be okay.
I've gotta go work
on the crash victim.
Dr. Kovac will take
care of you, okay?
Let me see that EKG
as soon as it comes back.
Lidocaine's on, second
liter of saline is up.
Do the ultrasound, Malucci.
Pulse ox, 89 on two liters.
Up it to five. 32
French. Thank you.
Open a chest-tube tray.
Set up Thora-Seal
to low suction.
Get serial crits, due
20 minutes, okay?
Ah, damn it!
What's wrong? Nothing.
Pulse ox down to 85.
Hurt yourself? No.
I can give it a try if you want.
I'm fine. Open another tube.
Can you shove this
under the desk for me?
I belongs to
Mr. Simpson in Exam 4.
You don't wanna know.
Abby, shouldn't you be
at the courthouse? Huh?
Your mother was just transported
to her commitment hearing.
Aren't you supposed to testify?
Uh, what commitment hearing?
State Attorney's Office
should have called.
Well, nobody called me.
Okay, um...
Your mother has contested
her certificate of commitment.
By law, she is entitled to a
hearing in front of a judge.
And, what, he could release her?
Technically.
Attempted suicide is a good
argument for a 90-day hold,
but since you witnessed it...
W-When is this happening?
11:15, county courthouse.
Tube placement looks good.
Pressure's up to 120.
I'll meet you at the
elevator. How we doing?
No chest pain after
two more nitros.
Where are you admitting him?
He's fifth in line
for Tele admit.
How long will that take?
Sometimes we rule
out MI, send them home.
He spent two days
in the ER last time.
It's okay, Mr. Ferris.
I'll sort this out
and get you a bed
as soon as I'm done in the O.R.
Thank you, Peter.
Sure.
She sat there and let
me apologize to her,
and she knew she
was going to court.
Maybe she didn't
wanna get you involved.
Maybe she doesn't want
me to testify against her.
Are you? I don't know.
I have to find this state's
attorney, whoever that is.
I'll go with you. No.
I can get somebody to cover.
I can't wait.
You shouldn't have
to do this by yourself.
I shouldn't have
to do this at all.
You'd rather Carter go with you?
What's that supposed to mean?
He helped you
deal with her before.
I'll call you later.
Hey. Nice basket. Is that
for Greene and Corday?
Yeah, and you still owe $50.
Fifty? For that?
We got them a
baby video monitor.
Nurses pitched
in 20, doctors 50.
I pay the same as
Benton and Weaver?
Aren't you a doctor?
That's debatable.
Cleo, can you take
a lady in Exam 2?
I'm already juggling
seven patients.
I'll trade you one.
Well, then can you
lend me 50 bucks?
Hey, Jing-Mei. I got
a woman in Exam 2
who hasn't had a bowel
movement in over a week.
She needs a rectal.
So do it.
Well, she threatened to Mace me.
You should be used
to that. Take this one.
No. Forget it.
What's the problem here?
I don't know.
Maybe it's your B.S.
Or maybe it's PMS.
Excuse me?
Look, I'm just saying...
That it's okay for you
to dump a patient on me
and okay for you
to refuse handoffs.
But the minute I do,
it's because I'm a bitch
or it's because it's
that time of the month!
Screw you.
Forget it. I'll leave.
I'm tired of your crap!
Another 2-0 silk.
Pressure's holding at 120.
Dr. Benton, what are
you still doing in here?
The gastrosplenic and
splenorenal were very vascular.
Are you suturing
with your left hand?
Yeah, I'm ambidextrous.
The hell you are.
I've seen third-year
medical students sew faster.
Let me see you
use your right hand.
Uh-huh. Sterile gloves.
What happened?
I may have bruised my wrist.
How? Fell to an
outstretched hand.
Ah, perfect mechanism
for a fracture.
Get your hands out
of the field, Peter.
What?
Hold them out like
this. Fingers spread.
Your radius and ulna feel okay?
I'm fine.
Ouch. Point tenderness
at the snuff box.
We call that a scaphoid
fracture. Scrub out.
I can finish this
case. I'm almost done.
No, Peter, you are done.
If this poor devil had
some complication
and his lawyers
discovered his surgeon
was operating
with his wrong hand
we both might as well bend over.
Be thankful you're
not a racehorse, Peter.
I'd have to take you
out and shoot you.
Dr. Benton, your wife's here.
What? I'm not married.
I'm sorry. Carla.
Where is she?
How long have you had
the pain? A few hours.
When was your last period?
Uh, seven weeks ago.
When I didn't get it,
I did a home pregnancy
test. It was positive.
That was two weeks ago.
Have you seen your gynecologist?
Do you have a
history of migraines?
Yeah.
And are you on any medication?
Inderal and sumatriptan.
But they're not helping.
It just keeps getting worse. Hm.
So where's the pain?
It's all around my right eye.
How many other pregnancies?
This is my first.
Am I having a miscarriage?
I can't tell until
we do some tests.
And a pelvic exam as well.
It pounds with every heartbeat.
I think it's the numbers.
What, you're an
accountant or something?
No, no, binary numbers.
Ones and zeros. Electronic data.
80, 146, 72, 109.
Deb. What?
Freaky.
I warned you!
- What happened?
- Patient Maced him.
You happy now?!
Flush his eyes with
saline. Call Security.
Give me that pepper
spray. Hey, give it to me!
Do you want me to
have you arrested?
I told him not to touch me
or my personal possessions.
Dr. Malucci was
only trying to help you.
You could have
seriously injured him.
Well, I hope I taught
him some manners.
Have you been in this ER before?
I've been in a lot ERs.
And to be honest,
this one's substandard.
Oh, well, maybe you'd
feel more comfortable in jail.
You know, they used to
drown redheaded babies
because they
thought they were evil.
And they used to
burn crazy people
who they thought were witches.
I just need something to
help me go to the bathroom.
Is that too much to ask?!
She's historically
non-med compliant?
Well, she has phases.
But this time she's
been off for about...
Ma'am. Six months.
How many serious
suicide attempts?
This one makes three.
Don't you know this stuff?
Just reviewing before we go in.
I got the case this morning.
Hey, Marty. You got Wyninski?
Wyczenski.
Wyczenski. Sorry.
Yeah. Drug overdose.
So you're stipulating to
an attempted suicide, right?
No, but nice try. No intent.
I'm sorry, what was
your name again?
Um, Abby.
Did you witness
the attempt, Abby?
I was with her.
She took the pills in a
bathroom. Who was that?
Your mother's public defender.
Since they won't stipulate
I'll have you testify
to the intention
and lethality of the attempt.
Nobody called me to testify.
That's why you're here, right?
You want your mother
to stay committed.
Well, yes, but... But
somebody should have...
Okay. You're here now.
Come on.
I think we pretty
much have it all...
Just answer all the
questions that we talked about.
All right.
Peter, I thought you
would never get here.
What happened?
I was carrying Reece.
I stepped in a
grate in the sidewalk
and twisted my ankle so bad
I thought I was
going to pass out.
Was he hurt? Hey, are you hurt?
He scraped his elbow. He's okay.
Carla, you were carrying him
while you were wearing these?
They said they want to operate.
I kept telling them to call
you. I do not want an operation.
Yeah, well, you have
a trimalleolar fracture.
They'll have to put a screw
in it so it'll heal properly.
Can't you do it?
No. You need an
orthopedic surgeon.
Well, how long am I gonna
have to stay in the hospital?
A couple of days.
I can't. Roger's out of town.
Yeah, is he ever around?
We haven't been getting
along too well lately.
Which is one of the reasons
why I cannot deal
with this right now.
I'll take Reece for
a couple of days
till you get back on your feet.
I don't think that's
gonna be a good idea.
Why not?
Jackie told me that you
moved in with that girlfriend.
And that's a problem?
I don't think it's a very good
environment for our son.
Carla, give me a break.
She's a pediatrician.
I'm just saying she don't
seem like the motherly type.
DeRAAD: She was admitted
following a suicide attempt.
That's not what I
asked, Dr. DeRaad.
Has Mrs. Wyczenski
shown any signs of suicidality
since her admission?
Not that I'm aware of.
She has voluntarily
submitted for all treatments
and medications recommended
by your department?
That's correct.
No further questions,
Your Honor.
Thank you, doctor. Does the
state have any more witnesses?
Yes, Your Honor. The
people call Abby Lockhart.
Hold on. All right, I was next.
I was next. It's my turn.
That's enough.
The testimony you
shall give in the case
will be the truth and
nothing but the truth?
Yes. JUDGE: Please have a seat.
It was my turn.
You're Mrs.
Wyczenski's daughter?
I've been waiting.
This bitch took my turn.
Settle down.
Miss Lockhart?
Yes.
And as such, you
support a mandatory hold
for your mother because
she might attempt
to kill herself again.
Objection. Leading.
JUDGE: Sustained.
Miss Lockhart, do you
feel that your mother
should be involuntarily
committed?
Yes. Why?
No. There are no
such thing as cuts!
Russell?
No back cuts! No front
cuts! No, it's my turn!
That bitch stole my
spot! Take her! Come on.
You take her out! I
didn't do anything!
Shut up.
She took my spot! No! No!
He was pushed
down in an altercation.
No LOC. Tenderness
to mid-shaft clavicle.
You said there's no
LOC? He's faking.
Vitals are normal.
No chest or belly pain.
What's his name?
He refused to give it.
He said it was "O. Possum."
Ow.
His name's Brett
Paxton, and he's crazy.
What's this? Human
bite to the left hand.
I'll need stitches,
thanks to this freak.
Hey, cool it! Cool
it! Okay. Okay.
Take the opossum to Exam 1
and get the kangaroo
to Sutures. Come on.
Aah! God! Okay, okay, okay!
You need to flush them out.
Well, you've flushed
enough already. Okay?
Here you go.
You know I've never
worn one of those.
Well, maybe it's
time you at least
started dressing like
a doctor. Come on.
Ah.
What? What?
Carter, your
pregnancy's bleeding out!
Where is she? She's
passed out in the bathroom.
Noni?
Oh, my God. Hey, Noni,
can you hear me? Wake up!
I can't find a pulse.
She's got a weak
carotid. Get a gurney.
You're divorced, Mrs. Lockhart?
Objection. Irrelevant.
Goes to living arrangements.
I'll allow it.
Yes.
And when was your
divorce finalized?
Last summer.
Have you been dating anyone?
Your Honor?
Get to the point, Mr. Nesmith.
Your mother can be eccentric,
maybe a little
embarrassing at times?
She suffers from a
debilitating mood disorder.
Having her live with
you while trying to date
would be a major inconvenience?
I've tried having her live
with me before several times.
It doesn't work.
Doesn't work?
No. She stops taking
her medications,
she loses control
and she disappears.
Does she look out
of control to you?
She's on her meds now.
So she does take her medication.
She's only taken
them for a week.
But as long as she's med
compliant, she's not a danger.
She doesn't stay med compliant.
That wasn't my question.
Have you known your mother
to be a danger to herself
while med compliant?
No. Not usually.
You think locking her
up in a psychiatric facility
would be better for
her than living with you?
I can't take care of
her. Can't or won't?
She tried to kill
herself while with me.
Nonresponsive,
Your Honor. Please.
Just answer the questions.
Well, tell him to ask them.
Miss Lockhart.
You okay? Yes!
Would you like some
water? No, thank you.
BP's 60 palp. CARTER:
What's her HemoCue?
10.8.
Good. She's got
a little reserve.
No fetal pole, no heartbeat.
Just blood and POCs.
That's an incomplete
miscarriage.
Call OB. She needs a D and C.
I'll do a pelvic to see if...
Carter, this is her boyfriend.
What happened?
Your girlfriend
had a miscarriage.
But it's incomplete.
She needs a D and
C to stop the bleeding.
She's gonna be okay?
She might need a transfusion.
I'll speak with you
after she's stabilized.
Oh, God! Can you
take him outside?
Call for packed cells.
If pressure's not
up after two liters,
HemoCue every 30 minutes.
Is it true human bites
are worse than dog bites?
Yeah, because of the
virulence of the bacteria.
If germs infect the joint,
it can cause scarring
which can limit
your range of motion.
You don't wanna lose
your opposable thumb.
So you guys rival
mascots or something?
No, we were at the
Furturama show.
It's a convention for furries.
People who like to
dress in animal costumes.
He started it. I think
he'd been drinking.
One minute he
was skritching me...
Skritching?
Scratching. Mock grooming.
Sort of our version
of a handshake.
Next thing you know, he's
got his hand in my pouch.
So I decked him. I'm
not into the weird stuff.
It makes me sick. I
never felt like myself.
I told the doctors that. They
never really listen to me.
They just keep
giving me more pills.
How do you feel now? - Better.
So you're no longer depressed?
No.
Did you try to kill yourself
during your last
depressive episode?
I took an overdose
of sleeping pills, yes.
But I never meant
to kill myself.
She's lying. Shh.
Why did you take so many pills?
Who in their right mind
wants to drive from
Oklahoma to Chicago, really?
I get carsick.
I just thought if I could
sleep, I'd be all right.
I took some pills.
She took 900 milligrams.
They didn't work right away.
You know, I foolishly
then took some more pills.
She took 900
milligrams. That's 36 pills.
How much did you take?
I know it was stupid.
I just thought if
I could sleep...
The next thing I know, I
woke up in the hospital.
But I never meant to
hurt myself or anyone else.
Abby, I'm so sorry.
I never meant to
put you through that.
Ask her where she got the pills.
- She stole them.
- Mr. Rifkin,
could you please ask
your witness to be quiet?
If your daughter's not
ready to take you in,
are you able to
take care of yourself?
I always have. I've
always worked. Always.
Do you have any money?
I have a few credit cards.
They're all canceled.
I mean it, Miss Lockhart.
HemoCue every 20 minutes.
Set up a DIC panel and
call me with the results.
What's happening?
She's going up to the O.R.
I removed some
tissue from her cervix.
She's still bleeding
but it's slowed to the point
that her pressure's okay.
Did you have to give
her a blood transfusion?
We gave her plasma. Her
blood wasn't clotting properly.
Why isn't her blood clotting?
Uh, it could be a
sign of liver disease.
The liver affects
the clotting factors.
She ever have hepatitis?
No.
She drink alcohol every day? No.
Tylenol? Any other medications?
Maybe some herbal stuff.
Uh-huh.
What kind of herbal stuff?
Root extracts. They're
supposed to induce miscarriages.
Oh, I thought she
wanted this baby.
She didn't know.
How could she not know?
I gave them to her.
You what?
Put them in her tea
for the last few days.
She didn't even ask
me if I wanted the baby.
So you poisoned her?
I wasn't ready.
I thought she'd just...
What? Bleed to death?
I didn't mean to make her sick.
Ugh.
No, man, you just
meant to kill her baby.
You have a large
tumor on your left ovary.
I came in here
because I couldn't poop.
The tumor is large enough
that it's blocking your
bowel movements.
Cancer, huh?
Well, well, well.
Every day comes
with its own surprises.
What?
Nothing.
That's how I know you.
You're Princess Taffeta.
And you had that children's show
I used to watch all the
time when I was little.
And you always used to say,
"Every day comes
with its own surprises."
I don't think so.
And you worked with
those great puppets.
There was Mojo and
Mr. Whiskers, and what was that...?
Coconuts! The chimpanzee
in the sailor uniform.
We got that monkey from a lab
and we had to dress
him in that stupid outfit
to hide his open sores!
We need to admit you.
A gynecologist
will want to see you
and start treatment right away.
No, thanks. I
don't like hospitals!
Look, the tumor
will only get worse,
and you'll feel sicker.
Is there someone
that we can call?
A family member, perhaps,
who can talk to you about this?
Nope. Don't have
any brothers or sisters
and never got married.
I was engaged once to a man
named Christopher Clemmons.
He was gonna be a
famous jazz musician.
I was gonna be a movie star.
Doesn't really matter now.
In the end, everybody
dies alone. Right?
Excuse me, you got a light?
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
Hey.
♪ Sat at my window ♪
♪ Watched the world
Wake up this morning ♪
This is turning into
a freaking disaster.
You did fine.
Who's covering for you?
Don't worry about it.
I'm not hungry.
She's asking for you.
Maybe you should talk to her.
What for?
You're the one that didn't
want me to deal with her.
No. I thought she
needed hospitalization.
Well, why do you think I'm here?
Because you know
she needs your help,
even if she doesn't want it.
♪ Or do you just
Wake up one day ♪
♪ And say I'm going? ♪
I thought you should
eat something.
Thank you.
You lied.
You wanted to kill yourself.
I can't be committed.
Well, you need help, Mom.
And I obviously don't
know how to help you.
I understand. I don't want
to be a burden to you, Abby.
I swear that's the truth.
But I can't be committed.
So you'll just do this
to yourself over again?
You'll just roll through
the whole cycle?
No.
Then what?
What? What are you gonna
do differently this time?
I don't know. I don't
want to make any...
I don't want to break
any more promises to you.
I've put you through
so much already...
If you believed that, you
would seek treatment.
I will. I just...
Can't be committed.
Right. Well...
Well, just forgive me if I
don't trust your judgment.
I would have found
a way to try, Abby.
It's not your fault.
Nothing I do is your fault.
My company has this
Christmas charity event.
One year the guy who always
dresses up for
the kids got sick.
My boss made me
put on this reindeer suit.
The kids went nuts. The
adults thought it was great.
Everybody took pictures with me.
Sounds almost
fun. It was a blast.
I used to be so shy. But
the suit gives you freedom.
It lets you do things
you normally wouldn't do.
But I'm not a
plushie or a furvert.
A what?
Furverts like to wear
their suits during sex.
And plushies are overly
fond of stuffed animals.
What?
But not me. I
just like the suit.
Some people disapprove and
think it's wrong, but the truth is,
I'm never happier than
when I'm a kangaroo.
You have to rule
out appendicitis,
biliary disease, food poisoning.
Does she have a fever?
No. 98.8.
Good breath sounds.
What's that smell?
Oh, my God.
I've seen this before.
Get a surgical
consult. I'll call DCFS.
No. It's a folk cure.
They heat a coin over a candle
and drag it across the back.
Sometimes they dip
the coins in essential oils.
Just because it's
an ancient tradition
doesn't mean it's
not child abuse.
The minty smell is
probably oil of wintergreen.
It's got a high
concentration of salicylates.
It could have caused
the aspirin toxicity.
Let's get a blood gas and
a salicylate level, okay?
You do that. I'm
calling Family Services.
Will I be able to
have more children?
Yes.
Noni, what your boyfriend
did was really wrong.
You need to consider whether
or not to file criminal charges.
Victor loves me.
He just got scared.
That doesn't
justify what he did.
I was so excited to be pregnant.
What do you want to do?
Mrs. Wyczenski, are you
familiar with reading directions
and warnings on
over-the-counter medications?
Yes, I suppose so.
Would you please
read the label on this?
I'm sorry, I don't have my
reading glasses. I can't see.
Allow me, then. - Okay.
"One tablet at bedtime.
"May repeat in four
hours if necessary.
Do not exceed four
tablets in a 24-hour period."
You took 36
tablets, did you not?
I didn't have my reading
glasses with me then either.
You took 36 pills and you
didn't intend to kill yourself?
I was depressed, but I didn't
want to kill myself. Really.
Where did you get the pills?
I got them at a
convenience store.
How did you pay for them?
I didn't. You stole them?
Objection. Shoplifting has
nothing to do with suicidality.
Goes to intent.
Get to it quickly.
Why did you have to steal them?
Why didn't you ask your
daughter to pay for them?
She wouldn't have. Why not?
She was worried.
Worried that you'd
try to kill yourself?
She worries when
I get depressed.
Because during other depressions
you have attempted suicide.
In fact, you've been committed
on two other occasions
for attempted
suicide, haven't you?
In '83 and 1974.
Yes.
What method did you
use for those attempts?
Carbon monoxide poisoning.
In '83.
What about in '74?
I took some pills.
Did you coin Lynda
because she's sick?
I don't understand
what you're saying.
Could someone get me a
translator? Where's Chen?
Hey, look who's here!
Your cardiac enzymes
are back, Mr. Ferris.
Yeah, you had a
small heart attack.
What did I tell you, huh?
I know my heart attacks.
I guess I'm lucky you
showed up when you did.
Hey, we kept you
alive till he got there.
If there are any
blockages around the heart,
we'll open it with an
angioplasty balloon
and we'll keep it
open with a stent.
Thank you, Peter.
Not bad for a guy who blew
up a rubber in your classroom.
I'll check on you later.
Hi, Reece. What
are you doing here?
His mother broke her ankle.
So she's waiting to
be admitted to Surgery.
Ouch. Could you
look at a belly? Sure.
Excuse me.
I don't understand
what you're saying.
Could you just
calm down, all right?
She seems pretty
upset. You think?
Hey, you speak Cantonese?
You think? I was a
translator in the Army.
Could you ask her what she
treated her granddaughter with?
I think I can manage. Excuse me.
Malucci. Her labs are back.
Electrolytes are
normal. No anion gap.
PH 7.4. Salicylate level's
10 milligrams per deciliter.
Well, that's not a
toxic range. Nope.
Her liver-function tests and
her head CT are also normal.
Then it's one hell of a
case of gastroenteritis.
We've given her 10 of
Compazine and she's still puking.
Peter's looking at her
now. I'll let you know.
Well, anything?
She said she used
hot coins and liniment.
Yeah, I know that.
But did she say why?
Uh, she's possessed.
Grandma or the girl?
What are we talking
here, demonic spirits?
No, more like evil
thoughts. Sinful behavior.
You know, S-E-X.
Faye? Faye!
Hey, Faye, where are you
going? Where're you going?
I got a garden party at 6.
You need to be
admitted to the hospital
so you can start treatment.
We both know that's
not gonna happen.
You can't leave. Come on.
I've never been one for
hospitals. They smell funny.
Besides, I already
signed the papers.
Will you at least
speak to a psychiatrist?
Mr. Whiskers.
Take it.
No, I can't. Really.
Look, honey,
I'm gonna be dead in a few
months. You said so yourself.
Make me feel better
knowing he's with someone
who'll appreciate him.
Stupid puppet ended
my acting career.
But it did buy my first house.
Thank you.
Every day comes
with its own surprises.
A statement from a former
employer of Mrs. Wyczenski...
I don't need any
more statements.
The employer affirms that...
We've spent enough
time on this one already.
Let's move on.
Mrs. Wyczenski is released
on her own recognizance.
What's next, Mike? Well,
that's good. You won.
Wait. JUDGE: Is this yours?
Yes, it is. So I can just go?
Yes, you can go. Wait
a minute. That's it?
I'm sorry.
No, she's letting her go?
She needs hospitalization!
I'm not debating it with you.
You've counseled your client?
Yeah, but, I mean, that's...
We did all we can. I'm
sorry. We have to move on.
You're done. It's good.
Just go back to the
hospital and sign out.
Okay. That's good. Move on.
All of you should just move on.
We wouldn't want
to waste time on this.
I've been dealing with
her for 30 years. Russell?
You didn't have to
drive her to the hospital.
Pour charcoal down her
throat. Or breathe for her.
This way. I'm getting my coat!
Just don't touch her.
She's not your mother.
What do you care?
The rest of us will
just take care of her.
And maybe, maybe if
you're really lucky next time
you won't have to
hear the case at all.
Because maybe next
time you'll do it right!
And then it'll be the
coroner's problem.
No evidence of
appendicitis or pancreatitis.
Biliary colic? No.
I'm about to give up.
Did you check for pyelo?
Yes. And hepatitis.
You should get an x-ray of
that wrist if it's bothering you.
I'm fine.
What will you do with Reece?
I left a message for Jackie.
Hopefully she can pick him
up on her way home from work.
Why don't you take him home?
You can't do anything
with that hand.
I wanna stick around
until Ferris gets a room.
Then I'll take him home
with me. I'm off in an hour.
No, I don't want you
to have to do that.
I don't mind.
We'll have fun, right?
All right. Thanks.
You have to let
me take an x-ray.
Come on, you're
resorting to blackmail?
What the hell is that?
I remember Mr. Whiskers!
Where did you get him? On eBay?
Princess Taffeta was the
patient who Maced you.
Wow. That's probably
worth some money.
Looks like roadkill.
Malucci, there's a
priest in with Lynda An?
Yeah. He's doing an exorcism.
Excuse me?
Actually, he's a chaplain,
and it's more of a blessing.
But it should work. I think
her problem's psychosomatic.
Based on your vast
knowledge of psychiatry?
That and the fact her
grandma caught her
messing around with her
boyfriend. It's all about guilt.
Hey, how's it working
out with Lynda?
I think she's gonna
be fine. Excellent.
How are you feeling? - Hungry.
No more nausea?
No. I'm starving.
She's eating solid
foods and not vomiting.
She's ready to go home.
I'd like to admit you,
keep you in overnight
for observation and rehydration.
Could I get a
pizza or something?
We'll see what we
can work out, okay?
Nice catch, huh?
I'd still like to do
some more tests.
Why, because you can't admit
that a surgeon
and a pediatrician
got outsmarted by a goombah?
Yeah. Don't sweat it.
You're not the
first to be deceived
by my rugged good
looks and boyish charm.
By signing, you
acknowledge that doctors feel
it's best you
remain hospitalized
and that you accept
and understand
by leaving against
medical advice
you risk a deterioration of
your psychiatric symptoms.
What about my meds?
Can I have a prescription?
I will give you
three days' worth.
I want to see you Monday.
If you're doing well, I'll
give you a week's worth.
Okay. Okay what?
What does that mean?
Could I call you?
Sure.
All right. You can
call me anytime.
You can call me just to talk.
Okay.
I got some stuff
from that motel room
and some stuff you
left in my apartment.
Thank you.
Figure out where you're going?
Yeah. Dr. Legaspi gave
me the name of a shelter.
I'm gonna go
there for a few days.
Okay. Okay.
Good luck, Maggie.
See you next time.
Next time?
Yeah, whenever it
is, wherever it is...
Maybe there won't
be a next time.
You're gonna walk out of
here on your own one week
after swallowing a pharmacy,
as close to death
as I see people get,
and you think there's
not gonna be a next time?
I hope not. I don't know.
I promised myself I
wouldn't make any promises.
You know,
when I saw you seizing
on that table, I thought:
"This is it. This is it. This
is how it's all gonna end.
I am going to watch
my mother die."
I still might not be
wrong about that.
It could still end that way.
And there's not one
thing I can do about it.
But I'll show up.
Because you will always
have that power over me.
I will show up and
I will try to stop it.
I love you, Mom.
How long will she
be in the hospital?
We'll keep her
overnight for observation.
Could I see her?
I don't think so.
I wanna talk to her.
She prefers to be alone.
You need to speak to the police.
This the guy? This is the guy.
Wait a second. This is
between me and Noni.
What did you do, talk
her into pressing charges?
I didn't have to.
Murder is a felony.
Come with me, sir.
It wasn't even a baby.
Can I speak with
Dr. Quaid? Daryl Quaid.
Well, he gave me his card
and it has this number on it.
Right. Okay, thanks.
One of those days, huh? Mm.
Did you ever find
out what happened
with your numbers guy?
Was he some kind of a savant?
Don't know. He left with
this doctor from the VA.
I just called to follow up but
there's no record of my patient
or the doctor I
let him leave with.
What will you do? Same
thing as I always do.
Hit a bar, get drunk,
go home with a stranger
and have wild sex until I
pass out from exhaustion.
Takeout and a hot bath? Yeah.
Randi, have you seen
my puppet? Your what?
Mr. Whiskers. I didn't
touch it. Trust me.
Can't believe somebody
would steal that.
So where do you guys
want Super Larry? Exam 1.
The opossum
guy's still in there.
Okay. Well, let's
get rid of him.
Mr. Paxton?
Mr. Paxton? You
still playing opossum?
Mr. Whiskers!
Whatever happened
to Mrs. Lindstrom?
Retired.
She was mean.
That woman was born mean.
Even the other teachers
were afraid of her.
I'm sure you thought
the same of me
with all those
detentions I gave you.
Hey.
Your detentions steered
me towards medicine. So...
I might have played
a small role in it.
I'm proud of you, Peter.
Yeah, well, thanks a lot.
And you should be
proud of yourself.
I am. Look, don't get me wrong.
Sometimes it's hard
when people's lives
depend on your success
and you're not
always successful.
Sometimes you...
Sometimes you get
so tired that you start
forgetting what's important.
And what is that?
Two things in this
world I'm certain of:
My love for my son and
my skills as a surgeon.
I'm a father, I'm a doctor.
At the end of the day,
that's enough for me.
What about a teacher?
That was never one
of my greatest skills.
The only skill you need to
be a good teacher is to care.
That's all.
Who knows? Maybe
one of your students
will wind up saving
your ass one day.
Hi.
I, uh, heard you were
here, but I haven't seen you.
Uh, yeah.
Most of my day is
spent in the jail ward.
I'm sorry.
I was glad to hear that
the charges were dropped.
Shannon Wallace
decided to tell the truth
after she got the
treatment that she needed.
That's good.
What do you want, Kerry?
I thought you might be hungry.
No. No, I'm not,
and I have a ton
of work to do. So...
Right. Well, uh, if
you change your mind
here's some Kung Pao
chicken from George's.
Abby, are you okay in there?
Want some dinner?
You need to eat.
♪ When you're haunted ♪
♪ I'll be near ♪
♪ When the shadows
Come to call ♪
Have you been watching
Martha Stewart again?
Mm-hm. Mm-hm.
Thank you. For what?
For being there.
And here.
Everything.
Is the food here?
What food? I'm
making dinner by myself.
Why are you laughing?
I just hope you didn't order
from that Thai place again.
♪ I will take care of you ♪
Who is it?
Abby?
♪ Long as you want me to ♪