I feel good
I knew that I would, now
So good so good
I got you oh!
I feel nice
Like sugar and spice
So nice so nice
I got you
When I hold you in my arms
I know that I can do no wrong
And when I hold you in my arms
my love won't do you no harm
And I feel nice
like sugar and spice
I feel nice like sugar and spice
New Amsterdam Hospital.
So nice so nice
I got you
Massive carbon monoxide
poisoning from a faulty furnace.
There was a climate
change conference,
so we've got dozens more
ambassadors coming out.
Give him 100% high flow
and get him to The Dam.
So good so good
Yeah, he's something.
On the move.
So good
I got you
Hey
There you are. I
knew you'd get lost.
All the new medical
directors get lost.
And...
I'll take those odds.
Grab a sheet, will you?
EMS just dropped off.
Wait. What?
Do you hear that?
Hear what?
Dr. Bloom, she's dead.
No pulse, no BP,
cyanotic, rigor mortis.
I need a defib ventilator, ALS,
and resuscitation team, now!
That's impossible. She's dead.
Well, at least you
didn't kill her twice.
New Amsterdam
has a public school,
prison ward, and
facilities for the UN.
We performed the world's first C-section
in the world's first maternity ward.
New Amsterdam is
America's first public hospital.
Patients don't need
insurance, money...
Dora, I know the history.
The Dean makes me tell it
to every new medical director.
And how many of those
have you worked with?
Five in five years.
Dr. Helen Sharpe.
Max Goodwin, how can
I help? You're too kind.
Welcome to The Dam.
Why are you in scrubs?
Because I'm a doctor.
Going somewhere?
I have to tape segments with The
Morning Show and Megyn Kelly,
then give the keynote address
at the oncology conference in Vail.
I'll take that for
you. Thank you.
Wow. You're gonna do
all that on your lunch break.
You're funny. I'll
be back next week.
We'll lunch at the
Tavern. My treat.
Unlike the previous
medical director,
I actually expect you
to practice medicine
at this hospital because,
I don't know, it's your job.
You're funny.
You said that.
I'll tell you what. I'll continue
giving speeches all over the world,
because you can't afford the
kind of publicity I give this hospital.
And I'll continue my on-air
appearances with Ellen, Oprah,
and anyone else powerful
enough to go by one name
because someone
has to remind New York
that even though New Amsterdam
is an under-funded public hospital,
we can still go toe-to-toe
with the privates
from basic care to
state-of-the-art procedures.
I will be back next week.
We'll lunch at the
Tavern. My treat.
I like her.
If she comes
back, let's keep her.
Sorry.
Max.
Is everything okay?
Just calling to say hi.
Really?
Isn't that what people do?
People, yeah.
You? Not so much.
I'm trying.
How's the... Can I...
Sorry. What? No, you...
I was...
I was just going to ask
about the apartment.
It's great. Yeah.
You should come by
sometime, sit on the floor,
eat some soy sauce packets.
Have you had
any time to think...
Max.
It's time.
Georgia, I have to...
Save the world? I know. Go.
But listen, listen. I know
what I did was wrong.
I should have put you and the
baby first, but I am going to change.
And I'm gonna win you back.
Well, you have 12 weeks.
Hey, Reynolds. One second.
Hey. I've been
thinking about you.
You wanna grab a
drink later? I can't.
You know when I say "grab a
drink," I don't really mean grab a drink.
I do.
Sorry. I'm so sorry.
Sorry.
So sorry.
You guys okay?
There he is.
Uh...
My sister Luna and I were
born here in New Amsterdam.
And then, eight years later, uh,
Luna died here.
It was a
hospital-acquired infection.
Entirely preventable.
So,
working here, being able to
save someone else's sister
or someone's daughter,
it's a dream come true
for me.
Anyway, so...
How can I help?
Uh... Sorry. That's
not a trick question.
I'm really just asking.
I work for you, so you
can work for your patients.
How can I help?
Shout it out.
Really? No one? Wow.
Okay, why don't we
try this? I'll go first.
Will everyone in the
cardiac surgical department
please raise your hands?
Don't be shy. Just
get them up there.
Great.
Great, thank you.
You're all fired.
Any department who
places billing above care,
no matter how much
money you make this hospital,
you will be terminated.
Oh, I am serious.
Bye-bye.
We're gonna be
starting over, all right?
Without you.
Sorry.
Next, will all the department
chairs raise your hands, please?
I have no idea how you managed
to keep this hospital
afloat with so little help,
so I'm gonna hire
you 50 new attendings
because untrained residents will
no longer be running this hospital,
regardless of how much
money their university makes
off their indentured servitude
or how much time it affords
some of you to play golf.
So let me ask again,
how can I help?
Yeah. Person not
calling their lawyer.
Lauren Bloom,
emergency department.
I want to get rid of
our waiting room.
Okay, what do you...
Where do you want to put it?
I want to get rid of it.
I want to move patients
direct to bed. No waiting room.
Done.
Really?
Sure, let's try.
Yeah.
Hi. Dr. Iggy Frome,
head of psych.
Can we do something
about healthy food?
What do you want to do about it?
Have some.
To eat in the hospital.
Okay. Done.
Aces. Thank you.
Thank you.
You know, we all feel like the system
is too big to change, but guess what?
We are the system.
And we need to change.
So just tell me what you
need, what your patients need.
And I don't care if it's not covered.
I don't care if the board said no.
Let's get into some trouble.
Let's be doctors again.
Okay, I appreciate it. Go,
and I'll see you out in the wards.
Thanks.
Uh, Bloom.
Sorry, uh, could I
borrow you for a minute?
Um, I need you to
do a throat biopsy.
It'll just take a second. Sure.
For what patient?
Uh... Me.
Hello? My name is Alain.
I wrote my name down.
Then we'll call you when we
have a doctor available. Okay, hon?
At New Amsterdam's department of
pediatric oncology, we strive to ensure
that the children feel that they are
in a relaxed, positive environment...
You know what?
She is good. She is.
How long have you
noticed irritation?
Do you think she's
coming back early? No.
Max? Yeah, four weeks.
Six. Maybe eight? I don't know.
You look tired. Do
you need a nap?
I need you to stay still.
Good luck with that.
Who's calling? Dean
of medicine. Third time.
Ignore. BLOOM: Max.
Please stop talking. Yeah.
Wait. What's on my hot list
after this? What's a hot list?
It's a to-do list,
but, you know,
with a cooler name.
Call the Dean back.
After that.
You know, I can come back later.
Well, you've got the entire
United Nations in the ICU
and a cardiac patient
being prepped for surgery.
Right... Wait. Why is a
cardiac surgery on my hot list?
Because you fired all
the cardiac surgeons.
Right, but I had all the new
patients rerouted to University.
Not the ones from Rikers.
Maybe you shouldn't have
fired the entire department.
They were all corrupt and lazy.
See? Except for Dr. Reynolds.
How do you know that?
Just read his file.
Ow.
Dr. Frome?
Please sign in and take a seat.
Dr. Frome.
Young lady, it is way too early in
my day to call security, but I will.
Dr. Frome! Dr. Frome! Dr. Frome!
It's okay! It's okay! I
got it. Jemma, hi, hey.
I got this. Thank you.
All right, come
on. Come with me.
Thank you.
It's okay, whatever it is.
It happened again.
Floyd Reynolds?
Max Goodwin. Yeah, I
remember you from an hour ago.
When you fired me.
Yale. Fancy.
What secret society were
you? Skull and Bones?
Scroll and Key? The one
that took a poor black kid.
Which one was that?
School of Medicine.
So, Floyd, why did you become
a cardiovascular surgeon?
You know, all due respect, I don't
need a pat on the back on the way out.
That's good because I don't
intend to pat you on the back,
given the appalling history of
patient care in your department.
If I were you and I had
analyzed our performance,
I would have done the same.
By performance, do you mean the
highest mortality and infection rates
in New York City?
'Cause that's like the
Beyoncé of performances
if Beyoncé, you
know, killed people.
Yeah, and don't forget our rampant
culture of inflating billable hours.
Except you didn't.
I read your files. You have the
lowest billing rates in the department.
What's wrong? You
don't like surgery?
I love surgery.
Then why did you perform half as
many procedures as your colleagues?
Because my patients
didn't need them.
Because there's other ways to help
people than by cutting them open.
It's a cute kid.
It's my nephew.
I'm unfiring you.
To do what?
To run the cardiac
surgical department.
There is no cardiac
Then build one.
A good one.
I mean, it's only people's
hearts we're talking about.
You do know the whole
system's rigged, don't you?
I mean, they're not gonna let you
come in here and just help people.
So let's help as many as we
can before they figure us out.
You can't say no.
You already unpacked.
Jemma first came
to me eight years ago
after she was sexually
abused by her foster father.
Just tell me how long
before I can place her.
Two years after
that, she came back
after she was found chained to
a radiator, being fed like a dog.
How long, Iggy? This
girl has been abused
three times in the
foster care system,
and you want to
put her right back in?
What other options do we have?
I'm keeping her.
What do you mean, "keeping her"?
I mean I'm not discharging
her. I'm keeping her.
Until when?
Until she's 18.
But that's...
Two years.
So you are committing a patient
just to keep them
out of foster care?
Yeah.
Dr., uh...
Goodwin, but call me Max.
I was just taking an interest.
Surely, you don't have the time to
take an interest in every single case.
Well, that's why I
wear my running shoes.
I've been practicing
here for 25 years.
The key to survival is to
have more than one speed.
I can go faster.
That's not what I meant.
Just keep me in the
loop on this, will you?
Hi.
Good afternoon, Mr. Martín.
I'm Dr. Vijay Kapoor,
your wife's neurologist.
What happened to her?
Let me first find my glasses
so that I can read her chart.
There they are.
Thank you.
Presented cyanotic
and rigor mortis.
Administered
Diazepam and Valium.
So, Mr. Martín,
it appears Patricia's
brain convinced her heart
that she was dead, even
though she was very much alive.
We are going to perform
a few tests to find out why.
In the meantime,
you and I are
going to talk. Talk?
Talk about your life together,
how you met, how you live.
What does that have to do
with what happened to her?
Everything.
Get a resuscitation team.
Give me a bio. ER
NURSE: Respiration shallow.
Okay, give me a CBC, BMP,
chem 7, and a saline lock.
Anybody know who this is? I
found a boarding pass in his pocket.
Stop.
Everyone back
away from the patient.
Masks on, now.
This is Max.
We have a patient in the ED
from Liberia presenting
with all the signs of malaria,
Lassa fever, TB, or...
Ebola.
First thing we do is call the
Mayor's office and the CDC
if we even suspect Ebola virus.
Now, the patient is in
an isolation chamber
with negative pressure airflow.
That chamber is equipped
with every available medicine
should the patient
need to self-medicate.
What about us?
Ebola isn't airborne,
but if you develop
symptoms, you will join him.
Until then, you will help him.
Everyone interacting
with the patient is required
to wear personal protective
equipment at all times.
No shortcuts ever.
Good.
Once blood is drawn, the
test results will come back
in 24 to 48 hours.
Commencing a code green blood draw
at 1:10 p.m., New Amsterdam Hospital.
Your husband said you
are taking Haloperidol.
For two years.
For depression.
And last year, you were
diagnosed with Parkinson's.
Does any of it explain
what is happening to me?
Not yet.
I'm going to run some
more tests, and hopefully...
More tests? But she's in pain,
and she's not
getting any better.
Mr. Martín, I need some more
information before I can make a diagnosis.
How can you not do
something for her?
Shh.
We are going to do something.
We are going to keep talking.
Where are my glasses?
Thank you.
Whoa, whoa.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
What's the problem?
I demand doctor. He
wants to be discharged.
Dr. Chen needs
him for observation.
Mr. Ambassador, I'm Dr. Goodwin.
I am the new medical director here,
and I am officially discharging you.
Ah. Thank you.
Before you go, can you just translate
one thing for your security detail?
What?
Since you're being released early
and against the wishes of your doctor,
they should look for any signs of
lethargy, brain damage, cardiac arrest,
sudden loss of
consciousness, and, of course,
rectal bleeding.
Mr. Ambassador?
Maybe I stay.
Can I have our menus back?
Hey. Welcome back.
I heard you got promoted.
Right after I got fired.
Lord works in mysterious ways.
She does, doesn't she?
A patient from Rikers
was admitted with 17 lacs.
Ruptured spleen, aortic tear.
We got him stable in the
ED, but the tear is all you.
Okay. You wanna
grab a drink tomorrow?
I can't.
You know when I say "grab
a drink," I don't actually...
Yes, I do.
Okay.
Wait. You're not trying to...
Look, Lauren.
I think you're great.
Oh, wow. You are
trying to. Okay, I...
I guess I'd rather us
just be friends again.
You know, colleagues.
But I thought we...
We did.
And I thought you... I do.
So then why not
see where this goes?
I wish I could. I
really do, but I can't.
Because?
Because...
Hey, I'm a big
girl. I can take it.
What?
Because you're not black.
Gate!
Hands. Thank you.
Hands, hands. Thank you.
Hands, hands...
Jemma.
You know pens and pencils aren't
allowed outside the classroom.
The pen's attached
to my journal. Okay.
You'll have to give
me the journal, then.
No.
You'll get it back
in the morning.
It's mine. Jemma,
give me the journal.
Jemma, don't do this.
Jemma.
Please... But it's mine!
Let me go! It's mine! It's mine!
Dr. Frome told me that
he gave you that journal
when you were 10.
It's mine.
Can I ask why you pushed...
It's the only thing that's mine.
Jemma,
what do you want to happen?
Jemma.
What do you want to happen?
Nobody's ever
asked me that before.
Do you want to stay here, Jemma?
Do you want to stay
at New Amsterdam?
Well, would you like me to get you
placed in a new home by Social Services?
Just decide for me. I mean,
you're gonna do it anyway.
That's not true. That... No.
Hey, Jemma.
Keep it.
Like, what's the point?
Return them to baseline and
put them through the system.
That's my job.
Look.
If you can't help
Jemma as a doctor,
then just help her
as a human being.
Am I allowed to do that?
You are now.
Dr. Goodwin?
How can I help?
Dr. Kapoor's patient in 1208.
You wanted to be
kept in the loop?
Yes, thank you. How's she doing?
I think Dr. Kapoor
is going to kill her.
Max.
This is Detective
Rose from the NYPD
and Agent Bratton from the FBI.
The CDC alerted us to
your patient with Ebola.
We're still waiting on the test
results. I'll be with you in five minutes.
The NSA just intercepted
a video made by ISIS.
They claim they sent
one of their followers
from Liberia to New York City,
infected with the Ebola virus.
Your patient is now
a terror suspect.
A man came to my village.
What was his name?
Ayaan.
Last name?
I don't know.
He was showing off
money he made in America
from selling kufi hats and
dashikis in Times Square.
He offered to give
me clothes to sell
and a plane ticket if I give
him half of what I make.
And you believed him.
Yes.
He took me to doctor
for traveler's vaccination.
Alain, where did Ayaan want
you to go when you got to America?
Youth hostel in Times Square.
Then why did you come here?
This is the only hospital
in America I heard of.
He's not a terrorist.
We'll gather the evidence.
If he was a terrorist, he would
have gone to Times Square,
where he could have
infected the entire city,
but he didn't. He
came here to get better.
He was clearly tricked
into getting something
injected into his bloodstream.
You see that, right?
Dr. Goodwin... Just
please promise me
you will look into his story.
I'll look into it.
What does that even
mean? Because I'm not black.
Patient is stable in case
you were wondering.
Oh, good.
So are you gonna
answer my question?
I'm 35 years old. I
want to get married,
I wanna have kids, and
I want them to be black.
You know you can't just
order that off a menu, right?
Well, yeah, but I also know
I'm not gonna meet anyone
if you and I are...
Getting our swirl on?
Look, I don't expect
you to understand.
I'm sorry, okay?
I want to. I do.
I have this plan for how I
want my life to look, all right?
I have for a long time, and
that plan's important to me.
So what part of the plan was
taking me back to your place and...
Whoa, whoa, hey. Look,
okay. It wasn't, all right?
But when I was with
you, I forgot I had a plan.
No, sorry. I still
don't understand.
Well, I guess that's
the point, right?
You can't. You can't understand
how confusing it was growing up,
watching every black athlete
have a white girl on his arm,
or how betrayed
black women felt,
my mom, my sisters, watching
it happen time and again.
I get it. You're just
taking one for the team.
I love black women.
So do I.
But I don't see one
asking you out for a drink.
I asked you to keep
me in the loop on 1208.
I needed to conduct
thorough patient...
I'm taking the patient
out of your service.
Because?
Because you should have
made a presumptive diagnosis.
aggressively treated the Parkinson's.
Except she doesn't
have Parkinson's.
PET scan.
Small black flecks
over her heart.
Artifacts.
Look closer.
Two years ago, Patricia was
misdiagnosed with depression.
She was prescribed Haloperidol,
which caused stiffness... Right.
As the result, she was misdiagnosed
with Parkinson and prescribed Levodopa,
which made it
impossible for her to sleep.
So she was
prescribed hydroxyzine.
That toxic combination caused
both cardiac arrest and rigidity.
But this whole time, her true symptom
was her immune system fighting a tumor
which nobody could see.
Small black flecks.
Malignant thymoma. Yeah.
If I continued treating
her for Parkinson's,
she would have another
cardiac arrest and died.
By taking my time,
by slowing down,
I bought her another year.
Maybe two.
How can I help?
When she wakes up,
you can help me tell
her she's going to die.
Well, move Sugarman
to Wednesday,
and I'll do Hinkle via
Skype from the hotel.
Just make sure I
have his updated...
Ron.
Ron, I said JFK. Why are
we back at New Amsterdam?
Hi. Remember me?
You told my driver to
bring me back here?
No, I told our driver
to bring you back here
because Ron works for New
Amsterdam, and so do you, remember?
If I miss my flight...
You can keep your job.
Why do you care
about me so much?
Because you're a good doctor.
Because you bring in patients
who would otherwise never go
to a public hospital,
which helps pay
for the patients who
can't go anywhere else.
So it's about money.
It's about care,
which is why I can't figure out
why'd you'd rather give lectures
to semi-retired physicians than
actually provide care to patients.
I'll see you next week.
Come back in 48 hours,
or don't come back at all.
Blanca?
Hi. Dr. Frome from
New Amsterdam.
Hi. Thank you so
much for meeting me.
I brought you donuts.
I ate one already. I'm sorry.
I actually ate two. I don't
know why I said one. That's...
I have to be at work soon, so
I don't... Yeah. No, of course.
I wanted you to see this.
It's a journal from the patient I
was telling you about. Jemma?
Normally, there'd
be privacy issues,
but, uh, you know, this is
the one thing that Jemma kept
from foster home to foster home.
And, uh, one of those homes
was actually your mother's.
Camilla, right? That
was her name? Camilla?
Well, Camilla was the first foster
parent to really make Jemma feel safe.
You know, safe to grow
and safe to be a kid, really.
And after Camilla died,
Jemma wrote pages and pages
about her in here. You can read.
My mother and I were
estranged when she died.
I didn't even know
she took in foster kids.
Oh.
I was a tough kid to
raise. Stubborn, wild.
Left when I was 16.
You know, that sounds a lot like
Jemma. Tough, but she's got a big heart...
I can't be her foster parent
if that's what this is about.
I'm sorry. This was a
long shot. I know that.
Thank you for meeting
me. I really do appreciate it.
Can I just leave this with you?
You don't have to
get it back to me.
I'll come back
and pick it up later,
but can I just
leave it with you?
Why?
I think that you'll see that
your mother gave Jemma
all the love that she
couldn't give to you.
That love didn't go to waste.
I don't understand.
I never had Parkinson's?
And the depression?
Hormones from your tumor.
They triggered your immune system
and set off a cascade of symptoms.
Patricia,
your mind is
strong and resilient.
I'm sorry you were led
to believe otherwise.
Mrs. Martín,
you could stay here,
but, in this case, the treatment
is worse than the disease.
And with so little time,
maybe there's someplace
else you'd rather be.
No, we stay here. We
fight. She get better.
No.
I want to go home.
To see my parents,
my girls.
I haven't seen them in 11 years.
That's a wonderful idea.
We can't go home.
Home is Chiapas.
We crossed the
border without papers.
We cross back,
we will be arrested.
I have to go home.
Mr. Ambassador?
Yes. Can I ask a favor?
Of course. You need
some Yankees tickets?
I need you to repatriate
two of your citizens.
Hemoptysis! He's crashing!
Can someone help me in my suit?
Alain! Alain, you need
to grab the oxygen mask!
Alain!
Alain, it is right above you.
Helmet, now!
Forget it.
I'm going in.
Dr. Bloom, wait.
Okay.
Bloom!
Get out of there, now!
Too late! I'm already in!
There's too much blood,
I can't see anything.
Heart rate is dropping.
He needs adrenaline.
I can't stop bagging.
Adrenaline first,
oxygen after, okay?
Go.
Okay, now push
10 mls. Open wide.
But that's too much.
Not for this kind of virus.
It'll send his
heart rate too high.
Push 10 hard
and fast, right now.
Lauren.
I know what you're
gonna say. That was...
That was stupid. I
violated the protocol.
Lauren.
Your glove.
Doctor.
Sorry, I can't talk right now.
There's something wrong
with the baby. Oh, my God.
She's bleeding.
I need a trans-abdominal
ultrasound, mag sulfate, four grams, IV.
BP 160 over 110.
How we doing with that second...
Draw a chem 24 and coag panel.
Let's get the fetal monitor on.
How can I help? By
getting out of the way.
This is my wife.
And she needs you.
Off the O2. Off the O2.
One, two, three.
Baby's in distress. No...
No... MAX: I'm here.
I'm here. I got you.
Push 4 mag sulfate.
Max. No, no, just focus on me.
I'm right here.
Ultrasound's up.
She's complete
previa. What's that?
It means your placenta
is obstructing your cervix.
There's nowhere
for the baby to go.
Corticosteroids and a unit of
O-negative, and type and cross.
This is because of me.
You did nothing wrong.
It's my fault.
Georgia, if we can't
control the bleeding,
we're going to need to do an
emergency caesarean, understand?
The baby is not
ready. She's not ready.
We're not gonna have a choice.
Is she still bleeding?
Bleeding's slowed down.
I still want a transfusion, and
someone tell me baby's heart rate.
I can't find it. What?
I can't find the
baby's heartbeat.
Suzanne?
Come on. It's okay.
Suzanne...
Where are you?
There you are,
baby girl. Oh, God.
Looking good.
It's okay.
Does baby have a name yet?
Luna.
When you try your best
but you don't succeed
When you get what you
want but not what you need
When you feel so
tired but you can't sleep
Stuck in reverse
Dr. Frome?
And the tears come
streaming down your face
When you lose
something you can't replace
Lights will guide you home
And ignite your bones
And I will try to fix you
And the tears come
streaming down your face
When you lose something...
Mija...
Lights will guide you home
And ignite your bones
And I will try to fix you
Alain, that shot they
gave you in Liberia,
they might have thought
it was Ebola, but it wasn't.
It was the Lassa virus,
which is just as deadly,
except, as Dr. Bloom
can tell you,
the Lassa virus can be
treated with antiviral medication,
which we gave you.
Tears stream down your face
Nice job, Dr. Bloom.
You wanna grab a drink?
Seriously? Now?
I'm talking about a
nice glass of scotch.
What are you talking about?
Yeah. Yeah, I could use a drink.
Lights will guide you home
And I will try...
Dr. Sharpe.
I hope I'm not interrupting.
No, no, I was just, um...
My sister was here,
in this room, a long time
ago, and I was just, uh,
introducing her to someone.
I, um...
I saw the Farmer's Market.
Oh, yeah? Did you buy anything?
Couldn't. They were sold out.
Hmm.
Made a few changes
while you were gone.
I didn't think you
were coming back.
Neither did I.
So much death here.
Got to you, didn't it?
No, actually. I became immune
to it, which is even worse.
So why did you come back?
Because of you.
People are excited, Max.
For the first time in a long time,
they are excited to be doctors again.
I wanna be excited too.
But you need to slow down.
Yeah.
I get that a lot.
You have cancer.
Squamous cell carcinoma.
But you knew that, didn't you?
How can I help?