"I Had a terrible day."
We say it all the time.
A fight with the
boss, the stomach flu,
traffic...
Okay, try and breathe for me.
I'm trying.
Okay, okay.
That's what we
describe as terrible
when nothing
terrible is happening.
Okay, okay. You're
gonna be okay.
Let's get a good line in him.
Okay, and where is X-ray?
Get them in here, stat.
He hasn't been having
trouble with his VHL.
No tumors since...
When was your
last CT? It was June.
Dr. Webber did a full workup.
Okay, then let's page
Dr. Webber, please.
Right away, Doctor.
His veins are shot.
Let's go ahead and
put in a central line.
We're gonna put a line in
so we can give you IV fluids.
Once we get the X-ray back,
we should have a better
idea of what's going on.
We got him. Okay?
Yeah. Yeah.
All right.
Okay, well, what about the eye?
Good. We'll be waiting.
Okay.
Oh, hey, Avery. We got a kid
with half his face torn off by a dog,
so can you get Sloan
and meet me outside?
And see if Shepherd's still
here, 'cause we may need him.
Okay.
Dr. Robbins.
You're popular tonight.
Hey, this is Robbins.
Right now?
Where?
That was pathetic. Shut up.
She told you to
go screw yourself.
We could hear it all
the way over here.
It's not 'cause
she wasn't into me.
Oh. Does "go screw yourself"
have some secret meaning
we're not aware of?
I kinda already knew
her. I just didn't remember.
You slept with her
before and forgot about it,
and then tried to pick
her up all over again?
You're not even drinking.
I have a history of
Alzheimer's in my family.
What's your excuse?
It's O'Malley's fault. I mean,
talking about dead people,
it throws me off
my game, that's all.
Mmm. Mmm.
It's Janet. Can you
pay for my thing?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Hey, hey, Janet. I gotta run.
Would you pay for mine?
No. I'm leaving. I'm
going to the skills lab.
Oh, come on.
She had the social
worker on the phone.
You can fish 20 bucks
out of your pocket.
I want to see you for
a follow-up next week.
And listen, I know Drew
is a kid with a lot of energy,
but we just put a bunch
of screws in your back,
so you gotta take it
easy for a few weeks.
And I am not kidding
about physical therapy.
You're gonna need all
the support you can get
to keep up with that little one.
I'm gonna do it. I really am.
You feelin' okay?
I still kinda like
the idea of keeping
you here another day.
No, it's been three days.
You know, it's hard on
Drew. He needs his mom.
I just want to get home.
Okay.
Mommy! Hey, sweetheart!
Hey! Hi.
How are you? Hey,
careful with Mommy, okay?
No bending.
Hi, sweetheart. Hey.
Oh, I missed you so much.
Oh!
You all right?
Yeah, just stitches.
Okay.
Hey, Drew.
I am gonna need you to
be really gentle with Mommy
for a few days, okay?
Okay. All right. Okay.
All right, guys.
Call me if you need
anything, okay?
We will. Thank you so much.
Anytime. Bye.
What did Janet say?
Meredith?
We're not getting her back.
What do you mean?
What exactly did she say?
That we're not getting her back.
She said that?
She said that the court
canceled our hearing date.
And when they do that, it
means either one of two things.
That they looked at our file,
and they love us and
they're giving her to us,
in which case, they call
Janet and they tell her that,
or that they hate us
and they're giving
her to another family.
And she didn't get
the "they love us" call.
Well, maybe they
didn't get around to it.
She said we should move on.
That's what she said.
You want to know
her exact words,
were "I think it's time that you and
Derek start thinking about moving on."
Oh, my God.
Oh, God. How can they do this?
You can cry. I
don't want to cry.
I know.
I'm never gonna see her again.
God.
Okay, stop. I don't want to cry.
Okay. I know.
Call up to CT. Tell 'em
we're on our way up.
Screw CT. And go straight
to the bronchoscope.
You need to find out
what is down there.
CT will clarify what
we're dealing with.
It won't delay anything,
and you're not his doctor.
Richard is.
I hear he's good. I mean, I don't
know. He's new around here.
She doesn't like it
when I'm in the hospital.
Makes you wonder why she
married a guy with chronic illness.
Masochist. Call me
if you need anything.
I'm coming to CT.
I wouldn't have
it any other way.
Good.
Meredith is in the ER.
Look at this. Scalpels
from the 1860s.
I want to get 'em for Meredith.
She needs to talk to you.
Oh, can you distract
her? It's on eBay,
and I got 25 minutes
left on the auction.
Derek, Janet called.
The baby was born
a couple of hours ago,
and it looks like a
tracheoesophageal fistula.
You know what that is?
Yeah, it's the connection between
the trachea and esophagus.
Fills the lungs with secretions.
Baby can have a hard
time breathing and feeding.
Exactly. Bentley Hospital
is tiny. They can't handle it.
So you need to go pick
up the baby, bring her back,
and then hopefully,
I'm done with the kid
that's on his way in
by the time you're back.
You need to reconfigure
the ambulance
for intensive
neonatal transport.
And I think you should
get someone else to go...
Grey, ride with Karev.
He's on a baby run.
Well, I have to talk to Derek.
Well, newborn life hanging
in the balance. Make it fast.
10-year-old male,
dog bite to the face.
Vital signs stable in the field.
All right, trauma three.
Laura.
Hey, Dr. Avery.
Honey, this is my guy.
You must be Griffith.
Yeah.
And Drew.
Hey, your mom said
that you were a kid,
but you are almost
as tall as me.
You're not that tall.
So, listen, thanks so much
for taking such good care of her.
My pleasure. How you feelin'?
Just ready to go home.
Okay, but you make
sure to give me a page
when you come in for
a follow-up, all right?
Nice to meet you. Okay.
I see what you mean
about those eyes.
If I weren't such
a confident guy,
I might have to, like, challenge
him to a duel or something.
Honey.
Can we get some help, please?
Maybe there's an appeal
process. Did you ask?
I didn't.
You talk to the lawyer?
I just got off the
phone with Janet.
We'll appeal. We'll sue
the agency if we have to.
They don't think we should
be Zola's parents, Derek.
They don't think
I'm trustworthy,
and they're not the first
ones to raise that concern.
Meredith.
They don't think I
should be Zola's mother.
She's gone.
It's gonna be okay.
We're gonna find a way.
Zola was our baby,
and she's gone and I
don't want another baby.
She's barely got any
pulse. What was she in for?
A thoracic spinal
fusion to fix her scoliosis.
Dr. Torres just released
her, and she was doing fine.
Okay, heart sounds are
muffled. Let's call Altman.
She's not protecting her
airway. I'm gonna intubate.
Is she okay? Sir,
there's a waiting room.
What's happening?
Take your son out of here.
We will let you
know when we know.
We're gonna need the ultrasound,
and somebody find Torres.
Right away.
They can put on some music.
No, I'll just take a nap.
You're gonna be fine.
You know that, right?
I do.
Good.
I just wish I hadn't
spent the day
trying to kill your
hopes and dreams.
You know, that's why I
started spitting up blood,
so I'd win.
I'm happy to have you
go to medical school.
You don't have to be happy.
No, I am. I'm not...
I love med students.
I'll help you study.
You'll be my study buddy?
I'll make you flash cards.
That's so hot, I'm not
sure I can even handle it.
It'll be fun.
It's your worst nightmare.
Yeah. Whatever.
We'll figure it out. Mmm-hmm.
Don't move.
Where's Bailey?
Henry doesn't need both of us,
and we all agreed that
you'd be less of a hassle
with the former
Chief of Surgery.
Nice. You're nice people.
So are you planning to
get a look with contrast
or just the non-contrast study?
Which would you prefer?
Both.
Um, can you get
some contrast ready?
Got it. Thanks.
Are you kidding me?
The ER. Owen wants a consult.
Well, go ahead. It'll
take five minutes,
and we don't both need to
stand here watching the CT load.
Are you sure?
If you're not back in five, I'll find
you as soon as the film comes up.
You will?
I said I would, didn't I?
Thank you.
Oh.
Look at that.
What the hell happened?
That's what I was gonna
ask you. She's in shock and...
It looks like her
pericardium's full of blood.
She just had spinal
surgery. Why would she...
I was hoping you
would answer that.
She's arresting.
Uh...
All right. I'm gonna
do a thoracotomy.
Open up a chest tray.
Kepner, prep the chest.
You're gonna crack her
chest? She's not a trauma.
Yes, but she's dying.
It's probably a mistake.
You know, courts...
They screw up all the time.
You call 'em in the morning...
It's over, Alex.
It's been over for a
while. Everyone knew it.
No one wants to say it.
So get a surrogate or whatever.
You can't just write off
having a family like that.
Get Yang to carry a kid for you.
She gets knocked
up at the drop of a...
If you don't shut up in
the next three seconds,
I'm gonna shove you
out of the back of the rig.
What the hell is happening?
What do we got? I
had to open her up.
Her pericardium
is full of blood.
Ton of clots. Gunshot?
No, she had spinal
fusion three days ago.
What?
I don't know. She has no history
of heart disease
or risk factors.
This is crazy. Could it be
a retrograde dissection?
No, I don't think so.
She has no history of Marfan's
or aortic widening on X-ray.
Her heart's beating again.
All right, let's get
her upstairs now.
Throw a sterile towel
on her and move.
All right, people. Let's go.
I don't need you
in there. I'm good.
Okay. Well, she's my patient.
Did you cut her heart
open in your spinal fusion?
No. Then, she's my patient.
All right, Henry's in CT.
Somebody tell Webber where I am.
Hold on.
Teddy!
Right there. The bronchus.
Judging by the ossification,
probably a carcinoid tumor.
Because of his tumor condition?
Yeah, he's bleeding in
his lungs and trachea.
Lexie's prepping him.
We're gonna take it out.
You're gonna bronch
him and use a laser?
I was planning to open him up.
Take out the lung, resect
the tumor, put it back in.
A laser is less invasive, and
the recovery time is much faster.
I hear that, but I've never
done one with a laser.
What?
Not for this kind of procedure.
And I don't want my first
one to be on your husband.
Well, I...
Um...
I think we should
get another surgeon.
Cristina. No. Come on.
Taylor is on vacation.
Goldman is 45 minutes away.
I did an endobronchial
tumor with Cristina last week
with a laser.
I barely did a
thing. She did it all.
We've done three
in the last year.
Teddy, it's just
too much pressure.
Now, she's a resident,
it's her mentor's husband.
She's a machine. She
doesn't care if it's my husband.
No, she's not, and
we can get Rudzki.
Rudzki's an ass,
and he's sloppy.
Gown.
I think we should reconsider
having Webber do this.
I don't have anything to prove.
If I'm not state-of-the-art,
have Yang do it.
There's no question,
Henry's on his feet
faster if we don't open him up.
Cristina doesn't have
to know that it's Henry.
Drape his face, don't
show her the chart,
give her a verbal history.
You put a bronchoscope
and a laser in her hand,
she's not gonna ask for the
guy's name and a family photo.
She is gonna cut.
You really think
this is a good idea?
Look, I'll be there
the whole time.
If she has trouble, I'll go in and
open him up the old-fashioned way.
Lap sponges, please.
Owen? Is he scowling?
Yeah. So am I.
I don't like it either.
Frankly, the only thing
that I'd be comfortable with
is doing it myself.
But since we all know that
that's not gonna happen,
the next closest thing is Yang.
She is the only one who
will do it the way I would.
Fine.
What'd he say?
He said, "Fine." Thank you.
Richard, watch her like a hawk.
If she screws this up, you're
gonna have to take out half his lung.
And the last thing I need is to
have to explain to my husband
why that happened.
I'll watch her.
Cautery. Keep suctioning.
You gotta get some
of those clots out.
Okay. Good.
Hey, we're here to pick up a
newborn, take her to Seattle Grace.
You're looking for me.
I'm Jordan Wagner. I am
really glad to see you guys.
Yeah, I'm Alex
Karev. Meredith Grey.
Okay. Listen, she
was born six hours ago,
right away, trouble breathing.
Stomach looked distended,
so we put down an NG tube.
But the X-ray showed that it
was just coiling in her chest.
We've done everything we
can to keep her breathing,
but it's been a struggle.
You don't have a neonatal mask?
We're not set up
for neonatal or OB.
She was an emergency delivery,
otherwise, we would've sent
her to the hospital in Leavenworth.
Pulse ox is 79.
Respiratory rate is 80.
She's got retractions.
How come she's not intubated?
The smallest tube
we had didn't fit.
Please tell me that you
brought a neonatal tube.
We're gonna need X-ray in
here for a post-intubation film.
This IV's no good.
Yeah, you don't even have
a neonatal central line kit.
No.
IO needle?
You will not call
Dr. Yang into the OR
until Henry is
intubated and draped.
You will make sure to
drape every inch of his face.
You will give a verbal history,
and you will simply
omit the patient's name.
But Dr. Webber's
gonna be in there?
Yes. And he knows?
He knows, you know.
Dr. Yang does not.
Can you handle this?
You sure?
Yeah. I mean, I'm gonna
be wearing a mask, right?
I mean, as long as I don't
start giggling, then we're fine.
Mmm-hmm.
She doesn't want
any kids at all?
Zola was her baby. She
doesn't want another baby.
She'll come around. She's
upset. Give her some time.
I don't know.
Look, if it doesn't work out,
you can always share Sofia.
There's three of us parenting
her already. It kinda works.
No one gets too exhausted,
you're not on every night.
We can work you
into the rotation.
She's a baby. She's
not a time-share in Cabo.
You're closed-minded.
That's your problem.
That's my problem?
Avery.
What's the deal?
Nose is hanging off and
a lot of soft tissue loss.
Probably nerve damage.
I'll let you know when
Dr. Robbins is ready for you.
It's Karev.
How's it going?
The kid's septic.
She's got pneumonia.
Was she intubated
when you got there?
Yeah, well, they don't have
any neonatal stuff here at all.
We intubated, we
started an umbilical line
to hang D10 normal
saline and antibiotics.
But her SATs aren't coming up,
and all the oxygen's
going into her stomach.
You're gonna need to
put in an Amplatz umbrella.
They don't have a 3-0 ET tube.
You think they're
gonna have an Amplatz?
All right. Elevate her head.
All right. Get her head up.
All right, do they have
a Fogarty catheter?
They use those on grown-ups.
A Fogarty catheter?
Yeah, what else?
You're gonna have to thread
the Fogarty down her trachea,
pretty far down, then
blow up the balloon
and pull up until
you get traction.
That'll occlude the fistula and
get the air flowing into the lungs.
You're gonna have to keep the
blind pouch clear on your way back.
And I'm not sure
you have anything
in your box that's
gonna do that.
Uh, how about an 8
French suction catheter?
Yeah, that'll work.
Got it. All right.
We're gonna call you
when we get to the rig.
Hey, Alex. You don't have a
lot of time. You know that, right?
Yeah, I know that.
Look at that.
There's a huge tear
in the left ventricle.
Can you repair it?
No, it's too big. We're
gonna have to go on bypass.
Dr. Altman, I've
got your husband.
Oh, good.
Henry. Hey, babe.
I am so sorry.
This woman's heart is
spouting like a fountain
for no apparent reason.
That sounds like fun.
Well, if there was any way I
could get out of here, I would.
Stop worrying about it.
You can hold my hand
in post-op. You were such a wuss
before my last surgery, it's
probably a good thing anyway.
Yeah, that wasn't my best work.
We're an old married couple now.
You don't have to
drive me to the airport.
walk me to the OR.
Well, I still want
rides to the airport.
That's 'cause you're
high maintenance.
You know it.
Look, I'll see you after.
Henry, don't ask
for extra morphine
just 'cause you like the dreams.
Get back to work. Love you.
Yeah, you, too.
I'm good.
More sponges, please.
There aren't enough
sponges in the world.
Suction.
Must be hard for
her to be in the OR
and not here with you.
Can I tell you something
kind of embarrassing?
Yeah.
I want to go to med school.
That's not embarrassing.
I wouldn't exactly be the
youngest kid in my class.
Yeah, but you'll be mature.
You'll have perspective.
None of us had
that in our class.
Teddy's not crazy
about the idea.
We kinda had
a big fight about it right
before all this happened.
Well, she might need some
time to get used to the idea.
None of this is very
easy on relationships.
You seem to do okay.
Jackson, right? He's great.
Yeah. Though we're
not together anymore.
Oh. Um, Mark Sloan?
We're not together either.
So who's gonna
be operating on me?
Dr. Webber?
I don't know.
Hey. Teddy's got a patient
with an endobronchial carcinoid.
She wants you
to take care of it.
Now? Yes.
Why can't she do it herself?
Well, she's working on a woman
who almost bled out in the ER.
So, she can't do it.
Well, how about Goldman?
She's giving you a chance to
fly solo on a major procedure.
I know, but we just
did a similar one.
I basically handled
the whole thing myself
while she planned the
menu for what sounded like
a really boring brunch.
And I'm supposed to do my
first Bentall procedure tomorrow.
It's from my bucket list.
I'm practicing the
steps. You want to see?
Okay, drop the damn
suture and go scrub. All right?
Okay. Relax.
This better be fast. I
want to be fresh tomorrow.
Cristina, this is emergent.
Yeah, I'm going.
I'm just saying, I'm
glad she likes me,
but if she's gonna call me
every time she has a procedure
she doesn't feel like doing...
I mean, I'm not her valet.
Maybe it's not the end.
You'll call the
lawyers in the morning.
And maybe there's something
else you guys can do.
Meredith didn't want kids.
I pushed her. She
opened herself up.
Now, I feel like
I did this to her.
She wanted it, too,
or it wouldn't have happened.
She'll blame me,
like I've been blaming her.
We lost Zola, and
now if I lose Meredith...
She always comes back.
She might need a
minute to back away, but
she comes back.
Try this patch on the tear.
We're gonna have
to cut it to size.
Hang on.
Sorry. My glove is
stuck on something.
I'm taking my hand out.
What happened?
There's a hole in my glove.
You're kidding.
Can we get Dr. Kepner
a new glove, please?
Right away.
Did it break the skin?
No. I think I'm fine.
Here you go. Thanks.
My God.
What the hell is that?
Dr. Yang.
We just started
the bronchoscopy.
Looking forward
to seeing your work.
Hopefully I'll learn
a thing or two.
It's an honor, sir.
Uh, 35-year-old male,
endobronchial carcinoid tumor
presented with
active hemoptysis.
He's been given two liters
LR and a unit of packed cells.
Okay.
So we'll resect
with the CO2 laser.
Is it ready to go?
Yes.
You know, I think
I'm gonna time myself.
Last time I did
this, it took me, like,
two and a half
hours, skin to skin.
That's too long.
I think I get hypnotized when I
watch that laser or something.
We should be able to get
it down to, like, two hours.
Let's start the
timer for Dr. Yang.
Okay, laser, please.
Is that them?
Wait. I'm coming with you.
Dana?
Why is she out here?
She said if I didn't
take her, she'd walk.
I was afraid she'd try it.
Please let me come with her.
Dana, you just had surgery,
and you've lost a lot of blood.
I'll be fine. Please.
I need you to take
care of yourself.
These guys, they're the best.
She is in great hands.
Please.
She's my baby.
We're supposed to be together.
I can't leave her.
She's so little.
Please.
I have to be with her.
Please let me go with her.
I'm Dr. Grey. And
that's Dr. Karev.
And we're gonna
take your daughter
to the best baby
surgeon there is.
She doesn't even
have a name yet.
Well, you're gonna give her
one when you come to Seattle
and hold her in your arms.
And until that time, I'm
gonna take care of her.
You hear me?
I have her.
Okay?
What happened?
Show her the tray.
That's the screw that I just
pulled out of your patient.
It was stabbing her heart,
slicing into cardiac muscle
every time the heart tried to beat.
This thing looks like
hamburger meat right about now.
Oh, my God.
You want to tell me
how this happened?
You know, why not
try adoption again?
Social services just
took our kid away.
What do you think, if we
wait a week, they'll forget
and give us another
try with a new kid?
All right. So get a surrogate.
Alex. Why not?
Because I don't
want a surrogate.
Okay? Just drop it.
No. You just don't
give up like that.
It's nice that you care, but it
really isn't any of your business.
It is. It's my fault.
I can't handle being responsible
for you not having kids.
It's too much.
It's not your fault.
Yeah, it is.
No, it's my fault.
I got the ball rolling. I
messed with the trial.
What you did was turdy,
but what I did was illegal.
Who cares? You
just don't give up.
It's lame. You're not a
quitter. That's not who you are.
Dude, what's the problem?
I'm kind of in the
middle of a surgery.
No, here's what
you're in the middle of.
The surgery on Laura Lewis,
where I supervised you
inserting pedicle screws
and a plate to
stabilize T6 to T8?
Yeah?
One of them's
stabbing her in the heart.
She's half dead,
and we're about to
go tell her husband.
So using a laser's
not much different
than a normal
bronchoscopic resection?
Uh, yes.
You just have to
be extra careful
with hidden vascular structures
when using this
high a level of energy.
But you're forming
an eschar as you go,
so the blood's
coagulating along the way.
Pretty much.
That is pretty handy.
Okay. What happened?
Ugh! I must have
nicked a vessel.
Pressure's dropping.
Okay, so I'm giving
it more irrigation.
Ah, the whole field's obscured.
What happened to the engine?
I don't know
what the crap it is.
I called for another unit, but
we're in the middle of nowhere.
It's gonna take forever.
I'm putting these out,
and I'm gonna run back.
It looked like there was a store
or something about
half a mile back.
Maybe they got a truck.
You gotta get out of the rig.
It's pouring rain and freezing.
We can't go out
there with the baby.
There's no shoulder. It's not like
we can just take the incubator out.
I mean, there's not
even anywhere to stand.
This thing is full
of oxygen tanks.
We get hit, it'll go up
like a Roman candle.
You gotta get out.
And leave the baby?
She'll die. You want to all die?
I'm putting these out. You
better hope people can see 'em.
You're on a hill and
you're on a curve.
I'm telling you, get
out the damn rig.
Hey, you need some help?
Why?
Well, his pressure dropped out.
Oh, there was a
nick in an artery.
I cauterized, and his
pressure came back up.
Okay, but what if it
was a carcinoid crisis?
Uh, I doubt it.
But if his pressure
drops out again,
I'll think about a
dose of octreotide.
Cristina... I'm on a clock,
and you're wasting my
time. What is your problem?
Cristina, there's a
patient on the table.
Let go of the clock and
focus on what you're doing.
I am focused.
I'd focus a whole lot better
if you weren't standing
here with your pants on fire.
We've got it, Dr. Hunt.
Apparently, one of the screws
we placed in her spine came loose.
It could be that the bone isn't
strong enough to hold the screw.
But at this point,
we don't know.
Okay, and so what, it just...
And so, the screw,
it cut into her heart?
Dr. Altman's repairing
her heart right now,
and she's an incredible surgeon.
But we won't know for a while
exactly what the situation is.
Situation? I don't understand.
Where's my mama?
Buddy.
Come here.
Look at that.
Very nice.
Right?
If I do say so myself.
Hang on. We've
got some bleeding.
Okay, you have some
clots blocking your scope.
Why don't you take out your
laser and pass a brush through it?
Okay. Okay.
SATs are down to 88.
Okay, I'm gonna
have to open him up.
Just let me just try this first.
Yang! Yang, you have blood
coming in through the ET tube.
Get outta there.
I can clear the field...
Get his chest ready,
Grey. We're going in.
Okay, okay, I'm pulling out.
10-blade.
Find all the films,
pre-op, post-op.
You go over every
inch of every image,
and assuming she survives, you
get a CT to check the hardware
and run a bone density test,
so we can get a clue as
to what the hell went wrong.
I, uh...
I'm so sorry. I have to
go, Dr. Torres. I'm sorry.
What?
Avery put pedicle screws in
a woman's spine this week,
and one of them turned out to be
tearing holes in
her left ventricle.
Whoa!
I can't even breathe right now.
Yeah, well, come
on. It's part of the deal.
We have to let students operate.
They don't always get it right.
I was reading a magazine.
Hey, come on.
Now don't beat
yourself up. We all do it.
I know what J.Lo wore
to the coffeehouse.
That's what I was doing. Shh.
Vascular clamp.
He is losing way too
much blood way too fast.
Okay, put the blood
on a rapid infuser
and get me another
two units up here.
Right away. He's
really bradycardic.
Okay, let's push
one atropine. Now.
Uh, hold on. Wait, wait, wait.
This tumor has eroded right
through the pulmonary artery.
Damn it.
Let me see.
Sir.
Okay. Let's clamp the hilum.
He's already lost half his blood
volume. This lung is like a sieve.
Give me bovie.
We're maxed out on
dopamine, maxed out on norepi.
Sir, I'm not sure
what we do next.
V-fib.
Okay, push one of epi. Now.
I'm gonna start compressions.
Let's get this outta here.
Come on, people.
Okay, here we go.
Come on.
Look at that.
His nose is gonna be perfect.
This is gonna be beautiful.
If you do say so yourself.
I offered to time-share
Sofia with Derek and Meredith
if they don't end up
with kids of their own.
He said, "No." Why?
Because your child
is not a rental car.
We're not gonna take
her out one week a month.
Have you seen her? 'Cause
she's heart-stoppingly adorable.
You're missing the point.
He's missing the point.
No, she's delicious.
She's addictive.
Why wouldn't you want
to parent her? I just find...
Ambulance broke down,
like, in the middle of the road.
They can't move.
They can't get out.
Did they send a backup?
It's coming, but it's slow.
Put her on speakerphone. Yeah.
Alex? ALEX: We can't move.
We're a friggin' sitting duck.
We... The...
All right, hold on. I can't
hear you. Say that again.
We gotta take the
baby out of here,
but the two of us can't
move the damn incubator
and all this crap on a highway.
Did you set up the flares?
Okay, leave the phone. See if
you can get a helicopter up there.
Yeah. Take this?
Sir, it's been 20 minutes.
There's no way that
heart's coming back.
Sir, there's no blood left to
circulate. I'm not sure what you're...
Um, time of death, 8:52 p.m.
There was no way to take
it out without killing him.
And there's no way
he could've lived with it
in him for much longer.
Well, I'll write the op note.
But if you can add a few
lines that make it clear
that I didn't come up
with the treatment plan.
It's a bad outcome,
and I don't want to take the
heat for it in my fifth-year boards.
It was Dr. Altman's idea.
Oh. Hey.
The tumor eroded right
through the pulmonary artery.
The guy bled right out.
We were done before we started.
Is there, um,
a family or something
we need to, uh, talk to?
Secure the umbilical
line with extra tape.
You need the D10.
Put the oxygen tank in the
holster and take the paramedic kit.
Get out of the rig.
Swaddle her so
that she stays warm.
We can't regulate...
What?
We can't regulate her
temp without the incubator.
They may have to leave the kid.
We are not leaving the baby.
At least one of you
should get out of the rig.
What are they
gonna do, flip a coin?
They're sitting in a powder keg.
Get out. Alex...
Go. There's no reason
for both of us to get killed.
Well, I'm not safer in the
middle of the damn road.
I'm telling you to get
out of the damn rig.
Alex, if you want to go, you go.
We're not gonna fix your guilt
by me letting you die in
an ambulance so that I...
Is it possible the bone was
intact when they closed, and then...
And what, it just fell apart
in the last couple of days?
I don't know how you don't check
if a vertebra is compromised
before you drop a screw in it.
Hey. How's it going with Henry?
They're done.
You almost finished here?
It's gonna be a while.
Torres missed a loose
screw in this woman's spine.
It tore apart her
whole left ventricle.
I've never seen anything
like it. I put in a patch.
I've still gotta reinforce
it with a muscle flap.
It's a mess.
Hey, will you check on Henry
and see if he's feeling okay?
I told him I would
be in post-op.
And I wasn't in
pre-op. I'm a bad wife.
I'll take over here.
You can go out.
All due respect, but
you are out of your depth.
Why does your
face look like that?
Uh, there was a... Ambulance
broke down on route 2,
so we lost contact.
Oh, I hope everyone's
all right. Route 2 at night?
Awful. Going over
those mountains?
So, Henry
wants to go to med
school. Can you believe it?
No.
I mean, I squashed
the idea like a bug,
which I feel awful about,
but I mean, come on.
I mean, a med
student at his age?
That's crazy, right? Or
am I just a terrible person?
No.
No, I'm not, or it's not crazy?
The patch isn't holding.
We cannot get a break here.
All right, let's try a pledget.
Check on him, let me know
how he's feeling, would you?
Yeah, of course.
And, you know, if you get bored,
I mean, you could mention
that med school is a long haul,
and, you know,
he may want to try
to get a degree
in something else.
And he's a real
stoner on Dilaudid.
So don't be surprised if
he compliments your eyes.
I just spoke to
emergency dispatch.
Another ambulance is coming now.
The cops are a few minutes out,
and the helicopter
wouldn't be any faster
since they leave
out of Skykomish.
Are we still on speaker or what?
We were talking to them, and
there was a loud noise and...
We lost them.
Avery,
Dr. Shepherd's gonna
put down his instruments,
and you're gonna
step in for him.
Fancy part's over. We'll
walk you through the rest.
Derek.
All right.
It's not right.
Who's gonna take over
in the middle of a bypass?
There's a woman on the table who
dies if Teddy walks out of that OR.
It's her husband, Richard.
Another hour isn't
gonna change anything.
Goldman's on his
way. Tell her then.
She's my friend.
You're not her friend right
now. You're the Chief of Surgery.
If she finds out that I waited,
she will never forgive me.
Her husband just died in our OR.
She'll never forgive any of us.
Hunt.
Meredith and Alex are
trapped in an ambulance
in the middle of
the highway. I know.
We just lost contact.
I think they got hit.
We need to get emergency
dispatch on the phone.
What is it?
What?
All right. The ventricular
laceration is still bleeding.
We need more volume.
We need some more
blood. Right away.
She's dropping again.
Come on, Laura. You
gotta pull it together.
Okay, good. There
we go, 90 over 60.
Good. Hello again.
How's he doing?
Uh, he's fine. Woozy.
Vitals are good.
Did they run a post-op CT?
Not yet.
But Cristina felt she
got clean margins?
Oh, yes.
Did she figure it out, who
she was operating on?
No.
See? I told you.
Sometimes her lack of interest
in the patient as a human being
can come in handy.
Did you mention the
med school thing to Henry?
No.
You're a coward.
You know, if you think you
are off the hook, you are wrong.
I mean, this could ruin the
next five to 10 years of my life.
You do understand that, right?
These are the things we beg for,
a root canal,
an IRS audit,
coffee spilled on our clothes.
When the really
terrible things happen,
we start begging a
god we don't believe in
to bring back the little horrors
and take away this.
Are you okay?
You're bleeding.
Mer, what are you doing?
Get me a blanket.
I'm taking her out.
Mer, put her back in.
She just got thrown
around a plastic box.
She needs to be held.
I'm not putting her back in.
Are you okay?
No, I'm not okay.
Mer, listen, we gotta get outta
here before this thing blows.
Well, how are we gonna do that?
She's connected
to a million things.
You got the bag and the baby.
I'll get the O2 tank and the IV.
And we're gonna disconnect
her from the antibiotics.
Is that gonna be okay?
Yeah. It's gonna have to be.
It seems quaint now, doesn't it?
The flood in the
kitchen, the poison oak,
the fight that leaves
you shaking with rage.
Would it have helped if we
could see what else was coming?
Would we have known that those
were the best moments of our lives?