Question:
when was the last
time a complete stranger
took off her clothes
in front of you,
pointed to a big purple
splotch on her back and asked,
- "What the hell
is this thing?"
-  OK. How about it, Mark?
You know you've always
wanted one of... these.
If you're a normal person,
the answer is, hopefully, never.
If you're a doctor, the
answer is probably,
- "About five minutes ago."
- Nah, I'm good.
- I will take that waffle iron.
- What?
I have never seen
you eat a waffle.
I would if I had a waffle iron.
Callie, we're not gonna
take a waffle iron to Malawi,
and it's not gonna do anybody any
good sitting in storage for three years.
People expect doctors
to have all of the answers.
Congratulations. You won
yourself a waffle iron. Oh!
- And a French press.
- Hey. Stop giving
my things away.
Maybe I should pass
on the French press.
The truth is
we love to think that we
have all of the answers, too.
So The Art & Lesley Phillips Foundation
has a few more hoops to jump through
than the others, but their primary
focus is Alzheimer's research.
And if you get this grant, it is
more than enough to get us started.
- You really did your homework.
- I'm a great student.
Just the kind you want around
when doing a clinical trial.
- How's that going?
- It's fine.
Is this because Richard gave
Hunt the million dollars and not me?
Is that why things are
frosty between you two?
We're not frosty. We're fine.
But if you're
looking for solidarity,
I would be more than
happy to skip Owen Hunt's
trauma certification lab.
- Go get certified.
- OK.
Basically, doctors
are know-it-alls.
Until something comes along
that reminds us we're not.
I need someone to help
me set up the trauma lab,
to keep things running smoothly.
You'd get your certification that way.
- And it's a pretty easy day.
- It's a skills lab.
- It's already an easy day.
- Dr. Hunt.
- I'm going to need
to borrow Dr. Yang.
- Oh. Uh, what's up?
Lungs have become
available for Roy Henley.
And since he found
himself on the transplant list
based on Dr. Yang's
recommendation, I would say
- that would make
him her patient.
- OK, what do you need me to do?
I just need someone to monitor
him while I go pick up the lungs.
- So I'll be on my own?
- Nope. Dr. McQueen,
cardio fellow,
he will be around on the off
chance that you need anything.
Oh, and I finally was able to get
Roy's daughter to agree to come in,
- so just keep
an eye out for her, OK?
- OK.
You'll be fine.
Still an easy day.
I know.
Am I early? I tried
really hard not to be.
- That doesn't bode well.
- We did the
same thing with Bailey
when we were interns.
Take turns treating a dummy,
get an early lunch, then
get back to work. It's lame.
A charter plane was forced
into an emergency landing,
and collided with a Greyhound
bus. Mass casualty situation.
Do we need to say
it again? Let's move!
Close to 30 victims in
the field, some critical,
multiple blunt trauma injuries.
I was so looking
forward to an early lunch.
This is gonna suck.
You're kidding me, right?
Welcome to trauma certification.
You will work in teams of four.
Each team will be
responsible for nine casualties.
You may treat your patients using only
what you can carry with your two hands
from this ambulance. The
evac helicopter is on its way.
You get your patients on the helicopter,
you get certified. Are you ready?
Get to work.
- Dr. Grey?
- Uh, Christy Cornell, age 28,
she's here for a gluteoplasty?
She's so tiny. There's
hardly anything there to lift.
That's sort of the
point, Dr. Grey.
I'm... I'm sorry. That was...
- Oh!
- I'm sorry.
Christy's not here for a lift.
She's here for
a gluteal implant.
Yes. I'm finally gonna get
some junk up in this trunk.
This program shows a rendering of what
you can expect the gluteus to look like
after the implant.
Oh... Um...
Could I see what it'd look
like kicked up a couple points?
Sure.
Mm... Couple more?
Couple more.
Stop. That's it.
That's my ass.
Come on, that was funny.
Any joke that starts with
an animal walking into a bar
is scientifically unfunny.
Humor me, Dr. Yang. I
need something to focus on.
I don't know if I'm more
nervous about getting new lungs
or about actually
seeing my daughter.
Don't think about it
as getting new lungs.
Think of it as getting
rid of old, crappy lungs.
Or don't think at all. OK,
Roy, take some deep breaths.
- Corinne?
- Roy.
- How ya been?
- This week,
or for the past 20 years?
I'm sorry. That was snarky.
No, snarky's good.
I like snarky. You
get that from me.
Roy? Roy!
Get the crash cart!
- He's not breathing!
- V-fib!
Page cardio.
Aren't you the
doctor? Do something!
Um... What's happening?
Your father's developed cor
pulmonale and his heart is overloading.
What? I-I don't understand. I
thought his lungs were the problem.
His lungs are putting
extra pressure on his heart.
Dr. Altman is picking up
the new lungs right now.
I'll call her and apprise
her of the situation.
What situation?
What is going on?
His heart is failing. And the
damage seems pretty severe.
So... uh, there's a possibility
- he'll need a new one.
- A new what?
A new heart?
You know what? Take over
here. I'm going to call Dr. Altman
and I'm gonna get McQueen.
Dr. Bailey, do you
have a second?
Only if what you have to
talk about is more important
- than my being
on time for an autopsy.
- It's arguable.
We're throwing Torres and
Robbins a bon voyage party
- in the doctors'
lounge this evening.
- That sounds lovely.
Uh, I have a full day,
but I'll try and stop by.
Well, the thing is, Altman
volunteered, uh, to pick up the cupcakes,
but she had to pick up lungs
instead. And I just figured,
since you're close
to both these ladies...
You're asking me to take
time out of my very busy day
to go to the bakery? Or would you prefer
I ran on home and baked some myself?
No. 'Course not.
- Just an invitation.
- Uh-huh.
Mark, I need to talk to you
about Christy Cornell's...
- butt.
- OK.
But first I need to talk
to you about cupcakes.
Callie! Check out all of the great
stuff the kids in Peds made me.
They want me to take
pictures of their crafts in Africa.
Wow! That's awesome.
You'd be surprised how often you
find yourself in need of a macaroni face
glued to a paper plate. It's way better
than gauze, malaria pills, antibiotics.
You are a delight this morning. Is
there something you'd like to talk about?
Um, no. No, I'm just...
No.
- Ah! Torres. Robbins.
- Hi.
I thought you'd be
halfway to Malawi by now.
We had some
last-minute paperwork.
Plus, I promised the kids
I'd come say goodbye.
That's good. The work
you two will be doing there
will reflect very, very
highly on this hospital.
Sure, uh, it was
a surprise to learn
that I'd have to replace
two excellent attendings,
as opposed to just the one.
But then, that's
the chief's problem.
No one wants to really
hear chief's problems.
It's a shame, though, Torres.
I had, uh... I had
such big plans for you.
Big plans.
Can I get suction? Thank you.
Clamp please.
Dr. McQueen, I really need
you to take a look at Roy Henley.
They tell me he's developed cor
pulmonale and circulatory collapse.
- Yes, sir, that's correct.
- Did you put him on dopamine,
milrinone and nitric oxide?
Yes, I did. He's stable.
Critical, but stable.
What would you do for a patient
with reduced cardiac output,
hypotension, sinus tach
and metabolic acidosis?
I'd insert an intraaortic
balloon pump.
Exactly.
I'll be there when
I can, Dr. Yang.
But it really doesn't sound
like you need me at all.
Permeate the suction.
You must be Dr. Bailey. I'm
Dr. Stanley, head of pathology.
And this must be
Mary Portman, 30.
Multiple organ failure,
cause unknown.
She came in for a standard
colostomy reversal and never woke up.
Well, all right. Looks like we've got
something we can sink our teeth into.
Um, I have a list
of possible causes
I'd like to check as we proceed.
We have a specific order to
the way we work down here,
so we'll see what we see
when we see it. OK? OK.
According to this card, this
guy's got a blown right pupil,
an atlanto-occipital dislocation, open
book pelvis, large open abdominal wound,
jeez... a sucking chest
wound with seven broken ribs...
- This guy is all messed up.
- Or he's dead.
Ah! Right. Yes. Moving on.
Cristina? Hey, how
long you been here?
Oh... Not long. I just
needed some fresh air.
- How's the patient?
- He's fine. He's great.
Uh, couple complications,
but... I'm handling it.
- Are you sure that you're OK?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
It's, uh... chilly out here.
That's him. Um...
I need to... I...
- have to go look.
- OK. All right.
- Cristina.
- Uh-huh?
You can do this.
OK. Thanks.
Grey! Congratulations.
You're, uh... You're certified.
Now, you go inside
and give Cristina a hand.
What does she need?
Did she ask for me?
Meredith, please.
OK, thanks.
- Hey.
- What're you doing here?
- Owen sent me.
- I don't need a baby-sitter.
I'm just an extra set of
hands. What's the situation?
He went into cardiogenic shock, so
I'm inserting an intraaortic balloon pump
and hoping there are no other
complications before Teddy gets back.
So we are watching for
hemolysis, a gas embolism,
a blue leg from
peripheral ischemia.
OK, if you want to do something,
his daughter is up in CCU
and she needs an update.
OK.
Blue Team. Status report.
We arrived on the scene
to find nine casualties.
We identified three as priority
one, requiring immediate evacuation.
Four were priority two,
allowing for delayed evac.
One was priority three and the
last was, sadly, dead on the scene.
Nice work, Kepner, but it seems to
me that you now have two dead patients.
- Excuse me?
- While you were standing around
waiting for the helicopter to arrive
and not keeping a constant eye
on your patients' injuries, this
one developed a femoral bleed,
bled out and is
now, sadly, dead.
Uh... A femoral bleed?
That wasn't on the card.
Really? Well, it's on this one.
- No, wait, that's not fair!
- - Patients don't suddenly die.
It just seems that way when
you stop paying attention.
Food for thought. Red Team, go.
I'm so sorry, you guys.
Awesome.
Tell me about the
bandaging on these two...
Right. The reservation's
under Stanley. Jennifer Stanley.
Four people, for 8:00.
Well, that doesn't
make any sense.
Why would eight people
want to have dinner at 4:00?
Dr. Stanley, the clots could
indicate a pulmonary embolus.
- Let me talk to your manager.
- Dr. Stanley?
- What's up?
- I was asking
about those blood clots.
Couldn't a pulmonary
embolus have led to her death?
Those are post-mortem clots,
Dr. Bailey. Perfectly normal.
Hello? Hi, yes. There's been a
mistake with my dinner reservation.
Big plans.
You know what? I don't
care. I've got big plans, myself.
- Great big African plans.
- Yeah, you do.
Yeah, I don't need to grow cartilage
in a lab, I'll be building bones from dirt.
I'll be figuring out how to
create unbreakable joints
out of blood diamonds. I'll be making
artificial limbs out of elephant ivory.
I'm pretty sure a couple of those would
be frowned upon by the world community.
Whatever. Science isn't
about making friends.
The helicopter has to be getting
here soon. It's been three hours.
Just a few more minutes.
Right? Right, Dr. Hunt?
The helicopter will
be here any minute?
Nice rain gear, Karev.
Shouldn't you be more concerned
- with your patient staying dry?
- Yeah, well, he's a dummy
- and I'm a person, so...
- A dry patient
is less likely to die
of hypothermia or shock.
Something to think about.
Alex, you can't break
the rules like that.
That's unsanctioned
use of a trash bag!
You're gonna mess
up our certification.
You need to relax.
This whole uptight thing?
- This is why you
have no friends.
- Hey.
OK, this is why
you have one friend.
Give me that back!
Are you crazy?
There you go, little guy.
No hypothermia for you.
Everyone, Green Team's
patients are all dead.
Only Red Team and
Blue Team remain.
Whoa! Do you see a helicopter?
- Take a knee
and learn something.
- Take a knee?
He's gonna scalp them.
We're in Apocalypse Now
and we're gonna get scalped.
That, right there.
See what she's doing?
OK, I swear I'm not an idiot.
If Dr. Altman doesn't
get this new heart,
is that, like, game over
on the lung transplant?
Uh, there are a variety of
factors. Right now, I'm not sure.
- But I can get
an answer for you.
- Fine. Uh...
Where are we on the heart?
Again, not sure. Dr. Altman should
be calling with an update very soon.
- OK. Uh, when can I see him?
- I have to check with Dr. Yang.
You're just like a wealth
of information, aren't you?
I'm sorry, I'm new to your
father's case, and Dr. Yang...
I called him Roy. I decided
to do that on the drive over.
'Cause I hadn't
seen him in 20 years.
And I want to
blame him for that.
I do blame him for that,
except... he tried.
He tried to be my
dad in the beginning,
and I couldn't forgive
him for leaving my mom.
And then he stopped trying.
And... I have
twins. They're three.
And I don't even know if he
knows that. I never told him.
And then... then
I walked in there
and I called him Roy.
I called my dad Roy.
And I just... I need for that
to not be the last
thing he hears from me.
Please.
The daughter really
needs to talk to you.
She has too many
questions that I can't answer.
- Why don't you try
reading his chart.
- Cristina, if you wanna be
- pissed at me, that's fine.
- We're not gonna
do this right now.
- 'Cause I'm kinda busy here.
- Crap.
All right, get him on ECMO.
That should keep him alive
until I can get back with
these lungs. There's a shot that
once we get them in, the
heart damage will reverse
- without the excess pressure.
- Teddy says get him on ECMO.
- What does it look
like I'm doing?
- OK, apparently,
Cristina's on it.
- Grey, how's she doing?
- She is doing great.
- She's doing great.
- Good. Good.
Intestines show a well
healed anastomosis
with no evidence of infection,
inflammation or necrosis.
I think this is as good a place as
any to call lunch. What do you say?
Lunch? We have to check the
adrenal glands and the kidneys.
What if the thyroid
shows pathology?
Don't worry, those
kidneys aren't
- going anywhere on their own.
- Yes, I'm aware.
But microscopic pathological
changes are harder to interpret
once the organs
start decomposing.
We'll only be gone 45
minutes. They'll keep.
Still, I don't
think it's right...
Dr. Bailey, I'll see
you in 45 minutes.
I don't know, they're
chocolaty-looking with sprinkles.
- Where'd you get them?
- That grocery store
down the street.
This isn't a baby shower for some nurse
who couldn't keep her knees together.
Torres and Robbins deserve
better than off-brand crap.
I'm not an errand girl. I'm a
doctor with a patient who is about
- to make a giant
butt-shaped mistake.
- That's not for you to say.
OK. Well, someone has to. The
only reason a woman does something
like this to her body is to impress a
guy. Sure, it starts with a giant butt.
Then the next thing you know,
she's giving up her friends.
She's moving in with him
before she's even ready.
If she's not careful, she'll find
herself a 26-year-old step-mother
to the pregnant daughter
she didn't even know he had.
Then she's single, dying
her hair a new color,
and, you know what? It's
really hard to manage your roots
when you've been
committed to the psych ward.
Psych ward?
It happens.
Great. You're in here.
Now, where can I sulk?
There's plenty of room. That's
all I'm doing. Please, sit down.
- What's the matter?
- I have been down in the morgue
all morning trying to determine
the cause of death for Mary Portman,
who survived the
horrors of Gary Clark,
only to die from a surgery
that I perform every day.
So it's very important to me, and
it's very important to Mary's husband,
to find some answers today.
But do you know what is important
to the pathologist who
is leading the autopsy?
Oh, her dinner reservations.
And her lunch break.
Basically, food, that's what's
important to this pathologist.
- Feeling better?
- No. Not really, no.
What's all this?
Oh, I'm just trying to
write this grant proposal.
- Why only trying?
- Because the more you research
Alzheimer's, the more depressing
it gets. And then, when you include
the early onset, the type that Ellis
Grey suffered from, it just gets worse.
There's a woman
in England, she's 32,
she can't recognize her
three-year-old daughter.
It's just terrifying.
This pathologist also
chews gum while she works.
Oh, my God. That's disgusting.
Thank you.
- Christy.
- Yes.
Dr. Grey is concerned that
you might be going
through with this surgery
for the wrong reasons, that you
might be trying to
please someone
who prefers a more...
robust body type.
Dr. Grey, I hope you don't
take this the wrong way.
But even through your lab coat, I
can tell you have an amazing ass.
And with an ass like that, I
bet you know what it's like
to find a perfect pair of jeans.
Jeans that make you feel like
you're the sexiest person
to ever put on a pair of pants.
And I envy that
'cause I never have.
Every pair hangs off me. Unless
I shop in the boys' department.
And I've tried gaining
weight, Dr. Grey.
It turns out I'm a person whose fat goes
straight to my upper arms and my boobs.
Which makes it really hard
for me to wear a sundress.
Which is all I can wear,
because jeans don't fit.
So, Dr. Grey, I'm
getting a big, juicy,
easy-to-grab-onto ass, and you'd
better believe I'm doing it just for me.
And I'm telling
you, I can't wait.
You are so nice.
Red Team's
patients have all died!
Only Blue Team remains.
Keep an eye on Karev.
That's what
resourceful looks like.
Good effort, Avery.
But this incision
you made is too wide.
You lacerated the
superior thyroid arteries.
- Move on.
- Damn it!
- I hear it. I hear the helicopter!
- You what?
- I hear it! I hear it!
- Wake up!
You don't hear the helicopter
because A, it's imaginary,
and B, the imaginary
helicopter is never coming!
Hunt's trying to break us, trying
to teach us some BS lesson
about how trauma
isn't fair or whatever!
We're not done until he says
these dummies are dead! The end!
It's not true! No,
you are wrong!
- Screw this. I'm done.
- What?
Jackson!
Avery, where are
you going? Avery!
- Avery, get back here.
- No.
No?
No, sir.
That should do it.
Close her up and call it a day.
Aren't we gonna get a
sample from the brain?
Sure, in about two weeks,
when it's had a chance
- to firm up in the formalin.
- It's possible
to cut the brain fresh.
It's also possible that the
moment you cut into a fresh brain,
it slides apart like Jell-O. If
you don't want to risk that,
you put it in formalin
and wait two weeks.
I'm not trying to tell
you how to do your job...
That's exactly what you're trying
to do. And I'm trying very hard
not to hold it against you. This
is what I do all day, every day.
I mean, do you think I
failed medical school?
Is that your actual belief, that
people become pathologists
because they fail to
become surgeons?
The autopsy was
inconclusive, Dr. Bailey.
And believe me, I hate that,
at least as much as you do.
- He's stable?
- He's critical,
I have to keep checking his
acid-base balance, but yes.
- He's stable-ish for now.
- Great.
So let me take over here, and you
can go give his daughter an update.
No, you go. Um, tell her that
his blood pressure is coming up.
- She needs to hear from you.
- He needs to be monitored.
- Well, I can do that.
- OK.
She doesn't need to
hear an update from me.
All she wants is to make sure
that I know that she's afraid.
And I can't hear that right now
because I'm scared enough as it is.
I was scared when he coded.
I'm scared now that he's stable.
I'm scared walking across the
lobby. I am scared all the time.
- Well, let me help.
- You cannot help!
- You can't help me!
- Dr. Altman's 30 minutes out.
We need to get him to the OR.
- Dr. Grey can help with that.
- Cristina...
Bon voyage!
Oh, my God, it's a
going-away party! You guys!
Um, this is a party?
It's a busy day.
No, yeah. I mean I'm...
Just been at this
hospital since residency.
But, uh, if people are too busy
to see me off, they're too busy.
- Callie...
- It's hard
to blame them, Torres.
We're down a
couple of attendings.
Things are going to be
busier all around for a while.
Well, I'm glad you
could find the time, chief.
With all your chief
problems and big plans.
Which were what exactly?
Now, why would I just
give away my good ideas?
- - He's just crabby. He's
messing with your head.
Yeah, well, I'll
never know, will I?
Thank you both, so much.
Um, I actually have to finish up
some packing, so I'm gonna go.
- Good luck.
- Give 'em hell.
I don't want to go home yet.
You want to see us give
a lady a really big ass?
Oh, my God, yes.
Sir! You said the helicopter
was gonna be here hours ago!
And it's not here! And
I'm not complaining,
- but where is it?
- Well, the rain's
still pretty bad.
Probably got caught
in a hail storm.
No! No! I know what
that card is gonna say!
It's gonna say he has
cardiac tamponade
with associated hypotension
and bradycardia! But he can't,
'cause I already did a
pericardiocentesis and bolused him
- with IV fluids!
- She's right. What do I do?
Karev, grab his feet!
- The patient! Come on!
- Hey, hey!
Son of a bitch, that's awesome!
What do you think you're doing?
- The ambulance is not in play.
- You're just making stuff up!
Which I can do, too,
and I say it is in play!
You can't fit nine patients on an
ambulance, but two will fit just fine!
Seven of my patients may have
died today, but these two won't
because I'm gonna get
them on this ambulance
and I'm gonna take them
to that hospital right there!
All right!
Kepner, this ambulance was involved
in the accident and no longer runs.
The keys are in the
ignition, so let's see!
Looks like I got AAA.
Apparently, they could get here
when the helicopter couldn't!
Now, move, or I will run you down!
Go!
John Doe, multiple chest
and extremity trauma.
Still hypotensive despite two
large bore IVs started in the field.
- All right, Kepner. That's enough.
- He needs a full work-up
and likely a thoracotomy. I
suspect active bleeding in the chest.
Will you tell us we won,
or she's never gonna stop.
- It's not a contest.
- Karev, call the OR
- and make sure
a room's available.
- Will do.
All right, all right, fine!
- Blue Team wins.
- Blue Team wins?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. You win.
He's gonna live
for 40 more years
and have 15
grandkids. You happy?
- Blue Team wins!
- Yes.
Yeah!
Yes!
Here. Check that out.
"Alzheimer's is a bad
disease. We should cure it."
Twelve hours worth of work.
Dr. Stanley refuses
to cut into Mary's brain
without letting it set in
fixative for two weeks.
- I need you
to go over her head.
- I can't do that.
She's right. I can't speed up the
process any more than she can.
That is not what you
were supposed to say.
Miranda, I know this has been
a very personal loss for you.
But you need to let it go.
I have to go and
tell Mary's husband
that I don't know
why his wife died.
That I can't answer the
one question he has to ask.
And I can't answer that
question because medicine,
because science, is failing
me. That, I take personally.
That, I can't accept.
And don't you dare stand there
and talk to me about letting things go.
I'm not the one who can't stop
thinking about the possibility of his wife
getting Alzheimer's long
enough to write a damn essay.
- Shouldn't you be
with the patient?
- He's prepped and in the OR.
And now you're gonna talk to me.
Please just go back downstairs.
Cristina.
How are you fine?
How are you just
completely fine?
I'm ruined, OK?
I am dead. I am wrecked.
And you're just walking
around baby-sitting me,
as if you didn't go through
the same thing, too?
- Why are you OK?
- I don't know.
You were there, too, you
know. You were there, too,
with your sad eyes,
screaming at me to save his life.
Telling the guy to shoot you,
and not giving a crap about yourself
- or your pregnancy!
- Cristina!
I didn't have a choice!
And you did that!
If it was anyone else on the table,
if it was anyone else standing there,
- I would have walked away.
- You would not...
I could have walked away!
And then I wouldn't be here!
Walk with me, Dr. Yang.
Tell me everything.
Now, who am I gonna
talk to about women?
- You have Derek.
- He's married
and self-satisfied.
It's irritating.
You can always email.
- What?
- It's not my place. Um...
Say it.
- I give a lot of boob jobs.
- OK.
Not where I thought
you were going.
But I also reverse
a lot of boob jobs.
Women come to me, a year, two
years after they've had work done,
and they're totally unhappy
with the decision they've made.
Today, though, you watched
me give a lady a really big ass.
And I'm not the slightest
bit worried about it
because I know for a fact there's
no boyfriend pressuring her.
It wasn't about anyone
else. It was for her.
As your friend,
I gotta tell you,
you sound an awful lot like
someone who's getting double-D's
just 'cause her
girlfriend likes a big rack.
By big rack, I mean Africa.
- I love her, Mark.
- I know you do.
But you need to figure out
how to love Africa, too.
Avery, hey.
Hey. You don't get to just
walk away when I'm teaching.
Two of my friends died
during the shooting. So thanks,
I don't need lessons
on how unfair trauma is.
I lost dozens of friends
in the field. Dozens.
And I have never, never
used them as an excuse to quit!
You're a doctor, Avery. And that doesn't
stop because you're up against a wall.
You need to figure
out how to be a doctor,
no matter what you're dealing with,
no matter what tools you don't have.
That is the lesson you need
to learn. You don't get to quit!
So if I need to drag
you outside by the throat,
you're coming with me
and you're going to finish!
If his heart doesn't start beating
soon, we're not gonna be able
- to take him off bypass.
- - He's back up to his core temperature.
I don't see any leaks. All
the connections are right.
We're just gonna have to wait and
see if Dr. Yang's hard work has paid off.
There it is. Nice
work, Dr. Yang.
Well done.
Clamp.
You know, sure, there's
not a lot to do over there,
but, uh, that just means less
to distract us from the medicine.
It'll just be us, focusing on
the medicine, which is great.
What? Oh, my God. Did
you forget your passport?
I won the Carter Madison Grant.
Do you know how rare that is?
Do you know how special that is?
This is the biggest opportunity
of my professional career.
I get to go to Malawi with almost
unlimited funds and help children,
help tiny humans who might
otherwise never see a pediatric surgeon.
I get to change lives.
That's the dream.
I am living the dream. And I am
over the moon about it, or I would be.
But you are ruining it for me.
First with your whining, and
now with your fake, smiley
passive aggressive enthusiasm.
You're ruining Africa for me.
- I'm not.
- You are!
OK. Fine. I don't
want to go to Africa.
OK? But I do want to be with
you, OK? So I'm really trying here.
We're gonna miss
our plane. Let's go.
Oh, my God. OK, you wanna fight?
The flight's 18 hours.
We can fight on the plane.
You are ruining this for me.
- And I don't want to do this.
- What... What does that mean?
What, you suddenly
don't want to go, or...?
I don't want to go
to Africa with you.
Arizona...
No. OK?
- No.
- I'm sorry.
- You're sorry? It's three years!
I'm gonna miss my plane.
You take care of yourself.
No! No!
Please. Please, I can...
We can do this. We
can figure this out.
You stay here and be happy.
And I'll go there and be happy.
If you get on the plane, if you
go without me, we are done.
Do you hear me? We are over!
We are standing in the middle of
an airport screaming at each other.
We're already over.
Yang.
Dr. Altman told me
about your work today.
I know it's been hell
for you these past few months.
So... well done.
Thank you, sir.
Chief?
Do you have a minute?
I can't wait until
the next skills lab.
I'm totally on your team.
"Move or I'll run you
down!" Freaking hilarious.
We're all looking for answers.
In medicine...
in life...
in everything.
Were you just
checking out my ass?
Not the first time.
Won't be the last.
No.
Sometimes, the
answers we're looking for
have been hiding
just below the surface.
I had the worst day today.
I've been working, um...
working on the grant proposal,
and I just, I couldn't do it.
Then I realized...
it was you.
It's a clinical trial
for Alzheimer's.
It's serious work, and I
couldn't think of anything but you.
I know you want to
be a part of the trial,
but I can't have you
anywhere near it.
Cristina blames me.
She hates me.
Other times,
we find answers when
we didn't even realize
we were asking the question.
Avery, good.
Sometimes, the
answers can catch us
completely by surprise.
Hey, hey, hey. Did you hear?
The lab, it could not have gone
better. You should have seen Kepner.
You wouldn't think it to look at
her, but there is a trauma surgeon
in that girl. I wish you
could have been there.
- How was your day?
- I quit.
- What?
- You were right.
I can do it. I can
still be a surgeon.
I just... don't want to anymore.
And sometimes, even when we find
the answer we've been looking for...
Avery, that's enough.
We're still left with a whole
hell of a lot of questions.