Meckel's is like a
rose-colored index finger
protruding from the
antimesenteric border...
Then you bake it in a
400-degree oven for an hour...
Occasionally attach itself
to the umbilical
area, producing...
Fresh rosemary,
a little pepper...
which is a, uh, pipe
connecting Meckel's
to the outside world.
Clove of garlic under the skin.
You know, excuse me.
I'm trying to visualize
here, all right?
You might want to
visualize setting up soon.
Your intern's late.
Gloves and gown for Dr. Keaton.
What size gloves does she wear?
I don't keep a chart.
Good morning, Dr. Benton.
Carter, you're late.
Two minutes.
You're supposed
to set up for Keaton.
Okay.
You know what size
gloves she wears?
Seven and a half, no powder.
"A man pushes a vacuum cleaner
"with a force of 70 Newtons
at a 45-degree angle
"and moves the vacuum cleaner
"a distance of five meters.
How much work has he done?"
Well, let's start
with the unlikelihood
of a man pushing
a vacuum cleaner.
Work equals force
times distance.
I thought work equaled one-half
of MV squared.
It's both.
Oh, God, I'm
never going to pass.
It's just a midterm.
It's one-half of our grade.
You have all day to study.
No, William. I have
to go to work now.
So, you're not
going to eat that?
Okay, the daily specials are...
Doubled-over gas pains in two,
hemorrhoids in three.
It's a below-the-belt
kind of day.
I know the feeling.
Oh, and a puking
toddler in five.
'Tis the season.
Everybody have their flu shots?
I'd rather puke.
Gant, can you
handle a hemorrhoid?
Not in this life.
Hey, that leg ulcer in
one is getting cranky.
Yeah, I'm getting to it.
Poor kid.
Got the dark cloud today, huh?
12 patients already
and he's got a
rule-out appi in four
and a rigid abdomen in six.
Hey, where's Mark?
Getting ready for
a staff meeting.
Oh, I can't wait.
Weaver and the
sound of her own voice.
A love story.
Dr. Greene called this one.
Mark called a meeting?
Do I look delusional?
Meckel's diverticulum.
Start with the rule of twos.
Uh, yeah, go.
Okay, Meckel's occurs in
two percent of the population
of which only two
cases are symptomatic.
The diverticulum is located
approximately two feet
from the ileocecal valve.
Diagnosis?
Technetium
pertechnetate imaging.
Complications?
Intestinal obstruction,
hemorrhage, volvulus
inflammation and perforation.
Treatment?
Excision.
You know this stuff cold.
Yeah, right.
Only if Keaton thinks so.
They have to give me
time off for my honeymoon.
It's not like I get
married every year.
Just every other year.
Well, I worked extra
hard for this one.
I deserve a reward.
Honey, your man is your reward.
That's right. 40 years of
snoring, hairs in the bathtub
and "Honey, can you find my...?"
Okay, I'll bring it up
at the re-engineering
committee today, but no promises.
Hey, Gant is screaming
for a suture kit.
I put it right under his nose.
That child needs a honeymoon.
Hey. Hey.
Have you seen Mark? Is he okay?
Let me put it this way:
He called a staff meeting.
Mark Greene?
Yep.
Glasses, receding
hairline, broken heart?
That's the one.
Scan demonstrated
a diverticulum.
And what caused
this one to bleed?
Presence of aberrant
gastric mucosa
in the Meckel's.
Very good, Peter.
There's the Ileocecal junction.
Uh-huh. I see it.
Now, follow my motion
as I move the bowl proximally.
Got it.
There's the Meckel's.
You've done your prep
on this one, haven't you?
Just your standard visualizing.
Sorry to interrupt, Abby,
I got to steal Dr. Benton.
For?
Perfed ulcer.
Dr. Grady was going to assist
but his wife's gone into labor.
She went from two
centimeters to six in record time.
Can't argue with Mother Nature.
Dr. Morgenstern, I'm not
prepped for that.
Oh, it's a nothing surgery.
You can do it in your sleep.
It's okay. Go ahead, Peter.
John can take over
the camera.
Since we're short
one resident for now
things are going
to be a little tight.
You might have noticed, what
we have is kind of controlled chaos.
Yeah, it's not all
that controlled, Mark.
Yeah, well, we're
going to fix that
with teamwork and a
new schedule, Kerry.
Now, what I've made
up is a chart here,
to help illustrate
how it's going to work.
Every doctor has been
designated a color.
Green is obviously taken.
Weaver is yellow.
Gant, red; Sanders, orange.
Ross is blue.
Doug, you have a problem?
No. Uh, no. You
just call me Mr. Blue.
All right. This is going to
be up in the admit area today.
Learn it, know it, do it.
This is an excellent
starting point, Mark
but since we're all
together, I'd like to bring up
food at the admit desk.
Someone spilt guava
juice on my labs yesterday.
All right then, no uncovered,
free-standing liquids
in the admit area.
All right. That's it.
Let's get busy.
Did I miss something?
You're not the one
missing something.
Oh, it's going to be a long day.
I wonder who drinks guava juice.
Mark, wait up.
Not now, Doug.
The chart was very
nice, very colorful.
Uh, "free-standing liquids"?
Don't start.
Think you're going
a little overboard?
Well, what? If they're
spilling liquids everywhere...
That's not what I meant.
I think your heart is broken
and you're overreacting.
No. I'm not. I'm
doing my job, okay?
The last few months,
I've been distracted.
Had other things on my mind.
That's right, and
despite everything
that's going on with Susan
you're still getting
the job done.
No. I'm not.
I'm letting Kerry
Weaver do my job
and that's going to stop.
I'm the Senior Attending
and it's time for
me to take control.
So you're going to step
back up, so to speak?
That's right.
Mm-hmm. Okay.
Everything else okay?
Everything else is fine.
All right. If you
ever want to talk...
Everything else is fine.
All right, I've already had
four cases of flu this morning.
Should I mention
the "shot" word?
Had mine. Me, too.
I'm done.
How about you,
Randi? I take garlic pills.
Good. Very cutting edge.
What about you, Carol?
Huh?
Who's taking this guy the
paramedics are bringing in?
Is he a child?
I'll take it.
Malik, hey, where's Dr. Gant?
Just took an admit up to O.R.
54-year-old male
putting up insulation
took a 15-foot fall
from the ladder.
Alert and oriented times three.
Vitals stable, BP's 130/90
possible fractured
left pelvis and tib fib.
Gave six of
morphine in the field.
Okay, let's get him
into trauma one.
Page Dr. Gant.
Mark, I can use you.
Yeah, I'll be
there in just a sec.
Doug, you're aware
that the board is full.
Luck of the draw. No pedes.
Well, you are aware
that the adult anatomy
is remarkably similar.
I don't know
if a 50-year-old with chest pain
will be thrilled with having a
baby doctor take care of him.
Arthritic diabetic in four.
Rule out MI in three.
If you need any help, just ask.
I don't know if I'm color-
coordinated enough for this.
Doug, can you help me out here?
If a red quark is attracted
to an anti-red quark
is it a gluon or a meson?
Thank you, Carol,
for pointing out
something else I
know nothing about.
Mostly in my legs today.
Chest pains.
I'm guessing it's a
vaso-occlusive crisis.
Sounds like you understand
your disease pretty well.
I've been living with
sickle cell all my life.
Temp's 101, BP's 110/80
Tachy at 110.
What do you take for pain?
Darvocet usually does it.
Not today.
Okay, we'll get you
something stronger
soon as we get an I.V. going.
Thanks.
Connie, let's get her changed
and get a CBC
with retic count
chest film, and start a line.
O2 two liters by nasal cannula
and five migs of morphine.
Can you hang on?
If you hear me screaming,
you'll have your answer.
A simple patch
closure should do here.
So what did I pull
you away from?
Meckel's.
Goodness.
Baptism by fire.
I was holding my own.
Still, it's tough, isn't it?
What do you mean?
You've chosen
the most difficult elective.
Many are called,
but few are chosen.
Did Keaton say something?
Retract, please.
Uh, I mean, did she
say how I was doing?
If you're concerned,
you should ask her.
No, no, I'm not concerned.
I just, you know, look,
all of my procedures
haven't been perfection,
but Keaton knows I could've
handled that Meckel's.
"Man's reach should
exceed his grasp,
else what's a heaven for?"
Browning.
Or was it Keats?
Ah, well, they're all a
bunch of hopheads, anyway.
Peter? What are you doing?
Oh.
Give me a broader scope there.
Good.
How late are you on, Dr. Carter?
Late?
Not late, 7:00.
Um... big plans?
No.
Well, uh... maybe.
Just dinner... eating.
I was thinking of
Indian food myself.
Indian food?
You got a problem, Shirley?
You got a problem
with Indian food?
Oh, I'm sure she
doesn't, do you, Shirley?
Good for the sinuses.
It's that spice they use.
Hold still, please.
Good.
Maybe I'll just order in
and rent a movie.
My VCR's broken.
Which is probably
why I'm not going
to, uh, myself.
Rent a movie,
that is... tonight.
So maybe you'll just eat
and call it a day?
Yeah, that's probably
what I should do.
Just study, prep for tomorrow.
Cumin.
What?
That's the spice... cumin.
Oh.
Right.
BP's 120/80, heart
rate's 90, resps 30.
He's HIV-positive.
Complaining of
shortness of breath.
Al Boulet?
Is he some relative of Jeanie's?
Not that I know of.
Al Boulet?
Dr. Greene.
Yeah.
Any relation to Jeanie Boulet?
We're divorced.
Oh. So, you're having
trouble breathing?
Just a little.
No-nothing big.
And when did you first
test positive for HIV?
About six months ago.
Mm-hmm.
And you're on AZT, 3TC
and a protease inhibitor.
Your last t-cell count was 200?
Yeah.
CBC, chest film and
sputum induction.
O2 nasal cannula, four liters.
Bactrim, four
amps I.V. piggyback
60 migs solumedrol I.V.
And let's admit
Mr. Boulet to medicine.
Yep. Okay.
So, when'd you get divorced?
Uh... separated about a year.
Uh-huh. Open.
Divorce just came through.
The new float system
seems to be working well
across the board.
E.R. and ICU both had a
few adjustment problems
but altogether, I would
say things are settling down.
From where risk
management sits, we're fine.
Incident reports
haven't increased
since the new rotation started.
Can you give us an idea
how long this floating
is going to last?
Indefinitely, Carol.
This is not a Band-Aid.
It's the cure.
It's being negotiated
into the new contracts?
Financial affairs is ever so
pleased with this temporary fix,
but we still need to cut
non-physician related care.
Meaning the nurses?
Honestly speaking, nurses
simply don't generate the revenue.
And what about saving lives?
They don't tend
to do that either.
Hold on a minute, Dean.
You're just
talking statistics,
aren't you, Dean?
Averages, numbers...
Whatever you want to call it.
I think you're
calling it nurses.
And in the E.R.,
nurses are in trauma
situations every day.
It's only going to hurt
an emergent patient
to have some floor nurse
set up the wrong lavage kit.
You want a lawsuit
over that one?
Look, Carol. That's
why we're all here.
To help iron out these problems
before your contract's up.
Now, have you got a suggestion?
Stop floating them.
E.R. nurses
are not interchangeable.
They work differently.
They work longer, and
the stakes are higher.
So we should show them
preferential treatment.
We should show emergent
patients preferential treatment
by giving them nurses
trained in handling crises.
What do we say to pedes or
ob/gyn when they complain?
You tell them it's like triage.
Critical cases come first.
Hey, Jeanie.
Hi.
I just treated your husband Al.
Ex-husband.
Still, I-I-I didn't realize
that you've been
going through all this.
Unfortunately, it's Al
who's going through it.
I mean, I'm doing
what I can to help.
So I guess you guys have
been separated for a while.
Yeah, quite a long time.
And the marriage was
over long before that.
I guess you didn't feel
any need to get tested.
No, no. I did.
I got lucky. I was negative.
I'm glad.
Yeah. I got to get
this suture kit to Gant.
He is just swamped
with patients.
Hey, that's a central line kit.
You're right.
Right. Thank you.
Now, Mrs. McCourt, when
did the chest pains start?
Uh, this morning,
right after breakfast.
What did you eat?
Toast with raspberry jam.
Well, those jams
can be pretty acidic.
Oh, I've eaten toast
and raspberry jam
every day for 40 years.
It doesn't give me heartburn.
I know heartburn.
Yes, I'm sure that you do.
All right, let's get a 12-lead,
pulse ox and a chest film.
And maybe cardiac enzymes?
Oh, uh, yeah.
Are you on any medication?
Of course I am. I'm 73.
Hmm. Uh...
Digoxin,
for my heart,
and allopurinol for my gout,
glipizide for diabetes
and simvastatin for, um...
Ooh, I never can
remember this one.
What am I taking that one for?
Uh... High cholesterol.
Oh, yeah, you don't
want to skip that.
It's very important.
Yes, I...
And, uh...
What a cow. Famotidine.
Kerry, you got a minute?
Sure. What's up?
We might have a
problem with Jeanie Boulet.
What sort of problem?
This morning, I treated
her ex-husband Al.
He has AIDS.
I see.
Did she mention anything to you?
Why would she?
She claims she tested negative.
Well, we'll have to take
her word on it, won't we?
Doesn't this make
you uncomfortable?
Not especially.
She says she's negative.
What else can we do?
I guess I'm just
a little surprised
at your lack of concern.
It's a lack of alarm, Mark.
There's a difference.
I'm in the tall grass
and so... I take the five iron
and I sail that puppy, like,
two inches from the cup.
It was poetry.
It was a sonnet.
It was practically a haiku.
Excuse me, Dr. Morgenstern.
Are we done yet?
Looks good to me.
Thank you, Peter.
What happened to
the pelvic pain in two?
Ruptured ectopic. OB
took her up to surgery.
Yeah, well, then why
don't you erase the name?
Is that too difficult?
I was busy calling up
the charts you asked for...
Al Boulet.
He was Kerry Weaver's patient?
That's what it says.
You're welcome.
So you're telling me
this Indian food
thing has a purpose.
I'm just trying to prep
myself for Pakistan.
Why didn't you tell me sooner?
Well, I only found out
yesterday afternoon.
I haven't told anyone
but Anspaugh.
You're not sleeping
with Anspaugh.
Are you?
Um, maybe...
You know what?
We got it. We'll take it.
Thank you. Thank you.
Listen, it's a
great opportunity.
Three of us from the
U.S. going to teach
pediatric surgical techniques
to Pakistani surgeons.
Think of the help
we'll be giving.
They don't need that kind
of help in, like, Indianapolis?
Well, it's only for four months.
Thought you said six.
Well, you know, it could be six.
Well, then that means
it could be a year or five.
Next thing you know, you're
going to become Mother Teresa
and start living amongst them.
Did you have long-term
plans for us, John?
Well...
I don't... you know...
Well, neither did I,
so, for the next few weeks
why don't we just
keep having fun?
Same kind of fun, though, right?
Yes, the same kind of fun.
Okay.
I've got a patient
present with PCP pneumonia.
Been tested positive
for HIV six months ago
and I'm worried he
didn't tell his wife.
Uh-huh.
I need to see if she was tested.
Those are private
files, Dr. Greene.
In the case of spousal
report, I'm allowed to check.
In the case of spousal report,
you're allowed to tell the other spouse
not to look into
someone's private files.
Give me a break, huh?
I don't think this
guy's telling her.
Okay. Name?
Uh, Jeanie Boulet.
B-o-u-l-e-t.
You know, that re-engineering
committee is a joke.
It's downsizing in
sheep's clothing.
I should have spent
the time studying.
I still don't know
iodine from cosine.
Okay, well, if memory serves me
one is an element that
you find in antiseptic
and the other has
to do with right angles
or hypotenuse...
Something like that.
If that's how your memory serves
how did you get through it?
Well, they told us we could
bring one sheet into the exam
with all the
formulas written on it.
And?
I brought in a really big sheet.
Have you seen Weaver?
What color was she?
Never mind.
Excuse me. I've
been waiting here
for two hours
and I have a luncheon
in less than 20 minutes.
Right, well, we'll be
right there Mrs. Uh...?
Murison. If I don't
get my B-12 shot
I might as well just
resign from my job.
Someone is going to help you.
Gant, can you...?
No, no.
Gant, the answer is yes.
You give Mrs.
Murison a B-12 shot.
I've got 17 surgical patients.
She's not one of them.
I'm sorry.
You're going to have to wait.
Natalie, you get a lot of
ear infections, do you?
Can you just give
me the amoxicillin?
I have a playdate.
Mm-hmm.
You don't need to look.
Just give me the antibiotic.
Augmentin will be just fine
if you're worried
about resistance.
You know a lot of things
about a lot of things
don't you, Natalie?
Yes, I do.
So, you want to
tell Nurse Hathaway
about Coulomb's Law?
That's the fundamental
law of electrostatics
which states that the force
between two charged particles
is directly proportional to
the product of their charges.
And inversely proportional
to the square of the
distance between them.
Isn't that right, Natalie?
You can't give me another shot?
You've already had two doses.
The attending physician
has to approve a third.
Jeanie.
Mark, I'm glad you're here.
I've got a patient
in sickle crisis.
She's in a lot of pain.
I'd like for you
to evaluate her.
She needs more narcotics,
maybe an admission.
Right, well, I'll
see what I can do.
But right now, I need you
to cover the waiting room.
The waiting room?
Yeah, there's about a dozen
people need to be triaged.
But I'm with a patient.
I'm going to handle
this from here.
Understand?
So what kind of movie
do you want to get?
I was thinking maybe a comedy
or maybe a comedy.
Forget it.
Tonight, you're
going to participate
in a long-standing
Carter family tradition.
Sounds painful.
Every year, at exactly this time
the intrepid Carter
male goes into the woods
picks out the perfect
Douglas fir tree
and with his own
strong, Protestant hands
he cuts it down.
We're going to cut down a tree?
Not just any tree.
The Carter family
Christmas tree.
Oh, oh, I do not
saw after hours.
Don't worry.
That's my job.
Oh, Dr. Benton,
how was the ulcer?
Uh. Uh... fine.
Look, I saw the thyroglossal
duct on the board
and I was hoping to assist.
I haven't had a
lot of experience
with neck surgery
and, you know, considering
that I was called
out of the Meckel's...
Sorry. I already called
in Wallace to assist.
Yeah, but is there any
possibility of rescheduling
considering everything that...
There'll be plenty
of other opportunities,
Peter, really.
Carter, don't you
have something to do?
No. Actually, I'm all caught up.
What about post-op notes?
They're on the charts.
I'm done.
That's it.
I'm going to lunch.
Here. Earache in four.
I'm not going to lunch.
Hey, Carter,
otitis media in four.
Sorry, Doug.
I beeped him.
You might want to
check on your friend Gant.
Why? What's wrong?
Well, surgical admits
are in a holding
pattern and piling up.
You've got four patients
on your service.
He's got 20.
Give him these... The
labs on lung cancer.
Hey. You heard I was here, huh?
I'm better now.
It must be the Jell-O.
Why did you tell
Mark Greene about me?
I didn't.
Then how does he
know I'm positive?
I don't know. We were married.
I guess he just assumed.
He's not assuming, Al.
He knows.
Well, it didn't come from me.
Did it ever occur to you to go to
a different hospital for treatment?
My insurance is still a mess.
I know the doctors here.
I know the doctors here!
Well, even if they found out
they couldn't fire
you, could they?
That's not the point, Al.
Do you think at all about
what I'm going through?
This is not just about you.
I know this is
not just about me.
Then act like it.
Jeanie.
Look, I know how
mad you are at me.
And you have a right to be.
Living with AIDS, that's...
nothing, but...
knowing...
I gave it to you...
There's no pill for that.
I just have to face it...
Every day.
Hating me might feel good,
but it won't change anything.
It doesn't feel good, Al.
Nothing about this feels good.
I don't see Weaver as yellow.
I see her more
in the red family.
Yeah, something in burnt sienna.
Lavender's too pastel for Doyle.
She's more like an eggplant.
Are you redecorating my board?
Just a little
constructive criticism.
Mark, I need to speak with you.
All right, I'll be
there in a second.
I'll wait outside.
What the hell are you doing?
Funny, I was going to
ask you the same question.
Why is Jeanie
checking vital signs
when we're swamped?
Patient safety.
She is not a health risk.
Oh, maybe you know that
but I haven't had the opportunity
to assess her condition.
Why didn't you tell me that
you treated her husband?
I didn't think it was relevant.
You lied to me.
It wasn't any of your business.
If someone in my
E.R. is HIV-positive
I think it's my business.
Hey, it's our E.R.
and you don't even
know if she's HIV-positive.
The hell I don't.
I checked with medical records.
You went into her
confidential file?
I wouldn't have had to if
you had told me the truth.
Nice try, Mark, but there's
no excuse for what you did
and you know it.
Hey. I've been looking for you.
I heard you could use a hand...
That you're getting buried.
I'm fine.
Yeah, well, I don't
mind helping you.
You've certainly bailed me
out when I've been under.
Benton minds. Look, he
wants me to pull my weight.
I'm damn well going to pull it.
I'm not letting him
get another shot at me.
Gant, lower abdominal pain.
Rule out small
bowel obstruction.
We may have a
problem in the E.R.
I thought you should
know about it right away.
Is this going to
give me acid reflux?
If so, save it until I'm done.
I have reason to believe
that we may have a worker
that's HIV-positive.
Say no more.
I don't want details.
This could have
serious ramifications.
I've already removed the person
from direct patient care.
Well, I hope you
didn't indicate why,
or else we're going to have a
discrimination suit slapped on us.
No. What is the hospital policy?
We'll deal with it.
We're not going to race at it
like a herd of buffalo.
The first thing I want
to do is talk to Legal.
Does Kerry know?
That's part of the problem.
I believe Kerry may have
known for as long as six months
without informing anyone.
Good.
I want you to be
equally discreet.
But by keeping this to
herself, Kerry may have left us
wide open for litigation.
I know that all too well
but right now, it's just a
suspicion, Dr. Greene.
And please...
don't correct me if I'm wrong.
I had a dream like this once.
Now it's come true.
What happened?
We were on our
winter nature hike
identifying perennials,
varieties of moss.
One of the boys
found a sick bat,
brought it back to the van.
Before I knew what was going on,
he had passed it around.
Were any of them
bitten or scratched?
Maybe. We don't know.
Their stories changed
when they found out they
were going to get a shot.
I don't understand it.
The bats should be well
into hibernation by now.
Okay, let's get the bat in
the lab and see if it's rabid.
Oh, we don't have a bat.
No bat?
No bat. I threw it
out the car window.
I'm going to go
start some charts.
Mm-hmm.
It was flopping, drooling.
And you panicked.
Yes... I suppose I did.
All right!
Anyone seen Randi?
Went to the roach
coach for a sandwich.
This has to be a mistake. What?
"Please observe that all
E.R. nurses will be exempt
from the flotation
schedule currently in effect."
No way!
Does it say anything
about my honeymoon?
No, you must be dreamin', girl.
What'd you say to them?
Who?
"No more floating."
You must be kidding!
Good work, Carol.
No wonder management wanted you.
I'm not management.
Paramedics got a live one
coming in right behind me!
Haleh, Carol...
Bring these to
Doug in exam three.
Order a series of R.I.G.
and rabies vaccines.
How many?
Eight... no, nine.
What happened?
Ten-year-old
male, vitals stable.
BP 100/70.
Severe throat
pain with bleeding.
I took him to the circus.
He thought he could
be a sword swallower.
He tried at home with
one of our carving knives.
Let's get him into
trauma one.
Who's covering surgery?
Gant, but I think
he's in Radiology.
Yeah, you know what, you're
going to have to wait out here.
Page Carter and Benton.
Uh... Dr. Keaton
I see you're going to
have a trisegmentectomy
for a hepatoblastoma
this afternoon.
No. I decided
the child needed a
course of pre-op chemo.
But it's on the board.
Well, it shouldn't be.
I canceled it.
Peter, you were unlucky today
but you've already seen more
during a single
rotation than I ever did.
Yeah, I know, Dr. Keaton.
I just feel that if I
get more experience
I'll be better prepared
for the future.
That's not how you
should be looking at it.
Damn.
Uh... what do you mean?
Focus on what's in front of you.
Your residency
is five years long.
It's a marathon, not
a sprint. Excuse me.
I feel crepitation.
He's got subcutaneous
air in his neck.
Probably perfed his esophagus.
I'll start a second line.
You want a chest film?
And a soft tissue neck.
You paged me?
Probable perforation.
The temp's 100.
Let's get a gram of Unasyn.
He might be
developing an infection.
You going to scope him? Yep.
I wouldn't.
He's obviously perfed.
Carol, let's go ahead and set up
for endoscopy.
This is Jeanie Boulet.
I'd like to know if anyone
inquired about my file today.
Around noon?
All right.
Thank you.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
It's so damn swollen in here.
Can you visualize the cords?
All right, what do we got?
Ten-year-old trying to
be a sword swallower.
Used a carving knife.
Vitals are stable.
Gave him a gram of Unasyn.
We're trying to
see if there's a perf.
Okay. Carter, what the
hell are you doing here?
I thought Gant was
covering the E.R.
Gant's jammed.
I paged Carter to help.
He's not jammed.
The kid is slow and
we're not helping him out
by picking up his slack.
I thought the patient was
more important, Peter.
Carol made the right call.
Well, they're Peter's interns.
It's his decision.
Well, in any event, he's
perfed his esophagus.
We all knew that one.
Anybody want me to drop an NG?
Nope. We'll do it up in the O.R.
I'll page Dr. Keaton.
No, why don't you stay down here
and help your friend. Let's go.
All right.
Now, next time you see a bat
what are you going to do?
Leave it alone!
All right!
Good, good, good.
Now, hop out of the way here.
Let's send some
instructions home with them.
We want follow-up injections
on days three, seven, 14 and 28.
Okay... Mr. Wilbourne.
Time for your shot.
I barely touched the thing.
Well, rabies is nothing
to fool around with
as you well know.
Can we watch?
Mark, do you have a minute?
What's up?
Well, I just wanted
to talk to you
about the memo I got from
the re-engineering committee
about floating the nurses.
Carol, that's your
responsibility.
I really need you
to handle it yourself.
I am handling it.
You want me to put a word in?
No.
You know what I'd really
like is just one 24-hour period
where no one
complains about their job
and maybe just one person
might appreciate the
fact that they have one.
Is that too much to ask for?
Well, actually, what I
was going to tell you is
that they agreed to my request
and they're going to
stop floating the nurses
which will make both
our jobs a lot easier.
I just thought you might
want some good news.
Thanks.
Eh... poor kid.
Trying to swallow a knife.
I've seen worse.
Mobilize the esophagus.
Okay. Got it.
Debride the wound.
Okay.
Mm-hmm.
And...
I'm there.
Uh... Dr. Keaton?
Mm-hmm?
I need to ask you something.
Suction.
Well, uh...
I'm a little concerned
about... how Carter's doing.
How do you think he's doing?
Well, he... had to
scramble this rotation...
Well, we both did...
But, uh... I-I don't know,
I-I think he's doing fine.
So do I.
You know, he had a
rough bit in the beginning
but he listened, he learned...
He's very, very good with kids.
Yes, he is.
If that's the way you feel
about Carter, you should tell him.
It's very important
for the teacher
to keep his intern
informed of how he's doing.
You-you think so?
Absolutely. That way, he
knows he's on the right track.
It's very easy to get
discouraged in a vacuum.
I... yeah, I agree.
I... yeah, agree.
Hey, it looks like snow.
Smells like snow.
Carol, what does that mean?
You can smell snow coming.
It has a smell.
It smells like burritos.
Look, what are we
going to do about Mark?
Put him on a plane,
or have him killed.
I don't think I can take this
much longer, you know?
Maybe you should talk to him.
I talked to him once;
he said he was okay.
If I ask him again,
it gets a little weird.
Oh, you'd be
violating the guy code.
The guy code?
Yeah, of non-communication.
Don't you have a
test to study for?
You can't let him self-destruct.
Well, let him get it
out of his system.
If he stomps around,
acts like a jerk
then he'll be back.
Yeah, but will he
have any friends left?
Didn't you get more morphine?
He said he would,
but never came back.
Dr. Greene?
I don't even remember.
Please, I really can't
take this anymore.
I know. Okay.
Jeanie, what are
you doing in here?
I hold you to handle triage.
Could I speak to you?
I'm treating a patient
that you've neglected.
Do you have any idea
how much pain she is in?
Yeah, when I
assign you to an area
that's where you go.
Oh, is that how it works?
You make the rules?
Yeah, that's how it works.
And you get to break them
by going into my file?
I requested that information
under the Spousal Report Law.
That's a lot of crap, Mark.
You wanted to know,
and you found out.
It was completely unethical.
You want to talk ethics?
How about you lying to me?
Well, I guess the truth
is out now, huh?
You should've come to
me from the beginning.
Why, so I can lose
my job sooner?
No. So I could have dealt
with the situation
appropriately.
No. It's better this way.
You know about me, and I know
a hell of a lot more about you.
Excuse me.
I have to attend to a patient.
It's not the flu.
I'm not saying anything.
It's allergies.
I didn't say a thing.
I'm gone.
Break a leg.
Hey, where you going?
We're going to celebrate!
Celebrate what?
It's happy hour! We're
not floaters anymore!
First pitcher of
margaritas is on us.
Oh, it sounds
like fun, but I can't.
I have an appointment.
Oh, come on! What
can be that important?
You're the guest of honor.
Sorry. Have fun.
Be right there.
Hey, are you done?
Yeah.
Benton just ripped me a new one.
Huh. About what?
About not being in trauma
for the perfed esophagus.
Ah.
Why didn't you come
get me out of Radiology?
Hey, they paged me.
Look, I know you
were trying to help
but you didn't.
You made it worse.
I'm sorry.
The best thing you can do for me
is to leave me alone.
Mm-hmm.
-
- millionaires money can...
Anything good?
Just surfing.
Done for the day?
Almost.
Al, about this afternoon...
Hey. No, it's okay.
No, I'm sorry that I
jumped to conclusions.
It's just... I get up
every morning thinking
"What's going to happen today?
How's this going to get worse?"
What else am I going
to do to ruin your life?
No...
Yeah.
Maybe.
I do want to blame you.
I know things happen.
They happen for no good reason.
I see it every day
but when it's happening to you
you want it to be
somebody's fault.
I haven't told anybody at work.
Still play poker on Tuesdays.
Shoot hoops on Saturdays.
Some of the guys I
could tell, some I couldn't.
But, uh...
none of them would ever
treat me the same again.
You don't deserve this.
Neither do you.
So, what's in store
for tonight, the usual?
Karate class, a couple
of laps around the track...
Actually, my goal
is to stay awake
through the 10:00 news.
Ah. How's Susan's
apartment working out?
I don't know why
I was so worried
about where I was going to live.
I'm never there.
Look, I'm sorry.
Today, I was, uh...
What was I today?
Uh, officious, humorless,
pain in the ass.
Yeah. Right. Thanks.
You want to talk?
I want to sleep.
Look, it's...
nothing's the same.
You notice that?
It's just not fun
in there anymore.
It was fun once?
You know what I mean.
Sun-Times.
It's just...
I'm up to my ears in
administrative problems.
Kerry Weaver and I are
constantly butting heads
and it's just like...
the whole staff is lying to me.
I used to think
of this as a family.
Didn't it feel like that?
Well, you got to remember
my idea of a family
is a little screwed up.
Look, Mark, it's
okay to miss her.
No. It's more than that.
Well, I think, whatever you do,
you should keep it separate.
My mom, she used
to work at this office,
and she never put
a picture of me out,
and I asked her why,
and she said, "Never
confuse where you work
with where you live."
Your mom didn't work in the E.R.
I just shared with you
a very profound
childhood moment...
Okay, I'm sorry.
It's moving, and your
mother is a very wise woman.
Thank you very much.
I can't face going home
to another frozen dinner.
Do you want to get a
burger or something?
I can't tonight.
I got this thing I got to do.
But if you want to talk
later, you know where I'll be.
No, I don't know where you are.
Well, at home.
After 10:00. Alone.
Dr. Benton. Hi.
Hey.
How was the surgery?
Well, I, uh, missed out
on the thyroglossal duct
but then a perfed
esophagus fell into my lap.
Good. Great.
Listen, uh...
Carter, I wanted to talk to you
about your work.
I, uh... I know I
don't usually give you
a lot of feedback, but...
you know, the fact is...
you're doing good work.
Yeah. I mean, you've, uh...
your work has
consistently improved.
You're more confident.
You've become more proactive.
Great.
Yeah. Now, listen,
there are still some areas
that need improvement,
like focus, you know?
What?
Focus, Carter.
Focus.
Yeah.
Yeah. Anyway,
we'll work on that.
Okay, great, good.
Hey... I don't know.
I just wanted
to tell you that...
you're doing good work.
Thanks.
Yeah, um...
Listen, I got to run.
Uh...
All right.
Good night, Carter.
Good night.
Hi.
Okay, you...
you just missed
Benton by a second.
I saw him.
I slowed to a stroll.
I can hardly breathe.
It's okay.
Ah.
Jeanie.
About today...
Mark Greene looked in my file.
I know.
I got a memo from
Anspaugh this evening.
He set a time for
Mark and I to meet
and discuss hospital policy.
Okay.
It's going to
remain confidential.
I don't put much faith
in that around here.
Maybe it's not going to
be as bad as you think.
At least you're
dealing with doctors.
There's some degree
of understanding
about the disease
and how it's transmitted.
Right.
Mm.
Well... you know what?
I'm starving.
The aroma coming
from the cafeteria...
isn't... well, it's
not too scary.
Want to join me?
Well?
Hey, what are you doing here?
Hey, I'm invested in this exam.
And I helped you study.
How did we do?
We did pretty good.
I think we got lucky.
Ah, luck nothing.
You know what you did?
You earned yourself a night out.
A couple of
Manhattans straight up...
Carol! What did you get
on that fireman question?
35 Newtons.
All right!
Doug, you remember William?
How you doing, William?
How's it going, Doug. So...
the entropy question?
Rudolf Clausius.
Yes! Man, I'm starved.
Anybody feel like ice cream?
Lead the way, William.
You all right?
Yup.
Thanks for bringing
the extra boots.
I know they're a little big.
Oh, just three or
four sizes, that's all!
You want to carry the axe?
No. No, thank you.
Oh! So what are we looking for?
We're looking for that...
A Douglas fir with
perfect branches
and a very, very thin trunk.
Uh-huh. Well, are
you sure this is legal?
Whose land is this?
It's our land.
What, as in public land?
As in, uh...
see that light coming
through those trees?
The smoke coming
out of that chimney?
No.
There. Right... there.
No? Well, it's there
and it's the house I grew up in.
Tell me we're not going to have
cocoa with your parents later.
No. You're safe.
They're in London.
Oh, look!
Look!
It's the perfect tree!
All right. Stand back.
Did I ever tell you about
my lumberjack fantasy?
Abby, this is a very
sacred tradition.
Oh, it's a sacred fantasy.
Let me turn you
into a little snowman.
Don't you dare!
That is not part
of your fantasy.
of your fantasy!