- Previously on The Resident...
- Hey, Cindy.
- You're exhausted.
- Red Rock can
schedule more operations
and make more money.
I'm pulling rank. Go home.
There's got to be someone
- who can swap with you.
- Me. I got you covered.
You just finished
back-to-back surgeries, too.
Well, then I'll be in
back-to-back-to-back surgeries.
They are still working
on my request for
Hemopleatin data.
The more time, the
more patients could die.
We need help with something.
We're doing a little research
- on a drug.
- An exclusive with
DiaCure renal services
would help us all out.
Chastain uses the drug
Hemopleatin to treat anemia.
Nic's sister, Jessie...
she was on it.
She died of a massive
pulmonary embolism,
just like five more of our
patients on Hemopleatin.
I think this drug is causing
these fatal blood clots.
Get to the point. I
have a busy day.
Well, you're familiar with
the company DiaCure?
The biggest dialysis
provider in the country. Yeah.
Yeah. I-I met their
CEO at their annual
shareholders'
meeting last night.
He agreed to give us access
to all their patient records...
in exchange for an
exclusive deal with Chastain.
Since when did you start
doing business deals?
I didn't agree to
anything, obviously.
- Well...
- Yeah, it's your call.
But bottom line, if
Hemopleatin is killing people,
and Chastain can prove
it, we're saving lives.
I'm, uh... I'm not gonna go
into business with anyone
on the basis of
your wild hunches.
Take my wild hunch
out of the equation.
DiaCure is still an excellent
partner for Chastain,
regardless.
It's Jessica.
Car versus tree.
GCS 7 on arrival.
Head trauma with
positive seat belt sign.
- BP 60 over palp.
- Okay. How long
was she out there?
Took an hour to extricate
her. Not sure how long
Jessica was waiting
before she was found.
Oh, my God. Jess. Jess!
- Oh, my God.
- You're home now, sweetie.
Jess!
- How is she?
- We don't know yet,
but we got her.
Unhook her. Let's move her.
And on my count, let's go.
One, two, three.
- What happened?
- Don't know. Nobody around,
no skid marks.
Might have fallen
asleep at the wheel.
Oh, my God.
What's her access?
She needs volume now.
One 22-gauge in her
thumb. We're trying
to get a bigger peripheral,
but her veins are all collapsed.
She was tired. She was
coming off a double shift.
You need to leave, Dr. Feldman.
Give me an introducer.
I will get access.
Nurse, hold her C-spine.
Abdomen's soft. I got the FAST.
I'll do it. I have
to do something.
You need to let
us take care of her.
- What?
- You need to let us
take care of her. We got this.
We got it.
No.
- Pravesh,
Pravesh. Pravesh!
- No!
- Whoa, whoa.
- Pravesh, get him out of here!
- Get him out of here now!
- No! Get off of me!
- Go.
- No! Get your hands off of me!
- Wait. Wait.
- Let me stay! I want to stay in the room.
I've got to stay in the room.
Now anything?
♪ ♪
- Wait. Wait, wait, wait.
- She's been down too long.
- How much more time?!
- Another 20 seconds.
- Where's
that introducer?
- Happening as fast
- as superhumanly possible.
- Ah.
Come on.
All right, and we... are... in.
Get that blood in her now
and add an amp of bicarb.
Two minutes. Pulse check.
I got a pulse. We got a
pulse. All right. All right.
All right. All right.
- It's thready,
but it's there. Jess?
- Okay. All right.
- It's thready, but it's there.
- Here we go.
Jess. Jess, welcome back.
Now stay with me. Stay with me!
Okay, come on. All right.
Abdomen's not so soft now.
Come on.
It's full of blood.
We got to find the
bleeding and stop it now.
Hundley, call the OR.
Hundley!
- Page Neuro.
- How are the pupils?
They're reactive, but...
We need Neuro.
Let's go. Come on.
Come on, come on,
come on, come on.
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
How is she?
Massive intra-abdominal
hemorrhage.
- She's in good hands now.
- I got the page.
What's with the audience?
She's one of your scrub
nurses... Jessica Moore.
She's been in nearly
half of your surgeries.
- She needs a head CT.
- No time. She'll bleed out
on the CT table. We do this now.
I'll just put in an
extraventricular drain
to measure pressure
and control the swelling.
I can do that blind.
Well, that's quite reassuring.
My job isn't to reassure you.
So, that's where we are.
Thanks for checking in.
- I'll keep you posted.
- Dr. Bell?
- Yeah?
- How is she?
They're taking her for
an emergency ex-lap.
This is on Red Rock.
- I...
- They cut staff,
overscheduled the OR, and
now Jessica's paying for it.
- We need more nurses.
- Can we just talk
about this later?
No!
We lost some of our
best due to the hours
and salary cuts that
Red Rock instituted.
- Uh...
- I have people working
a double shift right now.
- Do you want more Jessicas?
- No, of course not.
I'm devastated by this. I...
You have... you have any idea
how many hours I've
spent in an OR with Jessica?
How many times she's had
my back in a tough surgery?
Don't suggest that I don't
care what's happening to her.
She's not just a
member of my team.
She's like...
She's family to me.
Look...
I have one nurse today,
and she's a student.
Even if she was fully trained,
that's not nearly enough.
We can't keep doing
this. We need help.
I'll see what I can do
about getting more nurses.
Okay.
Hey.
Hey, how is she?
Cain and Raptor are
just getting started.
Did you get ahold
of her parents?
They're on their way.
From Europe.
They go twice a year...
Bordeaux and Tuscany.
This is their, uh,
Bordeaux trip.
Apparently, they're
really into wine.
She was going to introduce
me to them at Thanksgiving.
Um... they're getting
on a plane right now.
No contact for several hours.
Have they designated a health
care proxy until they get here?
Yes. Me.
Good. Good choice.
You're a doctor.
Let me help you start
that paperwork, okay?
No. No, no, no, no.
I'm not leaving her.
Irving, I know that
you are scared.
Scared?
Scared does not cover it.
This is all my fault.
How is this your fault?
She's been pulling
doubles for days.
And then, we had
that game night.
I knew she was exhausted.
And... yesterday,
she was heading out, and I...
Okay. Five seconds of
action, and then I'm on the road.
Oh. Mmm.
Usually, it's at least
- ten seconds.
- Well...
- You look tired.
- Thank you.
It's totally what a
girl wants to hear
from a guy whose scrubs
she wants to get into.
No, no, no. You know I
always think you're beautiful.
- Mm-hmm.
- I'm just wondering
if you need a ride home.
Okay, least sexy
supply closet time ever.
I'm sorry.
- Okay. Much better?
- Mm-hmm.
I let her go.
No. No.
You did not let her do anything.
This is not on you or her.
If you want to blame
someone, blame Red Rock.
Assigning blame
doesn't help Jessica.
Focus on what you can do now.
Okay?
I will stay on the OR floor.
I will be right here
to get updates.
I will let you know as
soon as I hear anything.
I will meet up with
you in the ICU.
Go.
Before we begin,
a quick gut check.
One of our own is on the table.
Anyone too tired... physically
or emotionally...
Should step out now.
Should I step out?
I worked two 30-hour
shifts this week.
Oh, wait. I'm the brain
surgeon. I should probably stay.
It's important that we are all
in tip-top shape for Jessica.
So again, are we good?
Nurse,
how many shifts have
you had this week?
Not as many as Jessica.
She, um...
She covered for me yesterday.
Then I'm going to have
to ask you to step out.
For Jessica.
Okay.
That's a nice plan. Now
we're down a scrub nurse
without enough
time to replace her.
- I'll do it.
- Aren't you a resident?
I'm a surgeon. Surely I can
handle scrub nurse duties.
Well, then it's settled.
Nurse/Doctor Mina Okafor
is on the case. Let's go.
How long have you
been in nursing school?
Uh, two years. I'm so excited
to finally be here
in a real hospital.
Can't wait to get into
the trenches, you know.
Really start
practicing medicine.
Good, 'cause you're about
to hit the ground running.
We're working general
medicine and the ICU today.
Wow. Is that, is that normal?
No. It's a disaster.
We're shorthanded, and we're
down one very important woman.
I heard about the scrub nurse
while I was filling
out my paperwork.
- I'm sorry. I hope she's okay.
- Me, too.
I'll be going between
our patients and checking
on Jessica today, so... I
need you to keep up with me.
Oh, yeah. I'll try.
- Oh, my God.
- Dad.
Ah. Oh, I heard
there was an accident,
a Chastain nurse.
I was terrified.
Well, I'm fine.
Okay, you can let go now.
All right.
I'm okay. Uh, this is,
uh, Clara. She's
our student nurse.
- Hi.
- That's my dad, Kyle Nevin.
I will update you
on Jessica later,
but right now I got to go.
Hey, hey, hey. I can help.
Uh...
Isn't it pretty great?
First day on the
job as a volunteer.
Well, I guess I will be training
you both simultaneously.
Go Team Nevin.
Thank you. Thank you.
Hi.
How is she?
Um...
she had massive internal
injuries from the accident.
But Austin and Mina were
able to repair everything
- in her abdomen.
- It's her brain
that's the issue.
She was showing
signs of increased
intracranial pressure, so...
Cain put a drain in.
Have they done a post-op CT?
Yeah, and there was no bleed.
That's good news.
But there are signs of swelling.
Keeping an eye on her.
And being positive.
Here, let me do that.
I'm her health care
proxy and a doctor, so...
I'm responsible.
We're all here for you.
So we're all responsible.
No matter how busy it
gets, Jessica is the priority.
Right. Good.
The post-op labs.
- I got to check to see
if they're back. Yep.
I'm on them.
You stay here with Jessica.
We'll all be here
as much as we can.
You're gonna be sick
of seeing our faces.
Thank you.
Both of you.
Can I help you?
You must be Dr. Bell.
Yeah, that's the
name on the door.
You are?
Logan Kim. Exec VP of Red Rock.
You left a message
with my office.
I left a message
with Emma O'Neil.
Emma is head of Red
Rock's transition team.
Transition's over.
I'll be overseeing the
day-to-day operations
of the hospital now.
I oversee the day-to-day.
It's a partnership.
No.
We have distinct duties.
You make payroll. I'm CEO.
Let-Let's avoid a-a
pissing contest, shall we?
Sorry. Yeah.
Um... we've had a rough morning.
One of our best nurses
fell asleep at the wheel,
and her life is hanging
by a thread. She's...
she's working double shifts
due to our nursing shortage.
Let's-let's walk that
back, uh, immediately.
A single car accident doesn't
mean that she was asleep
at the wheel. Could have
been a suicide attempt.
Maybe she was texting.
Well, when she
wakes up, we'll...
Well, if she wakes
up. If she doesn't,
we may never know for sure.
Did PR feed you that?
I know exactly what happened.
She was overworked.
She was exhausted.
She had a long drive home,
and she fell
asleep at the wheel.
You could spin it that way,
which might lead the press
to investigate other
overworked employees,
like a resident who fell
through a skylight on your watch.
I-I'm not pointing any fingers,
and I hope no one else will,
but one CEO could easily be
made a scapegoat for both incidents.
Are you threatening me?
Absolutely not.
But I'm trying to make you see
how much smoother
things will run
if we're both playing
for the same team:
the shareholders of Red
Rock Mountain Medical.
Anything?
Post-op blood
tests aren't back yet.
Yeah. Come on.
I take it all that optimism
was for Irving's sake.
I'm scared to death.
For both of them.
If something happens to her...
Don't even say it.
If it had been
you, I would be...
- I have no idea what I'd be.
- Hey.
I'm fine. Okay?
But we have to do something.
This is on Red Rock.
Jessica was overworked.
We're all overworked.
It's this system.
It's not right.
What do you want to do?
Today,
we focus on Jessica.
We make sure she's okay.
We make sure Irving's
okay. But tomorrow?
Tomorrow we keep fighting.
Oh, sorry.
I was just looking
for an extra pillow.
Jessica.
Top shelf, Dad.
Yeah. Sorry.
Why don't you
- figure this out. Look at the...
- I-I'm sorry, sir.
- I don't know anything
about the TV.
- I'm gonna take this to 921.
Hey.
Hey! Hey, how do you... how
do you change the channel?
Because the-the TV's
just showing birds.
Well, that's a nature
channel. I think
- it's meant to keep you calm.
- Yeah, well-well,
I hate birds, and
it's driving me crazy.
Uh, see, I'll just, uh...
I'll just...
I'll get a new one.
Thank you.
Her ICP
has been increasing
over the last few hours.
We need to get her back into
surgery to control the swelling.
Well, she's still recovering
from the last surgery.
I'd advise we go forward
with nonsurgical care
- while she's still fragile.
- We've already been doing that.
Medical management
is not cutting it.
We need to move on to surgical
options. Now, you want her
- to have irreversible
brain damage? Hey.
- A little sensitivity.
- The next step is
a decompressive hemicraniectomy.
Temporarily pop off
a piece of her skull
and allow her brain
room to expand.
She's febrile.
In renal failure.
And have you seen
her post-op CBC?
Her platelets
are critically low,
which makes a
craniectomy far riskier.
I think we still have time left
to optimize her the best we can
before going back
in for another surgery.
All right, so, everyone listen
to the third-year resident
and follow him anywhere.
- I'm the attending.
- I'm also the attending,
and Irving asked
Conrad to coordinate care.
All right, so why don't we
just go find the nursing student
who's been bumbling
around the floor somewhere?
Maybe she would
like a say, as well.
Conrad has the last word.
Right, Irving? He's
making the call.
Let's get this straight.
I'm a neurosurgeon.
This woman is in
need of neurosurgery.
If her brain continues to
swell, she's gonna herniate.
She's either gonna die
or have zero chances
of waking up tomorrow
as anything more than...
Why don't we all say
this one together...
A vegetable.
We can place her
in a barbiturate coma.
That'll give us a chance
to control the swelling
while she recovers
from the trauma of the
surgery she just went through.
Look, we've all been
here before in medicine
where there is no
clear-cut answer.
- We need to work together...
- Now an intern speaks. Really?
Why don't we just
poll all of Atlanta.
Maybe everyone should
have a voice at Chastain.
Jessica's only in this
situation because you
- overworked her for weeks.
- Oh, right.
So now I'm
responsible for a nurse
who didn't know
enough to call an Uber.
No. But you will be responsible
if she arrests on the table
because her body can't handle
another invasive surgery.
Conrad makes this call.
Some medical proxy you are.
When she dies,
it's gonna be on you.
Look, I didn't want to
contradict you in front of Cain,
but I'm not 100%
about waiting to address
Jessica's intracranial pressure.
I know. I feel the same way.
But it is a judgment call,
and I don't want to send her
back to the OR with a
dropping platelet count
that we can't explain when
there are other medical options.
Are you sure that continuing
with conservative management
is gonna help her ICP?
It's worth a try,
particularly in this case.
If she doesn't clot
in surgery, she dies.
Okay, I'm on board.
But a word of caution.
You know Cain has the
juice with Red Rock, right?
You know he is their
cash register, Hawkins.
I am well aware.
Since he came here,
invasive brain and spine
surgeries are up 49%.
Now, you ask yourself, how
many of those are necessary?
Cain cuts when
no one else would.
So, you think he might be
doing it again with Jessica?
I think he's a cowboy.
I love surgeons with attitude
- and even a healthy ego.
- Hmm.
If they put patients
first, like you do.
Well, I don't mind
residents with cojones.
But you tread lightly.
You just made a dangerous enemy.
How-how about bald
but still banging
with the best of them.
Hey, Nic.
Hi. Uh, this is my daughter.
She's a nurse practitioner
here. Nic, this is Jackie,
a 70-year-old woman
with congestive heart failure
here for IV diuretics,
which requires monitoring
throughout the day.
Well done, Dad, but I
know. Jackie's my patient.
Did you know that Jackie
and her daughter Leslie
here have a business together?
They cross-stitch pillows
with risqué phrases on them.
- Mm, I did not.
- Did you know that?
- I did not. I need one of those.
- Oh.
- Um, did you get Jackie's lunch?
- Uh...
I came to take her
order. We got to talking.
I'm-I'm on it.
Uh, does he like older women?
Mom.
What? He's adorable.
Okay, this isn't the bar.
This is Clara. She'll be
starting your IV today.
Have you ever done this before?
On a, uh, mannequin.
But I always won when
we did IV races in class.
- Clara's in training.
- Ow.
Nic, she's gonna kill me.
She's not gonna kill you.
Listen to your patient.
The band's too tight.
Got it.
Oh, pro tip, girlie.
Real people feel more pain
than mannequins.
She's stable.
She's resting.
Buddy, you need
to eat something.
- I'm not leaving her.
- You need
to take care of yourself
- in order
to take care of Jessica.
- Come to the cafeteria.
We're gonna get you some food.
Conrad ordered more labs.
I'm waiting until they come back.
They're not gonna be
back for another hour.
Come on. It's
tri-tip sandwich day.
You love tri-tip sandwich day.
I'm not hungry.
You need to eat anyway.
Don't make us drag you.
Dr. Feldman.
I'd like to spend a few
minutes with Jessica,
if that's all right.
See?
She's not gonna be alone.
Everyone loves her.
I think she'd be
honored, Dr. Bell.
I know how much
she respects you.
All right.
Hey.
What can I get you, Dr. Feldman?
Uh, his usual.
Tri-tip sandwich coming up.
You don't look so good.
Go sit.
Grab that free table, okay?
We may need to get a social
worker to come talk to him.
Get him something
for his anxiety.
He needs to keep a clear head.
Let's get some food in him.
We're out of tri-tip.
Tuna salad?
It's tri-tip day.
The man needs
a tri-tip sandwich.
He doesn't like tuna salad.
Do you understand?
So go back there
and get some tri-tip!
We're all having a bad day.
That was uncalled for.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
I heard about Jessica.
I understand.
We're all in it together.
What's going on?
Got more labs back.
Platelets are still falling,
and now she's anemic,
so I paged Austin.
That doesn't make any sense.
She's gotten over
20 units PRBCs,
15 FFPs, ten
units of platelets...
Yeah, well, you better
keep 'em coming.
You think she's still bleeding?
I don't see anything
in her chest.
Her belly's nice and soft.
Well, where's all
the blood going?
We're working on that.
You're sure you didn't
miss a bleed somewhere?
Maybe the retroperitoneum
or pleural cavities?
No, I didn't miss anything.
You can't know
that. Maybe, this time,
you missed something and
that's why Jessica's still too sick
for surgery. And now
she's running out of time.
Hey. Remember, we
are on the same side.
I'll take her for another CT,
just to make sure we're
not missing anything.
I didn't miss anything.
But let's get another
CT, so we can be certain.
I'm sorry I left you, babe.
I'm sorry.
What's going on?
She's still anemic
and thrombocytopenic
despite multiple transfusions.
Why?
I'm working on it.
Honestly, I don't know.
There's nothing on the CT?
No.
I called the CEO of DiaCure.
We made a deal.
We're gonna use their
dialysis equipment exclusively.
You can get the data you need.
I-I just, uh...
just felt like I had to
do something positive.
J-Jessica's...
She's my favorite
of the OR nurses.
You know, she's
a... She's a pistol.
You know. And...
sweet.
And a lady.
So this one's for her.
Wish it were more.
It's all I got.
Thank you.
Your dressing
needs to be changed.
Get me a real nurse.
He's been picking
at his cellulitis.
Yeah, bec... I can't
help it, because it itches.
All right? So why don't... Why
don't you give me something
in-instead of
getting in my face?
That sounds like drug
seeking to me, and...
- Sir, you can't-can't do that.
- Steve.
Sir. Sir...
- You need to get back in bed. Hey, hey.
Steve, come on. You
got to get back in bed.
Nic!
The meth head is
trying to kill your father!
Help! Hey, hey, hey!
Code gray!
- Hey, hey.
- Hey, hey, hey.
- Ow! Oh!
- Hey! Hey!
Ow! Ow! Ow, ow! Ow, ow, ow!
Hold him down!
Let go of me!
- Dad, are you okay?
- Yeah. He bit me.
Is that bad?
He didn't break the skin,
but we'll take a look at it,
just in case.
- It's okay.
- Oh, it's a good... it was a good thing I was here.
Right place at the right time.
He could've hurt... uh, Clara.
Clara, I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have left you alone.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I'm fine.
Ooh, ooh.
He s-spit on me.
Oh, God.
You okay?
Yeah, it's fine. I'm fine.
It's okay not to be fine.
Nursing school doesn't
prepare you for a day like this.
I quit.
You can't.
I'm sorry.
I'm short of nurses, and I
need everybody that I can get.
Plus...
you can do this.
I don't want to.
I mean...
it was one thing
when it was on paper.
What are the warning
signs of heart failure?
How many milliliters?
I liked studying medicine.
But when it comes to this...
Look, you've had a
seriously difficult first day.
But, hey, at least no
one threw up on you.
No one pulled a chunk
of hair out of your head.
That happened to you?
First day.
God, why do you do this?
Look, we don't have
to like all of our patients.
But we do have to
take care of them.
Because, whoever they are,
they're sick and in pain.
And it's our job
to deal with it.
And sometimes,
yes, it is so hard.
But...
not many people get a
chance to make a difference.
A good nurse can.
You've invested...
two years in this?
Student debt, I imagine?
You can always quit
on your second day.
Come on.
You got this. Let's go.
You figure out what's going
on with her blood counts?
No.
Her ICP keeps going up.
We don't have any more time.
You delayed this surgery
for no good reason.
You failed.
Self-important neophyte,
you don't even know
how much you don't know.
I'm gonna remove the
pressure from her brain
and hope it's not too
late. So, congratulations.
Your narcissism almost
killed your patient.
Saw to me.
Are you sure you're
okay to be here?
This is the last place
on earth I want to be,
and I won't be anywhere else.
Scalpel.
Lap pads. Cautery.
- There's too much blood.
- Get suction in, damn it.
Suction.
Oh, my God. No.
This is exactly what
Conrad said would happen.
Why isn't she clotting?
Hey, man,
we didn't have a choice anymore.
When you wait too
long, her brain swells
and she dies. You
go back in there
without correcting her
coagulopathy, she bleeds out.
It was my job to figure it out.
Maybe we still can.
Let's work on the differential.
Together.
Okay.
All right, she's
bleeding. It won't stop.
Why?
- And where does the blood go?
- Into the body
- or onto the floor.
- In this case, neither.
Jessica's not losing platelets.
Her body is destroying them.
Hemolysis, low platelets,
renal dysfunction, fever.
- It's got to be TTP.
- Oh, God.
If she has TTP, her platelet
count will just keep dropping.
She'll never clot.
This surgery is
going to kill her,
and I gave the okay
to go ahead with it.
Now that we know what it is,
we can treat it.
So you're gonna
start plasmapheresis
while she's in surgery?
Hell yeah, he is.
Move faster. Get that bleeder.
I'm moving as fast as I
can. It's oozing everywhere.
Keep hanging those platelets.
Get out of my OR! Now!
I'm chief of surgery.
Every OR in Chastain is my OR.
Hawkins stays.
- What's happening?
- Jessica has TTP.
- Giving her more platelets
won't help.
- Scrub nurse, ignore him.
- I need you with me
on this cautery.
- All you.
- Conrad, I'll get access.
- Thank you.
You can do that
plasmapheresis when I'm done.
You have no idea
even if you're right,
let alone if it's gonna help.
Okay, now we can cauterize.
Now she has a chance.
Dr. Bell, just wanted
to congratulate you.
What for?
Heard you made a
very lucrative deal today.
- DiaCure Dialysis Centers.
- Yeah.
They gave us a great
price for exclusivity.
That deserves an
"attaboy" from the new veep.
What kind of kickback did
they offer us for the contract?
Some data we required
for patient safety,
and they committed to help
us with the money we need
- to fill out our nursing staff.
- Whoa.
Punching above
your weight there.
I'll make the call on
where the money goes.
I'm thinking Neuro.
Barrett's got a laundry
list of line items.
Barrett?
You on a first-name
basis with Dr. Cain?
We go way back. He's
the one who got me this job.
Lured me away from a
hedge fund on the West Coast.
You have no
background in health care.
I have a
background... in profits.
Well, this profit
goes for more nurses.
It's... it's part of
the agreement.
It can't be undone.
No more deals like this
again without my input.
Hey. I'm just gonna
change the dressing.
All right, let's see
what we have.
There isn't very much
blood around the incision.
It's starting to clot.
We'll get another CBC.
Yeah, well, we can send
it in, but this is good news.
The plasmapheresis is working.
She still might not wake up.
And if she does,
we have no idea what
kind of shape she'll be in.
We'll know more in 24 hours.
- Hey, Dad, wait.
- Oh, Nic.
I just finished my shift.
- You need something?
- Look, um...
Thanks for being here today.
I love volunteering.
I know you were scared
that it was me when you heard
about the accident this morning.
I brushed you off.
I'm sorry I did that.
You're all I got, kid.
We're Team Nevin now.
Still no change in Jessica.
What's this?
DiaCure records.
You got them.
Yeah.
It's worse than we thought.
20% higher complication
rate with Hemopleatin.
Look at all these PEs.
This drug is probably
what killed Jessie.
I think so.
What do you think
the next step is?
Tomorrow I go in to
see Bell and Red Rock,
and get this drug
pulled off the shelves.
Permanently.
You know how
dangerous that is, Conrad?
Big Pharma is ruthless.
They could go after you.
They always like to
discredit the messenger.
The numbers don't lie.
We'll make sure what
happened to Jessie
doesn't happen to anyone else.
Her death could save lives.
As awful as this is, I
learned something today.
I really love her.
I don't think I
realized how much
until I thought I
might lose her.
If she comes back
to me, I'll tell her.
Please come back to me.
We all see how much
you guys love each other.
You know, I beat myself up
about leaving
Priya at the altar.
But now I know it was right.
Because what we
had... it wasn't this.
Don't make this
about you, Pravesh.
Hey.
Thank you.
Oh!
- Um, okay.
- It's happening.
Give into it.
- Oh, that's tight. But...
- Yeah.
Come on. There you go.
Oh, buddy.
Hmm, you're certain you
have enough patient information
to prove that Hemopleatin
is causing sudden death
in a significant
number of patients?
Yes.
We need to pull it
immediately and warn the FDA.
No, I've looked over the
data; Dr. Hawkins is right.
The complication
rate is off the charts.
I'll-I'll have my people
go over the figures,
and if this checks out,
we'll use it to
make a PR splash.
Chastain catches a deadly drug
- and saves patients.
- And in the meantime,
we can go back to using an
older drug that we know to be safe.
And, more good news,
it's actually cheaper.
Well, that's a huge
win on all fronts.
- Really nice work.
- All right.
Thank you.
That info...
was part of the DiaCure deal.
So you helped him?
Yeah. Yeah.
But I'm happy to let the
hospital take the credit.
Okay.
Wake up.
Me or her?
Both, I think.
- Mm.
- Jess? Honey?
- Jess?
- Mm.
Can you hear me?
- Can you hear me? Hey. Hey.
- Hey. Hey, hey. Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Careful, careful.
Shh, shh. No, don't do that.
- You're okay. Hey.
- Hey, Jess.
Honey.
Hey. You're okay.
You're fine. You're fine.
It's a long story, but
everything's gonna be just fine.
Okay. Here we go. Here we go.
You could use
some vittles in ya.
All right. I'll eat now.
- This is a mess.
- Do the honors.
- This looks good.
- Yeah, this is not
from the cafeteria.
Okay, I want the little
baby one over here.
I heard the good news.
- Dr. Hawkins, a word?
- Yeah, sure thing.
I just want to say, I, uh,
appreciate what you did,
and I actually regret
that we had words.
It-it was an emotional
day for all of us.
No doubt. No doubt.
But don't ever question
my decision again.
Well, when I'm wrong,
I've learned to listen
to my colleagues.
You're not a colleague.
You're a subordinate
and I don't give a damn
what your process is.
You're not invincible, you know.
No one is.
You sure about that?
We on the same page?
You tell me.
Hawkins is a whistleblower.
My concern is him deciding
in his self-righteous way
that Red Rock is doing
something he doesn't like.
That's not something
I can live with.
Then there's our answer.
He's a threat to the hospital.
I'll handle it.
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH