OR 2.0 is the fruit
of years of development.
Dean won't be swayed
by Dayton's new shiny toys.
I don't know if we're
on a path to getting back
together or divorce.
I'm here if you ever
need to talk.
I know.
Liliana? I've been out to her
house twice for dinner now.
Third one's on the books.
That's wonderful.
I'm so happy for you.
In the OR,
you were in pain.
I'm fine, Dr. Asher.
But you have to let
somebody check you out.
Any nausea, vomiting?
Nope.
Trouble sleeping,
headaches?
I mean, you've met
my interns, right?
Come on, Mark. I see
the pulmonary edema
in my X-ray.
What's going on?
BUN, creatin,
potassium all elevated.
Heart rate and BP
are up, too.
Fluid retention. Crap.
You been staying
off the NSAIDs?
Of course.
Sticking to
the renal diet?
Man, I think I've maxed out
on the amount of cabbage
I can eat in one day.
So what now? Diuretics?
We'll start you
on low-dose Lasix,
see if that reduces
the swelling.
It's gonna be hard
to run an ED
when I'm in the john
every half hour.
You could always let
your kidneys fail
and kill you
if your interns
don't get you first.
Sweet release.
All right, Mark. Thanks.
Sure.
It's open mic night,
so there'll be more people
there than before.
I'm gonna get there
very early.
I got a seat
right down front,
right there.
You don't have to come
to every single time
I sing.
Of course I don't
have to come.
I enjoy it.
I enjoy
watching you sing.
Morning, Dan.
Peter,
how you doing?
Hey, Peter, have you...
Have you met
my friend Liliana?
No, I mean,
that is yes.
I've seen you around.
Housekeeping right?
Yes.
We met actually
at a nightclub where
Liliana was performing.
She is a sensational
opera singer.
I just sing for fun,
for myself.
Well, it's very nice
to meet you,
and thank you for
excellent work
around here.
Mmm-hmm.
Damn.
You know, I can't believe
this has never occurred
to me before, but, um...
But my... I have a really good
friend who was on the board
of the Lyric Opera.
No, no.
They're very nice, Daniel.
No, I was just
thinking maybe
I could find out when
the next round of auditions
are or something.
No, I don't think so,
but thank you.
I should get to work.
Okay.
I will, um...
I'll see you later.
Okay, thank you.
Thank you.
Maggie.
Sharon.
You're a lifesaver.
What happened?
Said it was the fan belt.
I don't know.
Oh, man.
You know Ben normally
takes care of these things,
but, you know,
I'm trying to give him
a little bit of space.
It's not easy, is it?
Yeah. Oh, thank you.
Thank you.
No.
No, I just...
I don't know how
we come back from this
if we don't talk.
Well, you know time
is a great healer.
I hope so.
Sorry I made you
late for work.
Oh, please.
With Jack Dayton in charge,
no one's watching me clock in.
Help!
Did you hear that?
Yeah, over here.
Help! Help.
She's been hit.
That car hit her!
We're nurses.
Let us help you.
That maniac
hit her straight on.
What is her name?
Rose Howard.
Rose.
Rose?
Are you okay?
I'm fine. I'm more worried
about her.
Please, please.
Okay.
Rose, nod if you can hear me.
Let me call an ambo.
Please, you have to
help her.
I'm gonna look
into your eyes, Rose.
There you go.
There you go. Yes.
Okay.
Ambo's on its way.
Great.
I'm right here.
Gonna keep you warm, girl.
There you go.
Here's the ambo.
Eyes open. You're good.
You're good.
Ms. Goodwin, Maggie,
what've we got?
Peds versus auto.
No loss of consciousness,
but she's shocky.
Her name
is Rose Howard.
All right,
we gotta move her.
Okay. A little help.
On my count,
one, two, three.
Rolling.
Okay, it's okay.
It's okay.
There we go.
I'll switch places
with you.
On my count,
one, two, three.
All right. There we go.
Yeah, we got
an ambo coming in.
We're trailing.
I'm sorry.
You can't ride along.
Rose is too unstable.
We'll send another ambo
to come check you out.
No, I'm fine.
Go on. Get her
to the hospital please.
She needs to be examined.
Go. We got her.
I have a first aid kit
in my car.
Listen, listen, we work
at the hospital
where they're
taking Rose.
Okay.
Maybe you can ride with us
and so you can stay close,
and then we could get
you checked out, okay?
Okay.
It's all good, okay.
Okay. Yeah, let's go.
Let's go.
All right, let's go.
Hey, Jack.
Thank you.
You have a moment?
Yeah. For you, always.
Oh, actually,
you two ought to meet.
Now this is
Dr. Grace Song.
She's an incredible surgeon
in her own right,
and I managed
to lure her away
to Dayton Corp.
Crockett Marcel.
Pleasure to meet you.
I heard you and 2.0
are a match made in heaven.
Well, it's a remarkable
advancement
and exactly what
I'd like to talk about.
Yeah.
So I...
I'd like to train
other surgeons on it.
Mmm-hmm.
Right now, it's just me,
but it would help
if more could
familiarize themselves
with the suite.
Well, 2.0 was always intended
to be an adaptive platform,
so more users,
more data, better outcome.
Yeah, bring in
who you want.
Great.
I'll see you around.
Mr. Dayton...
Yeah.
Did you get a chance
to read my email?
I saw it. I just haven't
opened it yet.
Okay, I'd really like
to set up a time...
You know, just hold that
thought. This may address
your concern.
Good morning, everyone.
Promise not to take up
too much of your time.
Now, it's become clear to me
over the past few weeks
that, well, I have a lot
to learn about medicine.
And when
I don't know something,
I like to turn to the experts,
and that's you,
which is why I asked
Dr. Grace Song here
to spend a little bit
more time in the ED.
Now she is one
of my top minds,
and I've tasked her
with finding ways to make
your jobs easier,
more efficient,
so that you can keep doing
your incredible work.
So please feel free to discuss
with her any areas
that you feel
can be better optimized.
Thank you so much.
I hope that helps.
Actually, no,
that doesn't help.
So is that your plan,
replace us with robots?
Dr. Archer.
Yeah, you'd get more jokes in
if you were actually on time.
Or we can program
the robots to be funny.
No one likes change,
and tech can feel
overwhelming, but I...
I'm not some Luddite.
I just don't think
we need to invent
high-tech solutions
for problems
that don't exist.
Totally.
That's part of
what's exciting right now.
We're deciding
how to use tech
so that it's empowering
without it making us want
to pull our hair out.
It works for us,
not the other
way around.
Couldn't have
said it better myself.
See you in a bit.
That's a fine sentiment,
Dr. Song.
I'm curious to see
how you put it into action.
Okay, well, take
Ginger Spice over there.
You could be verbally
charting directly
into our new EMR instead
of wasting time typing
or copy-and-pasting.
Typing after I see
a patient is how
I've always done it.
You're creating more work
for yourself.
You still have
to manually input your notes
and, in the interim,
hope that there's no gap
in communication
with nursing.
Hasn't been
a problem before.
Besides, it allows me
to have time
to wrap my head around
patient history, lab results,
before handoff.
Or you could be spending
that time with more patients.
With my nose buried
in a screen.
This little debate
is stimulating,
but I'm sure you'll find
it's also very inefficient.
Case waiting for you in 4,
Ginger Spice.
Thanks anyway
for the suggestion.
Here to help.
Mr. and Mrs. Rouse.
Please, Connie.
David. Our son Jason.
Hey, Jason.
Hey, heard you're not
feeling well.
What?
Where am I?
We're at the hospital, honey.
I'm gonna listen
to your chest, all right?
Leave me alone.
Sorry, buddy. Almost done.
He's been irritable,
confused.
We thought
he was just tired.
He recently joined
the soccer team.
He's crazy about it.
Wouldn't stop playing.
But then he stopped
eating as much
and didn't have
the energy to play.
Please,
you gotta understand...
Twelve years ago,
we lost our son Axel
before his first birthday.
First, he wouldn't
stop crying,
then he got weak,
and then finally seizures.
We had to watch our son
disappear right in front
of our eyes.
The doctors poked
and prodded him
with thousands of tests.
They even came up to our house
to check for lead and mold.
Yeah, all that and they never
figured out how to help.
I'm so sorry.
We've been vigilant,
probably paranoid,
ever since.
Every sniffle, every scrape,
he goes to the doctor,
but now this.
Well, without a diagnosis,
I don't want to speculate
about a possible connection.
I think Jason is likely
dealing with an infection,
but I'll make sure
we're casting a wide net.
Okay?
Yes, please, anything.
Hang tight.
We'll figure this out.
Dr. Asher, incoming
postpartum and bleeding.
Got it.
Jackie, going to 3.
Laurel Wilson, 26 years old,
G1P1 postpartum day nine.
Found unresponsive.
There was so much blood.
GCS 11, BP initially 90 over
palp with heart rate of 120.
Liter of saline improved her
to 110 over 60, rate 110.
Okay, how much does
she been bleeding?
I don't know. How could we?
That's the problem.
Okay, on my count.
Ready. One, two, three.
Has she passed
any clots?
Uh, yes.
What size?
Golf ball, apple?
Uh, golf ball, I think.
I told her to call 911,
but she was passed out
when I got home.
CBC type and cross-match,
CMP coags, and hang
two units of O neg.
On it.
What's wrong with my wife?
I believe she has a piece
of retained placenta,
which is why she hasn't
been able to stop bleeding.
Okay.
Yeah, there it is.
I can bring her
through this, but I need
to perform a procedure
to remove the tissue, okay?
Yeah.
All right,
open the hybrid OR
for an emergency D&C.
You got it.
We're going to Baghdad.
What do we got?
Rose Howard,
32-year-old female, MVC.
I gave her
500 normal salines
on the ride,
but her BP's
still hovering
at 88 over 56.
Rate's 140s.
Okay, two units
of whole blood please.
Pelvic fracture?
Yeah, Ms. Goodwin and Maggie
thought they felt instability,
so they wrapped in the field.
All right,
we need X-ray in here.
All right, let's get her
transferred.
Nice and easy on my count.
Here we go,
one, two, three.
All right, thanks,
Caesar, Tanya.
All right, X-ray chest
and pelvis,
and let's get her
on the rapid
transfusion, please.
Hey, Rose. I'm Dr. Marcel.
We got you, okay?
It still hurts.
Okay, well, let's have a look.
Fast scan.
Yeah, good amount
of fluid in her belly.
Yeah, she'll need a lap.
All right, let's see what
the X-ray shows.
Okay. Thank you, Kaley.
X-ray up.
Comminuted pelvic fracture
to the iliac wing.
Mediastinum's high.
Right, we'll deal
with those later.
The abdominal bleeding's
our priority.
All right, Rose,
we're gonna take you up
to surgery now.
Kizzy, yeah, call upstairs.
We need an OR.
2.0 is open.
Better imaging's available,
and we still don't know
the full extent
of her injuries.
And emergent trauma
is not the time to play
with your fancy toy.
No, we're gonna treat
this abdominal case
like all the others,
all right?
Let's go.
It's all my fault.
We were arguing.
She started
to walk away.
I ran after her
and tried to grab her,
and that's when the car
came out of nowhere.
If I just let her go,
maybe she would have...
No, no. It was
the driver's fault.
Paola, you okay?
Talk to me.
I can't breathe.
I don't know...
Maggie,
there's a stethoscope
in the first aid kit
in the back.
Paola, listen to me.
Focus on your breathing.
Take long, slow breaths.
Okay?
Diminished breath sounds
on the left.
Distended neck veins.
Tension pneumothorax.
What's that mean?
Paola, did the car
hit you, too?
Didn't think it was bad.
You probably have
a broken rib that's punctured
your lung.
That's why you're having
problems breathing.
We can't wait.
We have to relieve this
pressure on her chest.
Okay. There's an IV catheter
in the inner pocket.
Paola, we're gonna help you.
I'm gonna
pull down your shirt,
and in count of three,
you're gonna feel a pinch.
Okay.
One, two, three.
Unfortunately, I can't offer
any solutions yet.
Jason has no signs
of electrolyte imbalance,
no markers for infection,
or any other abnormalities.
By the numbers,
there's nothing to explain
his symptoms.
You're kidding me.
Look at him.
I know this is frustrating,
which is why I'd like
to order a few more tests.
There's always more tests.
Can you at least tell us
what you're looking for?
Of course.
Jason symptoms still
strike me as an infection,
but it could be hiding,
okay, in his spinal cord
or his brain,
which would explain
the lethargy, his confusion,
and the kind of infection
that wouldn't show up
on standard tests.
So I'd like to do a CT
of his head
and a lumbar puncture.
Basically,
I'd insert a needle...
He's seizing.
Jason!
Nancy, need a hand
in here.
1.5 of Ativan.
Okay, Ativan's in.
Hey, buddy.
Jason, can you hear me?
Okay, can you look at me?
Look at my finger.
That's good.
Good.
Mom, Dad?
It's happening again,
isn't it?
It's just like Axel.
Dr. Charles,
can I get your help?
What's up?
Patient in treatment 7
Richard Wyatt.
The guy that's...
That's running
for city council.
Yeah.
He was supposed to do
some interview this morning,
but his campaign manager
found him disoriented
and slurring his speech
with a small bruise on
his head. Brought him in.
Anything interesting
in his chart?
Yeah. Workup was negative.
He's fine.
Except for the combo
of alcohol and benzos.
Don't know if it was
an accident or intentional.
I will, um...
I'll go chat with him.
Yeah. Thank you.
How you doing?
I'm Dr. Charles.
I hope you come bearing
discharge papers.
Not sure that those
are quite ready yet.
Any chance we could
expedite them?
The sooner we leave,
the sooner I can reschedule
the interview with Mathews.
He doesn't know why
we're rescheduling, right?
You handled it?
Of course.
Do you mind if I just get
a quick moment with Mr. Wyatt?
Fine. Okay.
Be in the waiting room.
Thank you.
Feels like I'm in
the principal's office.
Is something wrong?
No.
Not at all.
I just wanted to
have a quick chat.
You know, I really need
to get going, all right?
Lots to do.
Completely understand.
You did have a mixture
of alcohol and benzodiazepines
in your system, though.
I know what you're thinking
what this might look like,
but it was just
a stupid accident.
Well, look,
that's good to hear.
I just want to make sure
your prescribing doctor
did make it clear
that it's a potentially
lethal combination.
I mean, I know you shouldn't
mix medication and alcohol,
but, you know, I defy anyone
to get through a fundraiser
without at least
one scotch.
I mean, if I'd known
it was that dangerous...
Well...
Your fundraisers sound
pretty stressful to me.
You think that might be
why you took the medication?
What? No.
No, look, I just needed
to take the edge off for the
Mathews interview, all right?
He's tough.
Do you mind me asking
why you were prescribed
benzodiazepines
in the first place?
Look, this was
a one-off mistake,
and I'd appreciate it
if you'd just check on
my discharge papers.
Got it.
I will get with
Dr. Jacquerie and see if
we can move that along.
Nice to meet you.
So what's his deal?
I don't think
this has ever
happened before,
but, you know,
he's definitely
self-medicating.
Depression?
I think it's some kind
of anxiety disorder,
but anyway,
he just wants
to get out of here.
I don't have a reason
to keep him,
but if he's got an issue...
Not enough to hold him.
I'll just, you know, make sure
he has the proper referrals
before he leaves.
Yeah. This is why
I like surgery.
Patients don't talk.
Hmm.
Saw you ordered
DNA sequencing on
your patient Jason Rose.
You reading my charts?
It's a pretty unusual test
to order in the ED.
Caught my eye.
Apparently no one
has anything
they wanna optimize
around here,
so I'm just twiddling
my thumbs.
Jason's brother Axel
died 12 years ago
from uncontrolled seizures,
no diagnosis.
And now that Jason's
had a seizure...
You think they're connected,
so you ordered the sequence.
And these.
Epileptic encephalopathy.
I ruled out infection,
environmental factors,
and most
autoimmune diseases.
Genetic mutation's
the only thing
that makes sense.
Trouble is, epileptic
encephalopathy
has link to hundreds
of different mutations.
More like 1,500.
And every disease path
has a different course
of treatment.
So it's gonna take
forever to narrow down
this differential.
I think I might be able
to do that for you.
I could construct a neural
network using existing
DNA databases.
Basically bundle them
all together and put
Jason's DNA
and compare it against
tens of thousands
of known mutations.
This neural network
would take a few hours
to code,
but it could give you
a highly probable diagnosis.
Assuming the mutation's
already in one
of these databases.
We work with what we have.
I appreciate
the offer, Dr. Song,
but these parents
are terrified and need
a human they can turn to.
So I have to figure this out
the best way I know how.
You know where to find me.
Yeah.
You know,
my mom said Nathan's
looking all around.
Sweet boy.
So, Laurel, the piece
of retained placenta
has been removed,
which should resolve
the bleeding.
Thank God.
I'll still be able to get
pregnant, right?
A big family has always
been the dream.
Infertility is an extremely
rare complication
from a D&C, so yes.
Then I can go home soon?
I'd like to continue
monitoring you for a while.
You did have
heavy bleeding
for nine days.
You know, we called
the doctor's office to try
to get checked out earlier,
and they said it was fine.
Yeah, I...
I felt like
something was off,
had no appetite,
and the bleeding
seemed heavy,
but I didn't know
if heavy to me was normal
to the doctors, you know.
Bleeding can be difficult
to gauge and is subjective.
And even harder
to evaluate over
the phone.
Should I still be bleeding?
Doris, give her a gram of TXA,
0.2 milligrams methergin,
and I'll also need
1,000 micrograms of Cytotec.
Yep.
Don't worry.
We can handle this.
It's okay.
So this is those referrals
that I was telling you about.
Top two guys
on the list are excellent.
I know them personally...
Dr. Charles, you know,
you've been very thorough,
but I'm all set.
Hey, just in case, you know.
And, look, good luck
with the election.
We can't
go out this way.
Mathews must have followed
my car here.
Oh, God,
this can't happen.
They can't see me.
I have to get out of here.
Is there another exit
we could use?
You know, we might be able
to get you out through
the waiting room. Yeah.
No, there could be
more press out there.
Damn it.
How could you
let this happen, Carla?
Hey.
What am I
supposed to do?
It's okay. It's okay.
This could ruin me.
Look, you'll be all right,
all right.
Keep...
Oh, God,
Okay, breathe in
and out.
The insinuation.
In through the nose.
The rumors.
Oh, God.
Richard, you're all right.
Come here.
Come sit over here.
No, I can't!
No, no. Get over here.
Sit down.
You need to sit down.
Okay, look at me.
Look at me.
Look at me. Breathe in
through the nose
and out through
your mouth.
With me.
In through the nose.
There you go.
You're fine.
Okay.
Out through the mouth.
Zach, Paola Rivera,
the other half of the MVC,
delayed tension
pneumothorax.
Needle decompressed her
in the car.
Aw jeez, got it.
Going to 2.
Maggie, she's okay.
You need a breather.
Yeah.
Good job.
Thank you.
Spleen's out.
Rose's bleeding
is under control.
I'll just close and move
to the ICU.
You better
chest X-ray.
Widened mediastinum
could mean an aortic injury.
Yeah.
Once she's warm,
we'll get her over to CT,
clearer imaging.
In the meantime,
we can control
her blood pressure
and heart rate.
But if we find anything,
we gotta move her again
to IR in order to stent.
Yep.
That's protocol.
Come on, let's go.
Look, Dean, if it's
a contained pseudoaneurysm,
we're playing musical chairs
with a ticking time bomb.
I really think
that we should
take her to 2.0.
All right, listen,
she's still being
resuscitated.
I mean,
who knows if she'll
even be able to undergo
another procedure?
We have to warm her
either way.
Might as well do so
where we can knock out all
our birds with one stone.
Listen, 2.0 has advanced
imaging sensors.
If the aortagram
finds anything,
we can stent right there.
If Rose takes a turn,
we can easily convert to open.
No waiting, no scrambling.
Come on. I mean,
don't risk our patient where
there's another way.
All right,
after we close,
we'll get her over to 2.0,
but it's still my case.
Yeah, of course.
Thank you.
Hey, by any chance,
did you build that
neural whatever?
Neural network? Yeah.
I fooled around
with it. Why?
Jason had another seizure.
I got him out of it,
but two seizures
this close together,
risk of anoxia
is increasing.
I'm on the edge
of intubating him.
I'm running out
of ideas.
I thought it might be
Tay-Sachs or Batten disease
or Wernicke's,
but I'm basically guessing.
Can I send you Jason's DNA
to run through your system?
Absolutely.
I pulled from every
public genetic database,
but they're so new,
there isn't a ton of data.
I think I'll need to borrow
from a few private companies
to expand the pool.
Okay.
How long do you think
it'll take to get
the diagnosis?
An hour,
maybe a little longer.
I don't know if Jason
has an hour.
Is there any way
you can buy me
more time?
So you wanna put
my son in a coma?
Temporarily, yes.
The barbiturates
would reduce
the likelihood
of another seizure,
and he would be
on a ventilator,
which would
protect his airway.
So you can what,
Google search
his diagnosis?
You can't be serious.
The neural network
is scanning nearly half
a million patient profiles.
If Jason's genetic mutation
has been documented even once,
we'll find it.
And if it hasn't been
documented?
Hey, I know
we're asking a lot,
but this is Jason's
best chance for
a swift diagnosis.
Okay.
Do what you have to
to save him.
Thank you.
All right,
I'll page anesthesia.
Dr. Asher, we need you.
Shouldn't the drugs
have stopped this?
Laurel, I'm afraid
you have what we call
uterine atony.
What's that mean?
Your uterus can't contract
enough to compress
the blood vessels,
so you will keep bleeding.
Until what, I die?
Unless we act quickly.
Okay, what can we do?
Well, we only have
one option left:
a total hysterectomy.
No.
No, no, no, wait.
Wait, please.
There must be
something else.
I'm so sorry, but there's not.
You are decompensating
too quickly.
Come on.
She's just 26.
We just started our family.
I know, and I wish
that there was another way.
But in my opinion,
a hysterectomy
is the only way I can
guarantee saving your life.
Just... Just do it.
Get me home to my baby.
I promise.
Archer.
Yeah.
I feel like I'm operating
at a freaking sports bar.
All right, let's get
the stent measurement.
2.0 can calculate
that for you.
Yeah? You think it can
give me the over-under
on the Blackhawks?
All right, we've got
a 31-millimeter diameter.
Calculating.
Wait, wait, wait. Come on.
Just keep that up there,
will you?
Recommend stent size,
thirty-two millimeters
with proximal neck
of 18 millimeters.
Suggest placing
1 millimeter distal
to the left subclavian artery.
Looks good to me.
Get the stent please.
Don't you be smirking
under that mask.
Oh, I wouldn't
dream of it.
Yeah.
Thank you.
All right.
All right,
nice and easy.
User's heart rate is elevated.
Fine motor coordination
may be compromised.
Risk assessment increased 7%.
That thing talking about me?
Yeah, it says your rate's
up to 110. You okay?
Steady as a rock.
User's heart rate is elevated.
Risk of surgical error
increased by 1 1%.
Come on. Would you
shut that thing up?
Listen, I could step in,
deploy the stent.
Dr. Marcel, do you think
I'm incapable
of completing
this procedure?
I didn't say that.
Okay, then stop trying
to make friends with
a machine and assist me.
Heart rate is now 1 15.
For Christ's sake, stop...
Stop it already.
What the hell?
System malfunction.
Dean.
Error.
System malfunction.
Relax.
We'll deal with that later.
We have a patient
on the table.
That was unnecessary.
System malfunction.
Error. System malfunction.
It's over.
My campaign, everything
I've worked towards for years,
gone.
You know, I'm just not
so sure that that's
actually the case.
That kind of thinking,
by the way, we call it
catastrophizing
'cause, you know,
anxiety will do that.
This is a catastrophe.
Well...
Did you miss my meltdown
out there?
You know,
that wasn't my first.
They keep coming.
They keep getting worse.
Hmm.
What about if I have
one in public?
You think the electorate
wants to see that
or hear how sometimes
I get so panicked that
I can't think or function?
Half the time,
I have no clue why
I'm even anxious.
Yeah, you know,
that sounds like
a real winner.
I don't think
you realize
how many people
actually go through
precisely the experience
you're describing.
You know, did you know
that fully 20%
of American adults
struggle with anxiety
disorders of some kind?
You just confirmed it.
I'm crazy.
No one will elect me,
the mentally ill guy.
Would you?
Do you mind if I tell you
something personal
about myself?
A long time ago,
I was actually diagnosed
with depression,
and I vividly recall
what a blow that was.
How ashamed I felt,
like I was defective.
And then a really
smart person asked me
if I would
feel embarrassed
if I'd been diagnosed
with diabetes,
if I had
a heart condition.
Of course not.
Really helped me reframe
my diagnosis,
because that's what it was,
Richard. It was a diagnosis.
All of a sudden,
I had a name
for how I felt.
Right? I had a path
towards help.
You are not crazy,
my friend.
I think you're making
assumptions about what
other people think
and letting it influence
your decisions.
What is that?
He's having a seizure.
Another one.
Give him another
1.5 of Ativan.
You said the coma
would stop them,
that this would help him.
This is much less traumatic
than if he were awake.
Baby, it's okay.
Stay with us.
We love you.
Now we're just
watching him die.
I'm not doing this again.
Do something more.
Autosomal recessive
thiamine metabolism
dysfunction, syndrome 2.
What? What does
that all mean?
It's what's wrong with Jason,
and it's treatable.
It's a really rare disorder
where Jason can't
transmit thiamine
from his blood to his brain.
Yeah, thiamine
helps the body produce
energy from food.
So we'll hit him
with a heavy dose.
After that, over-the-counter
supplements should resolve
the problem.
Jason's gonna be okay.
Are you sure this time?
Yes.
Absolutely.
So I'm very interested
to get your input
on all this.
I can see you're busy,
so I'll just paraphrase
my email.
Dr. Asher,
you can't just burst
into our meeting.
The Department of Public
Health has a new program
partnering with hospitals
for in-home postpartum
wellness checks
on mom and baby.
We need to join.
Yes, I'm familiar
with it.
However, it requires
too much in terms of cost
and resources.
It's pennies to you.
We can revisit it
once the initiative
proves its worth.
Mr. Dayton,
it has already
proven its worth.
I just did a full hysterectomy
on a 26-year-old.
For nine days,
she was bleeding so badly,
she almost died,
and no one knew
because no one saw her.
If my patient would have
had that program,
a nurse trained
in postpartum care
could have seen that
that bleeding wasn't normal
and gotten her help
before she hemorrhaged.
Instead, she has given up
the chance at more children.
This never had to happen.
So put your money
to good use and sign us up.
Okay.
Get us enrolled.
Would you excuse me, please?
Hey, hold on.
How's Rose?
Should be able
to extubate her soon.
I'll connect with ortho,
schedule her pelvic
fixation for tomorrow.
We'll leave her
wrapped up
in the meantime.
Paola's stable,
and she's really
anxious about her.
She'll be able to visit
with Rose shortly.
Great.
Thank you, doctors.
Yeah.
Hey, Dean, I know you
didn't mean to...
Here we go.
No, listen.
2.0 adds a lot of value
to what we do.
It did in seconds
what usually takes
us half an hour.
Yeah, it's a backseat
driver, man.
It's a tool, just like any
other instrument in the ER.
Except I don't need
a scalpel to tell me
my heart rate is up.
I know it's up, and I make
the adjustment.
2.0 just takes some time
to get used to.
Yeah, maybe that's
the difference between us
all right, 'cause I trust
my hands and my instincts,
and you've abdicated
your judgment to a machine.
Come on, Dean. I mean...
You broke it deliberately,
didn't you?
Hold on. No,
it was an accident.
You're fired, Dr. Archer.
That's not necessary.
I'm not talking to you.
I want you off campus
in 30 minutes.
I'll get my things.
I can come back.
No.
No, no, I was actually...
I was looking for you.
I want to talk to you
about this morning.
I just felt a little...
I don't know.
Felt a little weird
the way we
left it. Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah. I couldn't help
noticing that people were...
I don't know,
looking at us
a little funny.
Yes, I saw it, too.
So I don't know.
I'm just...
I'm sorry if it
made you uncomfortable.
I think you were, too.
Oh, sure.
Absolutely.
Is that's why you told
that man I was a singer?
I think I wanted him
to know how...
How wonderful you are.
So he wouldn't just think
that I was a housekeeper?
What?
No. No.
Are you sure?
Yeah, I think I'm sure.
I mean, I don't know.
Daniel,
I will never be
a true opera singer.
I know my voice,
and I'm happy.
But I am wondering
if that can be
enough for you.
I suddenly hear
my old med school professor
reminding me adherence
to orthodoxy
is the physician's curse.
I wonder if you might train me
on that new EMR program
you were talking about.
No, you're gonna
have to wait.
I wanna modify
the dictation
microphone
so doctors don't have
their noses in iPads
when talking to patients.
Excellent idea.
We need to talk.
Look, I don't have time
to discuss my decision.
You fired
the chief of my ED.
You need to make time.
Your ED?
Personnel decisions
fall under my authority.
Feel free to weigh in
on his replacement.
Dr. Archer is a vital part
of our hospital.
His knowledge,
his experience,
his leadership...
Dr. Archer is a liability.
He destroyed
expensive equipment.
He's antagonistic towards
my staff and a general pain
in my ass.
Now, look, I'm happy
to consult with you
over matters
concerning the operation
of this hospital,
but this decision
is final.
If Dr. Archer goes,
then I go.
Are you serious?
Over Dean Archer?
I am.
He steps out of line again,
it's on you.
Hello.
Brought you
a visitor.
Hey.
How are you feeling?
Like I got hit
by a bus.
Or a souped-up
sports car,
I guess.
Sense of humor's intact.
That's a good sign.
Yeah.
Maybe we should let you
get some rest.
No.
Stay.
Please stay.
I'm sorry.
Come on in.
Hey.
You're working late.
Yeah.
Well...
Look, Ben,
the longer
we don't talk,
it's like the bigger
the divide
between us becomes,
and I can't stand it.
You can't?
Maggie, you lied to me.
I'm sorry.
And I know that I need
to earn back your trust,
but I can't let
this stupid mistake ruin
the best thing that's ever
happened to me.
I'm not gonna give up on us.
Our marriage, our...
Our love
is stronger than this.