"Battle." "Fight."
"Win." "Lose."
These are the words we use
when someone is diagnosed
with an illness or a disease.
♪ No wind, no rain ♪
♪ Or winter's cold ♪
♪ Can stop me, baby ♪
♪ Oh, baby ♪
♪ If you're my goal ♪
♪ Ah, ah, ah, ah ♪
We use militarized language
that implies
it's a fair fight.
- God grant me the serenity
to accept the things
I cannot change,
the courage to change
the things I can,
and the wisdom
to know the difference.
But when it comes
to life and death,
what does winning
really look like?
Is a person a loser for dying
when the outcome isn't really
in their control...
Oh. Damn it.
If any patients
see you like that,
they might go
to another hospital.
Always gets me
in the mood.
Plus, you know, I'm seeing
what daylight feels like
while I still can.
How's Catherine?
She's ready.
- And you?
- Shh, shh, shh, shh.
Ah.
Funny bone.
Not as easy as it looks.
Okay, then.
I have real patients,
so, you know,
good luck with... all this.
I'm messing with you.
You're gonna do great.
You and Amelia.
You're ready.
Charley horse.
There he is.
Thought you might need this.
Oh. No, thanks.
But I'm... I'm good.
I'm running late
for Catherine's scans.
Okay, well, I have cleared
all my surgeries today
and shored up child care,
so I'm here for you,
whatever you need,
- whenever you need it.
- Like I said, I'm good.
Okay, Richard,
it's gonna be a very long day.
Look, Meredith,
I have plenty of doctors
and plenty of friends
looking out for me.
You know who doesn't?
Your father.
Molly had to get back to Bahrain
with her kids.
He's all alone.
And I will make time
to see Thatcher this week,
but today is all
about you and Catherine.
Meredith, Thatcher may not
have a week.
Now, I know it's never been easy
between you two,
but the time to change that
is running out.
Excuse me.
Captioning provided by
ABC Studios and ABC, Inc.
And brought to you by Ford.
Going further, so you can.
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 15  Episode 11
Episode Title: "The Winner Takes it All"
Sync corrections  by  srjanapala
Oh, I'm sorry
I missed your scan.
Oh, please.
I went in. I came out.
Same as the first
million times.
Well, I could have
been there for you.
You had a good excuse.
There's my girl!
Let me get her for you.
Relax.
Do you want to go
to Grandma?
Say, "Hi, Grandma."
"Hi, Grandma."
Hey!
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
Did Koracick re-check
the CT angio?
Yes,
and please stop.
I appreciate both of you
wanting to be a part of this,
but I have
a crackerjack neuro team.
I need you to be my husband
and my son today.
And
we need you to be our patient.
Hmm, Thomas, you're getting
ready to cut open my spine.
I will be
whatever I want.
Oh. Music to my ears.
Now, we will go in
posteriorly
with our stealth system
and our newly pilfered
ORBEYE scope.
Hmm.
The plan is to go in
and remove it en bloc.
And you really think
that posteriorly
is the way to go?
Oh, it is fun to have so many
surgeons in one family.
Remind me, Avery...
When did you become
double board certified in neuro?
That's really how you talk
to your patient's family?
It is, actually.
We need to
go in posteriorly
to avoid the carotid
and the jugular,
and to avoid having to weave
through the brachial plexus.
Look, I know how hard
it is to be on the bench,
but we are the A-Team.
And we don't lose.
Just ask Shepherd's tumor.
Oh, wait, you can't.
Because I removed it.
Flawlessly.
Okay,
any last questions?
Um... it looks like
you've got this.
We do.
Mm-hmm.
I'm good.
But, you know, I-I um...
I think I'd like to
just take a little walk
before we get started.
- I'd be happy to...
- Oh, no, honey.
I want to go alone.
Okay, then,
but no guarantees
I won't watch you
walk away.
You always do.
Hi. I'm...
Meredith?
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
You look...
just like
your picture.
You're the surgeon,
right?
Yeah.
Uh, do you
want to come in?
That's a loaded
question.
I'm not sure
if he's awake.
He sleeps more and more
these days
as you can imagine.
Uh, can I get
you something?
Water? Gin, maybe?
All right.
Thatcher?
You have a visitor.
Meredith!
Hi...
Hi.
He's not on any pain meds.
Clean and sober.
His wishes.
So, just the oxygen,
if he needs it.
But you know
how that works.
I do.
Well,
I'll leave you to it.
My cellphone number
is on the fridge.
If you need anything,
give me a call.
I probably
can't stay very long.
I just...
There's so much to say,
I-I...
I don't know what to say.
I didn't come here
to say anything
or to hear you
say anything to me, so...
we can just sit,
if that's okay.
Okay.
Mom.
I was looking for you.
You know I give Amelia
and Koracick a hard time,
but... they're the best.
I was thinking about
my first surgery.
The very first time
I held a scalpel in my hand.
It was a simple lipoma,
but I was terrified.
Hmm.
I expected to feel
so powerful, invincible.
But the second
that scrub nurse
put that 10 blade
in my hand,
I went ice cold.
Okay, so then
what did you do?
Diana Ross.
"Ain't No Mountain High Enough."
The first time
I heard that song,
it just filled me with joy
and such calm...
so I just sang it
over and over and over
in my head, in that O.R.,
until that same sense of calm
and joy washed over me.
And it's been
my secret weapon
for everything
that's ever scared me...
My first surgery.
Labor with you,
it was on an endless loop.
Every PET scan,
every MRI.
I remember you singing that song
in the kitchen
when I was doing
my homework.
You told me it was old people music.
You wanted Michael Jackson.
I love me some Michael.
Ooh.
I had to pry that
red leather jacket off of you
to get you to go to bed
at night.
Ah, that's true.
Oh.
I guess I used to do
the same thing.
My first surgery,
I sang a song in my head.
- I mean, it calmed me, you know?
- I know.
I watched you.
My first...
How did you watch?
Child, please.
I am Catherine Fox.
Do you think
there's a world
where I wouldn't
sneak into the gallery
of my baby's
first surgery?
Oh, you were a sight
to see...
Mm.
I bet Harriet does
the same thing someday.
Well, I'll be sneaking up
into the gallery with you, then.
Deal.
That's a deal.
Now, can we please get you
to your room?
Not yet.
- Mom...
- I left the foundation in your name,
just in case
anything happens to me.
Cecilia runs
the day-to-day operations,
Charlie keeps
the books humming,
but they'll need a leader,
a North Star.
And in the event that I'm left
totally paralyzed...
Mom, even if
you can't operate,
you're still gonna run
the foundation, okay?
You'll teach.
You're Catherine Fox.
What are you gonna do?
You're gonna be all up in my
business and everybody else's.
We both know you're gonna
find a way to do that.
Keep this.
Turn the page.
I've already...
You planned
your own party?
Mom.
If I get out of this alive,
the fun we're gonna have...
And don't you even think about
scrimping on those egg rolls.
You know
they're my favorite.
You really
planned everything.
I always do.
All right, then.
Shall we?
Victoria Falls, Zimbabwe.
Phillip put these everywhere
for me.
He said it's supposed to
be soothing.
Truth be told,
it just makes me
miss it more.
A few years back,
a student told me about
a semester he took abroad
building schools.
Lexie was gone,
and I thought I could either
drown my grief
in a bottle of Scotch
or do something.
So I did something.
In Zimbabwe.
The sunsets, Meredith...
and the quiet.
The people that I met,
they have this passion
for... life, loving,
learning...
And then you got sick.
I thought
I'd just come home,
do whatever treatment
I needed to do,
and then go back, but...
It was good. Coming home.
It gave me a chance to...
It was the right thing to do.
You went and got
a whole new life.
I did.
I'm glad for you.
I'm glad you saw sunsets
and built schools
for people who needed them
and you stayed sober.
You went and got
a whole new life.
Halfway across the world
this time.
But you didn't
give a damn
about the people
you left behind.
Say it again.
We make an incision posteriorly
from C3 to T4,
and then use
the stealth probe
to mark the coordinates
of the tumor.
And then do
partial laminectomies
to access the tumor
and remove it en bloc.
Perfect. Brilliant.
We are incredible.
Someone should really do
a study on us.
Okay, say it.
What? Wh...
Oh. No.
Ha ha! I'm good.
Good, good, good, good.
Big Gun.
Ready to Big Gun the crap
out of this tumor.
Damn it.
- Even my arrogance is off.
- Right?
Right.
W-What if we try, uh,
your thing?
You know, the... the word-vomit
and the feelings?
That seems to work.
For you.
Okay.
You... you first.
This is the largest tumor
I've ever seen
on the biggest legend
I've ever known,
and if I screw this up,
I'm gonna have to live out
the rest of my
ill-fated surgical career
fixing idiot teenagers
who get hurt cow-tipping
in Lawrence, Kansas,
'cause I can't look
Richard in the eye
knowing I gorked
his legend wife.
That is specific.
Well...
I'm saying,
how do you get hurt cow-tipping?
It's a thing.
Just... You. Go.
Uh, Catherine Fox is an icon,
and a magician,
and a giant among men...
And not just
for the reasons you think.
She's saved more penises
in her O.R.
than any surgeon
on the planet.
And all I keep imagining
are the dozens of men
with zero-functioning penises,
doomed to live out
their sexless lives
if I botch this surgery.
That's what
you're worried about?
Men and their junk?
That,
and if I lose her...
I've lost enough.
So let's keep her alive.
Let's keep her alive.
I told them I didn't need
a personal escort
to my own surgery.
Well,
that's just making sure
you don't make a break
for it.
Thomas,
make sure that I wake up
with good motor
and nerve function.
And don't forget
to get clean margins.
I wouldn't dream of it.
And would
you tell my husband
he does not have to sit up
in that gallery all day?
"For better, for worse"
does not include
seeing your wife's insides.
You know,
you wouldn't be you
if you weren't
bossing us all around
up until
the last second.
You nervous?
Were you?
A little bit.
But I turned out just fine.
That's because
I was perfect,
which I'm willing
to be again.
Well, you better be.
Oh, Richard,
I always liked you.
No, you didn't.
And I'm fine
as long as she's fine.
Okay, okay, can I have a minute
with my husband, please?
I will see you...
when I wake up.
Jackson?
Where's Jackson?
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
One for the road?
Oh, ha ha!
My baby!
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ If you need me ♪
♪ Call me ♪
♪ No matter where you are ♪
♪ No matter how far ♪
♪ No wind ♪
♪ No rain ♪
♪ Can stop me, babe ♪
♪ If you're my goal ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Ain't no mountain high enough ♪
♪ Oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ Ain't no valley low enough ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh-ooh ♪
♪ Ain't no river wide
enough ♪ ♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ To keep me from you ♪
♪ Ain't no mountain
high enough ♪
♪ Nothing can keep me,
keep me from you ♪
♪ Ain't no mountain high enough
to keep me from you ♪
♪ You've been running
all over town ♪
Just like that,
we are ready to navigate.
Don't you want to
confirm the accuracy first?
Oh, what would I do
without someone hee
to remind me
of the obvious?
I'm just saying,
maybe a little less music,
a little more
concentration.
♪ All you want to do
is ride around, Sally ♪
♪ Ride, Sally, ride ♪
Whoo!
This is going to be
a long day.
And you are gonna love
every minute of it.
We're gonna get don
in there.
Get down and dirt.
Here we go.
♪ All you want to do
is ride around, Sally ♪
♪ Ride, Sally, ride ♪
♪ All you want to do
is ride around, Sally ♪
Mind if I join you?
♪ Ride, Sally, ride ♪
I'd like that.
♪ One of these early mornings ♪
♪ I'm gonna be wiping
those weeping eyes ♪
How's the resection
going?
So far so good.
Come on.
Let it loose. Let it out.
Are you sure you don't want
to be in the waiting room?
I can watch, and I can report
back to you guys.
No, I'm fine right where I am.
I-I'm good.
♪ I bought you
a brand-new mustang ♪
Do it with me.
Come on, now.
You're mad.
I'm not mad.
Meredith...
Fine. I'm mad.
Because I moved away.
Because you ran away.
Because you have never fought
for anyone or anything
that you cared for
in your life.
You just disappear.
When I gave you
a piece of my liver,
you said we would try,
right?
You said we could
get to know each other.
You didn't try.
You didn't fight.
And when Lexie died...
I know. I know.
No, you don't know,
because you weren't here.
I lost my sister.
I lost my husband.
And you were
nowhere to be found.
That's not...
Meredith, I was there
after Derek died.
No, why would you say
something like that?
Because it's the truth,
Meredith.
Richard told me Derek died.
I bought a ticket.
I flew all day,
all night.
I got to the funeral just...
Just in time.
I stood a few rows back.
Next to some of your doctor
friends from the hospital.
I would remember
if you were at his funeral.
I was there, Meredith.
But you were barely there.
You were a ghost.
You looked like me
when I lost Susan and Lexie.
Are you saying
you came to the funeral
and didn't speak to me?
I felt like it would...
Would have been for me,
- not...
- not... not...
For...
for you.
Let's get you
to the bed.
I came home, Meredith.
For you.
♪ And you're standing
here beside me ♪
This microscope
is a game changer.
I know. I feel like I could
just walk into the screen
and surf
on the spinal cor.
♪ Never for money,
always for love ♪
♪ Cover up
and say goodnight ♪
♪ Say goodnight ♪
All right...
it looks like we are clear
to remove the tumor en bloc.
Except... hang on.
I can't get it free.
Okay, then.
Time to suck and pluc.
- I'm sorry, what?
- The tumor's like a grape.
You suck out the inside,
then you pluck out the skin.
Suck and pluck.
- Could you call it something else?
- Like what?
Literally anything else.
I hate this dude.
- Jackson, sit.
- No, I hate him. For real.
I want to jump through this glass
and just, like, choke him out.
He is bopping.
He's bopping
over my mom's spine.
I mean, who does that?
Maybe you should take a walk.
I'm gonna
take a walk now.
Richard, this can't be good
for you either.
The first year or so
Catherine and I were together,
we figured out how to make
the long distance work
because we'd promise
to show up
whenever we needed,
however we needed.
It's what you do
for the people you love.
She may fuss,
but I don't need to ask her
where she wants me to be.
I'm already here.
♪ Make it up as we go along ♪
Are you okay if I...
It's fine. Go.
♪ Head in the sky ♪
♪ It's okay,
I know nothing's wrong ♪
♪ Nothing's wrong, oh ♪
♪ I got plenty of time ♪
You gonna lecture me, too,
on how I shouldn't be here?
You shouldn't be.
♪ Oh, you got light
in your eyes ♪
But that's not my call.
It's not decompressing. What do
you mean it's not decompressing?
It's too dense,
like it's made of...
I don't know what...
Cartilage,
small chips
of hard calcifications.
Damn it.
I can't get it either.
Kill the music.
We need to go in
from the front.
Her spine is open.
It's all exposed.
If we move her,
we risk losing function
in her forearm and hand.
It's the only way.
Okay, well, let me ask you
one question first...
Are you insane?
We close up the incision.
We flip her onto her side.
I go in from the front.
We meet in the middle to
decompress and unearth this thing.
So the answer is yes,
you are insane.
We'll get a few more peope
in here, we can flip her.
And keep her still
and not sever her spine?
Not to mention having
to break scrub,
- re-drape, rescrub...
- Cow-tipping in Kansas!
Dozens of sexless men!
If it were you again
on the table,
what would you want?
For the record,
I do not like you.
Shut down the gallery.
There you are.
Mom's always been
larger than life, you know?
Laughs harder,
yells louder than anyone.
She's the life
of the party.
Even if it's
my birthday party
and she's taking over
the dance floor.
Sounds amazing.
I was 16. It was mortifying.
She'd always do that.
She always
inserted herself
in every single aspect
of my life, you know,
whether I wanted her to
or not...
Hell, whether I even knew
about it or not.
And, um...
Now I can't, uh...
I can't imagine what a room
would even feel like
without her in it
taking up all that space.
It was different...
losing Samuel.
That was more like...
Like my world collapsing
around me, you know?
And this, I just...
I feel like...
a scared little kid.
Like nothing is safe.
Like the world's
upside down
and nothing makes any sense
anymore.
Yeah.
- I don't like it.
- I know.
- I know. I know.
♪ Hold on ♪
♪ Hold on to yourself ♪
♪ For this is gonna
hurt like hell ♪
Okay.
Let's rock and roll.
On my count,
one, two, three.
Good, good, good.
Easy.
♪ So now you're sleeping
peaceful ♪
♪ I lie awake and pray ♪
♪ That you'll be strong
tomorrow ♪
Let's secure her hips.
♪ And will see another day ♪
♪ And we will praise it ♪
She's good.
♪ And love the light
that brings a smile ♪
- Okay, they did it. She's okay.
- ♪ Across your face ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, hold on ♪
♪ Oh, God ♪
♪ If you're out there,
won't you hear me? ♪
♪ I know that we have never
talked before ♪
♪ I know that we have never ♪
You ready, Bokie?
♪ Talked before ♪
- ♪ Oh, God ♪
- Okay. Deep breath, everybody.
- ♪ The one I love ♪
- Scalpel.
♪ Is leaving ♪
♪ Don't you take her
when she comes to your door ♪
♪ ..door ♪
Dr. Koracick?
Tom.
I think
I'm gonna have trouble
getting around
the C7 facet
while keeping the tumor
retracted from this angle.
Maybe you could give it
a try?
♪ And love the light
that brings a smile ♪
Please,
I could do that in my sleep.
- ♪ Across your face ♪
- Show off.
♪ Hold on ♪
♪ Hold on to yourself ♪
♪ For this is gonna
hurt like hell ♪
- Scalpel.
♪ Hell ♪
Is that when you and Richard
started talking?
After the funeral?
I tried calling you.
You never called back.
And I worried.
At first,
I was just checking in on you.
Mm, Richard and I started...
Talking about
a lot of things.
We both
had amends to make.
There are so many things
I could say I'm sorry for,
Meredith.
But all I really want to say
is thank you.
Thank you for what?
For so long,
I measured my life
in the things done to me,
taken from me.
Now I can see my life
for exactly what it is.
Some people have
more pain than others.
But no one, nothing,
was conspiring against me.
When you gave me
a piece of your liver,
you gave me time,
precious time.
Time to get your head
out of your own ass?
Y... Y...
You could say that.
I had a life, Meredith,
'cause of you.
My own real, honest,
painful, incredible life.
I just wish you
and I could have shared it.
Well, I guess you did
try this time.
I just didn't know.
I miss Lexie.
I miss her so much.
Me too.
I'm sorry you lost her.
I know how much it... it meant
to you, having a sister.
I have another sister.
But you and Molly,
you were never close.
Her name is Maggie.
Oh...
She's brilliant.
And kind.
She's the best of Ellis
and Richard.
Your... Your mother
and Richard had a baby.
At least something good
came from all that.
I'm gonna get
a humpback operating with you.
I'm already standing
on a step stool.
What more do you want
from me?
Heels?
Okay,
it looks like the tumor
is free of
the brachial plexus.
Should we try
to pull it out?
Let's do it.
We've lost
all the signal from one arm.
The tumor
is moving pretty easily.
Check your machine.
Could be artifact.
No, there's still a little
tension from my side.
I... I think it's coming
from the root.
Which means there's no way
to remove this without...
Risking paralysis.
If they can't remove
the whole tumor,
they're gonna have to do it
piecemeal.
But then they risk
leaving some of the tumor
behind.
What?
My path pen.
Remove the tumor piecemeal,
and then use the pen
to see if you got it all.
Okay, it hasn't cleared
FDA process yet,
and it isn't on the market,
but I'm telling you, it works.
I really have
always liked you, Richard.
No, you haven't.
Yes. Get it.
And that twitch
over her right eye
when you switched
the ice maker
from cubed to crushed.
"What kind of a monster
crushes ice?
It's uncivilized."
Crushed ice
was uncivilized.
Taking my last cup
of coffee...
- uncivilized.
- Uncivilized.
Getting an A-
in Chem Lab.
- Uncivilized.
She was...
Kind of a tyrant.
But brilliant.
Oh, I can't argue
with that.
Terrible driver.
Can't argue with that.
But she was
extraordinary.
Yeah.
Oh.
Do you regret
marrying her?
The entire time
she was pregnant with you,
she pretended
she wasn't.
I don't know if it was
stubbornness or denial.
Maybe both.
Nine months, she had to do
everything herself.
And I had to let her.
The night she went into labor,
she came home after surgery,
and she just stood
in the doorway, wide-eyed.
"We're having a baby,
Thatch.
We're having a baby."
As if the idea just hit her,
right there.
She... She started to laugh.
She couldn't stop laughing.
Laughed all the way
to the hospital.
I never heard her laugh
like that,
so big, so free.
And I just thought,
"Wow.
What a way for you
to come into the world."
We weren't perfect.
We weren't even happy
a lot of the time.
But I'd marry her
all over again
for that night,
that laugh.
And you.
And this.
I'd do it all again
for this.
How can there
still be cancer there?
We've been at this
for hours.
It's still lighting up
like Christmas.
Let's just keep going.
We'll hit clear tissue
eventually.
Signal's fading again.
She's losing function
in her arms.
- We've barely touched anything.
- Breathe.
We are going
in the right direction.
Losing the signal
in her other arm...
Okay, stop it! We know!
If we keep going,
we cost Catherine
her motor function,
her career, her life
as she knows it... we know!
Meredith...
Okay,
don't try to speak.
But... the closet.
I left something...
I don't need anything.
For your kids.
I wish...
I wish I knew them.
I thought of...
I thought of them.
Ahh.
Your hands are so cold.
Sorry, I can...
No, no, no.
Oh, it feels good.
Zola is so smart
and so strong.
Yeah?
And she keeps me on my toes
every minute
of every day.
And Bailey says "funny"
before every sentence.
"Funny,
I'd like an apple.
Funny, I need pajamas."
It's so cute.
And Ellis...
she is brave.
And she's obsessed
with hip-hop.
They are exhausting...
and amazing.
I wish you knew them,
too.
Because they are so,
so beautiful.
How...
Easy. Easy, Mom.
How... How...
Easy, easy, easy, easy.
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh, shh,
shh, shh, shh.
Hey.
- Mm-hmm.
- Uh-huh. -I feel that.
Okay.
Hold on, hold on.
All right. Well,
your reflexes are normal.
My hands and feet move.
Whoo.
I'm not dead?
With that tumor?
No, you're most definitely
not dead.
Oh, I thought for sure
they were gonna kill me.
What?
Tell me.
Catherine, when we went in
to get the tumor,
it was adherent
to your brachial plexus.
We were able
to remove about 95% of it,
but we had to leave
one nodule behind.
So... radiation? Chemo?
They've had some success
with proton beam therapy.
Some?
It's likely,
even with treatment...
I'll have to live
with this cancer
the rest of my life.
I was sure you'd get it all
or kill me trying.
So did we.
Catherine,
I'm so sorry.
Sorry? I'm alive.
I can live with this
for many years.
People live with cancer.
We've all seen it happen.
You're gonna have to get, uh,
scans every three months
to make sure the tumor
doesn't, uh, grow.
And in between,
I'll operate.
- Mm.
- And I'll hug my son.
Mm.
Make love to my husband.
Okay...
Chase my Harriet,
make mistakes,
and fight about who gets
to pick the movie on date night.
You two have given me
my life back.
Now what?
'Cause we didn't
plan on this.
These two pulled off
a miracle.
Miracles aren't always
punctuation marks.
But they are worth celebrating.
So we are gonna have
that party.
We just might have to wait
a couple of months
so I can get
on the dance floor.
I love you.
Hey.
I heard about the surgery.
Congratulations.
Oh. I know, I know.
You knew I had it in me
all along.
Honestly?
I was on the fence.
You should be
really proud.
There are not a lot of surgeons
who could do that.
Which part?
Where I flipped my friend
like a pancake
or failed to leave her
cancer free?
The part where
you saved her life
and her surgical career.
Yeah, that part
wasn't half bad.
You should celebrate.
Why don't you get
cleaned up?
I'll meet you at Joe's,
and I'll buy you a drink.
Uh... w...
Can we take a rain check?
I... I'm wiped.
And I-I smell bad.
And when you spend money on me,
I want to smell good.
Yeah. Okay.
Night.
Goodnight.
♪ Red lights are flashing
on the highway ♪
When it comes to medicine,
who's to say
what is winning or losing?
♪ I wonder if we're gonna ever
get home tonight ♪
There's just as much value
in trying again
as there is in letting go...
- I saved my friend today, David.
- ♪ But if you break down ♪
♪ I'll drive out and find you ♪
I didn't think I-I could,
and it wasn't perfect.
♪ If you forget my love ♪
Your dad was kind of a badass.
♪ I'll try to remind you ♪
Letting go of suffering, regret,
- pain, fear.
- ♪ And stay by you ♪
♪ When it don't come easy ♪
♪ I don't know nothing
except change will come ♪
I operated on a freaking
legend's spine today.
And it was terrifying.
And exhilarating.
And imperfect.
♪ I wonder if we're gonna
ever get home ♪
Mostly terrifying.
Because she's not
just a legend.
She matters so much
to so many people that I love...
♪ And all of the signs
got blown away ♪
♪ Sometimes you wonder if you're
walking in the wrong direction ♪
Most of my life,
I have been chasing
the kind of high
that I feel right now.
♪ But if you break down ♪
I gave a surgeon back
her hands today.
I gave a husband his wife,
a son his mother.
And I am so incredibly grateful
to be sober...
To be present enough
to have felt
every terrifying,
exhilarating,
imperfect moment.
♪ When it don't come easy ♪
Instead of saying
someone we love
is battling, beating, fightin,
winning, or losing,
why don't we just
tell the truth.
♪ So many things
that I had before ♪
There you go, sweethearts.
- ♪ That don't matter to me now ♪
- We get sick.
We take our medicine...
Wow. So cool.
Where did you get it,
Mommy?
Uh, your grandfather,
Thatcher.
He wanted you to have it,
and he wanted you to know
that he cared about you
very much...
Funny, I love it.
Some of us live, some die.
Mommy, are you okay?
- ♪ When it don't come easy ♪
- Yes, Zo-Zo. I will be fine.
♪ When it don't come easy ♪
Sync corrections  by  srjanapala