Previously on ER.
I think these results
don't have anything
to do with the accident.
All this time,
I'm worrying about HIV
and I get Hepatitis‐C?
Why don't you
do what I did?
Apply to
a locum tenens program
filling in for vacationing
surgeons in rural hospitals.
They pay you a bundle
to step in.
Oh, yeah? What's a bundle?
Eight, ten grand
for a couple weeks.
'Can you say "father?"'
Can you say "daddy?"
'Yeah.'
'Hey, Peter.'
‐ Morning.
‐ Hey. Morning.
Wow, all this
for just two weeks?
Well, it's been 30 below
in North Minnesota.
Ah‐huh. So, will you be the only
surgeon in this hospital?
No. One of three.
So, you're all set?
Yeah. I mean, it's tough
getting Reese squared away.
Carla can't pick him up
from daycare on Thursday
and that's
Jackie's rough day
but, you know,
other than that..
Well, I can cover.
No, no, no.
I couldn't ask you.
You didn't.
I just offered.
What are friends for?
Okay. Yeah.
Have Dr. Edson follow up
on these before discharge.
The weather channel said
a front's moving
across the Rockies.
Hope you packed
your long Johns.
I'm wearing
my long Johns.
Peter.
Good thing I caught you.
The locum tenens folks
just called.
Change of plans. You
are needed at another location.
You better hustle. Your flight
for Atlanta leaves in an hour.
I'm going to Atlanta?
You're connecting
from there to Biloxi.
I didn't sign
up for Biloxi.
Biloxi's where you're
picking up a rental car.
Then you still have a few
hours' drive to Laverne.
Laverne?
Whoa, wait a minute.
I signed a contract.
These people can't just
switch this at the last minute.
Well, that's what the fine print
is all about, but I'm sure
it's a medical necessity
and you can't back out now
or else we'll both look
very unhippocratic.
Besides, you're going
to need the dough
if you accept the cardiothoracic
fellowship next year.
You're offering me
a cardiothoracic spot?
Well, not officially until May,
but between you and me..
'Isn't it a pain that the most
prestigious fellowships'
'always pay the least?'
It's like you're
supposed to be honored
to let them put you
deeper in debt.
Have a good trip.
‐ 'I'm sorry. It's the rules.'
‐ Let me up. I work here.
Please, ma'am, I
could lose my job.
I feel like an idiot
in this thing.
Hey, Jeanie, you being
discharged today?
Yep. One final indignity.
Excuse me, miss, miss,
you know what, I'm running out.
I'll take over
from here, okay?
Be my guest.
Go, go, go, go.
So, you're lucky you didn't,
uh, break any bones.
Yeah. Apparently, the windshield
looks a lot worse than I do.
Yeah. Hey, listen,
I'm sorry about the hep‐C.
Hepatitis doesn't scare me.
Dr. Makadon thinks
I'll respond well to the meds.
Where you off to?
Oh, I'm doing a stint
at a rural hospital.
At the last minute, they stuck
me in the middle of nowhere.
In Mississippi,
a place called Laverne.
‐ You're kidding? Laverne?
‐ Yeah, you know it?
I have aunts and uncles all over
that part of Mississippi.
On my father's side,
the Murdocks.
I can give you
some phone numbers.
I don't know how much free time
I'm going to have.
Mmm. I haven't been there
since I was a kid.
‐ I used to love that place.
‐ Oh, yeah?
I used to climb trees
and get dirty
and they're all
great cooks.
Well, uh,
I'll keep an eye out.
Listen, if you run into
any of my relatives
just don't mention
my HIV status.
Of course not.
I haven't told anyone
in my family.
Just give them my love.
Yeah, yeah, sure.
♪ Mm‐hmm‐mmm ♪
Hey, how you doing?
Can't complain.
Is there a phone inside?
Sorry.
My car broke down. I need to
call the hospital in Laverne.
Son...you in Laverne.
Is there a hospital here?
Who you looking for?
Okay, Tavius, this looks
real good, but I want you..
'Maureen?'
...to keep the patch on
it for a couple of days.
Excuse me a minute.
This gentleman
looking for you.
Miss Chapman,
I'm Dr. Benton.
Oh, I'd given up.
They said you'd
be here yesterday.
I didn't know I was
coming here till this morning.
You're here for a month?
No, no, no. Two weeks.
Hear that, leg?
You've got two weeks.
I'm a nurse
practitioner.
I'm supposed to
stay off my feet
but all these patients
keep getting sick.
So, there's no hospital here?
I mean, just a clinic?
Our nearest hospital is
80 miles, in Green Cove.
What, you walk here?
His car broke down
on Barney Jones Road.
Oh, well,
my boy is good with engines.
Sonny?
He'll take care of you.
Is the head doctor
on duty now?
Dr. Benton,
you are the doctor
and please don't tell me
that you're a dentist.
Okay, sweetie, I want
you to keep that..
I'm a fifth‐year
surgical resident.
Oh, Lord.
Sonny..
'Dr. Benton's
car broke down.'
Yeah, I seen it.
'You think you
can fix it up?'
You're hurting. Get to bed.
'Well, I need to help
Dr. Benton get settled.'
'No, no, no, no.
You know what?'
'There are only
a few patients here so, um..'
What time do you close?
When the last
patient's gone.
Have you ever
practiced medicine?
I can handle it.
'Let's go.'
'Alright, suit yourself.'
Um, weather like this,
folks sit out here
and you see them
inside, and, um..
I expect you'll find everything
where it should be, and..
'Oh, everybody,
this is Dr. Benton..'
'...from Chicago. He's gonna
take care of y'all.'
Alright.
Who's next?
Bentons.
I don't recollect any Bentons.
My family's
not from around here.
So...what can I do
for you today?
Might've been some Bentons
over near Hattiesburg.
I believe it's so.
'Course, there was
this schoolteacher Benton'
over to Winona.
She was a white lady.
Died of consumption.
Coughed herself to the grave.
Ms. Johnson,
uh, what is your complaint?
Oh, I ain't got no complaint.
No need to complain,
and complaining make it worse
what they say.
Do you have a medical problem?
No. J‐Just the burn.
Okay, so, where's the burn?
I believe there's some Bentons
up off the riverfront.
Or maybe Benders.
Maybe they was Benders.
'Mmm. Benders.'
Mr. McCoy?
Ruth Blalock?
‐ They left?
‐ Appears so.
Jesse Morgan.
That's me.
I figured I‐I'd let you
take a look at my leg.
That's okay, Mr. Morgan,
you can stay seated.
Sorry it took so long.
That's a pretty
nasty‐looking ulcer.
Yes, sir.
I tried mustard seed on it.
That usually stops my leg
from aching.
No, no, no, no. You're going
to need some antibiotics
and you need
to stay off this foot
and you need to soak it
three times a day
in warm water, okay?
Stay off it?
‐ And soak it?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
'Where do I put this, doctor?'
Excuse me?
Oh, I'm sorry.
Uh, you can put it
on the counter inside.
We'll send it out to the lab
or however they handle it.
Does Miss Chapman have a number
where we can reach you?
Oh, Maureen
tells me on the spot.
You take this in the back room,
and you do your test.
Mr. Morgan.
Miss Pearl.
'Well, how about the Greens?'
'You can pick out
the ham hocks.'
'No, thank you.'
I'll just have another biscuit.
After Dr. Rajiv..
He lasted about a month.
We sort of gave up.
It's hard to keep
a doctor here.
Well, I can see why.
‐ No offense.
‐ Oh, none taken.
We was doing fine
until you thought
you was more stubborn
than that mare.
Fractured your leg, huh?
Ligaments in my knee
and a herniated cervical disc.
I guess it's lucky
that you don't mind lard.
I'm sorry
you missed your son.
What, had he
gone to bed?
I heard you send your love.
No.
My son is deaf,
so the phone is of no use to us.
I'd arranged
for a videophone hookup
at the hospital in Minnesota..
But I guess
you don't have one here, huh?
Maybe in Green Cove.
Now, did you..
Sonny get you settled
in the trailer?
I don't work for him.
Maybe you saw the motor home
behind the clinic.
I'm afraid it's a little cozy
for a man your size.
It'll be fine.
'A‐And take care when
you open the door.'
Or did you get
it grounded, Sonny?
Damn!
'Take the baby's temperature
every four hours'
'and call me if..'
'Or see Dr. Benton
at the clinic'
if it doesn't drop
below 100 by tomorrow.
‐ Thank you.
‐ Mm‐hmm.
Busy day?
No, not at all
since half my patients
are coming here.
Well, it'll take time for...
some of them to accept you.
No, it won't.
I'm not staying.
'You don't need
a surgeon'
and if you're going
to get any rest
you need a doctor
that everyone can... accept.
This isn't just about race.
I don't care
what it's about.
Well, so you only
came for the money?
You can get by with a nurse.
Sonny hasn't even got
your car running yet.
That's okay.
I'll find a ride.
So...thanks for the ride.
Oh, best reason we've had
to go to work all year.
Ooh, ooh, ooh,
when we get to the dock
you make sure every woman
coming on the shift
sees you
getting out our truck.
Ain't that right, Annie?
Your Jake hears about this,
he won't be going out
on no boat no time soon.
Ooh, Amen to that.
Now, tell me something.
Now, is you really a doctor?
Yeah.
Well, take a look
at Annie hand there.
Becca, I'm driving.
Go on, girl,
show the man your hand.
Mmm. Now, has you ever seen
anything the likes of that?
Looks like
a pretty bad infection.
Ah, it's from the shrimps.
They got poisons in their head.
If I were you,
I'd take some antibiotics.
Give it a rest.
Give it time to heal.
Stop working?
Not unless you gonna
stow me back up to Chicago.
I don't know if I could afford
to keep a woman like you.
Ooh!
Hold up, what's that?
What the hell?
'Help!'
Help me!
'Help me!'
Russell! Help him!
Sir, sir, sir,
lie down, lie down.
‐ I'm a doctor.
‐ Branch caught in the throttle.
‐ I couldn't get it out of gear.
‐ Don't move.
‐ Oh, my God!
Russell. My boy.
Find my son.
Your son was
on the tractor with you?
‐ In my lap.
‐ Okay. Okay, don't worry.
‐ I'll find him.
‐ He's only four.
He couldn't
have gone far.
Ladies! Over here!
Wha..
Oh, my God!
'I need you to
drive to a phone!'
‐ Was he run over?
‐ Nearest town's five miles.
Sir, do you have a phone?
Yes. Next driveway.
My wife's home.
Go! Go! Call an ambulance!
Tell them it's a matter
of life or death!
Come on. Come on.
Morning, doctor.
Hey.
You staying off that foot?
Soaking it three times a day.
What?
Anybody ever tell you
that smoking will kill you?
Nah. You the first.
Hey, Adelina, you
been shopping?
What it look like?
You got something for me?
You know she do, Hubert.
Yeah? A smack
upside your head.
Wait, where you goin'?. You
never showed us what you got.
And I ain't going to.
'That girl crazy.'
'You know, I think it's looking
a lot better, Tavius'
'and, uh, if you come back
in a couple of days'
I believe we'll be able
to take it off then. Alright?
Did you decide
not to go?
You can go
and get some rest.
I'll, uh..
I'll take over.
Somebody's waiting
for you. Sally?
I'm Sally Mannon.
We didn't really get a chance
to meet last night.
Oh. I saw you.
She told me about
the tractor accident.
So, how's your husband
and son?
Fine, thanks to you.
I brought you a pie.
Sweet tater.
I hope you like that.
Sweet potato pie?
Mrs. Mannon, are you kidding?
This is my favorite.
I'm going to dig in right now.
'Dr. Benton gave my boy oxygen
all the way to Green Cove.'
‐ You bagged him for 80 miles?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
'In the back of a pickup.'
Mmm!
This is delicious.
I'm sorry. Whoo!
This is the best thing I've had
since I've been here.
I got to go.
God bless you.
Mm‐hmm.
Oh...thank you.
You going to
stay, then?
It's not that busy.
Well, that's 'cause I make
rounds on Tuesdays.
‐ Rounds?
‐ House calls.
I heard one
of the Ebee girls is pregnant
'and the Ebees live far out.'
I'm sure she hasn't had
any prenatal care.
I haven't done OB since...
med school.
Well, never mind. I'll go.
No, no, no. Look,
I'm not saying I won't go.
I'll go
if I can borrow your truck.
Sonny hasn't fixed my car yet.
You can't get there by car.
What y'all want?
I'm Dr. Benton.
Miss Chapman sent me to check
on your daughter.
She don't need checking.
That it?
Alright. Hurry up
before your pa gets back.
You know how he is.
‐ Alright.
‐ Sir?
Doctor, sir, if you don't mind?
I was feeling faint yesterday.
You want me to examine you?
Ma says you can check me
out here.
Believe me..
...you don't want to go in.
'Well...I'm concerned
about your blood pressure.'
'It's a little high.'
Have you had any other
problems besides dizziness?
Um... a little bit
of blood came out last week.
Well, I'm no
specialist, but, uh..
'I think you should get
an ultrasound and blood tests'
'in Green Cove.'
What's going on?
Uh, papa
'Dr. Benton
is looking after me.'
Well, this would be the doctor
for you, wouldn't it?
Sir, your daughter
needs some tests.
She don't need nothing from you.
Her blood pressure is elevated.
Melanie Irene, get on inside.
Get this man
off my property.
'Melly's had enough help
from his kind already.'
We'll see what the authorities
have to say.
Well, you can call the president
as far as I'm concerned.
Ain't nobody gonna tell me
how to do for my kid.
R‐e‐e‐s‐e.
Reese..
The knuckles of the "A" hand
rub against one another
in circles.
Wash...
'The prone right hand
is drawn...'
'Wash your hands, Reese.'
'Reese, wash your hands.'
Mr. Morgan?
Oh, morning, doctor.
I thought I told you
to stay off that foot.
You also told me
to wash it three times a day.
Right. So what are you doing
walking on it?
Now, I can't wash my foot
without water, now can I?
Have a good day, doctor.
Your glucose level
is too high.
Now what do you
want it to be?
Adelina, answer the doctor.
Between 70 and 120, sir.
Mm‐hmm. Now, nurse Maureen
diagnosed you a month ago.
You should have better control
over your diabetes by now.
Have you been checking
your glucose level
three times a day?
Did you check it
the other day
after you drank
that bottle of soda?
Adelina!
I only took a sip.
That's one sip
too many, okay?
If she doesn't keep
her glucose level
under control, she could damage
her kidneys and her heart
'not to mention
going blind.'
She could have another seizure
like she had last month.
Well, it was my fault
for not bringing her in.
I don't think
too highly of doctors
since we lost Adelina's mama.
Alright.
Alright. So, you going to show
me how to inject this?
No, sir.
Alright. Well, I'll show you.
Been shopping?
Yeah. Thought I'd cook
some vegetables tonight,
if you don't mind.
Be fine.
How'd the clinic go?
Adelina Young came in
with a glucose level of 280.
Her grandmother claims
they haven't gotten
a supply of insulin
or glucose strips.
Oh, Lord.
The grandmother doesn't
understand the routine.
Adelina should've been
admitted to a hospital
for diabetic teaching.
Well, that's not gonna happen.
Or try a Subq insulin pump.
Have you heard of those?
Something newer than leeches?
Look..
...I'm just trying to raise
the standard of care here.
We should expect a 100%.
I do, but I've learned
to settle for 60%.
60% is failure.
‐ It takes time for people‐‐
‐ They've had a month.
Adelina is an athlete
and she's probably
scared to death that this is
gonna end all that.
Well, she could go
into a diabetic coma.
Don't you think I know that?
I‐I don't know
what you know.
'Maureen.'
Maureen, you gotta come.
Something's wrong
with Melanie.
She's been
a laborin' and..
Well, the baby
won't come.
Um, Dr. Benton.
N‐No, I want you, Maureen.
'Well, you're a damn
fool, Eli.'
'I can't
move that fast.'
'Just think
of Melanie.'
Well, come on.
Oh, sweet Jesus!
‐ I need more light!
‐ The generator's busted.
You get on outside.
Come on!
Oh, mama, help me!
Okay, okay. Melanie, Melanie,
I need you to relax, okay?
I know, I know.
Come on.
I don't think the head
is engaged.
Ah, damn it. I feel the foot.
What does that mean?
The baby's upside down.
Well, what the hell
are you doing?
I'm looking up how
to deliver this baby.
‐ What, you don't know how?
‐ Look, I'm a surgeon.
Not an OB. Do you have
any flashlights?
‐ Couple of battery lanterns.
‐ Well, go, go, go, get them.
And somebody blow out all
of these candles.
I'm gonna use ether
if I can find it.
'Hey, Melanie, I need
you to breathe nice and easy.'
'I can't.'
You're gonna
have to try.
Well, what the hell
are you doing to her?
She has to be sedated.
If her uterus ruptures,
it could kill her.
Yeah, well,
I might kill her
myself once I see
the bastard.
You hush.
Mrs. Ebee, I need
you to hold this bottle
over Melanie's face
letting it drip slowly
into the mask,
just like this, okay?
‐ Alright.
‐ She brought this on herself.
Well, okay, Mr. Ebee,
can you read?
‐ Of course I can.
‐ Okay, good. Go.
I need you to read off this
computer screen right now.
You do it, mama.
"Insert, uh,
the right hand
into the ker‐ker.."
Cervix, cervix.
Okay, that's it.
'Come on. Go on.'
"Push the head
"and with the left
hand external
bring the rump down.."
‐ Rump.
‐ Hold it. Stop.
Okay, okay. Go on.
Uh, "lift the feet up
'"and push the head'
"over the pel..
...pelvis rim."
Oh, damn it.
Alright.
Oh, come on.
Come on.
Alright.
I got one foot out.
Alright. There's the other one.
Ah, damn it.
The head's stuck.
Oh, please, Jesus.
Okay, okay, okay.
Come on, come on.
Alright, alright.
We're almost near.
Alright.
Okay, stop the drip.
Hey.
Okay, you got a granddaughter.
Oh, she looks just like an Ebee.
See, Eli?
I see.
Melanie's damn lucky.
How're you feeling?
Happy.
Is my baby okay?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. She's fine.
You know, from what
your father said
I have to ask,
is there any chance
that the father
of this baby is black?
You see her baby.
She's white.
Yeah, I know.
Just so that you know
a lot of
African American babies
don't get their
full pigmentation
until a few days later.
So if there's any chance
of that happening
for your baby's safety
and for yours, you..
...you need
to let me know, okay?
'I got worried.'
It was a breech.
Mother and baby
are fine, but..
I'm gonna have take
'em back to Laverne.
Not in my boat.
Hey, doc.
Don't take off
just yet.
Here.
There's no charge.
Maureen?
Much obliged, Eli.
Now, that took a lot
for him to offer to pay you.
I don't want his money.
The baby's jaundiced.
I hope she and the mom can stay
at your house for a few days?
Jaundice usually goes away.
No.
Explain to the Ebees
that the mother
and baby have
to be taken in.
How you doin'?
I don't wanna talk about it.
Good.
I didn't come
here to talk.
Come on.
Morning, doctor.
Hey, how you doin',
Mr. Morgan?
Did you drop that big jug
of water off on my porch?
Yeah.
I sure want
to thank you.
But I had to come
to town anyway.
If I don't sit
in this chair
who's gonna do it?
'Come on.'
‐ Hey.
You're on your
feet again.
Well, I only got your help
for a few more days.
I thought maybe we
could hold down the fort here
and send you to pick up
from the pharmacy.
How's the baby?
Her jaundice doesn't
appear any worse.
Melanie's itching to go home.
Sonny, why don't you
go get Dr. Benton his keys.
You know, it's only been
three days.
If the baby's pigment
was gonna darken
it would have started.
Probably.
That was smart
the way you handled Ebee.
You know, you may
have a flair
for country medicine
after all.
I don't think so.
Oh, I don't either.
Look, I really don't
feel like driving 80 miles.
Adelina and her grandma
are willing to keep you company.
The grandmother says
she doesn't trust hospitals.
Well, she must be sweet
on to you.
And I heard, they have
the videophone hooked up.
Might could see your son.
Dr. Benton said
the pump is better.
'And I sure, I'll consider
putting you on one'
'if you learn to control
your glucose level'
'by the time
we get 'em.'
How's that?
I'm a little more
concerned about, uh
another finding that
we got here, little, uh..
Dr. Benton, did you detect
a pansystolic murmur
when you examined Adelina?
‐ A murmur?
‐ Oh, yes, sir.
'And I listened
to her chest'
I thought I appreciated
a slight murmur
along the left
sternal border.
The echo
shows a VSD.
What's that?
No, I didn't listen
to her chest.
She's was in
for diabetes monitoring.
What's wrong?
Adelina has a small hole
in her heart.
A hole?
‐ From the diabetes?
‐ 'No, ma'am, it's unrelated.'
'She's probably had
it since birth.'
Uh‐huh.
She, uh, she should just
get it repaired
before it
gets any worse.
Excuse me.
What does he mean
by repaired?
It's a simple surgery.
I'm having surgery?
I don't want her cut.
You never said
I needed surgery.
I missed it.
Dr. Benton, call's ready.
Excuse me, please.
'Come on, Reese.'
'Who're you laughing at?'
Reese, come on.
Come on, man, wash your hands.
'Excuse me.
That's it for today.'
‐ Okay.
‐ 'Oh.'
Uh, they're actually saying
that we've got to go now.
Oh, thanks, Elizabeth.
Um, just four more days to go.
‐ 'Alright.'
‐ I'll be home on Friday.
He'll be thrilled to see you.
Okay. Okay, Reese, okay,
I got to go.
Bye‐bye.
Bye‐bye. Come on, Reese.
Say bye‐bye.
You goin' home this Friday?
Well, uh,
yeah, uh, but
Dr. Brooks will find
you a good surgeon.
And what else is he
gonna find wrong with her?
Miss Deane, I know it's hard
to plan ahead sometimes
but if we could just set a date,
then it would give us some‐‐
I'll think it over.
Yes, ma'am,
I'm sure you will.
You really shouldn't
put this thing off.
What was wrong
with next week?
I have to think about it.
But you will call
Dr. Brookes, right?
As soon as I can.
Well, that took a while.
Ignorance, you know,
it's just ignorance.
There's no reason why
a kid in this century
couldn't have
that surgery..
What happened?
‐ They found Jesse dead.
‐ Oh, man.
In front of Suggs' store
about an hour after you left.
What was it an MI? I mean,
why didn't you page me?
'Well, It could have been
his heart.'
'It could have been
a stroke..'
Or an embolism.
'I mean, he said his leg ached.
And I..'
...I should
have checked him out.
He was an old man,
Dr. Benton.
There was nothing we could do.
God rest his soul.
'Funeral's Friday.'
I've been saying
Jesse wanted to
lay with his wife
in our churchyard
but he born a catholic
and I know he'd want the sister
to offer a prayer.
What sister?
May the angels lead you
into paradise
and may the martyrs
come to welcome you
and take you
to the holy city.
The new and eternal Jerusalem
and may the choir of angels
welcome you
where Lazarus
is poor no longer.
May you have eternal rest.
Eternal rest grant
unto him, oh, Lord.
'And let perpetual life
shine upon him.'
'And may he rest
in peace.'
Goodbye, Jesse.
Amen.
You is a liar,
you do not.
I do too.
You just stick it
and push the insulin.
That's right.
Adelina thinks maybe she gonna
be a doctor herself one day.
Hubert.
That's what you said.
So, what's wrong
with that?
Adelina will make
a fine doctor.
I changed my mind.
Oh, yeah, why is that?
'Cause doctors act like
they know everything
when they don't.
Yep.
We make mistakes.
I made a mistake
with your diagnosis.
But I learned something.
It's because of you.
I am sorry, Adelina.
That's okay.
That is for me?
If you're thinking of arguing
with grandma Deane
I'd save my breath.
Adelina needs
that surgery.
I just can't leave.
Well, I'll work on her.
She'll come around.
‐ Finish packing?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
I appreciate your
sticking it out here.
I didn't do anything.
What?
Well, maybe not by
Chicago surgeon standards
but you took good
care of Laverne.
I love this town.
I guess that's hard
for you to understand.
Yeah, well, I'm not
the missionary type, you know?
No!
And I never did well with
a doctor over my shoulder.
This is a good
place for a nun
with authority issues.
What's your specialty
gonna be?
I bet you got
that figured out.
Yep.
Five years ago I decided
to go into cardiothoracic.
Well, no wonder
it stung you
to miss that
heart murmur.
Well, I missed it too.
Yeah, but you're
a nurse.
Look out, now.
I don't know, this last year,
I've been, uh..
I don't know, I've been
distracted, you know
with my son and all.
Well, it's not easy
raising a child.
Yeah, well,
you would know that.
Oh, I've just had Sonny
the last few years.
I took him in
when his folks died and..
Being a parent's
a full‐time job.
Yeah, it's hard work, but..
...I love being with my son.
Oh, man.
Well, being with people.
It's as simple as that,
isn't it?
And what a blessing
when you..
...can hear the sound
of your own heart.
Hey, shrimp boat blew
down at south port.
How many hurt?
‐ I'm a doctor. How bad?
‐ 'They sank their boat.'
Radioed us one guy got blown
through the roof.
Shrimp boat bringing
them in
had to fish another guy
out of the water.
Why're they just
sittin' here?
'Have to raise the outriggers
supporting dock.'
‐ How long does that take?
‐ 15 minutes.
That's too long.
Can you get me out there?
High up. Kenny's boat's
right here.
Doctor needs to get out
to the Gulf Prince.
Maureen, round up a first aid
kit and some fresh water.
‐ You got it.
‐ Go, go.
Alright, here we go.
Nice and easy. Nice and easy.
Maureen, we got two guys
injured pretty bad.
This one has a flail chest
with evisceration.
'Other one has a partial
amputation'
'of the upper right thigh.'
We got bottled water
and two first aid kits.
Well, let's lay them down
over here.
Crazy fools didn't secure
their propane tank.
Rolled down
into the engine room
hit the clutch on the boiler,
whole boat blew.
If I can stabilize the chest
wall, he may be able to breathe.
'Come on, come on, don't
die on me.'
I need somebody to go and find
the smallest fishing fly
you can find and some leader.
Does anyone have any pliers
for taking out fish hooks?
Got a needle nose
in my tackle box.
Alright, go, go!
Sonny, are you with me?
‐ Yes.
‐ 'Listen to me.'
This man is gonna die
without your help.
I need you to find some
saran wrap and plenty of this.
‐ Saran wrap?
‐ That's right.
‐ What is that over there?
‐ Uh, shrimp factory.
Alright, try them. Go, move!
‐ Where is that ice?
‐ I got some flies.
‐ And fishing leader here.
‐ Open up.
Okay, take that small one.
You peel all the fur
and feathers off.
I want you to thread
it with the leader
and then run some
alcohol over that.
I need some alcohol
from the first aid kit.
‐ Maureen, how you doing?
‐ 'This leg's skin is ischemic.'
He's gonna loose it if we
don't get this tourniquet off.
‐ This ice ain't that clean.
‐ 'It'll do.'
Let's just pack
it around his leg.
‐ How's yours holding up?
‐ I got a faint pulse.
'Thank god for small miracles.'
Where the hell
is Sonny?
They wouldn't give it to me
so I had to steal it.
Now, listen to me
carefully, alright?
I'm depending on you.
Come on, over here.
I'm going to stabilize his chest
with the saran wrap.
I want you to wrap it
around him, alright?
Here we go, boys, here we go.
Roll him, roll him.
Lift him. Lift him up.
Here we go.
Let's go.
Maureen! You got any
gauze or bandages over there?
I used it up on this fella.
I need something to hold
this guy's guts in with.
'How about my T‐shirt?'
Yeah, fine. Take it off.
Here, take this.
Alright, here we go.
Sonny, you just stay here.
Here, give me your hand.
Put it right there.
Now, you feel his pulse?
Now, as long as you can feel
a pulse, he is alive.
If it stops,
you let me know, alright?
‐ Needle's threaded, doc.
‐ Alright, you ready?
Come on, come on, come on.
I'm gonna tie off
the superficial femoral artery
to stop the bleeding.
Alright, now,
release the tourniquet slowly
'so I can isolate the artery
and clean out any clots.'
Ah, ah, ah. Okay.
Okay, now, tighten
the tourniquet.
Here we go.
How we doing there, Sonny?
Uh, he's breathing.
Still has a pulse.
Good.
Good. Come on, cut.
Nice work, Dr. Benton.
Yeah.
You, too.
Guess I'll try
to borrow a shirt.
Sonny, you did
good today, man.
We were mighty lucky
there was a surgeon in town.
And I'm sorry you missed
your flight.
Yeah, well, I'll
catch one tomorrow.
You're leaving so early?
Yeah. I got to take care
of something.
'Hey, you're back.'
So, uh, how was it?
Different.
Congratulations.
Robert Romano told me
that you're a shoo‐in
'for a cardiothoracic
spot next year.'
Yeah, well, you know
cardiothoracic is a pretty
time‐consuming specialty.
I have a son, you know.
Hey, what are you doing
up here, anyway?
I'm, um, I'm visiting Jeanie.
Hey, Jeanie.
Peter, hey.
So, how was the
middle of nowhere?
Wasn't bad. I‐I didn't run
into your family, though.
Oh, well.
So, uh..
Had a setback, huh?
Yeah.
Th‐The plasma will help.
Damn it.
Th.. Peter, don't touch me.
For god's sake.
I'm a poison.
I can't do this.
I can't.
You can't do this alone.
'Hmm?'
Hmm?
Yeah.
Okay.