Psych? My daughter
doesn't need a psychiatrist.
I just need to talk
to her. That's all.
Can you get him on the phone?
- When did he die?
It's Dr. Carter in the ER.
How long does a CAT scan take?
- I'll hold.
I'm off at 4 if you
want to go get coffee.
Two hundred people
back at the house.
There's coffee
there, isn't there?
I wouldn't ask you to
subject yourself to that.
Dr. Weisman? MAN: Yes?
You have a patient here, Holly Evans,
who was supposed to be admitted last night.
Say he doesn't die on
the table or in post-op.
You ship him back to his
convenience-store alley.
But this time, instead
of getting beaten up...
he gets eaten by dogs
because he's too weak to move.
- Eaten by dogs?
- It happens.
- In Chicago?
- A lot. A cop told me.
Dr. Romano needs you
in his office immediately.
- Did he say why?
- Something about the Fossen case.
He says it's important.
- Something wrong?
- I don't know.
- Hey, Mark, you got a second?
- No.
Look, is Cleo having
trouble with the triple cocktail?
- What?
- She was nauseated.
She's alone and afraid. And has
now been waiting for almost 20 hours.
No.
No, pull your thumb out, get
down here and admit your patient.
Give her another gram of
cefoxitin and order a clear-liquid diet.
- "Pull your thumb out"?
- Call me in half an hour...
if someone from Pedes
doesn't get down here.
Exactly what don't you
want me to subject myself to?
- Dr. Weaver.
- Abby, John.
Things are a little
tense. I'll see you later.
I can imagine.
Queen Elizabeth wants
me to meet her boy.
- Got room for a Haldol deficiency?
- Over there.
Because we are compatible.
- Who, you and Prince Charles?
- He likes coffee and so do I.
- I could be princess.
- He is mine, honey.
Abby? MVA with PSI rolling up.
- Coming.
- Hey, you stay away from him.
- I promise.
There's an apartment
listed in that building.
- Which?
- The one you like on Clark.
Two bedrooms, big
closets, wood floors.
- You went there?
- Yeah. I called the manager.
She already had
two people interested.
- Are you seriously considering it?
- I thought you liked that area.
Oh, I can't afford
that kind of rent.
- Don't worry about it.
- And I'm pretty happy where I am.
- Oh, I...
- You know...
- How much is this?
- For you, $20.
- Is it real?
- Of course.
No. I mean authentic.
Direct from Kenya, pretty lady.
Imported with my own two hands.
All right. I'll take it.
Don't bother. It's not a gift.
At some point, we have
to have some standards.
Who decides, you?
They decided when
they chose to participate.
You judge someone based on
what they do in their bedroom?
Look, I have no problem
with alternative lifestyles.
But we're talking
about role models here.
So you would
oppose gay teachers?
I oppose any homosexual in a job
where they interact and influence...
Okay.
Exactly what don't you
want me to subject myself to?
- Dr. Weaver.
- Abby, John.
- Hey, chief. Back in the saddle so soon?
- Yeah. We weren't expecting you.
- It's been three weeks.
- Already?
Man, the time really flies when
you're, you know, missing a colleague.
Malik, you got that x-ray going?
- What x-ray?
- The one with the kid.
Yeah.
Abby, MVA with a PSI rolling up.
I love your hair color.
It's perfect on you.
Oh, thank you.
- It's strong. It's very...
- Thank you.
- Awesome bracelet. Where did you get it?
- A place in Nairobi.
- Was it totally amazing?
- What?
- Africa.
- It was exactly as I remembered it.
She's not breathing.
Pulse is thready,
bradying down to 50.
P.E.A. Starting compressions.
Two of O-neg on the
infuser. Get some saline.
- How'd she get upstairs?
- She's an ER patient?
Came in with facial fracture,
abdominal pain, broken wrist.
Waiting for Psych. Pregnant
with her brother's baby.
- Why wasn't anyone monitoring?
- Short-handed with Legaspi gone.
Another 2 cc's in the cuff.
Hey, give me a vascular clamp.
They haven't replaced Legaspi?
- Someone said she got a job in California.
- We should be so lucky.
Is that true?
Dr. Weaver, have you
heard from Dr. Legaspi?
- Probably a tension pneumo.
- What happened?
Four-story fall. GCS
of 3. Now in P.E.A.
- How did she fall?
- She jumped.
Pulse ox, 74 on 100 percent.
Did she ever have a pulse? - No.
- Try for a central line.
- No. Open up another tray.
We've got this, Kerry.
Go get cleaned up.
- Prep for a subclavian.
- I want a second chest tube first.
- 10 blade. Let's move.
- Really, Kerry, we've got it.
- Set up a Thora-Seal.
- Holding compressions.
Pretty agonal. You want atropine?
BENTON: Yeah. Push a milligram.
Let's set up a
pericardiocentesis.
What did you say to her?
- Nothing.
How long are we going?
Dr. Weaver, how was your trip?
Hot. It was hot.
Hey, I never got a
chance to thank you.
- For what?
- I got my Chief Resident confirmation.
- I won't let you down.
- I'm sure you won't.
No! No!
No, no, no!
- You should sue that Scottish bastard.
- What?
Sleazebag host will say
anything to get you on his show.
Mr. Peterson started a
brawl at a talk-show taping.
Somebody smacked
me with a microphone.
Carl?
Stay the hell away
from me, you queer.
- Carl, let me drive you home.
- I don't dig penises, okay?
- I have only one more operation.
- Touch me, I swear...
Hey. You need to calm down.
Calm down? This thing makes
me look like some twisted fairy.
You knew. Part of you knew.
- Security.
You see this, huh?
Man, woman. That's
what I know. That's normal.
It's still love,
Carl. Love is love.
It's perverted, you faggot!
It's sick. You disgust me.
- Calm down, sir.
- You're a freak!
- Please calm down.
- Damn homo.
You all right?
Take it easy, all right?
- You going to the M&M?
- What?
On Fossen. The M&M's starting.
Luka, has there been any talk...
about me?
Kerry, people always
talk about their bosses.
No, I...
- I mean personally.
- Personally?
Well, Dr. Weaver.
I thought maybe you fell under
the spell of some Masai warrior...
and were never
coming back. Coming in?
Why wasn't lidocaine
given for a stable V-tach?
I didn't have the
ACLS drug box with me.
When transferring
a critical patient?
The Trauma nurse
ran out to get it...
but then the doors
closed unexpectedly.
Leaving you alone with the patient?
- Right.
Dr. Legaspi, however,
is a lesbian. Am I right?
Yes. MAN: Isn't
that a little barbaric?
I've never hidden that fact from
this administration or my colleagues.
Don't worry. Your
secret's safe with me.
How many openly gay
women do you know...
in hospital
administrative positions?
None. It doesn't happen.
Then deal with the
stigma of being gay.
You care to comment on that?
Dr. Weaver.
In your opinion, was the
patient's care compromised?
Compromised?
Did the ER accept too many
Trauma patients that day?
Uh, I don't believe so.
We were busy, but we handled it.
Watch your back.
Kerry, you under the weather?
- Excuse me?
- You were a little slow on the uptake.
Jet lag.
Oh, yes. Your trip
to Africa, was it?
Spontaneous decision.
Doesn't seem like you.
Half of my accrued personal
days were about to expire.
Well, it still doesn't justify you going
MIA for three weeks with no real warning.
You know what? I took a vacation. I may
take another. I still have 19 days banked.
Uh-huh. I see.
You might want to try
Papua New Guinea next time.
I hear they put gourds
on their penises.
Give some notice next time.
- Wait. Robert.
- Careful, Kerry.
- You okay?
- Yeah. I'm good.
You know, you could just call my office.
You don't have to go beat up the elevator.
You, uh...
- Who have you told?
- Told who what?
About what we
discussed before I left.
Oh, yes. Legaspi. As
ordered, I backed off.
But she was determined to leave,
decided she didn't like us anymore...
and was gonna move and work in
San Francisco, I understand. Go figure.
Have you told anyone about me?
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- I think you do.
Have you told anyone
that I'm a lesbian?
Oh, um...
No, Kerry.
I assumed that that
was confidential.
Was I wrong to assume that?
I mean, if you want to tell
everyone, that's your business.
But I don't see how a
person's sexual affairs...
are appropriate subject matter for a
workplace conversation, do you, Kerry?
No.
Glad we're on the same page.
- We got aluminum rotors in stock?
- Doubt it. Want me to order some?
- If it's not too much trouble.
- Pads too?
I'm sure your father
will give me a deal.
If I ever need an operation,
you better not charge me.
Just for parts.
- What's this, summer session?
- Chem 2.
Look, if you can pay
him, you should pay him.
- Mom got fired.
- What happened?
You can only take a leave
of absence for just so long.
Hey, you know what?
You should bring Cleo over.
- We haven't seen you guys in a while.
- We're taking a little break right now.
- What did you do?
- Nothing.
She's going through
some rough stuff...
and she needed a little
room. I'm respecting that.
Did you reach him?
- No, not yet.
I'm gonna try
him again in a few.
Look at that. You'd
think she had fangs.
He said he'd come back to check on me.
- I know.
Nine years I've been hosting a
talk show. I've never gotten bit.
- I thought those fights were all staged.
- Not exactly.
But people usually
don't get hurt.
We use lightweight
furniture, just in case.
Guys tend to get unglued when their
lover tells them they used to be a man.
- Can you catch AIDS from a she-male bite?
- What?
I think one of the
transsexuals bit me.
Excuse me.
She broke the skin.
- Cleo? Hey, you all right?
- Yeah.
- I heard you got sick.
- A little nauseous.
- Trouble with your meds?
- I'm fine.
You're still taking
them, though, right?
- Do you want to help out?
- Sure.
A 20-year-old girl fell down
and broke her left wrist.
Doesn't sound surgical.
Then smacked repeatedly with a
folding chair to the face and abdomen.
- Talk-show brawl?
- She's a little worked-up.
Just found out her boyfriend
is also her half-brother.
Right. Up.
Down.
Okay. You might have a facial
fracture. I need to see some x-rays.
Is this tender? How about here?
I need to use an
ultrasound machine on your
belly to rule out any
internal bleeding, okay?
- Alice.
- Get out!
- Let me explain...
- You tell me on TV.
- I know.
You keep this from
me. You let me date him.
And you knew we were having
sex, and you tell me on TV!
- The producers made me do that.
- Get out!
- You need to sit and let us monitor you.
- I need to talk to Alice.
Alice, honey, I love you.
- I can explain this whole thing.
- Get out!
I can explain this. - Get out!
- Please.
- Alice?
Can you tell if I'm
pregnant with that?
Do you think you are?
I might be.
It looks like about 10 weeks.
I was gonna keep it.
This can't be happening.
This can't be true.
I love him so much.
It's not fair.
There's no intra-abdominal bleeding, but
I'm gonna get a CT scan of your face, okay?
Could you close the curtain?
Sure.
- Dr. Benton, can I discharge Molton?
- As soon as he's done with his IV.
Also, this girl needs a facial
CT and a Psych consult.
Weaver's here! MALUCCI: What?
Why didn't someone
say she was working?
- She's on the schedule.
- Take this down.
I know I know you
from somewhere.
- I wouldn't forget that smile.
- All right.
Put Neosporin on it three times a day
and don't wash your hair for two days.
No way. I'm a bridesmaid on Saturday. I
have to wash my hair. I want to look good.
Dr. Romano needs you
in his office immediately.
- Did he say why?
- Something about the Fossen case.
He says it's important.
- Something wrong?
- I don't know.
- Hey, Mark, you got a minute?
- No.
Is Cleo having trouble
with the triple cocktail?
- What?
- She was nauseated.
- Has she had a repeat antibody test?
- You should ask her.
I want to make sure
they're following her LFTs.
Peter, you should talk to her.
- Uncle Peter.
- Joanie?
- What's wrong?
- Can I talk to you?
Your parathyroidectomy's
ready to go.
Put his film on a view
box. I'll be right back.
- What's up?
- I think they're gonna break up.
- Who?
- My mom and my dad.
I didn't notice it until
I came home for the
summer, but it's
really bad, Uncle Peter.
I mean, one minute,
Mom seems okay.
The next, she's crying and
locks herself in the bedroom.
Dad won't even say anything. He
just gets all quiet and stares into space.
- Look, they lost their son. It's normal.
- No, it is not normal.
They fight all the time about
her job, about Jesse's room.
Dad washed a shirt that had his
scent on it, and Mom went nuts.
And then Dad stayed out all night.
I don't know. It's just messed up.
Somebody's gotta talk to her.
There's nothing I can say, and there's
nothing you can do but give it time.
- It's almost been a year, Uncle Peter.
- Joanie, I know, but it...
- Trauma 1?
- Yeah. It's your patient.
- My patient?
- Yeah, the girl from the talk show.
What?
Probably a tension pneumo.
What happened?
- Four-story fall. GCS
of three. Now in P.E.A.
- How'd she fall?
- She jumped.
Pulse ox, 74 on 100 percent.
Did she ever have a pulse? - No.
- Try for a central line.
- Let's open up another tray first.
We've got this.
Go get cleaned up.
- Prep for a subclavian.
- Not until I get a second chest tube.
Really, Kerry. We've got it.
- Set up a Thora-Seal.
- Holding compressions.
- Pretty agonal. You want atropine?
- Yeah. Push a milligram.
Let's set up a
pericardiocentesis.
- What did you say to her?
- I didn't say anything to her.
I'm in. Check the tamponade.
Give her 8 units packed cells.
I feel a pulse. ABBY: Injury
occurring on the monitor.
Blood in the pericardium.
220 cc's out.
- Rate is 29.
- Still no pulse.
All right. Resuming
compressions. Another amp of epi.
- Mother's outside.
- Keep her out.
- I'll tell her.
- I'm not ready to call it yet.
You will be.
Let it circulate.
Dr. Benton?
Asystole.
No!
No, no, no! No, no!
Time of death, 12:17.
- Peter.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- What, are you spring-cleaning?
- Getting rid of some crap.
- It's not too dark?
I wanted to finish. Salvation
Army comes tomorrow.
- All right. Well, let me give you a hand.
- I'm almost done.
Want a hamster cage?
- No?
- You okay?
What did you need, Peter?
I... What? I just came
by for a snow shovel.
All right. I came
to check on you.
I heard you lost your job.
We'll just have to wait
to expand that porch.
What's wrong with the porch?
I don't know.
I thought it was
time for a change.
Walt took some pictures of the back
yard that we could xerox and draw on...
make plans.
When I went to
pick up the prints...
I found three pictures
of Jesse left on the roll.
I fell apart.
Right in the store.
I realized...
that's it.
There'll never be any
more pictures of him.
Fifteen years old.
And he's never gonna change.
You think every day you're getting
a little better, getting through it.
And then you're right
back to the day it happened.
He's still my baby, Peter.
I'm supposed to
take care of him.
I feel like...
somewhere, sometime...
he's gonna be sad...
or cold...
or scared.
Who's taking care of him?
Who's being his mother?
"I am the resurrection and
the life," sayeth the Lord.
"He that believeth in me, though
he were dead, yet shall he live.
And whosoever liveth and
believeth in me shall never die.
We brought nothing
into this world.
And it is certain we'd
carry nothing out.
Wherefore my heart is
glad and my spirit rejoiceth...
my flesh also
shall rest in hope."
The Lord gave, and the
Lord hath taken away.
Blessed be the name of the Lord.
In sure and certain hope of
the resurrection to eternal life...
through our Lord,
Jesus Christ...
we commend to almighty
God our brother John.
And we commit his
body to the ground.
Earth to earth...
ashes to ashes...
dust to dust.
Dad did a nice
job with the eulogy.
He worked on it for a while.
- Grandpa would have liked it.
- Yes.
Gamma seems to be holding up.
I expect she would.
Is that for your convenience
or someone else's?
Hello. ABBY: Bad time?
Yeah. Kind of busy. Why?
Wait, wait. She's
not on the ward?
Weisman was supposed
to admit her last night.
- She's sitting right here.
- What's her hemoglobin?
Okay, yeah. No,
I'll be right there.
Fifteen minutes.
We need to make a stop
at County General Hospital.
- Just get off on Division.
- Yes, sir.
This shouldn't take long.
You mind?
Pow!
- Can someone shut him up?
- Why don't you both shut up.
I got a right to be here,
same as you. Pow, pow.
Hi.
- You left without saying goodbye.
- You were asleep.
- For about 10 minutes.
- I'm sorry. I had someplace to be.
- I don't like it here.
- I know.
But we're gonna make sure that you get
your own bed and your own room upstairs.
- You said that last night.
- Well, they're still working on it.
- But I'm gonna go hurry them up, okay?
- Okay.
Any more pain in your stomach?
- A little.
- We'll take care of that.
And Abby here is gonna hang
out with you until they bring you up.
Tell her to call me again
if you want to talk to me.
- Thanks for coming back.
- You're welcome.
What was her last crit?
Thirty-six, after two
doses of Solu-Medrol.
Give her four more,
MS, then Q2 p.r.n.
- When are her parents getting here?
- Around 3.
- They missed their connecting flight.
- Dr. Weisman, please.
Nice suit. Who died?
My grandfather.
I'm sorry. I didn't know.
Uh, no, no. Can you get
him on the phone now?
- When did he die?
- It's Dr. Carter in the ER.
- Monday.
- Wow.
You okay?
I'm off at 4 if you want to
go get a coffee or something.
I got 200 people
back at the house.
There's coffee
there, isn't there?
I wouldn't ask you to
subject yourself to that.
Dr. Weisman? This is Dr. Carter.
You have a patient, Holly Evans, who
was supposed to be admitted last night.
Wait.
- Thank you.
- Did the driver get lost?
John had something
more pressing.
It was trouble with a patient.
- Decent turnout.
- It'll do.
- Where's Gamma?
- Lying down. Said she was tired.
- Where are you staying?
- The Drake.
The Ritz-Carlton was booked.
Did you think
about staying here?
Oh, there's Peter
Harkins. I should say hello.
- Who's Peter Harkins?
- He's handling the probate.
I'm gonna check on Gamma.
- I did. She's fine.
- Still...
You want to help your
grandmother, be a good host.
Introduce yourself to Senator
Herrero's daughter. Arthur.
Dr. Carter, your friend is here.
- Holly got her bed.
- Yeah? Did Weisman come down?
Yeah. A few minutes
after you called.
Amazing what a little "pull
your thumb out" will do.
- Did you eat something?
- No.
I couldn't decide between the smoked
tongue pâté and the whitefish mousse.
We must have run out
of the pigs in the blanket.
Well, somebody should
really talk to your caterer.
You're gonna have
some dirty birds.
Grandpa liked to drive the
power lawn mower around.
- And he drove it into the birdbath?
- Not on purpose.
He was having a
fatal MI at the time.
Oh, God.
I'm sorry.
- You gotta die somehow.
- Mm-hm.
It's not a bad way to go.
A sunny day...
out on the mower.
- Don't... Don't laugh.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't laugh.
- Well, stop it.
Oh, God.
I hope it's all right that I came
here. I'm not usually a funeral crasher.
Figured this would
be a good one?
And I felt bad...
that your grandfather died
and we didn't even talk about it.
John, have you seen Millicent?
No.
Mom, this is my friend Abby.
Abby, this is my mother, Eleanor.
- Hello.
- Hi.
Things are winding down. She
really needs to make an appearance.
- I will go and look for her in a minute.
- Please do.
Sorry.
- It's okay.
- It's my parents. They don't...
They don't handle loss well.
Who does?
It's been a while since we've
had to deal with this sort of thing.
- Since your brother died?
- Mm-hm.
You'd better go.
54. That was back in July.
Oh, come on.
Fall from grace for the NASDAQ.
- John?
- Hey.
- Is everything okay?
- Yeah. Just took a hit on Parning.
Biotech's in the basement again.
- You want a drink?
- No, thank you.
Have you seen Gamma?
Haven't given up
that quest, huh?
Oh, Mom thinks she
might be hiding out.
I don't blame her. That
room can get insufferable.
Dad, I think you
should stay here tonight.
Don't worry. We have a driver.
No. I meant for Gamma.
- You know how your mother feels about it.
- Well, then stand up to her this time.
Thanks for the counsel.
I'll take it under advisement.
She buried her husband today.
Yes, I know. My father.
- Then don't run away again.
- Drop it, John.
Leave it alone.
I've left it...
alone.
Bobby's not coming back.
If Mom wants to walk around in a
bubble for the rest of her life, then fine.
But don't let her keep
holding you inside of it.
You might want
to try the garage.
Damn it.
Gamma?
I can't get this
stupid thing started.
Well, it sounds
like it's flooded.
You need to let it sit.
- Your mother sent you.
- Yeah.
- People want to pay their respects.
- Well, they can wait.
I'm the widow.
I hope you weren't thinking
about drinking and driving.
We were saving that bottle
for our 60th anniversary.
Missed it by a year.
Open it.
No, you can still wait.
Let's drink to your grandfather.
It's a very nice vintage.
Are you sure you wouldn't
rather share this with...?
- Whoa!
- Whoa-ho-ho!
We don't have any glasses.
You can drink from the bottle.
To John Truman Carter...
entrepreneur...
philanthropist...
family man.
And friend.
We gonna take this old
girl out for a spin, or what?
Damn right.
Okay, that's it.
How'd it look?
Have to wait for the
radiologist to read it.
You saw it.
- I'm just a tech.
- Did you see anything bad?
- You want to take on Fossen, Mark?
- What?
The shooter. He
coded in the elevator.
I thought maybe you
should present him in M&M.
Yeah, sure. Whatever.
- Did you give nitro?
- Two sprays, no relief.
Can you see if they brought my
daughter? I think she broke her arm.
- Is this from the talk show?
- How'd you guess?
- They're stacked up in the waiting room.
- How'd it start?
How do any of them start? I heard
somebody bit the host this time.
So I only present the
cab driver. That's it.
Luka, relax, okay?
Just stick to the
facts. You'll be fine.
Cleo, check a 12-lead and a...
The meds?
Third time today.
- You tried Compazine?
- Yeah.
- We can get you some Zofran.
- I can live with the nausea.
- My liver enzymes were up last week.
- Meds might be giving you hepatitis.
Only one more week.
- Three out of four might be enough.
- Maybe.
- You don't want to hurt your liver.
- I want to be safe.
- Malucci, need something to do?
- No. I'm swamped, actually.
- Want my opinion?
- I guess so.
Reduce your dose
and monitor your LFTs.
- Talk show? EMT
1: No. Casey Square.
A bunch of teenagers
beat him up for his coin cup.
Trauma 2.
Contusions to the
face, chest, everything.
- Didn't anybody see this happening?
- The whole plaza saw it.
All right. Get a surgical consult
and x-ray. I'll be right there.
- Nobody did anything?
- Just his homeless buddies.
- Hi, Adele.
- Hi.
- How's physical therapy?
- It's hard.
- Have you got up on crutches?
- Yeah, with leg braces, yeah.
- That's a good sign.
- Well, I'm trying.
But I'm also realistic.
Romano wanted me to go to the
Morbidity and Mortality as a show-and-tell.
- Are you presenting Fossen?
- Yeah.
Well, have fun.
I need an ultrasound. - Coming.
C-spine's ready.
Did you get his pressure up?
- 90/60 after a liter.
Hi, it's Abby calling about
your colitis patient, Holly.
She keeps asking for you.
Could you call me? Thanks.
Everything hurts.
Okay, we can take
the collar off now.
- How'd it go?
- What?
Oh, right. Good.
Yeah. Still have a brain.
- Mark.
- Everything's normal.
I still can't believe people would stand
there and watch someone get beaten.
- How are you holding up?
- Six weeks of maternity leave, not enough.
We have fluid in
Morrison's pouch. Call O.R.
Where? CORDAY: There.
Sir, it appears you're
bleeding internally...
Hold on. It could be
ascites from cirrhosis.
I can't assume that.
- What's his blood alcohol?
- 315.
- When was your last drink, Mr. Skapinski?
- They took my last drink.
- He's hypotensive with a low crit.
- He could be septic from pneumonia.
- High risk for surgery.
- Even riskier if he bleeds out.
Let's take a deep breath
and do a peritoneal lavage.
- He's a surgical candidate.
- He's a homeless alcoholic with pneumonia.
Therefore not worth saving?
He's as healthy as he'll get.
I'm trying to keep him that way.
- Surgery could kill him.
- Delaying surgery could kill him.
Say he doesn't die on
the table or in post-op.
You ship him back to his
convenience-store alley.
But this time, instead
of getting beaten up...
he gets eaten by dogs
because he's too weak to move.
- Eaten by dogs?
- It happens.
- In Chicago?
- A lot. A cop told me.
Dr. Romano needs to speak
to you in his office immediately.
- Did he say why?
- Something about the Fossen case.
He says it's important.
- Something wrong?
- I don't know.
M&Ms. They serve their purpose
in the practice of medicine, I guess.
- But they can be a pain in the ass.
- Needed something, Robert?
I hear you're presenting
this serial killer.
- Mass murderer?
- Right, right. This Fossen guy.
- You don't want me to?
- No. It's just that...
Legal flagged something they'll ask. I
wanted you to be prepared for the question.
Sure. Go ahead.
It's no big deal. It's
their job to be anal.
Yeah. What is it?
Well, uh, the nurse's notes show
that you left the Trauma Room at 1625.
And the code-blue notes
from pre-op began at 1642.
Why'd it take you 17 minutes to
transfer a patient up four floors?
Well... I, uh...
Dr. Romano, there's an
incident in the ambulance bay.
I'm in a meeting, Brenda.
An ER patient jumped
out a fourth-floor window.
That's great news, Brenda,
thank you. Are they dead?
I don't know. They're
working on her.
Keep the press away. No
statements from anyone to anyone...
and get Risk Management down there.
Why I wanted this job I will never know.
All right, Greene, let's go. As you
can see, I've got bigger fish to fry.
Doors opened on
the surgical floor.
I was alone doing chest
compressions, ran down the defib battery.
Took time to get help...
transfer the patient to pre-op.
Okey-doke. Brenda,
get PR on the line.
- Is that it?
- Yeah.
I don't think anyone's gonna
be crying over this guy. Do you?
Autopsy also revealed injuries to the
spleen and superior mesenteric artery.
Cause of death: exsanguination
from multiple vascular injuries.
Why wasn't lidocaine
given for stable V-tach?
I didn't have the
ACLS drug box with me.
When transferring
a critical patient?
The Trauma nurse ran out to get it,
but then the doors closed unexpectedly.
Leaving you alone with the patient?
- Yes.
I don't know if it would
have changed the outcome.
I'm sorry. Did you say the original
dysrhythmia was stable V-tach?
Yes.
He had a pulse?
That's correct.
- So the patient was conscious?
- Yes.
I didn't realize that.
Were you involved with
this case, Dr. Corday?
No. No.
Wait a minute. You cardioverted
a patient without sedation?
- Yes. MAN: Isn't
that a little barbaric?
Under the circumstances,
it's what I felt I needed to do.
Was there any delay in the
O.R. accepting the patient?
Dr. Greene?
No.
Did you know him?
- Who?
- His grandfather.
Yeah. I met him at
that charity event.
Charity event?
Abby, where's my patient?
Dr. Corday took
him up to surgery.
- I thought you okayed it.
- Yeah.
So you're going? - Uh, yeah.
- Mrs. Jenkins.
- Could you take this tube out?
They wouldn't
take this tube out.
This is a coroner's case.
I'm sorry, we have to wait.
They flew us to Chicago
and put us up in the Hilton...
gave me money to go shopping
with. They even took me to a dentist.
The producers said not to
tell her until after the taping.
That it would be more real if she
didn't know what I was gonna say.
It was a lie.
It was all a lie.
All that stuff about them
having the same daddies...
I just said that to get
them on the show.
I used to say, "Alice, you
must always tell the truth."
And she'd go,
"Well, why, Mommy?"
And I'd say:
"Because when you don't...
God gets very angry."
How is she?
Catherine said she slept
for three hours this afternoon.
- Has she fed?
- Just now.
How's our patient?
Extubated in
Recovery when I left.
I repaired a little
omental oozing.
But it might have stopped
on its own. It's hard to say.
Judgment call.
You do what you
think is right, Mark.
Elizabeth, in the
elevator with Fossen...
I think we've talked enough
about Fossen today, don't you?
I'm going to bed.
You coming?
Just wait a few minutes.
Make sure she's down.
Okay.
- Good night.
- Night.
Night-night, sweetheart.
Mark...
I'll get up with her.
Okay.