Okay, you're doing
good. You're doing good.
You still got the thing...
The stupid thing is still on!
You don't have
to yell at me, Mom.
I've been in labor for over a
dozen hours, Justine, I have to yell.
I thought you were gonna
miss the whole thing.
Mom, it's a three-hour drive.
That's why I called you
yesterday after my water broke.
I'm sorry, a partner just
dropped a brief on my desk.
You're doing good.
Yeah. Right.
I remember what it's
like, but family comes first.
I need you to keep
pushing, I can see her head.
All right, come on,
we're doing good here.
Get this, this is what I wanted.
Gross.
Crowning. Are you getting this?
Kind of. Well, not
the actual vagina.
It's your baby sister!
It's my mother's vagina.
Freeing the shoulders.
There she is! Oh,
my God! There she is!
Get the NICU team in here.
Baby's hypoxic.
Is something wrong?
What's going on?
I don't know, Mom.
My baby! How's my baby?
- What are you doing?
- O2 sats are low 80.
Respiratory rate...
What are they saying?
I can't tell.
Find out what's going on!
You need to back
up. Turn that off.
She's not responding.
What's happening?
She's not...
What's wrong with my baby?
Why doesn't someone talk to me?
Cancel your dinner plans.
Short on medical history,
she's only eight hours old.
What she's not
short on is doctors.
Unfortunately, none of them have
been able to solve her breathing problems.
Immature lungs?
Full term. And they gave her surfactant.
Looks like they're fully developed.
Need you a minute.
Silent reading
time till I get back.
My nanny called.
Her daughter has a dance
recital tonight. She can't work late.
And I have a board
meeting tonight.
That's a problem.
My mother can't come.
She has a cooking class.
You've really got a problem.
If only there were some
mature adult in my life
who could pinch hit in
emergencies like this.
Would love to.
But I'm catching up
on my back issues
of Nudist Circus.
You should see what the fat
lady's got under her big top.
All I need is a warm body. And
she'll be asleep the entire time.
I got a sick baby here who
needs me. Yours is healthy.
You can deal with
your team by phone.
How about a little something
extra when you get home?
I'm not bargaining
sex for babysitting.
Besides, you owe me.
For what? Sex.
I still don't see a female
doctor in that room.
It's making me very unhappy.
Fine. Out of the
goodness of my heart.
Which will make you happy,
which will make
you desire me more,
which will turn into more sex.
Be at my place at 7:00.
The sperm donor card from the
father did note a history of asthma.
What if her lung problems
are not coming from her lungs?
Her heart looks fine.
Her liver enzymes are elevated.
When the liver fails, it
stops producing proteins.
Specifically the ones that keep
your plasma inside your blood vessels
and outside your lungs.
Fix the liver, she'll have enough breath
to keep the entire ward up all night.
Foreman, you need
to stay after school.
I apparently need to apologize.
Last week, I should not
have gone over your head
and allowed Chase to
hire a new team member.
So go hire someone who liked
The Bridges of Madison County.
You want me to
hire a white girl?
Go find a woman.
And wipe that self-satisfied
grin off your face.
This'll be quick. I've been
interviewing people all week.
Have it narrowed
down to two candidates.
Narrow it down to one,
before Cuddy starts
withholding sex.
She hasn't said
anything to me about that.
I said wipe the grin.
Yeah, she's fine. I can hear
her breathing in the monitor.
I just checked. I'm
checking every 10 minutes.
Fine, I'll check again.
Aw, she's so cute
when she's asleep.
You should see this. She's
got one hand over her head.
Okay. Well, you take
as long as you need.
I'm thirsty.
Your mommy says
no, 'cause she's mean.
If it was up to me...
Juice!
No. Go back to bed.
I said bed.
Wilson, hey! You up
for a boys' night in?
Believe it or not, breathing problems
can be caused by a liver problem.
Then what's wrong
with her liver?
Probably an abscess.
If we find it with
the ultrasound,
we can drain it,
make her better.
You'd be able to take her
home by the end of the week.
Is she bleeding?
She's oozing from her IV site.
It's a symptom of liver failure.
It's what we would expect to see.
Dr. Cheng, we might need
a unit of blood over here.
Echogenic area in the
liver. Can you make it out?
Doesn't seem to have the thick
walls you'd expect from an abscess.
Lift her left shoulder so
we can get a better look.
Can I do it? I haven't
been able to hold her yet.
She's hooked up to
too many tubes and IVs.
Can I at least donate blood?
Of course. We'll draw your
blood and see if you're a match
as soon as we're done here.
That's definitely
not an abscess.
It looks like
dilated bile ducts.
What does that mean? Can
I still take her home soon?
You were right about the liver.
On ultrasound, we found
intrahepatic dilated bile ducts.
Extrahepatic ducts were normal.
Are there any masses
causing an obstruction?
No.
Are you okay?
Just talking in
a soothing voice.
Not for your benefit.
Why, is it turning you on?
House, there's someone
here I need you to meet.
I just hired
Dr. Christina Fraser.
She's a board-certified...
Nice to meet you.
You're fired.
What? FOREMAN:
House, you're kidding, right?
I've done my due diligence.
She's the best there is.
What did I do?
You had the misfortune to be
the lesson that Foreman is learning.
That whooshing sound is
the air being let out of his ego.
You are such an ass, House. You
could've made the same point without
crushing the hopes of
a young doctor who was
actually excited
to have this job.
I'm not sure I could have. You
keep giving me far too much credit.
Taub, it's your turn to find a young doctor
who's actually excited to have this job.
For you to fire?
Not until you, or she, earns it.
Dilated bile ducts
could be congenital.
It means that it's a stricture in the
ducts themselves. Caroli syndrome.
So open her up.
Surgery?
This is a newborn
with liver failure.
She's oozing blood
from every puncture site.
It's insanely risky
to open her up.
Yes, it's unfortunately
also the only way to fix her.
So make teeny tiny incisions
with a really small scalpel.
Gotta go.
You told me you gave
them your credit card.
And you were dumb
enough to believe me.
Cuddy will be back in
an hour and 10 minutes.
I'll be back in
an hour and five.
Oh, no, you don't.
Oh, yes, I do.
You're not gonna
leave the kid. Yes, I am.
Because unlike you, I
don't have a conscience.
Unlike you, I'm not having sex
with Cuddy, so I actually can leave.
You're bluffing. I'm leaving.
You're not gonna leave a
two-year-old unattended.
True. I'm leaving her with
you. A responsible adult.
You better get back in
there. The kid's all alone.
It's kind of bugging you,
isn't it? Not my problem.
Since objectively,
you care more about
leaving a child alone
than I do, it kind of is.
Objectively, since I never accepted
this responsibility, it kind of isn't.
True. And yet it is.
Because you're you.
I'm leaving.
You're not gonna
leave. You can't.
Fine. You're right.
You know what I can do?
I can go in there and call a
babysitting service for 15 bucks an hour,
then call Cuddy and tell her
who's watching her kid and why.
I'll stay if you stay.
We were gone two minutes.
What you got there, sweetie?
Come on now, spit it out.
Come on, sweetie. Open.
Open.
Ow!
Rachel.
How many coins did you eat?
Isolating the common bile duct.
And mobilizing the
distal end for cannulation.
BP's down to 50 systolic.
You've gotta stop the cannulation.
I haven't started yet.
Hit her with a bolus
of phenylephrine.
That should buy us enough time
to get in and dilate those bile ducts.
BP's rising, 70 systolic.
Nice.
I'm in the common bile duct.
Advancing past the cystic duct.
No strictures or
blockages so far.
BP's dropping again.
Another bolus of phenylephrine.
She can't take more, the
first bolus is still in effect.
BP's still dropping. You
gotta pull out. We're done.
I was barely in.
This doesn't make sense.
A liver problem alone is not
gonna mess with the baby's BP.
Whatever this is, it's
gotta be affecting her heart.
Heart plus liver, could
be tuberous sclerosis.
Or it could be a vascular malformation
in the liver causing both problems.
So what do you guys
think of Dr. Cheng?
Best treatment for a vascular
malformation is surgery.
And I think your wife thinks you
shouldn't think anything of Dr. Cheng.
No surgery. Newborn baby
can't handle another trip to the OR.
I didn't mean think think. I
meant think as a potential hire.
What if we start
the baby on steroids,
an anti-angiogenesis
agent and dopamine?
Could work just as well as surgery,
snap those bad blood vessels shut.
I'll call House to get approval.
So, what was that shrug? A
"Dr. Cheng could work" shrug?
Or a "House is gonna crush you
for even considering her" shrug?
You suck.
House is gonna hate anyone we hire,
because he doesn't want to hire anyone.
So you think I should abstain,
just give the decision back to him?
Then he'll just mock you for
being a wuss. You're screwed.
Unless
House feels like
hiring her is his idea.
He's still not answering.
We should just
start the treatment.
She opened up a Chinese
food bag to eat money.
What an idiot.
Okay, you ordered
the moo shu pork
and the orange
cashew chicken, right?
Like I always order.
Have you cleaned up in
there? Yeah, it's good enough.
Okay, so with tax, the change
should have been 68 cents.
There's only 58 cents out
there. There's a dime missing.
Well, they could have
short-changed you.
Fridge magnet is
not getting anything.
That's because
it's a fridge magnet.
And unless she swallowed a
Canadian dime, it's not magnetic.
Really?
I mean, kids swallow
things all the time, right?
She swallowed a dime, she
poops it out, she'll be fine.
Absolutely. Unless it gets stuck in
her intestines, causes a blockage.
Which could kill her.
Then she won't be fine.
You have to tell Cuddy.
Well, then, I won't be fine.
If you don't tell Cuddy, I will
go out there and tell her myself.
Yeah? What are
you gonna tell her?
You're gonna tell her that you left coins
out and you left her child unsupervised?
Hey, hey, hey! You are
not gonna pin this on me.
Rachel needs to be monitored for
24 hours to see that the dime passes.
You know, just to make
sure she doesn't die.
You're telling me to do the right
thing while climbing out a window?
Tell her!
She wake up at all?
One time.
That's not like
her. Is she all right?
She's fine.
How about I stay the night?
And you can really thank me.
I have to get up early. You
won't be able to sleep in.
I'm a deep sleeper.
Round two. Did Justine go home?
She said she was going
downstairs for a few minutes.
A few hours ago.
So you two are close.
It's been getting
better, actually.
At least she's
here in the building.
That's pretty
supportive for her.
What is it?
She's pinker.
Is that bad?
That's good.
That's very good.
Is that her?
Can I hold her?
I think it's long overdue.
Oh!
My first time.
Finally.
Technically, it's
your second time.
I didn't mean... I know, Mom.
Looks like it was a vascular
malformation. The Grogan baby is better.
Nice job.
Okay, ready, honey.
So stay very, very still.
And hold your
breath. Don't move.
She moved. They always move.
It is a good job.
Diagnostics. Solve
a mystery, save a life.
But I suppose you're
pretty attached to pediatrics.
I'm sorry, Mrs. Young, but
I'm going to have to ask you
to restrain your daughter.
And now the mom's
not gonna want to do it,
because she'd rather I just keep
blasting her daughter with radiation.
You're telling me there's an
opening in House's department?
Would you be interested?
No more kids? No more parents?
One case at a time instead
of 17? Set up the interview.
It's possible you
won't need to interview.
Relax, I got this.
Thanks.
Is everything okay?
Yeah. Sorry. Just
new to all this.
You want me to reset the alarm?
God, no.
Case is under
control. I'm sleeping in.
Your boss must really like you.
Hey, Marina.
There's pasta in
the fridge for lunch.
I assume, since
you're calling so early,
that the surgery was
a rousing success.
And I assume since you still
think we actually did the surgery,
you haven't checked your messages
in eight hours. Where are you?
I believe this is what your
people term a "poopy call."
Uh, the word's "booty."
I don't know what you're
doing, but this is a poopy call.
It's not Caroli Syndrome.
Dr. Cheng spotted...
What?
I knew about the Jew, the
black and the croc hunter.
But when did we get
our Asian persuasion on?
Dr. Cheng is the NICU attending
on the case. And she's not here.
Well, I just wasted a
perfectly good racial epithet.
She spotted a vascular
malformation in the baby's liver.
Good call. Except for
everything you just said.
There's no way that our patient
has a vascular malformation.
And you can tell that
from the vast amount of information
you've gleaned from not being here?
Don't need to be there to remember that
the patient's ALTs were three times normal.
The baby's liver damage is far
too extensive. Dr. Cheng's an idiot.
In fairness, it wasn't
completely her idea.
More of a Foreman kind of thing.
Well, then you're an even bigger
idiot for trying to cover for her.
House, we treated for
a vascular malformation.
And she got better.
No, she didn't. Call me
when she crashes again.
That went well.
Everything okay?
Come on. I know that look.
I'm just not used to seeing
such emotion coming from you.
Well, I just gave birth. I'm like
one big vat of hormones right now.
It's not just the hormones, Mom.
You're different with her.
It's okay, it's
good. It's just...
I can't help thinking, "Where was
this mom when I was growing up?"
Well, I never realized you considered
me such a failure as a mother.
I don't consider
you a failure. I just...
I never knew that
there was an alternative.
Mmm.
I think she feels wet.
Can you hold her a sec?
I'm gonna grab a diaper.
Okay.
Mom, something's wrong.
Oh! Nurse!
She's bleeding again!
All right, she's in
her office. Move fast.
You see a double-wide tuchus
coming this way, you scream like a girl.
If Rachel wakes up, she's
gonna tell Cuddy everything.
She's two.
Last night she was whining about the
giant moose that lives outside her window.
Medusa at six o'clock.
Don't look back. Move, move.
Hello.
I'm the friendly moose who
lives outside your bedroom.
She hates that moose.
Hand me the gel.
Okay.
Make it short. And
do not pardon the pun.
She's crashing
again. Where are you?
Is it actually important that
I understand what you say?
What?
Yeah.
The baby's bleeding again.
I'm shocked. Oh, no,
wait a minute. That's you.
Yes, you're a genius.
The bleeding
means her liver is still
failing. It's not a
vascular malformation...
House, come take a look at this.
Hold that thought.
House, no. I need to...
Just past the ileocecal valve.
It's nothing.
Just an irregularity.
It's a dime.
Or a pocket of air.
Yeah, with FDR's face on it.
That's not a face.
It's a shadow.
House, the thing
is perfectly round.
Move the wand to the side.
Tickles!
That's because I'm
the tickle monster.
Look at that.
We need an X-ray
to be sure. Great.
Just give her an unnecessary
dose of radiation? It's a dime.
House? I know you're
in there. Open the door.
I saw your
extension on the call.
What are you doing down here?
Uh, Wilson's got a
two-year-old with cancer.
She's in a lot of
pain. It's very sad.
He also has an
outstanding bedside manner.
Her liver failure
is getting worse.
You were right. Now what?
The interesting question
is not why she's worse now,
but why she got
better in the first place.
Could've been something we
did that temporarily relieved the...
What'd you put her on again?
After the transfusion, we gave her
steroids, dopamine, and the anti...
Steroids can treat
idiopathic hepatic fibrosis.
Would explain why she
got better, then worse.
But not the multiple
dilated ducts.
House, I need you back in here.
Cancer kid trumps liver kid.
Sorry, confidentiality.
There are rules, you know.
That is a dime.
Looks mobile, it's right
in the middle of the colon.
Prime location for pooping out.
We'll give her some
laxatives to help it on its way.
Sounds to me like someone's
going to get some yummy chocolate.
Chocolate. Yum, yum, yum.
You're gonna make a
great mommy one day.
Thanks for waiting.
Hook the mom up to the
baby. Direct blood transfusion.
And what else?
Nothing else.
It's amazing. She's
pink and healthy again.
Mother's touch.
It's a miracle. Thank you.
A blood transfusion
isn't a cure.
Or a miracle.
Then why does the baby
seem like she's cured?
I have no idea.
Our patient can either go through life
with the world's longest umbilical cord,
or we can discuss the
differential for magic blood.
Baby's O2 sats are holding.
Either you're Dr. Cheng, or
you're early for my mani-pedi.
I thought her expertise could...
Tell us the O2 sats?
I hope you come with
some original ideas.
Either the mom's
blood is special,
which would mean it's
treating something specific,
which means the
baby has a disease.
Or Mom's blood is just blood, and it's
replacing something the baby is missing,
which means the baby
has a simple deficiency.
Given the liver failure,
deficiency of clotting
factors, enzymes,
or vitamins are the most likely.
So let's find out.
Hook the baby up to someone
else's blood and see if she gets better.
Find a donor. I'm O
negative. Universal donor.
Hook yourself up.
Dr. Cheng, hook
me up. Walk with me.
My team seems to have
taken a shine to you.
I like them, too.
I assume you're hanging
around, because you want a job.
That would be a fair assumption.
Well, I'm gonna
have to test you.
Let's say, two-year-old.
Swallowed a coin 20 hours
ago. She's gonna be fine, right?
Any signs of obstruction?
For the purposes of
this quiz, let's say not yet.
I'd give laxatives, although
I wouldn't wait too long.
Her bowel could become ischemic,
or worse, an intussusception.
Define "too long."
Another six hours, max.
By then, her system's clear. If
it's not out, it's not coming out.
And then what do I do?
I mean, what do
you do? It's your test.
I'd go in with a
scope and get it.
Did I pass?
It's not up to me. Talk to Taub.
Men's room?
Turns out toilets are
handy in this situation.
And I felt relatively sure
that Cuddy wouldn't come in.
Oh, Cuddy's been in here.
Seriously? This must be
a terrible place to have...
Is there such a place?
We have six more hours, then we're
going in with a scope and pulling it out.
Scope a two-year-old?
It's dangerous.
And as you keep pointing out, so is
a dime ripping through her intestines.
Cuddy will be home
from work in six hours.
But no big deal. I'll just
scream, "Look over there"
while you quickly shove a
scope up her daughter's rectum.
I could offer to babysit again.
Let her have the night out.
Sure, that won't
raise any suspicions.
I wish I was nicer.
Give me your
radiation dosimeter.
Why?
Because it matches my eyes.
I think we can say
this isn't working.
We'll get her back on your
blood. That'll help for now.
But this means
there's an infection.
First we need to identify it.
We know it's in her liver,
so we'll get a sample.
Then we can figure out
how to help her get better.
I had this baby because I wanted
a chance to be a special mom,
but not this way.
Problems in radiology.
A radiation dosimeter
badge turned positive.
I could have a CT scanner that's leaking,
or a spilled vial of thallium somewhere.
I don't even know
whose badge it was.
The code was scratched off.
That had to be intentional, I
mean, why would anyone...
I don't know. All I know is that
I'm gonna need to work late.
I was actually hoping
that you could babysit.
No. Not two nights
in a row. Please.
Please?
I have a life, you know?
I will make it worth your while.
I am not going to
bargain babysitting for sex.
Who the hell said that?
Of course I will. Thank you.
That thing's nearly
as big as she is.
Don't worry. I've done
this at least once before.
Advance another
centimeter, and you're in.
God, that looks awful.
Is that from the infection?
No.
Means we were wrong.
It's a melanoma.
You mean like skin cancer?
How did she get that?
She's never been outside.
But you have.
You're saying I gave
my baby cancer?
I found a mole under the
nail on her left index finger.
The biopsy revealed
it's melanoma.
That's it?
And how come no one got me food?
What do you mean, "That's it?"
The woman has melanoma,
she could die if we don't...
Boring.
Since the baby has a melanoma,
we kind of already knew Mom had it.
Yes, but now we
know where it is,
so we can treat it much
more effectively, so...
Great. So treat her.
Also boring.
What's interesting is that Mom's
melanoma spread to the baby in utero,
which means it's metastatic,
which means it's late stage.
How many people with late-stage
melanoma are as healthy as she is?
Clearly something's
going on in Mom's blood
that's treating her melanoma
as well as her baby's.
Antibodies.
If her immune system
was fighting the melanoma,
it never would have spread.
Exactly, which means
it's fighting something else.
And the melanoma cells are
getting caught in the crossfire.
So what's Mom's immune
system really shooting at?
Scleroderma can cause
cancer-fighting antibodies.
So can Churg-Strauss, pretty
much any auto-immune disease.
Or infections that cause
granulomas, TB, mycobacteria.
See, Dr. Cheng?
This is not boring.
Start with auto-immune.
Go test her blood.
And leave your food.
Just a little pinch.
So I'm not actually making
her better, I'm making her sick.
You can't blame yourself.
I ate all the right foods, I read
all the books and the studies.
And I even hired a private detective
to research each sperm donor.
I just missed one big
thing, my own cancer.
I'm all done here. We'll
have the results soon.
And if that's what this is?
An auto-immune disease?
The treatment's fairly simple.
And if it's something else?
Let's just take this
one step at a time.
And stop beating yourself up.
I'm sorry, Mom.
Not just for this. But
for what I said earlier.
I was jealous and
angry and I lashed out.
You were a great mom.
You are a great mom.
I don't deserve such
a good daughter.
Negative for scleroderma.
So, what did House want earlier?
He just gave me a little quiz.
Then said he was
okay with hiring me.
But that it was your decision.
Negative for dermatomyositis.
He's just saying
that to set me up.
So, you're not
offering me the job?
If he wants me to offer you
the job, something's going on.
That was my thinking, too.
It's not lupus.
Things with House are
never as simple as they seem.
Trust me, he's got
an ulterior motive,
and I gotta figure it
out before I do anything.
Okay.
Mom's negative for Churg-Strauss.
This isn't auto-immune.
Time to scan her for infections
that could cause granulomas.
Third poop in
the last half-hour,
still nothing.
All right, that's it.
Time's up. Operation
Valkyrie is now in effect.
Either it's a trap or
it's not. Just hire her.
Lungs clear for granulomas.
Yeah, who cares?
Did you enjoy that bear trap
snapping on your leg yesterday?
You realize it's just
a metaphorical trap.
You'll still have
all your limbs.
Fourth rib, about the
mid-clavicular line.
You're over-thinking this.
House fired my
pick sight unseen.
He was never even
interested in Chase's pick,
he was only obsessed with
how she reflected on Chase.
Dr. Cheng is the only candidate
he's actually responded to.
You wanted House
invested. He is. Hire her.
And you think I'm
over-thinking this?
Shut up and hire her.
Look.
Oat cell lung cancer.
She has two cancers?
Cancer treating cancer.
You have lung cancer.
I thought I had skin cancer.
As unlikely as it
sounds, you have both.
Actually, the lung cancer is
basically treating the skin cancer.
It's why you're
not feeling sick.
And why your blood's
helping your baby.
We found it early, so
it should be treatable.
In a way, your
daughter saved your life.
We'll get you set up for the
surgery and start you on chemo.
What about Kayla?
She'll only need the chemo.
Can't you just keep
giving her my blood?
Not once we cut out the tumor.
Your body will stop making the antibodies
that are keeping your baby healthy.
Can you hold off on my surgery?
Over the last day, your baby's
liver tumors have shrunk 15%.
Projecting forward, it
would take eight or nine days
to completely eradicate
her cancer cells.
So let's take the
eight or nine days...
The cancer probably won't spread in the
next nine days, but there are other risks.
Cancer thickens your blood,
which could cause clots...
And what are the risks to
putting my baby on chemo?
It could damage her brain,
or affect her development.
But these risks are small compared
to the risks that you would be taking
by leaving your
cancers untreated.
I want to wait. Mom,
are you listening?
This is way too dangerous.
I'll take the risks. I want
what's best for my daughter.
I'm your daughter, too.
She's a baby. You're an adult.
So, what? I don't need
my mom anymore?
No. You never did. Because
I wasn't there for you.
But look at you.
You turned out great.
You don't know if I'm great.
You don't know me at all.
And I'm not gonna let you martyr
yourself for a two-day-old infant
just because you feel guilty,
because you weren't around for me.
I'm not martyring
myself. It's nine days.
Let's hold off on the surgery.
You brought food?
This is a medical
procedure, not a dinner date.
I'm aware that this is
a delicate procedure.
I'm also aware that my hands
are shaking from low blood sugar
because I haven't eaten all day.
So while this may seem insensitive,
this crucial lifesaving moo shu...
Where are my extra pancakes?
Damn it. They forgot the extra
pancakes in my moo shu pork.
Every time that new girl with the blue
streaks in her hair answers the phone,
they screw up.
Was she there when
you picked up the food?
You ordered extra pancakes?
How much do they cost?
55 cents. I ordered two.
So that means the
total on the last bill was...
Was...
$18.42. $18.42.
Rachel couldn't have eaten a dime,
because there was no extra dime.
Yeah.
So, the image that we
saw on the ultrasound...
Was obviously just a pocket
of air like I said all along.
But you saw the
worst-case scenario,
like every irrational,
worried parent.
You'd make a terrible mommy.
Throw me some dumplings.
Mom, I brought you some...
Mom?
Mom!
We need help in here!
Somebody help us!
Massive pulmonary
embolism. She died in seconds.
Wouldn't have happened if
she'd let us remove the tumor.
Probably not.
Post-mortem, we were able
to harvest all of her blood.
It's enough to treat the baby.
That's something.
Pretty amazing case.
Thanks for your help.
I was glad for the
chance to work it with you.
I've thought about it,
and I'd like to formally
offer you the job.
It's funny. I wanted to
work on House's team
until I started
working with his team.
Yeah, I know. Chase and
Foreman can get a little...
Actually, it's you.
I get that House is an
ass, but at least he owns it.
You don't understand. This whole
thing was just a game to House.
I didn't have a choice, but...
You're a grown man, Dr. Taub.
You can make whatever
choices you want.
And instead of hiring me
when he said you could,
you chose to act like a
paranoid, scared little kid.
I hate kids.
Goodbye, Dr. Taub.
I'll make sure you
never forget her.
And what she did for you.
She was just trying to be
the best mom in the world.
She was.
This one's all yours.
What happened to helping out?
I did.
Did someone go poopy?
RACHEL: Mmm-hmm.
What... How did you eat a dime?
House.