All right, okay.
Uh, coming.
Morning.
Hey.
Almost ready to go?
Getting there.
Emily's still in the bathroom.
She's gonna make
us late again.
Ethan, hold on.
Em!
Hey!
Em, hurry up!
Can I just have, like,
20 more minutes, please?
We have to get to work.
Look, I'm covered in spit up.
I haven't showered in days.
I'm...
Look, I'm so exhausted.
Okay, Em,
take your time.
You're going to visit
Bernie, right?
Yeah.
We'll take Vincent
and meet you at the hospital.
Thank you so much, April.
Don't say it. I know.
Take Vincent so I can
finish getting ready.
Thank you. All right.
I saw that they
just put Sophie's surgery
on the schedule.
How's Phillip holding up?
Ah, he's trying
to stay positive.
He's looking forward
to being on the other
side of it, though.
Oh, yeah.
In other news,
a little birdie told me
it was your birthday today.
Oh, yeah? Did that
little birdie happen
to have long, dark hair?
Don't look at me.
I never reveal my sources.
Mmm-hmm.
So any plans tonight?
No, just dinner with Robin.
So you and Robin have been
spending some time together.
You thinking about rekindling?
Wow. You are just
brimming with curiosity
today, aren't you?
Mmm-hmm.
Maggie.
You want me
to turn the air on?
No, I'm fine, I'm fine.
I always run hot.
Well, you got through
the polar vortex.
And now you just have
the sweltering Chicago summer
to look forward to.
I'm gonna skip town
before that heat wave hits.
What, you going
on some cruise
I don't know about?
Actually, I'm...
I'm headed back
to Minneapolis.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
What, for the weekend?
Umm...
I was gonna
fill you in later.
Hamline made me an offer
I couldn't refuse
to go back and teach,
so I'm going to tie up
some loose ends here
and then head back in a week.
Well... Well, what about...
What about the trial?
What about
your clinical trial?
They're gonna let me continue
my treatment back home.
It's good.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Guess it'll be good to sleep
in your own bed again.
Yeah, yeah.
And you know what?
I'm gonna get in that
claw-foot tub you tried
to fight me for.
You offered that woman
ten dollars more than I paid.
You ain't right.
That's a great tub.
Your echo report looks good.
You're gonna have to
continue cardiac rehab
for a couple of weeks.
But best guess,
you're going home tomorrow.
Well, thank God.
'Cause that chef
can't make a poached egg
to save his life.
All the money
I'm spending here,
this place should be
Michelin starred.
Look, Dad, I've gotta run,
but I'll be back to
check in later.
Hey, before you go...
Happy birthday.
Shocked I remembered?
Yeah, frankly.
Well, I will admit
that I almost forgot.
But Carlotta was cleaning out
the attic a few weeks ago
and she found your
old Ninja Turtle mask...
From my seventh birthday?
Yes.
Wow, yeah.
Mom made that Donatello
birthday cake from scratch.
She planned every detail.
You mean your nanny.
No, I mean Mom.
Mom was having
a depressive episode.
She'd been in bed for weeks.
That's not how I remember it.
That doesn't surprise me.
Now, what is that
supposed to mean?
You always paint me
as the absentee father
and your mother as the saint,
and I'm telling you
your nanny planned the party,
I paid for it,
and your mom never came.
Why do you feel the need
to disparage her?
I'm not disparaging her.
Yes, you are.
No, I'm not!
You do this every time.
I'll... I'll come back later.
No, you stay. I'm leaving.
Need some help out here.
Got a patient down.
Get a gurney out there.
She's seizing.
She looks like
she's full term.
Must be eclamptic.
Lucy, get me ten grams
of magnesium.
On it.
Name's Desiree Parker.
She had just signed in.
Husband went to park the car.
Desiree, I'm Dr. Manning.
Can you tell me where you are?
What? What?
You're in a hospital.
You just had a seizure.
Let's get her
on the backboard.
Yes, Doctor.
Gonna get you into the ER.
All right, let's lift her
on my count.
Ready? One, two, three.
All right.
She's seizing again.
Lucy!
Excuse us.
Injecting magnesium.
The magnesium isn't working.
Get her
two milligrams of Ativan IM.
Let's check her vitals
and get her some oxygen.
Well, there's the fetus
but she's not even close
to full term.
Maybe 20, 21 weeks.
But she's so big.
Whoa, that's all free fluid.
Maybe she's cirrhotic.
No, no, she has cancer.
My wife.
She has ovarian cancer.
Stage four.
Thanks.
What is it? What's wrong?
Honey.
It's okay.
Desi, your CT scan
shows that your cancer
has metastasized
to your brain.
Oh, God.
There's a large tumor
on your right temporal lobe.
That's what
caused your seizure.
I knew the risk I was taking
when I decided against
treatment.
Yeah, we, um...
Got the diagnosis
when we were three months
along with the pregnancy.
With Elijah.
That's his name.
I was already stage four.
It was highly unlikely that
treatment would be successful.
Unlikely, not impossible.
I didn't want any
interventions that could
harm the baby.
What are our options?
Well, given the size
and location of the tumor,
a craniotomy
is recommended to resect it.
Brain surgery?
That could hurt Elijah, right?
Well, they would take
every precaution,
but, yes, general anesthesia
does pose a small risk
for the fetus.
Then, no, I won't do it.
Desi, we agreed
not to take treatment
off the table completely,
especially as
circumstances evolve.
Could you give us some time
to discuss it?
Of course.
Getting dolled up.
Where you headed?
Having breakfast
with my sister.
Oh, Denise is in town?
Mmm-hmm.
Third time this month.
Little sneak's been
dating someone
in Streeterville.
Finally agreed to make
the introductions.
Does she...
Never mind.
No, spit it out.
Probably a dumb question,
but does she date
men or women?
Oh, Will.
Every trans woman
is different.
But Denise dates men.
Speaking of... Denise!
Look at you! You look awesome!
Stop it. Hey, Will.
Hi.
I'm serious.
She isn't lying.
Well, if I look good,
I owe it to Trevor.
We've been
on a low-carb kick.
Oh, no, you can thank
your folks for that.
I see good genes
run in the family.
Okay.
He's a keeper.
Trevor, this is Will Halstead.
Nice to meet you.
I got you covered. Have fun.
Thank you. Well, come on.
Yeah, good luck, man.
You're gonna need it
with those two.
Okay.
Ow.
Matt Jacobson,
14-year-old male.
Fell attempting
a skateboard trick.
It hurts!
Complaining of pain
to the left forearm.
Vitals stable.
All right.
You notify his parents?
Dad's right behind us.
Keep breathing, kid.
I know that it hurts.
Just try to keep breathing.
He was screaming his
head off the whole way here.
All right.
On my count. One, two, three.
Thank you, you guys.
Hey, Matt, did you put
your arms out in front
of you to break your fall?
I can't remember. Ow!
All right, easy there.
Breath sounds are normal.
Dad, did you see
what happened?
No, I was in the house.
I got to him as quick
as I could.
But I don't move so fast.
Yeah.
All right, Matt,
can you move your head for me?
My arm hurts so bad.
All right, just touch your
chin to your chest, then.
Make it stop hurting, please!
He's too distracted
to clear the C-spine.
Let's take care of his pain
and then we'll reassess.
Monique, get a line in
and give four of morphine.
No, no, no, I hate needles.
Can't you give me pills?
They're gonna take
a lot longer to work, bud.
I don't want a needle.
Just give him a pill. Please.
All right, fine.
Give 7.5 hydrocodone.
Once the pain subsides,
we'll do a chest x-ray,
AP and lateral x-rays
of both arms.
Be right back, okay?
It hurts.
Dr. Rhodes, you smell
alcohol on dad's breath?
Oh, yeah. He reeked of it.
It hurts!
Hey.
Just the lady
I was looking for.
Uh-oh. What's up?
You still friendly
with the chairman
of the anthropology department
at University of Chicago?
Yes, I just saw him
last weekend at a fundraiser
for the Boys
& Girls Club. Why?
Well, you know, they've been
trying to recruit CeCe
for years.
And I was just thinking...
Daniel.
What? Oh, come on.
They would jump
at the opportunity
to have her on the faculty.
And let's face it,
she should stay in Chicago
and stick with the same
medical team.
Why don't you just
tell her how you feel?
Do you have the number?
All right.
Send it to me.
Sent.
Thank you.
Emily should be here soon.
I'll hang
with him till then.
All right, I can take him.
He's still sleeping.
I got it.
Thank you.
Hey.
You got a pep in your step.
Trevor knock it out
of the park?
The guy's a prince.
I can't believe Denise
kept him hidden for so long.
Poor thing was so nervous,
she didn't eat a bite.
Well, maybe she was
worried her big sister
wouldn't approve.
I mean, you can be a little
judgmental at times.
I think you mean discerning.
Whatever. Where are you
going, anyway?
Forgot my phone in the car.
Be back in a sec.
All right.
Hey!
Denise!
Hey, Denise.
You all right?
I'm fine, really.
Your lip's bleeding.
Let me...
I said I'm fine.
I just need to call
me an Uber.
Listen, why don't
you come inside?
Let me
check you out properly.
Looks like you're
banged up pretty good.
I'm not coming inside, Will.
And you can't mention
this to Maggie. Promise me.
I won't mention it to Maggie.
But you gotta let me
examine you.
I don't...
Denise?
Whoa!
Denise.
Denise?
Denise? Oh, my God.
What happened?
She fainted.
Where? How?
And where's Trevor?
He had to, um...
I'll let her fill you in
when she's feeling better.
Is treatment four open?
Okay. Here, this way.
All right.
Given the kid's
description of what happened,
I'd expect a Colles
or Smith fracture.
But this is not
a fracture from a fall.
And with the bruising pattern,
I'd say he was struck
with something.
Like a cane.
You think his father did this?
I think there's
a strong possibility, yeah.
It's odd, though,
that he brought his son in.
I mean, usually they try
to hide the abuse
or delay seeking medical
treatment.
There's something off here,
Miss Goodwin. I know it.
Okay.
Pull social work in to do
an evaluation and have them
check for any pending
or prior claims of abuse,
but let's wait to involve DCFS
until we're absolutely sure.
Of course. Thank you.
All right.
Dr. Rhodes, Matt's requesting
more meds for the pain.
Really? Oh, come on.
That kid is 120 pounds
soaking wet.
He's had two tabs
of hydrocodone.
He should be high as a kite.
Do me a favor.
Get a new urine sample
and run a tox.
On it.
Caleb, I was just
headed to you.
Have you and Desi made
a decision about surgery?
Not exactly. Can we...
Sure.
My wife and I, we agreed
that if the cancer
progressed quickly
that she would reconsider
treatment.
The tumor in her brain,
it could be impairing
her judgment, right?
Yes, it's a possibility,
but...
So maybe she can't
make this decision.
Caleb, I understand that
you're overwhelmed,
but Desi did appear to have
all of her faculties...
Hey, I know my wife.
She's not thinking clearly.
I'm telling you.
Okay, I will have the head of
psychiatry evaluate Desi.
Thank you.
You said she fainted.
What happened to her face?
Her lip is busted.
It looks like she got hit.
I told you you're gonna have
to talk to your sister.
Wait. Did Trevor do this?
So this is why you didn't
want us to meet.
You told her?
He didn't have to.
How long has Trevor been
putting his hands on you?
He hasn't. He just lost
his temper today.
It's my fault. I was
pushing his buttons.
We have to call the cops.
Don't!
Say anything and I'll deny it.
Why? What is wrong
with you, Denise?
No, I don't expect you
to understand, okay?
Look, Trevor
may not be perfect,
but at least
he loves me for me.
Loves you? This man
doesn't love you.
He preys on you.
He preys on you
because he can.
Mags, let me talk to you.
Look at your face!
Come on. Let's go.
Denise, sit tight. I'm gonna
have plastics come take
a look at that lip.
What?
Just listen.
You shoot from the hip
and we all love
that about you,
but maybe try
a softer approach.
Sometimes the truth hurts.
What's going on?
I couldn't find Emily.
She wasn't in Bernie's room.
He said she hasn't
come by yet.
I'll call her.
I did already.
She didn't pick up.
I left a voicemail.
She had a really rough night
with Vincent.
I don't think she slept
more than an hour.
I know it's a lot.
I just hope she's not falling
back to her old ways.
Well, she's made a lot of
strides these last few months.
Let's try to give her
the benefit of the doubt.
All right.
I'll run Vincent down
to the daycare center,
see if they have
room for him.
Okay.
Hi, buddy. Hello.
Hey, Desi.
How are you feeling?
Okay. Just a bit,
um, drowsy.
That's from the Ativan.
Should wear off soon.
In the meantime, I wanted to
introduce you to Dr. Charles.
He's our head of psychiatry.
Psychiatrist. Why?
Desiree, I just wanna ask you
a couple of quick questions
if that's okay.
You can... Me... Desi.
I'm sorry?
Call me...
Bag her.
Desi!
What's going on?
Let's give them
some room.
Her right pupil is dilated
and sluggish.
I need to tube her
and send her to CT stat.
I suspect edema.
It's a swelling in the brain.
20 of etomidate, 100 of sux.
Do the surgery!
Mr. Parker...
I'm her surrogate
decision maker.
I said do it. Now!
Where are the pills?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Did you take them already?
Just tell me.
Where are the pills?
Hey, hey.
What's going on in here?
Guy abused his son
and came here
to score opioids.
Are you insane?
I ran a tox on Matt.
He hasn't taken any
of the pills we've given him.
Meanwhile, I search
the Illinois Prescription
Database.
Turns out Mr. Jacobson
here has been flagged
as a frequent flier.
I swear to God I didn't lay
a hand on my son.
And I sure as hell didn't
take his pain meds!
Take a drug test
to prove it, then.
I don't have to prove
anything to you!
All right, look,
I have a better idea.
Why don't we all go speak
with Matt, all right?
Please.
I took the pills.
Dr. Rhodes ran
a tox screen, Matt.
They're not in your system.
So? Maybe the test was wrong.
We're going around in circles,
Miss Goodwin.
That's it. I'm calling Child
Protective Services.
No. No, my dad
never touched me.
Please don't call them.
They're right here.
Fine, he told
him to pocket 'em.
Dr. Rhodes.
How did you hurt
yourself today, Matt?
Did you really fall off
your skateboard?
Son. Just tell us the truth.
You won't get in trouble.
I slammed my arm in the door.
On purpose?
I'm so sorry, Dad.
I'm so sorry.
I just wanted to help you.
I got into
an awful car wreck
about ten years ago.
My back's been a mess
ever since.
Doc had me on Oxy,
which was working pretty well,
but then some new
government guidelines,
something came out.
Yes, the CDC introduced new
prescribing recommendations.
A response to
the opioid crisis.
With opioids, there is always
the concern with, um,
overdose or misuse.
Yeah, well, I wasn't misusing.
Hit up just about
every doctor in the city.
But no one would write me
a new prescription.
And how are you currently
managing your pain?
Drinking, mostly.
I thought I did
a better job hiding it.
But, God, I can't believe
he'd personally harm himself
to try and get me pills.
Well, Mr. Jacobson,
I'll give you the contact
information of a general
practitioner in Schaumburg.
I'm confident he'll be
able to help you.
I appreciate it.
Sure.
Mr. Jacobson,
for what it's worth,
I am very, very sorry.
I apologize, Miss Goodwin.
I just... I...
I can't believe that
I was so off base.
Well, I appreciate
your intent, Dr. Rhodes.
But next time just
ask more questions
before you start accusing.
Well, Denise,
your blood sugar's pretty low.
I suspect that's what
caused you to faint.
'Cause you haven't been
eating enough.
Thanks to Trevor. Am I right?
What, he told you
to lose weight?
Just lay off, okay?
I'm gonna have a nurse
put an IV in.
Give you some fluids and bring
you a glass of orange juice.
Fine, but can I leave
after that, please?
Yeah, that should do it.
I'll send the nurse in now.
My sister needs protection
from that monster.
I want you to report what you
saw today to the police and...
Maggie, I can't do that.
Excuse me?
Look, I want to see
that prick behind bars, too.
But what if she's not ready
to leave him?
Which I don't think she is.
I think Denise will be
better off if we convince
her to report it herself
and walk away.
My sister won't do that!
But I got an idea.
Grab your coat
and meet me out front.
Daniel, do you believe
Mrs. Parker lacked
the capacity to refuse
brain surgery?
I never got a chance
to evaluate her.
But a tumor in that area
certainly has the potential
to affect reasoning,
understanding...
Desi has been consistent
in her refusal of treatment
since her initial diagnosis.
She also agreed to consider
additional treatment
if the disease progressed.
Well, is there any written
record explicitly stating
her wishes?
Just the advanced directive.
Which clearly establishes
her husband
as her surrogate
decision maker.
This isn't right.
Her husband is taking
advantage of the situation.
But doesn't the fact that she
granted him power
of attorney in the first place
demonstrate a bond of trust?
A bond that he is breaking
by completely disregarding
her wishes.
If we operate and anything
happens to the fetus...
I'm sorry, Dr. Manning,
but the advanced
directive stands.
Will you guys
excuse me really quick?
I will be right back, sorry.
Maggie! Hey, beautiful.
What do I owe the pleasure?
Don't you touch me.
Come near my sister again,
respond to a text,
answer a phone call,
and I will call the cops.
I don't know
what she told you,
but you know your sister.
She's a drama queen.
Don't you try me.
That's what you came
down here for?
Warn me to stay away?
That's right.
What's it gonna be?
Could have saved
yourselves a trip.
I was done with that
freak anyways.
You better back up...
Go ahead.
Take your shot.
Connor!
Hi, Carlotta.
Hi. Come inside.
Thank you.
Is this what
you're looking for?
Yeah, that's it. Thank you.
Hmm.
Carlotta, are there
any other albums
between '88 and '94?
Don't see any. Why?
Well, there's hardly
any pictures of my mom.
Your poor mother.
So much of the time
she wasn't feeling herself.
Hey, baby.
Call me back.
I didn't mean to...
Denise.
If you're here to lecture me,
you can save your breath.
I already signed
my discharge papers.
Trevor's not gonna pick up.
How do you know?
I went to talk to him.
You what?
You won't be hearing from him.
No, no. Trevor wouldn't...
He wouldn't run scared.
You're lying.
I told him I knew
about his abuse.
And I was never gonna
let him hurt you again.
You had no right.
Denise...
What did he say?
He said...
He said you meant
a lot to him.
He was really upset.
Devastated.
But I gave him no choice.
I told him that if he ever
spoke to you again,
I was gonna call the cops.
You stay out
of my life, Maggie.
Denise...
CeCe. Hey.
How did everything go
with your check up?
Good. Good, good.
Great. Listen.
Are you doing
anything tonight?
Do you have any plans?
No.
'Cause I am having dinner
with the head
of the anthropology
department at U of C.
Okay.
There's a position
opening up next semester.
So what's that
got to do with me?
Well, I just thought you'd
like to join us because
the position sounds great.
I mean, two classes
a semester, sabbatical
every three years,
you could...
You could write your book.
I already have
a position at Hamline.
I know, but this way
you could...
You could stay in Chicago.
You could keep working
with Dr. Singh.
Maybe I don't want to
stay in Chicago.
Have you ever thought of that?
Damn, Danny.
Sometimes you don't
know when to quit.
Can you heat up his bottle?
It's on the top shelf
in the fridge.
You got it.
Ethan? Come here.
All of Emily's clothes
are gone.
So is her suitcase.
Dr. Charles?
You know where
Dr. Manning is?
I think she's
with another patient.
But they should be
coming to prep Desi
for surgery very soon.
No, no, it's not that.
Without the operation, Desi's
never gonna wake up, is she?
It's unlikely.
So she'd lose the baby, right?
Well, not necessarily.
Plan would be to continue
to treat the swelling
in her brain with steroids
which should allow her
to remain on the ventilator
long enough
to deliver via C-section
once the fetus
becomes viable in a few weeks.
You mean she'd become
one human incubator.
You know, that's not
the term that I would use.
But, um...
I know what she would
want me to do.
I just, uh...
You're terrified.
Desi and I were
just kids when we met.
Freshman year of college.
You know, we've really
grown up together.
You know, we've seen each
other through everything and
she knows me
better than anyone.
Yeah.
And you know her
better than anyone.
Which is why she trusted you
to become her voice
when she was no longer able
to speak for herself.
And, Caleb, look.
Letting go of someone that
you love when every instinct
is telling you
to hold on, to fight,
I mean, it's the hardest thing
in the world.
But Desi knew that you
were up to the task.
Now you just have to
come to believe
that you are, too.
Mags?
Are you okay?
Me and Denise...
We'd just gotten close again.
And now...
I probably lost her for good.
Clear!
Dad?
Epi.
Charge again to 200.
What happened?
We don't know. He flipped into
V-fib. Might have had an MI.
Charging. Charged.
Clear.
Epi, charge to 200.
I'm taking over.
Charged.
Clear.
Asystole.
Epi.
Meds are in.
Come on!
Come on, Dad! Come on!
Connor, he'd already
been down ten minutes
by the time you got here.
Connor.
No!
No.
Time of death, 17:42.
Hi.
We'll be moving Desi
up to pre-op
and Dr. Abrams
will be waiting
for us up there.
No.
I'm sorry?
No surgery.
Can you
give us a moment?
Caleb, are you sure?
Yeah.
The cancer took everything
away from Desi.
But this is the one thing
she was determined
not to let it touch.
She's been so brave.
For me, for Elijah.
The least I can do is try to
have an ounce of her courage.
Em, it's me again.
Call me back.
Took a lot of rocking
but Vincent's finally asleep.
She still not picking up?
No.
I'm gonna talk
to Bernie tomorrow
and let him know Emily's gone.
And after tonight,
I'll keep Vincent at my place
till... Till Bernie's
released.
The baby can stay here.
April, no.
What?
I already know his routine.
Hey.
His stuff is here.
Vincent's not your
responsibility.
It's no problem. Really.
Listen...
I'm not sure how long
this is gonna last.
Even after Bernie's out
of the hospital, the guy...
Guy doesn't have a job.
If Emily doesn't come back,
Vincent may be with me
for the foreseeable future.
With us.
I'm not gonna let you
do this alone.
April...
What?
Anyone else would have
bailed on this whole mess
a long time ago.
But you're still here.
Because it's you, Ethan.
I was coming
to tell my dad that...
He was right.
And that my mother wasn't
at my seventh birthday party.
In fact, she...
She wasn't there
for most of my life.
I turned her into this
doting, perfect mother.
Turns out it was all fiction.
All these years,
I blamed my dad for her death.
I thought that it was his
cheating that drove her
to kill herself.
Hey. Hey.
You were just trying
to make sense of it.
What else am I inventing?
I'll go check on Vincent.
Ethan... Oh, what's going on?
Where have you been?
Look, I'm so sorry.
I was feeling
really overwhelmed
and I kinda freaked out.
You ditched your son.
I know it was really
irresponsible for me
to just take off,
but I only made it
to St. Louis
before turning back.
I couldn't leave Vincent.
Hey, sweetie. It's Mama.
Are you ready
to go for a ride?
Do you know what time it is?
Where are you going?
Back to the hospital
to see Bernie.
ICU's no place for a baby.
It's fine.
No. Vincent's staying here.
Excuse me?
Give me my son.
You can't keep him from me.
No, I'm not keeping
him from you.
But Vincent needs consistency.
Em, this is no kind of life
for Vincent, all right?
You need to come up
with a plan.
All right, all right.
I'll put him back to bed
and stay here tonight.
If that's okay
with you, April.
Yeah, of course.
And in the morning
I'll figure something out.
With or without Bernie.
I promise.
Oh, honey.
Hey. Hey.
Hey.
I wasn't sure that
you were gonna show.
So what's up?
Um...
So that's a really...
That's a good situation
at Hamline.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
Do that. Right?
Yeah.
What's this?
You're resigning from Med.
Caroline, these last
few months with you,
I don't... I don't understand
it. It's crazy.
It's felt...
It's felt like...
Like coming home.
I wanna go with you.
Oh, Danny.
I want to marry you.
Again.
I lied.
There was no...
There was no offer
from Hamline.
They didn't ask me
to come back.
They didn't?
No.
I found out a couple days ago
that my lymphoma
is progressing
and the clinical trial
isn't working
and there's nothing more
they can do.
And I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have lied
about any of that.
I just thought that
it would be better
for everyone if I just left.
I want to be there.
For all of it. All of it.
You know, in sickness
and in health?
If you'll have me.
Please don't make me
get down on one knee.
I don't think I'd ever
be able to get back up.