.
- If you were going to move
to another country,
you wouldn't tell me
at a party, right?
- You still upset?
- Not that they're together.
I mean, that part could not
have taken any longer.
But moving to London?
- What about the hospital?
Max is the glue.
He holds us together.
- New Amsterdam survived
before him.
It'll survive after him.
Plus, they have
a new deputy chair of surgery
who's kicking ass.
- You know he was the first
person there to believe in me?
- You know, I've never said
this out loud before, but...
he's kind of my hero.
- He's not dying.
- Feels like he is.
And Helen--
- She was always there
whenever I needed a friend.
- First Vijay, now this?
What's next, Gladys?
It's oh--God, I can't
even--that's not--
It's too much, too fast.
- What if the new
medical director goes back
to the way it was?
I mean, do I quit?
I just--I don't know.
- Stop talking.
- Yes, ma'am.
- I think I can help.
- How am I gonna survive
five days without you?
- Relax.
They don't need your anxiety,
they need your support.
Just be happy for them.
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Why should they be
the only ones having
exciting new sex, right?
- Right.
- This is the morning song!
Sing along. Come on.
- It's Miss Abigail.
- But is she in the apartment?
- Just on YouTube.
I think we're fine.
I think we have five minutes.
- Let's get this day started
with today is--
- Waffle, waffle, waffle.
- Oh, dear God.
- One sec.
- Waffle, waffle, waffle.
- You want waffles?
Who wants waffles?
- Me.
- You do?
Do you want extra gooey syrup?
I think so.
Let's get some.
♪
- Looking for the six?
- I'm--I'm sorry, what?
- It's all good.
Tourists always get confused,
but this isn't
a subway entrance.
It's actually a hospital.
- You don't say.
- Guessing you already
knew that.
- Well, it was the hundreds of
people walking around in scrubs
that kind of tipped me off.
Do you happen to know where
there's a Dr. Max Goodwin?
- You know what?
He's off campus today.
But I can take you up
to his assistant.
- Oh no need.
No need, Dr.?
- Reynolds.
- Dr. Reynolds.
Besides, I think it best that
Max not be here for this.
- Welcome to the NovaCo
Five-Borough Science Fair.
I'm Ron Elgin, chief
advancement officer for NovaCo.
And I'd like to introduce
our judge for the festivities.
Let's give a warm welcome
to Dr. Max Goodwin.
- Thank you guys.
Thanks for having me.
Thank you to Ron and to NovaCo
for putting this together.
This is amazing.
When I was your age,
I built a can crusher
for my science fair,
and it was not the coolest.
I didn't win, but it did crush
cans like nobody's business.
So I'm very excited to see
what neat things you guys
have come up with.
Let's judge.
- It's about automated
segmentation
for color quantification
in African cichlid fish.
- Interesting.
Question:
should I still be the judge
if the only word I got
there was fish?
- I got a college lab
to let me use
their 3-D printer for accuracy.
- Oh. Good for you.
Looks expensive. Sorry.
Wow, even the old volcano guy
is crushing it.
This is amazing.
Smoke and everything.
Even dinosaurs. Very cool.
- Picking a winner
won't be easy.
- Yeah, what about
a 14-way tie?
Is that a turnip?
- I grew it myself.
- Not the flashiest entry.
- You'll change your mind when
I tell you how this turnip's
gonna fix the world.
- Okay.
Imani Moore, bring it on.
- So this is a smart suture.
It's what most
American hospitals use.
It's coated with sensors that
are like tiny thermometers.
Infection raises temperature,
so when your wound's heat
goes up,
it uses smartphone technology
to alert your doctor.
- We have these
at our hospital.
They're super cool, right?
- Unless you live
in a place where
your doctors can't afford
smartphones.
Then the smart suture's
a dumb piece of thread
that knows you might die
but can't tell anybody.
- Yeah, that does seem
less cool now.
- Suture number two:
no sensors, no thermometers.
Made from a common turnip.
And it knows
if you have an infection
just as fast as the fancy one.
Infection doesn't just change
a wound's temperature.
It also changes its pH.
And the natural pH level
of a turnip-infused suture
will, upon infection,
change color.
So when it does,
you go to the doctor.
See, smart sutures need phones,
high-speed Internet,
1,800 microscopic thermometers.
I just need a root vegetable.
- Imani, this could save lives.
How did you come up with this?
- I'm a first generation
immigrant, Dr. Goodwin.
Surgical site infections
in impoverished countries
are nine times higher
than in America.
That's some ripe you-know-what,
so I'm gonna fix it.
P.S., if I win, I plan to use
the prize money to help pay
for Banneker Medical School,
which would get me a big step
closer to my goal.
- And what is that?
- Like I said,
I'm gonna fix the world.
- Oh.
- Any new life-changing
announcements
I should brace myself for?
- Mm-hmm.
Yeah, I just spent
my first full night at Max's.
And it was eye-opening.
- Okay, if you think I can be
bought off
by salacious gossip...
- The man snores.
I'm on, like,
zero sleep right now.
It's not just the snoring.
He's messy.
He's really messy.
Like, Luna is the clean one.
And he's disorganized.
His place is cramped.
My closet is bigger
than his entire apartment.
- But to be fair, your closet--
it's amazing.
- And to top it all off,
he was out of toilet paper.
I mean, is this my life now?
My God.
- At least you're not freaking
out about the little things.
- I was so busy falling
in love,
I forgot that being
together
actually meant living together.
- Maybe you should dump him.
At least then we get to keep
at least one of you.
It's just a thought.
- Here is your medal
for first place.
And perhaps better yet,
your check for $50,000.
- I can't believe this
is happening.
- It's about to get better.
Follow me.
Ron, I'd like
to introduce you
to the future,
Miss Imani Moore.
- Great project.
Congratulations.
- Thank you.
- And because NovaCo's
underwriting all of this, they
can make your idea a reality.
And New Amsterdam wants in.
We'd like to preorder
$35,000 worth.
How does that sound?
- I gotta call my parents.
- Max, NovaCo already produces
a chemically based
smart suture.
- Yeah, but this is totally
different.
I mean, it uses turnips.
- And after all of the R&D
that went into our sutures,
they'll never cannibalize those
margins with a similar product.
- But you own her concept.
So what are you going
to do with her research?
- To be honest?
Shelve it.
- Shelve it?
- She still won, Max.
It's a great honor.
She should be very proud.
♪
- Dr. Wandy Agliar
in the house.
Look out now.
- Are you always this peppy?
- Yes, I am.
What are you gonna do about it,
huh?
So how's
my star resident today?
What--what are you doing?
You out there mending hearts?
Changing lives?
- Actually I'm only a modernist
on the surface.
Deep down,
I'm really just Jung at heart.
- Oh no you didn't.
Oh, my God.
You know you get extra points
for puns
in this department, right?
- I didn't know there
were points.
- I have a chart in my office.
- You have a point chart?
- Yeah.
Sorry, Gladys, is Dr. Agliar
our powerhouse or what?
- Sorry it's actually about one
of your patients,
Olivia Torres.
- Olivia?
I just saw her yesterday.
- Why?
What happened?
- She committed suicide.
♪
- Tyler Grace, 35, penetrating
gunshot wound to his shoulder.
- Shooting at
a supermarket near 123rd.
The guy had an AR-15.
- You're about to be swamped.
- Okay trauma one, let's pull
Leyla and Roxana to assist.
- On it.
Roxana, Leyla.
- Incoming.
Male, 40s, GSW to the abdomen.
- Walsh.
- On it.
- Go with him.
- Let's go.
- Female, 52, GSW to both legs.
- Okay, keep her moving.
Keep her moving.
- 14-year-old male,
single GSW lower left leg.
- I need the ED cleared.
Let's move him in there.
I need surgery down here now.
♪
- Another shooting?
- We're getting slammed.
- When does it end?
- I need to take this one up
for a CT scan for a CTA.
- Dr. Bloom, we can't get
the patient ventilated.
- You're with me.
♪
What's the problem?
- The bullet--
- The bullet shattered
the scapula, the ribs,
and the clavicle.
- And dropped the lung.
We're having
difficulty oxygenating him.
- Move.
♪
Okay, let's place a chest tube
and get him to the OR.
♪
Floyd, what is it?
- I know him.
.
- So because I won, NovaCo's
just gonna bury my research.
- I know, I know, but hey,
50 grand for med school.
That's a big deal.
- For myself.
How can I feel good about that
when I was trying to foster
global health equity
for millions of others?
- Look, this sucks.
If you're trying to break
the system, you're gonna run
into this feeling a lot.
Trust me.
But ask anyone
who's changed the world.
They'll tell you the same
thing.
You got to be bold.
It's not about
when they say no.
It's about what you
do next.
- Hmm, you're right,
Dr. Goodwin.
- Oh, that's very bold.
I was kind of thinking maybe
you just had another idea.
- I'm in
the world-changing business.
So let's be bold together.
- How can I help?
♪
- Oh!
- Oh, my--Sorry.
Pardon me.
- No, I'm sorry.
Helen, I just heard the news.
London. Wow. Big change.
- Oh, um, yes, well it, um,
it was time.
- Wait, so is
the oncology department
really in that much trouble?
- No, of course not.
The department is fine.
I have to apologize.
Do we know each other?
- No, no, no, no.
I'm the one
who needs to apologize
because you don't know
me from Adam.
- Oh good.
- I know everything
about you, though.
- Excuse me?
- Dr. Helen?
From the telly.
I'm sure it's really bad but--
- Course.
- But I have a question.
I couldn't help
but connect the dots.
So Max is moving to London,
and you're moving to London.
So the two of you--
- Yes.
- Well, that's good.
That's good, then,
that you're both leaving.
- Really?
And why is that?
- Well I mean, because
he's clearly your superior--
at work I mean.
And that could get you into
a lot of trouble with HR, so...
♪
- Excuse me?
I didn't catch your name.
-  Well, the flood of
patients has finally subsided.
We're back under control.
Hey, how did Leyla do
back there?
- This my life now?
Spying
on your girlfriend for you?
- Obviously. Spill it.
- What can I say?
She has excellent technique.
Her experience shows.
- Okay, don't test me, Casey.
I will break you.
Details.
Who ran the trauma?
- Roxana.
- And who attempted
the initial intubation?
- That was also Roxana.
- So Leyla's just gonna
fade back?
Let everyone else shine?
No way.
No, she has to step it up.
- Glad you dating a resident
hasn't made things weird
around here.
- Today was rough.
You know, I remember
losing a patient
my first year
out of med school.
Gabriel Amato.
I still remember
our last session.
Just leveled me
all the way down.
I had to take
an entire week off.
So anyway, I wanted to let
you know that I read
your SOAP notes
from your sessions, and it is
so abundantly clear
that you knew
your patient's
underlying issues
and you were treating
her conditions, all of them.
Wandy, you did--you
did everything right.
- I know.
- Oh you--oh, you do.
- I mean I wrote my thesis on
cognitive behavioral therapy.
- No no, I know.
Yeah, I read it.
I just, um...
Losing a patient is, um--
- Tragic.
- Yeah.
- Yes, but as they say,
you can be the best
cardiologist in the world,
and you'll still lose
some patients to heart attacks.
- Yeah, that's not
the comparison I would make.
- We're clinicians, Dr. Frome.
We're not their friends.
Intellectually, it's a loss,
certainly, but...
I still have a full afternoon
of other patients
who still need my help.
Are we done here?
- Oh, yeah, okay.
Yeah, yeah.
- Thank you.
- No problem.
- Picture it: turnips as far
as the eye can see.
By the way, how many do you
think you're gonna need?
- Around 95,000.
- Wow, okay.
We may have to find
some more balconies.
- And there they are.
- Mom, Dad, this is so cool.
- These are your folks?
Wow I'm Max Goodwin,
medical director.
It is an honor to meet
the people who created this
incredible, passionate,
talented, young woman.
Have you come to
check out her new venture?
- No they're here
because of this,
curtesy
of NovaCo Pharmaceuticals.
Turns out they also heard
about your little venture,
and now they're suing
for breach of contract,
$550 million.
- Wow.
Well, we'll just see what
our legal department has
to say about this.
- They aren't suing
your hospital, Dr. Goodwin.
They're only suing
our daughter.
- Heads up.
Make a hole.
Coming through.
Come on, come on.
Come on.
- Patient with a GSW
to the right thorax.
Here for a thoracotomy
with a subsequent
vascular and chest wall
reconstruction.
- We're gonna lift on three.
Ready. One, two, three.
Wait, this--this--
- Dr. Reynolds,
when you're done scrubbing in,
we'll be ready to go.
- Yeah.
.
- They have a strong case.
- This morning, our daughter
was valedictorian.
She won the biggest
science fair in the state
with a cash prize that would
help pay for med school.
And then you encourage a child
to throw her life away.
- I'm not a child.
And if NovaCo wants to sue,
let's go to court.
- You're not going anywhere.
You're grounded.
- What I'd give to be able
to ground you, too.
- I'm sure you would. Listen,
we're gonna figure this out.
Okay? I can call
Banneker Med School right now.
I promise you
they're not gonna care
about some ridiculous lawsuit.
- Dr. Goodwin, NovaCo's
on the board at Banekker.
- Really?
Wish I had that information
before I said that.
Um--
There are a lot of
other great schools.
And NovaCo's on the board
of just about all of them.
They're gonna make sure our
daughter
never gets in anywhere.
She's not
from generational wealth.
This was her shot.
This.
- All I can say is that
until I make this right,
I'm gonna be by
your daughter's side.
- No, you'll be by her side
for the next five weeks,
and then you're leaving
the country.
We do business with NovaCo.
I know their top people.
I can get them to back off,
but only if Imani agrees
to leave her turnip sutures
back at the science fair.
Let it go.
- She will.
Thank you.
- Hold up.
Dad, I'm 18.
This is my decision.
This is my life.
Look, making the world better's
hard but I learned it's not
about when they say no.
It's about what you do next.
Whatever you think I should do
next, Dr. G, I'll do it.
♪
- I hope you don't think
I'm being too forward.
- I do not. I'm glad
you're speaking right now.
I hate elevator silence more
than anything in the world.
- You're Dr. Ignatius Frome,
chair of behavioral health,
right?
- Yeah, yeah.
So much for being incognito.
- Um, I couldn't help
but notice that
your nurse-to-patient ratio
on your ward
is very disconcerting.
- Yeah, it is.
I know, right?
But, I'm sorry,
what's your name?
I didn't catch it.
- 13-to-1 ratio, to be exact.
- You counted.
- I did, yeah.
Unfortunately, those numbers
puts your department
at the bottom of most
of the New York State
public hospitals.
So...
- Yeah. Why--
Yeah, you know,
I've written HCC,
and I've petitioned the board,
and at this point
I would do anything to get them
to take me seriously.
- Anything?
- Yeah.
Yeah, anything within reason,
you know.
Well, you know, I used
to work at this hospital
that, for legal reasons,
I can't really name.
But we had
the exact same nursing shortage
on our psych ward,
and we fixed it overnight.
- Overnight?
How did you find the nurses?
- Oh, no, we didn't.
We cut the patients.
Oh, this is me.
Very nice to meet you.
- Yeah, yeah, you too.
Take care.
- You, too.
- You paged me?
- What?
Yes. Yeah I did.
Um, I need you--I need you
to reassign
all of Wandy's cases.
Clear the decks.
- All of them?
- Yes. Do it, please.
Thank you.
- Hey.
- Why you letting
the other residents
take the lead
on every procedure?
- Are you spying on me?
- You are the most
skilled resident in my ED,
but you don't act like it.
It's like you're stepping up
to the plate
and you're gonna
strike out looking.
Okay, you gotta take some cuts.
Give the ball a ride.
- Is that basketball?
- Baseball.
- Hmm.
- Never mind.
Look, I was like Roxana
when I was a resident.
Cutthroat, driven.
She's gonna take
every advantage she can,
which is why you need
to show everyone
just how capable you are.
I mean, where's
the woman who pulled off
a renegade
needle decompression?
Where's the woman who pinned me
down in bed this morning?
- She's right here.
- Well, then show them.
Stop keeping how amazing
you are all to yourself.
- Okay.
Okay, I will.
I will ride the ball
or whatever.
- Maybe you're more
of a hockey person.
- We assume you've come
to comply with our demands.
Sign this,
and the suture matter
will be settled.
- No, thank you.
- So you're choosing a trial
against the fourth largest
pharmaceutical company
in the country?
- No, absolutely not.
That sounds terrifying.
No, we'd like
door number three.
That's the one
where we don't fight
because we're working together.
You could sue this 18-year-old
girl for half a billion dollars
that she doesn't have,
or you could walk out of here
with a vast,
new, untapped market:
the entire developing world.
Think about it.
There are over 100 countries
that can't afford
your smart sutures,
but they can afford turnips.
You can improve health care
for half the planet
and turn a profit
while doing it.
I don't know how you could
say no to that.
- We'll see you in court.
- Wait, wait, wait.
Um, don't do this.
This could change the world.
- And this is the clause
in the science fair application
which states that NovaCo owns
the winner's IP.
We can sell it, sit on it,
we can put it in a cookbook.
And that's Imani's signature.
Next time, read the fine print.
- Bullet's out.
- Blood pressure's
dropping.
- Bleeder?
- I don't see it.
- Well, it must be
something else.
- Myocardial infarction?
- I was thinking
adrenal crisis.
- Could be a
renal--There, look.
Piece of the bone fragment
from the scapula must have
penetrated the diaphragm
and lodged into the abdomen.
- Like a small dagger.
- Yeah.
- Hang a unit of blood.
- And push calcium chloride
to help the clotting.
Wait, stop.
- Would you rather go with TXA?
- Sorry, no. No, no, no.
Just, um--
Push the calcium chloride.
Sorry.
- Okay. I'm gonna go and
grab Dr. Hartman to assist.
.
- Not now.
- It's important.
- Like your love
of kickboxing important
or like a patient is coding
important?
- If I'm forced to choose,
somewhere right in the middle.
That woman has been
hanging around
our ED for the last half hour.
- She with a patient?
- Nope, just walking around,
taking notes
like that dude in "Moneyball."
- Hey.
You.
What the hell you doing here?
You know what?
I don't even care. Okay?
You're a walking
HIPPA violation, and maybe
you've been living
on a desert island or a--
I don't know--the
International Space Station?
But, uh, here on Earth,
we've been dealing
with a mass global pandemic,
so we don't really take
too kindly to strangers just
hanging around
the emergency department
of a public hospital.
So take your failed screenplay,
or whatever the hell it is
you're writing, and, uh,
get the hell out of here
before I have my bouncers
throw you out.
- You must be Dr. Bloom.
♪
- Thank you.
- When were you going
to tell me?
- Uh, Karen, listen--
- Were you waiting to give
a pedestrian two weeks' notice
or just shoot me an email
when you and Max
were somewhere over
the Atlantic?
- I wanted to tell you,
but it was never 100%.
- So instead you just
blindsided me
in front of the whole hospital.
- That was selfish.
- Damn right, it was selfish.
And incredibly romantic.
I'd throw flowers at you myself
if I wasn't so pissed.
- Well, if it's
any consolation, I have no idea
how I'm gonna live
with the man.
He is chaos personified.
- A whirling dervish
of unbridled optimism.
Always overreaching
but, more often
than one might expect,
somehow making the world
just a little bit better.
And yet never quite remembering
to cap the toothpaste.
I don't know.
Everything just seems--
it seems so out of control.
- There's a thousand reasons
you two
shouldn't move in together,
and a thousand more
why you shouldn't move
to London.
But only one reason to do
any of it.
So if you're thinking about
how he squeezes the toothpaste
this early on,
maybe it's because
you know it's a mistake.
♪
For what it's worth,
I'll take him off your hands
in a heartbeat.
♪
- So that's it, then?
They win?
It's over?
- Yeah.
Oh, but I did get something.
Might cheer you up.
- What is this?
- One share of NovaCo stock
in your name.
It's worth exactly $17.10.
- Okay?
- You're officially
disqualified from the Five
Borough's Science Fair.
Students are prohibited
from having any kind
of financial relationship
with NovaCo
or its subsidiaries.
You gotta read the fine print.
- So that--that means?
- Volcano guy won.
And you get your idea back.
You get your ide--No?
It's great news.
- Why?
No one's ever gonna buy it.
I could create
50 game-changing innovations,
but no big pharma
company's gonna sign on
to make less money.
How can I fix the world
when the people in charge
want it to stay broken?
- Well, you could,
you know, go rogue.
Do it indie style together.
I mean come on, the roofs
of New Amsterdam are calling.
- Are you really leaving
in five weeks?
- Uh--
Yeah.
- And can you promise me
that the next medical director
will keep my turnip farm going?
- No.
- You know, you taught me
something important,
Dr. Goodwin.
When someone says
they can change the world,
don't listen.
- Cardiogenic shock,
likely anterior wall
myocardial infarction.
- Sending labs including
troponin and paging cardiology.
- Placing central line in case
we need pressors.
- Okay.
- Use ultrasound guidance.
- Don't need it.
- Your patient is hypotensive,
Dr. Shinwari.
That's a tough placement,
you're gonna need it.
- I actually won't.
- Okay, that wasn't
a suggestion.
I said use ultrasound guidance.
- Yes, and I disagreed
with your assessment.
So I'm doing it my way.
- And risk a pneumothorax?
- There's always a risk,
and you know it,
even with ultrasound.
- But it is less of a risk.
We have the technology
for a reason.
Use it.
- You can use it
with your patient, but
I'm not using it with mine.
- Okay, that is it.
Dr. Shinwari, step away
from the patient.
- Quiet.
I need to focus.
- Leyla, this is not what I--
- Got it.
Hand me the introducer.
I trained in Kashmir
when the killing
of a Hizbul Mujahideen militant
caused an uprising,
and we had to learn to do
every procedure in the dark
or during a mortar attack.
So all of this technology,
all of these crutches,
they only get in my way.
♪
- Bone fragment lacerated
multiple arteries.
As soon as I suture one,
another bleeder breaks loose.
Where the hell's my backup?
-  artery.
Not lacerating.
Lin?
What are you doing here?
Where's Hartman?
- Hartman? Why?
I'm here to remove
a bullet fragment
from a patient's uterus.
- What the hell?
♪
- Is something wrong?
- I'm just...
♪
Give me a second.
- You okay, Floyd?
- Sorry, it's just...
Okay, I'm good.
- You benched me?
- Uh, we can discuss
my decision if you calm down.
- I did everything right,
Dr. Frome.
Those were your exact words.
And now--now I'm being
penalized for it?
- You lost a patient today,
and I'm concerned that you are
not processing your grief.
- Why, because I'm not reacting
to it the same way you would?
Taking a week off,
wallowing in it?
- You are one
of the brightest residents
I have ever worked with,
but if you can't be honest
about your feelings,
how can you be there
for your patients?
- So--so what, you--you want me
to say that what happened today
freaked me out?
- Sounds good.
Let's start there.
- Okay, it did.
Of course it did,
but I can't let that in.
I can't let it even get close.
- All right.
I want to try something, okay?
An exercise.
- Dr. Frome--
- Just an exercise.
- Dr. Frome,
I'm not your patient.
- Listen, close your eyes.
Close your eyes.
- Good. Okay.
Now take a deep breath in.
And then slowly exhale.
Okay.
Now, just for a moment,
I want you to acknowledge
what happened.
Actually let it in.
♪
Is this what you wanted?
- Wandy, these are
your feelings.
- So what?
I can't feel like this
every time a patient has
a setback.
What in the world would make
you think this way is better?
God.
♪
- This has been going on
for a week.
One
mass shooting after another.
♪
I don't know how
he handled it.
This has been going on
for a week.
.
- Gladys, can you put
these cases
back on my rotation, please?
- Sure.
Who should I assign them to?
- Wandy.
- I see.
You helped her.
You worked your Iggy magic
on her.
- No. No magic.
- So what changed?
- Nothing.
Not a thing.
I just--I can't expect her
to have all the answers when
I don't have them myself.
- Oh shoot.
- What?
- I didn't know that having all
the answers was required of us.
Maybe I should pack my bags
and go knit with my retired
aunts in Tallahassee.
- That's a really
strange alternative, but okay.
- And I know Raul doesn't
have all the answers,
so he should probably stop
training the nurses.
- Okay.
Clever, thank you.
I get it.
- I mean,
you didn't actually think
you had all the answers,
did you?
- Uh, yes, I did.
- Did Wandy think she had
all the answers?
- Yeah, I think she did.
- Then it seems
like a lot changed today.
Or...
I could assign these cases to a
really wonderful shrink I know.
- No.
Wandy's ready.
♪
- Dr. Rahul Nagendran
and I go way back.
And I'm telling you,
the guy just loves it
when I show up out of the blue
and just rock his world.
- He sure didn't see happy
to see you.
- No he didn't.
Uh, excuse me.
Is that aloo tikki?
Thank you very much.
Oh wow, that's so good.
Holy moly.
- You know, I hate to admit it,
Max, but you were right.
This proposal is phenomenal.
It's exactly what we look for
in our students.
- I forgot to mention,
Dr. Nagendran is the dean
of Columbia's college
of arts and sciences.
- Imani, I'd like to offer you
a full scholarship.
- Shut up.
Are--are you serious?
- In addition to our thorough
science curriculum,
we offer classes
in microfinance,
entrepreneurship,
and even marketing.
- Now, if you'll excuse me,
I probably should get back
to my daughter's wedding.
- Of course. Um, Rahul--
- Yes.
- Thank you.
- You did all this for me?
- You earned it.
Now you learn how to take your
idea to market all on your own.
And then,
and I truly believe this,
you're gonna fix the world.
♪
- There was so many this week.
I couldn't keep them all
straight in my head.
I mean the nightclub shooting
after the...
high school shooting
and then the...
warehouse shooting.
And Monday was that shooter
at the grocery store
near my place.
I see him around
my neighborhood all the time
with his wife
and his two girls.
He was just picking up
groceries,
just living his life.
It could've been you.
It could've been me.
It's everywhere.
I used to feel...
outrage.
You know what?
I used to think
it didn't have to be like this.
We don't have to live
like this.
But now,
it's like we traded
one pandemic in for another.
- Here's an idea:
your place tonight.
- I wish...
But it's not my night.
- So we make an exception.
Meet me downstairs.
- ♪ I been awake
for so long now ♪
♪ Just can't get to sleep
- You.
- ♪ Tuggin' at my eyelids
- In here.
- ♪ You been dawning on me
- ♪ And there's a life
coming through the window ♪
♪ But all I can see
- Whoa, wait, whoa.
- That was so freaking hot,
I can barely contain myself.
- You're not mad?
- That's the woman
I fell in love with.
Okay, here's
a baseball reference for you.
When we get home later,
you're not gonna be striking
out.
- It's just that tonight,
I have plans
with Roxana, believe it or not.
After I stood up to you,
she invited me out
with the other residents.
I just had to show them
who I am.
Thank you.
- Well, I guess were just gonna
have to make do here.
But if you ever do that
again in my ED,
war-torn Kashmir will feel
like a vacation
compared to the hellfire
I will bring down upon you.
But more of that
in private, please.
- ♪ And the spirit that
moves them ♪
- How are you?
Your place or mine?
You're scaring me.
- Okay, can I, um--
I just have to say...
- Mm-hmm.
- That all day, I have been
thinking about
our living situation.
- Situation does not
sound great.
- No, that's because
it's not great.
♪
Your place is just so, um--
it's, uh, it's--it's cramped.
And don't take this
the wrong way,
but you're not exactly
a neat freak.
Plus, there's all
of Luna's things
perched everywhere you look.
There's no privacy.
Our London flat
wouldn't be any larger,
which means something has
to change.
Um...
I have made
a unilateral decision.
♪
We have to get used to this.
I am moving in with you.
- Kind of thought that was
going in a different direction.
- I'd be lying if I said that
wasn't somewhat intentional.
- Well done, 'cause
you kind of nailed me.
- Thank you.
- Are you moving in?
- Yes, but there will
be tidying.
♪
- Yes.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry,
I'm a little emotional.
I'm sorry, this is--
I'm just so damn happy
for you guys, and I'm--
I'm gonna miss you both.
- Get in here.
Just get in here. Bring it in.
Bring it in.
♪
- ♪ Dawning on me
♪ I been awake
for so long now ♪
♪ Just can't get to sleep
♪ You've been calling on
the sunlight ♪
♪ You been dawning on me
♪ From your lips
to your belly ♪
♪ To your knees
and your feet ♪
♪
♪ And the spirit that
moves them ♪
♪ You been dawning
♪ On me
- I'm glad you all are here.
- Oh, because you want to--
you want to bring it in.
- No, because I'd like
to introduce you all
to the new medical director
of New Amsterdam.
Veronica.
♪
-  No.
Really?
You hired her?
- Good to see you, too.
We go way back.
Don't we, Max?