Richard, this is
the first time 2.0
is being used on a patient.
We were able to remove
the patient's tumor.
And we're optimistic
for his future.
I'm not taking
my son's kidney, Hannah.
Donating could be a really
positive experience for him.
If you turn out to be a match,
I won't say no.
I was wanting you
to meet my brother.
So tell me, Doctor,
you deal with any
crazy people today?
Pawel.
I didn't mean
to offend.
I was meeting
with a headhunter.
I have a bad feeling
about the direction that
Jack is taking us.
Jack.
He got the votes.
We are now
a for-profit hospital.
Hello, Daniel.
Hoping I'd run into you.
Walk you out?
Your desk, bottom drawer,
left you a treat.
You didn't have to do that.
We don't get to see
each other during the day.
It's my way
of feeling close to you.
Wow.
The esteemed Dr. Charles,
Chicago's very own Carl Jung.
Pawel, how you doing?
Fine.
Hurry, Liliana. Get in.
Let's not keep him.
He must be very busy.
Just a minute.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Pawel can be rude.
He was a lawyer
back in Poland.
And he has had a hard time
finding a career
here in America.
I think he feels...
Left behind?
Yes
Yeah, it's hard.
Making jokes
is just his frustration.
He has a big heart.
Have a good day, Daniel.
Morning, Sharon.
Hey, Maggie.
Good morning.
You know that recruiter
that I met with last week?
Well, she may be calling you
for some references.
You're really doing this,
leaving Med?
Well, just testing the waters.
And what would it take
to make you stop testing?
You got a time machine?
Take Med back to when
patients came before profits?
All right. I get it.
I'll let you know
if someone calls.
Thank you.
I wish you didn't have to take
a day off work for this.
I feel bad.
Testing to see
if I can give you my kidney
kind of trumps
parking a few cars.
Mmm.
Hey, guys.
Big day.
You ready, Sean?
I'm cool.
He's a nervous wreck.
Mmm.
I'm grateful.
My job as a dad
is being there for you.
And you being there
for me
has been more trying
than I thought.
Oh, thank God.
I'm needed in the ED.
Too much emotion
for you, Dean?
Yeah, way, way too much.
Yeah.
Hey, Dr. Asher.
Just the usual chai tea?
Yes, please.
Thank you, Carly.
Sean.
You sure I can't get you
a coffee?
Not today. Just water.
Okay.
I think Carly just gave you
flirty eyes.
Is there, like,
something-something
brewing between you two?
Just friends.
Oh. Because smart, kind,
and super cute
are just not your type.
No, that's my type.
Mmm.
Mind's just somewhere else
right now.
What if I'm not
a donor match?
Then we'll figure
something else out.
Good morning.
So are the rumors true?
What rumors?
The rehab clinic going
part-time.
The dialysis center
possibly shutting down.
Oh, those rumors.
Well, maybe.
New mandate says that if
a department is losing money,
it could be
on the chopping block.
Well, what about the ED?
I don't know.
Maggie, I need some help.
Talk to me.
Name's Jan Dover,
30s, single vehicle crash,
low impact,
backed into a light pole.
GCS 15, laceration
on her left palm.
Appears slightly jaundiced,
and has some
very interesting theories
about the medical
industrial complex.
Ma'am, please.
It's policy.
What about my autonomy?
Am I not allowed to govern
my own health and wellness?
She was a little rattled
at the scene.
I think that's why
she didn't fight us
getting into the ambo.
But now that the shock
has worn off,
she won't come out.
Okay. Let me see
what I can do.
Thank you, Cesar.
Hi, Jan.
I'm Maggie.
I'm a nurse here
at Chicago Med.
I know what
you're going to ask,
and I'm not
going inside.
Well, the thing is,
you're already here.
And your hand, it looks like
it needs stitches.
Oh, it's fine.
Well,
let's confirm that.
And then we'll send you
on your way.
They've got you
on the payroll,
don't they?
I'm sorry. Who's "they"?
The pharmaceutical companies.
All you nurses
are on the take.
I can assure you,
I'm not on any take.
No. I've read about it.
And I know that the minute
I walk through that door,
you're going to inject me
with a virus,
and I will spend
the rest of my life
paying for
overpriced medications.
You'll get a cut,
and your pals at big pharma
will make a fortune
keeping me alive.
Told you.
Okay, um,
Jan, I'm not sure where
you got your information.
But if you come inside
with me, maybe we can...
No. I'm not going anywhere.
She's very distrustful
of hospitals, paranoid,
maybe even delusional.
And she says
her name is Jan Dover.
It sounds like a variation
on Jane Doe, doesn't it?
Exactly. And she's been
white-knuckling those handles
ever since they got here.
By the way,
her hand's been bleeding.
That lac must be deep
and hurt like hell.
Is she angry? Combative?
No, she's just
terrified and thinks
we're going to hurt her
and has a ton of internet
research to back it up.
You know, COVID,
with all the isolation
and loneliness
really amplified
the conspiracy theories
in general,
made the medical system
in particular an easy target.
Jan, how you doing?
I'm Dr. Charles.
A psychiatrist.
Here we go.
What do you mean?
Medicine's answer for people
who don't play along
is call them crazy.
Jan, we just met, okay?
The only thing
I know about you
is that you're losing
a lot of blood,
and we gotta...
We gotta take a look
at that hand.
And I appreciate that,
but I already told her
that I am not going
inside the hospital.
It is too dangerous.
How so?
X-rays, gamma rays,
infrared radiation.
I mean,
we can keep chatting
if you can fix those.
Well, we actually
have a protocol for that.
You do?
Yeah. Trust me.
You are not the first person
to come into this hospital
with that set of concerns.
Okay. Fine then.
Great.
Wheelchair, please.
We have a protocol for
the electromagnetic spectrum?
We do now.
By the way,
she is very jaundiced.
It could be
something serious
Yeah.
So look,
in order to actually
get her into a treatment room,
I'm going to ask you to get
with the X-ray techs, okay?
And here's what I want you
to ask them for...
Tim, how long has your
stomach been bothering you?
A few weeks or so.
It's mostly when I eat.
Yeah? And how does it
feel now?
Mild? Sharp?
Kind of like
indigestion or bloating,
but then last night
it got a little worse.
Seriously, Tim?
A little worse?
He woke up from
a dead sleep screaming.
He had tears in his eyes.
Pam.
My wife overshares
when she's nervous.
And my husband downplays
when he's in pain.
Can you tell
we've been married forever?
That's all good. Okay.
So one to ten,
how's the pain feel now?
Ow! That's like a six
or seven right there.
Nope. Downplaying.
That's a ten face.
I see it every time
we have a stair day.
Stair day?
Our resolution for 2023
was to lose weight,
get fit.
And one of our workouts
is walking the stairs
in our building.
She makes it sound like
it's a mid-rise.
It's not even close.
It's 35 stories.
Well, he never makes it
past the eighth floor.
Meanwhile, I make it
to the top every time,
and I haven't lost a pound.
Tim here's lost 22.
Twenty-four.
Yeah, I don't know.
It must be my metabolism.
Or it's whatever's going
on with your stomach,
and, if that's the case,
I want it too.
Ow! You can have it.
Okay, well,
we'll give you something
to take the edge off, okay?
Uh, 25 of fentanyl
and a GI cocktail.
Also, order an upright
and flat abdominal X-ray
and a CT abdomen and pelvis.
Okay. Just take
some deep breaths.
It'll help with the pain.
George, a minute?
Sharon. Of course,
of course.
Just sketch in the aquarium.
I'll be right back.
An aquarium?
I thought we were only
taking over a couple
of rooms
for this new VIP build.
Well, demand was much
greater than expected.
So, at the 11th hour,
Jack decided to take
the entire floor.
But this is
the geriatrics unit.
Did he even consider
those patients?
Well, the plan
is to fold geriatrics
into the orthopedic.
Oh, so that's the plan, huh?
Clearly, word didn't
get to you.
Well, clearly.
I'm so sorry, Sharon.
It must have been
an oversight.
Since turning for-profit,
there have been
dozens of new voices
in the mix.
And it's really gummed up
the lines of communication.
Well, un-gum them.
Because I will not be left out
of the loop
in my own hospital.
Well, anything further,
and I will notify you myself.
Good.
How far do we have to go?
Uh, just number three
down here on the right.
These poor people,
staring at me,
yet they have no idea
how dangerous this place is.
All the things
they're being exposed to.
You know,
I used to be like them
till I discovered the truth.
The truth?
What, um, what exactly
do you mean by that?
Jan, every machine that
could be removed has been,
and the equipment
that we couldn't
has been draped
with a lead vest
like the one
that you're wearing.
And the walls
have been insulated
with anti-radiation blankets.
Wow.
You did this fast.
Yeah.
Protocol, right?
Here we go.
Fine. Okay.
Jan, that's Tracy.
Be right back.
Well, she's in.
Yeah.
Hopefully she's comfortable
enough to let us fix her hand,
but we really got to
figure out this jaundice.
How we going to do that?
She's taking every tool
we've got out of play.
Richard, Vickie.
Dr. Halstead.
How you been?
Wonderful.
Last week, he was
five months cancer-free.
That's fantastic.
I only wish you could
have treated my clumsiness.
I think I busted
my ankle.
Yeah. I can see that.
What happened?
Uh, I tripped going down
the stairs.
I've been icing it for a week,
but it's not getting
any better.
Vickie made me come in.
I need him in walking shape.
We're going to Machu Picchu
next month,
hiking the Inca trail.
We got time back that
I never thought we'd have.
Uh, we're trying to make
the most of it.
That's wonderful.
We'll get some X-rays,
but I suspect
it's just a sprain.
Oh, that's good to hear,
considering last time
we were here.
Thank God for OR 2.0.
Yeah, Richard, you were
its first patient.
Your success
was a real inspiration.
Shoot, honey,
I left my cell in the car.
Do you mind
grabbing it for me?
Sure.
I'll be right back.
Oh, God.
Richard, you all right?
I needed her to leave
for a minute.
What's going on?
I tripped because
I've been weak.
There's a dull pain
in my belly,
and I haven't had
an appetite.
The cancer's back. I know it.
Let's not get ahead
of ourselves.
We'll run some tests
and go from there.
So I assume
Vickie doesn't know.
I can't bring myself
to tell her.
Since my surgery, we've been
living our best lives.
She's so happy.
I don't want to take that
from her.
I understand.
Free fluid and free air
in my abdomen?
What does that mean?
That there's a hole somewhere
in your intestine
or your stomach.
From what?
Could be
a perforated ulcer.
It might be something sharp
that you swallowed.
Honestly, I won't be sure
until I get in there.
Get in there?
You mean surgery?
Yeah. A leak in the GI tract
needs to be
addressed immediately.
But he'll be all right?
Yes.
It's a routine operation.
There's a waiting room.
We also have a cafe,
if you like.
I don't know.
I want to be close.
Pam, honey, you know what?
Why don't you take a walk?
You love this time of year,
nice weather.
You can get your steps in.
I guess the fresh air
might do me some good.
Quell the nerves.
Sure. Okay.
So we're good here? Yeah?
All right, well,
I'll change my scrubs,
and I'll get the techs
to bring you upstairs
to pre-op holding.
Hi.
Sweetie, you need to let go.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Don't worry.
We'll keep you updated
throughout
the entire operation.
Thank you.
Oh, and another one...
Vaccines.
You want to know
who they're helping,
just look at the sponsor
behind it.
Hey, a lot of people
have problems
with vaccines, you know?
It's a complicated issue.
Exactly.
I didn't think
you would understand.
It's really important for
somebody in my position
to keep an open mind.
Refreshing.
You know, Jan,
I'm noticing some
skin discoloration.
Oh, it's just
the fluorescent
lights in here.
You know, it could be.
But it also
might be jaundice.
You mind if I just take
a tiny bit of blood,
do a couple of
very simple blood tests?
Yes, I mind very much.
Got it. Understood.
You were saying?
Oh, HIV.
I read
a very persuasive article
basically saying that
they intentionally dusted it
over low-income communities
as a form of
population control.
Wow.
Yeah.
I mean, people
wanted to blame
the Reagan administration,
you know, the FBI,
but the research I've done
points to the CIA.
What kind of research?
I'm just curious.
I mean, written literature,
podcasters, YouTubers.
But I prefer online forums
because people are always
sharing information.
So, I mean,
do you have, like a...
A favorite forum that
you could show me?
Yeah, I don't know.
Look, I will draw
my own conclusions.
It's just the more
up-to-the-minute stuff
I have access to,
the better.
No big deal.
Okay, uh...
All right.
Look at this thread.
It talks about the scanners
that they use in hospitals.
We're
seeing that, yeah.
CTs, ultrasounds,
especially MRIs,
and how they inject
dangerous hydrogen protons
into the body.
Wow.
Hospitals kill people.
They kill them.
Okay. We had
a good chat, but...
Look, you seem like
a nice guy, but I would...
I would really like
to go home now.
Got it. Um, let me
just quickly go
find somebody
to stitch you up.
No, no, no, no.
I don't think so.
That's a deep wound, okay?
If we don't close it up,
it's going to keep bleeding.
And what I really
don't want to happen
is that it gets infected.
No, no. I'll keep it clean.
You want to risk having
your hand infected?
You could lose it.
Okay. Fine.
But no scans, no IVs,
just a needle and thread.
And then you let me go.
Deal.
Back in a flash.
Mags?
Yeah.
Find Zack.
Have him stitch up her hand.
She's gonna let us treat her?
Just the hand,
not the jaundice.
Well, that's a start.
What about her mental state?
You know, conspiracy theories
are not necessarily connected
to any kind of paranoid
personality disorder.
I mean, certainly not
in Jan's case.
And she's what?
Just gullible?
I'd say more like
a combination of,
I don't know, lonely
and prone to persuasion.
I'm starting to think that
something bad happened
to her in a hospital.
That makes sense.
How do we get past that?
Because I'm concerned
that her jaundice
means that
her liver's failing.
Yeah, I mean, look.
She wouldn't let me
draw blood, all right?
Scans are
out of the question.
So I guess we're just going
to have to go with, you know,
her medical history.
Well, we don't even
have that.
We don't even have her name.
It's Jacqueline Warner.
She handed me her phone.
The settings trick
that I taught you.
Anyway, it's not going to
take Zack that long
to stitch her up,
but she's already
asking to leave, so...
Don't worry.
I'll buy you some time.
Thank you.
Got you.
Vickie, Richard.
Dr. Marcel?
Nice to see you both.
Yeah, it's nice
to see you too.
Yeah.
I don't understand.
You're a surgeon.
You said
it was just a sprain.
Richard,
what's going on?
The cancer's back,
isn't it?
I'm afraid so.
CT scan showed
multiple lesions
in your liver.
So it metastasized.
It spread
from my pancreas.
Yes.
Oh, Richard.
You knew something
was wrong.
Why didn't you tell me?
I wanted to.
But I also just
didn't wanna face it.
These last few months,
the way you laugh
at my dumb jokes,
burn my toast on the edges.
I've fallen for you
all over again.
You beat cancer once.
You can beat it again.
No, honey.
I'm a science guy.
The odds of that happening...
Are good.
Richard, OR 2.0
knows your body.
It's been learning
and improving
with every surgery
it's done since yours.
Now, don't get me wrong.
This procedure you need now,
high-frequency ablation,
it's a delicate operation.
But 2.0 has all the tools.
But a third lease on life?
Really?
I believe so.
Okay.
Let's do it again.
Good.
Thank you both.
Yeah.
Here we go.
Perforated ulcer
on the anterior surface
of the first portion
of the duodenum.
Got some undigested
food remnants, lavage.
Betcha it's corn
and green beans.
Close.
Corn and cauliflower.
I was going to
say cauliflower.
All right.
Uh, suction, please.
Let's move on
to the omental patch,
3-0 silk suture.
Whoa!
What the hell was that?
That's a tapeworm.
Where the hell did it go?
That's a good question.
Booked the whole day for
one person's pacemaker?
Apparently, Jack has
decided to rent out OR 2.0.
As long as you have the money,
you can reserve it
for as long as you want.
I know
this is unorthodox,
but when Jack started
analyzing revenue streams...
No, he's selling seats
on a rocket ship,
making up rules
only his rich pals
can play by.
Okay. Right now, I need
a solution for my patient.
Rich is ready for surgery,
and this other guy
is still in Colorado.
And my priority
is patient care,
and I'm not going to
have an operating room
held hostage by Jack Dayton.
Start your surgery.
Wait. Just hold on.
Jack's already made it clear
that he's no longer
subsidizing 2.0.
We sure
Evans can pay?
Are you kidding me?
We're talking about
a man's life.
Dr. Halstead,
the way I see it,
Mr. Evans's initial surgery
was pro bono,
so we can consider this
a necessary follow-up
and forgive the bill.
Start your surgery,
Dr. Marcel.
Thank you.
You know, Jack's ideas,
chasing profits
for the hospital,
it only widens the gap.
It's not right.
Wow. I got to let Jack know
what's going on.
No, no, no.
You let me tell him myself.
We're going to keep this line
of communication direct.
Dr. Charles,
Zack's finished
stitching Jan up.
And I've stalled
all that I can.
She's antsy,
and she wants
out of here.
Okay, well,
I'm starting
to see why.
Nothing glaring
in Jan's chart,
but it turns out
her sister, Deborah,
was seen at East Mercy
right before the pandemic
for a broken arm.
Upon examination,
they discover
aggressive pancreatic cancer.
She's dead in a month.
So in Jan's mind,
her sister went into
the hospital healthy,
had a bunch of scans
and tests,
and came out
with a terminal disease?
Exactly. She has this sudden
catastrophic loss,
and she's furious
and looking for
someone to blame.
Oh, my God.
Jaundice is a symptom
of pancreatic cancer.
Isn't it hereditary?
Yes.
And it was killing her sister
before she even knew
she had it.
Same thing could be
happening to Jan.
She needs a full workup now.
What are we going to do?
Okay, look.
I'm going to dive back into
these sites, these forums,
see if I can find something
that we can connect on.
In the meantime,
start the discharge,
but slow roll it for me.
Okay. Work fast.
All right, Trini, I'm back.
What've we got?
Nothing.
Seriously?
Since we stopped taking
walk-ins without insurance,
numbers are down.
Well, we can't do that.
It's illegal.
I don't know. I guess
we're only taking
"true emergencies" now.
I know you've been
waiting a long time.
And I'm sorry, sir.
They'll be able to help you
at East Mercy.
We're turning him away
because he doesn't
have insurance?
Yeah.
Excuse me, sir.
I'm Dr. Halstead.
What's going on?
Gout's flaring up again.
I'm sorry.
I know that's painful.
How about your chest?
Any pain?
What? No.
Are you sure?
'Cause if you do,
well, that'd be considered
an emergency,
and we'd have to
treat you here.
So no chest pain?
I might have
a slight feeling of tightness.
Well, in that case,
let's get you checked out.
Okay, what do you feel?
We got grilled cheese,
dim sum, pizza.
Any of them.
I'm starving.
I had to fast
for the blood test,
then no time to eat
before the scans started.
Any idea when the results
come in?
Well, they said
a couple of days.
Probably going to feel like
weeks though.
Mmm-hmm.
Oh, my God.
Are you hurt? What...
I don't know.
I was just walking,
and then all of a sudden
my stomach...
Argh!
Okay, all right.
Help me get her
to the bench.
What's your name?
Pam.
Pam, I'm Dr. Asher.
That's Sean.
Thank you.
Is it okay
if I feel your belly?
Yes.
Yeah? Okay.
My husband's in surgery
right now
for a hole
in his intestine.
Could I have
the same thing?
Sorry.
It's okay.
Squeeze as hard
as you like.
Oh, God.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I just peed myself.
Oh, no, Pam.
That's not urine.
Your uterus is enlarged
and firm.
Your water just broke.
You're in labor.
What? I'm pregnant?
I'm sorry.
You didn't know?
Wow, okay.
So I imagine you have
a lot of questions.
But right now, we need
to get you inside.
I'll get a wheelchair.
Wait. I'm scared.
I need to
hold on to someone,
and my husband's in the...
I'll step in for him,
if you'd like.
Thank you.
Okay. I'll go
get that wheelchair.
I see.
Oh, lost it. Damn it.
Is this
a cause-and-effect thing?
Tapeworm lead to the ulcer?
No.
Ulcer's usually from
the H. pylori bacteria,
super common,
almost all of us have it.
Tapeworm's from a bad meal.
I'm never eating again.
Gotcha. Ha ha.
Wife's not picking up.
Leave your number.
Ask her to text you.
Pull this out slowly.
Tapeworms regenerate.
Don't want this
breaking off on me.
How long
do you think it is?
No idea.
But I can't wait to find out.
Need some help in here!
Move it.
Where?
Anywhere but here, Mike.
What happened?
They took an X-ray
in the treatment room
next door
and it set her off.
I heard them.
They said X-ray. And then
someone yelled, "Clear."
See, they're admitting
the radiation is bad
for you.
And these blankets
are not enough.
Okay. I'm sorry.
But we got rid
of the X-ray machine.
Well, Dr. Charles said
I could go,
so I'm leaving right now.
Jacqueline...
What? How do you know
my name?
I can explain.
No. Forget it.
I don't trust any of you.
We know about your sister
and her cancer.
Yeah, that the hospitals
gave her
with their X-rays
and their CTs
and their MRIs.
Those scans killed her!
It's not true.
Deborah had cancer before
she went to the hospital.
No.
Her death had nothing
to do with the test.
It was genetic.
That's why you need
to get tested too.
No. Stay away from me.
You have all been lying to me
since I got here.
That's not true.
We've been trying to help you.
Then let me go!
Maggie, just a word.
Be right back.
I'm done here.
Give me five minutes.
I'll walk you out myself.
Mags?
What are you doing?
We've got to get through
to her somehow.
Reinforcing her paranoid
fantasies is not the way
to do that.
She may have
a terminal cancer,
Dr. Charles.
She needs
to get screened.
Well, of course she does.
But it's got to be
her decision to do that.
Well, we know that's never
going to happen, don't we?
Yeah, it's a safe bet
this is why Tim was
shedding weight.
Tapeworm was
stealing calories.
Tim's wife text you back yet?
No. Still MIA.
I don't get it.
So worried about Tim
having surgery.
Where'd she go?
One last push!
Awesome, Pam.
You're almost there.
Keep going.
Okay.
Oh, my God.
Full-term?
Ultrasound revealed that
the gestational age
is around 37 weeks.
It doesn't make any sense.
I have polycystic
ovarian syndrome.
I get a period once,
maybe twice a year.
We've tried forever,
and nothing.
Okay, we can figure out
the hows and whys later, Pam.
Right now,
I need you to focus.
Here comes
another contraction.
All right.
Ready, Pam?
Push as hard as you can, okay?
Sean?
Right. Breathe through it.
Short, short, long.
Okay. I see
the top of the head.
All right, Tim.
Can't imagine
there's much more.
Holy smokes.
One more pull. One more.
And, ugh!
It's out.
Whew.
He is out.
It's a boy, Pam.
Oh, my God.
This is incredible.
I'm a mom.
Congratulations.
Thanks.
Here he is.
There we go.
Oh, my God.
My husband is...
Is he still in surgery?
I'll find out for you.
He is not going to believe
what just came out of me.
2.0, give me a lateral
cross-section of the liver.
Rotating.
Okay. I've got visuals
of the lesions.
2.0, triangulate.
Guidance initiated.
Angle three degrees left.
Three degrees.
Okay.
Probe has penetrated
the first lesion.
Activate radiofrequency.
Activating.
Very nice.
First lesion has been ablated.
Six more to go, Richard.
2.0, guide me to the next one.
Calculating.
2.0, guide me
to the next lesion.
Calculating. Calculating.
Push forward three millimeters
to circumvent
the common hepatic vein.
All right.
Advancing forward.
That came out of my intestine?
Yeah. All six feet,
four inches of it.
No more YOLO moments for me.
YOLO? You Only Live Once?
Yeah.
Nine months ago, Pam and I
went to Thailand for our 10th.
I was all over
those street carts.
Pork, chicken, fish, insects.
I probably picked up that
tapeworm somewhere
in that smorgasbord.
Perhaps.
Although, tapeworms
only take two months
to reach adult size,
so it's possible
that you were infected
more recently.
Same thing goes for
the H. pylori bacteria
that caused your ulcer.
Could've happened
any time, any place.
So the two
aren't connected?
Well, not medically.
But tapeworms can go
undetected for years.
So if you hadn't
developed an ulcer
which required surgery,
then who knows how long
it would've taken
to discover it?
I guess it was
my lucky day,
then, huh?
Yeah.
Actually, yeah.
About your trip to Thailand...
Pretty sure you didn't bring
anything back in you,
but I'm very certain
that your wife
brought something back in her.
Surprise.
Who is that?
Our son.
What?
We're parents.
And who is that?
That's my son.
Parents? Is this really
happening right now?
Yes. It's really happening.
And I guess now we know why
I haven't lost any weight.
But your OB, she said you
couldn't ever get pregnant.
Yes, well,
she was wrong.
Whoa.
I know.
It's a lot.
Oh.
Do you want
to hold him, Dad?
Yeah.
Yeah?
Ow.
Here he is.
Hey, bud.
I can walk.
I hate these things.
I'm sorry. It's just,
it's hospital policy,
you know.
Of course.
Get me out of here.
I've been thinking about
these conversations we've had.
It occurred to me
it wasn't that long ago
that doctors actually thought
that cigarettes
were good for you.
I mean, we sold them
in hospitals, right?
Point being that
the medical world
always has been,
always will be
constantly evolving.
I mean, look, I do this
for a living every day.
I'm a doctor.
No way I can keep up.
You know what I mean?
How's your hand?
Feeling any better?
Yeah. A little.
Here. Let me...
There we go.
Okay.
So listen, uh,
I just wanted to say that
the last couple of years
has been really hard
for a lot of people, right?
Loneliness, isolation, loss.
I really miss my sister.
I bet you do.
And that's why I was thinking
there might come a time
when you might want
to talk to somebody
about her, about her cancer,
about what it was like
to lose her.
And I thought of somebody
who you really
might respond to.
A doctor?
No. Not an MD.
This is an MSW, actually,
trained therapist,
but somebody
who really thinks,
like, way outside the box.
Anyway, this is her card,
you know,
I mean, just in case.
Okay.
All right, bye.
A referral, Dr. Charles?
That's the best
we could do?
Hey, Maggie,
she took the card.
I mean,
under the circumstances,
for me, it's a plus.
And by the way,
already talked
to that therapist.
And in case she ever calls,
first order of business,
encourage her to get screened.
So you know, I'll take it.
I'm sorry about earlier.
Maybe I made it
a little too personal.
Hardest part of my job is just
constantly checking myself,
make sure I'm not projecting
my life onto the people
I'm trying to help.
So I get it.
Yeah. It's not easy.
Yeah, and then, bam,
there it was.
You know, just looked at it
right in the eyes, you know?
Wait. Do tapeworms
even have eyes?
Eyes, no eyes,
you know what I mean.
Mmm. Okay, well,
afraid I'm going to have
to listen to the rest
of the saga later.
I promised Pam that I would
visit her and the baby.
Mmm. Okay.
Sean,
you want to come?
Pretty sure after today
that Tim and Pam
consider you family.
No. I'll stop by later.
I wanna hit the gift shop,
get something for the baby.
Okay.
See you guys later.
I know that look.
Yeah.
I've been feeling it
for a while.
I mean, Hannah's smart,
kind, and super cute.
And seeing her
in action today...
Yeah. She's a catch.
No question.
But, you know, you're just
getting back on your feet,
you know?
I know. Lot of cons.
But the pros?
I feel good with her.
I trust her.
Yeah, I get it. You know,
you're still in recovery.
And so is Hannah,
for that matter.
Did okay?
Surgery was flawless,
just like the first time.
2.0 took care
of all the lesions
and ran additional scans
that confirm
the cancer was confined
to his liver.
Oh, thank you.
They say third time's
a charm,
but I hope we never
have to see you again.
I totally get it. Yeah.
How we looking?
Just lowered his sedation.
Okay. Richard, hey.
Time to wake up, buddy.
Richard?
Hey.
Richard, can you hear me?
Last time,
he woke right up.
Yeah. It was a long surgery.
He may need
a little more time.
Richard.
Not responding
to deep, painful stimuli.
Need a head CT.
What's happening?
Is something wrong?
Difficulty coming out of
anesthesia could indicate
he's had a stroke.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Richard?
Richard? Open your eyes.
Richard, open your eyes.
Richard, it's time to wake up.
Richard, wake up!
Oh, Maggie.
Oh, hey.
The recruiter called,
and I sang your praises.
Thank you.
Tough day?
It was just the case hit home.
I just wish
I could do more, you know?
Yeah, well, I know
exactly what you mean.
Chin up.
Yeah.
Oh.
All good with Pam
and the baby?
Yup. She is
online feverishly
ordering baby bottles
and clothes and diapers.
Yeah. Tim too.
Crib, car seat,
and a stroller.
What a day.
I know.
I mean, I wonder what's
going to happen next, right?
Yeah, you got me.
I mean,
where did you get this?
The hobby store on Madison.
Oh, man.
The paramedics got them
for me in-between runs.
Yeah.
How long were you
sitting there pretending
to read your chart while
waiting for me to come in?
Since I clocked out.
Hey, Doris.
Seen my father?
Uh, Doctors' lounge.
Thanks.
No, no, no.
Yeah.
Oh, hey, Pawel.
What are you doing?
Dropping off Liliana
for her shift.
Did I miss her?
She will be back.
Grabbing me a sandwich
from the cafe.
Nice photo.
Very impressive.
Used to have my name
on the wall.
But that's the past.
You know, Pawel, I...
I can't imagine
how frustrating it must be
to feel like you've got
to start all over again.
Look, it's none
of my business.
But I do have a buddy,
pretty good buddy, actually,
who has a small law firm...
No, I don't need your help.
I have a plan,
and I'm not one
of your patients.
Pawel.
I'll pick you up
in the morning.
My brother. I'm sorry.
What he's going through
is very difficult.
We've got to give him
some time.
He'll be okay.
Daniel, you're a very
patient man.
Me?
I'm a...
I'm a lucky man.
Pupils were fixed
and dilated.
I mean, no gag reflex.
No corneal reflex.
Stroke. No chance
of recovery?
Vickie's decided
to discontinue life support.
She's saying goodbye.
Dr. Marcel.
Yeah.
Hey. How you doing?
I don't know what happened.
2.0 didn't indicate
anything was wrong.
No alarms.
Vitals were stable
the entire time.
This had to be on me.
I must have done something,
you know?
Had to have done
something wrong.
I know that's how it feels.
But sometimes, even under
the best of circumstances,
patients don't survive.
And I'm not
telling you anything
you don't already know.
It's awful. It is.
But it's the burden
we bear.