Previously on The Resident...
Medical devices
gave me my life back.
Total hip replacement. It
made me a true believer.
Have you arranged for
someone to teach you Bhangra?
You studying up to
do a Bollywood dance?
My fiancée insists,
but I've two left feet.
Well, maybe I can
help. I was a dancer.
I've been thinking about
creating my own medical device.
Watching what you
do gave me the idea.
- What am I doing here?
- Oh, I'm assigning you to Ortho.
- Okafor belongs to me.
- I belong to no one.
My sister. She OD'd on Oxy.
I'm not just doing
this for me anymore,
I'm staying clean
for both of us.
I'm not worried.
Do I look worried?
Perhaps you should
let go of kitty's leash.
Camping for a bachelor
party weekend? Really?
What I want to know is
who sleeps in the middle?
Was this Devon's idea?
He was fine with a couple
beers at Waylon's. But Irving...
Is making up for getting
kicked out of Boy Scouts.
Hey, the nurses are
planning a girls' night tonight.
We're thinking bowling.
Oh, I do not like sports
where I have to wear
other people's shoes.
Okay, fine. Karaoke? Come on.
Jessica's in Savannah
for the weekend.
I have zero obligations.
This is the first
time I've been free
since she got out of rehab.
It's Conrad. Hey, what's up?
You're kidding me.
Okay, yeah. I'll be right there.
What's going on?
Jess is not in Savannah.
I'm burning up.
What's wrong with me?
Jess... You okay?
I'm fine. I told
Conrad not to call you,
but clearly, he can't
keep a promise.
I made no promise and,
Jess, she needed to know.
Since when does
Chastain do drug trials?
Since Bell discovered
they're a cash cow, I imagine.
- What kind of trial is this?
- It's for cancer.
Healthy people volunteered.
Half of us got a cancer
drug, half of us got a placebo.
Do we know who got the placebo?
No. It's a double-blind.
Jessie's fine right
now, but John isn't.
Fever and vomiting.
Why didn't you just tell me?
Because I knew
you would lecture me.
This is my fault.
I told Jess it'd be a good
way to make some money.
I've done them before. I've
never had a reaction like this.
Excuse me. Who authorized this?
- Who are you?
What... what are you doing here?
I'm a doctor. She's an NP.
And John here is in
significant distress.
He's having a
normal reaction for
a Phase 1
first-in-human clinical trial.
Reactions are what
we're here to document.
Now, I'm gonna
have to ask you to go.
Oh, you don't have
to ask. Jess, come on.
Um. No, I'm not
gonna leave John.
Uh, you will lose
your fee if you quit.
I want to go.
I don't care about the money.
- What?
- Call rapid response!
We need to get
him to the ER now!
♪ ♪
John Losurdo. 30 years old.
Fever, vomiting, a
syncopal episode.
A suspected reaction to
an immunotherapy trial drug.
- We do drug trials now?
- Apparently so.
Uh, BP's 90/55. Hang
one liter of normal saline
and give him four Ondansetron
to help with the vomiting.
One, two, three.
- Is John gonna be okay?
- I hope so; we don't know enough
about the drug, or his
health when he took it.
- How do you know him, Jess?
- Rehab.
He's such a great guy.
Every time I wanted to bail,
he convinced me to stay.
I'm supposed to have a
consult with Mina right now,
but I want to stay
here with you.
No. It's fine. Go.
- Are you sure?
- We've got this.
Go. Steth.
Let's get a second line
and some blood work.
Babe, when you check the time,
this tiny little camera...
It scans your retina,
and it sends your
vitals to me like that.
That is so cool.
I can't believe
you designed that.
Yeah.
If my dad had been wearing this,
I could have caught his heart
attack before it happened.
Now, wait, there is just
one more thing that I need.
Priya Nair, would you
do me the honor of being
my first trial participant?
My beta tester?
Oh, yes. Yes, yes.
Um. First, there is
actually something
I need to talk to you about.
All right. Listen, If this is
about who's sitting where,
honestly, whatever you want...
No, nothing about the wedding.
Um, Devon, I've
been offered a spot
on an investigative
journalism team.
W... That's amazing.
Babe, I'm so proud of you.
It's at the San
Francisco Chronicle.
-If I take it, I have
to move there. Soon.
When? Because we're
getting married in two weeks.
How would that even happen?
A lot of couples
live in different cities.
We could make it work.
Nothing is decided yet. Let's
talk more when you get back
from your bachelor
weekend, okay?
I'm late.
You need to stop the trial now.
Are all your nurses
this dramatic, Dr. Bell?
Oh, I hear that one
of your participants
is in our ER with
life-threatening symptoms.
One of our participants got sick
to his stomach and
a bit dehydrated.
- Nothing life-threatening
about it.
- Oh, please.
Two more are
deteriorating as we speak.
Cancer is a ferocious enemy.
We fight it with strong drugs.
Please get your
staff to back down,
or Chastain won't see a dime.
Oh, and what's a
lawsuit gonna cost
if one of these patients dies?
Your trial can continue,
but I expect you to
notify me right away
if any of your
participants have reactions
outside the range of normal.
One of them's my sister.
Perfect vacation:
mountain, desert or sea?
Uh, desert.
When you're done
with this charade,
I need to talk with you.
Okafor, you are my ex-resident.
I'm looking for
my next resident.
And as you can see, it's
an embarrassment of riches.
Or just embarrassing.
Next!
Here.
What are you doing here?
I need a consult from you
and Conrad on a patient.
His name is Ernest LeVasseur.
Ernie?
Oh, woman, you
should've led with that.
He owns the Grill and Gumbo
and makes the best ribs in Atlanta.
No, not anymore, he doesn't.
Why? What's wrong with him?
The better question
is "What isn't?"
Mr. and Mrs. LeVasseur?
This is the brilliant
Dr. Hawkins.
He's one of our top
diagnosticians here at Chastain.
Oh, and this is Dr. Austin.
Cardiothoracic. I'm just
a smidge above average.
Ernie, it is an honor
to meet you, brother.
I am a huge fan of your dry rub.
Oh, he's nearly blind, and
his hearing's almost gone.
The doctor loves
your dry rub, Ernie.
- I had an egg with some bacon.
- Honey, they don't care
what you had for breakfast.
He talks nonsense like this
all the time now. My
brother-in-law says
it's early onset dementia.
Neurology doesn't think so.
When did he lose his vision?
About six months ago,
and then hearing went next.
Like, every other day,
another part of him was gone.
Mind if I have a look?
Yeah, sure.
First he developed
hypothyroidism,
and then reflux esophagitis.
His echocardiogram shows
heart failure due to cardiomyopathy.
Some kind of rash
around his neck,
warm to the touch.
Let's get another
thyroid and renal panel,
and let's add on an RPR,
folate and B12. Medical history?
Left hip replacement in 2012.
Kidney stones last
year, but that's about it.
Any complaints of pain?
No, he doesn't complain
about anything. He never has.
Ernie's always been the
happiest, most optimistic...
You know, it's like
he's here, but he's not.
There's almost
nothing left of him.
We understand how
difficult this must be.
Oh, I doubt it. I get up
at 6:00 every morning
and I change his diaper and then
I shower him, and after
he's fed and dressed,
I do it all over
again with the kids.
And after they're fed
and they're dressed
and I send them off to school...
Oh, my God.
I can't do it anymore.
Janine?
Darling?
W-Where are you?
I'm right here!
At least he still
remembers my name.
Sometimes, I...
I really wish that he didn't.
No one takes care
of the caretaker.
We're going to take
care of him here.
You go home, rest.
I will call you as soon
as we know more.
She needs help.
She's close to breaking.
I've notified social services.
They're scheduling a home visit.
A year ago, Ernest
was the life of the party.
What do you think
is wrong with him?
I think he's being poisoned.
I... made...
T-shirts.
I'm not wearing that, bud.
Campsite's booked,
rafts are rented.
Firing up the minivan
at 6:00 p.m. sharp.
Snack situation's on point.
I got ten flavors of chips,
including Nacho Mamma's Nachos.
Don't be late. I already told
Conrad we have a hard out.
Hey, guys.
- How's the dance coming along?
- Oh, uh, we're crushing it.
You still want to practice
when you get back?
Ooh!
Please, never do that again.
Wait, is that
what I think it is?
Beta version 1.0.
How's the retina scan function?
That's what makes it so unique.
Yeah. So far, so good.
Sends the data
directly to the...
Smartphone app. I remember.
Yeah.
Some of my friends
in Silicon Valley
have been
troubleshooting it for weeks
and it seems to be working well.
Well, you can't
test it on yourself.
You need a beta.
I'll drop an obvious
hint one more time.
You need a beta.
You?
- Really?
- Yeah. Why not?
Okay, so, um...
It tests for
- your heart rhythm...
- Uh-huh.
Uh, blood pressure and, um,
your pulse.
Oh, and it's also gonna
tell me I'm late for surgery.
I got to go. Keep an
eye on me, Pravesh.
- How you feeling, John?
- Not great.
His back is killing him.
Well, it'll take time
to metabolize the drug
they gave you, but we
can up your pain meds,
manage the symptoms
in the meantime.
Is that your family?
Yeah.
Ingrid, light of my life.
My wife, Sarah.
She keeps giving me
chances, you know?
They live in South Carolina.
This last stint in rehab was
the first I did on my own...
'cause I want to get better,
for me and for them.
This drug trial was just a way
to come home with
some cash in my pocket.
Help pay the bills,
Ingrid's music lessons.
Love her to death, but
she cannot play her recorder
so well.
At all, really.
Jess, you okay?
Yeah, yeah, I think it's just a
stress headache or something.
Hey, where was that? Right here?
- Yeah.
- All right.
Jess?
Jessie?
Devon! Irving!
Jessie didn't get the placebo.
Come on, let's get her on a bed.
We're gonna take
care of you, Jess.
Nic, what's
happening? I'm scared.
- I know, but I'm here.
- Oxygen sats are dropping.
- John? Hey, John!
- He can't breathe.
We need to intubate him. Hurry.
Page Conrad to the east wing.
Tell him to check
the other trial patients.
Just like that.
Get them to the ICU.
Again? I-I told Dr. Bell...
Two of your trial patients are
in the ICU with complications.
It cannot be from of our drug.
This dose was scaled back
500 fold for what was
proven safe in monkeys.
Monkeys?
Really?
Hey. Hey, hold up.
What do you think you're doing?
Clearing the room. Get these two
to the ER for observation.
- I am beginning
to lose my patience.
- And mine's long gone.
Trust me, you don't want
to push me any further.
I'm calling Bell.
I already did.
Give me an update.
Adele and Mauricio
have a fever, pain and vomiting.
Jessie is having
trouble breathing,
so we have her on oxygen,
and John is on a vent,
with multisystem organ failure.
I don't have to tell
you your trial is over,
and Chastain is not responsible
if anyone dies from
whatever the hell
- you gave them.
- I am telling you,
it is sepsis from an infection
they caught here.
The drug vials were
prepared by your company.
- If there's any
contamination...
- Hey, the blame game can wait.
We need information
on this drug.
Yeah, well, that's not happening
because it's not the drug.
Look, you don't know
that. I want every bit of data
you have in my hands
in the next ten minutes.
I'm not asking.
It's really deep in there.
Well, it's only a
quadruple bypass,
but I'm sure your inability
to get deep enough will be
just fine with the family
- after their loved one has...
- Wait, wait.
I think I got it.
Yup.
Sam's dead, and so are you.
Allow me to demonstrate.
Oh.
I'm starting to get the
feeling you miss me,
but your position's
almost filled.
Ernest's tests are in.
The levels of cobalt in his
blood are 200 times normal.
He has metallosis.
So you were right.
He is being poisoned.
But from what?
Here's the culprit...
His metal-on-metal
hip replacement.
When the metal ball and metal
cup slide against each other,
tiny particles can flake off
and enter the bloodstream,
sending cobalt and
chromium to every major organ.
And causing muscle
and tissue atrophy,
acetabular and
femoral osteolysis,
- and pseudotumors.
- I don't get it.
Why would anyone sell a hip
implant that could leak poison?
Imagine the lawsuits.
Oh, pennies to their profits.
The question is, how
does something this flawed
get FDA approval to begin with?
The 510 process. This
lets companies fast-track
a device, if a device is
similar to an existing device.
Which helps lifesaving
devices get on the market fast.
Even if that existing device
was recalled for defects.
Surely there are
protections in place
that stop people
from taking advantage.
Not when medical device
executives sit on the board
of the FDA.
The fox is guarding
the henhouse.
Well, let's focus
on what we can fix.
Mr. LeVasseur is going to need
a left ceramic on polyethylene
hip prosthesis to
get the metal poison
out of his system.
Does QuoVadis
carry one of those?
We do. I'll have it couriered.
Well, the good news is
when leaking metal
hips are replaced,
most patients
make a full recovery.
I don't think he'll ever
regain his eyesight.
No, but surgery will certainly
help all of his other problems.
If it doesn't kill him.
Atlanta was never
Priya's first choice,
but I'm finally feeling settled,
like my life is on track.
So move, or deal
with living apart.
You're not so great
at this, are you?
I'm exceptional at it, actually.
I made you face the
stark reality of your choice.
If you want hand-holding,
go elsewhere.
Well, Julian's got
a healthy pulse.
Her vitals are impressive.
You are taking stalking
to a whole new level.
I'm just testing
my device, Mina.
Hm. Keep telling yourself that.
- Is that our new hip?
- It is.
Safe and tested... Okay.
Is she always so...
Yeah, yeah. She's, uh,
she's very consistent.
So, how are my numbers?
Beautiful.
I mean, they're, you know...
They're-they're
good. They're great.
Your device is working.
So far, it is. But less coffee,
more water. You're
a little dehydrated.
So a fourth latte
is overdoing it?
Fourth?
Are you being serious?
Do not even judge. I saw
you in the residents' lounge,
chugging what I'm pretty
sure was a can of grape soda.
Okay, don't knock
it until you try it.
Oh, I tried it, when I was six.
All right, you know what?
The residents' lounge
is for residents,
not device reps, so...
Oh, so that's how
it's gonna be, huh?
Yeah, it's gonna
be just like that.
Okay.
I saw this really cute
apartment in Inman Park.
Landlord wanted a
cash deposit, so...
I'm too old to
live with my sister.
Way too old.
I shouldn't have lied to you
about Savannah. I'm sorry.
I just...
I wanted to show you I could
do something on my own.
I thought maybe
things could go back
to the way they were when...
- when we were close.
- Hey.
We're close now.
We're, like, too close.
You're like a barnacle.
Stop. It hurts.
- I'll be right back.
- Okay.
What's going on?
We have information on the drug.
It's an agonist for
the CD28 receptor.
So the drug targets the
immune system to fight cancer.
Kisic claims the participants
all have a massive infection.
Septic shock fits the symptoms.
I don't think it's septic shock.
I think it's a systemic
inflammatory response
from a cytokine storm.
There's no way to know for
sure. There's no quick test
for a cytokine storm.
They both have the
same presentation,
but cytokine is caused
by an immunotherapy drug.
If there is any hope
of stopping this
attack on their organs,
we need to at least
start John and Jessie
on high dose steroids now.
But if it is a
massive infection,
high dose steroids
could kill them.
We can't wait, we
have to act now.
My mom died from
a bad judgment call.
We need to be certain.
You know that's not possible.
My gut tells me this is right.
Okay.
So let's start steroid treatment
on John and Jessie,
with your permission.
And the others, we wait
until we know for sure
that you've made the right
call, and hope like hell it is.
Ernest can't make this decision.
You are his medical proxy.
Without the surgery,
how long does he have?
Another year, maybe, but
he will continue to deteriorate.
But the surgery
could kill him today?
Yes, but if he survives, he
can finally be himself again.
Janine?
I'm Korean.
He learned to speak Korean
so we could speak it together.
Ernest has always
been so romantic.
Don't cry.
Don't.
It's okay.
I said I couldn't stand to
take care of him anymore,
and now I can't
bear to lose him.
Will you both be in the surgery?
Oh, Dr. Okafor
will be assisting Dr. Voss,
who is an exceptional...
But-but what if something
happens with his weak heart?
I'll sign the consent form...
if you'll both be in
the room with him.
- Nic, I'm drowning.
- Your...
your lungs aren't
getting enough oxygen.
We're bringing in a
ventilator to help you breathe.
- Okay?
- I'll take it from here, Nic.
The steroids aren't working.
- What if it is sepsis?
- Steroids take time.
But, Nic, you know
there are no guarantees.
God, why did she do this?
We can't think
about that right now.
Nic.
If you have something
you need to say to Jessie...
now would be a good time.
Jessie, I need you
to be strong, okay?
I need you to fight for me.
All right? I'm
gonna be right here
- the whole time.
- Ready to intubate.
I love you, okay?
I'm right here.
Patient Ernest LeVasseur
in for a left hip revision.
One ceramic-on-polyethylene
hip device.
Left. Correct.
Time-out complete.
Surgical field prepped.
It's showtime, party people.
And don't worry, Dr. Voss.
I'm just here monitoring
Monsieur LeVasseur's poor heart.
I promised your resident
that I would be quiet.
It will be hard for him.
Let's relish it, ladies.
10 blade.
Dr. Okafor, retract the
subcutaneous tissue.
Retractors.
Oh, crap.
The metal particles have
caused the soft tissue
around the joint to harden.
When I cut into
it, it liquefies.
The necrotic tissue's completely
encompassing the hip joint.
Gross.
I-I've never seen...
anything like it.
Suction.
If you're going to
hurl, best to not do it
in a sterile environment.
I'll be right back.
What were you chopping?
Carrots.
They kind of
looked like my pinky.
Irving!
Somebody dying over here?
I only cut my pinky.
Wait, am I dying?
Take over for me.
Julian's having a heart attack.
You're not dying.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah.
I was just feeling faint.
The surgery... It
got kind of ugly.
Tachycardia.
Not a heart attack.
Safe to say
that my device overreacted.
Big-time.
It'll get there.
Thank you for checking on me.
Of course.
You should have
seen that hip implant.
That poor guy, his
whole life is ruined.
And who knows if it's
the same one that's in me?
You have to call your
ortho and find out.
I will.
Thank you, Devon.
Jessie's stable on the
vent and vasopressors.
That's...
That's good news.
Go to the lounge. Lie down.
I'll come get you if
anything changes.
Thank you.
She's gonna get better.
And I'm a thousand
percent not going river rafting
with Devon and Irving,
which means I'm here
and I'm here with you
and I'm here with Jessie.
I always thought, if we
ended up here, it would be
because of an
overdose, but a drug trial?
I can't even imagine how
difficult this must be for you.
He's in V tach.
Get a crash cart in here!
His pulse is thready.
I need one of epi
and an amp of bicarb.
Lost his pulse.
Starting compressions.
John got the steroids too late.
He was 30 years old.
His poor wife and little girl.
What if we didn't give
Jess the steroids on time?
She could be next.
Okay. I'll call you back.
This is unbelievable.
This is a disaster.
You can expect an
independent investigation.
- I am gonna have you...
- Of Chastain.
The wing you leased us
is clearly not up to code.
I would think hard before you
threaten us with malpractice.
A man is dead. A lawsuit is
the least of your problems.
You could be facing
manslaughter charges.
Me? He misdiagnosed
and didn't treat
for what they
actually have: sepsis.
We need to stop steroids
and start an aggressive
course of antibiotics.
Antibiotics alone
will kill them.
What we need to
do is up the steroids.
And when they
die, that's on you.
Just... give us a minute.
No, no, no. Uh-uh-uh-uh-uh.
I need to be privy to
any and all conversations.
Yeah. In your mind.
This is my hospital.
Back off.
So why, exactly, are you
so sure it's a cytokine storm?
Well, we've seen no improvements
in patients on
antibiotics alone.
We have seen some in Jessie
since we gave her the steroids.
And John was the first one
to get the drug, so
the cytokine storm
had already done
irreversible harm to his organs.
It wasn't that the steroids
were the wrong call.
It's that we were
too late for John.
- But maybe not for the others.
- And the longer we wait...
Yeah, the less likely
the steroids will work.
Hawkins, just try talking to me
like I've been
practicing medicine
for almost as long
as you've been alive.
It'll prove useful
in these situations.
All right.
Stay the course.
Up the steroids on Jessie.
Start steroids on the other two.
I'll handle Kisic.
- You okay?
- Yes.
My apologies. That's
never happened before.
Hey, things are a little
shaky over here, people.
This is taking way
too long for his heart.
The structural
damage is extensive.
Removing the old
acetabular component
took out some of the bone
and created pelvic discontinuity.
I'm not sure we're gonna be
able to complete the surgery.
So you're just going
to close him up?
We'll put in a
temporary spacer, close,
then open him up
again once we get
the proper revision components.
I did some research
before the surgery,
and I brought a triflange
cup as backup, just in case.
Yeah, that works.
It's not something we
typically stock, but... good call.
Glad you made
it back to join us.
Oh! Bloody hell.
The deteriorated hip
caused me to hit the
exterior iliac artery.
- Pressure's dropping fast.
- We need to repair the artery.
Austin, scrub in.
Not enough time.
Okafor is sterile.
I need you, not a
third-year resident.
I've converted a right ventricle
to the center ventricle in a
heart the size of a walnut.
Performed an emergency
tracheotomy in 30 seconds flat.
I'm not just any third-year.
What she said.
Suction.
Pressure's still dropping.
- We're losing him.
- Clamp.
There's too much damage.
It's too risky even to bypass it.
When I took over
and made the incision,
you put his life in my hands.
I can do it. I'll use the patch.
What she said.
Adele and Mauricio are
improving on the steroids.
We were right.
The trial drug caused
the cytokine storm.
Yeah, but Jessie isn't
getting much better.
She's breathing on her own,
but her kidneys
are getting worse.
She's in acute kidney failure.
We're gonna have
to put her on dialysis
- until her kidneys recover.
- Yeah, that's if they recover.
Hey.
Hey. Oh, my God, I
was so worried about you.
How's everybody else?
Mauricio and Adele
are doing great.
And John?
I'm so sorry, Jess.
Oh, no.
John didn't make it.
No, don't tell me that.
- No.
- I'm sorry.
No, no.
Is, uh... is this a bad time?
No.
I talked to my
orthopedic surgeon.
My hip isn't metal-on-metal.
It's safe.
It's tested. All good.
Well, that must
be a huge relief.
Yeah, but I just looked
up how many people
have metal-on-metal hips.
It's well over a million.
This is my industry.
How do I not know
this is going on?
It's impossible to know
everything we should know.
All we can do is
the best we can.
About earlier...
There are no excuses
for what I did, so I...
I pulled you into a dark room
and I threw my arms around you.
I'd say that we share the blame.
As far as I'm concerned,
what happened never happened.
Okay?
Could have been worse.
Not for John.
Every medicine,
surgical procedure
or intervention ever
prescribed or performed
is because of a clinical trial.
Without them, medicine
cannot advance.
Without them...
we'd still have polio.
But does everyone
who volunteers...
Do they understand the risk?
- They signed the forms.
- Because they're desperate.
They needed the money.
A student trying to
pay for his tuition,
underpaid schoolteacher,
recovering addict...
dad trying to provide
for his little girl.
And now...
that child has no father.
Mrs. Losurdo.
- Can I see John now? Is he okay?
- Would you like to sit down?
No, I... I-I want to
see John. How is he?
Well, when we spoke
earlier, on the phone,
John was already
experiencing serious side effects.
And during the course
of the day, he worsened,
and... although we
did everything we could,
we were unable to save him.
And he died a little while ago.
I don't understand
what you're talking about.
He was fine. When you
called me, he was fine.
No, he was already in distress.
Please, have a
seat. Have a seat.
- I'm sorry.
- Mom, is Dad okay?
Mom?
You know, John
always reminded me
to be grateful for the people
that don't give up on us.
Not every recovering addict
has that person, but I do.
And I am so grateful.
When the phone
rings at night, Jess,
my heart stops.
Is it gonna be
someone calling to say
that you're in trouble again
or that you're in jail?
Or dead?
So I hover.
And I worry.
And, yes, I do too much,
but here we are again.
You almost died today, Jess.
You got to start
making better choices.
I know.
You're right.
I promise I will
try to make sure
this is the last time that
you have to go through this.
So let's start now. Okay?
Get out of here.
Go sing and dance
and do whatever
the hell you want.
I'm safe.
And I'm gonna be okay.
- You're touching me.
- Mm-hmm.
- And you're smiling.
- Ah. Which is more offensive
- to your delicate sensibilities?
- What the hell are you doing?
I am guiding you toward victory.
You put together
a team of doctors.
You expertly
stepped up in the OR
to repair an
exterior iliac artery.
Mina, you saved Ernest's life.
Now, we do what we
do for moments like this.
So go ahead. Finish
the job, princess.
Don't call me princess.
Ernest should
make a full recovery.
In a few months, he may even
get his vision and hearing back.
His mind will clear.
He will barbecue again.
I'm sorry you both
had to go through this,
but it's over.
Thank you.
- Really, thank you.
- Oh, yes. Of course.
Thank you.
Hear us out: camping,
rafting isn't gonna happen
because we all realized
we don't really raft,
or do things outdoors that
involve water, animals or bugs.
I'm not even certain I can swim.
Well, I can swim, but
spending two hours in the car
with this guy, after this day,
is not my idea of a good time.
- So...
- Are you inviting yourselves
to girls' night?
Well, we're hoping
to get invited.
We'll be on our best behavior.
What if I don't want
your best behavior?
♪ Mailman, mailman ♪
♪ Tell me what
you got for me... ♪
What would you do if you were
no longer free to be a surgeon?
Uh, I don't know really.
Um...
a lumberjack?
Well, I have to
cut up something.
I miss the OR. I just
think about it all the time.
You've been kicked upstairs.
I moved myself upstairs,
and now it's just hell.
I'm trying to get back down.
Some days are
better than others.
Today... not one of them.
Sense a bit of a crisis here.
You know what would help?
Buy a Porsche.
It's parked outside.
- Sailboat, then.
- Just sold it.
High-end prostitute?
I won't judge.
I like you.
Even though you
are a bit of a bastard.
Cheers.
♪ Been looking
every which way... ♪
♪ Making love with
each other, ah-ha ♪
♪ Islands in the stream ♪
- Devon.
- ♪ That is what we are ♪
♪ No one in between ♪
- Yeah! Let's go.
- ♪ How can we be wrong? ♪
- Let's go, Devon.
- ♪ Sail away with me ♪
♪ To another world ♪
♪ And we rely on
each other, ah-ha ♪
You look...
Like I just had one of
the worst days of my life?
I was gonna say "amazing."
With a good outcome for Jessie.
This time.
♪ If the love was gone... ♪
Come back to me, Mina.
I hate working alone.
- You are never alone in the OR.
- Yeah, well,
without you, I am.
Say it.
- You are irreplaceable.
- Mm-mmm.
Mm, mm-mmm. Use
the bass in your voice.
Say it like you mean it.
You... are...
irreplaceable.
I'll work with you
and Dr. Voss.
I get to choose the
surgeries. And I get to cut.
The queen has spoken.
The king bows down.
You are no king,
and I am not your queen.
- I am your mentee.
- No.
You are my partner.
Speech!
Yes.
Everybody having
a good time tonight?
I hope so, because it
is a really great chance
to practice the wedding
dance. What do you all think?
Let's do it!
And, thankfully, a dancer
who is way better than me
helped me put this thing together,
and that is Julian Booth.
Let's do this!
Follow along.
You got it.
♪ ♪
All right!
Yeah!
That was... that was tough.
But amazing.
It really was.
Thank you.
♪ The garbageman
left all the trash... ♪
I guess, uh, it's a bad
idea for us to dance.
Just for tonight. Last dance.
♪ And the hinges
fell off of the gate ♪
♪ And this morning
at breakfast ♪
♪ Spilled all the coffee ♪
♪ And I opened the
door on my knee ♪
♪ Oh, the last thing I needed ♪
♪ The first thing this morning ♪
♪ Was to have you
walk out on me. ♪
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH