Previously on ER:
- You're a doctor?
- Yeah.
Yes, I am.
Leaving that stripper in 4
with the broken toe for you.
- Try not to T.U.B.E. her.
- What are you talking about?
Totally Unnecessary Breast Exam.
It's Sandy.
Sandy Lopez died today.
What am I supposed to do now?
Give me back my son!
Mom, guess what. Dad's here.
I don't like working on old
people or children or drunks.
Go to bloody Iraq and tell yourself
you've done something noble.
Hey. Hey, Mom.
Mom, look at this.
Hey, that's pretty good.
Dad's been teaching me, says
we might get my own guitar today.
Oh, really?
Alex, you want scrambled eggs?
- Sure.
Should have told me you needed
the groceries. I would have gone.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
- Mm-hm.
Listen, take this, okay?
What's this?
It's, you know, grocery
money, rent money, guilt money.
It's not much guilt.
There's more where this came from.
I got a few jobs lined up, and the...
There's something you need,
so I'm gonna leave this here.
What, like a guitar?
Why not? It's good for a
kid to learn an instrument.
I mean, music, it
stimulates the brain.
Yeah, prove it.
Well, it helps score the
hot chicks. That's for sure.
- Hey, Dad, teach me something else.
- All right, buddy. Here, let me see.
This one's a little trickier,
but it's very cool. You'll like it.
I've had pretty good luck
with this one with the ladies.
- Let go of me, you dirty freak!
- Calm down.
- No!
- Want Haldol?
Yes. That and a hammer.
- Need help, Morris?
- No, this is going great!
- Stop touching me!
- Relax.
- Just try and relax, Mrs. Garrison.
- You know her?
- Yeah, she's off her meds.
- You think?
Five or 10 of Haldol?
- Ten.
- Five.
Whatever.
All right, this is gonna sting
a little, Mrs. Garrison, okay?
Want hard restraints?
- No.
- Soft restraints?
No. No restraints.
She'll be fine.
Ah!
Guess you should've
put her in restraints.
Ah!
Their argument is Sandy was his
mother and you never legally adopted him.
- We were in the process.
- And that will help, perhaps.
If the child's genetic father was
willing to assign you his rights.
He was an anonymous donor.
Well, we will establish
parental intent.
And I'm confident we can
secure some temporary...
Temporary? Henry is my son.
The good news is that the state has
adopted a sexual-orientation-neutral...
approach to child-custody
determination. But...
there are other
factors at play here.
- Like what?
- In addition to being gay, you're single.
And your work requires a great
deal of time away from Henry.
Now, the Lopezes present a
blood relationship with a loving...
intact family unit and
a stay-at-home mom.
I'll change my schedule.
Hell, I'll quit my job if I have to.
- What happened to you?
- Bitten by a patient.
- What are you doing here?
- Working.
- Have a nurse look at that.
- It's okay.
Sam, wash out Dr. Kovac's
bite, update his tetanus...
and check for hepatitis
and HIV on the source.
- Sure.
- I'll call you. Let you know how it goes.
There's another difference between
Sandy's family and me: money.
And I'll use everything I
have to get my son back.
- Make sure they know that.
- I'll make them aware of that.
What are you doing?
Icing my nads.
- Excuse me?
- One of the patients grabbed my junk.
So Alex must be excited.
What?
Today is first day of
spring break, right?
Oh, yeah. Right.
You guys want to do
something after work?
He's been talking about this
rock-'n'-roll bowling alley with...
glow-in-the-dark
balls and lasers and...
We can't. Not tonight.
Alex's father is in town.
He just showed up.
- Oh.
- Yeah, he does this every now and then.
Usually without warning.
Kind of like a tornado.
I wish he'd just
stay away for good.
Oh, well. He's the boy's father.
Barely. He sticks around long enough
to run up my phone bill and drink my beer.
He's staying with you?
Somebody call for
a psych consult?
- You on Psych now?
- Yep. But don't worry...
I'm keeping an ID in my pocket in
case someone mistakes me for a patient.
That was a joke.
She's in the Suture Room.
- Give me the chart.
- It's my patient.
- Done an H & P?
- I pulled the chart.
- What are you doing?
- He's stealing my patient.
- What? I'm trying to help you.
- What are we talking about?
Back pain in 2.
- I'll settle this.
- You should be ashamed of yourselves.
Well, here's a beauty for
you. Blue and puking in 1.
Blue?
Mrs. Garrison, we're gonna take
you upstairs and get you lunch.
I'm really not hungry. Although I
wouldn't mind a nice glass of merlot.
See what I can do.
- I'll try to get her admitted.
- She'll be fine once she's on her meds.
- How's the Psych rotation?
- It's kind of scary.
- What? The patients?
- No, me. I like it.
How about you? Everything good?
Sam's ex-boyfriend's
back in town.
Hey, Abby.
Can you take
Mr. Chen here upstairs?
- If you want him in Psych.
- Don't tempt me.
Fall into outstretched
hand. Nothing serious.
It's his right arm, and now he won't be
able to do anything. Not that he would.
I've already been through
four home-care workers.
I can help you out.
Can't get more shifts. I need
money or I have to drop out of school.
Abby, you don't
want any of this.
- Coffee?
- Yeah. Good idea.
- So?
- So.
How's Kem? She
must be getting big.
- Very.
- You should see Susan.
How's she doing?
Well, you know how some
mothers talk to their unborn children?
Susan threatened to pull hers out
with her bare hand if it didn't hurry up.
Doing anything differently?
Exercise? Sports?
- No.
- Any heavy lifting? Help a friend move?
- Anything like that?
- No.
- Slip or fall recently?
- Nothing.
- I'm just checking your lymph node.
- I'm ticklish.
I'll make a note of that.
- You ever have a mammogram?
- No.
You do self breast exams?
- Sometimes.
- Hey, Sam. Can you give me a hand?
- I need a breast exam on Miss Campbell.
- Sure.
- You do? PRATT:
It's just routine.
You should do this every month.
You have to get to know your
breasts. You can't rely on friends.
- Right after your period is the best time.
- Blood bank's on six for you.
Thanks. PRATT: All right.
- This is Taggart. PRATT:
Look in the mirror...
- for any changes in shape...
- Yeah, I drew blood on Mendoza.
Then you lift up your
arm and do it again.
- I signed all of them.
- Okay?
Then you gently squeeze the
nipple to check for discharge.
- Okay.
- Now, you start by circling the nipple...
- moving out in larger circles.
- Okay, it's been busy down here.
Feeling for any lumps along
the way until you reach the edge.
He needs two units
typed and crossed.
Okay, lie down.
Feel the breast tissue beneath the skin...
- He's vomiting blood.
With a soft touch. And down to
the ribcage with a firmer touch.
From the collarbone to
the top of the abdomen...
and from the
armpit to the midline.
- Want me to come down?
- I don't appreciate any masses.
- That's good, right?
- It's perfect. You can sit up.
- Forget it. Just send two units O-neg.
- You should also do this in the shower.
The skin's a lot more slippery
when it's wet, and sometimes it helps.
Oh, make it stop! Oh,
please! Give me something!
- Connor, James. Passenger in an MVA.
- Oh, my God! Help me!
Car T-boned into
them pretty good.
- Give me something!
- Vitals?
He's been thrashing too much
for us to get a BP. No LOC.
Walking and
swearing on the scene.
Three-centimeter temporal
lac with some glass.
- My arm is killing me! Come on!
- The driver's right behind us.
- She got the worst.
- Where's Pratt?
- Right here.
- Okay, this guy is yours.
- All right.
- Neela, come with me.
Oh, my God!
- Seat belt, harness.
Air bag didn't deploy.
- Where do you hurt, ma'am?
- All over.
- What happened, man?
- We were driving...
and some guy blindsided us.
Oh, God! Oh, God! Save my arm!
- Save my arm!
- You're not gonna lose your arm, sir.
- Is she your girlfriend? JAMES:
No, man. I just met her last night.
She was driving me home from
her place. I should have taken a cab.
Closed deformity on the
right elbow. He's dislocated.
- No radial pulse. 100 of Brevital.
- Brevital?
Yeah, and 100 of fent. All
right. Just hang in there, okay?
We're gonna fix
this up real quick.
- What do we want?
- Trauma panel, HemoCues and x-rays.
- Want me to guess?
- Chest, C-spine, pelvis.
- Thank you.
- I'm gonna be sick.
- On the monitor. Get suction.
- Periumbilical ecchymosis.
- Pretty tender in the upper right.
- Systolic's 90. First HemoCue's 11.
- My head feels funny.
- Okay, get another line.
Already done with
a liter onboard.
- Is Dr. Pratt working?
- Next door.
Two units of O-neg
on the rapid infuser.
Can you get him?
- Tachy at 118.
- She's gonna crash.
Get a seven and a half.
I need the ultrasound.
- I'll get it. KOVAC:
Somebody call Surgery again.
- Brevital's in.
- It's not helping! It's not...!
- Thank God.
- All right. We got about 20 seconds.
- Pull.
- Dr. Pratt, this patient's asking for you.
- For me?
- He's waking up.
Almost there.
- What happened?
- We fixed your elbow.
Holy crap, you're good.
You can pick up your Dr. Greg
Pratt Fan Club ring at the door.
Barely holding at a 100
systolic. Blood's running.
- Hypoechoic in Morrison's.
- How are we doing in here?
- Greg, is that you?
- Yeah.
Foley is on. Blood on the dip.
- What's the name on the chart?
- Rena Carlson.
We hooked up last year.
We met on the El, remember?
Oh, yeah. Right.
Make sure the blood
bank gets a clot.
Let's drop an NG
tube and pack her up.
Rena, you injured your spleen.
You're gonna require surgery to repair it.
- God. I'm all messed up.
- No, you're gonna be okay.
We're gonna take
very good care of you.
Abby.
- Hi.
- I see Mrs. Garrison is back.
Yeah. She bit one of
the Attendings in ER.
Oh, well, better
them than one of us.
- Mr. Rosenblum was asking for you.
- Oh, great.
Take it as a compliment.
Took me two years before
the duke would even talk to me.
Maybe it's your
nursing background.
It's probably a combination
of nursing and genetics.
My family's pretty
high-maintenance.
You can lead the group today.
- By myself?
- No better time than the present.
Okay.
Hi. Hi.
I'm Abby. I'm a medical student, I'm
going to be running the group today.
Ow!
Elbow's good. Sutures
will come out in a week.
But the Ortho clinic will wanna get
some more x-rays and start you on P.T.
So does that mean I can go?
You're not gonna
stick around for her?
- Like I said, I just met her.
- You spent the night together.
That don't make us married.
What's the status?
Stable after four units of
packed cells and some fluid.
Corday's waiting
for her upstairs.
I have to have an operation.
Don't worry. Dr. Corday's
an excellent surgeon.
- Will you come see me after?
- Sure.
- Friend?
- Not really.
Could you let me
know how she does?
- Okay.
- Thanks.
Labs and films on Campbell.
Sussman is starting to get
short-term memory back.
Thanks.
Neela.
- Neuro checks on Mr. Sussman Q hour.
- Can't. Working in the lab.
- Doing what?
- Stroke physiology research.
- Going to the mouse house?
- It's an elective.
I'm doing a lousy job. Everyone
thinks I'm better suited for the lab.
Yeah, well, God forbid
you disappoint them.
Hello. I'm sorry
this is taking so long.
- Yeah.
- So, what's going on with you, Denise?
I've just... I've been feeling cruddy,
like sick to my stomach and headaches.
At first I thought
it was the flu...
till I started losing feeling
in my hands and feet.
So you're not here
because of your skin?
No, that's from the amiodarone.
I have a ventricular arrhythmia.
Pretty sad, huh?
You know what the
guys at school call me?
Smurf.
Everything looks good. No
fractures, no arthritis, no bony lesions.
I'm thinking it's
just muscle strain.
But I told you I
didn't do anything.
Maybe you didn't realize it. It
may not have been sudden strain.
You could have slept
funny or been sitting too long.
- That's it?
- Yeah. It should get better with time.
Try a warm bath
and some ibuprofen.
Come back and see
me if it gets worse...
or you feel numbness
or weakness in your legs.
- Yo, doc.
- Excuse me.
Twenty-nine-year-old
with syncopal episode.
- Housekeeper found her in the kitchen.
- She on meds?
- Not that we could find.
- Neela.
Ma'am, can you hear me? Ma'am?
All right, let's get
her in Trauma 1.
Excuse me. Could I speak
with someone in charge?
What do you need?
Would it be possible to speak
with Dr. Pratt's supervisor?
Yeah. Okay.
What are you doing
here? Where's Alex?
- Thought I'd take you to lunch.
- Where's Alex?
He's showing one of
the doctors his guitar.
- Was this a bad idea?
- I can't leave for lunch.
- I asked Alex. He said it'd be all right.
- He's 10.
Hey, Mom, look. He did it.
Dad said he'd buy
me a guitar and he did.
- So I see.
- This is my dad.
Hi.
Isn't it cool?
- Do you know how to play, Luka?
- No.
Well, my dad's in a band.
- Your old lady stopped breathing again.
- It was nice meeting you.
You too.
Some gal stopped
breathing, can't be good.
People die in here all
the time. It's no big deal.
He already sounds
like a doctor. It's great.
You gonna play something for me?
Fainted and altered.
We're looking for?
- Normal sinus. Not having an MI.
- Think about the differential.
No ectopy, interval isn't
prolonged, QRS duration is 0.10.
Normal.
Pupils equal and reactive.
The common pathway in syncope?
Low blood pressure.
Don't hear a murmur.
No. Lack of vital-nutrient delivery to
the brainstem reticular activating system.
Caused by low blood pressure.
Or hypoxia or hypoglycemia.
Abdomen is soft and non-tender.
- So, what are we ordering, kids?
- CBC, lytes, head CT.
And a urine tox screen. And call a family
member to verify she's not on any meds.
What meds cause
orthostatic hypotension?
Antihypertensives. Beta-blockers,
Dig, diuretics, phenothiazines, nitrites...
antidysrhythmics, antidepressants,
alcohol and cocaine.
You know, we don't have to do this
if you've got something better to do.
I've got the papers here. I'm gonna be
stuck at the hospital for a couple hours.
Is there any way you can
have a notary come here?
That'd be great. Thank you.
Carter, I'm so sorry I stranded
you here. They're gonna admit him.
So I can drive you home.
I arranged for somebody to come
here with papers for me to sign.
I gotta be at work
soon. I'm just gonna stay.
I just ruined your
whole day, didn't I?
Don't worry. Know
what you can do?
You can help me
pick out nursery colors.
What do you think? Circus: colorful,
fun, developmentally stimulating.
Aquatic: soothing yet educational,
sort of for the young scientist. Or jungle:
Environmentally positive, a
celebration of his African heritage.
If you had a baby, which wou...?
I like the jungle.
I'm sorry. I wasn't
even thinking.
Carter, no. It's okay.
Don't worry about it.
You know, sometimes I
forget about him myself.
That's when I feel the worst...
when I realize that I haven't thought
about him in, like, a week or so.
You know, ever since my...
mom died and
my dad got sick, I...
I've been thinking
about him a lot.
You know, when my dad goes,
I'm not gonna have anyone else.
No aunts, cousin...
Nothing.
Have you ever gone to see him?
Maybe you should.
Maybe I should have kept him.
I mean, he is 3 years old now.
The nightmares have stopped,
but I feel like killing myself.
- So, what else is new?
- I smell something.
I can't smell anything. I developed
anosmia after my accident.
Nobody accidentally puts
their head in a paint mixer.
- Let's let Larry finish.
- Why?
It's the same thing every week.
"I wanna kill myself." Blah,
blah, blah. He needs new material.
- You need a soul.
- Please stop fighting.
- What's he saying?
- No one here speaks Klingon.
- It's rather odd, don't you think?
- Yeah. No. No.
- I think we should take a minute.
- Where did you go to school?
What?
I'm going to school.
I wanna be a lawyer.
Last week he wanted
to be a lion-tamer.
At least he has goals beyond
how many women he can screw.
- You jealous?
- Hey. Okay, okay.
You're a pig. - Oink.
Stanley, if you continue
to disrupt the group...
I'm gonna have
to ask you to leave.
- That's good.
- "That's good. It's what you should do."
- Can we all get along?
- Is it just me or are we kooky?
- I smell gas.
- Sit down.
When I'm a lawyer,
I'm suing the hospital.
Can't sit on a jury with
multiple-personality disorder.
Does anyone else smell gas?
- It's coming from Larry.
Why don't you shut up.
You cut yourself,
start with your tongue.
Leave her alone. You have
nothing inside, dirty person.
Nothing inside you...
You make everybody sick.
Hey. Hey!
No.
You can't smoke in
here. It's against the law.
- So is suicide.
- You've got an addiction.
- Well, I'm trying to quit.
- I'm allergic to smoke.
Only takes 11 seconds for
nicotine to reach your brain.
There are 50 different kinds
of carcinogens in cigarettes.
You better put that out
before somebody catches you.
Stanley, what about you? Do
you have a problem with this?
My mother died of lung cancer.
It's a nasty habit.
Well, now that we've all
agreed on something...
let's talk about personal goals.
I don't wanna make a big deal.
He just made me feel uncomfortable.
- How so?
- He did a breast exam, and...
I don't know, he
seemed to enjoy it.
- Was there a nurse present?
- Yes.
It was her.
Did you voice your
concerns to Dr. Pratt?
No. I guess I was
caught off guard.
I can assure you he's a
very professional physician.
However, if you want to
file a formal complaint...
Oh, no, no. I don't want to
make a big deal out of this.
I just felt I should tell someone.
Maybe they could speak with him?
- I'll speak to him.
- Thank you.
Where's Pratt?
- With a patient. What do you need?
- I need Pratt. Where are you going?
I'm going to grab a bite
with Alex and his dad.
Did you assist Dr. Pratt in examining
Campbell, the woman in Curtain 2?
- Yeah.
- Anything unusual about the exam?
- I don't think so. Why?
- He gave her a breast exam for back pain.
I don't know what
her complaint was.
I was on the phone and
juggling other patients.
- Sounds like he T.U.B.E.D. her.
- She wasn't intubated, Morris.
No, no. You know,
T.U.B.E. T-U-B-E.
- Totally Unnecessary Breast Exam.
- You're such an ass.
- What was that?
- Sorry.
No, not you. Where
did you hear that term?
I don't know. I
didn't make it up.
Well, who did?
What happened?
Where's my daughter?
Your daughter's with your
neighbor. My name is Dr. Pratt.
You fainted at home. But
all your tests look good.
We checked your heart,
lungs and your brain.
You're not anemic or dehydrated.
And all your electrolytes are normal.
- I feel fine.
- Are you taking any medications?
- No.
- Could be anything over the counter.
- Diet pills, cold medicine.
- Nothing.
You ever have any heart problems?
Palpitations? Shortness of breath?
I'm healthy.
Anyone in your family
ever have seizures?
I did when I was a kid,
but I grew out of them.
How long ago was your last one?
I don't know. Years and years.
I was on phenobarb
until, like...
fifth grade. They said I had epilepsy.
But when I stopped the medicine...
they went away. I never had
another one. That was 20 years ago.
- Dr. Pratt, can I see you for a second?
- Just give me a minute.
- Can I go home now?
- I need you now.
- All right, I'll be right back.
- I have a baby at home.
I just need to run a
few more tests, okay?
Here. What's up?
- Did you treat this patient?
- Yeah. Why?
She accused you of
sexual harassment.
What?
- Did you T.U.B.E. her, Pratt?
- What?
That's what you call it, isn't it, when
you wanna feel up a good-looking patient?
If she hires a lawyer, you could
be charged with harassment.
If I found a lesion, I
would've saved her.
You didn't.
I'm being punished
because she's not sick?
It's not her condition,
it's your behavior.
Nothing's wrong
with my behavior.
She had tenderness over the fourth and
fifth lumbar vertebrae. Bony tenderness.
None over the paraspinus muscles. I felt
a 1-centimeter lymph node in the axilla.
- You saying you weren't attracted to her?
- Oh, come on.
Bone pain and lymphadenopathy in a
woman who's never had a mammogram?
You would've done the same.
It's not about what
you did, it's how.
- With a nurse present, per policy.
- The patient felt you enjoyed yourself.
Come on, please.
Give me a break?
You ever got turned on
giving a breast exam?
You don't have a
nurse in the room.
- I'm a woman.
- Who sleeps with women.
- I never T.U.B.E.D. a patient.
- Yeah? Neither have I.
- You coined the phrase.
- It's been around since I was a student.
You've been overheard using it.
It doesn't mean I've done it.
If she was uncomfortable,
why not say something?
I don't know. Maybe she
was intimidated by you.
Scared the big black doctor's
gonna bend over the bed...
Don't you turn this
into a race issue.
When you're black,
it's always an issue.
- I'm not gonna let you hide.
- I'm not hiding.
- A call for you.
- Take a message.
- It's your lawyer, line four.
- Don't go anywhere.
- Where's Sam?
- I think she's with her son.
Hey, Dr. Pratt, Neela's
patient collapsed.
She was coming
back from the restroom.
Hey, ma'am. Can you hear
me? Somebody find Neela!
Let's get her up on the gurney,
okay? Ready? One, two...
- Malik, monitors.
- Positive sternotomy sign.
- What happened?
- V-tach.
Ventricular arrhythmia.
On amiodarone.
- "Tetralogy of Fallot repaired in 1975."
- Why is she in today?
- Flu.
- What's her lab show?
- Haven't come back.
- Need hands?
Did you open your
big mouth to Weaver?
What? NEELA: Airway clear.
Start bagging. Did you tell
Weaver I T.U.B.E.D. a patient?
V-tach, no pulse.
Denise, stay with us.
Charge to 200.
MALIK: I'm charged.
- Clear.
- No change.
Going again, 300. Well, did you?
- No.
- Somebody did, though.
Clear.
Sinus. NEELA:
Good carotid pulse.
100 of lidocaine.
What'd you say?
Nothing. That hot patient
was complaining about you.
Good breath. I'll
call about her labs.
Perhaps you two referring
to a patient as "hot" is a clue.
I never called her that.
She's the one with problems.
Can you even imagine what it
was like for her to come here?
Feeling ill, worried, scared.
Waiting several hours to be seen...
- only to have a stranger fondle her.
- Secondary survey.
Good gag. She's waking up.
You're okay, Denise. - Labs?
CBC, electrolytes,
calcium, LFTs, creatinine.
Labs report her amiodarone
level less than zero.
She sometimes
forgets to take it.
Must have stopped taking
it weeks ago to have zero.
She give you any
indication why she'd do that?
Maybe. Because men are idiots.
- Can I play pinball?
- Sure.
Finish your lunch first.
I'm full.
- Barely touched your hamburger.
- I don't wanna get mad cow disease.
Then finish your fries.
God, he's grown a foot
since I've seen him last.
Been a year.
You've done a great job, Sam.
He's a cool kid.
Thanks.
I guess I can't take
much credit for that.
- Anyway, is he doing good in school?
- Yeah.
When he's not being expelled...
for performing medical
procedures on himself or...
- dissecting dead squirrels.
- Really?
It's not funny.
He seems to like
that Russian doctor.
Croatian.
You two...?
We've gone out. Nothing serious.
He have any friends his own age?
- He's got some buddies at school.
- That's good.
Considering how much you
move around, that's good.
Well, you gotta go
where the work is, right?
Tell me about it. That's the
good thing about Chicago.
- Always building...
- How long are you planning on staying?
You sick of me already?
It's not about me.
It's about Alex.
Well, he seems
happy that I'm back.
That's the problem.
The longer you stay, the harder
it's gonna be on him when you leave.
Well, maybe I
won't leave this time.
What's going on
with Hollings in 2?
Cardiology was
supposed to get him.
Call them again. What
about Dunn in Exam 3?
Some recurrent seizure
disorder. Waiting on an EEG.
They can do that upstairs.
We need to free up some beds.
- Medicine won't take her.
- Why not Neurology?
They don't think
she had a seizure.
Was there witnessed
tonic-clonic activity?
- Not really.
- Did she bite her tongue?
- No.
- Was there urinary incontinence?
- I don't think so.
- Not a seizure.
Discharge her, she
can have an EEG.
If she passes out,
she could hurt herself.
Send in a DMV card.
There's also a baby at
home who could get hurt.
Look, she had a syncopal episode.
And I'm gonna rule her out for MI.
While we wait for the six-hour troponin,
we might as well throw in an EEG.
Dr. Pratt, Denise's parents
are coming in to talk to her.
Her cardiologist's gonna switch her
to sotalol which should help the skin.
Hey, Neela, when does
your research rotation start?
- Fifteen minutes.
- Good luck.
Thank you, Dr. Kovac.
- Let me ask you a question.
- Yeah?
When you do a breast exam on an
attractive woman, it's awkward, right?
- For you and the patient.
- Right.
See, I'm just as nervous
and uncomfortable as they are.
I don't know. Maybe it comes
across as something else.
What do you mean?
How do you do it so that they don't
think that you're enjoying yourself?
It's a medical procedure.
It's no different than looking
for rebound or guarding.
I pretend it's my mom.
Yeah, it's a little trick I picked up
from my OB-GYN Attending. It works.
I mean, unless
your mom's hot too.
You're a freak.
Every workstation has its own
microfuge. We share the ultracentrifuge.
Cold room for tissue-culture
media, bacterial plates, DNA ligations.
Arun and Angelie are
looking at expression of...
heat-shock proteins in
glial cells. This is Neela.
Hi. Is that an
electron microscope?
Yeah.
EM's kind of old school for showing
apoptosis in neurons, but, you know...
looks sexy on the page,
so Lundgren still likes it.
- Lundgren?
- Dr. Lundgren, the guy whose huge...
R01 grant is funding your butt.
I'm not getting paid. Rotation.
Fourth-year med student.
- I'm an eighth-year, Ph.D. program.
- Eight years? God.
We don't get credit around
here for wiping snotty noses.
I've actually gotta discover
something new in neuroscience...
in order to get my degree.
- Takes a while.
- I'm helping with some stroke study?
Everyone here is
researching some aspect...
of brain hypoperfusion
and tissue injury.
You're gonna be
with Yuri and me.
Looking at the
effects of ketamine...
on cerebral ischemia
and tissue damage in mice.
- Yuri, Neela. Neela, Yuri.
- Hey.
No one said anything
about working with animals.
Is that a problem?
All tests look good. We'd like to
figure out why she had a seizure.
Yeah. I thought that was
something she outgrew as a kid.
It may be totally
unrelated. Here we go.
What's all of that?
We're doing an EEG to monitor
her electrical brain activity.
It takes several hours, some
of which is done while sleeping.
- Can I stay with her?
- Sure. Just try not to wake her up.
We're more likely to pick up
the seizures when she's asleep.
Thank you. You hear that?
We're gotta let your mama sleep.
Hey. You know...
when I ask you to assist
me on an exam of a female...
it's so I don't get accused
of things I didn't do.
Don't blame me for this.
You were there. I did everything
I could to put that patient at ease.
- Guess it didn't work.
- I was trying to be friendly.
One man's friendly is
another woman's creepy.
- You're a flirt. You can't help yourself.
- I was breaking the ice.
It's a breast exam, not a cocktail
party. You don't have to break the ice.
- Nice package, by the way.
- What?
Package. Amira and I were
noticing it earlier. Must be those pants.
I see what you're trying
to do. You're way off.
I didn't say anything remotely
inappropriate to that woman.
- It was going through your head.
- It wasn't.
You weren't thinking about her
great rack when examining her?
Hell, no. And even if I was,
which I wasn't, so what?
- She can't read my mind.
- Of course she can. We all can.
It's not that difficult,
believe me. You're a guy.
Men only think about three
things: food, sports and sex.
Dogs are more mysterious.
If they invent a refrigerator with
a wide-screen TV and a vagina...
- we're all doomed.
- Yeah, okay.
You think I'm kidding, but I'm
not. When you check us out...
you're asking us to show
our tits. That's what it feels like.
- It's not a nice feeling.
- I didn't check her out.
Dr. Pratt, your
patient's seizing again.
All right, find Kovac.
- Jordan?
- Push two of Ativan.
- I knew it.
- Pulse ox, 97.
- Up the nasal oxygen to five liters.
- What's happening to her?
Malik, another two of
Ativan. Mix up Dilantin.
She's gonna be okay. Give
the medicine a chance to work.
How long has she been seizing?
- Less than a minute.
I stepped out for a second.
It's okay. It's okay, Jordan.
It's okay. You're okay.
- Caught the seizure on the EEG.
- Is this just gonna keep happening?
She needs anticonvulsant medication.
After that, everything should be fine.
- See any spikes?
- Not yet.
- Can she hear me?
- Sure, you can talk to her.
- She's not gonna be awake for a while.
- Hey, sweetie, it's me.
I'm here with Caroline.
Everything's gonna be okay.
You're doing good.
- Dr. Pratt?
- I'll be right back. She's gonna be fine.
Looks like Neurology can't
refuse to admit her now.
- That wasn't a real seizure.
- What are you talking about?
The EEG doesn't lie.
No focal spikes, no sharp waves,
and no spike-wave complexes.
She's faking it.
She had a pseudo-seizure.
Call Psychiatry.
- I learned a little Klingon.
- That's good.
We had to get rid of
our Klingon translator...
in the most recent
round of budget cuts.
You're serious?
My buddy's hospital in Seattle had to
hire someone who speaks Elven full-time.
Thank you, Mr. Tolkien.
- That was an interesting approach today.
- Yeah. I'm sorry.
Look, I know it's cruel throwing
students into a group like that.
But it is a good indicator
of who has what skills.
I was kind of freaked out.
I've never seen them respond to
a student the way they did to you.
Of course, they've
never seen anyone...
show as much disregard
for hospital policy.
I think you scared them.
You kind of scared me.
- I am being paged to the ER.
- Yeah. We could try hypnosis.
- On who?
- You. It might help you quit smoking.
I'll get back to you on that.
I told her to look for any changes
in the shape or size of the breast.
And I felt for any lumps.
I told her to watch out for
dimpling or puckering. This is stupid.
Continue.
I told her to check for discharge.
Then gently squeeze the ni...
Jerry.
I can't help it. My
nipples are sensitive.
- What?
- Your lawyer, Mr. Brooks, is here.
- Excuse me.
- So are we done here?
I want you to prep a lecture
for the med students...
on gender sensitivity in
the physical examination.
Abby's down from
Psych for your patient.
- Pardon me.
- Yeah.
Do you mind?
Bored yet?
Actually, I find it
extremely interesting.
I prefer working with
empirical data over patients.
- Not a people person?
- Not when they're sick.
- Watch it! Ugh!
- Sorry.
- You contaminated my ELISA.
- Shouldn't have coffee in the lab.
I always have coffee in the lab.
- You just ruined my sample.
- Do you have to rerun it?
I can't. I don't
have any serum left.
You just set us back six weeks.
- Maybe she's faking it.
- Not if it's a conversion reaction.
Nothing on the EEG.
Doesn't mean her symptoms
are under voluntary control.
Whatever's happening is
on a subconscious level...
maybe due to some sublimated
emotional trauma or something.
Would you listen to Miss Freud
here? Okay. What are we talking about?
- Postpartum depression?
- Maybe.
In some, it can turn
into full-blown psychosis.
- Hey, where are you going, Mrs. Dunn?
- Home.
Miss Dunn, hi. I'm Abby
Lockhart from Psychiatry.
I already told him I
don't need a shrink.
I have to go. My
husband's waiting for me.
Jordan, if you don't
stay, we can't help you.
That was my easiest
consult all day.
- Get your prescription filled,
Mrs. Epstein. EPSTEIN: Thank you.
- Hey.
- I got these back today.
Oh, my God. Look at you guys.
You can keep those.
I got double prints.
- Thanks.
- Good night.
Luka.
I didn't know he was coming.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Hey. How did Rena
Carlson make out?
MVA, came up for an ex-lap.
She had a lot of clot in the
belly. We took out the spleen.
- What about the liver?
- Good. Mesenteric arteries are fine.
Kidneys too. She's a lucky girl.
She should be awake
by now. I think she's in 10.
Thanks.
You working banker's hours now?
Hardly. I only stepped out of surgery
once today and that was to pee.
I'm sorry to hear that,
for you and your bladder.
Are you up for some dinner?
- Tonight I can't.
- You can't eat?
- Not with you.
- Oh, really?
What's wrong?
Who's that? A patient?
- It's difficult to talk about.
- Sounds serious.
It could be. I still
have some tests to run.
- Anything I can do to help?
- No, nothing. I think I'd better go.
- Hey.
- Oh, what are you doing here?
- I thought I'd surprise you.
- Well, you certainly did.
Hey.
Dr. Jeremy Lawson,
Mr. David Spencer.
Mr. Spencer.
- How's it going?
- It's going very well, thank you.
Have a good evening, Dr. Corday.
It was nice meeting you.
- What's with the James Bond routine?
- He's English.
Oh, that's nice.
- A little taste of home?
- Hm.
Dr. Weaver, sorry to bother you.
If I don't get more nursing shifts...
I'm not gonna be able to
pay for my spring tuition.
You okay?
Why don't you take some time off?
You need to give yourself time to grieve.
I don't have that luxury.
I lost my wife. Now I'm
fighting to keep my son.
I'm sorry.
Been begging and arguing with lawyers
all day to get Henry for the weekend.
And they're granting
me two days with my son.
Well, if there's
anything I can do...
Thank you. And don't
worry about your tuition.
- It's been paid.
- What?
Yeah. The registrar said it's
been paid through graduation.
I'm sorry. You
need to sign this.
- What is it?
- It's a visitation agreement.
Basically, it says you'll return Henry
to the Lopezes by Monday at noon.
Hey, baby.
Hi. Hello, baby.
There you are. Oh, how are you?
He's been a little fussy.
Maybe he's teething.
Yeah, I don't think so.
It's too early. Isn't it?
You don't have any teeth, do
you? You just miss your mommy.
- That's my baby.
- Not all of us think like my parents do.
They're pretty old-fashioned.
I know Sandy would be pissed
if she knew what was happening.
She'd be cursing up a storm.
I know she'd want you
and Henry to be together.
I hope it works out for
the two of you, that's all.
Thank you.
Thank you. That's my boy.
That's my beautiful baby.
- What?
- What are you doing?
- Waiting for an ambulance.
- Carter.
- What?
- I'm not taking your money.
- What are you talking about?
- You know.
- I'm not one of your charities.
- I was hoping to count you as a friend.
Well, neither a
borrower nor a lender be.
Abby, I'm not loaning you
the money, I'm giving it to you.
Think of it as an investment
in the future of medicine.
You'd be better
off with tech stocks.
In the time that it's taken
us to have this conversation...
I've made your salary for
the rest of your life in interest.
When you put it that way, how about
a couple extra grand for a new car?
You can't park here. This is
where we bring ambulances.
He's with me.
And I will pay you back.
You know, you both
should be wearing helmets.
My throat hurts.
It's from being intubated.
I didn't think you'd come.
I said I would.
I think you said
you'd call me too.
Well, this place
keeps me pretty busy.
You don't remember
me, do you, Greg?
That's okay.
Is there anybody
you'd like me to call?
My mom lives in Detroit.
Her last name's Henderson.
Julie Henderson.
I'll write the number
down if you've got a pen.