I ought to have this framed.
My last bill from Princeton.
And I thought we
were celebrating
the fact that I
actually graduated.
I always knew you'd
be able to graduate.
What I didn't know was whether
I would be able to pay for it.
Your mom, she'd
be so proud of you.
You always say that.
I'm so proud of you. Always was.
Come on, Dad, you're gonna cry.
You wanna be
embarrassed? You got it!
Look, don't party
too hard tonight.
Your grandmother wants a
picture of you getting that sheepskin,
and it'd be nice if you didn't
look completely hung over.
Oh, no, don't worry,
I've had enough
alcohol in the past week
to last me another four years.
Good, I think.
Drink! Drink! Drink!
More! More! Drink! Drink! Drink!
12:55!
Man!
You are the man! Tell
me something I don't know!
Hey, that's not
funny, man. What?
Yeah, right, you shocked
me. With what? I got nothing.
Well, hey, whoever's
doing that better cut it out!
What the hell's going on?
Maybe there's a short somewhere,
the floor's covered with beer.
No way, no, the outlets are GFI,
plus he's got
rubber-soled shoes on.
- Oh, my God!
- Somebody call 911!
Patient experiences
shock-like sensations
as well as headaches,
nausea, and drowsiness.
Shocks?
Excruciatingly painful shocks.
ER docs referred
him to a neurologist,
who referred him to five other
doctors in the last seven days.
Shocks could be Lhermitte's
sign. Early symptom of MS.
No. MRI showed no
white matter lesions,
and the shocks aren't
accompanied by neck flexing.
Good morning! It's almost noon.
Really? That must
be why I'm so hungry.
Who's up for lunch?
What's with the jacket?
It keeps me warm and
cool. How does it know?
We're discussing
your new patient.
Must be a boring discussion, seeing
as I haven't accepted a new patient.
You accepted him the
moment I loaned you 5 grand.
Oh, wait, wait.
When I said I'd do anything for
the money, obviously I didn't mean it.
You're gonna like this. The kid's
getting shocked every few minutes.
Why would you need $5,000?
Bad night at poker, or
great night with a hooker?
Thank you for
saving me the trouble
of deflecting that personal
question with a joke.
College student?
Nitrous oxide's fun at parties.
Caused the shocks, and
drinking till we puke every night
can cause everything else.
Give him some B12.
Been there, done that.
Also ruled out cancer,
MS, pyridoxine toxicity,
and all the popular
neuropathies.
Cervical spondylosis. Doesn't
explain the low white count.
He's black.
I'm assuming he's not just really
dirty, but is of African descent,
which means he'd
have a lower white count.
Not this low. He's a wrestler.
Probably uses
diuretics to cut weight.
That can also cause
low white count.
Not this low. "Not this low."
Behcet's. No skin lesions.
Cervical herpes zoster,
myelitis... No external outbreak.
Something's missing.
Find out what it is.
I don't even know what
that means. Well, figure it out.
Find it out, and then
find me. I'll be at lunch.
- No ideas?
- Lots of ideas.
Too many ideas, that's
why so many tests.
Have you used any
recreational drugs?
What? I'm gonna get mad
at you for getting stoned?
Not today, not here.
At Christmas, one of the
guys had some ecstasy,
I mean, I... It was...
Son of a bitch!
ANA is negative
for lupus, again.
House wants more information, not
the same information done over again.
"Find what's missing."
For all we know, the kid is
dying and he's giving us riddles?
Did a more detailed history,
went back three generations.
And? His mom died
in a car accident,
his mom's mom had arthritis,
and his mom's mom's dad
served in an all-black
tank battalion under Patton.
Fascinating. If it's not a
tumor, it has to be MS.
Wilson already ruled out...
MRI can't rule out
MS 100% of the time.
MS doesn't explain the low
white count. Alcoholism does.
On admission, his BAC was
2.0, liver enzymes off the chart.
It was graduation weekend. He
barely drank in the weeks before that,
and he didn't drink at all
during his wrestling season.
If you believe him.
I did a tox screen...
It doesn't matter if she believes
him or not, it's already in the chart.
We're supposed to
find out what's missing.
Well, this... This is perfect.
Invite me to dinner
on Thursday night.
Come on, we haven't had
a nice meal together since...
Yesterday, when I loaned
you $5,000 to buy a new car.
My treat.
Two-wheeled vehicles
that travel 150 miles an hour
don't really go well with crippled,
irresponsible drug addicts.
Actually, two-wheeled vehicles that
go 180 miles an hour do not go well
with healthy,
responsible architects
who don't know how to
separate braking and turning.
Good news is, it brings
the price right down.
You're taking it back. Mom!
How about we talk about this over dinner?
Forget dinner, you're gonna kill yourself!
Nice bike! Thank you.
See, that's how you do
it. Compliments, dinner.
What do you do with your cane?
If he buys me
dinner, he'll find out.
Evel Knievel had the same setup.
And he broke every
bone in his body.
We went through all the imaging
studies and redid the blood cultures.
I don't want hand-me-downs,
I want brand-new stuff.
Well, there's nothing...
There's nothing missing!
Sorry, I didn't
catch that last part!
There's... There's...
There's nothing else we can do.
Did you check the
police report? On what?
On his mom's car accident.
That was 15 years ago.
The kid wasn't even in the car.
She veered off a straight,
dry road in broad daylight.
That doesn't seem odd to you?
She probably got distracted
changing radio stations or something.
That's what the police thought.
Of course, they didn't know
that she has a family member
who is frequently incapacitated
by shock-like sensations.
A genetic component seems
unlikely. But it's interesting.
Type II neurofibromatosis
could cause the shocks.
You knew this was missing?
I knew something was missing,
maybe this, maybe something else.
Get a DNA analysis of the
long arm of chromosome 22.
You'd rather have dinner
with your wife? Yes, I would.
If she were speaking to me.
Unlike her, I could
make it worth your while.
Fine.
Shall I drive?
No.
And I'm not letting you in
my car until I see your wallet.
NF2. It's an inherited disease.
It could cause abnormal
growths on the cranial nerves.
It would explain the
shocks and other symptoms.
DNA analysis will
show whether your son
has the specific
chromosome mutation
which causes the disease.
But if it's inherited, that means
someone else in our family would have it.
We think your wife
may have had it.
No. She never had any
sort of health problems.
No odd-looking freckles,
nodules in the iris?
Nothing. I mean, why
would you think she was sick?
We think it may have been
what caused her car accident.
Wait, what do you mean? My
mom's car was hit by a drunk driver.
That's not what the
police report indicated.
Well, you must have
gotten the wrong report.
No. They didn't.
When you started driving...
You lied about how Mom died?
I figured if her death could
somehow mean something, it...
How does lying about
it mean something?
How could you use her
like that, Dad? Her death?
I was just trying to protect
you. What else isn't true?
She wasn't a teacher,
you just wanted me to read?
What's that smell?
I don't smell...
We're gonna need a nurse.
What the hell? It's
okay. We'll take care of it.
You didn't feel anything?
No.
You feel that? Yeah.
But you didn't feel any of this?
No.
Sphincter paralysis plus shocks
equals Miller Fisher Syndrome.
Not if you add the stool sample,
which is negative for C. jejuni.
He lied to his son
about how his mom died?
He was just protecting him.
Manipulating him.
That's what parents do. They
lie to us because they love us.
Who's getting teary?
Mom's death is irrelevant.
DNA revealed no NF2 markers
or any other inherited disease.
Apparently, she really
did fall asleep at the wheel.
So, what exactly are
we talking about here?
A little peeker, or did the prairie
dog actually come out to play?
Excuse me? Are
we talking explosive?
The hemoccult was
negative for blood,
and I wouldn't say he actually
exploded. More like gushed?
Good, then we're
getting somewhere.
Yeah? Where?
I have no idea.
Of course. Hello?
Love the riddles. Hi, Mom.
Look, I have a business dinner on
Thursday night. I can't get out of it.
I know, I really
wanted to see you, too.
Actually, can I call you back?
I'm in a meeting right now.
Okay, thanks.
Who was that?
Angelina Jolie.
I call her "Mom."
Who thinks that's sexy?
So, explosive or gushing...
She never calls here,
is everything okay?
Great, yeah.
My dad's taking her to Europe.
They got a nine-hour layover
in Newark on Thursday.
If it's gastrointestinal... You lied
to avoid seeing your own mom.
Are you kidding? I
can't lie to my mom.
Seriously, I can't.
Wilson's invited me to dinner.
It'd be rude to stand up a guy
who just loaned me 5 grand.
Transverse myelitis.
Could cause numbness,
anal sphincter dysfunction,
and the shocks.
Thank you for taking
no interest in my mother.
But that begs the question,
what caused the
transverse myelitis?
Well, we've ruled
out cancer and MS.
Leaves infection.
If there was infection,
there'd be a fever.
And his blood and CSF
cultures are all negative.
Maybe the infection's gone
but the memory remains.
Molecular mimicry.
Nice.
Okay, get an immunoglobulin
level and electrophoresis.
You're good, my friend.
I'm sure we'll meet again.
Do you really think that
was his mom on the phone?
Probably, don't know
why he'd lie about that.
Who cares?
You're not the least bit curious
what his parents are like?
I'm sure his mom's
a piece of work.
Only a mother could
do that much damage.
My bet's he was
born the way he is.
Probably tormented his
parents, not the other way around.
Yeah, he was either a fast
runner or one hell of a fighter.
Where are you going?
You guys can
handle the tests, right?
Is there something important that you
and House need to discuss over dinner?
Other than the skyrocketing
interest rates on
personal loans?
You know, this is the fourth
time I've loaned him money.
Not lunch money, money-money.
House's parents.
They have a layover in
Newark Thursday evening.
I'm canceling dinner. No.
I thought maybe you could
just invite a few more people.
An infectious agent's
molecular structure
can resemble the spinal cord's.
And when the immune
system attacks the infection,
it ends up attacking
the spinal cord's as well.
So he has an infection?
They just said I don't.
Even after the infection is
gone, it goes right on attacking
because the spinal
cord is still there.
Is there a treatment?
Depends on what the
original infection was.
All right, you're done.
You need to lay flat after a
lumbar puncture for about an hour.
I feel like I'm gonna throw up.
Hey, Dad, can you
get me a Coke, please?
Yeah, that usually helps.
You're done.
If you're nauseous...
No, I'm not nauseous. I
just want him out of here.
He's your dad. He's
gonna be around.
Yeah, I know.
It's not that, it's...
Are these people
completely incapable
of telling the truth
to each other?
He went to Jamaica
with his friends.
No wonder he lied.
Children aren't supposed
to have good times.
One of his friends
flew them down.
Carnell's dad has this thing about
him accepting stuff from rich friends.
He wants him to remember
who he is, where he came from.
Where have you been?
Making dinner plans. What's up?
The boys have
uncovered the shocking fact
that the patient has a crappy
relationship with his dad.
They seem to actually
care. Well, I don't.
There's only one reason any
kid with a plane flies to Jamaica.
It wasn't for marijuana. He
doesn't do anything but drink.
He said that to you or his pops?
Tox screen was negative for THC.
Spring break was
over a month ago.
Even pot would have
washed out by now.
Even if he'd smoked,
no way marijuana
causes transverse myelitis.
True. But the stuff
they put on it does.
Pesticides.
Well, why would he come clean
about the trip but lie about smoking pot?
He wouldn't necessarily have to
smoke to get pesticide poisoning.
He could have eaten
fruit that'd been sprayed,
or been exposed
through his skin on a hike.
Or he could have
smoked it. A lot of it.
Then lied about it because
that's what this family does.
Start him on IV pralidoxime.
Two grams per liter,
and then one gram every eight
hours until you see some improvement.
You have no evidence to
support a poisoning diagnosis.
Which is why it's gonna be so
cool when I turn out to be right.
Cameron.
Who are you making
dinner plans with?
No one.
You bastard.
You invited my
parents to dinner.
Cameron's got a big mouth.
Not as big as yours.
Hey! You used me to
avoid seeing your parents.
Well, what do you care? I don't.
I just thought it might be
interesting to find out why.
You could've just
asked. You would've lied.
And you would've believed me.
Which would've
kept us both happy.
You want your money back?
Is that what this is about?
No!
Wait, have you got the money?
If you have the money, then
why did you need the loan?
I didn't. I just wanted to
see if you'd give it to me.
I've been borrowing
increasing amounts
ever since you lent
me $40 a year ago.
A little experiment,
to see where you draw the line.
You're trying to
objectively measure
how much I value our friendship?
Hey, it's 5 grand. You've
got nothing to be ashamed of.
So, what do you say? One
little phone call, one big check?
Fine.
Thanks.
Now, be a grownup
and either tell Mommy and
Daddy you don't wanna see them,
or I'm picking you
up at 7:00 for dinner.
What do you mean?
You just said that... I lied.
I've been lying to you
in increasing amounts
ever since I told you you looked
good unshaved a year ago.
It's a little
experiment, you know,
to see where you draw the line.
How's the patient?
Haven't been in yet, today.
As long as he hasn't
gotten any worse.
We're treating him
for pesticide poisoning
without any proof of pesticides.
I'm gonna have a hell of a time
explaining that to our lawyer.
I told House not to...
Wow.
Lawyer's not gonna believe this.
He's got his appetite back.
Whatever you did, it's working.
He's healthy,
so all is forgiven.
Now I'm feeling nauseous.
He is not healthy.
Nausea and diarrhea
were not his only symptoms.
The shocks have also decreased.
But not disappeared.
And he's out of the diaper,
which is good news for everyone.
What about his low white count?
Well, the little buggers
need time to grow.
Don't worry, our wrestling
Rastafarian will be back on his feet
and sneaking around behind
Pop's back again in no time.
Yeah.
Check it again.
I'll be right there.
What happened?
Apparently I can save money
by switching to another
long-distance carrier.
Oh, I was right, wasn't I?
Oh, yeah, it's always
about you, isn't it?
He has the chills and
his temperature's spiking.
It's nearly 106. KEN:
What's that mean?
I mean, what's happening?
You want the truth,
or you want me to make
something up to protect you?
We think a drunk driver
broke into his room...
What's happening to my son?
The truth is I have no idea.
There's the fever that
Cameron was looking for.
We knew if it was myelitis,
there had to be an "-itis."
This must be the infection
that set it off. Yeah.
Except in this universe,
effect follows cause.
I've complained about it, but...
Maybe the tests were wrong.
No. The tests were right. Yesterday
he had no fever, no infection.
So he just happened to
catch a bug while he was here?
That's all this is?
Yeah.
Because his white blood cell
count was down, he was vulnerable.
Because it's really down, it
might kill him. That's all this is.
Is he still pooping his pants?
It just started again.
Again?
It stopped when he
was getting better.
When he was feeling better.
He was never getting better.
So, all we have to answer is,
what causes a 22-year-old kid
to become immunocompromised
with GI involvement and shocks?
Just stop and start
for no apparent reason.
And we need to find an answer
before this infection kills him.
That would be the ideal.
You. Intravenous broad
spectrum antibiotics.
You get a cervical, thoracic, and
lumbar T2-weighted fast spin-echo MRI.
And you, track down all those
Richie Rich's who went to Jamaica,
see if any of them have got
the shocks, the trots or the hots.
The hots, it's the fever.
You guys gonna join
us for dinner Thursday?
Gotta do my laundry.
You're not curious?
I'm curious about crocs, but I
don't stick my head in their mouths.
I'm out, too. Look,
House is a freak!
There's no virus that
causes that, no DNA mutation.
You're gonna have one
dinner with two people.
Sixty minutes, most of it spent
chewing or talking about the weather.
Unless they say something like,
"Do you prefer the
chardonnay or the merlot?"
and, "Oh, we kept Greg
locked in a closet for 17 years."
You're not gonna learn anything.
Okay.
We'd like to talk to
some of your friends,
see if they have any
similar symptoms.
The doctors in the ER
already asked me that.
We understand,
but they didn't have all the
information that we have now.
What kind of information?
Would you mind if I spoke
with Carnell alone for a minute?
Is this bad news?
No. It's just confidential.
Why is something
suddenly confidential?
I mean, if you know
something about my son,
I need to know what's going on.
I'm sorry, I have to insist.
I'm his father,
and if I'm going to take care
of him, I need to know the truth.
Dad.
She wants to know who
I went to Jamaica with.
You've never been to Jamaica.
Taddy's dad flew a bunch
of us down over spring break.
You told me you had two
papers to write over the break.
'Cause I didn't want to come
home and work my ass off.
I wanted an actual break
during a break for once.
I shouldn't have lied to you.
No, what you should
have done is come home
instead of partying
with your rich friends.
I'm sorry, we need those names.
What do you want?
To apologize.
I realize that my attention to the
clinic has been somewhat lax of late,
and I wanna make amends.
How about tomorrow
night? I take the night shift.
The clinic's closed at night.
Yeah, but I'm sure there's
plenty of things to be done,
there's charts to be reviewed,
supplies inventoried...
Dinners avoided.
You're going, too?
I love their Cobb Salad.
Give me a reason
to get out of this,
and I'll tell you who
started the rumor
about you being a transsexual.
There is no such
rumor. There will be,
unless you get me
out of this dinner.
No one's making
you do this, House.
Just do what
everybody else does.
Lie to them.
You lie to your mother?
Only since I was 12!
My mom's a human polygraph.
My dad should be taking
her to Vegas, not the Louvre.
Trust me, your mom
would much rather think
you have a business
meeting than you hate her.
I don't hate her. I hate him.
We all had headaches,
nausea, vomiting.
You know, we figured
it was connected
to the massive
amounts of drinking.
What, you think what
happened to Carnell
has something
to do with the trip?
Don't know.
You haven't had
any unexplained pain
or strange feelings
since you got back?
No, except for a little
athlete's foot, I'm fine.
Can I see it?
See what? Your feet.
There's a common
parasite in Jamaica
that can resemble foot fungus.
It's not really my feet.
You know, I figured
fungus is fungus.
It's my groin.
I'm going to need
to take a look at that.
Now?
Unless you wanna come
down to the hospital with me.
No, no, I can't. I mean, I
just started two days ago.
We're right in the
middle of a big merger...
Then drop your pants.
Reilly, I need the... What
the hell's going on here?
She's a doctor.
I'm a doctor, he has a
rash, and a friend of his is...
Right. Well, as soon as
she's done treating your rash,
I need the numbers
on D-Port Technology.
Yes, sir.
And, Doctor, why don't you
leave a card on your way out?
Except for one guy with a rash,
no one else on the trip
has any health issues.
What kind of rash?
I don't know, I took
some scrapings,
it doesn't appear
to be ringworm.
What did it look like,
aside from "not ringworm"?
Basically like diaper rash.
He's been working
around the clock,
he said he hasn't changed
his clothes in three days.
Kaposi's Sarcoma can
look like diaper rash.
Any discoloration
around the edges?
Get him in here. We
all wanna take a look.
Even if it is Kaposi's,
it's not related.
Our patient doesn't
have any skin symptoms
and we've already
ruled out cancer.
What are the odds of two friends
who just returned from
a trip outside the country
coming down with unexplained
but unrelated illnesses?
- Get him in here.
- He won't come.
Just started a new
job after graduation,
they're working on
some big merger.
Tell him his friend's
life hangs in the balance.
That's what I told
him the first time.
Still wound up
driving into Manhattan.
Tell him his life
hangs in the balance.
Tell him the rash
is flesh-eating,
and the next course on the
menu is his frank and beans.
Where's Stacy?
Speaking at a conference in
Baltimore. Why, what do you need?
Can I subpoena a patient?
House wants me to lie to
the kid to get him in here.
Well, then you'll be the
one getting the subpoena.
Well, we do need him
to diagnose his friend.
Take the test to the kid.
There is no test, House
just wants to look at it.
Then take House to it.
Yeah, like that's gonna happen.
Tell House his parents called.
Said they were coming in early.
He'll go anywhere
just to avoid them.
So, it's okay to lie to
House but not to a patient?
Yup.
What's wrong? KEN: His
stomach's getting a lot worse.
It's rigid!
He's bleeding into his abdomen!
What's going on?
We need a surgeon
and an OR, stat! On it.
Try to hang in there, Carnell.
The infection caused a
perforation in his sigmoid colon.
It's repairable.
But it means the
antibiotics aren't working.
Double the dose, and
add Tygacil to the list.
Soon as he's out of surgery.
Where's Richie Rich?
He said he can't leave work.
Yeah, you told me
that two hours ago.
I'm not gonna lie.
Why, 'cause it's wrong? Or
because you're a coward?
Tough choice.
You'd be wasting two
hours of the kid's time.
Is that deeply and
unforgivably morally wrong? No.
Because it's not a waste of
his time. Unless we're wrong.
Unless his condition's got
nothing to do with his friend's.
You're just afraid
of being wrong.
Your parents called.
They had to catch an earlier...
You don't have to lie to him.
Kid's on his way here.
He got off work?
Yeah, by vomiting blood.
Ambulance is 10 minutes out.
You Taddy? Why?
Love the name.
If I ever had a dog.
Take off his pants.
Hey.
Don't talk to her, listen to me.
He's vomited in excess
of three units of blood.
He needs to be admitted before...
If you wanted to be a doctor,
maybe you should have buckled
down a little more in high school.
Bite me. What are you doing?
Exactly how close
were you and Carnell?
Not so close.
Spend a lot of time
together in Jamaica?
Share a room?
Wait, you don't think...
Look, we're not gay.
I'm not saying you're gay.
I'm saying you had sex.
Look, we're not gay.
We hardly even hung out.
Right. Guess you just
flew him down to Jamaica
'cause he won a contest.
No, he's in my frat.
All right, between
school and wrestling
and going home every break
to work in his father's junkyard,
Carnell didn't have any time
to hang out with anybody.
It's not fungus.
- I - already told you that.
There's no pustules,
it's not staph.
His dad's what?
His dad owns a scrap
metal salvage yard.
Carnell worked
there during breaks.
You lied.
What are you talking about?
Oh, yeah, of
course, in this family,
you probably need
more specifics.
You told us you owned a construction
company, not a salvage yard.
I know the way things work.
The better my job, the
better my son gets treated.
Right, that's why I'm mad,
we wasted all that
filet mignon on you.
Did your kid find anything unusual
the last time he worked for you?
No.
Braided wire?
Metal weights on each end, a
lead canister, maybe just a lid.
Probably used it as a
doorstop or a paperweight.
Why would he wanna...
Okay, here it comes.
I gave him an
early graduation gift,
an old plumb I found,
looks like a fishing weight.
Put it on a keychain, so he'd always
remember where he came from.
So he could lie about it later?
Where's the keychain? I
don't know, he never used it.
Just kept it as a
good luck charm.
Kept it where? I don't know.
Why? Why does it matter?
Where are the kid's clothes?
In the bureau back
in his regular room.
You two, get it to
radiology. His clothes?
The bureau. Don't open it.
You, come with me.
Set it down there.
Now get out of here,
this thing's radioactive.
The chances of radiation
causing CNS symptoms?
Whoa.
Call the boys in
the lead pajamas.
The radiation measurements
weren't high enough
to cause central
nervous system damage.
It mightn't have
caused nerve damage,
but it definitely destroyed
his immune system.
And caused tumors.
We don't know that. None
of the MRIs showed anything.
Do a PET scan. Check
his cervical spine.
It's not gonna be good news.
Mr. Hall, it's not good news.
The piece of metal
you gave Carnell
was from an industrial
device used to test wells.
People aren't supposed to
just dump radioactive material.
But they do.
So, what now? I
mean, what do you do?
Anyone who's had
contact with the source
will have to immediately get
treatment for radiation sickness.
Taddy carried it on
his lap on the flight.
So there is a treatment?
Transfusions.
And we try to get the fluids
and electrolytes balanced.
Carnell,
he's had much more exposure.
The equivalent of about
70,000 chest X rays.
His ability to create white blood
cells has been completely destroyed.
And that's why he can't
fight off this infection?
Yeah. He's gonna need
a bone marrow transplant.
And we did another PET scan.
There's a cavernous angioma
within his spinal cord, it's a tumor.
That's what's been causing
the shocks and CNS symptoms.
He has a tumor inside
of his spinal cord?
The cord is made of strands
put together, sort
of like a kite string.
The surgeon should be able to pull
the strands apart and excise the tumor.
But surgery on someone who's as
hemopoetically compromised as your son
is extremely risky.
And,
if you don't do the
surgery? I mean...
The tumor could cause
his breathing to stop.
Possibly his heart as well.
There's no way you
could have known.
Now, you're gonna
have to come with us.
You need to start
treatment yourself.
No. No, no.
I can start my treatment later.
But he can't.
He needs to be in a sterile isolation
room to prevent further infections.
Mom. We're early.
It's great to see you.
Oh, Greg, don't lie.
We came at a bad
time, didn't we?
Actually, yeah, I think I
have to take a rain check.
Oh, plans have been
made. Wilson made them.
I asked him to cancel.
I'm dealing with a kind of a
complicated case right now so...
Well, we'll just come back
when things aren't
so out of control.
My team is busy.
You don't wanna see us.
Mom, don't make me feel guilty.
No, no, of course not. Sorry.
I've got a patient who's probably
gonna die of radiation poisoning.
So that means you can't eat?
Come on, let's grab
a bite in the cafeteria.
I'll buy you a Reuben.
Well, I guess I got
time for a sandwich.
Good.
Yeah?
I just wanted to let you know
that Carnell's
prepped for surgery.
Thank you.
Hi, I'm Allison Cameron.
I work with your son.
Greg's told us all about you.
Really?
New, huh?
Nope, just gullible.
I'm sorry, I was just
making fun of my son,
not of you.
We were just about to
go to get something to eat,
would you care to join us?
You don't have a lot
of time with your son.
Maybe another time.
Do you like the
Beatles? They're all right.
My 12-year-old just
turned me back on to them.
McCartney's gotta have
more money than God.
I think that's all
of it. Reverse him.
How's he doing?
Looks pretty good down
here. Do I rock, or what?
His pressure's dropping!
Give him another
two units. I did already!
His heart rate's falling.
He's hemorrhaging.
They're talking about
Mom's last trip to the dentist.
Grown children
talking to their parents,
nothing gets talked about.
Trust me, you're
not missing anything.
So, besides work,
what you been up to?
Not much.
You always say that, "Not much."
It's always the answer.
Any new babes you
might wanna tell me about?
Leave him alone, John.
Got a new motorcycle.
Might have seen it out front,
it's orange with
a gigantic scrape.
Is it the one in the
handicapped parking?
Yeah.
Looks like crap,
but it drives great.
Well, you'll be careful, right?
Last I checked, you
still have two legs.
Actually, three.
You know what your
problem is, Greg?
Shifting gears?
You just don't know
how lucky you are.
Where's the head?
Well, good thing we
got that cleared up.
Oh, he was just trying to help.
I don't need help.
I know.
You're absolutely perfect
just the way you are.
Thank you.
So, how much longer do
you think he'll be in surgery?
It's hard to say.
You know, he just started
school when Ann died.
I was a mess.
Still adjusting to being a
parent, much less a single parent.
You know, I used to put cold
pancakes in his lunch box.
I mean, that was the only thing
I could make that he would eat.
You did okay, he's
a good kid. Yeah.
Hey. So, how is he?
Well, the surgeon
has removed the tumor
without damaging
the spinal cord.
But, the infection has caused
another intestinal perforation.
We stopped the bleeding,
but his white
count keeps falling.
Okay.
So what now? Another
drug, antibiotics, what?
I'm sorry.
The reality is, no
matter what we give him,
it's unlikely he's gonna be
able to fight off the infections.
Okay, okay.
The father and the friend are
responding well to treatment.
Things aren't looking
so good for Carnell.
Thank you,
for not eating.
It was none of my business.
They seem perfectly
pleasant, don't they?
They are.
He was a marine pilot.
She was a housewife.
Married 47 years,
they had one child.
Mom is just like everyone else,
she's nice enough,
no great sense of humor,
hates confrontation.
My dad's just like you.
Not the caring till
your eyes pop out part,
just the insane moral compass
that won't let you lie to
anybody about anything.
It's a great quality
for Boy Scouts
and police witnesses.
Crappy quality for a dad.
Hey.
How you doing?
I'm hanging in there.
I'm sorry I lied to
you about Mom.
I'm sorry I lied to you, too.
There was nothing good
that came out of her dying.
I'm not mad.
I know why you did it.
It worked.
I never drink and drive.
I'm scared, Dad.
Come on.
There's nothing to be scared of.
You're gonna be just fine.
Don't play me.
I wanna know the truth.
I'm telling you the truth.
You're gonna be fine, I swear.
I love you, Dad.
I love you, too.
Why does he hate
seeing his parents?
So his dad tells the
truth, he can't handle that?
He hates being a disappointment.
He's a doctor, world famous.
How disappointed can they be?
You know what I figure is worse
than watching your
son become crippled?
Watching him be miserable.