- Previously on The Resident...
- Just so we're clear,
you're my one-hour person.
If I had one hour left to live,
I would want to
spend it with you.
I will take it.
It's stupid to question
the love of your life
for something
that's just... stupid.
So Jessica
is the love of your life?
She has Moyamoya.
She could die of strokes
before she turns 30.
Unless I perform
a cerebral bypass.
Your intracranial
pressures and post-op labs
are trending in
the right direction.
Thank you.
Dr. Pravesh, have you ever
saved a princess before?
It was a team effort.
The king will want to thank you.
I expect he will
be calling shortly.
- Well, what do I call him?
- Your Majesty.
♪ ♪
Well, you are a
pleasant surprise.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Ah, today's been
full of surprises.
My father's coming into town.
Your father? The king?
He's throwing me
a last-minute gala
for my 25th birthday next week,
and he wants me to
invite the team of doctors
- who saved my life.
- A gala. Wow.
That sounds fancy.
It's too fancy.
Black-tie. I know
it's a lot to ask.
No, I'm in.
Especially if I
get to see you in...
princess mode.
That's great.
Uh, here's the thing.
My father would have to
meet you when he arrives.
- It would be a whole thing.
- Say no more.
Just tell the king that I'm
looking forward to it, okay?
♪ I'm here again,
I hate this game ♪
Hey, you.
♪ My heart jumps
when I hear your name ♪
Oh.
♪ But you never even... ♪
- Hi.
- Hello.
Come on. We have to go.
- Mm-hmm.
- Two minutes.
♪ Took a hit ♪
♪ Right to the ego ♪
♪ Yeah, it was a low blow ♪
♪ Knowing that you
never wanted me ♪
♪ But you never even called
to say you were too bored ♪
♪ To spend any time
in my company... ♪
- Mm.
- Looks good.
- Okay.
Now your turn.
Way ahead of you.
- Now, that's just cheating.
- Get out of here. We're late.
Hi. Uh, I got a page.
I'm supposed to
meet somebody here.
Irving.
What's going on?
Nice coattail by the way.
"Let me not..."
"Let me not
"to the marriage of true
minds admit impediments.
"Love is not love, which
alters when it alteration finds,
or bends with the
remover to remove."
"Oh, no!"
"It is an ever-fixed mark..."
Shakespeare? Babe,
that's... that's so romantic.
More romantic if
you let me finish.
- Oh, right.
- Uh, it...
You know what? Never mind.
I'll just show you.
What?!
Jessica Moore...
- Oh, my God!
- Will you...
You didn't let me finish!
I don't care. Yes, yes, yes!
Yes? Come here.
- Yes?
- Yes!
We're getting hitched, baby!
♪ ♪
Tonight's the night.
Pravesh's royal debut.
Is that notes of
sandalwood I smell?
- It's just a birthday party.
- Mm.
One where I'm going to meet
my princess girlfriend's father,
the king, for the first time.
Wow, you're right. Sounds
just like any other birthday party.
Can't be too good a party
considering I
didn't get an invite.
You weren't on Nadine's
medical team, man.
Besides, you're not
exactly the life of the party.
Hey, I'll have you know I
was an animal in my day.
A-A wild man.
I once woke up
vomiting in St. Louis.
- So?
- I began the evening in Kenosha.
Uh, which reminds me,
Garrison called out sick,
and you need to take her shift.
Uh, cool story, Nolan, but no.
I did an overnight just so I
could have the day to prep.
Too bad you're needed here.
Looks like Cinderella
might not make it after all.
Did you know you
can lighten armpit skin
with raw ground potatoes?
I did, actually.
Don't ask me how.
You're on your way?
You're gonna meet
me at the salon, right?
Yeah, that's the thing.
You haven't told
your dad yet about us,
- have you?
- You're not coming?
If you haven't told him...
It's too late. I already did.
Okay, don't worry.
I'll figure something out.
Just don't replace me yet.
Well, I do have the prince
of Zamunda on standby.
I've seen Coming to America.
Zamunda is not a real place.
I will see you soon.
♪ In a heartbeat, we got... ♪
Do you remember what
happened when you fainted, Mary?
I was in gym class.
I've been fighting
with the school
about these PE requirements.
Mary's punished
academically for not having
the energy to run laps.
Do you get tired often?
I guess.
Here we go again.
Try flying 30 hours from
Beijing to Atlanta. That's tiring.
Hey, darling.
Sweetie, I told you I
would take care of this.
I love my husband, but
he indulges her every
- ache and pain.
- Mom, I fainted.
I know, sweetie, and
I'm sorry that happened.
But you have to stop
making yourself sick
to get out of your
responsibilities.
Maybe she's sick because
you push her too hard.
Well, you don't push
her enough. She's 17.
She needs to be
getting ready for college,
but you're keeping
her tethered to you.
Okay, why don't
we do a full workup.
That'll give us some answers,
and we can move
forward from there.
Thank you. Finally,
we can put this to rest
- once and for all.
- Okay. I'll be right back.
Any luck finding a replacement?
Butler's out of town.
Ward is on maternity
leave. I got nothing.
Nadine will forgive
me, eventually.
I'll take your shift.
Really?
Yeah, you came through
for me during my proposal.
Plus, if I go home now,
Jess'll make me decide
between teal and aqua napkins.
Spoiler alert.
They're exactly the same.
Just figure out what
she likes and tell her
it's your favorite, too.
See? Solutions like that are
why I'm going to cover for you.
All right, give me another
hour and then go to your ball.
Can I help you with something?
Shut the door,
if you don't mind.
Red Rock is dismantling
the Department of
Obstetrics and Gynecology
effective six weeks from now.
You're letting them all go?
You think it's wise
to just get rid of an
entire department?
It's already been
decided. It's a black hole.
Jettisoning it will help
with our bottom line.
Respectfully, our
bottom line isn't
the only consideration here.
What about expectant mothers?
Those patients will be taken
care of at Atlanta General
where they have a
fully-functioning OB.
We have a
fully-functioning OB here.
Not for long.
Hundreds of crucial
staff will lose their jobs.
As for staff, I need you to
give notice to the residents.
Wow.
The chair and
chief resident of OB
are at a conference, so
you don't have a choice.
Neither do those residents.
If you let them go,
they won't get accepted
into another
residency, not this year,
not when they're in the middle
of their training
here at Chastain.
And you still want to
set them back like this?
This is a business.
You wanted this
"chief resident" title.
It's time to earn it.
Give the obstetrics
residents notice.
- Gemma, I'm Dr. Pravesh. I'm here...
- Shh.
Trust me. This is why I chose
to dress you for
the Met this year.
You are my only priority.
The dress will be
perfect, I promise.
Ms. Lin, I'm here
to examine you.
Mind taking that call later?
Jen, we'll continue
this conversation later.
Talk soon.
Three years, I've been the boss.
Sometimes I forget I don't
call the shots everywhere.
Your chart says that you're
having abdominal pain.
Plus some vomiting
and weight loss.
But I like that part.
Is something wrong?
Does it hurt when
I press down here?
A little uncomfortable,
but, no, it doesn't hurt.
I'd like to get a CT
before I let you get
back to work, okay?
No, thanks.
Fashion isn't for the
young or the weak.
Uh, since the deck is stacked
against me at the moment,
I have to get back.
Look, Gemma, you want
to be somewhere else.
Somewhere more important to you.
Believe me, I get it.
But you're here because
you're not feeling your best.
So let me get some images,
and we'll go from there.
Deal?
You're a little bossy.
I like you, so I will stay.
But if you make me wear one
of those hideous hospital gowns,
we're gonna have a problem.
I'll be right back.
Oh, my God.
You kept our
participation trophy.
Oh, yeah, to punish myself.
Never in the history of medicine
has peds won the
Resident Olympics.
Until that year.
I remember you were so mad,
you punched a hole
in the locker room wall.
Hey, they never
proved it was me.
And we both know
that game was rigged.
That night, you told me
I should switch into OB.
Now I can't imagine
doing anything else.
So, what'd you
need to talk about?
Gabbi...
I hate that I'm the
one telling you this.
Red Rock is shutting
down the OB department.
I wanted to let you
know as soon as possible.
In six weeks, you won't have
a residency here anymore.
Chastain is my home.
This is the only place
I've... I've ever worked.
I have left word at every
single hospital across the state
to try and get you transferred.
I can't make any promises,
but I'll pull every favor I can.
But I'll have to start over.
Be an intern again.
I-I'm a year away
from a real salary.
I have student loans that
have been in deferment.
This is my career.
I know, and I've spoken
to every department head
to try and keep you here.
There just isn't room.
Oh, my God.
I took a year's lease
on my apartment.
I'm gonna have to move
home with my parents.
I'm-I'm sorry. I
need, I need to go.
And just like that,
good doctors sacrificed
for the bottom line.
These residents are
still in their training.
It's almost impossible for them
to get reassigned
into a new program.
Even if they do
find a new hospital,
they might have to start
over from their intern year.
I came up with some
of these OB interns
from med school.
These are good
doctors, good people.
I can't let them go until I know
I've done everything
I can to stop this.
Mary Lawson's
test results are back.
Thank you.
Huh.
Not the news you
were hoping for?
I'm not convinced any
news would be sufficient
for this family.
- You need backup?
- Not yet.
But if they start trying
to kill each other.
I'll stand by.
Well, I just reviewed
Mary's test results,
and I'm happy to report
that everything looks normal.
So there's nothing
wrong with me?
Well, your symptoms
are real, but the tests show
that nothing is emergent,
so that's good news.
See?
I told you.
Here. Drink this.
It helps with your stress.
She said Mary's
symptoms are real.
You don't look good,
kiddo. Are you okay?
Actually, I'm not
feeling that... that good.
I...
I'm having trouble breathing,
- but I guess it's nothing.
- Let's listen.
Take a deep breath.
And another. Feeling any pain?
My chest hurts. I-I feel hot.
- She's having a panic attack!
- That you gave her.
Your sats have dropped.
I'm gonna put you on oxygen
- and admit you for observation.
- You're going to admit her?
You just said she was fine.
I told you something was wrong.
Okay, I'm gonna need you
guys to leave the room, please.
Thank you.
All right.
Introduce me to her.
What?
Gemma Lin is
single-handedly responsible
for bringing avant-garde
to streetwear.
There is no one who
can hold a candle to her.
She's an icon.
But I wouldn't expect you
to know anything about that.
What? 'Cause I'm a guy I
don't know about fashion?
You tell me. What are
you wearing tonight?
It's a royal ball. I have a tux.
You have a tux,
or you rented a tux?
I figured.
Introduce me or don't.
I will find a way.
Well, that explains
the abdominal pain.
A mass in her stomach
extending into her small intestine.
Doesn't have the appearance
of a typical stomach cancer.
Regardless, she's gonna need
an endoscopy to biopsy the mass.
Hopefully, I'll have
some answers
for her before I leave.
Don't you mean "we"?
That's surgical.
Gemma's our patient now.
I told you I'd find a way.
How are you feeling?
Better.
I know I seem like the girl
who cried wolf, but, uh...
something feels... wrong.
I believe you.
And we're gonna
figure out what it is.
That's why my dad
doesn't want me in PE.
He says I'm not
like the other kids.
But I want to be. I just...
He means well,
but ever since Mom
died, he's been a little...
overprotective.
- Susan's your stepmom?
- She just wants me
to be independent, mm?
Move out and... and
stand on my own two feet,
and I want that, too.
Could all this just
be my anxiety?
Ah, you'd be surprised
the toll that stress
can take on the body.
Are you feeling
anxious right now?
No. I just...
My legs feel, like...
tingly, like Jell-O.
How about this?
Do you feel this?
I don't feel that at all.
What does that mean?
Dr. Bell. I need to
get new assignments
for some obstetrics residents.
You have room for,
say, two in gen surgery?
Depends. Why are
they leaving OB?
Red Rock is shutting
down the entire department.
You know, I should've
seen this coming.
OB has the highest premiums
and malpractice claims
- of any department.
- Yeah, and new moms can stay
for days without Red
Rock billing a dime.
It's their nightmare.
Maximum care, minimum profit.
No, I think this new
neurosurgery center
has them overextended,
and this is just the beginning.
- Well, how about we stop it?
- Well, we-we can't.
No one can. The only thing
that talks in medicine is money.
So unless you
got a whole lot of it
- lying around...
- I know, I know.
Well, maybe we can't
stop it, but what we can do
is try and help at least
some of these doctors,
who will lose their
careers if we don't.
Two residents?
- That's all I'm asking.
- Yeah. I'll see what I can do.
Your doctor is going
to a black-tie event,
and I think he needs your help.
He's clueless. You're brilliant.
No, seriously, your fall line
was my favorite collection
of the year.
- I am such a big fan.
- Thank you.
Hey.
Ooh.
No. No, no, no, no, no.
What are you wearing?
What do you mean? It's a tux.
Says who?
Okay, I'm leaving, but I
will be back to check on you
after your endoscopy.
But right now, I have a
princess waiting for me.
- Is she blind?
- Uh, seriously, though,
you can't go looking like that.
I appreciate all your concern,
- but I really don't have
the time to...
- I do.
And I can't, in good conscience,
send you to a party like this.
My team can get you into
something amazing immediately.
Okay. Fine.
What's your chest
measurement? 38?
42, at least.
You're a 38.
Whoa.
Who invited 007?
Well, you better bring your
A game tonight, Hawkins,
'cause I ain't
messing around here.
I can see that.
How did this happen?
My patient is a famous
fashion designer,
and, as it turns out,
part fairy godmother.
And you mix that with Mina's
very aggressive comments
about my rental tux, and voilà.
Yeah.
Well, you look good, man.
- What happened?
- Well, she just got back
from an X-ray.
- I came to take her
for the endoscopy.
- Oh, make it stop.
All right, let's get
four of morphine.
Does it hurt more
when I push my hand in
- or when I take it away?
- When you take it away.
Rebound tenderness. Guarding.
Surgical abdomen.
I'll check the X-rays.
- Air under the diaphragm.
- She's perforated.
Wh-What does that mean?
It means we're
skipping the endoscopy.
You need surgery now. Get Nolan.
- No. No, no, no, no. I can't, I can't go alone.
- Shh. Shh.
- I have no one.
- Shh.
- I'm gonna die alone.
- You're not gonna die, Gemma.
- I will not let that happen.
- Dr. Pravesh,
please stay with me.
I'm so scared.
I'm not gonna leave you.
I promise.
All right? I'm right here.
I got your page.
What do you need?
- Her O2 sats are in the 80s. We need to intubate.
- I can't breathe.
Hey. I need meds
and an airway kit.
Please just help her.
Her paralysis is
progressing rapidly.
She's not gonna be able to
keep breathing on her own.
- What's causing the paralysis?
- We don't know.
Got it.
All right, it's gonna
be okay, Mary.
This is gonna put
you to sleep, all right?
All good.
- Okay, here we go.
- Ready?
Yep.
- Oh, my God.
- You never believed her.
I'm so sorry. I didn't know.
- Got it?
- Got it.
All right, the tube's in.
- She's stable, for now.
- For now?
You-you mean she
could get worse?
Not if we can help it.
I'll begin with an incision
in the gastric fundus.
10-blade.
Got any tips on
crashing a royal ball?
Don't.
Hey. I know. I'm late.
I'm sorry, Nadine.
- My patient needed me.
- I understand.
It's just...
people are starting to arrive.
Traditionally,
you'd be by my side.
I will be there
as soon as I can.
Look, I promise you, this is
a straightforward procedure.
- I'll be out of here in no time.
- What the hell?
Is that...?
A giant,
stomach-shaped hairball.
Nadine, I have to go.
You good?
I think I got hair in my mouth.
I've heard about this before,
but I've never seen such a
severe case of trichophagia.
Gemma's eating her own hair?
That would explain
the no eyebrows.
An obstruction this
big, she's been eating
more than just her eyebrows.
And that's not all of it.
There must be a-a tail.
Extends from the gastric
body, beyond the pylorus,
into the duodenum.
- It's Rapunzel syndrome.
- Yeah, it appears so.
We have to untangle the
hair that has wound itself
through the
intestines to extract it.
Yes, repairing whatever
damage we need to along the way.
Sounds complex.
You should call your
princess and let her know.
This is gonna take a while.
Sinus bradycardia
with increasing pauses,
up to five seconds.
Labs are pristine.
The spinal tap
came back negative.
Nothing on imaging.
But her paralysis
is moving so fast.
She could go into sinus arrest.
Let's put the pads
on her, just in case.
Let's keep the crash
cart bedside, ready to go.
This doesn't make any sense.
When she came here, her
symptoms were so vague.
Respiratory failure and...
and now her heart.
- We're missing something.
- Mm-hmm.
It's just the pulse
ox. It's been finicky.
Nail polish can sometimes
prevent the pulse ox
from giving an accurate reading.
Wait.
Mees' lines.
Sometimes found in
chemotherapy patients
or ones in renal failure.
Or when exposed to heavy metals.
Mary's blood levels are back.
The heavy metal in
her blood is thallium.
- What?
- Good news is,
with some Prussian
blue and dialysis,
- we can treat her.
- The bad news is
thallium is not a naturally
occurring element.
Someone could be
giving it to her intentionally.
Someone's poisoning Mary?
Uh, who?
Someone with access and...
proximity.
Susan married a man
who's way more invested
in his daughter than he is her.
So maybe she couldn't take it?
She does want her
out of the house.
Thallium is illegal
in the United States,
impossible to get.
Except for places like China.
Susan just got
back from Beijing.
We need to get
that tea canister.
What is it you're giving her?
Prussian blue.
It'll help flush any toxic
chemicals in Mary's body.
Toxic chemicals?
Does that mean you know
what's been happening to her?
We're getting closer.
Hello. Mark, Susan, can
I steal you for a second
to sign some paperwork?
Of course.
You probably only
need one of us.
I'll stay here with Mary.
Um...
Yeah. Actually, I need
both your signatures.
It'll be real quick.
I'll keep her company.
I'm not going anywhere.
All right. Just right
there at the top.
Thank you.
Oh, I'm sorry. I
should've had that...
Uh, there we go.
And if, uh, could
give me the date.
Nah, we're good. We're good.
Never mind. Thank
you. Thank you.
Do you have any
reason to believe that...
that Susan would try
to poison your daughter?
Um, uh, of course not.
She's hard on her, but
she loves Mary like her own.
We found traces of thallium in
the tea that Susan gives Mary.
Sue gave Mary the tea,
but I'm the one who got it
for her from her acupuncturist.
I was just trying to
help her feel better.
The tea is supposed to calm
her and give her more energy.
- This is all my fault.
- No. We're not pointing
any fingers just yet, but...
but we just need to know
how the thallium got in the tea.
I don't know.
It comes in sealed packets.
Do you have one with you?
I mean, we give it
to her all the time.
I mean, I...
I mean, I can't read
any of these ingredients.
These kind of
alternative remedies
are completely unregulated.
There could be
anything in there.
We need to get this to the lab.
My wife.
She didn't do this.
You have to believe me.
Please tell me
you're on your way.
They're ready to announce us.
I'm not, Nadine.
I'm still at the hospital.
I had to stay with my patient.
I'm so sorry.
They're about to
announce you as my escort.
I'm gonna look like
an idiot out there.
I don't even know what to say.
Bye, Devon.
So, they did find
traces of thallium
in the packets from
your acupuncturist.
We contacted the manufacturer,
and they have submitted a recall
of the contaminated supplements.
And I'll be okay?
With a bit of rest and a
few more rounds of dialysis,
you should be fine.
I am so sorry.
I should've listened to you.
Honey, this isn't your fault.
I... I sent her to
the acupuncturist.
I told you the acupuncturist
was a bad idea.
At least I'm not impossible
to please, like you.
This is so embarrassing.
Who eats their own hair?
Look, stress can be triggering
for these kinds of
compulsion disorders.
Cut back your hours.
Take on fewer clients.
Easier said than done, I think.
And I will put you in
touch with a professional
who specializes in
trichophagia, okay?
I've been so stressed and
scared someone would figure it out.
I pushed everyone away.
All I had was my work.
It paid off, but, uh...
You were alone.
I shouldn't have asked
you to stay with me.
- You missed your ball.
- We all need support.
I wanted to be here for you.
Well, I'm okay now,
and you can still make it.
It's too late. I
can't show up now.
Hey. It's like you said,
everyone needs support.
Late or not, your
princess wants you there.
And, besides,
it would be a shame for
that tux to go to waste.
Thank you, Gemma.
Hmm.
Now, that is how you wear a tux.
Well, if I remember correctly,
you have a spectacular
wardrobe yourself.
I'm just popping in,
but I have a plus-one,
if you're interested.
You want arm candy.
Are you offen... Are
you offended by that?
Usually, yes.
But I do have a dress
I've been wanting to wear,
and I desperately
need a night out.
The whole night.
So I will drive myself.
Okay. It's a deal.
Uh, see you there.
Mm-hmm.
Hey.
Wow.
You in that dress is exactly
what I need right now.
It's time for you to
return the feeling.
- You want to talk about it?
- Eh.
Being chief resident is not
what I thought it would be.
You know, we
don't have to go out.
We can go home, get some wine,
- relax.
- Mm.
And lose a night dancing
with you in that dress?
Absolutely not.
Mm.
All right, but if you're not
fist pumping in a half hour,
I'm calling it.
Okay. All right. Enough of that.
Get changed.
♪ L-O-V-E ♪
♪ I ain't ever giving up ♪
♪ I'm feeling
something electric ♪
♪ L-O-V-E ♪
♪ Higher and I
can't get enough ♪
♪ Want to reach
out and touch it... ♪
Now, my daughter,
where's the boy I've
heard so much about?
He's, uh...
he's being a good doctor
and saving his patient's life.
But you wish he were here.
I'm sorry, my love.
It's fine.
♪ ♪
♪ L-O-V-E ♪
♪ I ain't ever giving up ♪
♪ I'm feeling
something electric... ♪
Nadine, I'm so sorry.
- I tried...
- I'm so happy you came.
♪ Want to reach
out and touch it ♪
Devon, may I have this dance?
Heck yeah, you can.
♪ L-O-V-E ♪
♪ Higher and I
can't get enough ♪
♪ Want to reach
out and touch it. ♪
Unhand me, sir.
I am a respected neurosurgeon.
My name is Dr. Barrett Cain.
I work at Chastain H...
A little help, please?
- I will be right back.
- Sure.
♪ Some things don't
start so innocent... ♪
Great party, isn't it?
Can't even imagine the cost.
I would say about as much as
an obstetrics floor for six months.
I know you considered
decimating OB when you were CEO.
But I decided against it,
because when a hospital
decimates departments,
it loses prestige and status.
Chastain and Red
Rock would no longer be
a world-class medical facility.
And you think Chastain's
our only hospital?
If Chastain crumbles,
Red Rock will be fine.
We always are.
Now, if you don't
mind, I have a...
a king who's very
grateful to Red Rock
for saving his daughter.
You know, I've begged for
money at enough parties to know
it always ends in embarrassment.
Just schmooze now,
ask for money later.
Just tread lightly.
If you did my job
as well as I do,
you would still have it.
Enjoy the party, Dr. Bell.
Your Majesty, uh, Logan Kim.
I wanted to thank you
on behalf of Chastain.
You saved my daughter's life.
Well, I can't
take all the credit.
We were able to
provide exceptional care
because of the
generosity of our donors.
- People like you...
- Mr. Kim,
you see that woman over there?
Rupa is one of my goddaughters.
Her unborn son has a
condition called ectopia cordis,
a very rare condition
in which his heart
is growing outside his body.
Now, who do you
think has the best
pediatric cardiac surgeons
in the whole world?
Red Rock Mountain Medical...
Boston Children's Hospital.
That's where I give my money.
Now, if you don't
mind, others are waiting.
Thank you.
Would you happen to be
in need of a dance partner?
♪ Go ahead and bark after dark ♪
♪ Fallen star, I'm
your one call away ♪
♪ Motel halls, neon walls ♪
♪ When night falls ♪
♪ I am your escape... ♪
You know her?
No.
But her dress is...
- exquisite.
- Hmm.
Well, it's beautiful, no doubt,
but yours is better.
You made it, I assume.
Couture technique.
Hand stitched every bead myself.
Oh, wow.
Well, I must say,
you never cease to
amaze me, Dr. Okafor.
♪ If you've been waiting
for falling in love ♪
♪ Babe, you don't
have to wait on me ♪
♪ 'Cause I've been aiming... ♪
Well, we came, we
saw, we had punch.
Oh, we haven't danced yet.
Okay, one dance.
Oh, one dance is all I need.
♪ Not anyone ♪
♪ You're the one ♪
♪ More than fun ♪
♪ You're the sanctuary... ♪
Oh.
Oh, yep.
That's it. That's what I
needed the whole time.
Oh, just you, me and a ballroom.
It is like a fairy tale.
Are you the fairy tale
type, Conrad Hawkins?
I wasn't, but you
make me believe.
♪ But an angel
ain't what I need... ♪
After everything that's happened
this year, I know that together
we can get through anything.
♪ Oh, so close ♪
♪ 'Cause you never know ♪
♪ Just how long
our lives will be... ♪
- Now, let's get out of here.
- Mm.
I was hoping you'd say that.
♪ For falling in love ♪
♪ Babe, you don't
have to wait on me. ♪
This is Dr. Pravesh.
It's an honor, Your Majesty.
- Baba, he can speak Urdu.
- Ah.
Devon's genius diagnosing
is what saved my life.
It's my job. I'm happy to do it.
Nadine is, um, really special.
My daughter is my everything.
If it weren't for you
and your colleagues,
she would not be here today.
For that, I thank you.
Did you tell him?
Tell me what?
I just signed with the
hottest music agent in Atlanta.
Nadine, I'm happy for you.
But I'm afraid your time
here will be coming to an end.
What?
You can't be a
musician in Atlanta.
You're a princess.
You'll be returning
home with me.
Your Majesty, if I may please...
You may not!
Please leave me and
my daughter alone.
- No. He's not going anywhere.
- No. It's okay.
- You have a lot to talk about.
- Devon.
I'll go.
Yo, Pravesh!
- What's going on?
- Her water broke.
This baby has ectopia cordis.
His heart is on the
outside of his chest.
- He's high-risk.
- I need you to call
the ambulance now.
Clock is ticking, party people.
She delivers or the baby dies.
She says her doctor's
at Boston Children's.
He's gonna operate
when she delivers.
She has to deliver at Chastain,
and then we can try to
arrange transport to Boston.
We have to do the
C-section quickly
- to save the baby.
- Peekaboo surgery
like this needs the dynamic duo.
We should go in the ambulance.
Mina told me what happened.
Do me a favor and remind them
how important it is that
this operation goes well.
It's a shame it'll
be one of the last.
With OB gone,
deliveries like this
are gonna go to Atlanta General.
And not to bore you
with more bad advice,
but if I learned anything
from fundraising as a CEO,
it's that new parents tend
to be the most grateful.
And to let a billionaire family
like the Nours go
to another hospital,
I don't know, you might be...
risking more than
just an OB floor.
Nothing's been finalized yet.
Good night.
All right, everyone.
Let's get this baby out.
♪ ♪
There he is.
He's not crying.
- O2 sats in the 80s.
- Get him on oxygen.
Echo probe with
sterile cover to me now.
If this was just ectopia cordis,
he wouldn't be hypoxic.
It's not.
He also has tetralogy of Fallot.
These ectopia cordis babies
often have other complex
congenital abnormalities.
Which means he has less than
a five percent chance of survival.
There are only a handful
of surgeons in the world
- prepared to handle
cases like this.
- One of them is in Boston,
waiting to save
this baby's life.
Well, he's not gonna
make it to Boston.
And I'm not sure if
we can save him here.
Well, we don't have a choice.
He needs surgery.
I mean, that party
was good, but...
Nice.
But this...
You know,
I was talking to my accountant,
and she gave me some
really good reasons
as to why we should
probably just get married.
Think about it.
Discounted auto insurance.
- Joint taxes.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, hold up.
Is this your way of
proposing to me?
I don't know.
It just feels like the
practical thing to do.
And, I mean, are we really
the romantic proposal
kind of people?
Oh, my God.
You are proposing.
- What?
- Oh, I reject your proposal.
- What, you... you reject it?
- Y-Yes.
If we ever decide
to get married,
I'd want the perfect
proposal for us.
And I'm sorry, seducing
me with insurance rates,
- that's not my idea of perfect.
- It...
It just seems like
the logical next step.
I mean, we're committed.
We should at least talk
- about making it official.
- Listen,
I-I love you deeply.
I mean, you were my
rock when I got fired.
You pushed me
to forgive my father.
You gave me chickens.
You will always make those
annoying sounds when you eat,
and I'll probably never
learn to pick up my socks, -
but nobody's perfect.
What matters is that
we just keep trying
to make each other better.
What matters is that we...
we belong together.
Conrad.
Wait, are you
proposing to me now?
Why do you think I'm saying
all this lovey-dovey stuff?
And why do you think I've been
carrying this thing around
in my pocket for weeks?
Nicolette Marie Nevin,
- will you do me the hon...
- Yes.
Are you sure?
I have never been so sure
of anything in my life before.
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH