.
- Previously
on "New Amsterdam."
- I'm glad that you're up
for complicated
because I'm pregnant.
- Do you foresee any problems
working in a public hospital
system like New Amsterdam?
- The only problem I see having
is getting any work done
while staring into those
amazing, blue eyes of yours.
- You lied to me!
I asked you if this residency
was on the level,
and you said yes.
- I'm going to wait you out,
and then I'm going to undo
every bloated program,
every underfunded clinic,
and everything that you've
built on very shaky ground.
- I am going to miss
this place,
but we are getting ready
for a brand-new chapter
of our lives together
in London.
- JFK, terminal four.
♪
Oh, my God!
- Not too bad.
Welcome home.
- No!
♪
- Whoa!
It was an accident!
♪
- Get back!
- ♪ Chelsea, Chelsea
♪ I believe
that when you're dancing ♪
♪ Slowly sucking your sleeve
♪ The boys get lonely
after you leave ♪
♪ It's one for the dagger
♪ And another
for the one you believe ♪
- Hi, baby. Yes!
- Reed,
about those conferences,
I really need to--
oh, well, you can tell whoever
you're not talking to
that I said hello.
♪
Good morning, Ava.
I just wanted to--hey.
Well, there's a name
I didn't need to learn.
- Hello.
- Adam, you're late.
- By one minute.
As of now.
- What's your point?
- Great.
First up, you need to appoint
the medical commissions
for your
inter-department outreach
the general way that we--
- And why didn't you take care
of this yesterday?
- Yesterday was the weekend?
- Well, you know what they say.
If you don't show up
on a Sunday,
do not bother showing up
on a Monday.
It's--
oh, hey, watch this.
Hey, Mike. Can I talk to you
about something?
Did you see that?
Oh, God. Max has been gone
for six weeks,
and these people
still don't realize
that they cannot hide from me.
Call a department head meeting.
One hour.
- That's not a lot of notice.
- No?
I guess if they don't show up,
then they are fired.
- Oh, ho, ho! Merry Christmas.
- It's January.
- He's here all year.
He's an inpatient
at the psych ward.
It's part of Dr. Frome's
new vocational program.
Apparently he really does think
he's Santa Claus.
Kids love him.
- Oh, God.
- Pumpkin spice,
extra cinnamon.
A basic drink for a basic boss.
- I will not be coffee-shamed
by you.
This drink is joy in a cup.
- I don't know how you drink
that stuff
and still look
as good as you look.
- Yeah, right.
- Are you kidding? The way
you're wearing that jumper?
Fits you like a glove.
- Oh, thank you.
Yeah, it was a gift
from a family member.
- You should ask for
a few more. You're killing it.
Okay, then.
♪
Oh, that's a new one.
- Getting good images.
Singleton fetus,
strong heartbeat.
- And the placenta's in good
position for transcervical CVS.
- It is, but you know
chorionic villus sampling
is never totally risk-free.
- Spinal muscular atrophy
runs in my family.
I got to know.
- Probably a good idea anyway,
this being
a geriatric pregnancy.
- I am a peace-loving woman,
Jan,
but you say that word again
and I'll smack you
with the ultrasound probe.
I didn't think I was able
to get pregnant.
- Baptiste must be
over the moon.
♪
- You know,
this test Linda's taking...
can also confirm
who the father is.
♪
- Message after the tone.
- Hey, uh, Leyla, it's me.
Just checking in.
Want to hear how your
VA orientation's going.
So weird not having you
at the hospital.
Look, I know that you took
that job to get away from me,
and I want to respect
your space,
but please, please just let
me know where you're living.
I just don't want you to be
somewhere unsafe because--
- Help!
- Man struck by lightning
while hailing a cab
now with LOC and severe burns
to his left foot and left hand.
- What happened?
- Sir, you're going to find
this pretty unbelievable,
but you were just
struck by lightning.
Typical.
♪
- You can't fire Santa.
- Well, the real Santa, no,
but the psychiatric
liability issue
wandering our hallways,
yeah, I can fire him.
- The patients in my vocational
therapy program,
who I vet thoroughly,
by the way,
are far less likely
to be violent
than anyone you would hire
from a résumé
and a five-minute interview.
These are safe people.
These are people that have
held down jobs before.
And most importantly, Veronica,
Dr. Fuentes, they are healing.
- Mm-hmm.
- These jobs are a bridge
to life after this hospital.
They need that.
- Yeah, Dr. Frome,
I'm so sorry, but yeah,
Christmas is over,
and so is this program.
Sorry. Dr. Reynolds.
Doctor--
- Yeah.
- Ah, Dr. Reynolds.
I need you to oversee
the rollout
of our new quotas for
invasive surgical procedures.
- Right.
We've worked very hard to
minimize unnecessary surgeries.
- Mm-hmm.
- Less invasive procedures
like stenting,
avoid unnecessary risk.
- Well,
they also avoid profits.
Dr. Bloom, there'll be no more
sending your patients
up to surgery
for elective procedures.
If it's not emergent,
discharge them.
Insurance companies,
they want people to schedule
their elective surgeries from
the comfort of their own home.
- No.
When I send a patient
up for surgery,
it's because they need it.
When insurance companies
dictate what's elective,
people die, and I'm not
sending patients home
to call their
insurance companies
when many patients
don't have insurance
and they don't have a home.
- Well, unfortunately,
solving the social ills
of the world
is not this hospital's job,
despite what your former boss
might have said.
Dr. Wilder.
Dr. Wilder, please be advised
that we are lowering suggested
screening age
for mammograms from 40 to 30.
- Consider it done.
- Well, that's the spirit.
Well done and thank you,
Dr. Wilder.
Everyone, I know
that this budget squeeze
has been very, very hard
on everyone
so I am so happy
to share with you
exactly what you've been
sacrificing for.
Will you please join me
in welcoming Dr. Mia Castries,
chair of holistic medicine.
- Did she just say
"holistic medicine"?
- I lost a third
of my department
for hand massages and crystals.
- I sense
a powerful energy here.
I'm just kidding.
I'm not a crazy person.
- Because obviously,
this is black tourmaline
and to get your pineal gland
ready for energy discernment,
you would need amethyst
or lapis lazuli.
Blessings.
I'm excited to be here.
- And we're so excited
to have you. Welcome.
- Dr. Castries comes to us
from the university hospital
where she's emerged
as a leader in one of America's
most rapidly-expanding
medical fields.
♪
- Hello?
This is creepy.
- Yeah, just a touch.
- Anyone alive in here?
- Oh, God!
Why?
- Thank you for coming.
- Okay, so you sent us
that text.
- You mind telling us
what this is about?
- We have a shared enemy
who's too powerful
to defeat separately,
so we need to work together
in secret
to undermine her from within
and make sure our patients
get the care they need
and deserve starting now.
We are forming an insurrection.
Vive la résistance.
Now, who's with me?
♪
Sorry, I forgot to say
it's Veronica.
The person we need to defeat
is Veronica.
- Yeah, we figured.
- Still nothing?
- We literally just heard
you enthusiastically agree
to downgrade
women's healthcare.
- That is part of our strategy.
We can't defeat somebody who
knows we're coming for them.
- Mm.
- Okay, even if that's true,
I'm out.
I have four kids.
I'm not going to risk my job.
I'm sorry.
- Don't look at me.
I got too much going on
in my personal life
to squeeze in a revolution.
- Yeah, and I don't know
you from Adam.
- Sorry.
♪
- What would Max do?
- You didn't even know Max.
- My last hospital was run
by somebody just like Veronica.
All they ever cared about was
"Oh, how many people
did you cut?
How much money did you make?"
Max reminded me that a hospital
can be more than that.
I could be more than that.
I rearranged my entire life
after knowing him
for two weeks.
You knew him for years.
What did he do for you?
What would Max want you to do?
Right now?
- But Max isn't here,
and he's not coming back.
.
♪
- Dr. Clemit,
I owe you an apology.
I've been here a month,
and I have yet
to address your department's
chronic lack of patients.
- Occupational therapy
has a low profile.
We do our work
with quiet dignity
and let our reputation
speak for itself.
- Or we could slap your face
on the cover of magazines
and tube stations.
I'm thinking a full
PR offensive,
community outreach, lectures,
you talking up our hospital's
unrivaled rehabilitation clinic
to anyone who'll listen.
- But that's boasting.
- I should jolly well hope so.
Dr. Grey,
I couldn't help but notice
your pediatrics department
is bursting at the seams.
- The NHS allots its resources
using an algorithm
based
on neighborhood demographics,
and four doctors
is all they gave us.
- That's because
their algorithm is from 1997.
Since then the number of minors
in Hampstead has tripled.
- Can't fight the algorithm,
can you?
- And yet, I just did.
I've hired six
new pediatricians.
- Patient satisfaction surveys.
- Ah, Liz, I've been
looking forward to these.
Let's hear from the people.
In the States, this is scored
on a scale up to 100.
All these single digits
are giving me a turn.
- In the UK, they're also
scored on a scale up 100.
- What?
But these scores are terrible.
What are we doing wrong?
- Ah. Yes.
No, yes, yes. Absolutely.
I'm just going
to write that down.
Now, I'm going to put you
on a quick hold, I think.
Hi.
How can I help?
- I need to reschedule
a procedure.
- Okay.
- My name is Ruth Gleadle.
- Gleadle.
That's a lovely name.
Ah, excuse me.
Yep.
This way,
Gleadle, Gleadle...
- Oi, while we're young!
- Ah, yes, indeed.
Yes, indeed.
While we are--found it.
Found it.
Let's just take a quick look.
Shall we?
Okay, I see biopsy scheduled
for a growth on your pancreas.
- That's right.
- Well, if I may, Ruth, that's
a fairly serious procedure.
Your biopsy is part of a
endoscopic retrograde
cholangiopancreatography
that you really
don't want to put off.
- Are you a doctor?
- Yes.
No, technically at the moment.
The license is in the mail,
but don't let that scare you.
I'm going to tell you exactly
what's going to happen.
So first you're going
to get a sedative.
It's going to help you
feel calm and relaxed.
Then you're going
to have liquid anesthetic
applied to the back of your--
- Any available porter to--
-  Grab discharge
paperwork for Greg Treize.
I'm going to reset his wrist,
and then he's out of here.
- You mean Lightning Guy?
- Don't call him that.
Mr. Treize--
where's Lightning Guy?
- Oh, that tingles.
- What the hell?
I don't know
how things were done
in the lost city of Atlantis,
but here in this hospital where
we practice real medicine,
we don't just take
other doctors' patients.
Are we clear?
- Yes.
Listen, I don't want
to bum you out,
but Atlantis
was not a real place.
- Get those needles out of him.
- This man needs
his chi rebalanced.
- And I'm a Pisces.
- Why don't you tell her
what you told me?
- I'm cursed.
- Okay, there is no such thing
as a curse.
- I was hit by lightning
in January.
- Climate change.
- I've been bit by a shark
in a river.
I got hit on the head with
a golf ball while I was skiing.
One time, I was kicked
by a horse while surfing.
- When your energy is out of
alignment, bad things happen.
- The man was hit with
50,000 volts of electricity,
and he survived.
That's not a curse.
That's a blessing.
Oh!
♪
- We're fired.
We're really fired?
- Call it laid off.
- So we can claim unemployment?
- No.
The vocational
placement programs
for inpatients don't--
they don't qualify.
- I know I can do better.
Please just give me
another chance.
- Tracy, I can't.
I really wish I could.
- But what did I do wrong?
- Nothing.
You did nothing wrong.
- Sure she did.
We all did.
We have mental illnesses,
and people don't want
crazy people working for them.
Tell me that's not
what this is.
- Cheek swab done. You?
- Done.
My father would not approve.
- Man, if I told my mom
about this,
it would kill her dead.
That's good that you were close
with your father, though.
If, you know,
this is my kid,
I'd like to be a dad like that.
My dad wasn't exactly the
role model I wish he'd been.
- Floyd, you're gonna be
a good father.
Damn good.
- Thank you.
- And if this child
isn't yours,
no shame in stepping away.
Linda and I will be just fine.
- I mean, you and I
took the same test.
Have you ever thought
about what your plans would be
if it's mine?
- My plans?
- Yeah.
There's no shame
in stepping away.
- Oh, is that how this is?
- You see any other way?
- Okay, Greg.
No talking.
I want you to take some nice,
deep breaths for me, okay?
This is just to make sure
there's no brain injury
from the door
or from any of your
other hundred head injuries.
- Okay, so that's not actually
going to help you find
what you're looking for.
- Yeah?
Well, call me old-fashioned,
but everything I do
is rooted in science.
Unlike energy work or curses,
or magic rocks whose only power
is in your head.
- Oh, so you're saying they
have a psychological impact
rather than a measurable
physiological effect.
- Yes.
- That's the definition
of placebo.
Belief has power
when a patient
believes that they're healing.
They can and that's why
Greg's belief that he is cursed
is a medical issue and one
that you should take seriously.
- Okay, Greg.
I'm looking at your CTs
and you are concussion-free.
For those scoring at home,
that's curse, zero,
modern medicine...
♪
- What's that blotch?
- That's cancer.
- Easy.
Ugh.
- Oh, brutal.
- Yes, Trotsky, it's brutal.
Keen observation.
Thank you.
Max and I were very proud
of this program.
Showed my patients
they could have jobs,
they could have independence,
they could have hope.
Showed everyone else, too,
and now this.
- Veronica told you to stop
placing patients in jobs
at New Amsterdam.
- Correct.
- But she didn't say anything
about them
just getting hired
on their own.
♪
- What do you mean? Hire them
as real baristas and janitors?
- They are real janitors
and real baristas.
- I know.
- You have already proven that!
And who is more likely to give
them a shot than the people
who have already seen
how well they can do?
♪
- You know who you sound
like, right?
- Vive la résistance.
♪
- Okay. Viva, indeed.
.
- Hey, Boss, just about
to head out for a spot of tea.
- It's 12:30.
That's just lunch.
- Well, what if I have tea?
- Still lunch.
- Oh.
Tea time sounds more fun.
Uh, I would've
have invited you,
but I figured you were slammed.
As soon as I get my license,
I can take a few things
off your plate.
- That sounds amazing,
but right now,
the patient satisfaction
surveys just came out,
and they didn't paint
the rosiest of pictures.
- Mm, yeah, I know
how tough it can be
to pinpoint the exact reasons
for patient dissatisfaction.
- And yet.
- What?
- Um, out of curiosity,
have you noticed any delays
in your waiting area?
- Oh, yeah, yeah.
Crazy delays, long lines,
angry patients.
I mean, there's a lot
of problems
with this nationalized
health care thing.
You know,
some of these patients
have been waiting months
for simple procedures.
- Right.
So the thing is
Roderick Cantleigh,
who is a knight commander
and the NHS executive
who controls our funding
is coming this afternoon
to discuss my new initiatives.
- That's great! Look at you,
people taking notice.
Sir Roderick Cantleigh
taking notice.
- No, not Sir.
- But you said he's a knight.
- Knight commander.
- What's the difference?
- It's not important.
- Okay.
- But what is important is
if you could somehow
expedite things in your domain,
like, I don't know,
answer the phone when it rings.
Just keep the line moving.
That would help me
greatly today.
- Right.
For you, my love,
I will answer the phone
when it rings.
- Thank you.
- I got you.
I gotta grab some tea.
But not teatime.
Just tea in the afternoon.
- Just tell me again
how this is good news.
- Okay, look, I will grant you
that a lightning strike,
followed by a freak head injury
is unlucky,
but if those things
hadn't have happened,
we would never
have found the cancer.
- It just never ends.
- Look, I get that cancer
sounds scary,
but we can take care of it
with a simple surgery--
- No.
No surgery.
- But Mr. Treize,
it is a routine procedure.
- Until the curse makes you
drop a scalpel in me.
- That is not gonna happen.
- Yes! It will.
If it can go wrong,
it will go wrong.
This is my life.
You don't understand.
- You're right.
She doesn't understand.
She has no idea.
The fear that you live with?
- Dr. Castries,
can I just have a word--
- You've tried everything.
You say that you'll be
more careful, kinder.
You pray, and none of it works
because the universe
is against you.
♪
- What can I do?
- Get the surgery.
See, someone has to fix your
cancer, and that's her job.
And someone has to fix
your curse, and that's me.
And I'm going to be with you
every step of your journey.
- Okay, I'll do it.
- So Carl, I spoke to your
former boss in janitorial,
and it seems the only way
to keep you on
is if he hires you
the old-fashioned way.
- Wait. What are you saying?
- That you're rehired.
Yeah.
First shift is this afternoon
if you want it.
- Hell yeah, I want it!
- Good!
Okay, big guy.
- I'm going to learn to draw
your face in latte foam.
- Okay.
Oh, this is excellent news!
I got some real innovations
in mind for that pasta bar.
- Good.
Good, good, good.
- I tried, but no department
can pay for a year-round Santa.
- You know...
people really do need Christmas
spirit the whole year round.
- Yeah, I really am sorry.
- I'll do it for free.
- Maybe we can try again
after Thanksgiving. Okay?
Yeah.
♪
- Veronica just deemed
the removal of my cancer
patient's tumor elective.
Which means I can't send him
to you for surgery,
but delaying him even
a couple days could kill him.
- Agreed.
- You said you wanted
a revolution, right?
Well, here's your chance.
Do the surgery anyway.
Defy Veronica.
♪
- No.
- No?
So your whole
"what would Max do" spiel
this morning,
that was all just BS?
- Wait!
If I said yes,
Veronica would see the surgery
on the OR schedule
and shut it down,
but this is a big hospital.
So many other floors,
other rooms.
♪
- Hey. How's it going?
So good to see you.
- I just, uh,
I just need to vent
and for someone to listen,
and since I'm not trying to put
all my business
on the front street
in this hospital--
- Okay.
Hey, hey, hey, say less.
I got you.
I'm here.
- Thank you.
- Okay.
- 'Cause I just found out
that my genius husband
went and got himself
a paternity test.
I mean, what was he thinking?
Now is not the time for that.
Now is a time for all of us
to be focused on--
- Well, well, uh,
maybe he had
certain questions.
You know?
Feelings.
- Oh.
No.
- Look, I--I--I--I know you
talked about us being a team.
- What is this, "I talked"?
We talked.
- You're asking me not to care
about whose baby this is?
That's against human nature.
- I get it, Floyd.
You want to know.
I want to know.
My problem isn't human nature.
My problem is the fact
that you went behind my back,
and you took a test whose
whole point is to tell you
if my baby isn't your problem.
- That's not why I took
the test.
- Then why'd you take it?
- Well, it's complicated!
-  Well, you said
you were in for complicated.
Oh.
Oh, God--okay.
- Lyn?
- Oh wait. No.
Oh, something--
something's wrong.
- Yeah? Talk to me.
What's wrong? What is it?
- Stabbing pain.
I think I'm spotting,
I think I'm spotting.
.
- Did the CVS cause this?
Did the CVS cause this?
- No.
- We need to test
that bloody discharge.
- And look for ferning.
See if the cervix
is still closed.
- Just--please just let her
do her job.
- I say just start magnesium.
- We got any evidence
of premature contractions?
- What evidence you
waiting for?
- Out.
Both of you.
- Lyn, everything's gonna
be okay.
- Yeah, we're just trying
to take care of you.
- I want them both gone.
- Get out.
Get out!
♪
- Yes, of course, sir,
I will transfer you now.
Well, ta to you as well.
Does anybody need anything?
Good afternoon.
- Oh, is it my turn?
- No, no.
I just noticed that you were
filling out your
patient satisfaction surveys
and thought I'd cut out
the middleman
and hear from the people
directly.
- You selling something?
- Uh, no.
I'm just, uh, the new guy
and, uh, want to make
some big changes.
- The receptionist
is making big changes.
- I have the boss' ear.
So, uh, hit me.
What do you got?
Your harshest critiques.
- Well, it's the same old song,
isn't it?
Month to see your GP.
You want to see a specialist,
God help you.
- Yeah,
it's always a new person.
Makes you feel like nobody
gives a toss.
- And if you want anything
above and beyond,
people treat you like
you're selfish.
- I get it.
- No, you don't, love.
We're all in this room
because we have cancer.
- I'm a cancer survivor.
Two years in remission.
And my doctor was--
she was everything.
When I was half dead
from chemo,
last thing I would have wanted
was to be shuffled around
from one new person
to the next,
so you're not being selfish.
You're just asking for dignity.
- You're a receptionist?
Side hustle.
My main gig
is fixing broken systems.
So what do you say
we work on this one?
♪
- Before we begin,
I want to be very clear.
This is an open act of defiance
against a corrupt regime.
Everyone in this room
is now part of the resistance.
♪
- This might be unorthodox,
but the surgery is not a risk.
I'm confident of its success.
- And the only risk
is to our jobs,
so I need to know.
Is everyone in?
♪
All right.
Let's get started.
♪
- You know, I've been fired
a few times in my life,
and by few, I mean several.
I think the worst time
was probably--
- It's not the same.
- Yeah, you're right.
It's hard to find
the right comparison, you know?
- The suit, the beard.
Being Santa is not my job.
It's who I am.
It's why I am.
Without it, it's like...
I'm falling.
If I'm not Santa,
I'm nothing at all.
- Mm.
Yeah.
I'm not buying it.
- Ho, ho, ho!
- I'm not!
I mean, yeah, Santa,
that's your dream gig,
but if we're talking
nuts and bolts here,
you are extremely employable.
- Ah, you're patronizing me.
- I'm not!
Why would I patronize you?
I mean, unless you're telling
me that being Santa is easy--
- It's not easy!
There's a lot of
hard work involved!
- That's what I'm saying!
We're on the same page here.
I mean, the amount of work
that goes into one night--
- One night?
It's not one night!
Everyone always thinks
it's one night,
but the prep
starts December 26,
and it does not stop,
believe you me.
- I do.
I do believe you.
I can barely manage
the logistics in my department.
- Logistics, record-keeping,
organization,
overseeing all types
of interesting personalities--
- Hold on.
I got it.
♪
- What?
- Your perfect job.
♪
- Roderick Cantleigh?
Hi. Dr. Helen Sharpe.
Thank you so much for coming.
So exciting to have
the NHS Regional Director
for all of London
visiting our humble hospital.
- Unexpected visits
from one's boss' boss' boss
are rarely cause
for excitement.
- Right. Okay.
Um...
look, I know that my
proposed reforms are ambitious,
but I assure you
they are useful,
they are commonsensical,
they're patient-focused--
- American.
Your ideas are American.
- I am aware that there
are differences
between the American health
care system and England--
- Ours is better.
- But...
England shaped me
as a doctor and as a person,
and I promise you,
under my leadership,
Hampstead will be the essence
of English health,
and the community
that I am proud to call home
will support it wholeheartedly.
Shall we?
- We demand personalized
oncology services!
- Doctors of our choosing
available when we need them!
- And you should get out
your bloody cell phones!
- We want it the American way!
- This is a human right!
.
- Dr. Baptiste, your wife
and the fetus are stable.
- Thank you.
- Would you like to
come be with her?
- Yes.
You coming?
Hey.
Dr. Matsudaira said
you're doing good.
- And the baby, too.
- Yeah.
We're good.
- I'm so sorry, Lyn.
- Yeah, we both are.
- Can't speak for Floyd,
but for me,
this ride that we're on can
bring up a lot of insecurities.
- Amen to that.
- None of it's an excuse.
You needed us. Both of us.
And we were off playing
who's the alpha.
- And who won?
♪
- We don't know.
We told the lab
to destroy the samples.
We got so wrapped up
in that test
that we didn't even ask
about the test that mattered.
♪
- What did your CVS show?
- It came back clean.
- That's good.
♪
- I want to know too
who the father is.
How could I not?
But if we're being real,
you don't need a DNA test
to know if someone's a father.
He's the guy who doesn't have
to think twice
about showing up.
♪
I wanted us to be better
than this.
♪
- How you feeling?
- You can skip the preamble.
You opened me up and you found
that the cancer had spread.
- No.
- Or an aneurysm
or a plague of locusts.
- No.
No, it went great.
- Did I die?
Am I dead right now?
- Mr. Treize,
I just looked at your labs.
We managed to remove
all the cancer.
Margins are clear.
Medically speaking,
you're cured.
- She did it.
- Who did what?
- Dr. Castries.
She said that she was going
to break the curse,
that she was going to be
by my side during surgery.
And here I am.
Here I am.
And you were skeptical
at first,
but you got to hand it to her.
- I guess I do. Come on,
let's get you to post-op.
You know,
I feel a real sense of harmony.
like the universe and I--
- Whoa!
- Sorry!
- All right. I'm going
to take you up there myself.
♪
- I'm in the market
for a second assistant
because my schedule
is just too complex
for one person
to handle it alone.
This job is demanding.
It is high-octane. It is fast.
Do you think you are up
for that, um, Chris?
- Absolutely.
- It's only part-time.
- Perfect.
- That said, may call you in
on the weekends.
- It'll be like I never
leave the hospital.
- Hm.
Now it says here that
you worked for Goldman Sachs,
left three years ago,
haven't worked since.
Bit of a red flag.
Why the break?
- I needed to take some time
off to see the world.
- Wow.
Anyway,
this all sounds great to me.
Is there anything else
that I should know?
- Um, yes, there is.
Um, I hope this isn't
a dealbreaker,
but I'll need
December 25th off.
- Hi.
I was paged?
- Greg Treize wants to talk
to you about his chi.
- Yes. Where is he?
- Post-op.
- But his surgery
was cancelled.
- No.
I heard it went well, actually.
- So you're telling me that
Veronica's new assistant
is a secret Santa?
- I am.
- Oh, my God. It's too good.
- It felt good,
I got to be honest.
What about you, though?
This place is
a surgical theater,
it's a revolutionary hideout.
I mean, you almost forget
it's chock-full of dead bodies.
They're right there.
- Well, you know, famously,
they tell no tales.
That's so dark.
Oh, guys,
I'm having some feelings.
♪
This place feels like
New Amsterdam again
for the first time
since Max walked out,
and it's because
of who walked in.
♪
- Nothing says I'm sorry
for starting a rebellion
like dosas and chutney, right?
My mistake.
You can't help
but rebel against the system.
It's in your blood.
- Well, to be fair,
you did leave a Yank
in charge of a British system.
Uh, you should count yourself
lucky no one threw tea.
- Roderick repealed my reforms.
Every last one.
- Could be worse, right?
- He also cut 10%
of my funding.
- Should have let you finish.
But good news,
I got my license,
so I am now a fully-certified
practicing UK physician,
and I am ready to rock.
Put me in, Coach.
I am ready to help
this clinic in any--
- You're fired.
- I'm--I'm what?
- I can't hire you, Max,
and you are fired
from being quite possibly
the worst receptionist ever.
Today I had to face the fact
that my, um,
my "American fixes"
are not going to work here.
They're not going to work
in this system.
And that includes you.
I know that you're
looking for something,
and I will do anything
to help you find it,
but I have to figure out
Hampstead on my own.
I need to make it work, like,
on my own.
So.
♪
why are you smiling?
- 'Cause I'm
the terrible receptionist.
Yeah.
- Terrible.
Really very bad at it.
But also because
I'm in awe of you.
♪
And everything that you are.
- Well, you shouldn't be.
You should be very deeply
frustrated with me
because this whole transition
has been way harder
than I expected it to be.
♪
And I'm so worried that
you're going to hate it here
and worried that you're going
to think it's all a mistake,
and you're going
to resent me for it
what with everything
that you left behind--
- I love it here.
Because I love you.
And, you know,
you're here, so...
so I love it here.
And I don't know
if I'd say worst receptionist
just 'cause there's a lot
of receptionists in England.
Oh, my God.
- So, you know,
maybe really bad, but--
♪