I have been fantasizing
about this for months.
Forget it. We're not here to fool
around. I'm not fooling around.
I need this.
You're an idiot, you know that?
Just shut up and
give me a boost.
Hurry your ass up!
Hey, sometimes a guy's
gotta do what a guy's gotta do.
Jaguar One to Control.
Sorry for the delay. Glenn had
to take a leak. It was unavoidable.
Target area is clear. Repeat,
target area confirmed clear.
Dr. Lee, target area's cleared,
launch vehicle's in range.
All systems go. Thank you,
Cesar. Whenever you're ready.
The CT-10's light enough
to launch from a UAV,
but can penetrate 8 feet of 6,000
psi concrete before detonation.
Bombs away.
The precision guidance system's
not affected by darkness or weather
and can hit a 2-foot wide
target from 69,000 feet.
- What about sound?
- None in-bound at all.
We've developed a new fin
and a baffling design that...
Ordnance on target
in three, two, one.
I feel better already.
You need to see a shrink.
Seriously.
Well done. That's
really... Wendy!
Call 911!
Karma's a bitch.
You think her seizures
are the result of bad karma?
I think if you spend your days
designing ever more effective
ways to blow people up,
stuff's bound to
come back to you.
Thirsty. Side effect of the
new antihistamine I'm on.
You don't seem congested.
Intriguing. You have any
thoughts about our patient?
Got some questions about whether
Thirteen really believes in karma
or just wants to.
As to the patient, it's not gonna
be easy to break into her office.
You might want to
start with her home.
We could ask to look
through her office.
And we could do an MRI first.
Sure. Go ahead.
If you're not interested in
the case, why'd you take it?
I'm definitely interested.
Could be a tumor,
could be a CNS bleed.
But what do you do when
you got two interesting puzzles?
Two?
50 bucks! Pay up.
- Let's go. Let's go.
- Bet's off.
The fight was fixed.
The punch barely
even touched him.
You bet on Foley
to beat Zachary?
Speed beats power.
Unless speed has been
paid to speedily take a dive.
He touched him enough
to put him on the canvas
and the official
counted him out,
which means you
officially owe me
50 bucks.
We bet on a sporting event.
That was not sporting.
At less than 30 seconds,
that was barely even eventy.
Okay, here's what I
saw, you lost and I won.
Well, you can take that to your
grave. You're not taking my 50 bucks.
Prove it. Prove it or
pay up. You got one day.
And don't make me send
my boys out looking for you.
What?
All right.
So, two puzzles.
Tie goes to the one
that cost me money.
We'll keep each other posted.
I've always been healthy.
I never even get colds.
I guess your luck
finally ran out.
I take it she doesn't like
people who make bombs.
I'm sorry, I didn't
mean to... It's all right.
Half of my family
feels the same way.
Of course, they all
work on Wall Street, so...
Ever since the first Fourth
of July I can remember,
I've always loved explosions.
When I got to college
and I had to pick a major,
I figured I might as well pick
something I'm passionate about.
Destroying things. You weren't
passionate about anything else?
Bombs are tools
just like anything else.
You can use it to
make things better,
or you can use it t
make things worse.
I also like romantic
poetry and picnics.
Is there anything else you wanna
know before we do this MRI?
No. Try to stay
as still as possible.
This shouldn't take long.
Hey, how's it going?
You mind? There are
plenty of other seats.
I'm not here to judge.
You did what was best for you,
and I got no problem with that.
I'm not gonna ask you
nice again. Just go away.
Or what? You're
suddenly gonna fall down?
Listen, I got a problem.
A guy who knows absolutely
nothing about boxing,
because of you
now thinks he does.
You can imagine the
potential ramifications.
I need you to get on the phone
with him, and tell him you took a dive.
I didn't take a dive.
Take a picture of you to prove that
it was really you, and we're done.
Just enough to convince him, not
enough to get you in any trouble.
I didn't take a dive.
Yeah, that story's
getting boring.
Look, I'm not from the
commission, I'm not some bookie.
I'm a doctor. Here's my ID.
If you were a bookie,
you'd know no one pays a guy to
throw a fight he has no chance to win.
I was a 12-to-1 underdog,
lost my last five fights.
But you were the better fighter
and that last punch
barely touched you.
You ever been barely touched
by a guy who weighs 230 pounds?
Look at me. Look where
I am, what I'm wearing.
Do I look like a guy
who just got a payday?
I didn't throw the fight,
I just suck.
Ha!
Proof.
Just because he
wasn't hit in the face...
Look at his pupils.
He has anisocoria, which, given his
age, the adrenaline surge in the fight,
and the fact that he's still
alive, means he was tachycardic.
He has Wolff-Parkinson-White
syndrome.
The bet was on who would win,
not who would live the longest.
If he's physically unable to continue
because of a pre-existing illness,
then it's technically a no contest,
which means all bets are off.
You know that just because I
was right about this one fighter,
doesn't make you
any less of a man.
Actually, it would
if you were right.
Then, as I said
earlier, prove it.
And one possibly photoshopped cell
phone pic does not a diagnosis make.
Excuse me, Dr. House.
I'm a co-worker of Wendy
Lee's. I'm also her boyfriend.
Great. I'm a guy
who doesn't care.
She's your patient.
You thought I didn't know
who Wendy Lee was?
That makes sense.
I'm not good at names.
Did Dr. Fortune tell you that?
Her last boyfriend was a real
nut. He's basically stalking her.
See, this is what
I don't care about.
I don't care who cares about
her, who used to care about her.
If either one of you falls down
dead, you can drop me a note, but...
I think I know what's
wrong with her.
What, you screwed up in the lab and
accidentally spilled some bomb on her?
No.
He really is crazy.
Poisoned?
Apparently our mad scientist
is also a slutty scientist,
whose milkshake's got all the
nerds in the yard fighting over her.
She's a slut because she's
dated two different guys at work?
I'm sorry, I thought we
were still judging her.
She's not a slut
and it's not poison.
When we tested her blood and
cerebral spinal fluid for toxic exposure,
it was negative for every
poison we could think of.
Well, that just leaves every
poison we didn't think of.
She works in a bomb factory.
So do a lot of other
not-sick people.
If the guy had any actual
evidence she was poisoned,
he would've gone to
the police, not to us.
And if we had any evidence
of what was wrong with her,
you'd be showing us MRI results.
I assume they were negative.
Couldn't hurt to start activated
charcoal, see what happens.
You know what
else wouldn't hurt?
This case is
getting interesting.
Let's add a little danger.
Just because he has guns
doesn't make him a murderer.
Tell that to the bear.
Look in the desk. See if
he's got a diary or a journal.
Something tells me he's
not exactly a diary kind of guy.
Maybe a manifesto.
Just look. I'm gonna check
out the rest of the place.
See if he's got a computer.
It's Foreman. Yep.
You break in yet? Yeah,
we're in the abattoir now. Why?
You can leave. I think Taub
and I found what we're looking for.
Looks like she actually was being poisoned,
but she's been doing it to herself.
- I'm not an alcoholic.
- I know, I know,
the whole label
thing is so limiting.
You're a person who happens
to suffer from alcoholism.
You broke into my house and
now you're being a smart ass?
During your history, you
said you didn't drink. At all.
I don't. You just
collect bottles.
Yes.
I collect them for my friend.
She uses them in her art projects.
And you're ashamed of these art
projects. The bottles were hidden...
That's because my housekeeper
keeps throwing them out.
I've told her a
dozen times not to,
but either she doesn't
understand or she doesn't care.
Why would she lie?
That's the easy question.
She needs a government
security clearance for her job.
And what's the hard question?
If she's an alcoholic,
why doesn't she have at least
some partially full bottles in the house?
And why keep the empties?
Why not just throw them away?
So she's probably telling
the truth. So what do we do?
We start her on Valium
for alcohol withdrawal.
It's the best we've
got right now.
One normal EKG does
not a healthy person make.
Look, I told you, I just suck.
Oh, you make me so sad.
Don't talk like that. Why
do you care so much?
Kill me for loving my
patients. It's just what I do.
Hey, stop.
Stop!
My leg hurts. Just talk
to me for a moment.
You don't have to
be a loser. Thanks.
Whatever's wrong
with you, it's real.
Sick is good.
Sick means it can get
better. You could get better.
I don't mean healthier. I mean,
maybe you don't have to suck.
Figure out what's wrong with
yourself and leave me alone.
Abdominal pain.
She said it felt like
she was being stabbed.
Give her morphine,
5 milligrams IV.
Is it a symptom of the underlying
condition or a symptom of our treatment?
We'll know soon. I stopped our
treatment. We should restart it.
Acute pancreatitis from alcoholism
would cause this kind of pain.
It's stress related.
She's in a lot of pain.
She's under a lot of stress.
She's got two guys
fighting over her
and she just got done with
the final test of a new bomb.
Her guilt is killing her.
As far as you know, she likes being
the center of attention and loves her job.
As far as you know,
she doesn't drink.
What if it's a kidney infection?
Acute pyelonephritis could kill her
if we don't start her on IV antibiotics.
Would kill her if it
was pyelonephritis.
But since her urine and CSF
don't show signs of infection...
I paged House.
What? We got nothing.
Less than nothing since he's
actually ignoring my pages,
which means we have a sick
patient and apparently a sick boss.
Tell him you admit he's right.
Let's get him back to work.
If he's ignoring you, it's
because he trusts you.
No, it's not. No, it's not.
But he does. Thanks,
I feel warm inside.
But right now I'm debating which
bad idea I should pretend is a good idea
and force everybody
to implement.
I think this is good for him.
Obsessing over a bet is good?
And doing his actual job,
treating actual patients, that's bad?
House only doing what House
wants, is the only way he can function.
Since the breakup, he's been seeking
out crazier and crazier things to do
because they're crazy.
This... Well, it's not crazy.
No, just irresponsible
and possibly dangerous.
By House standards, it's dull.
This he's doing just
because he's interested.
I think House getting back
to doing stupid House stuff
for stupid House reasons is the
best thing that could happen to him.
I'll go explain
that to the patient.
It's definitely
not pancreatitis.
Restarting the treatment
obviously didn't help anything.
Assume you
tested for infections.
And I assume that look
means yes and I was wrong.
You call for a psych consult?
Wow, that's the same
look I just got from Chase.
So an hour ago, we had three
theories we couldn't agree on.
Now we've got no theories,
but we're in agreement.
CT and ultrasound show
inflammation in the renal capsule.
Could be an obstructing
calculus or perinephric abscess.
Blood cultures came back negative.
It's probably just a benign cyst.
Yeah, so let's just dismiss an
idea because it's probably nothing.
It could be gas in
the perinephric space,
in which case we should be
prepping her for emergency surgery.
What looks like
Wolff-Parkinson-White, but isn't?
Her EKG was normal. So was his.
That's why I said looks like, as
in similar to, but not the same.
You want us to help you
get out of paying your bet,
while your actual
patient lies in agony.
Who's the real bad guy here?
The guy who doesn't
care enough to help,
or the four guys who aren't
competent enough to help?
Works out too much,
gets pounded too much,
and not in the romantic way,
his pupils... I got it.
Your patient? No.
Plenty of time to save her
life after we save my money.
Underlying neurological condition
exacerbated by an acute UTI
brought on by her
sexual escapades.
Slut, escapades. How
do we treat? A scarlet A?
Sorry. Acute UTI brought on by her
healthy enjoyment of her womanhood.
We start her on IV ampicillin
and an aminoglycoside.
You ignore us all the time, you
go on crazy joyrides all the time,
but you answer pages, you sleep.
I know I'm gonna regret
doing this, but I'll ask anyway.
Is there anything
I can do to help?
Although...
Great news.
You have an underlying
neurological condition,
which together with your heart...
You said my heart was fine.
Yeah, I also said that I would
get you your career back.
But that doesn't seem to matter
since you've so clearly been
handed the golden spit bucket here.
Sympathetic overdrive.
It's a medical term,
so is "great news."
'Course if you
prefer wallowing...
All you need is a chin,
and a heart, apparently.
You can go back to being the
guy who won 20 of his first 20
instead of the guy who
lost five of his last five.
Technically I counted the
last one as a no contest.
And you save 50
bucks. I'm a doctor.
I don't tell a fat guy to lay
off bacon for less than 300.
This is about
dignity. For both of us.
Give me your arm.
What the hell?
Don't worry, it's just
epinephrine. Is it dangerous?
In the wrong hands,
very. So yeah, sort of.
This will only take
a few seconds.
And you are tachycardic.
You're... Are you psycho?
We combine the increased
heart rate with chest trauma
by applying a little sweet
science to the science.
Don't worry. I'll explain
more when you wake up.
Now, the punch that
supposedly knocked you out
looked like it was thrown by
an old cripple. Kind of like this.
Stop it. Three, two, one...
Huh.
Guess I must be older and
more crippled than I thought.
You're embarrassing me.
It doesn't make sense.
Maybe if I...
Get the hell out of
my life, you lunatic.
She's in V-tach. BP's dropping.
Whatever you're
doing isn't working.
Again. There's gotta be
some way to stop the seizures.
It's not a seizure. She's
having a heart attack.
No pulse. CESAR: That's
impossible. She runs marathons.
Charging 200. Clear.
Still no pulse.
Charging 300. Why
is this happening?
Clear.
My theory is that he's only avoiding
us because he really wants to avoid you.
Mah nishtana?
You made it through med school
without ever attending a seder?
It means, "Why is this night
different from all other nights?"
I'm not sure it is, but usually when
push comes to shove he shows up.
If the patient's still alive, then
push hasn't met shove yet.
The patient is hanging by a
thread and we don't have a clue why.
Then we have to assume
he does, and she isn't.
We could. Or we could assume that
something is seriously wrong with House,
and try to do
something about that.
This way, even if we're
wrong, nobody dies.
House is fine.
House is always fine.
I'm expanding my theory.
He's avoiding you and you're avoiding
him, and this patient is gonna die.
Not if you do your job.
You're an idiot.
How'd you get in here?
My boss has me break
into places all the time.
Pain's been getting worse.
Figured if I upped the Vicodin any
more, I'd end up back in a rubber room.
So this seemed like
the smarter choice.
You're an idiot.
You drove all the way over here
to break in and call me an idiot?
No, I drove all the
way over here to tell you
we're implanting an
automated cardio-defibrillator,
which won't actually do
anything to help the patient
except maybe give us enough
time to come up with a guess
as to what's actually
wrong with her.
Oh, that makes more sense.
And I broke in here because Cuddy
and Wilson, both, separately, asked me to.
Even more logical.
And that's not heroin.
Which means you knew
I was coming over here
and Cuddy and Wilson are
right. You're just playing a game.
Throwing out a bone and
watching us fight over it.
There is another theory.
Compound CS-804.
It's an experimental drug that's
supposed to re-grow muscle.
This experiment
was done on rats.
It's groundbreaking.
A huge success.
In rats.
They got four legs. Think
how fast it should work on one.
You're an idiot.
We've got a problem.
AICD not working?
If it was the defibrillator,
I'd be looking elsewhere.
Smells like bleeding. Rectal?
And vaginal.
Is it possible something got
perforated during surgery?
Is that an accusation?
Sounded like a question.
Just a straightforward inquiry
that only someone with serious
insecurities would take issue with.
Okay. So in answering I have to
decide between the only two possibilities,
"No," and "Yes," we
might have screwed
something up but are
intentionally hiding it
"because we're incompetent
and we're asses."
The answer's no. Glad we
didn't short-change that avenue.
It's a blood disorder,
a coagulopathy.
That's not a diagnosis. It's like
saying she has a runny nose.
True. But not saying she has a
runny nose risks getting snot all over us.
We can treat it. Cause
could still be a toxin.
She must have been
exposed to who knows...
Past tense. Which means she
would've been better now that she's not.
Same goes for House.
If this was about Cuddy, he
would have checked out weeks ago.
Something else is
going on. Something new.
That's an awfully simplistic
approach to matters of the heart.
House is rational.
He prides himself on...
No one is rational about emotions.
That's why they're emotions.
What do you think?
Me? I didn't say anything.
Exactly. You always have
some opinion on these things,
especially when
it comes to House,
doubly especially when it
comes to men and romance,
but suddenly you're
keeping your mouth shut.
House can't help us.
I respect his privacy,
no matter how stupid,
and I'd appreciate it
if you'd respect mine.
We need to treat the
underlying condition.
Could be cancer, sepsis, trauma,
liver disease, haemorrhagic fever...
I'm gonna start treating the symptoms while
you finish listing the possible causes.
The rats are doing great.
"Great" is a little vague.
Even better than
the previous study.
12% increase in
strength, 22% in flexibility,
and some improvement in
at least 60% of the subjects.
Have you done maximum
tolerated dose studies?
Not yet. But that's
part of the beauty.
Since the compound is
easily excreted in the urine,
as long as they keep hydrated,
there's really no reason to expect
any danger at virtually any dose.
I mean, obviously,
can't know for sure, but...
If it's worthy of the
preface "obviously,"
then obviously, it only needs
to be explained to idiots.
Do I look like an idiot?
Sorry. Cranky.
What I meant to say was, why
don't scientists have groupies?
Because I'd do you right now
if society wasn't telling me that
you're just an underpaid dork.
Thank you.
Are you all right?
Leg hurts.
Would you mind
getting me a coffee?
How does coffee help your leg?
It will prevent me from
walking to get the coffee.
Right.
The page said she's now
bleeding from her mouth.
You started treatment?
I said I would.
A "yes" would have been fine.
Not asking the question
would have been even better.
Any breathing issues? No.
But I'm not sure it's internal.
If it's coming from
both ends, it's internal.
Her gums look like
they were burned.
Experimental drugs?
That's unfair. 'Cause at one point,
even Vicodin was an experimental drug.
I have to go. Well, unless
you're going to do your job,
it can wait. I'm
going to do my job.
I'll give you a lift.
I'll give you two minutes.
But first I'm going to tell
you that I'm off the drugs
and then you'll feel silly because
you got nothing to say for two minutes.
Hmm.
Why are you off them?
'Cause they don't work.
Why were you on them? Because
they come in banana flavor.
You know the answer.
You think fixing your
leg will fix your life.
I think that my life will be
somewhat better if part of my life,
specifically my leg,
is somewhat better.
You think all your
problems are your leg.
So you're here to tell me that no matter
how depressed I may be, it's not enough.
I think you want
everything to be physical,
tangible, simple.
You want unhappiness to have
a cure. House, you obviously...
I hate that word.
I have to go now.
Actually, I don't. It would be rude
to walk out without saying anything.
What about this?
28-year-old woman presenting
with burn-like wounds in her mouth
and esophagus from
a candidiasis infection.
Interesting. And it would also be
relevant if the woman had had seizures.
If the fungus had
entered her bloodstream...
We would have seen
it in the blood work.
Acute myeloid leukemia can
cause swelling of the gums...
Again, interesting, but not
relevant. Again, you're being an ass.
She doesn't have a history
of blood diseases in her family,
her blood count's normal, and she
hasn't been exposed to a chemical toxin.
Not that we know of.
The guy she works the most
closely with is also her boyfriend.
You don't think
he would've told us
if there'd been some sort
of chemical spill or accident?
There is one other cause of AML.
Wait, where are you taking her?
We need to get her
into an isolation room
and prep for a hematopoietic
stem cell transplant.
Isolation? Why?
We think her blood and immune
system have been destroyed
by an exposure to
ionizing radiation.
We don't work with radiation.
Well, apparently your girlfriend does.
No. She doesn't. You're
wrong, it must be something else.
We found reports that your company
was developing tactical nuclear warheads
for bunker busting bombs.
Where? On Wikipedia?
Some paranoid idiot's blog?
I don't care where
you read it. It's not true.
You're saying there's absolutely no
chance that anyone in your company
is doing any experimental
research that you don't know about.
No. But I know Wendy,
and she wouldn't.
Maybe you don't know her
as well as you thought you did.
Excuse me. We have to go.
You need a drink.
I'm fine.
That wasn't a question.
You really do need a drink.
We found a match.
We'll start treatment as soon as
we get the HSC from the donor.
Shouldn't be long.
Where's Cesar?
Uh, he's, uh, in
the waiting room.
I want to see him.
We can't. It's too dangerous with
your immune system this compromised.
Why can't he just put on a
gown and a mask like you?
I'm sorry.
The more people you're exposed
to, the greater the chance of infection.
I'm scared.
I know.
We're doing everything that we
can. Cesar will be with you soon.
Dr. Foreman, you
should look at this.
What is it? You feeling any
pain in your pelvic region?
No, why? Your genitals,
they're engorged.
I drink anymore,
I'm gonna explode.
You're not gonna explode.
You're just gonna have a seizure.
Which will prove that your
kidneys are not working,
which will also prove they
weren't working Saturday night.
That's why a glancing body blow
sent your blood pressure into the toilet
and you onto the canvas.
How many bottles is
this supposed to take?
Six.
And I've drank how many? Eight.
It's not an exact
science. In other words,
nothing's gonna prove you wrong.
You're just gonna keep making me
miserable because you're too miserable...
You're an idiot.
And no, you're not gonna hit me.
Because somewhere deep in
that way too thin skull of yours,
you know that
you're full of crap.
That's why you stopped jogging for
me, it's why you drank eight bottles.
Because even though you want to
think that I'm wrong because it's simpler,
you also desperately
want me to be right.
I'm only an ass for building
your hopes up if I'm wrong.
Last one.
You're an ass.
You were wrong, it's
not the end of the world...
Anything else you want to say?
You have a problem.
I think if you seriously
look at everything that...
Anything else?
Okay, look, this isn't...
Okay! Okay, okay.
No, I don't.
Just get out of here.
Go home, we'll talk later.
Someplace without
any of my stuff.
Nothing to talk about.
That was my point.
Inflammation of the genitals
means we were wrong.
Thanks for the
statement of the obvious.
You'd think so, wouldn't you?
Foreman wants to keep
treating for radiation poisoning.
Because the seizures have stopped,
because her fever's gone away,
because she's improved. By luck.
I don't think the patient cares.
Yes. She's gonna die in considerably
less discomfort thanks to you
treating a few of the symptoms
instead of the disease.
I paged... Shut up.
You're drunk.
Well, whose fault is that?
Give me another
scotch. I can't serve you.
Is it because I'm black?
Because I'm not,
so... Come on, buddy.
What? You can't get me drunk and
then give me crap for being drunk.
That's like dumping someone, and
then giving them crap for being upset.
It's just not decent.
Let me explain why
people come here.
They come here to drink.
Which causes us to ask,
"Why do people drink?" Mmm?
Is it sustenance?
No. Is it taste?
Nope. Don't be a jerk.
Is it the company of
stout-hearted men?
I don't think so.
Is it killing pain?
Yes. 7.5% life duller.
That's the business you're in.
You're in the
screw-the-world business.
You're in the reality-sucks-
and-fantasy-temporarily-
appears-to-not-suck business.
Just get the moron a drink
so he'll shut the hell up.
No.
I'm giving you your
drink. Have you no pride?
Either serving me is a
good idea or it's a bad idea.
Shutting me up is a crappy reason
for compromising what you believe.
And not even an
effective one, apparently.
Am I gonna have to hit
him? Not a good idea.
But what if it's the
right thing to do?
Compromise is never the answer.
Stand up.
I will allow you to
throw the first punch.
Sit down. I'm not gonna hit you.
Just as well,
'cause I was lying.
You can relax.
She's getting better?
The bad news is,
because of your extended
exposure to her and her workplace,
we're gonna need to
treat you as well. I feel fine.
Unfortunately, that's the
way it can be with radiation.
No symptoms until it's
too late to do anything.
You're gonna need a
bone marrow transplant.
No.
A marrow transplant does leave
you exposed to all sorts of illnesses,
but there's really
no choice here.
She doesn't have radiation poisoning.
- She's getting better.
We need to start our
treatment before it's too late.
No.
You're either suicidal,
or you know we're wrong.
And the only way you can know
for sure what wasn't killing her
is if you knew what was.
And you do, don't you?
Because you've
been poisoning her.
And the reason she's getting better,
is because you haven't been near her.
Our co-workers are on their
way to your home right now
to search it for poisons.
You mind saving
them the trouble?
Attempted murder
is better than murder.
What are you doing here?
Training for my big
fight. Just need you to...
Drink five more bottles, get
punched a few more times?
Look, just get out and give up.
Nah, that's your specialty.
Ooh, looks like you
already lost your big fight.
Look, I may not be able to take
a punch, but I can still throw one.
Three, two...
What a lovely day.
Where's Cesar?
Uh...
In jail.
He was trying to kill you.
He found out about
you and Glenn.
Which, he admitted,
shouldn't have surprised him,
since he started seeing you
while you were dating Tony.
He poisoned me? Repeatedly.
With Spanish fly.
The active ingredient
cantharidin is a potent toxin
and can cause a lot of the
same damage as radiation.
He poisoned me?
I'm sorry.
He had a security clearance.
What's this?
A palm.
Hmm. Useful for many things.
Slapping, greasing, probably
some other applications, too.
Right now it's ready
for $50 and humiliation.
He was actually sick? He
wasn't knocked out by the punch,
he was knocked out by
the clinch before the punch.
He took a shot to
the back of the neck.
More specifically, to an abnormal growth
of nerves caused by a glomus tumor.
Kind of like a built-in taser sent a
massive shock to his entire body,
shut everything down.
Wow. Fascinating. Completely
explains exactly how he lost.
Oh, you are not gonna be like that,
because you've got a lot more posters here.
No. I'm not. Well done, House.
You might have saved that
guy. Given him his life back.
No, no. He needs surgery.
He's never gonna fight again.
What happened to
your eye? You okay?
Better than okay.