Before we operate,
we place drapes
over our patient,
exposing only the area
where we'll be working.
They not only help us focus
on what we need to see,
but they keep the field clean
and minimize debris
getting in the way.
Incoming! And I don't
have a lot of time.
Do you want to use one of our
other three bathrooms to vomit?
Shh!
I feel decent for the first
time in weeks, so don't jinx it.
Oh, and don't forget we have
our first OB appointment today.
I thought - that was after work.
- It is.
- So what's the rush?
- Well, the kids are still asleep,
my charts are done,
and I've got just enough
time for a quick shower.
♪ Pull me back, let that
slingshot set me free ♪
How quick?
If it's too quick,
I'll kill you.
Drapes are specialized to fit
the needs of various surgeries.
The challenge comes
when there's a complication
under the drape.
Oh, and we switched
to a new EMR.
Now you select the
medication on top
and then scroll all the way
down to enter the dosage.
Makes no sense.
Medication up top. Dosage
on the bottom. Got it.
And you only allowed
two pairs of scrubs now.
It's all automated.
Miranda, I've been
a resident before.
- I'll be okay.
- You're not nervous?
No, I feel great.
It's like coming home.
Dr. Bailey, welcome back.
Yeah, welcome back
to the both of you.
Oh, Warren, do... do
you know a Dr. Ndugu?
Are you kidding? I tore up the
dance floor at his wedding.
My moves were basically a meme.
I was like, "uh, uh!"
How's Catherine?
Oh, feeling better every day,
especially now that we know the
biopsy results were negative.
Thank God. She wants
to throw a party.
Caviar and champagne,
and not the kind you get from
your regular grocery store.
Well, I'd expect no
less. Send her our best.
- Will do.
- Okay.
This... means stop talking.
What? Ndugu and Pierce
are getting a divorce.
- Oh.
- Aw.
When the body's draped,
we can't see something going
pale or a leg turning blue.
I refuse to be late on
Bailey's first day back.
Tell that to the guy who
took a 20-minute shower.
Says the guy who
doesn't live there.
Hey. There was a
fistfight on my bus.
I thought I was gonna be late.
Hey. Where's your sister?
We want to meet your mini-Mika.
Late, and we're
not alike at all.
When we can't see
the whole body,
we might miss a telltale
sign something's gone wrong.
Thank you.
Sorry. I left my
phone on the plane,
and the line for the
bathroom was really long,
and then Dumbledore
missed the freeway exit.
My rideshare driver
looked just like him.
I couldn't see it.
Yep. Not alike at all.
That's Lucas,
a.k.a. Skywalker,
Simone, Blue, and, uh, Jules.
Hi.
This is my youngest
sister, Chloe.
I have cancer.
Don't be late for Bailey.
We'll see you later.
Come here. It's gonna be okay.
Dr. Webber is the best.
We'll figure this out.
Come on.
Huh?
Here is the overnight
roster list.
You need to follow up
on Ms. Borgman's CT,
and there are two rule-out
appy consults in the ER
waiting for ultrasounds.
Good morning to you, too.
Not all of us just spent
two weeks in Paris.
Clearly. Mm.
This is nothing
like a café crème.
Will you just take
this so I can go home
and face plant onto my pillow?
Morning. Good morning.
I mean, uh, hi. I... Hey.
This is James, the
hospital chaplain.
Enchanté.
Taryn.
- You work nights?
- I work when I'm needed.
Is that from the coffee cart?
Oh, no. I drink French now.
It's, uh, Le Gateau
Jolie down the street.
Okay.
I could use some coffee.
Would you want to go for a walk?
Oui. Oh! That's
French for "yes."
Nice to meet you.
Welcome back, boy.
So Bailey's her husband's
boss. Is that allowed?
Oh, one of your aunts is
head of the neuro department,
and your other aunt's
name is on the building.
Heron hired him before she left.
Everyone says he's impressive.
Bring it. You
all slow me down.
Oh, my God. He's not
your competition.
He's a fourth year
on a trial basis
until the ACGME
approves him to stay.
Well, there's a finite
number of people
who can fit around
an operating table.
Everyone is my competition,
including Mr. Dr. Bailey.
Uh, it's Warren,
actually. Ben Warren.
Looking forward to working
with you again, Dr. Kwan.
I see you've met Dr. Warren.
Yes, he is my husband.
No, he will not be
getting special treatment.
As for the rest of you,
any bad habits you picked up
while I was gone... lose them.
You have four months
left in your intern year.
I want you sprinting
to that finish line.
Understood?
All right. Helm has
your assignments.
Any problems, she'll be
happy to hear about it.
Get to work.
Okay, Griffith is with Ndugu.
Warren and Kwan, to the pit.
Adams and Millin with me.
Ah. Oh.
Dr. Agana to PEDS ICU.
Dr. Rachel Agana...
100 unread e-mails after
operating all night.
Why do I like this job again?
Were you in the OR? Yeah.
Nasty bus accident
at the airport.
I was called in around
4:00. Kids are at my mom's.
Oh, no. Why didn't
you call me?
I didn't want to disturb you
while you were in surgery.
- What's wrong?
- I had muffins and bagels delivered to the house
because you've been on the
morning routine so often,
I wanted to take care
of breakfast for you.
You should have said something.
It was supposed
to be a surprise.
Do you think that your mom could
go over there and grab them?
I am in back-to-back meetings,
and Richard wants the
quarterly budget report
before it goes to the board.
Sounds like you need a break.
That is the opposite
of what I need.
Trust me. I had your job.
You have to pace yourself.
This job is very
different than the job
you had 10 years ago, but,
um, thanks for the tip.
I'm just trying to help.
I have to go fire an
anesthesiologist. Okay.
Uh, you said we'd
be saving lives.
I said you'd be
helping to save lives.
You are contributing to one of
the most memorable experiences
in a medical
student's education,
providing the opportunity
to learn human anatomy
while developing their
own understanding
of what it means to be human.
Uh, are those... I
hate this already.
Cadavers for Ander-Simmons's
med school anatomy lab.
We scan them so
students have images
to help them diagnose
how their cadavers died
during their
anatomy-class dissection.
- Good luck.
- Uh, you're not helping?
Ce n'est pas la mer à boire.
Pretty sure that
means "we're screwed."
Dr. Karascos to PEDS.
Dr. Vivianne Karascos to PEDS.
Dr. Ndugu.
Am I getting out of here today?
This pneumonia's taking
up all of my field time.
I supposed to be out
blocking the half-time show.
Mr. Riley's a high
school band director.
You win the state championship
three times in a row?
Oh, come on, don't take the
fourth one away from me.
All right, well, we'll make this quick
so you can get back to it, all right?
- Dr. Griffith.
- Darren Riley, 55, history of smoking
and pulmonary
fibrosis, admitted for
multi-drug-resistant
gram negative pneumonia,
currently on seven liters
nasal cannula and Vanc-Zosyn.
Oh, there's music in
the voice. You sing?
No, but I marched
in high school.
Birds of a feather.
Which instrument?
Trombone.
Oh, former 'bone
player and a doctor.
- That's not bad.
- It's not.
SATs are low, despite
the nasal cannula.
Okay, uh, let's put
him on high flow
and then get him to CT.
Dr. Griffith's gonna take you - for some scans.
- More scans?
We're doing everything we can
to get you out of here, okay?
Stay close. No local family,
and his last ABG
came back borderline.
I reviewed your
scans with radiology.
There is some
suspicious-appearing lymph nodes.
It's likely stage 3B
rectal cancer due to...
Wait. 3B? I thought it was 2A.
Mimi, can you just stop moving?
Sorry.
Okay. Uh, what happens next?
Chemotherapy? Radiation?
Correct. Mm, surgery
is a possibility,
depending on the
tumor's response.
- Will I lose my hair?
- It's possible.
What other side
effects are there?
Oh, it varies from
patient to patient.
Radiation often causes
impaired ovarian function.
There is nausea and fatigue,
and changes in mood and
weight are common, too.
I won't be able to have kids?
We'll have you talk to an
OB/GYN about your options.
Do you have any other
questions for me?
How long does
chemo usually take?
Wait. So you went from
Wyoming to Raleigh
to St. Louis to Seattle?
There were a bunch
of places in between.
I-I did the whole global-nomad
thing before divinity school.
I've only ever lived here.
But you travel, right?
Well, I used to visit my
grandparents in Illinois.
Well, but then how did you
end up becoming a chaplain?
I grew up in Wyoming with
two devout Episcopal parents.
I-I love them, but it
was, uh, complicated.
Was it like a... like a
hard coming-out thing or...?
No, not really. Um,
I'm an only child,
and I always felt this pressure
to be their everything.
And, uh, I don't
know, I needed space.
So left home, never looked back.
And then they died.
I'm so sorry.
Yeah, I wish I had a more noble
reason for becoming a chaplain.
But truth is, I only
really found my faith again
because of grief, guilt.
Sometimes you have
to help yourself
in order to help others.
That's very poetic.
That's my mother.
She's a whole
other conversation.
You know, I have time.
Wanna get lunch?
Yeah.
I called up CT.
They know we'll be
there in two minutes.
They told us to come
in in Trauma One.
Warren, nice to see you back
on this side of
the ambulance bay.
On a trial basis for
now. You back full time?
But don't go easy. I'm
just another resident.
Well, uh, why don't you
warm up with some sutures?
We have a small thigh
lac in bed three.
I just gave her some lido.
And Kwan, you can help him out.
After you.
Uh, Ms. Dunn.
I'm Dr. Warren, and
this is Dr. Kwan.
Judith is fine. Not Judy.
Judy is my mother, and
she talks to her plants.
Judith it is.
So it says here you have
a cut on your thigh.
Let's take a look.
Roll over, please.
Okay.
Okay. Uh...
It's my own dumb fault. Oh.
Six-inch stilettos
and tequila don't mix.
Oh. What was the occasion?
The tequila was for
my friend's birthday.
The heels were for my new peach.
I got a BBL two months ago...
a Brazilian butt lift.
Oh. We're familiar.
Careful, Doctor.
All that drool could
stain your white coat.
No, no, no, it's, um...
it's not what you think.
Um, I grabbed the wrong sutures.
Can you grab me a 4-oh-monocryl?
Uh, I was just getting a
better future for your cut.
How are you feeling?
You need more lidocaine?
I don't feel the cut
anymore, but, ugh,
it's my hip - that's killing me.
- From the fall?
I finally feel well enough to
take this booty out for a spin,
and now my hip's
hurting like hell.
Ah, it's probably just bruising,
but we'll get some labs
and X-rays just to be safe.
Can you grab the labs and
I'll take care of the X-rays?
You got it, boss.
Oh!
Oh, why is it that everybody
who donates their body
to science weighs
like 800 pounds?
They don't. They just can't
change their center of gravity
like live people. They're
literally dead weight.
Okay. Can you... Can you
hold your side up more?
I am. He's sagging.
I don't think he cares.
Oh!
Well, the good news is, uh,
we only have 29 left of these.
What's the bad news?
He's on feet first.
Uh, Griffith?
How busy are you?
I'm almost done inputting
orders for Dr. Ndugu.
And then I should start
rounds in about 20 minutes.
Oh, uh, just enough
time to run to the pit.
You need something there?
There are a couple of patients
on Dr. Hunt's service.
Can you check on them for me?
You need me to add
someone to my roster list?
Oh, no. No. Uh, just see
how things are going.
Like, check and
see if the patients
are satisfied with
their care here?
Um, you don't need to
say anything to them.
Just discreetly observe.
See how the patients are doing.
See how the
doctors... are doing.
Got it. And then I should
circle back with you after.
Took the words right
out of my mouth.
We typically recommend
hormone-replacement therapy
for the loss of estrogen
production and fertility.
So that would allow me to
have kids later if I want.
Well, there's no guarantees,
but i f you want to
increase your chances,
many patients opt to retrieve
and freeze their eggs.
What do you think?
Uh, It'll take at least a month
to do a round of egg retrieval.
That's if your body responds
to the hormones correctly.
The cancer could spread to a
later stage during that time.
There are other options, right?
At this time, egg freezing is
the most effective and common.
Okay. Find something else.
Look at other
colorectal cancer cases.
- Meet with your department.
- Yasuda...
There has to be a way.
It's okay, Mimi.
I'm not sure I really
want kids anyway.
Warren, nice to see you back.
What do we got?
Uh, 34-year-old female,
history of type-two diabetes.
Tripped and fell onto her
left thigh three days ago.
Sustained a thigh laceration,
but has pain with weight bearing
that's getting more severe.
- How are her labs?
- Still waiting.
I just called to
put a rush on it.
You think it's a
hip joint effusion?
I couldn't tell you.
This is a lateral hip.
I need an AP view.
I-I don't know what happened.
I ordered an X-ray series.
Oh, the system is
a little funky.
You gotta go to the dropdown - to order the AP view.
- Oh.
Hip joint effusions are
difficult to see on X-rays.
A CT scan would give
better visibility.
Kwan's right. Page us
when you've got it.
Mm.
You want me to show you how...
No, I-I got it. I got it.
- Oh!
- Whoa!
- Oh.
Are you okay?
Chloe's cancer is more
advanced than we thought.
I'm so sorry.
Webber asked
Dr. Sugihara to see her.
Chief of Oncology. That's
good. It's terrible.
She has to start chemo
and radiation right away,
which means she doesn't have
time to protect her fertility.
Oh. Does she want kids?
She's 22.
She doesn't know what she
wants for breakfast tomorrow.
She's the eighth out
of eight sisters.
She spent her whole life
getting dragged to our
practices, our recitals.
She only ever had hand-me-downs.
Always had to watch us
on the roller coasters
because she wasn't tall enough.
And now that she's
finally out of our shadows
and starting to
live her own life...
this.
Her future should be wide open,
not limited by an awful disease.
Well, at least she'll
still be alive.
What is that supposed to mean?
Nothing. I'm just trying
to look on the bright side.
My sister has cancer.
There is no bright side.
But you wouldn't
get that, would you?
Because you don't have sisters.
You have one brother who thinks
celery juice changes lives,
and you don't even like him.
So please don't pretend to
understand what this feels like.
You never will.
No. No way. You're living
in complete fantasy.
You asked my opinion.
Well, I wasn't expecting
it to be wrong.
I am a man of science.
I don't know what
else to tell you.
The Millennium Falcon
can go faster than light.
It has hyperdrive.
That thing breaks
down more often
than my mom's old Ford Taurus.
It made the Kessel Run
in under 12 parsecs.
The Kessel Run tests
navigation, not speed.
The Enterprise is
exponentially faster.
How do you figure? Warp
1 is the speed of light.
Even the original Enterprise
went up to Warp 5.
- Who are you?
- So you would rather be the captain
of the Enterprise than Han Solo?
Obviously.
Do you want to go
back to my place?
Obviously.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
I thought you were
on cardio today.
I am. I had to run
downstairs for something.
Well, I'm, uh...
glad I got to see you.
Mm.
Hi.
Can I ask you a
hypothetical question? Yeah.
If you were asked to review
a colleague's performance
and they made an
inconsequential mistake,
would you mention it?
Are we getting peer reviewed?
No, more of a
informal observation.
- Will they get in trouble?
- I don't think so.
Okay, so, uh, nothing
major went wrong,
and there are no consequences.
I think you answered
my question.
How's your project with Helm?
Is it something
fun? Deathly boring?
Definitely the latter.
Mm.
Your sister went
outside to get some air
and call your parents.
Oh.
Colorectal cancer and
fertility studies.
Just educating myself.
I know you want things
to be better for Chloe.
She's my sister.
And you're also a surgeon.
We like to believe we can
solve everyone's problems.
I really thought there'd
be other options,
but Wilson's right.
You know...
I've seen a lot of cancer
patients in my career.
And no matter the type or stage,
the treatment process...
it's grueling.
Some people say the
side effects of it
or just as horrible
as the cancer itself.
Everyone has the same questions,
and they reckon with
the same concerns.
Cancer is universal that way.
It's universal.
What if I can find a precedent
for protecting fertility
when treating other cancers?
Then I'd be willing
to bet it's relevant
to colorectal cancer, too.
Oh, Jo. Jo.
Ben Warren. Oh, my God!
You missed me, I missed
you. It's great to be back.
I just gave someone a heparin
drip instead of prophylaxis.
How do I stop it?
Oh, yeah. The new EMR
system is confusing.
Okay, type in the
patient's MRN there,
and then you are
gonna click here.
- Okay.
- Here.
- You're done.
Okay.
I've had three careers.
You think I'd remember that
the first day is always rough.
- It'll get better.
- Kwan is lapping me,
and he's only been a
doctor eight months.
You'll be fine. You've
been off fighting fires.
I went from splicing intestines
to delivering babies,
and I still have no
idea what day it is,
and I'm a constant mess.
Yeah? What's new in your life?
Can you keep it a secret?
Yeah.
Yasuda, are you okay?
I need your help.
Okay.
Hey. Turkey burgers
from the cafeteria.
Listen, I think earlier
I might have, uh...
Insinuated that you know
the job better than me?
You're lucky I'm hungry.
Hey, would you ever
get a butt lift?
Uh, no, no, no, no, no,
I'm not suggesting...
you are... you are perfect.
But there's a woman in the ER.
She just had one, and,
uh, I don't get it.
What don't you get?
Well, it's a surgery
with risks, and why?
So you can wear
different clothes?
Wait. You think that this
woman underwent anesthesia,
had surgeons cut into her
glutes, suck fat from her belly,
and put it back in her butt
just so that she could
wear different clothes?
I mean, why else
would she do it?
Let me break it down for you.
The world that you live
in, where you do a good job
and you get rewarded for it...
that is not the world
that women live in.
In our world, you
can be smarter,
you can work harder,
but the prettier person who
has a more desirable body
most always gets ahead because
the people who decide that
are almost always men.
So before we rush to judge the
woman for being so desperate
that she underwent surgery
to change her body,
maybe we should think about
how our culture prioritizes
the wrong things
and think about how
we can change that.
I was just asking.
And I was just answering.
Sorry. I have to take this.
Um, thank you for the burger.
Yeah. No. Um, I
want to review that.
I never thought I'd say this,
but I am missing Pearl.
Is that your partner
or your friend?
My booty pillow.
These cheeks could
use a good cushion.
Are you in more pain?
A little.
Well, the scans will be quick,
so just try to sit still.
I know what you're thinking.
Trust me.
My family gave me grief
for getting surgery, too.
But for 30 years, no one
blinked an eye at me.
I was a sidekick
with a pancake butt.
But then overnight,
I became the star.
I've never felt more
empowered in my own skin.
Forget the jobs
that work from home
and the movies on the couch.
I'm planning on taking this
beauty all across town.
Oh, the labs are in.
- White count is 18,000.
- That can't be right.
Are you sure you're
looking at the right value?
Yeah, I'm more than familiar
with our lab results system.
If you want to rerun them,
I'll let Dr. Hunt know.
These numbers are
off the charts.
Scans are up.
You see that? Extensive
signs of infection
to the muscle along
the fascial planes.
Are we done?
Judith, I'm gonna have
to check your hip again.
May I? Yeah.
Is that...
Necrotizing fasciitis.
Someone help me
with this gurney?
What's going on?
What's happening?
You have a fast-moving
soft-tissue infection.
But don't worry. We're faster.
I need you to page the attendings
and book an OR right now.
On my count. One, two, three.
I like that painting.
Get to wake up to the sunrise
even when it's raining.
I thought you were gonna say,
even in the middle of the day,
Mm. That, too. Mm-hmm.
I, um...
I got it at an
Italian restaurant.
Is it Nicoletti's?
No, it was a little
cafe in Cortona, Italy.
I was going through
a rough time,
so I booked a
redeye to Florence.
And I told myself I would
visit every art museum
between there and Vatican City.
I strained my neck, gazing
at Michelangelo's work
in the Sistine
Chapel, and, uh...
I don't know. When
I saw that sunrise,
it lifted something up in me.
So I asked the restaurant owner
if he would sell it to me.
You know how
sometimes you just...
feel a strong connection?
I do.
Page me as soon as
his ABG gets back.
Dr. Ndugu's asking.
Dr. Griffith?
So how was everything with
the patient in the ER?
Things seem smooth?
Everything appeared in control.
I don't think you have anything
to worry about on the case.
Wait. You think or you know?
Are we talking about
Big-Booty Judy, or... right.
Look, um, it's not that I
don't think he will succeed.
Um, I also want to make sure
that he has an
objective experience,
the same treatment as everyone.
And if I go down there,
my appearance in the room
takes away that objectivity.
I can spare another
five minutes.
Thank you.
So you'd move my
ovaries into my abdomen?
We'd move them up and attach
them to the abdominal wall
so they're out of the
field of radiation.
Has this been done before?
Ovarian transposition
is often used to help
preserve the fertility of
cervical cancer patients,
but there's no reason it
couldn't apply to your case.
I'd be able to have kids later?
There is a 50% to
80% success rate.
That's better than zero.
And if we can preserve
your ovarian function,
then you likely will not
need hormone replacements.
This is great.
Thank you so much.
Thank your sister. She's
the one who thought of it.
Can we do this today?
That way I can start
treatment sooner,
finish my last semester before
my scholarship runs out.
I should totally do
this right now, right?
I mean, just get it done?
Yeah, I'm gonna call Mom
and Dad first, but yes.
You want Dr. Weber
and Dr. Wilson
to be the ones to do it.
And you can be in the
operating room with me?
I can't, Chloe.
Family's not allowed.
Oh. Right.
Hey, think of it like one
of your cross-country races.
It'll be over
before you know it.
And I will be as close
as I can be, okay?
- Okay.
- Okay?
Okay. Let's do it.
Do you always eat when
you're scanning patients?
Well, I mean, technically
he's not a patient,
and he's in a bag and dead.
Oh, Yasuda's sister
is getting surgery.
Is it an emergency?
It doesn't seem like it.
They're waiting
for an OR to open.
What's going on between you two?
Uh, nothing.
Oh.
Is that her? No, it's Maxine.
Spaghetti and
meatballs for dinner.
Yasuda's not texting me.
She basically accused
me of having no empathy.
Well, her sister has
cancer. She's just stressed.
Well, you know what's not going
to make her sister get better?
Being mean to me.
Really?!
He can't hear me.
Heart rate's in the 140s.
Systolic's around 100.
We broadened IV antibiotics
and started low-dose norepi.
Judith, we're taking
you up to the OR
to remove the infected tissue
and stop it spreading, okay?
You're gonna take my butt?
The infection seems to
have spread to your glute,
but we won't know
till we get to the OR.
No, I want a second opinion.
There's no time for
another opinion.
You have to trust us.
I don't understand. I
just fell on the sidewalk.
The bacteria must got in
through the cut on your thigh.
It's rare, but it happens.
Do you know what it's
like to be invisible?
If there were any other options,
we would tell you,
I promise, Judith.
Judith. Judith. Judith!
Damn it, she's septic.
Come on, come on, come on.
Okay, let's go! Let's move!
Mr. Riley, hold on. I got ya.
I need a hand in
here! Griffin!
He started crashing
a minute ago.
I need to intubate.
Push 30 of etomidate,
- 150 of sux.
- On it.
- Where is Griffith?
- I got the intubation tray.
All right, let's
get you some air.
Here we go. Here we go.
Ah, come on.
Damn it! Help!
Helm, get in here!
I need you to apply
cricoid pressure.
There? Higher.
There. You're right
there. Right there.
And I'm in. Al right.
Come on.
Oh, his sats aren't improving.
We need to get him on
ECMO before the hypoxemia
puts too much stress on
his heart and he codes.
I need an ECMO
machine right now!
What happened?
He was intubated, but
he wasn't oxygenating.
You'd know that if you were
monitoring him like I asked.
I'm sorry. I ran down
to the emergency room...
I don't want to hear
it. Wait outside.
Helm, get the tube ready.
Okay. I hit a pocket of fluid.
Suction.
Oh!
Oh, she's gonna be devastated
when she wakes up
and it's all gone.
Well, at least
she'll still be here.
If we can work fast enough.
I'm gonna need
another set of hands.
Warren, are you
ready to get in here?
Sure. Scalpel.
Good. Quick and intentional.
I can help if you need it.
Just keep up with the suction.
Actually, you know, I
could use a hand in here.
Kwan, you wanna help break
up some of this tissue?
Yeah.
Oh, I see healthy tissue.
Yeah, there it is.
Bleeding edges.
Nice work... boss.
Moving on to the superior
aspect of the thigh.
Last one.
Do you remember your
med-school cadaver?
Yeah. 68-year-old female,
lungs full of mets.
Uh, we assumed she was a smoker.
Named her Marge and
decided she was a trucker.
Mm. Mine was my grandma.
Uh, wait. You, uh,
dissected your grandmother?
What? God, no. No, no.
My dad's mom died
before I was born,
and then my mom
really hated hers,
so I-I kind of grew
up without a grandma.
But we had been dissecting
our cadaver for weeks
before we finally took
the towel off her face.
And I remember looking
at her and thinking,
she could be my grandma.
And I just hoped that
she didn't feel... alone.
I hoped she felt that she
was surrounded by people
who truly appreciated her.
I, uh... I never thought
about it that way.
Yeah. And then we cut open
her neck and her head and...
finished it.
Um... could you transfer the
scans to the CDs by yourself?
There's something I
really need to do.
Yeah? Yeah, okay.
♪ But with you, I'll follow ♪
♪ We've made it through winter ♪
Hey, any, uh, news from the pit?
How is he?
He's on ECMO and stable,
but I don't know if he'll
ever breathe on his own again.
I'm so sorry.
What were you doing in the ER
when my patients are up here?
Please explain that to me.
Oh, uh, w-why don't
we take a breath?
I'm breathing just
fine. Thank you.
I was checking on a
patient for a colleague...
In the ER?
Doctor Ndugu...
Dr. Bailey, hold on.
If I can't trust you to
follow simple instructions,
I can't have you on my
service. Dr. Ndugu...
I asked you to step in
because... I need a word.
In private.
♪ Follow you ♪
♪ I'll follow you ♪
Okay.♪ Follow you ♪
♪ Follow you, follow you ♪
♪ Follow you ♪
♪ I'll follow you ♪
We're about to start
the anesthesia.
Are you ready?
Okay. Wait. Um, excuse me.
Is it all right if I...
♪ Follow you ♪
Hi. I'm Jules. We
met this morning.
I'm one of the interns.
I know who you are.
♪ Follow you ♪
♪ I'll follow you ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Follow you, follow you ♪
Hey, I asked Griffith
to check on the patient
in the emergency room.
I didn't realize that your
patient was borderline critical.
She knew. She
should have said no.
I'm her boss, right?
It's not her fault.
Why... Why did you
send her downstairs?
You're not working there today.
I don't know. I...
First day back in a while.
I wanted to see how
things were going.
That's all.
Okay. Take it from
the guy who married
and then divorced his boss.
Get out of your husband's way.
I beg your pardon?
I'm saying at home
you need to be a team.
At work, let him
be his own person.
Hey. I'm sorry, I'm sorry,
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
The appointment
was at 5:00, right?
I know. I just got so
busy with patients,
- I completely forgot.
- You don't have to apologize.
- DeLuca had to leave.
- We were gonna see the baby.
Mm, we'll just reschedule.
Wait. Come with me.
Judith, how are you feeling?
You really have to ask?
You should be
feeling better soon.
We were able to remove
the infected tissue.
Yeah, we'll keep you in
the ICU for a few more days
to wash out the
wound and make sure
there's no more necrotic tissue.
Okay, Trauma.
Kwan, come with me.
Uh, check on the cultures,
and we'll see you downstairs.
Judith, I will come
check on you soon, okay?
♪ A little bit of good news ♪
Ah.♪ I can't help
but feel like life ♪
I know it feels like
you're going back
to an old version of yourself.
But I've learned when it feels
like you're losing ground,
you're still moving forward.
Everything you've learned,
everything you've experienced,
it all comes with you.
I can't tell you what's
not coming with me.
The $8,000 I spent on my butt.
No, but all that confidence
you gained after the lift...
we didn't take any of that.
Are you saying I
have big-butt energy?
I'm saying all is not lost.
But if down the road you
decide you want reconstruction,
I know a great plastic
surgeon in Boston.
Now you're talking.
Get some rest.
♪ Someday I will look back ♪
♪ I hope I understand ♪
♪ Why I had to
go through that ♪
She's doing well.
There were no complications,
and Dr. Webber says
she should be able
to go home soon.
I'm sorry for what
I said earlier.
Sometimes I can be such a...
Thank you for sitting with her.
You have no idea how
much that meant to her.
How much it meant to me.
Well, I knew you
couldn't do it, so...
didn't want her to be alone.
♪ Need a silver
lining, oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ I need a silver
Thank you for everything.
Well, I was glad to help.
Oh, it's not easy to watch
someone you love fight cancer.
They'll be days you feel like
your heart's being
ripped to pieces.
Remember to take care
of yourself, too.
Thank you.♪ Just
give me a sign ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Please just give me a sign ♪
♪ Please just show me a sign ♪
Hey. You still haven't finished
uploading all the scans.
Yeah, I know.
Adams, they have this covered.
Hey, hey! Show some respect.
These people
donated their bodies
so that future
doctors could learn
how to help others live
longer, healthier lives.
Okay, sorry.
I wanted to help.
Hey. Oh, aren't you supposed
to be getting the kids?
Yeah, well, I thought we
could grab a bite first.
Oh, I can, uh,
either eat with you
or feed the kids, but I
don't have time for both.
- Do you not feel this?
- Feel what?
Ever since we got rehired,
we haven't had a single
meal alone together.
We haven't had a conversation
that wasn't about surgery
or the kids' schedules
in almost three weeks.
Well, work has been
busy, but, you know,
we'll get back on
track eventually.
It's just...
feels like we're not
connecting, you know?
It feels like there's
something eating away
at this relationship.
And I know I stepped in
it more than once today...
No, it's... it's not just you.
I feel it, too.
When a patient codes in surgery,
the first thing we do
is remove their drape.
We need to see if there's
something we missed.
Is this a mistake?
Me being your boss?
When are you not my boss?
"Ben, can you take
out the garbage?
Ooh, ooh, babe,
kill that spider.
Ben, why haven't you changed
the light in the refrigerator?"
Oh, don't be cute.
You know what I mean.
We're professionals.
I'm not worried.
♪ The lines are weak ♪
Okay, but if it ever gets
uncomfortable for you...
I will let you know.
I promise.
♪ But I know my name ♪Hey.
Let's get home so I
can get some sleep.
Ah!
I have pre-rounds
before sunrise.
Welcome back, Dr. Warren. Oh.
Much like in surgery,
sometimes in life
we lose sight of
the bigger picture.
♪ I'm not talking 'bout fire ♪
Mimi. ♪ I'm just
trying to make sense ♪
Hey.
How are you feeling?
Tired.
And I kind of want a donut.
Go back to sleep.
You need rest.
Mimi. We will get donuts.
♪ Please don't
tell me you can't ♪
Thanks for everything.
I didn't do anything.
I couldn't even be in
your surgery, remember?
I meant as my sister.
Shh. Close your eyes.
♪ I fell in love with you ♪
- Hi.
- Hey.
We brought things.
- How's she doing?
- Good.
She's already
asking about snacks.
- That tracks.
- Yeah.
Let you both sleep.
Thanks, uh, for all the stuff.
We also took all of your
shifts for the next week
so you can spend
time with Chloe.
♪ And I know my name
♪ Thank you, guys.
When we're stressed or worried,
it can be hard to see the
things that are going well.
♪ And I'm not
talking 'bout hope ♪
♪ I'm not talking 'bout fire ♪
♪ I'm just trying to make
sense of this desire ♪
♪ So put your
hand on my head ♪
♪ And put your
hand on my heart ♪
And when we're
floating on cloud nine,
it's just as easy
to miss red flags.
Expanding our perspective
can give us a better,
more accurate view of
ourselves and the world.
I don't see anything. Do you?
Mm. Just my intestines.
Stop moving it around.
Well, I still
don't see anything.
Oh, wait. Is that...?
Yeah. There's our baby.
And there's the heartbeat.
♪ Show each other ♪
You don't see it, do you?
You see it right there?
♪ Let's show each other how ♪
Oh, and also there.
Oh, my God!
Twins. Twins?
It may end up being more than
you could have ever imagined.