♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
♪♪♪
Just one more minute.
Hold still.
♪♪♪
Now when did you become
so graceful?
All the years
we were married,
you were blatantly
devoid of rhythm.
Yeah, but not
when it counted.
Mm.
I've been watching
"dancing with the stars"
for pointers.
Ooh.
Maybe we ought to go
to Buenos Aires
for our next trip, huh?
We can learn to tango.
I don't think I'm gonna
be traveling for a while.
Why not?
Let's just
keep dancing, hmm?
Sheldon, you're worrying me.
I don't want to. You know,
that--that's the point.
You see, that doesn't help.
What's going on?
♪♪♪
Prostate cancer
is what's going on.
Come on.
What's the prognosis?
The biopsy was positive.
It was a gleason score
of 6, so it's intermediate.
And it hasn't metastasized.
Okay. Well, um,
what--is there a--
is there surgery
or--or--or meds?
I mean,
what happens next?
I haven't decided.
I told you
we should keep dancing.
Look, I'm sorry. It's just--
it's kind of a shock.
Yeah, for me, too.
But you can come here,
and when I'm doing
whatever it is I decide to do,
we can check out
those five-star hotels.
I can't come to L.A.
every week.
But flying to Buenos Aires--
that--that works for you?
Sheldon, my practice
is in New York.
I don't know
if I can pack up and...
And come help you
through this.
I didn't ask you to.
I suggested you pack up
and join me poolside.
Well, that's not
what this is anymore.
Yeah, right, right.
Now that there's a modicum
of reality to this scenario,
why bother?
Okay, this is
what we both wanted.
These weekends
were supposed to be
a-a vacation
from real life.
Well, I'm sorry if my cancer
ruined your vacation.
Oh. That's the hospital.
Maybe I should find
a hotel.
Yeah. Yeah,
why don't you do that?
♪♪♪
Check in after each room
you clear.
Hey. Is there any update
on the missing girl?
No, but it's a big hospital.
There are lots
of places to hide.
Yeah, well,
what can I do?
Are you a security guard
or a cop?
Well, no, but i--
your patient's stabilized,
and you discharged him.
Get back to whatever
the tux was for.
Yeah.
Come on.
Need a hand?
Please tell me
you weren't the groom.
I guess I'm out
of practice.
Oh, that's not necessary.
No, it is.
I'm having a bad night,
and sometimes the best way
to cheer yourself up
is to try and cheer
someone else up.
You read that
on a bumper sticker?
It's Mark twain.
Mm.
I'm more of
an Agatha christie gal.
Thanks for the chocolate.
It's one of the few things
I can still keep down.
Sheldon,
it's been five weeks,
and your fascination
on this particular subject
is bordering
on the obsessive.
He's my patient, okay?
I have
a responsibility to him.
Only if he wants your help.
And since he's not returning
any of your calls
or showing up
for his appointments,
clearly he doesn't.
But that's my fault.
I need to win back his trust.
Look, you thought he took
the little girl.
He knows you thought that.
So now there's nothing
you can do,
except perhaps
use your session
to try to figure out
how your issues got in the way.
My issues didn't get
in the way,
because i-i...
I don't have any issues.
Really?
Because most people
would consider cancer
an issue.
Well, most people don't have
my incredible optimism
and sunny disposition.
Okay, fine.
It's an issue.
And there are options,
but none of them palatable.
What are they?
Well, if I choose
door number one,
I get surgery--
radical prostatectomy.
It comes complete
with the possibility
of incontinence
and impotence.
Door number two
is active surveillance,
where we watch and wait
while the cancer cells that
are already in my prostate
perhaps take up
residence elsewhere,
maybe my lungs or my liver.
And then
there's door number three--
toxic levels of radiation
beamed into my manhood
five days a week
for eight weeks.
Call me crazy,
but opting for a treatment
that's associated with
duck-and-cover drills
just... gives me pause.
What does Laura think?
Oh, Laura's gone.
I mean, cancer didn't really
fit into her plans.
Not everyone
has the strength of character
to go through this
with someone.
Yeah, I don't want
to talk about Laura.
Oh, you don't want to talk
about Laura.
You've made up your mind
not to make up your mind
about cancer.
Is there anything else that
you'd like to not talk about
in the remaining half-hour?
No, I think that
pretty much covers it.
At least you get
to wear pants.
Because I have
breast cancer.
Oh.
I'm sorry.
Um, I'm just nervous.
You'll be fine.
This is a great facility.
I'm in every morning.
Are--are you?
Let's hope.
Right.
Hold still.
You sleep through
your alarm this morning?
No, I joined a gym.
Decided it's time
to start working out.
Oh, Sam gettin' on you
to stay healthy?
I know how to take care
of myself.
I'm--i am a doctor.
Um, what the hell
is that?
Look at that rock!
She's like
a heat-seeking missile.
Jake, I'm a woman,
and you could see
that ring from space.
How could you not tell us?
Oh, well, we didn't want
to make a big deal about it.
That's, uh, that's great news.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Congrats.
Thanks, Sam.
Mm-hmm.
Congratulations.
Thanks, buddy.
All right.
Congratulations.
I love weddings.
You know, they're so full
of love and joy and promise.
You can fool yourself
into thinking
that's what the whole world
is like.
But it's... it's not.
It's fraught with danger
and disease,
and there's no loyalty,
you know, just...
None at all.
I'm thrilled
for both of you, though.
Dr. Wallace?
Nick.
I've been calling you.
Yeah.
I... got your messages.
I didn't know whether
I should call you back
or get a restraining order.
I was worried, all right?
And when you didn't call,
I was afraid--
what,
I took a little girl?
When you first came to see me,
you were suicidal.
Yes, and you helped me
through that, and I'm grateful.
But after that night
at the E.R.--
that was a mistake.
I rushed to judgment,
and that was wrong.
I didn't take
that little girl.
I know. I know.
And... I want to continue
to help you.
Actually, um...
I'm doing pretty well.
Good. Good.
What's been going on?
I got a promotion at work.
Been finishing some projects
around the house.
And the, uh, the urges?
I'm managing them.
I'm working the checklist,
avoiding triggers.
And i'm--I'm keeping busy
with a new friend.
Well, that sounds like
a positive step.
Yeah.
Did you meet him at work?
It's her, actually.
Oh.
What's her name?
Alyssa.
Is--is she a colleague?
No. No,
she's just a friend,
but she's... she's great.
We're into a lot
of the same music
and TV shows,
and she understands me,
you know? And--and she's kind
and so pretty.
And... I don't know.
I've n--
I've never felt
this way before.
It's just nice to connect
with somebody, you know?
So it's romantic, then?
I want it to be.
I get the feeling
she does, too.
Nick, I have to ask you...
How old is she?
He said she was 25,
but... he hesitated.
That doesn't mean
he was lying.
No, no. His demeanor.
He was excited.
Almost euphoric.
Euphoria isn't uncommon
when the s.S.R.I.S
start to work
and the depression lifts.
He was acting
like a schoolboy in love.
So you're afraid he's in love
with a little girl?
I'm afraid he's in love
with Sarah Nelson.
Wow. That's quite a leap.
Aw, come on, Diane.
You saw him in the E.R.
after she disappeared.
How could he
have taken her?
I don't know,
but I do not believe
that he would be this excited
about having a relationship
with an age-appropriate woman.
You're an excellent therapist,
but there are some things
that make even the psychiatric
community uncomfortable.
Oh, this has
nothing to do
with finding pedophilia
to be repugnant or--
okay, then maybe
it's cognitive dissonance.
What?
You effectively accused him
of taking Sarah,
and you were wrong.
Obviously, the guilt you feel
over destroying
the trust with a patient--
it's overwhelming.
Wait.
You're saying that I concocted
this scenario where he took her
to assuage my guilt about
accusing him in the first place?
I don't know. Did you?
I wouldn't do that.
Sheldon, your patient
was suicidal
and just came back
into therapy.
Your willingness to accuse him
without any evidence--
it worries me.
A little girl's life
is at stake.
I think this is
about your life.
Mark twain.
You're the tuxedo guy
from the E.R.
Oh.
Oh, you're
the chocolate girl... woman.
I didn't recognize you.
I had a wig on
at the hospital,
out in public,
and listen,
I was really rude
the other day.
No, it's fine.
I understand.
No, it's just, you know,
I've bonded with people
in this situation before,
not here, but in chemo,
and one day you show up,
and... she doesn't.
And you really want
to tell yourself
that she's in remission
and she's taking
that trip to Paris
that she's
always dreamed of.
But since you broke your own
rules and got friendly,
you're friends.
So her husband calls you
and tells you that she died.
Well, I'm sorry.
Me, too.
So we can chitchat,
'cause it's weird to sit here
and not say anything,
but it doesn't go
beyond that, okay?
Nice weather,
don't you think?
Beautiful.
Miranda?
See ya.
Yeah.
Hold still.
Got a minute?
No.
I came to apologize.
The cops made an arrest
last night.
The guy who took Sarah Nelson
from the E.R.?
It wasn't your patient.
They found Sarah?
Not yet, but they say
it's only a matter of time.
Who was it?
Contract worker
on the janitorial staff.
Since he wasn't
an actual hospital employee,
it took a while
to connect the dots.
He's a registered
sex offender.
They're sure it's him?
Sounds like it.
I heard from a paramedic.
He heard from a cop buddy.
I was a jerk.
I was out of line,
and I'm sorry.
No hard feelings?
James, thank you.
Thank you.
You have to write
"whole cumin"?
I need whole cumin.
Yeah, but why not
just write "cumin"?
You afraid you're gonna
get to the spice aisle
and see "cumin" on the list,
and accidentally buy it ground?
Well, I don't need ground cumin,
I need whole cumin...
Which is why I'm writing
"whole cumin."
Miranda?
I thought about
canceling today,
'cause I'm good.
Really good.
Well, why didn't you?
You know things about me
that no one else does.
So sharing my happiness
with anyone else,
they don't...
Understand what it took
for you to get there?
Exactly. But you get it.
What do you do?
Guess.
Oh, come... I'm really
bad at guessing.
You can't be bad at guessing.
It's not a skill.
Just say random things.
Okay. Musician?
Yeah. I play
and teach violin.
How'd you guess that?
You had a violin
on your keychain.
I saw it in your hand
at the E.R.
That was ages ago.
We didn't even know
each other then.
Well, paying attention
to detail
is an important part
of my job.
Which is?
Psychiatrist.
Oh.
You take naps
on your couch?
You know, lately I do.
My oncologist told me
I'd be exhausted, but, uh...
It's like kindergarten,
right?
Well, I keep waiting
for someone
to bring me
milk and cookies.
Miranda?
Hold still.
I was thinking about
what you said last week
about discontinuing therapy,
since you feel okay.
I don't want to.
I like coming here.
It's just...
When I feel good,
I can't help but wonder
if it's a crutch.
Well, you know, a lot of people
have more difficulty
handling happiness
than trouble.
They feel they haven't
earned it.
Oh, I-I get that.
I mean, right now
I have everything
a normal person
could ever want, you know?
But...
Given where we started,
do I deserve it?
Divorced, then briefly
back together,
but it...
It's done now.
Mine asked me for a divorce
in an e-mail.
I take it
you don't miss him, then?
Just sleeping
next to him.
He had a bad back,
and he slept on his side
facing out,
and I'd sleep
with my back next to his.
Not quite touching,
but close enough to feel warm.
That part was nice.
I don't miss my ex.
She couldn't ever be...
Still.
It felt like we always had to
be busy doing something,
or she'd get bored.
It's better to have someone
you can just be alone with.
Yeah.
Miranda?
♪ I didn't mind ♪
♪ bodies in the road ♪
♪ I was coming for you ♪
Hold still.
♪ I didn't know ♪
♪ the forest was on fire ♪
♪ I was coming for you ♪
It hasn't happened yet.
We're...
We're taking it slow,
you know, physically.
Which is okay, I guess.
Well, there's no timetable.
I mean, it's up to you
and Alyssa
and your respective
comfort level.
I'm nervous.
I mean, I want to,
you know...
Get closer to her.
But liking someone and being
attracted to them is one thing,
but...
Sex just takes it
to a whole different level.
♪ I was coming for you ♪
Intimacy comes
in many forms, Nick.
And our culture pressures people
to believe that sex
is the ultimate expression
of love,
but that's not always
the case.
And waiting until it's right
and taking it slow,
you know, that's...
That's healthy.
♪ I'd follow ♪
♪ your footsteps ♪
♪ here ♪
You have the most boring
sock collection in the world.
I made a decision
not to let cancer change me,
not even my socks.
What does your shrink
say about that?
Every shrink has a shrink.
We don't talk
about my socks.
Here's something
I've never understood--
why do all psychiatrists
take off the month of August?
There must be a rash
of suicides then.
People can't just
put their issues on hold.
Cancer's not gonna
go away for a month.
You still need
to discuss it.
I take my vacation
in may.
And as for my cancer,
I don't really discuss it
with my therapist.
So who do you talk to,
then?
Honestly? You.
I don't want my colleagues
to know what's going on.
I don't want them
to start looking at me
like I'm just cancer guy.
You understand.
Yeah, I do.
You know,
every beginning violin student
learns to play
"twinkle, twinkle, little star."
And at first, it's awful.
And they play it over
and over and over
till I don't think I can
listen one more time,
and then it clicks.
The finger placement,
the pressure on the bow.
One day it's noise, and then
the next day, it's music.
I love that moment.
I'm really gonna miss that.
You don't teach violin
anymore?
My cancer has metastasized.
It's in my brain.
So the radiation is just...
I promised my niece I would go
to her college graduation.
So I'm holding on
as long as I can,
but this is just delaying
the inevitable.
I'm terminal, Sheldon,
So you should probably
find someone else to talk to.
Miranda?
Hold still.
Ugh. How am I gonna
sign payroll next week?
Need one of those astronaut pens
that writes upside-down.
Makes your head hurt, too.
Mason tried laying like this
on the sofa at home.
Oh. How long
did you make it?
Ten minutes,
then I thought my brains
were gonna explode.
Dad only made it five.
Well, clearly,
the man is weak.
I'm gonna go
to the vending machine.
You guys want anything?
Mnh-mnh.
No, thank you.
Hey.
Come right back.
How are you holding up?
Ugh. How do you think?
I'm already jumping
out of my skin,
it hasn't been that long.
I got two more months laying
here like a sack of potatoes.
If I even think
about getting up to pee,
there's a whole chorus
of "hold still,"
like the world's
gonna come to an end
if I move half an inch.
It's no fun, Sheldon,
staying in one spot,
contemplating every bad thing
that could happen
on a continuous loop.
It's...
Oh, it's no fun.
I get that. I do.
Sheldon...
You have an abundance
of empathy,
but how could you possibly
imagine what this is like?
Well, this morning...
Well, every morning
for the past few weeks,
i-i--I've been going...
To the gym, and I use
a stationary bike,
and you know,
you just don't get anywhere,
no matter how hard
you pedal.
And I'm not losing
any weight.
I mean, look at me.
So you do understand.
You're right. I have no idea
what this is like.
But you're
the strongest person I know.
And just being around you,
I...
I think it gives me
strength, too.
You're late.
Yeah. Traffic.
So I was thinking of trying
this lunch place down the street
that has salads with
really motivational names,
like "you can conquer anything"
and "it's never too late."
Let me know
if it's any good.
Miranda?
Hold still.
Why didn't you go to lunch
with Miranda?
Our friendship doesn't go
outside that room.
That's the rule.
I think it's already
outside that room,
and you know it.
She told me
she's terminal.
Aha.
What "aha"?
Not everyone
has the strength of character
to go through this
with someone.
At least that's what
we discussed with Laura.
Well, I'm not Laura.
Laura was selfish.
Or scared.
Getting closer to someone
who's sick is terrifying.
No, it's not
the same thing.
Laura and I
have a 20-year history.
I met Miranda
seven weeks ago.
We spend five minutes a day
together five days a week,
and our--our friendship
is, uh...
Three hours old.
And yet, the experiences
you're sharing--
that creates a deeper bond
than you would normally have
with someone you've known
for three hours.
I like her.
But I...
I can't take the next step.
Why?
What are you afraid of?
Everything.
How are Ron and Dana?
Imaginations
are running wild.
How could they not?
The guy in custody
had their daughter
for how many days
before he was arrested?
54.
I mean, if you think about what
could have happened to her...
I don't wanna.
Well, people are stronger
than you think.
And kids can survive
most anything
if they get
the right kind of help.
Well, to be helped,
Sarah has to
actually be found,
you know, alive.
And who's to say
the guy in custody
is even the one
who took Sarah?
The guy did it before.
As far as I'm concerned,
he should be tortured whether
it helps find Sarah or not.
Oh, my god.
I'm serious.
You know what? I got Mason,
I got two on the way,
I have a baby
in the nicu
who's never done anything
to anybody.
I have no sympathy
for a pedophile. I'm sorry.
I like vigilante Coop.
Where'd he come from?
Vigilante Coop is just a guy
who put a bid in on a house
and then he checked
the sex offender registry.
You know how many live
within a 5-mile radius
of our dream house?
Six.
And those are just the ones
that are registered.
Four blocks away,
there's a guy that did time
for sexual penetration
with a--
oh, stop. Stop, Coop.
No, Cooper's right.
It seems like there are
more of them right now,
but that's because people think
it's okay to talk about it.
They have a disease,
they want our support,
they want our help,
they want us to tell them
that god
didn't make them wrong.
But I mean,
how can we do that?
There's some maladies that
are simply contrary to nature,
and there are some people
that no loving god
would put on this earth
unless it was to demonstrate
to the rest of us
that there was a limit
to humanity
and Patience
and compassion...
Which further justifies
my utter lack of faith.
The only life
some people deserve
is a life sentence.
And yet,
we help them live freely,
and while we do that,
we're supposed to be able
to sleep at night.
Nick, are you all right?
You know how
you imagine something, and...
In the beginning
it feels amazing,
but then slowly,
the reality sets in.
It just isn't
what you planned.
Is this about Alyssa?
I thought it was love.
But real love...
That's supposed to grow,
right, over time?
One hopes.
Well, it's not growing
for me.
She just doesn't seem happy,
no matter what I do.
Maybe this wasn't
meant to be.
Every relationship
is exciting at the start.
The person you're with
is a blank canvas,
and everything is new.
Of course, the novelty fades,
and sometimes
you have to give
that relationship time,
you know,
to--to really know--
maybe love just isn't
in the cards for me.
Nick, you're a young man.
The search
for the right woman...
Alyssa's not her.
And, uh...
I don't wanna hurt her, but...
I think I have to end it.
♪♪♪
The Sarah Nelson case.
I think you might have
the wrong man in custody.
Why would you say that?
What do you have
on your suspect?
Well, he's a registered
sex offender.
Did it at least
once before.
Same type--
blonde, blue eyes...
They all have a type.
Four witnesses put him
in the emergency room
mopping floors minutes
before the girl went missing.
And that was ten minutes
after his shift was over.
That's evidence?
Been a cop 30 years,
shelley.
He's a lowlife,
through and through.
Yeah, but...
But he hasn't confessed.
Why would he?
We got him on felony possession
of child pornography
and parole violation.
He's not gonna add life
on top of that
just to help us
with our investigation.
All right.
I'm breaking protocol,
I'm breaking probably
the law,
and I'm risking my...
I'm risking my license
by saying this,
but I count you
as a friend, Joe.
All right.
I had a patient who was
at the hospital that night,
and... I think
he took Sarah.
He has a history
of sexual urges toward children.
Has he said anything
about the girl?
No, no, no.
He's too smart.
You know, he knows the rules.
But he was in love
with someone,
and now he's having mood swings
because it went bad,
and I think
if that someone is Sarah,
he could be getting ready
to hurt her.
You're not giving me anything
to go on here, shelley.
I can't bust down the door
to a guy's house
without probable cause.
Joe, come on.
I-I just have a feeling.
A feeling?
Now I know you're a shrink,
but come on.
She's out there.
He could have her. He...
You have to do something.
Look, the best we can hope now
is to find her body
so that the parents
have something to Bury.
You can't give up on her.
I'm sorry, shelley.
There's nothing I can do.
Nick. Hey.
Thanks for
coming back so soon.
I-I have to leave town
next week,
I wanted to make sure
we didn't miss an appointment.
No problem.
Okay.
So did you... did you have
any trouble getting here?
'Cause traffic can be heavy
this time of day.
No. No trouble at all.
Well, why don't you wait
in my office?
And I'll, uh,
I'll be right there.
Sure.
Okay.
Could you please make this call
in 15 minutes?
Okay. It's important.
Thank you.
How's it going
with Alyssa?
Oh, the same.
So you didn't end it?
Not yet.
I'm sorry, but that couple
in the lobby--
this is
highly unprofessional,
but I am...
I'm distracted.
Why?
Well, they were the parents
of that little girl that went
missing from the E.R.
"Were"?
What?
You said they "were"
the parents
of that missing girl,
but...
They're still her parents.
Well, not if she's dead.
Well, yeah,
but maybe she's okay.
Maybe she's doing
even better.
How do you figure?
I was there that night.
Those parents are awful.
Fighting like that
in front of her?
That's... that's no way
for a kid to live.
Kids need to be loved.
Yes, they do.
Yeah.
They absolutely do.
So you think maybe
she's still alive?
Sarah?
Yes.
I do.
I think she's okay.
I can't sit home anymore
and just wait.
I can't do it.
Well, I can't pretend
that we never had a kid.
That's not what I'm doing.
Dana, this isn't helping.
Please, why don't you
tell me what's going on?
We have to pay the mortgage.
We have to eat.
He went back to work.
Our baby is missing,
and he is treating it
like it's a regular day.
Right, but we have
discussed this.
Even though two people
share the same loss,
they may not experience or deal
with grief the same way.
Exactly.
And for a few hours a day
when I'm in court,
I can forget.
Well, I can't, and I won't.
Dana, she's dead.
What's wrong with you?
How could you say that?
I just needed
to say it out loud.
I... can't walk around
on eggshells anymore
and pretend to hope.
I... I'm not hopeful.
Dr. Turner,
you are a mother.
You tell him he is wrong.
Well, we just...
We don't know.
I know.
A mother knows.
Sarah is alive.
I feel like there's something
you're not telling me.
What are you talking about?
Your depression.
I'm not depressed.
I just said my relationship
isn't working.
Well, you came to me
in the beginning
because you wanted help,
because you don't like
what you are.
What I am?
You said
that's not my fault.
The urges
aren't your fault,
but acting on them
would be.
You'd be responsible
for that.
Are you accusing me
of something?
No. No, I'm just
asking you to be honest,
because our deal,
after I saved your life,
was... no more secrets.
I didn't ask you
to save my life.
You took a bottle of pills
and came to my office, Nick--
a doctor's office.
What did you think
would happen?
I thought I wouldn't be alone
when I died.
You know,
the terms that we discussed
for my continuing
to help you--
the only requirement
was your honesty.
I've been honest.
Who's Alyssa?
The woman I've been seeing.
Where's she from?
Here.
What does she do?
She's, um... a waitress.
I don't have to keep
answering these questions.
Where does she live, Nick?
Venice.
Do you have a photograph?
No.
Not even on your phone?
What color are her eyes?
Are they blue?
And her hair blonde, too,
like Sarah?
Because there is no Alyssa.
It's only Sarah,
and you took her.
And that's how you know
she's still alive.
Sarah is dead, okay?
And you keep encouraging her
to hope, Dr. Turner.
It's gonna kill her.
I don't know that, Ron.
You don't know that.
They have the guy
in custody.
That's what the detective said.
He's the guy.
And if they didn't find Sarah
after a couple of days,
the odds that they were
ever gonna find her alive--
the detective doesn't know
our baby. He doesn't know us.
It is just a job to him.
He is on to the next case.
We are the ones who are
supposed to keep caring.
I'm the only one caring!
Dana, Ron cares. He cares.
Of course I care!
Do you even know what it means
if she's alive?
Do you know
what that means,
what he must have done
to her?
All those nights that you
sat there taking pills,
I was awake
staring at the wall,
and I couldn't stop
imagining...
In your dreams, you could hear
Sarah asking to bake cupcakes.
But all I could hear
was her screaming...
Screaming
for daddy to come save her.
I need to think
that she's dead, Dana,
because otherwise...
Oh, my god,
I can't even...
You are wrong.
Her parents fought
and she ran away,
and when you left
the E.R. that night,
you found her outside,
didn't you?
You have no idea
what you're talking about.
She was upset, scared,
probably hiding from the rain.
I mean, what did you do?
Did you charm her?
Did you buy her something?
How did you get her
to go home with you?
You're crazy.
I get it, Nick. I do.
You wanted to give her
a better life.
I mean, that's it,
isn't it?
Why would I keep coming here
if I took her?
That doesn't make any sense.
Because you want to tell me.
Just like you wanted
to share your joy with me,
and now you want to confess,
because the urges,
they got to be too much.
You couldn't stop yourself.
You never thought
you could help me.
But she doesn't love you.
How could she?
She's a child.
And she doesn't want
to be with you.
And maybe you haven't been
able to be a man with her.
Maybe you couldn't perform,
and maybe that's
why you're depressed.
God, you're guessing!
You're... you're guessing.
You're making this up
as you go along.
You think you're so smart,
but you don't know anything.
You're powerless.
You are powerless
and weak.
Where is she?
I have no idea.
Where is she?!
I can't help you.
He's acutely suicidal
and combative.
What the hell?
He's paranoid
and externalizing,
so expect accusations
of persecution.
What are you talking about?
Now he is sleep-deprived,
so we'll need one-on-ones
until he can be
heavily sedated.
Sedated? No, I'm not suicidal.
I'm totally--I'm fine.
I'll follow up directly
with the intake doctor.
We're putting you on
a 5150 psych hold, okay?
It's for your own safety.
No, no, you can't do this.
I haven't done anything!
It's gonna be okay, Nick.
Shelley, I just did a double.
I'm going home.
My patient, Nick Calhoun,
has Sarah.
He took her and he has her
at his house.
So what changed
since this morning, huh?
You get some proof?
No, I'm telling you
I know.
How? Did you see her
at his house?
Did he tell you
that he has her?
Yes. He told me.
Nick confessed.
You know where he is?
He's 5150.
You had him committed?
He was in danger
of hurting himself.
Or someone else.
Yes.
That's probable cause.
Let's go.
Okay.
Living room clear!
Kitchen clear!
Bedroom clear!
Shelley?
She's here. She...
She has to be here.
There's a basement.
She's
under there. Find the lights.
Hi, Sarah.
My name is Sheldon.
I'm here with the police.
And we're--we're gonna
take you home, okay?
Is he...
Is he coming back?
No. No, sweetie.
You're--you're safe now.
Where's my mommy?
They'll be here soon.
Your mommy and daddy
are on the way.
It's gonna take
a little while.
So you...
You wanna come out?
No.
Okay.
Okay. That's okay.
You're not gonna
leave me, are you?
No. No, I'm gonna wait
right here.
I'll tell you what--
I'll--I'll just put my hand
right here,
and if you need to,
you can hold on to it.
You know,
your mommy and daddy
have been looking for you
this whole time.
I was bad. I ran away.
No, no. That's--that's okay.
I'm scared. I want
my mommy to sing to me.
How 'bout if I sing to you
until she gets here?
♪ Twinkle, twinkle,
little star ♪
♪ how I wonder what you are ♪
♪ up above the world so high ♪
♪ like a diamond in the sky ♪
♪ twinkle, twinkle,
little star ♪
♪ how I wonder what you are ♪
♪ Darkness settles
on the ground ♪
♪ leaves the day
stumbling blind ♪
♪ coming to a quiet close ♪
♪ and maybe just in time ♪
♪ we've almost lost
the heart to know ♪
♪ how to keep
our best in mind ♪
♪ we've almost lost
the heart to know ♪
♪ how to keep
our best in mind ♪
♪ Time has turned
an angry face ♪
Oh, my god.
I can't believe it.
This whole time, she was
less than a mile from here.
You saved her.
You found her.
I should have found her
months ago.
♪ We'll practice unforgivingly ♪
♪ as if might
and will make right ♪
♪ or either one
could make us free ♪
♪ As if might
and will make right ♪
♪ or either one
could make us free ♪
Nice socks, Sheldon!
You weren't here
yesterday.
Oh, yeah, my car was--
What are you doing?
I want to see you--
here, outside of here.
You light up this room,
and I want that light
everywhere I go,
so I'm gonna take you
to lunch,
and then dinner,
and lunch again tomorrow,
and every day after that.
So just say "yes."
Say you'll go out with me.
Why aren't you saying "yes"?
Just say "yes."
But, Sheldon,
I'm dying.
♪ But I'll try to be
your light ♪
Not today.
♪ In love ♪
♪ pray that it's enough
for now ♪
♪ well, I'll try to be
your light in love ♪
♪ and I'll pray
that is enough for now ♪