He cut me open
and rewired my circuitry.
Dean, we don't
medicate patients
to get the answers we want.
At the end of the day,
it's my word versus Neil's.
The guy who thinks
this whole thing
is a game of Tetris!
Enough. Dean, take a walk.
If I told Vanessa the truth,
that I'm her mother...
I don't know, Maggie,
once you take that step...
I know.
I got my interview
for Med's Nurse
Practitioner program today.
You forced me
into a procedure that
I am not supposed to do.
As a nurse practitioner,
I thought you'd welcome
the challenge.
How'd your
interview go?
Oh, my God!
Who gave
an unauthorized patient
our trial drug?
Me.
You realize you've
compromised the trial,
not to mention your career.
I stole meds
from Will's trial, and now,
my mom is dying in there,
and she needs
a new heart.
Hey, Nat...
Hey.
We found a donor heart
for your mom.
It's on the way.
Really?
Yeah.
But it's not perfect.
Come on, I'll explain.
So, the donor's a 50-year-old
woman, type AB like your mom,
and her thoracic cavity
was very similar in size.
Good.
There are issues.
The heart has already
been refused
for several recipients
by their physicians.
Why?
The organ has an intracardiac
tumor in the left ventricle.
Sarcoma?
No. Myxoma.
Benign. Okay, then,
you can remove the myxoma
before Dr. Latham implants
the heart. That's doable.
Yes, but there's
another issue.
The heart was harvested
in Los Angeles.
Now,
under normal circumstances,
by the time it arrived,
it would be outside
the window of viability.
Then why are we even
suggesting this?
Because of how
it's being transported.
Warm perfusion.
An experimental procedure,
still in its trial phase.
A machine
perfuses the donor heart
with warm blood.
Ergo the name.
Should prevent
tissue damage,
keep it functional.
"Should"?
You're already suggesting
a dicey heart that could
turn out to be useless.
We will apprise your mother
of all the risks.
But her blood type
is rare, Nat.
Even though
she's high on the list,
it'd be unlikely to find
a heart that matches.
Highly unlikely.
Okay.
Yeah, 70-year-old male,
Pavel Zorin,
came in last night,
minor injuries after
assaulting his landlord.
Claimed there were rats
in his apartment.
Agitated, combative,
probably delusional.
"Probably"?
Most of the time,
he was babbling in Russian,
no one around to translate.
When he came in,
he was clutching these.
Psych resident sedated him,
put him on a 72-hour hold,
now, they're just
taking him upstairs.
Lease, naturalization papers.
Bunch of old documents
in Russian.
Unfortunately,
my Cyrillic's a little rusty.
I'm sure I can find
a translator for you.
I was actually thinking
about Mischa Lenkov.
Didn't he retire?
He's in the process of.
But something tells me
he'd wanna help out
a fellow countryman.
Let me give him a call.
All right.
On our way home,
we pass by that
Jamaican place.
Could pick up
some jerk chicken.
Sure.
Today's her last day here.
You're doing
the right thing, Mags.
You can't tell her.
I know.
I gotta go to work.
I will see you later.
Okay.
Hi.
Just one second, okay?
One second.
Are you ready, Mom?
Oh. This was my mother's.
And I want you to have it.
You're gonna be okay, Mom.
How about this?
I will keep it for you.
Okay.
Okay. Let's go.
I'm right here
with you, Mom.
Okay.
Thanks, guys.
All right. Thank you.
You okay?
Just one second.
I love you, Mom.
I love you.
Mmm.
There it is.
Nat. It's gonna
work out. Okay?
Okay.
Dr. Marcel,
Mrs. Conte is prepped.
Please start
on the myxoma.
Okay.
I'm so sorry for missing
yesterday's appointment.
I got caught up with a case.
I really appreciate you
seeing me today.
April, you're
a very good candidate
for our
Nurse Practitioner program.
And most of your
recommendations are excellent.
"Most"?
There was one...
What was the issue?
An ED doc had some concerns
about your judgment.
Look. Miss Scott,
I think I know who that is,
and I just want to say...
No need to explain, April.
Trauma surgeons
can be a prickly bunch.
So, it was a trauma surgeon?
Let's put that aside.
I see that we've received
all of your transcripts,
so, I think I have
everything I need.
Apparently, the episode
was triggered when he saw
a rat in his apartment.
Yeah, Mr. Zorin
in September of 1980,
was committed to the Leningrad
Special Psychiatric Hospital.
"Special"?
So, what's that for?
For bigwigs?
For party members?
No, it's more likely
for a particular type
of mental illness.
It says here, he suffered
from... How would I say it?
Sluggish schizophrenia.
"Sluggish"?
I'm not familiar with that
particular diagnosis. You?
Not really.
I've heard the term
back then, when I was
a psych resident in Moscow,
but sorry, I wish I could've
been more help.
Wait, Mischa, could you just
give me a few more minutes?
Help me talk to the patient?
Uh, Daniel, I...
Five minutes tops.
I just... I might
need a translator.
Mr. Zorin, I'm Dr. Charles.
And this is Dr. Lenkov.
How are you feeling?
Mr. Zorin, do you
understand me?
Do you speak English?
Mr. Zorin,
you're safe here.
You are absolutely
safe here.
Mischa!
Five of Haldol, please.
Got it.
Mischa, you all right?
Hey. Morning.
Morning.
Look, Dean,
we need to talk.
Uh-oh. Am I that late?
This is really tough,
but I've got serious concerns
about our working together.
Really? Why?
It's a lot of things.
Look, I know
we got off to a rocky start.
I take full responsibility
for that.
But I don't know,
I thought you and I
were in a good place, now.
Take yesterday,
for example.
The way you lied
to the patient.
Oh, come on, man.
I was just...
I was just trying
to establish a rapport,
so I could treat her.
There's nothing
in the Hippocratic Oath
says I can't do that.
That's just the latest.
Tell me something.
Is there something
going on with you, Ethan,
that I don't know about?
This is all
so out of the blue.
Don't do that.
Don't make this about me.
No.
'Cause you ambush me
right here, and you lay
this whole thing on me.
We were gonna have this
conversation somewhere.
I thought it'd be
better out here.
All right. I gotta be honest
with you, Ethan.
I'm getting a feeling here,
and I hope I'm wrong.
But maybe, you just
hired your old CO,
so you could knock him down
a few pegs, maybe?
That's not true,
and you know it.
Is it?
Tell me
it's not a game.
Here you are. Here I am.
You think that just happened?
Uh, you remember
Mr. Dietrich?
He's my patient
with appendicitis.
I do.
No, I wasn't sick.
I was about to wake up. I was
about to see the real world.
But then you NPCs
took the red pill out!
All we did was remove
your ruptured appendix.
Yeah. To save your life.
Yeah. More lies!
Hey, hey.
Take it easy, okay?
Let's talk about this.
Yeah, what's the point?
Everything that you say
is programmed.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Over here! I'm the one
who took out the red pill.
No, no, no, no, no.
But I'm the chief
of the ED, okay?
I'm responsible
for everything
that happens there.
It doesn't matter, okay?
You're both the same!
But guess what?
I'm not ones and zeroes.
I'm real!
Okay.
And you're deleted.
Ethan! Ethan?
Maggie, I got a GSW
in staff parking. And another
person with head trauma.
I need two stretchers
and the rapid response team,
stat.
There's no exit wound.
The bullet's still in you.
How're you doing, Ethan?
Talk to me.
I'm okay.
No, Ethan!
Dr. Archer,
Baghdad's ready.
Dr. Halstead!
I'm on it.
Hey, I'm right here. Okay?
I'm right here.
Ethan?
So, um...
what happened down there?
It's a hiatal hernia.
Acts up sometimes.
Oh. Really?
You know, I thought
maybe it had something
to do with something
that Mr. Zorin said.
Sometimes the stress
of dealing with a patient
can set it off.
What was that word
that he kept on repeating?
It's Russian slang for
a psychiatric hospital.
Huh.
And I'm guessing
that's where he developed
his phobia to rats.
So, rats in a hospital?
You have something stronger?
You sure that's a good idea?
I mean, for a hiatal hernia?
No. Of course not.
Oh, boy. You know what?
There's an emergency
down in the ER.
Sure.
Are you gonna be
all right?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
You mind just waiting
a few more minutes
till I get back?
I just had a couple more
questions about the patient.
You know what?
I'll get you
some lansoprazole,
make you feel better.
All right?
Be right back.
Hang a unit of O blood
and trigger the MTP.
Satting at 85.
He's not protecting
his airway.
Start bagging. I'll intubate.
Twenty of etomidate,
100 of sux.
X-ray!
Coming.
Ethan, you're
gonna be all right.
Okay, I'm in.
BP 90/55. Heart rate 118.
Blood's going in.
Clear!
We have a left-side
hemothorax.
I'll put in a tube.
No, I'll do it.
Okay. Hang two more units
on the rapid transfuser.
BP 100/70. Heart rate 110.
Better.
Let's take him to CT.
Oh, my... What happened?
He got shot.
By this guy.
All right.
With me. Trauma 2.
Neil Dietrich, 25. GCS 13.
Suspected concussion.
They took
the red pill away!
You know he was here
a couple weeks ago, right?
Patient of Dr. Archer's.
I consulted on the case.
Completely delusional.
Thinks he's living in some
kinda computer simulation.
They took
the red pill away!
Image is lousy.
There's too much scatter
from the bullet.
We need an MRI.
No. Can't. The bullet is
pseudo-ferrous, it'll heat up.
We can assume
he's got a cord hematoma.
He needs surgery.
Hold on. A hematoma
may or may not
be a problem.
All right, look.
The bullet is near the cord.
This could be more than
just spinal shock.
Early decompression
is the right course
of action here.
What if you injure
the cord?
Create a CSF leak?
Then he's paralyzed.
Perfusion precautions
in the ICU,
hematoma could very well
resolve on its own.
Yeah. Unlikely. All right?
And I've spent a career
treating gunshot wounds.
I think my tenure in the ED
in Chicago gives me
some insight into GSWs.
Your animosity towards
Dr. Choi is well known.
You've resented his authority
ever since he was made chief.
I don't think you're
capable of making an impartial
clinical assessment.
Whatever my issues
with Ethan might be...
They aren't affecting
his clinical judgment.
As if you're in a position
to judge. I am taking him
into surgery!
Hey. Surgery is Neurosurg's
decision, not yours.
That's right.
Okay. Okay, fine.
Call Neurosurg.
But know this,
both of you,
that every minute
we delay surgery
puts Dr. Choi at greater risk.
Mischa, I am so sorry.
Dr. Marcel, I have a patient
on bypass, her chest is open.
Where is my heart?
Dr. Latham,
I thought I mentioned
the myxoma invaded
the anterior mitral leaflet.
Yes, but the clock
is ticking.
How much longer?
Hold on.
Dr. Marcel?
I'm still repairing
the leaflet.
Okay, here we go.
It's all yours.
Let's proceed.
Okay. Thank you.
Where would you
like to begin?
Well, on... Okay.
All right.
Lighten his sedation.
Ethan, can you hear me?
Ethan?
Ethan, this is Sam.
Can you blink your eyes?
Ethan, can you blink?
Okay, good.
Can you wiggle
your toes?
Ethan. Come on.
Try to wiggle your toes.
Okay.
Ah, it's clear
there's weakness
in his lower extremities.
Perhaps my input's
not needed.
Sam, what do you suggest?
If we don't take him
to be operated on
as soon as possible,
then it'll only get worse.
Why don't I just go home?
Laminectomy, right?
Yes. Laminectomy.
Maggie, would you please
open the Hybrid OR?
Unless you want
to take him upstairs.
It's better for the patient
to avoid the trip.
Hybrid OR will do.
Where is he?
Treatment 5.
Mischa!
He was found in the parking
garage, seems to have fallen
down the stairs.
Respiration's ten.
Smells of alcohol.
He lose consciousness?
Can't say, but you see
the head injury.
Mischa, can you tell me
what happened?
Mischa, can you hear me?
Do you know where you are?
We need to clear
his C-Spine.
Leave the collar on.
Send him up for a head
and neck CT.
Hang in there, buddy.
We're gonna get you
all fixed up, okay?
Bullet's accessible.
I just heard about Ethan.
How's he doing?
Yeah, they got the bullet.
Hematoma's minimal.
You can close.
Oh. Hold on.
There are retropulsed
bone fragments.
Yeah, I'm aware of that.
But we need to extract them.
Spine's decompressed,
that's all we need to do.
Any damage from the fragments
has already been done,
and we'll only make
things worse
going after them.
No, no. Listen.
We're here, we're open.
Let's find
the fragments and then
we'll fuse the spine.
That's a longer, riskier,
more invasive surgery.
But it will allow Ethan
to begin the recovery
process immediately.
Yeah, if he isn't paralyzed.
Chasing bone fragments
is more dangerous
than it's worth.
Dr. Abrams
makes a good point.
That is so distracting.
Would you turn
that off, please?
You should close
him and start...
Damn it.
Maybe Ethan needs
a neurosurgeon who's more
confident in his abilities.
That person doesn't exist.
Well, then...
What do we know
about Dr. Choi?
He's still in surgery.
Okay. Listen, um,
he emailed me last night
and said from among
the med students
auditioning,
he decided to go with
Vanessa Taylor to come back
and rotate in the ED.
Oh.
At first, I thought
about quashing it,
but then that wouldn't
be fair to Miss Taylor.
No.
I take it, you haven't
told her who you are?
Good. I'm counting on your
professionalism to treat her
like any other med student.
Absolutely.
I mean it, Maggie.
No favoritism.
No special treatment.
Dr. Virani, a word please?
Of course.
How are you feeling?
Terrible.
Well, I mean,
you did drink almost
800 milliliters
of 90-proof whiskey.
I'm so sorry about
the whiskey. I normally
don't drink that much.
Look, I'm sorry, again,
for dashing out
on you like that.
Leave you hanging
for so long.
But it turns out
that a member of
our staff was shot
by a delusional patient.
Yeah, he's in surgery now.
Oh, my God.
Mischa. Here's what you
can do for me. All right?
You can tell an old friend.
What's really going on here?
Your Mr. Zorin
was never psychotic.
And the worst thing you can do
for him is confine him
to the psychiatric ward.
Do you know him?
No, not personally.
But I have known
others like him.
The sluggish
schizophrenia
is a phony diagnosis,
which was given
to political dissidents
in order to incarcerate them.
And special psychiatric
hospitals were nothing
more than prisons.
Awful places.
And that's why Mr. Zorin
reacted so violently
when he woke up
and realized where he was.
His worst nightmare.
In the Soviet Union,
psychiatry was weaponized.
It was used to punish.
So, Mischa, were you
already practicing
at this point?
You're asking,
did I participate?
You can't understand...
That we were trained
that Soviet Union was the most
perfect form of government.
And if someone was against it,
they had to be insane.
Political deviance was
a failure to grasp reality.
Oh.
I mean, still, though.
That must have been
very difficult.
It was a different world.
And...
It's like this man
who shot your colleague.
We were all delusional.
The heart is in place.
Okay. Steroid.
Dosing...
Remove the cross clamp.
Okay.
It's not beating.
Give it a moment.
I need to step out.
Come on.
Hey. She's good.
We were able
to pace the heart.
And once we got
it jumpstarted,
it continued on its own.
Oh, my God.
Yeah,
contractions were good.
The repaired mitral valve
is working well.
She's gonna be okay.
They're closing up now.
Crockett, thank you.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Oh, God.
I wasn't fair to you.
I wasn't fair
and I wasn't honest.
Look, I understand
why you kept me out.
I just wish you felt
you could've trusted me.
How's that for irony?
I was always talking to you
about commitment,
that you needed to trust.
Yeah.
Look, Natalie,
I want you to know,
regardless of everything,
I'll always be
grateful to you.
Why?
Well, my life
was pretty empty
till I met you.
It was closed off.
Lot of fears.
You showed me
what could be.
How to take a chance.
Any news?
Still too soon.
Everything all right?
With Goodwin?
BP 90/48.
Heart rate 50.
Eighty-five over 42.
Heart rate 45.
He's in shock.
Betty, what's going on?
We haven't lost any blood.
Oh, God.
I didn't give him
anything different.
It's not a reaction
to the meds.
Volume status?
Good. And he was
ventilating fine.
It's not cardiac
or pulmonary.
Ventral and lateral cord
is well-decompressed.
No active bleeding.
It's neurogenic shock.
Something must be pushing
on the cord ventrally.
Eighty-one over 40.
Heart rate 39.
Betty, up his
meds and pressors.
On it.
Get the paddles ready,
in case he codes.
Heart rate's
down to 35.
Ah. He's bradycardic.
Dean's brilliant idea
is gonna kill Ethan.
Dopamine drip.
Riluzole 50 milligrams
down the NG tube,
and start
the Solu-Medrol protocol.
Yeah, you need to decompress
the other side of the spine.
I know what I need to do.
Still falling.
Seventy-three over 39.
Heart rate 33.
Damn it.
Rod distractor
and set screwdriver.
Distracting the spine now.
He's gonna code any second.
Done.
Vitals improving.
Ninety over 55,
heart rate 43.
Now 110/65. Heart rate 60.
Drill.
Get the second rod in
and then you can close.
I'll need O-Maxons
and a large needle driver.
There. It all worked out.
They did it.
And?
He pulled through.
Thank God.
Yeah.
This day.
I gotta see Ms. Goodwin.
I'll be right back.
It's my understanding that
you took drugs from the trial
and gave them
to Dr. Manning's mother
without authorization.
That's correct.
As a result, Dr. Halstead,
Kender has pulled the trial
from this hospital,
which you know has major
financial implications.
There's the immediate
loss of revenue, of course,
but it's also safe
to assume that Kender
will be reluctant
to run trials
here in the future.
You have anything to say?
Ms. Goodwin, I was
trying to help a patient
in desperate need.
At the expense
of the trial
and all the other patients
that might benefit from it.
You know, you asked me
last summer why I didn't
name you as chief of the ED.
And it's precisely
this kind of
reckless behavior
that at this point,
I have no choice
but to address.
You're fired, Dr. Halstead.
Heard you're gonna be
joining us. Congratulations.
Thank you.
Believe me, you're
gonna get an education.
Congratulations,
Vanessa.
I know. Thank you.
I heard. Congratulations.
Thank you.
Um, we need to talk.
After work?
Okay.
Ethan.
Hi.
April.
How you doing?
Okay.
You would
say that if you were lying
on a bed of nails.
The bullet
was lodged at T6.
You had a laminectomy.
Dr. Archer insisted
on a corpectomy
to remove bone fragments,
and it was
the right call.
They say you'll need PT,
but that eventually,
you'll have a very
good outcome.
Ethan,
ever since
you and I broke up,
I've tried really,
really hard
to move on from us.
But seeing you brought in
this morning on that gurney,
everything just
came back to me.
Just how much I love you.
Come in.
Ms. Goodwin?
Dr. Archer,
I understand
you did yeoman's work,
treating Dr. Choi today.
Oh, I just did what
I thought he'd want.
I assume he'll have
a protracted convalescence.
When Dr. Choi hired you,
he sang your praises.
He had great faith
in your abilities.
And everything
that I've seen lately
only supports that.
So, if you're willing,
I'd like to name you
Interim Chief of the ED,
until Dr. Choi
can resume his duties.
Uh, well,
I'd be honored
and, uh, I'll do my best to
maintain the standards
he's set.
Good.
I think he'd be pleased.
Yeah. Thank you. Thanks.
It doesn't matter what
happens or where you take me.
Okay? It's all fake.
My real body is floating
in a tank, drugged,
interfacing with
the master computer.
Are you listening to me?
How did we get here?
There's just so many
troubled, lost souls.
Mischa, you remember
the delusional patient
I was telling you about?
You know, the one
who shot my colleague?
Yes?
You compared yourself
to him,
saying that living in
the Soviet Union was like
living in a different reality.
Mmm-hmm.
Right? And I was thinking,
the difference is,
is that this guy,
I mean, he's insane.
He's clinically delusional.
Whereas,
you and your colleagues...
Daniel, why do you
torture me with this?
Mischa, I'm so sorry.
That's not at all
my intention.
I'm actually trying to
figure out a way that
we might help Mr. Zorin.
"We"? How can I possibly
help this poor man?
You know what?
I think that you might be
ideally suited to the task.
I think
these were a mistake.
Let's get them off.
April, this just
came in for you.
From the NP
Admissions Department.
Yeah.
Oh, boy. Okay.
I got accepted. Yes!
Of course you did.
How about that?
Hey.
Listen, I love my parents.
They're caring,
wonderful people.
They adopted me
when I was an infant.
But you know that.
Yeah,
I kept wondering
why you were
so interested in me,
why you would look
at me the way
that you do.
You know, my parents,
they always said to me
that they would help me
find my birth mother,
but I wasn't interested.
I was happy. What would
have been the point?
Anyways, it, um...
It wasn't difficult for me
to find out who you were.
Oh, Vanessa, I was just...
I've worked my whole life
to get where I am.
If anybody thought I was
accepted here just because
I'm your daughter...
I... No.
That was entirely on
your own merit. Honestly.
I had nothing
to do with it.
I hope so.
Because I'm not going
to give up this opportunity.
You shouldn't.
There's no reason to.
I don't want anyone
to know about us.
Of course, and...
They won't.
What did you want, Maggie?
I just...
I wanted to meet you.
It wasn't right.
You coming
into my life like this.
It just wasn't right.
I know. I...
Mom.
Oh, Natalie.
Hi.
Am I alive?
Yes.
You are alive.
And you are gonna live
for a long, long time.
Thank you.
Who was that?
He is the best CT surgeon
in Chicago.
Wow.
Mmm.
Hey, Carol. You did great.
Nat, can I see you a sec?
Sure. Mom, I'll be
right back, okay?
Yeah.
Okay.
It's about Will.
What about him?
Goodwin fired you?
Just let it go, Nat.
Because of my mom's pills?
Will, did you tell her
you took them?
Answer me!
I had to.
Why?
It's everything.
Everything we've been through.
Everything we've been
to each other.
What else could I do?
Tell the truth!
No, I think a change
will do me good.
No, Will. I'm sorry.
I cannot let you do this.
Nat, I'm okay. Really.
Will, please, don't do this.
It's done, Nat. So...
It's done.
Hey.
You up for
a little visit?
Yes, ma'am.
No. Please don't.
You know,
when I saw you
get shot this morning,
I immediately thought,
"hate crime."
And I've since learned
that wasn't the case.
No.
But that's exactly
where my mind went.
This has been
a difficult year.
The madness,
the heartache.
I have to admit, Dr. Choi,
I'm a little bit
shell-shocked.
I know.
Yeah, I'm sure you do.
Well, I'll let you rest.
You need to heal.
We all do.
Ms. Goodwin?
Mmm-hmm?
I may be down,
but I'm gonna get back up.
I'm counting on that,
Dr. Choi.
I'm counting on that.
Ms. Goodwin?
Yeah?
You have got to
reinstate Dr. Halstead.
Dr. Manning, I realize
that you two are close...
No, you don't understand.
I was the one
who stole the trial meds
for my mom.
I am the reason the trial
was canceled. Not Will.
He said that to protect me.