Hello?
Who is this,
and why are you
calling me at 7:00 am?
It's just a day off, Ma.
No big deal.
Yes, I usually do work Fridays.
Huh?
Marshall Field?
Uh... no, no.
I... I got enough sheets.
What?
No, no, I have a lot
of stuff I want to do
around the house today.
No.
No, I don't need your help.
Nope, Mom...
Mom? Mom?
Ma! I don't need your
help, but thank you.
Yeah... no.
Go check out the sale, okay?
Okay, bye.
Morning, Leon.
Morning, Carol.
Hate going to work
on a morning this cold.
Yeah, I know what you mean.
Hey, Leon!
Hi, Miss Hathaway.
Slow down there, Robert.
I hate that he calls
me Miss Hathaway.
Yeah, it's a real crime when
kids show that kind of respect.
Have a good one.
Oh, and Happy Valentine's day.
Oh, God, I forgot.
Yeah, you, too.
Hiya.
Hey. Good morning.
Good luck. Thanks.
Good morning, Mrs. Novotny.
Good morning. Good morning.
No, Javier, not the dog cans.
We need the little biscuits.
Okay, Mrs. Novotny,
the little biscuits.
Hey, it's for my wife.
I think she has an ulcer.
Do you know which
one she should take?
I'm sorry. I can't help you.
This one says four times a day.
This one says two times a day.
I just do the baked goods.
Know what I mean?
Miss...
Just go now, no problems.
I don't call anyone.
Give us the damn money.
We should have waited. Shut up!
I'm going to need more
shelf space for the muffins.
Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
Hang on. Hang on.
I'm not doing anything.
I'm not moving.
Get them down... all of them!
Let's go. What are you doing?
Just shut up and keep them down.
Okay, get down!
Face down!
You, too, go on!
Don't look at me.
James, let's just go.
Listen, didn't you hear him?
He said to get
down, so get down!
Let's go.
You stop right
there, you bastards!
Come on, Pops.
Joseph, no, no!
Go back!
Come on.
Oh, jeez.
Anton!
Oh!
Please, he needs help... please!
There's a police car
right down the street.
Oh, God.
Where's the back?
Damn it.
Where are the keys?
Give me the keys!
Lady...
Lady, just give us the keys.
Just give us the keys.
You leave him
alone, you bastard.
Leave him alone!
Duncan, I need help.
Sure. I'll get you some help.
Just give me a minute.
I want everyone just to stay
where they are.
You got it?
I don't want anyone moving.
I don't want anyone talking.
I want everyone just
to stay where they are.
Anton! Anton!
Duncan, check out
those guys on the floor.
Over there... Two
of them on the floor.
Oh, God! He's so bloody!
We should have waited
till there weren't
any customers.
The welfare checks
come out today.
People come in to cash them.
We wait, we miss the money.
Oh, man.
Jeez.
How many?
Just a couple so far.
Robert...
Get behind those crates.
I don't want anybody
moving around, right?
Nobody's moving
around here, right?
He needs a doctor.
You shut up! Just shut up!
Get behind those crates.
Okay, shut up!
We've got to go.
You shut up, too, okay?
Robert, listen.
Get behind those crates.
Just crawl in behind
those crates.
Why would he go and do that?
I just told him not to move.
Get over here.
I said, get over here.
I don't want to.
Don't want to?
What the flying...?
Robert, just come
over here by me.
It's okay, come on.
Come on.
That's it.
Come on. It's okay.
Quick.
Brilliant.
Please...
Oh, please!
Please!
He needs help!
Shut your mouth.
I need help here, too, you know?
Duncan, would you shut her up?
Just shut up.
Help us! Please!
Listen, lady, what are we
supposed to do?
Now, stop your yapping now.
Wait.
Wait, I'm a nurse, and
maybe I can help him
and then Mrs.
Novotny will be quiet.
Won't you, Mrs. Novotny?
Hey, James, that's a bit
of luck. We got a nurse.
Get her over here.
What's your name?
Carol.
Carol, well, maybe you can go
and help my cousin James, Carol.
I think her husband's
a lot worse...
Yeah, sure, but you better
take a look at my cousin first,
or else, he'll get pissed off.
Go on.
You, what was your name?
Robert, you go with her.
Please, he's just a little boy.
He shouldn't see
something like that.
None of us should
see something like that.
Now go on.
And you, you go with her.
Go on!
Miss Hathaway... I think
I'm going to throw up.
Don't look, Robert.
Robert, don't look.
You, what's your name?
Don't point that thing at me.
I want you to stay over here.
Where am I going
to go, 7-Eleven?
No talking, either.
Over here!
Please, someone!
Please...
Hey, Duncan, don't
you go anywhere.
I won't.
You stay where I
can see you, okay?
Look, I'm not going anyplace.
There's police everywhere.
I need to take your pulse.
Don't.
I need to take the
pulse in your neck.
Please!
Should we get that?
You just let it ring, okay?
Carol, help us!
What's the matter
with the old boy?
I'm fine.
I think he hurt his wrist.
God! You'd think
I'd shot everyone.
Now, you look like
a fairly strong guy,
but just remember
I got the gun, okay?
I'm not doing anything.
I... I'm not moving.
You should answer
the phone.
Please, we need
a doctor for him.
Get him some help!
Oh, please!
James, maybe we should get that.
I just need a minute to think.
Maybe it's not for you.
The wound is very serious.
The bullet may have
hit your kidney or spleen.
You just make it stop bleeding.
We need to get a doctor in here.
We're not getting
anyone in here,
so you better do
something yourself.
I don't have the supplies.
Look around.
You got a whole store full.
Okay.
No, he stays with me.
Let her go.
She's going to
look for some stuff.
If your friend doesn't...
He's not my friend;
he's my cousin.
If your cousin doesn't
get to a hospital soon,
he's going to bleed to death.
Please, help us. Please.
Carol!
Duncan, get something
in front of the door.
Come on. Come with me. Up.
Go around there.
We're going to
move this over there.
Okay.
Kind of a heavy sucker, huh?
I just stocked it.
I love America.
Everyone has a job here, huh?
You...
do you have a job?
Uh, yeah, I teach school.
Out.
What?
I teach school... first
grade. That's good!
If you get them young enough,
then you can teach them right.
I guess no one got to you, huh?
She has a mouth.
Duncan, stop chatting with them.
Get down there.
This will stop it for now.
Good. Good.
I'll come back
and change it in a while.
Do you still need me?
For what?
I'll just go and check
on the old man?
Whatever.
Pray for us sinners now
and at the hour of our...
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with Thee.
Blessed art Thou
amongst women...
Mrs. Novotny...
Mrs. Novotny, I need you.
I'm going to do five
compressions in a row,
and on the fifth compression,
I want you to hold his nose
and blow into his mouth.
Hey, cops are
moving their cars back.
One, two, three, four, five.
I need some help!
She's helping.
Why are they doing that?
How should I know?
You're the American.
I can't do this.
I need medical supplies...
I.V. fluid, blood, monitors.
Shut her up!
I need someone to do CPR.
I can do it.
No, you... you don't move.
You sit there,
and you say nothing.
Listen to me, Duncan.
You do not want this man to die.
Okay? Those cops out there
consider that a
much bigger deal.
Now I need some help.
You, can you... can you
do this CPR thing?
We Just want to know
if everyone's all right,
if anyone needs
any help, that's all.
We need you to answer
the phone when we call you.
I got the straws, but
I couldn't find the...
What was it?
Rubbing alcohol.
That's good, Robert.
Get me some liquor.
What kind? Any kind.
Grain alcohol is the strongest.
That's all we need to know
right now. You got that?
We got to think
what to tell them.
Tell them anything.
You need to start
talking with us,
let us know what's going on.
I should just keep going, right?
Uh-huh.
Okay, you can move
back now, Mrs. Novotny.
Mrs. Novotny, you
can move back now.
Marita...
All right.
Oh!
It's okay.
Okay, it's okay.
Okay, Robert, pour
some on the straw.
Robert?
I'll do it.
We need to get out of here.
I know. I know.
I just... I just need
to think, you know?
You weren't thinking
very much at all, were you?
This is all my fault?
Well, it was your bloody idea!
Is that it?
Yeah, he's breathing.
He's got a pulse.
You can stop the compressions.
That's good. That
means you've got it huh?
Quiet, I'm trying to listen.
Listen I know you
say he's breathing,
but he looks kind
of blue, doesn't he?
He's going to be fine.
We're going to do this.
What is it? Is he all right?
I need a... ice pick.
Get me an ice pick!
They're by the freezer.
I'll get it.
No, Grandpa, you stay there.
I'll get the ice pick.
And I need a little tiny straw.
This is too big.
We don't have
anything like that.
Those little cardboard juices...
My kids drink them.
Those have those little straws.
Robert, get those straws.
Now, Robert! Please, now! Go!
Duncan, how long
is this going to take?
Have you got
someplace to go, James?
I shot the man.
If he pops off, then it's my
ass they've got, not yours.
Right. Like I'm going
to get probation.
Okay. Okay.
Should I start again?
No.
What we need to know is
how many people you got in
there and is everyone all right.
Are you guys all right?
Get on the phone.
If you need some help, we
can try to work something out.
What are we doing now?
He needs a chest tube.
Do it. Do it.
It's not what I do. I'm a nurse.
Please, we need supplies.
You've got to send
for a doctor in here.
They'd love that chance,
wouldn't they?
Oh, please,
you have to help him.
Okay.
Third... no, fifth intercostal
neurovascular bundle
above the rib.
All right, screwdriver.
Pour some liquor on it.
Rip open the tampons
and pull off the tube.
Ah!
Ahh.
All right, cut me a piece
of tape, Robert.
Give me the tampon.
All right, tape.
All right, I need more tape.
Great.
Okay, Mrs. Novotny,
blow into his trach tube.
We've lost his pulse.
Should I start CPR?
No, I got it. What's your name?
Angie.
I got it for now, Angie.
Thanks.
Come on.
You can't do it, can you?
Your cousin's losing
more and more blood.
There's nothing more I can do.
We'll get out of this.
Yeah, right.
Shut up, bread man,
and just keep dragging.
I'm going to throw up.
I have to go to the bathroom.
He goes nowhere.
He's just a kid.
You don't want him
throwing up in here.
Believe me.
It's okay, James. I've
checked the bathroom.
There's no way out of there.
Hey, go on.
Guys, listen to me.
I don't need to talk to both
of you, okay, I just, uh...
Figure out which one of
you want to get on the phone
and start working with us.
Duncan, you've got
to help your cousin.
He's got to get to a hospital.
Yeah, and I have to get
to one of your fine
American prisons.
They'll go easier on you.
You've never killed before.
Just how do you know that?
You haven't, have you?
Duncan, what the
hell's taking so long?!
Come on.
You've got to start
working with me.
Hey! Hey!
It's me, Javier.
Quiet. Quiet.
There's a door
behind me, but I can't get out.
It's locked.
I've got a baseball bat.
No, no, no! They'll shoot you.
Just stay right there.
I'm going to try
and get the keys, okay?
Hang on. Don't move.
What are you going to tell them?
Tell them we want
a way out of here...
A truck or van... or something.
Tell them to send
in medical supplies.
Oh, right. Like what?
What do we need?
What medical stuff?
Don't be stupid.
Some blood... at least
four units of O-negative,
a couple I.V.s, saline...
Right, and then she fixes me
up and we just walk out of here?
I don't know. Maybe.
They send in medical supplies,
they'll send them in with a cop.
Now look what you did.
I don't like the big guy.
Tape him up.
What?
I don't like him.
And I don't like her
moving around like that.
She's trying to help.
Here, put this on.
Thanks.
This wouldn't be necessary
if he hadn't shot the coffeepot.
Angie, don't talk back to them.
Next time, maybe you should
shoot the milk or
the cold drinks...
There won't be a next time.
I'm not listening
to you anymore.
What'd I do?
I said we shouldn't come in
when there were customers.
It was the flipping
owner that shot me.
You wouldn't listen to me.
Listen to you?!
Where are the keys?
The keys?
The keys to the door
off the storeroom.
Javier is hiding in there.
He could get out.
First shelf under the counter.
I try to get them.
Okay. Shh.
What's taking that kid so long?
He's throwing up.
Give him a break.
I want to talk to
the hostages now!
I want everyone to know
we've got lots of help out here.
Don't they ever shut up?
We're all going to resolve this!
You have a fracture dislocation.
I should reduce it,
but it's going to hurt.
You might want a
drink of that liquor.
I couldn't do that.
I'm an alcoholic.
Okay. Angie, can you get
us some aspirin, please?
Yeah.
No, no. I can do it.
I can do it.
Where do you
think you are going?
I'm going to get
him some aspirin.
I think I saw them over there.
Try not to shoot it, okay?
Angie!
Try not to shoot the aspirin.
That's not funny.
You know what?
Maybe the old man over there
will toss up his Alka-Seltzer.
You'll have a little
target practice... bang!
James, shut up!
Shoot out that whole
row of dishwashing liquid.
Just pow! Pow!
I said it's not funny.
You could shoot out the lights
while you're at it. Bang! Bang!
He shot my husband!
Isn't that good enough for you?!
He shot him here...
and here.
Mrs. Novotny!
All he could do was
bleed and bleed.
He couldn't move.
He couldn't breathe.
He couldn't... talk.
He couldn't...
He couldn't say good-bye.
He couldn't say how
much he loved me.
I wanted to hear him say
that just one more time!
Shh.
You see?!
You see? I shot her old man!
I killed her husband,
and a good job I did, too,
before he put a hole
through your other side.
You didn't thank me
for that, did you?!
Where's that flipping kid?
Wait a minute.
He's been in there half my life.
Yeah, but if he's sick,
he might need me.
Okay, okay, whatever.
Hey, kid!
Kid, are you still in there?
Come on out now.
You can't throw up forever.
We're all eating free
hot dogs out here.
Don't you want one?
That was a stupid thing to say
if he's chucking up.
You try.
Robert, come out now.
Robert, it's me. It's Carol.
It... it's Miss Hathaway.
"Miss Hathaway."
That's very sweet.
Come in.
Are you feeling any better?
Hmm?
That's good.
We can go back out now.
Duncan doesn't like me.
Well...
I don't think Duncan
likes any of us,
but you're going
to be okay, Robert.
You don't know that.
No, I don't, but there are
a lot of police out there,
and at some point, they'll
come in here and help us.
Duncan will shoot them
just like he shot Mr. Novotny.
No, he can't shoot them all.
'Cause there'll be like
80 of them or something?
Or something.
What if they all start
shooting at the same time?
Well...
Then we'll have to duck.
Why did you take your
shoes and socks off?
My feet were hot.
Okay, I want you to put
them back on and come out,
so we can join the others, okay?
I suppose you've seen
a lot of dead people...
I mean, in your line of work.
Yeah.
This is just the way it is?
Yes.
Guess you sort
of get used to it.
Not really.
Hey, there, buddy!
There you go!
Hey, hey...
what are you doing?
Robert?
Robert, come out!
What are you doing now?!
Stay away from me!
Robert, come out now!
You can't even
catch a little kid?
I don't see you helping me.
I'm not coming out!
Just leave him in
there. Who cares?
Robert, come out now.
Get away from me!
Come here!
Let go of me!
Don't hurt him!
Don't hurt him.
I'm not going to hurt him.
I'm just going to kill him.
James, will you answer
the frickin' phone?!
You're coming over here with me.
You're going to
sit in the corner.
Get down and stay there!
No, better still...
better still, I want you
feeding quarters into that thing.
Both hands on at all times.
I'm going over there
and answer that phone.
I want to hear a
little ping, ping, ping
coming from this direction.
I don't hear it, I'm most likely
to turn around and shoot, okay?
Ping, ping, ping.
Now, we all know that
I shot the coffeepot,
so I'm not afraid of
shooting this thing
or anything in the
way of this thing.
Get down!
You, breadman, down!
Miss Hathaway, do you want
to come and attend to
my poor cousin James,
who's so weak he can't
even pick up the phone?
What do you want?
Oh, we're fine.
Thank you very much.
Sweet of you to ask.
No, we don't want
much of anything
except perhaps a van or a truck,
or how about a tank?
No, we don't need
any medical help.
Our very own Nurse Hathaway
is doing quite beautifully
all on her own.
They don't think
you can handle this.
They want to send
in some doctor.
I think she resents
the implications of that.
I think we all do.
Hey, come down
from there!
Kid!
Get away from me!
Let go now!
Get down from there!
Get away from me!
I'm not coming down!
There are dead cats up there.
Is that what you want?
A face full of dead cats?
Just go away.
Get away!
Hey, hey, hey...
I need to start, Duncan.
How long does
that thing go on for?
I'm going to start now, okay?
Robert's probably told
them all about us by now.
"The Scottish one...
He killed the old man,
burnt the schoolteacher
and stole my shoe."
What are we going to do?
I don't know. I need
some time to think.
He's bleeding badly.
I don't know how
much time he has left
if we don't get
him to a hospital.
I can keep changing
his bandages,
but it's not going to matter.
Just shut up, okay?
Don't talk to me like that.
I've just tried to help him.
That's all I'm trying to do now.
Do you have any glue?
Yes, we do.
It's on the shelf
behind the counter.
I know, Duncan.
We'll ask for a chopper,
and they can fly us to a boat
out in the middle
of Lake Michigan.
The lake is probably frozen.
Then one of those
ice sailing boats.
I did that once...
A couple of winters
ago, up in Lake Geneva.
It was incredible.
They're really fast, right?
60 miles an hour.
Felt like 100.
They'll never catch
us at that speed.
We'll be home free, right?
Sure. Home free.
What are you doing?
The cut's too deep.
I can't close it,
unless you want me to
get you a needle and thread.
No, no. Glue's fine.
You weren't lying, were you...
About his bleeding?
You have to give up now, Duncan.
Duncan, maybe we
should go to that place
you were telling me about.
The fifth of something.
Firth, the Firth of Clyde.
You take a ferry.
Yeah. To the island
of Great Cumbrae
and then, sneak a tiny
boat over to little Cumbrae,
because it's privately
owned, you know?
You can get caught, of
course, but it's worth it
if the sun's in the sky
and the Firth is blue.
The big mountains of Arran
all purple, jutting up
in the background.
Sounds beautiful.
I wouldn't know.
I've never been.
Never even seen the Firth.
Maybe that's what I should have
pledged at Hogmanay, you know...
To go to little Cumbrae.
A clean break with the past.
A fresh start.
But I came to America
instead to stay with my cousin.
My father thought I was crazy.
He's a pallet driver
on the shipyards in Glasgow...
30 years, loading
on and loading off.
Got me the same
job when I was 19.
I was laid off by 20.
It was a good job, you know,
but I always wanted
something else,
wanted to be something more.
I have, too.
With all you can do? Why?
I don't know.
So then
I end up in here.
Duncan Stewart comes to America,
and on a Friday
morning, comes in here.
We just needed the money.
Yeah, but look
what we got, James.
Look! You're a bloody mess,
and I don't know what to do.
But you're all right.
I'm not all right at all.
I killed a man.
I killed a man!
Do you know
what that feels like?
Huh?
Do you?
I do.
I killed a man.
I gave him the wrong blood.
You didn't mean to kill him.
You didn't mean
to kill Mr. Novotny.
And how many of
those cops out there
are going to care about that?
It's all right, James.
I'll get us out of this somehow.
I just have to
think of something.
I don't know what, but...
I have to think of something.
Maybe Robert
had the right idea.
Maybe that's the way out.
We stack these
crates high enough
to support the ceiling.
Duncan, behind you!
Don't, Duncan.
You already know
what it feels like,
except this time,
you'll mean it.
Don't! Don't!
Where the hell were you?
Don't hurt him.
Where were you? Where were you?
The storeroom, by the door.
The door?
You're telling me
there's a door?
Here, just take them, take them.
Just take the keys, Duncan.
Where does it go?
It's a fire escape.
The ladder leads up to the
apartment building behind us.
There's a building behind us?
You're coming with me.
Just don't move your wrist.
You'll be fine.
I hope it is you
who will be fine.
James, I have to go.
There's a way out.
I have to go.
I don't want to
leave you, but...
We should have waited.
They'll take good care of you.
I know they will.
Come on. Let's go.
Go on.
This is called taking
the long way around.
Come on.
We did it, Miss Hathaway.
We did it.
When we get to
the end of the alley,
I want you to let me go, Duncan.
Sure.
I wouldn't want you
to slow me down.
Hold it right there!
Stop right there please.
Stop!
Is that one of them?
Yes. Don't run, Duncan!
Don't run!
Stop or I'll shoot.
God!
Call the paramedics!
This is unit 2418.
I'm in the alley
behind 3312 Woolcott.
I've got one offender down.
I need a wagon or an ambulance.
What about the other suspect?
The other suspect?!
Internal bleeding...
he's still inside.
Probably passed out.
The second suspect is
inside, possibly unconscious.
Come on.
Get the paramedics!
Clear Trauma 2!
Carol, you all right?
We can get it from here.
Duncan Stewart.
Multiple GSWs to
the chest and thigh.
Two liters saline in.
Just gave high dose epi for PEA.
James Rogers,
single entrance wound
left abdomen,
massive blood loss on scene,
shocky BP 80/45,
pulse 144,
good breath sounds bilaterally.
Okay, on my count...
My count.
One, two, three, go.
All right, give me
two more saline,
four of O-negative
on the rapid infuser.
We got spontaneous respiration.
Hold the CPR.
Okay, let's move him.
One, two, three.
Where's Benton?
Out with an appendectomy.
He's got a pulse.
What about Morgenstern?
He needs a surgeon.
I got it.
Duncan, hey.
You hang in there, okay?
Think of all the
beautiful places
you told us about.
Think about the Firth of Clyde
and little Cumbrae.
You hang in there, okay?
We'll pull you through this.
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Lost his pulse.
I'll intubate him.
Give me a 7.5 ET tube, please.
We need a portable chest!
Two units in!
I need the tube.
Got it?
Pulse ox is 85.
BP 75/50.
Sinus tach at 150.
Pulse thready.
Cap refill's poor.
There's no exit wound.
Probably got the spleen.
Give him a gram
of cefoxitin, CBC.
Type and cross for six.
Still no pulse.
Decreased breath
sounds on the right.
He's going to need a chest tube.
Haleh, take over.
I'll do the Foley.
Malik, dip the urine for blood.
Kerry, Duncan
needs a chest tube.
Duncan?
The patient in 2.
I think Doug can
handle the tube.
Who's the senior
surgical resident on call?
Carol, what are you doing here?
I'm trying to help!
You know, I think we got it.
Why don't you take a break?
Call the OR.
They can explore
this guy up there.
Got a blood gas?
Done.
Two more units of O-neg
on the rapid infuser now!
Get an H and H
and cross for eight.
You want type-specific?
That's a good idea.
I already ordered it.
How about the portable chest?
I ordered that, too.
Doug, can you
take over CPR?
Yep.
Carol, call Radiology again.
Carol!
Hey, Carol.
Hey, Carol, let's go.
I got it.
Hi, this is Carol
Hathaway in the ER.
We need a portable
chest in Trauma 2.
Asystole!
Let's crack him.
Got it?
Give me a number ten blade.
Rib spreader.
Doug, can you start
internal compression?
Amp of epi.
Okay, two more units
of O-neg. Statinsky.
Mig of atropine.
Give me some suction.
Hey... anyone talked to Carol?
How's she doing?
From the looks of her,
she ain't giving up her job.
Is this guy going to make it?
Yeah, probably.
Weaver thinks
it's just his spleen.
How many units?
Four O-neg, four type-specific.
Last epi?
Five migs, three minutes ago.
How long has he been down?
25 minutes.
Time of death: 1348.
Hey, Carol, how are you?
I'm fine, Jerry. Thanks.
Do you know where
the others are?
Yeah, the lady with
the burned hand
is right here, Curtain 2.
The rest got
transferred to St. Mary's.
The little boy...
Robert Potter, ten years old?
I didn't hear
anything about him.
Thanks, Jer.
Second-degree burns.
I'm going to go get
some Thermazine salve
and dressings.
Hey, you're okay now.
You're okay.
Yeah, I guess so.
And, uh... and you're all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
How about the others?
Uh, that bread guy, Lockhart...
He was fine.
And, um... Javier and Mr. Dusak
went to some other hospital.
And Robert?
Robert.
Robert crawled back down
the hole he crawled up in.
He didn't have a scratch on him.
I didn't think I would
be this shaken.
But we got out all right, huh?
Yeah.
Well, they'll just
put some cream
and dressings on your burns,
and you'll be fine in no time.
Okay.
Hey...
you really saved
our lives in there.
None of us could have done that.
I'll see you around.
Are you all right?
Well, it's been
a busy day, but...
Hey, are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
When we first heard
that you were in there,
and the police
didn't tell us anything,
we didn't know
what was going on.
You sure you're okay?
Okay.
Oh, and Doug...
I'm really sorry about
what happened in there.
I didn't mean...
I don't care about in there.
It doesn't matter.
Just glad you're okay.
Jerry, uh, could you...?
Carol.
Do you, uh... do
you need anything?
No, thanks.
I'm fine.
You know...
we've missed you around here.
I've missed it, too.
I love my job, Kerry.
I know.
I'm going home.
That's a good idea.