You look good.
Stop.
I've just been
worried about you.
Things are going well?
No more rats
since they put me
on the risperidone.
That's good. That's good.
So, you're feeling
better, then?
Yeah. And I
want to get the hell
out of here.
Robin, there's something
that I have to tell you.
The reason why
you're in here...
I asked your father
to check in on you.
I had no idea
that he would
do something like...
It's not your fault.
You couldn't have known
he'd do this.
It's not all bad.
Hey, they let me
use the shower.
Not without
supervision, though.
They are worried
about suicide in here,
so no shoelaces, no belts.
See the sink?
No faucet.
Evidently,
if you wrap your gown
around your neck just right,
you can use it
to strangle yourself.
You don't belong in here.
Not according to
the petition Dad filed.
Article 6 of the Mental Health
and Disabilities Code.
No. I'm serious, Robin.
So you heard rats.
So what?
This is not
the solution.
What can I do?
Oh, I really appreciate
your being here.
Support from friends
and family is crucial
for the therapeutic process,
so thank you.
Committed against her will?
She can't even
shower by herself.
That is some
therapeutic process.
I think we all wish
this could've
happened differently,
but, you know,
at least she's getting
the care that she needs,
and she's safe and secure.
No. She's locked up.
In prison.
It's not the same thing.
This place is what is
gonna drive her crazy.
She needs to be out of here.
Good morning, Nat.
Morning.
Hey, Natalie,
have you seen Reese?
No. Sorry.
Hey, how's Robin doing?
I've been meaning
to ask, but...
I know,
it's a delicate situation.
She's dealing. Yeah.
Okay.
Well, if you need anything,
just please ask.
Thanks.
Okay.
April, today's match day.
Did Noah land here at Med?
Texted him a dozen times.
No response.
They're only taking
one local student,
so that makes me think
he didn't get it.
Or maybe he just wants
to tell you in person.
No news could be
good news, too.
Let's hope.
It means "White butterfly"
in Portuguese.
Yeah, that doesn't
clear things up.
It's a Brazilian
superstition.
So, if the first butterfly
you see in the year
is white, it's good luck.
I saw one a few weeks ago.
Technically, doesn't that
only bring you luck?
Wouldn't Noah need
to have seen this white...
Seriously? You really want
to analyze the cosmic power
of an insect sighting?
Probably an argument
I don't win, huh?
Dr. Choi, incoming!
Peds versus auto.
You're going to Baghdad.
Courtney?
Gary Foster, 32.
Tripped and fell
into oncoming traffic.
He got plowed by a taxi.
GCS 15, vitals stable,
16 gauge in the right AC.
Loss of consciousness?
Yeah, briefly,
but he was talking
by the time we got there.
Wanted to make sure
no one blames
the cab driver
for what happened.
It was my fault.
I felt myself falling.
I just couldn't stop it.
It's okay, Mr. Foster.
It was an accident.
Let's transfer on my count.
One, two, three.
Breath sounds clear
and present bilaterally.
BP 122 over 70.
Heart rate 112. Sats 100%.
Let's roll him off
the board slowly.
Easy.
Okay, okay, okay.
Good God! That hurts!
Okay, Mr. Foster,
listen to me close, okay?
Okay.
Can you touch your chin
to your chest?
Hmm?
Good, good, good.
Now, left to right.
Good. C-spine's clear.
We can lose the collar.
All right, April,
50 of fentanyl for the pain.
Let's get X-rays.
Chest, pelvis, left humerus.
I also want a CT head,
abdomen, and pelvis,
and let's get an EKG.
This is bad, isn't it?
Just try to stay calm,
Mr. Foster.
Okay.
It's okay.
We're gonna help you.
Reese, you got a second?
Uh, so,
I just saw Robin.
It seems like
her therapy's going well.
It is. It is. She is lucid
and responding
to her medication.
Most importantly,
she is letting us help her.
I wasn't sure
she'd be so trusting,
considering how
this went down.
So, she tells me
that you guys
are diagnosing this
as schizophreniform.
Yeah, it's looking
like that.
Now, from what I've read,
to be able to make
that call,
the symptoms have to last
for at least a month.
Is that how long
you guys are planning
on keeping her?
Uh, well, right now,
it's all about making sure
her psychosis is under control
and her meds
are dosed appropriately.
Anything about...
Thank you.
...release dates,
you really should speak
with her attending.
Right. Dr. Kwon.
I actually did.
He reminded me that
patience is a virtue.
I'm pretty sure
that Dr. Charles
put those words
in his mouth.
Reese,
this is all messed up.
I'm sorry, Connor,
but I don't know
what you want me to say.
If Robin had been
committed in Indiana,
she'd be released already.
Same with Michigan.
Same with Wisconsin.
All of those states
have shorter holds.
But this is Illinois,
and I don't make the laws.
Tell me
this couldn't be treated
on an outpatient basis.
That's not up to me.
Is she, or is she not
a danger to herself?
At this exact moment, no,
but it's not that simple.
Yes, it is.
Ah! So, what's the word?
I matched my first choice.
Really?
Emergency medicine.
That's great!
I'm so happy for you!
Really? You got
the Med spot?
Knew you could do it.
I had my eye on you
from the get-go.
Don't worry about Stohl.
I won't.
Does Natalie know?
Not yet. I was waiting
to see where I wound up.
Hmm.
Keoni? What did you do?
No clue.
Jeff, with me.
We're going
to Treatment Two.
Doing a DIY reno
on the bar.
Been tripping over
construction supplies
all week.
Must have twisted my ankle.
Didn't notice till
it got really bad.
All right, cool.
Let's take a look.
Hop up there.
Take a look at this flat tire.
These your construction boots?
I'm Hawaiian, brah.
Slippers are multipurpose.
You got a nail
in your foot, dude.
You're kidding?
Wow. It doesn't hurt?
Been barefoot
or in slippers
since I could walk.
Calluses so tough,
I could walk on hot coals
and wouldn't even flinch.
Swing your foot
up there for me.
Let's get a CBC,
a CMP, and a tetanus,
and have Danny come down
with a portable X-ray machine.
Okay.
You've been living
in Chicago 20 years, Keoni.
Put on some shoes.
And give up
the endless summer?
Never.
Hey, April.
Bummer about Noah.
What?
You didn't hear?
Jeff got the Med spot.
Oh. Well, good for him.
I'm sure Noah
matched somewhere great.
Her stomach's been hurting her
for a few days now,
but an hour ago,
everything just went haywire.
She's been screaming in pain.
She gets really confused.
Abdominal pelvic ultrasound.
On it.
Okay, Allison,
can you tell me
exactly where it hurts?
I just got braces
put on last week.
See the confusion?
And her eyes,
she can't even focus.
It's called "nystagmus."
Is she taking any drugs?
No. No, no, no.
Has Allison
started menstruating?
I don't know. Maybe.
Is she sexually active?
Could she be pregnant?
She's only 13!
Look, I don't think so.
I'm just a stepdad, so...
Ali, baby! I'm sorry.
I came as fast as I could.
Baby, what's happening?
I don't understand.
She said
she was feeling better
when I left for work.
Not seeing any free fluids,
no ovarian abnormalities.
All right,
let's do a CBC, CMP,
chest X-ray, cultures,
head CT, tox screen,
blood and urine,
and a serum pregnancy.
Wait, pregnancy? What? No.
Ali is still a virgin.
She hasn't even started
talking about boys yet.
I understand, but these
are standard tests.
We just need to run them
to be safe, okay?
Can you just give her
something for the pain,
please?
I'm sorry, but we can't
do that until the tests
are finished.
Baby, what's going on?
Keep away from me!
We will figure
this out, okay?
I'll be back shortly.
I can grab you
some more pillows
if you need them.
If it were only that easy.
Mr. Foster,
I got your X-rays
and scans.
There are
multiple fractures
on your left side.
L1 through L4 of your spine,
humerus, pelvis, and ribs.
Good news is
they won't require surgery.
They'll heal on their own.
How long will that take?
On average,
six to eight weeks.
After that, between rehab
and physical therapy,
likely a year
before you're back
to full strength.
A year.
Might as well
be forever.
Now, there is
one more injury.
The head CT revealed
a left-sided
subdural hematoma
and skull fracture.
Our neurosurgeon,
Dr. Abrams,
wants to schedule
surgery immediately.
What happens if I decline?
Mr. Foster,
you're bleeding
inside your brain.
If the pressure
within your skull
isn't released,
it will get worse.
It's highly likely
you'll die.
I'm already dying.
I have ALS.
It's progressing rapidly.
That's why I fell.
By the time my bones heal,
the disease
will be ravaging me.
Yeah, but you'll be alive.
Barely.
Confined to a wheelchair,
hooked up to a ventilator.
No. I don't want that.
No surgery.
I mean, there shouldn't
even be a debate. We can
save Mr. Foster's life.
I understand, April,
but unfortunately,
that's not the issue.
His hematoma's worsening.
He's gonna bleed to death.
At this rate, he's got
a couple weeks at best.
We have to act.
We can't.
I've studied Mr. Foster's
advanced directives,
so has the hospital's
legal counsel.
It's ironclad.
So, that just makes it
okay to do nothing?
April, part of
Mr. Foster's directive
instructs that upon death,
his organs and tissues
be donated.
Clearly,
this isn't a rash decision,
so what's the discussion?
That we have to sit by
and watch a man die
when we can easily
extend his life.
It's wrong.
Yeah, well,
we may not agree
with his decision,
but it is his choice
to make.
Transfer the patient
to the ICU.
Sharon?
I need a minute.
Yes.
Hey, update me on Allison?
White count's
moderately elevated,
but her fever's rising,
and she's disinhibited
with a decreased level
of consciousness.
Drug overdose?
Tox screen was negative.
As was every other test.
Pregnancy, urinalysis,
chest X-ray, CT,
pelvic ultrasound.
Neurologic infection?
Meningitis?
Encephalitis?
You get an LP?
Just did. CSF was clear.
Whatever this is, it's viral.
The lab's running a PCR.
Okay. Keep me posted.
Mmm-hmm.
Hey, Doris told me
you matched in
Emergency Medicine.
That's awesome.
Way to go, Clarke.
Good to have you.
Thanks.
Hey, um, there is
something that I've
been meaning to talk...
Natalie!
She's seizing.
Oh, my God,
make it stop!
Two of Ativan.
Got it.
Sats are dropping, 77, 76.
Allison,
can you feel this?
I need to intubate.
No drugs.
Her jaw is loose.
We're gonna fix this.
Okay, almost.
Yeah.
No, no, no, no, no.
You're gonna choke her!
She won't be able
to breathe otherwise.
I'm in.
Okay. I got it. I got it.
Secure the tube
and start bagging.
Stat chest X-ray and call
up to the pediatric ICU
for a bed.
Wait, ICU?
What's going on with her?
Hey, man. I got your labs.
Good news only, please.
Can I sit?
Uh-oh.
Everything's normal
except your blood glucose.
It's extremely high.
Diabetes.
Yes.
I'm gonna start you
on IV fluids and insulin
and order hemoglobin A1C.
Get a better reading
on your sugar levels.
Diabetes can make
your feet numb.
That's why I didn't
realize I had a nail
in my foot, isn't it?
Yeah.
I've been sick for a while.
Look, the important thing...
We caught it.
Some lifestyle adjustments,
and you'll get way
out ahead of this thing.
Yeah, sure.
Look, I get it.
Change isn't easy,
but in the long run,
it's the only way.
I'm gonna page Endocrinology,
have them come down
for a consult.
They should be able to answer
all your questions.
Hey.
Allison's LP results.
Encephalitis.
Oh, my God. HSE?
Yeah.
Fever, neuro issues,
seizures, now the coma...
Virus fits the symptoms.
Yeah.
I just didn't see it coming.
I mean, she's 13. Herpes?
April!
BP's falling.
94 over 66.
Heart's racing.
Pulse is 120.
All right,
lungs are wet. Sats?
Can't get a reading.
Fingers are swollen,
purple. Pulse ox monitor
can't register.
Get a blood gas.
Toes are purple.
Earlobes, too.
Blood in the eyes,
nasal passage.
What's happening?
Your circulation's
being cut off.
Oxygen's not moving well
through your body.
Why?
I'm not sure.
PCO 256, PAO 255.
All right, let's increase
the oxygen to 10 liters.
April?
Is he still being
transferred to the ICU?
Hold off for now.
Let's test for DIC.
If that's what
we're seeing,
I think there may be
a way to convince Gary
to fix his brain bleed.
Oh. Hey, were you
looking for me?
Uh... Please join us,
Dr. Charles.
This is Nicole Jansen
of Shipley...
Shipley Austin & Shea.
I'm representing
the interest
of Robin Charles.
Lawyers?
I'm hoping you can
provide some clarity
on the circumstances
surrounding Ms. Charles'
involuntary hold.
I don't see how
it's not clear.
A petition was filed
in accordance
with state law.
And within 24 hours,
Dr. Kwon here signed...
I will get to Dr. Kwon.
First, I want to talk about
the filing of the original
petition by Dr. Charles,
the hospital's
Chief of Psychiatry,
but also my client's father.
Interesting.
Allison has HSV type 2,
which is more
commonly associated
with genital herpes than oral.
Genital? No.
Ali doesn't do that.
And when? Where?
She's either at school,
or at home with one of us.
Right, Kevin?
Yeah, look, I work from home.
Nothing's going on
at the house.
Okay, no boys
come over, ever.
I know girls
don't tell their mothers
everything.
God knows I didn't,
but Ali and me, we talk.
Have you noticed
any change in Allison's mood,
or personality
in the last few days?
No.
Besides being sick,
she's been her usual
happy self. Why?
Allison's abdominal pain
is inconsistent with
the HSE diagnosis,
and it may be a sign
of sexual assault.
We'd like to perform
a more extensive pelvic exam
just to be sure.
Is that
really necessary?
Come on, it's not gonna
have any effect on how
you treat her, is it?
There might be
some internal damaging
and bleeding that needs
to be repaired,
and it is possible
she may have contracted
another STD.
Look, can it just wait?
Can it wait
until we just have
a moment to figure out...
It's okay.
You can perform the exam.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Um, if this is that,
I need to know. I'm sorry.
Babe. Baby...
We'll get started
right away.
I'll start Robin's
discharge paperwork.
Thank you.
Hmm. Little heads-up,
you know,
would've been nice.
I found out just
before you did.
I mean, come on.
Rhodes' name's
on the building,
so he gets to decide
who's fit to be released?
Is this a joke?
Sharon, it's Robin!
I thought that you guys
would at least
go to the wall for Robin.
Daniel, if we don't
make a deal in this room,
the next place we'll meet
will be in front of a judge
with Robin
and a team of doctors
that they've assembled
to challenge our every move.
That's not good for anyone,
especially for you.
Okay, well, then,
I appreciate
you looking out for me.
Daniel. Daniel, come on.
Thank you very much.
Absolutely.
Dr. Charles, don't.
It'll just start...
Not now, not now.
Hey, Connor. Connor.
I'm just curious.
So, you're the one
who's gonna be taking care
of Robin now?
Yeah.
I mean, you're
a surgical fellow, buddy.
You're working
36-hour shifts.
Uh-huh. So, I'll adjust
my schedule and
we'll make it work.
But what happens next time
she has a psychotic break?
I mean, even if you're home,
you're not equipped
to deal with it.
Every second
that she spends
in that ward,
her resentment
towards you grows.
Can't you see
that I'm trying
to do you a favor?
Don't do me
any favors! Don't!
Look, I came to you
out of concern
for Robin, not panic!
And you escalated things!
You don't have a clue
what you are dealing with.
Is this some kind of game
to you where you get
to be the hero?
Is that what it is?
No, this is not a game.
You made a mess,
and I'm fixing it.
Right.
By bringing in
Daddy's big guns.
Well done.
She is not
a little girl anymore!
Okay? You can't
make up for your own
failings as a father
by treating her
like one now!
Give it up.
Allison's pelvic exam
yielded evidence
of vaginal trauma.
Perforated hymen,
mucosal tears,
severe edema, swelling.
All clear evidence
of sexual assault.
Timeline?
The status of
the bruising indicates
the trauma took place
about five
to seven days ago,
consistent with
the incubation period
of the encephalitis.
Poor baby.
All right, I'll activate
the rape protocols
and notify PD.
This case
is now a crime.
Yeah.
We'll talk to the parents
about what comes next.
All right.
Thanks, Ms. Goodwin.
Mmm-hmm.
And where are you going?
Gonna go get
some fresh air.
With your clothes
over your arm?
I've seen
too many people skip out
after getting bad news.
It never ends well.
What does it matter
if I stay or if I go?
The results
are the same.
I doubt that.
Move.
No chance.
So, where does
that leave us?
I'm scared.
It's okay.
Come on back.
I know someone
you should talk to.
Ah, a shrink?
Something like that.
The trauma nurse
won't let me be
in there with her.
It's protocol,
just while they're
collecting evidence.
It won't be long, though.
I'm gonna go get
a cup of coffee.
You want one?
No.
Wait, wait. Can I ask you...
Can I ask you something,
Dr. Manning?
Of course.
Could you be having
unprotected sex regularly
with someone with herpes
and not catch it?
Not even be aware
that they have it?
Yes.
I don't want to believe
it could be true,
but the only person
who was alone with Ali
in the past week was Kevin.
I can't think
of anyone else
it might've been.
Ms. Nicholson,
Huh?
You can be with
your daughter now.
Thank you.
I'm just being
paranoid, right?
I suppose I can't talk
to the girl for
some time, right?
No.
Um, the mom thinks
the stepdad
might've done it.
Wouldn't surprise me.
That's where
I was gonna start.
Seriously, Jay,
I don't know
how you go to work
and do this every day.
I could say
the same thing
for you.
I gotta take this.
My feet are cold.
I'll get you
some more blankets.
Everything hurts.
It's from
Disseminated Intravascular
Coagulation, DIC.
Clots are forming
inside your vessels,
blocking blood flow
and depriving you
of oxygen.
Your organs are failing.
Unfortunately,
in this condition,
they're not suitable
for transplant.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
I won't be able to donate?
No.
There's got
to be something
you can do.
Mr. Foster, if you allow us
to operate on the hematoma,
that puts us
in a better position
to treat the DIC.
No. Then we're back
to where we started.
I'm laying here
with broken bones
that won't heal
before I'm locked up
on life support.
Listen, you can't let
my organs die
before I do.
Please?
There is a fix
for the DIC. Heparin.
It's a drug
that prevents the clots
from getting larger.
Mr. Foster,
heparin is a blood thinner,
which means it will
also significantly worsen
the bleeding in your brain.
Instead of weeks to live,
you'll have only hours.
Weeks weren't much,
but that gave me time
to say goodbyes.
Hours, though.
Mr. Foster,
if we're gonna start
the heparin...
The sooner, the better.
Yeah.
You don't have to do this.
You can change your mind.
What would you like to do?
Give me the heparin.
Gary, are you sure?
Yes.
Okay. Excuse us.
April!
We cannot do this, Ethan.
He was clear in his decision.
Because you pressured him,
made him feel he had
to choose right now.
No, I gave him
his medical options,
and he decided on
what was best for him.
Don't put this on me.
It is on you.
Your hands may have been tied
by his advance directive,
but giving him heparin,
knowing it's lethal,
that's assisted suicide.
April, we can't save Gary,
but one organ donor
can save up to eight lives.
One tissue donor can improve
the lives of up to 50 others.
Because of him,
58 people get a second chance.
Put in the order for heparin.
No.
Then I'll do it myself.
This is everything you had
when you were admitted.
Thank you.
You can't hold me
here any longer.
I know.
Look...
Whatever you have to say,
I don't want to hear it.
I just want you
to be safe, Robin.
I'm going to be.
With Connor.
What is up,
family?
Matched at Chicago Med!
Emergency Medicine, baby!
Let's get it!
April, we did it!
What? I don't understand.
I thought Jeff
got the match.
What? No, no, no.
It's official.
Only one local spot at Med,
and it's all mine!
Oh, I'm home!
I knew you'd do it.
Had my eye on you
from the get-go.
Hey, what's going on?
I matched in Honolulu.
Chicago Med wasn't
even on the list.
Good luck, Clarke.
Thanks.
I just assumed...
I mean, you must have known
about this for a while now.
Yeah.
Why didn't
you say anything?
I don't know.
I just felt like it
was time to move on.
Okay.
Hey, Nat?
Sorry, Jeff. I need her.
Will, can I grab you
for a second?
Let's talk later?
Yeah.
I spoke to the parents
together and independently.
And?
I don't like the stepdad
for the guy.
He offered
to give a polygraph
and submit his DNA.
Offenders don't usually
behave that way.
Any other leads?
Uh, Allison's
comprehensive tox screen
detected trace amounts
of triazolam in her blood.
That's a benzo, right?
Yeah, a sedative hypnotic
with amnestic properties.
The stepdad's an accountant.
I don't see him
getting his hands on that.
Unless maybe
he was prescribed it.
I mean, it is sometimes
used for insomnia.
Yeah, it definitely
puts you out.
The hospital uses it
mostly to treat
patient anxiety,
usually before procedures,
MRI scans, things like that.
So, she could've
gotten it here.
Did you give it to her
before the CT scan?
No.
Another doctor then, maybe.
Did the mom mention
any other recent
medical issues?
No. Nothing.
Other than the symptoms
that brought her in today.
Braces. Allison did
just get her braces on.
Dentists also sometimes
use triazolam.
After you pass,
you'll immediately
be taken into the OR,
where your organs
and tissues
will be recovered.
When that happens,
will it hurt?
No.
The bleeding in your brain
will starve it of oxygen.
You'll lose consciousness,
and then you'll shut down.
I'll be dead.
Your brain will be.
But your body
will still be alive.
But you won't be able
to control your breathing.
The organs still
need oxygen, though,
so we need...
You want to adjust
my advance directive.
Just the DNI.
We need your consent
to intubate you
once you lose consciousness
to protect the organs
until you get into the OR.
Do we have
your permission?
Yes. Mmm-hmm.
Okay.
Right there.
You think
I'm making a mistake.
Earlier this year,
I suffered a miscarriage.
My child never got
a chance at life.
I would give anything,
just for one moment.
You may not have
as much time as others,
but you still have some.
I'm sorry for your loss.
But my time is over.
The only positive is
my death can help
other people.
I know.
It looks like
I'm giving up.
But this is everything
I've been living for.
This is it.
Yeah.
Okay.
I'm ready.
Hanging meds
is a nurse's responsibility.
I will do it.
Making a break
for it, Keoni?
Really?
Seemed like
a good idea
at the time.
Figured Maggie was
sending over a shrink.
Oh, no. You get me.
I appreciate the red carpet,
but there's nothing
you can do.
In the back of my mind,
I knew it was diabetes.
I should've never
come to the hospital.
Because what?
Denial is a good solution?
You don't understand, Sharon.
My family, diabetes kills.
Now, it's my turn.
Your genetics
don't doom you, Keoni.
No? I eat healthy.
I don't drink the coladas
or the daiquiris
that I make at the bar.
I exercise. Yet, here I am.
I did what I was
supposed to do.
Yeah, and unfortunately,
people like you and I
have to do that and more
to break the cycle.
Yes, I have diabetes, too.
And I've lost family also.
I didn't know.
Many don't.
And it's not
because I'm hiding it,
but because I've got it
under control,
and I have for
the last 14 years.
There are people
in this hospital
who have to surrender.
You have an opportunity.
You better take it.
It's gonna be okay.
Dr. Reese?
If, um, you would like
to continue your residency
under a different attending,
I would
completely understand.
Hey, Keoni.
Wanted to say goodbye.
You good?
Work in progress,
but I'll get there.
Heard you're taking off
for the sunshine.
Oahu. You're
my last patient.
A native Hawaiian.
Must be fate.
You might be right.
Uh, Ms. Goodwin wanted you
to have your nail.
You know what?
I don't need it.
He ho'omaka hou 'ana.
"A new beginning."
You and me both.
Yeah, we'll just
have to wait.
Oh! This view.
Oh, how I've missed
this view.
Or just a view.
So, uh, dinner.
The pantry is
not really stocked.
We could go out.
Or order in.
It's probably for the best.
Just for tonight.
Look, I know you went
out on a limb.
So, thank you.
I'm just so happy
to be out of there.
Come here.
Doctor? Doctor?
What is it?
She's awake.
Breathing trial looks good.
I'm gonna take this
tube out, okay, Allison?
All right.
Ready?
It's okay.
Breathe, and there
you go. Okay.
Where am I?
You got sick, honey.
We had to take you
to the hospital.
How long am I gonna be here?
I don't want to miss
the school dance.
Aw, sweetie.
Hi, baby.
The orthodontist?
I was in the waiting room
the whole time,
just checking my emails.
When she came out,
she smiled,
showed me her braces,
didn't seem any different.
The police suspect
instead of nitrous,
he used triazolam.
It knocked her out,
ensured she had no memory
of the assault.
Sick bastard.
I know this is a lot
to process, but once
Allison is stronger,
the detective would like
to come in and ask her
a few questions.
Look, Ali just had
a brush with death,
and all she cares about
is if she can still go
to the Junior High Dance.
She's so innocent.
I don't want
to take that from her.
One day,
we'll have to,
but not today.
We understand.
We'll be back
in the morning
to check on her.
Good night.
Jeff's locker's
cleared out,
and he left.
Yeah, about an hour ago.
Did you know?
That he wanted
to move on from Med?
Yes. But I didn't know
that you didn't.
He left without
even saying goodbye?
That's not cool.
No. It was
the right play.
The conversation about
why wouldn't have done
either of us any good.
Slips out in the night,
and still somehow
he makes it chivalrous.
I'm happy for Jeff.
Fresh start.
Yeah.
Dr. Halstead.
Night, Maggie.
Nina and I
are gonna meet Jay
at Molly's.
You want to join?
Put this day behind us?
Uh...
Yeah. That sounds great.
Uh, I just... I have to
do something first,
so I'll meet
you guys there.
Okay.
Gary's organ recovery
went well.
A lot of lives
are being saved tonight.
Just wish it felt
more like a win.
So much
for white butterflies.
I think we make
our own luck, anyway.
I should get back
to the ED.
Yeah. Yeah.
I'll see you tomorrow.
So, then the guy says,
"If we would've
done it my way,
"we could've
walked out of here."
Oh...
That's really
horrible, Jay.
Who told you that one?
Dad.
I should've known.
Come on.
Of course.
He's disgusting.
Whoa.
Hey.
Wow.
Big change.
Yeah. I, um, felt like
I needed something new.
Looks really nice.
Thank you.
Yeah, it looks great.
I like it.
Thanks. I'm glad.
Well, we all like it.
What are you
having to drink?
Oh, I will, um...
I'll take a beer.
Four shots of tequila.
Got it.
Yes, please.
Babe?
Robin?
No!
Robin, look at me. Robin.
Ah! God!
Robin! Robin!
No, no, no, no, no!
No, no, no. Please.
Robin, open the door.
Open the door.
Please open the door.
Please open the...
Open the door!
Robin, please.
Please open the door.
Get away from me!
Please! Robin!
No, no, no, no, no!
Robin, please.
No!
Come on!