I came in with
this patient and I'd like
to see it through.
I got a team, thanks.
Hey, April.
You saved his life.
Pretty good for a nurse.
Should've gone
to med school.
We have to stick
with the playbook.
Or we try
something else.
You have something
better in mind.
How do we sit here
and not even try?
I'm with you.
Charge. Clear.
Let's give it a minute.
Going behind my back,
throwing up Hail Marys.
But you and I
have a problem.
Dr. Marcel,
I've got this new device.
Promoting your
products for unapproved uses?
It could've worked.
This is far beyond
the bounds of
professional conduct.
I started seeing
someone new.
Dr. Marcel.
You haven't introduced him
to Owen yet, have you?
Where is all this
coming from?
It was pitch black.
I couldn't see my hand
in front of my face.
So, here I am,
moving slowly, cautious,
skimming my flashlight
across the water,
when there he is.
You do remember that
I have a heart condition?
Oh, in that moment,
I did too.
He was big,
terrifying big.
Right? But I was
gonna get him.
Oh, dear me,
you went in closer?
Oh, I had to.
All or nothing.
So, I eased in,
lined him up,
then, pop! Got him.
Ah.
Look at this.
Oh, wow!
Look at that.
That's amazing.
No, it's like,
he's right there.
Right?
Yeah. Wow!
Hey.
Owen tucked in?
Yes.
Fell asleep before
the door got closed.
What'd I miss?
I asked Crockett
about his hobbies
and he said photography.
Yes. We were about,
what, five minutes
into our first dinner,
before you pulled
that story out,
and showed me the picture?
Yeah, I think it was
his move to try
and impress me. Mmm-hmm.
Busted.
But here we are,
many dinners later.
Mmm.
Mission accomplished.
So,
Crockett...
Mmm-hmm.
...I know that you
are a surgeon
and have an eye
for reptiles.
What else?
Any siblings?
Yeah, a younger sister.
Lives in Baton Rouge.
Mmm-hmm.
And your parents?
Natalie tells me
that they emigrated
from Iran.
So, does that mean
that your family is Muslim?
No. We're actually
Zoroastrian.
Zoroastrian?
I'm sorry... I...
Yeah, it dates back
to ancient Persia.
Three main pillars,
"good thoughts, good words,
good deeds."
Mmm.
Not always so easy.
That's very interesting.
Yeah.
I had no idea.
Does anyone want
some coffee?
Yeah, I'll take some.
Great.
Mom, tea?
Yes, sweetheart,
thank you.
Okay. I'll be
right back.
Sure.
Very nice.
Is that a new suit?
You wanna tell me
what's going on?
Just got the new
pharma rep rules.
Re-sterilization of
proprietary equipment?
In-house device review?
Lots of red tape.
It's just some adjustments,
so all the reps
are on the same page.
We need to make sure
no one's overstepping.
This is about Dr. Marcel
and me last week, isn't it?
Indirectly, Michael, yes.
Ma, I am not the only
red hat who has pitched
a device off-label.
I'm aware of that.
Then why's this
feel personal?
This wasn't intentional.
The updates are solely
to protect the hospital.
Sounds like
the company line.
Michael. Michael.
Uh-oh.
Michael and I...
It's been rocky
the last few weeks.
Parenthood,
a life sentence, right?
Oh, you telling me?
Wanna grab a coffee?
I don't have time.
Maybe later?
Yeah.
Five courses?
Yeah. Website says they'll
send all the ingredients.
We just prepare it.
Okay, I'm in.
This weekend?
I know, I know.
I'm late by 33 seconds.
I was just gonna say
good morning.
But I guess you are late.
Meet up for lunch?
Sounds good.
Still waiting to hear back
on that invitation
to play Chess.
Beginning to think
that you're dodging me.
No. Long days.
Time my shift ends,
I don't have the brain power.
Maybe play Will.
Tried.
It didn't go well.
He's a Checkers guy.
Anyway, offer's out there.
Dr. Choi, incoming.
Treatment Three.
Courtney?
Montez Price, 21.
Pro tennis player.
Hitting partner
accidentally drilled him
in the chest
with a tennis ball.
Trainer said
he was unresponsive
and pulseless.
Grabbed an AED
and shocked him once.
When we got there,
he was awake
and in sinus rhythm.
Tested negative
for COVID in the ambo.
Get ready
to transfer, huh?
Everybody, ready?
One, two, three.
Vitals stable. BP 120/82,
heart rate 78.
Heart is good,
regular rate and rhythm.
Let's get a CBC, BMP,
cardiac labs, a 12-lead EKG
and a chest X-ray.
Hey, Montez?
I'm Dr. Choi.
Can you hear me?
Chest hurts. Did I have
a heart attack?
No. Your rhythm on monitor
looks good.
It was likely
an episode of what's
called commotio cordis.
The blow from the ball
disrupted your
heart rhythm,
caused it to stop beating.
But it's all better now?
Yeah.
The impact caused it.
It's not your heart.
But it still feels funny.
"Funny"? Funny how?
Hey, Montez? Montez?
BP's dropping, 72/40.
Heart rate's spiking, 180.
He's in narrow complex v-tach.
Connect the pads
to cardiovert.
It's synced.
Clear. Hit it.
BP's back up, 120/70,
but heart rate's
still high, 110.
Bolus 150 milligrams
of amio and hang a drip.
Before, his heart
wasn't beating at all.
Now, it's beating too fast.
What's going on?
Maybe you should
check her chart first,
before you waste my time
with this dumb question.
Morning, Dr. Lanik.
Maggie said you requested me
for the COVID ICU.
Yeah. One less person
for me to micromanage.
Almost sounds like
a compliment.
Anyway, thanks.
I've really missed...
Yeah, sure.
You good to go?
Always.
Counting on you.
Go suit up.
Dr. Halstead, you're
going to Baghdad.
Yeah.
Liam McIntyre,
65-year-old male.
COVID negative,
GCS 15, BP 100/70,
rate 120.
Suspected left shoulder
dislocation.
Okay. Mr. McIntyre?
I'm Dr. Halstead.
You know where you are?
Hospital.
All right. Let's get
ready to transfer.
On my count.
One, two, three.
Thank you.
Diminished breath sounds
left side.
Kathleen, we're
gonna need an X-ray.
Any pain
where I touch?
No.
Okay. Chin up.
Down, left, right.
Any pain?
Good. C-spine's clear.
Mr. McIntyre?
Liam? You with me?
I'm fine.
Just a little rattled.
X-ray's up.
Everybody get back.
Yep. Small amount
of fluid left chest.
Left shoulder dislocated.
Fifty of fentanyl,
two of Versed.
Maggie.
Yep.
Counter-traction.
All right, Mr. McIntyre.
I'm gonna put this
around your arm.
Okay.
This is gonna hurt.
I'm gonna need you
to breathe, okay?
Okay.
All right.
Yep, all done.
Shoulder's in.
So sorry.
You're good, Liam.
Now, you just rest
for now. Okay?
Thanks.
Draw up trauma labs.
Yeah.
But did you catch how
he keeps on looking
into the corner of the room?
Yeah, it's weird.
No evidence of
head trauma, though.
He's doing it again.
Remember our trip to Tahoe?
I was in a cast for weeks.
But there's
no one else there.
Yeah, do me a favor.
Yeah,
contact Dr. Charles.
Done.
Thanks.
Hey.
I wanted to apologize
about last night. My mom...
No. No apology necessary.
Look, I grew up
in the Bible Belt.
You were either
Catholic, Methodist,
or Southern Baptist.
Not different, you know?
I'm... So, I'm used to it.
Nat, Crockett,
patient in Treatment Four,
her name is Lisa Holtzman.
Okay.
Thanks, Mags.
All right.
Hi, Lisa, I'm Dr. Manning.
This is Dr. Marcel.
Hey.
Belly radiating.
"Radiating"? Not a lay term.
You a doctor?
No, professional patient.
You mind
if I lift your gown?
No.
Okay.
Scars on your abdomen,
laparoscopic ports?
Appendix, gallbladder,
all gone.
I'm gonna...
Fullness in
the pelvis.
We're gonna do
an ultrasound, okay?
Okay.
Can't see anything.
Bladder's huge
and in the way.
Lisa, when's the last time
you urinated?
I don't know.
Yesterday, I think.
Pain could be coming from
urinary retention. Foley.
We're gonna
drain your bladder.
Okay.
It should help ease
the pain, okay?
We'll get you some
meds too, all right?
My bag.
Grab what's inside.
What is all this?
My medical records.
Hey, Montez,
how you feeling?
Exhausted. And then
there's all this.
Your heart's
still beating irregularly.
Too fast. I'm trying
to get a read on why.
Your vitals are fine.
EKG and echo
were both normal.
So, you're saying
I'm healthy?
No, the chart is,
but it's wrong.
The heart of
a 21-year-old pro athlete
should not spontaneously
go into a-fib.
This can't be it.
I'm too close.
My father loved tennis.
I was, maybe four,
he'd toss me balls,
pretend it was the US Open.
He'd say, "One day, Montez.
Arthur Ash Stadium."
He died when
I was seven.
Been training
for the Open ever since,
and now, I'm inches away.
I need to play
in that tournament.
I'll keep looking,
figure this out.
Seriously? Damn it!
Put pressure,
lean your head forward.
Ice pack.
I got it. I got it.
Happens when I'm stressed.
It'll stop.
What the hell, Sharon?
Ms. Goodwin, I'm so sorry.
That's all right, Cheryl,
I always have time
for our COO.
My phone has been
ringing off the hook
this morning.
Angry reps.
Your unilateral changes
to our red hat protocols,
they're trouble.
I have to do what's best
for the hospital, Gwen,
which means reducing
liabilities wherever they are.
Our relationship
with pharma and biotech,
they help keep the lights on.
If Med is suddenly
difficult to work with,
they move to East Mercy,
we lose funding.
This is our house.
They can play by our rules.
Not these.
I'm shutting them down.
Three.
Good.
Mind me asking
where you were
headed this morning
when you had
your accident?
Nowhere, really.
Four.
Right.
Just out running errands?
Just driving. Was cooped up
for over a year.
But now,
that I'm finally vaccinated,
I'll take any excuse
I can to leave the house.
I hear that.
Who ever thought
we'd actually be
looking forward
to picking up
our dry cleaning, right?
No fingers yet?
Now, I see it. Two.
Okay. Okay, good.
So, Liam, tell me, uh,
what's in the corner?
What? No one.
Wait, is it a person?
It's my wife. Terri.
Oh.
Okay.
She died
three weeks into lockdown.
Aneurysm.
I'm very sorry
to hear that.
We were actually
looking forward
to being quarantined.
Cook all those recipes
we never had time for.
And then,
she was just gone.
Look,
I know she's dead,
but I swear,
she's right there.
You know what?
I believe you.
Tell me, how long roughly
have you been seeing her?
A few months.
I know my mind
is playing tricks on me,
but I don't care.
Losing Terri
was devastating.
So, having her back,
even like this,
it's salvation.
You know,
I actually lost my wife
not that long ago.
So, trust me, I get it.
Look, I'm going to
have a quick chat
with Dr. Halstead.
And then, I'll be back.
All right?
Okay.
So, what do you think?
Dementia?
No. He's... You know,
he's lucid, he's oriented.
His peripheral vision
is virtually nonexistent
on the right side
in both eyes, all right?
And that blind spot
is exactly where
he's seeing his dead wife.
So, she's a visual
hallucination.
Right. I think
we're looking at
Charles Bonnet syndrome.
Right? Where the brain
responds to visual loss
by filling in the blanks.
But here's the thing,
I'm not seeing
any evidence of
standard signs of
vision loss, which makes
me think that we're...
I don't know, we might be
looking at some deeper
brain or eye issue.
I'll order an MRI.
Thank you.
Yep.
Lisa, hi.
So, we got your initial
lab results back.
And it was normal,
all across the board.
Ugh.
Sorry, normal's
usually good news.
I let myself
get my hopes up,
shouldn't have done that.
Volume seven
of my 16-year war
with abdominal pain.
All I know, it's not IBS.
Or endometriosis.
Or interstitial cystitis.
Kidney stones. Pancreatitis.
Bowel obstruction.
It hurts the worst right here.
There has to be a reason.
But I have been
poked, prodded,
scanned, cut open,
and no one ever
finds anything!
Lisa, I can't even
imagine your frustration.
Look, I don't need sympathy.
I need you to fix me.
We'll do our best.
Unfortunately,
that does require
more pokes, prods,
X-rays, scans.
Have at it.
Okay.
Hello, Miss Caine,
I'm April.
What happened
to your cannula?
Pulled it out.
Who knows what's really in it.
You don't need
the space suit.
One day. But for now,
it's a precaution we take
in the COVID ICU.
I don't have coronavirus.
No?
It's not real. Big scam.
Okay, but I can see
you are having
trouble breathing.
It's just the flu.
Get it every year.
Flu or not,
a little extra oxygen
might help you feel
more comfortable.
What do you say,
wanna give the cannula
another shot?
Fine.
Okay.
I saw him play,
couple of months ago.
On TV, that is.
You're a tennis fan?
I was that night.
Couldn't sleep.
His match was the only show
that was on at 2:00 a.m.
Hell of a player.
Is he gonna be okay?
Not sure. A-fib problem,
don't know why.
I'm a cardiologist,
can I help?
Thanks, but technically,
you're limited
to seeing patients
who're part of your
clinical trial.
Totally understand.
I cauterized
the active bleeders.
Should help
stem the tide.
Kid keeps asking me
if his career is over.
I didn't know what to say.
Neither do I.
Thanks.
Dr. Virani?
I reconsidered.
I'll send you the chart.
Hey.
What's this?
That is a Persian
spice set.
Gift from your mom.
Oh.
Even comes
with an array
of popular recipes.
Oh, this is awkward.
I'm Iranian.
We love to cook.
It's a wonderful gift,
thoughtful.
Never got a gesture like that
from my ex in-laws.
What do you mean?
A Persian,
Zoroastrian son-in-law
is not what they had
in mind for their
Southern belle.
From the little
I know about Claire,
you two seem
pretty different, so...
Yeah, opposites attract,
I guess.
Didn't keep us
together, though.
Uh, is that Lisa's
latest test results?
Yes, her labs
are all normal.
Same with the KUB
and trans-vaginal
ultrasound.
Next step is a CT.
I'll squeeze that into
my locker and meet
you upstairs. All right?
Sharon, you know the ED's
hurting for staffing.
Mmm-hmm.
But at the same time,
with the pandemic,
nursing and med school
enrollments have surged.
A silver lining.
Mmm-hmm.
I was thinking we expand
the ED training programs
to match demand.
Puts Med on the map
and we get helping hands.
Win-win.
I like it.
Write a proposal.
All right.
What's up?
I updated Med's protocols
for the pharma reps,
and Gwen's undoing them,
playing hero in the process.
And now,
all the reps owe her one.
No doubt, she'll enjoy
using that against me.
My smile
convincing enough?
Very professional.
Mmm.
Grand mal seizure.
Five of Ativan.
Yep.
Mr. McIntyre,
you just had a seizure.
Terri?
Terri! Terri,
where are you?
Terri? Oh, there you are.
There you are.
Thank God.
A tumor?
In your brain's vision center,
the left occipital lobe.
It's caused your seizure
and it's safe to assume
an earlier one led
to your car accident.
Vision center, the...
That's also why...
That's right.
The tumor created
a blind spot, right?
And in order to make sense
of that void,
your brain has been
filling it in with
images of your wife.
Now, Liam,
I know "brain tumor"
can sound overwhelming,
but yours
is treatable.
Surgery.
Right.
It'll eliminate the risk
of another seizure
and it'll correct
your peripheral
vision loss.
But I'd lose my wife.
She'd disappear.
Yeah. I mean,
you would no longer see
those images of her.
I don't want the operation.
Mr. McIntyre,
without the surgery,
you will have more seizures.
And they'll be more severe.
You could even lose
your eyesight entirely.
When Terri died,
I was lost.
But now, it's like
I've got her back again.
She's everything to me.
You know that
I understand
how grateful you are
to have Terri
back in your life,
but another seizure,
probably put you
into a coma.
It would kill you.
Since Terri died, I haven't
really been living, anyway.
I wanna go home.
Mr. McIntyre,
I can't in good conscience,
discharge you
without a treatment plan.
I'll sign whatever I have to.
I just wanna be with my wife.
You know,
we will get the
paperwork going. Okay?
Thank you, Liam.
We're not letting him
go home.
I agree.
Okay. Psych hold, then?
Will, he's not mentally ill.
He's grieving.
I mean, we're asking him
to say goodbye to his wife,
you know? Again.
So, what's our play?
Honestly,
I don't know.
Hey, buy me a little time?
Yeah, I can slow-roll
his AMA paperwork.
Thank you.
All right.
You brought Dr. Virani in
on your case.
Needed a consult.
Usually, we call
Cardiology for consults.
No one upstairs has
London Heart Hospital
on their résumé.
So, I'm sure the resident
Cardiology would've sent down
will understand.
Dr. Lanik? Gina Caine,
in Three...
Oh. Miss "COVID is a hoax"?
I upped her high flow O2
and RT is ready to convert
to a BiPAP,
but it's just delaying
the inevitable.
She'll need to be intubated.
Yeah, but is she
gonna give consent?
It's been tough just
keeping her on the cannula,
so, it's doubtful.
You better change her mind.
It looks like
there's mildly distended
loops of small bowel,
could be
a partial obstruction.
I'm not sure.
If it were an obstruction,
I'd expect the bowel
to be a lot more
dilated than it is.
So, what? We just
agree to disagree?
That doesn't help her.
Damn it. I know
something's causing
her pain. It's in there.
Just don't know
what it is,
can't see it.
Uh, Cara,
build the scan into
a hi-res 3D rendering.
Focus on the left flank,
where her pain is the worst.
Well, how about that.
Renal vein is compressed.
And it looks like it's
causing significant left-sided
venous congestion.
That isn't just painful.
It's excruciating.
Same drill as before.
Set up to cardiovert,
then 200 milligrams
of amio followed
by a drip.
A-fib with RVR,
replay on his intake.
Synced.
Clear. Hit it.
BP is coming
back up, 122/73.
Heart rate
settling, 140.
Still too high.
Add an esmolol drip.
It happened again?
My heart?
Yeah.
Doesn't make sense.
His heart's beating
irregularly,
but there's no evidence
anything is actually
wrong with it.
I looked at his chart,
the only other anomaly
is the nosebleed.
You think the nosebleed's
connected, then?
Could be.
I once treated a guy
who slipped in the shower
and dislocated his shoulder.
Random accident, right?
Turns out, he had
undiagnosed celiac disease.
A poor B12 absorption
leads to anemia...
Leads to weakness
in his feet, leads to
falling in the shower.
Nothing random about it.
Trini, repeat CBC,
BMP, cardiac labs,
echo, leave the EKG.
We're starting over.
This is the reason?
The renal vein
is being compressed?
It's called
nutcracker syndrome,
because the pain
feels like
you're being squeezed
by a nutcracker.
All this time,
right there.
How'd all the other
doctors miss it?
It hides. Only get
to it by ruling out
everything else first.
I'm relieved to finally have
an answer, but my pain,
it's more than a squeeze.
I'm being crushed
by a car compactor.
Yes, we suspect
a compounding issue,
a second disorder
affecting the ureter.
Loin pain
hematuria syndrome.
So, misery on top of agony?
What's the fix?
Surgery, with two options.
First is a renal vein
transposition.
It'll relieve
the nutcracker syndrome.
But unfortunately,
it may not do anything
for the loin pain.
Option two?
Embolize the renal artery.
This will help
with the loin pain,
but may aggravate
the nutcracker.
So, let's do both.
The thing is,
you can't do both.
Together, they would
put too much stress
on the kidney's blood supply.
The organ would fail.
Then, no. To both options.
Neither ends my pain,
so, what's the point?
Less pain could
make a huge difference
in your life.
Zero pain is something.
Everything else is
just history repeating itself.
Procedure after procedure,
all of them colossal failures.
I can't take another one.
I will lose my mind.
I am always going
to live in pain.
It's just time
that I accept that.
Hey. If you're busy,
I could come back later.
Oh, hell no.
This case had me
going in circles.
Thank you very much.
You're welcome.
So, your day
going any better?
No, in fact,
it fell off a cliff.
Wouldn't have anything
to do with these
updated protocols
I've been hearing
so much about?
The reps are angry with me.
Defcon 1 with Gwen
because I got
the board involved.
And then
there's Michael,
who thinks these protocols
are solely because of him.
And you don't think
there's even a tiny bit
of truth to that?
Really? You, too?
If it were any other rep
at the center of this thing,
you think it would've
gotten quite this far?
Probably not.
He's my son, Daniel.
When he started
working here,
I was so excited, but...
I just don't know how,
eventually, that doesn't
get complicated.
Yeah.
Ain't that the truth.
Well,
I've got a hard decision
to make.
I'm here if you need me.
Thanks.
Montez's repeat labs
all good,
same for the repeat echo.
His heart's now
beating normally,
he's back in sinus rhythm.
Yeah, but still
no clue as to why
it started beating
irregularly, or now,
why it stopped.
Dr. Choi, Dr. Virani,
it's Montez.
What's happening?
Coughing up blood, that's
not a nasal or a cardiac
problem, it's a lung issue.
Yeah. They sound junky.
We need another chest X-ray.
I'm falling apart!
Hey. Just hang
in there, Montez.
X-ray up.
Bottom of the right lung
is partially whited out.
Two prior chest X-rays,
that wasn't there.
No, but it is now.
We need a CT.
Hey.
Got your text.
All I've been hitting
are dead ends.
You got something?
Yeah. Think so.
Kidney is at
the center of Lisa's
pain problems. Right?
There's not enough space
for the blood and urine
to flow smoothly.
So, what if I were
to move it to a place
where there is?
That's a massive
undertaking.
If you're willing
to go that far,
why not just remove
the kidney altogether?
Less risk of complications.
Possibly. But there'd be
a huge trade off,
she'd be losing
a perfectly healthy organ.
I mean, look, if there were
a better option, I'd be
all over it. I'm just...
I'm not seeing one.
A kidney transplant?
A kidney autotransplant.
It's more like
a relocation.
The new positioning
decompresses the renal vein,
so, there's no more pressure
on the ureter.
So, it both addresses
the nutcracker
and the loin pain.
I've been let down
so many times,
you're sure this will work?
The theory is sound.
Look, I believe
it will work.
Okay. I'll hope.
Okay.
Miss Caine,
you need to be intubated.
No tubes. You put people
on that machine,
and never take them off.
It's part of the scam,
so they can bill you forever.
Just give me more oxygen.
That won't work.
COVID attacks your...
It's not COVID!
Gina. Okay. I'm not
supposed to say this,
but you're right.
COVID is a hoax.
It is. I know it is.
About time you admit it.
I couldn't say anything
before because I don't
wanna get fired.
Can't go against
the hospital machine.
Exactly.
Please, just agree
to be intubated.
Let me help you
get past this flu,
and then we can
talk about the truth.
Okay.
All right.
Dr. Lanik?
Intubation in Three.
Let me suit up.
Copy.
No, no, no,
no, no. Gina?
Dr. Lanik!
She's crashing! No pulse!
What do we got?
Dr. Lanik?
Bag her.
I'm on it.
Sats are dropping.
What happened?
She went into PEA.
All right.
Milligram of epi.
Already in.
What? You pushed meds
on your own?
You weren't gonna
make it in time.
You can't do that
without a doctor's order.
Got a pulse.
Sinus rhythm.
Sats are still
terrible, though.
Kit's ready.
Sux and etomidate?
Give me the tube
and the blade.
Paperwork's ready.
It's now or never.
I'm gonna leave.
You can't stop me.
Liam, I was just
hoping that you
would indulge me
with one more minute
of your time
before we signed you out.
Okay. What is it?
Well,
I told you about my wife.
About CeCe and how
she had recently
passed away.
Um, whenever I had
a big decision to make,
I mean, she was just
always there. Right?
And she made me
feel safe that way.
Was it the same
for you and Terri?
Yeah.
Mmm.
So, I guess
my question is,
how do you think
that Terri would feel?
I mean,
about the surgery?
What do you think
that she would
want you to do?
Liam, I can see the way
that you're looking at her.
And I'm guessing that
she is looking back at you
the same way.
She loved me.
So,
honor that.
Honor that love.
She would want me
to have the surgery.
Yeah. I think so, too.
Look at that,
bottom of the right lung.
You were right.
Everything's connected.
It's an arteriovenous
malformation, AVM.
An abnormal tangle
of blood vessels.
They tear easily,
results in bleeding.
The blood I was
coughing up.
Yeah.
And for some,
AVMs are a symptom
of a genetic disease called
Hereditary Hemorrhagic
Telangiectasia, HHT.
The hallmark of HHT
is frequent nosebleeds.
Also, recently,
research shows
that HHT patients
have a predilection
for a-fib.
These initials, AVM,
HHT, could I die?
No.
The conditions
are treatable.
Surgery, embolization,
medication.
I'm gonna admit you
and figure out
what the best option is.
And my career?
Can I still compete
when I get out of here?
Nosebleeds may continue
to be an issue,
but today should be
the last time you see
yourself in hospital.
Get you back on the court,
US Open awaits.
April!
So, Lanik
just went on a rant.
He was so pissed,
I could barely
understand him.
But I did manage
to make out
"super reckless"
and a threat to fire you.
What happened?
I pushed meds
without his order.
What? What were
you thinking?
The patient was coding.
Lanik was still suiting up.
What was I supposed
to do? Let her die?
Of course not.
But does it mean...
He told me to
solve the problem.
What would
you have done?
April, we are nurses.
Just because
we know what to do,
it doesn't mean
we have the authority
to do it.
I did
and I saved her life.
Hey! Great work today,
appreciate the help.
I really enjoyed
the challenge.
Been a while since
I've been on the
detective side of a case.
If you ever
need me again, I'm in.
Deal.
And, uh, next time,
I won't hesitate.
Truth is, I was
actually deflecting.
I know you and Will are close.
Just didn't want to overstep.
If it helps, I find nothing
untoward with me seeing Will
and playing Chess with you.
Good to know.
So, now that
that's settled,
how much brain power
do you have left today?
Game on.
All right.
Hey.
So, Lisa's gonna
be sore for a while
from the procedure,
but her pain,
no more.
That is fantastic.
I was worried she was
gonna have to add us
to her list of failures.
Yeah, I was, too.
But we pulled it off.
We're a good team.
Yeah, I hope so.
Oh. A wistful tone
after a huge win?
What's going on?
No, I just, um...
You know, we broke
Lisa's cycle of pain,
and put her on a new path,
and I guess,
I'm just wondering
if you broke yours, too.
I'm not following.
I mean,
you said this afternoon
that opposites attract,
and they do.
They don't always
stay together.
Yeah.
You know, Manning?
The moment
you came into my life,
my history
became just that, history.
I love you, Natalie.
I love you, too.
Liam. Heard the surgery
went really well.
How you doing?
How're you feeling?
Lonely.
She's gone for good now.
You think so?
I mean, for myself, anyway,
I feel CeCe's presence
all the time.
Honestly, I don't know
if they ever really leave us.
I knew it.
No. No,
you did not know that.
Michael.
Can we not, Mom?
Son, let me talk to you.
Give me a minute.
Come here.
I just wanted to let you know
the board is backing out
my protocol changes.
There'll be
a new memo tomorrow.
And you were right,
some of my motive
was personal.
Okay.
You've got my attention.
Sit with me a minute?
You know, I always
want you to succeed.
But this hospital
is my responsibility.
And when those two things
don't line up,
that's a problem.
I know.
And that's
not all on you.
My ambitions,
they're big.
I push.
So, when management
pushes back,
it stings.
Yeah.
But you're also my mom.
It just hits closer to home.
Yeah.
And that's why
I've decided to leave Med.
Really?
I've been thinking
about it for a while.
You cast a long shadow.
About time I get out
from under it.
I raised you right.
I think you're making
the right decision.
I want to stay
in the city.
Kender has a presence
at Northwestern.
That's what
I've put up for.
Well, they'll be lucky
to have you.
Oh, thanks, Mom.
And I'm gonna miss
seeing you every day.
I'm staying in Chicago.