Backaches, jaw pain, nausea.
Hey. Did you eat?
Amelia got dinner.
It's nothing special.
Just a little pasta
from our regular place.
Sit down. I'll grab
you a plate. I got it.
In men, these things are probably
exactly what they seem like.
Amelia's back.
What's that supposed to mean?
You leave all the doors
open, everywhere, all the time.
What? Hey. Uh,
try the artichoke.
Bathroom doors, cabinets,
everything open all the time.
But in women, they're all
symptoms of a heart attack.
Hey, Mer, do you want some wine?
Unless that's not...
Is that... It's fine.
Okay. You invited me back.
It's fine. Just close a
thing once in a while.
Mer, if you've changed your
mind, say the word. I can go.
No, it's fine.
Sometimes the symptom
is actually hiding what's
going on underneath.
So which resident are
you guys nominating
for the Preminger
Research Grant?
I'm just gonna
go to bed. Me, too.
We were just sitting
down together. Tired.
Early morning.
It's all in the way
it presents itself.
"The winner of the grant is
awarded one full research year
"in residence at the
Preminger Research Center.
"Each attending will
nominate one candidate
"and submit them to
the chief of surgery,
"who will then review and
make a decision based on..."
Oh.
I didn't know I was
eligible to apply.
Yeah, it's open to
any resident any year.
You gonna apply? No.
I just got to Grey Sloan. I
can barely find the bathroom.
"Resourceful." Okay, do
you think that I should write
that I'm "resourceful"
or "inventive"?
Mmm. Put that you're both.
Put that you're annoying
when you think out loud.
Why are these spaces so small?
These spaces cannot
contain how awesome I am.
Okay.
Yes, this is gold. See?
I just won this thing.
You don't even need
an awesome application.
You have Shepherd
in your corner.
Oh, I did, until you
took over her service.
I didn't do it.
Webber's scramble did it. Sure.
Well, when you apply next year,
Shepherd will have your back.
And Grey and Torres.
You'll be set. Hmm.
Remember when they
all hated you? Vividly.
Okay, I'm done. Me, too.
Press submit on three?
One, two, three.
I did not meddle!
You meddled. You are a meddler.
He is the father of that baby.
Suing his ex-wife for fraud
is no way to be a father.
That hussy wouldn't be an ex-wife if
she hadn't signed those divorce papers
without disclosing
her pregnancy. Hussy?
This is April Kepner
we're talking about.
And this is my grandchild
that we're talking about
that I won't get to see unless
Jackson overturns that divorce
and gets his
parental rights back!
Meddler.
You better stop saying that.
I'll say what I want.
I am trying to help my son.
You are a meddler, a busybody,
a helicopter mama, a
nosy Nellie, a buttinsky!
That is trash talk!
All up in the bug juice.
You don't know
the flavor, woman.
We said no trash
talk in the bedroom.
We said no work
Just for the record, I
am right. You are wrong.
Meddler.
I still think I should
wait until next year
to apply for the grant.
Why? You're eligible now.
Technically, but they
always give the grant
to a senior resident anyway.
Except for when they don't.
So you think I should try?
Look, if this is what you
want, then sure, apply.
It's just I'm finally
getting settled in here.
I have friends.
I just met Sofia.
I don't want to run across
the country for a year.
I can wait. I want to be here.
Well, I can accept that.
So you are 14.
Um...
Are your parents
here? Who brought you?
I took the bus.
Is this gonna take long? I have
to get back for my history test.
Um, well, I mean, it just
kind of sounds like a cold.
I know, but it's just...
My stomach just
hurts when I cough
or sneeze or move sometimes.
Okay, let's take a look.
Can you lean back?
Can you lift up
your shirt for me?
Also, I'm pregnant.
Okay, you buried the lede there.
Page OB. Okay.
I don't understand.
You haven't called back any of the
family law attorneys I recommended.
Ma, I've really got to prep
this nasal reconstruction.
Oh. Well, we have
choices. Money is no object.
My baby needs a lawyer,
and I'm gonna get you the best.
Ma, I'm done having
this conversation.
Reynolds is hard to
get a sit-down with,
but you're an Avery, and that
ought to get us a phone call.
I'm not sure I want
to Avery this yet.
Oh. Yes, you do you
want to Avery this.
Mother!
April has the
power, all the power.
You better get some power.
So there is an organ
procurement at Overbrook?
Yes, heart and liver.
Patient is getting critical.
I am so glad, not about the
patient, about the procurement.
It is the perfect excuse to
ditch Bailey's budget meeting.
I want to ditch Bailey's
budget meeting.
I think we got it covered.
Oh. Come on, Owen.
It's a budget meeting.
Okay, fine. I'll meet you
in the ambulance bay in 10.
DeLuca's getting the coolers.
We're... What are you doing?
DeLuca's coming?
Sorry.
Finish up a consult.
What are you doing here?
Pierce asked me to cover
a heart recovery with Grey.
It's my heart recovery,
and you're making us late.
Well, I got here
as soon as I could.
What happened to Pierce?
Said she had a budget meeting.
She didn't want to ride with
DeLuca. Why isn't DeLuca here?
Why am I here? All right.
We're good. Let's move.
How far along are you?
I think, like, six months.
Who's your doctor?
You?
Have you been getting
any prenatal care at all?
I am her mother. Jennifer.
Oh, my God. That's my mom.
What is she doing
here? You called her?
No. No, I didn't,
but... She can't know!
What? She doesn't
know I'm pregnant.
You can't tell her,
please. I won't.
Promise. Yes, I promise.
Jenny, um, I can help
you talk to your mom.
No, you can't. She'll freak out.
You're six months pregnant.
She's gonna find out soon.
Why not tell her so
that she can help you?
Because this is not what we do.
That's what she says any time I
forget to do the dishes or get a B.
"This is not what we do, Jenny."
I'm not supposed to even
have a boyfriend, so this would...
Ow.
Dr. Kepner, this is...
Jennifer? What
are you doing here?
Did you track my phone again?
Yes, I tracked your phone again.
Mom, that is so invasive.
I pay for the phone, I
get to know where it is.
Same goes for you.
It's the middle
of the school day.
Why are you even
tracking me right now?
Well, you're not
in school, are you?
This is not what we do, Jenny.
Hi. Jenny, I'm Dr. Robbins.
I hear that you're having a
little... A little abdominal pain.
And Dr. Robbins is
an abdominal doctor,
so we're gonna take Jenny
up to CT to get a closer look,
and we'll let you know as soon
as we get the results, all right?
Thank you.
Guess who's joining you on
Shepherd's DBS implantation.
Uh, can you get me up to
speed? Getting a little face time
in with Shepherd before
the meeting tonight?
I am the wind beneath her wings.
I just need to be sure
she remembers that.
Well, I've got
your back. Ladies.
Let's go.
Wait, wait, wait. Let me lead.
That's very nice.
Oh.
No, don't clap at that.
That was garbage.
Uh, Dr. Blake and
Dr. Shepherd and...
And who is this? Haven't
seen your face before.
It's a nice face.
This is Dr. Edwards.
God, why are all the
doctors in this hospital so hot?
Well, that's... Seriously,
it's like a condition
of employment here.
Let's talk about your brain.
Edwards, business time.
Kyle Diaz, 34.
Diagnosed two years ago
with relapsing and
remitting multiple sclerosis.
Increased symptoms recently.
How come you know
so much about me,
and I haven't even met you yet?
Symptoms include persistent
tremor in the right hand.
Yeah, this damn thing showed up
right as I was
landing a 13-city tour.
Only time I had bad timing.
I prayed for a long
time for this break.
I mean, this is... This is big.
Yeah, it's huge for me. I
mean, I'm the opening act.
The audience won't
be there to see me,
but I swear they'll
leave knowing my name.
And I have to kick ass, but I
can't, not with this wobbly hand.
Well, deep brain
stimulation has been proven
to help alleviate intractable
tremors like yours.
So when I wake up, maybe I
can show you how I really play.
The plan is to actually keep
you conscious while we operate,
using MRI images to target
the general area of concern.
Hmm.
Blake?
No, I figured we'd be using
intraoperative micro-recordings
to precisely locate the nucleus.
Exactly, and how will we know
when the procedure is working?
Having our patient
perform delicate motor skills
while we introduce
the electrodes.
In Kyle's case, he
will play the guitar.
Wait, so I'm... I'm
gonna play the guitar
while you are poking
around in my brain?
That way, we can know
exactly when we nail the tremor.
Well, it's impossible.
No, it's possible. You'll
be awake and able to play.
No, for you. I mean, I don't
know if you know what happens
when women hear me play.
Your hand is gonna
get a little shaky.
Well, I'll push through it.
And Blake and I will be
performing the operation.
Edwards, I need you with Kyle.
I'll be... Blake's assisting?
I need you to monitor the
tremor, let us know when we got it.
Well, it's gonna be
one hell of a first date.
Her mother really
doesn't know? Nope.
It's got to be a lot of
work, hiding it for this long.
Yeah, it is.
It's a hard thing to
keep under wraps.
Aren't we sort of obligated to
tell the mother she's pregnant?
I mean, if the
kid's in danger...
Legally, we're obligated not to
unless the patient gives us permission.
If it were my kid, I'd
want us to break that law.
Oh, Warren, what
do you see here?
Blood in the lesser sac.
Is that an aneurysm?
Yeah, splenic artery
aneurysm. What are the risks?
If it bursts, it could cause an
instant massive hemorrhage.
The patient and the baby
both could bleed to death.
Now can we tell the mother?
No. Yes.
Hmm.
Is that your name up there?
Seems that way. "Bowel
resection with Dr. Webber."
They say he's good.
Easy on the eyes, too.
Some men would send flowers.
Nasty-ass necrotic
bowel is nice, too.
Mmm-hmm. Complicated procedure.
Gives us time to talk,
and since we are at work,
no subject is off limits.
I'll see you in the
scrub room, Dr. Avery.
You can yammer on all you
want. Doesn't mean I have to listen.
So who do you like for
this Preminger thing?
You know, who I don't
work with is Edwards,
but Cristina really liked her.
Amelia loves her.
Why aren't we moving?
Bridge traffic. Amelia
moved back in, you know?
Did you know that? No.
She was asking about you.
Yeah, well, you can tell
her that I'm not an alcoholic
if that's what she's
worried about.
I don't think that's what
she was worried about.
I think she's one. That's
what she's worried about.
Shepherd?
Shepherd drinks. I
bought her one once.
When? Months ago. I didn't know.
You did that. What?
You did that to her? I
did what? I didn't know.
I asked her. She said yes. She
didn't tell me she's an alcoholic.
You did it! Hold on! Wait!
We have a job to do. The two
of you can kill each other later.
A bubble in my artery?
Did I hurt the baby?
No, no. It's so big that even a
sneeze could have made it bleed.
Yeah, and the good news is
that the bleeding has stopped,
but the splenic aneurysm
could burst at any moment.
Yeah, which would be very
dangerous for you and for your baby.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Jenny, listen, I can fix this.
I can operate and make
sure that it doesn't bleed.
Surgery? Uh-uh.
If we do surgery, my
mom will find out for sure.
Maybe she should. I mean, don't
you want your mom's help and...
No! She'll send me away or
make me give my baby away.
Can't you just give me some
pill to make it stay the way it is?
We can give it time. I keep
you under close observation,
and there's a chance that
it could resolve on its own.
Then let's do that. We'll wait.
Jenny, it's far less dangerous to
do something about it right now.
I think if your mom
had the information,
she would opt...
You said we can wait.
I want to wait.
Okay, then we wait.
The better option is surgery.
The only reason
she's choosing to wait
is to avoid telling her
mother that she's pregnant.
She has the right to tell
her mom when she's ready.
She's 14.
She needs her mom's
help to make this decision.
You're thinking like a mother
because you're about to be one,
but you're not.
You're not her mother.
We're her doctors.
What if it were Sofia?
April! We can't.
We can tell her about the splenic
bleed but not about the pregnancy.
She's just gonna put her
baby and herself at risk.
Jenny's the patient.
She has the final say.
It's the end of the discussion.
This day is already
on my nerves.
I've rounded on both
Grey and Torres' services.
I've finished their
post-op notes.
My beautiful, genius brain is
on fire. I'm gonna get this grant.
My beautiful, genius
brain is being wasted.
I've got to hold hands
with a hot rock star
while Blake assists
with his brain surgery.
Ooh. Wait. Back up.
No. No, don't.
He's hot, but he's nasty
hot, like in-your-face hot.
He keeps aggressively
eye-sexing me.
He's not my kind of
thing. It's a distraction.
Oh, God, I haven't
had sex in so long.
Oh. I had sex this morning.
I thought we were sharing.
The point is, Shepherd
needs to see me shine today,
and there is Blake
being all shiny, too.
I knew it. You
hate that Shepherd
is taking Blake under her wing.
Because it's my wing!
Blake has been on neuro
for, what, two weeks?
And she gets to scrub
in over me? Really?
Blake probably can't
even clip an aneurysm.
Stephanie... No, come
on! She's from Dillard.
All right, listen, I know
you don't want to, but...
No, you listen.
She sat across that table,
looked my son in the eye,
didn't say a damn thing
about the pregnancy,
treating him like he's
some inconvenience.
And he is the baby's
father. Well, that may be true,
but we should be
helping them through this.
What choice do we
have other than to fight?
A lawsuit, though?
If Jackson can make a case
that April committed fraud,
he's got a shot at getting
full custody of that baby.
If April's gonna fight
dirty, Jackson can, too.
This is about my
grandchild. Oh, really?
Because I don't
see a grandchild.
All I see are two
kids in trouble.
And they aren't your kids.
Maybe just keep your
opinions to yourself.
Understood.
But you're my wife,
and I think I should
be able to tell you
when you're making a wrong turn,
and this is a very wrong turn.
I can't believe we sat
in traffic for an hour.
You can just relax. We made it.
What are they doing? Are they
already recovering the heart?
No, no. Hunt, something's wrong.
Hey, what are you
doing to our heart?
Crapped the bed
about two minutes ago.
You guys are Grey Sloan?
What are you saying?
Lidocaine. It's in
V-fib. Arrhythmic.
We're trying to keep it pumping
to perfuse the other organs.
Okay, move aside. Let me see.
You told me this is a
good, healthy heart.
He became hyperkalemic.
We tried to reverse it with insulin.
Why is it fibrillating now?
Okay, Hunt, just let me work.
Charge it 20. SURGEON 2: Charge.
We have no heart,
we have no liver.
One's no good without the
other. They'll reallocate it.
Riggs? NATHAN: Clear.
Come on!
Come on! Come on, baby. Come on.
It's gone.
This heart's dead. I'm sorry.
We need to do the
calculations with MRI.
I need someone to go
supervise Kyle's head frame.
I can do it. Blake, go.
I was hoping to be
in the field, assisting.
I need you with
Kyle. He likes you.
He thinks I'm a
challenge, correctly.
Then challenge
him. He'll be calmer.
So the Preminger Grant
nomination is tonight.
Edwards,
I'm not gonna discuss a
confidential recommendation.
I know. I'm not asking. Mmm.
I'm just hoping you bear in
mind our significant history
when making your
recommendation. Edwards!
I'm not asking.
Edwards, look at me.
You and I are not
allowed to discuss
whether or not I will be singing
your praises to
Dr. Bailey tonight.
To do so would be
unprofessional, unethical,
and not at all cool, so I
am not going to discuss it.
Understood? Understood.
All right.
She said, "She's from Dillard,"
like it's a welding school.
And what'd you say?
Nothing. I just stood there.
Ouch.
I know. I know. I didn't have my
words. Why didn't I have my words?
Well, just say your words now.
Okay, okay. I thought
we were friends.
No, weak. Better words.
I know this place
can be competitive,
and that you can be an
insecure bitch sometimes,
but you would not be
talking behind my back
if you weren't scared to death
that somebody might give
you a run for your money.
And I might be from
Dillard, but I am here now!
I'm right behind you,
breathing down your neck,
and I am a dark freaking horse!
Drop the mic and walk away.
And I'm having sex tonight.
Hey.
I'm inviting all
you lovely people
over to the house
tonight for dinner.
Oh.
Like a... Like a dinner party.
We're not doing that again.
Just takeout. Whatever.
Just come over at
8:00, and I'll feed you.
But we have the nomination
meeting for the Preminger Grant.
Fine. 8:30.
Ben and Bailey will
be going home at 8:30.
I'm having great sex tonight.
I might be having sex tonight.
I mean, I don't know
yet. We don't really plan it.
You guys have to come.
Amelia just moved back in,
and Meredith and Amelia
need to ease into it, okay,
or it's gonna be... It'll be...
It's gonna start
as something small
that will snowball
into something big,
and there will be blood.
This thing is fragile.
But if you guys are
there, then it can stay nice.
Oh! Oh.
So you want us to
come to be a buffer?
Yes, thank you. Mmm-hmm.
Like a human shield? You
get it. So you'll be there?
Sex. God, no.
So for now, we wait to see
if your daughter's abdominal
bleed resolves on its own.
You think waiting
is the best option?
Well, it's what Jenny wants.
Jenny is 14.
When I was 14, I was
stealing street signs,
and getting knocked
up by my loser boyfriend,
so forgive me for not trusting a
14-year-old to make judgment calls.
I'm asking what you think.
I think that surgery
is the better option.
Then that's what we'll do.
Of course, you know, with
surgery, there are always risks.
Surgery would happen
when? Today or...
Actually, there
is one more thing.
Dr. Kepner. What is it?
What are you not telling me?
There is also the risk that
Jenny could lose her baby.
Her what?
Jenny is pregnant.
How long? Mom, listen...
How long?
I don't know, like, six
months or something.
Why would you tell her?
Look at me. Not them. Me.
How many times have I told
you, "Be careful, be smart"?
Not to end up like
me. How many times?
Yeah, Mom, like a million times
that I am your biggest,
stupidest mistake!
Sorry I messed
up your life so bad!
Jennifer, that is
not what I meant.
And I'm sorry I'm
screwing my life up, too.
Go ahead. I'm just
waiting for you to say it.
"This is not what we do, Jenny."
It's not.
You screwed this up.
She needed to
know all the risks.
No, she didn't. Yes, she did.
If she was gonna convince
Jenny to get that surgery, yes.
How's that going so far?
There's a risk either way.
God, Mom!
Are you done with your side?
I'm working on it.
It's just these...
Damn adhesions.
Yeah, I see them.
Yeah.
I've been here before.
We need enough space
to get a secure closure.
I'm talking about Jackson.
Looped PDS.
Jackson's father could be
loving and generous and fun.
He also could be a
child. Selfish, spiteful.
When we ended, he
just wanted to hurt me,
so he took the only
thing that mattered.
He took Jackson.
He took him across country,
thought he could
take my boy from me,
and that I would just roll over.
I told him he didn't know
who the hell he married.
I fought for my son, and
I'm not about to stop fighting.
Richard, war is ugly,
senseless, and scary as hell,
but there are some things
worth going to war over.
Maybe you can close without me.
We can monitor
each cell in his brain.
Mmm-hmm.
Dr. Shepherd, you have
plus 10 y, minus 20 on z.
Almost there.
Keep him talking.
Kyle, what kind of
music do you play?
Oh. Now, you want
to get to know me?
Right now, it's my job.
How's he doing, Edwards?
Why don't you try to
play me something?
Uh, persistent tremor.
No improvement.
Don't you think
it's a little weird
that you're seeing
the inside of my brain
and you haven't seen the
inside of my apartment?
You do not know
when to quit, do you?
Come on! Amuse me.
You said it's like
your job or something.
Dr. Shepherd, he's
developed a left facial droop.
Signal's getting distorted.
I have a small hemorrhage
here. What next?
Uh. Pull back on the
probe, close him up,
and wait for the bleed to stop.
Or you can control
the bleed right now.
Use a biopsy needle
to irrigate the bleed,
then dilute and
suction until it stops.
Good call, Edwards.
Biopsy needle.
I ca... I can't feel parts of
my face. What is happening?
You have a very small
bleed in your brain.
Don't worry. Dr. Shepherd
has it under control.
Syringe. Blake, now.
What is she doing?
She's free-styling.
She's a rock star, too,
all right? I'm right here.
What happened?
I was giving her a routine abdominal
exam when her pressure bottomed out.
It hurts so much.
Tell me what's wrong.
We're gonna take a look, okay?
She's hypotensive,
and her crit's at 18.
Tell me what's
happening. It's not labor.
Your aneurysm has ruptured,
and I know you didn't want
surgery, but now we have no choice.
We're gonna get you into the OR.
Mom? They've got you, honey.
Everything is gonna be fine.
What a waste. How's that?
Such a waste. The heart.
I'm sorry for your guy.
Well, maybe if we'd
gotten here sooner.
It wouldn't have
made a difference.
The heart was in V-fib.
Damage was done.
They should have
known... You're right.
It couldn't have been your
fault. It's never your fault,
not with Amelia...
I didn't know, all right?
If I caused her a problem, I'm
sorry, but she didn't tell me...
Disaster happens
wherever you are
because you are
there, like with Megan.
All right, no! Owen, I'm
not gonna do this again!
No? Okay, no, all right?
I think you're starting
to drive yourself crazy.
It's him.
At some point, you just
have to learn to let go.
Amelia took that drink. It doesn't
matter who offered it to her.
She would tell you that herself.
Riggs tried to talk your
sister off that chopper.
What?
She needed to
be with her patient.
He tried to go. She
wouldn't let him.
That's what he told you, that
he... That's what he told me.
Meredith, he didn't
say anything to her.
He wasn't anywhere
near that chopper.
He was off screwing some
woman from supply corps again.
That's why Megan got on the
chopper, to get away from him.
My sister was leaving him.
When I said, "We
hate him," I meant it.
You hanging in there, Kyle?
Oh, hey.
You're all right.
Loss of speech is normal.
It's temporary, okay?
Hey. It'll come back.
Dr. Shepherd's almost done.
Stay with me, Kyle. Almost done.
- You're okay.
- Give me a minute.
Dr. Shepherd, there isn't any...
She said give her a minute.
Bleeding has stopped.
Kyle, check your hand.
Okay.
No tremor.
Okay, can you speak now?
You miss me?
Welcome back, Kyle.
I showed you my moves.
Time to show us yours.
All right, come on.
Your turn to free-style.
This wasn't my fault.
Telling the mother.
Stress doesn't just
cause arteries to rupture.
You know that. ARIZONA: I do.
Doesn't make it right.
It felt right.
It felt like she needed to know,
like it was the
right thing to do.
I know the feeling.
This is not the same thing.
I'm just saying that
I know how you felt
in that moment. I know.
Mmm.
Turn around.
Oh.
God bless your heart. Mmm.
I'm glad you told me
about Jackson's father.
Now you understand
why I'm doing this.
Not a bit.
Ah.
It was an awfully sad story...
but it was your
story, not theirs,
and stop trying
to make it theirs.
I don't have a choice, Richard.
The woman I married
believed in second chances,
that anything was possible
and that the glass doesn't
always have to be half empty.
You said your ex-husband
didn't know the woman he married.
Well, I do.
I'm only letting you yammer on
because your hands are so magical.
Lower.
Well, that's a start.
We had to remove your
spleen to stop the bleeding.
But the baby's fine.
Good fetal
heartbeat, very strong.
And my mom?
She's waiting to see you
whenever you're ready.
Yeah? Okay. Warren.
Is she okay?
She is.
And the baby? They're both fine.
Mom. Don't speak.
Listen.
This just isn't what we do.
You tell me when
you're in trouble.
You don't walk around
scared and alone,
not when you have
me. Do you hear me?
Uh-huh.
Not when you're
having my grandbaby.
Hey.
Hi.
Listen, what I said before,
that was just me being...
Insecure.
I deserve that. You could
have said a lot worse.
I did, earlier.
I'm very sorry.
The attendings got
out of their meeting.
Already? Did you hear anything?
Uh. Yeah, I heard
that Penny applied,
which is weird because
she didn't say anything.
You applied? When? Today.
The deadline was at noon,
and I decided I should at least try,
even if I don't really
have a chance.
Oh. You have a chance.
Alex told me that your
name came up a lot.
Actually, Grey had your back.
Shepherd even. Shepherd?
I just don't understand
why you didn't tell us.
You pretended to
be all cheerleadery.
It's just, it's a
little... Snakey.
I wasn't trying
to hide anything.
Wow.
Never saw it coming.
Well played.
I wasn't playing
anything. I just decided...
Yeah.
Wow.
Good luck.
And on the 8th, he had a 4.1
rise. Let's get it to 3.2 just to make...
Excuse me. Okay.
Mate, this has to stop.
You're right. This has to stop.
Megan called me
right before she...
All right, she told
me everything.
So yeah, you should just stop
'cause I see you. You can't do this.
You can't just come in here
and pretend to be some nice guy,
pretend to be this hero,
and lie and fool everyone,
like Grey and Bailey
and Pierce and Amelia.
You can't just take more
people away from me.
You can't do it,
and I won't let you.
Benjamin Warren.
Miranda Bailey.
You didn't submit your
application for the Preminger Grant!
No, of course I didn't.
What do you mean, "of course"?
You're asking me why
I didn't apply for a grant
that's gonna take me
across the country?
What, am I supposed
to jump at the chance
to leave my wife and
kid for a year or more?
It was an incredible
opportunity.
We could have
figured something out.
You know, it's not
my turn. Not right now.
You're Chief. We
need to be here.
And you're okay with that?
Well, it'll be my turn sometime.
You know, when it is,
you'll, uh, do the same for me.
Right?
So who'd you pick, Chief?
Are you kidding me? It's me.
I read the e-mail five times
to see where I got it wrong,
but I didn't. I won.
Bailey gave me the
Preminger Grant.
Are you kidding me?
Why do you keep saying that?
Oh, no. No, yeah.
Well, it's just... Yay, you!
Come on. Let's go celebrate.
You recommended Blake?
I recommended you.
Well, then why
did Karev say you...
Then Blake's name came
up from a few people.
They asked my opinion.
And what did you say?
Well, I'm not gonna
tell you what I said.
I gave an honest
answer to a question.
You sunk me.
I endorsed you.
After that, it's
out of my hands.
You've been trying to find a
way to get rid of her for months,
and to use this,
you go right past somebody
who you know deserves it more,
someone who has
been there for you,
who stepped in when you couldn't
even handle doing your job...
Edwards.
This is the attendings' lounge.
Are you all right?
Am I all right? Yeah.
You lost that shine in
your eyes. I liked that shine.
I'm fine. I'm shiny.
All right, I just played a private
concert for you with my brain open.
I think you can
give me something.
I got screwed over by
a friend today. That's all.
The redhead? Mmm.
That sucks.
Mmm-hmm.
When I started playing, I
had all these musician friends,
and, you know, we'd
hang, and we'd jam together.
We grew up together, you know.
And then I started booking
gigs, selling out those gigs,
and, you know, I had the fans
and the girls, and it was fantastic.
It was everything
we had hoped for.
It was everything we had
talked about, you know?
And then when I went
to share it with them,
they weren't there. All
my friends were gone.
Poof. Just like that. It turns
out they weren't my friends.
They were my competition.
You and I are a lot alike.
Okay, how is that?
Well, you're smart,
incredibly good-looking.
Cocky.
But with the
goods to back it up.
Now, if you'll excuse
me, I'm gonna go to sleep
'cause my head hurts.
I'm supposed to watch you.
I'm okay with that.
I had a crappy day.
Mmm. Me, too.
I found out why
Owen hates Riggs.
I don't want to know. Okay.
Do I want to know?
I'm here.
We can see that.
Really, with the
cabinets? Sorry.
You open, you close.
It's not that big a deal.
It's tedious.
Oh, my God, I was
promised sisters.
I just got you guys
back in the same house.
I've never had sisters. It's
nice, but it's going to implode.
You know it, and I
know it, so have at it.
Go to town over the cabinets.
If you're gonna kill each
other, just do it already.
I can't keep this family
together by myself.
Nobody asked you to.
We're adults.
We're going to fight.
A lot. I'm annoying.
She is.
But I don't plan on kicking
her out anytime soon,
so are you good?
I'm not homeless. I'm good.
Good.
Though Maggie is starting
to get on my nerves.
Agreed.
Well, you wanted
sisters. You got them.
Close the cabinet.
I was just on my
way to your place.
I really don't have time for
one of your lectures now, Mom.
No, I was coming to
say that I was sorry,
to apologize.
I doubt that.
No, let me finish.
I overstepped, but
you are my baby,
and if somebody messes
with you, watch out.
I... Well, I was just
protecting my baby.
You know I'm a grown-ass
man, right? Language.
As long as I'm living, my
baby forever you will be.
But I do need to let go.
Roots, wings.
You can fight your own battles.
Yes, I can.
And if you don't want
to fight April on this,
maybe there is another way.
I mean, we're still all family.
Maybe you can go to counseling,
or I could get the two of
you in a room together,
and we could...
Sorry.
This is gonna
take some practice.
Honey, what are you going to do?
I'm an Avery.
Somebody messed with my
baby, so I got myself some power.
I'll round on Jenny in the
morning after you've been in.
All right, good night.
I think Jackson's gonna
sue me for custody,
full custody once
the baby's born.
His mother, she is awful.
I overheard her saying
it, and I just want to...
I am so mad. I am furious.
I feel like my skin is on fire!
Oh, my God.
Sorry, I know. I'm ranting, but
I don't have anyone to talk to,
and I need to talk
to someone. No!
And I've been treating
you like crap. No, no, no!
You need to talk
to me. It's fine.
I'm here for whatever you
need 'cause we're friends.
Rant away, and then
we'll think about what to do.
I already thought of what to do.
I'm not gonna be the victim.
He can't do this.
I won't let him.
April, what did you do?
What happens when
the gloves come off
and you stop hiding
behind your mask?
I just don't want to hurt her.
You know, it's in
my power not to, so...
Here's to that.
Do you need a drink?
Hey, Dr. Avery! Yeah.
Dr. Jackson Avery?
That's right. Do we...
You've been served.
Have a good night, guys.
What's your next move?
Do you take your best
shot and see where it lands?
Or do you hang
back, wait a minute,
and see if you get
sucker-punched?
"I don't want to fight. Whatever
you want to do, we'll do."
It's your move.
Oh, no.
A restraining order.
April filed a restraining
order against me.
You can either retreat
or go out swinging.
So what you gonna do?