Oh, my.
On the dance floor again.
Thank you, Bubbles.
Should I try a one?
Nope. Use a three.
You got more control.
What did you get
on the last hole...
Six, five?
Uh, six.
Take a five.
Use your Mulligan.
That was six with my Mulligan.
You know what you got to do?
You got to go to
the driving range
with me more often.
You don't have to carpool
on Tuesdays, right?
You know, I think a car full
of screaming eight-year-olds
arguing over who's got shotgun
is less aggravating than this.
Okay, hang on. Wait.
Straighten up
your back like that.
Keep your head down.
I'll watch the ball.
Okay.
You're in the fairway.
It's the wrong fairway,
but you're in the fairway.
I think it's this whole
doctor-golf cliché
that's really throwing me.
Well, you can't fight it.
You got to play nine
holes twice a week
and then 18 on the weekends.
You'll be shooting in
the low 80s by Labor Day.
Dr. Benton, I see you have
a thymectomy scheduled.
Would you mind if I
gave it to Dr. Levin?
Uh... yes, I would.
Because Drs. Fecteau
and Loesch are looking
for a resident to assist them.
On a transplant?
35-year-old with lupus.
Her brother is
giving her a kidney.
I thought you'd
like the opportunity.
Oh, yes, yes, I... I would.
Dr. Carter can still
scrub in on the thymectomy.
Sure.
Unless, of course, uh...
the transplant team
could also use Dr. Carter.
Perhaps Dr. Carter
could assist the donor's team.
I'll ask.
Dr. Benton, thanks.
It means a lot to me that you...
Carter, I'll see
you up there, okay?
Jeanie...
Jeanie, it's after 7:00.
Oh, my God.
Didn't my alarm ring?
Every ten minutes
for the last hour.
My 7:00...
Pills. Yeah.
That's why I woke you.
I can't believe I overslept.
Here's some juice and toast
to take with it.
You take AZT first, right?
Yeah. Then I can
take my nine o'clocks
on an empty stomach.
Thanks for letting me stay...
and for not asking why.
Sure.
I didn't want to be alone,
but I didn't feel right
calling anyone else.
I'm glad you called.
Minor meltdown, you know.
I was doing great,
and then out of the blue,
it snuck up on me.
Yeah, I forget sometimes
for a couple of hours,
and then I remember.
What's that?
They're playing
around with my meds.
The good news is, if I
start the day with this stuff,
then I can work in
my Oreos at bedtime.
You still haven't
outgrown that Oreo thing?
Hell, no.
Why are they adding
to your meds?
Is your viral load up?
I'm fine.
I got to be on the
job in about an hour.
You want to walk
to the El together?
Al, how are you doing?
You know, it seems I'm
resistant to something or other.
What about some
of those new drugs...
The nucleoside analogs?
Yeah, my docs
are trying to get me
into a trial study for those,
but they only take 20 people.
Why didn't you tell me?
It's not your problem.
Well, I might be able to help.
I do know some doctors.
I didn't want to bother you.
I could probably
get you an interview.
Where's the study?
At County.
Some docs who work
in, uh... Infectious Disease
are running it.
It's a hassle.
No, no. It's, um...
it's a simple request.
Are you sure?
No problem.
I told you.
"She reached to
hang his banana bag,
"her breasts swelling
under the pink of her uniform.
"'Carly.' His voice
was hoarse with desire.
'Call me Nurse... Hallonan'"?
Carly Hallonan...
That's you, girl.
No, you got to read the part
about the gentle
giant at the Admit desk.
You didn't mind he
was Neanderthal?
More brawn than
brains... He's a dude.
Who wrote this trash?
It had to be Randi. I
found it under the desk.
Or maybe it was Lydia.
She had a poem in
Good Housekeeping once.
No, it was definitely
written by a woman.
No man thinks like this.
Wait. Listen to this:
"Witchcraft attracted
her as a child
"when Zulu tribesmen on
her father's game preserve
tried sorcery to heal
her shriveled leg."
Weaver's in it?
Oh, man, you're cruel.
"Now she aimed her spells at
fellow attending Martin Bean.
"She nightly stirred
"and whispered in
a frenzy of jealousy
and, yes, perhaps a
perverted yearning"?
Yikes.
You know what?
We should be careful with this.
Yeah, people's
feelings could get hurt.
So, how many
copies should I make?
Yeah, a lot.
That LOL in curtain
one's still waiting.
I'll get it.
Water cannot wash away prophecy.
Still, we'll start
with a shower.
Those who minister
to the anointed
must shun the flesh of pigs,
refuse the carnal
touch of any man.
No meat, no men...
I'm your woman.
And all we know
will crumble unto dust
and the face...
Did you call Psych?
They're on their way.
You shouldn't play
into their delusions.
I was telling the truth.
The world is delusion,
and truth shall rain upon
thee with fists of thunder!
Okay, let's go take a bath.
Rejoice, lost man.
Chaos is your destiny.
I am the prophet...
Carol, I'll be in
curtain area one.
Okay.
Good.
I thought I was late.
You are.
Dr. Coburn's later.
Oh.
So, how you doing?
I'm glad to be out of the house.
Yeah, I know.
How was the cab ride?
You know, I would
have picked you up.
The cab ride was fine;
I'm fine, Peter, I'm fine.
The Lamaze class... You
were able to reschedule it?
I did, but I'm not going
to need you to be there.
You're fired.
What are you talking about?
Peter, I cannot work with you.
The way you bark orders at me?
"20 seconds! Blow!"
Uh-uh. Please.
Nah. No, no, no, no, no.
You're going to scare this baby.
He's not going to
want to come out.
Carla, look, I didn't
make up the drills.
Well, I'm planning on a
birth, not a military maneuver.
Folks, I'm sorry,
but Dr. Coburn's
been called into
another delivery.
She's going to be delayed
at least another hour.
Oh, damn!
Peter, it's okay.
I know you're working.
Yeah, but I wanted to ask her
about your iron supplement.
Go save a life.
Okay.
Um... I'll call you later, okay?
Are you kidding?
Look at all the typos.
You think I'd put out
something so sloppy?
Sorry.
I'm going to Rachel's
school for a conference.
I'll be back...
It's only in a couple
inches of water.
So he puts on his waders...
But you're still sitting sweet?
Oh, yeah, two under after 15.
Is Doug's fellowship
in question again?
No, he's just angling an invite
to play golf at Fair Oaks.
Anspaugh's a member there.
Dr. Ross has gone
to the dark side.
Help! I need help.
I'm looking for the
Emergency Room.
You found it.
My daughter's leg
was cut with a saw.
She's bleeding a lot.
I'm Dr. Greene.
Why don't you come this way?
Call Doyle. Have her
meet us in Trauma 1.
I thought you were leaving.
I am soon.
It's not that bad, Daddy.
This is why girls
shouldn't take Shop.
But it was Jim
Rentschler who did it.
I'm going to take a look at it.
Jeanie, I got your message.
You didn't need to come down.
It's my pleasure.
I called last night.
You didn't pick up.
I got in late.
I need to ask a favor.
Shoot.
Dr. Kramer in the AIDS Clinic
is doing a trial study
of nucleoside analogs.
Are they still
looking for subjects?
Jeanie, are you having
trouble with your meds?
No. I'm fine... Knock wood.
That's a relief. Want
to have dinner tonight?
I can't.
You'll tell me if I
should stop asking.
Yeah. I have someone I'd
like to recommend for the trial.
I'll make sure any
patient you recommend
gets an interview,
and I'll flag their file
if they fit the protocol.
That's wonderful,
but it's not a patient.
Actually, it's my ex, Al.
I'll get him an
interview this afternoon.
Thanks.
Irrigate. Debride.
Single-layer closure
with 4-0 nylon.
Sounds right.
You're lucky it
didn't cut deeper.
Was she talking
about stitches, Doctor?
That's right.
You're in good
hands with Dr. Doyle.
Are you going someplace?
Yeah, I'm not on duty right now.
You're leaving
us with a student?
Dr. Doyle is an intern.
This is a simple skin repair.
Another attending
will consult with her
if there are any problems.
There's already a problem.
I don't really want an intern.
I don't want my daughter
to end up with a
scar on her leg.
Am I going to have a scar?
A small one.
But I'm a majorette!
Get a plastic surgeon down here.
Mr. Gunther, we don't
consult plastic surgeons
for lacerations of this kind.
Well, for God's sakes, don't
stick us with a student doctor.
I am an emergency
medicine resident.
You're learning
on the job, dear.
This is a teaching facility
and a county hospital.
If you want to investigate
a plastic surgeon
on your own, that's your right.
Oh, like I can afford that.
Dr. Doyle is fully qualified
for this kind of repair.
I'm running late,
so I'm leaving now.
You're not the only one
that's leaving, Dr. Greene.
Alyssa, get your shoes on.
My daughter's injury
may be nothing to you,
but I bet if it were your kid,
you'd make sure
she got the best!
Yeah, whatever you
think, Mr. Gunther.
Yeah, great. Just walk away!
I owe you one, Kerry.
Don't worry. I got it.
Give a damn, Doctor!
Is this going to
put me to sleep?
No, this is just for I.V.
access, Mr. Twomey.
They won't start the anesthesia
till you get to the OR.
Good, because I was hoping
I could see my sister
before I went under.
It's a great thing you're
doing, giving her a kidney.
She practically raised me.
Our family wasn't
too interested,
and... then she got lupus, and
she's been through so much,
you know, with dialysis and all.
Hang on a second.
This might be her.
Jean Twomey?
Yeah?
Got someone here
who wants to see you.
Oh, my God!
He is going to bug me
until the last minute, isn't he?
If I can.
Change of heart, crybaby?
Of course not.
I already offered him my stereo
in a trade.
A stereo for a kidney? No.
You're going to have to
throw in the jet ski, too.
Okay. As long as that settles it
and I am not beholden
to my kid brother
for the rest of my life.
Does this sound fair
to you, Dr. Carter?
Hey, fair and square.
All right, it's a deal, then.
Deal.
Are you going to
be with my brother?
I sure am.
Well, take care of him.
He's a wimp.
Excuse me.
I'm looking for a head doctor.
Which one?
Bald, white guy, little glasses.
Dr. Greene... He's not here.
What do you need?
Well, a few weeks ago,
he took care of my brother.
Now I got this.
Yeah, you're going
to have to take this
to the third floor, past
reception to the East Wing.
They can help you there.
Thank you.
The secret to putting,
since you didn't ask,
is you got to change your focus.
These machines are for idiots.
Anybody can sink the same shot
over and over again.
I'm really getting
hooked on this.
You know, I think Randi
has a hidden talent.
She said she didn't write it.
Well, a nurse didn't write it.
Nurses go home
too tired to write, so...
Maybe a doctor did.
No, the medicine's too cheesy.
She has got you down:
"The suave resident
cocked his head boyishly
"and winked... a quick wink,
"almost a reflex.
"She trembled, her resolve
crumbling."
Who's he winking at?
Huh?
My character...
Who's he winking at?
Oh, you know, a lot of these
characters are just made up.
Douglas, there you are.
Hey, Donald, how are you?
Listen, I'm glad to see
you're not swamped.
I need your help.
Yeah, okay, sure, absolutely.
Do you mind?
No. Here, go ahead.
Listen, I just got a phone
call from a friend of mine...
P.K. Palmer, of the
railroad Palmers?
Sure, yeah.
Oh, damn it.
You know, I know P.K.
from the club, of course...
A hell of a guy, a two handicap.
Yeah.
You know, this
floor must be sloped.
Yeah, it slopes.
Anyhow, P.K. just called
from Hilton Head.
He's down there with his missus.
Seems their little one
stayed home with the nanny
and took a spill...
Could be a fracture.
Their pediatrician's
out of town,
and he called me and
asked for a referral.
Well, have his
nanny bring him in.
They're on their way.
There we go, right in the heart.
Anyway, the parents
are flying home now.
I promised them
that their son
would get the best.
I'll take good care of him.
By the way,
if you're interested,
you couldn't ask
for a better recommendation
to Fair Oaks than P.K.'s.
Yeah, I hadn't thought of that.
Fair Oaks is one of the, oh...
25 best courses in the country.
Really? Well, maybe you
could take me as your guest.
You don't play golf.
Oh, well, that's a good thing,
because they
don't allow women...
or blacks.
Jews either.
No, I think they changed that.
Nope.
Pretty sure they changed that.
Hey.
Hello.
Chris Law.
My brother was Kenny.
Yeah, I remember.
How you doing?
Not so good.
My mother got this yesterday...
A $19,000 bill
from a hospital
that killed her son.
My mother doesn't
have insurance.
I'm sure the Billing
Department can...
What? Be happy to
make a payment schedule?
See, they don't understand
that my mother,
who pays every bill,
is not going to pay
one penny of that one.
She's not going to
pay because, well...
I'm telling her that
that bill's a mistake,
that you don't get bills
from people who kill your child.
You don't pay people
who lose your son's body
between their morgue
and the coroner
so that you have to postpone
a funeral for two days.
I'm sorry. I had no
idea that that happened.
Nobody has any idea,
but you tell them
that she doesn't get
another piece of mail
from this hospital...
unless it's an apology.
I'm very sorry for your loss.
I'm not threatening to sue...
because I'm sure you have
a department for that, too.
But if my mother
gets another bill
from this hospital,
maybe I'm going
to kick some ass.
Maybe I'll start with yours.
If it were me, I'd
report it to security.
He was just blowing off steam.
He had a good point, actually.
I called the morgue,
and they did mix
up the body transfer.
How's Rachel?
That's the good news...
She's doing a lot better.
She'll be Marco Polo
in the school play.
Save me a seat.
They didn't have chocolate chip.
It's chocolate.
Okay, thanks. Hey,
aren't you in there with me?
Lydia's on it... One
RN per collarbone,
even for the country club set.
Who's getting the VIP treatment?
I get yogurt for kids
when they have to wait.
All right.
I've got some chocolate yogurt
for the big guy with
the sore clavicle.
Thank you very much.
You're very welcome.
You want to see why it hurts?
Yeah? Here, hop down.
Will you give me ice
and a sling please, Lydia?
Be right back.
There's his anomalous
left renal vein
posterior to the aorta.
Can you see that, Dr. Carter?
Yes.
We're standing by.
Houston, do you read me?
Loud and clear.
This is very cool.
Our first time
on intercom.
We usually have a nurse
running back and forth
between the donor
and the recipient.
Ready for countdown, Fin?
Ready and waiting.
Clock starts.
And why does it become
interesting now, Dr. Carter?
You want to monitor
your ischemic time.
Bingo. I'm lifting
the kidney out.
Basin, please.
Ever pass the baton
in a relay, Dr. Carter?
Ran the 440 in high school.
Good. Perfusate.
Good.
That's it.
Well, Dr. Carter...
don't get lost.
Dr. Carter is
bringing the kidney
your way, gentlemen.
Oh, my God.
Is there a problem, Dr. Benton?
No, no. Not at all.
Somebody want to sign for this?
What's your name, Doctor?
John Carter.
Well, John Carter,
why don't you scrub in?
You can join us
for the second act.
Great.
You see this line right here?
Hey, come here.
Take a look.
See that?
You know what that is?
That is your first broken bone.
You're officially a man.
I shouldn't have let him
talk me out of
bringing him last night.
He said it didn't hurt.
Because he's such a tough guy.
Because he didn't
want to get in trouble.
He's not supposed to
play outside after dark.
It's tough to stay in
when it's this warm.
My mom says I'll get hurt.
She does? What
does your dad say?
I'm a klutz.
He does?
P.K. gets a lot of
bumps and scrapes.
His father's quite
an athlete, you know.
You fall down a lot?
Yeah, I'm not supposed
to let him run around
without watching.
Listen, you and I
play a game, okay?
I'm going to cover my eye.
You do the same thing.
You cover your own eye.
Okay, ready? Now, tell
me if you can see my finger.
Tell me when you see it.
Don't do that. Don't look.
Look straight ahead.
Cover your eye.
There you go.
Okay.
See it?
I see it.
Good.
Okay. Let's try the
other eye, okay?
So, you found it, huh?
Certainly did.
How much have you read?
I've gotten past the part
where the "alpha
bitch attending"
goes to a faith healer
to cure her limp.
The seduction scene
after that is... is really hot.
Really?
I don't think whoever wrote
it was being mean-spirited.
It's just a sleazy romance...
Tongue in cheek, you know?
You got to take it that way.
Sounds like you got into it.
Yeah, it's kind of a hoot.
I think it's meant to be.
Oh, my God, Kerry, you wrote it.
I did not.
You did, too.
Why would I waste my time?
Well, for the money.
I mean, there's a big
market for this kind of thing.
Too bad I didn't write it.
Hey, somebody!
I need help now.
Is this the ALOC 57 called in?
He had a stroke.
Why aren't you in uniform?
Day off.
It's okay, Gramps,
we're here now.
You'll be okay.
Take it easy, Pam, we got him.
He had a stroke, I know it.
Okay, okay.
We had acute stroke
training last week.
I did the SAS test on him.
Slow down.
He's got one-sided weakness.
I went by to take
him grocery shopping.
I always go by on my day off.
Give me the bullet.
73-year-old
African-American male,
ALOC, slurred speech.
Loss of motion on the left side.
He's never been sick before.
Vitals?
BP 175/100.
I didn't have a cuff.
Pulse was 140.
When did you find him?
20 minutes ago. I
called it in right away.
We were closer to Mercy, but
Pam insisted on coming here.
Why?
I knew you'd set up
a new treatment
program for stroke.
Call Dr. Greene.
How's the time, Dr. Carter?
You're at 43 minutes.
And anastomosis is completed.
Dr. Benton, why don't you
remove the DeBakey clamps?
Can everybody see in here?
Okay.
It's pinking up.
Look at that.
Wow.
Yeah, that's what I live for...
The sight of urine flowing.
Hey, Fin, we've
got trouble in here.
What is it?
Our donor's hemorrhaging.
Pressure's falling.
He's tachycardiac.
Sounds like a tie slipped off.
The renal artery?
That'd be my guess.
Let's open him up.
He's losing blood fast.
Get me a tonsil clamp.
Okay, people, let's
stay in the game.
We got to close here.
Is that pedes
ophthalmologist still in 3?
He's got a bunch of messages.
Yeah, he's finishing up.
Ophthalmologist?
You really are giving that
boy the million-dollar work-up.
What do you mean?
I guess if you're a Palmer,
you get the full
treatment around here.
You think I'd put a kid
through unnecessary tests
just to impress his family?
I guess not.
You were right...
Retinitis pigmentosa.
He's going blind.
I was afraid of that.
All right. His parents
are on their way.
They'll want to
hear all the options.
Possible brain attack?
Yes. This is Paramedic
Olbes's grandfather.
Let's get a CBC, PT, PTT,
platelet count, fibrinogen.
Type and cross four units.
Team's on alert.
Malik, record the BP.
Stick of glucose.
Alert Radiology
that we're coming in
for a noncontrast head CT.
BP's 185/110.
I.V. labetalol... 15 migs.
Sir, do you know where you are?
Are you going to
be able to help him?
What's his name?
Ralph, but everybody
calls him Gramps.
Hey, Gramps. Gramps, can
you tell me what happened?
Sir, can you squeeze my hand?
Can you squeeze?
Was he complaining
of any headaches?
No, I talked to him last night.
Nausea, vomiting?
No.
Is your grandfather
on any medications?
No.
Does he take aspirin?
No, he hates pills.
Are you going to give him TPA?
That's what he needs, right?
That's what we're
trying to assess.
Do you know when
the symptoms began?
No.
Do you know anybody who might?
Maybe his neighbor.
They walk to get their
papers in the morning.
Can you give them a call?
Go, go.
CT's ready for us.
All right, let's
get him upstairs.
Mark, this is what
I was afraid of
with the stroke team.
People have heard
there's a miracle cure.
They don't understand the risks.
I understand the risks.
I've seen patients
hemorrhage with TPA.
It's no cure-all.
That's why we follow protocol.
The results aren't convincing.
Look, Kerry, I understand
that you have reservations,
so that's why I'm on the
stroke team and you're not.
Fine.
But if she can't clarify
the onset of symptoms...
I'd be a fool
to give TPA.
It's just an interview.
They're going to ask me
a bunch of nosy questions.
Well, they have to make sure
they're getting
reliable candidates.
That's what makes me nervous.
I don't deserve all this help.
Everyone deserves
help from their friends.
Friends, huh?
It reminds me of
when we first met...
Before we even started dating.
No, we were never friends.
I always had my eye on you,
wondering when I
could make my move.
See, you're a good liar.
You'll do fine in the interview.
The CT confirmed
an ischemic stroke,
and Gramps' neighbor
was able to verify
that he had no
symptoms two hours ago,
so he's easily within
the 180-minute range.
Mark, if you're looking
for my blessing on this,
forget it.
Actually, I was hoping
you could talk to Olbes.
She's heard from the
neurologist and from me
that we think her grandfather
is a candidate for TPA.
I'd like her to hear
about the risks from you.
Why?
I happen to believe
that he'll respond
to thrombolysis,
but if I'm wrong, he could die.
She needs to hear
that loud and clear.
You want me to tell her?
Who better than a
respected colleague
who's on the other
side of the fence?
I suspect you
won't soft-pedal it.
I won't.
Mark...
thank you.
How's he doing?
Looks like they got the
bleeding under control.
They're starting to close.
Wow, this is a first.
Usually, Keith has had a shower
by the time I get finished.
Would you gentlemen
care to join us
for the post-game wrap-up?
We find that
debriefing can be useful
when there's been
a complication.
Uh... yes.
We'd be honored.
Dr. Benton, you had a
call from Carla Reese.
Would you like the number?
No, I got it.
Carter, coming?
Hey, Shirley, can you call
Recovery, ask them to page me
when Jean Twomey wakes up?
Sure.
Dr. Kramer, I was wondering
if I could interview
this candidate.
Al Boulet?
You know him?
No, but I'm familiar
with his treatment.
I'm curious to
see what he's like.
Be my guest.
I'm Dr. Fischer.
Thanks for taking the time
to fill out all these forms.
I thought I was
meeting a Dr. Kramer.
I'm helping him out.
All the information
looks complete.
You mention a couple of slip-ups
with your drug
regimen in the past.
There were so many
pills to keep track of.
I've got it under control now.
You began treatment a year ago.
That's right.
You contracted AIDS through...?
Heterosexual contact, I guess...
I mean, since I never shot
up or had sex with a guy.
Uh-huh. But you were unable
to identify the partner
who infected you.
No, no. I contacted
all the women I could...
to let them know, you know.
No one had any prior infection.
But it was a lot of years
and a lot of women.
Now you live alone?
Right.
Well, that's the only factor
that mitigates against
your inclusion in the trial.
Those who
participate must adhere
to a strict regimen.
Ideally, participants would
have someone to back them up.
I'm sure I can handle it.
And I have backup.
My ex-wife is around off and on.
Off and on?
A lot recently.
I mean, she's, uh...
kind of back in my life...
Stays over and all.
She's a physician assistant.
She'll keep on me...
Make me stick to it.
I see.
I mean, once Jeanie
takes something on,
she doesn't mess around.
Ten migs TPA over one minute.
Follow with 50 milligrams
over the next hour
for a total dosage of 60 migs.
Monitor his vital signs
and maintain a
diastolic of under 110.
Now we wait?
Now we wait.
In retrospect, studying
Mr. Twomey's renal angiogram,
we might have predicted
a potential problem.
Yeah, with the angiogram
and a crystal ball, maybe.
No, no. Look at
the short renal vein.
Do you appreciate
that, Dr. Benton?
I think Dr. Fecteau is
being hard on himself.
How did we do on ischemic time?
We can do better.
Yeah, we could do
better if you weren't
so chintzy with the ureter.
Let's go step by step.
Now, I lost time
dividing the vein.
Well, our biggest deviation
was anastomosis... 41 minutes.
Yeah, so? What are you
saying? We weren't working...
Of course she denied it,
but I could tell it was true.
I bet she wrote it
when she had all that free time.
Yeah, when she
was on suspension?
Carol, did you get that history
from the abdominal pain
in Exam 2? Yep.
What?
You little slut.
I see you in a whole new light.
We know you wrote the book.
I didn't write it.
You ought to be proud of it.
Kerry, did you tell them...?
She wrote the book.
Yeah. Nice try.
Like I'd make
myself the villain?
I knew it was you.
I didn't do it.
You thought it was Jeanie.
Or Carol. I mean, I knew it was
an incurable romantic
who was very warped.
I'm not warped.
This is cool.
Watch it! The big spinout!
Baby!
Look out for the folks, baby.
Hit the button.
Hit the down button. Hop up.
Listen, I know you've been given
a lot of information.
This is kind of a tough time.
There are a lot of
new interventions.
P.K.'s doctor will be able
to fill you in on those, though.
I like Dr. Ross.
We all do, sweetie.
Well, I like you, too, buddy.
Make sure you keep these
glasses on for me, okay?
Hey...
where's your sweater?
I know where I left it.
All right, let's
get that sweater.
Go get it.
One thing you need
to be careful about is,
you have to make sure
that he doesn't feel like
he's been bad in any way.
Sometimes, kids with RP...
They feel like it's their fault.
Well, we'll be careful of that.
Thank you, Doctor.
Okay? All right. Great. Thanks.
Thank you.
Bye, you guys.
There you go!
No holding you back!
Bye.
Bye-bye.
You know, some
people think of RP
as looking through a telescope.
It's a good way to think of it.
Doug, I owe you an apology.
Oh, forget it.
No, I was wrong.
I have no reason to ever
question your integrity.
As a doctor, at least.
Everything's so glib
with you these days.
You know, I don't
know you anymore.
I don't know what
matters to you.
Me either.
Great job, Carol.
Did you know she wrote the book?
Wrote the book? Are you kidding?
She stole the idea from me.
I did not write the damn book!
Welcome back.
You're doing well.
Why isn't Carl here?
Nobody will tell me anything.
He's still under anesthesia.
Why? What went wrong?
Your brother's fine.
There were some complications...
Some bleeding...
And they had to
open him back up.
Oh, no. I was afraid
of something like this.
Jean, he's stabilized.
He's fine.
I wouldn't tell you
that if it wasn't true.
In fact, I'm going to go see
if they can move
him in here with you.
And I'll stay with him
until he wakes up.
Okay? Yeah?
Great.
Any response?
Not yet.
You seen Dr. Greene?
You just missed him.
Dr. Ross, I'd like you
to meet a new resident,
Anna Del Amico.
This is our pedes
fellow, Doug Ross.
My pleasure.
Mutual.
So, you're starting early.
I'm doing
an emergency pedes elective
before my residency
starts in July.
We always welcomes
slave labor in Pedes.
Okay, I'll show you around.
Dr. Del Amico
is a pediatrician.
She's double-boarding
in emergency medicine.
Great. What we
need around here...
More overachievers.
There you are.
Hi. Can you believe it?
I'm actually getting
out of here on time.
Al qualifies for the trial.
He should read
over this material
and then come in Tuesday
to pick up his meds.
Shouldn't you tell Al this?
We left him a
message, but I figured
you'd probably
be seeing him first.
Greg, what's going on?
You know, I've been
asking myself that question
for the last two months.
I thought that I was
pretty honest with you,
that I understood
all the reasons
you might be hesitant
about getting
seriously involved.
I guess I missed one.
Greg, I don't know
what you think...
I think that you're
still involved
with your ex-husband.
After the way he treated you,
he can still manipulate you
into getting him
the latest meds.
He did not manipulate me, Greg.
But you do still love him.
I don't know.
Dr. Greene, can I
ask you something?
Sure.
You ever think Carol Hathaway
might be interested
in me at all?
I mean, did you ever
pick up on anything?
Uh... no.
No, I can't say that I have.
You haven't read
her book, have you?
What book?
Uh... Carol wrote a book.
There's some parts about
me that are pretty flattering.
She say anything about me?
It seemed a little amateurish.
Really?
I was impressed.
I didn't read too much
of it, just a few pages.
Oh, you've got to
give it a chance.
Reading good trash is
like reading Shakespeare.
Oh?
You got to get into the rhythm.
But, hey, don't
take my word for it.
Chuny, didn't you think that
Carol's book was pretty decent?
The part I read was racist.
Don't tell Carol I said that.
You didn't like
the Latina nurse?
It wasn't real.
I got to go.
I didn't think the
ethnic characters
were handled differently
than anything else.
I don't know.
Have you seen Mark?
Gramps' blood
pressure is coming down.
That's a good sign.
No, I was looking for him, too.
Look who's here.
Hey.
You did it.
Okay, no fighting.
I did it.
Dr. Carter.
They're doing really well, huh?
Where'd you go?
I wanted to make sure
they saw each other.
Carter, two of the best
transplant surgeons
in the country
let us look over
their shoulders.
They're debriefing on one of
the most fascinating procedures
you and I ever participated in,
and you just get up and leave.
Well, I promised the sister.
I knew she'd be worried.
Is that a problem?
I don't know.
Another message
from Carla Reese.
It's okay. I called her at home
and got her machine.
No, she left an
extension... OB, I think.
I've never lived
anywhere but Philly.
Kerry, will you take
Dr. Del Amico back?
I'm intimidated enough already.
Anna, please.
All right, Anna, welcome aboard.
Thanks.
You find a place yet?
No, I don't know Chicago at all.
I figured I'd look
around this weekend.
Is there a neighborhood?
Hey, guys!
Oh, my God!
It's Mark.
Stabilize his neck.
Where do I find a C-collar?
I'll get it.
You help Doug.
Hold his neck.
In-line
stabilization... I got it.
Good breath sounds.
Good pulse. Is he an ER doc?
Yeah, attending.
Give me the collar, please!
Mark?!
Get the board ready.
Slowly, slowly,
slowly, okay.
Here we go.
Now we're going to roll him.
Nice and easy.
Just roll him towards me.
Okay. Slide the board in.
Nice and gentle.
Good. That's fine, right there.
Roll him back.
Go. Roll. Roll him.
Gently.
Mark,
you're going to be okay,
buddy. Hang in there.
Okay, let's get him
monitored right away.
Cross-table C-spine, chest,
CBC, type and hold, dip a urine.
On my count, we're
going to lift him.
Got that? Nice and
gentle, real slow.
You all right, Malik?
One... two...
three... go.
Let's go.
Alert CT.
He's vomiting.
Watch out for aspiration.
All right, let's roll him.
What's going on?
Oh, my God! Mark!
Pulse is 120, resp's 24,
BP's 100/60.
What happened?
We need to put him on a mask.
15 liters.
We need to rule
out a pneumothorax.
Chuny, aren't you
with the stroke team?
Yeah, but...
Go back to your patient.
Kerry, he's...
Go on! Now!
Kerry, come on!
Get back there.
Pupils are round
and sluggish,
react to light.
Possible hyphema.
DTR's two plus bilaterally.
Babinski's negative.
Radiology's on their way.
Oh, my God, it's true.
We got some crunchy ribs here.
I'll get this bleeding
under control.
Who are you?
New resident.
Guarding and tenderness.
Abdominal CT?
You bet.
Give him the works. Come on!
She was still in my office
when the contractions started.
The good news is, her
membrane hasn't ruptured,
and the baby's not in distress.
Is she dilated?
Just two centimeters.
So I admitted her. I put
her on complete bed rest.
With some luck, we can keep her
from going into labor.
Thank you, Dr. Coburn.
You're welcome.
Hey... Carla.
Hey.
Dr. Coburn said they
stopped the contractions.
Mm-hmm.
Do you mind if I sit?
No.
So, you, uh... pretty much
have to stay like this, huh?
Exactly like this...
for eight weeks.
Can I get you anything?
No. Mm-mm.
No, just sit there...
and entertain me.
Never mind!
What? No, no...
You know, I was...
wondering about it, and...
I think I know when
this baby was conceived.
Yeah.
Me, too.
Really?
Oh, yeah, really.
You remember that morning?
Mm-hmm.
Oh... well...
seems like a long time ago.
Yeah, it does.
"Possible side effects:
bloating, nausea,
sustained diarrhea..."
Oh, stop reading that.
I don't have a single vice left.
Forget beer.
Sometimes, I'd
double my viral load
for an old-fashioned
glass of milk.
I don't mind the soy stuff.
Well, you were
always a pushover.
Yes, I was.
And I took it for granted.
You know what I
miss most about us?
Hearing you laugh.
The sound of you
laughing in the dark.
We both took a lot for granted.
I don't take anything
for granted anymore.
I better go.
Sure.
Or stay.
On the couch, if you want.
I don't want to
stay on the couch.
Then you better go.
Okay. I'll stay on the couch.
Me, too.
Oh, Jeanie...
Wait. Can you... can
you stay right there?
I doubt it.
No...
I'll be right back.
I don't have a condom
that's not over a year old.
And I have to have one, right?
You're right.
I mean, I could
have a different strain
or a stronger strain than
you, and we need to be safe.
Uh-huh.
I'll be two minutes.
Will you wait?
Yeah, I'll try.
That's it.
That's what I missed.
Oh...
CT is negative.
He was really lucky.
Let's get Ortho
to take a look at
that broken hand.
I'll go see what's keeping them.
Any change?
Nobody saw anything?
I told the cops that
basketball player's brother
was around earlier.
A psych guy kind of threatened
Dr. Greene this morning.
Cops will want
to hear about that.
Dr. Ross,
that kid with the allergic
reaction is still in Exam 2.
Oh, I'll take it.
That's okay. You
don't have to do that.
Can you
rustle me up a lab coat?
I'll find you one.
It's usually not this
crazy around here.
Not a problem.
Dr. Weaver, can
you check this out?
I'll be back.
Keep working, people.
We've still got an ER to run.
What about Rachel?
The sitter called.
She's going to keep
Rachel overnight.
He had an on-the-table
response a few minutes ago.
His speech is coming back.
Something... was wrong.
Yeah, Gramps.
You had a stroke.
You're going to be better now.
I couldn't... do that.
He's being admitted upstairs.
Guess Dr. Greene
made the right call.
I want to thank him.
I'll tell him for you.
He'll be very pleased.
GCS is still 13.
I know. You just
did a neuro check
ten minutes ago.
How's his I.V. rate?
Fine.
Don't want to overhydrate him.
That's why I cut it back.
Yeah, I have him
on 80cc's an hour.
He weighs about 80 kilos...
Doug, why don't
you go call Ortho,
find out what's keeping them?
I'm bugging you
that much, right?
Mm-hmm.
I guess I'll go call Ortho.
That's a good idea.
All right.
Doug!
He's back.
Hey, Mark. Hi.
You're going to be fine.
Hey, buddy.
What happened?
Well... you got beat
up, but you're okay.
You got some bruised
ribs and a concussion,
midshaft fractures
of two metacarpals,
but other than
that, you're fine.
I signed you up for a
double shift on Saturday.
What happened?