.
male announcer: Previously
on "New Amsterdam"...
- All my patients,
all their despair,
it just becomes a part of me,
and I'm not going
to see patients anymore.
- Dr. Sharpe and I are leaving.
We're leaving New Amsterdam.
We're moving to London.
- I'd like to introduce
you all
to the new medical director
of New Amsterdam.
- We go way back,
don't we, Max?
♪
- Listen, Karen.
Yeah, uh, Karen,
would you just stop walking
for one second?
- Why? So you can ask me
to reconsider hiring
Veronica Fuentes?
- No, so I can beg you.
Plead, grovel.
She is the exact wrong person
for the job.
- She's far more qualified
to be medical director
than you are.
- Maybe on paper,
but I trained under her.
- And look how wonderful
you turned out.
- Despite her.
I have seen her in action.
She is ruthless, corporate,
financially motivated.
- Like, like, love.
- She's not one of us.
She completely lacks
the New Amsterdam spirit.
- Unlike you, Max, the board
had to consider
the future of this hospital,
and we were thrilled when
Dr. Fuentes accepted our offer.
She's here to stay.
- Where's my desk?
- Oh, I just thought
the natural light
was better on this side
of the room.
- Oh, you thought
the light was better there?
That's--that's lovely.
I am still the medical director
of this hospital.
My decision stands,
and I happen to like my desk
on the shady side
of the office.
- Max, put on some sunscreen,
and let it go.
I want you to spend the next
five weeks passing the torch.
Bring Dr. Fuentes up to speed.
From this point on,
I want you two
joined firmly at the hip.
- Oh, just like old times,
except back then,
you were a bit more
in the background.
- Yeah, this isn't gonna work.
- Wow, seems like the only one
lacking that New Amsterdam
spirit, Max, is you.
- As it turns out,
you'll get the chance
to collaborate
right off the bat,
thanks to this.
A generous donation...
- I got it.
- From Steve and Susan Gerlach,
philanthropists
and longtime hospital donors.
They've gifted New Amsterdam
with attractive land
in East New York worth--
- $10 million.
- That's right.
I want you and Veronica
to decide what to do
with the land.
- What if we can't agree?
- I don't care
if it takes a thumb war.
Figure it out.
- Bye, Karen.
- Thanks, Karen.
- Bye!
♪
- Pardon me, thank you.
Make a hole.
Thank you. Thank you.
Excuse me.
Okay.
Babe, surprise!
I got you a bagel.
Where's Leyla?
- You just missed her.
She went home
about ten minutes ago.
Hey, since she's gone,
can I--can I have that bagel?
♪
- Turkey, egg white omelet,
spanakopita,
and two joes to go.
- Right here.
You can keep the change.
- Does your wife want
honey or agave?
- Oh, actually, the queen
accompanying me isn't my wife.
She is my lover
from a blossoming
and healthy
polyamorous relationship.
- It's fine. It's fine.
Here's your spanakopita,
Dr. Woke-in-stein.
- Well, I know you clown,
but I can't help it
if she saw the vibe in us.
- Oh, our vibe, huh?
And you are embracing our vibe?
- What's there not to embrace?
I mean, love is love...is love.
Hey, look, we do us.
- Attached at the hip
with a total corporate shill.
In a dictionary
under "corporate shill,"
it says, "See Veronica Fuentes'
LinkedIn page."
- Mm, she is cagey, that one.
However, her superpower
seems to be the ability
to thoroughly
get under your skin.
- That's why she does
what she does.
She--she smiles, you know,
and she tells you
what you wanna hear,
and she plays nice.
Stroke, stroke, stab.
- And?
- And I have five weeks left
to leave a lasting impression
on this place.
To stir up some good trouble,
you know?
And despite my best effort,
Veronica Fuentes
is gonna come in
and undo everything
that I've fought for.
- Funny enough, I, too, have
just a little over a month
in which to affix
a lasting imprimatur
on the oncology department.
- It's fancier
than the way I said it.
- I've put my heart and soul
into oncology.
I'm gonna leave it
ship-shape in Bristol fashion.
- Good. What?
- A well-oiled machine, dear.
So while you're busy
stirring up good trouble,
I will be dotting my Is
and crossing my Ts,
updating patient files,
replacing old equipment,
even sprucing up my office.
By the time
I leave New Amsterdam,
I'll have everything
in perfect order.
- We're very different.
- I need your help,
'cause I am going crazy.
Leyla is working nights
this month, and we go days
without seeing each other,
and it is making me insane.
- No, you're missing
your girlfriend.
That sounds perfectly normal.
- No, not like this.
I mean, this is like
a--like a need.
Like--like a craving
for her smell and her touch.
- Okay, let me ask you this.
Have you lashed out at Leyla?
Have you blamed her unfairly
for things?
- No, no.
- You abusing your power
at work at all?
Adjusting the work schedule
to make your life
a little easier?
Okay, so that is
a slippery slope, my friend,
one that you've
skied down before.
- Oh, God.
God, I'm making Leyla
my new drug, aren't I?
- Well, I don't know.
I mean, I wouldn't
slalom down that hill just yet.
I mean, you're willingly
acknowledging your behavior.
That's huge.
That's a big step, right?
You've worked really hard
to be here.
So I would say, uh, hash it out
with your sponsor,
and focus on your triggers.
- Yeah, thank you.
You're right.
- Yeah, you got it.
- Uh, and you know, if you ever
wanna get back in the saddle,
you know, seeing patients...
you still got it.
- Ah.
Cool.
- Hi, Doc.
You wanted to see me?
- Ah, Adena. Yes.
Please, do come in.
So you know how I'm trying
not to leave any
unresolved department issues?
- Sure, sounds like you.
-  Yes.
And I found a list of people
who had had mammograms
who were identified
as having dense breast tissue,
but who didn't follow up on
the letter that they received.
I found your name on that list.
- You mean that letter where
they say you have dense
breast tissue,
but we couldn't see everything?
Yeah, I get it every year.
- So why didn't you follow up?
- Was I supposed to?
- Okay, to rely solely
on mammograms
when you have
dense breast tissue
could place you at higher risk
for undetected breast cancer.
Now, an ultrasound or an MRI
is the best way to establish
a definitive baseline scan.
- Well, when you put it
that way,
it sounds
a bit more motivating.
- And you've worked in oncology
for 15 years.
I have a feeling
that every patient on that list
needs to be having
this conversation.
Now, where do we keep the files
with the letters like yours in?
- Technically,
they're not patients,
so we just kind of keep
their files in limbo land.
♪
- She's over there.
Name's Carrie Logandorffer.
- Has she vomited
any more bowel or blood?
- Not since the ultrasound.
I still have no idea
what's causing
the shadow on her abdomen,
she hasn't passed anything.
- Just breathe, Carrie.
- This is Dr. Reynolds.
He'll handle it from here.
- Hey, Carrie,
and you must be her coach.
- Jessa Wilkes.
We're in town
for dance regionals.
We were practicing,
and then all of a sudden,
Carrie collapsed.
Then she started vomiting.
Scared us half to death.
Her parents are on the way.
- Okay, Carrie,
I'm gonna touch your stomach,
if that's okay.
Have you experienced any
other symptoms besides pain?
- Oh--just kind of dizzy.
- Okay, yeah.
We're concerned
you might have some blockage
in your belly area.
We're gonna
take a look at that.
Okay? All right?
I'll keep you posted
until her parents get here.
- Okay, thank you very much.
- Feel better, Carrie!
- Bye!
- Stay strong, girl!
- I'm still waiting
on your medical file,
but do you know if you have
sickle cell disease
or the trait?
- Trait?
I'm--I'm sorry. Sickle what?
- Sickle cell, it's common
among African-Americans.
- What? No, I'm not Black.
♪
- Dr. Fuentes.
Hey, I owe you an apology.
I had no idea who you were
when I had you bounced
out of the ED.
- Oh, it's like being back
at CBGB's.
- Indeed.
- So look, about this
little donation that we got--
- Uh, you heard about that?
- Uh, yeah. Yeah.
And if you haven't figured out
what to do with it yet--
- I'm figuring that out
right now, actually.
- Actually,
we're figuring that out.
What you got?
- Yeah, but talk to me.
- Okay, I honestly have
no idea who to look at.
both: Me.
- Anyway, what about an
elevated urgent care facility?
Better equipped
with an ED resident rotation?
- Ooh, I like
the sound of that.
- Yeah, we will take it
under consideration.
- But not before you consider
a geriatric drop-in center.
Kaboom. Dr. Ignatius Frome.
We've met before.
- Sorry, you heard
about that too?
- Seniors are just
so often neglected.
It causes higher rates
of depression, homelessness,
and I thought
this might help stem the tide
and foster connectedness,
you know?
- Yeah, uh, Iggy.
- Yes. Oh, hi.
Lame-duck, huh?
- No, no. Active duck.
- Oh, Dr. Fuentes.
I'm Dr. Lyn Malvo.
- I'm Dr. Agnes Kao.
- Chair of obstetrics
and gynecology.
Chair of neurology.
- Impressive.
- The new boss
did her homework.
- Old boss still here, gang.
- I heard we picked up
a new satellite property--
- Uh, yeah, the land
is actually already spoken for.
- But I have a great idea.
- As do I, Dr. Fuentes.
- Uh, still here, gang.
- Good, because a new birthing
facility would be optimal.
The lack of quality
prenatal care has severely
affected birthing outcomes
in this area of the city.
- And there's a lack
of neurologic care.
The area is rife
with chronic illnesses
that often expresses conditions
like seizure and stroke,
and if I had
neurological screening
and rehabilitation there,
and we reduce
our hospital census.
- Killer idea, Kao,
right next to my
drop-in center, right?
Plenty of room.
- These are all wonderful,
wonderful ideas, I have to say.
- Dr. Fuentes--
- Not you too.
- Totally controversial,
but I think laser-tag
would go gangbusters there.
That and Dr. Reynolds
wanted me to suggest
a elective surgery center
in case, you know,
you didn't go for laser--
- Guys!
Love all your ideas, really.
I don't know when this became
Land-grab Tuesday,
but the decision
for how this land will be used
will be made
the New Amsterdam way,
meaning it won't come from us.
- No, it'll come
from the community.
We'll reach out directly
to the people
and we'll find out
what their greatest needs are.
- Yeah.
That's what I was gonna say.
.
- While this land may be our
project, it is not our focus.
We're here to talk
to the community
about their needs
and their concerns,
and we're here to listen.
Think of it like an
intelligence-gathering mission.
- Okay, well,
that being said,
they definitely do not need
another Chicken O'Cluck.
- Well, whatever decision
we do make, these people
and whoever is still working
for New Amsterdam
will have to live with it
for a very long time.
So I think it's very important
that we--
- Welcome to Desmond Park!
- Hi.
- How can I help?
- Oh, well, that's
sort of my line.
- Friends call me Domino.
Whether it's direction,
confection,
connection,
I'm all about satisfaction.
Yeah, consider me your plug,
amigo.
- Oh, my gosh, that's so cold.
- Domino, I'm Max,
medical director
of New Amsterdam--not her.
So you know this area
pretty well?
- Yeah. Know it?
I grew up here
my whole life, man.
Anything you want I can get,
and if I can get it,
you probably don't need it,
yeah?
Anyway, seven bucks
for waters, each.
- I mean, look at this place.
The kids make do,
but they shouldn't have to.
Build a playground
into whatever it is
that you're building.
- So safer spaces for kids
to be kids
and for people
to actually gather.
- Yeah, and maybe
a closer OBGYN clinic.
It's hard to get the time off
to get to the good one.
It's, like, 11 stops away.
- What we need
is a homeless shelter.
My wife and I
founded this church.
Fed and clothed
at least a fifth
of the folk
in this neighborhood.
- A fifth?
That's a--that's
a lot of pressure.
How are you and your wife
holding up?
My wife's passed.
- I'm so sorry. That's hard.
I--I can't even imagine
how it would feel
to lose the most important
person in your life.
The most valuable conduit
to your flock.
That's--that's a lot.
- What kind of a doctor
did you say you were?
♪
- It's like a broken record.
That's the third
Chicken O'Cluck in five blocks.
- I guess this area is known
for its "round-the-cluck"
coverage.
- You know,
you may have fooled
some of our employees
with your faux charm,
but don't forget,
I know exactly who you are.
- Max, it's been ten years.
Please give it a rest.
- Free of charge for
the lovely medical director.
- She's not--
- Oh, Domino, you spoil me.
Thank you. Hi, fellas.
- Hi.
- Uh, we just wanted to talk
to you guys
about any ideas
you might have health-wise
about what
the neighborhood needs.
- Jobs.
Definitely better jobs.
- Okay.
- A gym would be really nice.
- A strip club.
I mean, you guys asked.
- For your health?
- Strictly for my health.
- Okay.
- I'm gonna get another chair
for Dr. Max
before he gets all up
in his feelings, all right?
- Thank you.
- Ooh.
- You okay?
Your foot all right?
- His diabetes is acting up.
- Come on.
- Type one or two?
- Two.
It used to happen when I
forgot to take my pills,
but I've been on it all year.
- You gotta rest it,
and it'll be okay.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Who's next?
♪
- Helen, to what do I owe
this pleasure?
- Dr. Ketner, hello.
Do you have any idea
how many of our patients
have kept up to date
with their mammograms,
but still have no idea whether
they might have breast cancer?
- Well, if I had to guess...
- Yes, this many.
These many people were sent
a vague letter
from your department
telling them that they
have dense breast tissue,
but that their mammogram
might not actually be
telling them the whole story.
- Well, that's not good.
- No, that's not good.
That's why radiology
is gonna reach out
to each and every one
of these people
explaining exactly what dense
breast tissue actually means,
and then bringing them in
for ultrasounds or MRIs,
as indicated.
- Nothing would
delight me more.
Place will be humming 24/7.
- Great.
- We just need you to get
new referrals for each of them.
- But it's still
just a breast screening.
It's only more targeted.
- And insurance considers it
a diagnostic exam
and they require it.
- Right, 'cause why
draw one straight line
when four crooked ones will do?
I will get this sorted,
and you--you will
be hearing from me.
♪
- Bilateral kidneys, normal.
10 centimeters
and approximately 160 grams.
- No explanation for the pain?
- No. Let's move north.
- Retractor.
- Gall bladder, liver,
all look normal.
Retract laterally.
♪
Ooh.
- That doesn't look normal.
- Mm.
Her stomach's distended.
Scalpel.
♪
Ah, pills.
- Looks like the cause
of her pain.
- A suicide attempt?
- I don't wanna talk about it.
- No, we are going
to talk about it.
- Yelling at her
isn't helping, Holly.
- Are you kidding me?
Our kid just tried
to kill herself, Clark.
- Okay, let's--let's take
a deep breath.
I know this is a lot to digest,
but I think it might be best
to call in
a psychiatric evaluation.
- No.
I wasn't trying to kill myself.
- Then why else would you take
a bunch of pills?
- I don't know.
- That's not
a real answer, honey.
Not for this.
- Carrie, look.
Self-harm is serious.
- I wasn't trying
to hurt myself.
Why don't you believe me?
- We want to.
You're not just giving us
anything to go on.
- They're skin lighteners.
The pills.
♪
I wanted them to work faster,
so I just took a whole bunch.
♪
- There's a lot of
unchecked hypertension.
- Rampant childhood obesity.
- Very few outlets
offering emotional
support services.
- Good jobs
was a running theme.
- Heart disease everywhere.
- What they really need
is a whole other hospital.
- Well, the city's not gonna
foot the bill for that.
- Then what's
our next best option?
- Max?
- Ooh!
Ah, ah, I'm good.
- Okay, easy.
- I'm good. I got it.
I got it.
- No, no, no.
Just have a seat.
You okay?
Here.
We're gonna take a look, okay?
- It's badly infected.
We can't leave him here.
- Call transport now.
- I'm fine.
- We're taking you
to New Amsterdam, okay?
♪
There's cheap fast food
on every corner,
but if you want
a fresh head of lettuce,
you gotta take two buses.
You know, that's why this area
is so full of chronic
medical conditions.
There's no nutrition.
There's no food options.
- Well, there's nothing we
can build to fix that, Max.
- Sure, there is.
We're gonna give
this neighborhood
exactly what it needs.
We're gonna build
a grocery store.
♪
- Welcome to New Amsterdam.
.
- Seriously, a grocery store?
Look, I'm all for giving
unexpected objects
to our patients.
Next time a guy comes in
with a heart attack,
we should give him
a little tinker toy.
- Your snide mockery
of original ideas,
I have so missed that.
- Oh, please,
like you've changed.
You're still the same
idealistic, noble dreamer--
- Guilty as charged.
- Wasn't finished.
- Oh.
- You know, your naivete
was awfully cute
when you were in your 20s, Max,
but now that you're
smart enough to know better--
- Well, Desmond Park
was redlined
by the government,
depressing the investment,
making it impossible for
anyone there to own anything.
You know who could afford it,
funnily enough?
Fast food restaurants,
and now it's a fast food swamp.
- Okay, I think
you're skipping the part
where this healthy--
and when I say "healthy,"
I also mean "expensive"--
grocery
can stand to make
any money at all
in an economically
depressed area.
- Right.
Well, that's the best part.
It won't have to
because it'll be nonprofit.
Oh, just when I thought your
idea couldn't get any worse.
- Here I was,
all these years later,
hoping you'd changed.
- Oh, that's not fair.
My hair's totally different.
- It's not a joke.
It's an opportunity
to make a lasting difference
in people's lives.
You were there today.
You met them.
What do you think they want?
An overpriced care center
for after they get sick
or for us to help them
not get sick
in the first place?
We're doing it.
- No, we're not, Max.
- Really? Watch me.
♪
- I need a full
debridement kit,
general surgery, and an OR now.
- My bike,
somebody's gotta watch it.
It's all I have.
- Someone grab his bike.
♪
- Ah! Ah!
- I'm hitting bone.
- Crap.
♪
- Okay, Domino, your foot
is infected really bad.
- You're gonna fix it, though,
right?
- I can't, my friend.
Look, the surgeons
are gonna come,
and they're gonna take you
to the OR,
where, most likely,
they're gonna have to amputate
your foot.
- What? No, no.
What are you talking about?
- I'm sorry.
You are in safe hands, Domino.
- No.
Hold on a second.
Dr. Bloom, hold on a second.
Dr. Bloom, please don't
let them take my foot.
Dr. Bloom, please!
Please, Dr. Bloom!
♪
Not my foot, Dr. Bloom!
Please!
- Nokic, go back to where
we picked up Domino
and grab his bike.
- What do you want me
to do with a bike?
- You pick it up,
and you put it
in your ambulance,
and you know what?
It better be here
by the time he wakes up.
♪
Go, now!
Thank you.
- But you have
such beautiful skin, Carrie.
We've always told you that.
- I'm still trying to wrap
my head around why, kiddo.
- You being adopted means that
we chose you for who you are.
Remember?
- Just tell us where
you got those pills.
- Probably on the internet.
Mr. and Mrs. Logandorffer,
uh, I'm gonna need to run
a few more tests on Carrie.
Can you leave the room
for a few minutes?
Thanks.
- Are the tests going to hurt?
- Just another blood draw.
But you looked like
you could use a break.
- Yeah, we're all
kind of crazy,
and this is...
- It's a lot.
You know, Carrie, based on
how you're dealing with race,
I'm still going to order
a psych consult for you.
- I know I'm mixed race,
Dr. Reynolds.
My bio mom's white,
and my bio dad's Black.
That's why I look the way I do.
- And you're tired of the way
your skin looks?
- Only when it causes
a problem.
♪
Like when people stare
at my family
or at the dance tournament.
- Did something happen there?
- Why do you care?
- Because you're my patient,
and you don't know me,
but sometimes it makes it
easier to say stuff.
♪
- We were changing,
and I forgot my leggings
in the van.
Coach Jessa let me go get them,
but when I tried to get back
into the dressing room,
this judge lady stopped me.
I told her I was with
the Dancing Dells,
but she said that there was
no way I could be with them.
And she just wouldn't
let me in.
Then, like, forever later,
Coach Jessa came out,
and she was mad
that I took so long.
- Well, did you explain
what happened?
- Yeah, but she said
that the lady
had just made a mistake.
No big deal.
- But it felt like one.
♪
- I just...
I just wanna be like
everyone else in my family.
♪
- Oh! No!
- No, no, no!
- Okay.
All right, don't panic.
This isn't bad as it looks.
We'll just---we'll shove it
back inside the box, right?
- They're supposed
to be alphabetical.
- Oh, my God. What?
Okay, yeah, this is horrendous.
- I started thinking today
about my legacy,
and now life has provided me
with the perfect symbol for it.
- Cautionary tale
for paper cuts?
- A big mess that everyone else
has helped clean up.
- Oh, please.
You are not messy.
You're drawn to mess.
You're dating Max, are you not?
You're right there.
- Yeah, I know.
- But the ironic thing
is that's
one of my favorite things
about him.
- Oh.
- When something isn't working,
he creates a mess
on purpose, right?
To force people
to pay attention
so that something gets done,
and if some people
don't like it
what he is "supposed" to do,
he doesn't care.
It just rolls right off him.
How does he do that?
- I mean, I suppose step one
is being a tall, hot,
straight white guy.
- Doesn't hurt.
I just called him hot,
didn't I?
I'm just--I'm just saying,
you know--
You know what I'm saying?
I'm saying we all know
that when women are disruptive,
let alone women of color,
they're labeled crazy
or difficult
or a  bitch.
And when Max does it,
he's a maverick with dimples.
- Man, who couldn't I have been
if I wasn't petrified
that the powers that be
wouldn't approve?
- Well, if you want
that legacy,
you may have to find out.
♪
- You should charge
by the hour.
- Just saying.
♪
- It's time to make
a big, old messy mess.
- Okay, then I'll just--I'll
take care of this, I guess.
Yeah, no problem.
- No.
- Just listen.
- Are you gonna say
anything other than--
- No.
- Okay, I don't get
to explain?
I don't get to make my case
to the board?
You're about to say no again,
aren't you?
- None of it, Max,
because you don't make
the decisions anymore,
not unless Veronica is behind
each and every one.
And since I conspicuously
don't see her here
joined at your hip as mandated,
no new hires, no new programs,
and just so
I'm perfectly clear,
no grocery stores.
♪
.
- Hi, you've reached
Dr. Leyla Shinwari.
Please leave a message.
- Hey, hey.
I--I know you're sleeping.
I saw last night's ED census.
Brutal.
I just called, uh...
because I miss you.
I know that's weird
and, um, very creepy,
but just...
I miss the smell of it.
I don't know. It's...
I don't know, like, you,
warm and rosy,
fresh out of the shower.
I can't--
I can't stand
being away from you.
♪
- Oh, whoa.
Unnecessary roughness
on the vending machine.
The doctor declines
the penalty.
What's up, man?
You having a bad day?
- It's just a patient.
It's not worth talking about.
- Skin lighteners?
- Yeah, this kid
is obviously struggling
with profound self-hatred.
- Yeah, well, I mean,
before we label it,
let's try and remember
she's a 13-year-old
transracial adoptee, right?
- One who almost died, Iggy,
'cause she's surrounded
by no one who looks like her
and has learned to hate
the color of her skin.
How is this anything
other than that?
- Yeah, but you're applying
your life experience
and your identity to hers.
- Yeah,
because I have no choice,
and the way she looks,
neither will she, right?
- Well, yeah, perhaps.
Absolutely.
But that's her journey, right?
Not a retread of yours.
Identity formation
is about boundary testing.
It's about struggle.
And for her, it looked like
changing the color of her skin,
which is extreme, yeah,
but it implies that
she knows there's a difference,
which strangely is healthy.
♪
- Make it make sense.
- Yeah, okay,
that was a little verbose.
You said yourself
just over there
that she is being raised
bereft of people
who look similar to herself.
- Right.
- Right?
So she could have just
as easily denied
that there was
any difference whatsoever
and grown
into a cratering reality
and just crushing her.
You know, frankly,
these are complex issues
for any teenager
to deal with, right?
So they need to be around
people who are safe for them
to be vulnerable with.
- Like another person of color
who can relate to the things
she's going through.
- Yes, and you are her doctor.
- And a Black man who has
lived through some things.
I mean, someone's gotta
help her through the terrain.
- I agree 100%, but not you.
♪
- My brother. Ah--
Damn. Thank you
- Yeah, and man, if you wanna,
you know, role-play it out
or whatever,
talk about it more, I'm here.
♪
- Do I have breast cancer?
Is this their way
of telling me?
- Big plans!
I've seen "Beaches."
- I'm just gonna--
excuse me, please.
Sorry. Ladies. Ladies!
- Thank you.
And thank you all
for your patience.
I look forward to sitting down
with each
and every one of you
and going through
the breast screening options
in detail.
- Please try to stay to one
side of the hallway, okay?
Everyone to your right.
We can't block this area.
Okay, ladies?
- We need to talk. Now.
It's like the last few minutes
of a sample sale out there.
Why would you
email them letters
explicitly saying
that they could have cancer?
- Because for years,
they've been receiving
confusing letters,
so I told them the truth,
albeit provocatively,
to get them in the door,
and now they have
a real choice.
- Being petrified
or very petrified?
- Look, half of our patients
are flying blind
on their breast health,
and we have to change that.
- But we are obviously
not equipped to do that.
You see this line?
That is just today.
- Well, then we outsource.
There's already a scan van
doing this kind of work.
We help them scale up.
We could send scan vans out
across the city.
We could make it easy.
Patients walk up.
They get their mammogram.
If they need
the extra screening,
they get it on the spot.
No waiting, no new referral,
and no extra charge.
- It's a radical
and noble idea, Helen.
Very Max of you.
But these things
don't happen overnight.
- Okay, well, maybe I can get
the ball rolling
before I leave and then pray
that my successor
keeps this a priority.
♪
How does Max do this?
- You have to accept that you
may lose as often as you win.
And from here on out, there's
gonna be a lot more losing.
♪
- Max...
Do you know why they hired me?
'Cause you're building
too many grocery stores.
Under your leadership,
New Amsterdam
is running a deficit
of 21 million per quarter.
That is $84 million a year.
COVID dried up all your most
profitable revenue streams,
and profit margins
are down overall.
- Less profit equals more care.
What else is the money for
if not to spend it on
the people who don't have it?
- Yet not all patients.
In your efforts to end
systemic racism and bias,
you have
unfortunately alienated
so many of your white patients.
- If amplifying other voices
is so threatening, then maybe--
- Max, your lobby looks like
a progressive piñata
just exploded.
- There are so many
memorial plaques
and so many apologetic
commemorative poems.
I mean, you might as well
be getting a checkup
at a Bernie Sanders rally.
- And if money is all you care
about, then why don't you
just turn New Amsterdam
into a private hospital
and shut the doors on anyone
who can't pay enough to live?
- I will take that
under consideration.
- I think that's a good idea.
- I have a lot of good ideas
for New Amsterdam,
including what to do
with that land in Desmond Park.
I am gonna sell it
to the highest bidder,
and I am going to put
that money into our endowment.
- Great, so not a single cent
is gonna go to patients
or research or new facilities.
- I already have an offer.
- From who?
- Unifell.
Huge corporation.
You might know them
as the parent company
of Chicken O'Cluck--
no, hear me out.
They want to build a factory.
What does that mean?
More jobs for the community.
- Making the very food
that's killing them.
There's no way
I'm signing off on that.
- I don't need you to, Max.
I'm gonna wait you out,
and then I'm gonna undo
every bloated program,
every underfunded clinic,
and everything that you've
built on very shaky ground.
♪
It's coming down.
- You know, all I've tried
to do is create a place
where people can heal,
people who have
nowhere else to go.
A places where they can heal
physically,
psychologically, emotionally,
and I think...
I think I've been
successful with that.
♪
- Oh, Max...
I have never
in my entire career
replaced a successful
medical director.
♪
.
- She shouldn't suffer
any long-term effects
based on our tests.
- Oh, thank God.
- Thank you.
- She's lucky.
I mean, kids are resilient.
Please. Uh...
But I would be remiss
if I didn't share my concerns
about her identity struggles
that--that caused this.
I mean, she's gonna need help
navigating through that,
and as the only biracial child
in your family--
- We're very aware
that we're raising
a biracial child, Dr. Reynolds.
- And we don't treat her
any differently
than the rest of our children.
- Yeah, but she is different.
Very different
than her whole family,
and the predominantly
white community
you're raising her in--
- You make that sound
like an indictment.
- You might be feeling that,
but I'm just stating a fact.
I mean, do you know what
happened at her tournament?
A bigoted official
didn't believe
Carrie was with her team
when she tried to rejoin them,
and then her coach dismissed
her experience
of the encounter.
Called it all
an honest mistake.
It sounds like Coach Jessa
was clumsily trying to handle
an awkward situation.
- Right, but in the process,
she racially gaslit
your daughter.
♪
- She knows she can talk to us
about anything.
There's nothing
we can't talk about.
- Yeah, but you can't
put this on Carrie,
Mrs. Logandorffer.
I mean, she's a child.
It's your job
to talk about race, right?
I mean, how else
is she gonna get comfortable
talking about it?
- We just don't
wanna make a mistake.
You say one wrong thing--
- Everyone gets so angry.
- Well, but you gotta be
willing to make those mistakes.
I mean, we've all lived
long enough to know
that there will be anger,
but you need to get over
your own discomfort
for the sake of your child.
♪
- Surgery went as well
as we could have hoped.
Just below the knee.
- Don't worry.
I got your bike
and all your merch
down in the ED.
Yo, one of my boys needs
a new pair of earbuds, so--
- See if he needs
a new bike too.
- Domino, I know
this is shocking,
but you could have died
out there on the sidewalk.
You're gonna recover,
and we're gonna help you.
♪
- Seeds?
What am I supposed
to do with these?
- Plant them.
Your diabetes
got out of control
because medication alone
can only do so much.
You have to completely change
the way you're eating
to have a fighting chance.
Leafy greens, legumes,
lean proteins--
healthy living.
- What, I'm expected
to be Farmer John now?
- Oh, I'm sorry, I thought
that I was talking to the guy
who made 50 bucks off us
in five minutes flat.
Bringing you an opportunity,
but if that ain't you anymore--
- All right, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Take it easy.
No reason to put that kind
of energy out there.
- Okay, well, that land
out in Desmond Park,
they are gonna build
something on it.
But honestly,
that's gonna take some time.
- Yeah, with inspections,
planning,
those permits gonna take longer
than a G train on Sunday night.
- In the meantime,
who's to say
what happens on that land?
- Maybe somebody
plants some vegetables,
sells the rest for a very--
- Say no more.
If it makes dollars,
it makes sense.
♪
Thank you.
- Oh, come on. I made plans.
- Healthy living.
- Hey.
- Sorry. Uh...
I know you're not really doing
the whole therapy thing.
- That's okay. Come on in.
- Yeah?
- Yeah. Actually, come on.
Come on over here.
Set up for you.
There we go.
Dust it off. Grab a seat.
What can I do for you?
- Um, yeah.
Am I, um...
I mean, uh...
Did I ruin this place?
- No.
God, no.
Why would you think that?
- ♪ I see the crystal
raindrops fall ♪
- Because, uh, I don't know.
I guess...
- ♪ When the sun
comes shining through ♪
♪ To make those rainbows
in my mind ♪
♪ When I think of you
sometime ♪
- You should go.
- Mm, just a little longer.
- Mm, no, ma'am.
I play by the rules.
I gotta take this seriously,
for you and for us, all right?
- You're right.
- ♪ Just the two of us
- And since we are
a loving, rule-abiding
polyamorous couple...
Claude deserves to know.
- Why? What--what changed?
♪
- ♪ Good things might come
to those who wait ♪
- I fell in love with you.
- ♪ Not for those
who wait too late ♪
♪ We gotta go
for all we know ♪
♪ Just the two of us
♪ We can make it if we try
- ♪ Just the two of us
- ♪ Just
the two of us ♪
♪ Building them castles
in the sky ♪
♪ Just the two of us
♪ You and I
♪
- I think you nailed it.
- Nailed it? Really?
Are you mad?
- Hey, you helped
someone today.
- Only because Adena felt bad
and got an ultrasound
out of pity.
She's negative, thankfully,
but to get that one scan,
I literally terrified
thousands of patients
in the process.
- Yeah, there's that.
- It's not exactly the legacy
I had in mind.
- If it makes you feel
any better,
think I'm gonna be remembered
as the medical director
who nearly bankrupted
America's first
public hospital.
- Oof.
♪
You know what?
That's not nearly as bad
as what Veronica is gonna do.
- She's gonna sell this place
for parts
till there's nothing left.
- You know what?
We still have five weeks.
- ♪ Just the two of us
- ♪ We can make it
- You wanna get into
some trouble?
- How much trouble?
- ♪ Just the two of us
♪ We can make it,
just the two of us ♪
♪