The risotto isn't bad, but it's not
what Chef Zane did back at Fortunato.
He replaced the rosemary
with saffron, for one thing.
And what is this stock?
Did he get it out of a can?
My fish isn't bad.
But it's not great either, I'm sure.
I warned you against the snapper.
Do you think it'll calm down?
God. I hope so.
That guy is a bit of a
blowhard, though, isn't he?
The food's not spicy at
all, you can barely taste it.
Mine's pretty spicy. Try it.
I don't taste anything.
Have you been
throwing rolls at me?
It wasn't me.
Really, he didn't.
I'm so sorry someone would
choose to behave that way. Really, I...
I'm so sorry. Really,
really, really sorry.
No, no, no, no. I swear, I...
It's not me.
A bloody tear could just mean
subconjunctival hemorrhage.
He sneezed too hard from a
cold, which caused his lack of taste.
House isn't going to care.
Does "black tie optional" really mean black
tie, 'cause I don't want to rent if...
There's been a glitch
with the wedding.
And House will be interested.
A "glitch"?
Patient had his
corpus callosum cut
to correct a seizure issue.
A "glitch"?
The seizures stopped
after the surgery.
But he's having trouble
adjusting to a split brain.
A "glitch"?
This is Dr. Taub. Tell
him about shopping.
I go into a grocery store,
everything seems normal.
I get to the checkout, and there's
all these extra items in my cart.
Stuff I didn't put
there. Stuff I hate.
My left hand hates me.
Yeah. I think
House'll be interested.
Just warning you.
I'm in a good mood
and largely pain-free, so I've
got no idea how things are...
Alien hand syndrome.
Set off by a stroke, or is
there a pony in the backyard?
Split brain. Right hemisphere
controls the left, and...
It's making life miserable.
Non-logical thinkers often do.
The current issue isn't the split
brain. The surgery corrected...
You're dissing the
right hemisphere?
Most people who have this operation
don't even notice they're missing anything.
The left brain has language,
arithmetic, rationality,
and right brain is a mute loser.
The right brain is more aesthetically
oriented, has greater facial recognition.
I couldn't have been a
plastic surgeon without it.
Yes, and where
would junior high be
without our ability to
judge people on aesthetics?
Right brain's also more
aware of the present moment,
our place in the universe.
It's a universal daisy chain of peace
and love that throws buns at people.
His present symptoms could
mean autoimmune disease,
a nasolacrimal tumor,
an infection or just a cold.
Good morning, sunshine. We got
a brand new toy, you want to play?
We need to talk.
Great. I love euphemisms.
By "euphemism," I mean when you
say something but mean something else.
Begin eliminating.
Search the home.
Isn't that locking the barn door
after the horse has put his face
between your breasts
for an hour and a half?
I'm your boss.
You're an employee.
I'm not normally into
role-playing, but if you want to...
People who get close to
you get hurt. That's a fact.
You're also a valued doctor in
this hospital. That's another fact.
From now on, we're going
to focus on the second fact.
So, this isn't you freaking
out over last night?
This isn't an emotional decision.
I'm just giving you the rules.
You can either
accept them or leave.
I slept with Cuddy.
After she helped me
detox from Vicodin.
I've been clean for
almost 24 hours now.
Okay. Thought I'd mention it.
Wow.
One for each.
That's what she said. Ah!
How's the pain?
She's probably
got some bruising.
Yeah, I get it, you're a
stud. This is serious, House.
I feel better than I
did four hours ago.
Four hours from now,
I'll feel better than this.
The other "wow." You
were sober? She was sober?
Clean and sober and hot.
Wow. This is fantastic. How
are you gonna screw it up?
Several good options.
Unfortunately, I don't think
she's gonna give me the pleasure.
She left before I woke up
and five minutes ago, she told
me that I'm just an employee.
Ha. Yes.
Well, either she's actually
in love with you and scared,
or she realized last night
was a gigantic mistake.
You were needy and
vulnerable, she was maternal.
You think she
jumped me out of pity?
No, I'm saying whatever is
going on, you need to talk to her.
Absolutely.
Does our patient
freak you out a little?
No.
If he's two people, then we're all
two people and we just don't know it.
And what does that
say about identity?
It says we're making it up as
we go along, which I find freeing.
Wow, I haven't been in a bathroom
this size since my dorm in med school.
Is that fungus?
It's from the steam buildup.
What do you think of this "glitch"
with Chase and Cameron's wedding?
It's always a sad thing when
sperm comes between people.
I hear the sperm
is very good today.
I mean, the salmon.
Go away. No other tables.
You'd let your wife keep
another man's offspring on ice
next to the frozen
peas, just in case?
That's what this is about.
She's not ready to commit to
me. She's planning for failure.
Did you know that male fruit flies
have toxic chemicals in their seminal fluid
that inhibit the
sperm of other males?
Wilson says we need to talk.
We talked. I agree.
This has clearly gone
past the talking stage.
What?
Hey. Great, did you find my MP3?
Not yet. But I got your shaving
stuff, toothpaste, deodorant,
some magazines, and this
cactus from your window.
You didn't have to do that. Really,
the hospital supplies all that stuff.
I'm still trying too hard, huh? Trying
to get your other half to like me.
No, no, no. Don't say that, okay?
I like you, which means that...
We shouldn't read into that.
Anti-fungal meds.
Ordinarily we'd
put them in your IV,
but since your right brain
doesn't seem too fond of IVs...
You should be feeling
better in a few days.
I have to get back to work.
Rick says your shift will be
waiting for you when you get back.
Thanks.
Oh, my God. I'm
sorry. I'm so, so sorry.
I'm sorry.
I have to go. I have to get
back to work. No, no, no...
Babe, wait. Hold on.
No, no. It wasn't me...
I can't walk.
Well, obviously it
wasn't the fungus.
And it's not a coordination issue.
Dehydration can cause loss of balance.
We haven't had him on IV.
No. Good skin
turgor, not orthostatic.
Could be our tax
dollars at work,
constantly building new
roadways and bridges.
Meningioma. Slow-growing.
It could extend along the
sub-osteal layer of the cranial cavity,
and be hidden by the bone.
The cancer cells are actually
re-growing a connection
between the left and
right hemispheres.
If you're right, the two halves have
begun sending messages again,
but it's too early in the
process for him to pick up on it.
But we can test for it.
Proof.
You didn't talk to her, did you?
If I'd talked, she'd
have lied, I'd have lied,
and though two
negatives make a positive,
I thought thermal-imaging
photos seemed simpler.
Note how many more heated areas
appear after less than a minute with me.
So it's either love,
or possibly rage.
Don't talk to her.
I have no plans to talk to her.
Manipulation is in
your genetic code.
You think I'm making a
mistake, you move in to correct.
You are making a mistake.
She lied to me.
Either last night or today. I
need to find out which and why.
And clearly, thermal
imaging is the way.
This isn't a case. You're
not looking for a diagnosis.
If this matters at all to you, please,
for once in your life, be an adult.
Keep your eyes
focused on the plus sign.
Any image that appears on your far
right will only be seen by your left brain,
and any image on your far left
will only be seen by your right brain.
Okay.
Just start by saying the words.
Book, giraffe,
willow, fortunate.
You're not saying the word.
I didn't see a word.
Could you draw a picture of
what you think the word might be?
Look, I didn't see...
Candle.
This is so cool.
Yeah, that's not freaky at all.
No communication.
So far.
Scott, why are you standing?
I'm a little chilly. I thought I'd get a
sweater or something from my room.
Is that okay?
Just a few more minutes.
And that, ladies and
gentlemen, is the left hemisphere.
The side that's obsessed
with finding answers,
the one that needs things to
make sense, the interpreter.
That's where we tell the story of
who we are and why we do things.
That's also the
side that was wrong.
The right brain's advantage
is that it isn't logical,
it doesn't choose
which details to look at.
It makes connections you could never see.
You owe your insight to the "mute loser."
I'll send it tickets
to a Phillies game.
Confabulation means no
communication. Means your theory's wrong.
But he is cold.
Why are you scratching?
It itches.
Ammonia breath.
Your liver is failing.
I know for them to approve this price,
they'll need statistical documentation...
What? Why are you looking at me?
When you first walked in,
I was under the impression
you wanted to say
something else.
Nope. About House and me.
There's nothing to talk about.
I want permission
to do a liver biopsy.
We're looking for sarcoidosis.
Fine.
What do you mean, "Fine"?
What do you mean,
what do I mean?
Do you mean that because
a liver biopsy is not a test
that by any stretch of the
imagination could be considered risky,
so asking my permission is
essentially wasting my time,
and you're wondering what
my reaction to that will be?
Yes.
Are you trying to make me angry?
Do your biopsy. And
also, do your clinic hours.
I'm blowing off my clinic hours.
Really?
Let's see how that goes.
Still not angry.
Try again later.
Sorry. I know I'm a little ripe.
Just a sweaty guy. Recently?
Always.
With a crazy left hand. Sometimes
I fantasize about cutting it off.
Just a fantasy. It's the
hand that's crazy, not me.
What?
If it doesn't like an ultrasound wand,
how's it gonna react to a needle?
Can you get music
into this room?
I think you're using your relationship
with Cuddy as a replacement for drugs.
You should be in more
pain so soon into detoxing,
but your body's full of
romantic endorphins,
and on top of that, you create
this distraction of looking for proof.
You think I should stop
and let the pain flood back?
Cuddy is not a
Vicodin substitute.
Quite the opposite.
You have to wait
for her to be ready.
Great advice. You pretend
that I'm going to do that.
You've made two major
changes in your life,
not a time anyone's
judgment is at its best.
Didn't you used to argue that my
judgment would be better off drugs?
Admit it. You're curious
why I want to make her angry.
I'm sure it's convoluted,
wrong and stupid.
You're dying to know what
I found on her coffee cup.
No, because... Oxytocin.
Oxytocin, the chemical
involved in emotional bonding.
Her lips say "no," her hormones
say "Oh, my God, yes, more."
No. For you to know
her levels were elevated,
you'd need a baseline
to compare them with.
I paid the guy in the gym to retrieve
one of her water bottles from the trash.
Love inspires us to greatness.
So I need to make
her lose her temper,
which breaks her delusion, which
demonstrates to me, and to her,
that there is something
underneath this facade.
And then what happens?
She admits everything
and falls into your arms?
That's outcome one.
Outcome two is she kills me.
I think it's 50-50 right now.
Great.
I thought you'd say that.
You're committing yourself
to something. To someone.
I mean, it's childish in a
way, but ultimately great.
Assuming... Are you absolutely
sure you want this to succeed?
Why is an old guy
standing in my doorway?
Eugene Schwartz.
Dr. Cuddy asked me to
come up here from the clinic.
She says you're seeing
patients in your office.
It's still free,
though, isn't it?
She sent him. That's
gotta mean something.
I'll go get my decoder ring.
I squawk. Like a parrot.
No, that's not it. It
started a few months ago.
I was doing some woodworking in
my garage. I was trying to make a chair.
Was it the chair?
Anyway, all of a
sudden, from nowhere,
this strange noise comes
bursting out of my mouth.
Tough to fake that.
Nice pants.
My wife Mona thinks I'm busting
her chops. It's ruining my marriage.
Where are we going?
So your left hand would rather play
air guitar than give me a hard time?
It'd rather play air guitar
than tie shoes, eat dinner...
Your right hand's playing, too.
I don't want to discourage it.
Splinter hemorrhages
under his fingernails.
What's that...
BP and O2 sat are dropping.
We need a bag of
B-negative in here!
So much for sarcoidosis.
Points to a clotting issue. Clots
would explain all his symptoms.
Why aren't we in the office?
I'm tired of clinic duty.
There's only one thing that
could cause squawking, right?
Yeah.
We gave him heparin
and did an echo of his heart
to see if it was
throwing clots, but...
More air guitar?
The heart's fine.
We wanted to test for Factor
V Leiden, Protein C, Protein S,
but the hand got tired of cooperating.
We finally knocked him out.
And all those tests
came up negative anyway,
or you'd have opened by
telling me your brilliant diagnosis.
He apologized for being sweaty,
said it had always been an
issue. But what if it's a symptom?
There are cancers that cause night
sweats and can lead to clots. Lymphoma.
Or pancreatic cancer.
Go scan his pancreas.
And try Led Zeppelin.
We've always remembered what this hospital
did for Leo when his appendix burst.
Still, a check this size...
Sorry to interrupt,
here's my poo.
Dr. House said to bring it over and
leave it with you as soon as I could.
I don't know if you people
have an official term for it.
Stool sample. Ah, yes.
Thank you. I'll take care of it.
It's hard to rush these things.
Even if you've eaten a lot of broccoli.
Where are you going?
Annie called. She's
not coming back.
This is not the best time...
Look, you said the heparin
would keep new clots from forming.
Maybe. But something's
obviously causing the clots.
If you have pancreatic cancer...
We're not trying to scare you,
but even in its early
stages, the fatality rate...
You walk out of here...
Stop!
Look, I'd ask you to
put yourself in my place,
but nobody can put
themselves in my place.
Did she find somebody new? Was
I not being attentive enough? No.
She's just tired of
being insulted by a limb.
She said that my feelings toward her
were mixed. Well, my feelings aren't mixed.
You're not going anywhere.
Unless you want to go naked.
Your right brain
knows you need to stay.
My right brain's an ass.
Got a minute?
There's something
wrong with this cup.
I need someone to bounce ideas
off of. Someone to be my whiteboard.
That's how you
taught me to work.
I have three choices.
First, I can accept it's over, pretend
we don't work in the same hospital,
have selective visual impairment
when we pass each other in the hall.
Second, I can accept
it's over and leave.
Or you could try
making him angry.
Standard choice number three.
Third, I can talk to him.
But it's not like I have any
new facts I can present,
and Chase has this romantic view
of love that reality can't compete with.
I know how you could succeed.
How?
Just say the magic words, "I
will destroy my husband's sperm."
You mean, succeed without
doing that? Probably not.
I have doubts. Normal doubts.
It's not wrong to prepare for bad things to
happen, even if you don't expect them to.
I don't expect my condo to burn
down, but I have fire insurance.
Patient's girlfriend left him,
now he wants to leave us.
If your condo rules don't let you
buy insurance, do you go homeless?
His room is this way.
What? You think I can fix this?
We need to offer this guy
something he can only get
if he stays in the hospital.
Relationship counseling.
I don't know if
his girlfriend is...
I mean his two hemispheres.
That's the breakfast of relationships,
the most important one of the day.
We need your special skills.
Is the guy out there?
The guy that's gonna
make my right brain work?
Oh, for...
What do you think
your right brain wants?
How should I know? It's crazy,
it does things I would never do.
Duct of Wirsung slightly enlarged,
but within normal parameters.
Say something.
It's mute. It can't
communicate with you.
Maybe you should try
communicating with it.
"Talk to her." The
well isn't deep, is it?
You're the dominant half,
you make all the decisions.
The right side has no control
over anything. It must be frustrating.
No masses in body
or tail segments.
I can't communicate
with it, that's the whole...
When you decide to go and
get groceries, what do you do?
What do you mean? I put on
my jacket and I go to the store.
Your right brain has no idea
why you're suddenly getting
up and putting on your jacket.
It just gets dragged along.
Next time, try saying it out loud.
Just say to the empty air,
"Hey, I think I'll go to the store
because we're out of peanut butter"?
How much did they teach
you about people like me
when you were learning
to be a therapist?
I'm an oncologist.
Your right brain likes what he's
saying. Hasn't moved the entire scan.
Hasn't gotten us anything, though.
Scan's clean. It's not pancreatic cancer.
Clotting could be a problem
well before a solid tumor forms.
It could still be pancreatic.
Yes, but if you want a diagnosis
backed by actual evidence,
we should probably
look at other cancers.
House. I just squawked!
What? Eugene Schwartz.
Your patient from
yesterday. I just squawked!
I was buying some flowers for Mona. It
happened when I was paying the clerk.
I assume Dr. Cuddy
gave you this number.
Yes. She told me to call you
any time I squawked, day or night.
I'm sorry, but I'm
about to lose you,
because I'm about to drive into a
tunnel in a canyon on an airplane
while hanging up the phone.
I might be getting some more
phone calls, so let's make it fast.
Lymphoma.
That's right, pancreatic.
I know it's pancreatic. I
know there's evidence.
I know we've
seen it. I just can't...
Right brain/left brain issues?
If the cancer's too small
to find, let's make it easier.
Let's open him up and paint it.
There's a new procedure using
scorpion toxin and infrared paint.
The paint only works on the cancer
cells, makes them easier to spot.
Just agitating the
pancreas can cause clotting,
and you want to do it to a
guy whose problem is clotting?
If I'm right about
pancreatic cancer,
the only chance he's got is finding
and removing those cancer cells now.
His brain MRI showed narrowing in the
blood vessels leading up from the neck.
If we do shake something
loose, we could kill him.
Or one of him.
A clot in his brain could kill one
of them without affecting the other.
He might actually
be okay with that.
How long is it going to take?
Assuming he doesn't
crash, a few minutes.
Hey, you and
Cameron... I'm sorry.
I'll be right back.
I don't want to be homeless.
Okay. You can stay in the
condo. I'll find some other...
That's not what I mean.
I want to marry you. I got
the forms to destroy the sperm.
You sure?
Yeah.
I want to hug you, but
then I'd have to re-scrub.
I know.
BP is dropping.
Go.
No sign of cancer.
BP is 90 over 60.
You never answered my question.
Relax. Our friendship
is not doomed.
Thank God. But my question
was, do you really want Cuddy,
or is this just
another challenge?
You're worried that
once I'm in a relationship,
you and me will be over.
Hey, I'm actually for
this. I think this is great.
But if you're serious, and you don't
treat it seriously, then you will get hurt.
And if you don't accept that,
then accept that she will get hurt.
I was told it was your birthday.
I understand.
So, so sorry.
I know.
Clearly, there was a mix-up.
Have a nice day.
Does she look angry?
If you're standing there
when she looks up here...
Oh, no.
Systolic's 80.
Gotta finish this suture
before I can get out.
Give him a dopamine drip.
We weren't looking
up at the right time.
Get to your point.
We're a little busy here.
The clots aren't from cancer.
They're coming from his heart.
We echoed the heart. No clots.
Not while we were looking.
Didn't I open with that?
The clots were caused
by an arrhythmia.
No arrhythmia.
Not while we were looking.
Intermittent arrhythmia.
This guy pulls our equipment
off at the slightest provocation.
We'd have to be watching at
the exact moment it happened,
which I'm guessing, given the way
you two are scrambling around like idiots,
is right now.
Yes, I'm saying do a
transesophageal echo.
We have to get his BP stable.
Absolutely. Right
after the echo.
Systolic's 70.
The heart looked
healthy at the last echo.
And an arrhythmia wouldn't
cause clots in a healthy ventricle,
so start with the
left atrial appendage.
Wow.
Yep, I did it again.
Now get this poor guy's BP under
control and seal off the appendage.
And then all we have to do is
find out what damaged his heart
before it goes after
something he really needs.
So what damages a healthy 20-year-old
heart enough to make it send out clots
like it's bombing Dresden?
Rhabdo.
Would've fried his kidneys, too.
What about Graves'?
Thyroid function
tests were normal.
Cushing's. Cortisol overproduction
could interfere with heart rhythm.
Run a dexamethasone
suppression test.
Annie.
You hit me.
I know. I'm so sorry.
But it wasn't me.
I know you would never have done that
if you were in control of yourself, but...
But you came back.
To talk with your doctors.
I've been going over
and over what happened.
And I had this
thought, out of nowhere.
Ever since I've known Scott,
I've seen his left hand throw things,
but always sort of
playfully, thinking it's fun.
But when he threw
this, it was angry.
And that's when his hand slapped
me, too, when I brought it to him.
Could it mean something?
Deodorant shouldn't...
How often do you use it?
A few times a day. It's
special, heavy-duty stuff.
I have to send away for it.
Sprayed around a bathroom
the size of a shoebox.
I'll check the ingredients
from the manufacturer.
I'll check for any references
associated with health issues.
Somebody's grateful.
We'll just leave the
three of you alone.
Why is there no
lipstick on this cup?
Cuddy was wearing lipstick
when she drank from it.
It was on my face.
Why isn't it on the cup?
Why is it always reasonable, in
Houseland, to take an emotional problem
and sidestep it by turning it
into a mechanical problem?
Because, in Houseland, and the
rest of the universe, by the way,
when a question presents
itself, it calls for an answer.
If the left brain is the
interpreter of reality
and the one that tells us the story of
who we are, then what is your story?
Do you want to be the
man with the answers?
Or do you want to be
the man with Cuddy?
What do I do?
You make her angry.
Do you really think that was
the best time to mock me?
I'm as surprised as you,
but I think I'm serious.
Communication can't
start unless you're both...
I've been trying to
make her angry for...
No, you haven't.
Come on. Poo? Strippers? It's routine
stuff. You've been pulling your punches.
You're scared.
You should be.
Now go terrorize her.
You don't want to
destroy it, do you?
I said I was gonna
do it, I'll do it.
But you don't want to.
I want to be with you. Maybe
I'm not comfortable with it, but...
Let's say it's our fifth anniversary.
Are you ready to destroy it now?
Tenth. Three kids.
They spend their summers in
Melbourne and have annoying accents.
It's disgusting how happy
we are. You ready now?
You don't have doubts.
You just don't want to kill the only
thing left of someone you loved.
Don't do it.
I do have trouble
giving things up.
For example, I never cancelled
any of our wedding plans.
Attention! I have
an announcement.
As you go about your day,
I would like you to be aware of
the fact that I slept with Lisa Cuddy.
This is beyond asshood.
You have the luxury of not
caring about your image. I do not.
I can permit a lot of crap,
but an employee shouting about
his sexual exploits with me, no.
That is zero tolerance. So
congratulations, House, I'm angry.
I was wondering if we
should move in together.
You're fired.
I wouldn't worry about
it. I think she likes you.
If I'm fired, I think that probably
means I don't have to see patients.
I'm here as a squeaky wheel.
I know how you doctors are,
you're busy, you get distracted.
My lab results could
be sitting in your inbox.
I don't need your labs,
you have acid reflux.
Well, how could you...
Acid splashes on
the vocal cords,
they tense, make that squawking
sound. It's completely harmless.
I'm gonna give you a prescription,
and you're gonna go away.
You are a great doctor.
Why'd you move your belt?
I always move my belt.
It makes me sore.
You didn't tell me that.
At 86, what isn't sore?
Soreness is less
important than squawking.
It's the squawking that
was bothering my wife.
That's not a potbelly.
That's a tumor.
That's why pancreatic
cancer was on my mind.
My brain was
trying to tell me...
This isn't sounding good.
Pancreatic cancer?
Can cause acid reflux.
We should scope you.
So it's not good. Even
for cancer, it's not good.
No, it's not.
The deodorant has a high
proportion of propylene glycol.
Same stuff made a kid in
Singapore develop a heart condition
and, get this, seizures.
Our patient may never have
needed split-brain surgery.
I'm sure he will half
appreciate the irony.
Can you take this man to
Radiology? Pancreatic scan.
And stay with him.
Eugene Schwartz.
Whatever it is,
just say it quickly.
Do you have more than one
lipstick in the same shade?
Maybe one that has a sealing
agent, and one that doesn't?
How could that possibly
be relevant to anything?
You really don't think you're just
overreacting to the other night?
Fine. I am overreacting.
You've said plenty of
lousy things to me before.
But reaching the final
straw has been a good thing,
because it made me realize we not
only don't have a personal relationship,
we never could.
You're...
You've been overreacting
to something I said?
You insulted me, I walked out.
It's nothing that hasn't
happened a hundred times before.
I quit.
Great.
My nanny is off the clock
at 7:30. So your week off...
You can go suckle the little bastard child
who makes you feel good about yourself.
Screw you.
No, no. That's not
what happened.
I told you that I needed
you. You helped me.
Are you okay?
So, this is the story you made up
about who you are. It's a nice one.
Too bad it isn't true.
No.
I'm not okay.