Previously on ER:
- What's this?
- That's for you and the little bastard.
Thanks, Frank.
- Ow! I need a total hip replacement.
- Not necessarily.
You've gotta help me, Greg.
I've been trying damn hard.
For me, for K.J.
- What's your name?
- Jose Rodriguez.
Did your drunk ass hit that kid?
The cops brought in a friend a
while ago for a blood-alcohol level.
I drew my own blood,
switched the tubes.
I made him turn himself in.
You got your friend to
own up to what he did.
Take your own advice.
Kerry? What are you doing here?
Good morning to you too, Luka.
- Thought I'd come in and lend a hand.
- On your day off?
Neela's still doing her surgical elective
and with Clemente on medical leave...
As department chief, I felt
the circumstances warranted it.
And I supported your
decision, but in the meantime...
It will be fine. Go home,
spend the day with Henry.
Henry is spending the day with
Sandy's mom at the science museum.
- If we get busy, I'll call you, okay?
- Look, I'm here now.
You are making this up.
Toilet training at six months?
Hookah bar asthma attack.
I saved the article.
I'll bring it for you.
Parking meter versus fist.
Sounds like a direct
route to the shrink's couch.
And in Curtain 1, a
severe case of over-golding.
- Over a what-ing?
- Prepare to be amazed.
- Here's a fax from the blood bank.
- Okay, everybody, listen up.
There's a statewide blood shortage.
So no extra servings if you can help it.
Employee blood-drive in
the cafeteria until 8:00 tonight.
- Got anything for me, chief?
- Oh, yes. For you, anal warts.
Every girl's dream.
- And raw oyster anaphylaxis.
- How can anyone eat those things?
- They're supposed to be an aphrodisiac.
- Trust me, they work.
Let's start with the lumbar disc, followed
by the rotator cuff and then the ACL.
Dr. Weaver, you're early. Your
surgery's not until this afternoon.
Yeah, I know. I'm
sorry. I have to cancel.
ER's getting slammed and
they begged me to come in.
And the dog ate your homework.
- I've heard this before. Twice.
- I know that I've canceled.
- But it's just not a good time.
- You can't keep doing this.
You should realize the havoc
you're wreaking with my schedule.
- You need this operation.
- Dr. Kline, can we talk in here?
You have end-stage arthrosis,
advanced degeneration...
with a piece of cartilage
that's flapping in the breeze.
I will take care of it soon.
Look, I realize that the prospect of
surgery can be scary, even for doctors.
- It's not that. It's just that I...
- Just what, Kerry?
You're in pain.
I'm sorry about your schedule,
but the ER comes first.
Fine, but I don't get it.
If I were you, I would be dying to
throw that crutch away once and for all.
- All I'm saying is you got to accessorize.
- And I can see that, Mr. Lemoyne...
but your rings and bracelets
are cutting off your circulation.
Is that why my neck hurts?
Let's see.
Um...
Your chains... Wow.
Have eroded into your
skin. It looks infected.
So you're gonna give
me some medicine?
Yeah. But infection can't get better
unless you remove your jewelry.
Oh, no, I never take it off.
I eat with it, sleep with
it and bathe with it on.
Let's see. Does it ever get in
the way of, say, airport security?
Oh, no. I don't fly.
Well, when you're having...
- When you're...
- Oh, the ladies love the bling.
I hear you, man.
All right, who left a
kielbasa in the drug fridge?
This is a clear JCAHO
violation. Who didn't know that?
- I'm guessing Frank. His name's on it.
- Tell him to keep his sausage to himself.
Do you wanna see something?
- What?
My 3-D sonogram. I just got it.
So that's his, or her, I
guess, first baby picture.
You okay? Kerry?
Yeah, I'm...
So you...
- You didn't find out what the sex is?
- No.
Luka wanted to, but I'm
old-fashioned, I guess.
Well, there aren't too many true
surprises left in life, are there?
No, and it doesn't matter
as long as it's healthy, right?
Right. So how are you feeling?
Very good. Very
energetic, actually.
That's how Sandy was. She
loved the second trimester.
The nausea was gone, she
could eat whatever she wanted.
Dr. Weaver, auto versus
peds, multiples a minute out.
Ray and Morris
are already outside.
- Be right there.
- Are you sure? You want me to get you...?
No, I'm fine. Make
sure you get that framed.
Rasgotra, perfect timing.
We may need a consult.
- That's a big lunch.
- They're cookies.
I've got an Army Spouse
Club meeting tonight.
I'd rather watch
World Poker Tour.
- You baked?
- Everyone has to bring something.
- You gonna show some love?
- The ER vultures can taste test.
All right, one cookie per
person. I'll see you inside.
Okay, fellas,
heads up. Let's go.
Donna Gallagher, unrestrained teen
driver, ejected when her car flipped.
Hit a jogger, coming in on the
next rig. GCS seven. BP 90 palp.
Ray, Trauma 1.
Passenger has facial injuries from
air bag and shoulder pain, vitals stable.
- Abby, sutures.
- Got it.
- What's your name, sweetie?
- Katherine Odachowski.
I feel you. I used to
be Abigail Wyczenski.
My friends call me Katie-O.
- Donna, can you hear me?
- BP 75 systolic, pulse 130.
- How are we doing in here?
- Nothing in the belly, no tamponade.
Why she hypotensive?
Ecchymosis on the thighs.
- Distal extremities too.
- She's in DIC.
- She has to be hemorrhaging somewhere.
- All right, let's get her to the scanner.
Oh! Her IV sites are oozing.
- She needs platelets and FFP.
- No, not with this blood shortage.
We can't give her
our last platelets.
She's unresponsive, bleeding...
- could have a head bleed.
- We don't know that.
Get me a gram of acetaminophen.
Why else would
she be unconscious?
- Acetaminophen?
- For me. Tablets, please.
Secure her airway. Let's
see what we find on CT.
By then it could be too late.
Okay, Katie, move your
head from side to side.
Does that hurt?
It's just a little stiff.
- Okay.
And I hurt all over.
And your forearms
are bruised up.
I must have hit them
on the dashboard.
Now, do you remember
what happened?
- We were at the mall.
- No school?
It was the last day before
spring break, so we cut.
But Donna got a headache and
she said she wanted to go home.
Okay. Okay, follow my finger.
The light really hurts.
The air bag could have
scratched your cornea.
BP 115 over 80, pulse 104.
I'm gonna press on your
abdomen, let me know if it hurts.
She fainted on the way home. I
tried to stop the car, but I couldn't.
Chest x-ray, shoulder series,
ICON, UA and visual acuity.
I'll set up the slit lamp.
- Thank you.
And then the car
was upside down.
I looked over at Donna, but
she wasn't there anymore.
It's okay.
Ah! NEELA: Abdomen's tender.
- Morphine, five migs. NEELA:
CBC, chemistry, coags and Foley.
This is what I get for
trying to be healthy.
Thigh deformity,
right femur films.
C-spine, chest and
pelvis. Sager Splint.
This morning, I started a new
diet and went out for a jog...
- BP's 94 over 40, pulse 140.
- Second liter of saline wide open.
When, bam, this car drives
into the sidewalk and hits me.
- Pedal pulse intact.
- Blood in Morrison's.
Two liters in. BP still 85.
Mr. Highsmith, you're bleeding
internally. You'll need surgery to stop it.
Just wait till I get my
hands on that driver.
Type and cross four
units and call the OR.
I'll look in next door.
Okay, check on Kerry while you're
there. See if she needs any help.
Sats 88 and dropping. RAY:
Laryngospasm, can't pass the tube.
Need surgery consult?
Not yet. RAY: Yes.
Well, page me if
anything changes.
- Need sux.
- Got it.
- You okay in here otherwise?
- Yeah, why?
Nothing. Dr. Kovac just
asked me to make sure.
We're fine.
Okay, go ahead, Sam.
She's bradying down.
Sats 82. RAY: Okay.
Trying again.
Neela, I need you to see somebody
in 3. And you're not gonna believe this.
Hypotensive femur
fracture and ortho's MIA.
Three more minutes
before I call your chief.
The guy's a professional
regurgitator. He swallowed a light bulb.
It's stuck in the duodenum,
so he needs the OR.
That's weird, but I can't help. I've
got a triple trauma, page Albright.
You hear the good news? Jose
Rodriguez, they're releasing him today.
Not anymore. He's
got a wound infection.
He'll need another
week of IV antibiotics.
I assume things went well with
Kovac when you told him what you did.
- You are still here.
- Right, yeah.
Neela, I got the
x-ray on our jogger.
Okay, I gotta go.
- Did you reach my parents?
- They're on their way in, so are Donna's.
Is she okay?
She's got some really good
doctors taking care of her.
Can I get something for my headache?
- Sure.
Temp is up, 101.8.
Okay, 600 of ibuprofen.
And about my bruises,
when will they go away?
They've spread.
Yeah.
- Abby?
- Okay. Chuny, put on a mask.
Call the lab for stat blood cultures,
hang two grams of ceftriaxone on IV.
Make sure she
stays in isolation.
Don't worry, you'll
be jogging in no time.
Luka.
- Time of death, 12:17.
- It's meningococcemia.
Are you sure?
My patient has rapidly
progressing purpura and fever...
and I bet this one does too.
- It was DIC from trauma.
- I don't think so.
My girl complained of headaches,
stiff neck and sensitivity to light.
I'll call Infection Control.
I put her in isolation.
We need immediate prophylaxis for all
hospital staff exposed to these patients.
- That's a lot of people.
- We're all at risk.
When can we go in? I
wanna be with my daughter.
Not until we get
her up to the ICU.
- When will that be?
- We're still waiting for a bed.
I don't understand.
How did the girls get this?
Who else was exposed?
Public Health will
need to figure that out.
We have two other children.
They need to be treated
immediately and you do too.
Chuny, let's make sure that
Katie's parents are treated...
and then show them
to the family room.
I'll get you as soon as
we send Katie upstairs.
This is County General, the
parents of Michelle Sutton called.
Here you go, Frank.
I better not get this. I
can't even pronounce it.
We're halfway through the
student list from the girls' school.
- Morris. WEAVER: How
are we doing on Cipro?
Mercy's sending 150 doses.
The pharmacy called the distributor.
They're sending more within the hour.
- Here you go.
- Can't take that, it's contraindicated.
I didn't know that.
I'll find you some...
That's all right. I'm on it.
- Did you take your Cipro?
- Yes, did you get your shot?
No, I'm researching
alternatives right now.
- You should just get a ceftriaxone...
- I wanna make sure.
- It's safe for you and the baby.
- You can't know that.
- It's category B, not category A.
- Abby, there is no category A.
Nobody does controlled
trials on pregnant...
"In most cases ceftriaxone
is probably safe." Probably.
- I'll give you the shot myself.
- You're fine with probably?
Thank you, Mrs. Riley.
Hey, Jose. How's it going, man?
- What are you watching?
- Rock 'n' Roll Soldiers.
Oh, yeah? Any good?
Yeah, it's cool.
Did you hit your head when
you passed out, Mr. Elliot?
I don't think so.
But then again, I was
unconscious at the time.
He slumped over in the back seat,
but he was wearing his seatbelt.
Malik, a little help?
What, are you giving away
free toasters here or something?
Conjunctiva are
pale. Tachy at 120.
I'll order an EKG.
Any history of heart problems?
No, my heart's fine.
Hello. Yeah. Let me
call you back, all right?
Give me 10 minutes. Yeah.
Okay, your spleen
is enlarged, so...
No, not my spleen...
Look, I'm sorry, Morris.
Thanks for your thoroughness,
but I don't need tests.
I just prefer my driver...
John, just take me home now.
I'd prefer your driver
take me home too...
but we have to stay and
find out why you passed out.
- And you are?
- Sam Taggart.
Well, Ms. Taggart,
I'm anemic from MDS.
- MDS?
- Myelodysplastic syndrome.
His bone marrow doesn't
like making red blood cells.
- Exactly.
- What type do you have?
Just the kind that requires
frequent transfusions.
Iron chelation therapy
five nights a week.
Will the owner of the
ginormous SUV parked outside...
please move said vehicle.
You're blocking the ambulance
bay. You will be towed.
John, I believe that's
us. Let's get out of here.
Wait, I have to advise
you not to leave.
You could pass out, you
could have a heart attack.
Yeah, I appreciate...
I got it. Why don't you let us
get two units into you, okay?
You're here, might as
well let us top off your tank.
- Top off my tank?
- Yeah.
All right. John, move
the car. Take a long lunch.
I'll call you when I'm ready.
Sam, CBC, retic, type and cross for four
and see if there's an open bed in Exam 3.
Where do you normally
get your transfusions?
Home. I keep a
blood supply there.
- Really? Where do you get it?
- EBay.
- Work on your injection technique.
- Come on, it didn't hurt.
I wish I didn't have
to take anything.
Don't let your mind go
there. It'll stress you out.
I'm already stressed.
I'll buy you a hot chocolate.
I don't want a hot chocolate.
What I wanna do is
worry about the baby.
- What?
- Don't reassure me.
Don't tell me
everything's fine. Don't...
- Buy you hot chocolate?
- I'm serious.
Don't you think I'd be
concerned if there's any chance...
- that something bad could happen?
- So, what? Now I'm the crazy one?
I didn't say that.
We're in this together.
Really?
- Yeah, 100 percent.
- Really?
Well, it feels more
like 60-40 to me.
Well, sometimes I'm
completely terrified.
And I just need to worry
about it every now and then...
and I need you
to let me do that.
Would it help if I
worried along with you?
We could try that, yeah.
- How long should we worry?
- Ten or 20 minutes.
- Can I have two hot chocolates, please?
- Okay.
Hold still now, Mr. Lemoyne.
- Do you have a patient belongings bag?
- Sure.
Ooh. Pizza? I didn't know
there was a collection.
- Yeah, your money's no good here.
- It's on Kovac.
All right, I'll take two.
His way of saying, sorry you
were exposed to a deadly bacteria.
Please ask for Dr. Archie Morris
when you call back. Thank you.
Hey, how'd it go with our jogger?
- He's in recovery.
He should be fine,
but I'm a pariah.
Everyone in Surgery has
to take Cipro because of me.
Frank, you're supposed to
be the keeper of my cookies.
Leaving them out anyone could
take as many as they wanted.
Probably all gone by now...
Oh.
Has anyone tasted them?
Reviews are still coming in.
Morris, have you
tried my cookies?
No, but I would love
to try your cookies...
as soon as I'm done with lunch.
Mm. I'll save this for later.
- Do you have a second?
- Yeah, sure.
Kovac, thanks
for the pizza, man.
Enjoy it, Malik.
Frank, what was all that about?
If you don't want a three-day
bellyache, lose the cookie.
How late is your Spouse
Club meeting going tonight?
Eight or 9. Why?
I made a date with this
hot girl named Ashley.
- She's really hard to pin down.
- And I should care because?
I invited her to the apartment.
I'm making penne à la Barnett.
Great, Ray. I'm
absolutely knackered.
All I wanna do after this meeting
is go straight home and watch TV.
- Please, Neela, I really like this girl.
- You like them all.
I owe you.
- What's up?
- I just made Ray happy.
You're such a giver.
- You wanna have dinner with me tonight?
- I can't tonight.
Too bad. I was looking forward
to sharing a meal with someone...
who doesn't calculate
every ounce of protein I eat.
Is Luka being a
little overprotective?
He doesn't understand
that sometimes...
the baby wants a hot
fudge sundae at night.
So I have some themes in
mind for your baby shower.
Themes?
I'm not sure I'm really the
baby shower kind of person.
We could have a tea
party with a garden theme...
or a diaper party or a
books-for-baby party.
Isn't it a little early to
be talking about this?
Maybe you want a co-ed shower?
Before you know it, the
baby's gonna be here.
- And my life, as I know it, will be over.
- In a good way.
In a good way.
We can talk about
showers next week...
but I'm telling you, I'm not wearing
a paper plate hat with ribbons on it.
Looks like fun,
can anybody play?
I was just...
Practicing.
I dropped a syringe today
and I couldn't pick it up.
- Your hip?
- Mm.
It is a pain, literally
and figuratively.
Thanks.
Have you given up on the
idea of replacement surgery?
Three times now,
including today.
- Today?
- I cancelled.
It's not a good time to be off
my feet. The ER needs me...
and what mobility I do have I
need for Henry, because he's...
All he wants to...
do these days is drive this
little hot rod that I got him.
He steers and I push.
Well, Henry's only gonna
get older and more active.
Are you afraid of the surgery?
Sorry, need the room. Kovac
just got an assault victim.
Buy you a free cup of coffee?
That's... That's very generous.
James Bucci, 21, blunt
trauma to head and chest.
Pulse in the 80s, resps
18, BP 160 over 95.
Okay, ready?
One, two, three.
Get Pratt.
- I'm Dr. Kovac, what's your name?
- Go, Huskies.
Disoriented to place and
time, but he's had a few.
Okay, how'd this happen?
Got punched by
another basketball fan.
- You know, March Madness.
- More like March stupid.
You gotta get out of the way.
Come on, this is not a playground.
Be gentle.
- What do we got?
- Bar fight, head trauma...
alert on arrival but bradied
down, hypoventilating.
- Sats only 79.
- Okay, he needs a tube.
Eight-O and a Miller two.
What's with the Three Stooges?
I'd say they can't
hold their liquor.
BP's 210 over 100, heart
rate's down in the 50s.
It's herniating.
Okay, 50 of mannitol and
hurry with that tube, Pratt.
You guys need to wait outside.
- Suction.
- It was just... It was a stupid bar fight.
- They usually are.
It was nothing. The
bartender called 911.
Probably was scared
he'd get his ass sued.
Knock it off. Knock it off!
He's gonna be all
right, though, right?
Call CT and tell them we'll be
there soon as we get an airway.
All right, I'm in. Bag him.
You're very good. I
didn't even feel the needle.
Fastest stick north
of the Mason-Dixon.
Hey, how are you feeling?
Pizza really hit the spot.
Well, I figured you
for a deep-dish guy.
Has this Dr. Morris heard
back from my primary?
You know, I am
not sure. Hold on.
Hey, Frank, can you tell Morris
I got a repeat on his 12-lead...
and can I get a
troponin to the lab?
Yeah, and do you know
if Mr. Elliot's doctor...?
- Robert Gorman.
- A Dr. Gorman has called back yet?
Okay, thanks.
Nope.
Tell me why I'm paying 20,000 a
year on personalized medical care.
I can't even get it
in an emergency.
Twenty thousand dollars?
Well, Gorman's
a boutique doctor.
Yeah, well, if there's any such
thing as a boutique nurse, sign me up.
- Listen, Ms. Taggart...
- Sam.
- For Samantha.
- Samantha, huh?
If life were fair, you nurses
and cops, firemen and teachers...
you'd all be paid like baseball
players and movie stars.
Huh! I like the way you think.
Hey, you know, if you
don't mind my asking...
what is it that you do?
We manage hedge funds.
I started out in imports and
exports, that kind of thing.
- What are we doing here?
- You're cold.
All right, I will check
back in on you in a bit.
- V-tach, lost the pulse.
- Starting compressions.
- What's wrong?
- Charge to 200.
Ready with lido.
His heart went into
an abnormal rhythm.
Clear.
Charging to 300.
- Man, I can't believe this is happening.
- Drop it, Phil.
- One of you needs to call his parents.
- Clear.
Sinus, he's back.
- I think I'm gonna hurl. PRATT:
Nope, not in here you're not.
Come on, guys. Let's
go. Out. Out, damn it.
Okay, let's get him to
CT before he codes again.
What's the matter with you guys?
Your friend's sick and you
act like jackasses, huh? Go.
Hey, make sure these
guys stay in the waiting room.
Man, we're not always like that, all right?
We've been friends since we were little.
Do yourself a favor and
get some new friends, okay?
Hey, look. Look, man.
I did it.
You know, Jimmy kept
riding me about our team...
how we had no inside game,
he was getting up in my face...
and I punched him.
Well, friends get
into it sometimes.
I lost it, man.
You know, it was just...
It was a split second and he fell
and he hit his head on the table.
You didn't mean it.
Now, believe me, everybody's
done something in the past...
that they wish they
could take back.
Look, I should call his parents, you
know, and let them know what's going on.
All right.
What do you see
when you look at me?
- What?
- How would you...?
- How would you describe me?
- I don't know.
Okay, you're a woman.
Doctor, mother.
- A friend.
- Thank you.
You're pretty.
Um...
Red-head, nice dresser...
- I'm a disabled person.
- Well, that's not how I see you.
Why not? Why?
It's... It's... It's who I am.
It's who I've always been.
That's how I grew up.
It's how I see myself.
I have never considered
myself handicapped or broken.
I don't need to be fixed.
If it weren't for
this pain and the...
The limits that I am
facing at work and...
trying to take care of my son, I'd
never even consider getting a new hip.
I don't...
This surgery is gonna
take away my crutch forever.
And everyone
says that's so great.
But what else
will I be giving up?
Who will I be then?
Okay, you should be good...
for another two weeks
before your next transfusion.
And, I'm sorry, your
primary never called back.
Don't worry about it.
Thank you for your help.
Anytime.
I'll let you in on a secret. I
fired Dr. Gorman an hour ago.
Well, that'll teach his
non-responding boutique butt.
Hey, Sam.
Alex, what happened?
- I got jacked.
- What?
A couple of older kids
beat me up walking home.
Does it hurt much?
No, but they stole
my cell phone.
That's okay, don't
worry about that.
Hey, Chuny, will you
take him to Curtain 4?
I get off in 15 minutes.
We'll leave then, okay?
- Okay.
- Come on, Alex, I'll get you an ice pack.
That's my kid, Alex.
Sounds like you and your husband will
be moving to a nicer neighborhood now.
It's just me and Alex.
And on a nurse's salary, where
we live is a nice neighborhood.
It must be hard raising a
child on your own like that, huh?
He's a good kid.
Okay, all done.
Someone will be here
shortly to wheel you out.
- I'd rather walk.
- Yeah, hospital policy says you...
Do I look like I need
a wheelchair to you?
Ladies first.
I have two sons...
and a daughter.
Denny and David
are out west now...
and Kelly's in Boca. They're
trying to convince me to move there.
Florida's nice.
If you like hurricanes
and early bird specials.
I like my view of the
ice on Lake Michigan.
- Well, it was really good to meet you.
- It was good to meet you, Samantha.
Okay, keep me posted
on our college kid.
- Good work in there.
- Thanks. You too.
Dr. Kovac.
- You got a minute?
- Sure.
- In private?
- Yeah.
Are you okay?
Morris, you have the
handwriting of a serial killer.
Excuse me. My friend
wants to ask you something.
- Yeah?
- I have this bruise.
- You think I got what those girls
have? ABBY: Let me see. Where is it?
Right there.
- I think what you got there is a...
- A hickey, right?
- Right.
- See, told you.
You're just jealous
because Kevin likes me.
- Am not.
- Are too.
Well, guys, if you go this way,
someone will take care of you, okay?
Hey, Abby, what
do you think Pratt...
and your baby daddy
are talking about in 1?
- It looks pretty serious.
- Mm.
- Maybe they're talking about you.
- You think?
Frank, I'm leaving.
I need my cookies.
- Fellas.
- Today would be nice.
Hey, Neela. We
need to have a talk.
- We?
- Yeah. Um...
Because we care about you...
- Since when?
You know, it just makes
it more difficult if you're...
Have you all been hit
on the head with a mallet?
What are you
blathering on about?
Your cookies.
- My cookies?
- Yeah.
After careful consideration
from your ER peers...
plus Hector in
janitorial services...
Just the feeling is
that your cookies are...
The worst cookies ever
made in the history of baking.
Shut up.
Bollocks to you all.
The truth hurts.
All right, if anyone needs me...
I'm gonna be in Exam 3
doing a shoulder reduction.
A shoulder reduction is tricky.
I had one where I had
to use my whole body.
Practically had to stand on
the guy to pop it back in place.
But you gotta get it right the first time
otherwise the patient's in a lot of pain.
That would be bad.
I could take this if you want.
I think that is an
excellent idea, Ray.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hm.
Frank, see if you can get
me Dr. Kline on the line.
Okay.
You falsified a police report.
Yeah, I guess I did.
That's great.
You... You know, I'm obligated to
report this to the state medical board.
- I know.
- They'll investigate...
and from what you told me, there's
little doubt they'll suspend your license.
Your career and reputation gone
because of one moment of stupidity.
- It didn't seem like that at the time...
- And now that I know...
you've involved me too.
- I had to tell you.
- What would you do?
What would you do if you were
me, huh? What would you do?
Would you risk your career for
someone who did what you did?
Dr. Kovac, Ortho needs you to eyeball
an open tib-fib before he goes upstairs.
- Dr. Kovac?
- Yeah. Just give...
Give us a minute, please.
Okay, you're
going on a vacation.
- What?
- Five days unpaid, starting now.
- You're kidding, right?
- Don't have fun. Don't enjoy it.
Spend it thinking about
what it means to be a doctor.
- Thank you.
- No, no, don't thank me.
It's not a reward.
Thanks again for letting me
get off work early for my date.
Anything for love and pasta.
Basal skull fracture
being admitted for obs...
as soon as you take
care of your head lac.
It's already irrigated,
just needs a few staples.
Mr. Gauthier, this
is Dr. Lockhart.
I leave you in her
capable hands.
Hello. How'd you hurt your head?
- Trying to stop an epidemic.
- An epidemic?
Of antisocial behavior.
Why do some parents think it's
okay for their kid to yell "doody"...
- over and over again in public?
- I've often wondered about that myself.
Or that it's good manners if little
Emma or Julian sprawls on the floor...
or hurls themselves at display
cases while you try to enjoy a latte.
So a latte led to
your skull fracture?
When I told Doody Boy
to use his inside voice...
his mom threatened
to call the cops.
I tripped over a double
stroller on my way out.
- Thank you for being on my side.
- No.
It's not that.
It's my baby, I...
I just felt it move.
- You did?
- Yeah, it's the first time.
Great. It's all
about you, isn't it?
All forms of anesthesia
involve some risks.
Although rare, unexpected
severe complications can occur...
and include remote
possibility of infection...
bleeding, blood clots,
paralysis, stroke, brain damage...
loss of sensation,
heart attack or death.
I understand that these risks
apply to all forms of anesthesia...
and that additional or specific
risks have been identified below.
That concludes the business portion
of our meeting, ladies and gentleman.
Let's eat.
I want... Just a moment.
- Neela, there you are.
- Joan, I am so sorry I'm late.
I know they're not homemade,
but they're very good.
I had a baking setback.
It must be hard.
Frankly, I don't know how you gals do it,
married to your careers and the military.
Hey, can I have
pizza for dinner?
I can cook, you know.
Yeah, but not pizza.
Someday you're
gonna turn into a pizza.
- Hey.
- Is that yours?
- Yeah, what do you think?
- It's pretty cool.
- Pretty big.
The next time you and your
mommy wanna take a ride in that...
- just let me know.
- Awesome.
- Hey, can I have a soda?
- Sure.
You wait inside that store for me,
okay? And be careful crossing the street.
Hey, John, go with him.
Great. He is gonna be bugging
me about that ride for weeks.
I meant it.
I'll think about it.
I got something else
for you to think about.
I was in a real
firing mood today.
I fired my primary care doctor.
- I fired the home-care nurse.
- Why'd you do that?
I don't know. I saw you in
action today. It got me thinking.
I could do better.
Well, it's too bad
that I'm not available.
You're not? That's a shame.
I was offering you the job.
It's very flattering, but
I already have a job.
Which you can keep.
It's a part-time job.
Flexible hours, good pay.
Just check my crit, give me the
transfusions when I need them.
The overnight chelation therapy
that's gotta be done five times a week.
Wait, did you say overnight?
No, I can't. I
can't. I have Alex.
I can't be running back and forth to
your house in the middle of the night.
That's why you and Alex would be
more than welcome to come live with me.
- Move in.
- Excuse me?
Listen, you could take a whole
section of my house right now...
and have it all to yourselves.
My live-in housekeeper, Mrs.
Harrison, has been with me 15 years.
The place is so big, I
hardly see the woman.
She can even watch
Alex after school.
What, is it you feel sorry for me,
because I'm a single-mom nurse?
We're not a charity case.
It's no charity,
it's an opportunity.
This is just weird.
Think about it, Samantha.
I look forward to
hearing from you.
So how's Michael doing
back in the saddle again?
- Bless him, volunteering to go back?
- He's fine, doing well.
- Says he's very busy. He misses me.
- Of course. He'll be home again soon.
Is Joe gonna be home
in time for the birth?
I don't think so. He'd pass out
in the delivery room anyway.
- I did.
- Seriously.
Of course I want him home.
I knew what I was getting
when I married a soldier.
The long absences, the moving
for the umpteenth time, the pay.
It's sad he's not gonna be here.
It's hard sometimes...
but that's why I'm so glad I
have Spouse Club and all of you.
Our loved ones are serving our
country, it's a small price to pay.
I think it's a huge price to pay,
especially under the circumstances.
- What circumstances?
- The way the whole thing's been handled.
How we got into it,
how it's being managed.
What exactly do you mean?
- Never mind, I'm sorry.
- No, no, go on.
Well, I still haven't seen any
weapons of mass destruction, have you?
Who's thirsty?
If you don't support the war, how do
you justify what Michael's doing there?
I don't justify it.
And I don't support any war...
but I do support our troops
and I am proud of my husband.
- Doesn't sound that way.
- You can't tell me...
that you believe 100 percent in your
heart that we should be in Iraq, can you?
- I don't think it helps to talk that way.
- Our duty is to support their duty.
My duty is to be a good
doctor and to be a good wife.
Not to be brainwashed into falling in
line with some pseudo-patriotic delusion.
I got your page. Are you all right?
- Yeah.
- They'll be in for you soon.
- Thank you.
- I thought you cancelled this.
- I un-cancelled.
My surgeon was afraid I'd
change my mind again tomorrow.
There's something
I need to ask you.
Want me to hang around,
check on you in Recovery?
No, that's not it.
If something were to happen in surgery,
I'd need someone to look after Henry.
- Nothing's gonna happen in surgery.
- But if it does.
Would you be
Henry's legal guardian?
Well, what about
Sandy's parents?
They're... They're wonderful with
him, but they're getting older and I...
I just need to know
that he'd be okay.
And you know that
it's... It's not just me now.
That Luka's in my life.
He's a good man. He's
gonna be a great father.
Look, is this even
possible to do now?
I mean, isn't there something I have
to do? Sign a legal thing? Something?
I had these drawn up the first
time that I scheduled the surgery.
Can you just give
us a second, please?
You know, sometimes
it's hard being alone.
But I've always felt like
I could depend on you.
You can.
Thanks.
Ray? RAY: Hey.
- Were you watching Ghost?
- What?
No, no, it's the...
It's the game.
- Where's your date?
- Oh, yeah.
Something happened.
She stood you up.
Yeah, fine.
You know, if that's what you
wanna hear, she stood me up, okay?
Well, you are a
mere mortal after all.
Rough night?
Is it possible to kick
yourself out of a club?
Well, to better times, huh?
Yeah.
You know, I feel very
proud of Michael...
but sometimes when I'm
with those other wives...
I start to get so
angry, frustrated...
and I talk too much.
You? Talk too much?
It's only because I miss him.
- This is utterly pathetic.
- What?
This. A married woman
living like a college student...
crying next to her
roommate on his sofa.
Okay, well, I have something
that'll make you feel better.
You recorded it for me.
Anything for my roomie.
It's lights, camera, action...
tonight on the World Poker Tour.
They play until one player
wins all the chips on the table.
Take some deep breaths.
You'll start feeling sleepy.
Count backwards from 100, Kerry.
One hundred, 99...
98, 97...
96, 95...