Previously on ER.
Well, grandma?, if
that is all you think of me
then you can keep your money.
As you wish, John.
Cancer's back.
Your bone marrow...
failed to match
the last two
potential donors.
I don't want any more chemo.
Gather all
the charts and the tape.
The tape?
We frequently tape
laparoscopic procedures.
Don't pull
so hard with the babcock.
You'll tear
the gastric artery.
‐ I'm not pulling.
‐ Oh, son of a bitch!
He's lost too
much blood. We've got to open.
We're losin' him.
Dr.Morgenstern, it's
been three minutes!
He's dying. Move!
Cubs fan, huh?
Please don't touch that.
Right. Sorry.
Before I
make any decisions
regarding your loan
application, Dr. Carter
I have to
clarify a few points.
Yeah?
You only included
one tax return, 1996
listing your income
as a surgical resident
with an annual
salary of $28,000?
Yeah, before taxes.
We'll need
your other returns
from previous years.
There aren't any. Before
that, I was a med student.
No summer jobs?
Well, I, uh, crewed
in the Whitbread in 1990.
Where was that?
Cape Town, Freemantle.
Capsized between
Sydney and Auckland.
It's a yacht race.
And you earned...?
Ah, a few thousand..
...but after living expenses..
I, uh, I spent more than I made.
You're a resident
in emergency medicine now.
Is that correct?
Yeah.
When I shifted from surgery
I agreed to do so without pay
but I'm gonna ask for a
paycheck next year for sure.
I would hope so.
What about this trust fund?
The holdings are in
my grandfather's name
and I am no longer
drawing funds from it.
Would your grandfather
be willing to cosign
for your loan?
You know, I‐I want my
application to be judged
on its own merits.
On its own merits,
I'm gonna have to reject it.
Why?
'I think you should
either talk'
to your grandfather
or acquaint yourself
with the ingredients
of a peanut butter
and jelly sandwich.
Peter.
Oh, Dr. Morgenstern.
I, um, I
looked over your report
for the Morbidity and
Mortality conference.
It...it was quite evenhanded.
Well, I just
charted what happened.
Sometimes these things can
become so "he said, she said"
but there's
no need for that.
No, no.
Contact the journals.
Lizzie and I just did
an aortobifemoral bypass
in two hours, 20 minutes.
Well, that's wonderful, Robert.
So, is M&M still on,
or can I buy Lizzie
'a well‐earned five egg omelet?'
No, it's still on.
Huh, looks like you're not out
of the hot seat yet, uh, Peter?
'Will Anspaugh
be joining us?'
No. He requested that I
messenger the meeting notes
over to his house.
‐ Is the funeral today?
‐ Yeah.
I sent flowers
from the department.
Well, looks like
a cruller and a Coke
is all we have time for.
My treat.
♪ 'Tis a gift to be simple
'tis a gift to be free ♪
♪ 'Tis a gift to come
down where we are to be ♪
♪ And when we see ourselves
in a place that's right ♪
♪ We will be in the valley
of goodness and light ♪
Hey, Mark?
I'm going to a surgical M&M.
Can you
cover for an hour?
Sure. No
problem. What's going on?
It's the
Swanson laparoscopy.
Oh, right,
Peter's case.
No, it's
actually Dr. Morgenstern.
Right. Well, have fun.
I will hold down the fort.
Thank you.
‐ I thought you said..
‐ Hi!
I thought you
said he was the best.
He is. He
rolled over my med school loan
into some kind of
Sallie Mae, Fannie Mae
Ellie Mae, whatever.
All I
know is I don't have to eat
every meal out of a can anymore.
'Hey, Carter'
you catch
that Sox game last night?
Missed it.
Center fielder, pop fly
catching a few z's. Pay up.
I'm a little short
right now. Can I get you?
Yeah, sure. I know
you're good for it.
Hey, I had an aunt who made a
killing selling Tupperware.
Tupperware.
They're those
plastic storage things‐‐
Oh, I know what
Tupperware is, Anna.
How about, uh, Amway?
You're really
enjoying this, aren't you?
Yeah, a little.
Heads up, doctors.
'Carter, you're up.'
This day keeps getting
better and better, doesn't it?
Alright, Grabarsky,
who you got?
Mike Lembreaux hasn't grasped
the know‐when‐to‐say‐when thing.
'Fell over a curb.'
Uh, curbs, huh, Mr. Lembreaux?
Maybe we should
have those removed.
His wrist
looks pretty bad.
From the smell of things
we can skip
the pain medication.
Let's go check out
that wrist, Mr. Lembreaux.
I wanted to eulogize
him somehow, but I, uh..
I never felt comfortable
in his mother's church.
So austere.
No pomp and ceremony
just...silent judgment.
I thought the silence
was for contemplation.
It's just...well.
You could imagine how
her Quaker parents felt
when she brought
home a west point man.
Well, you ended up
getting married.
Yeah.
The hawk and the dove.
Long time ago.
Scotty...wanted you to
have the stuff in this box.
Green Day.
Surprised he didn't
burn a hole through this one.
What?
"Soap Opera Digest."
I knew he was getting those
future plots from somewhere.
Finally, let's remember
the most important aspect of M&M
is not to linger
on our missteps
but to analyze
every case as a teaching tool.
Dr. Benton.
Thank you.
Probably gonna to need
a reduction.
I'm thinking open reduction
and internal
fixation in the OR.
Not so fast. We don't need
surgery anymore..
'Go away!'
'Yeah, I
got my real'
ones knocked out..
‐ Please help him.
‐ In Joliet.
‐ He can't breathe!
‐ 'Hey, hey, hey.'
He can't breathe.
Hey, I'm just showing
him a thing or two.
Keep breathing
on the nebulizer.
Hey, Mr. Lembreaux, why
don't you leave this kid‐‐
Get him out of here!
Will you get him out of here?
Put your teeth
back in your mouth.
Hey, I got
a talking right.
Can talk to anybody I want.
Deep breaths, alright?
You can't
tell me what to do.
You better leave
me alone before I...
Hey, hey, hey!
Guys, get some
soft restraints!
Leave me alone!
Stop it! Leave me alone.
Please help him!
Okay, buddy.
Here we go.
Come on, buddy,
you're gonna be fine.
He's cyanotic.
I'm going to intubate him.
His right
wrist, it might be broken.
John, I'm going to intubate him.
Give me 40 of ketamine.
What the
hell are you doing bringing
a psycho in here with a kid?
Sorry. I didn't realize.
The boy is
a critical asthma patient.
Nobody gives a damn
about pedes. 5.0 ET Tube.
I'm really sorry.
Give me suction.
Dr. Morgenstern's attempt
to control the hemorrhage
by midline incision was futile.
Variceal bleeding
obscured the operative field.
‐ We were getting it in control.
‐ Okay?
'It was difficult to find
the bleeding site.'
What did you do next?
Called for additional suction.
After which, you decided
to change course
and open the chest.
And who made that incision?
I did.
Dr. Morgenstern
allowed you
to crack the chest?
‐ Well, not exactly.
‐ Well, actually..
...I didn't feel it was..
'Gentlemen?
One at a time.'
Dr. Benton?
I, uh, I took over the surgery.
'What do you mean take over?'
How could you take over?
In the, uh, heat of the moment
Dr. Benton became agitated.
'Dr. Benton?'
I pushed him aside.
'Peter, what
was your justification'
for such an action?
‐ The man was bleeding out.
‐ 'And?'
Actually, the
midline incision was adequate.
‐ It was the varices.
‐ No.
The man needed
to be cracked immediately.
And that justifies committing
battery on your superior?
The man was dying. What would
you do? Stood there and watched?
I would have assisted the
attending in saving his life.
Okay, after three minutes
of arterial bleeding
and profound shock,
cross‐clamping the aorta
was the only alternative.
No, Peter, I don't think
it was the only alternative.
No. It was
the only alternative. If we‐‐
'Alright, gentlemen.'
I think it best to adjourn
and convene the Resident
Review Committee at 12:30
'to discuss the situation.'
I agree. Dr. Morgenstern?
Um, yes.
I‐I think that
would be for the best.
Hey, what do you have here?
28‐year‐old woman,
18 weeks pregnant
found unconscious
at the scene.
GCS 11,
multiple lacs, vitals stable.
Let's go.
Chicago Reproductive
Center was, was bombed.
The abortion
clinic on Riverside?
Oh, they also do prenatal
care and family planning.
They're still extricating
people from the rubble.
Blowing up
clinics. Bastards!
‐ How many have we got?
‐ No idea.
It's complete chaos down there.
Got a 17‐year‐old,
second trimester.
Complains of chest
and abdominal pain
shortness of breath.
BP's real low 80/50
pulse 120, resps 24.
You're going to be okay,
sweetie. You're at a hospital.
They're gonna
take care of you, Zoe.
‐ Donny?
‐ No, I'm right here.
‐ What's her name?
‐ Zoe Kearney.
A wall fell on her.
How far along is she?
Six months, give or take.
Clear trauma one!
No, we cannot
release patient information
over the phone.
The hospital has no
official comment at this time.
Dr. Weaver, it's the
Trib on line three.
They want to know if any
abortion docs were killed.
They're called
"gynecologists," Jerry
we don't have any information.
A van load of protesters
with minor injuries
just came in.
Triage them,
leave them in chairs.
We're swamped with criticals.
Nurse, please, there's
something wrong with my ears.
They're ringing and
there's no one helping me.
We're really
busy but someone will
get to you as soon as they can.
No, please! I've been in
a bombing for God's sake!
I know. We'll get you
a room as soon as we can.
Hey, you should have
somebody look at that.
‐ What?
‐ 'Your head.'
‐ 32 French.
‐ Urine dip's negative.
‐ Blood gas?
‐ PO2 89, PCO2 25.
Ph 7.29 on ten liters.
Oral alignment okay.
Crit's down to 27.
Fetal heart rate 140, no
contractions. Mom's 110/60.
‐ Where's my boyfriend?
‐ He's outside.
‐ Is he okay?
‐ He's fine. You just relax.
Do you still want the blood?
Hang a unit of packed red cells.
Alright, let's get her to CT.
Come on,
let's go. Got it?
'Yeah.'
Send her blood to radiology.
Where is
she going? What's goin' on?
Taking her up to CT.
Alright, what's on the scope?
Sinus tach at 120.
Let OB
know where we're going.
I'm right here,
Zoe. I'm right behind you, okay?
Was she in for an
abortion or prenatal care?
Um, she's
18‐19 weeks.
Kind of late
for an ab, don't you think?
We've got
fetal heart tones 145.
Okay, CBC.
'Type and
cross for four units'
and cath a urine.
Pulse Ox 98, BP 90/70.
Good cap refill.
Also get a chest.
Uh, shield her abdomen and let's
'prep her for a pelvic.'
I've got her clinic chart.
Brianna Thomas,
18‐week pregnant nullip.
In for an elective
suction extraction.
An abortion?
Yeah, looks
like they didn't finish.
BP's dropped,
80/50. Pulse 110.
She's hemorrhaging.
We need to complete the ab.
'Grab a
gyn tray. Grab a tray.'
We need to evacuate
the uterus.
Now, doctor.
I can't.
Speculum. Betadine!
Set suction on high
and get me a size..
'...a size‐14 cannula.'
Let's go!
Second liter's in.
'Hang a
third and repeat a crit.'
Hey Anna, can I,
uh, speak to you for a moment?
Sure.
Alright Kerry,
you want some coffee?
'No, thanks.'
So what happened
in that trauma today?
I'm sorry. I froze.
Can't happen.
I couldn't
complete the abortion.
‐ Why not?
‐ I don't know.
The fetus was
so far...along and..
Well, what
about Brianna Thomas?
She was your patient
and she was hemorrhaging.
I don't know.
I didn't ex..
The baby had
a chance, you know?
Look, there are plenty
of patients and procedures
that we
might find distasteful.
Distasteful?
Come on, Kerry.
I'm not squeamish.
It just felt wrong.
We can't allow
our feelings to dictate
the standard
of care that we give people.
And I don't.
But you did, because of your
moral objection to abortion.
I don't have a moral objection.
Well, something
happened in there today.
I'm his son, Burke.
He lives with me and my family.
How long has he
been wetting the bed?
I don't know. Maybe two days.
Smelled pretty bad.
Oh, he's
had urine infections before.
Right.
Temp's 102 and
he looks dehydrated.
We tried to get him
to eat or drink something
but he won't.
Alright, let's start
a line of normal saline.
Give him 500cc bolus
CBC, chem 20, blood cultures
times two. Urine C and S.
'Got it.'
Uh, I don't think that's
really all necessary, doctor.
'Before, they
just gave him antibiotics.'
'It cleared it all up.'
We need to do a full evaluation.
Look if you're worried about
being sued I'll sign something.
Got nothing
to do with being sued.
So you're gonna poke
him and prod and test him
and then
thousands of dollars later
you'll give him
the antibiotics.
And send him
on his way, am I right?
Why don't you
go back and have a seat
while we work on your dad?
Unbe‐friggin'‐lievable.
Chuny, you
want grab a blood gasket
to show
Mr. Newton here to chairs?
I can show myself.
He's a charmer.
When's the last time
anyone bathed this guy?
From the looks of these bedsores
'about the
same time they turned him.'
So much for honor thy father.
'No, I don't understand
your argument, David.'
'The decision
has been made.'
Dr. Benton allowed his emotions
to get a little out of hand.
Other than that,
he's a good resident.
Who committed
battery on his attending.
It is a shame.
Peter's a good surgeon
But you can't let
something like this stand.
'Like you said, Dr. Weaver'
the decision
has already been made.
Unless you have
a problem with it, David.
No.
'Deborah, would
you ask Dr. Benton'
to come in, please?
'Dr. Benton, we have
reviewed Dr. Swanson's chart'
'and the autopsy.'
Well, I thought
the autopsy was inconclusive
due to
the state of the body.
This committee feels the matter
warrants further investigation.
Well, I don't know
what to say.
I mean, everything
I saw and did
is right here
in this report.
'Chart aside,
you pushed an attending.'
You're being
taken out of the rotation
pending a
formal inquiry.
You're suspending me?
'Until Dr. Anspaugh
returns and a full'
investigation can take place.
Well, uh...just how long
before I can return to my job?
'We don't know yet.'
This is effective...?
'Immediately.'
She threw 3 PVC's,
unifocal, no R‐on‐T.
Should I give her lidocaine?
'Three? No.
Let's observe.'
'Her chest tube
stopped draining.'
300ccs.
Resps are
a little high at 26.
Zoe, we looked at your CT.
There's no
evidence of organ damage.
We still want to admit
you for observation though.
‐ For how long?
‐ Oh, we're not quite sure.
'It's kind
of hard to breathe.'
‐ Pulse ox always 94?
‐ No. It's down.
I'm fine.
What what about the baby?
You have
fetal heart tones
which means
that the baby is alive.
As for kicking,
you're going to have to tell me.
We should
name him Lucky, huh?
Her. I have a feeling.
'You want
to see him or her?'
We're gonna do an ultrasound.
Yeah, cool.
‐ Zoe, what's wrong?
‐ BP's down to 60 palp.
‐ 'Tell me what's wrong.'
‐ Are you in pain?
Pulse ox 90.
She's bradying down. Let's
go, hon. Hang on. Step back.
‐ Pulse is 40.
'‐ She's fine.'
‐ You got to give us room‐‐
‐ She's fine.
‐ To work here, Donny.
‐ Oh, no, oh, no.
‐ Oh, no, no.
‐ Pulmonary embolus?
Probably. Repeat
a gas, .5 atropine.
Damn.
Alright, start CPR.
This one
is almost to the bone.
I've seen all I need to see.
I'll put this
paper work through.
Hopefully, we'll get Mr. Newton
into an extended care
facility by the end of the day.
I'd appreciate it.
I just need you to sign this
and I'll run it down to the
courthouse this afternoon.
Thank you for taking
care of this so so quickly.
I wish I could say
it was my pleasure.
But you see how people treat
their own parents, you know?
Yeah.
Hey, hey.
Dr. Carter, what gives?
I've been
sitting here forever.
Your father exhibited
textbook signs of neglect.
That's crazy.
He hasn't been
bathed for weeks.
He's covered in feces.
He's got
bedsores to the bone.
I've recommended
that he be placed
in an adult care facility.
Oh, you don't have any say here.
‐ I have power of attorney.
‐ Not anymore.
The hospital has claimed
temporary guardianship.
Really? Who's
going to pay for that?
I'm in charge
of the Medicare.
His Medicare
payments will be transferred
to the facility
he's placed in.
Expect to hear
from my lawyer.
Look forward to it.
Feels like
there's something in there.
With all that
glass flying around
after the explosion
I didn't want
to take a chance.
No. You did the right thing.
It's so sad.
These extremists..
...blowing up
buildings with people inside.
Yeah, it's pretty stupid
if the idea's
to save lives, huh?
Exactly.
I marched
with Dr. King in the '60s.
I thought the world would
learn something from him.
Yeah.
Would you, uh, put your
chin up here for me, please?
Must be
hard on you as a doctor
and, of course,
a young woman
to know that for
every life you save
they're taking one
away in that clinic.
I, uh, I don't think
about it like that.
I don't think
a lot of people do.
It's like
that old poem about the Nazis.
You know, first,
they came for the Jews
then for whoever
and when
they came to take me‐‐
Doctors who
perform abortions aren't Nazis.
Of course not.
But if you sit around while
they're taking the children
then who's next?
Alright, I see
something in there.
Oh, I knew I
wasn't crazy.
Okay, hold real still for me.
‐ I got it.
‐ Oh.
Okay. You're all set.
If you have any discomfort,
you can take some ibuprofen.
Use these
drops four times a day
and, uh, come back
tomorrow for a recheck.
‐ Thank you.
‐ Mm.
Um, this is some
information on our group.
We hold rescue strategy
meetings every Wednesday.
‐ The address is on the back.
‐ No, thanks.
Okay.
Oh, can't forget this.
Hey, Miss Martinez.
You forgot this.
I thought we felt the same.
No, we don't.
You're not
a peaceful protester.
That sign is a call to arms.
The bomber probably
saw it or one just like it.
It's reality, doctor.
If it upsets you,
then it's done its job.
The only job it's done
is to encourage violence
and yes, that upsets me.
She was okay before this.
She was, uh, she was
fine, she was talking.
'She had
a clot in her lung.'
'It deprived
her brain of oxygen.'
'There's no
way anyone could have'
'predicted it'd
would happen.'
'Are you sure?'
We're going to do
an EEG. and a brain scan
to confirm it.
Um, so, she's in a coma?
It's like
a coma, yeah.
Yes.
Uh, um...
people come out of comas.
Not when the brain
'has been deprived of oxygen'
'as long as Zoe's has, no.'
What about the baby?
Baby appears to be fine.
Can you save her?
Probably.
I think so, yeah.
And it's a girl?
Yes.
You hear that, Zoe?
You were right.
It's a girl.
Wanted to talk
to you before I left.
‐ Aren't you on till 7:00?
‐ No. I've been suspended.
You're not serious?
Yeah, well, I
wish I wasn't, you know‐‐
Need help here now!
Look, I'll call you later, okay?
‐ What have we got?
‐ She's my trainee.
She got crushed
underneath some unstable debris
during an extrication
at the reproductive center.
Thought we took care
of the clinic traumas.
People were trapped
underneath the rubble.
BP's 60 palp,
pulse 150 and thready.
IV's infiltrated.
Poor cap refill.
Dr. Corday.
Oh my God, Allison.
Clear trauma one!
‐ EBL on scene?
‐ Half a liter.
I hope you didn't mess up
my beautiful fibular graft.
48‐year‐old custodian
multiple deep lacs to
the left chest and back.
'Lost a liter at the scene.'
BP's 70/30.
Pulse thready at 144.
Sir, are you with us?
‐ Peter.
‐ I'm on my way home.
Very funny. Let's go.
Mark, I'm not joking.
I've been suspended.
'Not by me you haven't.'
Come on. I need you.
Alright, let's
get six units O‐neg.
Call the trauma team.
Tell them we're on our way.
Alright, let's roll him.
Open pneumothorax.
Let's tube him.
Ah, damn it! We got a pumper!
‐ No pulse!
‐ Alright.
‐ Start CPR.
‐ We need to crack him.
Thoracotomy tray. Let's move.
‐ Cricoid pressure.
‐ Here's your 10 blade.
7.5 ET Tube. Let's go.
‐ 'Suction.'
‐ Alright, there it is.
Traumatic aortic
dissection and rupture.
I'm in. Hyperventilate him.
Could you get the Statinsky in?
No. I'm sticking
my finger in.
Don't let go, Peter,
you stopped the bleeding.
Alright. I'm
holding CPR. Carotid pulse?
Faint.
Hey, pump in more O‐neg.
Let's get him upstairs.
Malik, you're gonna stay
with us, keep bagging him.
Let's go,
people! Go, go, go!
Alert the bypass team.
You set
the pace, Peter.
‐ We're following you.
‐ Watch that IV!
Call the OR,
and tell them we're coming up!
Dr. Benton,
I thought you understood..
Not now. He's tamponading
an aortic tear with his finger.
Come on, people,
don't jostle the gurney.
Alright, well, carry on.
Alright, hit five.
We need four units
O‐neg on the infuser.
What's up, Lizzie?
Decreased
breath sounds
hyper‐resonant, hemopneumo.
I've got the chest tube.
Can we
give her morphine?
‐ Check the BP first.
‐ It hurts.
You've got multiple
rib fractures. Try not to talk.
Now, where have
I heard that before?
Thoraseal's filling.
We need
an abdominal CT.
She's unstable
do a peritoneal lavage.
Type and cross
for eight and spin a crit.
Pulse ox is down, 90.
Here's the O‐neg.
You want me to do it?
No.
You do it.
Okay.
‐ Hey.
‐ Uh, hi.
I, uh,
I'm sorry to wake you up.
I was just resting my eyes.
I brought you some
orange juice and a sandwich.
I figured
you might be hungry.
Thanks.
You feeling okay?
Fine, considering.
‐ Were you my doctor?
‐ Oh, no.
That was, uh...Dr. Weaver.
Two docs
no waiting, huh?
My boyfriend
brought by my clothes
so I'll let you
have your bed back.
Are you sure you're
feeling well enough to go home?
Yeah, like I said, I'm fine.
I'd I'd just rather be at home.
So if you don't
mind giving me some privacy
I'm going to get changed.
Okay. Sure.
Sorry.
Doctor?
Hi, Mr. Newton.
How are you feeling?
I'm tired.
That's from the dehydration,
malnutrition mostly.
Where‐where's..
...where's Burke?
He left.
He deals with the..
...the paperwork.
Your son is no longer
your guardian, Mr. Newton.
For the time being...I am.
But why? What?
'The elder abuse unit
is filing paperwork'
'to put you into a home.'
But...I have a home.
You have some very serious
medical problems resulting
from what we believe has
been some very serious neglect.
I'm 86 years old.
I've slept in the same bed..
...for 70 years.
I'm...just trying to help you.
I want to die in my own bed.
You're not
sterile. Go scrub.
Not letting go.
Get ten
units packed cells. Let's move.
Okay, people,
on my count.
One, two, three.
Alright, let's
get this gurney out.
Alright, Mark,
help me roll him.
Alright.
Open an instrument tray.
No one's
gloved and gowned.
Come on. Just do it.
Get gloves, gowns,
masks and caps in here, now.
Ah. Okay, ten blade.
‐ Get him a mask.
‐ Let's move.
Tonsil sucker.
Alright, I'm going
to mobilize the aorta. Metz.
Let's move.
Let's move. Come on.
What's going on?
Peter's got his hand
on this man's aorta.
Potts clamp.
I'm going to
do a revised clamp and run.
Got a second Potts.
Stand by. Got it.
Okay, you
can take your finger out now.
Set up the bovie.
Pulse is stronger.
Okay, let's go for a BP.
3‐0 prolene on a
vascular needle, here we go.
Suction, please.
Somebody hoover that.
Systolic's up to 80.
Terrific.
Okay. We can take over now.
Bovie, please.
A 3‐0, please.
Keep them coming.
'Retractor and bovie.'
'4 x 4 on
a sponge stick, please.'
'Cut that.'
Good, good, good.
'3‐0. Keep them coming.'
'This is looking
very good, very good.'
Oh, sweet Jesus.
There's got to be
some other kind of test.
‐ My angel. Sweetheart.
‐ What's he doing here?
He was with her
when the clinic was bombed.
I bet he was.
We were getting
a prenatal checkup.
You killed my daughter.
I hope you're proud of yourself.
Miles!
If she stayed
with the two of you
she would have killed
herself a long time ago.
Everybody everybody
needs to calm down.
He needs to get the hell
out of my daughter's room,
that's what needs to happen.
I love her.
You guys treated her like crap.
I'm calling an OB Consult.
Why don't you come with me..
...and give
them some time alone?
Alright? Come on.
Here we go. Come on.
'She's been
in asystole for 20 minutes.'
‐ 'Let's call it.'
‐ Another seven of epi.
She's already had ten, Lizzie.
And we got a response,
seven more.
Two agonal beats.
It's not a response.
Let's start an epinephrine drip.
Why don't we also give her
a heart transplant
while we're at it?
Why don't you just
stop being such a prick?
Get me two units
of packed cells!
Thank you.
Dr. Weaver?
Yes.
I just wanted to say
thanks for all you've done
for me today,
the abortion and all.
Right. You're welcome.
It's got to be the most
memorable one I ever got.
You've had others?
A few.
I really thought Earl
would want this baby.
Like it would help
him get serious about us
but when he found out
he hit the roof.
You know
our clinic can advise you
on methods of family planning.
Earl doesn't like that stuff,
and those pills make me fat.
Still, there are
preferable forms
of birth control than abortion.
Why are you being
such a bitch?
Because you're
being irresponsible.
More likely it's 'cause
you don't get any yourself.
'And it's a very
difficult decision.'
'Neither of which
will bring Zoe back.'
'That's true, but if the
decision is to keep the baby'
'then you really
have two options.'
'The first is that we
perform an emergency C‐section.'
'We deliver
a very premature baby'
and then we take Zoe
off the respirator.
That means the baby
would have to go
in an incubator, right?
That's right.
Probably months
of intensive care.
What's the
other option?
The other
option is that we
keep Zoe on life support
until we can deliver
the baby full term.
And what
do you recommend?
I'd recommend
the later delivery.
So..
you're suggesting
that our daughter..
...be made into
a human incubator
even though
she has no chance of recovery.
It's the baby's best chance.
I don't want to
see Zoe left lying there
like some...kind of vessel.
She wanted this baby
more than
anything in the world.
You have no say
in this matter.
I'm the baby's father.
I'm Zoe's father.
And you and she are minors.
The decision..
..is mine and her mother's.
They can't
do this, can they?
I'm sorry it took us
so long to get to you.
Oh, I understand.
I was just
really freaked out.
It's not every day
the waiting room
you're sitting
in explodes.
Yeah, understandable.
Okay, you're all set.
Just keep it elevated and dry
and come back in two
days for a recheck, okay?
Okay, yeah.
Uh, you left
your insurance form blank.
Yeah, I left
my card at home.
Is there someone you
can call to come and get it?
Uh, no, I'll pay cash.
Oh, that's not necessary.
Your insurance
will cover this.
No, I know, I know.
I just, I, um
I don't want my husband to
know that I‐I was at the clinic.
Oh.
Yeah, I thought
I was too old
for this kind of
thing to happen.
Then I started to puke
up corn flakes every morning
and now I have to
find a new clinic
preferably one
that is not ticking.
So you haven't had
the abortion yet.
No.
And if my husband finds out
he just
won't have the heart.
Our youngest
daughter's in college.
He put all four
kids through college.
He worked five years
past his retirement
to be able to
pay for it, and..
I've never kept anything
from him before but..
What if you told him
what you just told me?
I can't. I'd love to,
but...I can't.
‐ Anyway, what do I owe you?
‐ Don't worry about it.
Just bring me
your card tomorrow morning.
I could leave a license
or something as collateral.
It's alright.
I trust you.
Thanks.
Oh, and if..
...uh, anybody asks..
...you can get a laceration
like that from a dog bite.
Hey, Shirley,
have you seen Dr. Corday?
She's still in OR Three
with that
paramedic, Beaumont.
Okay, thanks.
Hey. She made it, huh?
Mm‐hmm.
What's wrong? You okay?
Yeah.
It was,
uh...it was scary.
You can
put them back together
but, uh, you can't
keep them that way.
'Scotty always had such..'
'...great school spirit.'
I think I can speak
for the whole team when I say
we're really
going to miss him.
I was going to sing a hymn
but as I'm sitting
here thinking of Scott..
...here's a song that he loved..
..and it'll
always remind me of him.
♪ Another turning point
a fork stuck in the road ♪
♪ Time grabs you by the
wrist directs you where to go ♪
♪ So make the most of
this test and don't ask why ♪
♪ It's not a question
but an answer learned in time ♪
♪ Something unpredictable
but in the end that's right ♪
♪ I hope you had
the time of your life ♪
Hey, Zadro. Fancy seeing
you on the surgical floor.
'Cause I just wanted to tell you
we all appreciate what
you did for Allison.
Yeah, well, she's a fighter.
With a damn good
guardian angel.
Um, Lizzie, I, uh..
I just
wanted to apologize
for, uh, the way I spoke
during the Beaumont surgery.
I know that she
means a lot to you
and I, uh, just hope
you'll forgive me.
Of course.
It's been a
crazy day for all of us.
Um, I, uh, I get
off in about an hour.
You want to, uh, get
a drink, uh, decompress?
Look, I'm knackered.
Uh, any other day.
‐ Okay?
‐ Look, I understand. Look, um..
...If you change your
mind, you have my home number.
Yes, I do.
David?
I forgot what
this place was all about.
The teamwork,
the well‐oiled machine.
What?
I've let the situation
get...completely out of hand.
I told myself
the varices were too friable
that my field was obscured,
that I‐I was protecting
Dr. Swanson's dignity.
I wasn't.
I was covering my own ass.
Look, if you make a mistake
that's all that it is.
No.
No. It's more than that.
What are you watching?
What am I not watching?
That's the question.
This is the tape of
Swanson's laparoscopy.
Where did you get it?
I...I took it...
right after the surgery.
I've been too chicken
to look at it.
I guess I thought we
could avoid a confrontation.
A resident can take
a note in his file.
Right? Peter's got
so much less to lose.
I could toss this
right now.
No one would
be the wiser.
You wouldn't
have called me up here
if that's what you
were going to do.
Jeanie...I wondered
where you'd gotten to.
I'm just
sitting in here.
It's very peaceful.
Yes, it is.
When, uh, Scotty was
going through the worst of it
I went into
his room, found his journal.
I know I shouldn't
have looked at it
but I wanted
to understand him.
The way you and...
his mother seemed to.
He loved you very much.
He said, "Jeanie just gets it.
"I don't have to
explain anything to her
because she already knows."
That's very sweet.
I remember when he told me
about what he wanted
to be when he grew up.
Some kind of rock 'n' roll
star probably.
He wanted to join the army.
He did?
Mm‐hmm.
I paged OB.
Going to
send somebody down here
to discuss your options.
We've decided
to keep the baby
and wait until
it's closer to term.
Good. I'm glad.
Donny will be glad, too.
This is no longer any
of Donny's business.
Maybe if you give it
a little more time.
I've contacted
our attorney.
My wife and I are
filing for sole custody.
Is this to teach
Donny a lesson?
Nothing could teach Donny
the lesson he deserves.
I've seen
a lot of parents
twice his age who
weren't responsible enough
to seek prenatal care.
Responsible?
Getting a
16‐year‐old girl pregnant
forcing her to leave
home, drop out of school...
‐ 'Please, Miles.'
‐ No.
The doctor
seems to fancy himself
an expert on our family.
‐ I don't. It's..
‐ Hmpf.
Just what's...
best for the child.
We let Donny
into our lives once
and he took
our daughter away.
He's not going to
take our granddaughter.
I don't want to go.
Everything will
be fine, Mr. Newton
but this really is for the best.
I'm not so sure
this is for the best.
You filed and signed
a legal report.
You can't just
rescind that on a whim.
I want to go home.
There. If you're not
going to listen
to me at least listen to him.
Someone in an abusive
situation can't always
'determine the
best course of action.'
'You're not talking
about a hypothetical here.'
You're talking about
an adult human being
who's making a
decision to go home.
According to
your own report he was
non compos mentis on admission.
He was severely dehydrated.
Once we ran some fluids in him
he's become perfectly lucid.
Mr. Newton, I know you're scared
'but I'm scared about
what's going to happen to you'
if you're
not taken care of.
I'm fine.
Doctor, Dr. Carter, call Burke
he'll, he'll explain.
Don't force me
to get the police involved
and press formal charges
against your
son and daughter‐in‐law.
Can she do this?
Please...don't let her.
'Don't let her do that, doctor.
Doctor, don't let her do that.'
I‐I'm...sorry.
'I want to go home!'
Thank you.
Uh, Kerry?
Anna.
What happened
today, it really threw me
and it's been on my mind.
I wanted to talk
to you about it.
Same here. I...I should
have explained myself better
instead of
flying off the handle.
‐ No. You were right.
‐ No. Just let me explain.
I did some overseas work
in Africa, where
abortion is illegal
and I‐I saw
15‐year‐old girls
in septic shock
from botched procedures
and there was
nothing we could do.
I've made
it a priority
to be the best doctor
I can be and to support
all my patients' choices.
If you would have asked me
when I got up this morning
I would have...I would
have said the same thing
but in this case, she
was so far along, and‐‐
And what if
another Brianna Thomas
comes through those doors?
I'd love to be able to tell you
that if the same case
came in tomorrow
I'd be able
to do the procedure
without a second
thought, but I don't know.
‐ Peter, I'm glad I caught you.
‐ Dr. Morgenstern.
I was on my way
to your apartment.
Listen, um, I'm
sorry about that surgery
but I already
had my hand in it.
No, no, no. You‐you
did the right thing.
You were
thinking on your feet.
That's not what I wanted
to talk to you about.
I wanted to let you know
that one
of my last two acts
as chief of surgery,
is to rescind your suspension.
What do you mean?
That's Swanson's laparoscopy
in full living color.
The mistake wasn't yours.
I cut the gastric artery.
My last act as chief
will be to resign.
Uh...Dr. Morgenstern,
it was just one incident.
No.
When I saw you
in that trauma today
the passion
that you exhibited.
It's been years
since I've felt that.
It might have
had something to do
with my heart attack,
the pressure
of feeling that I just
don't belong here anymore.
What do you mean?
You're a great surgeon.
You taught
me everything I know.
I was a great
surgeon, but what happened..
...what I allowed to happen..
...it just proves that
I'm not a very great man.
That's what I
got to work on.
Here. You smell that?
What's that?
The smell of spring.
All green
and full of possibility.
Ramen delight.
You feeling suicidal?
No. I'm just...poor.
John Truman Carter poor?
It's a long story.
I've had a bit of a long week.
I overdid
it with a patient today.
Thought I was doing
what was best.
Better to overdo it
and be wrong sometimes
than not do anything at all.
Alright, I'll
tell you what.
Why don't you dump
that liquid sodium
and I'll take you out
and buy you a burger and a beer.
‐ I don't know.
‐ Come on. It's not an option.
‐ Hey, guys.
‐ Hey, Jeanie.
Is it still raining outside?
No, it's not so bad.
It's kind of nice, actually.
‐ Peter.
‐ Hey. Uh, look.
I hope I'm not disturbing you.
Oh, come on in.
I'll turn the music down.
Um, let me take that.
Um, yeah.
Here, look,
you're soaking wet.
Uh, yeah. Cheap umbrella.
What possessed you
to come out in these elements?
My day, my week, my life.
I heard about Morgenstern.
I'm really sorry.
I lost my mentor
today. And the hospital?
They lost a great surgeon.
You can, um..
...you can
be so close to somebody..
...and then they're gone..
...and you've never even
told them that you..
...you know how..
...well, you..
Hey, I'm sorry.
I'm...I'm babbling.
I'm not even making sense.
No, no, no. You are.
You are. Go on.