There's a baby in the bed.
I know there's a
baby in the bed.
There's no baby in the shower.
There is no baby in the shower.
All right.
There's a baby
in the shower, too.
Oh, come on. Just
look the other way.
I can't do it in
front of the duckies.
Yes, you can. Do it
in front of the duckies.
No. Come on.
Where are we gonna go now?
Okay, stop saying that.
Good morning.
Oh, my God.
Yeah, I'm watching
a pyeloplasty.
I can rewind it back to
the beginning if you'd like.
No, let's go.
Hey, listen for the baby. What?
Twenty minutes.
Okay.
Don't! Don't! Don't!
Stop, Derek.
Ow! Ow! What?
Let's just try to
move the seat back.
Okay, okay, okay.
Is that better? Yeah.
Good. Come here. Okay.
I'm sorry, but she woke up,
and she seemed like
she wanted you guys.
But don't worry. She
didn't see anything.
We're never gonna
have sex again, are we?
Aw. Happy Valentine's Day.
Okay, baby. There we go.
Well, listen, I can
babysit tonight
if you guys need some
time to yourselves.
'Cause I have no plans
'cause my life is empty.
I'm alone with no
plans whatsoever, at all.
That's great.
So did you make a reservation
somewhere beautiful with
lots of flickery candles?
I made a plan. I
think you'll like it.
You should pack a bag. Oh, wow.
Overnight? Oh, gosh.
Well, what about Sofia?
Mark got a sitter. He'll be home
at 11:00, and then he's got her.
All right. Well,
what should I bring?
A bathing suit? Or I don't
know. What are we talking here?
Uh, no bathing suit.
Boots wouldn't hurt.
All right. So, cold.
Could be.
Wouldn't hurt to bring long
underwear, extra fleece.
Yeah. Hey, don't make that face.
No.
It will be fun. Yeah. Romantic.
There are times in our lives
when love really
does conquer all.
Exhaustion,
sleep deprivation,
anything.
And then there are those times
when it seems like
love brings us nothing
but pain.
Tonight is still
gonna work out, right?
Of course it is. We have a plan.
I'm just saying
you cancel a lot,
because of the scalpels
and cutting people open.
Look, I was promised
an elegant dinner.
I rearranged my whole schedule.
I've got high heels
in the back of my car.
I'm gonna spend all
day thinking about them.
Is it camping?
I mean, does she think I'm
going camping on Valentine's Day?
I don't know.
Well, she's trying to
surprise me. I'm telling you,
the surprise is gonna be, I'm gonna
leave her on the side of a mountain.
I mean, do you think
camping is sexy? It's not sexy.
You can't take a baby
camping. Sofia's gonna hate it.
What... You're getting a sitter.
Callie said you're
getting a sitter.
Yeah, Callie also said
you were going camping.
Callie's lost her mind.
Ugh! Really, it's camping?
I don't know, but it's
your night with Sofia.
Well, I need to have
sex with my wife,
apparently in the woods
on cold, hard ground.
And you promised Callie
a sitter, so get a sitter.
Come on. This thing with
Julia is young and fragile.
There's a lot of pressure. I
got us a table at Campo's.
Well, then you
better find a sitter.
I have plans.
Yep. I got a hot date.
Our thing is young
and fragile, too.
We're gonna get a
zillion valen-traumas.
I bet a few of them will be
good surgeries for our boards.
Well, it's not Saint Patty's
Day. Those are good traumas.
Car crashes, bar brawls.
Yeah, Valentine's Day is all
swallowed engagement rings
and guys who threw out
their backs getting laid.
You're just bitter 'cause
you don't have a date.
First of all,
Valentine's Day isn't
for having a date
with some chick.
No, it's for macking the
chicks who don't have dates.
Besides, I have to
study for my boards.
You studying already?
Of course. You're not?
No, I am.
Who put up all this? I did.
Well, research shows
that a cheerful environment
reduces stress and helps
patients to feel more...
Wow.
Okay.
I have to get that
baby out of my bed.
She's ruining my sex life.
Yeah, well, mine's already dead.
He's gonna leave me.
He won't. Yeah, he will. He is.
I mean, I know it.
And you know what?
I don't care.
You know, if he wants to leave,
if he wants to
hate me, then fine.
I can't make someone stay.
Well, you could kind
of beg him to stay.
I'm busy. I'm
focused. I'm a surgeon.
Well, everyone's a
surgeon. That doesn't mean...
It does. For me, it does.
I'm brilliant. I'm
gifted. I don't beg.
You know, if he wants
to go, then fine. I'm good.
Hey, have you guys started
studying for your boards?
Yeah. Yeah. Why?
Yeah. Cool. Me, too.
I need labs in bed six.
About time, Grey.
Bed three. Okay.
Well, anything for me?
Six weeks of
headaches, like blinding.
We were in here last
week. They did a brain scan,
but they didn't find anything.
Said it was probably a migraine,
but the pills don't help at all.
Janell, can you rate your pain
for me on a scale of 1 to 10?
This morning, it
was, like, an 11.
But now it's more like a...
Janell? Honey?
Janell? Can you hear me?
Does this happen a lot?
Yeah. She just shuts down
'cause the pain's too
much or something.
We need an EEG over here.
And let's page Shepherd.
- Quickly, please.
- Right away.
This isn't a migraine,
right? No, it's not a migraine.
She's having a seizure.
I have been off of Dr. Altman's
service now for two weeks.
I stepped over a line.
You reprimanded me.
Continuing to punish me is...
Fine.
You're on her service.
Get down!
Look out!
What was that?
Is everybody okay?
Are you okay?
Yes.
You sure?
Airway seems fine,
but he's got some JVD.
He's tachycardic with
muffled heart sounds.
What happened?
Sir, you're at Seattle
Grace-Mercy West hospital.
Your van crashed.
No one was hurt, but we need
to get you examined. Come on.
I must have fallen asleep
at the wheel for a second.
I've been working
like a dog all week.
God. No, no,
no. I gotta go. I...
Sir, relax, relax.
Just lie down.
No, I have to go. I'm a florist.
These roses won't last in the
open air. They're gonna wilt.
Sir, you need to calm down.
We're gonna get you out of here.
Maintain in-line stabilization.
We need to get trauma
labs, films, and ultrasound.
Make sure that CT is
available, and page Altman.
Right away, Doctor.
She's not responding to the
seizure medication, Randy.
She is in serious danger of
suffering severe brain damage,
which is why I'd like to place
her in a medically-induced coma.
A coma? What do you mean?
Basically, a deep sleep
to prevent the seizures
from damaging her brain.
It will also buy us some time
so we can figure out
what's causing them.
She just turned 32.
We've never talked about
medical decision-type stuff.
Well, every seizure Janell has
hurts her brain a little bit more.
We need to do this now.
Oh, God. Yeah. Please do it.
Okay. Do it, please.
Push 150 milligrams of propofol.
Call respiratory while
I prep for intubation.
Kepner, forget the flowers.
Throw them out
and get back to work.
Kepner.
You're not throwing
those flowers away?
But he...
He doesn't need to know.
Throwing away
perfectly good flowers.
Everyone's a cynic these days.
Talking about not
believing in Valentine's Day.
I mean, what's wrong with a day
devoted to the person you love?
I take this day very seriously.
I know you do.
Happy anniversary, sir.
Thank you, Dr. Grey.
I'm getting home early,
try and spend most
of the day with my wife.
What about you?
You hitting the town?
I'm not hitting much
of anything these days.
Oh, God. I'm sorry.
That was crass.
I have no Valentine's plans.
What the hell was I thinking?
I should've listened to my mom.
I used to be young!
I used to be pretty!
I have wasted my
entire youth on you!
Charlie Bilson, 32, hit by a car
when he ran
head-on into traffic.
Complains of
chest and back pain.
Has abdominal
tenderness and palpation.
And it looks like a broken nose.
I cannot believe you did this!
Okay, if you hadn't made
me chase you down...
You should not have chased
me. You shouldn't have bothered,
because it's over.
This is over.
What happened?
We're having breakfast in bed.
One second, you're so happy...
I thought you were
going to propose!
Well, what do you think?
Well, she's wheezing,
but we'll treat that.
You're gonna be just fine, um...
Clementine. I think
the kids call her Clem.
You're not the mom?
She's on her way.
She was at the gym.
I'm just the moron that bought
the box of peanut clusters
for the kid who's
allergic to nuts.
My son wanted to
give her a valentine.
She took a bite,
and this happened.
I'm gonna start you on
a breathing treatment.
And then I'm gonna give
you an IV with medicine
to treat the rash, okay?
Okay. All right.
Here. If it hurts, you
can squeeze my hand,
hard as you want.
Okay, Clem, here we go.
Ready?
One, two...
Three. Okay.
Good.
Honestly, those little boxes?
They taunt me, Charlie.
I would rather a nice coffee
table book or maybe even a mug,
because then at least I
wouldn't get my hopes up
every freaking Valentine's Day
when you pull out
the little velvet box.
You didn't even
look at the necklace.
I didn't have to.
It wasn't a ring.
Oh, that's a
pretty nasty cut there.
Dr. Grey.
You want to take a look?
Sure.
Come with me.
A man should get
to bleed in peace.
Thanks.
What? Mmm.
I was trying to figure out why
this patient's having seizures
when I noticed she
has a hemolytic anemia.
Which means she's having
an autoimmune response.
Right. If antibodies are
attacking her red blood cells,
who's to say that antibodies
couldn't be attacking her brain,
causing the encephalitis?
And it's not a brain tumor.
That's why you paged me.
Well, yeah, and I
thought we could
spend Valentine's Day together.
Uh, you may not have
Valentine's Day plans,
but I do, Grey, plans that
I am not willing to forfeit.
So here's how
this is going to go.
In a timely and
efficient manner,
you and I will rule out
everything that could be causing
this woman's
body to attack itself,
virus by virus, tumor by tumor,
until we land on
the one thing...
It's a teratoma. What?
I sent off Janell's
CSF from her spinal tap
for anti-NMDA
receptor antibodies,
and it just came back positive.
Show-off.
Let's get a scan.
Is this our flower guy?
Yeah. He has an intrapericardial
diaphragmatic hernia.
Whoa. How did his
abdominal organs
get into the sac
around his heart?
His chest hit the
wheel when he crashed.
Well, I'm gonna have
to reduce the hernia.
Book an OR. Bump any
nonemergent patients,
and find someone
to scrub in with me.
Dr. Hunt has agreed to
let me back on your service,
so I can scrub in with you.
Really?
We need to get in
there and do the repair
before he tamponades,
so we should move
as quickly as possible.
Like I'm ever anything but.
You must think I'm such a bitch.
No.
It's been eight years,
and it's every Valentine's Day,
the buildup gets worse.
This morning he wakes
me up, and breakfast in bed,
and then he tells me he booked
dinner and a nice hotel at the pier,
and then he pulls out
another cheap-ass necklace.
Eight years.
We're not exactly teenagers.
Mmm. Maybe he doesn't
know how much you want it.
We go to 20 weddings a year,
and I sob like a lunatic at every one.
I'm not that sentimental.
He knows. He knows.
CT shows extensive
internal bleeding.
He's also hypotensive.
We have to get him
up to the OR. Now.
What's going on?
What's happening?
We're taking your
fiance to surgery.
He is not her fiance.
Suction.
Yeah, watch the...
Sorry. Sorry.
So anybody got any
good Valentine's plans?
My husband died in
this OR a month ago.
Dr. Yang performed the surgery.
I was in a seven hour surgery
and didn't know that he had died.
Dr. Hunt kept that a secret.
So I don't speak to him.
He wants a baby.
Dr. Yang doesn't.
So they don't speak to each
other even though they're married.
So...
No.
How about you?
Um, my girlfriend
and I are gonna...
Nothing.
We think this thing
on Janell's lung
is something called a teratoma.
It's creating antibodies
that are attacking her brain.
Well, I don't get it.
Basically, her body sees
the tumor as an invader
and is attacking it,
and her brain is getting
hurt in the crossfire.
So this thing on her lung
is causing her seizures?
I think so.
We'll have to remove it
and test it to make sure.
Okay, so you take it
out, her headaches stop,
and she wakes up from the coma,
and we get to go
on to live our lives?
That's the plan.
Okay.
We've known each
other since high school.
She's my better half.
I mean, I know people
always say that...
But she really is.
You paged me for this?
Why would I do this?
Because it's fair.
Because the three of us
are equal parents to Sofia
and this is the fair way to
decide who stays in with her.
Unless you'd rather raise her with
no sense of fairness or decency,
in anarchy and chaos.
Your call.
Okay. Fine.
Best two out of three?
Best two out of three.
You ready?
Rock, paper, scissors.
My rock crushes your scissors.
Rock... Hold on,
hold on. Time-out.
Time-out? I'm sorry, time-out?
Jackson, team huddle.
Oh, my gosh. Are
you guys kidding me?
I mean, some of
us have surgeries.
Can you just give us a second?
What do you think?
I think she's going paper.
She's going with rocks. I'm
thinking she's a rock thrower.
Yeah, that's what she
wants you to think. All right?
That's why she did
it two times in a row.
This time, trust
me. Go scissors.
Okay, you guys, it's
not a chess game.
Can we just do
this? Get out there.
Wow.
All right.
Here we go.
Rock, paper, scissors.
No! Yes!
Damn it!
I'm getting lucky tonight.
Happy babysitting.
See you later. All right.
Avery, I said rocks.
My gut told me rocks.
You messed with my
head. You asked my opinion.
Julia's gonna kill me.
She's having a severe reaction.
Sorry, Clem. It looks like I'm
gonna have to give you a shot.
Hand?
Yes, please.
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
Oh, Clem.
Oh, honey. You poor thing.
Hi, Mom. She's gonna be fine.
The doctor's gonna give
her a shot. He's on top of it.
Well, I'm glad someone is.
- I didn't know.
The school sends
home notes all the time.
It's in every newsletter.
She can't even be
near peanut butter.
I have a job, Terri,
okay? Three kids.
Excuse me if I don't read every
note the school sends home.
I gave her a shot of
epinephrine. It should do the trick.
He's hypothermic.
Yeah. There's too much bleeding.
He's not gonna make
it if we keep going.
Let's pack him and get him
up to ICU to stabilize him.
I am not babysitting.
I have made your
career, and I can break it.
I need to check for
a septal hematoma.
I'll be quick. I
got a date tonight.
What makes you
think I could babysit?
Well, you know CPR,
you can think on your feet,
you're fit,
you can run out of a
burning building in no time.
Septum looks fine.
And I'm not gonna cancel
a date on Valentine's Day.
Women claim that they
don't care, but they all do,
a lot.
Okay, let's prep him for ICU,
and I'll stay and monitor him.
No, it's your
anniversary. I'll stay.
I thought you had a hot date.
Really? With who?
Uh...
Dr. Sloan, I mean,
if you're finished
here, we'd like to...
Oh, I'll tell you
who's finished.
You're finished.
Thank you.
I already pressed it.
Whatever.
I'm moving out.
So if you need me, I'll
be at my mom's till I, uh,
figure something out.
Okay?
Okay.
Hey, I got your message
your lung resection went long.
I pushed our
reservations to 8:00.
Really? Just like that
on Valentine's Day?
I got connections.
I could even push
them to 9:00 if you like.
No. Absolutely not. No.
As soon as path confirms
that the mass we took
out was the teratoma,
I will go out to my
car, grab those heels...
Benign granuloma.
All right, fine. Push
the reservation to 9:00.
Mmm-hmm.
Why are you still
here? You can go.
I'd love to. I'd
love nothing more.
But Nico won't leave until he
knows Clem's gonna be okay.
He's 10. Who's the parent here?
You let that kid run wild.
At least I don't hover over him,
afraid to let him
out of my sight.
Well, maybe I need to hover
because you and your
son won't leave us alone.
What were you
thinking, dropping him
at my house today
when I wasn't home?
He wasn't gonna stay.
He just wanted to give
your spoiled daughter
a box of freaking chocolates.
Well, stop giving us things. We barely
survived the head lice he gave her.
You have no way of knowing
who gave who the head lice.
Okay, that's enough.
They're 10. They're
in love. They're cute.
Let them be cute,
for crying out loud.
Excuse me, Doctor,
something's wrong with Clem.
She's breathing funny.
Get me a size 6 ET tube.
What's happening?
Her airway is shutting down.
I'm gonna have to intubate.
Oh, my God.
Here you go. Give me
some crike pressure.
All right. I'm in.
There's good color change.
SATs are coming up.
What happened?
Anaphylactic shock.
We're gonna have to keep her
overnight and see how she responds.
But she's gonna be okay?
Yeah, yeah, I think so.
Now will you go? Please.
It doesn't make any sense. Janell's
labs show she has a teratoma.
Then the lucky
woman has two tumors.
The benign one that we
just took out of her lung
and another one...
Where?
Her scans and her
ultrasound are clean.
What if it's microscopic?
Okay, um...
What do we know about
NMDA receptor teratomas?
We know they're most
commonly found on the ovaries.
You want to take out her
ovaries? She's 32 years old.
They're always 32 and
nice and undeserving.
These kind of things don't
happen to nasty people.
His vitals are
holding. That's good.
His pupils are
a little sluggish.
Sharon, are you okay?
Can I get you anything?
I had a ring picked out.
I sent a picture of
it to all of my sisters
so they could help Charlie
surprise me when the time came,
'cause that ring was important.
It was so freaking important.
Look at him. He looks...
I don't care about
that crap anymore.
And I don't need a stupid ring.
I just... I just need him.
That's it. I just
want him to be okay.
Please. Just let him be okay.
Your incision looks good.
You should be back on
your feet in a few weeks,
but I wouldn't recommend
pulling any more all-nighters,
even on holidays like today.
Trust me, brother. I'm done.
I mean, what a stupid business.
People call you up, you know,
they ask you to make
something beautiful.
Yeah, so some sorry
schlep can forget
that they've been treated like
crap every other day of the year.
Yeah, like my flowers
are magic or something.
But I bought it.
Nearly killed myself
trying to make sure
everybody got
their little miracle.
What a joke.
People ought to just stop being
so awful to each
other, you know?
Leave me out of it.
Dr. Yang will
check on you later.
Thank you.
Can I just talk to
you for a minute?
I know you've been through
hell, and I know I was part of it.
And I know you're grieving,
and there's no magic
solution to that, but...
We used to be
friends. And I really,
really need a friend today.
So how about we just go
across the street to Joe's,
and I'll buy you a
drink, you know?
Or I will buy you
many, many drinks.
Are you done?
Are you finished?
Yes. I hate you.
From the moment you decided
to put the needs of your hospital
over my dead husband,
I have hated you.
I lie in bed at night alone,
and I look at the spot where
my husband used to sleep,
and I actively,
with every cell in
my body, hate you.
I wish you were
dead instead of him.
I think about all the soldiers, good
men, who died over there in Iraq,
and I don't understand what kind
of God would allow you to survive.
We are not friends. This
is not grief. It will not pass.
I hate you!
Please, don't speak to me
again unless it's work-related.
Let me get this straight.
All right, you take this
thing out of her lungs,
and it's not what
you thought it was.
Now you want to
take out her ovaries.
The kind of
antibodies that she had
are most commonly associated
with teratomas of the ovaries.
But they can sometimes
be found in other places,
which is why we thought
the mass on her lung was it.
Chances are high
that it's on her ovaries.
Chances are? That's
the best you can do?
She's young.
She still wants kids. We...
No. You're doctors.
You're gonna have to do a hell
of a lot better than "chances are."
If we do nothing, she will
continue to have the seizures.
And eventually, her body
will just completely shut down.
And by that time, she will have
suffered so much brain damage
that Janell, the woman
that you love, she'll be gone.
The nougats are gone. Sorry.
Aw.
Did you get these
from a patient? No.
I bought these for Julia,
but she's standing me up for an
emergency ocular transplant surgery,
so I'm gorging myself
on Valentine's chocolate.
Mmm. I'd mock you right
now if my mouth wasn't so full.
Try the square ones.
They're caramel
with sea salt. Mmm.
I didn't want to disappoint her.
You know, I bought
candy and flowers.
I got rose petals, Lex.
Bags of them.
I was looking
forward to sharing it.
But now I'm alone
on Valentine's Day,
eating chocolate.
I can do you one better.
My hot date tonight?
Zola.
I am babysitting.
Let's move! He's coding!
He's crashing.
What is that? What's happening?
What are you doing?
Can someone please
tell me what is happening?
Sharon... He was just
fine one second ago.
No, you need to go.
Now! What's happening?
- Somebody page Dr. Webber.
- Taking over compressions.
He's in v-fib. LEXIE:
Push an amp of epi
and charge the paddles to 360.
Is it loaded?
Yep, we're doing it. Okay.
Clear.
He's hemorrhaging.
Probably in DIC.
Okay, charge again. Go.
Hang some FFP at factor VII.
Clear.
Oh, God. No.
I'm so sorry.
His heart stopped,
we tried to revive him,
but despite our best
efforts, he didn't make it.
He died at 7:53 p.m.
No indication of a tumor.
It could be microscopic.
There's a lot of adhesions on this
one, that could mean inflammation.
Which could mean a teratoma.
So let's take out the right ovary,
send it to path, and
try to save the left one.
Dr. Grey, I'm the GYN.
I really should be the one...
Okay, but you're a third year,
and I can't trust
third-year hands.
Boki, clamp.
I'm going with her.
Ever thought you'd be
wishing so hard to find a tumor?
No! No! No!
Honey, we're leaving now.
No, I'm not! I promised
Clem I'd stay with her!
Nico, don't make me pick
you up. You're too big for this.
Come on. She's right, dude.
This is embarrassing, you know?
I'm a little
embarrassed for you.
I don't care. What's Clem gonna
think if she wakes up and I'm gone?
She'll think that
I don't love her.
Uh, look...
What if I'm there
when she wakes up?
I'll tell her whatever you want.
It's like the next best
thing to being there.
Promise?
Yeah.
You're gonna need a
pen and a pad of paper.
Oh, good. All right. Here
we go. Pathology's back.
The ovary specimen you sent
is normal. No pathology seen.
Damn. We picked the wrong ovary.
There's a chance the
other one's clean, too.
You don't have a very good
personality, you know that?
The teratoma is
there. It has to be.
Well, if not, we'll have just
sterilized a woman for no reason.
I'm done. I am done with him.
Owen? Yeah.
He actually thinks
that we can just forget
everything that happened.
I don't even know how to...
How can he think that we
would ever, ever be friends again?
Standing over me is not gonna
make me read it any faster.
This part of the specimen
is a little abnormal,
but until I look at a
couple more slides...
Move over. No.
Move... Over.
Fine.
Dr. Bailey, see what I see?
I haven't confirmed it yet.
A mix of different cell types,
which is compatible with teratomas.
Is that what you
see? Dr. Russell?
Okay, yes. I'd say it's
very likely a teratoma.
Yes! Teratoma!
Hey.
How you feeling?
Okay.
Yeah?
Where's Nico?
Well, he wanted to stay, but
you know, his mom made him go.
Figures.
Yeah.
But he told me a few
things he wanted to say.
But, well, here we go.
"Dear Clementine,
"I'm really sorry you're sick.
"But I'm not sorry
you're my girlfriend.
"It's the worst, being
alone on Valentine's Day.
"But I'm thinking
about you right now.
"I'm thinking about
holding hands with you
"and jumping on the
trampoline together.
"I love you." Whoa.
"And PS...
"I don't care who gave who lice,
"I'm just glad we both
had it together. Love, Nico."
I'd say you picked a good one.
What should we do?
You want to see
if the game's on?
I got steak and I
bought a really good red,
and a salad, and I'm
gonna cook for you.
Avery...
I have a girlfriend.
And she's operating tonight, so
as soon as you put Sofia down,
you can help me study for
my boards, 'cause I am behind.
Way behind.
What'd you pay for
that bottle of wine?
50 bucks.
I'm not great at surprises.
I wish I was, but I
know we're camping.
You know, I'm pretty sure that
we're smack-dab in the center
of one of Washington's
fine national parks,
and I'm trying to
have a good attitude,
but this whole blind thing
is just not helping matters.
Wow. This is you
with a good attitude.
Fine. I'll shut up.
Okay. Hey, are you peeking?
No! I'm not peeking.
All right. Okay.
Okay. Are you ready?
Are you ready? Are you ready?
Okay.
Ta-da!
Derek's trailer?
I figured, he wasn't using
it, so I asked for the key.
We really are camping.
Whoo!
Fun. Fun. Yes, fun.
Yeah!
We're not really camping.
No. You hate camping.
I do. I really do.
I mean, it's almost
camping, only...
There is a bed...
Oh.
And lingerie.
No one's around for miles.
Our patient's seizures stopped,
and you know why? No.
Because I found this
teratoma on her ovary.
Well, you know, you
could've told me this at dinner.
You didn't have to show
me a chopped up ovary.
Little sucker thought it could
hide from me, but it couldn't.
It took a while, but I finally
figured out where it was,
and I went in and nailed it.
You are so sexy when
you're looking at a teratoma.
Yeah?
Grade five?
Ruptured?
Yeah, send him over.
Ugh!
Blunt trauma to the kidney.
Guy crashed into a pole,
not only shattering his
kidney and his renal artery,
but ruining my Valentine's Day.
Let me do it.
Oh, no.
Sir, I don't want to
ruin your night, too.
Just go. Get home.
And it's your anniversary.
For God sake. Adele's
probably so angry at you...
I just went home.
She didn't recognize me.
She thought I
looked like a nice guy
and invited me to
join her for dinner,
flirted with me over steaks,
thought I had a nice smile.
So, no, Dr. Bailey,
my wife's not mad right now.
In fact, I think she's
falling in love with me.
Sir...
I'm so sorry.
Yeah, go. Go.
I'd like to be alone right now
with a kidney and a scalpel.
Go. Okay.
I'm just gonna go. I'm gonna
go and I'm gonna tell him,
and if there is a...
No, I'm not gonna tell him.
No, I'm gonna... Of course...
Oh! Okay, of course.
No, I'm gonna tell him
because if you don't say
anything, then you bleed out and die
and you read about
it in a plastic locket.
I mean, what do you think?
What should I do?
Zola? Well...
Tell me.
Look. Hey.
Look, look she's
up, she's eaten.
She's ready to roll. I'm
gonna take... So we just need...
No, I'm gonna take off.
Yeah, take her with you.
Drive her around.
She loves that.
No, what? What?
Zola, we'll be back.
Okay, I'm still in
my scrubs. I know.
I'm sorry. I had a surgery
and then another one came in,
and I know it seems
like I blew you off,
but I didn't. We
can still go to dinner.
Dinner is over. It's 11:23 p.m.
You blew me off
for dinner hours ago.
I ruined our Valentine's Day?
Miranda, I...
I'm a terrible person.
I know. I don't make
time like I should.
I'm not good at
romance-y things,
but, look, I am working,
and you can't fault me for that.
You can't fault
me for saving lives.
And if you're going
to break up with me
for missing a dinner
because I was saving a life,
then I don't even want to
have romance-y things with you.
Okay, Miranda. Wait.
Why are you in a suit?
Because it's 11:23 p.m.
Valentine's Day isn't over yet.
You threw this together today?
Oh, no. No, no, no, no, no.
I've been planning this for weeks.
See, I knew there
was no chance in hell
that we'd make a
scheduled reservation,
so I booked Marco here.
I mean, I'm dating Dr. Bailey.
I know the drill.
I know you.
You know me.
And I even had Marco put
extra crumb topping
on your mac and cheese.
I know you.
Okay.
Thank you, sir.
Miranda,
I happen to be very
good at romance-y things.
Yeah. You are.
We're always looking
for ways to ease the pain.
Hey.
I thought maybe the girls
could have a play date.
And we could talk about stuff,
'cause there's some stuff
that I've been wanting to say.
Oh. Is that Julia? I'll go.
Avery's cooking me dinner.
Is that Julia? 'Cause I can go.
Oh. That's...
But he can go...
If you want to talk.
Should he go?
Hey.
Nope. It's nothing. I... It's...
You know what? You two
have a very pleasant evening.
Don't be stupid. You love steak.
Sofia, your friend's here.
Sometimes we ease the pain
by making the best
of what we have.
Sometimes it's by losing
ourselves in the moment.
Please.
Don't hate me.
I'm begging you.
And sometimes all we
need to do to ease the pain
is call a simple truce.