If ever there's a reason to be swept
up in the season of the fallen leaves
And if the days grew shorter
And the darkness drew its order
From the autumn gray
I'd rather sit this out and
sleep the day away instead
My weary eyes a
bit too slow indeed
I'd rather sit this out...
To worry about the
emptiness that comes
If ever there's a reason to
be swept up in the season
Of the fallen leaves
And if the days grew shorter
And the darkness drew its order
From the autumn gray
I'd rather sit this out and
sleep the day away instead
My weary eyes a
bit too slow indeed
You won't believe the
crap Armen pulled last night.
He cut the power to my
apartment. That's right.
No lights, no Wi-Fi, nothing.
For 15 minutes.
And if I'd have
been on a ventilator,
I could've suffocated
in that time.
Right? You're a doctor.
You're not on a ventilator.
Thank God for
that. But I could be.
I mean, it was dark.
I could've tripped.
I should sue him.
Sorry, were you gonna
eat this? I stress eat.
Okay, listen, I
go to talk to him
and he claims that I was
playing my music too loud again.
I wear earplugs when
your music irritates me.
I miss the dripping.
You're missing the
point here, Shaun.
Okay, you knock, you ask.
You don't cut someone's power.
You'd knock, right?
Of course, you would knock.
Any normal person would.
I mean, am I crazy, or
is he a total sociopath?
You should get headphones.
Headphones?
They would
eliminate the sound...
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I got it. Thank you.
Thank you for being
so objective about this.
In fact, why don't you go help
Armen write my eviction notice?
Yeah, and I'll never drive
down that street again.
It was a pretty bad memory.
Yeah? But that sounds quite fun,
I mean...
It's kind of hot
for a hike, isn't it?
We're hiking. We're
gonna sweat. It happens.
All right, don't do nothing
stupid. Open the register.
Put everything in a
bag. Come on, right now.
Hey. Don't move. Give me
your wallets, phones, everything.
Keep your hands
where I can see 'em.
I said get out your wallet!
Do it now!
Wallet, now!
Is he okay?
We don't know. This was
routed through Basecamp.
They said Shaun was there, but
they didn't say if he was hurt or not.
Well, EMS has two
critical inbounding.
Their hands are a little
full to chat right now.
20-year-old female, single
gunshot wound to the abdomen.
Hypotensive and tachy.
Two liters of saline en route.
Her name's Avery.
We'll take good care of
her. Jared, you're with me.
Blunt-force neck injury. Oxygen
sats just dropped below 80.
Trachea's crushed.
I inserted a laryngeal mask,
but the airway is not secured.
Are you okay? You weren't hurt?
His oropharyngeal anatomy
is distorted from the contusion.
Subcutaneous emphysema.
He's barely moving air.
Let's take him to a bay.
And get me an OR. Now.
I need four units O-negative.
Type and cross her.
She has decreased
breath sounds on the left.
Let's get a chest X-ray on her.
What the hell is he doing here?
It's his fault.
This is all his fault.
Yeah. Clerk says the guy
entered, shouted orders,
and apparently, your
doctor didn't comply.
Girl gets shot
and the store clerk
clocks the gunman with
a bat. That's all we know.
All right. What do you need?
I need forensics on
the gunman and the girl.
All right, we'll let you
know what we find out.
Hey, the police are gonna wanna
talk to you. After that, you can go home.
I should be helping.
My shift is just starting.
You were at the shooting. I
don't have time to hold your hand.
I don't like my hand being held.
Small-caliber bullets.
They ricochet inside. They can cause
multiple and unpredictable injuries.
BP's 90 over 50.
And what do we
need to do about it?
Chest and abdominal X-rays, and
a focused assessment sonogram.
Could use your help
over here, Dr. Melendez.
Are you okay?
Yes, I'm fine.
- You're with me. Get a gown on him.
- Okay.
Entrance wound is down here.
The bullet fractured
the pelvis on the way in.
All right, let's look for an exit
wound. We're gonna roll her on three.
One, two, three...
Right, got it. Between
the second and third rib.
She's hemorrhaging here, too.
Murphy, get us the ultrasound
so we can find out what's inside.
Focused assessment with
sonography and trauma.
No chest contusions or
secondary injuries evident.
Oxygen sats 70.
I can't squeeze the
camera past this collapse.
OR Three's prepped
and ready, but that's it.
We've got a full house
right now up in surgery.
- Next show time's 15 minutes out.
- I could use it.
I gotta get this
bleeding under control.
What's the status on your guy?
Take her up. Take the gunshot.
Hold on. This airway's so damaged,
I can't even do a tracheotomy.
He's got five minutes
until anoxic brain death.
Mine's got pressure. I'll
see what I can do here.
You're scrubbing in with me.
Go ahead and feed the tube
under the collapsed trachea.
Starting high-flow O-2.
And we're good.
Now that our patient
is actually breathing,
we can realign and
repair. Four-O on a driver.
Scissors, sponge stick.
It's a slippery thing letting
your feelings about a patient
influence your medical judgment.
I didn't.
I get the instinct. She's a
victim, he's a shooter. A racist.
Often, we don't even
know we're doing it.
I would never let my personal
feelings impact a patient's care.
She was bleeding out.
And this guy just drew his first
good breath 30 seconds ago.
They were both critical.
He was dying. You
were wrong. Own it.
You know as well as I do that
that was not an easy call to make.
- Do I?
- Yes.
Clear the field, Dr. Browne.
Not my operative field,
the surgical field. Scrub out.
Excuse me?
You're done. Step out of my OR.
Gail, can you please relieve
Dr. Browne of her instruments
and page Dr. Cleland
to assist me?
Now, isn't this more pleasant?
Aside from the spleen, what
else are we dealing with?
The bullet ruptured her transverse
colon at the splenic flexure.
Put it on our to-do list.
Why does her boyfriend
think it's your fault?
It punctured her diaphragm here
and entered the posterior chest.
She's bleeding again.
Clamp the hilum.
I already did. It's
too damaged to hold.
Gauze.
Hold this right
there. Don't let go.
No, this isn't gonna work.
It's gonna be like sewing
ground beef back into a steak.
All right, new plan. She's gonna
have to live without her spleen.
Metzen and pick-up.
I need a ligating suture around the
splenic artery while I make the cut.
Can you do that for me before this
young lady bleeds out on us, Murphy?
Yes.
Okay, let's move
on to the bowel perf.
Shaun. Thank
God you're all right.
I just heard what happened.
Shaun? Are you all right?
Yes. I wasn't injured.
What happened this morning?
Lea ate my apple.
No, Shaun, at the store this
morning. What happened at the store?
Wallet, now!
- I can't.
- Why the hell not?
You said keep my hands
where you could see them.
My wallet is in my pocket.
You can't see my hands if...
Are you trying to be a hero?
I'm a surgical resident.
Hey. Hey. Shut the hell up.
- Okay. Okay. Okay.
- This isn't a game, man. I'm serious.
Put your damn phone and
wallet on the ground. Right now!
Hey, do you see this, man?
I am not playing around.
Just put your phone and
wallet on the damn ground.
Come on, man.
Just do what he says.
Please listen to him.
Shut up! Just shut up
and get on your knees.
Put your hands and
knees on the ground.
- Yes.
- Get your wallet out right now. Hey!
I will shoot your crazy ass,
- I swear to God.
- Okay.
- Are you listening to me? I'll do it!
- Yes.
Hey! You hear me? Hey!
Oh, my God.
Okay, you need to take
the rest of the day off.
Dr. Melendez said
that, too. Why?
Why? Because you just
experienced a traumatic event...
- It's not my fault.
- I know that.
Avery has multiple injuries.
Dr. Melendez wants me to monitor her.
Dr. Lim.
I was out of line. I shouldn't
have argued with you...
Primary closure went well.
We'll extubate him in a few hours to
prevent any further internal damage.
Oh, that's good.
It is. And you're gonna
make sure he stays that way.
You'll be baby-sitting
him tonight in the ICU.
I'm... I'm not on call.
Great, then you're available.
It should be a quiet night.
Just want to keep
an eye on those vitals.
You never know
with trachea tears.
Can't one of the
ICU nurses do that?
Yep, but they didn't lip
off in my operating room.
And he'd better be
breathing in the morning.
Excuse me, but why is
Shaun on the victim's case?
I assessed him and he
seemed perfectly capable.
You assessed him?
What does that mean?
You asked him how he was
feeling? Are you psychic?
Do you have an advanced
degree in psychology?
You don't know what's
going on in his head.
When I'm in surgery,
my focus is on the person
whose guts are open in front of me
rather than the soul of the
person standing across from me.
And it seems that Shaun doesn't
let anything impact his work.
So along with his
photographic memory,
I'm putting cold-hearted
in the plus column.
Dr. Murphy, do you
understand why you're here?
Yes. Dr. Glassman
said I had to talk to you.
After any doctor goes
through a potentially traumatic...
You have to determine
if I am a medico-legal
liability to the hospital.
Yes. And, more importantly,
it's an opportunity to provide
you with emotional support.
How are you feeling?
You don't have apples.
I'll try to have some
fruit next time we meet.
Good.
Do you regret anything
about this morning?
Why?
After bad things happen,
it's perfectly normal
to replay the events,
wishing you'd done
things differently.
It already happened. I
can't do things differently.
Is talking about
this upsetting you?
What are you thinking
about right now?
Systemic inflammatory
response syndrome.
Surgery went well.
After a serious trauma like
this, the body can develop
a self-destructive
inflammatory reaction.
Kidneys, liver, lungs, heart.
Any, or all of them,
can start to shut down.
We'll be giving her
anti-inflammatories
and monitoring her closely,
but the next 24 hours are critical.
Okay. Thanks. Just
get her through this.
Whatever you gotta do.
Yeah, well, I need consent forms
from your girlfriend's next of kin.
If you could please get her family
in here as quickly as possible.
I can't.
I don't even know her last name.
It was our first date,
we met on a dating app.
We were going hiking, so she
wasn't carrying a purse or ID.
Well, then you really
don't need to be here.
Someone out there
cares about her.
If she dies, I want them to
know someone was with her.
I'll have social work
try to locate her family.
Stay as long as you want.
It looks clean,
dry, and healthy.
My neck is killing me.
How long have you been using?
What's that got to
do with anything?
Well, you've likely built up
a tolerance to pain meds.
And now that you really need
them, they aren't there for you.
That's why I need fentanyl,
a hundred micrograms. Are
you gonna help me or not?
That wouldn't be helping.
The worst thing I could do
for you is feed your habit.
What?
You saw my tattoo.
Yeah.
And now you're punishing me.
- You want this to hurt.
- I am treating you professionally...
If you're treating me professionally,
I wouldn't be in so much pain.
- I'm sorry, but I won't...
- Just give me the damn drugs!
Come on!
Melendez thinks that he's okay
being on Avery's case. I don't.
Dr. Melendez may be right.
That case seems to be
Shaun's primary focus right now.
Maybe his condition is a
blessing in this situation.
"Maybe"?
Or obsessing over Avery's health
could be his only outlet
for a guilty conscience.
Watching her suffer could just
be worsening those feelings.
So either it's a huge problem,
or it's not a problem at all.
This is your
professional opinion?
Shaun has a very unique mind
and an incredibly introverted nature.
Well, thank you for that.
I'm sorry, but without a
lot more time with him,
that's the best I can offer.
What did Lim expect me to do?
Stand there and smile while
she called my medical
judgment into question?
Your patient nearly died
waiting on that OR, right?
It was bad. What do
you want me to do?
- Tell her to back off.
- No.
- He's a complete and utter...
- Not one of the nice racists?
- I shouldn't have to be...
- Claire...
Here's what you have to do.
Shut up and do exactly
what Dr. Lim tells you to do.
But, it...
Yes, sir.
Maybe we could take turns.
You keep an eye on my
patient, I keep an eye on yours.
No.
Her creatinine is 1.6.
A mild bump in renal numbers
isn't surprising after all her trauma.
This morning must
have been crazy.
Are you okay?
This morning, my neighbor
Lea came over and ate my apple.
That's too bad.
Yes, it was my last one.
She was upset with
Armen, our landlord.
She plays her music very
loud. I gave her some advice.
It seemed to anger her because
she left without saying goodbye.
And you think you
did something wrong?
No, it was good advice.
Shaun, sometimes a
woman wants advice,
and sometimes she
just wants support.
How can I tell which
one Lea wants?
Err on the side of support.
- That's not helpful.
- Yes, it is.
Dr. Browne, you're
being summoned.
All right.
About time.
All your struggling,
you've pulled out your IV.
Aren't nurses usually
supposed to do this kind of crap?
They let you go to med school,
but they don't trust you
with any real responsibility.
There must be a competent doctor
tucked around here somewhere
who can tell someone I
need more than aspirin.
- "Competent"?
- Yeah. You know what I mean.
Imhotep was the father of
modern medicine. An Egyptian.
Yeah? Good for your people.
I'm willing to bet there's
even been a couple of others
over the last 3,000 years.
But guess what? On average,
you look at most great
technological advancements,
you'll find a proud Northern
European holding the patent.
That's what you were
trying to do this morning?
Get the patent on stealing 30 bucks
from the corner store for a drug fix?
You don't like drug
addicts, do you?
There's a lot of
people I don't like.
Thieves, racists, violent
punks. But I'll treat 'em.
Was your momma a drug addict?
Wow.
That's the beauty of clichés,
is they're true so often.
You don't know
anything about me.
I didn't go to college.
I didn't have no affirmative
action to get me in, but you did.
All because some bleeding-heart
liberal in the dean's office
teared up reading your essay
about your crack-whore momma.
What the hell?
I guess we're all violent punks.
All you had to do was
give him your wallet.
Her urine output is low.
Whoa! Whoa! What are you
doing? Get away from her!
Hey, hey! You can't be in
here shoving my doctors around.
Me? He's the...
Oh, my God.
She needs dialysis. Her
kidneys are failing fast.
This is the first stage
of total organ failure.
We removed two liters of
excess fluid with dialysis,
but she's getting worse.
Fluid's building
up in her chest.
She's in pulmonary failure, too.
Draining the fluid
in her pleural space
would reduce airway resistance.
Yeah. Let's prep her
for a thoracentesis.
We're gonna have to work fast.
I'll prep the evac drain.
I'm gonna need you to put
that needle right between...
Sixth and seventh rib.
- Wait. You're gonna let him do it?
- Shut up.
Right, careful. Don't put
the needle in too deep.
- We don't wanna give her...
- Pneumothorax.
Right, you're in.
Now let me see
what I can pull out...
And, hopefully,
she settles down.
CO-2's down and O-2's climbing.
We can manage her
kidneys and her lungs,
but the last stop in multiple
organ failure would be her heart.
Watch her ventilation
pressures like a hawk.
Push cardio-protective meds,
and page me if anything changes.
Think you're being her hero?
Fact is, you hardly know her.
And you don't know him at all.
Go home.
Yep?
Okay, I am done. He is a
foul-mouthed, spiteful bully.
No problem. I'll
have the concierge
find a patient more
suited to your liking.
He doesn't need a doctor doting
over him. He doesn't want me.
I don't care.
Look... I am sorry I
disagreed with you, okay?
But I don't deserve to be
scolded like a schoolgirl
because your ego can't
handle being challenged a little.
That is some apology.
Look, I had a legitimate...
You really don't see
the problem here?
What? With challenging you?
Right now, you are confronting
me in front of two nurses.
Would you do that to Melendez?
Or would you wait five minutes?
I have dealt with men undermining
my authority my entire career.
We shouldn't do it
to one another, too.
Now go take care of him, like
you would any other patient.
Hey, hey, hey.
Food services, they
double-check every order.
- What are you looking for?
- An apple.
- An apple? Who's getting an apple?
- I am.
- No.
- Shaun,
forget the apple, please.
I'm sorry, can I have a minute?
Shaun?
Okay.
Shaun, there's no need
to get defensive, okay?
- Do you wanna sit down?
- No, thank you.
I want you to tell me again
exactly what happened this morning.
I told you exactly what
happened this morning.
Yes, but people have told you
that it's your fault, haven't they?
My actions and the shooting
were associative incidents.
It is not a causal relationship.
I paced and she got shot, but
pacing doesn't cause shootings.
Otherwise, every time someone
paced a shooting would soon follow.
Okay, that's a very good point.
When someone has a gun and
it's a dangerous situation, right?
You don't wanna upset the situation,
you don't wanna make it worse.
You think this is my fault, too?
No. No. It was the shoot...
It was the shooter's fault,
but your actions may
have contributed to it.
Okay, Shaun, wait a
second. Wait a second.
I know your behavior is not
completely in your control,
but I also know it's not
completely out of your control. Is it?
So, yes, maybe it is
a little bit your fault.
And definitely mine.
You weren't even there.
That's right, I wasn't there.
Can we sit down,
please? Just for a second.
Shaun, I convinced myself
that everything was fine,
because in here it is.
It's great.
But you need help.
Shaun?
You need guidance.
Much more than I can give you.
I'm supposed to
be with my patient.
I'm supposed to be
watching her like a hawk.
It's my fault.
I didn't like her.
When I first saw her
this morning, she just...
It didn't look...
I don't know, I...
I mean, I wanted to blow
her off, so I said I forgot water.
And I figured we'd
go to the store,
and then I'd pretend
that I forgot my wallet.
I knew she didn't
have her purse, so...
You can't go hiking
without water, right?
I mean, no harm, no foul.
She was there because of me.
She's here because of me.
It's not a causal relationship.
Wait, excuse me?
Lying and shootings.
Lying doesn't cause shootings,
otherwise, every time someone lied...
Her pulse pressure is narrow.
Wait, what does that mean?
She's dying.
Page Melendez. Stat.
Your respiratory rate is up.
- Are you having trouble breathing?
- Yeah, it's tight.
Find Dr. Lim.
Narrow pulse pressure
indicates a reduced cardiac output.
The inflammation
is affecting her heart.
She's in end-stage
organ failure.
Yes, we can insert an
intra-aortic balloon pump.
That may reduce some of
the workload on her heart,
but it's failing
fast. Really fast.
It only needs to work overnight.
The inflammatory reaction
will improve after that.
What if it's failing so fast
because it's not her heart?
Her hemoglobin's dropped from
14 to 12 between her last two draws.
What if the real problem is
she's bleeding somewhere?
Given what she's been through, a
two-point drop could mean nothing.
Or it could mean a bleed,
which would account for
the narrow pulse pressure.
Her heart could be fine.
If you're right, that means
we'd have to open her back up.
I don't know if her body
could handle another operation.
No, it can't.
Treating heart failure
with an aortic pump
is also a simple procedure.
So we're going to diagnose based
on which procedure is simpler?
If I'm right, there could be no
more blood to pump. She'll be dead.
She's crashing.
We should prepare
the cath lab for a pump.
We should prepare the OR.
Let's get her into an OR. Now.
Hemoglobin's dropped to eight.
She is bleeding out.
Yes, she is. But where?
Gotta find where the
bleeder's coming from
and clip it before she dies.
I got nothing.
It must be hidden underneath the
retro peritoneum or mediastinum.
That's a lot of real estate to cut
open and just go blindly looking.
We should start with the
abdomen. She was shot there.
The bullet passed
through the posterior thorax.
BP's 40 over palp.
She's dying, Neil.
Whatever you're gonna
do, you need to do it now.
We need to look everywhere.
Give me a knife and sternal saw,
I'm gonna open her
up from chest to pelvis.
Prep the sternum and
abdomen with betadine.
We're gonna need a sponge
stick to control the bleeding.
Stop!
Open her between the second
and third rib on the left side.
The bullet nicked the left
supreme intercostal artery.
The wall has blown.
How do you know?
I followed the injuries.
Pelvis to bowel to
spleen to diaphragm.
Next target has to be left
supreme intercostal artery.
All right. Prep the
left intercostal space.
I can't breathe. Why
aren't you helping me?
Dr. Lim will be along
in just two minutes.
You're a damn
doctor. Do your job.
Can't breathe.
I need to open up the
left neck compartment.
It'll relieve the
pressure. Procedure tray.
Have you done this before?
Nope. Scalpel.
It's too swollen, I can't
see the Adam's apple.
Okay, cut along the soft divot
between the carotid
sheath and the trachea.
Soft divot. Got it.
Update me.
What did you do?
He had a cervical hematoma,
I had to relieve the pressure.
Here?
Oxygen sats are going up.
It's rare, but post-op swelling
can happen with tracheal tears.
That's why we watch them
so closely the first 24 hours.
You mind if we finish this
off in the operating room?
I don't see anything, Shaun.
No blood and no arterial tear.
You're too high. It's
near the bifurcation.
Can I get some light in?
I got something. Blood's pooling
right under the
bifurcation. Clamp, now.
She wasn't in heart failure.
That means her heart is still strong
enough to get her through the night.
I was wrong.
Yeah, and you
just made up for it.
You were right, Jared.
Good work.
You know what? You were
right, my mother had problems.
So I couldn't
afford to sit around
expecting everything
to be handed to me,
or whatever else it is
that's holding you back.
And yeah, I got some breaks.
But I worked my ass off.
Two jobs, two room-mates,
every step of the way.
And that is what got me to the
place where I could save your life.
Your daughter's not
out of the woods yet,
but I do expect her condition
to improve day by day.
- Thank you, Doctor.
- Thank you.
You're welcome.
Hey. Avery.
Sorry we weren't here for you.
How are you feeling?
I probably won't be
hiking any time soon.
Hey.
Are you sneaking out
before I can thank you?
Please, you don't
need to thank me.
Yeah, I do.
And apologize.
I was wrong about you.
I thought you were
trying to ditch me.
I was hoping you
were trying to ditch me.
I'm sorry.
When you're feeling better,
I'd like a second
chance at a first date.
I'm sorry.
You were right. I
publicly disrespected you.
And so I thought it only
right to publicly respect you.
I am grateful for the
chance to learn from you.
I know you needed this victory.
Glad you saved a life today.
Just wish it wasn't a Nazi.
Lane number two.
Maddie always took that lane.
She'd tuck in behind me and
draft until the last 200 meters.
It's a dirty little trick.
- And it worked.
- Every time.
Thirteen years ago today.
Yeah.
I miss her, too.
Gave her space.
Right? I gave her space.
And she just drifted
farther and farther away.
Everything I did, I did wrong.
You did your best.
I was practically living
at your house back then.
And, I mean, if I hadn't...
You were both...
Teenagers. You were idiots.
You got lucky, she didn't.
If I was there more,
if I stayed on her...
You're there for him.
Here's your extended
forecast for the week.
Starting off with a little bit of
cloud cover in San Francisco...
expect dry conditions for
the next seven days here in...
I, uh, saw your light.
I'm sorry.
Claire told me to apologize because
you didn't want me to tell the truth.
You only wanted me
to support your position,
even though it's wrong.
Well, I don't accept.
I may have overreacted
this morning.
A little.
And you were honest.
Brutally honest,
but you shouldn't have to
wear earplugs in your own home.
And don't start lying to
me to make me feel good.
You're the only
honest guy I know.
So...
Have a good night, Shaun Murphy,
and I will try not
to keep you up.
I'll be your mirror
Reflect what you are
In case you don't know
I'll be the wind, the
rain and the sunset
The light on your door
to show that you're home
'Cause when you think
the night has seen...
I made a mistake today.
And someone got hurt.
Let me stand to
show that you are blind
Please put down your hands
'Cause I see you