The human body
is designed to
compensate for loss.
It adapts so it no longer
needs the thing it can't have.
Guess we should
take the crib down.
Oh, no. I'm just sorting
through the clothes
that Zola's grown out of
so I can give them away.
I mean, she's so big now,
when she comes back,
she'll never fit into these.
We haven't heard
anything in weeks.
Janet said it was gonna take
a while, and it's taking a while.
Just be patient.
Just fold these. It helps.
I don't know why, but it helps.
She's coming back.
But sometimes a
loss is too great,
and the body can't
compensate on its own.
That's when
surgeons get involved.
Stop it. I am making breakfast.
You don't cook.
I do...
Sometimes.
Here. Try these.
Eggs cooked almost
entirely with my left hand.
Teddy said the best cardio
surgeons have two dominant hands.
It's like a superpower.
So I am in training.
Want some more?
You know, I think...
I think I want something else.
Oh, no.
That's my superpower.
I only use one hand, too.
Hey. Where are you going?
To visit Molly for two days.
Oh, that's great.
Jackson arranged
it. It was a surprise.
Oh.
What do you mean by
that? Nothing. Just "oh."
'Cause it sounded
like you meant,
"Really, he arranged for
you to go visit your sister
"at the exact time his
mother's coming into town?
"Guess he's not
really that into you,
"otherwise, he'd want you to meet
his mother like a normal person."
No. You had a mother.
Jackson and I had
surgeons who procreated.
It's just a little complicated.
I shouldn't go, right?
No, I think it's sweet
that he wants you
to get out of the line of fire.
That's my cab.
Yeah, I should stay.
I think you should probably get
out while you have the chance.
Morning.
I'm in your OR today.
I can see that.
It's not gonna be
a problem, is it?
No.
Good, good, 'cause
I was avoiding you,
and now I'm not.
See, I'm told you're dating
a nurse, and kudos to you,
'cause who doesn't
love a nurse, but...
I've been bringing lattes
to some dude in
scheduling named Pierre
so he'd keep me
out of your surgeries.
You know, I wanted to
make it easier for you,
since you told me you were being
held together by tape and glue.
But now that you're being
held together by a male nurse,
I'm gonna let Pierre go
ahead and get his own lattes.
See you in surgery.
Hey, Miranda. You
coming to dinner tonight?
Yeah.
And is it just you and Eli
or will Ben's butt
be joining us, too?
Joking.
That was... That's just a joke.
I'll assume that it's
just two for dinner,
and you can... Bye.
Hey, I saw the board.
Three islet device surgeries
and a follow-up on Henry,
spreading it a little thin.
You concerned
about me or your trial?
No, your trial.
Well, the way you're
trying to micromanage me,
it seems like you
still think it's yours.
Yeah, but Meredith Grey's
stepping away from neuro.
I mean, she needs a new focus,
and you could use the
help. She's got a gift.
It's a gift, all right.
She could be a real asset.
The answer is no.
Ugh!
I can't believe Altman postponed
our surgery for grand rounds.
It's just a boring lecture.
Your husband said
it was mandatory.
One more hour of
sleep, that's what it is.
Oh, no. It's not
gonna be boring.
This is Jackson's
mother, Catherine Avery.
She's a urologist, right?
Yeah. I met her when I
was an intern at Mercy West.
She's amazing.
She is a lunatic.
No, she's not. She's brilliant.
She says these
things that shock you,
but then when you
think about them later,
they change your whole life.
Or they ruin your whole life.
She's toxic. She's a meddler.
My mom has no
boundaries. Be warned.
Hey, is that why you
shipped Lexie out of state?
What? Oh. You shipped Lexie...
Wow.
Who hides his girlfriend under a
rock while his mom comes into town?
Someone who's got a
hypercritical surgeon for a mom.
I get it.
Is your mom ambidextrous?
I bet you she is. All
the best surgeons are.
Wait a second. How often
do you talk to my mom?
We're Facebook friends.
You're... You and my mother?
She's a brilliant
surgeon and woman.
She's a trailblazer.
And she's got a stalker.
Hey, you know what?
Just meet her. You'll see.
So do you want us to
bring anything tonight?
Nope. I got it covered. Thanks.
What's tonight? A dinner party.
Teddy and Henry's new place.
You're... You're not invited.
Why? You're the babysitter.
Wake up, everybody.
I know, I know,
it's grand rounds,
where we have to sit
and listen to somebody
talk about how
somebody did something
and here's how they did it,
and there's not enough
coffee in Brazil for this.
Well, not today.
Today we are going to do.
Today I'm going to change a life
and maybe make
medical history, too.
And I can't do it alone,
so who wants to step
into the future with me?
Whoo!
Okay. That's all
right. That's a start.
Let's see if I can
get a few more.
Ryan, honey, would you
come out here, please?
Everybody, this is Ryan.
Hi.
Ryan, could you show everybody
what we're here to do today?
Ladies and gentlemen,
I'd like to invite a few
very lucky residents
to scrub in on
this country's first
penis transplant.
Thanks to a case
of penile cancer,
Ryan underwent a full
penectomy 11 months ago.
Good margins left him
basically cured and cancer-free.
So that's gone.
And today we'll be replacing
the other thing Ryan lost.
A suitable donor's
become available
here at Seattle
Grace-Mercy West,
and Ryan generously
agreed to fly out
and make this day a
teaching opportunity.
Who wants in on it?
Hello! That's more like it.
Uh, Mark Sloan, plastics.
Isn't penile reconstruction
the standard approach
in cases like these?
Why a transplant?
Well, I can answer your
question with a question.
Do you like your penis?
Yes.
It does the job.
If one day, it wasn't there,
wouldn't you want it back?
Or would you be satisfied
with a reconstructed organ
that has very little function?
Satisfied? No.
But that's not the...
Neither would Ryan here.
Yes, this is new ground.
But here's a young man with
his whole life ahead of him,
with the will to live
it as a whole man,
with a bravery and
selflessness to help
advance medical
science along the way.
So let's give Ryan
a hand. Come on!
Whoo!
And now let's give Ryan a penis!
Yes!
So nice to see you
again, too, really.
Thank you. Thank you.
Gotta make a big
show out of everything.
There's my baby boy.
Hi, Mom. Come here.
Ooh! You look skinny.
You're not sleeping?
Hey, I'm fine, mom. Mmm.
Which one is she?
She's a brunette, right?
We're not doing
this today, okay?
Maybe the real question is,
what kind of name is Lexie?
I never told you her name.
I have my ways.
Where is she?
She's not here.
She's out of town.
I come into town, and you
smuggle her across state lines?
Are you ashamed
of her? Dr. Avery,
sorry to interrupt.
Interrupt, please.
Oh, Mark Sloan, plastics.
The man who doubts.
Listen, I'm all for standing
up for the Johnson,
but this is a transplant,
and transplant
patients reject organs.
Now I see a 28-year-old guy
who could have a pretty good
life with a reconstructed organ
that my boy here and I
could make tomorrow.
Excuse me.
You're working with Jackson?
I'm mentoring him.
He didn't mention it?
No, he didn't.
Got a great set of hands,
this kid. You should be proud.
Why don't you scrub in with me?
And you can tell me
all the reasons why.
I'll be there. All right.
Can't you just stay out of it?
He's your mentor. Why
not get to know the man?
At least he didn't skip town.
All right.
No, I said I'm not competing.
Come on. It's gonna be the
microsurgery Olympics in there.
You're gonna kill it.
Exactly, and then I'm stuck in
the OR with my mom for 12 hours?
Forget it. Man up.
This is a once-in-a-lifetime
opportunity.
This kind of thing will
look good on your boards.
Now get in there
and make me proud.
Who has worked with the
tissue of the penis before?
Kepner, keep your
hand down. Shh.
Its delicate vascularity
demands a grace and elegance
that not many surgeons of
your station have mastered.
The two surgeons to do the
best end-to-end anastomosis
of their chicken's femoral
vessels will scrub in with me.
So be cautious,
be careful,
be brilliant...
Begin!
Yes! You have no idea how...
No.
Sorry, sweetie.
You're too tense.
You're all wound up.
This isn't woodshop.
Step to the back.
You need to lay
off the lattes, dear.
Your left hand is shaking
like a motel bedspring.
It's just tired.
I hear you, honey.
Aren't we all?
Step to the back.
It's very simple, people.
All it has to be is perfect.
Okay, last stitch.
Can I have the dressing, please?
Pretty snappy, huh?
Hmm?
It goes fast,
like magic.
Magic.
Okay, can I have the chart?
Is there a problem?
Not that I'm aware of.
Because I'm doing
my best to be pleasant,
but I don't owe you an
explanation for the fact
that I happen to be...
Sleeping with a nurse, I
believe, is what you're looking for.
You and I broke up.
You basically told
me to wait for you.
What? I did no such thing.
No, but you did.
You said it was too much.
Something horrible
had just happened,
you were traumatized, you
couldn't handle a relationship.
It wasn't me. It was you.
Okay, now that is not fair
and, look, I still can't
handle a relationship,
the kind of thing that you
and I were considering...
What I'm doing right
now is nothing like that.
Then what is it?
If you have a problem working
with me, take it up with Pierre.
Excellent.
Very fine work, Doctor...
Grey.
As in Lexie Grey?
Oh, she's my sister.
Oh.
Come on. Not now.
I gotta...
I'm out.
Hey, he forfeits, right?
He walked out.
Congratulations.
We have our winners.
He's your son, and
you're the judge.
Isn't there some
rule against that?
I don't play favorites, dear.
Nepotism is for the weak.
That's what my birthday
cards always said.
What the hell
happened? I don't know.
Does anybody else
know about this?
I don't think so.
She had a seizure.
Now it's gonna be
big, right? Chad.
What? I'm just sayin', maybe
you could be trading up, you know?
Have you seen it?
The donor organ? Yes.
How's it measure up? It's
nothing to be embarrassed about?
Chad, shut up.
I'm just sayin',
my little brother's
a good-lookin' kid.
He's gonna need...
He's gonna be happy with it.
And it's gonna work?
Not just the plumbing,
it'll stand up and
report for duty?
Chad, I swear to God.
That's the point of
doing a transplant,
to hopefully restore full
urinary and sexual function.
If you're worried, there's
always penile reconstruction.
It's less risky.
I saw the signs for months
before I saw a doctor.
By the time I finally saw
someone, they tell me it's cancer,
it's too far gone,
and I have to lose it.
I'm tired of, every
time I look down,
being reminded of
what a coward I am.
This feels like a second chance,
and like she says, if you
can learn something from me
that might help
out the next guy,
then I can feel pretty
good about that, too.
Okay.
See you in surgery.
Temp's 103.
Abdomen's tender and distended.
Her foster mother said
Zola was running a fever.
She's been crying all day.
They couldn't get her to stop.
High-pitched bowel
sounds. Call CT.
Yeah, and I'm gonna
page Grey and Shepherd.
You can't do that.
What? The kid's sick.
Their custody was suspended.
I know they're your
friends, but at this moment,
they're nothing more
than a third party.
It's a breach of
confidentiality.
They're right here.
Their custody is
under investigation.
The last thing any of us
needs is a breach of protocol.
It could jeopardize
the adoption.
Okay, okay, little
miss munchkin.
You're gonna feel
a little bit of a sting,
and then I'm gonna be all done.
Very impressive in
the skills lab, Meredith.
What are you specializing in?
Oh. Um, I was
thinking about neuro,
but I'm making a change.
Jackson had a
chance to be on neuro,
but he turned it down
to follow me into plastics.
You had an opportunity to
work with Derek Shepherd
and you turned it down
for plastics?
Jackson Avery, who raised
you when I wasn't looking?
Mom, let's not...
I'm standing right here.
I know, honey, but
this isn't about you.
This is about
this boy and... Oh!
And here he is,
the man of the hour.
Chad, honey, this is
as far as you can go.
Buddy, as soon as this is over,
I'm gonna take you
to test drive that thing
in every strip club
on Long Island.
Chad, stop.
For the past year, all
we've talked about is this.
I miss talking about the Knicks.
Tell me this is gonna work
so I can have my brother back.
It's gonna work.
I'm gonna go harvest
the organ right now.
I'll see you in the OR.
When this is over, you can
never mention my penis again.
Promise.
All right.
Bye, buddy.
Freakin' hell.
That's a pretty nasty
bowel obstruction.
Are you on your own with that?
No. Uh, Robbins.
Good.
Thank you so much for
letting me help you with this.
I mean, how often do
you get to harvest a penis?
Well, I thought it would
give us a chance to catch up.
Take this, dear.
Okay, here we go...
Like millions of angry
wives have dreamed of.
Except we'll start with an
artistic, elliptical incision.
So how's it going, honey?
Oh, you know, it's fifth year,
and chief resident
is like 20 jobs in one,
and on top of that, I've
got boards coming up
and surgeries to log,
so much to get done.
So when are you going
to have sex with a man?
When are you
gonna get that done?
Hmm?
I'm... I'm sorry. What?
Look, I don't know or care
why you're waiting, dear.
But unless you have a
good reason, I say do it.
You're all wound up.
It'll get you unwound.
It'll make you a better surgeon.
Oh, that's a nice dorsal vein.
Yeah. Easy to graft.
Is it really that obvious?
You keep looking at this
thing like it's gonna bite you.
I...
Catherine Avery.
Richard Webber. Oh!
Shame on you.
I send you my son to educate, and
you let him wander off into plastics.
Well, he seems happy.
Happiness is for
ordinary people.
He's my son.
Greatness is his legacy.
At a certain point,
you have to realize
that you've done
everything you can.
You can't force people to do
things they don't want to do.
Don't I know it.
When was it that we met
at that convention in Miami,
and I just flirted with
you shamelessly,
and you had to tell
me you were married?
I remember.
Are you still married?
'Cause after this surgery tonight,
I'm gonna need some dinner.
I'm still married. Damn it.
Well, there's always
next time. Yeah.
You know I don't give up.
Have a good surgery.
Thanks, Richard.
You're welcome.
What? I was about to do
an art line with my left hand.
Zola's got a bowel
obstruction. We have to operate.
What? Where's Mer?
She can't know.
Neither can Derek.
I mean, they get involved,
and social services flips out,
the adoption's shot.
Well, is she stable?
For the moment.
And that's the right call,
right? We don't tell 'em.
You just told me it was.
But I'm right. Right?
It'll blow the adoption?
Yeah, we can't tell them.
Okay. All right.
That's your decision.
Hey, you just
called me down here
so I could take responsibility
for your decision?
How small are your balls?
Meredith didn't
talk to me for weeks
because I screwed up her life.
The balls are pretty
small right now.
Dr. Karev. The
baby's seizing again.
Page Robbins!
We're tellin' Mer!
You bet your ass, we are.
All right, my dears.
What do you say we
get to anastomosing
these deep dorsal vessels?
Suction.
Dr. Grey, easy on
the suction, hon.
Lighter touch.
Like that?
That's perfect.
Dr. Grey, seems you've inherited
the hands of your
mother. Thank you.
Did your sister Lexie
inherit the same skills?
Dr. Avery.
I'm my mother's only child.
Lexie and I are half sisters.
Sounds like someone
picked the wrong Grey.
Ma...
Lexie is very
talented. She's brilliant.
Lexie's great. Great
surgeon, great girl.
Sorry. Excuse me. Sorry.
What is all the
bustling, please?
I'm sorry to interrupt. I
need to speak with Dr. Grey.
Dr. Grey is busy
making history right now.
Suction, please.
Meredith.
I... I'm sorry,
Dr. Avery. I'm sorry.
For the love of God.
Ellis Grey is rolling
in her grave right now.
Who wants to take
Dr. Grey's place?
Dr. Kepner. Yes!
Excuse me. Excuse
me! I have to scrub.
We're just doing a
standard workup today,
and if your blood's
clean, you're a free man.
Do I have to wait for the
labs or can you call me?
We'll call you. Good,
because I'm marinating
the fish for tonight,
and if it stays in that thing for
too long, it just turns into mush.
What? You don't like fish?
I do.
You don't like fish?
I like fish.
Good. Okay, wow.
I probably should've
checked earlier,
but I'm new to this whole
dinner party thing, so...
What's happening right now?
Henry and Teddy are
having a dinner party tonight.
So I gather. Yeah,
and we're invited.
Yeah, I got that, too.
Is there a problem?
I forgot to tell him.
It's a good thing Henry came
by and brought up the marinade.
That's not a very
masculine topic, marinade.
I should've cooked beef.
Are you free? I am.
I mean, 'cause, you know,
you don't have to come.
Wow. Best invite ever.
I'm...
Okay. This is my, um, bad.
It could be my bad. I mean...
Yeah.
You both suck.
See you at dinner.
Dr. Avery, thank you so
much for bringing me in.
This is so exciting.
Uh-huh. Relax, honey, relax.
Suction, please.
Lightly. Lightly.
And that, ladies and gentlemen,
completes the work
on this dorsal artery.
Everybody, stretch,
shake out your hands,
take a breather.
Your technique
has improved, baby.
Thanks.
It's easy to teach when there's
natural ability to work with.
Your boy's born for plastics.
That might be so, but, you know,
you gotta be careful
with that easy road.
A person can get used
to taking the easy road,
and next thing they
know, they find themselves
the boob-job king of Seattle,
a tummy-tuck tycoon.
I don't think that's fair.
More irrigation and suction.
Are you saying there isn't easy
money in plastics, Dr. Sloan?
Are you saying there's no
valuable work to be done there?
She's saying I don't have the
discipline to resist the easy money.
I'm just saying, there's a
temptation. Gently, April.
Yeah, well, maybe if you
knew a little more about me,
you'd know that I'm
incredibly disciplined.
And I'm not a tummy-tuck tycoon.
I'm sorry about that, Dr. Sloan.
She's obviously...
Don't apologize for me.
Yeah, well, somebody
needs to... Suction, April...
Right near the dorsal vein.
- I chose plastics.
- Right here?
I pursued Dr. Sloan.
These are my choices.
I'm not gonna sit here
and let you trash them
because they're not the same
choices you would've made.
Back off. You back off.
Not you, the suction. April.
Oh, God. The vein is stuck.
What do I do?
All right, shut off
the suction now!
Don't move. It's shredding.
She's mangling it.
Oh, my God. It's not stopping.
Oh, no.
Oh, God.
What did I do?
You destroyed my dorsal vein.
Is it her shunt? Is
it hydrocephalus?
What the hell were you thinking?
That was her CT
before, wasn't it?
I'm sorry. I couldn't
tell you. You still can't.
The hell he can't.
She's my patient.
Oh, thank God. Owen, I...
Look, Robbins told
me what is going on,
and she is right.
You can't see Zola.
Owen, stay out of it.
She's probably terrified.
She's sedated. She's not alone.
I have a herd of nurses
on a rotating schedule,
holding her, singing
her... We've got this.
Did you try an NG tube?
The bowels are
compressing the VP shunt,
and she's hypotensive, so
we're taking her to the OR.
Well, then I'm in there.
Shepherd, you can't.
I inserted the shunt. It's part
of the problem. I should fix it!
Are you out of your mind?
The adoption lady's
watching her like a hawk.
They're looking for a reason
to ding... Where is she?
I will page you the
minute that we're done.
I'll have Karev
give you hourlies...
Karev, look at me.
Where is she?
Pre-op. 1608.
Thank you. I'm going there. No.
Shepherd, don't.
Derek. Derek, don't
do this. Back off, Hunt.
You know how long the
shunt... Derek. Shepherd...
Had to have been
malfunctioning... You are making...
For her bowels to
have gotten this bad?
They didn't know
what to look for.
Exactly, because she
should've been with us.
And she's not,
and that's my fault.
And I may never sleep another
night again because of that,
but if there's a prayer
of us getting her back,
we have to just dot
our I's and cross our T's,
not mess with the rules.
Arizona is a great surgeon.
Please don't make it worse.
What is your
plan on fixing this?
It's just kinked.
Once I get in there, and
I remove the adhesions
and I fix the obstruction,
the shunt will be fine.
What if it's not? What if
it's disconnected or broken?
Then I convert to a VA shunt.
Derek, I can do this.
Let me do this.
I just left OR 2.
They've started.
Thanks.
I know I should
be with Meredith.
I see her pain, but I can't.
I can barely look at her.
This is all her fault.
Every time I think I've moved
on, I've started to forgive her,
something else comes up,
and I'm right back where I was.
You know, Cristina
and I, we just...
We just went through something,
and I know how you feel.
It's not easy.
You know, they
don't make it easy.
No.
Did you hear that Zola
came to the hospital,
had a bowel obstruction?
Yep.
Can't be easy on Meredith.
Can't be easy at all.
You are not
really using
Meredith's sick baby
to guilt me into
putting her on my trial.
Well, if you think she lacks
judgment, then help her.
You're the moral
compass of this hospital.
You don't...
I'm the moral
compass of nothing.
I am using one
man like a plaything
and had another one
bribing a scheduler.
Yeah, I really don't
want to know about...
Like a plaything.
Often.
And enthusiastically.
Maybe you should stop.
Did I mention that I
promised Ellis Grey
on her deathbed
that I would take
care of Meredith?
I am still not putting
that girl on my trial.
I am so sorry, Dr. Avery.
You gave me one job, suction.
I mean, what kind of a person...
Dr. Kepner, stop talking, now.
Okay, new game plan.
We harvest the
saphenous vein from his leg
and use it as extension tubing.
If we used a deep inferior
epigastric perforator flap,
we wouldn't need
to cut into his leg.
I'm not familiar
with that technique.
It's been used recently in
genital reconstruction surgeries.
I've seen him do it. The
results have been amazing.
More natural
looking, ages better,
there'd be no visible scarring,
less post-op pain, fewer
post-op complications.
You want me to go on?
I'm not gonna risk
Ryan's penile function
because I bruised your ego.
I'm not trying to impress you.
Let me do this, and
that'll come naturally.
Come on, Dr. Avery.
Step into the future with me.
Well, if you feel
comfortable doing it...
Hell, I feel comfortable
letting your kid do it.
Avery, prep the abdomen.
I'm on it.
So Alex was
supposed to call by now.
Yeah. In, like, 10 minutes.
Do you think it's bad
if we call him? Yep.
What if she...
She's not gonna
die. Do you hear me?
All right.
Do you know how to do
single-handed left-handed ties?
No. Try it.
Like that?
Did you just do
that on your first try?
Yeah. Well, you are
holding your string too tight...
Shut up.
Got a message from Karev.
They had to resect a
small part of the bowel,
but everything else
looks good so far.
Oh, thank God.
Yeah.
Did you...
Oh, I hate you people.
Don't touch it.
You know, I really
don't get you.
You should understand
better than anyone.
What if it was Sofia?
Do you have any parental rights?
If something happens to her,
Sloan and Torres aren't around,
you got some peds doc saying
you don't have a right to see her.
Mind your own business, Karev.
I'm sorry. I'm just
sayin' it sucks.
No, here's what sucks.
Zola's gonna be fine because
we're awesome surgeons,
and if Meredith and Derek
didn't know that she was here,
Zola would still be fine, the
adoption wouldn't be in jeopardy,
and they wouldn't be
in a room somewhere
going out their minds
imagining the worst.
All right. Good
anastomosis, Dr. Avery.
Perfect flap.
Thank you.
And Mrs. Dr. Avery,
here is your
brand-new dorsal vein.
Impressive, no?
If it actually works.
I mean, right now
all we've got is a sad
old gray penis with
a piece of belly in it.
Dr. Kepner, release the clamp.
Uh, maybe you should do it...
Shh! Girl, get in there.
Yep, pinker.
Oh, that is pinker.
Well, I don't know about you.
But I'd say that's just about
the pinkest penis I've ever seen.
Yep.
We were able to remove
all of the adhesions
and get the shunt working again.
We'll monitor her
while she's here.
She's gonna be fine.
I'll stay with Zola tonight.
Okay. I will call
if there's anything
to worry about.
So don't call
every five minutes.
You guys go home.
Okay.
Hey.
Do I have to set
a place for Eli?
Because I hear that
you forgot to invite him.
Why do people forget to
invite people to dinner parties?
Is that a trick question?
I need to break up with him.
Oh. Oh, oh, please
don't do it at my party.
See, the last time I
broke up with a man,
he thought I was
asking him to wait for me,
and then he did, apparently,
and he bought lattes
for a man named Pierre.
Is that slang for something
that I don't know about?
See, I try to preserve
the dignity of others,
and that's the problem.
And I'm poetic, which, you know,
I like to think
provides clarity,
but in fact may simply
cloud the message.
All right. Here's what I do.
Use short,
declarative sentences.
I'm ending this. All
the best to you. Got it?
Oh, and do it before the party.
No. Not before.
Uh. Tomorrow. Before is rude.
Before is depriving the man of a
meal, which he's now excited about
because your husband
couldn't shut up about the sauce.
I have to serve dinner
to a dead man walking?
Oh, buck up. You can handle it.
I...
I just need a second.
Take all the time you need.
It's like Christmas
friggin' morning, dude.
I will shut up.
Okay. I'm ready.
There's quite a bit of
swelling, but that will go down.
And it'll do everything
it's supposed to.
It's great.
Thank you.
You want to see? I'll
give you one last look.
I'm good, bro. I'm
happy if you're happy.
Well, that is great.
Clean wound.
You'll have a scar,
but who cares?
It'll make you look fierce.
Hey, you know, you
should go to the party.
Oh, I have to finish this.
Plus, I thought I'd
keep you company.
You know, I've been
practicing this all day.
And your parents, they can do
single-handed left-handed ties
with their eyes closed, never
mind closing a tube of cream.
Your dad
is a rock star. He is
a household name.
And your mom? She's a natural.
People say that she
got it from her mom.
So you're gonna get it, too.
You'll watch her resect
tumors all the time,
and when you slice
open your first abdomen,
people will say,
"Oh, my goodness.
"How did she learn
that so fast, huh?
"How did she
learn that so fast?"
And you'll say,
"Oh, I come from a long,
long line of surgeons."
You know, you're right. I'm...
I'm gonna head to that party.
Okay.
Okay, bye.
Bye-bye. Bye-bye. Bye-bye.
Hey. Hey.
Okay, I'm sorry.
Uh... I can't do this.
I need to say something to you,
and I want to make
sure that I'm clear,
because I apparently have
been unclear in the past.
Um... You're ending this.
Whatever this is, it's ending.
Yes.
You're perfectly clear.
You're the clearest
person I've ever known.
You do not have
a clarity problem.
I don't? No.
No. You've been telling me
you don't want a relationship
every day for weeks now.
And I've been ignoring
you because you're...
Different than any
woman I've ever known.
So that's my fault.
I should've walked
away a long time ago.
I can blame you for many things,
but a lack of clarity
is not one of them.
I'm...
I'm sorry.
Enjoy the party.
My son tells me that I have
trouble admitting when I'm wrong.
So this would be the
place where I should say
that was an impressive save.
Of course it was.
He's a good kid.
Probably 'cause you've
given him such a complex,
but for whatever the reason,
let him find his own way.
He'll do good.
Thank you.
Oh, and...
Don't count out Lexie
Grey till you meet her.
She's smart, she's beautiful.
She's perfect.
A guy couldn't do any better.
Dr. Bailey.
Dr. Warren.
Um...
Look, you're gonna
hear about something
because everyone around
here hears about everything.
Eli and I have ended things.
The nurse.
You're gonna think that it
has something to do with you,
and for the sake of clarity,
I would like to be
extremely clear
when I say it doesn't have
anything to do with you.
At all.
Are we clear?
It doesn't have
anything to do with you.
Mmm-hmm.
Ben Warren,
I am being very clear with you.
Are you listening to me?
Night, Miranda Bailey.
I'll see you tomorrow.
No. That is not what I said.
Benjamin Warren!
I am so sorry for
suctioning that vein.
I don't know what happened.
April, stop apologizing.
Would you let it go?
It's all worked out.
Yeah. Honey, you
gotta learn how to relax.
You're making a
good day feel bad.
Hey.
I just wanted to
thank you for the drink.
It was really nice.
I don't... I'm... I think
that you may have...
I think he has the
drink that you sent him.
Oh. Uh...
Oh.
And this is the part
where you get up and go
and play darts with him.
Why are you such a meddler?
I'm using my powers for good.
Cheers.
Did you try one of
these spinach things?
They're fantastic.
Is Cristina coming?
Um. She can't.
Sends her apologies.
Well, this many doctors, and
only three of you got stood up?
That's not bad.
Hey. Mine's here.
So is Eli just
gonna be late or...
Nope.
Stuck at the hospital.
That dress looks great on you.
I picked it out. Hot, right?
Can we talk?
Listen, I want a piece of paper
that says that Sofia's mine.
We always say that we're gonna
do it, but we never actually do it.
Then let's do it.
Because she's
mine. She's my baby.
I mean, she's yours
and she's Mark's,
but she's mine, too.
I mean, I'm the only one that
can get her to go back to sleep
in the middle of the night.
I know.
And she calls me Mama.
And I know that it
sounds like it's babbling,
but she's saying it to me
because I'm her mama.
I know you are.
We'll get you that piece
of paper, okay? I promise.
Okay. Okay. Come here.
Okay. It's okay.
Tell me about plastics.
Mom, come on. I'm tired.
And I don't want
to spend all night
trying to convince you
it's a legitimate specialty.
I'm asking you to
share your interests.
Or you can tell
me about this girl
you shipped off to
another time zone
in honor of my arrival.
Can you blame me? Honestly?
I mean, look how you
were all over Sloan. I mean...
Sloan can take it.
You're saying this Lexie can't?
I like her.
A lot. I don't
want to start this.
I'm gonna meddle one more time.
Yeah. See, if only I could
believe that, maybe we could talk...
Sloan, be careful of him
if you really like her.
Why?
Because he talks about her
the way you should, that's why.
Yeah. They were a thing.
That's over now. Mmm-hmm.
Are you in love with her?
We're not gonna talk about this.
We're so hopeful at
the beginning of things.
It seems like there's
only a world to be gained,
not lost.
That's her.
Hello. CRISTINA: Hey.
You ready? Yeah.
Okay, go.
Hi, baby girl.
Is Aunt Cristina getting
ready to put you to bed?
We love you.
Hey, Zo.
Ready to close your eyes?
Yeah?
They say the inability to
accept loss is a form of insanity.
We love you.
Good night.
It's probably true.
But sometimes,
it's the only way to stay alive.