Dr. Latham.
Dr. Rhodes.
Light day today.
That's good,
because we just
got a call
from Mercy Hospital
over in Rock Island.
They have a young woman
with a type A
aortic dissection
who needs a valve-sparing
root replacement.
Rare, difficult procedure.
Mmm-hmm. And none of
the surgeons there have
any experience with it.
Have the air ambulance
bring her in,
and I'll clear an OR.
I'm afraid we can't.
She's multi-trauma
from a car accident,
and she's too unstable
to travel.
Then they'll have to perform
the standard repair.
Dr. Latham, I...
I do not like to travel.
I can understand that,
given your situation...
You can say it.
My Asperger's.
Dr. Latham, these cases
are indeed rare.
And while I have
assisted you
on one before,
I would like to be able
to say that I have done
one running lead.
Now, it's only
a 20-minute chopper flight,
and we don't even
have to spend the night.
This is important to you.
It is.
Perhaps I shouldn't
be so rigid.
A broadening experience
might do me good.
All right, Dr. Rhodes.
You'll get your procedure.
We'll even
spend the night.
A hotel.
It'll be interesting.
I'll let them know.
More like five under.
It was 10 under.
I just like
to be careful, okay?
I have a history.
Hey, guys.
Morning.
Hey.
That a new
stethoscope?
Oh, yeah.
Owen got a hold of
the last one, so...
Hey, those stuffed animals
are not gonna
diagnose themselves.
All right, blondie.
Coffee later?
You got it, red.
Have a good day.
Thanks.
Hey, babe.
You forgot your lunch.
Tate, I could've
gotten something here.
Potato chips,
pickles and a Zagnut bar?
Pregnant ladies get
to pretty much eat
anything they want, huh?
We could fill you with
a gallon of hormones,
then analyze your diet.
Enjoy your lunch.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Incoming,
Dr. Manning. Treatment Two.
Got it.
Gabe Moore, eight years old,
with advanced
non-Hodgkin's lymphoma,
found seizing at home,
temp 104.
1 milligram of Versed
in the field.
All right,
hang in there, okay?
come on back.
All right, on my count.
Come on.
One, two, three.
All right, get this
out of here, please.
Compression bags.
Equal and reactive to light.
Does he see oncology here?
Er, yeah, Dr. Hurwitz.
Get his current med list
and give a dose of
vanco and ceftriaxone.
Vanco and ceftriaxone,
got it.
Does he have a mother
we should call?
She passed when
he was a baby.
Okay.
Dad?
I'm right here.
These doctors are gonna
take good care of you.
He's seizing!
Give one of Ativan,
push 500 milligrams Dilantin.
Oh, my God.
Let's get some labs,
CBC, CMP, CT head,
blood cultures and an EEG.
The seizure may be
caused by his fever.
However, it is possible
that the cancer's spread
to his brain.
When was his last scan?
Couple of months ago.
Let's get an infused MRI.
I just want to see
if the cancer's spread, okay?
Okay.
Dr. Manning?
Yeah.
Excuse me, please.
I just called
the pharmacy.
Dad hasn't filled
Gabe's chemo
in three months.
He's withholding
his medication.
Maybe he filled it
someplace else?
His oncologist
ordered straight
through the hospital,
no other way
to get it.
He's just waiting
for his son to die?
Mr. Moore,
we are aware that
your son was prescribed
a new oral chemo
and that you have been
withholding it.
I'm not withholding them.
I understand that
you're a single father
and that this must be
incredibly hard for you...
It's not about me.
But if you are willingly
keeping your son off
of his meds...
It's his decision.
Excuse me?
Gabe's.
He's been through
four courses of chemo.
The nausea, the pain,
the drugs to treat
the nausea and the pain,
it was awful.
That doesn't mean
you can just stop trying.
He begged me all through
the last course.
But I wouldn't stop it.
And it didn't help at all.
None of them helped.
So this time,
I let him decide.
Well, he can't decide.
He's eight years old, okay?
His brain is literally
not developed enough
to process this.
Life and death and forever
are concepts
that he cannot
fully understand yet.
Gabe does understand.
I'm sorry,
but we need to
start your son
on his new chemo.
No, I won't authorize that.
I will be back soon
to check on your son.
DCFS can have a court order
to start the chemo
in two hours.
Let's get
the MRI result first.
See if the cancer's
spread so much
that it's no longer
even treatable.
Ms. Holloway,
I'm Dr. Halstead.
I hear you had
some trouble today.
I fell down. Big deal.
Well, says here
your troponin level is 0.08.
That means you fell down
because you were having
a small heart attack.
Ever had any
heart trouble before?
I don't know,
I don't go to doctors.
Dr. Halstead?
Your blood glucose is 458.
You're diabetic?
Mmm. That's what they say.
Let's get a VBG,
give her 10 units
of IV regular insulin
and bolus her a liter of NS.
I'll call endocrine
for a consult,
and let cardiology know
we're admitting her.
Admitting me?
Yeah, that's right.
Diabetes can cause
numerous problems,
including coronary
artery disease.
And I wanna admit you
to run a few tests
on your heart.
And more importantly,
get your diabetes
under control.
Nope, not gonna happen.
Why is that?
Are you gonna feed
Zachary Taylor
and Millard Fillmore?
I'm sorry?
My cats.
Named after
the first 12 presidents.
Let's start getting
your sugar down,
and we'll talk
in a little bit.
Got us a crazy cat lady.
Mmm-hmm.
Drs. Rhodes and Latham,
Mayor Hendricks.
Call me Jim.
My family and I can't
thank you enough for coming.
I assure you we will do
everything we can
for your daughter.
If there's anything
that you need,
please let Bob or me know.
We will. Thank you.
Must be hard
staying upbeat
under such
trying circumstances.
Guess if you're
a politician,
it's expected.
Tough case?
Kids get sick,
I understand that.
But seeing what
their parents do to them,
that drives me nuts.
Yeah.
Coffee time?
That's right.
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm swamped.
Oh, no problem.
Uh, lunch maybe.
Absolutely.
Okay.
Hey, Will?
Yeah?
Did you and Natalie
ever have a thing?
What?
Natalie and me? No.
I mean,
we're good friends, and
you know,
she's a great doctor,
but we never dated
or anything.
Okay.
Besides, who cares?
The only person in the world
I have a thing for
right now is you.
You're such a charmer.
You saw Ms. Holloway?
Yep, thanks for
the heads-up.
Mmm-hmm.
Diabetes studies keep
the lights on upstairs.
Glad I could help.
Huh. That's odd.
She was an architect.
Why is that odd?
Well, her hemoglobin A1C
and lipid panel indicate
she takes extremely
poor care of herself.
You know, it seems
out of character
for someone,
I assume,
pays great attention
to detail.
Slow day for head-shrinkers
around here. You want me
to have a chat?
Sure, knock yourself out.
Shoot me her chart.
Sure.
Hello there, Mrs. Holloway.
Well, hello there.
He's breathing so hard.
He's septic.
We need to give
the antibiotics time.
He'd scream out in his sleep
when it first started
and get these pains.
But he kept on fighting.
I quit my job
to take care of him.
Then help him
keep fighting.
Tell him that
there's a chance
this new chemo could work.
But look at him.
He's not fighting anymore.
He's done.
And I will not flog him
against his wishes.
My boy deserves
better than that.
Incoming trauma.
Dr. Choi. We're going to 2.
Got it, Maggie.
Grace Snow, 26.
Driver in a two-car MVC.
Found hypotensive
and tachypneic,
but responded to
a liter bolus on the ride.
I'm Dr. Choi.
You're at Chicago Med.
All right. Let's transfer.
On my count. Ready?
One, two, three.
Grace, does any
of this hurt?
Let's get trauma labs,
blood gas and a fast scan.
Becca...
What?
Becca driving crazy.
Courtney, I thought
this one was the driver.
They said she was.
I'm her husband.
What happened?
She was in a car accident.
Oh, my God, Grace,
are you okay?
Crashed the car...
Possibly some small fluid
in Morrison's pouch.
Since vitals are stable,
let's get a pan scan.
She keeps
mentioning Becca.
Was there someone else
in the car?
Uh, I don't know.
Does she know
someone named Becca?
If there's another victim
still out there,
we need to find her.
Maggie, call PD.
Might be another injury
in the field.
Wait, wait,
there's no other victim.
Becca is Grace's tulpa.
Her what?
A sentient being
that lives inside her body.
Becca is Grace's tulpa.
I created her.
You created Becca?
It's how tulpas work.
First, you start
with an image in your mind
of a person
or a character
you might like.
Then you spend some time
with her each day.
Eventually, she takes on
a personality of her own.
She becomes
three-dimensional.
Huh. That's interesting.
So how do you know
what Becca thinks?
I talk to her.
It's tricky at first.
She likes to stay
in the background.
But lately
she's been fronting
more and more.
Fronting?
Taking over my body.
My muscles, my eyes.
Wasn't always easy,
giving over total control
like that,
but you get used to it.
There's a website
that teaches you how.
So, is that what happened
today in the car?
Yeah.
Okay.
I let her drive.
I shouldn't have.
She's not very good at it.
But we got into an argument,
and she got upset
and lost control.
Which is why we decided
that you, Grace,
wouldn't see her anymore.
Right?
Right.
They're ready for
Mrs. Scott in CT.
Okay, well, very nice
to meet you, Grace.
Um, we hope that
both you and Becca
are feeling better soon.
As long as
scans are negative,
I'll observe for a few hours,
and then you can
admit her to psych.
The differential's long.
Could be dissociative
identity disorder,
schizophrenia...
Or it could
just be a tulpa.
I mean, I'm not ruling out
any of that other stuff yet,
but until we see
signs of impairment,
we have to consider
the possibility
that she really
could've created
an alter ego
that she believes
cohabits her body.
But tulpas aren't
in the DSM.
So what?
She's clearly disturbed.
We need a diagnosis.
Well, it's challenging.
And I look forward
to seeing where you land.
Hey, I just got off
the phone with PD.
They've got several
eyewitness accounts
of the accident,
saying that your patient
accelerated directly
into traffic.
They think it was
a suicide attempt.
Hmm.
Just got a little
more complicated.
Mmm-hmm.
Graft is in.
Let's re-implant
the coronaries.
We'll do
the left coronary first
due to its anterior location.
MALE LOCAL SURGEON:
How far do you prefer
to dissect for implantation?
or 6 centimeters.
MALE LOCAL SURGEON:
Even when
it's a little shorter,
there could be some tension.
That rarely
becomes problematic.
FEMALE LOCAL SURGEON:
Though Kessler et al.
did report
pseudoaneurysm formation
in 20% of implants
under tension.
Which we can avoid
with added dissection.
MALE LOCAL SURGEON:
So, you'd prefer to risk
a branch injury
and possibly force
a double bypass?
No.
I believe Dr. Rhodes means
we can do a Cabrol,
attach an 8 millimeter
woven graft
to the left coronary
in order to ease
the tension.
Am I correct, Dr. Rhodes?
Yes. Yes,
that is what we should do.
Open an 8 millimeter
woven graft.
What's the verdict?
Definitely in the red
on the old
eccentricity meter,
but not really any
alarm bells to speak of.
So we can't hold her?
Not if she wants to go.
Totally her call.
Figured. Thanks.
You know, it used to be,
if a doctor told a patient
to do something,
they just did it.
You been binging on
Dr. Quinn,
Medicine Woman again?
No, I'm just saying,
things were different,
all right?
Like guys didn't need
to tell women
every single thing
they were feeling.
My father never did.
Are we still talking
about diabetes?
Brought the rest
of that assessment
for you to fill out.
Can I ask you,
that handsome doctor,
is he seeing anyone?
Dr. Halstead?
Actually, I believe he is.
Not the one with the hair.
The big one, in the vest.
Dr. Charles?
Actually, I have no idea.
Hey, buddy.
Where's your dad?
He went to the bathroom.
Can I go home?
Not yet. We're still
working on your fever.
Okay.
You like video games?
Yeah, I do.
So,
you know when
your character dies
and the game ends,
you can just start over
and play again?
Uh-huh.
Okay, well,
when people die,
it's different.
There are no do-overs.
You can't just
start a new game.
I know. You don't think
or do anything
because you're
not here anymore.
Like my mom.
Right.
So if you only have
one chance,
wouldn't you want to fight
like crazy to keep going
for as long as you can?
I did, but nothing worked.
It just hurt a lot.
I know.
Gabe,
we want to be able
to give you a new medicine.
And I'm afraid
if you don't take it,
you are gonna die.
And I don't want that.
Thank you.
But everybody has
their time to live.
I've had mine.
I want to see
what's next.
Grace, I'm sorry,
but we have to ask you,
did you try to
kill yourself today?
What? No.
You said before
that you and Becca
were having an argument.
What was that about?
Nothing.
She just gets upset
with me sometimes.
Upset?
Not upset, just...
Like, she doesn't understand
how I could love someone
who wants to keep us apart.
I imagine
that'd be hard for her.
It is. Really is.
I mean,
she's my best friend.
Why should I have
to stop seeing her?
I don't always connect
with other people.
So when there's one person
you can talk to
and be yourself with,
who isn't gonna judge you
or hurt your feelings...
Knowing I have
a really good friend
should make Mark happy.
But it doesn't.
I don't understand why.
Grace, are you sure
that you weren't trying
to end your life today?
No.
I don't know.
Maybe.
I just... I don't know.
Put her
on a five-day hold?
Yeah. Poor woman.
Mmm-hmm.
At least we can
narrow it down to
something psychiatric.
Maybe put her on a trial
of antipsychotics?
I don't know.
Becca tried
to kill Grace.
Yeah, but let's not forget,
Becca is Grace.
I mean, we might yet find
that she's psychotic,
but she could also just be
cracking under the pressure
of forcibly being cut off
from a part of herself.
Wait, you don't think
she is actually
within the bounds
of functionality?
I think we need
more information,
don't you?
Grab me when
her husband gets back.
I think it might be time
for us all to, um...
To meet Becca.
ST elevation,
she's having an MI.
Give her an aspirin, nitro,
and push five milligrams
of morphine.
What can I do?
Get her on 10 liters of O2.
Lydia, we're gonna
get you through this.
Stay with me.
Lydia,
lift your tongue up.
Morphine's in.
Send another troponin
and get a 12-lead.
Ms. Holloway, you just had
another heart attack.
I need to get you up
for angiography
and probably
a stent right now,
do you understand?
Yes.
Good.
But I'm not doing it.
I told you,
I'm going home to my cats.
Maybe I have not been
clear enough.
How many cats?
Twelve.
Draw a red top tube as well.
Give me a few minutes.
I think we might've
found a reason
for her to stay.
Hey, back in the OR,
thanks for not letting me
look like an idiot.
Oh, no need to
thank me for it.
Still, I appreciate it.
I always thought that
needing to be rescued
was a sign of weakness.
I'm starting to see
it's more complicated
than that.
Dr. Latham!
So glad
you could join us.
Now, we may not be Chicago,
but I bet you guys have
never had a wicked sidecar
inside a 100-foot
rock dome.
Come on.
No, I'm...
Dr. Rhodes, Mike Evans,
Chamber of Commerce.
Hey, pleasure to meet you.
Let's get you a drink.
Absolutely.
Strap yourself in.
Ms. Holloway's case
has a psych component
after all.
Toxoplasmosis.
That's a parasite
from cat feces.
Which lives
in the victim's brain
forever,
and in women,
toxo creates a compulsion
to take care of cats.
Makes one wonder,
do cat lovers
get toxoplasmosis,
or does toxo make
them cat lovers?
Interesting, but not
terribly relevant.
What is relevant
is its other effects
on women.
They become less concerned
with their own welfare.
Which might be
fueling her refusal
to let us take care of her.
All right.
Let's go tell her.
Sure you want to do that?
There's a parasite
in her brain.
Yeah. But there's no cure
for toxo.
You'd be giving her
information she can't
do anything with.
Her decision-making
capability is compromised.
Knowing the truth
could help her change
how she thinks.
Eh, a lot easier said
than done.
Still, it's our
responsibility to
let her decide.
Fair enough.
All right.
So what you're saying is,
I've been living alone
for 10 years,
keeping to myself,
all because of a parasite?
It's certainly a factor.
It alters your thoughts,
but it doesn't dictate them.
I mean, you must have
noticed differences
from when you were younger.
I used to go out more.
Had more friends,
always liked to travel.
But as the years went on,
I didn't really feel like
doing those things anymore.
But wouldn't it be great
if you did?
Maybe.
Doesn't seem
so interesting now.
Well, that's it,
why not?
You're the same person
you used to be.
Am I?
You just said
there's a bug in my head
pulling the strings.
But now that you know,
you can do something
about it.
Make better decisions.
There's no reason
you can't
reach down inside
and find the person
you were.
I don't know.
Ms. Holloway,
I think the chance
to be yourself again
is worth fighting for.
See if we can get her
in the cath lab today.
Sure.
You okay?
Nina asked if
there was ever anything
between Nat and me.
Really?
Well, technically,
there wasn't.
I mean, we never went out.
Mmm-hmm.
But okay, no,
I wasn't completely honest.
I should... I should
tell her the truth, right?
I mean,
we're in a relationship.
That should be
built on honesty.
You're asking my advice?
Women don't
usually appreciate
hearing about their
boyfriend's feelings
for other women.
But it's the right
thing to do.
Ah.
Isn't it?
Hi.
Gabe's blood gases
are getting worse.
We're getting to a point
where we may
have to intubate.
And that'll get him through
till you can get
the infection under control?
The antibiotics still
aren't turning it around.
And there's
a very good chance
that once we intubate,
we may not be able
to get the tube out again.
Wait, I won't be able
to talk to him again?
It's possible.
I'm sorry.
God.
Excuse me.
Dr. Manning.
We're not there
quite yet.
I'll be back.
The radiologist
hasn't read the MRI yet,
but I don't care.
We need to get Gabe
that chemo.
But, April, bringing in
Family Services...
Okay, you feel
for the dad. I get it.
But you are Gabe's doctor.
And that boy understands
more about his situation
than you think.
Natalie, if you don't
call DCFS, I will.
Okay. I'll talk to Goodwin.
You can see it
on their websites.
Tulpas go on dates
with other tulpas.
Dates.
How does that work?
You bring your tulpa,
they bring theirs.
It's nuts.
I can't believe
that you're
taking it seriously.
Well, what we're doing
is we're taking
Grace seriously.
Which is why it's important
for us to get a sense
of who this
alternate personality is
and how
she presents herself.
Okay?
Hi, Grace.
How are you feeling?
Okay.
So we were wondering,
um, if it might be
possible for us to
say hello to Becca.
You too?
Yeah.
Okay. It'll just take
a moment.
Take all the time
you need.
What's up?
Hello, Becca.
I'm Dr. Charles,
and this is Dr. Reese.
I think you know Mark.
Hey.
Mark, would you like
to get us started off?
Becca,
I heard that
you and Grace
had a fight.
So?
I'd like to hear
about it.
I'm sure you would.
Um, Becca, the more
forthcoming you could be...
Fine.
I was explaining
how you don't love her.
Of course I love her.
Then why don't you want her
to have any friends?
This is crazy.
Grace, can I please
just talk to you?
No. You deal with me.
I want Grace to have friends,
but she spends
all day and night online.
That's where
her friends are.
Chatrooms for tulpamancers!
For what?
Tulpamancers,
that's what they call it.
Grace wasn't always
like this.
She used to be normal.
"Used to be"?
Grace and I were married
for two years
before you showed up.
I didn't "show up."
Grace just told you
about me last year.
What does that mean?
It means she created me
in high school.
High school?
Yeah.
I'm the reason she was
able to move out of
her parents' house.
I'm the reason
she got up the courage
to meet you at that party.
Grace, can I
please just...
I'm the one
who's been with her
all these years.
Not you. Me.
Whoever you are,
you tell my wife
that she has to choose.
It's either Becca or me.
Obviously, she is
profoundly disturbed,
which we should've known
when she first said "tulpa."
Why are we treating her
like she is sane
when she isn't?
Wouldn't that be
a little too easy, though?
I mean, sure,
we could, you know,
slap a label on her,
put her in some
diagnostic box,
pour some medicine on top,
but sometimes
it's a little more
complicated than that.
She had an argument
with her made-up friend
while her subconscious
crashed the car.
It seems
pretty simple to me.
Grace is definitely
a fractured personality.
But it's all the more reason
that we have a responsibility
to dig deeper
and figure out why.
All right. I'm sorry,
Dr. Charles,
but I like boxes.
None of this
makes any sense.
It is all so subjective.
I hate it. I mean,
where's the science?
Dr. Reese,
every medical discipline,
psychiatry included,
is as much art
as it is science.
Well, I don't see
the science or the art.
You know,
everybody was so surprised
when I went into this,
me, the lab geek.
Well, they were right.
I don't belong here.
Uh, excuse me
for a second, guys.
Sure.
Looks like you're having
a good time.
Ah.
Very nice young woman.
We're going up to my room.
She has an irregular mole
she'd like me
to take a look at.
Was that her idea or yours?
Here, Doc,
let me freshen that up.
Uh... Why don't
the three of us go over
to the steakhouse?
My treat.
Dr. Rhodes,
are you trying to...
What is the expression?
Interrupt my flow?
No. No, I'm not.
Night.
Are they putting in
the tube now?
Dad, I'm...
Scared.
I know, buddy.
But the doctor's gonna
give you some medicine
so you sleep
and it won't hurt.
Right?
That's right.
Dr. Manning?
Yes?
I'll be right back.
DCFS is on their way.
Okay. Um... Just tell them
I need a minute.
Fine, but they won't
wait long.
Okay.
I just want you to know
you're the best son
a dad could hope for.
You are so brave,
and I am so proud of you.
And I love you
so, so much.
Ms. Holloway.
Where are you going?
Home.
Andrew Jackson gets anxious
when you don't change
his water.
Okay, but we decided
that you'd stay
and get a full workup.
You decided that.
But, Ms. Holloway...
I'm not sure I even believe
all this toxic
whatever business.
And even if I did,
would it be me
believing you,
or the parasite?
What was the point
in even telling me
all that stuff?
She's just gonna be back
with another coronary event.
Funny thing about the truth,
it rarely sets anyone free.
I think she likes you.
I hope
that's a compliment.
Actually, it's more
of a diagnostic clue.
Turns out men with toxo
are more attractive
to infected women.
And it also makes them
rumpled, introverted,
dismissive of rules
and secretive.
Are you
insinuating something?
Not insinuating,
directly stating
that you might have
toxo, too.
Yeah. Thanks, Nancy Drew,
but it's not possible.
You know I'm not
a cat person.
Actually, I had no idea.
Maybe because you are
so secretive.
Oh, I take it back,
Perry Mason.
You ever consider
the law?
Hmm.
You are avoiding.
Why don't we just
do a blood test?
Okay, yeah, sure.
Yeah?
Blood test,
good idea, great.
Great, I will find you
after work.
See you then.
Hey, somebody help!
She's tachycardic
and tachypneic.
Sats at 84.
Grace, does this hurt?
Hey, what's happening?
Is she bleeding?
I don't think so.
Belly's benign.
CTs were negative.
Rhythm's gone.
EKG leads
are coming off.
She's sweating like crazy.
Let's get the crash cart!
Heart attack?
No cyanosis or pallor.
Let's check
her rhythm.
Uh... Fast but regular.
Wait.
Grace, talk to Becca.
What?
Talk to her, Grace.
Sarah.
Can you talk
to Becca?
Is she there?
What's she telling you?
To breathe.
This could be
blunt cardiac trauma.
Let's get an EKG,
labs, and an echo.
No, no, no, wait.
Breathe.
Anything else?
Calm. Imagine us
in a peaceful place.
Okay, then listen to her.
Reese, we need...
Listen to her.
Sats back up to 96.
She was having
a panic attack.
And Becca talked her down.
Hey,
I got your call.
Dr. Latham, are...
Something wrong?
That woman,
she asked me to get ice
for our drinks,
and when I returned,
she was gone,
as was the $200
in my wallet and my watch
that my parents gave me
for graduation! I...
Really?
Your skepticism
was well-founded.
I should have
never allowed myself
to get involved like that.
My mother
will be very upset.
Gabe's MRI results.
His tumors are shrinking?
Doesn't make sense, right?
I mean, chemo can suppress
the immune system,
and the immune system
helps fight cancer.
So being off chemo might have
allowed his immune system
to recuperate.
It would explain his fever,
signs that his body's
starting to fight again.
And it's fighting
the cancer.
Yeah. I mean,
withholding chemo
might actually
have saved his life.
Ms. Goodwin,
we don't need to do this.
I'm sorry,
it's in the hands
of DCFS now.
No, no. I was wrong.
He doesn't need
the medication.
What's going on?
Mr. Moore,
I'm placing you
under arrest...
No, no, no, please!
...for medical
child neglect.
Dr. Manning?
No, just stop.
Everything is okay.
Excuse me, ma'am.
I'm not leaving my son.
No, you need
to listen to me.
Okay? Gabe's tumors
are shrinking
because he didn't get
the chemo.
Gabe is gonna get better!
He's gonna live?
He's got a long ways
to go, but yes.
Sir, I need your hands.
Adam, we'll fix this.
Whatever happens,
it was worth it.
Hey, man.
Hey, there.
So, here's the deal.
I'm gonna need everything
that she took from my friend,
and I'm gonna
give you one hour.
I'm sorry, I don't know
what you're talking about.
Dr. Latham came all the way
out here to save the life
of the Mayor's daughter.
So, how do you think
the Mayor's gonna react
when he hears
that you ripped
that doctor off?
The watch and the $300.
It was only $200.
Call it punitive damages
for pain and suffering.
Come on, man.
One hour.
Much better.
Thank you.
His temp's coming down.
Antibiotics are
finally working.
Goodwin said his aunt
will stay with him
until she can get
the charges dropped.
I'm sorry I got
so worked up earlier. I...
You had a point.
I get these thoughts
and urges now.
Maybe it's this
little tyrant
in my uterus.
You think?
I'll be really glad
when this part is over.
The part where
every decision you make
is because of your child?
I hate to break it to you,
but that one's forever.
Hey.
Hey, ready to go?
Oh. Yeah.
Hey, by the way, um,
you know, when I asked you
about Natalie before,
I really appreciate
your being honest with me.
Yeah.
Look, Nina,
about that...
Yeah?
Well, just...
Of course.
Relationships are
built on trust, right?
Yes.
Which is why I feel like
I need to tell you something.
You know Dr. Rauch
in Cardiology?
I dated him.
Yeah?
Okay. I like Rauch.
I also dated
Jay Flint in GI.
Flint? Heavyset guy?
Oh, it was just
a summer thing.
Dr. Sherman was
a little more serious,
but I don't know.
Your friend
wanted to make sure
that you got these back.
She had an emergency
phone call.
She had to leave.
It turns out
that the whole thing
was just a big, old mistake.
This is too much.
I only had $200.
Yeah, she just felt terrible
about the whole thing.
She wanted
to buy you dinner.
Hmm.
Is that really
what happened?
Dr. Latham, I'm sorry
that I brought you
out here.
My ambition
to do the surgery
got the best of me.
It was selfish.
Well, don't apologize.
All in all, I had
a really good time.
How's she doing?
Which one? Grace? Becca?
Who knows?
Mr. Scott,
if there's a part of Grace
that she didn't feel
comfortable sharing
with you before,
is it not at all possible
to see anything
that's happened here
as a sign of progress?
Progress?
Yeah, I just learned
how unbalanced
my wife really is
and that
she doesn't need me.
She needs Becca.
I'm done.
This was a total disaster.
I'm not so sure
that's true.
I mean,
from Grace's perspective,
this could be as close
to a win as we can get.
She just chose her tulpa
over her husband,
her tulpa
that almost killed her.
I just saw her tulpa
talk her off a ledge.
I have no idea
what to think.
Like it or not,
the line between
a psychological illness
and a coping mechanism
is a blurry one.
I mean, just 'cause
we don't give them
names and voices
doesn't mean
we don't all have
different sides.
I mean, our personalities
change based on
how much sleep we get,
how hungry we are.
Hell, intestinal bacteria
could be
the determining factor
in our emotions.
Look,
I know you think of yourself
as an analytical thinker
and a scientist,
and that you're wondering
if you have a place
in psychiatry right now.
But I also see this
other Sarah in there,
and she's filled
with intuition
and compassion, humanity.
And when you
put them both together,
like during Grace's
panic attack today,
it's when I see
a sensational psychiatrist.
Toxo screen. You a fainter?
Or can we do this
sitting up?
You mind if we hold off
on that right now?
Come on.
I got a better idea.
Believe it or not,
studies show that cat videos
are actually good for people.
Huh.
Mmm.
They increase energy
and positive emotions.
It's crazy, right?
Yeah.
But you know,
in the interest of
full disclosure
and to repudiate
this bizarre accusation
of secretiveness,
I never had a problem
with cats.
Really? Yeah?
Really.
Matter of fact,
I actually had a cat once.
Huh.
Yeah. Name of Pete.
Abyssinian-Siamese mix.
Used to jump on my chest
in the morning
to wake me up.
Had these claws
that could tear a tin can.
But he never hurt
a living soul, that Pete,
which was
especially good news
for all those mice
that lived in my walls...