Station 134, Unit
47 to Dispatch.
Roger, 47, this is Dispatch.
We're heading back to quarters
from Mercy for relief.
ETA is seven minutes.
Roger, 47. What
is your location?
Northbound on
Racine and Webster.
Uh, roger, 47. Stand by, please.
Buy you breakfast?
Wiener Circle?
For breakfast?
Come on.
Char dog, extra
peppers, cheese...
Unit 47,
respond to
residential building fire
at North Ravenswood and Nelson.
Neighbors report
occupants trapped.
Dispatch, this is 47.
We're deadheading
back to Station 134.
Any other units who can fill?
Multiple units
are requested, 47.
I can use the overtime.
Unit 47, responding
to the scene.
That's 47 to the scene at 6:18.
Hey, it's a fire.
At least we'll be warm.
Yeah, thanks for
letting Aunt Susie sleep.
You're so good.
Oh, yes, you are.
Oh, yes.
Oh, and you're wet.
Yeah, okay. I know.
Yeah, today's the big day.
Just me and you.
You nervous?
Are you nervous?
Are you?
Well, I'm a wreck.
Yeah, you'll be great.
I'll probably blow
the whole thing.
You want to go
take a bath together?
Huh? A nice warm bath?
Yeah.
Dispatch, this is Unit 47.
We're first on scene
at Ravenswood and Nelson.
Third story occupied.
Heavy fire showing second floor.
Three engines,
Truck 58, Truck 82,
and Battalion 6 are rolling.
Hey, everybody out of there?
I didn't see anybody come out,
but there was
this big explosion.
Just went "Boom!"
about two or three minutes ago.
People living in there?
Yeah, they're coming
and going all the time.
I think they selling drugs
in there or something.
Everybody, move back!
Move back, everybody! Come on!
Move back, everybody! Hey!
Is anybody else in there?
Is there anybody in there?
Help me!
Shep!
Get his legs! Get his legs!
Damn it!
Roll him! Roll him!
Help me, somebody!
Please!
Get away from the
building now! Come on.
No! No! My babies are in there!
How many?
Three. Please!
Where are they?
On the second floor in the back.
Okay, all right, listen...
Please get them!
Go over there with your child.
The ambulance is on the way.
Go, go!
Raul, we got
three kids up there.
Trucks are on their way.
Call it in. They're gonna
be here in seconds.
Second floor in the back.
Shep! Damn it, Shep, don't...
Shep! Shep!
Dispatch, Unit 47
at Ravenswood fire.
Three kids, second
floor in the rear.
We're going in for
a rescue attempt.
Have the first due
engine back us up.
Roger, 47.
I just feel funny
about taking it off.
She filed for divorce,
and she's living
with another guy.
Morning.
I guarantee you,
she's not wearing hers
while she's digging post holes
in bed with what's-his-name.
You know what?
I don't need any
more mental images
of Jennifer's new sex life.
My imagination
is already working overtime.
You asked me
why women don't
seem interested in you,
and I said that women
do not respond well
to guys who come on to them
while they're wearing
their wedding ring.
It just doesn't...
Randi. Okay.
You meet a cute
guy for the first time.
What do you do?
Run a credit check.
Normal women check on rings.
That's right, Mark,
and if he's not wearing one,
you look for that I'm-married-
but-it's-in-my-pocket
indentation.
I'm telling you.
Throw it in the river.
Throw the ring in the river.
Doug... Yeah.
6-year-old with
the flu, Curtain 3.
Okay.
You going to have
dinner tonight?
No, I'm sorry. I can't.
Here I am, pouring out my
heart about how I can't get a date,
and you're probably
going to go have dinner
with the entire KLM flight crew.
Bulls game with my dad.
Since when
did he and his dad get close?
They aren't.
They've seen each
other a couple of times.
Doug's trying, though.
Oh, man, I can't believe this.
They cut my shifts back again.
I may as well work part-time.
I'm down to eight
shifts a month.
Been moonlighting as a
per diem for a temp agency.
Better money, anyway. Really?
Oh, yeah. Overtime,
no paperwork...
Where's Susan?
She hasn't signed in yet.
Uh-huh.
Appointment. She called
and said she was
going to be late.
Appointment? What
kind of appointment?
This is County. Go ahead.
This is Unit 92.
We're en route
from a residential building fire
with a 20-year-old male.
Extensive second-
and third-degree burns.
Couldn't get a line or intubate,
so we scooped and ran.
Multiple victims at scene.
What do we got?
Crispy critters.
How many?
Three majors,
two minors, so far.
So far?
Still pulling them out.
All coming your way, County.
Our ETA's four minutes.
We'll be waiting.
Randi, page Susan.
Tell her to get here soon.
Notify the Burn
Unit and find Benton.
Lydia, make sure that we have
plenty of Silvadene
and Ringer's lactate.
Man, I hate burn cases.
Sorry. I know it's
here somewhere.
Need to use the phone?
Uh, no.
It's just my work
trying to find me.
So, you were saying
about the visit?
Your home visit went very well.
Ms. Pearline's
expressed a concern
about the hours
you're required to work
during your Residency...
Yeah, I'm trying to cut back.
But biological
relation adoptions
are simple procedures.
Frankly, short of finding you
in the midst of
an animal sacrifice
I doubt anything could
have slowed your petition.
That's good news.
Have you had any
luck locating your sister?
Um, I got a Christmas card
postmarked from Flagstaff.
No return address,
and the phone company
doesn't have a listing.
It's been five months?
What about the father?
I put ads in the paper.
Well, the judge
will terminate
their birthrights,
and then your attorney
can have the
adoption order entered.
That's it?
Except for a lifetime
of homework projects
and boyfriends, yes.
Approximately 20-year-old male,
ran from building
with clothes on fire.
Extensive second-
and third-degree burns,
Trauma 1. Singed nasal hair.
Unable to start
an IV or take BP.
Third-degree burns
to all extremities.
Weak carotid pulse at 150.
Carol, get Susan down here.
She won't answer her page.
Building caught on fire.
Just blew up. Meth lab.
Pieces of pressure cookers
and chemical burners
just blew up.
Carter. Six engines,
three truck companies.
We grabbed this guy and ran.
Easy now...
and go.
All right, let's get a
blood gas and a CO level.
CBC, Chem-20, portable chest.
Oh, God.
Two cut down
trays. Carter. Doug.
Cut down where?
Femorally. You take the right.
Number 10 blade, Curved Kelly.
I'm going to do an RSI.
Pulse ox is 65 percent
on 100 percent O-2.
Pulse 144, weak and thready.
Versed.
Don't forget the catheter.
Incise it and thread the IV in.
Directly into the vein?
A bunch of children
were in that building.
Adults ran, left them in there.
How many kids? At least three.
47 got there before
the engine companies.
They went in there after them.
Veck, 10 migs. Unit 47?
Veck! Second floor collapsed.
We're headed back. Lots
of firemen are in trouble.
7.5. Apply cricoid pressure.
Did they get out? Who?
47. Lydia, 7.5, please.
I think one of
them did. Oh, God.
Who's 47? Shepard and Melendez.
Got it.
Another one. 8-year-old.
I'll finish up here.
Doug, you take it. Okay.
Somebody ought
to tell Carol. I will.
8-year-old girl,
18 percent second-degree
arms, back, and leg,
third-degree, lateral thigh.
How's the airway?
Singed nasal hair,
nonproductive cough,
denied shortness of breath.
BP 110/70, pulse 112, resps 24.
Two IVs going, normal saline.
O-2 10 liters by mask.
It hurts! It hurts!
You're gonna be
okay, sweetheart.
I want my mommy!
Do we know where
her parents are?
Not a clue.
All right, here we go.
On my count.
Ready? Here we
go. One, two, three.
Blood gas with
carbon monoxide level,
CBC, PT, PTT,
Chem-20, chest x-ray,
urinalysis, and urine myoglobin.
Carol, Shep and Raul may
have got caught in the fire.
What?
47 was the first
responder on the scene.
They went in after some kids.
One of them might have
gotten caught inside.
Well, which one? I don't know.
We may have a
laryngeal burn here.
Get me a fiber-optic
laryngoscope.
A couple of paramedics
from Station 134, drive 47,
you know them?
They the ones that
pulled out the kids?
I don't know. Maybe.
Are they okay?
We scooped and
ran, it was chaos,
but units behind us might know.
Another run, ETA three minutes.
Carol, did you find Susan?
I beeped her 911.
Run down Benton, okay?
Because we are in over
our heads down here already.
PH 7.14, PO-2 60,
PCO-2 80, CO level 20.
He's going bradycardic.
Rate's 40. No palpable BP.
No pulse.
Hyperventilate him. Carter, CPR.
One amp epi, atropine one mig.
They're here, Dr. Greene.
Malik, why don't you
help them down front?
Lily, find out if
Doug's done next door.
Where the hell is Benton?
Hold still. We have to
look down your throat
to make sure it's not burned.
Doug, more coming in.
Mark wants to know
if you can take them.
Not yet.
Triage new arrivals
and give us a breakdown.
Lily, I'll do it. You
stay with Doug.
Carol, they're
going to be just fine.
Versed? Milligram IV.
Where do you want him?
Trauma 3.
12-year-old boy,
smoke inhalation.
Name's Max.
All right, Jerry,
take Max to Exam 1
and tell the nurses to put
him on 100 percent O-2,
and get Benton down here.
I've been trying.
He's still in surgery.
Well, get him out.
What else have you got?
Fireman,
first- and second-degree burns
of trunk and arm.
Vitals normal.
He's in some pain.
Okay, uh, Malik, I want
him in Curtain Area 2,
and get him an
order for Demerol.
Did you see a couple of
guys from 47 at the scene?
Radio said they got one out.
He should be in one
of the units behind us.
All right, what do we got?
Second- and third-degree burns.
Go, go, go.
Which one?
I don't know.
Um, Randi, what's the next ETA?
Less than a minute,
and they're loading two more up
on the scene.
Coming through! Coming through!
Jerry, what the
hell is going on?
There's a fire. A big one.
Susan, Mark's
been yelling for you.
We need help in Trauma.
Okay, well, I've got to
get Susie up to daycare.
I'll take her. I'll take her.
Oh, thank you. Thank you.
Go, go!
Now, Wendy's going
to take you upstairs.
I'll check in on you,
all right, darling?
Do you need a hand?
No. Why don't you
check with Mark in 1?
Have you seen Carol?
Yeah, she's still out back.
All right, you got her?
Excuse me.
What can I do?
Not much now.
Asystole. How long?
22 minutes.
Okay, Carter. That's it.
Call it.
Pronounced 8:20.
Where have you been?
I had an appointment.
It ran over.
You were on at seven.
I told Weaver I'd
be here at eight.
Yeah? It's 8:30.
It's 8:20.
Cover him up.
Take him to Holding.
We need the room.
Mark, I'm sorry.
It was really important.
So's your job.
Did you hear anything yet?
No.
Is this him? I don't know.
Altered level of consciousness,
coughing, second-degree
burns to the hands,
vitals normal, BP's 110/80.
It hurts!
Pulse is 142,
respiratory rate 36.
We'll fix you right up.
Did you hear about Unit 47?
Yeah, one saved this kid's life.
He's in 92, behind us.
Go, go.
On this side!
Pulled two kids out.
Went in again for the last one.
The floor gave away.
He fell 10 feet,
landed on his legs,
dragged himself to
the front of the building,
still had the kid with him.
Soft tissue
swelling, right knee.
Which one is it?
Shepard.
Where's Melendez?
They haven't found him yet.
It's okay. You're
going to be okay.
What do you got?
Paramedic, fell 10 feet.
Complaining of pain, right ribs,
lower extremities.
Mild shortness of breath,
partial thickness burns
on right arm and hand.
No LOC, C-spine precautions.
IV of saline, O-2, 15 liters.
Vitals stable.
Morphine IV for pain.
We're heading to Trauma 2.
They find Raul?
Not yet.
Any shortness of breath?
No, I'm okay.
The floor went
out from under us.
You've got to keep that mask on.
I had hold of that kid.
The mask.
Raul was right behind me.
They got to find him.
Okay, okay.
All right, let's go.
O-2, 15 liters.
Pulse is 132.
No sign of trauma.
You say that he fell
through the floor?
Yeah, but I think
the paramedic broke his fall.
Pulse ox 75.
CBC, Chem-20,
coag panel, chest x-ray,
UA, urine myoglobin, and ABGs.
BP's low. 80/50.
He's not breathing.
Nail beds are cherry-red.
Intubation tray.
Jerry, call Respiratory.
Get a ventilator down here.
Multi-focal PVCs.
Lidocaine 50, IV
push and then drip
at one milligram a minute.
Here we go. Lido in.
Bag! Give me the bag!
Let's go, buddy.
Okay, there we go. I'm in.
Hyperventilate him.
Ventilator flying in.
V-tach. Faint pulse.
All right, cardiovert him.
Hit the synch switch at 50.
Give me that. Okay.
Clear!
Clear.
Move it, Reilly. Move it.
Nope.
Again 100. Clear.
Clear.
Now he's in fib.
Off synch. Defibrillate at 200.
Clear. Move.
Clear.
No pulse.
300. Come on, buddy.
Reilly, get the hell
out of the way. Move.
Clear.
Neck hurt?
No. The kid's okay?
Any pain?
Yeah, my ribs hurt a little.
Tell X-ray to run a
spine and get a chest.
Those three kids okay?
We're taking care
of them right now.
Raul was right behind me.
We were on the second floor.
Stop moving your head.
The last kid was in a closet.
We'd almost given up,
then Raul found him.
We just wanted to
get the hell out of there.
Any pain?
Yeah.
What about here?
No, no, I'm okay, all right?
I thought we could
make it down the stairs.
The hall was going up.
I'm touching you
here. Do you feel this?
Yeah. Okay, wiggle your toes.
He was right there.
I was looking at him,
then there was a big noise,
and then I'm
falling with the kid.
Dorsalis pedis Okay. Shh.
And posterior tibial
pulses are intact.
They got to find
Raul. They're trying.
He was right behind
me. He's right there.
Okay, they're trying. Shh.
ABG with
carboxyhemoglobin level.
CBC, Chem-20, coags.
UA and myoglobin?
Yeah.
Dr. Greene, they found Raul.
Is he okay?
Bringing him in now.
They found him!
That's great!
That's great.
They found him.
Oh, that's good.
Short of breath?
No.
Coughing?
A little.
Is he hacking anything up?
Yeah, but it's pretty clear.
Portable chest,
blood gas with CO level.
100 percent oxygen
by nonrebreather mask.
You're gonna be fine.
They found Melendez.
He was on the second floor.
Second floor?
Yeah, those, uh...
Those paramedics
didn't have any gear.
They went in anyway.
Every one of those
kids would be dead.
ABG's back.
Carbon monoxide's high.
40 percent. PH 7.15.
He's seizing.
Bite block. Damn it.
What the hell else can
go wrong with this kid?
Ativan, 1 milligram IV push.
How much do you think he weighs?
30, 35 kilos.
Dilantin, 50 per kilo.
Load him with 450.
Who has a hyperbaric chamber?
University of Chicago.
Call Ira Blumen.
Tell him to get his damn
chopper down here now!
Found him trapped inside, ALOC.
Extensive partial and
full-thickness burns
to the chest, back,
and all extremities.
We've got you now, Raul.
LOC improved on
15 liters O-2 by mask.
No singed nasal or
facial hair. Shivering.
Complaining of severe pain.
Not able to get an IV.
No place for BP cuff.
Faint carotid pulse at 160,
resps 40 and labored.
Nice and gentle.
One, two, three.
Blood gas with CO level.
CBC, PT, PTT.
Portable chest. Put in a Foley.
Get a UA and a urine myoglobin.
It hurts. It hurts a lot.
Yeah, I know it does.
That's what we're
working on now.
Can you do a cut down?
Neck's not burned.
All right, internal jugular.
Let's go.
Let's get those
moist dressings on.
Gentlemen,
you're going to have
to wait outside, okay?
Doc! Mark.
How bad?
It's too early to say.
Please.
It's bad.
Shep okay?
He broke a couple of ribs.
He's mad as hell.
Morphine five, IV push.
Let's get that Ringer's going.
X-ray flying in.
What the hell's going on?
They're examining him.
Is he okay?
I can't tell from here.
Shooting.
What was that?
They're taking an x-ray.
You got to get me
off this backboard.
I want to see.
You also want
to be able to walk.
Take it off! Hey, hey, hey!
Take it off! Okay,
you could have a broken neck.
You do that one more
time, I put you in restraints.
CO level's normal.
PO-2 112, PCO-2 32.
Okay. Let's move
him to Radiology.
No, I want to stay.
No, you're going.
No, please, I want to stay.
Carol. Carol. Please.
There's nothing you
can do to help him now,
and we've got to
make sure you're okay.
Carol, I need to know.
Will you stay with him? You bet.
All right, I'll go
find out, okay?
You'll come right
back? I promise.
Tell him that I thought
he was right behind me.
Tell him I didn't
leave him there!
Excuse me, guys.
Guys...
Grab an ABG while
you're down there.
Hook it up to the transducer.
Got it.
Good. We're in business.
BP 70/30.
Open it wide.
Is he conscious?
Yeah.
Hey, Raul.
Hi.
It's Carol.
How you doing?
How extensive are the burns?
85 to 90 percent,
mostly third-degree.
Oh, my God.
Malik, let's do laryngoscopy.
Excuse me.
How's he doing?
Not so good.
Coming through!
Anything I can do to help?
PH 7.10.
PO-2 55.
PCO-2 50 on 15 liters.
Respiratory rate 40 and rising.
No edema. That's good, Raul.
His breathing's labored.
He has circumferential
burn of the chest.
He needs an escharotomy.
Where are the Burn Unit guys?
Finishing up a little girl.
All right, Carter and
I can do it. Come on.
Prep and drape.
Number 10 blade.
Let's go, Carter. Move.
How are the kids?
One was touch-and-go.
I sent him over to the
University of Chicago
for some hyperbaric
oxygen therapy.
The other two are okay.
The little girl's gonna
need some grafts.
Any parents yet?
A mother left the scene
with an injured toddler.
The police have out APBs,
but she hasn't shown
up at a hospital yet.
I'm gonna keep Raul
company. How's Shep?
Multiple rib fractures,
knee sprain, burns.
He's up in Ortho.
Dr. Greene,
there's a bunch of guys out
here asking about giving blood.
Send them up to the blood bank.
Okay.
Mother was going
to let her children
burn to death.
Same mother who was
cooking methamphetamine
five feet away from where
her kids were sleeping.
Okay, Raul,
your burns are constricting
and shrinking your chest,
so Peter's gonna
relieve pressure
so you can breathe, Carter...
all right?
All right,
let's get these dressings off.
Whew. God.
Let's start with two
lateral incisions.
Cut longitudinally
down the midaxillary line.
BP's still 80/50.
Give him a 500 cc bolus.
Pulse is thready.
I don't know if I can do this.
Come on, Carter. Just focus.
No, really.
Carter, deepen your incision
until you hit fresh tissue.
Come on. You can do it.
Uh...
I'm sorry. I can't.
I got it.
Dr. Ross, the boy's
back from Radiology
and the police
want to talk to him.
Okay. All right.
Will you let me know
if anything changes?
Okay, that's it. Better?
Burn guys are here.
Quite the crowd.
Morning, Mark. What have we got?
Hey, kiddo. How's it going?
His arm hurts.
Yeah? Well, you
got first-degree burns.
You know what those are?
No.
Like a bad sunburn.
Hurts really bad, but there's
no permanent damage.
How's his sputum?
Clear in the last hour.
Max, you like baseball?
You'll be back at
spring training in no time.
Where's my mom?
Well, we don't know.
Somebody saw
her outside the fire
and then she just disappeared.
Is Jessica okay?
Jessica, your sister, she
went to a different hospital,
but she's gonna be fine too.
And Jamie?
That's the baby?
He was with your mom.
You have any idea
where we can find them?
There's a police detective
here. He wants to talk to you.
Okay?
Let's get him up
to the Burn Unit.
He a friend of yours? Yeah.
He have a family?
I called them already.
Who's going to tell Raul?
I will.
No, I will. He's a fireman.
He already knows.
Give us room, guys.
Hang in there, Melendez.
You're gonna be okay, bro.
Stay up.
We're all pulling for you, man.
Hang tough, Raul.
You take care, now.
God bless.
Excuse me.
E.R.
Hang on. I'm on the phone.
Uh, no, you need
Media Relations.
Yeah. They'll fill you in.
Right.
Can I help you?
Is Dr. Lewis around?
Uh, no. She's busy right now.
Well, if you see her,
tell her up I'm in
daycare, okay?
I'm her sister, Chloe.
Okay.
You doing all right?
Is Raul okay?
He's in pain. Doesn't
want the Vicodin.
How's he doing?
What's happening?
Repeat gas is normal.
Hey, what the hell is going on?
Jeanie, can you
give us a minute?
No.
Oh, no!
No! No!
Dr. Benton?
What is it, Carter?
I don't know what happened.
I thought I'd seen
a lot of things
since I've been
here, but that, um...
You have to focus, Carter.
I know. I tried.
They announce the matches
in a couple of weeks
and I want to be a
surgeon, but that...
I don't know if I can do that.
You can.
Carter.
It doesn't get worse than that.
You stayed on your feet.
That says something.
Lily, get Dr. Ross!
I think he's dying!
Jerry, what's open? Trauma 2.
He was fine, and
then, all of a sudden,
he just started
having trouble breathing.
Airway obstruction!
Come on in here.
Pediatric intubation tray!
Soot in his airway.
CBC, Chem-20, PTT, PT.
Get a blood gas with a CO level,
portable chest,
cath urine. Stick
him for a glucose.
I fixed up those
burns on his arms
and I thought he was okay.
Epiglottal edema.
Think you can get in?
Pulse ox 65. Cyanotic nail beds.
Faint pulse at 32.
I don't think I can get in.
Oh, my God!
What is it?
Airway obstruction
from laryngeal burns.
Can't get the tube in.
I'm going to have
to needle crike him.
Please don't let my baby die.
Give me the scope.
Throat's swollen shut.
Prep for a crike.
I'll keep trying.
14-gauge angiocath.
Please don't let him die.
Come on.
Oh, my God, please don't...
Go on, Doug, I'm...
I'm almost in. Hang on.
Come on.
There. Okay, I
got it. Go. Bag him.
Good breath sounds.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, baby.
Is that the mother
from the fire?
Yeah. I think so.
Should have been her airway.
I would have let her suffocate.
Thank you.
I'm so sorry.
His BP's unstable,
serum myoglobin is climbing,
there's evidence
of rhabdomyolysis
and impending renal failure,
respiratory function
is deteriorating,
but he's conscious and alert.
He won't make it till morning.
His family here yet?
In the lobby.
One brother's on vacation.
He's flying in from
Florida tonight.
Hope his flight's on time.
How's he doing?
He's okay. Sedated.
Burns were mostly first-degree.
The cops come for the mother?
She's in with the
Homicide-Arson guys now.
The dad's flying
in from Florida...
Get the kids.
And you should get going.
For what?
The Bulls game
starts in an hour.
Oh, no. I got to wait
for Pedes to come down.
I want to check on
the other kids, and...
I'll do it. It's okay.
You should go, Doug.
I mean, you've gotten this far.
You should see it through.
No, I'm okay.
Hey, Mark?
Pedes was supposed
to be here an hour ago.
Why don't you give them a call?
Say hello to Benny
the Bull for me.
Hi.
Your family's here.
They're waiting outside.
Take my mask off, please.
Please.
How bad?
Over 90 percent third-degree.
Don't let them put
me on a ventilator.
It'll make you breathe easier.
No!
Okay.
Here, put your mask back on.
Uh-uh.
Are those kids gonna make it?
Yeah, thanks to you.
No.
It was Shep.
Balls of steel.
They gonna let him
come up and see me?
I don't see how they'd
be able to keep him away.
Carol, I'm scared.
I know.
I'm really scared.
Lydia?
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Ah, damn it, I hate to cry.
No damn privacy
around this place.
Yeah. Sorry.
Oh, no, no, it's
not your fault. It's...
It's just, some days...
I don't know what
to do with it all,
you know?
Jamie Nielsen's being
admitted to Pediatrics.
Can you find his x-rays
and have them sent up?
They weren't with the charts.
Raul's up in the Burn Ward?
Yeah. His family's
up there right now.
You guys want to
get something to eat?
I don't feel much
like going home.
Yeah, I'm in.
Yeah, sure.
Jerry, why are they still here?
Uh, those are the off-duty guys
from Station 134,
where Shep and Raul work.
They've been here for hours.
I don't think they know
what to do with themselves.
I hear that.
Hey.
Um...
you guys still waiting, huh?
Yeah.
Anybody hungry?
I don't know.
Listen, we're gonna
go across the street
and get something.
You want to come?
Hey, Dr. Lewis,
did your sister find you?
She's been here for hours.
She said she'd be up in daycare.
Oh, my God.
What?
Oh, my God. Valerie,
did she take her?
Where is she? What? No.
Where is she?
There.
Oh, my God.
Susie...
she is so...
beautiful.
Yes. Yes.
Yes.
Susie.
Shep?
You ready to go see him?
I can't.
Sure, you can.
We didn't have to go in.
Engine companies
were on their way.
We could hear them coming.
It's not your fault, Shep.
He only went in
there because of me.
You both did what you
were supposed to do.
We didn't even
have the right gear.
He knew it.
He looked at the fire,
then he looked at me,
and he knew it.
He followed me in anyway.
You have to go see him.
Your friend is lying up
there waiting for you,
and if you don't go,
you're gonna regret this
for the rest of your life.
The guy tells me,
"I showed her this morning
before the opening bell,"
and I said, "Well,
that was two hours ago."
Here you go, you son of a bitch.
Here you go.
Doug?
Who the hell was that?
My son.
Karen, excuse me.
Doug! Doug!
Doug, wait a minute!
Doug, listen to me!
Listen, I called the
hospital hours ago.
I left you a message!
Right. Right.
It was a meeting.
Yeah, it was a meeting.
What was her name? Was it
Barbara or Anne? Was it Dottie?
Wasn't that the name of the girl
that I caught you with
in the front of Mom's car?
I can't remember.
I get confused.
It's my boss.
Oh, it's your boss.
I thought you owned the joint.
It's complicated, Doug. I...
Yeah, it's complicated.
Complicated.
Damn it! For God's sake,
I would have been
there if I could have!
You know that!
Look, I left you a message.
I'm sorry.
Son, come on.
Come on.
Hey, I'll get tickets
for next week's game.
We'll sit courtside, all right?
Hmm? Please.
Come on.
I'm freezing my ass
off. Let's go back inside.
It's always about
you, isn't it, Ray?
It's always about what you want.
Never anybody else. Just you.
Just what It was
business! You want.
It was business?
I was standing there, Ray.
It was 7:30, and you
were supposed to be there.
I was standing there.
Where were you?
You know where...
You were exactly
where you have always been
your entire life, Ray.
Someplace else.
That's where you were.
Now, look.
I cannot change
what happened to you
when you were a kid.
I can't.
You did a good
number on me, Ray.
You did a good job.
I never committed to anything
in my entire life.
I've never been with a
woman for more than...
six months,
and most of the
time, it's six days.
Find a job where I see people
for a couple of minutes.
I fix them as best I can.
I send them on their way.
No mess, no fuss.
No messy details.
That's what you
taught me, right?
Isn't it?
That's your trick?
Well, here I am...
Dad.
I'm you.
What happened to you as
a child I'm responsible for.
You're 34 years old.
How you live your
life is your decision.
I'm going inside.
So the woman is buck-naked,
hanging over Shep's shoulder,
right? And Raul, he's
running behind her
with the damn poodle.
Now, the whole time,
the drunk husband's chasing him
with a butcher knife,
screaming how he's
gonna kill all of them.
"I'm gonna kill
you, you bastards!"
Shep's afraid of heights.
Did you know that?
A fireman afraid of heights?
Hey, it's true. He is.
Raul is always
making him go up the fire escape
or pull the jumpers
off the tops of buildings,
stuff like that.
Raul gave Shep skydiving
lessons for Christmas.
He ever play "La
Bamba" for you guys?
Hell, yes. I like "La Bamba."
You wouldn't if you
worked with him.
When I rode with him
a couple of years back,
he had it on tape.
Played the thing
over and over again.
Enough to make
you kill yourself.
Or him.
You guys remember
that little baby
they brought in
about a year ago?
Found it in a garbage bag
down on the South Side.
I remember.
Yeah.
It had been dead
at least three or four hours,
but those boys brought her in
doing CPR and mouth-to-mouth.
The child was cold, but
they wouldn't give up.
Yelled at us
when we told them
it was hopeless.
Then they both cried
like it was their own kid.
Hell, I cried.
Me too.
Hey, partner.
Okay.
Guess I missed
that free breakfast, huh?
Oh, man...
Hey, hey.
You gotta hang in there, okay?
I can't do it, bro.
You got to.
I heard those kids
are doing great.
You saved them, buddy.
No, I didn't.
You did.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, buddy.