I screwed up, okay? I know that.
I'm just trying to
look out for the guy.
I get that, but ideally,
you don't wanna risk
your job in doing so.
I've diagnosed
Bert with dementia.
I have to take care
of my ex-husband.
The decisions, the treatments,
that's all gonna fall on me.
This is Dr. Collins.
She started our center.
I think I've seen you
around the hospital.
Just so you know, your son,
he's been a real godsend.
- Yes!
- Oh, man! Yes.
Should have known better than
to invite a bunch of surgeons.
Oh, please. My talent
is innate, all right?
- Okay.
- Oh, yeah!
It's okay. It's not your fault.
- Clearly a recessive gene.
- Heh. Mean.
Okay, let's give this a whirl.
That was how it's done.
- Bam.
A good time for cupcakes, yes?
- Yes.
- Indeed, please.
- Hey.
- Buddy boy!
Happy one year sober.
- Whoo.
- Yeah!
Yes, congratulations on
this milestone, Sean.
- Speech, speech!
- Nailed it!
- Speech.
- Okay, okay, okay.
I actually have a
lot of thank yous.
Um...
I'm grateful for so many things.
My dad's health,
that the kidney
transplant was a success.
And now I have something
to hold over him
every time he's too
busy for a Cubs game.
Margo, thank you so
much for the opportunity
to work at your center
and help others
struggling with addiction.
I have such an incredible
group of people in my corner.
And I figure if I'm
anything like you, Dad,
I'm moving in the
right direction.
Aw.
Love you, kid.
All right.
- All right, show's over.
- Blow it. Blow it out.
Yep.
Yay.
Thank you.
- Congratulations, Sean.
- Good work.
- Thank you.
- Just keep them over here.
- Do you need a hand here?
Yeah, you better.
You gotta redeem yourself here.
You're apparently missing
out on Cubs games?
- Oh, no.
- Yeah, I know.
Where are all the
good men, I ask you?
Yeah, well, apparently,
Wrigley field.
Well, it's a
good thing opening day is,
you know, right
around the corner.
I just need to find something
to do with myself until then.
- Ah, Chicago.
- Yeah.
Plenty of stuff to do.
Okay.
We should stop after work,
pick up something
to make for dinner.
Oh, let's order in.
- Oh, you're lazy.
- I am.
I am indeed.
But here's the thing.
I love you too.
See you later.
Oh, Sharon, good morning.
Oh, Daniel, I was
hoping I'd catch you.
Just one second.
I'm telling Bert where
I put his cereal bowls.
Still getting the
place re-organized?
Well, I finished labeling
everything in the kitchen.
The bedroom's next.
But so far, he's not
taking to it well.
You know what?
Alzheimer's is just a very
tricky diagnosis to accept.
So you gotta be
patient with him.
Well, I keep reminding
myself of that.
You want me to stop by on
the way home from work,
just to look in
on him real quick?
That would be great. Thanks.
Any time.
One, two, three, four, five.
My friend, can we
pick it up a notch?
Oh, you're messing me
up. Just... please.
One, two...
- Hey, marathon man.
- What's up, Asher?
We missed you last night.
Yeah, sorry about that.
Thanks for the invite,
but I had to get up early,
you know, get in my run.
Yeah, I can see that.
So how was it? You
make it a burner?
Uh, kind of?
I tweaked my hammy.
Only three miles.
I'll ice at lunch and try to
get in another five tonight.
That's hardcore.
Yeah, yeah, I admit I
can be a little, uh,
type A when it
comes to my routine.
Trust me. I get it.
I go to meetings, you run.
We all have our things.
- Mm-hmm.
I'm gonna hit the
floor. You coming?
Go ahead. I'm gonna grab
a drip and get showered.
I'll see you out there.
So that's enough.
You need to step out.
- Take your time, man.
- Sorry. Can you just...
- We'll all wait.
- Yeah, please.
Can you not do that?
You're just messing me up.
What's going on?
Guy's been in the door
forever holding everybody up.
You mind if I have a chat?
Be my guest.
Everything okay, pal?
Yeah. Yeah, um...
yeah, I'm fine.
I'm fine. I'm fine.
One, two...
You know, there's a
lot of people waiting.
Yeah, I... I know.
It's just... it's just
people keep pushing the door
and they're messing up my count.
Please stop.
- Your count?
Two... I just need a
few more minutes, okay?
Three...
- Yeah, I don't think so.
- No, no, no.
- I need you out of there.
Hey, no, no, no, no!
No, please! Please,
please, please don't!
- I'm not gonna take...
- Okay. Whoa, whoa.
Easy, easy, easy. Okay.
You're okay. I need
some help over here!
Just breathe, buddy. I got you.
Okay, okay. Listen to my
voice. Listen to my voice.
I can't breathe.
Oh, he's moving!
I can feel him!
Dan, a little help, please?
Look at me.
In through the nose.
Out through the mouth.
- Oh, my God.
- In through the nose.
Oh, my God, oh, my God,
oh, my God, oh, my God,
oh, my God, oh, my
God, oh, my God.
Oh, my... Please don't hurt him.
I'm doing the best I can.
Got him, got him.
All right.
Here we go.
Oh, my God.
All right. Okay.
Sheesh.
Hey.
Can you put him in something
so I can take him home?
Are you really sure
you wanna do that?
Yeah.
He's Rupert. He's my pet.
Hey.
- Mm.
Do me a favor.
Let's not let Rupert share
your pillow anymore, okay?
Yeah, that's a solid suggestion.
Excuse me, Dr. Charles.
Do you have a minute?
- Well done.
- Thanks.
Name's Jason Davies,
32 years old,
brought his mom in for an
outpatient gallbladder removal,
dropped her off so
he could park the car
but got stuck in the
revolving door on his way in.
Stuck?
Refused to exit the door
until he had an even number
of steps per revolution.
Uh, had a panic attack the
second we tried to intervene.
He's got an OCD diagnosis.
That includes a need for
even numbers and symmetry.
We had to double everything...
BP cuff, pulse ox.
He made me rearrange the chairs
so there's one on each side.
It's such a
misunderstood disorder.
So many people think it's
just this silly thing
about people who wash
their hands too much.
But it can be
seriously debilitating.
The longer compulsive
behavior is entrenched,
the harder it can
be to bust it loose.
It's... it's tricky.
Well, I'm hoping you
can give him a jostle.
He's pale, sweaty, and
keeps rubbing his sternum.
I'm worried he could
have a heart issue.
I need an EKG to rule it out,
and so far, he's refusing
because the leads don't sit
symmetrically on his chest.
Well, um, let's
see what we can do.
Mm.
You all right?
Yeah, just a sprain. No biggie.
Snake's out.
Start a discharge.
And do me a favor.
Next time there's a
reptile in an orifice,
give it to a resident.
Noted.
Hey, you want me to pass a note
to Ripley from you after recess?
Please.
You're one to talk.
I saw you flirting
with Margo last night.
- You're imagining things.
- Okay.
Come on, Dean, you
could do so much worse.
She's smart and funny and sweet.
And Sean's boss.
I don't think he'd appreciate
seeing me around the office.
I think he would be
happy if you are.
Well, I'll keep that in mind
if I'm ever actually
looking for a date.
Dr. Archer, head lock in T4.
This isn't over.
Hannah, we've got incoming.
We're shorthanded today.
Can you start the workup?
- Yeah.
- Treatment three.
- Got it.
- Great.
- Going to three.
Marisol Robles, 26.
BP 117/79, heart rate 182,
experienced near syncope
unloading groceries.
This is so embarrassing.
All this fuss because
of some dizziness?
There's no fuss, Marisol.
Anything else we need to know?
No, I don't think so.
Seriously?
Okay, fine.
A few days ago,
I started getting
what feels like...
like a weird heartbeat,
like a pounding in my chest.
And she's been really
sweaty and gross.
Gee, thanks, hon.
You know what I mean.
All right, let's
get you transferred.
Oh, no, please, I got it.
Okay.
All right.
Any fever or loss of appetite?
No, but the heartburn.
I've been living off Tums.
Well, your lungs sound clear.
Lymph nodes don't feel swollen.
Any chance these are
early signs of pregnancy?
We've been trying.
- Well, it's hard to say.
But we can get a full workup,
including pregnancy tests.
Sound good?
- Yeah, thanks.
Great.
I will put that order
in and check back later.
EKG has too much artifact
with the leads out of place.
Jason, if I could
just shift these two
to the other side...
- No.
I told you.
The only way we do this is
if everything's balanced.
Okay, um
how about a fresh set of vitals?
- Okay.
- Okay?
Just to get us started.
Hey. Hey! What are you doing?
I'm just grabbing a thermometer.
No, no, no.
Please, I told you, you
have to stay... stay there.
Everything has to stay balanced.
And you have to stay there.
We understand, all right?
Just remember, buddy, we're
trying to help you, all right?
How about we start with
blood pressure, okay?
There we go.
So Jason, you've been diagnosed
with obsessive compulsive
disorder, correct?
What kind of treatment
have you had, if any?
Everything's failed. I
uh...
A... a... a strict routine
is the only thing that works.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
And what happens if,
for whatever reason,
you're forced to, you know,
deviate from that routine?
Jason, you're still a
little short of breath.
Without the EKG, we're stuck.
If you let me place
the leads properly,
they wouldn't be
on for very long.
No. No, no, no.
Please, I mean, how many
times do I have to say it?
You know what we could do?
We could, uh
we could draw some
blood, all right?
A little bit from each arm,
keep things nice and...
nice and symmetrical?
Same amount from each arm?
Down to the centiliter,
I promise you.
Okay?
- Thank you.
- You hang tight.
And, uh, we will
get that set up.
Trini, set up for a blood
draw. I'm gonna need two kits.
- Two?
- I'll explain in a second.
Blood's a good start,
but it's only
gonna get us so far
if he has a heart condition.
- I know.
But you can't really steamroll
a patient like this, right?
This is nuts. I mean,
I'm familiar with OCD,
but needing a
routine to the extent
that it's jeopardizing
his health?
The routine creates this
crucial illusion of control,
right, which is ironic
because it's compulsion,
which he has no control over.
But the theory is that
they are triggered
by these dark, intrusive
thoughts, right,
this fear that something
really bad is gonna happen,
a fear that something really bad
has already happened
that's his fault, right?
And that's the obsessive part.
The compulsions,
in Jason's case,
the whole symmetry
thing, they develop
as a kind of a ritualistic
coping mechanism, right?
So how do we help him?
Well, the first step,
try and figure out
what he's so afraid of.
Yeah, well, we got an
ED full of patients
who also need our attention.
Yeah. Is his mom
still up in pre-op?
She's rescheduling her
surgery for this afternoon.
So she should be down soon.
Okay, give me a heads-up
when she gets here.
She might be able to, you
know, shed some light.
Thanks.
- Yeah.
Okay, so you fell coming
down the stairs, huh?
I know. I'm such an idiot.
I was running late
for work again,
missed the last step.
Better than falling
from the top, I guess.
No doubt.
So it doesn't look too bad.
Besides this little goose egg,
any dizziness or
lightheadedness?
No, occasional headaches,
but that's probably
just because I've been
hitting dollar margarita night
a little too hard.
I know I shouldn't,
but a dollar?
Well, worse ways to
spend a buck, I guess.
There's my girl.
Dr. Dennis!
I got your text.
I came right down.
Sorry, I guess I should
call you Dr. Washington.
Oh, no, it's fine.
So what have you gone and done?
Mm, little altercation
with the front stoop.
I'm sorry to barge in
like this, Dr. Marcel.
Hillary and I go way back.
I can see.
Approaching two decades
cancer-free and clear.
Wow. That's fantastic.
I'll check in on you in a bit.
All right, I'll be here.
Okay.
All right, let's put
this back on there.
Best I can tell,
it's just a sprain,
but I'll get some
X-rays to confirm.
I'd also like to do some
additional tests and scans
just to make sure
it's the margaritas
causing those headaches.
How does that sound?
- Good.
- Okay, good.
I'll be back in a bit.
Just hang tight for me.
Dr. Washington, what
brings you down here?
Checking on a former patient.
Though I gotta admit,
it's certainly a nice
perk running into you.
Are you free for lunch?
Back-to-back meetings
with Everett.
I hope he doesn't
drone on too long.
Don't ask him about
his golf game.
You never have to.
Would you settle for dinner?
It's a date.
All right.
Okay, your white count's normal.
No sign of infection.
All other labs,
you're looking good.
But I am sorry to say that
your pregnancy test
came back negative.
Well, I've always wanted
to be a medical mystery.
No, no, no.
We still have plenty
of stones to turn.
We'll get this chest X-ray out
of the way and go from there.
Mike, we good?
- All set.
Everybody clear.
Marisol, it appears you
have a foreign object
lodged in your heart.
Oh, my God.
What is it?
I don't know, but it
shouldn't be there.
Your CT confirmed
a foreign object,
a rod about 4 centimeters long
lodged in your left
pulmonary artery.
How did it get there?
That's the
million-dollar question.
Have you ever had any surgeries?
Not since I was a baby.
They took out...
what's it called?
A bronco...
A bronchogenic cyst? Yeah.
Yeah, that's...
that's a big surgery.
I guess I don't remember.
What about any accidents,
traumas, procedures?
No, nothing.
What?
Marisol?
Three months ago,
I had a birth control
implant put in my arm.
What? Birth control? What
are you talking about?
I'm so sorry, honey.
- I can't believe this.
- I know, I know. I'm sorry.
You said you wanted kids.
I do.
I did.
I mean, you're not freaked
out about the world?
What?
War, climate change, pandemics.
We're really gonna bring
a baby into all that?
Honey.
You know what I'm saying, right?
To tell you the truth,
I don't think there's ever
been a good time to have kids.
If that implant was
placed improperly,
it could have traveled
through a large vein
into your pulmonary artery.
Oh, my God.
She should be fine once
the rod is removed.
It's a minimally
invasive procedure
done in interventional
radiology.
A catheter is snaked
up through your thigh.
The rod is grabbed.
And then the artery is repaired.
There's no major incisions.
And you might even be able to
get out of here by tonight.
Sound good?
- Yeah.
- All right.
I'll put you on
the schedule then.
Ah, oh.
I know that look. Spit it out.
This kind of surgery is
your bread and butter,
but instead, you punt it to IR.
She had a thoracotomy
when she was a baby,
so I'm guessing she has a mess
of scar tissue in her chest.
We open her up again, all right,
the complication
rates skyrocket.
IR is less invasive, sure.
But sneaking a wire through
her pulmonary artery
with limited visibility
is no cakewalk.
Yeah.
Have you ever seen
a birth control rod
in the heart before?
No? Yeah, that's what I thought.
No one has, all right?
There is no road map
for this procedure.
So we pick the
safest possible path.
IR, all right?
And if you're so
worried about it,
why don't you scrub
in and babysit?
Maybe I will.
Hey, looks like ortho
got you fixed up.
You were right. Just a sprain.
That's good. Good, good.
I know this move.
What is it?
So your CT scan showed
a tumor in your neck.
And it's compressing
your carotid artery.
Explains your headaches
and unsteadiness.
So my cancer's back?
It's hard to say conclusively
without a biopsy,
but given your history...
I've been dreading this moment,
more chemo, radiation...
Well, not necessarily.
Far as I can tell,
the tumor's confined
to your neck, okay?
Which means there's
a surgical option.
Now, we do have an OR available.
And if you give me your consent,
I'd like to operate today.
- Today?
- Yeah.
Wow.
Yeah, look, I know that
this is a lot to digest.
But this tumor, it's in
a precarious location.
What do you mean precarious?
Well, because it's on
the carotid artery,
it could cause
visual disturbances,
a loss of consciousness
possibly stroke.
Okay.
You'll let Dr. Dennis know?
Yeah, of course.
Of course. I'll go page him now.
You hang in there for me, okay?
- Okay.
We'll get this figured
out, all right?
You said Davies, right?
Yes, Jason. I'm his mother.
- Uh...
- Doris, I can take her back.
- Thanks.
- Miss Davies, I'm Dr. Charles.
I'm one of the physicians
who's treating your son.
Come with me.
Oh, how is he?
You know, right now,
he's doing okay.
Oh, thank God. I'm sorry.
I hear he made a scene
entering the hospital.
I wouldn't have had him
come, but he insisted.
Do you mind me asking
you when you noticed
these behaviors
showing up in your son,
at what point in his life?
Oh, even as a toddler,
he would have a meltdown
if his apple slices
weren't cut evenly.
We didn't really
think much of it.
Oh, of course, because
it just seemed like
normal toddler
behavior at the time.
Exactly.
It was really when
Jason's father
passed away that it got worse.
Yeah, he was only ten years old.
It was extremely hard on him.
He did say he has had
some therapy, though?
Well, he's been in
and out of therapy
but never gets too far.
In fact, lately, it only seems
to be getting more intense.
Really?
Any changes going
on in his life?
Any big transitions or anything?
No. Well, other than my surgery.
Excuse me, Dr. Charles, can
I talk to you for a second?
Dr. Ripley, this is...
this is Miss Davies.
This is Jason's mom.
Miss Davies, hi.
I just got your
son's lab work back.
And?
It seems Jason didn't
just have a panic attack.
Jason, your lab showed
elevated levels of troponin
in your bloodstream.
That's a protein that's released
when there's a breakdown
of heart muscle,
most commonly as a
result of a heart attack.
- A heart attack?
- Unusual in somebody your age.
But, you know, we
caught it early,
and so we can address it before
there's any lasting damage.
You'll need an angiogram to find
the source of the blockage and
potentially insert a stent.
It's a simple
outpatient procedure.
They're gonna get you
all fixed up, honey.
Nothing to worry about...
- Mom.
Mom, please.
Can you... can you move
back to the center?
Look, just sit tight, Jason.
Uh, we'll let angio
know we're coming.
Wait.
I only had one heart attack?
- Yeah.
I have to have another one.
I'm sorry, what?
Even numbers. Symmetry.
Jason, I just wanna make sure
you understand what
you're saying here.
We need to fix this now. And
if we don't, you could die.
Honey, please listen
to the doctors.
You need this treatment.
- No.
It's too important.
I'm not doing anything until
I have another heart attack.
Good to go?
Change of plans.
Based on the location
of the tumor,
I believe it's a paraganglioma.
Uh-huh.
Which means I expect it to
respond well to radiation.
Now, radiation's not gonna
do us much good here, Dennis.
This tumor is completely
encasing her artery.
I need to take it out.
And once I shrink it,
you'll be in a far better
position to do that.
Hillary and I discussed
all the options,
and it's clear that radiation
is the best place to start.
She's already
consented to surgery.
She's rescinded that consent.
- You're kidding me.
- This is now an oncology case.
And I'm taking over
Hillary's care.
And we are no longer
in need of a surgeon.
You know I'm gonna have
to take this upstairs?
That's certainly
your prerogative.
Okay, exiting the
right ventricle
and advancing over the wire
into the pulmonary artery.
Oh, jackpot. There it is.
Here we go. Opening the grasper.
Got it.
Wow, that's really
wedged in there.
Yeah, not budging.
BP and sats are falling.
What happened?
Must have perforated
the pulmonary artery.
Damn it. She's bleeding
into her chest.
Marty, start the massive
transfusion protocol.
I'll be right back.
Dean?
Hey, we need you.
- What?
- She perforated.
We gotta open her up.
So much for playing it safe.
If we had a court order,
we could wrap this
up, put in that stent.
Yeah, I just... I don't know.
Mrs. Davies, it is clear your
son is causing himself harm.
Any judge would agree.
- Miss Davies, do you mind?
Can I just grab
Dr. Ripley for a second?
- Oh, of course.
- Thank you.
I know what you're gonna say.
I'm not sure you do.
Look, Mitch, in any
other circumstance,
I'd probably agree with you.
The problem with forcing
treatment, though,
is that we would violate
Jason's sense of control
over his environment
to the extent that
we or anybody else would lose
any chance of helping him
with his OCD for
a long, long time.
At this point,
doesn't helping him
mean ensuring he doesn't
have a massive coronary?
Yes. The thing is,
I'm just starting
to figure out
what's behind this,
and I just need a little
more time to reach him.
Okay, well, you better hurry,
'cause time's the one
thing we don't have.
Paraganglioma,
headaches, syncope.
I mean, Hillary's
already symptomatic.
But as I've explained,
in her case, starting with
surgery's not the answer.
If I understand correctly,
your concern is for the
integrity of the artery.
Remove the tumor,
and you run the risk
of taking her entire
carotid out with it.
She'll bleed out on the table.
And if you radiate first,
it would scar and
distort the anatomy,
making surgery even
more difficult.
Actually, radiation
would save you
from a difficult operation.
If I shrink the mass, you can
likely avoid a carotid bypass.
Please, Ms. Goodwin,
Dr. Washington and I
can do this all day.
Surgery versus radiation,
I can't even begin to count
the number of times
I've heard this debate.
And there's never
a clear-cut answer.
But in this case,
given Dr. Washington's
extensive knowledge
of the patient and
her medical history,
he's in a better position
to make this call.
You can move forward
with radiation.
Thank you, Sharon.
This isn't right.
Dr. Marcel, you brought
me in for arbitration,
and that's what I did.
Yeah. Yeah, okay,
and your relationship with
him didn't play a role?
Excuse me?
Miss Goodwin, I...
You know, one thing
I wanna tell you
is that I just really...
I really get how
incredibly difficult all
this must be for you.
I don't have a choice.
Which must just
make it exhausting.
And that's why I wanna
which is why what I
ask you, like, what if
what if we could help you?
You can't.
But wouldn't you wanna
spend the rest of your life
feeling, I don't know,
like, a little less
less like a prisoner
of... of your own mind?
Yeah.
I mean, I'm wondering
if you were scared
that if we give you that stent
and disrupt your symmetry
that something really
bad is gonna happen
and that you're gonna
think it's your fault.
I mean, is that your take on
on what happened with your dad?
And his heart attack
when you were a kid?
My dad was walking me to school.
I was trying to get an
even number of steps
in between the
sidewalk pavement.
But we were late, so he
was hurrying me along.
And he just kept pulling
me and pulling me.
And I just... I
couldn't keep up.
And then when I lost count
he just dropped to the pavement.
It was just... he fell.
And now today
in the revolving door...
I couldn't... I
couldn't keep count.
And then I had a heart attack.
So now you're worried
that something bad's
gonna happen to your mom?
I don't wanna kill my mom.
That's why I have to have
another heart attack.
Right.
And the second heart attack...
You wanna have a
second heart attack
because you think that that
is gonna make that not happen?
Yeah. It'll be even.
- It'll be even.
- Even.
It'll make it even.
And your mom'll be safe
if you can have a
second heart attack?
Yeah, if I... if I have
a second heart attack...
Okay, I get it.
- My mom will live.
- Right.
Okay.
Pressure's in the tank.
She's still bleeding.
This damn lung is completely
fused to the chest wall.
Ugh. More suction.
Good. Can't even see the bleed.
Pressure's still down.
Keep transfusing.
Okay. All right, all right.
Got the lung.
Yeah. I see the tear.
All right, I'm pinching
the pulmonary artery now.
Okay.
I need a Satinsky clamp.
Wait, what are you doing?
What are you doing?
I need to perform
a formal lobectomy.
You're gonna remove a
whole lobe of her lung?
It's that or let
her bleed to death.
The last clamp on. And
the lobe comes out.
She's not doing well, Dean.
I'm having trouble
keeping her pressure...
Just buy me 40
seconds, Marty, please.
Okay.
Got it. Blowing mass.
All right. Lobe is coming out.
There it is.
Rod's still intact.
- Mm.
All right.
- Numbers are better.
All right, let's finish it up.
So Jason thinks that a
disruption in his routine
killed his father when
he was a little kid.
So then this morning,
after he messes up his
steps in the revolving door,
he becomes convinced
that his mom is next.
That's why that the
second heart attack
becomes so important
to him, because he
he thinks that that's
gonna restore symmetry.
Right? Get him back on track.
And that if that doesn't happen,
then his mom will never get
up off the operating table.
Wow.
Yeah.
So what's the next step?
Well, I think I
figured out a way
to sort of decouple his
compulsion from his fear,
you know, to break the delusion,
but, um, I'm gonna need
your help to do that.
Okay.
Uh, you're not
gonna convince me.
That's not why we're here.
So look, your mom knows
that you can get anxious
about her health, right?
She's in pre-op right now,
but she has gotten permission
from Dr. Tanaka-Reed
for us to bring you up
there so you can meet him,
see what great hands she's
in, and also say hi to her
before she goes into the
OR and when she comes out.
We'll each stay on one side
of you just like we are now.
And also, just because we really
wanna think about protecting
your heart at this point,
we're gonna give you a mild
sedative called a pyrazolam.
Have you had that before?
Yeah, I've had that before.
Great.
Good, well, Dr. Charles
and I split the pill in two
just to keep things balanced.
Taking Hillary
upstairs, as directed.
Hey, Hillary.
Richard here is gonna
take you upstairs
to radiation oncology.
Where's Dr. Washington?
He'll be up shortly to get
you started, all right?
Come on.
Whoa! Hey, hey, hey.
I got her. I got you, I got you.
It's okay.
Hey, you with me?
You with me? You okay?
Give her a liter of LR.
Hillary, please, you
need this operation.
No.
Dr. Washington's against it.
Dr. Marcel?
Hang tight for me, all right?
Is this a change
in her condition?
Mm-hmm.
And it's because of the tumor?
It's clearly starting to
intrude into her carotid now.
She can't wait any longer.
Jason, this is Dr. Tanaka-Reed.
Hi, Jason.
He is a first-class surgeon
who's gonna take excellent
care of your mom.
We'll be texting
Dr. Charles throughout
to keep you up to date.
I'll take good care of her.
Okay.
Okay, so obviously,
the hospital's not gonna let
you observe the procedure.
But we have arranged for
what we think is
the next best thing,
which is to monitor
it from in here,
in this little area
that we've set up.
Your mom will be in OR two.
As you can see, the
light is currently green,
which means her surgery is
just about to get underway.
It'll switch to red
as soon as she's done.
In the meantime, I think
we have things set up
pretty much the
way you like them.
And Dr. Ripley and I are
gonna be here with
you the whole time.
Thanks.
We've got Hillary on fluids
and she's stable for the moment,
but Dr. Marcel is
concerned the tumor
is disrupting the blood flow.
So we wanna revisit surgery?
Yes, Dennis.
This... this new complication
changes the calculus.
It does.
I'm afraid radiation
is no longer viable.
And Hillary is refusing to
consent unless you're on board.
In the early years
of my practice,
so many kids didn't make it.
I was burning out when
Hillary came along.
Her prognosis wasn't good,
went through more than most.
But she survived.
She gave me hope.
And that hope allowed
me to keep going.
And Dr. Marcel is a skilled
and experienced surgeon.
I have all the confidence in
the world that he can do this.
All right.
Are we ready?
Everything is gonna be okay.
I'll be right here
when you wake up.
Tumor-free.
Okay.
- Take good care of her.
- You have my word.
Ah, okay, looks like
they are almost finished.
What... what are you doing?
I just wanna show you something.
No, the light's still green.
The surgery isn't over.
Buddy, it's gonna be okay.
You wanna take a
deep breath for me?
Why are you doing this?
Because I wanna prove to you
that you had nothing whatsoever
to do with your father's death.
Move back. Please, she'll die!
No, she's not.
She's gonna be absolutely fine
because the truth is,
is that your behavior,
your routine, I appreciate
it makes you feel better,
but it has nothing whatsoever
to do with outcomes
out in the real world.
- No.
- It doesn't.
- Yes, it does! It does!
- Hey, Jason.
- Hey, no, no, no, no.
It does!
- Jason, Jason.
- Please, sit down! Sit down!
- Jason, just relax!
Look, look! It's red.
Surgery's over.
- She's finished.
She's fine.
What?
It's over.
Really?
Oh. Matter of fact, I'm
just getting a text.
Surgery on Frances has ended.
She's heading into post-op now.
So she's okay?
She's okay.
- Jason.
- What?
Jason, your mom's fine, okay?
But right now, it's
you who's in danger.
So please, before you
have another heart attack
let us place that stent.
Okay, okay.
Here it is.
Hmm? You did great.
Thank you.
Okay, you're looking
at several weeks
of rest and rehab, and once
you're feeling up to it,
you can decide if you wanna
put one of these back in.
We don't want you to leave
here with the wrong impression.
This is a safe and effective
method of birth control.
What you experienced
was improper placement.
But you have no need to
fear something like this
ever happening again.
Like you said, there's never
a good time to have a child.
I think I'm really just scared
about becoming a parent.
You think I'm not?
Why didn't you just talk to me?
I don't know. I...
I should have.
Because I just...
I felt ashamed.
There's no shame in
that, believe me.
You have kids?
Mm. A son, grown now.
And you were scared?
Oh, petrified.
Listen, my son and I give each
other a fair amount of grief.
Still, he's the best thing
that ever happened to me.
The trouble is, it's
impossible to understand
unless it happens to you.
It's one of the many
flaws of nature, I guess.
But the point is, there
are plenty of good reasons
not to have kids, but
fear is not one of them.
You might miss out
on something great.
I don't know about the implant.
I have a lot to figure out.
We have a lot to figure out.
Together, I hope.
All right. Well, get some rest.
So fear can make you miss
out on something great, huh?
Did I say that?
That's what I heard.
She did great.
Tumor came out intact,
successfully
bypassed the carotid.
Thank you.
You bet.
Listen, Ms. Goodwin
what I said earlier,
I was out of line.
That won't happen again.
You have my word.
My apologies.
You have a good night.
Good night, Dr. Marcel.
What was that about?
Dr. Marcel and I had
a little dust up.
Sorry you got put in
a difficult position.
Colleagues dating.
It was bound to happen.
Yeah.
We're still on for dinner?
Yeah, we still are.
Cardiology placed one stent
into his right coronary artery.
Thankfully, the damage
to his heart was minimal.
Oh, great.
So did you two
grifters pull it off?
I had that green light on
for almost ten minutes
after we closed.
The whole team kept asking
what the hell we were doing.
You know, just wanted to make
sure Mom was out of the woods
before we shook
things up, right, Doc?
Right.
Well, you owe me one.
We sure do. Thanks again.
Yeah.
Hopefully, this is a step
in the right direction.
Yeah, you know, hopefully,
we did crack that
door open today.
Well, there's still
time to get in my run.
On that leg?
Maybe I'll give
it a rest tonight.
Good call.
- See you tomorrow?
- You bet.
Oh, hi. Margo, hi.
- Oh, hey, Dean.
- Hi.
Hi.
Uh, what are you doing here?
Oh, one of my residents
had her appendix out,
so I just thought I'd stop in.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
Yeah.
- okay.
- Mm-hmm.
Well, uh, good night.
Stay warm.
- Thank you.
And, Margo?
- Yep?
Uh...
- Okay, so...
- Mm-hmm?
I was wondering if maybe you, uh
you know, you'd ever
wanna go out sometime?
- Yeah, I would.
- Oh.
So why don't you call me
and we'll make a date?
- All right.
- Okay.
Huh.
Hey!
- Hey.
- You're not running tonight.
What happened to
your type A routine?
I decided to rest my leg
and, uh... and walk instead.
Oh, no. You don't
need to do that.
I'll give you a lift.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, jump in.
- Thanks.
- Sure.
If you wanted to go to my place,
I've got some epic herbal tea.
Wow. Epic?
How can I refuse?
You can't.