Dad, what are you doing?
Thought I'd weed through
your mother's record collection.
The one we schlepped all
the way back from San Diego
along with that old turntable.
So now you can throw it out?
Did go through some
strange musical phases.
Bless her heart.
Ah. The dance
phase. Cha-cha-cha.
Tango.
And the lounge lizard
phase. Tom Jones.
I like a good show tune
myself. Remember Oklahoma!?
Oklahoma!? How could I not?
You played it for me
when I was a kid
a thousand times.
Then I guess you
won't mind one more.
As long as it means
no more "cha-cha-cha."
I gotta shave.
Go ahead. Don't wanna be late.
I thought surgeons were
supposed to have horrible hours.
Up very early.
We do. I was up very late.
I see your father's been here.
What?
Crown Essential Bouquet.
Oh. Over a year ago.
God, I don't think
I've even used it.
Well... I must be off.
Uh, what time is your
angioplasty? What?
You mentioned you were
doing a laser angioplasty.
I thought perhaps I
would come and observe.
Why would you want to do that?
Well... my work
with lasers is so...
Esoteric?
Romantic.
Wandering through
the atmosphere,
watching the stars twinkle.
I thought perhaps I'd come
and see the practical approach.
Hm. I don't think
it's even allowed.
Well, I'm sure as
associate chief of surgery,
you could make arrangements.
Anyway, I'll call and check.
Or perhaps I'll just drop by.
Wait. Mother. Mother,
I don't think that's...
such a good idea!
♪ Chicks and ducks
and geese Better scurry ♪
♪ When I take you
out In my surrey ♪
Say, Mark. ♪ When I... ♪ Mm.
I was hoping to get by
a pharmacy to
pick up some refills
on those prescriptions.
Dad, I told you I'm not gonna
give you any scripts.
Uh, I... I just need
the Combivent
and the Vanceril.
I've still got the Theo-Dur.
Dad, you have emphysema.
I haven't needed my oxygen
for over two months.
You haven't seen
a doctor in over six.
Okay, you need to see a
pulmonologist here in Chicago.
Damn doctors.
Ask a million questions, when
all you need's the medicine.
Hey. It's not good medicine...
For one family member
to look after another.
So, what the hell good is it
to have a son for a doctor,
when he can't write
you a prescription?
It's not that I can't, Dad.
No, no.
It's just that you won't.
♪ If you're thinkin'
'At I'd care to swap ♪
♪ Fer that tiny Little surrey ♪
♪ With the fringe On the top ♪
Could you give these
charts to Dr. Weaver?
She's off today.
You're tall. Hold this.
What's this? Hearts.
Valentine's Day.
You know, when you give people
flowers, candies, cards,
telling them how
much you love them.
Happy Valentine's Day.
Aw. Thank you,
Yosh. That is so sweet.
You see? Don't they have
Valentine's Day in Croatia?
Oh, yes, we do.
We even have these
little hearts. "Be mine."
I don't recommend
you eating that.
"Dear one." I gotta
get to Radiology.
"Cut-tie pie."
That's "cutie pie."
Oh, thank you.
I'm Abby Lockhart, Mrs.
Connelly. We'll help you.
Could you find
that young doctor?
He... He took care of my
husband Billy a-after the fire.
Oh, what was his name?
Dr. Malucci?
No. Uh, Carter.
Yes, that's it.
Okay. We'll try
to find him for you.
Do you have a
cough, Mrs. Connelly?
No. Pulse is thready.
Any pain in your belly?
Uh, no, no. No.
Any aching?
Oh, I'm 81 years old,
dear. I ache all over.
One, two, three. Oh.
There you go. Any
pain when you urinate?
Uh, no. But I seem
to go all the time.
Okay. Well, we're gonna
run some tests. Uh-huh.
BP is still low. 80/50.
And I'll see if I can
find Dr. Carter for you.
Oh, thank you. It's
probably urosepsis.
Start her on a liter of
saline, and send her to CBC.
A chem panel, blood cultures,
UA and a urine culture.
How about antibiotics?
Um... Uh, dip a urine
to confirm the diagnosis.
I'll see what Carter
wants to start her on.
Mark!
Hi.
We have to stop
meeting like this.
Just tell me we're going
out for dinner tonight, alone.
Valentine's Day?
I wouldn't miss it.
Fun morning with your mother?
Oh. She's actually threatening
to come visit me at work.
Oh, good. I'll finally
get to meet her.
Yeah, don't hold your breath.
This is the woman who
didn't even phone me
when she got into town.
Oh. So remind me again why it is
you invited her
to stay with you?
Don't go there or I'll have to
throw you into that snowbank.
Could you remind me again...?
Oh!
I can't believe... You are...
You asked for it!
You asked for it.
Paul Sobriki?
Yeah.
Watch out! CORDAY: Stop it! Ah!
Truce.
You promise? I promise.
You promise?
I promise. Scout's honor?
Scout's honor. I'm done.
You promise? Yeah. Yeah.
Ah! Mark!
Just the snowballs,
I guess, huh?
D... Sorry.
So you've got a bad
headache? Uh-huh.
And have you had them
before? I take aspirin.
Why don't we...? Where
exactly is the pain?
It's around my right eye.
Are you nauseated? Yeah.
Does light bother
your eyes? Yeah.
All right. Why
don't we find a room
and get you checked out?
Did you hit your head?
Let him answer my question.
He's my patient.
You weren't around.
I'm here now, okay?
Your face looks flushed.
This collar's pretty tight.
Good morning, one and
all. Who's running this?
I am. I am.
Dr. Chen, give me the bullet.
George Hudson, 55,
rear-ended at a red light.
Complains of neck
pain and mild headache.
Mr. Hudson, I'm Dr. Greene.
Actually, it's Dr. Hudson.
Has anybody asked Dr. Hudson
what his specialty is?
Family medicine.
I'm from Philadelphia.
I'm just here a couple days
taking a CME course.
I see I've landed myself a
couple of eager Residents.
That you have. So
far they're asking
the right questions.
Oh, I'm glad to hear it.
They don't exactly wait
to hear the answers.
My apologies. That's all right.
Let them continue.
Sure you don't mind?
No. It's kind of amusing.
I was a house
officer once myself.
Dr. Chen, Dr. Malucci,
continue your evaluation.
I'll be back to go
over your workup.
Scream if you need me.
June Connelly? Her
husband a few months ago?
Oh. Well, I probably saw
hundreds of patients since then.
Do you have a minute?
Seeing a patient.
This won't take
long. I'll be there.
I have a 23-year-old
law student with two days
of right periorbital
throbbing headache
associated with
nausea and photophobia.
No fever, no stiff neck,
no history of migraines.
But this one seems classic.
I'm thinking six
of Imitrex, sub-q?
Yep. Sounds good. You
don't want to examine him?
No, I trust you. Let
me know how he does.
There. Is that a little
more comfortable?
Yes, thank you, dear.
Mrs. Connelly.
Yes.
Oh. Here you are. Ha-ha.
Oh. You probably
don't remember me.
Yes, I do. How are you feeling?
Well, not too bad. Uh...
Th... They're taking
very good care of me.
I'm sure they are. Uh-huh.
You're in very good hands.
Pressure's up to 85, systolic.
Dipped 4-plus
positive for nitrates
and leukocytes.
Which antibiotic do you want?
Um, I was thinking amp and gent.
Hm.
Try 500 milligrams of
Levaquin, IV piggyback.
It's once-a-day dosing,
and a little less nephrotoxic.
Um, could I talk to
you for a second?
Mm-hm. Mrs. Connelly? Oh, yes.
I'm gonna stop back
and see you later, okay?
Oh, yes. Thank you.
You're very welcome. Bye.
Bye.
Pressure's dangerously low.
Yeah, she's septic.
She has bacteria
in her bloodstream.
So we need to get her
pressure up using fluids
and inotropic support.
Are you sure that
she wants all that?
Well, she came to the hospital.
We should do everything we can.
We should do everything
she wants us to do.
That may not include
machines and tubes.
Well, in OB, doing everything
was pretty much automatic.
This isn't OB. Talk to her.
Carter, you following
Lucy's patient?
Kid with migraine?
She presented it.
If you're gonna supervise,
do it more closely.
What's going on?
I was just coming
to get you. Name?
Paul Sobriki. How
are you feeling, Paul?
My wife doesn't like
the diner either, and I...
Uh-huh.
He suddenly started babbling.
Now he's puking.
He's altered. Why
didn't you get me?
I was on my way.
You can meet me there. Don't...
This could be
encephalitis or meningitis.
Damn it, Lucy, you
should've told me this
when you presented him.
He seemed fine. And I
was coming to get you.
Give him two of Ativan, IV push.
Lucy, check his
electrolytes, calcium,
thyroid panel and tox screen.
I'm gonna go get an LP kit.
Got your page. What have we got?
Insulinoma. Gretel
was having seizures.
Gretel? The patient?
Thought it neurological,
but workup was negative,
except for low blood glucose.
Which suggested an
insulin-producing adenoma.
CT of abdomen shows
a nodule in the pancreas.
I hope to God
it's not malignant.
Well, that's very caring of you.
Well, I am capable of
that, Lizzie, on occasion.
This being one of them.
Let's go. I want to see her.
Wait. I haven't even...
You can finish up
later. Come on, let's go.
She's ready for you, Dr. Romano.
There, there,
Gretel. There, there.
There, there. Good girl.
Robert, this is a dog.
Correction, Lizzie.
This is my dog.
Ativan put him right out.
Shh. Okay, draw the lidocaine.
One and four for cell count.
Protein and glucose in 2,
and Gram's stain
and culture in 3.
You got it.
Change over to a...
27-gauge needle.
I always do.
Very good. Okay. I'm ready.
Whoa. Whoa!
Hold him! Hold
him! What do I do?
Hold him! What are
you putting in? Stop!
Paul, relax. It's
okay. Just calm down.
Calm down. It's all right.
What are you
sticking in my back?
Malik, give him two of
Ativan. Lucy, keep going.
Oh. It'll be a traumatic tap.
We'll get blood
in the spinal fluid.
It's not gonna get any easier.
Okay. I feel some resistance.
Just keep advancing.
All right. I'm not
getting any fluid.
Did you feel a pop? No.
Keep going.
I can't.
Yes, you can. Stop, please.
You're hurting me. Please
stop. Check the stylet.
All right. We got it.
Great. CARTER: Paul.
Paul, just relax. Just relax.
Just relax.
Hey. Crystal clear. Good job.
Guess I have my breeds mixed up.
I always thought they
were wiry little runts.
More like that
Australian silky thing.
Nope, Alex. The
Bouvier is robust,
squarely built, well-muscled.
A hearty dog, then, you
could say, Dr. Romano.
Except for the pancreas.
Lizzie. Alex, how's Gretel's BP?
Uh, I don't know. We
don't have a dog cuff.
Then start an arterial line
and hook her to a monitor.
An arterial line? Just
pretend you're in dog lab.
That's what I'm doing.
Lizzie. I'm sorry, Robert.
I don't think it's proper to
be operating on your dog.
I'm chief of staff. Is that
proper enough for you?
Besides, what would
you have me do,
leave her to some
poodle surgeon?
Curved Crile to
clamp off that bleeder.
Dr. Hudson has
oat cell carcinoma?
We asked him about
previous hospitalizations.
Had six cycles of chemotherapy,
been in remission 15 months.
Now presents with
a mediastinal mass,
which is why he's flushed.
It's superior vena
cava syndrome.
The prognosis... A 25
percent one-year survival.
Which is why we should
blast him with radiation,
to shrink the tumor before
he gets elevated
intracranial pressure.
But recent literature
shows that chemotherapy
can reduce the tumor
in two to three days.
I think we should treat him
with platinum and VP-16.
Which does Dr. Hudson want?
Did you even ask him?
She didn't want to wait for...
I was about to, but Malucci...
All right, stop it, both of you.
Listen, I'm gonna check
in on another patient.
And then I'm gonna
go see Dr. Hudson.
I'll present him
with his options.
What are we gonna do?
You are going to watch
me and say nothing.
How are you feeling,
Mrs. Connelly?
Oh, pretty darn good here.
Pressure's 100/70.
The fluids we're giving you
are making you feel better.
Oh, no. I think it's
this young man here
who is making me feel better.
He gave me a
Valentine's Day card.
Oh, that's very
thoughtful of Yosh.
Could we get you anything?
Um... Well, I
am a little thirsty.
Okay. I'll get some ice chips.
Mm. Thanks.
Uh, I'm a little bit
chilly. Maybe you could
help me get my
sweater. Sweater? Sure.
Yes. Down there.
I didn't expect
a card this year.
What, with Barry gone. Huh.
I'm sorry about your husband.
Oh, he... He was awfully sweet
about these
little... celebrations
and anniversaries and things.
He always remembered. Ha.
Some of my lady friends
had to remind their
husbands. Heh.
I had to remind
mine he was married.
Oh, no. That... That's not good.
No, it definitely wasn't.
Well, huh... d-did
you, uh, see this pin?
Barry gave that to me last year.
I didn't bother to
tell him... that...
That he had given me the
exact same pin the year before.
Well, that was very kind of you.
Oh.
It's, uh... It's
lovely, isn't it?
Yes, it is.
Yes.
"Be still my heart."
Huh.
That's what Barry would say.
And I...
I still am.
I tried calling your wife again.
I got the machine.
Yeah. Well...
When she goes
sh-shopping with her friends...
I think she's getting me
something for Valentine's Day.
Paul, your spinal
tap was negative.
Well, you stuck me for nothing?
Well, we had to
rule out meningitis.
Sure. Okay. Yeah.
I have to go back to the diner.
What diner?
It's where I study. I
left my books there.
Do other students study there?
Sometimes. But usually
they go to the library,
because we had those
muggings a couple weeks ago.
Yeah, I think I read about that.
Yeah, it could happen again.
Someone tried to mug you?
Could've. It's a long
way from where I park,
and there are lot of
bushes that they could hide.
I tell you, I'd like to...
I'd like to go soon.
We have to do a CAT
scan of your head.
That... That's an x-ray,
right? Isn't that bad?
They shoot radiation
through you...
It's a low dose.
It's really not enough
to do any harm.
Lucy. CT's ready.
Okay. Thanks, Malik.
We'll be right there.
I did a hernia on a
gorilla once. Med school.
Dear God.
Funny. Gretel's
brother had a hernia.
Let me guess. Hansel?
Oh-ho. I'm sure you
all find it quite amusing
that I would care so
much about a dog.
There's so much about you
that we don't know, Robert.
What's going on?
She's tachycardic.
I think she's having a seizure.
We've lost her IV.
Making her hypoglycemic.
I can't get the line in.
Get me an amp of 50 percent
glucose. Get out of the way!
ET tube's come
out. She's hypoxic.
Well, tube her again, damn it!
She's in V-fib. Shirley,
get me the paddles.
Stand back, Robert. Hold on.
I said, stand back.
Clear!
Superior vena cava syndrome.
That gives me what? A year?
Radiation therapy is
the standard of care.
No. Chemotherapy is an option.
But it could take
two or three days
to resolve your symptoms.
And I'm worried
that the headache
you're experiencing
could indicate
elevated intracranial pressure.
I think it's more
likely a product
of listening to your
Residents argue.
That was a joke.
We can begin the
radiation therapy right away.
I had a patient
with SVC syndrome.
Went with radiation
and developed
a terrible esophagitis.
Pain, bleeding.
Couldn't eat for two months.
Well, If I've only got a year...
I at least want
to be able to eat.
I'll go with the
chemotherapy, Dr. Greene.
All right.
He had told the waitress at...
At the diner he was coming here.
Is that where you study?
No. We're in a group
that meets at the library.
But the last couple of
months, I don't know.
Did something happen?
He's gotten so weird.
I'd swear he's wearing the
same clothes all the time.
And what about his grades?
We went to college
together too. And he did well.
But he's been cutting classes
right and left since September.
So do you socialize
with him and his wife?
N-not so much anymore.
He keeps picking fights
with me about nothing.
Heh.
Keeps accusing me of
stealing his parking place.
Stupid stuff like that.
Is... Is it something serious?
We don't know enough yet.
Should I go in and see him?
Let him sleep. You
can see him later.
Yosh, what is it?
Pressure's down to
75. I paged Dr. Carter.
Mrs. Connelly?
Mrs. Connelly?!
What do you want to do?
Abby, what do you want to do?
Carter? Not now, Lucy.
Paul Sobriki, he doesn't
have a CNS infection.
It might be psychiatric.
I said not now, okay?
What happened?
Her pressure
dropped to 75, systolic.
I started her on dopamine,
10 mics per kilo per minute.
She's still not making urine.
You said she didn't want
any heroic measures.
She's in shock. I had
to get her pressure up.
Dopamine's a resuscitation drug.
She said no tubes or
machines. Dopamine's okay.
What if it's not enough?
I'm giving her more fluids.
She's on her
third liter of saline.
You'll put her into
congestive heart failure,
flood her lungs.
Then what?
You're gonna intubate?
Are you going to intubate?
I'll watch her closely
and stop the
fluids if I have to.
She'll have to be
admitted to the ICU.
Pressure's up to 90
on 10 mics of dopamine.
She's making some urine.
Good. Good, good.
It's working. Yeah, maybe.
What do you want? What
are you talking about?
That's enough, guys.
What's going on?
Paul's going off. He's
trying to mess with me.
This your patient?
It's Lucy's patient. Your
right. You're supervising.
He followed me down
here. No. I was concerned
when I heard he was here.
- Why's he up?
I don't know. I wanted
a... A drink of water.
Okay. OLIGARIO: Dr. Greene!
Chen and Malucci need
you. Dr. Hudson's gone south.
Go ahead. I'll
take care of this.
Uh, Malik, get Paul
settled back into his bed.
I don't want him to come.
He's not coming. Don't worry.
You all right? Yeah.
But I... I got to get back.
You'll tell that other doctor?
Yeah. Sure. GREENE: Dr. Hudson?
He's altered. Unarousable.
Elevated ICP. All right, Conni.
Get Radiation Oncology
fellow down here right away.
I'll call them. You're
gonna give him radiation?
He wanted chemotherapy.
He won't make it to chemo.
20 of etomidate, 100 of sux.
We need to intubate. CHEN
AND MALUCCI: I'll do it!
Why don't I do it?
Feeling better, Paul?
I'm kind of tired.
Lucy? I'll be right back.
What is going on with
your patient? I was...
Dr. Greene pulled him
out of a fight with his friend.
Dr. Carter. Abby's
looking for you.
Thanks. He might
be schizophrenic.
He meets the DSM-IV criteria.
You page a Psych consult?
I was waiting to
present him to you.
Get them down
here, hand this guy off.
You got medical
patients waiting.
It's so hard to breathe.
How's she doing?
Pressure's down, 85/55
on maximum dopamine.
She's got rales all the
way up to the apices.
Pulmonary edema
from all the fluid.
You flooded her lungs.
She was hypotensive.
Still is.
Her BP's too low for
nitroglycerine or morphine.
You could try 40 of Lasix.
Pulse ox is down, 79
on 100 percent oxygen.
I'm going to intubate. No.
She has an
infection we can treat.
She only needs to be intubated
for a day or two
until it clears up.
You don't know that.
She's an elderly woman
with multiple organ failure.
You may never
be able to extubate.
And then what? She
spends the next two months
up in the ICU hooked up
to every machine known to man?
Yeah, I know. But I just want
to make sure that I... Hey.
It's not about what you want.
What happened when
she stopped breathing?
It's called
Cheyne-Stokes respiration.
It's associated
with heart failure.
Shh, shh.
You change your shirt?
Yeah. I saw four 6-year-olds.
I think maybe they
ate too many of those
little hearts you
warned me about.
All over me. Everywhere.
Welcome to the ER
on Valentine's Day.
Luka, Carol. Multiple trauma
coming in. Five minutes out.
Okay, prep the Trauma
Room. Meet you there.
Watch out for rebound
with the glucose.
We'll monitor her closely.
Does Gretel have insurance?
Ha. I think we've had
enough jokes for one day.
I wasn't joking. I understand
certain vets offer...
Oh, my God.
Oh, Elizabeth, there you are.
I visited nearly
every department
looking for y... Good heavens.
Mother, this is
Dr. Robert Romano.
Um... Robert,
this is my mother,
Isabelle Corday.
She's visiting from
London briefly.
Lizzie never mentioned
a thing. It's a pleasure.
Likewise.
We... This, I take it, is
not the laser angioplasty.
No. No, this is, uh, Gretel,
who has been suffering
from an insulinoma.
But thanks to a brilliant
assist by your daughter,
she's going to be just fine.
Yes, well, I know how
hard Elizabeth trained.
Mother, perhaps we should...
How are you enjoying Chicago?
I'm here for a
series of lectures.
Adaptive Optics,
Wave-Particle Duality.
Heh-ugh. I don't know why
you'd want to tax your mind
with that gobbledygook.
We have a wonderful
city. Great shopping.
I'm giving the lectures.
Well, I should probably get
Gretel settled in Recovery.
It was very nice
meeting you. And you.
Please don't ask about the dog.
Wouldn't dream of it.
Was it an Old English?
Bouvier. Uh... I'm
being paged to the ER.
Oh, I don't think
I've seen that yet.
Good. Good.
Did I hear multiple trauma?
Yeah. MVA. Mom,
dad and two kids.
Help me with this one.
Thirty eight-year-old woman,
front-seat passenger in MVA.
Ejected 20 feet from
vehicle. Pulseless and apneic.
Tubed her. Two liters
of saline en route.
Robby Edelstein, 11,
rear-seat passenger. Restrained.
Complains of left wrist pain.
Alert and oriented. No LOC.
BP is 110/68. Pulse, 110.
And we've got
Julia Edelstein, 5.
Also a rear-seat passenger.
No head trauma. No LOC.
Multiple facial abrasions.
BP is 104/60. Pulse is 96.
What was your name, sweetie?
Julia. Where's Mommy?
Come on, baby. Come on.
What is it? Multiple
trauma. MVA.
Hey, Peter, this is my
mother. How are you?
You better stay here.
Oh, yes, of course.
A-aren't they bringing my
dad? I'm sure they are, Robby.
Where did they take Mommy?
They're helping
her. Don't worry.
Let's go help the two of you.
All right, let's go, let's go.
On my count. One, two, three.
Driver needed extrication.
The husband? I think so.
Hold compressions.
Heart rate at 40.
No Pulse. She's in P.E.A.
Pulse ox, 82.
She's pretty dusky.
Resume compressions. Set
up for bilateral chest tubes.
Your wrist sore? A little.
Can you tell me what happened?
Well, A car hit us. It
was going really fast.
Robby. Robby.
Let's make sure you're okay.
Come back.
I was sitting behind Mommy,
and I hit my face
on a broken window.
We're gonna get those scrapes
cleaned right up.
Hit your head or pass out?
No.
What about you, Julia?
Can I go see my mom?
We got a 41-year-old
man, restrained driver,
with significant
passenger-space intrusion.
The fire department had to
extricate him. Lost his pulse.
No time to tube him. Broke the
steering wheel with his chest...
Here we go. One, two, three.
Anything?
Looks like tension
pneumo on the left.
Let's get a 14-gauge needle.
Betadine. I'll intubate.
Eight ET tube.
Why don't you sit down
so I can examine you?
No, thank you.
Ow. It's probably just a sprain.
And how about you? Is this sore?
What? Aren't they
gonna let us see Dad?
They'll let us know, honey.
I'll clean up these
abrasions with saline
and put on some ointment.
Thanks. Let's get a
left-wrist film for Robby
and keep him in the splint.
And order a right-knee
film for Julia. Okay.
My knee's okay. I
wanna go see my mom.
Twelve hundred cc's
out the chest tube.
Run in two units of O-neg
and set me up on the left.
Pulse ox is down to 73.
What's on the monitor?
V-fib. Charge the
paddles to 200.
Stand by with epi.
And clear. HATHAWAY: Clear.
Charge to 300. What's your plan?
Two chest tubes and
a pericardiocentesis.
Clear.
Good rush of air.
Hold on compressions.
I've got a pulse.
Let's try for a pressure.
Lily, chest-tube tray.
Let's prep the left side.
Get some sterile
gloves. Let's move.
Systolic, 60 palp.
That's a start.
Keep the O-neg coming.
Let's get 4 units
of type-specific.
Ten blade.
Call for a vent.
Thirty-two French.
How are they doing?
Doesn't look so good.
Clear.
Just keep your elbow
at a right angle like this.
Thanks.
Ow. That hurts?
A little.
Hook him up now! - Peter.
Come on, people, let's move!
Let's start him on 100%.
AC of 14, 800 tidal volume.
Whoa, whoa, he's bleeding out.
Lost the pulse!
Start compressions! Julia.
Where are you going?
We've still gotta fix you up.
Why don't you come back with me?
Sixty cc's out.
Another liter out the chest.
You want to keep
autotransfusing?
No.
Hold compressions.
Asystole.
That's it.
Time of death, 15:35.
Please be sure she's cleaned up.
How's he doing?
He's bleeding out
through his chest.
Wife's dead.
Should we prep
for a thoracotomy?
It's a full arrest
from blunt trauma.
Thoracotomy won't help.
Isn't there something
else we can try?
Uh, he probably tore his aorta.
We can't save him. You
can stop compressions.
Asystole.
Time of death, 15:37.
What should we do
about the children?
I'll tell them.
I'll go with you.
Lily, can you
make sure...? Yeah.
Both their parents are dead.
Oh, God. Uh... Well,
what are we gonna do?
We need to let them know.
Cleo. That little asthma boy,
Neal Hartford, his
sats are dropping,
and he's starting
to have retractions.
Thanks, Lydia. Um... It's okay.
Robby and Julia.
Thanks.
Hello, Robby.
Julia.
I'm Dr. Kovac, and, uh,
this is Nurse Hathaway.
I'll wait outside.
No. Please stay.
We need to talk
to you for a minute
about your mom and dad.
As you know, the
accident was pretty bad.
The car was going really fast.
Yeah.
We and the other
doctors worked really hard
to help your parents,
but their injuries were
very, very serious.
And despite everything
we tried to do,
we were not able to save them.
And they died.
But I know they
would be so relieved
to know that you're both okay.
I wanna see them.
Okay. Then I'll tell
you what to expect
when we go in the room.
To help them breathe,
we put a tube in the mouth,
and that will still be there.
You will see other tubes
under the collarbone
and in the arm, that we used
to give them medicine.
And they had a lot
of scrapes and bruises
from the accident.
Oh. Okay.
Okay, it's all right.
It's all right.
Mom.
You're early.
I didn't wanna miss
the Valentine's Day parties. ER?
Seeing as how you
missed decorating.
Luck of the schedule.
At least she's willing
to answer the phones.
Dr. Hudson's starting
to make movements.
Oh, that's a good sign.
Well, the Doctors Chen
and Malucci are with him.
Doing nothing, I hope.
Dr. Greene, he's
starting to make...
I know, purposeful movements.
Ahem. Dr. Hudson...
could you take a deep breath in
and then exhale?
Dr. Malucci. Good
NIF and tidal volume.
Okay. Dr. Hudson...
we can extubate you
if you're ready.
All right. Take
another deep breath in.
And exhale.
Okay.
Very good.
What happened?
Dr. Chen?
You had papilledema
and elevated
intracranial pressure.
We did radiation.
They'll take you upstairs
and take it from there.
I guess I owe you my thanks
for going against my wishes.
Well, it did set a bad
example for my Residents,
but you're welcome.
So looks like radiation was
the right call after all, huh?
Chemotherapy would've worked
if he hadn't had
increased ICP. Yeah, but...
Dr. Chen, Dr. Malucci, you know
why I only had one child?
Because I didn't wanna
listen to of two them
arguing in the
back seat of the car.
I know you don't know
what she looks like,
but I don't suppose
you've seen my mother?
I do know what she looks like.
I met her. We had
a nice little chat.
She's delightful.
And we're all going out
to dinner tonight. We?
Yeah, you, me, your
mother and my father.
Well, how did that
happen? I'm not sure.
She kind of has a
certain way about her.
But I'm going in a few
minutes to pick up my dad.
I think she's over at Doc
Magoo's having a coffee.
Mother!
I thought I'd lost you. No.
By now I know this place
like the back of my hand.
I met your Mark.
Yeah, so I understand.
And...?
He has a way about
him, doesn't he?
Arranging this dinner tonight.
He seems to want
me to meet his father.
Don't be silly.
Oh, that's all
right. I don't mind.
By the way, Elizabeth,
I had no idea.
About what?
About what you
do. I had no idea.
This coffee's a bit weak.
You can have some
more after dinner.
Oh. I'm sure by then,
I'll be on to the gin.
Paul, what are
you doing in here?
I... I wanted a cup of coffee,
and the nurse guy
wasn't around...
Let's get you back to your room.
You're having a party here.
For Valentine's Day. Let's go.
Shouldn't it be bigger?
Shouldn't it be red?
Come on, Dad, they are waiting.
I don't like being set up, Mark.
You're not being set up.
It is freezing out here.
I imagine this was
Elizabeth's idea.
Not that I don't like her.
Dad, it's just dinner.
Mark, this is not
my first barbecue.
For God's sakes, your
mother hasn't been gone
but for five months.
Okay, fine. You stay here.
I'm going in.
She's a Brit too, huh?
Yeah, Dad, she's British.
We should've had
'em over to our house.
We could have played
that Tom Jones album.
Would you rather just go home?
Lucy?
I'll be right back.
What happened to Psych?
I called them twice.
They're backed up.
You've got to pick up
some other patients.
I just found him in the...
Have you sutured
the leg lac yet?
I've got the chart here. Good.
Let Malik stay with this guy.
Just forget it, Carter.
You know, my father's
convinced that this was your idea.
My mother thinks it was yours.
I tell you, she was
straddling the patient,
pumping on his chest.
That's nothing.
Mark saved this chopper pilot
down in San Diego last year.
Kid had a tension
pneumatic something.
Shoved a tube right
in the side of his chest.
I-I saw Elizabeth put a tube
right down a man's throat.
I should think
that's more difficult
than putting it into his chest.
How's it going? Yeah,
but we're talking about a
whole corps of Navy pilots.
Elizabeth was trying
to save an entire family.
You're getting on well?
Oh, absolutely.
Couldn't be better.
♪ My kind of town... ♪
What the hell?
It's one of those places
where people sing along.
♪ My kind of town ♪
You mean, like a karaoke thing?
Well, uh, not really. Kind of.
♪ My kind of people too ♪
It's too bad they couldn't
get someone good.
♪ Smile on you ♪
She seems to be doing well.
Yep. Is already chasing
rabbits in her sleep.
Yeah, yeah. So tell me, Shirley,
does everyone think
I'm completely nuts?
Oh, of course not, Dr. Romano.
Only those of us who
were in the surgery.
Yeah.
Well, you know, I live alone.
When I come
home, it's just Gretel.
Right? Right? Right?
Perhaps if you showed
the same compassion for people
that you show for... Never mind.
She's NPO, Dr. Romano.
No food till she's passed gas.
Yeah, yeah, give me
a break. She's a dog.
Has she passed gas?
Dr. Romano, the biscuit?
Thank you. You're welcome.
Come here, Gretel.
♪ A way out here
They got a name ♪
♪ For wind and rain And fire ♪
♪ The rain is Tess
The fire is Joe ♪
♪ And they call the wind Maria ♪
He has a really lovely voice.
Can you sing, Mark?
♪ And sends The
clouds a-flyin' ♪
Nope.
I think it's rather brave.
♪ Maria makes The
mountain sound like... ♪
When I was a kid, he
used to do this kind of thing
just to embarrass me.
Oh, parents don't try to
embarrass their children.
It's too easy to do by accident.
♪ Maria ♪
He is pretty fearless.
♪ Blow my love to me ♪
She's not in any pain.
I know.
And I know you were right.
She was right.
Let me know if
you need anything.
Thanks.
Asystole.
Time of death, 19:19.
Be still my heart.
♪ We met at 9 ♪
♪ We met at 8 ♪
♪ I was on time ♪
♪ No, you were late ♪
I can't believe that
your mother knows
all the words to this.
Are you kidding? We
watched this movie
a hundred times
when I was a girl.
You liked it that much?
Oh, no, no. She saw
it as an object lesson.
Women shouldn't define
themselves through men.
Sorry?
Well, Gigi. Gigi was
in love with Gaston.
But Gaston only wanted
her to be his courtesan.
Now, at first she agreed,
and her great aunt
and her grandmother
gave her lessons.
But then Gigi was unhappy.
So she told Gaston...
Elizabeth, please, stop, okay?
I don't think I can handle
this evening getting
any more bizarre.
All right, then.
You know, there's
warmer places to be alone.
There's a furnace
room in the basement.
And, uh, the incubators
up in the NICU.
I'd like to see you in an
incubator in the NICU.
I'm happy to try.
Well...
Y... you know, all those
years as an OB nurse...
98% of what you
see is just pure joy.
You know, it's the happiest day
of most people's lives.
And, um... the
tragedy is horrible.
Because it's a life cut short,
and it's a mom with a baby.
True.
Today was the first day
I saw an old person die,
and I guess I'm
just not used to it.
Well, you want the good
news or the bad news?
Give me the bad.
You never get used to it.
The good news is,
you never get used to it.
At least, I haven't.
So you may have come
up here to be alone...
but you're not.
So they're having a party?
Think they started without us?
I certainly hope not.
Heads will roll.
♪ Hey, Mr. Policeman ♪
♪ Is it time For getting away? ♪
♪ Is it time for... ♪
So this is your
Valentine's Day party?
Don't ask me, man.
It's my first one.
I think we have a
bigger knife in the lounge.
Couldn't find it.
Wow. It's a lot
more fun than OB.
Yeah. We like to party
down here in the ER.
Oh, Lucy didn't
suture that leg lac yet?
That guy's been
here for four hours.
Where is she?
Still waiting on Psych consult.
Her patient's in Curtain 3.
I wasn't sure you'd make it.
Yeah, well, who
can resist blue cake?
Yuck.
♪ Tell me Is it
time to get down? ♪
The patients don't
mind this music?
What? ♪ Got a revolution ♪
♪ Behind my eyes ♪
♪ We got to get
up And organize ♪
♪ Got a revolution
Behind my eyes ♪
♪ We got to get
up And organize ♪
♪ Got a revolution
Behind my eyes ♪
♪ We got to get
up And organize ♪
♪ You want a revolution
Behind your eyes? ♪
♪ We got to get
up And organize ♪
Aah!
♪ Come on, baby Tell me ♪
♪ Yes, we aim to please ♪
Somebody!
♪ Come on, baby Tell me ♪
♪ Yes, we aim to please ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ Come on, baby Tell me ♪
♪ Yes, we aim to please ♪
♪ Come on, come on
Come on, come on ♪
♪ Baby, tell me ♪
♪ Yes, we aim to please ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ Come on, baby Tell me ♪
♪ Yes, we aim to please ♪
♪ Come on, come on Come
on, come on, come on ♪
Lucy.