Mark, what are you doing?
Playing Tetris.
It's 5:30 in the morning.
Yeah, I couldn't sleep.
This wouldn't
have anything to do
with your father arriving today?
No, of course not.
You know, you'd
feel a whole lot worse
if he spent the holidays alone.
Yeah, what would Thanksgiving
be without turkey and guilt?
God, I hope we can
fake it gettin' along.
I just hope he'll be comfortable
with our sleeping arrangements.
Yeah, him and me in here
and you out on the couch...
Stop it.
Peter! Peter, wake up!
How long was I asleep?
How should I
know? I just came on.
We need you now.
Shh!
Watch your back.
Peter, rough night on call?
Yeah, we got slammed.
Nothing like a trauma
to get the juices flowing.
Ready and lift.
What happened?
Choir bus from Louisville
got hit by a semi.
Louisville?
Yeah, they drove up
for a gospel festival.
That's blunt abdominal
trauma. May need surgery.
I'm assigning him
to you, Dr. Benton.
Assigning him?
I am the Triage officer.
You need to let me know
what's going on with your patients.
Oh, God, this is a nightmare.
He's a senior. He
requested more responsibility.
Hey, let me know
if you need help.
Right-o, the blood bank
is running low on O-neg.
So let's all try and go
easy. Give me the bullet.
Twenty-six-year-old woman,
complains of neck pain
and midline tenderness. No LOC.
Vitals? Stable.
Let's shoot a lateral C-spine
and leave her on the backboard
until can come in and
clear the x-ray myself.
Whatever you say, John.
Chuny, where you going?
Taking this lady
for an ankle x-ray.
Wait, she might not need it.
And we don't wanna
tie up Radiology.
Ow!
Okay, take her to X-ray.
Good idea.
Lucy, so glad you could join us.
Sorry, I slept through...
I need you in 4.
Can't I take my coat
off? No, you cannot.
Coagulated Colles' fracture.
I have an open space
down here. Talk to me.
I'm on top of it. CARTER:
Check the wrist pulses?
No, I... I just thought
I'd just amputate.
Dave.
Neurocirc is fine. Don't worry.
Good, let's get her
something for her pain.
Get her to X-ray, and get
busy in the suture room.
Yes, maestro.
How we doing, Carter?
Under control.
What have you got?
Chest contusion. I'm puttin'
her on a monitor just to be safe.
What's the 12-lead show?
I just brought her in.
Oh, right. Uh, I got a
space open in Exam 4.
Do you think I can attend
the Emergency Services
committee meeting?
Carter, one step at a time.
Excuse me. Excuse me. Yeah.
I gotta go.
Haleh, can you take this guy...?
A patient in 3
needs a breathing...
Chuny, are you free?
Gotta run to the lab.
I need... Allergic reaction.
I need sub-Q epi.
If anybody needs me,
we'll be in the men's room.
I got it. Thanks, Conni.
Appreciate you filling
in at the desk, Carol.
Oh, sure. There's
not much else I can do
except answer phones anyway.
Dr. Weaver, that was
Dr. Romano reminding you
to bring Q/A data to the
Emergency Services meeting.
When don't I? Carol,
remember to elevate your feet
to reduce the
swelling in your ankles.
Conni, could you
give Carol a stool,
so she can put
her feet up, please?
Thank you.
Is there anything
else I can get you?
You know, a carton
of milk would be great.
And I could use some pens.
My pleasure.
Thanks. Oh, Conni, Conni, Conni,
could you slide the
phone over here?
Great.
Guess I'm all set now.
Morning.
Hey, you're back.
Yeah, Dr. Weaver called me in.
I thought you went
south for the winter?
Soon. Before the first snow.
You look great.
Really? Yep.
I feel like an
overgrown pumpkin.
Pumpkin?
Big round orange thing
you carve on Halloween.
Oh, bundeva, yeah.
Actually, I'd say
more like a lubenica.
What is that?
I forget how to say it
in English. See you.
Lubenica.
He's oozing.
Crit's 29. Want the
last unit of O-neg?
No, no, I've got the
bleeding under control.
Morning, Peter. Morning.
Laser surgery on a liver lac?
Yeah, I'm using the argon
to reduce the blood loss.
Would you like me to scrub in?
No, no, no. I got it.
But I do need to
ask you a favor.
What's that?
I need some time off.
How much time?
I'm not sure.
My custody case
is goi" to trial.
I don't know how
long it's gonna last.
Hello?
If you'd be willing to
trade holiday shifts...
Whatever it takes.
I'll see what I can do.
Dr. Benton,
chain-reaction pileup
off the Roosevelt.
They need you
to go to the scene.
Ah, damn.
Look, you finish
up here. I'll take it.
No, no, no, I got it.
Peter, even you can't operate
and fly on a chopper
at the same time.
I owe you.
Your ER compliance rate
is a meager 78 percent
for the pneumonia
clinical pathway.
Really, I expected
better from you.
This is only the
first month's data.
All the nurses haven't
been in-serviced yet.
Well, let's shoot for a minimum
of 90 percent next month,
shall we, ladies?
Sorry we're late.
To what do we owe
the unexpected pleasure
of Dr. Carter's company?
Oh, uh, Carter wanted
administrative experience,
so I appointed him as the
new Resident representative.
Thought I told you.
No, you didn't say squat.
Kerry, do you know about this?
Carter asked. I said, no.
Ah, so it appears Dr. Carter's
been playing Mommy
against Daddy.
I can step out if you'd
like to discuss this...
There's nothing
to discuss, Carter.
Have a seat. Really?
You're comfortable sending
the message to our Residents
that their opinions
are worthless
and, uh, they're just
here to serve you?
Actually, I'd be completely
comfortable with that.
But since I admire
the deviousness
with which you
got yourself here...
Good. Carter, welcome to the
Emergency Services committee.
Unfortunately, I
have to take off.
So, Carter, can you,
uh, take good notes?
So, what's on the agenda?
Chad's lost 20 pounds.
His grades are falling.
Mom, I'm fine.
Has your appetite
changed recently, Chad?
Not really. He's
doing drugs, I know it.
I told you a thousand
times, I don't get high.
Yeah, what about those
losers you hang out with?
Mom, you don't know anything.
Start with a few blood
tests. Try to rule out anemia.
I brought him in
here for a drug test.
You see, she never believes me.
And I don't feel
that it's appropriate
to force that on Chad.
Well, who's in charge here?
Let's, uh, call a social
worker and try to...
Is there a problem?
Yes, my son is on drugs,
and she refuses to test him.
Uh, Chad denies drug use,
and I was urging Mrs. Kottmeier
to consider family counseling.
Chad, do you object
to being tested?
Whatever. If it'll
get her off my back.
Problem solved.
Run a tox screen.
Fine.
Excuse me. Lucy.
I'm a medical student.
You're a Resident.
You have every right
to question my judgment.
Just don't do it in
front of my patients.
Chad had no objections. You
didn't have to choose sides.
I wasn't choosing sides. I
was trying to work with them.
Well, sometimes the path of
least resistance works best.
Since you've got
this all figured out,
why don't you take this case?
Meet Babette Fritzler,
28, GSW to the shoulder.
Neurovasculars intact.
Husband, Max, shot her.
It was an
accident. I... I... I...
I was trying to scare
the hiccups out of her.
No... Nothing else worked.
Sweet pickle juice is more
effective and a lot safer.
Why don't you go find
some, Dave? I'll do this.
Oh, no you don't, Carter.
Malucci, get an
upright chest x-ray.
I'll send Kovac in.
Come on, you're doi"
the positive charts.
Aw, can't I do that later?
No, people could be getting
sick and not even know it.
What do I have to do?
Okay, I want you to
review all positive urine
and sputum cultures
from the past 72 hours
and call back any patient
who wasn't treated with
the appropriate antibiotic.
When you're done sorting
through these, I want you
to check our compliance
on TB-mask fit testing.
You asked for more
administrative experience.
And yet somehow I
feel I'm being punished.
Yeah, no pain, no gain.
Multi-car pileup.
We're transporting
four to local hospitals.
Any criticals?
Truck driver's okay.
We don't know about the
guy underneath the truck.
What's this?
Neck and back pain.
How you doing?
I'm okay.
Can you wiggle your toes for me?
Great. This one's
clear to go by ground.
What's his status?
Couldn't get in to take vitals.
Is he awake? Talking?
He was groaning.
Okay, how soon before
we can get to him?
The gas tank's leaking. We
gotta finish foaming the area first.
How soon?
Shut it off.
I can't see anything.
Can you break through?
Help me. Please, somebody help!
Hello, can you hear me?
What's your name? Dean.
Okay, Dean, we're
gonna help you.
He's got a weak carotid pulse.
Hang on, Dean. We're
gonna get you out.
Hang on!
ER.
No, you don't need
an appointment. Stupid.
Hey, Carol, can you order
a stain on this sputum?
I'm just answering phones.
Oh, well, excuse me.
What are you makin'?
What's it look like?
A blanket.
It's a hat.
Sorry. Nice color.
Lucy, I wanna talk to you.
Did you change your mind
about drug testing that kid?
Nope, waiting for the results.
ER.
It's rough bein' a fourth year.
You wanna fly solo, but
nobody thinks you're ready.
Excuse me.
I got two members of my choir
out here still needs to be seen.
And a cut on my hand.
Cleo.
Lucy, why don't you assess
them, order their tests,
and I'll sign off before
you discharge them?
Sure.
ER.
Hey, Carol, can you
order my Gram stain now?
You the doc?
Yeah, Corday from County.
Detective Curson, Violent Crime.
Still alive? Just about.
What about his passenger?
There's no one else in his car.
Well, there should be. He
carjacked a lady this morning.
Help me.
What'd you do with her?
Somebody help me.
What'd you do with
the lady you carjacked?
Oh! Okay! He's cut his carotid.
Open a few bags
of four-by-fours.
He'll need two large-bore IVs.
Please... CORDAY: Don't move.
You've cut an
artery in your neck.
We'll have to remove the
collar to stop your bleeding.
Tell me where she is.
Who?
You know who,
you son of a bitch.
Don't move! Don't move. Now
back off him and let me work.
There's a woman in trouble.
God knows what he did to her.
Tape his forehead to
the board. Don't move!
Don't let me die.
I'm a doctor. I'll
look after you.
Listen to me. There is a woman
out there that could be dying.
Do you understand that?
We gotta find her.
Where is she, Dean?
You're bleeding really badly.
Where is she?
I don't know.
BP's down to 70.
This is your last chance.
Do you want to die?
Uh... Uh-uh.
Then you tell me where she is.
You tell me where she is,
or I'll let you bleed to death.
Do you hear me?
Linc... Lincoln Park,
under the bridge.
She's in Lincoln
Park under the bridge!
Lincoln Park! Lincoln Park!
Okay, we gotta
stop his bleeding.
Get me an atraumatic clamp now!
How's he doing?
He's stable. I intubated
him on the chopper.
I heard you tied
off his carotid.
That's a pretty aggressive move.
I had no choice. Are
handcuffs necessary?
He's not going anywhere.
Just following procedure.
He's under arrest
for attempted murder.
Carol, Judy Rogers.
I'm Meg Corwin's nurse.
She had a baby boy and
would really like to see you.
Why does she wanna
see me? She didn't say.
How's the baby doing?
Quite well under
the circumstances.
We were able to got Meg off
the heroin before she delivered.
She said you got her arrested.
Well, she refused treatment.
I didn't have much
choice. Hey, I'm with you.
If you wanna see her,
she's on the jail ward.
Thank you. Hey, Carol.
I hear UCAN's
flying in a trauma?
Elizabeth and Peter have it.
I'll go see if they need a hand.
Not so fast. I
checked over your list.
You haven't been
fitted for a TB mask.
Well, I'll do it later.
Yeah, I expect you
to set a good example
for the other Residents.
Let's go. Hmph.
He's shocky. Conni,
type and cross.
Hang two units of O-neg
on the rapid infuser.
Blood bank's out of O-neg.
We have to type him
first. We need blood now.
What do you know, he's
got a blood-donor card.
"I was an angel.
I donated blood."
He's B-positive.
Okay, I'll order it.
Send off blood, C-spine
and a chest x-ray.
All right, let's get
a gram of ancef.
Let's update the tetanus.
Recheck his chest.
Belly's soft. Chest is clear.
He's got an unstable
pelvis. Add an AP.
Pressure's down, 60 palp.
Okay, he's bleeding out. Let's
logroll him. Check his back.
Can't. He's cuffed. Uncuff him.
We're supposed to keep 'em on.
Lily, get the bolt cutters.
All right, but
you're responsible.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
All right, go.
No sign of any injury.
Could be a pelvic hematoma.
Could be an intra-abdominal
bleed. I'll do an ultrasound.
Why don't you take
a break? I got it.
No, I brought him
in. I'll stay with him.
All right. You got it.
Where's the
competition being held?
At Navy Pier.
They're sendin' over
a bus to pick us up.
So keep the sutures
clean and dry.
And in about a week, go see your
doctor and have them removed.
Thank you.
Are you okay, Mr. Owens?
You're breathing kinda fast.
You know, let me
listen to your lungs.
Oh, I'm fine.
I'm gonna have you
breathe in and out, deeply.
Again.
You've got rales. Wet lungs.
Are you on any medications?
Uh, Digoxin and, uh, Lasix
for congestive heart failure.
I'd like to run
some blood tests.
Oh, no.
I've had this for five years.
I need to round everyone
up and reassign parts.
Your lungs sound bad, Mr. Owens.
Well, so will my choir
if we don't rehearse.
He's got a pelvic hematoma.
He may need embolization.
Conni, call Steve in Radiology.
Lily, how we doing
on that blood?
Four units
B-positive on the way.
Radiology's ready.
They must've found her. Who?
The woman he
kidnapped. She's alive.
Pressure's 60. What?
BP's 60. You want
another liter of saline?
No. Lily, get the rapid infuser.
Multiple stab
wounds to the chest.
Decreased breath sounds.
You wanna put in a chest tube?
Yeah, 10 blade.
She's hypotensive.
BP 90, pulse 130.
The blood bank have any O-neg?
- Not yet.
Okay, does her husband
know her blood type?
He said he doesn't.
Type and cross here for four.
Are those scratches on her
neck? Step back. We need to work.
Dr. Weaver, you might
wanna take a look at this.
Abrasions to the
external genitalia.
Yosh, get the camera.
Sandra.
Can you describe the
man that stabbed you?
No.
Where's Ron?
Try and remember.
Sats have dropped to 88.
I gotta intubate.
You gotta get outta here. Go.
I need a positive ID. You
heard her. Get out now.
Sandra, I'm gonna put
a tube down your throat
to help you breathe.
Fifteen of
etomidate, 100 of sux.
My husband...
Don't worry. Your
husband is on the way.
She's bleeding out.
Hang the cell saver.
Chuny, run a red
top to the blood bank.
Tell them to drop everything
and get us four
units of type-specific.
Done.
Check the second HemoCue.
Prime the rapid infuser.
Peter, how're we doing
on that central line?
I'm almost there.
He can't hold his arm up.
Squeeze my hand.
Tighter. What's wrong?
He's got right-sided weakness.
You tied off his carotid.
He should still have good
collateral flow to his brain.
I got the B-positive.
Hang it on the rapid infuser.
We need to put in a shunt.
He could be stroking out.
Conni, get a Javid from the O.R.
All right, that's it. I'm in.
Bring down as many
sizes as you can.
Okay, Malik. Malik, clamp it.
Got it. CORDAY: Clothes off.
Prep his neck and
get a vascular tray.
What the hell are you doin'?
I'm saving his life.
No, you're destroying evidence.
That woman's blood could be...
That was a unit of donor blood.
It doesn't matter.
Okay, stop, stop
cutting his clothes.
I'm sorry, I didn't realize.
Keep all his
belongings separate.
Weakness is progressing.
We gotta get that shunt in.
Don't clean him up until I
come back with a warrant.
How much have you given her?
I autotransfused a liter back.
Okay, she's bled another liter
into the cell saver. Hang that.
Blood bank says another 10
minutes on the type-specific.
We can't wait that long.
She's lost too much blood.
Check and see if
anyone here is O-neg.
- What's your blood type?
- I'm B-positive.
Malucci, what's your
blood type? A-positive, why?
Tell me if you taste anything.
What's your blood type? AB.
Carter? O-negative.
What? O-negative!
You're the man. Come on.
Carter's O-negative.
What's goin' on?
We need you to donate. Set
him down. Get a 14-gauge needle.
Put this on.
Multiple stabbing
victim. Needs blood.
There's no time to type her.
Squeeze in another two liters
of saline. Get another pressure.
How about numbing
it with lidocaine?!
I got a flash.
Keep your arm straight, Carter.
This is a needle,
not a catheter.
She's tachycardic.
Heart rate's 140.
Stand by with the paddles.
Vessel loops are in place. Okay.
I'll cannulate the
proximal end of the shunt.
That way, we can flush it out.
Otherwise we could send
an air embolism to the brain.
Snug it down while
I do the distal end.
What's wrong? The
shunt's not advancing.
Hold on, hold on. You could
be raising an intimal flap.
He's throwing PVCs.
Give him 100 of
lidocaine and prep a drip.
There, I'm in.
Distal vessel loops are secure.
All right, let's open the
shunt and see how he does.
With any luck, he'll
be able to stand trial.
Blood's ready.
Hang it on the infuser.
You're a good bleeder,
Carter. What can I do?
Go to the lounge. Get some
orange juice and cookies.
Hey, I'm fine.
Carter! Oh, go!
Pressure's dropping.
We gotta control the bleeding.
I put in another chest tube.
Oh, my God.
Sir, you have to leave.
My wife, she's
gonna be all right?
Yeah, we're doing
everything we can.
Wh...? Where is that
music coming from?
Lucy's gospel singers.
Okay, ask them to stop singing.
We're trying to work here.
We've lost her pressure.
Thoracotomy tray.
What are you doing?
We have to stop the bleeding.
Get him out of here
now. Come on, sir.
We need a sternal saw.
♪ Lord ♪
♪ Listen to your
children Praying ♪
♪ Send us love ♪
Dr. Weaver wants them to stop.
♪ Send us power ♪
What?
♪ Send us grace ♪
Please, quiet down.
I'm sorry.
Y-you just can't...
You can't sing in here.
Then we'll rehearse
outside. Let's go, everyone.
No, Mr. Owens, you can't leave.
His blood tests aren't back yet.
Take it up with Dr. Weaver.
Where you goin'?
I gotta pee.
Do I have to go in a cup again?
No, you can flush this time.
Is that drug test back
on Chad Kottmeier?
Yeah, tox screen
came back negative.
That's good news.
But his liver function
tests were abnormal.
Could you call the lab and
add on a blood-alcohol level?
Sure.
Oh. Whoa, Carol, are you okay?
Dave, need a hand.
Carol's presyncopal.
I'm just dizzy. Yeah, okay.
I'm okay, really.
Take some deep breaths, okay?
Guys, I'm fine.
She's probably hypotensive.
We're putting you and
the babies on a monitor.
Come on, I'm all right.
Carol, breathe.
I've got the blood.
Okay, hang it wide
open on the rapid infuser.
Pulmonary vein is
shredded on my side.
Clamp off the hilum.
She's losing blood faster
than we can give it to her.
Give me suction.
Two-0 silk and pickups.
Okay, hilum is clamped.
Take over compressions.
Give me the stitcher.
She's in fib.
Heart's filling.
Give me the paddles.
Charge to 30. And clear.
Let's take him to
Radiology for embolisation.
Do you still need me?
No, I'll take him up.
All right.
Uh, Conni, you go on.
I'll be up in a minute.
Okay.
Can you tell me what
they're doing to my wife?
They're shocking her heart
to try to get it beating again.
Why are they stopping?
Mr. Perry, we
need to talk to you.
They okay?
Good variability.
No contractions.
Your babies are doing great.
It's you I'm worried about.
I'm taking it easy.
There's no such thing
as taking it easy in the ER.
You're in your third
trimester, with twins.
You need to go home and rest.
Heard you collapsed. You okay?
I didn't collapse. I'm fine.
Her blood pressure was low.
Normal for this stage
of the pregnancy. Okay.
Uh, call me if you
have any problems.
Thanks.
You need to... I
have to go home.
I know. Yes.
Hey, how's your dad?
He never got off the plane.
Was it the right flight?
Yeah, it's the only morning
flight from San Diego.
The airline wouldn't
give me any information.
Did you call him at home?
Yeah, and I checked with
a neighbor. She has a key.
And she went over to the
house. There's no sign of him.
Well, maybe he
took a later flight.
Yeah, or he's just
lost somewhere
in the continental
United States.
Guess I'm off the hook, huh?
Not quite.
Your tests are a
bunch of crap. I'm clean.
You're drunk.
If you call this drunk, lady,
you don't get out much.
When was your last drink?
I had a few beers last night.
Must have had more than a few
to still have alcohol in
your blood this afternoon.
Okay, so maybe I
had a couple six-packs.
I don't remember.
Is that because you blacked out?
Chad, you've already got
liver damage from the alcohol.
That means you've been doin'
some seriously heavy drinking.
I like to party with my friends.
Nothin' wrong with that.
We need to talk to your mom.
So, what's she gonna say?
She gets bombed
every night herself.
She just went to go
get us coffee. That's all.
Mr. Perry, could we
speak to you outside?
I can't leave.
Not yet.
We need to talk to
you about something
that's going to
be very difficult.
We have to do a rape
exam on your wife.
Please come with us.
I'm very sorry, but,
um, I must ask...
Have you had intercourse
with your wife in
the past 72 hours?
Why?
If the exam is positive,
we have to make
sure that it wasn't you.
No.
He's bleeding from
the internal iliac.
We'll have to
embolise the vessel.
Any other sites of hemorrhage?
No, he lucked out.
Nonetheless, he's
got a fractured pelvis,
shredded carotid, dislocated
hip, torn hypogastric.
All the radiologists
and all the surgeons
might not put Humpty
back together again.
Uh, step out please.
We're about to take x-rays.
I have a warrant
to gather evidence.
The charges against this
guy have been changed.
What do you need to do?
Fingerprint him,
scrape under his nails.
You're lookin' at
murder one, pal.
♪ He taught me how ♪
♪ To walk ♪
♪ I am grateful ♪
♪ God! Ah, yeah! ♪
♪ God is great ♪
♪ And he rejoices ♪
♪ And he rejoices... ♪
Your lungs sound
better since the Lasix.
Well, that damn stuff
made me pee like a fountain.
We're late. We
gotta be headin' out.
Uh, you can't leave until
your blood tests are back.
Well, I'm not gonna
disappoint my choir.
I'll come back right after
the concert. I promise.
Freddy, we're taking off. No...
Okay, you're leaving
against medical advice.
I'm gonna need
you to sign a waiver.
Just... I-I have to go
get a doctor, okay?
I thought you were a doctor!
I'm a medical student.
You stay there!
If the boy doesn't want help,
there's not much we can do.
If he keeps it up, he's going
to kill himself or someone else.
Well, I can give you the names
of some treatment programs
that you can refer him to.
I offered that. He refused.
Can't we commit him?
We can't pull him out of his
home for being an alcoholic.
What if I convince
the mom to sign him
to a treatment
facility? Dr. Finch.
Ah, Mr. Owens is leaving
AMA. You have to talk to him.
He's in congestive
heart failure.
What's his EKG?
Uh, no ST changes.
Lasix and Nitropaste,
and I'm waiting
on the cardiac
enzymes. Where is he?
Why didn't you get me sooner?
Thought I could handle it.
Well, if his enzymes show
he's had a heart attack,
you better find him.
Hey, how was the emergency
committee meeting?
I'll let you read the minutes.
Dr. Weaver is making
me type them up.
Mark, cab company from
San Diego called back.
They say they picked
up your dad this morning
and dropped him
off at the airport.
Thank you.
No, not yet. What are
you still doing here?
If I don't finish
these time cards,
the nurses don't get paid.
Well, can't somebody else do it?
Well, it's gonna take me
just as long to explain it.
Besides, I'd be doing
this at home anyway.
ER? Take it easy.
Yes, doctor.
Mark, the neurologist
wants to know if you
or Dr. Weaver can come
up. It's about Dr. Lawrence.
Where's Kerry?
Oh, she's doing a rape exam.
All right, tell him
I'm on my way.
Ooh, I almost forgot.
Some girl named Meg called.
She said she really
wants to see you.
Thanks. Mm-hm.
It's a volcano.
Whether it's Mount
Etna or... Vesuvius,
I couldn't tell you.
Okay, volcano will do.
This is ridiculous.
I feel like a lab rat.
Just bear with me.
All right, fine. Just
point me to the cheese.
What's this?
It's a martini glass
without the base.
Or it's a...
It's a cone.
Right?
Okay, let's try another one.
What's this?
Those are the picker-uppers
that you use to...
To put the ice in
the martini glass.
They're also called...
Call them whatever
you like. Okay.
They're tongs.
Great. They're tongs?
Who...? Who the hell cares?
How about this one?
No, stop this nonsense!
We're not quite finished yet.
I am. I'm not gonna sit here
and play guessing games
with you and a... And a
bunch of lousy drawings.
I'm sorry.
Why don't we take a short
break? I'll be right back.
Don't rush.
Saline.
Ready for the Wood's lamp?
Yeah, please.
I see a spot.
It looks like semen.
That's it.
Finished up?
I'm just waiting
for the test results.
Have a seat. Share my boredom.
Grab a cup of coffee?
Well, sure. Why not?
How are things going?
For a doc who can't practice
medicine, can't complain.
I called your son.
He's on his way over.
Oh, no. Come... Look, I just...
I told that neurologist, I
don't want my son involved.
You can't enlist in a clinical
trial without a caregiver.
You need someone to be in
touch, have on a daily basis,
make sure that
you take your meds.
My son is not gonna babysit me.
You took care of him
when he needed you.
Now it's his turn.
That's just it.
I was too busy being a doctor,
too busy helping everybody else.
Yeah, well, let your
son decide, okay?
No, I'm... I'm not gonna
be a burden to him.
Dr. Chow is gonna be
testing a new neurotrophin.
It could give you
some more time.
What difference is a couple
of more months gonna make?
So you're just giving up
because you're too damn proud
to ask your son for help?
If he says yes,
I'll still end up the...
The way I'll end up.
I don't think I could
bear for him to say no.
Just talk to him.
He might say yes.
I think it's too late.
I'm gonna clean out my locker.
Doppler showed and
intimal tear of the carotid.
We'll go in and tack it down.
Ah, sounds like a plan.
Lizzie, I understand you've
had yourself quite a day.
I'm not in the mood.
Perhaps you'd be in the mood
to hear what's been
going on downstairs.
No. Your patient
raped that woman.
Oh, dear God.
Yeah.
I also got a little visit
from an investigator
in the public defender's office.
It seems some bleeding heart
is claiming that
you coerced Rollins
into telling you
where he left her.
Did you coerce your
patient into giving information
in exchange for his life?
It's okay, Peter.
I'll answer that.
I think it's fair to say I
pressured Mr. Rollins.
Wow, Lizzie, you
never fail to impress me.
I didn't think you had it
in you to cross that line.
But you may wanna reflect
on whether that's really
how you'd characterize
what happened today.
Because, unfortunately,
in this country,
when a confession is
coerced, it's usually thrown out.
I'm here to see Meg Corwin.
Change your mind?
I wanted to see the baby.
Just in time. Social Services
will be here soon to take him.
She's in here. Kinda crazy
havin' to lock her in like this,
but County has its rules.
Hi, Meg. Hi.
This is Joshua.
He's beautiful. Hm.
Hi, Joshua.
They're... They're
sending me back to jail.
I need you to talk to someone
about letting
Joshua stay with me.
Oh, Meg, that
wouldn't do any good.
You... You did this.
If you hadn't gotten me busted,
I wouldn't be here right now.
I did what I thought was
best for you and your baby.
I'm gonna be in
jail for 10 months.
Think that's
what's best for him?
Look, I know how hard this is,
but if you get your
life back together,
and you prove that to them,
I'm sure you can
get Joshua back.
How can you be so
damn self-righteous?
Meg, Social Services is here.
Just give me a little
more time, okay?
You know the rules.
Moms can't keep
their babies in jail.
This isn't right. I-I
know I screwed up bad.
But he needs me.
I'm his mother. Carol,
please do something.
There isn't anything I can do.
Carol, please!
I'm sorry, Meg.
Please, Carol.
You did this! I...
Let him stay a
little while longer.
We're gonna help
find a good home...
Can you open this door?!
Just a moment. Yes, sorry.
He's really happy with me.
Please let him stay.
I'm sure, Meg, but...
Open this door now, please!
I'm his mother!
- -precious one a place to live.
No, no, please don't take
him. We'll take good care of him.
Please don't take my baby!
I'm his mother! When I get back
I'll get you something,
so you can get some sleep.
Mama loves you, honey!
Attendant, come with me.
I Love you. I love you.
Don't take him.
We'll be back for you.
I'm his mother!
Dr. Lawrence, what
are you doin' here?
Waiting for my ride.
Earl Rydiger. Wife
found him unconscious.
Seized in the rig
for three minutes.
Gave him two of Ativan.
History of Type Two diabetes.
He's seizing! Two
more of Ativan.
Load him up with
Dilantin, 15 per kilo.
Page Dr. Weaver.
I guess I got myself all
worked up over nothing.
Mrs. Kottmeier, alcohol
abuse is hardly nothing.
Oh, so he had a few
beers with his friends.
Thank God it wasn't
speed or coke.
Your son is an alcoholic.
He has a serious
problem we can't ignore.
With your permission I can
refer Chad to a treatment program.
Doctor, uh, Finch, I brought my
son here to be tested for drugs.
I did not give you permission
to test his blood for alcohol.
Your son needs help.
Look, he's not on drugs, right?
Are you avoiding this because
you have a drinking problem?
How dare you? Come on, Chad.
How much Dilantin's onboard?
Four hundred milligram.
All right, keep pushing it.
PH is low, 6.95.
Potassium's 6.8.
Why's he so acidemic?
He's diabetic. Could
be ketoacidosis.
Blood glucose is normal.
- Septic?
Temp and white count
are normal. BP is stable.
Seizure stopped.
I don't understand this.
- He's throwing PVCs.
- Lidocaine.
What the hell's going on?
He's seizin' again.
He's gonna arrest.
Dr. Lawrence, can you help me?
I don't work here anymore.
Please, got a guy who's coding.
His pH is falling, and
his potassium's rising.
He's having refractory
seizures. Please.
It's nothing obvious. It's
not DKA. It's not sepsis.
It's not aspirin.
It's not uremia.
He's throwing multi-focal PVCs.
Get me six of Pavulon. Pavulon?
Just do it.
Guy with refractory
seizures and acidemia.
Dr. Lawrence has asked
me to give him Pavulon.
Come on, push it, Carter.
I've never tried giving Pavulon
for acidemia and seizures.
It's strychnine poisoning.
Give me that. I'll do it.
It worked.
How did you know?
Strychnine
competitively antagonizes
the central
inhibition of glycine,
which causes hyperexcitation.
I had a case like
this 20 years ago.
A patient tried to commit
suicide by eating Gopher Go.
Once you see strychnine
poisoning, you never forget it.
Check his pH. I bet you'll
see it's coming back up.
Dr. Carter, your
patient will recover.
Thank you.
Score one for the
absent-minded professor, huh?
Well, I gotta go.
Gabe, that patient would've
died if you hadn't been here.
This old dog can still
teach you a few new tricks.
I wouldn't be here without you.
I just gave you a little
push in the right direction.
That's all.
What are you gonna do?
Mark called my son and
asked him to stop by today.
We talked, and...
Um, I agreed to live with him.
I'm glad.
He's pickin' me up now.
I'll see you, Kerry.
I'll see ya.
Did you find that patient?
I called. Nobody's seen him.
What do you got?
Fifty-five-year-old male,
complains of headache
and chest pain along
with gospel singers.
We suspected
carbon-monoxide poisoning.
This is all your
fault. Mr. Owens...
We missed the festival.
Call Cardiology, and
don't lose him this time.
Mark?
Dad? You all right?
Where you been? I've
been worried about you.
I'm fine. A little tired,
but 200 bucks richer.
What?
My flight was overbooked,
so I volunteered
to take a later one.
You know, they actually
pay you to get off the plane.
Dad, you don't have to worry
about savin' a
couple hundred bucks.
You know, I can
buy you a ticket.
I can afford my
own ticket, Mark.
Dad, how about a tour?
I've been in
plenty of hospitals.
Well, you've never
been in this one.
You're the boss
around here, right?
Yeah, one of 'em.
Dr. Kovac, thank you.
Oh, for what?
For doing a good
job on a tough case.
Oh.
Until next time.
Luka, I would like you to stay.
Permanently.
Uh, there's a-an opening here
since Dr. Lawrence is leaving.
Okay.
Great.
Wanna know how much it pays?
You'll be fair.
See you tomorrow.
See ya.
I'll close. What's
his blood loss?
Seven hundred cc's.
Okay, let's give
him another unit.
Normal sinus at 100.
Lucky bastard. I
should've let him die.
Ah, don't beat yourself up.
You getting him to talk
made it possible to find her.
Yeah, a fat lot
of good that did.
Hey, look, she didn't die alone
outside and under a bridge.
He's in V-tach!
His pressure's dropping.
All right, let's
get the paddles!
Charge to 200.
Paddles are charged.
What do you want
to do, Elizabeth?
Elizabeth?
Clear!
He's back.