Multiple casualties.
Request all available units.
Stand by. Repeat: stand by.
Suspect firing automatic
weapons. Be advised.
All units responding.
Go! Go! Go!
Three gunshots. One looks fatal.
You should have let
us land 10 minutes ago.
Suspect was pinned
down, he was still firing.
He was shooting at the school?
They were shooting everywhere.
Unit responded to an
armored-truck robbery.
The suspects opened fire.
I'll take this one.
Where are my glasses?
Is he alert? Sort of.
Name's Daniel.
Daniel... do you
know where you are?
I lost my glasses.
Can you tell me where you are?
School.
Exit wound out the right temple.
What kind of ammunition
were they using?
One had a
large-caliber assault rifle
to shoot through
the engine block.
We'll never get her back
with a head wound like that.
Stop compressions.
My dad! Somebody call my dad!
I'm Dr. Kovac. What's your name?
Nicholas.
Take a deep breath, Nicholas.
Could you call my
dad? Vinny Rosato.
He works at Covin.
312-54... How's he doing?
Chest is clear.
Good radial pulse.
Titrate 4 of morphine.
54... uh, 548...
Don't worry. I'm
sure the school has it.
That could take a while.
We're evacuating out of
the front of the building.
Why? We've
apprehended two suspects.
There might be another one.
Might be?
Can you feel your leg?
Kind of.
It's, like, going to sleep.
What, pins and needles?
Yeah.
Where are the paramedics?
We're waving 'em through now.
You got any Ancef?
Red bag, side pocket.
Is yours stable by ground?
Should be. Bullet
fragment missed the brain.
What about yours?
Clean through the shoulder,
but there's one to the
groin with a cold foot.
Okay. We've got
to revascularize...
Okay, clear out! What?
Go now! He's in the
building, coming out!
Let me examine him.
We have to search him first.
Is he still breathing?
Yeah.
He's clear.
All right, come ahead.
You shot him through the vest?
Right chest.
All right, BP.
Sir, I'm a doctor.
I'm here to help you.
Can you talk? Go to hell.
Okay. I'll take that as a "yes."
Diminished breath
sounds on the right.
BP's 100/65. His pulse is at 88.
All right, let's get
in a large-bore IV,
and let's roll him.
No exit wound. All right,
he needs a chest tube.
Let's get Betadine,
and a Steri-Drape.
And take that mask off of him.
- You got this?
- Yeah. Lidocaine.
I'm sending the eye by ambulance
and taking the
leg in the chopper.
Hold on, hold on. I
might need to fly this guy.
No room. Take him by ground.
Hold on. I want to
make sure he's stable.
Bring him to Mercy.
County is the closest
pediatric trauma center.
Just wait until I get
the chest tube in.
All right, 32 French. Come on.
Chris, take two units of O-neg
from the cooler
into the chopper.
I'm loading my kid.
I said, wait! Kovac!
The suspect is apparently alive.
We are waiting for
confirmation on that.
If you are just joining
us, this is a live shot
of Thalin Elementary School.
Is that Dr. Kovac?
I don't know. It's hard to say.
Nah, he's too short to be Kovac.
Has anyone seen the toolkit?
What toolkit?
The do-it-yourself kit.
The one with the
hammer, pliers, screwdriver.
What are you gonna
do, build a tree house?
A guy drilled a wood
screw into his tibia
with a power drill.
Somebody gonna get that?
Thanks, Abby.
Hey, what are you guys watching?
Where have you been?
It's a shooting near a school.
Weaver sent Benton and Kovac.
We... Wait a minute.
Why did they get to go?
Because they don't
get sick in the chopper.
Hey, I already told
you I had the flu.
Okay? I got it.
What are you gonna do,
take it out with a screwdriver?
Why? You got a better idea?
MVA coming in.
Single auto versus
parking structure.
ETA? Five to 10.
All right, get Weaver.
I'll meet you in Trauma 2.
Hey, hey. Why do you get it?
I'll call you if he
needs his oil changed.
The drive might be
faster in morning traffic.
It's your call. Hold on.
Pulse is weak and thready.
Hey, man, are you still with me?
Heart rate's 120. Chest
output's over 500 cc's.
He's bleeding out
through his chest.
A unit of O-neg.
BP's down to 70 palp.
All right, follow me.
Uh, where are you going?
We'll transport by chopper.
Half liter bolus, then TKO.
He's bleeding out!
What?! The guy. The shooter.
He's bleeding out.
Need the chopper.
Where are we going to put him?
We have to take the boy off.
He has a pulseless leg.
Yeah, but we got five
hours to revascularize.
I'm not going to waste
time transporting by ground.
This guy's pressure is
crashing! Then give him blood.
Get out of the
chopper... No way.
Look, my patient
is more critical.
Your patient killed people.
That's not our call!
Come on.
Close the door! Let's go!
Let's go.
Kovac, open up the door!
You have to be
clear! Stand back.
Open up the door! Stand back!
Ow, ow, ow, ow! IV's in.
That's it. I'm outta here.
Screw you!
Oh, you're welcome.
Thank you, Doris. Anytime.
What do you got, Carter?
We got a combative single MVA.
Ran into a parking lot booth.
Get this thing off my
neck! Was anybody in it?
No. I can't breathe!
He's altered, tachy
and hypertensive.
He'll need a head CT.
Get this thing off!
Neck looks clear.
Okay. Remove the collar.
BP's up, 200/100.
Okay, hold still.
Get it off. That's
what I'm doing.
Looks like a posterior
hip dislocation.
All right, titrate,
200 of fentanyl
and 6 of Versed.
I'll reduce it.
You might wanna look at this.
What's wrong? It's a
goiter, I think. A big one.
That's 1 of Versed.
And 50 of fentanyl.
What are you doing?
Don't touch me!
Keep going. He can take more.
Okay, did you notice
any hand tremors?
No. He was moving
around all over the place.
That's another 50 of fentanyl.
You thinking thyroid storm?
IV Inderal, 100 PTU.
So, he's not on drugs?
No, no. His thyroid
is hyperactive.
I'm gonna kill somebody.
I swear.
- How much Inderal?
- A mg every two minutes.
Okay. He's out.
Abby, you ever
reduce a hip before?
No. It's pretty easy.
You just want to
stabilize the pelvis.
Nope, from above. Up.
Yeah.
Yeah? Yeah.
All right, I'm gonna
pull up. On three.
One, two, three.
Oh, my gosh! Oh, sh... - Carter!
Carter, are you all right?
Let me up. I wanna get up!
Carter?
Push another two of Versed.
Okay, somebody grab
Malucci. He can do this.
I can do it. John, sit down.
I said, I can do it.
Is he out this time?
Yeah, he's out.
I don't want you to
aggravate your injury.
Are you ready?
You ready? Yeah.
Thank you. Now maintain
downward pressure.
Don't be gentle.
One, two, three.
Okay. I got it.
Femoral head is back in place.
Good job, Carter.
Oh, it's just like
falling off a horse.
Heart rate's down to 110.
Dr. Weaver, we got
a hot MI in Curtain 3.
Uh, you got it from here?
Hard part's over.
Let's get him up to Radiology.
And then we'll get a
post-reduction film later.
Ahem. I'm sorry about that.
Now you know it takes
a lot of countertraction.
Hey, can you babysit
him to Radiology?
Sure. Thank you.
Did I leave his chart in here?
Is it over on the Mayo stand?
Um, no.
Just cleaning up. Yep.
There it is.
Over on the pulse ox.
What? The chart.
It's over there.
Thanks.
Whoa, look at this.
A needle stick
waiting to happen.
Mm-hm. Can't be too
careful. That's right.
Hey, make sure they do a head,
abdomen and pelvis
on that guy. Sure.
And come find me, hunt me
down. Let me see the films.
Okay.
Thanks.
Yep. Thank you.
What's his last pressure?
Stable, 110/70. How is he?
GSW to the groin,
with a pulseless leg.
What about the arm?
Neurocirc is intact.
Does he have
sensation in the foot?
We're losing it.
I'm going to lose my leg?
Not if I have anything
to say about it.
Send Burns for a shoulder x-ray.
Subramaniam
needs a Dilantin level.
What the hell is that?
Mr. Goodwrench is
tuning up a patient.
What?
You gotta hold still, man.
Malucci, what are you doing?
Hey, boss. Uh, you know what?
Let's take a break, okay?
Okay. Okay.
Guy drilled a
screw into his leg.
Yeah, I can see that. Think
he needs a little more lidocaine?
Won't even take an
aspirin. Says it interferes
with the healing process.
You tell him he's wrong?
Yeah. The chief even tried
to talk some sense into him.
Well, lis... Tell him if he
wants to be a masochist,
he can't scream so much.
He's gonna scare
the other patients.
Right. I'll have him
bite down on a bullet.
Carter, I heard you got
punted across the trauma room.
Yeah, who told you that?
I hear everything.
Haleh. Yeah.
Malucci. I know.
So did you hurt yourself?
No, just knocked the wind
out of me. Everything's working.
Another tough guy.
Something rolling up?
Rolling down. It's the
kid from the shooting.
I thought I might jump in.
Okay, well don't jump
off any gurneys. Yes, sir.
So did you call any of
those Psych referrals?
What patient?
That list I gave you.
Oh, yeah. Uh-huh. How did it go?
Um... you know.
Okay, I guess.
Kind of tough to tell.
Yeah, it could take a while.
CBC, lytes, PT, PTT,
type and cross for two units.
Can we give more morphine?
Another 4.
And get a chest
x-ray and pelvis.
You want Ancef?
Got it in the field.
Nicholas, we are just going
to take a look at you here,
and then we'll bring you
upstairs for an operation, okay?
On my count. One, two, three.
Did they call my dad?
We'll take care of it.
Mary, call the police,
the school, or whoever,
to reach his father at work.
It's been all over the news.
I'm sure his dad's
looking for him.
Make sure.
Got it.
Lungs are clear.
BP 115/75. Pulse 80.
Left inguinal entrance
wound. Where's the exit?
Couldn't find one for the
leg. Bullet's still inside.
Should see it
on the pelvic film.
No pulse by Doppler.
Let's take a look at the back.
Through and through.
Missed everything.
I assessed it in the field.
I need to examine it myself.
Okay. Let's roll him.
Hold on, Nicholas.
We need to move
you on your side,
so we can look at your back.
Carter? Carter.
- Yeah, I got it.
- Let's roll.
Did you hit your
head or pass out?
Course I hit my
head. It's rugby.
Mm-hm. Any pain in
your chest or your belly?
No, nothing. I didn't
want to come in,
but the fellas made me. Mm-hm.
Hey, hey, what are you doing?
We need to cut off your shirt,
so that we can examine you.
Like hell you do. We
just got these jerseys.
If you've broken
your collarbone,
it'll be very painful to lift
your hands above your head.
Pain is relative, mate.
Mm-hm.
What was that?
Someone who didn't
want us to cut off his shirt.
Heh. Right.
Okay, Abby. Abby. Go ahead.
You are blue.
Did you know that, Mr. Tanner?
It happens as soon as you
sweat in these new jerseys.
Hm. Well. Maybe you
should wash them first.
It's brand-new.
Yeah.
Okay. Ahem.
Let me know if
you feel any pain.
Ah, yeah, yeah.
Uh, probably a
mid-shaft fracture.
Yeah, looks like it's broken.
Will I be able to
play next week?
I doubt it. But we're gonna
wait and see the x-ray.
Be right back.
Abby?
Get a clavicle film. Great.
Mm-hm. Is everything okay? Yeah.
You sure?
Do you have a minute?
I don't see a bullet.
Must be higher
up in the abdomen.
Let's shoot a KUB.
Are you sure your
stomach doesn't hurt?
It's just my leg.
PVC's on the cardiac monitor.
Where's the chest x-ray?
Whoa, run of five.
Bolus 60 of lidocaine.
Start 1 per minute.
What is it?
Just an extra heartbeat.
Nothing to worry about.
You're not gonna believe this.
What?
Found your bullet.
Oh, God. It's in his heart.
Traveled through
the femoral vein.
From there to the IVC, into
the right atrium and ventricle.
Lydia, call the O.R., tell
'em we're on our way up.
Carter, make sure there's
an open cardiac room
with a perfusionist standing by.
He may need a bypass.
I got it.
You'll have to revascularize
the leg at the same time.
Put him in right
lateral decubitus,
reverse Trendelenburg.
We don't want it to
embolize into the lung.
We need to move
you on your side again.
What's wrong?
Remember I said we
would take you upstairs?
Yeah.
Well, we're going now.
Hey. Good effort.
Eighteen-year-old
college student,
mugged outside her dorm,
stabbed in the abdomen.
Hey, Peter.
Two hundred cc's in the Foley.
Type and cross for six units.
Have two of FFP on hand.
She's gonna fix you up,
okay? Hang in there, buddy.
You'll get my dad?
I'll get your dad.
Send up the O-neg
in case they need it.
Peter, Elizabeth
needs another surgeon.
Congratulations. He's dead.
Who?
The man he
abandoned at the scene.
I didn't abandon him.
He went into asystole
five minutes outside of Mercy.
They cracked
him. It was too late.
Ten minutes would
have made a difference?
We won't know, will we?
We talking about the shooter?
First rule of triage:
The most critical patient,
that's the priority...
The boy has a
bullet in his heart.
It can embolize at any minute.
He could lose his leg.
Let's debate this later.
You didn't make a
medical judgment!
You made a value
judgment! I made both!
Get upstairs, Peter!
You didn't care, man!
I was caring for the boy!
Hey, hey, hey. That's enough.
That's enough.
Kerry, I need to talk to you.
Can't believe that guy!
BP's 118/78, pulse 84.
Can you describe the
man who stabbed you?
I-I don't know. It
happened so fast.
Chuny, get an ultrasound
and fetal monitor, Trauma 2.
Cleo, you need some help?
Yeah, I might.
Kerry, now. It's important.
You saw the boy. He needed
to get to a trauma center.
Calm down. Go help Cleo.
I'm supposed to delay care
while they take the guy who was
shooting at kids and cops?
Go help Cleo! FINCH:
One, two, three.
Can you give me any
kind of physical description?
Uh, he was, um, darker.
Maybe Mexican.
What is it?
Victim of assault.
Single right stab wound
to the lower right quadrant,
about four centimeters
off the midline.
What was he wearing?
A gray sweatshirt, I think.
Okay. A full trauma panel
and check a HemoCue.
How far along are you, miss?
W-what?
What month are you in?
W-what do you mean?
Your pregnancy.
When are you due?
I'm not pregnant.
You look about eight months.
Got the ultrasound.
Better cath a urine.
Anything else you can
tell me about the attack?
No. H-he just ran
up, grabbed my purse.
When I didn't let go,
he stabbed me. COP: Okay.
I'll be back. Fetal
heart tones are 142.
HemoCue's 13.4.
No intra-abdominal bleed on Mom.
How about the baby?
Thirty-two-week size.
Good cardiac activity.
I'm pregnant?
Very.
Oh, my God.
Hold on.
What?
There. A blood clot.
Abruption?
Could be.
Twelve milligrams of
betamethasone, now.
You can't tell my parents.
What's your name?
Uh, Gloria. Gloria Milton.
Gloria...
the stab wound has
damaged the placenta,
causing it to bleed.
Which would cut off
oxygen to your baby.
I didn't even know I had a baby.
Well, you do.
Right now it looks okay.
But we may need to bring
you upstairs for a C-section.
You mean, uh, cut me open?
Yes. Thirty-two weeks is early.
But we are giving
you steroids now
to help mature the baby's lungs.
No, wait. I don't
want an operation.
You might not have a choice.
If the abruption
continues, the baby will die.
But nothing bad will
happen to me, right?
Right now you're
all right, but...
Then don't.
Don't cut me open.
Don't do anything.
Hey, it's Dr. Torquemada.
Who?
Nothing. Did you discharge
your screamer yet?
It was pretty tough, Carter.
You couldn't tell
that from out here.
He took on the hurt
and won, my friend.
You gotta respect that.
Right. No brain, no pain?
Some cultures see
pain as a rite of passage.
Uh, somebody
call a staff meeting?
No.
Hey, you know, that kid
made it up to the O.R. okay.
Cardiac team's in.
Benton's working on the leg.
Good. Thanks.
At age 13, the Masai warriors
of Tanzania scar themselves
with red-hot spears
and yank out their
bottom front teeth,
with no Novocain, mind you. Hm.
Hey, Dave, why don't
you give us a minute?
Oh, yeah. Sure. Sorry.
Carter, hold on.
What's up?
I think you know.
Oh, look at that.
The guy leaves like
a millimeter of coffee
on the bottom of the pot.
Abby saw you.
She saw me what?
Abby.
I saw you inject the fentanyl
into your wrist.
What?
In the trauma
room, when you said
you were cleaning up.
I was cleaning up.
John. I have the chart here.
You drew up 200 of
fentanyl into the syringe.
What is this?
You gave 150
mics to the patient.
Okay. Hold on. Slow down.
This is a mistake.
But you stopped after 3 cc's.
Yeah, Haleh gave
him a bunch of Versed.
You were there.
What happened to
the rest of the fentanyl?
I don't know. Must have
wasted it down the sink.
Somebody's supposed
to witness you doing that.
Come on.
Come on. We do
that all the time.
We have a protocol
for disposal of narcotics.
Okay. Fine. Whatever.
That doesn't mean
that I injected it.
Abby...
f you thought you
saw something, why...?
Why wouldn't you
come talk to me?
It's appropriate for Abby
to come to us. Not
when she's wrong.
Carter, you still on
pain medication?
Why? What? For your back.
Yeah, why? A little. Why?
How much is "a little"?
Well, that's between
me and my doctor, isn't it?
So you're not overmedicating?
You think I'm a drug addict?
Huh? Do you honestly
think I'm a drug addict?
That I'm what, sneaking around,
injecting whatever
narcotics I can find?
Uh...
You guys... You know
me. This is ridiculous.
So you deny this?
Yes, I deny it! Abby.
I, uh, think you're
seeing things.
Maybe you're on drugs.
Yeah, I think I saw
you with a needle once.
Okay, Carter...
if this is a misunderstanding,
I apologize.
This is a misunderstanding.
You know why we had to ask you.
Can I go back to work now?
Thank you.
And thank you, Abby.
I really appreciate that.
He's lying, Mark.
I know.
We'll call someone
you can talk to.
It doesn't have
to be your parents.
It can be a friend,
a roommate...
No, please. I don't
wanna talk to anyone.
Gloria, we don't have much time.
If we're gonna save that baby,
we need to operate now.
I told you I don't want it.
You can give the baby up.
Your mom and dad
would never have to know.
I don't want an operation.
So just leave me
alone. All of you!
Just leave me alone! Okay. Okay!
All of you leave me alone!
Okay, but you're gonna
have to keep monitors on.
Why? For your own safety.
We need to know if you
start bleeding internally.
Dr. Kovac?
Why don't you spin another crit?
And cycle the dynamap
every five minutes.
Seventeen years of practice,
I thought I'd seen everything.
You're taking her up?
I can't. Not if she
doesn't want to.
The fetal heart rate
is down to a hundred.
The abruption is progressing.
She needs a C-section.
I made the consequences
very clear to her.
She doesn't care
about the consequences.
You can't cut a woman open
without her consent.
That's assault.
The baby will die.
I'm aware of that.
And you can stand by
and watch it happen?
There's nothing I can do.
You can operate.
No, I can't. I'm sorry.
I'm calling another OB.
Who? I am the head
of the department.
We don't force C-sections
on women in this hospital.
What if I can get her
declared incompetent?
I don't know. She
seemed coherent to me.
I think the stab wound
was self-inflicted.
You can prove that?
She is delusional.
She claims she didn't
know she was pregnant.
She was lying. That... That
doesn't mean she's crazy.
What kind of woman carries
a child for eight months,
and then refuses to
let us help her baby?
You know what? Call
Psych. Give it a shot.
Then I can bring her up?
Yeah, if they say yes.
Side-biting clamp.
5-0 Prolene.
If you ask me, Peter,
we're lucky to
have this extra time.
Ah, Kovac didn't know
the bullet moved to his heart.
Well, I'd have trouble
prioritizing someone
who shoots at a playground too.
BP's down, 80 palp.
Is that you?
Nope. No active bleeding.
Femoral vessels are clamped.
Shirley, recheck the pressure.
Still falling, 70
palp. What is it?
Did the bullet embolize?
Fluoroscope on.
It's still in the heart for now.
But it is moving closer
to the pulmonary artery.
- We got blood dripping.
- Where from?
Shirley, take the
towel off his shoulder.
He's bleeding out.
Oh, damn it. Saline sponge now!
We need six more units
of packed cells up here!
What are you doing?
I've gotta locate the source.
I just opened his heart.
It won't make a difference
if we don't stop the bleeding.
Wait! Just wait!
Clamp the auricle.
I can't! Just for a second.
The other bullet hit the artery.
Clamp the subclavian.
I need to get this bullet out.
Then I'll do it myself.
Move. Let's go.
Pressure's down to 60.
Where's the damn blood?!
Shirley, give him
a saline bolus.
Come on. Damn it! I
can't reach the artery.
All right. Crank the
sternum open a little wider.
He's in V-fib! Paddles! Paddles!
Peter, get your hands
out, now. Hold on, hold on!
Clear! Now! Got it. Go!
I don't know what to tell you.
But I've got a
tournament next week.
I can't miss the tournament.
You've broken your
collarbone, Mr. Tanner.
Aside from hurting yourself,
you'd be worthless on the field.
Well, can't I just put a
cast on it or something?
No, we sling it, and you rest.
Well, then, it
can't be that bad.
Yosh. Could you get
Mr. Tanner a sling?
I'll have to call Central.
We have a small. He looks large.
Hey, Mark.
You better make
that extra-large, mate.
I'll be back to discharge you.
So I talked to Legal.
Did you use his name?
No. I spoke in hypotheticals.
Uh, bottom line, we
need more evidence.
But he can't treat
patients, right?
I-it's one accusation.
We have to be careful.
Can we ask him to drug test?
He's taking a prescribed
pain medication.
He'll test positive.
And I'm afraid just asking
will push him further away.
What do you wanna do?
I wanna get him some help.
All right.
Let me talk to him again.
He might open up
if he doesn't
see it as a threat.
Mark, how could
we let this happen?
I mean, he showed all the signs.
I know. I know.
But it's Carter. Your
mind just doesn't go there.
She's a little calmer
now. That's a good sign.
He'll talk her into it.
How do you know?
He has to.
Dr. Kovac.
Yeah?
This is Vinny Rosato,
Nicholas' father. The schoolboy.
Oh, yes. Yes.
Hi... Hi, Mr. Rosato.
Your son is in surgery.
How bad is it?
He was shot in the
leg and the shoulder.
The surgeons should be able
to repair those injuries, but...
one bullet has
traveled to his heart.
He was shot in the heart?
No, no, no, no. The bullet
was swept through the vein.
But there shouldn't be
any major tissue damage.
Can they get it out?
We should take you upstairs.
There, you can get
more updated information.
I'll take you, Mr. Rosato.
Thank you, Cleo.
She's certainly
emotionally distraught.
She could be
clinically depressed
and even have a
personality disorder.
Can you declare her incompetent?
But she's not acutely psychotic.
She understands that failing
to perform the C-section
could endanger her baby's life.
You mean kill it.
She's willing to take the risk.
It's not a risk. She
wants it to happen.
She stabbed herself
to make it happen.
You have no evidence of that.
And she's a danger to others.
Who? The baby.
Doesn't count.
It's still her body.
Is the C-section
necessary to save her life?
Somewhere there
has to be a point.
Is it?
No.
Then without a court
order, you can't touch her.
I don't have time
for a court order.
That baby needs to come out now.
We can try to expedite it.
Our legal department
knows friendly judges.
You'll have to
write up an affidavit.
Yeah. Whatever.
When did you start smoking?
Well, that depends. Does
it make me a druggie?
Ask the Surgeon General. Hm.
I'm worried about you, Carter.
Look, I'm okay.
I got angry when
I shouldn't have.
Not that I didn't have a right.
I'm okay.
You didn't talk to
anyone, did you?
Any psychiatrists?
No.
Why not?
'Cause I didn't
feel like talking.
Look, I'm gonna be fine.
Or I hope... Nah, I-I will be.
It's been rough. You
can understand that.
I got stabbed in the back twice
with a 6-inch butcher knife.
I'm in a lot of pain.
And this place isn't exactly
the easiest work environment.
Lucy's dead, which
is partly my fault.
I haven't slept in months.
I... I had to take
more pain medication
just to function.
I didn't steal it.
It was prescribed to me.
Did you take the
prescribed amount?
Yeah. More or less.
I think you need help, Carter.
Look, I understand
that you have to make
this your business.
But please... Please
let me deal with it.
When are you off?
Midnight.
Okay, I don't want
you to see any patients.
You can work on
QA chart reviews.
I can see patients.
There's nothing wrong...
Carter, you have to trust me.
Let me figure this out.
We gotta write this one up.
Oh yeah, including the part
where you lifted
him off the table
while I was opening his heart?
Cranking his chest with one
hand and suturing with the other?
I still have a few
moves you haven't seen.
Oh, yeah? Listen,
okay, dibs on the bullet.
No way. It's mine.
I was the one that called it.
Yeah, but I fished it out.
Oh, yeah, but I... Hey, Cleo.
Hey. We just made a great save.
I can see that.
Yeah, we got the bullet
out of the boy's heart,
and Peter saved
his arm and his leg.
Father's outside Recovery
waiting to talk to someone.
Oh, okay. I'll do it.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Hey.
Dr. Carter, I didn't
know what to do,
so I asked Dr. Greene.
I'm sorry.
And I know I don't
know you very well,
but I think you're
a good doctor.
And I know you've been
through a lot in a short time,
and I'm sure I couldn't
handle it myself.
But I felt I had to tell them.
You feel better?
'Cause I have work to do.
Hey, Mr. Tanner.
Here's your prescription.
You need to take one
every six hours for pain.
And you're gonna
wanna ice the...
Mr. Tanner? Mr. Tanner?!
Yosh, get Dr. Greene now!
What is it?
Barely has a pulse.
Lily, I need a BP.
What did he present with?
Fractured clavicle.
Absent breath
sounds on the left.
Could be a tension pneumo.
Get a 14-gauge needle
on a open syringe.
Come on, let's go.
BP's 50 palp.
Betadine? Yep.
Quickly, quickly. Get
him on a pulse ox.
I got it. Okay, check a pulse.
Stronger.
He's gonna need a chest tube.
It was just a broken collarbone.
Not anymore.
Satting at 95.
Okay. Get me a 10 blade.
Carter, what are you doing?
Saving this guy's life.
You must have missed
an occult rib fracture.
I'll take it from here.
Needle decompressed.
Gimme the Kelly.
I got it, Carter.
I'm almost in.
Right.
Right. You take it.
32 French.
Suction's ready.
BP's 100/60.
You're welcome.
I'm in. Hook me up. Abby.
Call as soon as you
know. Yeah... Thank you.
He didn't sign it?
They got there at 6:30.
The judge had already left.
But the clerk is trying
to track him down.
Can't we try another judge?
They're already working on that.
I-I can't wait. Luka.
You can't do
anything until we get it.
I've waited too long already.
Promise me that
you won't do anything.
No. I'm going to
change her mind.
We need to do this tonight.
I don't believe it.
Well, it makes sense.
He's been so unpredictable.
I thought he might be bipolar.
Carter? Come on, no way.
He as much as admitted it to me.
Peter, he's using.
I don't know for how long,
but the behavior's
been there for a while.
But is this the
right way to do it?
Uh... He might
feel ganged up on.
It's either this, or we have
to kick it to some committee.
I'd rather approach
him as a small group
that he knows and trusts,
and give him a
chance to clear it up.
And what about Romano?
No. We don't want
to bring him in to this.
You know, uh...
Carter can be stubborn.
He might just walk out.
We have to be prepared for that.
All we can do is be
compassionate, but clear.
He has two options. That's it.
Are you with us, Peter?
Kerry?
You needed me?
Yeah, Don.
So, what's the big emergency?
Why don't you have a seat?
Fetal heart rate down to 60.
Get a baby warmer in here.
Gloria, we don't have
time to argue anymore.
This baby needs to come out now.
I want another doctor.
The placenta's detaching.
You could hemorrhage to death.
You're trying to scare me.
You should be scared.
If you don't care
about your baby,
at least think of yourself.
I don't believe you.
You... You would've
done something already.
Heart rate's down to 50.
You're going to have a boy.
I can tell from the ultrasound.
You really want
to kill your son?
Leave me alone. I w...
I want another doctor!
Down to 40.
Okay, that's it. 100
of ketamine, IV push.
Dr. Kovac.
You heard me.
Draw up the ketamine.
You can't. I'm the attending.
I'll take full responsibility!
What are you doing?
Please don't do this.
I-I-I don't want the baby!
C-section tray. Prep her.
I don't want the baby! Please!
Heart rate's down to 20.
Please. Please help me!
Cleo, set up the suction.
No, I won't. Then
get out of the way!
Luka, she didn't consent.
You could lose your license.
10 blade!
You can't do this.
You can't.
Is it over?
Carter.
Got a minute?
No. I'm done with these.
If you don't want me to see
patients, I'm gonna go home.
Not yet. I need to talk to you.
Is this my suspension?
Not here. Come on.
Oh, God. Give
me a break. John...
Carter, just listen.
Just hear it.
No, I told you.
I am on painkillers for my back.
But I'm functioning.
Dr. Carter?
You would be wise
to be quiet and listen.
My van is parked outside.
We have a ticket to Atlanta.
There's a drug rehab...
There's a drug
rehab center there
that specializes in treating
doctors with addiction.
Well, that's great,
but I'm on
prescribed painkillers,
and that doesn't
make me an addict,
and I think you all know it.
I'm not finished!
It's apparent to all of us
that you have a drug problem.
Therefore, we cannot allow you
to continue working here
or anywhere else as a physician.
So you have two choices.
Get in the van,
go to the airport,
check yourself in.
And when you come back...
we will support you
in any way that we can.
Or I'm fired?
Yeah.
Everyone in this
room cares about you.
No one is judging you.
Yes you are. You've
already judged me.
You have no idea
what I've been through
these last few months.
But I've been here.
I've showed up.
I haven't made excuses.
I haven't complained.
That's not the point...
No, that is the point!
Can anybody tell
me that, uh... Uh...
that I have endangered patients?
I mean, can
anybody here say that
my performance has changed?
Hmm? That I'm
some kind of liability?
John... you put a patient
into anaphylactic shock
by giving her Bactrim,
when she told you that
she was allergic to it.
And you almost killed somebody
by leaving a guide
wire in their chest.
Is this about mistakes?
Hm?
Who here hasn't made a mistake?
Hell, I saved your
ass this afternoon.
John... you've demonstrated
compulsive
drug-seeking behavior.
When. Just tell me when.
I think mainlining
fentanyl qualifies.
Well, I didn't do that. You
want to call me a liar, fine.
Call me a liar.
But I didn't do that.
Okay, show us your wrists.
Show us your wrists!
Are we looking for track marks?
Yeah.
Well, there. See?
Here. Want me to
roll up my sleeves?
Take off your watch.
Ah, you know... You know what?
Forget it. Forget it.
This is your only
chance, Carter.
Great. I quit.
Well...
Is that it?
No.
What are you doing?
I don't need this.
I've never needed this.
I wanted to be a doctor,
I wanted to help people.
But I don't need their damn job.
Carter, you don't wanna do this.
No, I'm not doing it. They are.
Carter, wait! No!
Carter, what are you
gonna do, piss it away?
Everything you've
worked for? Eight years?!
You're the ones
handing out ultimatums!
Carter, you're
getting in that van!
Like hell I am.
You're not gonna do this!
They tell you that I'm
some kind of junkie
and you believe them? And
you come and ambush me.
You're outta control.
If you can't see that...
You're getting into that van.
No. Get in the van.
Don't touch me. Get in the...
Don't touch me.
Where does it end, man, huh?
This week, fentanyl, next
week, you end up dead.
Or worse. You end
up like your cousin,
some babbling gork
in a nursing home.
Carter, you want to
fight, that's cool, man.
But either way, you're
getting your ass in that van.
It's all right, man.
It's all right, Carter.
Good job. That's good.
He's crowning.
Almost there, Gloria.
One more push should do it.
Ready? And push.
Push.
The head is out.
Okay. You can stop now.
Clamp.
And cut.
Does she want to see him?
Would you like to
see him, Gloria?
No.
You want me to pronounce him?
No, I'll do it.
Time of death, 19:47.
Did he get on the plane?
I don't know.
Peter hasn't called.
Wonder what he said.
Who knows? I just
hope Carter gets on.
Yeah.
Well! It's nice to
see the ER brain trust
is diligently
working after-hours.
Hello, Robert.
The ICU is a zoo. Seems
nice and peaceful down here.
Yep. Same old stuff.
Yeah, fun never stops.
Elizabeth, Walt Newman,
the intussusception
upstairs. What about him?
Tried to reduce with an enema.
Left a big mess.
We have to go in.
Now? Yeah.
It's not quite as sexy
as snaking a bullet
out of the heart,
but it's a life-saving
procedure nonetheless.
I'll be right up.
Thank you.
Good night, all.
Guess I lost my ride.
That's right.
It's all right.
I'll take the El.
You sure?
Yeah. See you at home.
I'll try not to wake
you. Good night, Kerry.
Good night.
You wanna go get something
to eat or something?
Uh, no. I-I think I'll wait
to hear that he got on.
Okay. Well, call me.
Okay.
Thanks.
Uh, just a minute.
Uh, Dr. Weaver?
Yeah.
I've got Legal on line 3.
They say to go ahead,
the judge signed a court order.