♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
We're Addison and Sam.
Addisam. We're a couple.
He talks to me about feelings.
He's amazing in bed.
He cooks for me. Food.
Yeah, he's perfect.
I'm perfect with him. Addisam.
She's freaking out.
Ignore her.
Addisam.
I can't just ignore--
say something
shrinky, then.
Uh, being a-- a happy couple
is a healthy thing.
What's wrong with him?
He has no flaws.
Well, he knows you.
You know him.
There's love.
You have a good foundation.
Is that a metaphor or like
floorboards and a basement?
No, like he knows how to commit.
Like Pete knows how to commit.
It's a good thing.
Really? Because in my--
shut up, bitches.
I need to get laid.
I need to get laid really bad.
So bad I am gonna run naked
through the streets
and grind a cop if something
doesn't happen soon.
Will one of you
just lie on top of me
and rub around
for like ten minutes?
I thought you and Mark Sloan--
that was weeks ago.
Which in sex years
is like a decade ago.
Where are all the men
in this city?
Sheldon is single.
Do you hate me or something?
Sheldon is smart,
thoughtful, charming,
and great in bed.
Really?
Oh, morning, ladies.
What?
Violet: Nothing, nothing.
I was just coming to find you.
Ready to go?
Security at the prison can--
can be a bit of a pain.
All right, look,
I know it's not sex,
but come watch me
deliver a baby.
Miracle of life,
always reaffirming.
Always puts me
in a good mood.
Sheldon?
Really?
It's always the quiet ones.
What do you think about
starting a family?
Now?
Not now, but soon.
We're engaged.
These are the kinds of things
that engaged people discuss.
How can you be thinking about
babies when we're doing this?
You do know that this is how
babies get made, right?
Not the way I do it.
Okay. I'm serious. We--
we do wanna have kids
of our own, right?
Can we talk about this later?
Babies are a wonderful gift.
They're god's
little creatures.
We should totally
discuss this later.
Sheldon:
Okay, I'm seeing five inmates,
you're seeing two.
You're just there
to assess the inmates,
give your recommendation
to the parole board.
You're not there
to make nice.
So no flirting
with the inmates?
You're making light, but these
are hardcore criminals, Violet.
They're persuasive
and charming
and good at getting you to think
that they're not criminals.
So just stay on your side
of the table. Be professional.
Violet:
Don't accept anything
from a prisoner,
don't offer to do anything
for a prisoner.
Relax, I read the file.
I got it.
All right.
I'm fine.
I'm a big girl.
I love you, Tracy.
You're doing a great job.
I love you too.
How are we doing?
Looking good.
The baby's starting to crown.
I can see her head.
Oh, you hear that, honey?
You can see Kyla's head.
She's gonna be beautiful
just like you.
Honey, could you not
put the camera--?
Please, don't film my--
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Okay, you guys
are the nicest couple
I have ever seen in a delivery.
All right, we're almost there,
Tracy.
Just one more push. Ready?
Push.
Good. Almost there.
Here comes Kyla.
I'll get oxygen
and an intubation tray.
I'll set up the ultrasound.
She's not crying.
Why--? Why isn't she crying?
Is something wrong?
She's just having
some trouble breathing.
I just wanna get her over here
and take a look.
Addison:
Tell me it's not as bad
as I think.
How can someone this small
have a tumor this big?
Okay, Mr. Cartwright.
You have completed 40 years
of a 50-year sentence
for murder
and armed robbery.
Well, I guess we both know
what's in here, right?
Why don't we
just talk instead?
Tell me about your
rehabilitation.
What do you wanna know?
Do you feel changed
for the better?
I'm definitely
a different man.
And what about remorse?
Do you feel sorry
for what you did?
I think about what I did
every day.
So you feel ready
for the outside,
ready to rejoin society?
Can I say something, ma'am?
Dr. Turner.
Violet Turner.
Dr. Turner,
I've been up for parole twice.
And each time a therapist
just like you
asks me the same list
of questions
and I end up saying
what I need to say
to get the result
I need to get.
But you seem like a nice lady.
I'm not gonna waste your time.
I'm gonna be honest with you.
I'm a model prisoner.
I've never had
a major write-up.
I've worked in the mail room
30 years.
I've co-led classes
in anger management
and taught young prisoners
how to read.
I'm proud of that,
but I know none of that's
gonna mean anything
once I get outside these walls.
I've lived more of my life
locked up than free.
I'm old.
And if released,
I'll get swallowed up
out there and I know that.
But here in prison,
I feel at home.
It's where my friends are,
my life is.
So I'm asking you...
To lie to the parole board.
Tell them that I'm dangerous,
unremorseful, and get me denied.
Do whatever you have to do,
but, please,
help me stay in prison.
It's remarkable.
And so intricate.
I mean, in just ten weeks,
it has partially compressed
the lung
and attached
to the major vessels.
Don't sound so gleeful.
Well, I'm sorry, it's just...
It's a beautiful tumor.
Sam?
It's a pleuropulmonary blastoma.
It's putting pressure
on the heart.
Amelia:
What are you gonna do?
It's a 12-hour surgery
and I need some help
separating it from the cardiac
vessels. You in?
Yeah, sure. We should probably
get Charlotte on the horn.
Start gathering the best team,
oncologist--
Daniel and Tracy
were so excited.
They're like the perfect couple.
I just hate
to shatter their world.
Well, that's the thing
about perfect.
Doesn't exist.
How was convict day?
Convict day?
Talking to prisoners about their
parole. You know, with Sheldon?
The state gives us a bundle.
Do you listen when I talk to you
in the morning?
I do. I listen closely.
You never said anything about
working with convicts.
Oh, well, I don't know.
Maybe I forgot.
Anyway, the point is
that my prisoner wants me
to lie to the parole board
and have him denied.
He wants to stay in prison.
Why?
He's old. It's home.
Good. You're done. Case closed.
No, not-- not done.
Not closed.
How can I just leave a man
in prison?
Just let him
stay in a system
when he clearly
doesn't belong there.
Doesn't this strike you
as so, so sad?
Not really.
Why is everyone here so callous?
Everyone's not--
we gave Betsey away.
Dell's child.
Our dead friend's child.
We put her in the system too.
This isn't about Betsey.
I know.
So, what is your problem?
You're my wife,
the mother of my child.
You were brutally attacked
by someone
who is now in the system.
So forgive me if I feel
a little callous.
Forgive me for caring.
You should feel like crap.
Oh, shut up.
What do you think about me
and Charlotte having kids?
Is Charlotte pregnant?
No.
Uh, but, you know,
she will be one day and...
We'd have cute kids, right?
So now you want a child?
This really
isn't about Betsey.
Okay, fine.
Well, uh, does Charlotte feel
like she's ready to be a mother?
We're, um, still talking.
Good. That's good.
Yeah.
Wow, Charlotte with kids.
I never thought, um...
Well, that's good
that you're talking.
Isn't she too young
for surgery?
The surgery is risky.
Every surgery is.
But we've got the best surgical
team assembled
and I'm confident
about their abilities.
Uh, Dr. Rodriguez,
meet Dr. Addison Montgomery.
How do you do?
Charlotte:
Daniel and Tracy woods.
Dr. Rodriguez is the oncologist.
He'll be part of the team
working to treat Kyla.
I know this is a rough time
for you,
but we're going to do everything
in our power to save your baby.
Charlotte:
You're actually on time.
We were just discussing
surgery.
Surgery?
Have you discussed chemo
as an alternative to surgery?
Yes, but I believe surgery
will be more effective.
Only if she survives.
Chemo's better than surgery?
Rodriguez: In my opinion.
Based on the ct,
Kyla has a type two ppb tumor.
Chemo is the treatment
of choice.
It's less invasive and risky.
I disagree.
I've seen the ct too.
I believe that Kyla
has a classic type one tumor.
Removing the tumor
will cure her.
I can tell you about
the advantages of chemo.
Excuse me--
maybe we should
step outside, doctors.
If you two wanna gunsling,
do it out here,
not in front of the family.
Chemo is the standard,
proven method of treatment.
You'd say that.
You're a cancer doc.
Chemo is all you do.
Of course you'd go against it.
You're a surgeon.
Cutting is all you do.
The goal here is to figure out
what makes sense,
not argue.
No way is it necessary
to do surgery now when there's
another viable, safer option.
It's safer to put a baby through
months and months of chemo
and watch it suffer?
That's safer?
If we can reduce the mass
and shrink the cancer cells,
it will make doing the surgery
later easier.
There's no guarantee chemo
is gonna remove the tumor.
Guarantee that with surgery?
Yes, I can,
or I wouldn't be standing here.
We don't make guarantees.
One surgery cures this baby
and she never has to see
a hospital again.
And you get to be the hero.
Yes, Dr. Rodriguez.
That's usually how it goes.
You're the chief.
It's your call.
The parents have obviously
put their trust
in Dr. Montgomery's judgment.
So have I.
We're doing the surgery.
Daniel: Help!
We need help in here.
Something's wrong with Tracy.
She's hemorrhaging.
I need two large-bore ivs
and an lr wide open.
I'll get them.
Pulse is racing.
She's hypertensive.
Type and cross two units.
And I need an O.R. now.
It was a postpartum hemorrhage.
It happens.
I was able to control
the bleeding.
She'll wake up soon.
We just have to give her time.
You date,
you get married.
You never even think
that something bad might happen.
We've never had any kind
of problems and now...
Now my entire family's in danger
and they're depending on me.
What am I supposed to do?
You sit down and you wait
for your wife to wake up,
because she will.
And then you let me take care
of Kyla.
Sheldon:
What are you gonna do?
I don't know.
Violet, you can't--
I know, I know. It's just...
Lewis has been locked up
for four decades.
He doesn't have any family,
doesn't have any support system.
He's got no one.
This isn't about Betsey.
I know.
Why does everyone keep--?
Do you?
How is he gonna make
a new life for himself
after being locked up
for so long?
I mean, he went to prison
in 1970. Nixon was president.
There were no computers or cell
phones or freaking microwaves.
Prisoners reenter society
every day. They don't all fail.
You know?
He could make it.
But how are people
gonna treat him?
You tell someone
you've done time in prison,
I don't care
how liberal they are.
They walk the other way.
Lewis is a man.
A man who made a mistake.
But he owes it to himself to
get out there and make a life.
And he deserves a chance
to do that,
even if he doesn't want to.
I have to get to the prison,
talk to the board.
Violet,
I'm gonna say the same thing
I said about Betsey.
Don't lose
all your objectivity.
Don't get attached.
Just do what you know is right.
Is she awake yet?
Not yet.
But Daniel still wants
to go ahead with Kyla's surgery,
so we're gonna do it.
Oh, Daniel, I was just coming
to talk to you.
This is Dr. Sam Bennett.
He'll be assisting me
with the surgery.
Well, actually that won't be
necessary anymore.
See, I spoke with that
oncologist again
and I'm going with the chemo.
Daniel, you have every right
to change your mind,
but I really think
that this is a decision
that you and Tracy
need to make together.
My wife is unconscious
and my baby has a tumor.
So I'm not into
taking any risks right now.
So no, I made the decision
for us both.
I think trac--
Dr. Montgomery,
I won't be needing
your opinion.
Dr. King knows about this.
She gave me her full support.
So you can
stay out of it for now.
Thank you.
Great. No messages.
Any of your patients
need brain surgery?
Nope.
You used to date Sheldon.
Date is strong word.
I used to screw Sheldon.
And would you recommend him?
And he knows
what to do with it.
Morning.
Afternoon.
There's plenty of coffee
in the kitchen.
You don't
have to go downstairs.
We should work together.
I've heard about your skills.
I bet you could
teach me something.
You're talking
about therapy?
And other things.
Did you see that?
What?
Amelia.
She was checking me out
like a piece of meat.
Amelia is young
and hot and, uh...
That's a lot of woman.
Yeah, well,
I can get women, Cooper.
I didn't--
I've had lots of women.
Just saying.
I can handle it.
Okay. Excuse me.
Where the hell is the coffee?
Just talk to Charlotte.
Maybe she can explain.
What's with all the noise?
So from complete faith in me
to totally shutting me out?
What did you do?
Did you lock the dad in the room
with that jackass oncologist
so he could convince him
to do the chemo
while Tracy's unconscious?
Charlotte:
Are you done?
Because once you stop talking,
I can.
Who wins, Venus or Serena?
Both: Shut up, Cooper.
First, I don't have to explain
anything to you.
It's my hospital.
I do what I want.
Second, my responsibility
is to the parents.
And the baby,
the actual patient here.
I'm not done talking.
Third, the man's been holding
vigil by his wife's bedside
while his baby
lays in an Incubator.
He didn't need
much convincing.
Although you wanna believe
big bad bitch Charlotte
shut everything down,
I didn't.
One parent made a decision and
I am obligated to enforce it.
Which means the father
has spoken,
the surgery is off
and I am done with this.
Oh, you know what, Charlotte?
I'm not done.
Let her go. Breathe.
Lewis is 70,
but his life is not over.
He is smart. He is strong.
He can make it.
There is life outside of prison
and Lewis should
be a part of it.
I believe he is ready
to be a part of it.
Lewis Cartwright
is not a threat to society.
In fact, if released, I believe
he'd be a model citizen.
What are you doing here?
I'm here to help.
You've done enough, thanks.
Lewis, please, hear me out.
Who is Addison to be questioning
my motives anyway?
What, is she
the motive police?
I don't have to explain
anything to her.
I mean, last time I checked,
my mama lived in Alabama.
What?
I'm just waiting
for you to finish.
Say what's on your mind,
Cooper.
You don't fight fair.
You don't listen
to the other side, Charlotte.
You don't hear people out,
you don't answer questions.
When you wanna
get out of something--
what are you talking about?
With Addison, you just walk away
and with me, you use sex.
You have a problem with that?
Yes!
No.
Yes, we are engaged
and having a discussion
about children is important.
In my mind, I asked you
a pretty simple question
that you don't wanna answer.
I told you we'd discuss it
later. What's the big damn deal?
Why? Why later?
No! See, this is what
I'm talking about.
Okay, I'm gonna finish this.
You can't dig your heels in
when you don't like
the conversation,
say "later," and walk away.
Yeah. At least I finished.
What happened to just coffee?
Everything's fancier now.
I haven't had to choose
what to eat in 40 years.
You know, if it helps, I usually
narrow it down to two choices
and then I just choose one
from there.
I'll have eggs and bacon.
Do you have
a place to live?
I got the name
of a probation officer
who's gonna set me up
at a halfway house.
The prison gave me
two pairs of pants and a shirt
and a couple hundred bucks.
I'm thinking it's not enough,
but it's a start.
I-- I made some calls too,
and I found a job for you.
It's just something
part-time at a car wash
until you get
back on your feet.
What do I owe you?
Nothing.
That's not the way it works
where I come from.
Somebody do you a favor,
they expect one back.
Well, that world
is behind you now.
You're a free man.
Lewis:
I feel like I've been dropped
into some foreign country
and I should speak the language,
but I don't.
It's gonna take a while
to adjust, Lewis.
But you will.
Come see me.
We can work together
to help you to transition.
Okay? I can help you make it,
Lewis.
I'm here to do
a repeat blood count.
We start chemo
in the morning.
She's all yours.
I know this isn't your choice,
but I really think
it's going to work.
Doesn't matter
what you think.
Daniel and Tracy came in
thinking
they were gonna have
a healthy baby and they didn't.
Now everything's a mess.
I didn't peg you
as a pessimist.
What?
Last month, I had to tell
three families about relapses.
I lost my favorite patient.
But then there was
this one woman with lymphoma
who walked out
of those doors.
That's how it happens. You focus
on the good, on the one.
Not on the bad.
Tracy woods. She's awake.
I have two highs.
Cutting into people's brains
and sex.
When I can't have one,
I search for the other.
And right now nobody's brain
needs cutting into.
You're propositioning me
for sex?
Yeah.
I'll think about it.
Excuse me?
I wanna see Kyla.
How is she?
She's doing as well
as can be expected.
Tracy, I wanted to talk to you
about the surgery.
Did you already do it?
Daniel didn't tell you?
Tell me what?
Daniel:
Honey, I called the family and--
what are you doing here?
She's our doctor.
Daniel decided
to go with the chemo.
Chemo?
But Dr. Montgomery said
she could remove the tumor.
Maybe. Honey, maybe she can
remove the whole tumor.
All right, that oncologist,
he told me that Kyla
is too weak for surgery.
And-- and you agree with this?
No, I don't.
You can't just make
this decision without me.
You know, I just don't want
our baby to die.
And I do? I'm her mother.
Yeah, and I'm her father.
Okay, the time
that you waste arguing
is time that Kyla
is not being treated.
You need to make a decision.
What do you both wanna do?
I told you, the chemo.
No. No.
Look, there's only two ways
for this to end.
Either one of them
goes to court
and gets medical
power of attorney or...
Or we get them
on the same page.
Okay, well, I can try
and talk to Daniel.
What?
Nothing.
Have I told you how beautiful
you look in the morning?
Okay, okay. Enough with the lips
and the hands.
Okay.
You're freaking out and--
if you touch me,
I can't think.
You're too sexy.
Just be ugly or something.
Ugh, woman.
Okay, look, I know...
All right,
I'm just gonna say this.
And I know that it's gonna make
me sound like a crazy woman,
but us, you, me, the addisam,
you know, it's just not...
All right.
Usually in a relationship,
I can see ahead and see
how things are gonna go wrong.
You know, I'm usually five
moves ahead or 15 moves ahead
and I can see
where it's gonna fall apart
or where the guy
is gonna disappoint me
or where he's gonna break
my heart or--
but you're perfect.
You have no flaws.
And I can't see ahead
and it's making me crazy.
Nothing is going
to break us up.
Don't say that. That's perfect.
You just said the perfect thing.
Daniel and Tracy
thought that.
Now they're ripping each other
apart over their baby.
What do you want me to say?
I don't know.
Just try not to be perfect.
Okay. Ahem. How about this?
I'm not perfect.
I'm just perfect for you.
See?
Now I'm gonna have to tear
your clothes off
and have my way with you.
Because that was the exact
perfect thing.
Okay.
Sheldon turned me down
for sex.
I figured he would feel like
he won the lotto.
Instead he looks me straight
in the face and says--
"I'll think about it."
How did you know?
Wild guess.
It's probably not as good
as I think it's gonna be anyway,
so...
It is.
It's better.
Damn it.
The whole,
"let me think about it"?
That's pure Sheldon.
That's his game.
And from looking at you,
it's working like a charm.
Hey.
What you looking for?
He hasn't called.
Who?
Lewis, the parolee.
I told him to come see me.
I hoped he would call.
I'm worried.
He's out there by himself.
Well, I'm sure he has access to
people, resources who can help.
Okay, look, i--
I know you don't like the idea
of me working with a prisoner
because of Katie,
but I'm good.
I'm not afraid.
So worry about Lewis,
not about me.
He's a murderer, Violet.
And that means--?
He can't be rehabilitated.
How could you even say that?
My life's work is based on the
belief that people can change.
I see it every day.
I say this out of concern
for you.
Don't get involved.
The world's a better place
without people like Lewis.
Okay, I know you're trying
to take care of me,
but this is pissing me off.
We care. That's our job.
That's who we are.
And this,
what you're saying right now,
it doesn't even sound like you.
Daniel:
This will be Kyla one day,
right?
Happy, healthy.
Yeah, we hope.
My baby's lying in an Incubator
with a big tumor in her body
and we're out here fighting.
If Kyla doesn't make it,
Tracy's not gonna be able
to live with that,
and I cannot lose them both.
You don't have to.
That's easy for you to say.
Actually it's not.
I know why you wanna
make the safe choice.
No parent wants
to see their child
go behind those operating room
doors and not come out alive.
The waiting feels like
it's gonna kill you.
But there comes a time
when you need
to put your trust
in each other
and make a decision together
as parents.
Right or wrong.
You want that,
do the surgery.
If I stop, I'll get fired.
I-- I hadn't heard from you
and I just wanted to make sure
that you were okay.
I'm making it.
I gave you my card
and I was hoping that--
I tossed it.
Hey, look, I'm working here.
Lewis, I'm sorry.
I'm not here to harass you.
I just wanted to--
help? You said that.
Look, I don't need a handout.
Well, how about a hand up?
Look, i--
I've been through things myself
and I know how hard it can be.
So I just-- I want you to know
that I mean it.
Here. Keep it this time.
Leave and don't come back.
But--
you don't know me.
I could do things to you to make
you regret you ever met me.
So for your own good,
I would leave and stay
as far away from me as possible.
Why do you have my child?
I hijacked him
from the nanny.
God, he's growing.
I think I might
have messed up with Lewis.
Who's that, the prison guy?
Why do you say that?
He threatened me.
And that is just
between you and me, okay?
Pete saying "I told you so"
is not what I need right now.
Yeah, but you need to walk away.
You've done enough.
Let the guy
make his own way.
I am. I'm done.
You think I wanna save this guy
because I couldn't save Betsey?
Do you?
It's like looking
into the sun.
So gorgeous it hurts.
Charlotte is acting weird
about the baby thing.
What if she never wants kids?
Well, you can hijack Lucas
whenever you want.
Preferably Friday nights,
so I can have sex
with my hot cranky husband.
Don't talk about sex
in front of the kid.
He'll end up impotent.
Or I will.
Motherhood is scary.
She'll come around.
Addison:
The tumor is even larger
and more intertwined
than on the ct.
Sam:
Maybe debulk as best you can
and get out for now.
Addison:
No. I promised I could get it.
Metz.
Nurse: Here you go.
Sam:
Whoa. The tumor invaded
the artery. It perfed.
Addison:
Satinsky. I need to clamp
the vessel.
I can't get it.
She's hypovolemic.
We lost her pulse.
We got the whole tumor.
It's gone?
Yes.
Her lung is fine
and so is her heart.
Would you like
to see Kyla now?
Yes, please.
In and out.
That was my plan.
I was just gonna
go in the store,
hit the register,
get some cash.
I never expected anything
to go wrong.
But when she saw my gun,
she started screaming
and screaming.
I knew she'd remember my face,
so I shot her.
Twice in the stomach.
I didn't even wait for
her body to drop. I just ran.
She was a college girl
on her way home from school.
Just stopped for gas.
Stephanie was her name.
And I wonder all the time,
what would she be doing
with her life right now?
Would she be married?
Have kids? A nice job?
And because she died,
you don't feel like you
deserve to live your life.
I didn't mean to scare you.
I'm sorry I did that.
It's just that
I don't deserve anyone's help.
Everybody deserves help, Lewis.
I killed someone.
And you feel like
you can't forgive yourself.
And I can never
repay it either.
Forty years in prison,
that's enough.
Is it?
It has to be.
If I enjoy a cup of coffee,
I feel guilty now.
If I just sit on a park bench
and watch the trees blow,
I feel guilty
about that too.
And now that I'm free,
if I lose myself
in a good moment, I feel bad.
But think about all the good
things that you've done.
All the ways that you've tried
to make amends.
And you've done this
all the while knowing
that you can never really pay
for what you did.
You helped
other prisoners.
You never caused trouble
for anyone else.
You got an education.
You didn't just sit there
and do time.
You made something of it.
You went into prison
and you came out a better man.
It's okay to live, Lewis.
Live.
Hey, Lewis was here.
We had therapy
and he had a breakthrough.
I believe he thinks
he can make it now.
That's great, Violet,
but be careful.
Everybody doesn't respond
to therapy.
Great. First Pete and now you.
Pete?
He has some issue with me
working in the prison.
Oh. Violet.
I can come back later.
What was that?
Psychology and brain surgery
are symbiotic disciplines
and we were thinking
about working, um--
okay, I'm not a good liar.
Amelia propositioned me
for sex
and I haven't been able
to give her an answer.
Ooh. What do you think
is holding you back?
Amelia and I have said
eight words to each other
since she joined
the practice.
Why me?
Nice, Violet. Real nice.
You've been sharing stories
with the class.
Oh, come on.
For most men, this would be
like a badge of honor.
She made it.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Can I buy you dinner?
And tell you how right you were
over and over?
I can't.
But-- but thank you.
Oh.
You probably
don't need to know this,
but I've had a string
of unsuccessful relationships
and now I have this amazing guy
in my life
who does amazing things
for me and...
You...
Well, let's just say
that I am focusing
on the good, on the one.
I'm not the mommy type.
I don't like kids
and I don't want kids.
And I'm a pediatrician.
I love kids.
I've always wanted kids.
I need to have kids.
They'll like you
more than they'll like me.
I'm not...
...warm.
They will love you.
What if I end up
like my mother?
Drunk at noon,
hating the rug rats
I'm supposed to love,
screwing up our kids,
damaging them.
See? Now you're gonna leave me.
This is why I didn't
wanna talk about it.
Charlotte, I'm not leaving you.
We're having the conversation.
And you didn't walk out
and you didn't shut down
and you didn't try
to confuse me with sex.
We're having the conversation.
And we can keep having it.
We don't have to decide
right now?
right now.
What now?
Now you can confuse me
with sex.
Yeah?
Yes, please.
Take your clothes off.
I know your game.
You perform like
a triathlete in the bedroom
to get women in elevators
all gossiping about you.
You play the "insecure, shy,
indecisive therapist" bit.
And in the end, you're the guy
who ends up with all the girls
and nobody
ever saw it coming.
You're horrible
at taking rejection.
Heh. I am not.
Horrible. You're the baby
of the family, right?
That's a little easy.
You know what?
I take it back.
This whole offer, i--
let me tell you
how this would go.
We'd sleep together and at first
it would be just for kicks,
but eventually
I'd fall for you hard.
And then you would do what women
like you, the bad girls,
the ones who like it
dirty and nasty
and a little bit kinky,
you know, the ones
with serious daddy issues do.
You'd run.
You'd avoid me. You'd be
intentionally mean to me.
My savior complex would kick in,
so I'd chase you,
keep calling you,
let you use me for sex
on the nights when
you were drunk or bored.
But you're too damaged
to appreciate the fact
that I'm a good guy
and I could actually care.
And then one day,
I'd show up at your apartment
with flowers or something,
trying to woo you,
only to find you on your couch
screwing some guy
ten years younger than me.
Am I wrong?
I don't need it, Amelia.
I'm a grown man
looking for a grown woman.
So when you grow up,
come find me.
Because I am as good
as they say.
Addisam, huh?
Yeah.
I will not hurt you.
The reason you're always trying
to see five steps ahead
is because you expect
to get hurt.
Those other men,
they hurt you,
so you're always
looking ahead,
trying to protect yourself.
There's no protection.
There's no looking ahead.
You're gonna
have to trust me.
I will not hurt you. Okay?
I will not hurt you.
Say it.
You will not hurt me.
I will not hurt you.
Hey.
Hi.
So, Lewis called me.
He got a job.
I mean, I went down there to see
and it's not washing cars.
It's good. It's a good job.
It's at a coffee shop.
He's making coffee.
The owner said he trusted
Lewis's smile, which is...
Yeah, he's gonna be
a barista.
Last week, he'd never heard of
a latte and now he's a barista.
I mean, isn't that just weird
and great
and somehow hopeful
for the world?
Like no babies in Africa
are gonna starve or--
so instead of being home
with your son,
you're out at 9:00 at night
hanging with your buddy,
the murderer?
No. You did-- did you ju--?
You did not just say that, Pete.
Okay. Pete, I'm gonna ask you
what's going on
and you're gonna tell me.
Nothing. There's nothing.
This is not about me
being out late. What's going on?
I don't wanna talk about it.
Well, you're married
to a therapist, Pete.
I can wait here all night.
I've done the prison thing,
okay?
My family...
My mother's in jail.
And my brother's--
well, I don't really know
where he is,
but he's probably in jail
by now too, so...
Oh, Pete.
I don't wanna go there,
Violet.
I'm not sharing.
I don't wanna talk.
They don't matter.
They're your family.
No.
You and Lucas are my family now.