When I was five, my
mom lost me in a park.
I don't remember much,
except that one minute,
I was riding the carousel
and the next, she was gone.
I don't remember
how I found her.
I don't remember how I got home.
Are you okay?
All I remember is
what happened next.
She told me not to worry.
She told me everything
would be fine.
You might have saved
your mother's life.
Don't put that on me. Stop it!
Don't touch me!
She told me it was time
to play the quiet game,
so I knew I wasn't supposed
to ask any questions...
Would you like to see her? - No.
No. Absolutely not. No.
Or else, I might have told her
I forgot my doll.
I loved that doll so much.
It killed me to leave it behind.
Funny, isn't it, the
way memory works,
the things you
can't quite remember
and the things you
can never forget?
You really should get...
your locks changed.
What are you doing here?
I need to talk to Alex.
Wilson, get out of the bed. I can't
get in the bed with you in there.
You can't kick me out of bed.
It's my house.
No, it's my house.
Then you kick her out.
I'm not wearing any...
I don't care about your
boobs, Wilson. Out.
Oh, my God.
Oh.
I guess I'll go make us
some coffee since I'm up.
Coffee would be great.
This is not our thing now, okay?
You can't just start
showing up at all hours and...
I mean, this is not what we do.
I told Derek I am
not moving to DC.
The children and
I are staying here.
All right, the miracle is over.
The miracle is not over.
We're not a miracle. Shut up.
You can't break into my
house and wake me up to talk
and then tell me to shut up!
Okay.
So, here's what happened.
Last night, I found
out I have a daughter.
Or at least, I think
she's my daughter.
All these years, I had no
idea, and now she's here.
She doesn't know who I am,
and I can't talk
about it to anyone.
So, I figure I'd wind
up one of two places,
either here or in a bar, so I...
Anyway, here I am.
You're here early.
Yeah, an MVC came
in last night after you left.
The driver had an open-book
pelvis, so I stuck around.
You've been here all
night? MedEvac just called.
Hypotensive patient en
route, possible multi-trauma.
All right, page Yang.
Pierce. Page Pierce and Grey and
ask them to meet me at the helipad.
Can you finish up here?
Uh, sure, yeah.
He's dying inside.
He seems fine.
Well, sure. He's a soldier.
He's stuffing everything
down, but he needs a buddy.
You could be his buddy. Nope.
Oh, come on!
How would you feel if I
were the one who left?
You lying awake at
night in your empty bed...
What kind of buddy
are you asking me to be?
Should they be flying in this?
No choice!
Hi!
What?
I said, "Hi!"
I'm Maggie! Pierce!
I know!
We haven't officially met!
Hello!
What?
I said...
Whoa!
Are we safe up here?
Oh!
Just answered my own question.
Okay, let's get ready.
We've got to be quick.
Okay, let's go!
Lost camper, extracted
from the desert,
Scablands west of Spokane.
Hikers found him,
thought he was dead.
Let's get him out. Be careful!
Okay.
This wind!
Grab him, bring him back in!
We cannot unload him
until this wind dies down.
Watch out!
What if she runs
off with our baby?
I mean, what if she does drugs?
What if she doesn't eat right?
What if she forgets
her prenatals?
Last night, you were all for
a surrogate. What changed?
No, nothing.
I just... I was brushing
my teeth this morning,
I saw my scar in the mirror.
I was pregnant with Sofia when
that accident happened. Me.
Even I couldn't protect
our unborn child.
How can we put that kind of trust
in someone we don't even know?
Sofia's fine. You know,
it was a freak accident.
There's no reason to think
that that's gonna happen...
Excuse me, out of the way,
please. Page downstairs.
We need more hands! Let's move!
Okay.
Get out of my way!
The best cases go
to the fastest resident,
and I'm the fastest resident.
I'm caffeinated, and
I've been up all night.
No more mister nice girl.
It's every woman for
themselves now. Oh.
There!
I need a central line and
an art line set up STAT.
Dibs. Damn it.
Somebody needs
to go help Chief Hunt.
The gurney just
flew off of the helipad.
Dibs. Dibs.
You can't double-dibs.
That's my dibs.
I can't tell which is better!
One of you, get over here!
Wait! My dibs!
Bitch!
I can't move! Help! Help!
Help! We're stuck! Over here!
Oh, my God!
Help us!
Somebody, please! Oh, my God!
- Somebody, anyone!
- Please! Help us!
Someone, help! WOMAN:
Somebody, please!
On three. One, two, three.
This guy got lost in a desert.
I didn't even realize
Washington State had a desert.
I'm from Boston. Mmm.
I heard you lived there, too.
Yeah, my mom moved
us there when I was a kid.
Ellis Grey, right?
That's your mom?
Yeah.
Oh.
No. Sir, don't do
that. Don't do that.
Find them. Find them.
His pulse is through the roof.
Edwards, monitor his sats,
and let's up his sedation.
Have to find them. Who
do you want us to find?
My family. Please find
them. They're still out there.
My family, please.
His BP plummeted.
Get him a fluid bolus,
and start 10 of dopamine.
His rhythm is erratic.
Repeat EKG, STAT.
Help us! Just hang in there.
We're gonna get
you out of there.
This door's jammed!
It really hurts. Is that normal?
Nothing about this is normal!
Dave, is that you? I think
that's Dave Oldroyd in there.
What, you know him? Yeah.
Yeah, yeah. Stage two
osteosarcoma patient.
He's due for his next round
of chemo in, like, an hour.
David, what are you doing
in there? Are you all right?
My head hurts when I move it.
Don't move your head!
All right, just hang in there,
Dave. Let me get a closer look.
No, no, no, no, no!
Everything okay?
Yeah. No.
They're sitting in each
other's laps with no pants.
Why aren't you
wearing any pants?
Well, I'll give you
one little guess.
Okay, we're gonna need
to get them both C-spined.
Who's gonna climb in there?
Not it. Bum leg.
Dibs.
I alerted the authorities
that the patient was
traveling with family.
Edwards, can you imagine?
He must have been out
there wandering around, lost,
looking for his family,
day after day, all alone.
Dr. Grey.
Do you want me to page
plastics to look at the foot?
Yeah. That thing's nasty.
Oh, God.
Hold on. Foot's
gonna have to wait.
He's got perinephric
fluid buildup.
We got to get him
up to CT right now.
Good news! The
tech is available,
so I'd like to get
that echo done now...
Book an OR. And get a new chem-7
because his potassium's
been all over the place.
I'd really like to
make sure there isn't
any underlying
cardiac pathology.
Should I, uh,
re-check his coags or...
Dr. Grey. What?
The echo. When can I get that?
Oh. That's gonna have to wait.
Excuse me.
Watch out. Coming through.
You guys aren't waiting on
the board meeting, are you?
That's been postponed.
Postponed? For how long?
Because Dr. Webber is
recommending me to the board
as the replacement
for Yang's vacancy.
He is?
Well, we will address
that when we reconvene.
Karev, you need something, too?
Yeah. Um...
These are Yang's shares of the
hospital along with a certified letter.
She gave her seat to me.
So, you can just hand off board
seats to whomever you want?
I mean, what about the
members of this hospital?
Don't we have rights?
Don't we have a voice?
What are the rules here?
I said I'll talk to legal. It's
an unprecedented situation.
It's not a situation. My shares
are legit. I have them in my hand.
And where the
hell have you been?
Well, I was... Tell
them, Richard.
Tell them that I belong
on the board, not Karev.
Karev? Yeah.
Yang's trying to give
Karev her seat. I don't...
No, she did give it.
Um, excuse me.
And what are you...
I just need to know
you won't talk to anyone
about what you
heard this morning.
It's anonymous for a reason,
Richard. Of course not.
But if you ever wanted
to talk, you could, to me.
I'm a really good listener,
and it's not like I
don't have things
that I would rather not
have everybody here know.
I mean, I haven't even
told my own brother about...
I don't want to talk.
The last name is Peterson.
The wind blew my son's
Frisbee up onto our roof.
My husband climbed up there...
If you could check
in at the desk,
I'm sure someone could help you.
Daddy fell and didn't wake up.
I got a page? All right.
Can you guys wait over there?
And I'll see what I can find out.
Come with me.
Good, you're here.
There's too much blood to
do the ventric. Can you help?
Geez.
He belongs to them?
Yep.
Oh, damn it.
BP's 220 over 123.
He's bradying down.
The family's asking
for an update.
Anything I could tell them now?
Well, nothing good.
Just hang tight, okay?
We're working to get you out.
Are you calling my mom?
Of course, we're
calling your mom.
Mrs. Oldroyd? Hi.
This is Dr. Torres.
Are you gonna tell
her that we were...
My parents are gonna kill me.
They don't even know I took the car.
Monica, babe, you're hurt.
I'm sure it's fine.
A gurney landed on you, the
sunroof shattered on your head.
Dave, can you see
anything, any open wounds?
Oh. Oh, God.
Door's coming off!
She's got a head
wound, bleeding profusely.
All right, let's get her out
of there and get her inside!
Be careful.
You want headfirst, okay?
There you go.
Good. On three. One, two, three.
Can I get a blanket? Thank
you. Yeah, yeah. Here you go.
Watch out for broken glass.
All right, buddy.
Make sure you're
protecting his C-spine.
One, two, three.
Good news is this day really
can't get any worse, can it?
Don't look! Don't look!
Now's your chance.
What? No, no, no.
Hey, Chief, you got a minute?
Uh, I've got to check on my
John Doe in CT, but what's up?
Well, are you busy tonight?
'Cause a couple of guys are
probably gonna get together,
you know, hit Joe's,
grab some brewskies.
Oh, yeah? Who's going?
So far, there's me, uh, and you.
Okay, well, um...
I don't know what time I'm
gonna get out of here tonight,
so can I let you know?
Yeah. Absolutely.
Yes. Let me know.
See? Was that so hard?
Yes. It was.
What I don't
understand is, why a car?
You're in a building full
of beds and supply closets.
We haven't seen
each other in weeks.
My dad was just transferred
to Portland last month.
Yeah, plus, it's kind of hard
to get privacy on a peds floor.
Because it's a place for young
children to heal, not to have sex.
You told her?
Two teenagers in a
car? I did the math.
Your collarbone is broken, Dave,
and your shoulder is
really badly bruised.
David Lincoln Oldroyd,
you were supposed
to be taking it easy!
You weren't even
supposed to be out of bed.
And you definitely weren't
supposed to have visitors.
Yeah, well, it's not like I planned
to have a gurney fall on us.
Don't you smart off to me.
Some of these glass shards
are embedded pretty deeply.
I may have to shave
some of your hair.
Are you kidding? No!
Yes! Awesome! Shave it all!
Rock on! No!
I've been trying to shave
my head in solidarity forever.
It's so dumb.
Why would anyone
volunteer to be bald?
No, you're gonna love it.
It's so smooth and so sweet.
You are so getting
separate rooms.
Okay, well, the good
news is everyone's fine,
so let's just focus
on that, okay?
Yikes, that mom was
harsh and judgy and...
I totally agree with her.
You do? You don't?
Robbins, I just stopped
by to check on the UTO
I repaired at 21 weeks,
and the parents could not
stop singing the praises of you.
You should have seen the surgery
that Dr. Herman performed
on this baby in utero.
It was masterful.
Yes, it was.
But the baby hits the air,
you do a few little stitches,
and you get all the credit.
How is that fair?
By the way, I'm still
looking to fill my fellowship,
if you hear of anybody good.
Maybe you should apply.
Yeah, then you could learn to do
something that's actually hard.
Well, I actually do
really hard things in peds.
Really? Like the teens in
the parking lot. How are they?
Fine. They're morons.
When do you leave
for DC, anyway?
I was gonna ask Meredith
if I could store some things
in your side of the closet.
Did Meredith tell you that?
You both did, loudly, until
about 4:00 in the morning.
How does it work exactly?
You're not separated, but
you're not living together.
Meredith's staying behind?
She is.
And you're cool with that?
You're together
but living apart.
Live-a-partners!
See that? I gave it a
name. Now it's a thing.
Yeah, I'm familiar
with that thing.
I did it with Miranda.
How did it work
out for you guys?
Well, seeing as I'm not living
in LA anymore, I'd say it didn't.
It's not crazy, right, to
go after this opportunity?
I'm not a bad person
for wanting this.
No, but Meredith's not either.
This is her home.
It's your kids' home.
You can't blame her
for wanting to stay.
How are you gonna get laid
when the person you get laid with
is here and you are in DC?
Oh, grow up. It's
a valid question.
Okay. Removing the skull flap.
This won't take long.
Dr. Hunt and I will
be just over there.
I have to go. Oh,
no, no, no, no, no.
I'm gonna need you
to stay still, okay?
They're still out there.
The authorities are
looking for your family,
and they'll notify
us as soon as...
I can't be here. I have to go.
Okay. How about if I
stay with you, right here?
Would you like that, if I just
stay here? I'll stay here with you.
I found footprints,
and they're so tiny that
they have to be hers.
It's my little girl, Lily.
She's only six years old.
We were trying to
find Nine Mile Falls,
and the car died and
I went to go find help.
I told them I would... I told
them I would be right back.
It's Lily and it's my wife,
and if they're separated,
if Lily is by
herself right now...
It's already been three days,
and she's not gonna
make it without any water.
So, I have to go right
now, and we have to hurry.
Please!
You've been in the desert
for more than three days.
Uh... I know.
It's maybe four days.
Based on your
state of dehydration
and your level of malnutrition,
I think it's been more
like one or two months.
What?
No.
They're gone,
aren't they? My Lily?
My Lily. She's six.
She's six years old.
My Lily.
Grey, we need to move him now.
Tell them we have a
name for his daughter.
- Her name is Lily.
- Dr. Grey!
And they found him
at Saddle Mountain.
That's 100 miles
from Nine Mile Falls.
They've been looking for
his family in the wrong spot.
Dr. Grey!
I stopped by CT to take
the patient for his echo,
but you were gone.
Echo has to wait.
Lily...
His right kidney has
severe EPN and abscesses.
We're taking him up
to OR three right now.
- I have to get off!
- Sir, lay down.
I have to get off!
Lay down, sir, please!
Lay down.
Please, sir. MAN: I can't
stay. I have to get off.
Sir, please.
I still need that echo. Not now.
Head up to OR three.
Tell Grey and Hunt that you've
got two of their patient's toes.
Try not to throw up on them.
Ew. Ew.
You know what's weird?
I keep paging
cardio and expecting
Cristina to just walk
through the door.
Pierce is no Yang.
She's perky and chatty.
I bet she likes cats.
Sorry to interrupt.
Mr. Crossley's
anastomosis may be leaking.
Oh, so, you're gonna take
him back for a wash out?
We're prepping him
in OR one right now.
Great.
Is there something else?
You have very steady hands.
Thank you.
Uh, have you ever played Jenga,
you know, where you
stack the little bricks
and try not to make them fall?
Uh, yeah.
You should come over sometime.
I'll make snacks.
Okay.
Or if you're not into
Jenga, there's checkers.
Hmm.
The blood supply to the
kidney is all clotted out.
But the kidney
itself is still fine.
Yeah, Edwards. Pop quiz.
We have one bad kidney,
one good kidney with
a bad blood supply.
We want to avoid dialysis
and the transplant list.
What do we do?
Uh...
She's not gonna get
it. Give her a second.
Mmm...
Oh! Auto-transplant.
You can use his good
kidney to replace his bad one.
You can transplant his own
kidney. Can I please scrub?
Yes, go on.
Oh, my God!
I can't believe we're
actually doing this!
Oh, my parents are gonna freak!
They're gonna freak?
What about me? I'm
fully freaking over here.
All right. That's it.
Ta-da.
Oh, my God.
Adorable, right?
We're like alien lovers.
One of the lacs
needs some stitches.
I'm gonna grab a suture kit.
Okay. Can you get me some
more tape, too, please? Thanks.
Monica?
What's happening? Is she okay?
Dr. Torres! CALLIE: Oh, no.
Why isn't she moving?
Monica!
What's happening? What's wrong?
Monica? Look at me.
Look at me. Monica?
Page Dr. Shepherd.
Okay.
They're calling for an emergency
neuro consult downstairs.
17-year-old female,
trauma to the head.
I can handle things here.
Okay.
Warren, you coming?
Well, actually, would
you mind if I stayed here?
No offense, but you've
already got one foot out the door,
and this Dr. Shepherd
is the new head of neuro.
So, you want to stay here
and not come with me?
Why not? Seems to
be the trend these days.
The site is prepped and ready.
Okay, let's flush this
with Collins and heparin
and put this kidney
in its new place.
BP just dropped out.
Is there a pulse? No.
Okay. Edwards, stay with the
kidney while I bring him back.
Let's get a crash cart in here.
Push one of epi. MEREDITH:
Starting compressions.
CVP is soaring.
Page Pierce, get her in here.
- And let's order an echo.
- Right away.
Stopping compressions
to check rhythm.
Pulseless V-tach.
Charge paddles to 150.
Clear!
How bad is it?
It's an epidural bleed.
I cannot believe they
snuck out to that car.
If I were her mother and
this brain bleed didn't kill her,
I would totally kill her.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
I sound like my father
when I was a teenager.
What is... What
is wrong with me?
I love him, but I don't
want our daughter
to have my father for a mother.
I don't know what you just said,
but it's nice to see what our kids
have in store for them someday.
Or kid.
You sure you don't want
to consider a surrogate?
Looks like it's deeper. We
need to get in there now.
Okay. I can't watch this.
I'm gonna go check on Dave.
Will you tell me
when it's, um, over?
Yeah. Okay.
What happened?
We were about to
autotransplant his kidney
when his BP dropped out.
I'll take over.
I think he's in
cardiogenic shock.
Thank you. I've got this.
He's got a failed mitral
valve from endocarditis.
He'll need a balloon
pump. Gown and glove me.
Let's pack the belly and
get a cardiac team in here.
Edwards, prep the right groin.
Edwards is
monitoring the kidney.
Edwards, now.
Let's get this OR changed
out. These need to go.
Dr. Pierce, you realize that
I have another surgery to finish
- as soon as you're done here.
- Quickly, people.
Dr. Pierce, I'm talking to you.
And I am ignoring you.
We've got a patient in cardiac
distress, which could have been avoided
if I had gotten
that echo earlier.
I let you overrule me before.
That is not gonna happen again.
No matter how important
you are around here, Dr. Grey.
I have a duty to
help this patient,
not kiss your ass.
Dr. Hunt, I could use an assist.
Dr. Edwards, let's make sure
that that kidney is
prepped and ready to go.
As soon as she's finished,
we'll get back in there.
- Oh, no.
- What's wrong?
It's gone.
What's gone?
The basin with the
kidney. The kidney is gone.
Well, look for it!
Look on the floor, look in
the hazardous waste bins,
look everywhere.
I'm sorry, Dr. Grey.
I took my eyes off
it for two minutes.
Because Dr. Pierce came in
and started ordering you around.
Yes, I was ordering
the resident around.
With no knowledge of
what she was already doing.
Are you blaming me for
your resident's incompetence?
That is ridiculous. You
should have never barged...
Hey. We have a
patient open on the table
who needs our
undivided attention.
- Both of you, settle down.
- She's the one...
She's accusing me of losing
a kidney... I said settle down!
Oh, I found it!
They dumped out the basin. It's
been in the sink the whole time.
Let's get it in here and
see if we can save it.
Pupil's blown.
He's herniating. Damn it!
Just want to get an update
on Mr. Peterson for his wife.
Push 100 grams of 20% mannitol!
ICP's still elevated.
More mannitol! His
brain injury's too far gone.
We've been trying
to salvage things.
How long has he been down?
Thirty-seven minutes.
I'm gonna call it.
Time of death, 18:32.
Kepner, is everything okay?
Yeah, yeah. No,
I'm fine. It's just...
He was just trying to get
his kid's Frisbee, you know?
Dr. Shepherd's doing
everything he can for Monica,
but it's just...
She seemed so fine,
giving me attitude.
Hmm.
Are her parents...
On a plane now. They
should be here soon.
When they're babies, you
spend every night by their crib,
just watching them, make
sure that they're still breathing.
They start walking,
so you childproof
every inch of your house.
They start climbing trees,
and you just pray that they don't
fall and crack their head open.
They turn 16,
and they get cancer.
And...
Just when you're
finally about to beat that,
they sneak out to a
parking lot to have sex
and a gurney
falls out of the sky!
I mean, how are we
supposed to do it?
How are we ever
supposed to keep them safe?
It's bad news, isn't it?
We'll be right in.
You should stay in bed, keep
that shoulder immobilized.
You guys have been
out here a long time.
Is it 'cause she's dead?
You're trying to figure
out how to tell me?
No, sweetie, Monica's not dead.
Yet. You mean
she hasn't died yet.
How am I gonna tell her parents?
How am I gonna explain to them
that I'm the reason she...
Oh, no.
No one has died, okay?
We're just gonna sit here,
and we're gonna
think good thoughts.
Don't you worry.
It's like the fight's
gone out of him.
He's been this way since
he woke up from surgery,
listless, confused.
His pupils are responsive.
Can you follow
this light for me?
I just want to sleep.
I know you're tired, but this
is an important examination.
You're a doctor?
I am.
Then help me. Give me something.
Put me to sleep.
That's when they come,
when I close my
eyes and I go places.
And then they come in
the door and everything's...
Everything's fine.
I shouldn't have left them.
I should never have left them.
Leave me alone, please.
I just want to sleep.
Karev?
What are you doing?
Nothing.
But you don't
want to go in there.
Asking personal questions.
You're ignoring
concerns about a patient!
You had no right to accuse me...
I have every right.
I have never experienced
this level of disrespect and
this lack of professionalism...
Respect is earned,
and if you want to talk
about being unprofessional,
I spoke directly to you and
you ignored me in my OR.
You ignored my request
for an echo this morning.
My patient was circling the
drain, and I was doing my job.
And I was doing mine.
I spent all morning
deferring to you,
trying not to step on
your toes, for what?
Because I wanted you to like me?
Guess what. I'm
kind of over that now.
Yeah, you definitely don't have
to worry about me liking you.
It took my last two dollars.
And it won't give
me my granola bar!
Everything okay?
Meredith Grey.
She's your sister.
Yeah, you figured that out, too.
I was hoping...
I was gonna talk
to her today, tell her.
First, I was gonna win her
over with my talent and charm,
and then I...
I found my sister,
and I think I hate her.
She's terrible.
She's not. She's...
What am I doing?
I have parents,
good, funny, kind,
goofy parents.
I don't need any... Screw it.
Screw her.
I am just fine without adding
any random, unwanted
blood relatives into my life.
Oh, gosh.
I'll pay you back tomorrow.
Not necessary.
Think he'll be able to hang on?
It's hard to predict.
Oh, did you catch
the game last night?
What game?
Wasn't there a game?
I don't know. I just asked you.
All right, screw this. See,
Kepner is worried about you.
She asked me to take you out.
What, like a date?
No, not a date.
It's like a man-date
thing but not like a date.
Listen, I'm fine. I'm gonna be
fine. You're the one who's not fine.
You're the one who's
splitting up with his wife.
I'm not splitting
up. I got a job.
On the other side
of the country.
Cristina's on the
other side of the world.
She's not my wife.
She and I split up,
whereas you two, you're...
Which is none of your business.
Just stop asking
me out on dates!
Hey.
How's this for solidarity?
You know what?
Dave's mom's right.
Even if you play it safe,
you aren't safe, not really,
so we might as well
take a few risks, right?
I'm so happy to
hear you say that.
You are?
Yeah, 'cause I...
I have something
to talk to you about.
Me too.
About this morning.
You were right. I
was overreacting.
You know what? We
can't control everything.
So we should do it.
Let's get a surrogate
and have another baby.
Absolutely.
Oh, no, well, actually,
I was talking about
the, um, fetal surgery fellowship
that Dr. Herman mentioned.
Oh! Oh, okay.
So, you're, uh,
recommending somebody?
I thought maybe me.
I could get double-certified.
It's an incredible opportunity.
So, you're essentially
going back to school?
It'll be hard, I know,
you know, study
sessions and longer hours.
And a new baby.
Right. So, that's
why I was just...
That's all. I was
just thinking about it.
You guys coming?
What's this about, again?
Yang's board seat.
Oh, that's a no-brainer.
It's Bailey. Yeah, it's Alex.
So, here is what we
know. Karev has a letter
from Yang's attorney granting
him her shares and her board seat.
So, that's Karev's seat.
Not so fast.
According to the
bylaws of the foundation,
new board members are
appointed by a majority vote
from other members.
That is the closest
thing we have to a rule.
So, what do we do?
I propose we let
them fight it out.
Can I talk to you after this?
Dr. Grey?
There's news about
the hiker's family.
I did.
Hi. Thank you.
Hey, look.
Yang gave me her
shares for a reason.
I know you don't think
I deserve the seat,
but I don't want to screw it
up, I'm not gonna screw it up.
I'm sure you'd make an
excellent board member.
May the best surgeon win.
That was nice of you.
Yes, it was.
You think he's got a shot?
Please. It's Alex Karev.
How is Mr. Peterson?
On my way to talk
to his family now.
It's gonna be super fun.
I love telling little kids that
dad is never coming home.
I'll go with you.
Actually, I'd appreciate that.
Yeah, somebody should
be there to make sure
you don't say things
like "super fun."
Ah. Good note.
Hey, Luca. Cool spaceship.
Where's your mom?
Dr. Shepherd?
Luca, we just need to talk to
your mom over here for a sec.
You cool to hang out,
work on that spaceship?
No.
Oh, no.
What happened?
Mom?
I'll stay with him.
Come on with me.
Come on. This way, Luca.
I want to go with my mom.
I haven't seen a spaceship
with a trap door before.
Want to show me how to use it?
My dad's dead, isn't he?
We should talk about that
when your mom comes back.
Dead means he's
gone away, doesn't it,
and he's never coming back?
It does.
I miss him already.
The nurses say you're
refusing your IV fluids.
You need them to
get your strength back.
There is a reason you
survived for so long.
I don't believe this has to be
the end for you.
Finally...
I'm asleep.
They're always
here when I'm asleep.
Papa?
Papa!
They found us the next
day, but they never found you.
We thought you were
gone. You were gone.
I love you, Papa.
There can be
beauty in getting lost.
There you are.
Grab your stuff. We're drinking.
Oh. I can't.
I have to go home
and deal with...
Fight with Shepherd?
I think you need to whine
about it some more to me first.
You definitely need to drink.
What are you afraid
of, that I'm gonna...
I'm afraid you're gonna
keep crawling in my bed
in the middle of the night.
Look, Yang left me her
shares and her board seat
and she left me you, too.
It's just us now.
I don't know, if you need
somebody to bitch to or just be...
My person.
I don't know what you mean.
But you do.
Sometimes, we have to
get lost to find each other.
I just don't know if my
marriage can survive this.
My mom asked me
to give this to you.
Oh, I see.
How did she seem?
Not great.
Though, I guess the idea
of becoming a grandma
is helping distract
her, at least.
That's right. Congratulations.
I'm really happy for you.
Thank you.
I'm a little freaked
out, to be honest.
I didn't grow up
with much of a dad,
so kind of working
in the dark here.
Oh, you'll be fine, Avery.
More than fine.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Uh...
Thank you for returning this.
Yeah. Sure.
For what it's worth, sir,
it would have been really
nice having you in the family.
And sometimes,
we find each other,
only to get lost all over again.
I'm a widow. She widowed me.
I'll never have Alex
to myself again.
Her best friend just
left yesterday, okay?
She needs someone to
talk to. You are overreacting.
She kicked me out of my own
bed in the middle of the night,
while I was naked,
and he let her.
Okay. So, you're screwed.
You can't always control it,
the thing that's
going to set you adrift.
I mean, people do it, right?
It's not conventional, it's
not easy, but people do it.
I mean, if we map brains,
we can figure this out.
Are you trying to
convince me or you?
I mean, I don't want to
split up our family, either,
but I certainly don't want to go
and then resent him
for the rest of my life.
And that's what would happen.
And he doesn't want
that, either, so I really just...
I need to go talk
to him about this. I...
Yeah, well...
Hi. What are you doing here?
I just got off the phone
with the White House.
I resigned from the
brain mapping initiative.
What?
I'm not moving to DC.
Why would you do that?
I don't want to
live anywhere else
when my kids are
growing up here.
I don't want to be
apart from them or you.
No job is worth that to me.
I want to be with
you and the kids here.
No. What?
This is not what we discussed.
I mean, you should
call them back
and tell them you were kidding.
I got to pee.
I did not ask you to do
this. I never wanted you...
I know you didn't. I chose.
I chose you and the kids.
And as you stand
there on your front porch,
staring at the life you're
about to leave behind...
I need a drink.
You have to accept it's gone,
it's lost, just like you.
All you can do now
is stand very still,
breathe in the moment,
and try to be open
to wherever the wind's
going to take you next.
Tequila. Tequila.