- Previously on The Resident...
- I loved my sister very much.
One night, I decided to take a
quick nap, and when I woke up,
the whole house was on fire.
- How's Jessie?
- Her kidneys are failing.
I was a project for you,
and now it's finished.
Tell me I'm wrong.
Tell me I'm right.
Either way, just open up
- like you asked me to do.
- And I will.
When I'm ready, when
I figure some things out.
I mean, my feelings
aren't just gonna change.
Conrad and I have fought long
and hard for our relationship.
We've been through it.
But I love him.
♪ Get up offa that thing... ♪
Come on!
♪ Get up offa that thing ♪
♪ And dance till
you, sing it now ♪
♪ Get up offa that thing ♪
♪ And dance till
you feel better ♪
♪ Get up offa that thing ♪
♪ And try to release
that pressure ♪
♪ Get up offa that thing... ♪
It's freezing.
They're expecting
six more inches.
Atlanta is essentially
shut down.
So is the hospital.
Bell canceled
elective procedures.
♪ Get up offa that thing ♪
♪ And try to release
that pressure ♪
♪ Get up off... ♪
The med students
need to go home.
They make good snowball
targets, but otherwise,
they're useless.
They need to go.
I don't know. A slow night
is a good time for them
to practice their skills.
You keep these children,
they're your responsibility.
♪ And try to release
that pressure ♪
♪ Get up offa that thing ♪
♪ And twist till
you feel better ♪
♪ Get up offa that thing ♪
♪ And shake it, sing it now ♪
♪ Get up offa that thing... ♪
Look at you.
The most popular
girl on dialysis.
Yeah, apparently kidney failure
comes with more
visitors than rehab.
How are you holding up?
I don't feel great.
It's hard to keep my eyes open.
It's really taking
a toll on her.
Dr. Shaw says that some people
have to do this
three days a week,
- four hours a session?
- Now, there's no need
to get ahead of ourselves.
We're doing a workup
to see if your kidney
failure's reversible.
We'll have a better
idea real soon.
I didn't know you added
another doctor to your dance card.
Well, yeah, the clinic's
closed because of the storm.
I came by to help out
and figure I'd drop in
- and meet Nic's sister, too.
- Can I steal you?
- Donna's asking for us.
- Oh, this is important.
It's a patient we've
had a long time.
- You'll be back soon?
- Yes.
Okay.
Alec is into you.
- I noticed.
- So I'm right.
He mentioned something,
but I shut it down.
Must be complicated
to have to work with him.
I'm fine.
I'm sure you are.
Can I punch him?
Kidding.
This is the new
Conrad, remember?
- Thanks.
- Thank you.
Look, I'm handling it.
- Trust me.
- Of course I trust you.
I don't have to be friends
with the guy, though.
No, you don't.
Hey, Donna.
- How you feeling?
- Not bad.
Ready to talk about
how I'm gonna die?
There. You'll be fine.
You probably
shouldn't try to get home
until the snowplows
come through.
Nurse Hundley will
find you a cozy spot.
What's going on?
Hmm? Oh, Bell's
making an announcement.
So, as you know, the blizzard
is getting worse by the hour.
We're already working
with a skeleton staff,
and because conditions
are so hazardous,
we expect the next shift is
gonna have trouble getting here,
so no matter what
your specialty,
just help where you're needed.
I mean, so far we've
been lucky, it's been quiet,
but we can expect
storm-related...
complications all night.
- Where does it hurt?
- Right here.
Are you guys okay?
Look, we're fine, but
my dad, he needs help.
He's in the back. He's frozen.
We dug him out of the snow.
♪ ♪
We don't have a pulse. Let's
get him to the trauma bay.
Wait, I have to
stay with my dad.
No, we need to check
you for injuries first.
- What's your name?
- Eva Garcia, and that's Eli.
Is my dad dead?
Nurse Hundley's
gonna take care of you.
The doctors are working
on him now, honey.
I'm leading this code.
This man is in asystole.
Everyone get in line
for compressions.
Bai, you're up next.
So much for a quiet night.
- We need access to the airway.
- I'll intubate.
- I'll get access.
- His body temperature
is 72 degrees.
None of this matters if
we can't get him warm.
We need heated
blankets and warm saline.
I'm having trouble
getting the tube in.
I can't get a view.
Let's try succinylcholine.
Maybe that'll help
me get the tube in.
Excuse me, but if possible,
could I maybe pronounce him
dead when compressions stop?
See, Dr. Pravesh said it's
good for us to practice our skills,
and I've never had
the opportunity...
Shut your mouth.
Listen, my dad is
not dead. He's frozen.
Erik, out.
How's my dad?
Your father's heart has stopped.
- Because he's cold?
- Yes.
His body temperature
is dangerously low.
We're hoping, if we warm him up,
his heart will start again.
I know you'll save him.
Promise?
We'll do everything we can.
I expect updates.
Call Dr. Austin. We need him.
Hundley, I'm four miles away.
Whatever it is, get Dr. Kays.
Kays is on vacation in Florida.
Mina has a patient with severe
hypothermia in cardiac arrest.
Just short of slamming my
feet through the floor of this car
and Fred Flintstone-ing
my ass there,
I'm not sure what
I can do about it.
Dr. Okafor told me to
tell you she needs you.
Then neither snow nor rain
nor heat nor gloom of night
shall stay this doctor
from the swift completion
of his appointed rounds.
Scale of one to
ten, how's your pain?
It's a little worse.
But I don't want
any more drugs yet,
because I have a
visitor coming tomorrow
and I want to have a clear head.
Well, with all the years you
spent working in hospice,
I'm sure you know
exactly what you want.
25 years.
If there's one thing I
understand, it's dying.
Uh, when the chemo
stopped working,
I signed a "do not
resuscitate" order,
so if my heart stops,
no one will give me CPR.
Well, I know you were
planning to get to hospice tonight,
but it looks like
you're stuck with us.
What can we do to help?
Your wish is our command.
Oh, just keep me comfortable.
No needle sticks.
Leave me be.
I really admire you.
- Oh...
- I've seen too many people
over-treated and
harmed in their last days.
Yeah, well, I'm hoping
for a few more weeks.
Do you know, many
people live longer in hospice.
I did know that.
Nic's got your back.
In hospice, it's going
to be so much nicer.
- Hmm.
- Scented candles.
"Northern Fir" is my favorite.
I just love the
smell of Christmas.
Me, too.
Friends surrounding me,
all of us drinking
Tennessee whiskey
and listening to gospel hymns.
Mm.
Okay, enough schmaltz.
I have a juicy audiobook
that's going to put me to sleep.
Oh, and I'll be
dreaming of that last item
that I'm gonna be
checking off my bucket list.
What is that last item you're
checking off your bucket list?
Bob.
Bob's the man, the
visitor that I mentioned.
He was my chance at true love.
After Bob, there was no one.
But you're gonna see him?
Yes, I am.
I saw online that he's divorced,
and, um, I wrote him.
And wonder of all wonders,
he's going to come see me.
He would have been here today,
but he was delayed by the storm.
That is amazing, Donna.
Yeah, I haven't
seen him for 30 years.
Oh...
Oh, words that were never
said will finally be spoken.
And I will die without regrets.
Look, I know I said
all hands on deck,
but it's been a while
since my pediatric rotation.
Did you get a hold of Dr. Jonas?
He's busy.
Feldman?
In with the injured paramedics.
So, you kids dug your dad out
of the snow all by yourselves.
How'd you get him
in the car, honey?
Well, we put him on the
sled, and we pushed him.
It was dark, and everyone
was gone, so we dragged him
into the car, and I
drove straight here.
By yourself? Incredible.
She's very brave.
Isn't she, Eli?
He doesn't talk much,
ever since my mom left.
Do you know how to get
in touch with your mom?
Uh, the judge says we
can't talk to her anymore.
Not for a while, at least.
So, just a few bumps
and scrapes on Eli.
So, your turn.
How about I have
a look at that wrist?
Okay...
He's not warming up
fast enough from fluids.
The quickest way is
to circulate warm blood.
- He needs to go on bypass.
- Let's get him into the OR.
Hey, hey, hey, wait, wait, wait.
Is my dad's heart beating now?
Uh, not yet. Uh,
we're working on it.
I know you'll save his life.
You do realize I'm doing
my damnedest to get there
even though I'm
freezing to death.
I'm about to scrub in, and
there's no attending here.
You have operated
without an attending before.
I'm two miles out.
I am in the initial
stages of frostbite.
I'd prefer not to
lose my fingertips.
What's the procedure?
I'm setting up
femoral cannulation
for bypass to help him rewarm.
Are you serious right now?
You can put a patient
on bypass in your sleep.
Start without me.
Finish without me.
But what if there's
complications?
Dissection. Pseudoaneurysm.
Limb ischemia.
Mina,
are you afraid to fly solo?
I am not afraid.
Well, you should be.
Fear makes us careful.
It's a good thing.
But never let it paralyze you.
It's a dad.
He's frozen. He's
in cardiac arrest.
He has two little kids.
The little girl is very brave.
She reminds me of my sisters.
All right.
As soon as my
extremities warm up,
I will head back out.
But you got this, Okafor.
Hey.
What are you doing here?
Look, I-I know I messed up
in the ER, and I'm so sorry.
But the kids aren't
down here anymore,
and I'd still like to
practice the death exam.
You realize we aren't talking
about an item on a checklist.
It's a person.
A father. A young man.
No, I-I understand that.
But I'm just a
first-year med student.
I don't get that much
time in a hospital.
And I haven't seen
that many dead people;
only my cadaver in
anatomy lab. Ernest.
I named him Ernest to
remind me of his humanity
and also to say, "We were
working in dead earnest."
Triage nurse to the ER.
- Triage nurse to the ER.
- Come here.
Quit hanging around here
like the angel of death, Erik.
I might have something you
can help me with later tonight.
Careful.
That's got to hurt.
Yeah. I think it's broken.
I think you're right.
We're gonna take a
picture. Don't move.
Okay.
See you've made a friend.
Yeah, it's not clear
what he sees in me.
But they're great kids.
It's kind of hard to resist 'em.
Not one word of complaint.
All they do is ask
about their father.
You want to take
'em for a while?
I'd love to.
But as soon as
I set Eva's wrist,
I have to go to the ER.
Our paramedic
has a dislocated hip.
It's all on you, Dr. Bell.
Okay, you ready?
So ready.
This guy is flying high.
You are gonna feel
this nonetheless.
But I'm not gonna care.
Do it.
Okay. In three.
One... two...
I think we overshot
on those meds.
Do we have any left?
You didn't say three!
All right.
I came in and
found her like this.
She's delirious, maybe
septic, and she's in pain.
Donna?
Could be a perforation.
What do you want to
do? Up the morphine?
Let's give her two milligrams
and get her up to CT.
She's DNR.
DNR doesn't mean "do not treat."
A scan could show
if there's something
we could do to
buy her some time.
What happened?
Donna was in pain and altered.
She almost fell off the bed
when I touched her belly.
Looks like a
strangulated hernia.
Which we could fix in surgery.
Did Donna say she
wanted surgery?
I mean, she's in and
out of consciousness.
She can't make
decisions for herself.
But I do know...
she wants to stay alive for Bob.
Who's Bob?
Remember the visitor
Donna was talking about?
- Mm-hmm.
- Well, after you left,
she told me his name was Bob.
He was the love of her life.
She hasn't seen him in decades,
and he's finally on his way.
Okay, but we have
her wishes in writing.
Her advanced directives says
she wants no
major interventions.
And I get that, but you
didn't hear what I heard.
And if she doesn't
have this surgery,
she might not make
it through the night.
Surgery could
have complications.
She could end up stuck in the
hospital tethered to machines.
Donna's health care proxy needs
to be making these decisions.
- Have you reached her?
- I've tried.
Several times. The phones
must be down from the storm.
So, if there's no
proxy, I have to decide.
She goes back to her
room on pain meds.
And I think we
should try to fix this,
so we disagree.
I'm her doctor.
This is my decision.
You're pulling rank?
I'm saying the burden is on me.
And Donna explicitly
decided to be DNR.
- I have to uphold that.
- And I believe we should
uphold the wishes that
she made clear to me.
I hear you.
And as painful as
this is for both of us,
I believe that we have to
uphold the written directive.
She's going back to her room.
♪ ♪
Flawless procedure, Dr. O.
Well done.
Body temp is up to 80 degrees.
Still no heart rhythm.
How long do we wait?
I'll let you know...
once I've figure that out.
I heard Eva's
quite the little boss.
I really like that kid.
Wh... Seriously, Dr. Okafor?
I really like kids.
Especially that one.
His temperature is up to 83.
84...
We have a rhythm.
Eva was right.
Her father is not dead.
All right.
This is Atlanta.
It's not Chicago.
Let's go, baby.
Go!
Ah. I'm doing it!
Dad, Dad, I'm doing it!
You know,
he couldn't ride that bike
until Dad put the cape on him.
Dad proved you're a
superhero, didn't he?
I did it. Yeah!
Come on. Doctors...
they can be superheroes, too.
Doctor Strange,
he's a neurosurgeon.
The Hulk... is a doctor.
Yeah, I like the Hulk.
I always did. I...
When I was your age...
I wanted to be the Hulk.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
- Dr. Bell, do you have a second?
Okay.
You have a fever.
You may have an infection.
- From what?
- The dialysis line
can be an entry
point for bacteria.
It's a common complication.
All right, let's have a look.
Yeah.
There is a little
erythema there.
We'll get a set
of blood cultures
before we start
you on antibiotics.
I didn't ask
Dr. Shaw to treat me.
He's a good doctor.
Maybe.
I prefer you.
So does Nic.
I know that.
So how are you doing? Really?
I'm just tired.
This is all like a bad dream.
It'll be over, and...
I'm gonna stay sober this time.
My dad's back.
My family's together again.
We can start over.
And my kidneys
will get better... right?
Well...
there's no reason
not to be optimistic.
Whatever's ahead...
we'll deal with it.
Okay.
Get some rest.
Nolan said that he can
do it laproscopically,
but because Donna can't
make decisions for herself,
we just need a second
physician to sign off...
Surgery is not gonna
cure her colon cancer.
She's got a DNR, and
she's going to hospice.
And normally I
would agree, 100%,
but, based off a conversation
that I had with Donna,
I really believe she wants
to make it through the night.
Why?
She's waiting on a
very important visitor
who's just been
held up by the storm.
Look, I have been with
Donna through years of chemo.
I know her, and I really think
that she would
want to go through
with this surgery if she could.
Is she insured?
Are you asking if the
surgery's covered?
Yeah. Sorry, that's my job.
CEO, fiscal responsibility.
Medicare and supplementals,
so yes, fully covered.
I'll sign off.
You know, better yet,
this is gonna be simple.
It's gonna be in and
out in under an hour.
I'll do the surgery myself.
Okay.
We're going somewhere.
What in the name
of God is going on?
They're playing med
student bowling, Dr. Bell.
You're not kindergarteners.
How many children
are there in this hospital?
Give them some scut to do.
Kit.
- Hi.
- Just who I'm looking for.
I have a surgery.
Are you free now
- to take care of these kids?
- Sure.
- No. No.
- I... you know, I'm...
I'm gonna tell you a secret.
Dr. Voss has superpowers
even stronger than mine.
I do.
I...
break bones and put
them back together.
So, if you go with her
for a little while,
she can show you.
Come on, kids, let's go.
Okay. Thank you.
Let's get something
to eat, shall we?
You must be starving.
It's been a long day.
I'm just putting it back.
He looks like my dad.
You said you wanted to do this.
We have to confirm
that he's dead.
Start the death exam, please.
He's warm. I
thought he'd be cold.
He looks kind of alive.
This is freaking me out.
What happened to this guy?
Cardiac amyloidosis.
Restrictive cardiomyopathy.
Heart failure.
Impressive you know that.
I want to be a cardiologist.
My grandpa died
young of a heart attack.
My dad had a heart
attack last year, but...
he's okay now.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. You all right?
Okay. Sit.
Head between your knees.
Been an idiot.
Can't declare a guy dead.
Can you do it?
I can.
But you'll have to watch
so you can learn, okay?
No heart sounds.
Pupils are fixed and dilated.
Go on.
Time of death:
2:41 a.m.
We're sending you
a 42-year-old man,
presented in full
arrest, now rewarmed
with normal sinus rhythm
and stable blood pressure.
So we're done here?
Uh, since his temp
is back to normal...
My feet are killing me.
And triceps are hurting
from doing all
those compressions.
Don't be a whiner.
Let's get him
ready for transport.
His pressure's dropping.
- I'll do a quick exam.
- I'm gonna give him
a liter wide open and
start him on pressors.
His heart sounds muffled.
And distended neck veins.
Bai, pass me an echo probe.
Where's the Raptor?
Is he here yet?
- How's it going?
- Not gonna be so simple.
There are a lot of adhesions
from prior surgeries.
Gonna take a while
to work through them.
Oh, wait. That's dead bowel.
I'm gonna have to
do a bowel resection.
There's no way I can
do this laparoscopically.
Look, if this could end
with her unable to control
the end of her life, then
you need to stop now.
You asked me to bring her here.
Now I'm gonna
do everything I can
to make sure she
gets off this table alive.
I'm not gonna have
her die in my OR.
Convert to open. 10 blade.
Raptor isn't here.
I can't even get
him on the phone.
Cell service is down.
So, what do we do?
I am making a pericardial window
to drain the blood
from around the heart.
The sledding accident must
have caused some traumatic injury.
Which started to bleed as
we rewarmed him on bypass.
The pericardium is
completely filled with blood.
15 blade.
Draining the pericardium.
He's bleeding too
much. I need to
open up his chest to control it.
Sternal saw.
What's going on?
Shouldn't we
wait for Dr. Austin?
This man could die
if we don't proceed.
Give me the saw!
Activate massive
transfusion protocol.
Take it easy, man. Thank you.
No injuries to the
atria or ventricles.
We're losing him.
I can't find the
source of bleed.
Okay. Tear in the
proximal P.A. Clamp.
Suture.
The Raptor has
arrived! Where are we?
Bit late. We've
already started closing.
He was in cardiac tamponade.
Mina had to perform
a pericardial window.
Then she had to open him up
and repair a
potentially fatal bleed.
It was awesome.
So...
you're telling me that
you didn't need me?
Sorry.
I love that.
I... I love that.
See? I told you.
Yes.
Fist bump to Okafor.
You got Bell to take
Donna to the OR?
I asked Nolan. Bell took over.
It was supposed to
be a simple procedure
to help with her pain and
get her back to hospice.
She didn't even
want a blood draw!
She was in pain,
and it was fixable.
I made the call.
She's about to go
into cardiac arrest.
- Are we coding her?
- Yes, we are.
No. No, she's DNR.
You got to let her go.
This isn't what she asked for.
- She's in cardiac arrest.
- Damn it!
A death in his OR
will go on Bell's stats.
He'll do anything to avoid that.
Get the defibrillator.
Dr. Bell, stop.
You have to stop.
Abductor pollicis,
flexor pollicis brevis...
Big exam?
Um, these hand muscles
are impossible to remember.
"All for one and one for all."
It's a mnemonic.
It helps.
Are you all right?
I always thought of
myself as a... a hero.
Saving lives.
I didn't even think about death.
Death is terrifying.
But here's the thing, Erik:
You're gonna see a lot of it.
Our job is to hold it
off as long as possible
while never losing
sight of the fact
that it is a
natural part of life.
His temperature's 105.
He's tachycardic
and hypertensive.
End tidal CO2 is high.
The urine in his Foley,
it's the color of cola.
Hey, what's going on?
His fever shot up.
His heart rate is sky high.
His limbs are rigid.
Sounds like a drug reaction.
- What have we given him?
- I'm checking right now.
Epinephrine, heparin,
succinylcholine...
Stop. That's it. He was
given succs in the ER.
His temp was so
low it probably caused
his metabolism to
dramatically slow.
So, once he warmed up in the OR,
he started to
metabolize the drug,
causing this rare reaction.
Malignant hyperthermia.
He's literally gone from
dying by being too cold
to dying by being too hot.
Well, let's treat
him with dantrolene.
That helps, but the problem is,
we need to get his
temperature down quick.
More snow.
Looks like you did
come to the rescue.
Got it?
His temperature is 105.
Hurry it up, people.
Pack the snow all
around his body.
Hey, how can we help?
Hey, more troops.
We're building a snow
angel. Why don't you pitch in.
Let's hope this works.
- You guys good?
- Yeah.
Her blood cultures came
back. Her catheter was infected.
Conrad was right.
I need a new one placed,
but for now, I'll finish
the course of
antibiotics you started.
That'll take care of it.
Well, thanks for checking in.
Okay, are you gonna say it,
- or are you gonna
make me say it?
- Say what?
Nic, the man with
the hair and the eyes...
he wants you.
Maybe you should
worry about your kidneys.
I am, but my
kidneys are so boring
compared to your love life.
Come on, tell me.
Spill. What's going on?
Look, I... I need Alec.
The clinic needs Alec.
The patients need Alec.
You're using him.
I'm being pragmatic.
Totally. I'm impressed.
Hey, if you're into
the hair and the eyes,
I can totally send
him your direction.
Oh, yeah. Nothing turns a guy on
like getting to second
base with a girl's catheter.
She's off the vent.
Off pressors.
Breathing on her own.
Vitals are stable.
Donna.
Hey.
- I am so happy you're awake.
- Ah.
Look who's doing great.
What happened?
You had a strangulated
hernia, and surgery
was the only way to keep
you from dying in the hospital.
We took a chance.
Been so worried we
did the wrong thing.
Well, you kind of did.
It might have been easier
if I just never woke up.
But I know you
were only trying to do
what you thought
was right for me.
I do respect that.
Besides, now I get
to go to hospice,
see Bob again.
You just saying that
to make me feel better?
Mm, maybe.
Well... maybe not.
Ah, sun's rising,
the storm's over, so...
we can get you to hospice now.
Not yet.
Donna has a visitor.
Oh.
How is he?
Still unconscious, but
his vitals are stable.
If he wakes up, he
could have brain damage.
Look, you guys
did all you could.
But did we do too much?
We had to try... For
him and his children.
Mr. Garcia?
I am Dr. Okafor. You're at
Chastain Memorial Hospital.
You were in an accident,
but you're all right.
Don't worry, we'll remove
the breathing tube. Okay?
Eva and Eli are fine.
They can't wait to see you.
♪ ♪
Good morning.
Morning.
How's my dad?
How about we go see him?
Thank you.
All right, come on. Let's go.
Here we are.
EVA and ELI: Daddy!
It's okay now.
We're okay.
Thank you.
For taking good care of them.
You bet.
Daddy...
You never had kids, right?
No. Not to my knowledge.
I got to wash up. Why
are kids always so sticky?
It's mostly snot,
and a bit of saliva.
- Some sugar.
- It-it was a rhetorical
question.
Robert Tuttle?
Call me Bob.
And what's your
name, pretty lady?
Uh, Nurse Practitioner Nevin.
- Ah.
- Donna's very eager to see you.
Apparently, it's
been a long time.
30 years.
I almost leaped out of my
pants when she reached out.
Donna was my first real love.
She was...
- She was quite a beauty.
- Mm.
I, uh... I guess we're
both in for a bit of a shock.
But I'm prepared for anything.
- I'm a romantic at heart.
- Mm.
I, uh, can't believe
we have the chance
to say a decent good-bye.
Would you look at that.
She's playing our song.
♪ I took my love,
took it down... ♪
You look great, honey.
Oh, you're still a liar.
I look like death,
which is appropriate.
Same old Donna.
Oh... when we first
met, I was so happy.
Then you left me.
Destroyed me.
You broke my heart, and...
you caused me so much pain.
For 30 years, I've needed
to say something to you, Bob.
Something I should
have said long before.
♪ Can I handle the
seasons of my life? ♪
Go to hell.
♪ Well, I've been afraid
of changing 'cause I've... ♪
That's what she wanted to say?
Yep.
Glad she got to say it.
Do you still think I was wrong?
♪ Even children get older... ♪
Ah, seems to me
we were both wrong.
Well, we got through it.
You're right.
I don't want us to regret
the things we haven't said.
Me, either.
There's still a lot we
need to talk about.
After a fight, it's
easier to let it go.
- Yeah.
- Not talk about it.
The same issues keep
coming up over and over again.
♪ 'Cause I've built
my life around you... ♪
It's been a long night.
♪ Even children get older... ♪
Yes.
So, not now.
Tomorrow? My place?
I'll swing by before work.
Perfect.
♪ The landslide
will bring you down ♪
I love you.
♪ And if you see my reflection ♪
I love you, too.
♪ In the snow-covered hills ♪
♪ Well, the landslide
will bring you down ♪
♪ Oh, the landslide ♪
♪ Will bring it down. ♪
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH