I heard you and 2.0 are
a match made in heaven.
Well, it's a remarkable advancement.
Need an OR.
2.0 is open.
Better imaging's available.
Emergent trauma is not the time
to play with your fancy toy.
Things haven't been great
between Ben and I.
I know it must be hard
not having him around.
Ben?
Sorry it took me so long.
I probably shot up,
like, a half dozen times
during my first trimester.
Going cold turkey is really hard.
I don't want anyone taking my baby away.
Hello?
Hey. No, no, no, no.
Hey. What did I tell you?
Day or night. Doesn't matter.
What's going on?
You... you're having an urge to use?
Uh-huh.
OK. Can you get yourself to Med?
I can pick you up.
OK, great.
OK. I'll meet you in the ED.
Wow.
So Ben moved back home?
End of last week.
Wow. I'm so glad to hear that.
It was like this huge cloud
has just lifted.
I'll bet.
Thanks for being a shoulder
throughout all this, Sharon.
Always.
The result of over a decade's worth
of testing and research,
here at Gaffney Chicago Medical Center.
They're doing infomercials for 2.0 now?
Jack Dayton insisted.
But I have a budget meeting to get to,
so enjoy the show.
I will.
Predict complications
before they happen,
generate highly accurate
imaging in real time.
The OR 2.0 is to surgery
what GPS was to travel.
Nitrazine swab.
I've noticed more discharge.
And the baby doesn't seem
to be moving around as much.
She usually kicks up a storm.
I told Hannah that she's
gonna be a flamenco dancer.
So you two know each other?
Yeah, we go to the same gym.
OK.
- So your water broke, Liza.
- What?
But I'm not due for, like, another week.
You see this?
When this touches
amniotic fluid, it turns blue.
That also explains why you
stopped feeling much movement.
After your water breaks,
the baby has less room to wiggle around.
- Is she gonna be OK?
- Yes.
This just means we need
to get you upstairs
and give you medicine to induce labor.
Can you let L&D know Liza's coming up
and page Dr. Patchefsky?
- Sure thing.
- Thanks.
- Dr. Patchefsky?
- Mm-hmm.
No, no, no. I-I want you.
Well, Liza, I'm sorry,
but unfortunately,
I need to stay in the ED.
But hey, Dr. Patchefsky's
gonna take great care
of you and the baby.
You know me, Hannah.
You know my history.
I don't feel comfortable
with anybody else.
Please.
I can't do this without you.
OK.
Let me see what I can figure out.
- Dr. Marcel?
- Yeah?
There's the movie star.
- Oh, come on now.
- Oh!
Can I get your autograph?
- Jack roped me into it.
- Sure he did.
Need some help over here!
Hey. What happened?
Rob here, he was working
a circular saw, and...
He was slicing some sheet metal.
- He cut himself.
- Follow me.
Number three's open.
- How long ago did this happen?
- Not exactly sure.
I found Rob by the machine
about 20 minutes ago.
He was just lying in a pool
- of his own blood.
- Let's get him up.
We were working at a job site
around the corner.
We just thought it'd be fastest
to bring him ourselves.
- OK. Mag?
- Yes. Gentlemen.
Why don't I show you
where the waiting room is at?
Dr. Marcel will update you
as soon as possible.
Wait, wait. What do I do with this?
- Dr. Marcel?
- Yeah?
We do the right thing?
Thought you're supposed
to put it on ice.
Yes, you did the right thing.
Thank you.
Thank you, gentlemen.
It's OK. I got you, bud.
- Synced and corrected by synk -
- www.addic7ed.com -
Liza doesn't have a primary OB
but I've seen her in the ED
throughout her pregnancy
for various complaints.
Doris, room seven.
There's a hypochondriac with a hangnail.
- So get an intern on it?
- Yeah, read my mind.
Dr. Hudgins, you're needed
in treatment seven.
I'm sorry. You were saying?
My patient, Liza Martin,
doesn't have a primary OB.
OK. Yeah, I heard all this.
What's the ask?
I'd like to follow her
upstairs and deliver her.
You're my only OB in the ED.
I can come back and forth
while she's in early labor.
And I'm also just an elevator ride away
in case something urgent comes up.
But I'm Liza's only continuity, so...
You know, she's comfortable with me.
We go back a ways.
Yeah. OK, go ahead.
- Really?
- Yeah, just don't dillydally.
Yes, sir.
As you know, we have a seat
opening up on the board.
Oh. Did you get a chance
to review my nominee?
I sent her CV around.
Sorry. Remind me the candidate's...
Gloria Jeffers.
She's chaired the fundraising
committee for eight years.
She volunteers here regularly.
She brings a lot of donors to Med.
Oh, well, sounds like
a strong candidate.
She is.
Now, are you familiar
with Dr. George Thomas?
Well, the name rings a bell,
but I'm not placing it right offhand.
Well, George is a close friend,
a renowned urologist,
and a former Wisconsin state legislator.
Now, he's mostly retired
but still lobbies for some
biotech companies part-time.
I think that his connections
could be very advantageous for us.
While my nominee is just
simply a devoted volunteer?
Look, Sharon, I'm not gonna try
to make you into a turncoat,
but take a lunch with George?
Um, of course.
Just give his information
to my assistant,
and we'll get something on the books.
Well, I hope you don't mind,
but I already took the liberty
of talking with your assistant,
and it turns out
you're free for lunch today.
What are you saying?
And as luck would have it, so is George.
Is that right?
1:00 in the executive dining room?
And I assume you'll be joining us?
Oh, listen, I wish I could,
but I am slammed with meetings today.
I'll be sure to check in
afterwards, though.
You know, Sharon,
I really think you two
are gonna hit it off.
You just hang in there.
And I'll get you an update soon, OK?
All right.
That was Rob's wife, Louisa.
Was getting her up to speed.
What are the odds
that he'll keep his hand?
Not good.
Immediate replantation is impossible.
Too much contamination?
Yeah, well, the proximal stump's
gonna need at least a week
of daily debridement
just to get it cleaned up.
- Real shame too.
- What do you mean?
'Cause the hand's actually in
good shape, all things considered.
I'll bet it's salvageable.
Maximum six hours
without blood flow, and...
Hand's gonna die.
Yeah.
But what about putting it
on a perfusion pump,
like you would with a heart and lungs?
Well, it's a good thought, but...
that won't buy us more than a day.
If only we could find a way
to perfuse the hand long-term.
Well, but like you said, it's a shame.
Jackie, going to treatment four.
Got it. This is Isaac Collins.
53-year-old male.
Motor vehicle collision.
Ambulatory at the scene,
refused board and collar.
- He was rear-ended.
- My fault, though.
Facial bruising's from the airbag.
I switched lanes without signaling,
then jammed on the brakes
to make a turn.
It was a bonehead move.
Luckily, the other guy's all right.
Glad to hear it.
I'm Dr. Halstead, by the way. Vitals?
Blood pressure's a little high, 150/97.
I'm always hypertensive,
especially when I'm due for dialysis.
I've got end-stage renal disease.
I appreciate you letting me know.
On my count, folks. One, two, three.
Thanks, guys.
I see you've got a fistula.
Yeah, I've been through a few of 'em.
Going on five years of dialysis.
- Dr. Cuevas.
- Isaac.
Dr. Jones told me the good news.
I was hoping I would see you
today, but not in the ED.
What happened?
She's my shrink.
I'm actually not, Isaac.
Do you mind if I disclose
to Dr. Halstead
how we know each other?
My wife, Samantha, and I
attend Dr. Cuevas's support group.
For patients and families
living with chronic illness.
Which, by tomorrow, won't be us anymore,
which leads me as to why
I was driving like a maniac.
I got the call.
I'm getting a new kidney.
Congratulations.
Anyways, you can see I couldn't wait
to get to the hospital fast enough.
But I'm fine.
Like I told the paramedics,
nothing feels broken.
Now, when you say nothing feels broken,
anything feel tender?
No, I'm good, really.
You know, Isaac,
when I spoke to Dr. Jones,
he said that the organ wouldn't
even be here for several hours.
There's no rush.
Why don't you let Dr. Halstead
check you out properly?
Neck and back's a little sore, I guess,
but it's really not that bad.
I just don't want anything
to mess up the surgery.
Well, even if you have
a sprain or a minor fracture,
it shouldn't postpone the transplant.
But better Dr. Jones
and his surgical team know.
That way, they can avoid
aggravating any injury further.
All right. Yeah, makes sense.
Let's get a CT of the CTLS spine.
- Sorry I keep you waiting.
- Mm.
- I was talking with my friend.
- No prob.
Chamomile tea, blueberry
muffin, chocolate croissant.
You're very sweet, but I can't eat.
My stomach is in knots.
What's up?
My friend thinks we may
be out of work very soon.
What?
Is this about your union's renegotiation
- with the hospital?
- Yeah.
Well, I knew they were
trying to iron out
a new contract, but I mean, honestly,
I haven't been paying
that close attention.
She says talks are breaking down,
that neither side will budge,
and the union may ask for a vote.
A strike authorization vote?
If I miss work for weeks, even for days,
this is not good.
I send money home to my parents.
But I mean, even if a vote passes,
that doesn't mean they're gonna strike.
It just gives them more ammunition
when they go back to the table.
These things, you know,
tend to take time.
You've got to let it play out.
I'm guessing they're gonna make a deal.
I think it's gonna be OK.
She just started having
fetal heart rate decelerations
with tetanic contractions.
I turned down the Pit.
Hannah, it hurts so much.
OK, stop the Pitocin.
Liza, we're gonna see
if it's time to push yet, OK?
Can you bend your knees for me?
I'm gonna check you out.
OK, you're only
about six centimeters dilated.
- What?
- We need to get you
onto your hands and knees
to let us help you
- turn you over, OK?
- What's going on?
What's wrong?
Your umbilical cord is
being squeezed somewhere.
That's what's causing
the baby's heart rate to drop.
Moving positions can help
relieve the compression.
I know. I know.
All right. I'm gonna check you out.
Uterus is still rock hard.
Let's give her
0.25 of terbutaline, sub-q.
Liza, you can lie back down now, OK?
- Gently.
- Gentle.
We're trying a uterine relaxant.
Now, if this doesn't work,
we're gonna need to deliver
your baby via C-section.
- Let's get an OR ready.
- No, I don't want that.
It's OK. Just one step at a time.
Let's first see
if this medicine works, OK?
Baby's heart rate's coming up.
That's really good.
Give it about a half hour,
and restart the Pitocin slowly.
- Mm-hmm.
- But let's keep an OR ready.
If the baby's heart rate
drops like that,
I'm doing an emergency C-section.
So you want
to surgically attach Rob's hand
to the back of his leg?
It's called ectopic banking.
You see, what the hand needs
in order to survive
is adequate blood flow.
And his leg can provide that?
The posterior tibial artery,
to be exact.
The PTA, it runs along
the back of the lower leg.
So you'd bank my hand
on my leg for a week or so?
That's right.
And then you'll reattach it
to my arm, right?
More than just reattach it.
Using the OR 2.0,
I believe that we can restore
a remarkable amount
of function and feeling.
So I can keep working construction?
Yeah.
I gotta be able to feel,
or I'm a liability
on a construction site.
Yeah, of course.
OK, so...
Well, 2.0's predictive modeling
estimated a...
85% likelihood of regaining some
or more sensation in the hand.
And that's after many, many months
of physical therapy and rehab.
Right, Dr. Marcel?
Maggie's correct.
Yeah, it's gonna be
a long road ahead, for sure.
And that's if you decide
to go with the surgery.
There's other options, of course.
There's been incredible
advancements in prosthetics.
And that's if this
banking thing doesn't work?
Then we can talk prosthetics.
But I want to give this a shot.
You've got this, Liza. Keep going.
Why isn't she coming?
Just do the C-section.
- It's too late for that.
- Please.
I know you're exhausted,
but you've got this, Liza.
So when I count to three, I need you
to give me everything you've got, OK?
This is it. Look at me.
One, two, three.
Yes! Yes!
You did it, Liza!
Is she OK?
Yes.
Oh, hi.
Isn't she beautiful?
She's perfect.
I think she needs something.
Can you check her again?
No, she's fine.
It's OK.
Crying helps the fluid
get out of her lungs.
- But she won't stop.
- It's OK.
The longer she's on your chest,
the more she'll calm down.
Please, just take her.
- It's a really good idea...
- Please just take her!
OK.
Here we go. OK.
I'm sorry.
I'm just... I'm so tired.
Of course. You just ran a marathon.
OK. We'll get the baby up to the nursery
and let you sleep a bit, OK?
It's OK, baby girl.
Just rest, OK?
Got Isaac's CT back.
He's got a compression fracture at L2.
Well, that's unfortunate.
But like you said, it won't
delay the transplant, right?
Well, take a look.
I could be wrong, but the bone
around the fracture has
a lytic appearance to me.
Do you think Isaac has cancer?
I think there's a possibility.
Lytic lesions are commonly
associated with metastases.
And if the bone was
already damaged from cancer,
well, even a minor trauma
could cause a fracture.
OK, but you're not sure
that it's lytic, right?
There's still a chance it could just be
a traumatic compression fracture?
Which is why I want to get an MRI.
It'll show us if there are other lesions
and just give us a better idea
if it's traumatic or pathological.
And if it is pathological,
that means a biopsy.
And Isaac is definitely
not getting a kidney today.
No.
I wish Samantha was here, his wife.
Where is she?
On a flight to Seattle for their
granddaughter's first birthday.
Isaac got tired of both of them
missing out on milestones.
But one time she goes out
of town, he gets the call.
You mind delivering the news with me?
In her absence, I think a familiar face
might be comforting.
- Yeah, of course.
- All right.
- Hey.
You got a second?
Yep.
OK, um...
Is this operation really worth the risk?
If anything compromises blood
flow to the hand or the foot,
Rob could develop an infection
and become septic.
The 2.0 will be assessing blood flow
every step of the surgery
as well as predicting
if perfusion can be maintained post-op.
OK, clearly, you know
this technology inside and out,
but it's also never been used
for this type of procedure.
So what are you saying?
What, I oversold Rob?
No, but I think that you've
got a lot invested in 2.0,
and maybe you feel
a certain pressure to use it.
I'm not gonna gamble
with a patient's life
just so I can show off
my shiny, new toy, Maggie.
Of course not.
- I'm just saying that...
- Crockett!
Here's the man I'm looking for.
Anything else?
I didn't mean
to chase Nurse Lockwood away.
No, she had to get back
to the ED. What's up?
Dr. Song briefed me
on the ectopic banking case.
- Very impressive.
- Yeah.
And my videographer's gonna film it.
We'll want to document it and
get as much press as possible.
Jack, I don't want anybody
in there taking pictures
while I'm in the middle
of a complex surgery.
You won't even know he's there.
I'll keep him out
of your way, I promise.
See you in the amphitheater?
- Yeah, right behind you.
- OK.
Hey.
Hey. Hope you're not
in any kind of hurry.
Elevators taking their sweet time today.
I am fine. I'm not exactly
anxious to get where I'm going.
Meeting with a friend of Jack's
whose seat on the board
is all but assured.
Oh, man, hospital politics.
- Yikes.
- Mm-hmm.
Speaking of which, what are you hearing
about what's going on
with the negotiations
with the custodial workers' union?
Liliana seems to think
they're getting all tense.
Between us, I don't foresee a strike.
- That's what I told her.
- Yeah.
A strike would wreak havoc
on the hospital system.
I gotta say, though,
it does make me wonder
why we can't give
our lowest paid employees,
I mean, even a 6% raise.
Well, it would be setting a precedent
that we can't afford to make
with the other unions, Daniel.
I mean, once we finish
with these negotiations,
we go into talks with the nurses' union.
And then, it's the plumbers' union.
I mean, you get the picture, right?
If I had just checked my blind spot,
we wouldn't be talking
about an MRI right now.
I'd be upstairs getting prepped
for surgery tonight, right?
- And that still might happen.
- Yeah, I'm sorry, Isaac.
I could not have predicted
the CT would reveal this.
Dr. Halstead,
I've waited five hellish years
for a kidney.
I've blown out so many veins,
they're running out
of access sites
to even deliver my dialysis.
If the fracture looks like
it's just from the accident...
Well, that's still a possibility, but...
Then that's good enough for me.
I'm not gonna fault you
for not running any more tests.
And no one else will either.
Please, I'm begging you.
Hey. I thought
you delivered your patient.
I did, yes.
Well, why are you still up here?
We need an OB consult in the ED.
OK, I can head back down
with you right now.
Just give me one sec to let Liza know.
OK.
Oh, hey.
Where's Liza?
Yeah, she, uh...
She had to use the bathroom.
I'm Mike. I'm her boyfriend.
It's not safe for her
to use the restroom alone.
She seemed all right to me.
Hey, Liza, it's Hannah. Are you OK?
- Give her a minute, will you?
- Get your hands off of me.
Get your hands off me!
Hey, you heard her!
Liza.
Help me get her back into bed.
OK. Watch your neck.
Support her head. Yeah, we got her.
You have no idea how hard
Liza worked to stay sober.
- You have no idea.
- Well, I don't doubt that.
But we just found her
strung out on heroin.
She was overwhelmed and exhausted
after a grueling labor and had
a serious lapse of judgment,
but I know that
she could get back on track.
Hold it. Wait,
you're not actually suggesting
that we send a baby home
with that woman?
No, of course not.
I want to find a sober
living situation for Liza,
a facility where she could
still receive treatment
while still caring for her baby.
You are swerving so far out your lane,
not to mention that you are
mandated to report this...
- No, not until...
- To, yes,
- the appropriate department.
- Not until I figure out
a way to keep Liza
and her baby together.
Then you let DCFS take care of it.
- They're far better equipped.
- What if they can't, huh?
Liza doesn't have family in the area.
Who's gonna take the baby?
Obviously, you care
a great deal about her.
Because I am her. I have been her.
And the only reason that
I'm standing here right now
is because people didn't give up on me.
So I am not giving up on Liza.
You have till the end of the day.
OK.
Dr. Song, what's the recommendation
for anastomosis?
Any deviations from the plan?
End to end ulnar to posterior
tibial artery anastomosis.
OK. What's the venous drainage?
Anastomose the main dorsal
vein to the saphenous vein.
OK, great.
Whoever that belongs to,
turn it off right now.
Sorry, that's me. It's my next meeting.
This is Jack Dayton. Great. Well...
Do you mind moving
to the right just a hair?
It'll give me a much cleaner shot.
No, that's where he needs to stand.
Let's keep noise down to a minimum
from here on out, folks.
In terms of speed and efficiency,
you're already performing above
and beyond 2.0's predictions.
We're on a good trajectory.
All right.
Let's say we forgo the MRI.
He gets the transplant.
If it turns out he does have cancer,
the immunosuppressants he'll be on
could interfere
with his cancer treatment.
And the treatment itself
could destroy his new kidney.
Valid concerns, yes.
But a malignancy of any kind
is a contraindication
for transplantation.
He'll be taken off the transplant list.
Right, which is...
All the more reason
to look the other way?
I have an ethical and legal obligation
to disclose this finding.
I fail to do that,
it could compromise our status
as a high volume transplant center.
I know it's a risk,
but, Will,
this could be
Isaac's only shot at a kidney.
I hear you. I know.
But it'd be irresponsible
to let the transplant proceed
until we know more.
I'm sorry, Nellie.
What, did Jack steamroll you
into having lunch with me?
What? No. No, not at all.
Jack's a good friend,
but when he wants something,
he can be like a dog after a bone.
Yeah, well, that has
been my impression as well.
Yeah, but in his defense,
he's trying to do me a solid
'cause he knows how eager
I want to be a part of Med's board.
Well, I'm curious.
How did a former legislator
turned lobbyist become...
Girl, what did he do,
tell you about my whole side hustle?
Look.
That's what my daughter calls it.
- Mm.
- Listen.
I'm not trying
to be a part of your board
so I can be a mouthpiece for
some special interest groups.
So why do you want to be on the board?
To start with,
I was born in this hospital.
- Get out. You're kidding.
- No, ma'am.
I'ma be honest with you,
my very first broken arm
was fixed right within these walls.
So this is a homecoming of sorts?
Well, my ex-wife was
a professor at UW Milwaukee.
We raised the family there.
But Chicago's home.
And this hospital has always held
a very special place in my heart.
I'd love to be a part of its future.
But I should warn you,
I'm not one of those board members
that's only gonna show up
at special fancy parties,
cut a check,
and is never heard from again.
Yes, I know that type as well.
I got a lot of time on my hands.
And I also have a lot of ideas.
I'm all ears.
Oh, hey, Hannah. I'm glad I caught you.
Would you mind pointing me
to one of your patients?
It's a Liza... sorry.
Um, I think that there's been a mix-up.
I didn't make a call to DCFS.
Well, I actually wasn't told
who made the call,
just that an eval was requested.
Oh, well, that's definitely an error.
Oh? OK.
I'm sorry you had to come down.
I'm the treating physician,
and that patient
doesn't need an evaluation.
Uh, OK.
Well, in that case,
I guess I'll just head back up
to my office.
Yeah.
What were
the patient's vitals on intake?
Let me check.
Well, you should have this
on the tip of your tongue.
Hey, I told you I was working on it.
You had no right to make that call.
Give us the room, please.
I'll check back later, yeah.
OK, you do not dress me down ever,
and definitely
not in front of a resident.
I repeat, you had no right
to make that call.
The hell are you talking about?
You called DCFS on Liza.
No, I did not.
Hannah, I'm serious!
Well, then who did?
OK. I'm gonna remove the clamp.
Nice and easy. OK.
Clamp out.
Yeah, the ulnar side's
showing some good perfusion.
But yeah, there's not enough circulation
through the palmar arch.
And the radial side's
looking dusky to me.
Could we hook in
the radial artery to something,
give it independent inflow?
I'll have 2.0 run
through the iterations.
It's assessing a number of variables.
It probably just needs a minute.
Not enough information.
Confidence interval is too low.
I think it just needs better
mapping of the radial artery
in the palmar arch.
Let me see if I can recalibrate imaging.
Not enough information.
Confidence interval is too low.
Unfortunately, the
real-time data is insufficient.
And the pre-op imaging is inadequate.
What other artery am I gonna use
to plug into the radial?
Without adequate blood flow,
the hand's not gonna survive.
I'm afraid 2.0 doesn't have enough data
to offer recommendation.
There's just not enough
published literature to draw from.
So what am I supposed to do here?
Use your best critical judgment.
Oh.
Of course.
I'm not getting the MRI,
not till after the transplant.
How about that? I refuse.
Dr. Jones won't proceed with the surgery
until he sees the results of an MRI.
You had no right to tell him anything.
Isaac, I had an ethical duty
to notify your transplant surgeon...
I should have just stuck to my story
and told you I felt fine.
Never should have mentioned any pain.
Isaac, I know this is upsetting...
Just do the damn MRI already!
Get me Dr. Jones!
OK, he'll be here shortly.
I'll put in the order.
So you requested DCFS be called?
Liza, why?
When I held my little girl
for the first time,
I could feel her depending on me,
needing me for everything.
I couldn't take it.
I broke.
Liza...
These last few months have
been the hardest of my life.
And it took everything in me
to stay sober,
but I did it for her.
And now, I just...
I can't muscle my way through this.
OK, I've been there.
Every time I got sober
for someone else...
A family member, a partner...
It lasted a year at the most.
Every time, I'd relapse.
It finally stuck
when I got sober for myself.
Care for dessert?
Coffee or espresso?
No, thanks.
None for me. Thank you.
Oh, my goodness. It's almost 3:00.
I really hate to cut this off,
but unfortunately...
The place won't run itself.
Not yet, although Jack is working on it.
Yeah, I imagine he would be.
Well, this has been quite
a productive conversation.
Well, you know, we can always
continue the conversation.
Should you join the board? Thank you.
Is that your more subtle way
of asking if I'm gonna
support your nomination?
No, ma'am.
That's my very unsubtle way
of asking you
if you'll join me for drinks tonight.
Oh.
Well, that's a very tempting idea,
but, um, I'm gonna have to...
Politely decline.
Politely.
Well, I appreciate you considering it.
I hope the rest of your day
goes easy on you.
And the same for you, Dr. Thomas.
Ah, ah. George.
Sharon.
- You're back.
- I am.
And I could use your expertise.
Tell me.
How do you calm your nerves
when your heart is beating very fast?
Well, the first thing you do
is you sit down.
And, um, just take
a couple deep breaths,
and well, tell me what's going on.
I'm nervous because I'm going to speak
with a reporter from "Tribune" tomorrow.
Our union boss, Mr. Wilson,
he's meeting me to prepare.
Wow. How did that come about?
You remember my friend
I was telling you about
- from this morning?
- Yeah.
She's, uh, told Mr. Wilson about me.
And he asked me to go on record
for a story the newspaper is writing
about the negotiations,
what's at stake for us.
I wonder if that's
really the best tactic
for the union to take right now,
to talk to the press while
negotiations are still ongoing.
I mean, it could be seen
as a bad faith move.
And honestly, Liliana,
I would be worried
about possible
personal repercussions for you.
Yeah, that's what I thought first too,
that it would fan flames,
- cause more harm than good.
- Exactly.
But my friend, she tells me
Mr. Wilson tells her this:
the hospital is flying in workers
from all over to replace us.
They're flying in scabs?
They're putting them
in hotels and everything.
That's why I said I would go on record.
- Hey, Sharon.
- Yeah?
George has been blowing up my phone.
He was eager before, but now he's ready
to go to the mat for this board seat.
Well, I will say he's
a very appealing candidate.
I still think Gloria Jeffers
would make an exceptional board member,
but I'm glad you brought
Dr. Thomas to my attention.
So you'll support his candidacy?
- I won't challenge it.
- Mm.
You know, not to gloat,
but, um, I told you, didn't I?
Sounds like gloating to me.
Sharon, hospital's negotiating
with scare tactics now?
- They're flying in scabs?
- Yeah.
I don't like it either,
but it's also a necessary precaution.
Did you know about this when
we were talking this morning?
I mean, I thought you told me
that the negotiation was going well.
No, what I said was
that I didn't foresee a strike.
But look, we still have to be prepared
for the possibility
of a work stoppage, Daniel.
I mean, anything less is negligence.
What I'd say to the board is I'd say,
look, isn't a 6% bump for a custodian
a fraction of what it would be
for a nurses?
Daniel, I don't ever tell you
how to do your job.
And I'm not telling you how to do yours.
I'm telling you people are scared
'cause they can't afford
to miss a paycheck.
Yeah, and that's the last thing I want.
That's why I'm trying
to do everything in my power
to avert a strike.
I can't give you all of the details.
I expect you, of all people,
to trust that.
Get the MRI back?
Yes, and it showed evidence
of a pathological fracture.
When are they doing the biopsy?
Tomorrow morning,
but Dr. Jones ordered an SPEP
and a UPEP after he saw the MRI,
and both blood tests came back positive.
Multiple myeloma.
In all likelihood, yes.
Isaac hasn't been told yet.
Dr. Jones wanted to wait
until it was confirmed by the biopsy.
Just this morning, Isaac
thought his luck was changing,
he was finally getting a new kidney.
And now,
he's potentially facing
a terminal cancer.
Or maybe not.
Maybe, thanks to your
diligence, we caught it early.
Maybe that MRI just saved his life.
- Hey.
- I spoke to Dr. Song.
She said the surgery went well
and Rob's hand has excellent
blood flow and venous return.
Yeah, things are looking all right.
I had a moment in there.
It's like I didn't know
how to trust my own judgment,
mostly 'cause I haven't
needed to in some time.
I'd just ask 2.0.
That's the price we pay
for ease and convenience.
I suppose.
Marilyn has been fostering newborns
for over five years,
ever since she retired.
So you have a lot of experience then?
I do.
And, Liza, like we talked about,
the goal is reunification, always,
so soon as you finish
the treatment program,
we'll reassess things.
All right.
OK.
Do you have a name picked out?
Yeah, it's Hannah.
Hey, Dr. Song.
Glad I caught you.
I wanted to let you know
you can sleep in tomorrow.
What happened to the exploratory lab
we had scheduled for 8:00 a.m.?
Yeah, it's still on the docket.
I just moved it to a normal OR.
If this is about what happened today...
It's not. I mean, it is,
but not because
I lost any confidence in 2.0.
OK.
You ever turn off the GPS
while you're driving
just to see if you still know the roads?
No, never.
Fair enough.
Me, I need to do that from time to time.
For my own confidence.
If you change your mind,
it takes a double shot
of espresso, and I am up.
Good to know.
- Good night.
Daniel, wait.
Oh, no. Oh, no.
No, I didn't want to interrupt.
No. No, no, no, it's OK.
Good you're here, actually.
How's the... How's the prep going?
OK, I think.
Mr. Wilson was asking if
I know any doctors at hospital
who would be willing to speak out.
How do you mean?
For newspaper article.
Talk to reporters, share why
you support us, our demands.
Because for me, that would be a
violation of my employment contract.
I'm not allowed to...
To speak the media without
talking to the hospital first.
Mr. Wilson said
you don't have to go on record.
Um, you would just...
We'd just say your department.
No names.
Liliana, I would love to help,
but I mean, I just think
that people would...
You know, they'd connect
the dots pretty quickly.
Don't you think?
I understand. It's OK.
Really?
You know how much I support you.
You don't have to explain.
I'll, uh, call you later?
Sure. OK.
- Synced and corrected by synk -
- www.addic7ed.com -