E. R.
Previously on E. R.
So what is my position here?
You have no position here, Peter.
- You're firing me?
- No, no, no, no.
You fired yourself.
- We're short on nurses.
- I'm an OB nurse.
- Are you planning on going back to med school?
- Yes.
Ok, then you might as well work
as a nurse in the ER.
You'll see more medicine down here
than upstairs.
Listen, if you need anything...
...talk about a case
or a patient or anything...
- ...just come find me.
- I will.
You could be a great doctor.
Oh, my God! I'm sorry.
You're an excellent surgeon, Peter.
And you're a good man,
and we'll work it out.
E. R. 7x04 "BENTON BACKWARDS"
I could come in for another interview.
As a matter of fact,
I could come in this morning.
Yes, I know.
But you said you were interested.
Actually, you said
you were very interested.
Right. But if you could just-
Right, right, right. Thank you.
- Want some breakfast?
- No.
- Going over applications?
- Yep.
I thought you took
the position at Loyola.
- Withdrawn.
- Why?
I don't know, Cleo. Maybe because I
took another job somewhere else.
- Have you tried Northwestern?
- Fully staffed.
- U. of C.?
- What do you think?
Right now, I think you're being an ass.
You barely say anything.
And when you do, it's rude.
- I talk to you, Cleo.
- Not about this.
- Why don't you let me help, Peter?
- I don't need your help. I need a job.
I should have left County
when I had a chance.
- Out for fresh air?
- Man found down. ETA is any minute.
- They're letting you work on traumas.
- If I only handle two patients at a time.
- Really?
- Weaver's rules.
- Play by them or die by them.
- Thanks.
She didn't exactly ask me
if I wanted to be assigned to the ER.
What are you supposed to do
while you wait for labs?
- Catch up on medical journals.
- That sucks.
Showtime.
- You with me on this one?
- Male, 50, found in the park. Full arrest.
- That's one well-fed bum.
- How'd you load him?
- Paid a bunch of his buddies 5 bucks.
- Come on. Let's go. One, two, three.
Large lac to the occipital scalp. Not sure
if he was rolled or fell out of his tree.
- What's he doing in a tree?
- Maybe he lived in it.
Why didn't you intubate him?
His neck's like a power pole.
We couldn't find the cords.
It was 40 degrees last night.
He's hypothermic.
- We might still get him back.
- With what, a blowtorch?
Active core rewarming.
Set up for pleural and peritoneal lavage.
All right, I'm in. Bag him.
Who's got scissors?
Good air bilaterally. So, Carter,
you know anyone who plays hockey?
- No.
- Get me some warm blankets.
- I need an extra guy for a game tonight.
- I'm busy.
- I was asking if you knew anyone.
- Okay. Looks like we're in fine V-fib.
- Core temp is 86.
- So is his pulse ox.
- Charge the paddles to 360.
- Why? He's a frozen dinner.
Put two chest tubes in on the right. Run
warm saline through the rapid infuser.
- You're kidding.
- He's not dead until he's warm and dead.
- I'll prep the chest. 32 French okay?
- Yeah. Okay, everybody clear.
- What the hell?
- Where did all the pigeons come from?
Give me an amp of epi.
All right. Charge again. Clear.
- They must have been in his coat.
- They're attacking.
Still in V-fib.
Damn it! Get over here and do CPR!
Charging to 360.
Do CPR? The guy's brain-dead.
Not until I say so. Clear.
E. R.
A bunch of beauty contestants were
in the salon getting final touches.
A worker mixed the wrong
chemicals, and boom!
- Who's the worst?
- That'd be Audrey Hoffman, Miss Skokie.
Lacerations and partial-thickness
burns on her legs, and smoke inhalation.
- Hi, Audrey. I'm Dr. Greene.
- My legs. Are they bad?
I'm gonna check your breathing first.
Can you lean forward?
- Any shortness of breath?
- No.
- Uh-huh. Any chest pain?
- Not really.
Miss Tri-State is tonight.
Is it bad?
Well, nothing that won't heal.
- Does this mean that I'm out?
- We're gonna do everything we can.
- What's your talent?
- Rhythmic dancing.
With hoops and ribbons.
Malik, how many times you gonna
pass by with the same cart?
- I got a spot on my hockey team.
- Do I look like I play hockey?
What about your pal in Cards?
Big East-Indian dude.
I can skate. I played in college,
if you're in a pinch.
Yeah, yeah. Sure thing.
Dr. Chen. Cute guy, Curtain 3,
daddy material. Just say thanks, okay?
- Malucci, wait-
- Chen!
- What?
- Your mother's been holding 10 minutes.
Not very pleasantly, I might add.
Just tell her I'm with a patient.
Thank you.
Lying might be part of your
job description. It's not part of mine.
Yeah. Hello, Mommy.
Well, I've been busy.
Morning, Dr. Weaver.
- Frank, any messages?
- Yeah. Quite a few.
- Thank you.
- Power meeting today?
I have a seminar
that I do not have time for.
Could you remind me
to leave by 6, please?
- Seemed like a good idea at the time.
- Super glue.
- I hope that's one of two.
- The bird man still dead?
It's one of one.
Are there any traumas coming in?
No. But I've got a guy in Exam 3
who cut his hand on a tin can.
Dr. Gottschalk, you have a minute?
Unfortunately, I'm on my way
to a conference and I'm very late.
I'll make this quick. I'd like to discuss
with you the faculty position here.
- I really have to go.
- I just need a minute.
I apologize for bothering
you like this, but-
After you turned us down,
we offered it to someone else.
- Has it been accepted?
- Well, not officially.
- Then you can withdraw it.
- Our candidate has excellent credentials.
- So do I.
- And he has positive recommendations.
And I don't?
I'm not at liberty to discuss
your current standing.
- Which means Romano said something?
- I can't get into this.
- What did he tell you?
- Dr. Benton-
No. I need to know what that man said
and who he said it to.
You may have difficulty finding work
locally. That's all I can say. I'm sorry.
- It's 1100 hours.
- Excuse me?
I need to ship out.
Okay. Sir, if you're waiting
for a transfer to another facility...
...why don't we have a nurse help you.
- We're taking Inchon!
- Inchon?
Korea. Huge battle, if memory serves.
- Sorry. He's a wanderer.
- What's his story?
72 years old, from the Golden Glen
Nursing Home. Altered mental status.
He became combative
and got punched in the nose.
History of dementia?
No. The military talk
started a few days ago.
- Anything on exam?
- His nose isn't broken.
But he has a low-grade temp
with no obvious signs of infection.
CBC, Chem-7 and UA.
If his pulse ox is low, get a chest film.
Damn tab busted off.
You ever think about
using a can opener?
Sure. But then what's the point
of having a tab?
I started digging
around the edges there.
It looks to me like you may need
a few stitches.
Of course, the tuna juice leaks out.
And it gets greasy all over.
And then, bam!
The knife goes right into my hand.
I'm going to do a regional block
to numb the area...
...around where I'm gonna be suturing.
Are you sure you've done this before?
Sorry. I need some I and D kits.
You might feel a little burning.
I'm going to the 8:00 tonight, Abby.
How about you?
I don't know. Maybe.
The exact same thing happened
when I tried...
...to open a milk carton
with a pair of scissors.
The bruises sort of sprang up overnight.
That's why I brought him in here.
He has Niemann-Pick's Type A.
I have some material here,
if you're not familiar.
Oh, no. That won't be necessary.
His liver and spleen are both enlarged.
That's from the sphingomyelin deposits
in both organs.
Well, a big spleen chews up platelets.
That's why he's bleeding.
- Is there anything we can do?
- We can make him more comfortable.
- I'll start him on some morphine.
- Would that make him unconscious?
Because I want him to be lucid
for as long as he can be.
It'll be a very small dose of medicine.
What about the spleen?
You said that's causing the problem.
Well, if it's taken out,
that might help stop the bleeding...
...but you do know
your son is end-stage?
Yes.
We'll get an ultrasound of his abdomen,
and I'll have a surgeon come take a look.
- Thank you.
- Okay. You're welcome.
Dr. Chen? I usually wait for labs
to come back before consulting Surgery.
He's got splenomegaly. Pretty clear case
of bleeding due to thrombocytopenia.
- I thought you said he was end-stage.
- It doesn't mean he can't have surgery.
I'd think about whether it's
appropriate at this point.
- Hi.
I need to get...
Thanks.
- Abby?
- Yeah.
- You have a feather.
- I have a...
We had these...
Thank you.
What?
I was just thinking...
I was just wondering, if you wanted,
maybe we could...
We could what?
Go out sometime.
Oh, you mean, like a date?
Yeah. That's sort of
what I was thinking.
Tonight?
Sure. Tonight works.
- Okay.
- See you then.
Romano.
- Peter, back for a visit? How are you?
- How the hell do you think I am?
Well, judging by your demeanor,
I'd say you were a tad dyspeptic.
- You've been trashing me all over town?
- Having trouble landing a job?
- Thanks to you.
- I'm offended.
You've made enemies
all over this hospital.
Why assume I'm the only one
saying negative-?
You're preventing me
from earning a living.
No, actually, I'm willing to help.
- What?
- Your personality sucks...
...but you don't have to prove
that you're a great surgeon.
Now, I am willing to offer you
a per diem position.
- Per diem?
- Yeah.
It has no benefits and even less stature,
but it's yours for the asking.
- You can kiss my ass.
- I take it that's a "no"?
You couldn't pay me enough to work
for you again, you arrogant little prick.
Fair enough. Just keep working
on those people skills, Peter.
- Labs are back on Mr. Mellonston.
- Good.
- Great color.
- Thanks.
UA's full of white cells. He's got
a rip-roaring urinary-tract infection.
Sorry I called you prematurely.
Always happens
with nursing-home patients.
Give an old guy a bad UTI, next thing
you know, he's General MacArthur.
I called the home, and they've
already given his bed away.
- Family members who can take him in?
- He's at the mercy of Social Services.
Hey, back to work! Get back to work!
Come on. Show's over.
Maybe not. He talks like a vet.
If he is one, he could qualify for the VA.
Yeah. That'll take days to process.
I know a caseworker at North Chicago
with pull. Maybe we can transfer today.
- Do you want me to call?
- Sure, if you think it can be done.
Anybody missing an old man
looking for brass cleaner?
He just walked into a pelvic exam.
Mr. Mellonston!
Mr. Mellonston?
- Kerry. Hold on.
- Peter, I thought you'd left us.
I could be talked
into coming down to the ER.
- As an Attending?
- As a liaison to Surgery.
As a resident you went out of your way
to take every procedure away from us.
If you had a surgeon teaching residents,
more procedures would stay here.
- How?
- I could expedite cases to the O. R.
We have surgical residents for that.
Could you tell me if there's
an elderly gentleman in there?
- Does 47 count?
- No. Thank you.
See, I could do scheduling and-
- God knows we could use the help.
- Kerry, hire me.
Look, I'd love to. Get Romano to pay
for it, you got yourself a job.
Trolling for work, Peter?
Dr. Chen. I'm interested to see what
required the interruption of my lunch.
As I explained on the phone,
splenomegaly and thrombocytopenia.
- So you'll operate?
- Well... no.
I would if he didn't have Niemann-Pick's.
Snow him and wait.
We can't just let him
slowly bleed to death.
It's a terminal disease. Surgery will
only slightly delay the inevitable.
If the surgery were successful, then the
family would have more time with him.
And if wishes were horses,
we'd all be knee-deep in crap.
I didn't become a surgeon
to torture dying children.
- Let the boy die in peace.
- But the mother wants it.
No surgery, Dr. Chen.
- What the hell is this?
- Explosion at a hair salon.
Sad cultural commentary, isn't it?
Pursuit of beauty at all costs.
Nice legs, though.
There you go.
- Oh, God! What am I going to do?
- It probably won't scar.
But they look hideous.
I can't go on stage like this.
- Can you wear pants?
- Not in the swimsuit competition.
You know, you probably think
this is so stupid.
I'm just trying to win a scholarship.
I'm premed.
I can give you something
for the pain if you'd like.
It's okay.
They look worse than they feel.
Okay. Excuse me.
Can you get ahold of Miss Pruitt
at Abbott and Sons?
- Oh, yeah. Miss Pruitt. You mean that-
- Don't ask. Just do it.
Hey, Dave? Did you find anybody yet?
- For what?
- For hockey tonight.
Yeah. A friend of mine. He might sign on.
Former pro, just looking for exercise.
Oh, okay.
- It's a rough game we play, actually-
- So you don't think I can handle it.
- I didn't say that.
- I used to play varsity, second line.
Well, if he can't make it, I'll call you.
Type and cross for four. Start two units
of O-neg on the rapid infuser.
- What happened?
- Multiple GSWs, one to the chest.
Looks like a hemopneumothorax.
Five hundred cc's out.
- Lost the pulse. Starting compressions.
- We need to crack her chest.
Right-sided GSW's an indication
for the sternal saw. Can I do it?
Next time, Carter. 10 blade.
Hold CPR.
Sternal saw.
- She needs a central line.
- I'll do it.
Mr. Mellonston?
Mr. Mellonston.
He said he lost his razor on Old Baldy,
wanted to borrow mine.
Gil didn't really need it though.
All he had was peach fuzz.
I'm sorry. I don't understand.
A mortar shell took his head off.
Why don't we take you back
to your bed so you can rest, okay?
Here we go.
- You've seen war, haven't you?
- Actually, no. I have not.
But you've seen men die.
Yes.
Mr. Mellonston, I'm afraid I have
some rather unfortunate news.
You've lost your bed
at the nursing home.
But we've already called the VA
to see if we can find a placement.
- They won't take me!
- I'm sure that you qualify.
- I won't go there!
- Please try-
- I can't go there! I won't!
- Calm down. We're only trying to help.
- Malik! Malik, come over-!
No, please!
Don't let them take me!
Don't let them take me away.
Please.
His nose stopped bleeding.
What'd you find out?
Well, the surgeon feels that it's
too great a risk to operate on Kenneth.
But he's suffering.
Can't you see that?
Ms. Stein,
Kenneth is barely conscious.
That's not true! He squeezes my hand.
He understands me.
That means everything that
can be done should be done.
Yes. But there's a good chance that
Kenneth won't survive the operation.
I know what you're thinking.
I'm selfish.
I'm keeping my son alive for me,
not him.
- Ms. Stein, I'm not thinking-
- He's my child.
I want every minute I can with him.
Wait till you're a mother,
then you'll know.
Get him the surgery.
Looks like a small-caliber GSW
to the right ventricle.
Okay. That should do it.
- Heart's not filling.
- She's had five units.
- We need more volume.
- Prep the paddles.
Can't shock an empty heart.
You'll never get her back.
- Run in another two units.
- Give me some 0 silk.
- Hold compressions.
- What are you doing, Carter?
Beck's suture.
All right. Keep traction on that.
I'll check the back side of the heart.
What do you see?
Exit wound in the left ventricle.
Give me 2-0 silk.
- I can repair it.
- Not from that side.
I have a better angle here.
I saw blood welling up behind the heart.
I thought there might be another hole.
- Okay.
- Charge to 20.
Okay, now cut it.
Clear.
Still V-fib.
Okay. Charge to 30. Clear.
Got a rhythm. Sinus tach.
- Got a pulse.
- Nice job, Carter.
Notify the O.R. She's got
a septal defect they need to repair.
Dr. Kovac, Mrs. Danzer's having more
chest pain, dropped her pressure to 90.
I'll be right there.
Are you gonna take her up?
Sterile saline dressings
and hang the FFP.
- Great save, Carter. Very slick.
- Thanks.
- Ativan?
- Yeah, point 5. He's pretty subdued.
- Did you hear from the VA?
- There's good news and bad news.
I found Mr. Mellonston a bed.
But it's in a brig. He's AWOL.
AWOL? From where?
Korean War. 1951, Army corporal.
Deserted on leave.
Unfortunately, my VA contact took it
upon himself to notify the active military.
Why would they care about someone
who deserted 50 years ago?
Who knows? They may want
to slap him on the wrist.
- They may want to court-martial him.
- For God's sake! He's 72 years old.
I know.
- Is there anything we can do?
- Legally? No.
Peter, what are you doing here?
Did you get any of my messages?
Yes. And I meant to call you.
I've just been incredibly busy.
I just didn't know what to say.
Yeah. Well, it's okay.
No. No, it's not okay.
I've been avoiding you for days.
Yeah. I got that.
I'm sorry. What Robert did was wrong.
And I've told him as much.
I just wish there was
something I could do.
Well, I didn't exactly expect you
to resign in protest.
That's a relief.
There is something you can do.
You can put the word out.
I know you've got a lot of contacts
at other hospitals.
Of course. I'm surprised you
haven't been snapped up already.
Yeah. Well, it seems that lately
my reputation has taken a hit.
He's a horrid little turd, isn't he?
You know what? I spoke with a friend in
Philadelphia who's looking for someone.
- I just wasn't sure you'd care to move.
- At this point, I'm open to anything.
- Dr. Benton, they need you in the ER.
- I no longer work at this hospital.
Weaver called.
Your sister Jackie is down there.
- What was the last BP?
-100/60.
- Okay, let's go.
- I'll grab the drug box.
- How is she?
- Who are you?
Her sister.
She was shot in the chest.
She's critical.
She needs surgery.
You can go wait in the-
- Oh, Lord!
- What happened?
- Call Security now!
- Oh, my God! Carter! Are you all right?
- Heart stopped beating.
- I'll start compressions.
- Any rhythm?
- Agonal at 34. Looks like P.E.A.
Amp of atropine, amp of epi.
Mix up the dopamine.
That girl must've been a gangbanger.
Chest is dry.
Pupils are fixed and dilated.
There's gray matter everywhere.
You won't get her back.
Blew her brains out.
Hyperventilators, 70 of mannitol.
Check cold-water calorics,
and we'll call it.
Somebody call the police!
- What happened?
- Jesse got into a fight.
You don't know, all right?
I was surprised when
they said you were here.
I had to take care of something.
How is he?
Superficial lac above the eyebrow,
mild periorbital swelling...
...but no bony deformity or tenderness.
- Nothing serious.
- Told you.
- He was bleeding pretty bad.
- Did you hit your head? Pass out?
He slammed me into the locker once,
all right? That's all.
- You get a CT?
- No. You think he needs one?
Maybe.
There was no LOC,
no focal neuro deficits.
With head injuries,
you can't be too careful.
Jackie, he's fine. He's fine.
Come on. Hey, Jackie.
How about I buy you a cup of coffee?
- Are you sure?
- Yeah. Come on.
- How are you doing?
- I'm okay.
- They found the shooter.
- Good.
Only 15 years old.
Why don't you go home?
I'll be all right.
Go home. You've probably seen
enough trauma for one day.
I'll tell Kerry.
- He's a teenager. It's normal stuff.
- No, he's changed.
You're just not around enough
to notice anymore.
What does that mean?
He's got a girlfriend now.
She's pretty rough.
- You try talking to him?
- We've tried everything.
Grounding him is a joke.
He goes out anyway.
I can't have him locked up.
The other day he shoved his father.
Took everything Walter had not to-
You all right?
Can you talk to him?
Can you try?
Talking to him?
Maybe he'll listen to you.
- You look nice.
- Thank you. You too.
So, what did you have in mind?
Dinner? Movie?
I was thinking of something
a little more physical.
Not if you go in laparoscopically.
Recovery time is reduced
and he gains back weeks...
...maybe even months of his life.
I don't understand. Are you saying it's
too risky for you or for the patient?
Yeah, whatever. Thank you.
- Problems?
- Can't find a surgeon.
- Is our department booked?
- No. Just uninterested.
- This your kid with Niemann-Pick's?
- Yeah.
Tough situation.
I all but promised his mother
I'd make this happen.
- Now you can't?
- There are a few other people I can try.
But you know they'll turn you down.
You know, sometimes as much as we
like to give it, hope can be cruel.
Dr. Greene.
Think fast!
8:00, tonight. You're in.
I can't believe the VA
is moving this quickly.
They're not.
I got him into another home.
Borrowed a Social Security number
from a corpse at the morgue.
- Sour cream and onion?
- No, thank you.
You borrowed a number
from a deceased person?
- Yeah. We do it all the time.
- I don't wanna know this.
- You said you felt bad.
- That is not the point.
I work with many elderly homeless.
You learn a few tricks.
- Not another word, please!
- You have to.
- Dr. Weaver, time for that seminar.
- Thank you, Frank.
- "Advances in Neuroleptic Therapy"?
- Yeah. How did you know?
I'll be there. Save you a seat.
- So where is this body?
- The patient is right here.
- Audrey?
- Can I go home now?
Not yet. This is Miss Pruitt,
and she's here to help you.
She's an expert cosmetologist.
Can you cover all of this
in time for the pageant?
- Honey, I've worked on worse. Trust me.
- Yeah, but I've got open wounds.
You're on antibiotics. But afterwards,
no makeup until you're fully healed.
- Thank you, Dr. Greene.
- Good luck.
Thanks.
Isn't that the gal who does makeup
on dead people?
Whatever works.
Mark, there you are. You know we
were meant to leave half an hour ago?
- For what?
- We're looking at artwork tonight.
- I'm subbing in a hockey game.
- What?
- Malucci. He asked me to play hockey.
- Malucci? Are you mad?
What?
You never said one word to me
about hockey before.
You never asked.
- Do you play well?
- Well, why don't you come find out?
You could wear your sweater,
you could bring some pompoms.
I'd be in uniform.
I didn't know sports
had this effect on you.
- Has something happened?
- No, why?
- You're home early.
- Yep.
- You never leave the hospital early.
- Someone fax you my schedule?
I know when you left this morning.
And I know the kind of hours you put in.
It was slow, so they sent me home.
- So it's been all right?
- Yep.
- What you expected?
- I'm hungry.
How about you? Have you eaten?
I'll take you to Dominic's.
John, to be honest, I hoped that you
would feel so uncomfortable there...
...that you wouldn't want to stay.
- I know.
- So I wouldn't have to ask you not to.
Well, then don't. Just give me
five minutes. I'll get changed.
John.
I know your heart is in the right place.
I know you enjoy being a doctor.
Start a practice.
I'm not fighting you on that anymore.
Can't we just agree
to disagree on this?
No. There are other ways
to help people.
You don't have to destroy yourself.
- Gamma-
- That place nearly killed you, John.
It killed your friend.
It drove you to drugs.
- No. I did that on my own.
- You don't owe them anything.
You don't have to prove anything.
You have a beautiful spirit.
I've seen them beat
that spirit out of you.
Gamma, I'm gonna be fine.
I promise.
I wish I could believe you.
Gamma?
Wait. Stop spinning.
You're not supposed to spin.
How am I supposed to keep you from...?
- It's all in the wrists, really.
- I think I pulled a muscle.
- Oh, maybe we should take a break.
- Good idea.
Draft, please. Abby?
- Oh, can I have a club soda?
- Club soda.
So next time I choose the sport.
Something more civilized.
- Such as...?
- There's a pool table at my hotel.
- Your hotel?
- Yeah. I don't own it. I just live there.
- You live in a hotel?
- Yeah. As a doctor.
I take care of the tourists.
They give me a break on the rent.
No, it's a good deal. I mean,
maid service, laundry, amenities...
No, it's great.
You'll have to come see it.
- Your hotel room?
- Yeah.
I mean- I mean, no. I mean-
I'd never ask such a thing of a lady.
- Well, especially after just one kiss.
- No. I should hope not.
Of course, that makes it two.
Come on, rematch.
- We out of here, or not?
- Yeah. After we talk.
About what?
Your mom says you've been
hanging out a lot lately.
- So?
- So she worries about you.
She worries about everything.
That's what she does.
- You got new friends?
- New girl. That's it.
- Using a condom?
- Uncle Peter-
- I'm serious.
- I'm not stupid.
Good.
I'm not doing anything, all right?
It's just...
I'm a man, you know?
And my folks just can't get
used to it. That's all.
Well, maybe they would
if you treated them with respect.
You mean do what they say.
Look, sometimes you gotta do
what you don't wanna do.
That's part of being a man.
- Peter, do you have a minute?
- Yeah. Hold on a second, okay?
Just do what your mother says.
All right?
- That job's yours if you want it.
- Are you serious?
You're a full Surgical Attending
on the academic track.
- Thank you.
- I'm so happy for you.
- What's all the celebrating about?
- I got a job.
That's great!
Elizabeth pulled some strings
with her friend.
Where?
Hahnemann.
They made me a full Attending.
In Philadelphia.
- Anyway, he's expecting your call.
- Oh. Right, right. Thanks.
Sure.
I didn't have much of a choice.
I mean, I'm being blackballed here.
- When will I see you?
- Well, it's only an hour by air.
- We'll work something out.
- I guess so.
- You coming home with us?
- No, I gotta make a stop.
- Can you do me a favor and take him?
- Of course.
I'll call you.
Okay.
- What?
- All I'm saying is:
You were at four
and then you were at six.
That's because I scored very quickly.
You're a bad sport.
- I can't handle losing to a girl, okay?
- Oh, no.
I'm kidding. I actually enjoyed
losing to you, Abby.
Thank you. Thank you.
That's much better.
Your hands are freezing.
You wanna catch a cab?
No. This is strolling weather
in Minnesota.
- Is that where home is?
- It's where I grew up-
Luka!
Give me your purse.
Give me the purse.
- Give me the damn- Give me the purse!
- Take it.
Luka! Luka, stop!
Stop! Luka, stop!
Stop it!
Let's play the game!
You okay, Dr. Greene?
I thought you said this was
a no-check league.
- There's no such thing.
- Thanks for the tip.
- Hi. I thought you'd left.
- Briefly.
You know, you don't need
to finish your shift.
I still got a couple hours left.
Carter, I think that you'd be
better served by taking it easy.
I'll go to a meeting after my shift's over.
If that's okay with you?
I need to finish.
All right. But not too much.
Keep it to minor medical.
- Thank you. Have a nice night.
- You too.
- What's open?
- Trauma 2.
- I thought you two went home.
- This guy attacked us.
Blunt head trauma with LOC.
GCS of eight.
Three seizures en route.
He's had four of Ativan.
- You're bleeding.
- I'm all right.
BP 180/100.
I'll take it from here. Luka.
Get someone to take care of him.
- Hey, Carter! I need you in here!
- Dr. Weaver doesn't want-
I don't care. Get in here now.
We've got a major head trauma.
On my count. One, two, three.
He's seizing.
Two of Ativan. CBC, chem panel,
coags, type and cross for four.
Give me suction. He's vomiting.
- Get X-ray in here for a C-spine.
- All right. I'll stabilize the neck.
Ativan's on board. Still seizing.
Hey, Carla.
- Peter.
- We need to talk.
- Here, okay? Really busy tonight.
- Sure.
- Here you go. Pick it up.
- Table eight first.
The hospital said Reece could stay
until the end of the month.
That gives us more time
to find another daycare center.
It'll be hard finding him
a place he loves more.
I know. Listen, I just got an Attending
position at Hahnemann in Philadelphia.
Really? Good for you.
So we just need to work out
Reece's visitation schedule.
Maybe he could fly down
every other weekend or something.
I'm sorry. You're not suggesting I put
my son on a plane by himself, are you?
- Carla, we have joint custody.
- In Chicago.
I already took the job.
Wish that had worked for me
when I wanted to move.
That was Germany, nine hours away.
That's completely different.
- No. It is completely the same.
- What is this about? Payback?
It's about our agreement. Now, either
you stay local, or you give up custody.
I can't find a decent position here.
That's right. You have your career
to think of. The rest of us just have jobs.
Table six needs more bread.
This is the only way for me
to keep my momentum.
- Yes. And Germany was Roger's.
- Carla, I'm asking you not to do this.
I'm not doing anything.
I'm just playing by your rules.
Hang Dilantin. One gram
per 1000 of saline.
- It looks pretty deep. You need suturing.
- I'm okay.
- Someone should sew it up, Luka.
Dr. Kovac?
Detective Stetler.
Can I have a moment?
Can you tell me
exactly what happened?
We were walking by the river.
He jumped us.
- Was there only one assailant?
- Yeah.
- Seizing stopped at 2142.
- Lateral neck looks good.
We need some more Kerlix.
He's soaked through these.
We got a pumper. Curved Kelly.
Pressure's sky-high, 260/140.
Pulse down to 42.
Start the Nipride.
Blown right pupil. He's herniating.
Eighty of mannitol.
Prep for a posterior burr hole.
Hurry up, Carter. I need you to assist.
Perforator drill with a chisel-point bit.
- Damn it, tie that off!
- I'm trying!
Stick a finger on it!
V- tach. No pulse.
Starting chest compressions.
- Charge to 200.
- Carter, can you grab the paddles?
- I'm controlling the bleeder.
- Get a pressure dressing on it.
- Give me those four-by-fours. Come on.
- Haleh, I need that drill.
- Okay.
- Clear.
I didn't see him coming.
After he hit you from behind,
what happened?
I went down.
- Did he take your wallet?
- Yeah.
- And you felt your life was in danger.
- Mine and hers.
Did he threaten to hurt you?
I'm not sure.
Did he say, "Give me your money,
or I'll kill you"?
He had a pipe.
He was going after Abby.
- And you can corroborate that?
- Yeah.
Let's wait and see what happens.
Seems pretty clear it was self-defense.
Shouldn't be a problem, doc.
There. That's the inner table.
Irrigate the bone dust.
- Looks like a subdural.
- More irrigation, Carter. 11 blade.
- Five minutes since the last epi.
- Give another amp.
Opening the dura.
Get ready to suction.
- Can you see the source?
- No.
Let's just pack it off.
What's the rhythm?
- V-fib.
- Charge to 300.
I need saline gauze.
Clear.
- Sinus brady at 50.
- Got a pulse.
Excellent.
Decompress the brain.
Amp of atropine.
Let's check the pupils.
- How about phenobarb?
- Go with pentobarb, 200, slow IV push.
- That'll induce a coma, you know.
- It's either that or watch him die.
Abby told me about what happened.
Can I take a look?
It's superficial.
- Did you lose consciousness?
- For a moment, yeah.
- Come on. Let's fix you up.
- No.
- Do you have a headache?
- Leave me alone!
I'm fine, okay? I'm fine.
Clear.
Still V-fib.
- How long's the bretylium been on board?
- Five minutes.
Clear.
Asystole. What now?
- Open up the dopamine.
- It's been 45 minutes.
I know.
Luka, wait!
Luka, wait.
Subtitles by SDI Media Group
ripped by blade2 for TusSeries
www.tvsubtitles.net