Previously on ER:
Dr. Carter, hi.
- As of today, I'm only an intern.
- I heard, I couldn't believe it.
Kerry, this is Dr. Dan Litvak.
Just here to get a few tips?
I had an interview
for the Chief position.
- Have you not told everyone?
- My son's deaf, I know.
- Don't you set policy?
- I'm here for the ride-along.
If he gets vomit in his lungs,
he could die of aspiration pneumonia.
Two of your classmates almost died.
It was stupid of me to think you
could take responsibility.
Doug, what are you doing? It's 5:00.
I'm a week behind
on my Q and A reports.
And that is the good news.
How long have you been up?
Haven't been to sleep.
Oh, God, anything I can do?
Go back to bed, no use
both of us being miserable.
No, it's Ionely there without you.
Keep that up, I'm never gonna finish.
Sorry.
Now I know how you felt
when you opened your clinic.
It's pretty scary, huh?
Are we both nuts?
Yeah.
But it's worth it.
Oh, Dr. Carter.
I didn't think you'd be up yet.
I left you a note.
I just wanted to tell you
how sorry I am that you lost...
...your R.A. Job because Halloween...
- Me too.
I wondered if you thought it might
help if I wrote the dean a letter?
Thanks, I think you've
done enough already.
At least I could help pack.
I'm not on until 7:00.
- No, I can manage.
- Where will you live?
Ow!
That's my leg.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't realize you had company.
See you at the hospital.
I'm very glad you're moving.
So your beef is with nurses asking
stupid questions over the radio.
I'll say. Patients freak out when
someone asks if they got track marks.
All right, I'll talk to the nurses.
They asked me to remind you not to
restock your rig with their supplies.
Oh, man, that is so lame.
Nothing'll change unless we all throw
our gripes out on the table.
Want to get some breakfast
before we head back?
Definitely, I'm hungry.
I could use an omelet and...
- What was that?
- Gunfire. Came from behind us.
Looks like bangers.
Someone's down!
Unit 63, we have a possible GSW
on the 1600 block of Halsted.
Gunfire in the vicinity.
Why don't you back up?
We have to wait for a secure area.
I don't hear gunfire.
That doesn't mean
it won't start again.
- I'm not gonna wait in here.
- Protocol says we wait for backup.
Wait!
Damn it!
What the hell are you doing?
Did you hear that?
We should not be out here.
Doesn't mean they'll come back.
Give me a hand.
Is he shot?
There's no entrance wound.
He's beat up.
Ready to roll him? All right, go.
Stopped breathing, intubate.
- Not here, in the rig.
- Now!
There's too much blood, suction.
Morales, gurney!
- Can't see the cords.
- Want to crank his head back?
We have to clear the C-spine.
He's still not breathing.
Extend his neck.
You ER guys are nuts!
- Yes, I'm in.
- Okay.
Let's move him and bag him.
One, two, three.
I'm losing his pulse.
We have to start two large IVs.
You want to do that here too?
No, we'll do it while we're rolling.
Next time you decide to do
a ride-along, I'm taking a day off.
Lights and sirens, let's go!
Morning, what have we got?
Sixteen-year-old male found beaten.
Sustained concussion, contusions...
Head, neck and extremities.
BP's 140 over 80, pulse 110, regular.
Good air entry bilaterally.
No evidence of pneumothorax.
- Any I.D.?
- No, just a couple of bucks.
Everybody, on my count:
One, two, three.
- Cowboy Greene to the rescue.
- Babinski's normal.
- BP 120/78.
- Regular rate and rhythm.
- Spontaneous eye-opening.
- Okay, can you wiggle your toes?
Yep, follows commands.
- How's he doing?
- Stable, no apparent neurodeficits.
That was some crazy stunt.
You lucked out this time.
What was that all about?
Paramedics got perturbed,
I tubed him in the field.
Radiology's here.
So word is Dan Litvak
turned down ER Chief.
- What happened?
- He played the committee for patsies.
Used the offer to negotiate
a bigger salary back home.
I shouldn't tell you this,
but you're the only other candidate.
Really?
- "Cat lover seeks roommate."
- Forget it.
Would you consider joining
a communal vegetarian household?
All right, here's one: "Furnished
apartment in old townhome.
Access to full kitchen.
Many amenities."
- That sounds promising.
- And not far from the hospital.
I can set up an appointment
for you after work.
- All right, see you later.
- Bye.
Take a deep breath.
All right, blow hard. Hard!
- You all right?
- Yeah.
Pulse ox holding at 98.
I'm Dr. Greene.
Do you know what happened to you?
I was with a john.
Bangers tried to rob us.
And my john pulled a gun.
That's where I go blank.
Found you on the street.
Brought you here by ambulance.
Why were you cruising
in my neighborhood?
Sometimes I ride along
with paramedics.
You're the first guy
who's ever saved my life.
I don't go out in the street
for just anybody.
- Guess I gotta grant you a wish now.
- What?
Like I Dream of Jeannie, when Major
Nelson rescued her from a bottle.
Start with your name and age.
Kevin Delaney.
I'm 16 years old.
Lily, why don't you find
Kevin's labs...
...and see if you can get us
an Exam Room.
Sure.
Where do you live?
Where you found me.
- Any family?
- None who want to know me.
Why is that?
Year ago my old man caught me...
...having sex with my gymnastics
coach, he kicked me out of the house.
Any other details you want to hear?
So you survive by hustling.
Yeah, well, someone's gotta pay
the bills, right?
Use condoms?
Sometimes.
Customers pay more
to ride me bareback.
We have a new rapid HIV test.
You can get results in 20 minutes.
How about it?
You want to bet I'm positive?
Well, if you are, we can treat you.
Sure.
Looks like a good turnout
for the BP screening.
I posted signs at the Senior Center.
If it stops raining, we'll be jammed.
- Not so tight!
- I'm sorry, Mr. Levy...
...but to get an accurate reading,
it has to be snug.
It's too damn tight!
Take it easy, I'll loosen it a bit.
My arm's gonna fall off.
Next time we should extend
the outreach.
Go into the community, take BPs.
What do you think?
That's not a bad idea.
Okay, your pressure's fine.
No thanks to you.
- Carol, you page me?
- Oh, yeah, I'll be right back.
What's up?
- I'm swamped here.
- I know, I know.
- A lab coat?
- Yes.
It's what every
division head should wear.
No backing out now.
What do you think?
- Come here.
- I thought you said you're busy.
- Not that busy.
- No?
Carter, you paged me?
Sixty-eight-year-old male with
a history of abdominal surgery.
I'm thinking small bowel obstruction.
- You do a three-way?
- Right here.
Air-fluid levels, and he's got
a stepladder pattern.
Good call.
- I must've driven you crazy.
- What do you mean?
My student, she's driving me nuts.
Makes stupid mistakes.
Asks too many questions.
Shows poor judgment.
- How'd you put up with me?
- I never gave you any thought.
- You didn't?
- Medical students don't know anything.
It's your job to teach them,
not be their friend.
Exhale, Mrs. Delpit,
like you're blowing out candles.
Before listening with a stethoscope,
test for tactile fremitus.
By placing your hand
on the patient's back...
...and asking her to repeat "99."
I haven't tested for that
since my first year.
I have to be sure that you
can do a complete exam.
All right.
Mrs. Delpit, will you please
repeat "99" for me.
Ninety-nine...
...99...
Blood alcohol level came back.
Did I set a record?
No, but it's up there, 0.16.
That's nothing, last time
I got picked up I scored a 26.
I also have your HIV results.
It's AIDS, right?
No, good news, you're negative.
I guess my johns don't need
rubbers after all.
I'm gonna charge them a fortune.
You won't stay negative
if you don't use protection.
Time to get your life together.
Yeah, I do kind of stink.
Do you think I could get a shower?
Maybe some clean clothes?
I'll have the nurses come
and take you to the shower room.
Care to join me?
No, thanks, I had one this morning.
Peter, hold on.
Have you got a moment?
Nope, I've got
a small bowel obstruction.
I know, I'm operating with you.
Meet your new intern.
- Since when?
- This morning, if you want.
- Go ahead, bring him in.
- Okay.
Was this Anspaugh's idea?
It was mine, but Anspaugh supports it.
Enthusiastically, I might add.
- I don't know.
- Come on, Peter.
Don't be a wet blanket.
Think, no more Dale Scott.
And you have the chance to work
with an alluring intern.
I'm not comfortable with that.
Why not? We've made a great team.
When we were both Residents.
Now I'd have to be your boss.
I don't mind if you don't.
I'll be accused of playing favorites
if I don't treat you like an intern.
I don't ask for special treatment...
...just the chance to do something
more than pull drains.
Elizabeth, I don't think it'll be...
I don't think it'd be good for us.
All right, I'll think about it, okay?
You know what, you don't have to.
I already heard your answer.
Orange juice?
You want orange juice, Reece?
Is that what you want?
- Coffee, please.
- You want a sip?
- You guys taking a lunch break?
- Hey. Yeah.
Figured we'd get some air
since the rain stopped.
Yeah, me too.
He's getting so big.
You're gonna be...
...tall like your daddy,
aren't you, huh?
I wasn't aware that Reece
had a hearing problem.
Yeah, we just found out recently.
He's deaf.
Come on, man.
What approach do you use
for language acquisition...
...if you don't mind my asking?
We're working with an audiologist.
Have you looked into speech reading?
He has residual hearing.
I'm looking for an aggressive ENT...
...who'll consider him
for a cochlear implant.
They'd have to destroy
his residual hearing.
Yeah, but the technology
is very advanced.
You should talk to Lisa Parks
at U of C.
She's an outstanding physician
and has expertise in this.
She's a friend of yours?
I'll give you her number.
She's cutting edge.
Thanks.
ER? Yep, hold on. Dr. Ross.
I'm busy here, Jerry.
They said it was urgent.
All right.
This is Dr. Ross.
You too, Carol.
Where are you?
I was just thinking about you.
I have to get my sugar checked!
Gotta go. What's the problem?
That other nurse said
I have to come back.
I have sugar diabetes.
I schlepped all the way here
on a bus in the rain...
...and she says I need an appointment!
- Now, what is that?
- Okay, hang on.
Did you tell Mr. Levy he'd need
an appointment for his blood check?
Did he give you that song
about taking the bus?
- He's got other complaints.
- Ladies, I hate to interrupt...
...but I haven't had a bite
to eat all day.
I have sugar diabetes. Hello?
Okay, Mr. Levy,
I'll test your blood glucose once...
...without an appointment.
Then we'll get you food.
- You're an angel.
- Okay.
Hope you got all afternoon.
How did the accident happen, Kate?
I lost it on gravel
coming down through a turn.
Your dad said
you hit a curb and then fell.
She fell onto the curb
after slipping on gravel.
Okay, have a seat.
You might have a fracture.
I'll call Ortho after we get an x-ray.
We'll be right back.
Have Medical Records send up
any old charts.
Good idea.
You feel any pain when I press here?
Yeah, a lot.
- When did you first feel the pain?
- In the shower.
You had a blow to your leg.
Could be a blood clot.
That's no big deal.
I've had them before.
- You have?
- Yeah, sure.
I've got a protein S deficiency.
My blood clots all the time.
Should've seen the mother
I had a year ago.
I wish you would've told me
your history before.
I can't take care of you
if you're not straight.
I can't be straight.
Guess you want to order
a coag panel...
...and clotting studies,
and start a heparin drip?
When was the last time
you were hospitalized?
Right before I took off from home.
All right, I'm gonna
start you on the heparin.
Then we're gonna move
to the Coumadin...
...before you're to be discharged.
- No, I'm not taking Coumadin.
Why not? You have a disease requiring
you to take a blood thinner forever.
Coumadin and the streets don't mix.
You ought to know that.
You don't want me back,
bleeding my brains out...
...because I got drunk
and hit my head.
You'd rather die of a blood clot?
I don't sweat it, why should you?
How much insulin did you take,
Mr. Levy?
I'm not sure.
The lady who used to come
always gave it to me.
She also used to trim my toenails.
I think one of them is infected.
I got pain in my left side.
Mr. Levy's still here.
Apparently, he took too much insulin.
His blood sugar is 61.
I told you I needed to have
my blood checked.
Look, you were right.
I'm really stuck.
His home health aide took a new job.
- Any family?
- No.
His wife died last year.
No one else in town.
We could try to get
a temporary placement...
...until we find a new aide.
I'm not going to a nursing home!
Just temporarily, Mr. Levy.
The desk guy said Mr. Levy's here?
- You got my Kung Pao?
- Yes, sir.
- Egg rolls?
- Yes, sir, all right here.
- That's $8.50.
- Very reasonable.
- You ordered Chinese?
- She said I needed to eat.
- I'll get my wallet.
- Why don't you make it an even 10?
Where's my fortune cookie?
I was just wondering...
...am I gonna get to work
with other ER Residents?
Why, is there a problem?
No, I just thought I'll learn more
by working with a variety of teachers.
That's up to the Attendings.
Why don't you tell me
about this patient?
Brad Enloe, 12,
history of recurrent leukemia.
Relapsed after
second induction of chemo.
He's here today for a fever
and a sore throat.
Poor kid's been through a lot.
It's our job to treat the patient,
not feel sorry for him.
Hi, Brad, I'm Dr. Carter.
This is my student, Lucy Knight.
I hear your throat hurts.
Yeah, it started this morning.
He had a temp of 101.
Check for cervical adenopathy...
...and look for infection,
particularly in the ears and throat.
- Does that hurt?
- Kind of.
It's probably just a virus,
Mrs. Enloe.
I'm gonna give Brad some ibuprofen,
and check his blood count.
He's a candidate
for immunotoxin therapy.
But unfortunately, he has
to be hospitalized to get the drug...
...and our insurance turned him down.
They won't pay for experiments.
If his neutrophil count
comes back under 500...
...we'll admit him for antibiotics.
He could get immunotoxins on the side.
Is that a possibility?
Why don't we cross that bridge
when we have the results?
Does your clinic have any information
about shelters for runaways?
- This for the kid you saved?
- You heard?
I thought you were smoothing
things out between ER and paramedics.
- I got a little carried away.
- Doesn't matter, you're a hero.
- Yeah, if I don't kill him.
- What?
He's got a clotting disorder.
If I give him a blood thinner,
he could die in the street.
If I don't treat him,
he could die of a clot.
Oh, God, between a rock
and a hard place?
Here's a pamphlet for a shelter
that takes in street kids.
- Think you'll convince him?
- We'll see.
- Good luck.
- Thanks.
Mr. Preston, can I talk to you?
I'll be right back.
I got Kate's old records. There's
a pattern that needs explaining.
She wasn't riding a bicycle.
It's not what you're thinking.
What is it?
She was riding a unicycle.
- A unicycle?
- Backwards, playing the violin.
We were trying to break
a Guinness World Record.
I didn't want word to get out.
- And her split lip two months ago?
- Balancing glasses on her chin.
- Knife cuts?
- We broke the potato-peeling record.
Kate and I went through tough times.
I was looking for things we could
do together. It sounds crazy...
...but I found a three-legged marathon
we could enter.
We won, and we kind of got hooked,
started breaking all kinds of records.
May I help you?
Yeah, I'm Peter Benton from County.
Kerry Weaver referred me.
I'm Sara Jackson. She's with
a patient. I'll introduce you.
Excuse me, on the door
it says "Family Medicine."
I thought she was a surgeon.
No, she has a family practice.
Hi, I'm Dr. Benton. Listen,
don't let me interrupt your patient.
No, that's not a problem.
I'm happy that you came over.
I'm sorry, there must be
some misunderstanding.
No, Kerry told me about your son.
I'd be happy to discuss cochlear
implants, and other options too.
I guess she didn't tell you
I was deaf, huh?
No, she didn't.
Dr. Parks asked that when you speak
to her, you look directly at her...
...so she can read lips.
Oh, I'm sorry. Look, I said,
I didn't know you were deaf.
That's all right.
Can we talk?
Do you have time for some coffee?
Yeah, all right, yeah.
Just let me finish up with
this patient, and then we'll all go.
Great.
You must be very confused trying
to decide what's best for your son.
Look, I want my son to be able
to function in the world.
As you can see, I function
pretty well without an implant.
Yeah, but if an implant can help
him to hear, why not get one?
Well, there are other options.
Look, I don't want my son to have
to depend on others, no offense.
Do you know any deaf people?
No, I don't.
Have you ever thought that being deaf
might not be so terrible?
So you're saying there's no problem?
You can never know
what it's like being deaf.
Just like I can never know
what it's like being black.
I don't look at me being black
as a burden. That's who I am.
And I don't look at my deafness
If you turn away
from your son's deafness...
...you will be robbing him
of his identity.
My son has a medical problem.
I'm not turning away,
I'm trying to fix it.
Late for a meeting?
If I can get through
this administrative hellhole...
...maybe I'll get to see
a few kids again.
You can do it, keep going.
You're doing great, Dad.
Beats juggling cantaloupes.
Two hours he's been at it,
hasn't dropped one yet.
The orthopedic surgeon is gonna
come and examine your wrist.
Is it all right if I watch
my dad till he gets here?
He's trying to break
the juggling record.
Kate, did your dad force you
to ride that unicycle?
Force me? Oh, no, it was my idea.
You've had a lot of injuries.
Dad and I always take
Guinness-approved precautions.
If you're gonna be a record breaker,
you gotta take chances.
Play it safe and life's boring.
Here's when we broke the marathon.
That's me and Dad, we're in the book.
I'll give you Accutane for the acne.
But you'll need birth control pills.
Birth control pills?
Accutane is a very effective
medication.
But if you were to get pregnant,
it could cause terrible birth defects.
I won't have sex, I promised my mom.
I believe you, Nava...
...but it's my policy to give birth
control to girls who take Accutane.
My mom won't let me take them.
Have her call me.
I'll explain it to her.
I don't think she'll change her mind.
Okay, then...
...I can't give you this medication.
- Brought you these.
- Thanks. What's that?
You might want to read about...
...advances on protein S deficiency.
Hey, look, I like you,
but I'm really not worth it.
There's a list of homeless shelters.
If you can't go home,
you might as well go to one.
There you can take your Coumadin.
Then what?
Maybe get a job at McDonald's?
You're a smart guy.
You get a GED, maybe go to college.
- Look, what's the use?
- Would you rather die on the streets?
You know, you're cute
when you get angry.
Is that the only way you can relate
to me, by turning me into a customer?
Okay, I'll read them.
Anything for you.
Hey, can you write me a scrip
for birth control pills?
That young lady decided
to take them after all?
Yeah, she said she would.
You know...
...you have no business
giving her birth control pills...
...since she and her mom
don't want them.
And what if she got pregnant?
You heard, she's not sexually active.
She's a teenager, that doesn't
guarantee she's not gonna have sex.
You are undermining her choice.
Giving her the pills
isn't gonna make her have sex.
Listen, how would you feel
if you were that girl...
...and a white nurse
said she didn't trust you?
I wouldn't like it
no matter what color.
All I'm saying is, you don't know
that girl or her mother.
You're volunteering to talk to her?
No, I just think it's wrong for you
to force birth control on the girl.
Well, maybe.
But I'm not gonna take any chances.
Dr. Carter, labs are back on
Brad Enloe. You should look at them.
His neutrophil count's over 1000.
- We can't admit him.
- He's not septic.
Right, he's only dying of leukemia.
He vomited after I gave him ibuprofen.
- Really?
- Yep.
- When?
- Couple of minutes ago.
He's dehydrated.
We're gonna admit him.
Call upstairs, tell them we have
an admit for Pedes.
- He only vomited once.
- I know, make the call.
- He needs to be rehydrated.
- I can start an IV.
You shouldn't do one on the kid.
- I can do it.
- Been through chemo.
His veins are sclerosed.
Not this one.
- Hey, Doug.
- Hey!
Write me a scrip
for birth control?
- Thought you swore it off.
- For a patient.
- When did you hear?
- Half-hour ago.
Hey, Mark.
Whenever you have a minute?
Yeah, I'll be right there.
Kerry knows this ER better than
anybody we'd hire.
I agree, but the committee wants
a star with a reputation...
...who can bring in grants.
- Mark, trauma's pulling up.
- I'll tell her.
You sure? Mark, no sense in telling
Kerry she was our second choice.
Only disappoint her even more.
Right.
- Here we go, here we go.
- What the hell?
Brothers got into a fight
on the expressway...
...Iost control.
I've never seen such a mess.
- You idiot, I said turn left.
- Sorry, Marcus.
You jackass.
Can't believe I let you drive.
You never watch the road.
Eddy and Marcus Haney, carpet-layers.
Carpet cement spilled all over them.
- Stuck to their seat.
- You get stuck, you're on your own.
- You're a moron, you know that?
- Just relax.
How can I relax
when that idiot did this?
Okay, pulse is strong.
Pupils react to light.
Lydia, get me a glove change here.
This stuff is like taffy.
How's he doing?
What is that?
Got an impalement of some kind.
Oh, my God! It looks like
some kind of tool with sharp prongs.
Not the hand stretcher?
- Four-by-fours.
- Eddy?
Just don't move so much.
- We're gonna take care of him.
- Oh, man!
Bleeding man here.
Let's take him to Trauma!
Gently.
- Malik, try and get monitor leads on.
- How?
Get a tongue depressor,
scrape off a few spots.
Why did Eddy stop talking?
Hold still.
If you move, you'll kill him.
- Pulse ox falling.
- Stand by with intubation.
I'll get a tray and an 8.0 ET tube.
Covering Dr. Benton, need consult?
We've got an impalement.
Watch out for the glue.
- Lucy, have you ever intubated?
- No, but I'd like to.
Pretty tough intubation.
Let's find out, talk her through.
Great.
Runs of PVCs when he's jostled...
...from the tool against the heart.
Carter, get the crash cart.
- Lydia?
- On it.
Malik, we need the cutter down here
as fast as you can.
Hang in there, Eddy, all right?
You're gonna be okay.
Carter, I need you here...
...and carefully pull Marcus away
so that Lucy has room to intubate.
- Can you get in?
- Yeah, a little more.
Lydia, snap some pictures.
New policy: We're documenting
our interesting traumas.
Take her through it.
All right, pass the tube.
Not too far.
All right, take out the scope.
Pull the stylet.
Confirm your position.
I'm in.
Good job.
Lets call Respiratory for a vent.
I hear good breath sounds.
- He's in SVT!
- We need to shock him.
Not while they're attached.
Try Adenocard.
Please save my brother.
- Carter, let go.
- I'm stuck!
Charging, 200!
Get out of your gloves and gown.
- My beard is stuck.
- Got the cutters.
Pull back, Carter.
I need some exposed skin!
I'm stuck!
Clear!
Got a pulse!
Good job, everybody.
Let's get him to the O.R.
- Still want pictures?
- Might as well.
Carter?
Carter, you all right?
Yeah, I think so.
Thank you for saving my brother.
Just doing our job.
We need to extricate Dr. Carter.
So, Lucy, why don't you start
with his beard?
He was juggling while on
a pogo stick?
- Yeah, a guy in Zurich.
- What about while skydiving?
Isabella from Tangiers holds
the record for juggling five balls.
How long has he been at it?
- For over 31/2 hours.
- What's the record?
Eleven hours, four minutes,
22 seconds.
It's in the book.
Kate's documenting the event.
This could be our first time on TV.
Less than eight hours to go.
- Dad!
- Jerry, watch out!
Congratulations, never thought
you'd unstick the glue brothers.
- Guess you can fix about anything?
- We try.
I got a call.
You picked up a kid, Delaney?
- We got a warrant for his arrest.
- What for?
Parole violation,
prostitution, the usual.
How long do you expect to keep him?
Hard to say, we're treating him
for blood clotting.
Call when you release him.
We'll pick him up.
Yeah, I'm a doctor, I'm not a cop.
He needs a second chance.
I'm a cop, not a social worker.
You do your job, I'll do mine.
If he gets beat up in jail,
he'll bleed to death.
If I don't pick him up,
somebody else will.
I have a sitter to guard him
until his discharge.
Good job on the trauma.
- You came pretty close.
- We'll try again later.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Kate ready to be discharged?
Bring her back for a cast check.
- No jumping around?
- Not for six weeks.
- Thank you for being so kind.
- You're welcome.
- Thanks.
- Okay, bye.
I'll miss the event at the pier.
Sorry, sweetheart.
You want to go watch?
- I guess.
- Okay.
Brad's bed is ready.
I've written orders for Oncology
to continue to rehydrate him.
Thank you, Dr. Carter.
You should feel fine in a couple days.
- Good luck with your treatment.
- Thanks.
- Malik, can you take him up?
- Yeah, sure.
He isn't dehydrated, is he?
He vomited, I gave him fluids.
What will Oncology say?
All they want is a diagnosis
for his admission.
I gave them one.
Can you give him an IV?
Was the only way to admit him.
- So you lied?
- Technically, yeah.
Sometimes you gotta work the system.
You lied?
I didn't know you were there.
Is it true Brad's not dehydrated?
It's a way for him to get chemo.
What if my insurance finds out?
- I see no reason why they should.
- I do, they've challenged claims.
If they find out,
Brad loses his coverage.
Then what do we do
when his leukemia gets worse?
I don't see another
way of going about doing this.
I'll talk to you later.
Cop stopped by earlier.
Still wants to take you in
after I discharge you.
- What did you tell him?
- That you were sick.
- Are they gonna put me in juvie?
- They want to.
I can't go back there.
I'm a punching bag for those guys.
I know.
I gotta tell you, getting heparinized
is the best treatment.
Great. Listen, I can't stick
around here if the cops are coming.
Figured you'd say that.
Are you setting me up?
If your leg starts to hurt or gets
swollen, you have to come back.
Here's 50 bucks and my pager number.
Coumadin and a list of shelters.
I never promised you I'd take that.
I know.
Maybe I'll see you around?
Hey, Peter, you missed a great trauma.
Yeah? I was out talking to Dr. Parks.
What did you think of her?
She had the audacity to say Reece
should be with deaf kids more than me.
Yeah, I should've warned you.
Lisa has very strong opinions.
Opinions?
Well, she doesn't mind being deaf.
She doesn't want to be cured.
I thought you'd want
to see what she's achieved.
I don't want my son to live
with a defect if I can help it.
"Defect"?
What do you mean by that?
It means, what I do with
my son is my business.
Be sure and let me know
how things work out.
God bless you, sweetheart.
I thought the nursing home said
they wouldn't have a bed.
Stan's not going there.
What you said earlier was right.
We need to know the patient's
community. I called his temple.
Another member with diabetes
said he'd stay with him.
- Good idea.
- Doesn't hurt to do a little outreach.
Mr. KIoner will be staying with you.
What's that son of a bitch doing here?
I should have known.
I spit on your grave!
I'll see you dead first!
You owe me $20,000 for
that time-share in Florida!
It's a shack in a swamp!
There you are. I've been looking
everywhere for you.
I'm late for an appointment...
What happened with Brad?
His mom took him home.
She decided not to risk it.
- I'm sorry to hear that.
- Me too.
I wouldn't have asked questions
if you'd told me what you were doing.
I'm sorry that you thought
it was your business to ask me.
What's going to happen?
He's gonna die.
Mark, I was putting together
a year-Iong ER coverage schedule.
Good.
Kerry, I want to talk to you.
Is it about the Chief position?
The executive committee has decided
to reopen the search.
The committee feels that they need a
candidate with a national reputation.
Personally, I think it stinks.
Well, that's that.
You're not out of the running, Kerry.
- They just reopened the search.
- No.
And I'm not interested
in continuing as Interim Chief.
- Who's gonna do it?
- Not my problem.
I shouldn't have yelled,
but he's so damn sensitive.
Hold still, Marcus.
Hey, welcome back.
I hear I missed quite a trauma.
You certainly did.
It's all my fault.
Eddy was driving, and I upset him.
I was just upstairs.
They finished the surgery.
They repaired your brother's heart.
Oh, thank God!
It was Dr. Corday here
who freed him just in time.
Well, that doesn't surprise me.
She's an excellent doctor.
When you're finished with Marcus,
we'll grab dinner.
I beg your pardon?
You're my new intern.
I just gave you an order.
Would you excuse us for a moment?
Peter, are you sure?
Elizabeth, you're no intern.
You'll still have to do scut work
and take call every third night.
But you'll have your patients
and can operate.
Thank you.
Yeah, don't mention it.
- I'll see you later.
- Aren't you on tonight?
Yeah, I am.
Sure you don't want something
to eat from Doc Magoo's?
No, that's all right.
I got indigestion there at lunch.
What are you doing?
I opened my big mouth.
I told Anspaugh that Pedes ER
was running at peak capacity.
Now he wants me to give a detailed
analysis of the daily census.
When will you be home?
Around April.
I won't wait up then.
- Good night.
Hey, doc, where are you headed?
Home, you?
To the firehouse, we're off duty.
Listen, sorry I broke protocol
this morning.
The adrenaline got the best of me.
Happens to me in a couple of hours.
My knees won't stop shaking.
- You got any cash on you?
- I'm tapped out.
Bunch of us are playing poker.
Want to come?
- Sure.
- We'll stop by the Ready Teller.
- Hop in.
- All right.
What time do we have to beat?
Six hours and 29 minutes.
We're trying to set
a new world record.
You're doing great.
- Thanks for stepping in for Katie.
- My pleasure.
Only six hours,
24 minutes to go, right?
- Dr. Weaver.
- Carter?
What are you doing here?
I came to see about a room for rent.
Is this the right address?
It is, I rent out my apartment.
I have a basement.
Would you like to see it?
Sure.
I don't usually advertise
at the hospital.
I always thought it might be
kind of, you know, awkward.
Sure, well, if you'd rather not.
No.
I was just having a drink.
Would you like one?
- Sure.
- Good, good.
Did you do something to your hair?
Hello?
Hey, baby.
Your census report?
Yeah, I think it's
on the kitchen table.
You want me to get it for you?
No, I can do it. It's just gonna
take a minute, okay? Just hold on.
Don't get out of the tub.
You look all happy.
Doug, what are you doing here?
I came to get this,
but then I was thinking...
...that I was working
all night last night.
You were.
- And I'll be working all day tomorrow.
- Yeah.
- Maybe I should take tonight off.
- That's a good idea.
You like that?
- What's that, a bubble bath?
- You want to come in?
www.tvsubtitles.net