E. R.
Previously on E. R.
You can't throw me out.
I'm your mother.
I'll keep taking my medication.
I won't be a burden.
- We got some leaking fluid.
- It's just irrigation solution.
- It's 10 to 6.
- I know.
I thought the procedure
had gone smoothly.
Well, it was a screaming success
if your desired outcome was paralysis.
Oh my God...
I'm being sued for malpractice.
Get out! I don't want you here!
You stay away from my son!
What's my prognosis?
You need to talk to a neurosurgeon
right away.
Hold on!
E. R. 7x08 "THE DANCE WE DO"
All right!
Coming.
- Sorry. Did I wake you?
- Yeah, kind of.
Dr. Kovac ordered breakfast.
I'm sorry.
- Have a good day.
- You too.
- Sorry. I told him to leave it outside.
- That's okay. I had to get up.
- Have some if you want.
- No, thanks.
You want to take a shower?
I'm almost done.
I have to stop home.
- You working today?
- Yeah.
- Are you?
- No, no.
Okay.
See you later, then.
Morning.
- How was your night?
- What's all this?
I borrowed the sewing machine
from Marge.
Who's Marge?
Marge is your neighbor in 2A. An adorable
woman. I'll introduce you to her.
Divorced.
- Coffee's fresh.
- Thanks.
- You been up all night?
- No. I got up early just to finish this.
I have a big interview today.
- Where'd you get all that fabric?
- Sale at the yardage store.
And then I talked them
into a bit more of a discount.
I used the money you gave me for
bus fare. I know it wasn't my money.
I will pay you back when I get this job.
It's a fabulous place. Very high-end.
Big commissions.
I'll buy us all-new furniture.
There. Finished.
Tell me what you think.
I copied it from something I saw in
a magazine. The skirt and everything.
I shortened the jacket. I changed...
- You don't like it.
- No, I do.
Do you?
You know what I got you?
Something great. Knit-jersey fabric.
I love the jersey. Where is it?
I'm gonna make you something.
Make that Euro-doctor take notice.
Euro-doctor?
I've been here long enough
to know what's happening.
He's very handsome but too old
to be playing hard to get.
- Well, I thought I had him.
- You do. You just don't know you do.
When you're not looking,
he stares at you all the time.
Here it is! Come here.
Come here. Come here. Come here.
We're gonna make a wraparound dress
with a plunging neckline.
There we go.
- He stares at me?
- All the time.
- I'm gonna take some measurements.
- No. I have to shower before work.
My interview isn't until noon.
- Maybe we could have breakfast?
- Okay. If there's time.
Well, hurry up.
Honey, have you got any-?
What are you doing?
Counting your pills.
- Why?
- Just checking.
- I told you I'd take them.
- I know.
Did I pass inspection?
You taking any Prozac?
I'm normal. I'm normal. I'm a little
nervous about this interview, but-
- Prozac. Zoloft. Effexor.
- I gave them to you.
- Did you get more?
- How?
Mom!
I told you. I promised you.
You don't believe me?
- Can you do me a favor?
- Anything.
Come to the hospital with me.
- What for?
- A blood test.
- A blood test?
- Yes.
- Would you do that for me?
- Sure. Sure, I'd do anything for you.
E. R.
There was no epidural. I was the only
one remotely close to the dura.
- Answer the questions. You'll do fine.
- I had to have punctured it.
It's a known risk.
It does not constitute negligence.
Mark, missing a leak does.
I don't even remember looking
before I removed the endoscope.
You've done 100 of these. You know
the procedure. There was a bad outcome.
They're looking for someone to blame.
It doesn't mean you did anything wrong.
- Do you want me to ride with you?
- No, go to work.
You sure?
Hey. Don't go jogging
into any more street signs.
- Hard as a rock.
- Apparently not.
- How long do these depositions last?
- Call me if it goes past midnight.
- What?
- I'm just kidding.
I hate to go on an interview
with a big Band-Aid on my arm.
- What will they think?
- You have a suit jacket.
Yeah. Yeah. Hope I don't have to take it
off if the room gets warm or something.
- Tell them you gave blood.
- Yeah. I don't wanna be late, though.
Rule number one is,
do not be late for an interview.
- This will just take a minute.
- I'd like to be early.
What if I go and come back?
Then if you want to do this...
Okay. Hold still.
I just don't understand, Abby.
I mean, you've let me in your home.
We're getting along so well.
This is an absolute gift. I mean,
what will taking my blood accomplish?
- Nothing, hopefully.
- Wait, stop. Stop. Stop.
Listen to me, honey. Listen.
When this test comes
back negative or positive...
...or whatever it's supposed to be,
then you're gonna feel foolish...
...and I'm gonna be hurt.
And then you're gonna feel bad.
You can't touch
the vein after it's clean.
- That can't be what you want!
- It's not.
Then, honey, let's just not do this!
- Need some help in here?
- No, we're fine.
- Hi, Dave.
- Hey. Hello, Mrs. Lockhart.
- Oh, it's Wyczenski.
- Right. Right. Are you not feeling well?
- No. Why, do I look sick?
- No, no. Actually, you look great.
Thank you.
You look good too.
Thank you. What's the draw for?
I'm giving blood.
- What? That's what you told me to say.
- Go. Just go. Go ahead.
- What?
- Just go. I don't want you to be late.
- Really?
- Yes.
- Honestly?
Sweetie, I love you.
Okay. Thank you.
- Bye, Dave.
- It's good to see you, Miss W.
Miss W. I like that. Miss W.
I'll call you, let you know how it goes.
Bye.
Must be nice having such good genes.
Knowing that you're gonna
grow up looking like that.
You got a...
- Is this about a patient?
- No.
- Bye, Randi.
- Hi, Maggie.
- Love that top!
- Thanks.
- He's supposed to be working.
- Abby, have you seen Dr. Malucci?
- He's around here somewhere.
- Tell him Stephanie stopped by.
- Your last name?
- He knows my last name.
I don't get it. He had some other
girl looking for him yesterday.
Fire enough shots,
eventually you hit something.
- Or catch something.
- Don't knock it until you try it.
What?
Abby! A girl out here needs
help! She's bleeding!
Some kids, they
just threw her from a car.
- Honey? Honey, here you are. Take this.
- What happened?
- They hardly stopped the car.
- I'm okay.
- No, you're not.
- Step back.
Okay. Let's sit down. Come on.
Careful. Okay, okay.
- What's your name?
- Kynesha.
Okay, Kynesha.
Lean back. Let me take a look.
- Did someone beat you up?
- I fell.
Nonsense. Honey, who did this?
- Mom, go to your interview.
- I'm trying to help.
We don't need your help. Go.
Did you have a loss of consciousness?
Any trouble breathing?
Get a gurney and page X-ray.
Abby?
Yeah.
Mr. Resnik called from the garage.
He's on his way up now.
Thank you.
We'll wait five minutes,
and then we'll leave.
I can stay.
I've taken the whole day off.
We shouldn't have
to play these kind of games.
- Gordy, good to see you.
- Bruce.
Sorry to keep you waiting. There was
a pileup on the expressway. Real mess.
- I'm sure.
- You must be Dr. Corday.
- Bruce Resnik. Pleasure to meet you.
- And you.
They didn't tell me
you were so stunning.
That's okay.
You don't have to respond.
- Has the court reporter set up?
- In the library.
Let's get going.
After you.
- Hey, Irene. How are you this morning?
- Fine, Mr. Resnik. Yourself?
- Can't complain. Hey, how are you?
- Fine, thank you.
Please have a seat.
Ignore the camera. Thank you.
Everyone was rubbernecking
past this accident.
I waited my turn. So, of course,
I take a look. You know, human nature.
And these firemen are using
one of those big steel things to cut.
- What do you call them?
- Jaws of Life.
Jaws of Life! Right. I mean,
it looked pretty dangerous to me.
- You ever use one of those?
- No, not personally.
It was cutting into the car like
a can opener. Anyway, shall we start?
Certainly.
Please raise your right hand.
- There's no Bible?
- No.
Do you swear to tell the truth
in this matter, so help you God?
Yes.
We are on the record in a deposition on
the behalf of the plaintiff, Al Patterson.
Plaintiff's attorney's Bruce Resnik.
Gordon Price for defense.
Doctor, state and spell
your name for the record.
Elizabeth Corday. C-O-R-D-A-Y.
Doctor, how long
have you been a surgeon?
Including Residency?
Ten years.
Have you ever had
a deposition taken before?
- No, this is the first.
- After 10 years, that's pretty good.
Well, only three have been in America.
Touché.
Extraocular movements are intact.
Okay, Kynesha. We need to remove your
pants so I can check for injuries, okay?
- It's just my face.
- I know, but we still need to check.
I'll be right back.
- Hey, Peter.
- Hey.
There's an inguinal hernia
in Curtain 3. Could you look?
Yeah, after the assault victim.
We've got it.
Probably just a facial fracture.
Well, I'll clear the belly.
She's stable.
There's blood in her underwear.
She says it's her period.
Get a rape kit.
Peter, wait.
You shouldn't take this one.
Why?
It's Jesse's girlfriend.
I can take care of her.
I'm gonna come in close
and check the back of your eyes.
Let's take a look in your ears now.
Peter!
Good. No hemotympanum.
- What's that?
- That means you didn't crack your skull.
- I'm Dr. Benton.
- I know.
Is there anyone you want us to call?
Mother, father?
She won't be home.
The re-enhancing lesion and central
necrosis on MRI was suspicious.
The biopsy confirms it.
Another pathologist should take a look.
Could be an astrocytoma.
Two neuro specialists have reviewed
the slides independently. They concur.
It's a GBM.
What's the survival rate?
Untreated, eight weeks.
With radiation therapy, the average
increases six to nine months.
So you need to go see
a radiation oncologist today.
What about surgery?
I'm afraid the tumor is inoperable.
- Why?
- It looks like it invaded Broca's area.
The speech arrest you were experiencing
was probably the result of a focal seizure.
Even if we removed the entire tumor,
you'd most likely be left...
...with the inability to speak
and understand language.
- Communication.
- More than communication.
You'd lose all ability to comprehend,
interact with the world around you.
Essentially, what makes you human.
Even if you consented,
I wouldn't even consider operating.
We'll keep you on Dilantin,
300 milligrams daily.
Do you have disability insurance?
Dr. Greene?
Yeah.
What's going on, Carter?
Why are we so backed up?
I just got here.
Weaver's not on till tonight.
This happens when she's off.
- Hey, what happened to your head?
- Jogging. I ran into a street sign.
She left you a note.
- Take the shoulder pain and the vertigo.
- Dr. Greene, guy with palpitations.
Tachycardic at 300.
BP is 100/70. Normal mentation.
- Six of adenosine. I'll be right there.
- Did you say heart rate was 300?
If it's Wolff-Parkinson-White,
adenosine could put him into V-fib.
Yeah, right. 100 milligrams
procainamide. IV every 10 minutes.
- Thanks, Carter.
- Sure. You okay?
Yeah. It's been a long morning.
Listen, we have to do
a blood and urine test on you.
- It's your three-month mark.
- Right now?
- Sometime in the next six hours.
- Whenever.
Listen, if you want privacy, I'll do the
stick. Otherwise, you can ask a nurse.
Yeah, I'll ask Abby.
- Randi, what's open?
- Exam 1.
Meet you there.
Liver and spleen are good.
No peritoneal free fluid.
No lacerations or contusions.
Kynesha, when's the last time
you had intercourse?
I don't remember.
Woods lamp.
I'll get the lights.
- What's that do?
- Hold on.
- There's no semen.
- What?
We got some abrasions, but no stridor.
I need to do a pelvic exam, Kynesha.
Do you know what that is?
- No. I'm on my period. I told you.
- I still need to check.
- Hey, hey, hey.
- Sit down.
- Let me go!
- Come on. Calm down.
Kynesha, it's important
we give you an exam.
Not down there. Just fix my face.
Look, we know it's hard, but if someone
sexually assaulted you, we have to check.
I didn't get raped.
I got beat up. That's all.
- Who beat you up?
- I got jumped out. No big thing.
- Of a gang?
- I did okay.
Some girls get real messed up.
I did okay.
So you concede Mr. Patterson's
surgery started at 5: 17 p. m.
According to the chart, yes.
And you sent Mr. Patterson
to Pre-Op at 2: 15 p. m.?
- Approximately, yes.
- Expecting to operate within the hour?
- Expecting to operate immediately.
- But you didn't.
You didn't start the operation
for another three hours, did you?
- No.
- Why not?
I'm on emergency call.
A life-threatening gunshot wound
to a 14-year-old boy came in.
I had to respond.
- And were you able to save this boy?
- No.
And this Jesse Robbins...
- Did you know him?
- By association, yes.
And that association was through
a colleague, Dr. Peter Benton?
- He was Dr. Benton's nephew.
- And Dr. Benton is your former lover?
Don't answer that.
Was the boy you weren't able to save
the nephew of your former lover?
Move it along, Bruce. That has no
probative value, and she's not answering.
- Are you refusing to answer that-?
- She's not answering.
Fine. She'll answer
in front of the judge.
So the death of his nephew
was upsetting to you.
- Of course.
- How long did it upset you?
I'm not sure.
Losing a young boy, a boy you knew, a
boy close to someone you cared about...
...it must have been
quite overwhelming.
Is that a question?
- Was it overwhelming?
- At that moment.
So overwhelming and tragic
that it was still on your mind...
...while you operated on my client.
Wasn't it, Dr. Corday?
Guess I should have had that
blood transfusion this morning, huh?
Come on. That was funny.
This is kind of ironic, isn't it?
Check my cholesterol while you're at it?
Hey, you!
You're supposed to be watching this.
You think I want
to be doing this, Carter?
I don't have better things to do?
- Okay. What should I do with this?
- Give it to me.
- Are we done?
- Yeah.
Abby, paramedics called.
Your mom's hurt. She's asking for you.
- What happened?
- I don't know.
She's outside a clothing store
on Oak Street.
If she wants to give names,
I'll check it out.
She's afraid.
She's not going to give names.
Dr. Benton? She wants to talk to you.
If she changes her mind,
give me a call.
- Peter, I said I'd take care of her.
- I got it.
Looks like you broke your cheekbone.
Gonna have to do
a CAT scan of your face.
So you're really gonna protect
the girls who did this?
I'm protecting myself. If they find out
I said something, they gonna kill me.
Like they did Jesse?
You don't know that.
I know he wasn't
a gang member and you are.
- Was.
- The only reason he was...
...in that neighborhood
is because of you.
He only came there twice.
Said he didn't like me banging.
Kept telling me that
I was better than all that.
That he loved me.
He was gonna get me out.
You're telling me
that's why they killed him?
He ditched school.
Tried to get me to come over.
Told me that his mom
was gonna figure things out.
We had a fight.
I was walking away...
...when it happened.
You saw who shot him?
That's why I don't want to be
a part of it no more.
I loved him too.
Who shot him, Kynesha?
You just said you loved him.
- You'll tell the cops if I told you.
- No.
- Why you asking?
- Because I gotta know.
- You swear you ain't gonna say nothing?
- Kynesha...
Who murdered my nephew?
- You need to hold still.
- My daughter is a doctor.
I don't need you to do any of this.
Don't touch me.
She's a doctor.
She will be here. She can do this.
Abby, this wasn't my fault.
This man came after me.
You her daughter?
- She was shoplifting.
- I was not!
Why would I shoplift
a $10 scarf?
- It's a $300 scarf.
- Well, it looks like a $10 scarf!
She ran straight into my door.
Shattered glass everywhere.
You don't want to arrest her.
It's not worth it. I'm a nurse-
- What's wrong with her?
- Nothing's wrong with me!
- What's wrong with you?
- She has a mood disorder.
- She was stealing.
- She wasn't stealing, she was confused.
You weren't there. She walked into
the store, demanded a job. I explained-
Let me tell you something, dearie,
I have better retail skills than you!
Be quiet, Mom!
Common courtesy
and politeness being two of them!
Can I give you my phone number,
and then I'll pay for the glass?
- Is that cool?
- What if she comes back?
- I have customers in there.
- She won't come back.
- You'll take care of it?
- Yes, I promise.
Fine! Just get her out of here!
Up to 5 of Haldol, p. r.n.
- You got it?
- Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
- What? You wanted to see me?
- Yeah.
Your naltrexone level
was nondetectable.
- My naltrexone level?
- You're supposed to be on 50 mgs a day.
I thought it was a drug screen. I didn't
know you were screening for naltrexone.
It's in your contract.
My prescription ran out,
and I haven't had time to refill it.
You know that
it's part of the agreement.
And I'm taking it.
I don't need it, and I'm taking it.
What?
You're not the only one
with something at stake here.
We put ourselves on the line
to give you a fresh start.
In any other circumstance,
you'd either be dead or in jail.
Fresh start, huh? You really
think this has been a fresh start?
I think that I've done absolutely
everything that you've asked of me.
And I've done it without complaint.
I think that I've obeyed these arbitrary
and arcane rules and regulations...
...about what patients I can treat
and what patients I can't.
I think I've peed into cups.
I think you've taken my blood.
And I think at some point,
it's gonna have to be enough.
I think at some point, you're
actually gonna have to trust me.
Hey, Mark!
I need some help in here! Chuny,
get in here and get me some Ativan!
- Mark!
- Oh, my God! What happened?
- Get the Ativan.
- How much?
Four milligrams now.
Mark.
- Did he hit his head?
- No.
- Does he have a fever?
- I don't know. He just started seizing.
Hold him still.
All right.
Start him on 15 liters of O-2.
Get a line going. And then
I need a pulse ox and a set of vitals.
Get a tox screen.
Finger stick of glucose.
- What do you want for labs?
- CBC and a Chem-20.
Carter?
Dr. Greene? Hey, hey, Mark!
Can you hear me?
- Squeeze my hands. Right and left.
- What happened?
You had a seizure.
Your vitals have been stable.
You didn't drop your sats.
We're gonna take you for a head CT.
See if you can follow my finger with
your eyes. Come on. Just lay back.
- No.
- We need to work this up.
- I don't want to work it up.
- Neuro is coming for a consult.
- It's not necessary.
- You had a new onset seizure.
I just need a Dilantin level.
I can go to the outpatient lab.
- Relax. I called Kovac in to cover.
- You've got a Hep-Lock on your arm.
- I'll handle it. I'll handle it!
- Mark. Mark.
- Dr. Greene, are you okay?
- I'm fine.
Hey, boss, what are you doing?
I heard you had a seizure.
Yeah? You heard wrong.
Mr. Patterson's condition needed
immediate surgical attention, did it not?
It depends on what
you mean by "immediate. "
- You had to operate that day.
- Within the next 24 hours.
The endoscopic surgery is certainly
the fastest procedure, correct?
- Among other benefits.
- So it was more convenient for you.
I base my surgical opinions
on what I perceive...
...to be in the best
interests of the patient.
- The recovery, how-
- Let me try again.
Perhaps you didn't hear the question.
The endoscopic surgery was faster...
...and easier on your schedule
than the alternate open procedure.
- Of course, but-
- Thank you.
How long does
the endoscopic procedure take?
My schedule had nothing whatsoever
to do with my advice to Mr. Patterson.
Please strike that as nonresponsive.
Dr. Corday, how long does the
endoscopic procedure take to perform?
About an hour.
But you performed Mr. Patterson's
endoscopic discectomy in 42 minutes.
Correct?
I don't know.
I'd have to check the operative report.
If the operative report
stated that you were in the O.R...
...less than 43 minutes,
would you say that's correct?
It could be.
Do you have any reason to doubt
the veracity of the operative report?
No.
Would it surprise you that
of the 87 endoscopic discectomies...
...you performed before November 16,
your fastest time was 54 minutes?
Twelve minutes slower
than Mr. Patterson.
- Objection. You're testifying, Bruce.
- It's a question.
- She can count.
- Would that surprise you?
Let's move on.
Did you know the fastest
you performed this procedure...
...was 12 minutes slower
than Mr. Patterson's surgery?
I do now.
- You don't time yourself?
- It's not a race.
Then why did the circulating
nurse remind you it was 10 to 6?
Objection.
Assumes facts not in evidence.
Do you recall the circulating
nurse reminding you that...
...it was 10 to 6 while you were
operating on Mr. Patterson?
- Yes.
- Why did you need to be reminded?
To keep me on schedule.
What did you have scheduled
after Mr. Patterson's surgery?
I had an engagement.
Someplace more important
you had to be?
No, and I resent the inference.
What inference is that?
That I rushed Mr. Patterson's surgery...
- ... to satisfy a personal obligation.
- That's it. We're taking a break.
- Did you rush?
- Don't answer that.
Did the nurse remind you of the time
because you needed to leave by 6?
- Yes.
- We're taking a break.
- Did you get that?
- We're off the record. Stop typing.
Now, I said we're taking a break.
Let's go.
All I wanted to do was talk to the owner.
If I talked to him, I knew he'd hire me.
- What happened?
- I don't know.
- Dr. Greene had a seizure?
- Yeah.
I've never understood people
who make themselves feel big...
...by making other people feel small.
Let me tell you. I've got experience.
- Sit down. Sit down.
- You know what? She was threatened.
She knew I could outsell her.
She knew it.
So she sent that Neanderthal in on me.
You know why? She was threatened.
Did you even have an interview?
Of course I had an interview.
Until she chased me into the window.
- God, this is bad! This is bad.
- You need stitches.
Here. Sit down. We'll get an x-ray
and make sure there's no glass in it.
- Keep pressure on it. I'll be right back.
- All right. Abby. Abby.
- You're mad at me.
- No, Mom, I'm not mad at you.
- I thought you would be mad.
- Sit down.
I have plenty of experience.
Plenty of experience.
Do you think I'm gonna
put up with that? Well, I'm not.
I'm not gonna put up with that.
See if I don't.
I hate people like that.
I have so much
more experience than you.
I don't think
she's gonna say anything.
It seems like
she wants us to get this girl.
I gave you the name.
Why don't you pick the girl up?
We have to get it from her.
What if she doesn't say anything?
Depends.
We can bring in the D.A., maybe a judge.
There's fluid in the maxillary sinus.
No depressed fracture.
Good. Good.
Kynesha, there are a couple of guys
out here that need to talk to you.
No! No way!
I told you I don't know nothing!
- Looks like you're feeling better.
- Yeah.
I got my prescription refilled.
Do you want to see me take it?
Thanks for helping me out.
Sure. You want
to tell me what happened?
Not particularly.
You know, I did treat you.
Technically, I am your doctor.
Anything you tell me is confidential.
Okay, doctor.
It's quite simple.
I have a brain tumor.
- What?
- Glioblastoma multiforme.
Bummer, huh?
Gets better.
I found out that it's inoperable.
- Mark. I'm sorry.
- Yeah. Well...
You're up.
What are you gonna do?
Die, I guess.
After today, I probably won't
be able to work anymore, so...
- Did you get a second opinion?
- They double-checked the biopsy.
No, by another neurosurgeon.
There's gotta be a clinical trial
going on someplace.
Yeah. Looking into it.
Looks like they need you.
Are you gonna be okay?
Stupid question, Carter.
Do me a favor.
Try and keep the rumors from spreading
before I get a chance to talk to Elizabeth.
Sure.
- Do you know what time it is?
-2:47.
- Correct, but it's not the right answer.
- It's not?
No, the right answer is "yes" or "no. "
Yes or no when possible.
Don't elaborate.
Not all questions
have a yes or no answer.
I understand. Yes or no
when possible. Don't elaborate.
We don't win cases in deposition,
but we can lose them.
At best, this stain follows you
for the rest of your career.
At worst, you lose your license.
We're not here to win an argument.
This is about information.
He's looking to gain information
to use against you in court.
We're looking to limit that information.
You mean hide the truth.
I didn't say that.
How many do you think? Stitches?
- Four. Five.
- Five?
You're so good at this.
You're so gentle.
Thank you.
It's hard to believe because you
have such great, big, masculine hands.
Sit still. Don't move.
Don't move. Don't move.
Eyelash. See?
Okay, now you have
to make a wish and blow.
That's all right.
Okay.
I'll blow for you.
What did you wish for? Don't tell me.
Don't tell me. Don't tell me.
- I'm sorry.
- You're sorry for what?
It's part of the disease.
Yes. We're going to now apologize for
your diseased mother, are we? Are we?
She's always misbehaving. Abby never
wanted me around her friends.
- She was always ashamed.
- Stop it.
Ashamed and embarrassed.
- You think I don't know?
- Let him finish your hand.
You would walk right by me
and pretend you didn't know me.
- You'd pretend I didn't exist.
- Let him finish your hand and shut up!
- Don't sass me! I'm your mother!
- Not by choice.
Okay. All right. Okay!
Do you want a 5 of Haldol?
- No! Abby, I'm sorry! Abby, I'm sorry.
- Do you want 5 of Haldol?
- I don't want Haldol!
- Behave, and we won't give you anything.
Don't! You let me go!
I'm leaving! I'm leaving!
I'm leaving! I'm leaving! I'm leaving!
I am leaving!
No! No!
- You want a 5 of Haldol?
- Get restraints, stat! Start an IV!
Abby! Abby! Abby, no!
Don't let them do this to me! Abby!
- Don't let them...
- Starting a line with saline.
Here! Arm restraints!
Okay, call Psych.
Put her on the monitor.
Please! Please don't let them
do this, Abby!
- Come on, Maggie. Calm down.
- No!
- Maggie! Maggie!
- Don't! Don't!
You're my daughter, you little bitch!
Make them stop!
They're ready to start again.
You okay? You look a little peaked.
I'm fine.
We're getting to the critical stage.
If you don't feel you can
maintain your composure-
- No. No, I want to get this over with.
- Okay.
- What's he doing here?
- It's his deposition.
He has a right to be here, like you
have a right to be at our depositions.
- Don't they have to tell us?
- He's here to rattle you.
- Just stay calm. Pretend he's not there.
- Pretend he's not there.
- Don't let it affect your testimony.
- Ready to start?
Yes. Okay?
You removed the restraints?
I can admit her voluntarily, but she
doesn't meet the criteria for a hold.
- She ran through a plate-glass window.
- An accident. She's not gravely disabled.
- Not a danger to herself or others.
- That's debatable.
She's rapid-cycling. Probably
experiencing a drug-induced mania.
- Blood alcohol's 0.092.
- Well, that'll do it.
So do you want me to admit her?
- I don't care.
- Okay, I'll do it.
She wants to talk to you.
She's remorseful.
- She wants to apologize.
- No, thank you.
Okay.
- Abby, I'm sorry.
- Hey, Maggie...
- I'll go in the hospital. I'll get better.
- Go back inside.
- Back to bed.
- I'll get better.
- It's all right. It's all right.
- I'll get better. I'll get better.
Get some frozen peas. Reuse them every
four hours on your face for 20 minutes.
You can take some
ibuprofen for the pain.
I want you to come back for a recheck.
Hey, he was my nephew.
You knew I had to do something.
LOL, complains of weakness...
- Yeah. Good luck.
- ... while under a hair dryer.
Ma'am, were you having
any chest pain or shortness of breath?
No, dear.
The dryer was just set too high.
Okay. EKG, CBC, Chem-7
and get a chest.
- I'll be right with you, Mrs. Fruhman.
- Thank you, dear.
They think they're gonna find
the shooters who killed Jesse.
Good. I hope it helps.
Yeah. Cleo...
I got angry, you know?
And I got you angry.
You're the only thing in my life
that makes sense right now.
You know, I'm trying to say
I'm, you know, sorry.
Buy me some dinner.
I'll consider your apology.
Well, then in your medical opinion,
what caused the meningocele...
...that cut off the blood supply
to Mr. Patterson's spinal cord?
A leak of CSF, cerebrospinal fluid
from the dura,
which covers the spinal canal.
Which means you must have punctured
the dura during the procedure.
That seems evident now, yes.
- It wasn't evident during the procedure?
- No.
- It was evident to the anesthesiologist.
- Objection. Argumentative.
According to the operative report,
Dr. Babcock, the anesthesiologist...
...drew your attention to spinal fluid
in the surgical field at 10 to 6.
- Correct?
- No.
- The note says 10 to 6, doesn't it?
- Yes.
- So the report is wrong?
- No. He did draw my attention to fluid.
- Fluid we now know to be spinal fluid.
- No.
- What could it have been, doctor?
- Saline.
But you understood the anesthesiologist
was concerned it might be spinal fluid?
Yes.
How did you satisfy
yourself that it wasn't?
I suctioned the irrigation saline
and did not see any persistent CSF.
Did you look?
I can't operate without looking.
Well, given that it was 10 to 6,
that you were in a hurry...
...the nurse simultaneously
reminding you of your date-
Objection. Can we get
to a question, Bruce?
Did you perform a complete and
competent inspection of the field...
...to ensure there were no CSF leaks?
Sometimes leaks are so small
you cannot detect them visually.
Nevertheless, did you perform
a thorough inspection?
That's procedure.
And you followed procedure
by performing a thorough inspection?
Objection. Asked and answered.
It's been asked.
It has not been answered.
What was the question?
Did you perform a thorough
and competent inspection...
...specifically looking for possible
CSF leaks before you closed?
Yes.
- Where did you go? I was looking for you.
- I took a walk. Got a cup of coffee.
- You didn't get my page?
- I knew what it was about.
Legaspi was trying to find a bed
for your mom, and she just took off.
I figured. Thanks.
Thought you'd want
to check your apartment-
She's not there.
- You checked?
- No. This is the end of the cycle.
Our cycle. She disappears.
And for months,
I don't know where she is...
...or what she's doing
or if she's alive.
And then eventually, she'll turn up
somewhere, and I'll have to deal with it.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't be.
I knew how it would end
when she showed up.
It's the dance we do.
You get lost in it for a little while,
but it always ends the same.
- Do you-?
- You ready?
Yeah.
Carter, I forgot to tell Weaver enzymes
are pending on Mr. Albe in 4.
- I'll tell her.
- Thanks.
Good night, Carter.
- You coming in?
- I don't want to intrude.
They're probably just eating.
Jackie makes so much food anyway.
They need some time to themselves.
I'll wait for an invitation.
All right. I'll just grab some stuff
for tomorrow. I'll be right back.
Dr. Benton.
What are you doing here?
- I went to the store, like you said.
- Jackie see you?
- No.
- You can't be here.
The cops was hooking up the cousins.
They gonna think it was me!
- Have you been home yet?
- No. They're gonna kill me! I'm dead!
- Come on. Get in the car.
- I talked to the cops. I can't go home.
- I told you this was gonna happen.
- Get in the car. I'll figure out something.
Mark?
I'm up here.
- What are you doing?
- Just thinking.
How did it go?
Terribly.
What happened?
What? What is it?
I lied.
The fact is, I rushed.
I rushed through and didn't inspect
the entire surgical field.
That man will never walk again...
...because I wanted
to get out early for the weekend.
And I couldn't
even claim responsibility.
I sat there, and I swore to God,
and I lied to save myself.
God owes us one.
I think you're allowed
to be selfish for a while.
I didn't run into a street sign.
I had a biopsy.
Those headaches weren't from hockey.
Subtitles by SDI Media Group
Ripped by blade2 for TusSeries
www.tvsubtitles.net