Previously on ER:
Glass of wine and a hot bath
at the end of the day helps.
Hmm, it sounds good to me.
...our water bill 'cause I need to...
- Do you live with someone?
- We love you.
- I can't do this anymore.
- There's a little girl.
Curtis Ames.
He was a patient of mine.
He followed my wife
and child to the park.
Help me protect my family.
Subtitles : Willow's Team
Transcript : Raceman
www.forom.com
My mom used to put it in a trash bag.
Chicken broth and a can of Crisco.
Yikes. Grill it on the barbecue.
You'll never go back.
I read that brining keeps the juices in.
Hey, did you remember to take
the giblets out of the marinade?
- Take what out of what?
- C-spine is clear.
Well, we should at least
try to pull off the gravy.
All right, sir, I'm gonna take
this collar off.
Let us know if anything hurts, okay?
Deep fried turkey
is a religious experience.
- Gross.
- You'd rather cook it in a trash bag?
Americans, so sentimental
about their holidays.
This from the guy that celebrates
Croatian Independence,
Croatian State Day and something
called Patriotic Gratitude Day.
- Oh, no.
- What?
I have ten minutes left in my shift
and the transport pager goes off.
- I'll go.
- No, you can't. You're an intern.
Maybe the dispatcher just wants
to say "Happy Thanksgiving."
Yeah, right, I'm sure that's what it is.
- Jane? Jane!
- Abby.
You're supposed to carry the transport
pager overnight, right?
- Uh, yeah.
- Well, it just went off,
and I was thinking maybe
you could just take it?
- Mmm... no.
- No?
Come on.
Why not?
Five more minutes,
it would've been your call anyway.
Sorry, Abby, it just doesn't
really work that way.
What way?
Well, if the pager goes off during
your shift, then you have to go.
Yeah, but I just want to spend
Thanksgiving with my kid.
You know, it's like that story with the guy
who's hunting dinosaurs and he strays off the path
and steps on a butterfly and then
everything in the future's ever so
- slightly different.
- What?
It's bad karma to mess
with the universal order of things.
Erase unicycle man.
He can go.
- Ray.
- Yeah?
- Take this run, I'll owe you big time.
- Ooh, I'd love to.
- Great.
- I can't.
Pratt thinks I'm losing too much ER time.
He banned me from transports.
Well, I just like having you near me, Ray.
Surprise, surprise-- you all get me
instead of Morris tonight.
He begged me to switch so
he could spend time with his kids.
That's why I'm here.
What's your excuse?
Henry went to Orlando with his grandparents.
I figured I might as well come in.
Oh. I love working on Thanksgiving.
Everybody's at home
eating and watching football,
even the freaks.
Ah, the great American tradition
of sanctioned gluttony. No, thanks.
I'm not trying to block the run,
I'm just asking does a garden variety
MI really need a doc on board?
Miss Lulu Davis, age 12, vomiting
and abdominal pain times two hours.
- Hi, I'm Dr. Figler.
- Hey, Lulu.
We'll take care of you.
I got this.
- Oh, I got here first.
- Yeah, but I'm good with kids.
- Are you saying that I'm not?
- No, hold on. Wait a minute.
H-H-Hold on a second.
Lulu, are you okay?
Oops.
Cranberries.
Sorry, Jane.
Karma sucks.
Three hours at 450.
- And don't forget to baste.
- How often?
I don't know.
30 minutes?
I don't know. I'll probably be home
in time to mash the potatoes.
- Okay, what do I do with the pumpkin?
- Oh... I forgot about the pie.
- Dr. Kovac, you got a minute?
- Uh, yeah, just a second.
I thought pumpkins
were only for Halloween.
You know what, screw the pie.
I never really liked pumpkins anyway.
Are you sure you just don't want
to order Chinese?
But baste, remember to baste!
I went to see your guy,
Curtis Ames, yesterday.
He didn't know anything
about any kid's toy.
Did he admit to following
them to the park?
He didn't know
what I was talking about.
Look, the guy's had a pretty
tough time at things.
You know, he's barely getting by.
Okay, I realize that, but that's no excuse
for messing with my family.
If you want my opinion,
he's too busy trying to feed and clothe
himself to mess with anyone, Doc.
Right.
- You get airsick?
- No.
Claustrophobic?
Maybe you should just
tell me about the patient.
88-year-old female, anterior MI.
I can't tell you how many docs
think they can handle this,
- then freak out at altitude.
- I work in an ER.
- It's pretty hard to freak me out.
- You do okay with heights, honey?
Loud noises?
Yeah, but mice make me jump
on a chair and say, "Eek."
Danny!
Meet Dr. Lockhart!
- Hi!
- Sit!
Don't stand.
Don't disembark till we tell you to.
Keep your headset and
your seatbelt on at all times.
If you need to speak to us,
slide this switch this way
to activate the intercom.
Do not press that button.
That transmits over the radio.
This baby is tight.
Excuse me?
First night out after
two months of upgrades.
Satellite phone, GPS, new hoist.
All the cool toys.
I'm Jasper.
This is Evan.
Hey.
What'd you say your name was?
- Abby.
# Come fly with me #
# Let's float down to Peru #
# In llama land #
# There's a one-man band #
# And he'll toot
his flute for you #
# Come fly with me, Abby #
# Let's take off
In the blue #
Does it hurt when I press
or when I let go?
About the same.
- I'm thirsty.
- Too bad. You're NPO.
- What's that?
- "Nil per os."  Nothing by mouth.
Food or liquids may exacerbate
or complicate an obstruction,
volvulus or inflammation.
Not to mention increased aspiration risk
during intubation should you
be going to the OR tonight.
Um... I'm sorry I threw up on you.
Oh, I don't mind the fact that I had to take
a shower to get the chunks out of my hair.
I just honestly don't know how I'm gonna
survive a whole shift dressed like this.
Hey, Lulu, I'm gonna order up a few tests
to see what's going on in there, okay?
I mean, bunnies, puppy dogs--
I'm like breaking out in hives.
Jane, why don't you let me
take it from here.
- Your parents are on their way, right?
- Uh, yeah, definitely.
I think it's hip. I think it's fetishy.
I think you totally pull it off.
Shut up, Gates.
Hey, Sam, I need a CBC
on the little girl in two.
And order up an extra red top if you can
just in case the blood bank needs it.
- Got it.
- Hey, Alex.
Don't ya have anything better to do than hangout
with a bunch of losers like us on Thanksgiving?
If he stayed at home,
he'd play video games all night, so
I figured I'd bring him in here and
make him do a little community service.
That's cool, man.
Yeah, handing out cookies to sick people.
That's really cool.
Hey, it could be worse.
You could be one of those sick people.
Four pages in the last 20 minutes?
- What's the crisis, Dr. Gates?
- Oh, no crisis.
It's just an incarcerated hernia, a gluteal
abscess, road rash that needs skin grafting,
an imbedded drill bit,
rule-out appy on a 12-year-old girl.
- You're making this up.
- I wish I were.
You're sure it's not just an excuse
to keep me down here?
Oh, please, I would never dream
of wasting your time like that.
But really...
must you look so hot all the time?
I mean, even in that ridiculous hat,
I can't concentrate.
- I can't even talk.
- You know,
enough of this harassment.
I have work to do.
Are you the team from County?
Yeah. Watch it. Watch it.
Hi, I'm Dr. Lockhart.
Mom was fine, cooked a 20-pound turkey.
She carved it and then she just collapsed.
- We thought she was kidding around.
- But then we couldn't wake her up.
- That must've been scary.
- Get the history later.
- You guys stay out here.
- We need to examine your mother.
Excuse me, I'm looking for a patient,
Elizabeth Timmons.
Thank heavens.
This way.
You didn't say anything
about her being intubated.
- They never tell the whole story.
- Vitals?
- Tachy to 124, sat 92.
- You got a BP?
Last one was 74/38 on dopa.
- Great. What about an EKG?
- Right here.
- Dr. Russo, thanks for coming.
- Abby Lockhart.
This place gets really backed up
when we have a patient like this.
- Sat's 82.
- She's tombstoning.
- What about thrombolytics?
- Already gave it, no response.
Okay, okay.
I'm sorry.
Can we have a reality check here?
Does this family know how sick she is?
They know she's having a heart attack.
Do they know that she's not breathing
and her blood pressure sucks
and she's probably not perfusing
her brain enough?
I mean, we can't move her.
- She's unstable.
- The family wants her out of here.
- She won't make the trip.
- You don't know that.
If she survives the helicopter, she will probably
die before the family makes it to County.
- What's your point?
- Well...
she's 88 years old.
She's not coming back from this.
Don't you think dying here
with her loved ones
is better than dying alone
in the ICU at County?
Listen, Doctor.
Our job is to scoop and run.
The longer we stay and jaw about it, the
more unstable this little lady's gonna get.
All right, you know what,
just give me five minutes.
I'm gonna make sure they understand.
52 years, rain or shine.
He drives me around the lake
on a tandem bike after Thanksgiving.
Ah, isn't that sweet.
You're blind, Mr. Hunter.
Maybe you should let her drive.
Oh, that wouldn't work at all.
I can't carry a tune.
He drives, I sing.
It's tradition.
Send him to radiology and call me
hen the films get back.
Ray, help.
I need an order for sumatriptan.
- Migraines?
- I get one every Thanksgiving.
- It's the stuffing.
- Okay, 20 milligrams intranasally.
Then why do you eat it?
Because it's amazing.
Mom makes it with bacon and almonds.
Lands me in the hospital every
Thanksgiving. Hmm, but it's worth it.
I'll be right back with your medicine.
Holidays weird me out.
The special foods, the little rituals.
- It's not my thing.
- Yeah,
when I was a kid, Thanksgiving was just an
excuse to stay home all day and watch TV.
I always figured when I grew up
and had kids of my own,
I'd do the whole family thing,
a big banquet, but you know,
here we are, just me and Alex,
hanging out in the hospital.
Didn't your parents demand you
come home for the holiday?
Nah, my mom's in Trinidad
with her new boyfriend
and my dad's never even heard
of a home-cooked meal, so...
Ah, well.
At least you got something hot
waiting for you at home.
What?
Missing your cell phone perhaps?
Yeah, how did you...
Hematology needed you,
so we called your cell phone
and you will never guess who answered.
Surgical med student Katey Alvaro.
- Oh, well, we were studying.
- Right.
I mean, well, she couldn't talk
'cause she was baking you something.
A little treat.
Any chance you could
be wrong about this?
Well, y-yes, but I just--
- based on my experience...
- Well, which is it?
First, you tell us that
he won't survive the trip
and now you say
that you might be wrong.
I know this is hard.
I'm sorry.
- I just think it's important that you take...
- Time's up. Let's go.
- All right, just wait.
- Find the clerk, sign the consent.
- We'll be at County in 45 minutes.
- But she just said that we should think...
It's your mom's only chance.
Okay. Uh, take her.
Come on.
She is going to die.
Yeah, and I'm doing my best
to facilitate a good death for her.
- That's not your job.
- Not your call.
Here's how it works.
The referring hospital refers
and the accepting hospital accepts
and we're just the deliverymen.
- Sorry, delivery people.
- You're denying the responsibility
- that comes with your job.
- I'm not the one who's in denial here.
Good death?
No such thing, babe.
If you think you can make this
a good experience for that family,
you're even more arrogant than I thought.
Mom, if you can hear me,
we'll see you in Chicago. Okay?
Hey, in a few weeks,
you're gonna be a great-grandmother.
Everyone stay back.
God bless you, Dr. Lockhart.
Systolic's holding above 80.
- Yeah, on 20 mikes of dopamine.
- Still counts.
All right, you know,
maybe you were right,
- maybe...
- D-Don't say it. Don't say it.
Nothing more painful than
listening to a lady eat crow.
- I'm not eating crow.
- Which reminds me, I am starving.
- Good idea.
- Turkey, cranberry sauce.
- Wife even baked the bread.
- We got a patient here. She's fine.
You know, I feel sorry for your old man.
What's that supposed to mean?
- It's just the turbulence.
- I don't think so.
Charge the defibrillator now.
Febrile to 101, vomiting
and mild rebound.
How long has this been going on, sweetie?
It started during the salad.
Salad for Thanksgiving?
Your family's weird.
- Tell me about it.
- White count?
Pending.
Are those chocolate chip?
Uh, no.
- Could I have one anyway?
- Um, yeah, sure.
You know, this holiday is a lie.
Really?
Yeah, the only thing the pilgrims
shared with the Indians were measles.
- Okay.
- I'm Lulu.
- Thanks for the cookie.
- Yeah.
Hey, you can't eat that, honey; you're NPO.
Oh, yeah, nil per os.
It's Thanksgiving and I can't even eat.
Alex, what did I tell you about asking the doctors
or nurses before giving away the cookies?
Labs are back.
Her white count's 14.
Let's get a CT. I'll call the scanner.
All right, you know, we talked to
your mom on the phone earlier
and she gave us permission to give you
a very special X ray on your tummy.
She didn't want to talk to me?
No, but she said to make sure
we treat you like a VIP.
- I'm sure she'll be here soon.
- That's okay.
Alex can wait with me.
Right, Alex?
Yeah.
Clear!
- Still v-fib.
- Damn it.
- She's 88 years old.
- Yeah, I tried to make that point an hour ago.
- We're committed now.
- Lido's in.
All right, another mig of epi.
- She's had five rounds of meds.
- Yeah, well, let's make it six.
We never should have brought her up here.
- Darling, it's the job.
- Oh, spare me the platitudes, okay?
Go again. Go !
Clear!
Nothing.
If the scar shows above my bikini,
I'm suing both your asses.
Need some help here!
Ladies, we're in a hospital now.
- Time to grow up.
- Don't tell me what to do, Grandma.
- Grandma?
- You bobble-headed little bitch!
Okay, let's settle down.
All right, what happened?
- She pushed me into the display.
- I fell, she fell.
These three were fighting over a bag
at Bovards' midnight sale.
- All right, come on. Let's go.
- Midnight sale? It's not even 8:00 yet.
The name's just tradition.
It starts at 4:00 in the afternoon now.
Bendi Brioche 80% off.
- Normally $1,800.
- They only did a limited run.
Somehow during the scuffle,
Mandy fell into the nativity display.
- I was pushed.
- Nativity display? It's Thanksgiving.
Yeah, well, that's when
the Christmas decorations go up.
Impaled by a fiberglass
Star of Bethlehem.
Jane, call surgery.
With all that's happened,
I can't keep this now.
Oh, that's so sweet, honey.
Give it back, evil grandma whore.
Wow, this is really sad.
- Hello.
- Hi.
I was just calling to say it's still probably going to be a while.
Are you okay?
Abby?
Abby? You there?
Don't worry.
We're taking good care of your girl.
Are you listening?
Who's that?
You guys are assholes.
- Abby?
- Luka, I'll call you when we land.
Hang up the phone.
- You didn't say good-bye.
- Hang up the phone!
Sorry about that.
- I accidentally mixed up my channels.
- What, are we in fifth grade here?
- Airmedic 6, dispatch.
- Airmedic 6.
Airmedic 6, we have a report of a vehicle
over the side of Highway 16 at Neosha Ravine.
Are you available?
- Why aren't you answering her?
- We're about to time out.
Pilots are only allowed to fly
for a max of 12 hours.
I've been up for almost 11.
Airmedic 6?
So you're just going to ignore her?
Don't worry.
Another unit will get it.
Yeah, but we're not far from Neosha.
Tell her where we are.
You don't have to look
to Daddy for permission.
Just do your job and
tell her where we are.
Dispatch, Airmedic 6.
We're at Highway 12 and county line.
- Are we the closest unit?
- Airmedic 6, that's affirmative.
Then put us on the call.
Airmedic 6,
you're assigned to the incident.
Who is this?
Abby Lockhart. I'm the doctor
on board and we're responding.
Darling, it's the job.
No free air, no fluid.
Looks like the star missed the peritoneum.
The Thanksgiving sales, the parades,
the blockbuster movies.
Those are all just to prime you for the bald-
faced commercialism of the holiday season.
Syringe.
Lidocaine, 1%.
- Your wounds are superficial.
- You got lucky.
Yeah, right.
By the time I get back to the sale, all they'll
have left are bad colors and big sizes.
You were impaled while fighting
over an overpriced vessel
for credit cards and lipstick.
Doesn't that sorta kinda feel like a sign?
Wake up.
A gram of Ancef, 3-0 silk
and irrigation tray.
Jane, uh, stay and assist the doctor.
We should be close!
She said "vehicle," not "bus."
Cheap trick.
How are we supposed to get down there?
If you're taking that long to find
a pulse, it's not worth looking.
Don't waste time with resuscitations.
- Help the people you can help.
- I know how to triage. Thank you.
That bus is unstable.
Keep triaging
until the cavalry gets here.
Help-- my arm!
It won't stop.
I'm telling you, it won't stop.
Okay, okay, okay, let me see.
Let me see.
Just sit down.
Sit down.
Keep pressure on this
and keep your arm up, okay?
We're all gonna freeze
to death out here!
We're gonna get you out
of the cold soon, okay?
How?!
Help! Please! Somebody!
- Over here!
- Stay like that.
- Stay like...
- Wait! Wait!
- I don't know what to do!
- Are more people coming?
- What's the plan? Do you have a plan?
- His foot is pointing the wrong way.
Can you tell me what your name is?
- It's Matt.
- Hi, Matt.
- I'm Abby. I'm a doctor.
- Hey, doc.
No, no, no, no, don't move.
Don't move.
Can you hold his head like this?
Make sure he doesn't move his neck.
I can't feel my leg!
Oh, God.
- Can you move your feet at all?
- No!
- Baby, no!
- It's all right.
I'm gonna go find something
to splint your leg with, okay?
Help! Somebody...
Somebody help!
Please! Help!
Mom, don't close your eyes.
Stay awake, somebody's coming.
- Mom? Mom!
- All right, don't move.
- I'm gonna come back there.
- Mom, she's here now! It's gonna be okay!
Hello?!
- Are you hurt, too?
- No, it's just my mom. Please.
- Hang on.
- You got to get her out.
Mom, it's okay.
Please get her out.
I'm Abby.
I'm a doctor.
- Can you tell me your name?
- Melanie.
- Melanie, can you move at all?
- She's stuck!
Okay. We're gonna get you out
of here, all right?
- Come on. Let's go!
- Are you ready?
One, two, three.
Is... Is that all my blood?
I don't know.
I don't know where
that blood's coming from.
Come on. Fix her!
I can't.
I can't move you now.
- I understand.
- Okay.
- You should take Milo out.
- No! I won't go!
- Baby, go with the doctor.
- No!
Milo, there are people coming with
special equipment. They're gonna help us.
- And I'll wait here with her!
- Milo, I love you.
- This is gonna help you with the pain.
- I need you to be a brave boy now, okay?
- Please, just get him off this bus!
- No!
- Go with the doctor, baby.
- No.
- Milo...
- You can be a good helper.
- No!
- Go ahead.
Milo, come on.
Please, just make sure he's okay.
Let's go, now. Come on.
- No!
- Let's go. Watch your head.
See, I told you it wouldn't hurt.
It's my mom.
She won't stop calling me.
You're lucky.
My foster mother only keeps me for
the money she gets from the state.
When I started barfing at dinner, she...
loaded me into the ambulance
and then went back to her ham.
So... she's not coming.
- That boy is smitten.
- Boys are easy.
You know, Meg and Sarah
are out of town tonight?
Liver looks good.
Which means I have
the place all to myself.
- And why are you telling me this?
- 'Cause Meg and I, it's over.
I thought you weren't together.
We weren't. But now we're not
even not together anymore.
- Fat stranding and a cecal phlegmon.
- She needs the OR. I'll call Crenshaw.
Sit down.
I have a very important job
for you, okay?
I don't want my mom to be alone.
I want you to take that flashlight,
and point it wherever I'm working.
Someone's gonna help her, right?
The fire department's gonna be here soon.
And they'll get her off the bus?
Yeah.
Promise?
All right, don't move, okay?
Just shine that light at me.
Four dead, nine criticals,
14 minor injuries, 11 delayed.
The driver had a passenger manifest,
and the numbers all match up.
Good job. Good job.
All the criticals are off site.
Does this include
the woman on the bus?
No one's going back on that bus
until it's stabilized.
Well, how long is that gonna take?
The anchors aren't holding;
it could be hours.
- She can't make it that long.
- There's nothing we can do about it!
- We are not gonna endanger our guys!
- Calm down.
Hey, nobody's getting back on that bus!
- But she promised!
- She said you guys would go back!
- Oh, yeah, what else you tell him?!
- Why don't you just back off...?
- Mom!
- Hey! Hey!
Mom!
Milo!
Hey! Hey!
Milo, you... Milo, you cannot
get on that bus right now!
- You said they would get her.
- I know.
- You said they'd try.
- Okay.
- I know. It's gonna be okay.
Come on, guys. Give him to me.
Pass him down.
No! No!
Get away!
Melanie?
- Melanie? Can you hear me?
- Milo, he can't...
All right.
All right, everything's gonna be okay.
- No, it's...
- Everything's gonna be all right.
Hey!
I need an IV and a liter of NS in here!
His dad's in Milwaukee.
- Would you... please tell him...
- Okay, Melanie.
Melanie, listen to me.
Help is on the way, all right?
Milo... Milo likes it...
if you break up his toast...
- and scramble it with his eggs.
- Okay.
He'll only let you comb his hair...
if he's wearing his Ronaldinho jersey.
Uh, uh, uh, uh.
No, no, no.
Melanie, stay with me. Melanie, come on.
Stay with me.
Melanie, tell me some more about Milo.
What does Milo like?
He... he likes to sleep with
an inchworm named Charlie.
- Okay, that's good. What else?
- Trying to get us all killed?
I'm trying to keep her alive.
- You are out of your mind.
- Well, what are you doing here?
Thought you might need this.
Hey, Katey, it's me.
Uh, I think you have my cell phone.
Want to come by later and pick it up,
if that's okay. Call me.
Marsupialized the abscess on your shooter,
sent the implanted chip to pathology,
convinced Captain Kangaroo to stop eating
erasers, and what's the deal with the new nurse?
- You mean Jane?
- Yeah.
- What about her?
- Nothing. You know, just wondering.
You like her.
- Quiet, you silly infant.
- What about radiology?
Alex loves the fluoroscope.
- I went there. Nobody's seen him.
- Okay, can you check MRI?
The tech there lets him
man the controls sometimes.
Sam, I got work to do.
Jasmine Chastek, 17, fell down
a couple steps, positive LOC.
- Hey, I'm Dr. Barnett.
- What happened?
We were doing hits of nitrous
from whipped cream cans at Grandma's.
She went a little overboard,
passed out on the basement stairs.
Okay, this should clean up just fine.
Uh, I have to go find Alex.
Teenagers are such idiots.
Push harder!
It's stuck!
Come on!
Got to go!
Now!
- Can I have a cookie?
- Uh, yeah, but they really suck.
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
- Listen, your mom's looking for you.
- Ah, man, now I'm in trouble.
No, she'll understand.
No, I mean, everything I do
makes her angry.
Sometimes you have to go
the extra mile for a girl.
She'll get it. Trust me.
Lulu's in recovery.
She's doing fine.
Good.
- Go get her.
- Yeah.
We're getting a critical victim
in from a bus crash.
I've got to go meet
a helicopter on the roof.
Don't you need to be in the ER
or something?
- No, my shift ended hours ago.
- Well, what are you still doing here?
Waiting for you, dummy.
Tony, you know, it's going to be a while.
I've got to get sign-out;
- then I've got to take the patient to CT...
- All right, here's the deal.
You're going home with me tonight.
Why is that the deal?
Because there's nobody at my house.
It's Thanksgiving.
And I really, really want
to make you... dinner.
Okay, chocolate cherry.
Amazing, right?
- Wow.
- Looks great to me.
Hey, Greg.
- Hey, I'm Dr. Greg Pratt.
- Oh, nice to meet you. Courtney Brown.
- Courtney is my producer at Channel 5.
- Wow.
You know, I think I might be able
to hang out for a while,
if I can get my neighbor
to let the dog out.
- I'll give her a call.
- Great.
- Who is that?
- I just told you who she was.
Come on, now, hook a brother up.
You know what, your gaydar is
terrible, even for a straight man.
Oh, well, you...
You have excellent taste
in women, Dr. Weaver.
Of course I do.
Hey, uh...
Can I ask you something personal?
Maybe.
All right. How, um...
No, no.
When... did you know you were gay?
Are you coming out to me, Greg?
No, no, no, no. I came home and found
my brother with another guy.
- Really?
- Yeah.
He says he's just experimenting,
that it's only a phase.
- And what do you think?
- I don't know.
Can a straight guy
go through a gay phase?
I think it's more likely that he's gay.
Hey, and he's telling you
what he thinks you want to hear.
Okay, but for today, right,
he's taking some hot girl from
school to the family Thanksgiving.
Now, if he was gay,
why is he doing that?
I don't know your brother. I mean,
I-I don't know what's going on in his head,
but I do know that when I was that age,
I brought a lot of boys home to meet my parents.
- You did?
- Hell, yeah.
I mean, I was 30 before
I faced up to being gay,
but my life got a lot better once I did.
- Hey, Abby.
- Hey.
- Your transport go okay?
- Um... yes.
Well, be grateful you got
to skip out on this freak show.
- It's been a real madhouse around here.
- Just got lucky, I guess.
Hey, Lockhart.
Hurry up and sign this
before I get called out again.
Bye.
And thanks.
You're pretty tough for a girl.
Go to hell.
- Hi.
I was afraid you weren't
going to show up.
Sorry, Crenshaw made me do
an I&D on my way out.
Come on in.
Hope you're hungry.
Couldn't do the turkey
thing so I made tacos.
Homemade salsa, I got these tortillas
from the Salvadorian market on Fulton.
- You ever been there?
- Uh, don't think so.
Some wine.
You okay?
- Uh, yeah.
- Some more wine.
- Want to take your jacket off?
- Uh, yeah.
All right.
Are you sure you're cool?
'Cause if you don't like Mexican food,
- just say the word and you know.
- No, I'm fine. Really.
It's just I haven't been in
a situation like this for a long time.
- I know.
- It just feels a bit weird standing here
knowing we're about to do
what we're about to do.
What? Have dinner?
Tony, I-I want to be here, I do.
I mean, I've thought about it a lot.
Not creepy-a-lot, but it's definitely
been on my mind
and I wouldn't want you to be
worried that I don't really want...
I'm not worried.
We can take it as slow as you want.
Slow?
- Hey, stranger.
- Hey. Well, thank you.
- And what are you doing here?
- Working.
Surgeons are such bastards making
med students come in on Thanksgiving.
That is really, really low.
No, actually, it's the bastards in the ER
who scheduled me for this.
- What?
- I started an ER rotation.
Tonight.
Now, see, you said
you were never going to...
Yeah, radiology fell through at
the last minute. I got reassigned.
Don't freak out.
I'm not stalking you.
- Okay, look, I can't evaluate you.
- We'll work it out.
And I can't have these people thinking...
- Okay.
Hey, Abby.
What took so long?
You were out all night.
Well, you know, sometimes
these things can take hours.
You sure you weren't just having
sundaes with the team?
Last run I did we burned off
the whole shift at the Plush Horse.
Good for you, Ray.
Well, well, well, look who's back.
She got to soar over Chicago while we
dealt with maggots and colostomy bags.
I guess I must have done
something good in a past life.
Yeah, well, you look wiped. Transports can
do that to you if you're not used to it.
- So you want me to get you a coffee? Or...
- No, thanks.
Right now I really just want to go home.
No, stay. We just got here.
I missed you guys.
I know we had no water or toilet paper...
Oh, my God.
Meg, Sarah, this is Neela.
How many times do I have
to tell you, Tony?
When you leave the glass directly
on the wood, it leaves a stain.
- You hungry?
- Yeah, I'm starving.
All right, let me get my stuff,
and then, uh,
we can pick up something
at the chicken place.
Sam, Alex, Happy Thanksgiving.
There's some food over there,
help yourselves.
Wow, thanks, Luka.
- Tofurkey anyone?
- Uh... no.
- I'll try it.
- Are you really a vegan?
Surgeons just shouldn't be carnivores.
It's a known fact.
- What the hell is that?
- Looks like milk Jell-O.
Mmm, no, coconut flan and it is killer.
Oh, hey, Dr. Weaver, do you remember me?
- Katey Alvaro.
- Oh, hi, Katey. How are you?
I'm good. Um, I started my ER
rotation about an hour ago.
Oh, yeah, well, I hope Ray's
giving you the lay of the land.
Oh, yeah, he is. Definitely.
All right, how do you stay
so skinny and eat so much?
Uh, look who's talking,
little skinny mini.
Well, it seems like good genes to me.
You want to come over and watch some
football with me and Kerry tomorrow?
Damn, you're lucky.
- I can't believe you made all this.
- Well, maybe I cheated a little.
If anything happens to me
you'll remember that
Joe likes strawberries but raspberries
give him hives, right?
- What are you talking about?
- And...
and if you put the ceiling fan on in the
bathroom, he doesn't cry when he's in tube.
- I know that.
- And it's absolutely mandatory
that he be exposed to everything
Stevie Wonder recorded in the '70s.
Dr. Lockhart, that trauma
you choppered in did well in the OR.
Oh, great. That's great.
Yeah, it required over 12 units but,
uh, she's holding her own in recovery.
Thanks.
Are you okay?
How did the transport go?
Hey, I have my kid here.
It's Thanksgiving.
I'll tell you tomorrow.
Subtitles : Willow's Team
Transcript : Raceman
www.forom.com
www.tvsubtitles.net