Previously on E.R...
So you're a proponent
of a national health plan?
If we had one, this guy would be home playing
with his kids instead of fighting for his life.
That was gold.
I want these two out of my O.R.--
Shirley, call security.
- Nice working with you guys.
- Bovie...
- Stand back!
- You want to hook up?
- Hook up?
- Yeah, prep for the M&M.
Thought I'd give you a head's up
before I kick your ass.
- Uh, is, uh... is Tony there?
- I'm sorry, he's a little busy right now.
- Nobody here goes to the doctor?
- Hell no. - Not me.
I just don't know how to fix this.
Yo, Dr. K.
- Hey, what's up, guys?
- Oh, my God, he's so cute.
Hi, Joe.
Don't let the good looks fool you.
He's a tough one.
- Takes after his mom, huh?
- Ain't that the truth.
- Let me give you a hand, doc.
- Thanks.
Our babysitter couldn't make it again.
We finally decided to hire a nanny.
My mom raised eight kids all by herself.
I don't know how she did it.
She available?
So what about your S.B.O. guy.
- Waiting on surgery.
- And your chemo boy in 4?
Up to oncology about a half hour ago.
Who's this, the new chief of ER?
Yep, training him so I can retire early.
Good. We could use some
new blood around here.
- I'm new.
- You're too old to be new, Gates.
Excuse me, Dr. Weaver, hi.
Courtney Brown, Channel 5.
Have you got a minute?
Not really--
give me the half-inch, please.
The station loved you
and our segment that we did.
They've given us a green
light to do some more.
- Wow, that sounds cool.
- Yeah, I don't think so.
I'm an ER doc, not a TV personality.
That's exactly what we're looking for:
someone real.
You'd be really great, Dr. Weaver.
That piece you did was so good.
You know what, why don't you take over.
Pack all four quadrants
and Dawn can help you.
GYN has a bed, but they can't take
the P.I.D. for two hours.
- Dr. Weaver, radiology on two.
- Sorry, I got to take this.
Oh, I get it, you're swamped.
I'll try to buzz you later.
- I think he has Abby's eyes.
- Yeah, and his dad's head.
- Yeah.
- He'll grow into it.
Could you guys keep an eye
on him for a minute?
Yeah.
Mr. Ames.
Luka.
Can I, uh...
Can I help you with something?
No, no. Got a meeting
with Angela Gilliam upstairs.
About my appeal.
- She didn't tell you?
- No, no.
Yeah, need to copy
some of my hospital files.
- You're appealing the case?
- Only if I have to.
You know, a settlement would save the
hospital a lot of time and a lot of money.
Look, this hasn't been
easy on any of us.
Least of all you, but...
But what?
Maybe it's time to move on,
put the past behind you.
I couldn't agree more.
I'm going to hop up the stairs.
I'll see you around.
I can smell 'em.
You can't, but I can.
They're here now.
I can smell 'em; you can't smell 'em.
I can smell 'em...
Hey.
- Are those Hot Wheels?
- Want one?
Yeah.
I got lots of Hot Wheels, too.
- What is this one?
- I don't know.
Number five.
Get off the floor.
- Come on, don't make me embarrass you.
- Mom, I'm racing!
Get over here now.
Come on.
Get out of the way, man!
Fast food guy dumped some hot oil.
Third degree burns to his hands and wrists.
Exam Three is open.
You can't, but I can.
I can smell 'em.
Hey!
Maybe you haven't noticed, but
you got a few people waiting out here.
You actually got any doctors working
back there? What is it, golf day?!
Sir, please sit down.
Don't "sir" me, bitch,
just let me see a damn doctor!
Calm down, or I'll call security.
Oh, oh, oh, call 'em--
go ahead, I'm right here.
- What?
- Calm down now.
You are not the only patient here, okay?
Yeah, I can see that.
I can see that.
You sign in?
Signed in what?
All I got's a little congestion.
You think you morons can handle that?!
Fill this out.
If you sit down and shut up, I'll bring
you back here in a few minutes.
I just got the flu, for God's sake.
I want to apologize in advance
for the smell in the break room.
- Luka changed Joe's diaper in there.
- Wow, how bad is it?
- We've got a men's room, you know.
- It's not carrots, is it? I hate carrots.
You know, I said I'm sorry.
My babysitter flaked.
I feel bad enough dragging him in here.
- Hey, has Radiology called back yet?
- Nah, I don't think so.
Excuse me, I'm here
to see Dr. Luka Kovac.
- How long you been congested?
- I don't know. Does it matter?
No, I'm just making conversation.
About a month or so.
- All right, what do we got?
- Temp's 99.
- U.R.I. symptoms.
- The flu.
Deep breath for me, please.
Get that damn thing off of me!
It's freezing!
- I have to take a listen, sir.
- I told you asshole... it's the flu.
Now just give me some antibiotics
or something, and let me out of here.
Listen, Prince Charming, the quicker
we check you out, the quicker you can go.
I need to check the oxygen in your blood.
Part of the exam.
- Omit that part.
- All right.
Look, you have the flu, that's an easy fix.
Then you can go home.
Believe me, I want you to go.
I need you to go.
Wow, Rio.
- So Chicago must be a big change.
- Have you been here for a winter yet?
No, but I love the cold.
In Brazil is always sunshine.
Geez, that must have been hard to manage.
- Um, why did you leave your last job?
- I didn't really like New York.
I wanted a change around the scenery, huh?
Change of scenery.
You wanted change of scenery.
- Ah, sorry. My English.
- I still make mistakes.
Great.
Thanks for coming by.
Discipline.
Especially with the little boys.
This is key.
Amway money ran out along
with my husband.
So I asked myself,
"Jackie, what do you love?"
Kids, love kids.
Crazy little bastards.
Oh, hey, can I smoke in here?
It was the best ten years of my life.
I really loved those kids.
I don't want to brag, but
for all the families I've worked for,
the kids always end up calling me
Mommy by the third week.
Okay, great.
Thanks for coming by.
What, you get lost?
Seems to be a little problem
with your heart.
Is that from the flu?
Normal heart's about the size of a fist.
Yours is twice that big.
I don't think you have the flu.
Your congestion, shortness of breath--
- definitely because of your heart.
- Sorry, I couldn't find the sonosite.
How many times do I have to tell you
to lay down and put the gown on.
- I ain't wearing that dress.
- Then lose the shirt.
You can at least by me dinner first.
Do you get in a lot of fights?
Have an accident or something?
You got what look like old fractures,
a lot of them--
- a few ribs, collarbone, your arm.
- I was an active kid.
What about the scar and those burns?
Yeah, well, my pop had
a two-pack-a-day habit.
Whoa. He's got a pericardial effusion.
- A what?
- Fluid around your heart.
Which restricts blood flow
and makes it hard for you to breathe.
I.V. Two of Ativan,
set up for pericardiocentesis.
Hang on.
W-what are you doing?
Sir, we need to do a procedure where I place
a needle into the sac around your heart.
- It's no big deal.
- What?
No. No way.
- You need this procedure.
- No, I don't.
- Yes, you do. You could die.
- Non! Not a chance!
You son of a bitch!
Where'd you get the doctor degree,
through the mail?!
Get out while you can
before Kevorkian starts sticking you!
Let me the hell out of here!
Now!!
What could we do for you today, sir?
I just need my cholesterol prescription refilled.
Cholesterol,silent killer.
It is so good that you're being vigilant.
Dr. Wong from the Family Medical Center
prescribed this for you?
And why didn't you go back to her?
Well, they can't take me for a few months.
I'm supposed to get a blood test, too.
- Check my liver when I'm on the stuff.
- You need to see Dr. Wong.
I'll call up personally and make sure they
know to give you an earlier appointment.
Doc, please, I don't know
when I can take another day off.
I work two jobs. I got his Grandma
watching him all the time.
Okay, I'll call up right now
and let them know you're coming.
Hope, please discharge Mr. Batista
and point him to the Family Center.
Hey, Morris, why is Grasso
still in Curtain Two?
Vertigo guy is still here?
You know, mine felt better after meclizine,
O.T.D. in 45 minutes.
Give him a break-- his first shift
in a month he hasn't killed anybody.
My case is a little bit more
complicated than that, Ray.
- You have an abnormal neuro exam?
- I just have a clinical hunch, okay?
Takes years to develop.
- CT results from radiology.
- That for your vertigo guy?
It's normal, isn't it?
Then we can all sleep a little bit
better tonight, can't we?
Sam, could you please get something
from the drug sample closet?
- There's a limited amount of samples.
- You should ask an attending to write...
Dr. Weaver asked me to get it
for one of her patients.
Oh, okay.
No, yeah, it's Batista. B-a-t-i-s-t-a.
Thank you.
That TV news gal,
Courtney Brown called again.
Oh, Channel 5 Courtney Brown?
What'd she want?
She offered me a job as a reporter.
What, you?!
I m... of course you.
What did you say?
I turned it down.
You turned down the chance
to be the next Sanjay Gupta?
- Are you insane, woman?
- I have no interest in fluff pieces
- about sunburns and bee stings.
- What's wrong with fluff?
Half the patients who come through
here are fluff. I'm the king of fluff.
Word is, you're the best fluffer in town.
- Hope, you ready for that fecal impaction?
- Sure I am.
This is an extremely uncommon error.
Our personnel were clearly
distracted by the ongoing debate.
It's all the more reason why ER
docs should remain in the ER.
I know "ER" sounds a lot
like "O.R.", but it's not.
Our guys were up there trying to keep
your guys from making mistakes.
Based on the information we had,
our decision to operate was correct.
Well, you know what?
You didn't have sufficient information,
because you didn't allow us
to complete a full evaluation.
This isn't a wich hunt, people. We're here
to learn from our mistakes and improve.
You mean their mistakes, right?
Okay, let's not forget that
we're on the same team here.
Oh, Dr. Gates, come on in.
- You missed a case presentation.
- Sorry, I had a patient.
You know what? Sorry.
I just got to...
No, that's okay. Timely enough,
Dr. Gates.  No need to sit.
Come on down.
Why don't you tell us what the differential
diagnosis was when this patient presented.
Um... triple-A was on the top of our list.
But there were other possibilities.
I should've stayed a resident.
No responsibilities, just heal 'em
and deal 'em. That was the life.
Morris, can I tell you something as a friend?
Sometimes you are such a little bitch!
You make three times as much as I do.
And for what?
To give orders instead of take them?
Boo-hoo for you.
Mr. Batista!
Hey, Hope, we got a double coming in,
you might want to jump on.
I'll be right there, Dr. Morris.
Mr. Batista, wait.
Um... I called the Family Care Center.
I heard they can't take you
for another month.
I'm very sorry about all that.
The system's...
Well... it needs work.
Lovastatin.
30 pills, 20 milligrams each.
Shh. This should hold you
till your next appointment.
Thanks a lot.
- This is us, Hope.
- Unidentified male, early 20s.
Altercation on a bus,
blunt trauma to the chest and face.
Ray, Malik, you take this.
Trauma Two is open.
Sam, Hope, you're with me.
He's tachy in the 120s,
resps in the 30s, BP 104/56.
CBC, I.V., type and cross, let's go!
Fred Douglas, 38, blunt trauma
to the face with epistaxis.
- Son of a bitch broke my nose.
- Keep pressure on it.
Dude was yelling
at some lady on the bus.
I tell him to shut up, next thing you
know he's throwing punches.
- How you doing in there, Ray?
- I'm doing good.
He could probably use when you done.
That guy I got in a fight with--
I didn't hurt him too bad, did I?
Hemocue's 12.8.
First, we look for an obvious source
of bleeding that can be cauterized.
Is it broken, Doc?
It sure fe...
God bless you.
Snuck up on me. Sorry.
You need a definitive triple-A diagnosis
before committing an unstable patient
to major surgery.
Au contraire.
Mortality of ruptured triple-A is 90%.
We don't have time
to wait around for tests.
Ultrasound can be done
very quickly at the bedside.
Theoretically, perhaps,
but not in this ER--
besides, every textbook in print says
that this type of patient
- should be taken to the O.R. immediately.
- Ultrasound in the ER is new.
- It's not in every textbook,
- So I guess, what?
- and recent studies have shown...
- ... it's a very accurate at identifying aneurysms.
- You have a new toy?
- People die with delays.
Valentine paper, 1993,
found that most patients
without triple-A's still need surgery
for one thing or...
Most, not all! With severe heart failure,
surgery can be fatal.
The guy's lucky all you did was
torch him. You could've killed him.
Okay, um... what is your experience
in the ER with bedside ultrasound?
Well, it's been going on
for a few years now.
He's cute.
- But I hear he lives with somebody.
- Really?
- I think he has a kid.
- We found 95% agreement
with final radiology interpretation,
no significant clinical disagreements.
What about for a triple-A specifically?
- I don't know, exactly.
- Well, finding a gallstone is one thing.
A ruptured aneurysm quite another.
Well, if we'd seen a normal aorta
with an enlarged liver, we...
would've saved the guy
the risk of surgery.
But you couldn't do it
in a reasonable time frame.
That's because we weren't given
a reasonable time frame.
Well, he was unstable,
and surgery was necessary.
Lighting the guy on fire--
was that necessary, too?
- The Bovie wasn't grounded.
- Whose fault was that?
- Yours. - Mine?!
- You shouldn't have even been in the O.R.
You were up there
being a pain in the ass.
We have certain O.R. protocols
for a reason, and you interfered!
Okay, that's enough, that's enough.
Thank you, Dr. Gates.
I think we can all see
what the real problem is here.
Providing the best care requires
communicating openly,
and when we fail to do that,
lives are lost.
I think that's something
we can all learn from today's M & M.
Crenshaw is such a little prick.
You know what?
I bet I could take him, too.
Actually, I definitely think I can
take him, and you could kick his ass.
- Luka?
- You're scaring me.
I was looking for you.
Sorry I didn't get back to you earlier.
Angela, you remember Abby.
Sure. Nice to see you back at work.
Nice to be back.
So, I probably should've warned you
Curtis Ames was coming in.
Okay, what's all this about,
the settlement?
There is no settlement.
We agreed to the meeting as a show of
good faith, in case we went back to trial.
But don't worry.
The appeal's never gonna happen.
Ames can't even find
a lawyer to take the case.
We're not settling.
It's over.
- Good.
- All right, what do we got?
Okay, hypotensive secondary to what looks
like a traumatic pericardial effusion.
Wow, guy's got a lot of fluid
around his heart.
Looks like I'm gonna do
a percardiocentesis.
- BP's still dropping. 88/52.
- It's weird, I had one this morning.
Okay, Malik, set me up.
- How's your guy?
- Just a bloody nose.
Did you say there's something wrong
with my heart?
- He's awake.
- I'm Dr. Morris, attending physician.
Wait a minute, it's you.
From this morning.
- You know him?
- Yeah. No, no.
- You were here earlier?
- No, I wasn't.
- Hey, Sam?
- Yeah?
He's our A.M.A. patient
from this morning, right?
Yeah, the flu jerk.
I don't know what you
people are talking about.
I don't have the flu.
I've never been here... before.
Joe, hey, what's it gonna be?
Good-looking Brazilian or big,
mean Russian, hmm?
Joe?
- Going home.
- Say "bye."
We use sound to see, insert the needle into
the pericardial sac to drain the blood.
You use sound to see.
That's fascinating.
Just like bats and dolphins.
It'll release the pressure on your heart
and make it easier for you to breathe.
- And I won't feel a thing.
- Not a thing.
- Can I watch?
- Yeah, sure.
- Okay, cool.
- Oh, come on!
This morning, bats and dolphins here
was ready to rip my head off.
- What are you trying to pull, buddy?
- Why is he so angry?
Sam, prep his chest
and have two of versed ready.
Mr. Payton, we'll be right back.
Morris, can we talk?
Morris!
I don't know what
this whack job's game is.
His game is he's probably a little kooky
from a blow to his head.
- He could easily be amnestic.
- He's got to be on something.
- He's totally different now.
- Give the guy a break.
He just got his ass kicked.
He really didn't want that procedure
this morning, right?
Maybe he was really
pissed off at you, Archie.
It wouldn't be the first time.
Now...
I know this may sound
a little corny, but, um...
I always catch more flies with honey,
you know what I mean?
That... that's good, that's good, Ray.
I li... I like that approach.
You'll make a great attending
someday, my man.
I'm sorry.
I know my wallet's in here somewhere.
- Damn it.
- I got that.
- And, uh, can I get a Polish, please?
- No, no. That's okay.
Don't worry about it. I insist, really.
It's not necessary. Really.
When you got your hands full,
it's the least I can do.
It's just a hot dog.
My mom always taught me, random acts of
kindness make the world a better place.
Well, I can't argue with that.
Thank you.
- What is he, about six months?
- Five and a half.
He's really cute.
He's got a set of pipes on him
you wouldn't believe.
Are you driving your mom crazy?
Nah. Nah.
Here's your frog. Ribbit.
This yours? There you go.
- Excuse me, Dr. Weaver.
- Yeah?
Something is weighing on my heart
and I just can't take it anymore.
What's the problem?
I gave Oscar Batista Lovastatin samples.
That sweet, hard working man--
I was afraid that he would stop
taking his pills
and then he would come back here
with a heart attack or a stroke...
That precious little boy...
it reminded me how moved I was
by your television piece.
I just thought some tiny act
of kindness might really be...
Okay, stop!
You did a good thing.
Really.
There might be hope for you, Hope.
You told me those drug samples were
for Dr. Weaver's patient.
Well, they were... technically.
Well, technically, you lied to me.
There are rules
for breaking the rules, rookie,
and rule number one is that you never
ever lie to the nurses, you got me?
I'm so sorry.
Fell off a ladder at work.
Dude wasn't paying attention, so I had to pay the price.
Oh, sounds like a dangerous job.
Nah-- carpenter.
It's tough doing it with one arm, though.
Well, sprains heal pretty quickly.
Yeah, that's what they told me
at the hospital.
Uh, I'm, uh, I'm headed for the red line.
Oh, I'm headed this way.
Well...
- nice to meet you.
- You, too. Thank you for the hot dog.
It's my pleasure.
I'll catch you later, Joe.
Hey, uh, any messages for me yet, Frank?
No, Morris! The TV producer lady
has not called back yet.
And if you ask me that one more time,
I'm gonna slap you so hard, you'll turn
brunette. Have you got it?
Position's been filled.
- What position?
- And stop calling the television station.
- I'm getting complaints.
- Oh, that... oh, that position, right.
They filled it, huh?
Who'd they... who'd the find so fast?
- Me.
- You?
- I thought you turned it down.
- Yeah, well I changed my mind.
Figured it was about time someone put
something worthwhile on television.
So, Smitty, how long you had the rash?
- About two weeks now.
- Got any food allergies?
No.
- You on any medications?
- Just my blood pressure pills.
All right, come on, have a seat.
What kind of pills?
All right.
Oh, you see, that's the problem.
Rash is a common reaction to enalopril.
Who prescribed these for you?
Doc up at the clinic put me on it
'bout ten years ago.
- This and something else.
- Ten years ago?
Who gave you these?
See, my man T-Bone-- you know T...
Smitty, you can't take other people's
medications, man. It's not safe.
- Everybody does it.
- Everybody who?
Up at First Mission Baptist, Pastor Watkins
does a drug exchange program.
You should come up there sometime.
Man gives a powerful sermon...
Okay, hold on, hold on.
He does a drug exchange program?
Hell, yeah.
I ain't got insurance.
You know how much this stuff costs?
You can't possibly think ultrasound
was contraindicated.
I do if it can't be done immediately.
You could've told me that before the M&M.
Well, I didn't realize I had to point
out the totally obvious.
- I can't... I can't win with you.
- Well, finally we agree on something.
- Finally. Yes.
- Yes.
You don't have to take the piss out
on me, you know.
- The piss? Piss?
- Yes. Yes.
Yep, you got a nice fluid pocket.
This is gonna be a snap.
Sam, draw up some one percent lido.
Okay, before I start, just a few things.
Main risks here, bleeding and infection.
Y-You-You could infect my heart?
- Come on, let's not make this any harder.
- Calm down and let them work.
No!
What about bleeding?
I have trepidation about bleeding.
Well, it's only a minor risk 'cause
we're using such a small needle.
Well, not so small, but... thin.
And you'll be all numbed up,
so you won't feel a thing.
Okeydokey.
Let's do this.
Stop it! Get that thing away
from me, you clown!
- I told you, I don't want that!
- You agreed to the procedure, Mr. Payton.
- Screw that!
- Mr. Payton...
And stop calling me that.
My name's Clyde Sandberg.
You people got short-term
memory loss or something?!
Huh?!
- You ambushed me.
- You were spewing absurdities.
- Do you not like me or something?
- I think you're a wanker.
- A wanker?
- You're cocky, you're arrogant...
And you're not as smooth
- as you think you are.
- Oh, really, I'm not?
- No, you're not.
- I never said I was.
You know, I called you the other night,
and a woman answered.
Yeah, I can explain that.
Now would be a good time.
Here! Here! Bats and dolphins guy,
I figured it out.
- It's DID.
- What?
Dissociative Identity Disorder.
Multiple personalities.
You're kidding me.
- Psych make that diagnosis?
- No, I paged them three times.
- They haven't come down yet.
- This is based off of what,
- your extensive psychiatric expertise?
- No, he's a classic presentation--
old abuse injuries,
keeps changing his name.
Okay, maybe it's you that needs
the psych evaluation.
No, I'm serious, Ray.
We have to double doctor this guy.
Listen, he keeps refusing treatment,
that effusion will kill him.
And who knows how long psych will take?
I mean, by the time their resident sees
him, they present to the attending,
they have their stupid meeting,
it could be hours.
Double doctoring-- that's a pretty big deal.
Can't we just treat with
- NSAIDS and steroids?
- He's refusing vital treatment.
And that, my friend, is grounds
for a double doctor.
- Come on, come on, get with me here.
- What, so I'm back on the case now?
Yeah.
Look, I tell you what.
I'll talk to him.
I'll try and get some sort of read.
But maybe you should hang back.
You already pissed him off enough today.
So... I have a few questions for you.
Can you tell me what day it is?
Thursday.
Month and year?
You know, they got this new thing out
called a "calendar."
My freakin' God-- November. 2006.
- Do you know where you are?
- What is this place, Romper Room?
I see "Stupid" and "Retard"
and "Jerkoff."
I'm at County General Hospital.
- I am not double doctoring.
- Ray, he's only going to get worse.
He's hypotensive
with reduced cardiac output.
Look, he already hates doctors,
especially you.
Do you really want to tie him down
and stick a needle into his chest?
- If it'll save his life, hell, yeah.
- I am out, Archie.
Fine, I'll get somebody else.
Hey, Pratt.
No, no, no, no.
Hasta-la-bye-bye.
Pratt, I need you to sign off
on a double doctor.
- What you got, a foster kid or something?
- No, he's a competent adult.
He's got a pericardial effusion
and doesn't want treatment.
Morris wants to get medieval
on the guy because he thinks...
I think he's DID.
- Multiple personalities.
- Yeah, I know what it is. What did psych say?
They're MIA.
Morris you do know that
multiple personality syndrome...
Dissociative Identity Disorder,
they changed it.
Yeah, whatever.
Some docs don't even think it exists.
There's a ton of literature to support it.
- Okay, so how are his vitals?
- Systolic's holding in the 90's.
- And mental status?
- Alert and oriented.
- Tox screen and CT?
- Clear.
You got to treat him conservatively.
Wait for psych, it's their call.
Pratt, you want me to be more thorough.
That's what I'm doing.
Pratt, listen to me
for one second, please.
If a patient presents within a week of
surgery, it's considered a bounce-back.
Make sure all bounce-backs are
logged in the follow-up book.
Hey, can I speak to you for a second?
We're in seroma. Removing
the staples and packing the dermis.
Uh, wasn't actually talking to you.
Um, okay. Go ahead.
I'll just get started.
- So how's surgery treating you?
- Like a stepchild.
Radiology's looking better every day.
It'll be over soon enough.
I hated my surgical rotation.
So, um, do you like hockey?
Tonsil or ice?
Uh, ice.
Mm, too bad.
But, yeah, I'll settle for a Hawks game.
He still refusing treatment?
Last BP was 84 over 50,
and he's developed pulsus paradoxus.
Found his old file.
Willis Payton is his real name.
Probably be the "host" personality.
His Clyde character must be
one of his "alters".
He was here a bunch of times
between '88 and '96.
Foster kid, abuse related injuries--
some bad ones, too.
It's a classic DID history.
Psych's still a no show?
I know everybody down here
thinks I'm a joke.
If Pratt said DID, he'd be a genius.
But I...
I know that I'm right about this.
And all I can do is suck on it
and watch this guy die.
You did what you could.
And you're not a joke, Archie.
You're an attending.
Thank you.
Was a time when that mountain
seemed so high,
like it stretched up to
the Pearly Gates themselves.
Promised land seemed like an idea.
Like no matter how hard we worked,
it was only sand between our fingers.
But we're still here.
Proud and strong, Lord have mercy,
we're still here.
But we got a whole lot of work to do,
because the more things change,
the more they stay the same.
Young-Young brother in the back.
You're new.
Stand up and introduce yourself.
No, no, you!
- Evening, everyone, I'm Greg Pratt.
- Welcome, Brother Pratt.
Come on up front.
Nice to see young folk in
the evening service, isn't it?
Heart's getting worse, you know.
Here we go again. No!
You need me to spell it?
If you keep refusing treatment,
it's gonna go down one of two ways:
one, the doctors are going
to come in here,
- tie you down, and do the procedure.
- They can't touch me, I got rights.
Or two, we get to watch you die.
Fun for you.
There's a third option.
You give consent, we fix your heart,
and you go home.
All we want to do is help.
Yeah, you've been loads of help so far.
- I know you're scared.
- No, I ain't scared of nothing!
I know you've been hurt.
A lot.
But you are safe here.
I know you don't want to trust us,
but you can. I promise.
Was, um...
was-was...
was I sleeping?
No.
I lost time.
I lost time again.
Willis?
Yeah?
Clyde's been giving us a hard time.
- I... I thought he was gone.
- You know about Clyde?
Yeah.
My friends told me about him.
He's very negative.
Well, Clyde doesn't want us help you.
So all we could do was give you some
medicine, but that's not working too well.
Um, well... can you, can you still fix me?
Willis, I need Clyde's permission.
I can't make him do anything.
I can't.
We can't start and stop again.
We're running out of time.
No. No, no, no.
No.
Willis! Damn it, let me talk
to Clyde right now!
Do not make me hurt you!
Let me talk to Clyde!
How many times I got to tell you
to get off me, bitch?
Huh, how many times?! Huh?!
I saw Willis.
- He's letting us do the procedure.
- He's a pansy!
Yeah, well, he's brave enough to let us
stick a needle in his heart.
Piss off, bitch.
Fine.
You be a tough guy all the way
to your funeral. I'm done.
Hey!
You stick my heart, that means
I get out of here, right?
Yep.
Do it.
I told you I ain't scared of nothing.
The drug exchange program is only
for people who have prescriptions
but can't afford the drugs.
Smitty's prescription was ten years old.
And he had Enalopril.
Enalopril is not the first drug of choice
for black folks with high blood pressure.
I suggest that you start
an exercise program.
Get your congregation to stop eating salt
and fried foods and start exercising.
Trust me, you'll do
a whole lot more good.
We don't just help people
with high blood pressure.
We have diabetics, asthmatics,
you name it.
Look, what you're doing is dangerous,
okay, not to mention illegal.
I have an obligation
to this community, Dr. Pratt.
These people are shackled by a system
over which they have no control.
The one thing I will not do is nothing.
Excuse me, Dr. Morris, can I ask
your advice on something?
I lied to Samantha about something
and now she's really steamed.
Ooh, bad move. Piss one nurse off,
piss 'em all off, like the mafia.
You know, whenever I'm in
a precarious situation,
I always ask myself,
"What would Jesus do?"
Right.
What would Jesus would do
if the nurses hated him?
Well, he would do the right thing,
of course.
That's the problem, I thought that
I was doing the right thing. I guess...
- I just... I did it the wrong way.
- Hey, it's the story of my life.
You know, sometimes it doesn't matter
how much we kick and scream.
Even when we're right.
"The prophet is without honor
in his own land."
- Matthew 13:54.
- Oh, I love that one. Big Matthew fan.
You have a good night, Dr. Morris.
Feeling better?
Drained almost half a liter of fluid
from around your heart.
Your blood pressure and pulse
are back to normal.
Soon as a bed opens up,
we'll get you upstairs to a room.
So, you're doing great.
You got my glasses?
Uh... let me check, yeah.
- That kid gonna be okay?
- Who?
Yeah, I'm sure he is.
Looks like he's leaving.
He was racing Hot Wheels.
His mom, she was mean.
Willis?
My name is Andre.
I like Hot Wheels.
I wish his mom wasn't so mean.
Hey, hey...
don't tell my dad I'm here, okay?
He can be pretty mean, too.
Your secret's safe with me. Okay?
It's kind of dark in here.
You're not gonna leave, are you?
No.
No way, buddy, no.
I'm here all night.
That's good.
So, what kind of Hot Wheels you got?
All kinds. I collect 'em.
Yeah?
I used to collect them, too.
What kind you got?
I used to have a '57 Chevy.
I got that one.
- Shelby Cobra.
- Got it.
Okay, all right... '65 Mustang Fastback.
- I got two.
- You got two?
- Yeah.
- Wow.
I used to have three,
but I gave one to my friend.
Well, you'll have to give one to me,
'cause I don't think I have mine anymore.
Subtitles : Willow's Team
Transcript : Raceman
www.forom.com
www.tvsubtitles.net