Previously on E.R.
Did you work on Edgar Dixon today?
Yeah,yeah,yeah. Um,why? What's up?
First Mission Baptist is dispensing
meds without a pharmacy license.
It's a felony,Pratt. A man died.
Thank you for the hot dog.
It's my pleasure.
I'll catch you later,Joe.
So,how long you staying,Gracie?
Just till you   row me out,not a bit
longer.
Luka,this is...
- Eddie. - Eddie.
Nobody called you a whore.
My mom did.
Your mom's mistaken.
I'm gonna find budget cuts somewhere
else.
There is no way we're losing.
Thanks,but I resign.
"A HOUSE DIVDEDE" This is Dr. Abby
Lockhart.
I'm calling from County General, and
ca  you te   him
I   t   s la  result
and he needs to come in   and discuss
them?
Th  ks.
Since when do   u call E.R. patients
from home?
I was worried about th   guy.
I want to ma   sure he gets seen.
Isn't that more of a job for his
imar  care physician?
He doesn't have one.
Well,no incentive to get  ne if you'r
gonna make h  se  alls.
I phoned his hotel to make sure he
comes    for follow-up.
Hotel?
Yes,he's from out of town.
- Who is this guy? - It's Eddie
Jackson. You met hi
What?
Nothing.
Well,why are you acting weird?
Hmm,I just... I j  t think   it's a lit
e strange
the amount of   rsonal attention
u seem to be giving some guy
you met in a b  .
You di  't talk to her,di
you?
I didn't  ee her.
I thought you were gonna talk to her
last night.
Yeah,but   got home so lat  and she was
excited about how well
she did on her history
presentation,so...
Tony...
I'm gonn  do it. I'm gonna do it.
You've  een saying that for   week.
She needs to hear this from you.
She needs to know that it was your
idea,
otherwise,   she'll never forgive me.
I right,I'll tell her.
Tonight,I promise.
Oh,man,would you     look at this
board?
We got cough,cough and vomiting,itchy
feet,diarrhea, diar  ea and vomitin
I haven't seen a decent trauma my last
three shifts.
People are getting too damned careful
these days.
Chop  r's bringing in some kind of
snowmobile accident.
Ca  ed it.
- Is this the snowmobile? - Yeah,one of
'em.
Clar   Sutton,13,lost control and hit a
fence.
It was an accident.
I was trying to turn.
Where's Dennis?
McKay's unloading the older brother.
I think this one got the wo  t of it.
His brother carried him almost a mile
to get help.
Can I be in the same room with Dennis?
It hurts to breathe.
Okay,try   t to talk. Gates,  hy don't
you go up to the roof,
grab the next one? I'll take this.
- No,I got this covered. - Nah,I got
this one.
Nah,I got this one. who knows how to
treat him,all ri  t?
This kid needs treatment, Okay?
And that'd be me. I'll call you if I
need you.
Okay,guys,knock it off Come on.
Okay,who gets this patient?
Me,if you're gonna act like babies then
that's how I'll treat  ou.
Luka,sats are dropping
Okay,bag him. Abby,run ahead and
intubate.
Way to go.
This was your fault.
- Yeah,right. - Yeah,I am right.
- Don't be an idiot. - Ass for brains.
Edgar never liked to talk about his
troubles.
In fact,the only thing he ever talked
about was football.
*****
But I remember... one Sunday Edgar
looked troubled,
and I said to him "Well,is there
anything I could do for you?"
So he said,"No,no,Pastor,you can't help
my problem. "
I said,  ell,maybe I can't,but I know
someone who can.
You know,God always listens. "
Oh,amen.
Dr. Pratt.
Pastor,that was a nice service.
- Thank you. - Very nice.
Um,Mrs. Dixon, I just w    d to pass on
my condolences once again.
I just,  ,
want to let you know if there's
anything,
anything I can do,
please don't hesitate to call the
hospital.
Thank you,Dr. Pratt.
Thank you.
ER Season 13 Episode 13
Greg!
The Medical Board called me.
I bet they did.
They said that they're issuing a letter
for us to cease and desist our drug
program.
at's not a surprise.
I told 'em to go to hell.
You did what?
They don't understand what we're doing.
Yeah,but I'm sure they got a pretty
clear idea now.
Look,I like what you're doing,but it
doesn't work.
People need a continuity of care and
the church clinic isn't open every day.
How many people do you think we've
helped since we started this program?
I'm sorry.
Well,we're not giving up on the
program.
Then you're headed for trouble.
My people have now  re else to turn to.
They're already in trouble.
I'm out.
Sats are drifting into the 70s.
Come on,Clarke,stay with us.
- Want me to do that? - No.
- You sure? - Yeah.
If you want to help,you can give me
some cricoid.
I got blood here. What do you want?
Uh,CBC,LFTs,chem7...
I'm in. Bag him.
...UA and a blood gas.
You're probably not gonna need that.
Decreased on the left. Pull back the ET
tube.
No,I stopped just past the cords.
Well,it's obviously not,so pull it
back.
I'm gonna call the Blood Bank.
Uh,good idea.
Still decreased. Sterile sixes and a
chest tube tray.
Hold on. Let's not  ump the gun.
He's got a bruise   d bad sats. I'm not
jumping the gun.
It's a pneumothorax.
Right,I'll call for a portable chest.
Good,good.
Let's see what we're dealing with here
first.
20% of all pneumothoraces are missed on
X ray. You taught me that.
Nice to know you were listening.
We have time to wait for the film
before we start cutting.
What about the sliding lung sign?
Okay,lungs are up. No hemothorax or rib
fractures.
What's happening with Clarke? Why isn't
he sitting u
They put a tube down his throat to help
him breathe.
Good bowel sounds.
He got the wind knocked out of him. I
had to carry him to the road.
It's a good thing you did.
Crits 38,pressure's still good; 122/76.
Let me know if anything's sore.
He kept begging me to let him drive
His father's gonna kill me.
Wait. I thought you two were brothers.
He's my stepbrother.
My dad died when I was little. My mom
remarried in August.
He thinks I'm a screw-up. This i  't
going to help.
Pretty much wrecked his snowmobile. Ow!
All right,left lower quadrant. Call
Surgery.
Not so fast. It's not a contusion. It's
an abrasion.
He's guarding.
Do you have to keep doing that?
I'm sorry. He's hemodynamically
stable,and his crit's good.
Let's get a CT of his belly,and if it's
normal, then we won't have to waste a
surgeon's time.
Well,I'm going to have to disagree with
your assessment.
Ah,okay.
Let's run it by Kovac.
Let's not.
I decide when we present to an
attending.
No lung sliding.
What the hell is lung sliding anyway?
Normally there's lung movement on
ultrasound.
If i  s not there,then the lung must be
partially deflated.
Showoff.
Okay,chest tube tray to Abby.
What? You don't want to do it now?
I wanted to do it 15 minutes ago.
Well,it looks like Abby was right and
Luka confirmed the diagnosis
radiographically.
Good work,team.
What the hell do I have to do to get
someone to come down here?
Dr. Gates from the E.R. That's with an
"E"   for "emergency. "
You called for a consult?
Actually,I dialed the Hot Surgeons chat
line.
Which room?
What's the matter? No,"Hey,how you
doing?
You look sexy in that white suit"?
Hey,what's wrong?
You mean besides the fact the last time
I saw youthe woman that you liv  with
practically assaulted me
and her daughter called me a whore?
I told you I was sorry.
I don't live with her anymore.Not for
long,anyway.
How's Sarah?
We're working through it.
No blood out. It's not the
chest.Xeroform and the thoroseal.
Could be cardiac contusion.
Get a 12-lead and hold off on the
blooduntil the troponin's back.
CT's ready.I'll take him up.
- I'll take him.- You sure?
Yeah,in case he crashes.
Well,that wasn't awkward.
Further proof workplace romance,bad
idea.
Is that so?
Uh,yeah.
Hey,look,the other night you
kindacaught me off guard with that
kiss,
and I don't... I have a ruleagainst
dating people at work.
You do?
Yeah,it's kind of a new rule.
Uh,yeah.
But a solid rule.
That's cool,really.
This is Dennis' father,Gary.Gary,this
is Dr. Gates
and Dr. Rasgotra.
Where's Clarke?
Oh,upstairs for more X rays.
Is this a social visit?
Tony asked for a consult.
I hope you're happy now.
I'm sorry. We were being really
careful.
You obviously weren't being carefulif
you put Clarke in the hospital.
I want to see my son.
Where is he?!
Uh,Lily,could you?
I can take you to him,sir.
Thank you.
You better pray he's all right.
Uh,Neela,I'm sorry youhad to come down
here.
Um,he doesn't need a co  ult.
Oh,well,I'm here nowand I'm almost
finished.
Okay,fine,then can you explain to him
why
Actually,I'm suggesting weadmit him for
observation.
Why? His kidneys look good.His liver
and spleen appear to be normal.
Did I miss something on the CT?
Well,an occult injurycould take time to
declare itself.
- He's right.- No,he's not.
The surgeon concurs with my assessment.
Hey,don't worry,boss.I'm not one of
those "I told you so" kids.
Can I speak to you outside?
- Certainly.- Okay.
Not you.
Sammy.
Hi,guys.
Ben,hello.
Hey,Gracie. What's up,Alex?
Hey.
Alex is signing up for theVolunteen
program today.
He's real excited about it.
I had to practicallydrag him here by
his ears.
Alex,even if you volunteerfor a couple
hours a week,
it'll still help on yourcollege
applications,okay?
And maybe you'll even like it.
Just keep telling yourself that,Mom.
When I was your age,I had two jobs.
Yeah,doing what,milking the T-Rex?
I worked on the Milfords'farm before
school,smartass,
and at night I worked in Addison's
Bakery.
If you'd like,I could take Alex to
thevolunteer center,show him around a
bit.
That's great. Thank you,Ben.
Well,actually,I probably know this
hospitalbetter than you do.
That's great. Then you can give me the
tour'cause I still can't find the gift
shop. Come on.
He gets cuter every time I see him.
Ben.
I heard you.
You should be going after that one.
It's a little tricky datingsomeone you
work with.
What's tricky about it?
Having sex without getting caught?
- Gracie...- Look,honey,
I know what your life has been like.
Trust me,Sammy,I know.
All the women in our family are the
same-
very fertile,allergic to chestnuts,
prone to bladder infections...
And we all have that damn gene
that predi  oses us
to bad boys.
Chestnuts?
Sammy,life is short.
You deserve to be happy.
You deserve a good man.
If you like this guy,go for it.
Okay,the least you can do is give mean
honest and professional opinion.
- I did.- No,you didn't.
Well,how would you know?You're not a
surgeon.
Neither are you.
Sorry. Sorry,look...
- No,you look. I came down,I
assessed...- We established... You
shouldn't have come down...
- I made a professional call. If- you
disagree with my opinion...
- ... it's personal,just like your
visit.- ... fine,tha  s your
prerogative.
- What you can't do... The reason- why
you're siding with Gates
- is because you're screwing him.- ...
is accuse me of being...
I can't believe you just said that.
So it's true?
No. And even if it were,it'snone of
your damn business.
And it certainly hasnothing to do with
this case.
It does if it's clouding your judgment.
Hey,maybe we should get anattending to
weigh in on this.
- No.- No.
Hey,hey,hey,hey,hey.
Somebody want to tell mewhat the hell's
goin  on here?
Oh,so everything's just all good
now,huh?
Well,somebody better havea good
explanation. Ray?
Okay. 13-year-old drovea snowmobile
into a fence.
Normal CT,stable crit and B.P.
Gates wanted a surgical consult,
I said we didn't need one, but
hedecided to call Neela down here
anyway.
Better safe than sorry,right?
Wrong.It wasn't your call to make.
Ray's above you.
Now if you have a problem with
yourresident or you disagree with his
judgment,
then you call an attending.
I wanted to present to Kovac.
And I didn't.He was busy with another
trauma anyway.
And now they've taken thehospital's
last surgical bed.
That kid needs 24-hour observation.
You cannot give up the last surgical
bed.
I need to follow serial exams.
- Then do it down -here.- You're
already full up.
Th   send him home and have him come
backin 12 hours for a re-exam.
Exactly.
You know,I'm trying to help you guys
here.
No,you give up your last surgical bedto
this kid and we can get stuck boarding
a real surgical trainwreck down here
for days.
Ray's patient,Ray's call.
Fine. Keep him down here.Less w  k for
me.
Thank you.
Yeah,you better be right.
Thanks for the vote of confidence,boss.
- Luka.- Yeah.
You get a chance to speak withAngela
Gilliam about Edgar Dixon?
Who?
The guy from the church clinic.
Oh,ye  ,she-she said she'd,uh,look into
it.
All right,I'm just a little concerned.
Someone called the medical boardand
they called the church.
Okay,I'll talk to her again.
All right,thanks.
You looking for something?
A patient.
Which one?
Hockey dad,Jim Singer,30.Hockey puck
versus face.
It was a slap shot.
This is his son,Jimmy,Jr.
God,he spit out his teeth.
Okay,Jimmy,we're gonna fix your dad up
and you get to play X- Box,okay?
Margo,can you take Jimmy?
How you doing,sir?
I can't breathe.
Looks like a fractured jaw,
multiplebroken teeth. His pulse ox is
down to 88.
Okay,he needs an airway.Pratt,you want
a piece of this?
sure.
How come they didn't bring Clarke back?
They probably moved him to another
bedto free up the trauma room.
And that can be a good sign,so...
Your stepfather hasn't come by,huh?
No.
Why didn't you  ell him youweren't the
one who was driving?
What's the point?
I don't know,maybe so that...
he knows you didn't do this.
He'd still find a way to blame me.
At least now he can't get mad at
Clarke,too.
You   o are close?
Yeah,I guess.
First,it was kind of wedhaving a little
brother.
But he's cool.
His dad's really stric   on him.
I'm afraid he thinksthat I'm a b
influence.
Sometimes I let   m dothings his father
doesn't.
Like drive the snowmobile?
I'll find out how he's doing,okay?
Thanks.
Forget it,we're nevergoing to see the
cords.
All right,let's bag him up and prep the
neckfor a seldinger crike.
Hey,Abby,what's the statuson the other
snowmobile kid,Clarke Sutton?
CT showed persistentpneumo,Kovac put in
a second tube.
But other   an that he'sgood. Try Exam
Three.
Okay,thanks.
Dr. Pratt,I'd like you to stop by my
officeat 4:00 today if that's possible.
Cricothyroid is right here.
Ye  . Um... did you talk to Dr. Kovac
ye
Yes,we need to have a quick sit-down
withthe hospital lawyers about Edgar
Dixon.
Guide wire.
Yeah,I was just at his funeral today. I
spoketo his wife. She's not pressing
any charges.
She's not the problem,the board is.
They're not too happy Mr. Dixon was
gettinghis medications through his
church.
Medications that you distributed.
Yeah,but... who got theboard involved
in this?
I don't know. 4:00.
- Abby,here's your introducer.- Greg...
Dr. Pratt,we got a hot MI five minutes
out.
Uh,Greg...
Yeah,all right,um...   est X-ray,call
for a vent,page Head and Neck,
and,uh,come find me when you're done.
Do either of these belong to you?
He   How'd it go?
Spectacular.
Sarcasm is a poor substitute for wit.
Do you know who said that,young man?
Do I car
Alex,don't be rude.Say you're sorry.
Just relax,okay?
Hey. Don't tell me to relax.
I think it's time we  ent home.
Okay,let's go.
March!
Hey.
So,uh,  nally get things  sort   out
with Neela?
There's nothing to sort ou   man.
You sure?
Because it looks like yougot some
sorting out to do.
Look,man,if you   need myadvice,all you
have to do is...
No,no,no,no.No,I don't need your
advice.
I don't want your advice.I took your
advice,remember?
You know,"Give her some time,Ray. "
"Give her so   s  ce,Ray. "
Yeah,I did that.
In fact,I gave her so much time and so
muchspace, she started seeing somebody
else.
- So thank you  or   the advice,Pratt.-
What? So that's...
Stop acting like a baby.
Why are you even here?Nobody invited
you.
It's time you startedshowing a little
res  ct.
And you need to mind yourown damn
business,bitch.
Don't   u ever talk...
Hey! And don't you ever to  h me.
You ever raise your hand to me
or your mother or any other woman
I'll break every bone inyour sullen
little body.
Grandma's got some game.
Ray...
your snowmobile kid's   t looking too
od.
The one you insisted didn't need su
ery.
Hey,I got  his.
Thanks.
Hey,look,um...
I'm sorry about Alex.
You know,he's not always likethat. He's
had a rough year.
You don't need to apologize for
him,Sam.
- I just don't want you to think
that...   - That he's what?
That h  s a teenager?
Sam,I was a holy terror at his age.
My principal suspended me fromschool
one time   r fighting.
So you know what I did?
I slashed all the tires on his
Corvette.
That is a little delinquent.
Yeah,I was a real piece of work.
My mom raised me by herself,too,Sam,so
I know it's not easy.
We fought every single dayfor probably
ten straight years.
And now we talk at   least once a week.
And we're best friends.
And in time,I'm sureyou and Alex will
be,too.
Hey,have you seen Dr. Pratt?
He's out in the ambulancebay waiting on
a rig.
Thanks.
Hey,Abby,I have a working girlwith a
mandible dislocation.
I've tried everything.
You know any tricks? No pun intended.
Can this wait ten minutes?
No,I've already paged Kovac and
Pratt.She pre-medicated,they're all
tied up.
I've tried everything. It  on't budge.I
gave her 100 of fent.
Add some midazolam.
How'd you do this,big yawn?
From what I gather,it was  an oral
occupational injury
she got while performing a service.
Oh. Okay.
Two milligrams in.
Did you try it from behind?
Oh,you're talking to me?
Relo  ting the mandible.
Oh. No,that's a new o  .
From the back,you've got better
leveragefor downward force.
And you can put your weight into it.
Makes sense.
You also get a better gri
Hey,Tony,got a visitor.
Sarah,what are you doing here?
I went up to your room    I saw your
boxes.
Why didn't you tell me?
I was going to.
You lied to me.
Sarah,this really isn't a good time.Why
don't you guys go in the break room?
Go with Sam and I'll bethere in a few
minutes.
You want to leave,thenleave. I don't
care anymore.
- Sarah.- Want me to get her?
Go ahead,I got this.
You okay?
Sarah,wait.
Hey!
Stop and listen to me.
No!
You can't tell me what to do,  you're
not my dad.
Yes,but I'm your friend.
Friends don't leave.
Damn it,abdomen's rigid with fever.
Crits stable,he's not bleeding.
Could be a bowel perf with peritonitis.
Blood cultures and Zosyn 3.375.
Should I get Gates?
No,no,no. No,I need  urgery down here.
I already called them.
Okay,mix up dopamine.
Dennis,De  is,can you hear me?
I need you to start fighting,okay?
Your brother wants to talk to you.
PageNeela. Tell her I need her down
here,now!
Here you g
"Thank you,Tony. "You're welcome,Sarah.
Hey,come on,you can'tbe mad at me
forever.
Why not?
Because of this...
What are you doing?
My sym  thetic doctor face.
You look stupid.
No? All right,you know what,you're
making me bring out the big guns.
When somebody is really sick and
it'svery fatal I say to them,"Mr.
Smith,
"it's very fatal   you're very sick,
"the tumor's too big"for your very tiny
little head.
"It's fatal. You're not going to live.
Sir,you're going to die!"
- Okay,stop.- Then I give 'em this
face.
Then I go...
Stop. Stop it.
It's not funny.
I'm mad at you.
I know. I'm sorry.I wanted to tell you.
Why do you have to go?
Because it's the right thing.
Is it because of Neela?
You called her?
She was worried about you.
Come on. Come on.
What's happening?
Free air under the diaphragm.
Systolic's only 90 after two liters.
I'll throw in a subclavian,then
straight to the O.R.
He s  med okay.Where's his stepfather?
I sent Dawn to find him.
- Thanks for coming.- It's my job,Ray.
Cordis introducer.
Prime the infuser.
All right.
You have a minute?
Yeah. Why,what's up?
It was me- I called the medicalboard
about Edgar Dixon.
You?
Why the hell would you do that?
Because I heard he was getting hismeds
from some  octor at a church.
I thought it was some unlicensed
crackpot.
Oh,Abby.
I'm really sorry.
It's all right.
I'm sorry,I thought Iwas doing the
right thing.
You were. We both were.
Sometimes you do the right thing an
youstill get shafted.    Don't sweat
it.
Hey,Greg,these detectiveswould like to
talk to you.
About what?
Your involvement with apatient named
Edgar Dixon.
I called Angela. She's on her way down.
All right,thanks.
Dr. Pratt,is there someplacewe could go
talk in private?
Yeah,sure.
Right this way.
Yo,Ab  ,I've been looking for you.That
patient you were asking about?
- Boom,he left a message.-   anks.
Let me g  ss,your friend Eddie again.
What,are you jealous?
No,I just don't understand   why
you'regiving this guy so much
attention.
He's a 60-year-old man with
lungdisease. I'm just trying to help
him out.
Hi.
Hi... Kerry...
Uh,we can talk about this later.
Or not.
Everything all right?
Yeah,just a disagreement about a
patient.
Hmm. Gotcha.
I still can't believe you're leaving.
Yeah,it feels a little weird.
Scary,but,uh,it's exciting.
I'm actually going to miss this place.
- You know...- List  ,I just want to...
- No,no,no...- No,go ahead.
- No...- You go.
I just want to say that Ithink that
you've probably
uh,seen me... at my best,
and um... and at my wo  t.
And even though we didn'talways see eye
to eye,um...
...you helped me go from a  urse
to a med student...
to a doctor...
...to a mom.
I'm the one who's supposed to be upset
here.
I know. Sorry.
You were always thereas a nurse and a
doctor
and most importantly,yo  ve  Iways been
here
as my friend.
Do you think this   ppens    the
guyswhen one of them leaves?
I heard Carter bawledlike a baby when
he left.
I'm going to miss you.
Thank you.
And now it's time for usto take care of
ourselves.
You can still hang out with Tony.
It won't be the same.
No,but it will still be good.
You can go to Tony's placewhen I get on
your nerves.
Oh,easy,now. I don't wantthe kid living
wit  me.
I can stay at your place sometimes?
If it's okay with your mom.
I'm going to have a swinging bachelor
pad.
I'm going to have abig-screen TV over
the Jacuzzi,
trampoline and a shark tank,the works.
Nothing stays the same forever,Sarah.
It's part of growing up.
Besides,you won't care about mein a few
years anyway.
You're going to run offand marry that
horn dog character
and have six kids and eight cats...
We broke up.
- What?- Yeah.
Oh,you know,I really never liked that
guy.
It was my fault.
He found out I I like Kevin Mclntyre.
Jezebel.
Better get going,kiddo.
Let Tony get back to work.
Hey...Hey.
Baby girl.
His vitals have stabilized.Let's get
him up to O.R. Two.
I'll call you when   's out of surgery.
Thanks.
Neela.
Neela,I need to say something.
No,you don't. You did what youthought
was right for the patient.
I respect that,Ray.
No,see... no,that's not it.
Then what is it?
Uh... this is probably wrong,I know.
It's the wrong place,thewrong
time,but,uh...
Why didn't somebody page me?
We handled it.
What happened?
Seems like your patienthas a perforated
viscus.
Really? Good thing we didn'tsend him
home,huh,Rock Star?
Looks like h  needed observation after
all.
It's not small bowel
perforation,okay,Tony?
This has nothing to dowith the seat
belt sign.
How do you figure?
Small bowel doesn't seedthe peritoneum
like this.
It's colonic,maybe diverticular.
Really? Interesting. Tell me
more,Doctor.
Where are they taking Dennis?
He's going up to surgery,if you really
care.
What the hell's that supposed to mean?
You know,I sent a nurseto find you 30
minutes ago.
I was with my son.
Yeah? Well,this one needed you,too.
You know what,actually I'm sorry.
He needed a parent. Maybe Ishould have
called his mother.
Hey,y    e gut    line.
ithe  one    them   would even
be(inhere   if Denni  wasn't scre  ng
aro
T/          Denn   w  n't  en   iving.
Clark  was.
- That's nkt true.- Ye   it is.
But did you even   ther to ask
him?No,you just blamed him from the
get-go.
Why didn't he say something?
Would you have   believed h  ?
He was trying toprotect his little
brother.
Dennis is older. Heshould have known
better.
He's 15.
Do you know that he carried
Clarkealmost   mile to the road to get
help?
So instead of busting his balls,
maybe you should be thanking him.He
probably saved your son's life.
Hey,you know,I don'tthink I like your
attitude.
Really? I   n't thin  I likethe way you
treat your kid.
ere do you get offtalking to me like
this?
Where's your supervisor?
You don't know a damnthing about me or
my family.
No,no,no,that's wrong.
'Cause I know that Dennis is a good
kid,
and I know that you are an asshole.
Yeah,and if I were you,I'd
probablystart to treat him a little
better.
Because in a couple years he'sprobably
going to be bigger than you,
and he is going to rememberevery single
time you treated him like crap,
and one day he is goingto kick your
ass,okay?
You got a valid medical license,Dr.
Pratt?
Of course.
What about a pharmacist   lic  se?
My medical license allowsme to write
prescriptions.
Write,yeah,
but diverting controlled substances to
anunauthorized distributor that's a
felony.
I wasn't diverting anything,Iwas
treating patients.
At this illegal clinic of yours?
Illegal clinic?
All right,come on,fellas,let's no  get
carried away here,okay?
Look,I was helping out at a churchwhere
most of the congregation
doesn't even have health insurance.
Like the man that you killed?
Isn't one of you supposedto be the good
cop?
Ray.
Look,Dr. Weaver,I just spent the whole
day withthis great kid who saved his
little brother's life,
and when his stepfather came in and
started toberate and belittle him in
front of everyone,I just...
I don't know,I guess he just reminded
meof someone I used to know.
Yeah,I was just coming to say good-bye.
I may have done a great disserviceto
the world of rock keeping you here,
but you could be a great doctor,Ray.
I kind of thought I was.
I'm kidding.  rt of. Um...
Wow,um...
Thank you,Dr. Weaver.Thank you for
everything.
So what do we do now?Um,hug,kiss?
All right.
So what's next,you guys gonnabeat me
with a rubber hose?
What the hell is going on?
Dr. Pratt is under arrest.
On what charges?
Violation of the Controlled Substance
Act.
Do you believe these jokers?
You had to handcuff him?
It's a felony charge,Doc.
Aw,come on,guys,you can't do this.
Back off,Doc.
Unless you want to go with him.
She's playing with thebunnies,I'm
looking for my camera...
d then,suddenly,we hearthis God-awful
scream,
and we see this billy goathas Sammy by
the pigtails.
Speak of the devil!
Gracie invited me to dinner.
She did?
Hi,Mr. Owens.
Evening,Sam.
Don't worry. I'm not staying for
dinner.
Thanks for the dessert,Gracie.
Anytime,Bennet.
I baked a blueberry pie.I'm making fish
and chips.
Night,Sam.
Hey,you need a hand   thanything,Mr.
Owens?
No. I'm good,thanks.
I... I was just telling the boys about
howthe goat ate your pigtails at the
petting  oo.
Great. Where's Alex?
He's in his room. He's doing his
homework.
At least he better be.
Nice shot.
Hey,what are you doing here?
Why didn't you  ome back   to the
hospital?
How did you find me?
Guy at your hotel said you might be
here.
And,in case you're interested,
your test results show that yourlungs
aren't expanding properly.
They've become fibrotic.
Guess I'll have to switch to menthols.
You didn't have to come here.
Eight ball,corner pocket.
You're not getting enoughoxygen in your
blood.
You're going to need an
echocardiogramto check your cardiac
function.
tter luck next time,chief.
You need to be referred to a
specialist.
No more doctor stuff,huh?
Well,we need to find outwhat's causin
this,Eddie.
No,we don't. Abby,listen...
I don't understand why you got the
tests ifyou weren't planning on
following through.
I don't care about my damn lungs.
I didn't keep coming tosee you for
health reasons.
Okay. Well,th  ,talk tome. What's going
on,huh?
I been taking care of myself my whole
life,
usually at the expense of others.
I appreciate your concern,
but I don't deserve it.
You know,I...    I shouldn't have come
here.
Abby?
Look,just stay away from me. Okay?
Let me explain something.
No,you don't... Don't.
You don't have to. It'sjust a
mistake,all right?
Abby,I know what you're feeling.
No,I don't think you do,because I don't
know what I'm feeling.
And you're right. Ididn't need to come
here.
And I shouldn't have come here.
Abby,I lied to you.
I didn't want to scare you off.
My name isn't Jackson.
It's Wyczenski. I'm your father.
Yeah. I talked to Maggie a while back.
- Probably going on three years.- No.
No.
Yeah. I got caught up onyou and your
brother,Eric,
- fore she started screaming at me.- No
no...
This is not happening.
Yeah,it is. She told me you wereworking
at the hospital here in Chicago.
You know,why are you doing this?
I wanted to see for myself.
After 30 years?
Yeah. I wanted to see what sortof a
person you grew up to be.
- Oh,God! I can't do this.- Took me two
years
- to work up the nerve to come and
visit you.- I cannot do this!
One of the nurses atthe triage desk,she
pointed you out to me,
- and I got cold feet.- Taxi!
You know,if you hadn't walked into the
bar,
I... I probably would have leftwithout
ever speaking to you.
But when I met you,I wanted to know
more,
but I didn't have thegut to tell you
the truth,
because I thought you'd tell me to go
away.
Well,guess what. You were right. Go
away!
- Go away.- Oh,Abby...
Abby,please.
No. Just leave me alon   All right?
You don't get to do this. It's not
fair.
Hey,Kerry!
Hey.
Hey. I didn't get a chanceto say
good-bye to Pratt.
I'm on my way to the policestation to
bail him out.
That's one of those parts of the
jobthey never tell you about.
One of the many partsthat I'm not going
to miss.
Look,hey,I never had a chance to tell
you...
Luka,Luka,you know what?
I'm done talking about th  . Really.
Please?
I... I know...but,hey,you... you hired
me.
I still remember my first day.
An oxygen tankrocketed through the
E.R.- almost killed me.
Well,no one ever said thiswas the
safest place to work.
You... you changed mylife by giving me
this job.
You may even have saved it.
I don't know where I'd beif   hadn't
found this place.
And you taught me a lot.
Thank you.
Come here,you big Croat...
You know what? Don't get up...
Don't get caught up inthe politics,all
right?
A good hospital is aboutpeople and
medicine.
Thank you.
I'll see y   around sometime.
Yeah.
Luka...
Take care of this place for me.
I will.
*******
It's getting late,so I'd better get
going.
But we don't   even work tomorrow.
Yeah,but I'm like Gracie.And I need my
beauty sleep.
Well... you could sleephere tonight if
you want.
It would save you all that driving.
Yeah,but you have that ruleagainst
workplace fraternization.
It's actually more ofa guideline than a
rule.
And it applies moreto doctors than
nurses.
Hmm. That's good to know.
And Alex and Gracie would be okay with
this?
Come on.
Here's a two bedroom onLakeshore with a
concierge.
Hey,I always wanted to livein a
building with a concierge.
You can't possibly   forda place on
Lakeshore.
$3,600 a month.
Like I said...
$1,8   apiece.
What? Are you going tosplit it with the
concierge
Funn   Make yourself laugh there?
You like that one? Is that a funny one?
Hold that thought.
Hello. Hello.
Sarah?
I think mom'  reallysick. I can't wake
her up.
What? Where are you?
In the car.
Where? Where... where's the car?
I don't know where we are,Tony.But you
have to do something.
I think she's dying.
Sarah? Sarah? * * * *
Okay. All right.
All right,one second.I'll get you out
in one second.
Sorry,honey.
Shh! Okay. It's okay.
Here we go. We're home.
Hey,hey. Just one sec,okay?One sec.
Here    go.
Come on,Luka. Pick up.
Hey,it's me. Um,uh... I'm home.
I just got Joe from Ellen's.
Listen,can you call meas soon as you
get this?
It's kind of... it's kind of urgent.
Thanks.
Here we go. I know. Sorry. It's okay.
Yeah,I know.
Shh! Shh! Sh   Shh!
Okay,okay,here  e go.
Call  our husband.
I... I just did. He's not picking up.
Call him again.
www.tvsubtitles.net