I don't like questions without any answers,
like "where do we go when we die?"
I mean, I know what happens
physiologically speaking,
but beyond that, what really happens?
Anything?
That's what you start asking yourself
when you live on a clock.
All these questions without any answers...
they'll drive you nuts.
That's why I like what I do...
fixing babies, birthing babies.
No ambiguity there, no questions,
just answers... clear,
precise, obvious answers.
And life... beautiful new life.
Hope for the future.
God, I miss that.
Morning!
Robbins, are you ever not chirpy?
Does that ever happen?
Are you ever not snarky?
Also, you snore.
I can't crash here again
tonight without earplugs.
Okay, so, we have seven cases today.
The first one is in two hours.
Also, it's Friday, so that's MRI day.
You know the drill.
47 minutes of my very
limited life-span wasted.
Mm, come on, come on.
God! I'm coming.
- Stop chirping.
- Stop snarking.
Whew! After this, we've got the
diaphragmatic hernia. Baby's 27 weeks.
We'll do a, um, tracheal
balloon occlusion...
hey. Figured you could use this...
Which should, if we're
lucky, ensure the blood...
- before the big lecture.
- Oh, um, thanks.
Thank you.
Um, they already scheduled
a follow-up procedure on the baby, as well.
You're cultivating quite
a bit of buzz, you know?
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
I heard from two hospitals
wanting us to record your talk.
But we won't be too close to the due date.
- And if...
- I have a lot on my plate right now,
just with, uh, Herman and her tumor.
Uh, her surgery.
I really need to focus...
On the tumor.
Don't need any distractions, and you're...
Very hard to ignore.
Hey, I ju... It was just coffee.
No, I so appreciate the coffee.
Uh, I was just getting some
coffee for myself, and...
It's good coffee. It...
It's great coffee.
I, uh... I can...
I can just get my own if... if you...
I mean, you can get your own so easily.
I don't want to get my own coffee. I...
I mean I do. I can. I will.
I... I can get my own coffee
all day long. I just...
Owen.
Thank you for bringing me the coffee.
I really like it.
Uh, you're welcome.
So, how's my head?
The tumor seems stable.
I was worried about
the inferomedial margin,
but the good news is,
there's no sign of growth.
It hasn't invaded the optic nerve yet.
Well, how long till it does?
I need a number, Shepherd.
I have things to plan.
About six weeks... Maybe eight
if you go in for the localized radiation
treatments I've prescribed for you.
- I'd like for those to start today.
- No, no, no, no.
I tried that. Hated it.
Doctor's orders. It is our best chance
to shrink the part of the
tumor on your optic chiasm.
- Oh, crap.
- Glenda Castillo!
We're headed to surgery, Dr. Bailey.
No time to talk.
But you haven't given me an answer.
Actually, I have. It was no.
But you haven't given me the right answer.
You could at least meet with her.
I've seen the case, okay?
I'm sorry, but I'm working
on a very limited time frame
with a very specific list of
surgeries to teach Robbins,
and Glenda Castillo isn't one of them.
Okay, well, as a personal
favor to me, just me per...
I have no time to make it personal.
It's a no. I'm sorry.
I'll get you some names... good people.
She can see one of them.
Um, sorry.
Three down, all these to go.
We've got four months'
worth of surgeries up here.
I mean, how are we gonna get four
months of surgeries done in eight weeks?
We just do, I suppose.
You'll do the next one
yourself. I'll watch.
What? No. No, thank you.
I appreciate the vote of confidence,
but I'm not even actually
sure that I know how...
I need to see what you've learned,
what you can and can't do on your own
while I'm still around to
fix it when you screw up.
Gee, thanks.
It's not a vote of
confidence. It's a necessity.
Training wheels are off, Robbins.
Time is up. What's next?
Uh, your radiation treatment.
Ugh. Radiation hasn't worked yet.
I don't see why it's suddenly
supposed to start working.
- Radiation is bull...
- Shepherd says that it's necessary.
She's the doctor here.
"Life will out."
The origins and lessons
of life and evolution
are long and complex,
but what they basically boil
down to is, life will out.
Life will always find a way to continue.
Always.
Life... will... out.
This is a massive grade IV astrocytoma.
I want you to take a look at it.
Really look.
Look at its size.
Look at the way it invades healthy tissue.
Look at its vasculature.
It is blood and tissue and flesh.
It's growing...
Adapting to its environment,
struggling to survive, to stay alive.
It is alive.
We don't like to think of it that way, but
it's nested in the womb of a human brain,
feeding on its host, growing
and fighting for life...
almost like a fetus.
No, scratch that.
Let's just for science and giggles
say exactly like a fetus.
Because like a healthy
fetus, it is thriving.
You know, there are
even some types of tumors
that grow teeth, hair...
A stray eye.
Have I repulsed you?
- It's gross, right?
- Yeah.
I mean, that is a problem.
Nobody wants something
that nasty in their head.
I'd like you for one
moment to consider the idea
that, to the tumor, we are the problem,
we are the invader.
We are the danger.
To the tumor, we are the cancer.
And the tumor?
Well, the tumor sees itself as
a sweet, cute, fat-cheeked baby
just trying to make its way into the world,
and we want to stop it, destroy it,
tear it from its happy
little home like barbarians.
To the tumor,
we are the soulless, murderous monsters.
Why do I do this?
Why do I call it "baby"
and talk about killing it?
Because this kind of
tumor deserves respect.
It deserves a little humanity.
Charming, isn't it?
They put clouds on the
ceiling to distract you.
Least they could do is put
something interesting up there,
like porn.
It's not just a tumor.
It's ingenuity.
It's strength.
It's adaptability.
It's poetry.
It's one of God's masterpieces.
It is alive.
Mm.
You okay?
Sure.
And like any living thing,
it wants to stay alive.
Like any living thing,
it is going to fight like hell to survive.
And when I saw open that skull
and come face-to-face with it,
with that tumor, with that living thing,
it will be almost impossible to remove...
Well, I'll see you after.
Because it would rather
destroy the brain that holds it
than go gently into that good night.
It is alive.
And what's it all come down to?
Life...
Will...
Out.
Grey's Anatomy 11x13
Staring at the End
Sync and corrections by Albanda
www.Addic7ed.com
So, our fat-cheeked-baby tumor
that's nestled in that brain,
it's a creature of habit.
It has the same routine
day in and day out...
to grow, to spread out, to take up space.
That's it.
At this point, our baby tumor
is so enmeshed, so invasive,
it's touching virtually
every single brain structure.
It's pushed existing tissue aside,
shoved brain matter out of the
way to find room for itself.
How do you remove it without
destroying the brain around it?
How do you kill the baby
without killing the mother?
I stare at these scans, and
the tumor stares back at me,
daring me to try to extract it.
I mean, this tumor is bold and brazen.
This tumor thinks it's in charge.
This tumor thinks it owns the place.
I don't have to explain myself to you.
You missed your radiation
session this morning.
- I told you, I'm not doing that anymore.
- That is not your call.
My tumor, my head... it
absolutely is my call.
The tumor will be
exponentially easier to remove
after the radiation.
Nicole, please.
Go to radiation!
- I will think about it.
- Okay.
The thing about a tumor like this is,
you can't let it intimidate you.
The tumor isn't smarter than you.
You just need a plan of attack.
Here. Feel that?
You must be methodical.
You want to find a spot with
just the right amount of give.
That's where you want to cut. Scalpel.
Point of access is key.
- You're up, Robbins.
- I know.
I've never done that part before.
So, um, you were really serious about that?
It's time. Make the cut.
- But I don't know... I've never...
- Make the cut.
And then you start.
That is the most daunting step...
pushing a blade into that
first squishy blob of flesh...
Because the first cut
is what sets the tone.
It determines every single
move from that point on.
So, you have to be careful.
You have to be sure.
Or you're in trouble.
It's like a...
- Just look at them.
- Who?
Arizona and Herman... they're
practically joined at the hip.
I'll take one of those, too.
Well, she is Herman's fellow.
Isn't she sort of supposed
to follow Herman around?
They're laughing all the time,
And Arizona seems so...
Happy... like really happy.
- So?
- You seem happy... Ish.
- Why do you even care?
- I don't, obviously.
I'm just making conversation.
Don't you guys think it's weird
how they're always together?
They're not always together.
- They do bunk up together sometimes.
- What?
- Alex.
- Robbins has been crashing with Herman.
She hasn't slept at the house all week.
- What?!
- Alex.
- I don't mean like that.
- They're not together
together, and you know that.
Mm-hmm.
Arizona used to hate her.
Now they're having sleepovers?
Well, it's a good thing, right,
that they're getting along?
Herman's not exactly
the warmest person, so...
When you talk to Derek tonight,
would you ask him something for
me without saying it's for me?
I don't know that I w...
Just ask him what he'd use
to avoid disrupting
the gratiolet radiations
off the geniculate body of the thalamus.
- Why don't you ask him that?
- No, no, no.
No, no. That's the point. You ask him.
I can't ask him for help.
I cannot listen to the
smugness in his voice.
You can hear it.
He has transcontinental
smugness. You know what?
Forget it. I'm fine. I don't need him.
I don't need Derek.
I will figure it out myself.
When did this happen?
She found the perfect rebound
without having to
actually find a rebound...
I mean, she just gets all
the good times and the fun,
none of the bad times or the mess,
no chance of getting hurt.
You don't even have to wax. It's not fair!
Oh, my God. Am I seriously
wishing for a sexless relationship
where I don't have to groom myself?
- Is that where I am now?
- It sounds good to me.
- Welcome to my life these days.
- You chicks need to get laid.
That also sounds good to me.
Not without the grooming.
It's in there. He can find it.
What, he can't do a little work first?
I like her.
Eddie.
- Excuse me?
- Uh, Glenda Castillo,
the patient you and Herman
turned down last week,
her husband's name was Eddie.
I lost him six months ago
after he was injured
in a head-on collision.
My hands were inside of his body
when his heart stopped beating.
My hands held Glenda's
when I told her Eddie died on my watch.
Three weeks later, she
found out she was pregnant.
She's not insured,
but she remembered me and this hospital,
so, she came here
to see if I could give
her some prenatal care,
and guess what we found out.
Her baby has a tumor...
a large, dangerous tumor
that's not just messing
with the baby's system,
it's messing with hers.
I couldn't save her husband's life,
but I can help save her baby.
I owe this woman that much.
Herman has to take her on as a patient.
Just... just have her
meet Glenda, all right?
- Then she'll...
- I can't, I can't!
I can't trick her into seeing a
patient she doesn't want to treat.
Who's in charge of her schedule?
Who tells her where to go and when?
Who tells her what surgery or
post-op or anonymous consult
she should see next?
Uh...
I'm concerned about her blood pressure.
It's increased to 140
systolic in the past week,
and her swelling's gotten worse.
Uh, I used to have ankles.
Now I have balloons with toes.
So, your baby has a large
tumor in his lower back.
It's most likely benign,
but because of its size
and vascular nature,
it could cause an accumulation
of fluids in the baby.
But the tumor can be removed, right?
Dr. Bailey says amazing things about you,
that you're one of the best.
Bailey said that?
How flattering.
That was Glenda Castillo.
I told you no twice now.
And you, how am I supposed
to trust you at all
- when you pull something like that?
- She didn't do anything
except try to get your help on a patient
who needs your help.
But if you heard her story,
if you knew she was...
Is that how Bailey convinced you?
It's a tactic, Robbins,
appealing to your sad, bleeding heart.
Doesn't work with me.
Well, then, let me appeal to your ego.
You walk around here telling
anyone who will listen
that you're the best.
Well, then, be the best.
You can save her baby's life,
so save that baby's life!
No.
Ohh.
- What the hell?
- Robbins, drop it.
No, I get that... I get that
I've seen tumors like that before,
but this can't all be about my education.
I mean, at some point, I have to...
At some point, we have to make
decisions and stick to them.
I wish we had time, but we don't.
We have very little control
over the time we have,
and we have a plan.
Can't we make an exception?
Can't we just, you know,
sort of adjust the plan?
You... fine. You want to?
Adjust the plan.
What are you doing?
Take down one of these cards
so we have time to help Mrs. Castillo.
Which one?
How about Meghan Carlson...
congenital airway obstruction?
Her husband's in Iraq right now.
Or Julie Hall... vasa previa.
She went through two years
of fertility treatments.
So, pick one.
Decide which baby doesn't get to live
so Glenda Castillo's does.
Go ahead.
Pick a card. You choose.
That's what I thought.
_
No.
Get me out!
Get me out of here!
- You have to.
- I don't.
The radiation treatments are going to help.
They are gonna shrink
the borders of the tumor,
which will make it easier to resect.
It's a minimal gain for you.
I will take what I can get.
I am trying to save your life!
You are making me feel
like I've already died.
I'm sick. I'm losing my hair.
I refuse to spend the
last few months of my life
feeling like a pile of crap.
No more. That's final.
Dr. Stanley, please report...
I am going to give you
more than a few months.
I am going to save your life.
And I am about to get up in
front of a bunch of people
and tell them how I plan on doing it.
It makes it really hard for me to do that
or even care about doing that
when you don't seem to care at all!
Well, that's your problem.
Well, the word's spreading.
This was a good idea, Hunt...
a master class in neurosurgery.
This is gonna put Amelia
Shepherd on the map.
Mm. Unless it fails.
It won't.
If it does...
There's a lesson in that, too.
So, she just spitballs this stuff with you?
It's just the two of you
hanging out, talking tumor?
Pretty much.
I want to talk tumor!
- I want to talk tumor so bad.
- Shh!
- Oh, my God. Look at that thing
- Yeah.
Previous attempts to treat Dr.
Herman's tumor with radiation
proved unsuccessful.
I had hoped to use high radioactive doses
to reduce the margins,
but at this juncture,
that course seems to be unrealistic.
But that's not enough to make me quit.
This tumor is fierce and
intimidating and aggressive,
but so am I.
Now, the trick to this is,
you can't touch the vessel
while you're lasering the mass...
not even a little bit. If you do...
The field fills with
blood, obscuring the camera,
and visualization is compromised.
First, I need to see
the tumor, all of it...
every margin, every last ripple and ridge.
So, what do you do?
I have two choices...
open her up and stop the bleeding if I can,
or deliver the baby
regardless of how early.
Very good.
So, I will employ fluorescein dye
to delineate every border of the tumor,
to help me anticipate
every possible problem
before I get to it.
I don't want to leave
anything up to chance.
What happened?
The pressure's dropped.
She's in a lot of pain, and she's cramping.
It hurts! It hurts, it hurts!
It's okay, Julie. We've
got you, we've got you.
She has a vasa previa.
She's scheduled for an ablation tomorrow.
I've been trying to get
her pressure back up,
but there is no fetal heartbeat.
Damn it. Where's her husband?
Is that blood?! I'm bleeding?!
- Gown me.
- Keep him out of here.
Robbins, you're gonna get this
baby out right here, right now.
Here?
We need a C-section tray set up in here.
Call peds. Get an incubator, stat.
Wait! What?! I'm gonna have the baby now?!
Julie, I'm gonna give you
something to calm you down, okay?
I never had to do a crash
C on my own before, okay?
- I mean, not like this.
- You know what to do.
It's the same three basic steps,
just like any other C-section...
Open the abdomen, open the uterus, deliver.
Okay, I'm okay.
Pressure's steady at 100/60.
- Okay, I can do this.
- Betadine.
Okay.
- Robbins?
- I'll do... I'll do this.
It's fine, Robbins.
I'll do it.
Scalpel.
I'm so sorry.
We did everything we could do.
Good job. Let's go.
Stop crying.
Oh, for the love of...
- Stop crying!
- I'm...
Stop it now! Just...
Stop it right now.
There's no time for crying.
We have work to do.
What?
How can you even...
'Cause that's the way it goes, Robbins.
Call Bailey.
Tell her we're on.
_
Now, arguably, the most
important part of the brain
is the part that makes us hope...
Dream...
Imagine.
One singular, almost immeasurable part
is what makes you you...
And me me...
And everyone... Everyone.
It's technically called the fornix,
but I call it the "dream box."
The question is...
What happens when the
dream box is being invaded,
when a tumor is so large, so demanding,
it's sucking the dream box dry?
It's taking over...
it's stealing away hopes and dreams.
Imagine, when that tumor is removed,
what... what will actually be left?
Or, rather, who is left?
Anything?
Anyone?
I remember my mom telling me once
that when we die, we go to heaven.
I couldn't picture it.
All I could imagine was
what we see in cartoons...
little people in robes with
wings, sitting on clouds.
But nobody really knows
what's up there, do they?
When I was a kid,
I used to think that we
were like dandelions...
like, the part that makes
us us would just blow away
and land and grow into...
I don't want to be buried, by the way.
- Have me cremated.
- W... Excuse me?
If I survive the surgery but don't wake up,
give me five days... a week, tops...
- then pull the plug.
- This is...
We don't need to be talking about this.
If I do wake up but I'm
dependent on vents or tubes,
pull the plug then, too.
You know what? You're
not... you're not dying.
You're not gonna wake
up gorked. Shepherd knows
- what she's doing. She does.
- Okay. Sure.
- She does!
- I heard you.
That bird is gonna poop on us.
Oh...
- What's next today?
- Glenda Castillo.
I'm so glad you brought me back in.
Have a look.
Well, the teratoma has grown.
It's showing early signs of hydrops.
- Is everything okay?
- Glenda, your baby's retaining fluid,
which is starting to affect his heart.
I'm recommending we do the surgery tonight.
Tonight?
No, that's way too soon.
The tumor is creating
pressure on your placenta.
It's not only endangering the baby,
but now it's putting you at risk.
But my baby wouldn't survive, would he,
if you suddenly had to deliver?
'Cause I'm only 24 weeks along,
and I know that it would help
him if he had time to grow, right?
If I could just hold on
for a few more weeks...
It's not what's best for you.
I don't care about me.
Glenda, if Dr. Herman thinks that...
No, my husband is dead.
But this baby that is inside of me,
this baby of ours, I cannot risk his life.
I won't.
So, if there is a choice
between helping me or helping my baby,
I choose my baby.
What does she think
we're trying to do here?
I am not negotiating with a patient.
I am the doctor. I'm gonna
tell her when we're go...
I'm sorry.
- Robbins, what's the hell?
- What's funny about this?
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
It's just... it's just...
it's funny listening to
you get so bent out of shape
when this is the exact same thing
that you've been doing to Amelia Shepherd
ever since she offered to save her life.
I mean, she has. Exactly.
"We'll do the surgery when I'm ready."
And it's so frustrating. It's
torture, and it drives us crazy.
So, it's just fun to
watch it happen to you.
It's like divine justice.
Pretend that I'm not here.
Keep going.
I will give Ms. Castillo an extra week,
but I want her admitted.
And if she so much as hiccups funny,
- I'm taking her to surgery.
- J... understood.
Hey, thank you for taking her case.
Oh, shut up.
I can't...
How do I access that area of
the brain when it's so hidden?
And once I access that area,
even with the perfect tools,
the perfect approach...
How do I keep from screwing it up?
If there's edema, it's post-fixed.
It's too narrow, too close the fornix.
If I hit the hypothalamus, game over.
Not gonna work, not gonna
work, not gonna work.
Do you want some food?
Have I figured this out yet?
No.
This has never been done before.
All these steps in this
order on this kind of tumor
has never been done.
Is that a good thing or a bad thing?
Who do I even think I am?
Who am I to even try this?
Okay, a bad thing.
Have you called your brother?
I know. You don't need him.
I was just thinking you could,
just to have someone to
bounce these ideas off of
who understands this kind of
thing the way that you do...
A peer.
He might have a suggestion.
I do not need my brother!
I am not stuck! I am thinking!
I am figuring it out!
I am right on the edge of figuring it out,
of making the breakthrough of a lifetime!
I am this close!
My genius is flying
around this room right now,
trying to find a clear path to land on me,
but I can't clear the runway for landing
because I can't find any quiet
because some idiot resident
keeps talking to me!
I didn't mean it. I'm
tired, and I'm frustrated.
I...
I am so sorry. I just
This tumor is making me crazy.
Edwards.
As bad as you want to get that tumor,
that's as bad as I want to
watch you get that tumor.
You're tired and frustrated
and terrified, but guess what.
I don't give a damn.
You're supposed to be my mentor.
You are my mentor.
I believe in you, I look
up to you, I want to be you.
That's an enormous responsibility,
so don't call me names.
And stop pouting because you
don't understand what to do.
Be worthy of being believed
in, of being looked up to.
Or if you can't actually be worthy,
if I am actually wasting my time,
if there is nothing about
you that is special or wise,
for God's sake,
at least have the decency
to pretend that there is.
Get it together, Dr. Shepherd.
_
Okay, bye.
Bye.
- Hey. Um, how are you?
- Uh, good.
How's Dr. Herman? Is she
good? Is everything good?
Yeah, I mean, she's killing me
with back-to-back surgeries but...
Yeah, and Amelia's
plan? You good with that?
- Callie, what are you...
- What?
I'm not... I'm just checking in, okay?
I'm just... Seeing how
you are and, uh, how, um...
- Callie?
- Well, it just seems like
you and Dr. Herman are getting
along really, really well,
and you used to complain
that she was killing you,
but now you're happy
that she's killing you,
and it seems like you
really, really like her.
I do. Actually, I do. She's great.
- She's... I mean, she's amazing.
- And she's sick.
- So, I worry.
- Amelia's got it covered.
- She's gonna be fine.
- I worry about you.
I know I shouldn't.
I know it's none of my
business, but, uh, old habits.
Well, that's, um...
Thanks.
- Oh, I got to go.
- Okay, okay.
Wow, that's tall.
Yeah. Really big.
Just so you know, the auditorium is packed.
The fire marshall actually
made me move a bunch of people
out to an overflow room.
Amelia.
Just give me a minute.
- Amelia.
- Shh!
Hang on.
You can talk to me.
You're wound pretty tight.
I just want you to know you can talk to me.
My whole career, I have
been the other Dr. Shepherd.
He's the real one. I'm the other one.
Right now, this plan
of mine is theoretical.
It's just talk.
But at some point,
I am going to slice
into Dr. Herman's brain,
and I have this sick feeling
that when I face that tumor,
I will discover that I am not
just the other Dr. Shepherd...
I'm the wrong Dr. Shepherd.
Hey.
911? What's going on?
Look, I know you've been having
me take the lead so I can learn,
but you need to handle this case.
- Why would I do that?
- Because it's emergent,
and I've never tried
cutting umbilical bands.
- First time for everything.
- Well...
Listen to me, okay?
I'm not ready to take this over yet.
Doesn't matter.
Stop! Stop!
You... You're not hearing me.
It does matter. I'm not ready.
And you think I am?
You think this is easy for me?
You think I'm ready?
I was fine. I got fine with dying.
And then you infected
me with your stupid...
with Shepherd and her
plan and your stupid hope.
And now it's harder than ever
to hand all this over.
I don't want to.
I'm scared to.
And I'm scared to let go of it,
and it's all your fault, so...
I think the very least
you could do is deserve it.
Take over, do well, make me not regret it.
Can you do that?
Please?
This is the part
where things get a little fast and furious.
It is arguably the most dangerous,
most precarious portion of the operation.
It also needs to happen the fastest.
Every step, every move before this
has laid the groundwork
for this very moment,
the moment where I place
the radioactive seeds.
It requires precision...
I just need to slip these
shears under the band.
And accuracy and speed...
things that do not go together well.
I can't get the last band.
This grip's not flexible enough.
Can you coax it through?
Mm. It's not... no. It won't give.
- You have to cut that last band.
- I know.
- Have you tried a smaller scissor?
- Mm. It's not the problem.
Imagine picking up little grains of salt
while wearing oven mitts.
That is what I'm doing
inside somebody's brain.
- Hand me a glove.
- What?
Somebody hand me a glove. Scissors.
There's this thing that
we used to do in peds.
I think it'll work.
I just need a more flexible opening,
and I can make it out of a glove.
That's not in my notes, Robbins.
- Are you serious?
- It's gonna work.
But once I do it,
once I place the final seed,
well...
It's smooth sailing.
Ha! Did you see that?!
It worked! It... it...
it absolutely worked!
'Night, 'night, tumor baby.
It has been lovely,
but we are done.
I'd like to open things
up to a few questions.
Yes.
Are you nervous?
Uh...
I'd be crazy not to be.
Yes, of course I'm nervous,
but I'm also very excited.
This is history.
This surgery will be history.
How could I not be excited about that?
Excellent, excellent.
You should be very proud of yourself.
Close up now.
Where are you going?
What you're describing is
seven different surgeries
all using the hardest
techniques you've ever tried.
How long do you anticipate the
entire surgery actually taking?
18 hours...
Give or take some hours.
Uh, follow-up question...
do you need a second resident on the case?
Uh, not unless Edwards
is planning to bail on me.
You planning to bail, Edwards?
No, ma'am.
Yes, in the back.
Will you have help?
Um... Sorry?
Well, I'm just, uh...
Well, are you gonna be doing
this whole surgery yourself,
or is Derek... uh, Dr. Shepherd coming?
I'm... I'm just... I'm just asking.
I mean, given everything,
is it a good idea?
Should you be doing this yourself?
Well, I am, so...
Next question.
I need you to scan me.
Something's happening. I'm
experiencing symptoms...
fuzziness around the edges,
a little like, uh, blinders,
and it's, uh, dark... darker
than it should be, I think.
Okay.
Let's go.
- Bailey?
- Where's Dr. Herman?
She stepped out. What do you need?
Uh... It's Glenda Castillo.
Hey, I need Herman right now.
Glenda Castillo's baby is in distress,
and Glenda is severely hypertensive,
showing signs of heart failure.
We need to operate on her immediately,
so if you could finish up...
What are you doing?
- Why are you standing there? I...
- Arizona.
Oh, God.
It's time.
Now?
I'm gonna go...
Get an O.R. ready.
Okay.
You ready for this?
Mm-hmm.
Amelia.
I'll get an O.R. prepped.
You'll inform the patient?
Oh. Robbins.
Surgery's all finished?
Yeah.
I see.
Shepherd's prepping the O.R.?
Yes.
If I had to guess, I'd say the
tumor's invaded the optic chiasm.
Ah.
My chariot awaits.
A little privacy, guys?
Did you, uh, need me for
something... a patient?
Um, yeah.
Glenda Castillo's baby has hydrops.
Mom is mirroring, and she's going into CHF.
Wow.
Looks like a big day for both of us.
What you need to do first
is try to embolize the
vessels fetoscopically.
Make sure her blood pressure is stabilized.
She has you.
Amelia has you.
This is the point where
you trust her, okay?
Don't go in without checking
Glenda's platelet counts
and crossmatching.
This is the point where
you trust her, okay?
All set.
Don't let Glenda's
platelet count drop below...
100. I know.
- Will you tie me?
- Yeah.
Let's do this.
I never placed much value
in wondering about an afterlife.
My concern was always this life,
what would I do with it?
How would I make my mark?
Be sure, be fast. You don't
have half the time you imagine.
Try to ablate all the vessels,
but don't wait too long.
Don't be afraid to make that call.
If she's awake, she'll
tell you for the 15th time
to save her child's life before hers.
Listen to her, let her say her piece,
- then you do what needs to be done.
- I don't think...
I don't... I don't know...
I don't know if I can do this.
- I can't. I can't do this.
- You can.
- Nicole.
- You will.
Let's get you inside now, okay?
I wanted to break new ground.
I wanted my life, my brain, my existence...
To mean something.
Hey, hey, hey, You're gonna be fine, okay?
Amelia's got this. You've got this.
The thing that I never
really thought about, though,
the thing I never really
wrapped my brain around
until now was...
Wait, Robbins.
No.
Don't you dare.
Don't you dare say it, Nicole.
In order to do that, in
order to be remembered,
in order to leave something
significant behind...
Time to go.
You have to leave.
Sync and corrections by Albanda
www.Addic7ed.com
www.tvsubtitles.net