do you see them anywhere?
Why don't we go back to their
house, wait for them there.
Yeah, 'cause they'll probably answer
the door the sixteenth time I knock.
There they are.
I'm sorry I followed you here.
I just really wish you could give
me a few minutes of your time.
I know you would never agree
to make it an open adoption,
but I just figured maybe
you never had a choice.
I mean, it's china, right?
W-what did he say?
He wants you to leave them alone.
Please... I just want ten minutes.
Learn what you're
like,tell you about my life.
He said they have no daughter.
I am sorry you wasted a trip.
I know that's them.
How does that work?
How do I pray?
You make a wish and lift the buddha.
I wish they could
understand how badly I need this.
Now make the wish again.
If you cannot lift the buddha this
time, your wish will be granted.
Are you okay?
-=http://sfile.ydy.com=-
proudly presents
sync:ﬂ«»‚»‚ µ∞∏‚∏‚
House Season05
Episode04 Birthmarks
I picked cameron's pocket down in E.R.
I came up with a doozy.
Your mother called-- twice.
She's still healthy.
This 25-year-old woman,
on the other hand...
her messages sounded kind of urgent.
Well, that's the way women sound
when their spouse of 50 years dies.
Your dad died? Are you--
yep. Fine!
our patient, who's been known to
take a few drinks on non-occasions,
vomits blood and collapses
on a trip to china.
Chinese surgeons cut
out a foot of bowel,
but the pain is worse
now than it was before.
House, call your mom.
What are you, my mom?
We can continue this
differential in five minutes.
Are those bags under your eyes?
You were up all night.
You told her, didn't you?
I don't know what your daddy issues
are, but don't deflect them on me.
Told his wife he's been
getting some strange.
She kicked his adulterous
tuchus to the curb.
Seriously, you told her?
Yes, I told her.
But no, she did not kick me to the curb.
We stayed up late talking.
We're going to continue talking.
Much like House should be
doing with his mother right now.
anybody read chinese?
Otherwise, we have no idea
what these doctors did to her.
Kutner, you're sort of asian,
right? Get it translated.
What about meckel's diverticulum?
If the surgeons didn't remove the
diverticulum, it can cause pain, bleeding.
Too high up for a colonoscopy.
Ct could miss it.
Ultrasound's fastest.
And since I'm fastest
with the ultrasound...
House, let me do the ultrasound.
You need to deal with
your dad and stop--
I'm not deflecting because
I'm avoiding something deep.
I'm deflecting because I'm
avoiding something shallow.
Seriously, I'm fine.
I didn't even like the man.
no meckel'S.
Were you there for the rice
or the reeducation camps?
I was there to track down
my biological parents.
Like a salmon returning to
the stream where it was born.
Did you become whole again,
or did you get eaten by bears?
They denied my existence.
Four parents, and not one of them
taught you to cover your mouth.
Oh, my god! It looks
like they cut you in half.
Doctor, we're her parents.
I'm just a technician.
Her doctors will be by
later. You can schmooze then.
Can you let them know that we, uh,
we went by her apartment and
collected all her medication.
I'm a technician and a doctor.
You went through my apartment?
We found alcohol.
We thought you'd quit.
- Did her drinking cause this?
- No.
Can you tell her it did?
Licorice root.
Uh, no, thanks. I'm good.
I threw it to you for a reason.
That's what the chinese
doctors gave her.
It contains glycyrrhizin.
They were treating her for sars?
Not very effectively.
But sars explains the cough, causes
hypoperfusion, which explains the ischemic bowel.
It's perfect.
Lung involvement isn't very severe.
Okay, well, so call it "ars."
Start her on ribavirin and interferon.
Sorry about your father.
I'm not.
Are we done emoting now?
If there's anything I
can do, just--
you know, you're right.I don't
think I can sleep alone tonight.
And you can tell me
that that is liquid vicodin.
We're giving I.G.Shots to everyone
who came in contact with your patient.
Shockingly, none of the nurses
volunteered to administer yours.
It goes better in a large muscle.
Drop your pants.
You know, I usually pay tens
of dollars to hear that.
The funeral's tomorrow.
My mom called you?
There is a 3:40 flight out of newark.
If you leave now, you can
be in lexington tonight.
Your mother wants
you to deliver a eulogy.
"Eulogy. "From the
greek for "good word."
Now, if she asked meto deliver
a bastardogy, I'd be happy to--
then be a grown-up.
Call your mother back and tell
her that you're sick with grief,
but you're too busy to be there.
She knows when I'm lying.
Then start writing.
they yanked my brother
and sister out of college.
Can you please tell them I'm not dying?
You have sars.
I'm wearing a mask.
It's a big deal.
Cut 'em some slack.
But I am gonna be okay, right?
That's what all this stuff is for.
We're gonna need the names and numbers of
everyoneyou came in contact with here and in china.
Flight numbers, dates...
that doctor that I coughed all over...
is he gonna be all right?
So far he's fine.
It's back.
This is where the pain all started.
She's tachycardic. Get
a crash cart in here!
What's going on? I need to know
what's going on. That's my daughter.
Her liver's failing. It's not sars.
I am not doing this because I care.
Cuddy drugged me. She...
my mom didn't call
Cuddy. She called you.
I knew you couldn't stay away.
I knew you loved me too much.
I'm doing this for your mom.
I'm not doing this at all.
If there were something to be done, I would
have done it in the year he spent dying.
You took my vicodin?
I'm in pain.
One?
So the vicodin is my leash.
One'll take the edge off, but it won't give
me enough relief for an escape back to plainsboro.
Where's my phone?
That's the team. It's their ring tone.
Forget it.
The patient's blood is on your hands.
House? You there?
I'm being held against
my will. Call the police!
Nicole had a clot in the hepatic vein.
Chase sucked it out,saved her liver.
No signs of a tumor or
venous malformations.
- Nothing that could
cause-- - she's an addict.
- Drugs and alcohol
wouldn't-- - she's a smoker.
Combine smoking with any one of a dozen genetic
disorders, and she's a clotting machine.
Multiple blood clots would tie together
bowel ischemia, lungs, and the liver.
we need to pinpoint which defect she has so
we can start her on the right anticoagulant.
Draw her blood--let's find out which
genetic gift her genetic parents gave her.
Thanks for calling.
My ring tone for you is
dancing queen, by abba.
Nicole?
I need to pee. Pull
over at the next stop.
I'll just pee on the floor.
You bought used floor mats?
That is brilliant.
There's a rest stop in five miles.
Cane.
The restroom's right there.
You can make it on your own.
I suppose I could talk about the summer
he decided he wasn't speaking to me.
Two months,not one word.
Anything he wanted to say,he typed
up and slipped under my bedroom door.
You don't want to say
anything,don't say anything, but go.
Tell your mom you're sad for her.
Just by being there,I'd be lying.
She wants to think,for a moment,
that she had a happy family.
So give her
a gift--lie!
Give me my cane...
I'll go to the damn funeral.
I said I'd go to the
funeral. I didn't say when.
We have these two
categories:Inside and outside.
Patients stay inside.
Then, when they're better,we
let them go outside.
Thanks. But they
don'tlet you smoke inside.
So why don't you go back there
and give me five minutes outside?
Make a fist.
'Sit such a beautiful day, we thought
we'd do all our doctoring outside.
People stare at me any
time I'm out with my family.
It's like a puzzle.
"Which one of these
things doesn't belong?"
Belonging's overrated.
I was adopted by a white
family when I was nine.
I like being different.
The view's better from
the outside looking in.
Must be easier to be
different when you're a success.
Is that a problem?
This is why we prefer inside.
You actually keep a flashlight that
doesn't need batteries in the trunk?
Next to the jacket, emergency water,nail
clippers, tooth brush,space blanket--
when things go wrong,I like to be ready.
Will you... please hold
the flashlight for a minute?
You know, those aren't just my car keys.
My House keys are on there too.
Amber gave me that key chain.
No, she didn'T.
Not unless your pet
name for her was "volvo."
A man who would lie about a
gift from a dead girl friend.
Is probably responding to a
childish, pointless act of petulance.
The struggle to resist one's
captors is never pointless.
Viva la resistance!
Well, I hate to break it to you,
che, but simple delay won't work.
Your mother will hold the
funeral till we get there.
My father was a punctual
man, beholden to time.
Two minutes late for
dinner,you didn't eat.
My mother would never disrespect
him by starting the funeral late.
Yeah, yeah, you clearly
have no issues to work through.
Come on, forget the
keys. Call a locksmith.
We'll go inside and play "guess that smell"
with the truckers while we're waiting.
Join me on the dark side.
The dark side's done,House.
I'm delivering you to your
mother, and that's it.
I have moved on.
What do you think House would send, the "gentle
comfort" arrangement or the "warm thoughts" bouquet?
I mean, if he wasn't an ass.
Send one of those giant
cookies shaped like a coffin.
His mom would believe it was from him.
I didn't tell you so
you could send anything.
Just wanted you to know the extent to which
the man is disconnected from the human race.
Took a six-pack of
ffp to stop the oozing.
She's bleeding and clotting?
Plus schistocytes on her smear means
it's dic, which means she's got cancer.
She's young. It could be leukemia.
Normal wbc makes that less likely.
The belly pain points toward a G.I.Tumor.
House already didan ultrasound.
He wasn't looking for
a tumor. Go run a ct.
I don't buy it.
Ct can find small intestinal
cancers that an ultrasound--
I don't buy House.
When my father died,I wound up
killing a patient. And I hated the man.
Whatever House says or doesn't
say, I'm sure the guy's a mess.
So he was a bastard. He
was still your father.
You're biologically programmed to
have feelings for him.
No, I'm not.
Feelings aren't rational.
I know you have trouble with anything
that can't be quantified and counted.
He's not my biological father.
I figured it out when I was 12.
Of course.
You were a brilliant,socially
isolated 12-year-old,
and you create a parallel universe
in which your life doesn't suck.
I look at the facts.
First of all, he was deployed on training exercises
off okinawa during the time I had to be conceived.
And since you're 150 years
old, air travel was impossible.
His second toe is
longer than his big toe.
Mine isn't.
This is sad. You don't
believe your mother screwed around--
I have a distinctivered birthmark on my scalp
that matches a certain friend of the family.
If you believed this story, you wouldn't
be telling me about his birthmarks.
You'd be telling me about the
genetic testing you had done.
And sinceyou haven't mentioned
it, obviously, you didn't do it.
Because you don't want
to--House, what are you doing?
Get your--get off
the-- there's a cop!
Nicole, lie still. This'll
only take a few seconds.
one millimeter cut
through upper abdomen.
She was adopted when the parents
thought they couldn't have kids.
Then they had three more.
She took the message as "thanks for
playing, but we have our real children now."
And the real children probably think
they're accidents while she was hand-picked.
Everybody's got
problems with their parents.
She's an addict. Something went wrong.
And it has to be the
parents? Magnifying pancreas.
I'm not saying the parents screwed up.
You're saying you like her.
So you don't want her
faults to be her fault.
But they're someone's fault, and
the only other people you know are--
I think we may need to call House again.
you lost track of your speed?
I think that was hitler's excuse.
Lost track of the jews.
No one held him responsible.
I'm not playing House.
You were protecting me.
Anybody in their right mind
would have ratted me out.
I'm just trying to speed things along.
You are going to this funeral.
Make it fast.
I don't want to miss the
anal cavity search.
Looks like a mass in the pancreas.
Not to me. This is radio.
And I want a full play-by-play.
It's fluid-filled.
Would you get out of
the car, please, sir?
Officer, if you want to give me
a ticket, I totally understand.
Just get out of the car, sir.
Cyst?
large cyst. Something going on there?
Wilson's getting arrested. how large?
suv sized,or mid-range sedan?
Seriously? What'd you do?
I'm obviously joking.
If wilson was getting handcuffed on the hood of
his car, would I be carrying on a differential?
Diameter is at least eight centimeters.
Is it in the tailor in the head?
the head.
You too, sir. Out of the car.
We've got a construction site.
A steamroller
is plowing--
out now.
No cane.
james evan wilson, there's a
warrant for your arrest in louisiana.
what are the traits of a steamroller?
Powerful. Maybe pancreatic cancer.
Great idea,except the only symptom it
matches up with is being steamrollerish.
You don't think House is onto something?
I think he thought he had an idea.
I also think his metaphors are tough
enough to decipher after he's said them.
We need to be focusing on the medicine.
No answer.
There's not gonna bean
answer. They've been arrested.
He was joking.
He reacted to the size and location.
That's what we should be focusing on.
Not playing mad libs while our patient's exploding
noun destroys her life-sustaining noun.
I'll try to get wilsonon the line.
What if it's not how a steamroller
works, but what it does?
Clears things.
This is a waste of time.
I need that phone call.
I'm a doctor, and when someone
tries to call you three times,
it's code for "pick up the damn
phone before someone dies."
I'm sure there's other smart doctors.
You'd be surprised.
You told me you'd taken care of this.
I did.
First words you ever said to me.
I took care of it.
You must've screwed up somehow.
Sir?
Not to hurry you, but we
need to be at a funeral--
nobody is going anywhere or taking any
phone calls till I hear back from louisiana.
It's a really old warrant.
Isn't there a statute of
limitations on this kind of thing?
It's suspended when you flee the state.
I didn't flee the
state. I left the state.
Because I don't live in the state.
And the charges were just so minor...
"vandalism, destruction
of property, assault."
There is a simple explanation.
There was a medical
conventionin new orleans...
you don't need to explain to me.
I was fresh out of med school.
I didn't know anybody at the convention.
You heard the man,wilson.
You don't have to explain.
I am not gonna sit here wasting time just
so you can avoid your father's funeral!
He's my father.
I have the right to avoid his funeral.
Not if your mother's alive,you don't.
Okay... explain.
did House react to
the eight centimeters?
He whistled. It's huge.
Anyone would think so.
House doesn't whistle because
he's impressed.
It means he wasn't expecting it.
It means he changed
his mind at that point.
a single super-sized cyst ruled out a
diffuse process like scleroderma or lupus.
Rule out diffuse process, you're stuck with
single process affecting just the pancreas.
Gallstones or pancreatic divisum.
Whatever he asked next would
have narrowed that down.
He asked about location.
Heads it's gallstones,tails
it's divisum.
It's at the head. She's got gallstones.
The steamroller meanspotholes--
relax. We got it.
You figured out she's got gallstones?
I was at the hotel bar trying
to unwind, have a drink.
There was this guy who kept playing billy joel's
leave a tender moment alone on the jukebox.
Leave a tender moment is a good song.
It's a great song. He was out of line.
Not as good as scenes from
an italian restaurant or...
so I--I asked the
man to stop, politely.
Yeah, you yelled politely.
I was polite the first couple of times,
but courtesy made no impressionon this ass.
So I threw a bottle into the mirror,
which successfully conveyed my message.
And smashed a ten-foot antique mirror.
And set an example to two other
patrons who threw shot glasses.
I had nothing to do with that fight.
The assault charge was totally bogus.
And I paid for the mirror.
I think I have the picture.
I assume you're the guy who
was playing the song.
No, I was the guy who bailed him out.
That's how we met. I was in jail.
This guy wasa total stranger
to you, and you bailed him out?
It was a boring convention.
Had to have somebody to drink with.
and there's the foundation
of our entire friendship.
If you hadn't been bored one
weekend, it wouldn't even exist.
Hey, there were 3,000
people at that convention.
You were the one I thought wasn't
boring. That says something.
It also says something that you lied to
me about getting the charges dropped!
I got a lawyer. He cut a deal.
You didn't call the guy? You
have to show up at the arraignment.
Everybody knows that.
Everybody with your
misdemeanor experience.
You can go.
What?
He--he's a
fugitive from justice.
That whole story was
lies. He stabbed a man.
Louisiana doesn't want
to pay to get you back.
Forget louisiana.
He was driving recklessly through
your comatose village.
Do they put lead in the
jelly doughnuts here?
Stop acting like such an ingrate and
go pay your respects to your father.
The ct confirmed gallstones.
Normally not dangerous.
Almost everyone has
them. But sometimes...
- they kill you?
- Yup.
Unless I take 'em out.
We do it laproscopically.
how long has her urine been brown?
Kidney's were fine this afternoon.
They're not now.
It's not the gallstones.
well, of course it's not gallstones.
Who thought it was gallstones?
You said "steamroller."
I also said "construction site."
Gallstones could cause a pancreatic cyst.
Just turn around.
The thing is two hours over already,
and that's the third time we passed that
colonial with the cross burning out front.
I'm not lost.
I'm not talking about
what caused the cyst.
I'm talking about what the
cyst caused. Everything.
Cysts are symptoms,not diagnoses.
Unless it's a multiple cyst,
with connections to other organs--
like a steamroller.
That's a long road down to the kidneys.
How do we prove it?
Won't be visible in a scan.
Chase isn't gonna go groping around
when she's got kidney failure.
Bubbles.
Is that your new stripper name?
Yes. And also,we inject bubbles into
the cyst and follow where they drift.
If they end up in the other organs, we
know you're right, cut it out, she's fine.
Bubbles is right. Go echo.
I'm not lost.
Nicole, you gotta stay still.
I'm--I'm nervous.
You're not nervous.
It's the dts, isn't it?
I haven't had a drink since I got here.
Good heavens,we haven't
missed it after all.
It's like the end of a christmas carol.
I'm so glad you're here.
Oh, it's a load off of
my mind just to see you.
Thank you, james.
Mom, how could you delay the funeral?
Honey, your dad is dead.
He's not going to care.
Do you know what you're going to say?
I don't know. Just let the minister
or one of his buddies from the corps...
you're talking.
I don't care that you didn't like him.
He was your father,and he loved you.
The war is over, greg.
Please do this for me.
Stop looking so worried.
I know he's gonna make me proud.
I'm sure you know him better than I do.
Her liver's been compromised.
And the dts will cause her muscles to
continue to twitch, even under sedation.
We need to paralyze
her to do this procedure.
I wanted to stop.
A phenobarbital coma will not only allow
us to inject the cyst,it'll treat the dts.
When she wakes up,she
won't be in withdrawal.
We've seen her through withdrawal before.
We've seen her through everything.
We've been supportive,
we've been combative.
We've picked her up from
bars in the middle of the night.
We've let her spend the night in jail.
I used to say it'd be okay.
That I'd get it together.
I don't say that anymore.
Let's make you healthy.
Then we'll worry about making you sober.
The lord is my shepherd,
I shall not want...
I am not talking.
We were strangers who shared
some geography 30 years ago.
Right, he had no influence on you at all.
The father who was
compulsive about punctuality.
His issue.
Which I deliberately made not my issue.
Thereby making it your issue.
Compulsively showing up four hours late,
ignoring discipline,ignoring rules.
Oh, god, he's here.
Who's here?
The one you're pretending is your father?
Nice pick. He looks like sean connery.
So back when you were devising this
fantasy, did you tell your father:
"Dad, I refuse to recognize your existence
because I have chosen james bond as my dad"?
I used different words.
What?
Hearing your own son hates you so
much he's replaced you in his mind?
That's gotta suck. How did he take it?
I already told you. He didn't
speak to me for a summer.
It means more to me than--than I
can say to have all of you here today.
And now, uh,our son gregory
would like to say a few words.
Greg?
There's a lot of people here today.
Including some from the corps.
And I notice that every one of them
is either my father's rank or higher.
And that doesn't surprise me.
Because if the test of a man is how
he treats those he has power over,
it was a test my father failed.
This man you're eager to pay homage to,
he was incapable of admitting any
point of view but his own.
He punished failure, and he did
not accept anything less than--
he loved doing what he did.
He saw his work as some kind of...
sacred calling.
More important than any
personal relationship.
Maybe if he'd been a better
father, I'd be a better son.
But I am what I am because of him...
for better or for worse.
And I just--I just wish--
Put it back.
Well, he's not gonna miss it.
I'm done enabling.
You can't even let them put him in the
ground without making it serve your agenda?
you really want to do
this in front of everybody?
You wanna punish me or them?
How can I still feel surprise?
You would take,even this, a moment of
real human grief, and turn it into a farce.
Oh, cut the crap.
You enjoy what I do.
I never had to force you.
You like coming along for the ride.
Yes, that's why I'm cheering you on now.
This is about you needing to
be prepared for the worst.
So you become an oncologist.
No surprises there. Worst
happens all the time.
But amber, she was young and healthy.
Her death came out of nowhere.
Don't bring amber into this.
And you weren't ready.
That makes you angry.
The world sucks, and you
didn't have time to brace yourself.
What happened out there is your show!
You're scared to death of
losing anyone that matters.
So you dump the person who
matters the most to you!
I'm not scared to death.
I'm moving forward!
Because no one can take away
from you what you no longer have.
Your father's death is about you.
Amber's death is about you.
I can't imagine why someone wouldn't
want to be your friend!
Admit it, you're angry and
you're scared of losing me.
- I'm not angry, I'm not scared.
- Admit it.
- I'm not afraid.
- I've lost people. It happens.
- Admit it. Admit it!
What are you,five? Stop repeating--
admit it. Admit it. Admit it. Admit it. Admit it.
Admit it. Admit it. Come on, admit it. Admit it!
Still not boring.
did you know I was gonna do that?
Because I didn't know I
was gonna do that.
I know you have trouble losing people.
In new orleans, I saw you carrying this
express package around the conference.
And you wouldn't let it
go,but you wouldn't open it.
So I peeked at the return address.
Diamond, fairbairn.
Divorce attorneys.
Your first wife had just
served you with papers.
Did you know that when you bailed me out?
Were you... doing something nice for me?
What did I say about being boring?
We owe your mom an apology.
Hello? It's House.
How'd the bubble test go?
The problem wasn't the cyst. It's
advanced dilated cardiomyopathy.
We did a three-dimensional echo.
Showed a mass in the left atrium.
looks like an atrial myxoma, but the
ultrasound images are a little grainy,
so it's hard to tell.
House?
The images aren't grainy.
They sure look grainy.
I've seen pictures of
you where you look tall.
It's iron overload.
Creates speckles on the
image,mas it look grainy.
Also makes her pancreas fail, her
blood clot, and her intestine--
atrial myxoma is more likely.
Mri for a better view.
And call me back and tell me you're embarrassed
because my eyesight is better 500 miles away.
I need a phone number.
I'm a doctor in new
jersey,treating one of your clients.
A young woman looking for
her biological parents.
You know, you could just wait for the
mri to have your curiosity satisfied.
What person who is nothing
like me are you saying that to?
Did the parents look tan?
The disease she has is genetic,
which means they should have it too.
They don't look more
tan than anyone else.
Discolored teeth?
They're farmers--the
village doesn't even have a dentist.
Right. Thanks.
But if it matters, I'm not
convinced they were her parents.
Why not?
Because they said they have no daughter.
The man was adamant, and the woman
seemed confused and frightened.
Thank you.
Differential.
Say you're a middle-aged
chinese woman...
- fine.
- Say it.
I'm a middle-aged chinese woman.
Girl comes to you, says that
she's your long-lost daughter.
Why would you be frightened?
I'm frightened because she's a threat?
Maybe she knows something?
She hasn't seen you
since she was an infant.
Maybe an inheritance issue.
They're peasants.
Her very presence is a threat.
She--what year was she born?
'83.
She's not supposed to be alive.
China introduced the
one-child policy in 1979.
Say they didn't want a girl.
They tried to kill her.
Maybe the baby doesn't die. Maybe
the father panics or regrets it.
Takes the baby to an orphanage.
Maybe he doesn't tell his wife.
Who freaks out like she's seen a ghost
25 years later when the girl shows up.
Why does attempted murder from 25 years ago
suddenly become relevant to her health now?
Maybe they gave her something toxic.
It would have to be fat soluble.
This is fun, isn't it?
Let me see the mri.
We don't have one.
She started vomiting as
soon as we started the scan.
Then let her vomit through the mri.
That's what nurses are for.
Her parents tried to kill her.
I don't know how, but I know it caused her to
get sick 25 years later trying to lift a buddha.
Explain.
I already had this conversation with
wilson--just go with it.
Poison?
Buddha wouldn't make it worse.
Maybe the weight stressed
her back, which--
makes sense if she's
never lifted anything in her life.
She actually didn't get sick till she
tried lifting it that second time.
I'm guessing the weight changed.
Anybody have taub's pager number?
What's up?
Maybe give him a call.
If he tosses that switch on
the mri, she's dead.
X-ray her brain.
pins.
Push them through the
soft fontanelle of an infant,
you skewer the brain,and the
hair hides the entry wounds.
It's the perfect crime.
She's had them in her all these years.
What changed at the temple?
Same thing that changed in the mri.
shockingly, not all religious
leaders are honest.
I'm guessing these particular monks are bilking
the faithful by pushing a magnet up buddha's butt.
There's another one under the table that'll
repel or attract,depending on how you shift them.
When she picked up that magnet,
it moved one of the pins deeper into the
sympathetic nervous center of her brain.
This sent a signal through the nerves to
the blood vessels in her small intestine
which caused the symptoms in china
and in the giant magnet we call an mri.
She's lucky.
We're all screwed up by our parents.
She's got documentation.
The pins will be removed
surgically, and she'll be fine.
We'll wake her from the
coma after the operation.
Is there any way you could not tell her?
Please. She's fragile.
She desperately wanted to
know her biological parents.
For her to find out that
they wanted her dead...
I don't know what that'll do to her.
She may not be as fragile as you think.
We know our daughter.
See this pin here?
It's been pressing directly on
her addiction center.
It's not her fault. And it's
definitely not your fault.
She's not who you think she is.
I hear your patient's gonna be all right.
Is that why you're here?
A colleague checking up on a patient?
Something goin' on?
I'm celebrating.
My mom hated him too.
Your dna test showed no
match? That's incredible.
At the age of 12, you actually figured
out your father wasn't your birth father?
That's what you wanted,wasn't it?
Why should it depress you?
It doesn't depress me.
Doesn't make any difference at all.
That's what depresses me.
Well, I guess nobody gets to
choose who their parents are.
I'm not even sure anymore if we
get to choose who our friends are.
I spoke with Cuddy. She
hasn't filled my position yet.
If you're coming back just because you're
attracted to the shine of my neediness...
I'd be okay with that.
I'm coming back because you're right.
That strange, annoying trip we just took
was the most fun I've had since amber died.
You hungry?
- Wilson.
- Yeah?
My dad's dead.
Yeah. My sympathies.
-=http://sfile.ydy.com=-
proudly presents
sync:ﬂ«»‚»‚ µ∞∏‚∏‚
www.tvsubtitles.net