Previously, on "New Amsterdam"...
- Dr. Bloom.
- Dr. Bloom?
The last few weeks, I've been taking
a little bit more Adderall
than prescribed.
- I think you may need help.
- I'm just tired...
Mr. Powell could have died.
Run the Cardiac Surgical Department.
There is no Cardiac Surgical Department.
Then build one.
When we aim high-energy
external beam radiation
at the cancer in your throat,
if you move then, you die.
I don't want everyone to see me so weak.
The answer's yes, Max.
I'll be your deputy.
I don't even know
what some of this stuff is.
Babe, I-I didn't know we had
so many friends.
This is a return, right?
- No way.
- No?
Cloth diapers are way better
for the environment.
Yeah, but disposable diapers
are way better
for sleeping in on Sunday.
- Fine, maybe pile.
- Maybe pile.
It's very cute that you think
you're sleeping in on Sundays.
Yeah. Electric snot sucker? Return.
How do you suggest we remove snot
from our baby's nasal passages?
The old-fashioned way.
You put your mouth on that nose
and you...
That's disgusting!
- Keeping.
- Babe, I'm just saying...
What about a baby... a baby blender?
That's a maybe. I mean, we
don't have an adult blender.
All right, well,
the Swedish here says, uh...
Oh, well, in that case...
- Mm.
- Return.
Return. Yeah.
Oh, babe, more nausea?
Mm. Mm-hmm.
Hey, I thought Helen said
that you wouldn't experience
chemo nausea so soon.
Well, maybe I'm, uh...
Maybe I'm special.
Maybe you should stay home.
Mm-hmm. Mm-mm.
I'm good.
I'm already over it.
It's fine.
I'm raring to go.
I'm not gonna let
a little cancer slow me down.
I'm fine.
Ow!
Synced & corrected by -robtor-
www.addic7ed.com
How can I help?
Figured out why the old
Cardio Department lost its way:
Our conflict of interest policy.
- What's wrong with it?
- Well, we don't have one.
Big pharma could buy me an island,
- and no one would know.
- Could be fun.
We should mandate total transparency.
Uh, how many other hospitals do this?
- Zero.
- I guess we'll be the first.
In clinical trials,
do you know what you want
in ideal candidates?
Ooh, I know this one. Sick people?
- Diversity.
- Yeah.
Our candidates need to be as diverse
as the country we're aiming to treat.
Yeah, so what's the problem?
The country I'm trying
to treat isn't Finland.
Hmm.
I can see that.
Yeah.
I'll make some calls.
More glitter, right? Okay, yes.
So New York has seen a spike
in Polynesian refugees
because their countries are, you know,
- sinking into the Pacific Ocean.
- Right.
Not a lot of them speak English...
like these little cuties right
here from Tuvalu, aren't you?
Imagine I just said
"how can I help?" in Tuvaluan.
I wish I could, but I can't,
because nobody speaks Tuvaluan
in New York...
literally, like, less than 20 people.
I need a translator.
Oh, okay.
So I just learned the word for "potty."
- Oh, did you?
- But I'm gonna take off.
Okay. Oh, oh. Gladys!
My department was just flagged by HCC
for "disproportionately
providing coverage
to patients ineligible
for Medicaid and for..."
Solved.
Thought that was gonna go in.
Still solved. Pretend it went in.
But they said they would cap my budget...
It doesn't matter.
We treat everybody here,
and if they're not covered,
if they're covered, it doesn't matter.
The price...
We treat everyone.
That's the power of New Amsterdam.
Excuse me.
- Max, are you okay?
- Yeah.
Ooh.
Max, you want us to wait for you?
Oh, God, what is the medical term
for "barfed my face off"?
This isn't a great time.
You don't even know
what just came out of me.
I'm not just talking quantity,
I'm talking quality.
I mean, what the heck
could I have possibly eaten...
- Max.
- What?
This is a consortium of top oncologists
being hosted by a WHO facility in Haiti.
Everyone, this is Dr. Goodwin,
our Medical Director.
How you doing?
- Hello.
Let's pick this up in 15, shall we?
- Sorry about that.
- It's fine.
I'm consulting
on a very challenging case.
A digression about the texture
of your vomit
was just the mood-lightener
that we needed.
Happy to help.
And you need anti-nausea meds.
Mm-hmm.
This is harder than I thought.
Silver lining?
When we start radiation tonight,
your throat's gonna be too sore
to eat anything.
Mm.
Less nausea.
So you'd walk by,
and you'd see all this smoke
seeping out from under the door.
But it wasn't a fire.
It was the cardiologists' smoking lounge.
In the hospital?
Yes, Building C.
Third floor.
They had the fire department
called on them
at least twice a month.
I can't believe you've never
told me that one before.
It was a different time.
It's just a wonder
more patients didn't die.
Yeah, no kidding... oh.
No, it's okay. It's okay, I got it.
No, no, no, I got it. Henry, it's cool.
- Thanks.
- I've been trained for such situations.
Just got to get the big chunks, right?
- Yeah...
- Thanks.
Kick the rest under the table.
Clumsy.
You know, my, uh...
my intern days were totally tame.
I-I don't have any
crazy stories, you know.
Oh, don't be so sure.
Those memories will come flooding back
once you're my age.
For example, I have
a temporal bone surgery
scheduled tomorrow.
Now, back in the day,
we wouldn't even consider operating
until we could see discoloration
in the neck and the jawline.
Oh.
That's crazy.
- Okay.
- Thank you so much.
- Lauren.
- I'm late.
Lauren...
I am deeply sorry.
If you would just hear me out...
You rooted through my bag for drugs
after I explicitly told you
that I was clean.
You just couldn't trust me, could you?
It's not that simple, and you know it.
I was concerned.
I overstepped. What I wanted...
We were friends.
- We still are.
- How?
You asked for help.
You admitted you needed help.
Let me help you.
How about this?
From now on, you stay
on your side of the hospital.
I'll stay on mine.
Oh, hi.
Max?
Hey, Dora told me
I could find you in here.
- Yeah.
- Oh, okay.
Uh...
that's all right. I can wait.
Oh...
- Hey.
- How can I...
Yeah, okay. Yeah, I got it.
So, um, let's say, hypothetically,
I have a friend here at the hospital.
Let's call him, uh, Dr. Dre.
Mm.
And, uh, what if he kind of,
sort of maybe...
shouldn't probably be
performing surgeries anymore?
We're not having
an unofficial conversation
about an impaired physician, Iggy.
We have a system.
I know.
I just don't want to ruin
anyone's career, you know?
Well, if you're concerned enough
to bring it to me here,
then it has to be official.
All right?
No half reports, no pseudonyms.
By the way, maybe pick a better one.
- I know.
- Just tell me what's going on
so I can investigate the doctor properly.
Come on, man. Can't we just
hypothesize about it
for a little while longer?
Iggy, your name will be
kept confidential, I swear.
It's Dr. Maravich.
What's going on?
¡Ayúdennos, por favor!
¡Él está enfermo!
- Do... do you speak English?
- Yes, yes, yes!
Please, you have to help him!
He needs help!
Severe dehydration.
Okay, let's get him over
to Bay 27 for a workup.
- What's your name?
- Ivan Velez.
- Ivan, how do you know him?
- Uh, Miguel, we are brothers.
- You must help him, please!
- He feels hot.
Ivan, look at me.
How long has he been sick like this?
Uh, about a week.
He started shivering, and he...
he couldn't, uh, drink or eat anything.
We thought he needed sleep,
but it only got worse.
Does it hurt to swallow?
- You have to help him!
- I'll do everything I can.
Bloom, lymphs are swollen.
Okay, open for me?
What? What do you see?
He needs an FNA, ASAP.
- Who's on call for oncology?
- Dr. Sharpe.
Daddy, who is that man?
Shh.
My name is Dr. Kapoor.
I'm going to help your mom.
She can't see.
Her eyes are broken.
Then I'll try to fix them.
Let's find a healthy snack, kiddo.
Yeah.
We'll be just outside.
I see from your records, Maren...
- you've had a rough time.
- Yeah.
My organs, they shut down
during Violet's birth.
I couldn't stop bleeding.
I was in the ICU for, uh, nine months.
Ian had to make arrangements.
Just in case.
- But you survived.
- Mm-hmm.
Well, most of me.
So you developed an adenoma
at the base of your brain.
It's pressing on the optic chiasm
and causing your blindness.
Yeah, and everyone says
they can't remove it
because I can't have anesthesia
'cause of my liver.
That's right.
But there is a new treatment...
non-surgical.
I won't even need to break the skin.
How?
It's MRI-guided focused ultrasound...
noninvasive, no anesthesia.
Just one catch.
Yeah.
There's always a catch.
Before I can address your brain tumor,
we need to replace one
of your heart valves
also weakened by Violet's birth.
But I'm sure my colleague, Dr. Reynolds,
can do that without anesthesia as well.
Wow.
I would love to see my daughter's face.
I would love to see her eyes. I would.
Hi.
I got your page.
Yeah.
Mr. Velez?
This is Dr. Sharpe.
She's gonna biopsy your brother's throat
so we can figure out
what's making him so sick.
Open up for me, Mr. Velez.
Arroyo. His name is Miguel Arroyo.
I thought you guys were brothers.
We're like brothers.
You know, we are Boricua.
We grew up a town apart on La Isla,
but we never knew each other
until we came to New York.
When did you move here?
Hurricane Maria took everything.
My home was washed away,
and no one was coming to help.
So I left to find work
so I could rebuild one day.
Took any job I could get...
construction, picking apples.
And that's where I met Miguel...
on a farm upstate.
- El destino.
- Sí.
We both lost everything but faith.
She brought us together
to protect each other.
You see? So we are more than friends.
Hermano.
Ah... specimen cup.
Here.
Admin sent me about a nameplate?
Oh, yes.
Great. Thank you.
I've been calling for a month.
Just tell me what you need, Dr. Merritt.
No, actually, I'm, uh, Dr. Reynolds.
Oh. Nameplate says "Merritt."
Right, and I want it
replaced with "Reynolds."
- "Dr. Reynolds"?
- Correct.
Okay, gonna have to get
the Chair or Cardiothoracic Surgery
to sign off on a request like that.
Not a problem.
I'm the Chair of Cardiothoracic Surgery.
Dr. Merritt.
No, Dr. Reynolds.
Well, it says Dr. Merritt's the Chair.
Well, he's not. I'm the Chair.
Well, then why are you in his office?
This is my...
Um... you see how confusing this is?
Well, I have this same conversation
with every patient that comes in here,
which doesn't help them to be confident
in the doctor they chose to cut them open
because he can't even get
his name on the door.
Yeah, I'm thinking you might
need a new nameplate.
Yeah.
Henry.
Chemo stomach. It's no joke.
You're telling me.
- Thanks for coming.
- Sure.
You know what this room used to be?
Mm, I think legal had it?
Well, the fun part
is who had it before legal.
Hmm.
In '67, we'd call this
the "Nookie Closet."
Did you?
Now it's a stone's throw from HR,
so why don't we let that one
sail right by?
You mind if we get right to it?
Not at all.
I'd like to schedule you
for a medical evaluation.
Nothing wrong with my health,
Dr. Goodwin.
Just consider it a formality.
Okay?
This hospital requires a medical eval
every two years.
I passed my last exam
less than a year ago...
with flying colors, I might add.
I don't like it any more than you do,
but it is my job.
I've been in practice
for more than 40 years...
all of them here.
I can do my surgeries blindfolded.
I appreciate that, Henry.
I do, but I would still like
to schedule you
for a routine eval.
Tomorrow.
Of course.
You got to do your job.
So you need me to perform
a valve replacement
so that you can do
an MRI-focused ultrasound.
- It shouldn't be a problem.
- Keep scrolling.
Oh, your patient
can't withstand anesthesia.
That's right, but if I can
perform a procedure
on the brain without anesthesia,
you can certainly do
the same thing for the heart.
Yeah, the only noninvasive surgery
is catheter aortic replacement therapy.
Yes, do that.
Which requires a C-ART device,
which New Amsterdam does not have.
So we'll get one.
Yeah, sure. "So we'll get one."
A C-ART device costs $3 million.
I made Maren Thompson a promise
that I would help her see her daughter.
I'll get you this device.
Okay, Guruji, look,
I can't even get my name
on my own door, all right?
They're not gonna just buy you
a $3 million device.
We will see about that.
Uh, remember when you told
me we'll treat everyone here
no matter the price?
That's the power of New Amsterdam.
Yes, well, we need a C-ART device.
Okay, I'll call ACC. Done.
Do you know what a C-ART device is?
Will it help your patient?
It's the only thing that will help.
- Good enough for me.
- Thank you.
- Yeah?
- Hey, hey, hey.
I thought you were gonna handle
that whole Dr. M situation?
Yeah, handled. Medical
eval scheduled for tomorrow.
Well, he moved his temporal bone surgery
up to today.
Help! Help! He needs help!
What's happening to him?
Push two milligrams of Ativan.
Biopsy results?
They just came back. It's not cancer.
Must be an infection.
Given the ulcers, it's got to be viral.
I'll start Acyclovir.
I saw polys on the biopsy.
Bacteria's much more likely.
Or the polys are due
to a secondary infection
on top of the viral infection
and irrelevant.
It's my ED, my call.
And if I disagree with your call?
Bloom, we got four more!
Similar symptoms to Mr. Arroyo!
Visible ulcers in the back of the mouth.
Four more?
- Where did they come from?
- Watch out.
We all work together.
They were all sick, too!
Mind if I scrub in?
What are you trying to prove?
Nothing, just here to observe.
I've done this surgery
hundreds of times, Dr. Goodwin.
I don't need the hospital's
Medical Director
standing over my shoulder
evaluating my every incision.
Then pretend I'm not here.
You trying to throw me
off my game, is that it?
I expect all the surgeons in my hospital
to perform at their best
whether I'm here watching or not.
Anyone's not performing
at their best, it's you.
Running a hospital
while undergoing chemo?
You have no right to judge me.
This isn't about me.
I've helped thousands
of patients at this hospital.
Thousands.
My record is sterling.
My reputation impeccable.
Henry, you're a legacy here.
Damn right I am.
But what story do you want
told in the end?
That you were a titan in your field,
or that you were a doctor who didn't know
when to lay down the scalpel?
There'll come a day, Max...
when you won't be able
to perform as well as you once could.
Maybe sooner than you think.
Well, they all work together
out at some vineyard out in Long Island.
And they're all exhibiting
the same symptoms?
To a T.
What at a vineyard could have
made them all so sick?
Let's find out.
The owners made us sleep
in this old, rundown barn.
All crowded together, cramped.
How many of you?
17, sometimes 18.
At night, I just tried to think
of my family back home.
Las ratas.
Yes, there were so many rats.
I've been picking
since Hurricane Georges.
Been 20 years since I've seen
Puerto Rico.
Have you harvested
at this vineyard before?
No.
And I will not go back.
I will starve first.
The owner treat us like animals.
Pay us nothing.
And everything was damp
and wet all the time...
mold everywhere.
I'm thinking pesticides led
to an autoimmune reaction...
erythema multiforme.
EM would explain everything.
Their kidney function's fine.
The rats and the close quarters
are the perfect breeding ground
for the hantavirus.
Something's off.
- We're missing something.
- Really?
I think Sharpe
may have nailed it... hanta.
- No, it's not hantavirus.
- Okay. Because?
Because...
I have a gut feeling.
Or you're just disagreeing with me
because it's my diagnosis.
Everything okay here?
- Yes.
- It's fine.
Okay, at the risk
of stepping into something,
I'm gonna make the call.
Treat for hantavirus.
- Suction.
I dropped a bottle, Iggy.
One stupid bottle.
I was, um...
I was worried.
You moved the surgery up
because you knew you wouldn't pass
the medical evaluation.
I moved up my surgery
to prove the evaluation wasn't necessary.
No, Henry, come on...
I may not be a young man anymore, Iggy...
but I am a surgeon with over
40 years experience.
And that counts for something.
At least it should count for something.
You really buried the lede
on the whole C-ART device, didn't you?
Three...
$3 million.
To be fair, you did say,
"No matter the price."
No, you're right.
I really should have asked
more prudent follow-up questions.
Like, "Does it cost $3 million?"
To be clear,
New Amsterdam will never get
a C-ART device.
See, what'd I tell you?
The system can't handle the small things.
Why in the hell should we be surprised
when it can't handle the big ones?
Didn't let me finish.
New Amsterdam will never get
a C-ART device,
so you should do the surgery
at a hospital that does have one.
What are you saying?
University has a C-ART device.
We have a patient.
Peanut butter, jelly.
So, as our sister hospital,
they'll let us do the surgery there?
Not exactly...
and definitely not for free.
But her insurance won't cover University.
Yeah, and then I can't do the surgery.
No, you can't.
But Dr. Merritt can.
Last I checked, he's still
credentialed at Uni.
Okay, wait, wait.
Impersonating another doctor
is grounds for malpractice.
I can lose my license.
I can go to prison.
Nobody's suggesting
impersonating anyone, all right?
You are the Chair
of Cardiothoracic Surgery
at New Amsterdam.
- Just say that.
- This is crazy.
- Even for you.
- You want to help the patient?
This is how.
Are you really talking about this?
Sneaking a patient across the city
into University Hospital?
If the system can't handle
the little things...
then it certainly won't notice
the big ones.
Sure.
University Hospital.
Can I help you?
Dr. Nottingham.
I'm here to observe a C-ART procedure
as part of my residency.
- I called earlier.
- Observe who?
The Chair of Cardiothoracic
Surgery at New Amsterdam.
It's nice to meet you.
Dr. Merritt?
That's what it says on my door.
Pushing the delivery system
up to the aortic valve.
- You're nearly there.
- How much longer?
Ah, ah, ah.
Don't rush me, and I won't rush you.
If we get caught,
it's my name on the schedule.
Well, Dr. Merritt will cover for you.
I didn't see anything.
Thank you, Maren.
- Sheath's in place.
- Got it.
Inflating the balloon.
Leaflets are moving.
Maren, you'll feel some pressure.
Nice and easy.
Almost got it.
All right, new aortic valve's in place.
- Deflating the balloon.
- Wonderful.
Let's get her back to our hospital now.
- Dr. Reynolds.
- I see it.
What?
A bleed at the cath insertion site.
It's a common side effect,
but Maren's gonna have to remain flat
with a sandbag on her hip
to keep the pressure on.
For how long?
It looks like you're gonna have
to do your procedure here as well.
But I'm not Dr. Merritt...
either.
Got them all on a cocktail of antivirals,
and we're doing active fluid replacement.
Thanks.
You don't think it's hanta?
No.
What do I know?
You know, Henry was shattered...
just standing there watching the surgery
go on without him.
It's like looking at a broken man.
You did the right thing.
- Did I?
- Yeah.
Then why do I find myself
trying to recall
Judas's good traits?
Iggy, I know he's a good friend,
but so are you, okay?
You didn't betray him
because somebody could have
gotten hurt or worse.
Well, his body is going.
His mind is not.
Very few doctors have
that kind of expertise.
I mean, if... if we send him on his way,
all that knowledge, all that expertise
goes out the door with him.
You know, we might as well be
saying, "Hey, Doc, thank you.
You're ancient. Don't need you anymore."
Don't let the door hit you on the
wrinkly old ass on the way out."
Hi.
Oh.
Hello.
- How are you?
- Hello.
Good-bye, Iggy.
- Huh?
- Leave.
Yes, I'm sorry.
Bye.
Um, I'll be back in ten.
I just need to fire a few people.
You know you can't, uh, fire me, right?
I was referring to Iggy.
Yeah, you can't fire him either.
Yes, I know, Max.
But it makes me look in charge,
and right now I could use
a little bit of that.
How are things with you and Bloom?
Fine.
Um, h-how are you feeling?
Good, yeah.
Aside from Iggy starting
an international rumor
that we traffic in ageism, pretty...
Good.
- Your nausea?
- Chemo tried to slow this man down,
- but you know what?
- It failed?
No, it succeeded, big-time.
But, uh, the drugs you gave me
are helping.
Good.
Well, it sounds like you're
in the right frame of mind
to start radiation.
Aren't you glad you swung by?
So glad.
Okay.
Everyone just act normal,
like you belong here.
Like we're doctors in a hospital?
MRI lab is down this way.
How are we gonna get in?
You might have to schedule us again.
I'm starting to miss
the real Dr. Merritt.
- How are you doing, Maren?
- Nervous.
I haven't let myself be hopeful
in a very, very long time.
I know this whole process
has been rather unorthodox,
but I made you a promise,
and promise I will keep.
Dr. Kapoor, what are you doing here?
Funny story, actually.
Dr. Carlebach was one of my best interns
back in the day.
And now he's this big-time neurologist
here in University.
Yeah, Dr. Kapoor tried
to recruit me to New Amsterdam.
I wanted to go... I really did, Vijay...
but my med school loans
were out of control.
I had to go private.
- It's nice to meet you.
- Likewise.
But I got to admit,
I still miss my days at The Dam.
Making the most out of nothing,
thinking outside the box.
Always such an adventure.
Funny you should say that, Dr. Carlebach.
Initiating sonication pulse.
And going again.
Mrs. Thompson, we're using
high-intensity focused ultrasound
to pinpoint the tumor
at the base of your brain.
Oh, okay.
Maren, how are you feeling?
Honestly, I don't know.
I thought I was doing this
so that I could see
my daughter's face, but...
I don't think I am.
I think...
I wanted her to see mine.
I want... I want her
to see me seeing her,
being...
Proud and growing up and falling down,
being scared.
I want her to know...
all her life...
that she's seen.
The tumor is responding.
Hey.
Is, uh, this seat taken?
You know, we're, uh, doing
everything we can for Miguel...
and the others.
Thank you.
What's that?
A santo.
After Maria, our house
was just mud and water
and the trunk of a huge tree
where my bedroom once stood.
I went to a santero in town
and asked him to carve this
from the wood of that tree.
- As a reminder?
- No, no.
There are many a santo on the island.
This one is Anima Sola...
the Lonely Soul.
She is in Purgatory,
bound to the flames forever.
And I pray to her
for strength and patience...
and redemption.
Why redemption?
I, um...
I liked to drink...
too much.
And I could not stop.
And I would be dead if not for her.
She helps me to say no.
She reminds me to always think
of tomorrow.
She keeps me alive.
And yet you work on a vineyard...
Surrounded by temptation every day.
Miguel helps me with that.
Never lets the others tempt me
with the angel's share.
"Angel's share"?
In the barrels, the top layer of wine?
It evaporates.
They call that the angel's share.
I like that.
So do all my friends, believe me,
and all the other workers.
At the end of a shift,
they would dip into the crush and drink.
After the way they treated us,
they felt like they deserved
a little taste.
Well, I'm sure the angels would agree.
Blood pressure 60 over palp.
- Then he's fading fast.
- Add Dobutamine.
Ten micrograms per minute.
It's odd that his heart rate is 78.
It should be 178.
The antivirals aren't working.
Mariana!
Mariana, hang a bag of streptomycin!
Wait, no, no, no, no, no!
The hantavirus is affecting his heart!
He needs a pacing wire.
He needs streptomycin, okay?
I-I don't have time to explain.
Do you trust me or not?
I am setting up a pacing wire.
Lauren, you open this door!
Lauren!
What are you doing? Don't do this!
Call Dr. Goodwin.
Ready?
Come here.
Here we go.
Mommy, will you be able to see me?
- Oh, I hope so, honey.
- Almost there.
What do you see, Mrs. Thompson?
Mommy?
It's okay, baby.
Because in my head
and my heart, I see you...
so clearly, okay?
I see you perfectly.
I don't understand.
I thought you said it was gonna work?
The tumors were destroyed.
Surgery should have worked.
There must be something we missed.
Miguel Arroyo is stable.
Let's, um... let's treat the others
for oropharyngeal tularemia.
They got it from drinking
partially fermented wine
right out of the barrels.
That's why Ivan never showed
signs of illness.
He's sober.
You know, you and I
working together like this...
It's not gonna work.
You're right.
Oh, hey, how was your
radiation treatment?
Mm, like a relaxing vacation...
at Chernobyl.
Right.
Henry, hi.
Um...
if this is about the exit paperwork,
I was about to get to it.
Yeah, good. Great, okay.
Don't get to it.
Excuse me?
Because you're not exiting.
Can I tell him because of your
whole throat thing?
Could I stop you if I wanted to?
No.
Okay, I am, uh...
very happy to tell you
that we here at New Amsterdam
would officially like to offer you
the brand-new position
of Chair of Telemedicine.
- "Telemedicine"?
- Video conferencing.
We can reach our sister hospitals
in Latin American, disaster sites,
war zones, all around the world.
Yeah, all in need
of experienced doctors like you
to help guide and consult them
through complicated surgeries.
Surgeries that you've done
hundreds of times.
I, uh...
Thank you.
It's your experience
that's irreplaceable...
not your hands.
I just don't see anything.
May I touch your face
to perform an examination?
Yeah, that's fine.
- Please close your eyes.
- Mm.
I would like to try latanoprost.
That's...
Uh, what's wrong?
Your eyes are harder than they should be.
This indicates glaucoma
might have developed.
But there is no way you would
have ever known about it.
There's always a catch, right?
Please lean your head back for me.
Yeah.
Blink.
Oh, that's a beautiful drawing, baby.
Yeah.
Oh.
Can you see us?
Yes, my love, I can see you.
- Can you see me?
- I can see you.
You can?
I can see.
It turns out being Dr. Merritt
does have its advantages.
Come here. Oh...
I see you.
Retractor.
Hey.
Oh, looks like someone's feeling better.
No, don't thank me.
Thank your brother and his santo.
She told me the answer.
- El Anima Sola?
- Yes.
You two are really lucky
to have each other.
I, uh...
don't really get along
with my real sister.
But what you two have...
you're gonna rebuild.
I know it.
Here.
Please, for you.
- No, I-I can't...
- Yes, yes, yes.
I insist.
My brother, he will take care of me,
and Anima Sola,
she will take care of you.
Thank you.
Max?
What's wrong?
I've, um...
I've been round and round in my head,
but I can't see
that there's any other way.
Helen?
This is harder than I thought.
I think that I need to report
an impaired physician.
No, we already took care of it.
- There's no...
- Max...
I'm talking about Bloom.
Babe, is that you?
Yep.
- Hey.
- Hi.
How is the guy who's not about
to let cancer slow him down?
Profoundly humbled.
I made dinner.
Steak, baked potato, and broccoli.
Wow.
Chemo?
Radiation.
- My throat, it's already...
- Oh, babe.
Helen said that I wouldn't even feel it
for four to five days.
Well, you really are special.
So special.
It smells...
it smells amazing.
- Sorry.
- Hey...
you have nothing to be sorry about.
Maybe you should put me
in the return pile.
Nope.
You are a keeper.
Stay there.
www.tvsubtitles.net