Violet!
Violet.
Oh, God.
Hey, Vi, you left your door open.
Call 9-1-1.
She's hypotensive with massive blood loss.
Respiratory rate is 8.
Elevate her legs. I'm calling them.
Pete.
Call them.
She's still alive, but I can
barely palpate her pulse.
Pete, where is the baby?
I don't know.
This is Dr. Naomi Bennett.
II need an ambulance immediately
at 3-2-6 Las Brisas Canyon.
Sync by honeybunny - corrected by chamallow35
www.addic7ed.com
B.P. is 70 palp, resps 8 and shallow.
Pulse is 130 after 2 liters of N.S.
Trauma "b."
I got an O.R. standing by.
Montgomery's on her way.
I'm here.
Set up a central line. We need
blood. What's her blood type?
Does anybody know her blood type?
C.B.C., chem-7, cross and type times 4.
Set up a rapid infuser.
Where's the baby?
We don't know.
There was a placenta
and... and the cord was cut, but there wasn't...
Okay, I got this, Pete.
I should know her blood type.
Pete, I'm taking over, all right? Stay here.
Cooper, a little help.
I... I was there. I was there and I heard a noise.
I was right at her door, and I left.
Okay, Nai, let's go. Come on.
Can somebody get her a trauma gown, please?
You gotta use O-neg.
Pete, just let me... let me do my job.
She's lost so much blood.
Okay, just wait here.
No, no, I gotta be in here with her.
No, Dr. Wilder. Look at me.
We don't have time for this.
I don't have time to convince you
to let me do what I know how to do.
There is no time. Wait here.
Cooper. Pete.
We have a kitchen!
At work, we have a... a kitchen.
It's nice.
At my last office, I had a, um,
I had a mini fridge wedged under my desk.
That's where I kept the urine samples.
This is fancy.
What do you think about Sam and Naomi?
They seem nice.
I mean, I like 'em 'cause they,
you know, hired me.
Why? What do you think?
They're happy.
They're... they're happy people.
They're happy people
in love with each other.
It's creepy.
Do you think it's real, the love?
Oh, it's real. Oh, my god. Oh, I'm just...
I was... I'm sorry, Sam.
I think what she meant to say
was thank you for our jobs.
If he's trying to get you to work here, say yes.
It's fancy. We have a kitchen.
No, I'm just...
I have my own practice in Beverly Hills...
Infectious disease.
I... I'm Violet. This is, uh...
Cooper Freedman. Hi.
Hi. Pete Wilder.
This is Pete, the friend I told you about.
Oh, yes. Pete.
Right.
Oh, yes. What? What am I missing?
I'm a patient. I'm...
Supposed to be a patient of--
Oh. Sam wants me to speak
with Violet about my wife.
Oh. Divorced?
Dead.
She died four days ago.
Hey.
Hey. I came up with a name.
Oceanside Wellness.
That's good, right?
Yeah.
What?
What happened?
Um, someone...
took Violet's baby.
They cut her and took her baby.
Katie. It had to be Katie.
Violet's patient?
I'm going in there.
No, no. Come on.
I'm family.
We're all family here,
all right? Addison's got this.
She... she said she wanted to be
with me. She said she loved me.
She said... we should get you cleaned up.
What?
Blood, man. You're covered in blood.
All right, come on.
Come on. Right this way.
Daddy?
Yeah.
Someone got hurt?
Uh, yeah, yeah. Someone got hurt.
Sam says you're great.
Well, he doesn't really know me,
but, uh, but I am. I'm great.
Well, he's great, too... Sam.
You're gonna like working for him.
And, well, these offices are nice.
They're big.
I'm stalling.
Therapy is hard for some people.
It's not hard. It's just artificial.
Sitting down and telling
your innermost thoughts
to someone you don't know?
Did you tell all your innermost thoughts
to someone you do know?
Did you do that with your wife?
Because that's what we're here to talk about, right?
Look, I'm not here for me.
I'm here because it's easier
than having Sam and Naomi be all over me
because they can't get the fact that I'm coping.
My wife died, and it's awful, and I'm coping.
Do you want to tell me about her?
No. I...
Her name's Anna.
It was.
She died of an aneurysm in her sleep.
So she didn't have any pain.
There was no suffering.
Look, I... I respect what you do,
and I get that Sam and Naomi think
That I'm not showing the right emotion
or I'm in denial or I'm not talking enough,
but I'm a private person.
It's not that I'm not feeling
this, that I don't miss her.
Uh, maybe I'm not displaying my emotions,
but I'm feeling this in my own way.
I understand that. I... I do.
But, um, I still think, as a professional,
talking about those feelings will help.
I just... don't really have anything else to say.
I... this...
What happened is horrible.
But I'll get through it in time...
On my own.
You say she had a mental illness, the attacker?
Yes. Katie. Katie Kent.
Is someone out looking for the baby?
We put out an...
It's been almost two hours.
We put out an amber alert.
Everyone is looking.
Have you checked her apartment?
She's cleared out. Everyone is looking, sir.
You were at the crime scene?
Yes, I told the other officer.
I found her.
Maybe if you'd put something on tv...
Sir, what is your relationship to the victim?
Violet! Her name is Violet!
Pete...
The guy is standing her asking me questions,
and the woman is out...
Just let him do his job.
Sir, your relationship to... Violet.
He's her boyfriend.
I was seeing a patient upstairs and I... I heard.
I'm sorry. I should've called.
And who are you?
I'm the baby's father.
Uh, well, kind... kind of the baby's father.
Maybe the father. So is he.
We're both... we're the baby's father.
It's a long story.
It's... just wear a condom.
Tell your friends.
There's a waiting room...
with chairs.
I had to call Violet's parents.
Those people are...
Okay, yes, they are worried.
But they're on vacation in London.
They didn't even contemplate
getting on an airplane to L.A.
They didn't even think about it.
She was raised by wolves,
by intellectual, snooty wolves.
I'm basically... I mean,
I'm her immediate family.
You're not gonna check it?
Nobody wants me treating their kid in this state.
The answering service
will refer whoever's on call.
You know, I was right there.
I was at the door.
And you called, and... and I... I...
I called because I got fired.
No... I called because you're
my boyfriend, and I needed you.
No, I'm not blaming you.
I'm not saying...
It's not your fault. It's my fault. I coulda stopped it.
You didn't know.
I coulda walked... I could've saved her.
You don't know that either.
If she had had the baby yesterday
like she was supposed to...
She doesn't do anything like she's supposed to.
Yeah, she's a real bitch that way.
Just making a point.
Which is?
She's not to blame.
I'm not to blame.
You're not to blame.
The only person who deserves blame
is that woman who attacked
her and took her baby.
You're not a superhero, Coop.
No, I'm her family.
Just take my hand and breathe.
All right, everyone.
We treat her like a multiple stab wound victim...
control the bleeding,
repair any organ damage,
and we get out as fast as we can.
Nai, scrub in. I need all the hands I can get.
Nai.
I was going over to her house
to tell her that I was leaving the practice.
We've worked together
every single day for the past nine years...
She's gonna be okay.
Are you sure?
No.
I.V. Tech to room 321.
Hey, did you hear anything?
No.
Violet wanted to have Katie committed.
She knew. And I made fun of her.
We made fun of her.
She knew something was wrong,
and I talked her out of it.
We talked her out of it.
I should've... I should've just let...
We. We. We. It is we, not you.
We are in love with Violet.
We are the possible fathers of that baby.
We are worried. We are scared.
We ignored her concerns about Katie.
We, not you, you smug, arrogant bastard.
But I'm the one she chose.
Come on.
All right. All right. I'm okay.
How does something like this happen?
I don't know.
I don't know. I don't know.
How's she doing?
Pressure's 60 over 40.
She's losing blood faster than
I can transfuse it in.
Oh, God. What did she use, a hatchet?
There. Got it.
Addison, her pressure's not coming up.
Damn it. She is bleeding from everywhere.
Nai, we're gonna have to extend the incision
to make it vertical.
We gotta see what else
is bleeding and tie it off.
Scalpel.
Addison.
What? They need answers.
Pete, Sheldon...
I... I need to be able to tell them something.
Addison!
It's not the liver edge. It's
one of the mesenteric arteries.
All right. Clamp.
We're all here, Violet, pulling for you.
Just thought you should know.
She can't hear you, Dell.
It's gonna be okay.
Everything's going to be okay.
Dell, stop talking! I can't hear myself think.
Addison...
He's just trying to help.
You just... you keep talking
to her, Dell. Go ahead.
Um...
I... I got Betsey back,
which was maybe the
hardest thing I've done.
Before Betsey, I didn't really have a family.
You guys...
You're my family.
You're my family, Violet.
So... I'm sitting here selfishly telling you...
not to die.
Okay?
So I just got off the phone with Leo Brinkman.
He has to push back his start date?
No, he got sued.
Yeah, apparently he likes
to touch his patients' feet...
Ooh!
For sexual reasons.
Great.
Ooh. Shoulda gone into podiatry.
That's not funny.
It's a little funny.
But it's awful. We're still short one.
D... does anybody know a good dermatologist?
Well, I actually was thinking,
maybe we could give his slot to Pete.
I thought he was infectious disease.
It's even better. He's got a great practice.
I like it. It's something we don't have,
and he does critical care... that's two for one.
I know.
But we can't... I mean, he can't work here
'cause he's a patient, so we can't hire him.
Wit, wait.
He goes to you once because I
make him, now he's off-limits?
Actually, yes. I had a session
with him, so he's a patient.
Even if he says he's fine?
He says he's fine.
I don't believe him.
You don't believe him,
otherwise you wouldn't have sent him to me.
Obviously he's not fine. His wife just died.
Is he a good doctor?
He's a great doctor.
Look, let's say Coop keels over
from a heart attack...
Ooh.
And I give him C.P.R.
Does that mean we have to fire
him because he's "my patient"?
Um, Sam, could you not put
things like that out there.
The universe has a perverse sense of humor.
We cannot hire him.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Is this an issue
Because he's a patient
or there's a problem?
Wait, you know Pete.
Yeah, I... I... I do.
But if he can't suit up, we can't use him.
That's the issue. Okay, we need
a new partner...  a good doctor,
and someone that we
get along with personally.
Pete is both. Look, there is
something there, okay?
I mean, he sat with me,
he said all the right things,
he knew all the right answers,
but there's something there.
And until I know what it is,
until he's ready to face what it is,
trust me, you don't want him working here.
I hate this.
I hate it. I should... I should be doing something.
I should be out looking
for Katie or the baby or...
That's not your job.
What if she dies?
I had a patient...
an old woman, a southern
woman, southern baptist.
Strongest woman I ever met.
And they were having a party
for her 90th birthday,
only she was having chest pains,
so they took her to the hospital.
A minivan T-boned her car on the way there.
She lost her husband,
two sons, a grandchild.
Her heart was fine.
It was, uh, indigestion.
Is there a point or are you
just spouting random crap?
She came to me because everyone was worried
that she was so devastated,
she wouldn't be able to go on.
So I... I asked her. I asked her how she was coping.
And she said to me, "son, God will provide."
That's it?
She loses everything.
"God will provide"?
My point was... we should have a little faith.
Do you?
Have faith?
No.
But I'm pretending I do.
Vascular clamp.
Okay, bovie here.
The bleeding's not slowing.
I know. Every time I sew up one bleeder,
another one appears.
She's lost so much blood. I don't...
I don't think she can take much more.
Take out her uterus.
A hysterectomy?
To save her life.
No.
I can embolize the uterine arteries,
block the blood supply and stop the bleeding.
She could die while you're
prepping her for the procedure.
Do the hysterectomy.
What if the baby's gone for good, Nai?
Violet wakes up, her baby's gone,
and she can't have another child?
We'll find the baby.
Okay, life isn't always
that simple and easy, Nai.
Babies don't always get found.
There isn't always a happy ending.
Yeah, things don't always have a happy ending,
but she would be alive, Addison.
She would be alive. I'm embolizing.
Whoa. What about Violet?
What about what she would want?
Hold these.
Apply pressure to the uterus.
Don't move.
Dell, keep talking to her.
I need a decision.
You save Violet.
You do whatever you have to do,
but you save Violet.
Is... is it really and either/or?
If you save her uterus, she could still have kids.
Yes.
But she could die.
Yes. If you take out her uterus...
Violet lives, which is the goal here. Violet lives.
Stop talking over me. I'm trying to understand this.
This is big. This... I need a decision. Pete?
Save Violet.
Sheldon?
No, she chose me. He doesn't
have... he doesn't have a...
I was going to agree with you. Save Violet.
Cooper?
Wait, no. What are you asking him for?
Because he's... her Cooper.
To Violet, he's her Cooper.
He's her best friend.
Cooper?
Yeah, o... you know, we don't have time for this?
Cooper! What would Violet want?
She'd want you to try to save her uterus.
She'd want you to at least give her a shot
at whatever she wants.
No, no. No, no, you guys love her. I know her.
I know every food she likes.
I know every thought
she's ever had about a guy,
including the two of you.
I know... Violet. This is what she'd want.
I'm gonna embolize.
Addison...
Damn it. You know what, Cooper?
Hey, Pete...
I am not on call!
I'm gonna take someone's head off right now!
I'm glad you came back.
According to Sam, I didn't have a choice.
You know about the job?
I have my own practice.
But in light
of what's happened,
Yeah, working with friends... seems good...
Seemed good... but not to you.
Well, no, no, I think working
with friends could be great,
however... you can't figure me out.
My emotions don't fit into one of your boxes,
so you think there must be
something wrong with me.
I don't have any boxes.
I'm just here to help you.
And what we're doing now...
talking about the job instead of your wife's death...
Well, that's just another way
of you avoiding dealing with something profound.
I told you about my wife.
Yes, you told me what she died of and that it wasn't painful.
And I told you what I'm feeling...
Actually, you... you told me that you were feeling,
not what you were feeling.
You're holding things in, and when you do that,
what happens is, eventually it festers
And it explodes.
It's like one of your infectious diseases.
Sometimes you leave it alone.
You let the body heal itself.
But your job is to figure out when to take action
in order to prevent further damage.
Well, that's my job, too.
And I look at you, and, uh,
I can't see leaving this alone.
I think we need to attack this for your own sake...
Not for me or Sam, for you. Are you
married? Have you ever been married?
I don't think that's the issue.
But it is. I... I'm sure you went to school,
and you learned all about
the brain and medications, people's feelings.
But if you haven't been
married, if you haven't had
a relationship like that, you're not qualified
to sit there and tell me anything about it.
I don't... I don't want to tell you anything.
I just want to listen. And judge.
I'm not judging you. But you are.
You're judging my grief.
And you know what?
I don't think you're qualified.
Cooper Freedman. You paged me five times.
Am I the only pediatrician in Los Angeles?
I am not on call.
You're the only pediatrician she wants.
Call security now.
I heard about Violet on the news.
They say she's alive.
Is she alive?
Oh, I had my baby.
He's beautiful, isn't he?
When Violet's better,
I want her to see my baby.
She's gonna be so surprised.
Everyone thought it was a girl, but I had a boy.
And, um, is he healthy?
What did the doctor say?
The doctor who delivered him?
Um... he's fine. He's perfect.
I just ask 'cause he... he looks a little pale.
Um, do you mind if I check him out?
Um...
Pete.
Hey, Pete. Um, Katie had her baby.
Isn't that great? Um...
Does he look slightly pale to you?
Yes, he does. Could indicate hemolysis.
You should check him out.
Yeah.
What does that mean, hemolysis?
It's a breakdown of the red blood cells.
It happens in newborns.
They used to die from it,
but it's very treatable now.
Well, he... he cries if anyone
else touches him, so...
Well, Katie, Cooper just wants
to help. Look, I know you.
I know how much you wanted
to have this baby,
how... how much you want it to be healthy.
Katie, look at me.
You need to let cooper
make sure. It's gonna be fine.
Just... just have a little faith.
Okay.
You... be careful.
Hold his head.
Hi there, little guy. Let's check you out.
Katie.
I got him. I got him.
I got him. Okay.
No, that's my baby.
No, that's my baby. You're taking my baby!
No.
No!
It's not your baby!
You're stealing my baby! That's my baby!
They're stealing my baby! No. No!
No.
I gotta stop Addison.
Pete. Pete.
Pete.
Give me my baby, please.
Please give me my baby. Please.
Inserting the catheter into the uterine artery.
Addison, we have the baby.
I was wrong. Stop the embolization.
Just take out her uterus. Do
whatever you can to save her.
You have the baby?
Katie showed up in the waiting room. Pete's got him.
Thank God.
Addison, stop.
It's too late, Coop. I've already started.
Is it working?
It's the baby. We need you, Coop.
There was bruising on the
abdomen. I checked his crit.
He's markedly anemic, going into shock.
I think his spleen may be torn from being cut out.
Did you get an ultrasound?
There's free fluid in the abdomen.
He needs surgery now.
I'm gonna go look.
You... you can't just leave Violet.
I'm almost done. You've done this before. You can close.
I've done this before in medical school.
I'll be right back, Nai.
Cooper, can get the baby, Addison.
Cooper is not a neonatal surgeon. I am.
I have a peds surgeon standing by.
Not as good as I am. Clear an O.R.
Addison, stop.
Let another doctor do this.
I can save them both, Nai.
I can save them both.
Coop?
If I had answered one of those pages...
Oh, my God. How much time did I waste?
How long was she waiting?
Hey, how'd it go?
Ooh. Not good?
You know, you don't have to listen to Violet.
Well, maybe you should see her some more.
No, Sam. I'm done.
That woman...
I'm sorry.
I don't want to trash your new colleague.
It's okay. I'm sorry.
What are you doing, spying?
Uh, yeah.
Oh, my...
I forgot how big Maya got.
Oh, she's starting kindergarten this fall.
I'm a lucky guy.
Yeah.
No. I mean it.
I'm... a lucky guy.
It's luck that Naomi was my lab partner,
luck that she went out
with me for that first time,
luck that she said yes when I proposed.
I'm just lucky that Maya's healthy
And that we're happy
and that we have this life...
when you're...
Yeah.
I'm a lucky guy. It's just luck.
She's the love of your life.
That's not luck.
That's... something else.
Yeah, but you know what I'm trying to say.
I'm gonna be fine, Sam. I am.
Hey, pete.
You're standing there so long.
You think she wouldn't see you?
She wants you to come in. She
wants us to take turns reading.
All right.
Do you have a patient?
No, no, I'm good.
Okay. Uh, do you want to wait?
No, we'll talk later.
I'm fine. All right.
Hey, Maya.
What's up with you?
Okay, one more suture.
Pulse ox is dropping. Check her probe.
The probe's fine.
But she's tachy at 130. 140.
What's going on? Is she... is she bleeding?
I don't know.
She's in v-fib.
Crash cart. Paddles charged to 200.
Epi and lido. Let's go. Charge.
Clear.
Anything?
No pulse. She's still in fib.
What the hell is going on?
I don't know.
Unresponsive... V-fib... bleeding...
electrolytes...
turn her on her side.
Give me a 60cc syringe and a spinal needle.
Got it.
Turn her on her back. Paddles. 360.
Clear.
She's got a rhythm.
And a pulse.
Pulse ox is coming up. 86. 90. 92.
I did it.
Dell, get addison.
Get Addison now.
So what have we got?
Grade 4 splenic laceration.
I'm trying to preserve the spleen.
Vascular clamp.
And the argon.
Right there.
Naomi says you need to come back, now.
Now. Violet is bleeding
from her nose and mouth.
It won't stop. She's not clotting?
Damn.
Naomi said now.
I hear you, Dell.
I can finish.
Addison.
Okay, let me just clamp this.
Got it.
Cauterize any remaining bleeders, gently,
but wait for me to come
back to set the vicryl mesh.
Do not kill this baby while I am gone.
Addison...
Not now.
What's happening?
I know. I know.
I should... try to have a little faith.
What's her fibrinogen level?
It's less than 100.
She's not responding to platelets, F.F.P.
Prepare antithrombin.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
She's not clotting, and you want
to give her an anticoagulant?
Addison--
With all the blood loss,
Her coagulation system is working overtime.
Hopefully with the anticoagulant,
it will stop the cascade, and her own clotting
will start up again. Or it will kill her.
It's her only shot.
Prepare the antithrombin.
I have to get back to the baby.
You can administer the A.T.3.
Addison, you better be right about this.
If she dies...
Do it, Nai.
We had a fight...
the night before she died.
Well, we had a fight almost every night,
but the night before she
died was our worst fight.
She said things...
we said things that you can't take back.
I woke up the next morning.
The alarm went off. I... her alarm went off.
I was still pissed.
I turned it off...
and she was just laying there ignoring me.
And it pissed me off.
I went to the bathroom.
I brushed my teeth.
I was trying to get her to talk to me,
and... she was just laying there.
So I called her a bitch.
I called her a bitch,
and still, she just lay there, silent.
So I ripped the covers off...
I ripped the covers off to
make her get out of bed
and talk to me.
She wouldn't talk to me...
because she was dead.
Five minutes, I argued with my wife,
and she was laying there, dead...
and...
I didn't know it.
Well, you... you just said the
most important thing, Pete.
You didn't know.
Your anger, it... it didn't kill your wife.
It didn't change anything.
People fight.
I hated my wife.
See? That's the thing.
I hated her.
And I don't know what that says about me.
I don't know what that says
about what kind of man I am,
what kind of husband I am.
Was.
But I hated my wife.
So if you want to know why
I didn't want to come and talk to you about it...
It's because my wife is dead,
and all I can think is...
I can breathe again.
Did she die?
No.
The bleeding, it stopped.
She made it.
Barely.
Good.
That's good.
What about Kline?
You know, the cardiologist?
He's got a really bad temper,
and he sweats a lot. His palms...
Yeah? Oh.
How about, uh, Moffet?
Oh, I love Moffet. She's great.
Really?
Yeah. Let me see.
I... s... slept with Moffet,
and it ended badly, but...
Okay.
How can L.A. have so many doctors,
and there is not one that we want to hire?
You should hire Pete.
I'm sorry?
Did... you said...
I... I know what I said, but we should hire Pete.
You cured him?
I referred him to someone else.
You think he's ready?
I think he's ready to start
doing the work on himself.
And I think he was your friend
long before he was my patient.
So, um, yeah, I think we should hire him.
It'll be good... for the practice.
How's the baby?
I did my best.
Time will tell. How's she?
She's not waking up.
You made the choice to do the embolization.
You made the choice to give her the antithrombin.
You left me alone in there.
You left me alone first.
I did what I had to do. I did what I could to save...
But you didn't have to operate on the baby.
Charlotte had a peds surgeon right there.
It's Violet. It's Violet's baby.
They are my people.
They are my responsibility.
Not yours, not anymore. You quit.
You quit on me. So...
I have to take care of them.
I have to do everything. Me.
Do you know what that's like?
Do you know the weight
that is pressing down on me?
If she had died... if that baby had died...
I know how to do one thing, Nai.
Okay, I have failed at every
relationship I've ever had.
I'm clearly not good at keeping friends
since I screwed up with you.
But there's one thing I'm good at.
I am good at surgery.
I am a brilliant surgeon.
That's what I have.
That's what I have to give
to my people, all right?
And I was scared to death in there.
The entire time, I was scared to death.
So you don't get to lecture me.
You don't get to fault me
for not wanting to lose another friend.
You walked out of the practice
and you left me alone.
I'm exhausted, Nai.
And you left me alone.
You're not alone.
I did what I could.
If she doesn't wake up, if that baby...
That's... that's on me.
You are not alone.
I would never leave you alone.
You're not alone.
He just keeps staring at her.
How's the baby?
Touch and go, like her.
It's not right
that he has to go through all this again.
I don't know if I could do it.
If God forbid...
I'm not going anywhere.
Look, about yesterday,
the practice...
Oh, it's okay, Nai.
People move on.
It's what they do.
We can do this.
We're gonna be okay.
All of us.
How are they?
I don't know.
She was crying when I
came back from the O.R.
I shouldn't have brought her,
put her through all this
waiting and worrying and...
I didn't have anywhere else to take her.
What am I doing, Cooper?
You know, I mean, I got her back,
and... and... and it's
everything I wanted and...
Oh.
What?
That's not what I should
be worried about right now.
Are you kidding me?
It's exactly what you should
be worrying about right now.
This little girl, man, this is your priority.
Yeah. Yeah.
I mean, I am a 25-year-old single father.
Yeah.
You know, I'm responsible for her.
I mean, how... how am I
gonna do this right
without, you know,
without screwing her up?
You just love her.
And you ask for help.
You ask us for help.
And take some time off,
get... get her settled in,
do what you need to do.
You know, we're gonna be here waiting
when you come back.
You guys would let me, uh, take time off?
We're your family.
You... you can't do it alone.
You know, you're just human, Dell.
You know, you're not a superhero.
All right? You just breathe, okay?
Why don't you go, uh, see Violet?
I'll... I got Betsey?
Yeah? You sure?
Yeah. Okay, thanks.
Why don't you go up there?
Everyone else is there.
No, I'm... I'm good here.
She could wake up. She'd want you there.
I'm good here.
Would you like to sit with him?
Yeah. I'd... I'd like that.
Thanks.
What's his name?
We have to ask Violet if she wakes up.
When she wakes up.
No suit?
Oh, I thought I'd switch things up.
You know, a fresh start.
I'm thinking about changing specialties.
Oh.
Alternative medicine...
different ways for the body to heal itself.
So now that we're... just colleagues,
can I still ask you how you are?
Uh, better, I think.
I don't know.
You know, you asked me
what kind of a man you are.
Do you want to know what I think?
I think you're the kind that
married the wrong person.
Maybe she married the wrong person.
Maybe I'm not cut out
for all that... -love, marriage.
Maybe I'm... it's just not in me.
It is. You're a good man.
And in time, eventually,
you'll, uh, you'll find someone.
You will.
You'll love someone.
I hope so.
Violet.
Where is he?
Where... where is he?
Is he...
He's here.
Oh.
He's so beautiful.
I didn't expect him to be so beautiful.
Sync by honeybunny - corrected by chamallow35
www.addic7ed.com
www.tvsubtitles.net