1
00:00:00,560 --> 00:00:02,690
<font color="#4096d1">-==http://subland.5286.cn==-</font>
<font color="#4096d1">sync:Jemands </font>

2
00:00:02,740 --> 00:00:03,570
<font color="#4096d1">Private Practice S01E05</font>

3
00:00:03,600 --> 00:00:04,220
Hey.

4
00:00:05,100 --> 00:00:05,830
Hey.

5
00:00:17,140 --> 00:00:20,580
This Isn't Good,
You Being Here.

6
00:00:21,270 --> 00:00:23,380
You Want Me To Take
The Stairs?

7
00:00:23,490 --> 00:00:24,600
Working Together. I--

8
00:00:26,360 --> 00:00:27,610
I Can't Focus.

9
00:00:27,630 --> 00:00:28,840
I Can't Think.

10
00:00:29,800 --> 00:00:30,650
Really?

11
00:00:31,010 --> 00:00:32,420
It's...

12
00:00:34,160 --> 00:00:35,720
Your Red Hair...

13
00:00:38,390 --> 00:00:39,660
And Your Brain.

14
00:00:40,430 --> 00:00:42,160
I Am Very Smart.

15
00:00:43,930 --> 00:00:46,990
I Barely Notice
Your Incredible Breasts

16
00:00:47,700 --> 00:00:50,220
Or Your Cellulite-free Thighs

17
00:00:50,520 --> 00:00:55,860
Because Your Brain Is Such An Immense Turn-on
To A Man As Highly Evolved As I Am.

18
00:00:56,000 --> 00:00:56,890
Yes.

19
00:00:57,770 --> 00:01:00,120
I Can See How I Might
Turn You On.

20
00:01:00,840 --> 00:01:01,610
Ahh.

21
00:01:15,080 --> 00:01:17,840
Pete?
Pete Is Your Dream Guy?

22
00:01:18,050 --> 00:01:19,810
Maya, Yore Gonna Be Late.

23
00:01:20,050 --> 00:01:21,230
She Had A Friend
Spend The Night Last Night,

24
00:01:21,290 --> 00:01:22,880
Which I Would Normally
Never Do On A School Night,

25
00:01:23,060 --> 00:01:24,980
But I'm Trying To Be
The Fun Parent Now So...

26
00:01:25,150 --> 00:01:27,180
Well, He's Not My Dream Guy, Okay?

27
00:01:27,330 --> 00:01:29,200
I Had A Dream About Him
Last Night...

28
00:01:29,360 --> 00:01:31,140
And The Night Before That...
Oh.

29
00:01:31,370 --> 00:01:34,270
- And...The Night Before That.
- Okay. Maya.

30
00:01:34,270 --> 00:01:36,680
I Can Do Dreams. It's Just
That These Particular Dreams,

31
00:01:36,860 --> 00:01:40,910
They're Just Making Me
Incredibly--
Do Not Sleep With Pete.

32
00:01:41,100 --> 00:01:42,150
I Don't Want
To Sleep With Pete.

33
00:01:42,340 --> 00:01:43,520
My Head Wants To Sleep
With Pete.

34
00:01:43,740 --> 00:01:46,080
It's Not Your Head That Wants
To Do The Sleeping. Maya!

35
00:01:46,270 --> 00:01:48,820
I'm Right Here, Mom. God.
Okay.

36
00:01:49,040 --> 00:01:51,100
Hi, Auntie Addison.
This Is Ruby.

37
00:01:51,850 --> 00:01:54,920
Uh, You Didn't--how Long Have
You Two Been Standing There?

38
00:01:55,120 --> 00:01:57,890
Why? What Are You Guys
Talking About?

39
00:01:58,170 --> 00:01:59,300
Shoes.
Shoes.

40
00:02:05,650 --> 00:02:06,420
Hey, Pete.

41
00:02:09,670 --> 00:02:11,100
You Guys Killed
At The Millrose Games.

42
00:02:11,310 --> 00:02:14,210
Yeah. Hey, Uh, I Was Hoping
You Could Take A Look At Nic.

43
00:02:14,380 --> 00:02:15,230
Hey, Nic.

44
00:02:15,650 --> 00:02:17,320
She's Got A Cold.
Doesn't Want To See A Doctor.

45
00:02:17,500 --> 00:02:19,710
She's Afraid Taking Something
Will Mess Her Up.

46
00:02:20,970 --> 00:02:23,130
My Stride Felt Off. I Got
Nothing Left At The End.

47
00:02:23,300 --> 00:02:24,650
Uh, Nic,This Is Pete Wilder.

48
00:02:24,970 --> 00:02:26,820
***

49
00:02:26,840 --> 00:02:30,020
~~~

50
00:02:30,050 --> 00:02:32,770
Well, Pete Does
Holistic Medicine.
Maybe I Can Treat You
Without Meds.

51
00:02:32,940 --> 00:02:34,700
Why Don't You Stop By Later Today?
We'll See What's Going On.

52
00:02:35,620 --> 00:02:36,400
Okay.

53
00:02:37,500 --> 00:02:38,590
Wanna Race?

54
00:02:38,880 --> 00:02:42,470
Uh... No.
You Go Ahead.

55
00:02:45,230 --> 00:02:47,130
Okay, I Think We All Have
A Pretty Full Day,

56
00:02:47,300 --> 00:02:48,920
So Let's Just, Uh,
Make This One Quick, Okay?

57
00:02:49,130 --> 00:02:50,350
Uh, Let Me Mention Quickly

58
00:02:50,540 --> 00:02:53,390
That Dell Is Doing His First
Solo Pap Smear Today.

59
00:02:53,540 --> 00:02:55,730
We Should All Be Proud.
Great.

60
00:02:57,660 --> 00:03:00,970
It's Just Pap Smears.
No Big Deal.
Y, Don't Choke, Man, Okay?

61
00:03:01,130 --> 00:03:03,490
I Know It Might Seem Dark
And Scary In There, But I--

62
00:03:03,560 --> 00:03:06,460
Do Not Mock The Midwife.

63
00:03:06,470 --> 00:03:07,910
Next Order Of Business.

64
00:03:08,080 --> 00:03:10,220
Nicole Clemmons Is Coming In
This Afternoon.
Oh, The Runner?

65
00:03:10,390 --> 00:03:12,270
She Says She Has A Cold,
But I Heard Wheezing.

66
00:03:12,310 --> 00:03:14,670
I've Ordered Some Pulmonary
Function Tests At St. Ambro...

67
00:03:16,510 --> 00:03:17,650
Why Do You Look So...

68
00:03:19,520 --> 00:03:20,660
You Look Hot.

69
00:03:24,930 --> 00:03:25,730
I...

70
00:03:26,600 --> 00:03:27,500
Do I?

71
00:03:29,750 --> 00:03:34,020
No, I Mean, You Look Hot
As In Flushed...

72
00:03:34,350 --> 00:03:35,620
Overheated.

73
00:03:41,400 --> 00:03:43,730
Um, The Next Order Of Business?
Let's...

74
00:03:52,530 --> 00:03:54,380
You're Fantasizing
About Pete?

75
00:03:55,130 --> 00:03:56,160
What? Naomi.

76
00:03:56,340 --> 00:03:58,260
She's
A Licensed Professional.

77
00:03:58,490 --> 00:04:01,420
I Do Not Need
Professional Help.

78
00:04:19,880 --> 00:04:21,620
William Jefferson Clinton.

79
00:04:21,940 --> 00:04:22,610
Huh?

80
00:04:23,230 --> 00:04:24,440
It's 2010,

81
00:04:25,370 --> 00:04:27,090
Bill And Hillary
Have Grown Apart.

82
00:04:27,250 --> 00:04:30,510
It's Nothing He Did.
Just... It Happens.

83
00:04:31,190 --> 00:04:34,250
We Inexplicably
Run Into Each Other Athe Lincoln Memorial,

84
00:04:34,260 --> 00:04:37,480
And It's Very Late
At Night.
Oh, My God.

85
00:04:37,650 --> 00:04:39,340
He Recognizes
Something In Me,

86
00:04:39,500 --> 00:04:42,190
Something That
Makes Him Feel Whole.

87
00:04:42,860 --> 00:04:45,710
Some Talk About
The Camp David Summit,

88
00:04:45,940 --> 00:04:48,170
Some Chat About
How We Can't Possibly,

89
00:04:48,390 --> 00:04:50,370
The Secret Service Is...

90
00:04:51,060 --> 00:04:51,860
The Next Thing You Know,

91
00:04:52,040 --> 00:04:54,610
I Have A Presidential Library
In Little Rock

92
00:04:54,790 --> 00:04:58,630
And There's
A Legendary Picture Of Me And Bill Laughing

93
00:04:58,660 --> 00:05:00,960
And Sharing Sections
Of "The Times,"

94
00:05:01,140 --> 00:05:03,910
While Our Child
Plays Under The Dinner Table...

95
00:05:04,120 --> 00:05:05,580
And...

96
00:05:08,330 --> 00:05:09,410
Orgasm.

97
00:05:10,810 --> 00:05:13,030
You're Really Over Allan,
Aren't You?

98
00:05:13,360 --> 00:05:15,840
Oh, I Got Bill Now.
Bill's All I Need.

99
00:05:16,010 --> 00:05:17,840
So You Don't Think About
Someone Real?

100
00:05:18,000 --> 00:05:20,560
Oh, Bill's Real.
Bill Is... Very Real.

101
00:05:20,810 --> 00:05:22,360
Not Pete Real.

102
00:05:22,520 --> 00:05:24,420
Not In The Office Real.

103
00:05:24,620 --> 00:05:26,290
M-my Point Is,

104
00:05:26,460 --> 00:05:30,000
Whatever Helps You
Scratch The Itch... Is Fine.

105
00:05:30,600 --> 00:05:32,810
Oh, I Don't Do That.
What?

106
00:05:35,310 --> 00:05:36,010
Hello.

107
00:05:38,620 --> 00:05:39,380
Uh-huh.

108
00:05:40,560 --> 00:05:41,680
Yeah, Uh, Okay.

109
00:05:41,880 --> 00:05:44,350
I Will, Uh, Be Right There.

110
00:05:45,960 --> 00:05:46,690
Okay.

111
00:05:47,460 --> 00:05:48,130
I Gotta Go.

112
00:05:49,030 --> 00:05:50,030
Uh, I'll See You Later.

113
00:05:53,400 --> 00:05:55,100
She Doesn't Do That?

114
00:05:57,750 --> 00:05:59,270
If You Have Any Pain,
Let Me Know.
Okay.

115
00:05:59,880 --> 00:06:02,650
Hey, A Patient Of Yours
Is In The E.R. Beth Burton.

116
00:06:02,860 --> 00:06:04,840
Somebody Broke Into Her House.
She's--she's Hurt.

117
00:06:05,010 --> 00:06:06,410
Her Husband Just Flew In
From A Business Trip.

118
00:06:06,570 --> 00:06:08,070
He'll Meet You
At The Hospital.

119
00:06:13,940 --> 00:06:15,060
Is She Gonna Be Okay,
Though?

120
00:06:15,230 --> 00:06:18,170
It Wasn't That Bad.
The Man...

121
00:06:18,780 --> 00:06:21,420
I Came Down The Stairs,
I Saw Him There,

122
00:06:22,350 --> 00:06:23,890
And He Got Spooked
And Took Off.

123
00:06:24,050 --> 00:06:26,510
And I Tripped And Fell
Into The Glass Table.

124
00:06:26,530 --> 00:06:28,380
Well, That's A Pretty Bad Cut.

125
00:06:29,110 --> 00:06:30,510
I'm Gonna Need A C.T.

126
00:06:31,830 --> 00:06:34,510
Okay, Well,
I'll Call Your Mom,

127
00:06:34,990 --> 00:06:36,430
Go Check On The Kids.Okay?

128
00:06:36,970 --> 00:06:37,690
Okay.

129
00:06:42,660 --> 00:06:43,690
Pretty Frightening.

130
00:06:45,000 --> 00:06:47,650
Oh. It Could've Been
So Much Worse.

131
00:06:54,440 --> 00:06:55,370
Mm. Bill.

132
00:06:56,300 --> 00:06:57,190
Bill?

133
00:06:58,690 --> 00:07:01,400
- Naomi Cannot Keep
A Secret.
- Okay, Okay, Okay,

134
00:07:01,550 --> 00:07:03,370
First Of All,
Who Are You To Talk?
Oh--

135
00:07:03,530 --> 00:07:07,190
Second Of All, Did You Notice
Who I Wasn't Talking About?

136
00:07:08,120 --> 00:07:09,870
Allan. Hey.

137
00:07:10,040 --> 00:07:10,850
I'm Tellin' Ya--
Yeah.

138
00:07:11,030 --> 00:07:13,110
I Am Over The Hump.

139
00:07:13,310 --> 00:07:17,690
Hey, Were You Expecting Allan? 'cause He's Here.
- Okay, That's--That's Not Funny.

140
00:07:18,070 --> 00:07:19,930
You Hear Me
Talking About Allan,

141
00:07:20,140 --> 00:07:22,960
And You Want To Mess Me Up,
Pap Smear Boy.

142
00:07:23,160 --> 00:07:24,620
No, Violet,
He's--he's Here.

143
00:07:25,140 --> 00:07:28,420
I Mean, Allan's...
In The Lobby Here.

144
00:07:29,590 --> 00:07:30,330
Uh, Okay.

145
00:07:33,740 --> 00:07:35,490
You--you Tell Him
To Get Lost.

146
00:07:35,670 --> 00:07:36,800
It's Like He's Got
Friggin' Spidey Sense.

147
00:07:36,940 --> 00:07:38,250
Every Time The Two Of You
Split Up,

148
00:07:38,410 --> 00:07:40,690
- The Exact Moment
You Can Breathe Again--
- Violet.

149
00:07:44,590 --> 00:07:45,670
Coop, Hey.

150
00:07:46,270 --> 00:07:47,170
Al, Hey.

151
00:07:49,220 --> 00:07:50,620
Do You--do You Have
A Minute?

152
00:07:51,670 --> 00:07:53,150
- You Have Patients.
- I Have Patients.

153
00:07:53,340 --> 00:07:54,830
Right. Yeah. It's The Middle
Of The Work Day.

154
00:07:56,460 --> 00:07:57,450
I Was Just...

155
00:07:59,180 --> 00:08:00,350
I Was Thinking About You.

156
00:08:01,610 --> 00:08:03,020
And, Um...

157
00:08:03,620 --> 00:08:05,630
A-another Time, Maybe.

158
00:08:09,500 --> 00:08:10,480
Good Girl.

159
00:08:10,660 --> 00:08:12,530
Allan, I--
I Have A Minute.

160
00:08:23,240 --> 00:08:24,010
Maya?

161
00:08:34,620 --> 00:08:36,730
What's With The Stealth Call
And The Hiding?

162
00:08:36,900 --> 00:08:38,410
Aren't You Girls
Supposed To Be In School?

163
00:08:38,560 --> 00:08:39,890
You Didn't Tell My Mom,
Did You?

164
00:08:40,040 --> 00:08:41,080
Not Yet.

165
00:08:42,300 --> 00:08:43,340
What's The Emergency?

166
00:08:43,650 --> 00:08:44,590
It's...

167
00:08:44,890 --> 00:08:46,500
We Think--i Mean...

168
00:08:47,050 --> 00:08:49,530
I Think That--
Maya Totally Has
A Disease.

169
00:08:49,690 --> 00:08:50,580
A Disease?

170
00:08:52,170 --> 00:08:53,670
What Kind Of Disease?

171
00:08:54,000 --> 00:08:55,040
Tell Her, Maya.

172
00:08:56,450 --> 00:08:59,940
I'm...I'm Pretty Sure
I Have Gonorrhea.

173
00:09:18,560 --> 00:09:19,710
- Hey.
- Hey.

174
00:09:21,670 --> 00:09:23,950
John Went To Go Fill Out
Surance Forms.

175
00:09:24,320 --> 00:09:27,640
Well, Your C.T. Is A Negative.
How You Doing?

176
00:09:27,810 --> 00:09:28,970
- Cold.
- Yeah.

177
00:09:29,510 --> 00:09:31,870
Okay.
Dr. Bennett...

178
00:09:32,270 --> 00:09:35,810
Um... I Saw Something
The News

179
00:09:36,110 --> 00:09:38,560
About This Drug.

180
00:09:38,780 --> 00:09:40,880
They Said It Worked
For Some Katrina Victims.

181
00:09:41,050 --> 00:09:41,830
What Kind Of Drug?

182
00:09:42,010 --> 00:09:46,430
||it Makes You Forget
What Happened. Is It Real?

183
00:09:46,780 --> 00:09:48,670
Uh, I've Never Heard Of It.

184
00:09:48,850 --> 00:09:52,590
What I Went Through,
I Know, Wasn't That Bad.

185
00:09:53,530 --> 00:09:57,030
But John's...
Away On Business A Lot,And...

186
00:09:57,850 --> 00:10:00,760
I'm--i'm Just Afraid I'll Never Get
Another Good Night's Sleep.

187
00:10:02,310 --> 00:10:04,450
Mm-hmm. Okay.
Uh, I'll Look Into It.

188
00:10:04,810 --> 00:10:05,570
Please.

189
00:10:06,650 --> 00:10:07,940
And Don't Tell John.

190
00:10:08,100 --> 00:10:10,620
I Don't Want Him Thinking He Can Never
Leave Me Alone Again.

191
00:10:16,030 --> 00:10:18,300
Gonorrhea--that's
The Good S.T.D., Right?

192
00:10:18,460 --> 00:10:20,300
You Just Give Me Some Pills,
And It's Gone?

193
00:10:20,480 --> 00:10:23,170
No, I Need To Do
A Full Pelvic Exam.

194
00:10:23,400 --> 00:10:24,940
But--
There's No Buts.

195
00:10:25,110 --> 00:10:27,390
I Won't Know If It's Gonorrhea
Until I Check You Out.

196
00:10:27,720 --> 00:10:30,730
And I Also Need To
Rule Out Chlamydia.

197
00:10:31,290 --> 00:10:32,110
Besides...

198
00:10:33,490 --> 00:10:35,160
If You're Engaging In Sex...

199
00:10:35,380 --> 00:10:36,930
You Need To Be Getting
Regular Checkups.

200
00:10:37,100 --> 00:10:38,750
That's The Responsible Way
To Behave.

201
00:10:38,930 --> 00:10:43,040
<I>Although I Don't Expect You
To Be Responsible At 13, Maya.</I>

202
00:10:45,920 --> 00:10:47,180
Honey, Look At Me.

203
00:10:49,280 --> 00:10:50,050
Are You...

204
00:10:51,110 --> 00:10:52,360
Are You Okay?

205
00:10:53,170 --> 00:10:55,140
Did You Do This
Because A Boy...

206
00:10:55,440 --> 00:10:57,400
Are You Being Pressured
Because--

207
00:10:57,550 --> 00:10:58,550
I'm Not A Little Kid.

208
00:11:05,490 --> 00:11:07,420
Hey, Um, Mrs. Worth
Is Here For Her Yearly.

209
00:11:07,590 --> 00:11:10,050
This Is The One I'm Doing,
Right? This Is Mine?
It's Pap Time, Dell.
Get Papping.

210
00:11:10,200 --> 00:11:11,380
But You Don't--you Don't
Want To Be There?

211
00:11:11,540 --> 00:11:14,320
Just Ask Her If She Wants A Female Chaperone Present

212
00:11:14,480 --> 00:11:15,690
Before You Lay
A Finger On Her.

213
00:11:15,840 --> 00:11:18,010
Also Relax.
Patients Can Smell Fear.

214
00:11:18,170 --> 00:11:20,260
Keep The Speculum Warm
And Tell The Patients

215
00:11:20,420 --> 00:11:22,120
Exactly What You're Doing
Before You Do It.

216
00:11:22,330 --> 00:11:25,280
And Introduce Yourself.
Doctors Always Forget That.

217
00:11:25,430 --> 00:11:27,890
No, I-i Aced Bedside Manner.
I'm Gonna Give A Happy Pap.

218
00:11:28,050 --> 00:11:30,520
No Worries.
Good, Good.
Um, Where's Sam?

219
00:11:30,690 --> 00:11:32,190
He Had To Go To The Hospital.
And Naomi's In The Back?

220
00:11:32,350 --> 00:11:34,190
You Don't Think I Need Help,
Right? I Don't Need Help?

221
00:11:34,540 --> 00:11:35,630
You're Gonna Be Fine.

222
00:11:37,040 --> 00:11:38,340
I Can Do It Myself.

223
00:11:40,450 --> 00:11:43,040
- Hello. I'm Dell Parker.
And I'll Be Doing--
- No.

224
00:11:43,180 --> 00:11:44,970
Get The Checked Napkins,
The Red And White Kind.

225
00:11:45,140 --> 00:11:49,120
They Told Me
I Was Getting A Nurse.
I-i Am.
I-i Have My Nursing Degree,

226
00:11:49,270 --> 00:11:51,110
And--and I'm About
Be Certified As--

227
00:11:51,260 --> 00:11:54,710
- They Sent Me A Boy Nurse.I Know.
- Um, I Just--excuse Me.

228
00:11:54,860 --> 00:11:57,230
I-i Need To Ask If You'd Like
A Female Chaperone Present

229
00:11:57,380 --> 00:11:58,260
For The Exam.

230
00:11:58,570 --> 00:12:01,600
No, Just Do It. I Gotta
Pick Up My Daughter From Ballet.

231
00:12:01,960 --> 00:12:02,540
All Right.

232
00:12:05,210 --> 00:12:05,880
I Don't Know.

233
00:12:06,350 --> 00:12:08,870
He's Like 5 Years Old.
Yeah.

234
00:12:09,810 --> 00:12:12,200
I'll Just Get This...
For You.

235
00:12:12,470 --> 00:12:13,240
Okay.

236
00:12:14,440 --> 00:12:16,390
He Just Dropped The Thing.
Okay, Okay, Okay,
That Happens.

237
00:12:16,590 --> 00:12:19,150
<I>The Thing. Yeah.
Okay, Let's Do This.</I>

238
00:12:20,070 --> 00:12:22,480
You're Not Gonna Use That?
Uh, No, A New One.

239
00:12:22,630 --> 00:12:24,490
I'm--i'm Getting A New One.
I'm Getting A New One.

240
00:12:25,580 --> 00:12:28,450
Okay, Not A--not A Happy Pap.
Not A Happy Pap.

241
00:12:36,210 --> 00:12:37,610
Looks Like
You're Working Hard.

242
00:12:37,780 --> 00:12:39,830
Even With A Cold, This Pace
Should Be A Piece Of Cake.

243
00:12:39,990 --> 00:12:40,960
I Got An Audience.

244
00:12:42,660 --> 00:12:45,410
Just Wanted To See Nicole Clemmons
Run In Person Once

245
00:12:45,420 --> 00:12:47,260
Before She's On
My Wheaties Box.

246
00:12:48,200 --> 00:12:49,920
I've Done Some Marathons.

247
00:12:50,490 --> 00:12:52,780
Nicole, This Is
Dr. Charlotte King.

248
00:12:52,940 --> 00:12:54,250
She Does Marathons.

249
00:13:00,330 --> 00:13:03,330
Uh, You Should Stop.
I Just Gotta Push Through.

250
00:13:03,570 --> 00:13:07,000
No, That's A Bad Idea.
Get Off. Stop.

251
00:13:14,540 --> 00:13:16,190
They Been In There
Way Too Long.

252
00:13:16,690 --> 00:13:18,790
<I>They Are Not
Getting Back Together.</I>

253
00:13:19,050 --> 00:13:19,610
No.

254
00:13:24,300 --> 00:13:26,220
It's Good To See You. Thanks.

255
00:13:28,810 --> 00:13:29,690
Friends.

256
00:13:31,860 --> 00:13:32,370
What?

257
00:13:32,540 --> 00:13:34,400
Allan--
He Just Wants To Be Friends.

258
00:13:34,620 --> 00:13:37,440
We're Having Coffee.
Oh, Come On, Violet.

259
00:13:37,600 --> 00:13:39,790
You Know, Sometimes Friends
Can Mean Just Friends.

260
00:13:39,960 --> 00:13:43,070
I Mean,
Look At Me And Naomi.
Oh, You Two
Are So Not Friends.

261
00:13:43,260 --> 00:13:44,990
Yeah, You Guys Are More
Like A Corporation.
A Corporation.

262
00:13:45,170 --> 00:13:47,250
We Are Handling
A Really Tough Situation

263
00:13:47,420 --> 00:13:50,800
With, Uh, Maturity--
You Know, He--
He Apologized For Hurting Me.

264
00:13:50,990 --> 00:13:54,070
He Just Misses
Our Conversations.
Allan Always Blows In,

265
00:13:54,230 --> 00:13:55,140
He Makes You Feel All Good,

266
00:13:55,300 --> 00:13:56,750
And Then He Hurts You
Worse Than The Last Time,

267
00:13:56,900 --> 00:13:59,680
And I Pick Up The Pieces.
Sorry, Uh, To Interr--
I Need--can I Get, Uh...

268
00:13:59,860 --> 00:14:03,240
I Need To Borrow You
For A Consult.

269
00:14:03,430 --> 00:14:04,160
Gladly.

270
00:14:05,120 --> 00:14:05,780
Get Help.

271
00:14:07,130 --> 00:14:07,430
Hey...

272
00:14:07,730 --> 00:14:10,900
I... Allan--allan Wants
To Be Friends.

273
00:14:11,050 --> 00:14:12,550
That's Healthy.
We're Moving On. We're--
No, No, No.

274
00:14:12,700 --> 00:14:14,280
If--if--if Cooper
Doesn't Have To Listen To It,

275
00:14:14,440 --> 00:14:15,880
Then Neither Do I.

276
00:14:16,040 --> 00:14:18,210
Now I Have This Patient--
Beth Burton.

277
00:14:18,370 --> 00:14:19,890
She Interrupted
A Robbery In Her Home,

278
00:14:20,070 --> 00:14:21,180
And She's Interested
In A Drug

279
00:14:21,360 --> 00:14:23,110
Used On Post-traumatic Stress
Patients.

280
00:14:23,280 --> 00:14:24,990
Propranolol,
The Beta Blocker.

281
00:14:25,160 --> 00:14:29,220
So Then It's For Real?
Uh, It's Controversial,
But Yeah, It's Real.

282
00:14:29,390 --> 00:14:31,220
It--it--it Blunts
The Physical Response

283
00:14:31,370 --> 00:14:32,850
To The Memory Consolidation
Of The Trauma.

284
00:14:33,000 --> 00:14:34,590
So Then You Don't
Actually Forget?

285
00:14:34,760 --> 00:14:38,260
It More, Um, Lessens
The Fear And Panic

286
00:14:38,410 --> 00:14:40,620
When You Do Remember.
Will You Talk To Her With Me,

287
00:14:40,790 --> 00:14:42,560
Make Sure She's Really
A Candidate?
Yeah, Sure.

288
00:14:42,560 --> 00:14:43,520
All Right. Thank Y.

289
00:14:44,890 --> 00:14:46,490
Hey, Uh, Sam, Um...

290
00:14:47,260 --> 00:14:50,520
If I Were To Wear A Skirt
To Have Coffee With Allan,

291
00:14:50,690 --> 00:14:52,960
Would That Mean
"I Want To Get With You?"

292
00:14:53,980 --> 00:14:55,710
Not That I Want That.

293
00:14:55,900 --> 00:14:57,760
I'm Asking Because I Don't.

294
00:14:58,790 --> 00:15:01,790
Little Maya.
Little Sweet, Innocent Maya.

295
00:15:01,950 --> 00:15:02,740
Oh--from The Christmas Card

296
00:15:02,890 --> 00:15:05,360
And The Onesie With
The Pacifier And The Drool--

297
00:15:05,540 --> 00:15:07,330
Sweet, Innocent Drool--
And...

298
00:15:07,670 --> 00:15:08,800
God Knows
Where That's Been Now.

299
00:15:08,860 --> 00:15:13,250
Why Me? Why Did Maya
Haveo Come To Me?

300
00:15:13,600 --> 00:15:15,050
Oh, Poor Naomi.

301
00:15:15,340 --> 00:15:17,990
I Just Ran An S.T.D. Test
On Her 13 Year Old.

302
00:15:18,130 --> 00:15:19,280
I Mean,
How Do I Tell Her That?

303
00:15:19,430 --> 00:15:21,730
California Has Strict
Patient Confidentiality Laws,

304
00:15:21,880 --> 00:15:23,860
Especially For Minors.
I Know.

305
00:15:24,820 --> 00:15:26,680
But How Can I
Keep Something Like This

306
00:15:26,840 --> 00:15:28,020
From Sam And Naomi?

307
00:15:28,170 --> 00:15:29,620
She's Everything To Them.

308
00:15:29,780 --> 00:15:31,880
Maya Doesn't Need For You
To Tell Her Parents.

309
00:15:32,410 --> 00:15:35,390
What She Needs
Is Someone She Can Trust.

310
00:15:35,560 --> 00:15:36,840
Maya Could Use A Friend
Right Now.

311
00:15:36,890 --> 00:15:38,010
So You Be Her Friend,
Addison.

312
00:15:38,180 --> 00:15:40,250
You Give Her
What Her Parents Can't.

313
00:15:43,610 --> 00:15:45,640
Nicole, You Have
Severe Bronchospasm.

314
00:15:45,790 --> 00:15:48,440
Your Oxygen Levels Are Dropping
Dangerously Low When You Run.

315
00:15:48,600 --> 00:15:50,700
You'll Need Inhaled Steroids
And Continuous Neb.

316
00:15:50,880 --> 00:15:52,230
I Can't Use Those.

317
00:15:52,390 --> 00:15:54,250
I Have Nional Championships
Coming Up.

318
00:15:54,270 --> 00:15:55,450
Look, I Know You Want
To Stick With Herbs,

319
00:15:55,590 --> 00:15:57,270
But At This Point,
You Have No Choice.

320
00:15:57,420 --> 00:16:00,300
You Cannot Compete Again Until
You Get This Under Control.
What?

321
00:16:00,460 --> 00:16:04,760
If You Listen To Dr. Wilder,
Let Him Get You Stabilized,

322
00:16:04,910 --> 00:16:06,200
You Will Race Again.

323
00:16:06,450 --> 00:16:07,500
But Not Yet.

324
00:16:07,660 --> 00:16:09,460
This Is
An Olympic Qualifying Meet.

325
00:16:09,640 --> 00:16:12,910
The Condition You're In,
If You Run Too Hard,

326
00:16:13,080 --> 00:16:15,190
You Push Too Hard,
If You Even Walk Too Hard,

327
00:16:15,230 --> 00:16:16,140
You Could Die.

328
00:16:32,730 --> 00:16:34,040
Okay, Here She Is.
Good Morning.

329
00:16:34,200 --> 00:16:34,980
Hey.
Hey.

330
00:16:36,070 --> 00:16:37,490
- Just A-ask Her.
- Okay.

331
00:16:39,130 --> 00:16:40,580
What Did You Mean
The Other Day

332
00:16:40,740 --> 00:16:43,910
When You Said You...
Don't Do That?

333
00:16:44,060 --> 00:16:46,140
That I Don't Do That.

334
00:16:46,290 --> 00:16:48,280
You Don't... You...

335
00:16:48,450 --> 00:16:50,220
You Actually Do Not Do...

336
00:16:50,480 --> 00:16:54,310
You--you Physically,
Actually... Do Not Do That?

337
00:16:54,460 --> 00:16:57,820
I Don't Do That.
I Feel Like She's Speaking
Czech Or Mandarin.

338
00:16:57,990 --> 00:16:59,030
I'm Not A Prude.

339
00:16:59,190 --> 00:17:01,720
It's Just...
I'm From Connecticut.

340
00:17:01,900 --> 00:17:04,940
And--and Besides, For Me,
Sex Is A 2-player Game.

341
00:17:05,150 --> 00:17:06,590
The Solo Thing Just Doesn't
Cut It For Me.

342
00:17:06,730 --> 00:17:09,970
You Know
What I'm Talking About.
Showerhead Massager.

343
00:17:10,530 --> 00:17:12,370
What About Maya?

344
00:17:12,610 --> 00:17:15,060
I-i Would Think
As A Mother--

345
00:17:15,230 --> 00:17:17,940
A Mother With A Very Expensive
Showerhead Massager.

346
00:17:18,120 --> 00:17:22,300
Look, First... Self-pleasure
Is A Feminine Righ

347
00:17:22,500 --> 00:17:25,330
As A Single Woman, Sex Cannot
Always Be A 2-player Game

348
00:17:25,480 --> 00:17:26,510
'cause You're Gonna
Get Desperate,

349
00:17:26,660 --> 00:17:27,900
And You're Gonna Play
With The Wrong Guy.

350
00:17:28,050 --> 00:17:29,960
Pete.
Pete Is The Wrong Guy.

351
00:17:30,120 --> 00:17:32,050
Right. No. Except In
Your Fantasies. He's Fine.

352
00:17:32,210 --> 00:17:33,690
You Know,
Do Him In Dream Land.

353
00:17:33,860 --> 00:17:36,490
So You're Saying To Avoid
Having Sex With Pete,

354
00:17:36,650 --> 00:17:38,990
I Need To Have
"Sex With Pete"?

355
00:17:39,180 --> 00:17:43,360
No, You Need To Have Sex
With Yourself.
Yeah, Pete Is More
Just Like A...

356
00:17:43,660 --> 00:17:45,890
Helping Hand.
Please Stop Talking.

357
00:17:46,630 --> 00:17:48,430
Uh, Beth Burton Is Here.

358
00:17:48,590 --> 00:17:50,400
Yes, I'm...
I'm Coming Right Away.

359
00:17:52,700 --> 00:17:55,930
- We Were Just--
- Ah, No. Don't--Don't Explain.

360
00:17:56,040 --> 00:17:58,520
I Don't... I--mm.

361
00:18:00,090 --> 00:18:02,040
- He's Gonna Tell Pete.
- He's Gonna Tell Pete.

362
00:18:04,090 --> 00:18:05,350
Hey, Um...

363
00:18:05,770 --> 00:18:06,870
How's, Uh...

364
00:18:08,030 --> 00:18:09,580
How's Maya Doing?

365
00:18:09,730 --> 00:18:11,810
I Mean, She Seems So...
Grown-up.

366
00:18:11,980 --> 00:18:13,520
You Know, After The Divorce
And--

367
00:18:13,650 --> 00:18:15,620
You Know, Actually,
I Think She Kinda Digs

368
00:18:15,780 --> 00:18:17,310
Having Divorced Parents.

369
00:18:17,460 --> 00:18:19,680
You Know, Liketwo Houses
And Double The Clothes.

370
00:18:19,840 --> 00:18:21,800
You Knowshe's Good.

371
00:18:25,270 --> 00:18:26,260
Right.

372
00:18:27,930 --> 00:18:28,410
Hi.

373
00:18:29,250 --> 00:18:30,930
What,
Are You Watching Me Now?

374
00:18:31,090 --> 00:18:32,040
What, Does Addison Not Think
I Can Do This?

375
00:18:32,180 --> 00:18:33,110
'cause I Can Do This.

376
00:18:33,280 --> 00:18:36,800
I'm Just Observing.
Now Go. Do This.

377
00:18:36,960 --> 00:18:37,540
Okay.

378
00:18:38,070 --> 00:18:42,090
Okay, So, Um, What I'm
Going To Do Is, Uh...

379
00:18:42,770 --> 00:18:43,340
What I'm Going To Do--

380
00:18:43,510 --> 00:18:46,050
You're Cute.
He's Cute, Right?

381
00:18:46,200 --> 00:18:48,530
Let's Just, Uh,
Focus On The Exam, Okay?

382
00:18:48,690 --> 00:18:50,150
Okay, So, Um, Sorry.

383
00:18:50,320 --> 00:18:53,880
I'm, Uh, Gonna Tell You
The Names Of Stuff--
Is He Allowed
To Bthis Cute?

384
00:18:54,000 --> 00:18:55,540
Is She Allowed
To Ask Me That?
She's Allowed To Ask It,

385
00:18:55,680 --> 00:18:56,860
But You're Not Allowed
To Pay Any Attention,

386
00:18:57,010 --> 00:18:59,720
So Just Keep Going.
Okay. Okay.

387
00:18:59,880 --> 00:19:02,100
Uh, No.
This Isn't Gonna Work.

388
00:19:02,250 --> 00:19:03,510
You're Way Too Cute.

389
00:19:03,680 --> 00:19:04,810
No, No.
I'm Not. I'm Not.

390
00:19:04,950 --> 00:19:08,810
I'm Ugly. You Know, I-i-i Have
Moles In Weird Places.
No.

391
00:19:08,870 --> 00:19:09,580
So Just--just Let Me--
Unh-unh.

392
00:19:09,630 --> 00:19:13,740
I'd Be Having All These
Thoughts About Your Eyes And Stuff.

393
00:19:13,760 --> 00:19:15,400
No, No Way
You're Touching Me.

394
00:19:16,380 --> 00:19:21,400
Unless You Want
To Touch Me.
Okay, Dell, I Think
I Can Handle This One.

395
00:19:22,670 --> 00:19:25,120
I Would Like To Try
Some Therapy Sessions

396
00:19:25,290 --> 00:19:27,820
Before We Even Consider
Using The Propranolol.

397
00:19:27,990 --> 00:19:29,250
Why Can't We
Just Use The Drug?

398
00:19:29,400 --> 00:19:30,960
Well, Even If You Were
To Take It,

399
00:19:31,110 --> 00:19:33,080
It Would Still Involve
Sessions With Violet.

400
00:19:33,230 --> 00:19:36,130
Right. I Would Walk You Through
The Details Of The Event

401
00:19:36,280 --> 00:19:38,050
After The Drug
Has Taken Effect.

402
00:19:38,460 --> 00:19:40,070
All The Details?
Right.

403
00:19:40,220 --> 00:19:42,270
I, Uh, I-i Can't Do That.

404
00:19:42,660 --> 00:19:44,170
I Know--
I Know It Can Be Scary.

405
00:19:44,320 --> 00:19:47,900
No, No.
I Can't... Do That.

406
00:19:48,050 --> 00:19:48,860
Wait, Beth.

407
00:19:56,200 --> 00:19:56,730
Hey.

408
00:19:59,400 --> 00:20:01,350
I Got Your Test Results Back.

409
00:20:02,680 --> 00:20:05,070
You Don't Have Gonorrhea.

410
00:20:05,240 --> 00:20:06,030
Really?

411
00:20:06,510 --> 00:20:08,070
Well, That's Great.

412
00:20:08,570 --> 00:20:11,910
But Could I Get Some
Of Those Pills For The Guy?

413
00:20:12,080 --> 00:20:14,700
No, Absolutely Not.
No, He Has To See A Doctor.

414
00:20:15,790 --> 00:20:18,370
Maya... Can I Ask,

415
00:20:19,100 --> 00:20:22,300
How Long
Have You Been Having Sex?

416
00:20:24,020 --> 00:20:26,240
Mm, I Don't Know.

417
00:20:26,750 --> 00:20:27,650
A Year?

418
00:20:30,000 --> 00:20:30,920
Okay.

419
00:20:32,280 --> 00:20:34,820
A Year And... The Boy?

420
00:20:34,990 --> 00:20:37,160
Well, There's A Couple
Of Boys.

421
00:20:37,170 --> 00:20:39,990
A Couple Of Boys?
Not That I'm Judging.

422
00:20:40,150 --> 00:20:42,930
Friends Don't Judge.Just...

423
00:20:44,190 --> 00:20:46,760
Just Because You Didn't
Get An S.T.D. Now

424
00:20:46,950 --> 00:20:48,700
Doesn't Mean
You Won't Get One,

425
00:20:48,860 --> 00:20:51,770
Not To Mention The Risk
For H.I.V., Pregnancy--

426
00:20:51,920 --> 00:20:52,920
I Use Condoms.

427
00:20:53,080 --> 00:20:56,390
They're Not 100% Effective
In Preventing Disease And Pregnancy.

428
00:20:56,400 --> 00:20:57,110
They're Not?

429
00:20:58,380 --> 00:20:59,220
Maya...

430
00:21:01,380 --> 00:21:03,820
Sex At Your Age--

431
00:21:03,830 --> 00:21:06,610
Hey. I Didn't Know
You Were Here Already.

432
00:21:06,780 --> 00:21:07,950
She's Not Bugging You,
Is She?

433
00:21:08,120 --> 00:21:10,420
No. She's, Uh, No.

434
00:21:11,090 --> 00:21:14,060
I Just--i Just Wanted
To Say Hi To Aunt Addison.

435
00:21:14,220 --> 00:21:15,930
Well, Say Good-bye
To Aunt Addison.

436
00:21:16,080 --> 00:21:17,480
You've Got Violin.
Come On.

437
00:21:20,830 --> 00:21:22,230
Good-bye, Aunt Addison.
Bye.

438
00:21:29,180 --> 00:21:32,240
Beer?
Sudsy, Relaxing Beer?

439
00:21:32,420 --> 00:21:35,560
Violet Is Having Coffee
With Allan Tonight.

440
00:21:35,750 --> 00:21:38,310
I Deserve Beer Before I Have To
Wipe Her Off The Floor.

441
00:21:38,490 --> 00:21:40,320
I'm Going To The Track
To See Coach Mike.

442
00:21:40,740 --> 00:21:43,060
How'd He Take It When You
Told Him He Had To Bench Nicole Clemmons?

443
00:21:43,230 --> 00:21:44,560
He Hasn't Returned My Calls.

444
00:21:44,780 --> 00:21:46,230
Anyway, She's The One
I'm Worried About

445
00:21:46,370 --> 00:21:47,620
If She Can't Race
For A While.

446
00:21:48,560 --> 00:21:50,070
Maybe She Doesn't Know
About Beer?

447
00:21:50,360 --> 00:21:52,160
Have You Told Her About
R Good Friend Beer?

448
00:21:57,670 --> 00:21:58,380
Hi.

449
00:21:59,940 --> 00:22:01,810
I-i Left You
A Few Messages.

450
00:22:01,980 --> 00:22:03,250
And I W--i Was Just

451
00:22:03,410 --> 00:22:05,090
On My Way Out
For The Evening.

452
00:22:05,350 --> 00:22:06,960
I Need To Make Sure
You're Okay.

453
00:22:08,820 --> 00:22:10,960
Something More Happened,
Didn't It...

454
00:22:11,800 --> 00:22:13,120
Than What You Said?

455
00:22:19,850 --> 00:22:20,780
On Your Marks.

456
00:22:25,530 --> 00:22:26,520
Get Set.

457
00:22:36,350 --> 00:22:38,320
He Put
His Hand Over My Mouth...

458
00:22:39,410 --> 00:22:42,130
And Pushed Against Me
Until I Felt His Gun.

459
00:22:42,600 --> 00:22:44,040
He--he Had A Gun?

460
00:22:44,580 --> 00:22:47,570
I Told Him Just To Take
What He Wanted And To Leave,

461
00:22:47,740 --> 00:22:50,020
But He Shoved Me Down
On The Couch.

462
00:22:51,380 --> 00:22:54,550
Please Leave.
Please Leave.

463
00:22:55,080 --> 00:22:56,660
What Did He Do, Beth?

464
00:22:57,690 --> 00:23:00,840
She... She Hasn't Had
Any Trouble Breathing?

465
00:23:01,010 --> 00:23:03,730
No. Look At Her Go.

466
00:23:04,330 --> 00:23:06,090
You're A Miracle Worker,
Pete.

467
00:23:08,190 --> 00:23:09,450
I Didn't Do Anything.

468
00:23:10,960 --> 00:23:11,840
I Called For John.
I Kept Calling,

469
00:23:12,000 --> 00:23:13,520
And Then I Remembered
He Wasn't Home.

470
00:23:13,700 --> 00:23:15,090
I Was All Alone.

471
00:23:16,180 --> 00:23:18,710
It's Not Happening Now.
You're Safe.

472
00:23:18,890 --> 00:23:21,300
I Kicked Him, Hard.

473
00:23:22,150 --> 00:23:23,730
He Fell Off Me.

474
00:23:24,060 --> 00:23:24,990
You Did?

475
00:23:25,540 --> 00:23:26,570
I Got Up...

476
00:23:27,120 --> 00:23:30,350
And He Grabbed My Hair,
And I Fell Into The Table.

477
00:23:32,760 --> 00:23:34,070
My Son...

478
00:23:35,270 --> 00:23:38,590
- I Heard Him Wake Up Upstairs Crying...
- Beth.

479
00:23:44,750 --> 00:23:46,420
That Man Hit You?

480
00:23:50,960 --> 00:23:52,770
He Touched You?

481
00:23:57,820 --> 00:23:58,520
I've Never Seen Her Better.

482
00:23:58,670 --> 00:24:00,900
She's About To Break
Her Record.
You Should Tell Her
To Stop.

483
00:24:01,060 --> 00:24:03,120
Are You Kidding?
The Record--
She Should Stop.

484
00:24:04,730 --> 00:24:05,520
Nicole!

485
00:24:15,860 --> 00:24:18,040
He's Barely Said A Word Since
He Found Out What Happened.

486
00:24:18,200 --> 00:24:19,140
I Thought Maybe...

487
00:24:19,630 --> 00:24:21,360
Becae He Trusts You, He...

488
00:24:25,930 --> 00:24:28,250
It Was Right
To Tell The Truth.

489
00:24:28,890 --> 00:24:30,700
It's Just How He Is.

490
00:24:30,890 --> 00:24:32,510
He Takes Everything
On Himself.

491
00:24:32,720 --> 00:24:35,730
That Man Had His Hands
All Over...

492
00:24:35,910 --> 00:24:38,480
He Touched Her.
I Should've Been There.

493
00:24:39,040 --> 00:24:41,140
The Thing You Need To Focus On
Is Your Wife.

494
00:24:41,300 --> 00:24:42,400
I'm Gonna Give Notice.

495
00:24:42,710 --> 00:24:45,070
No More Business Trips,
No More Leaving.

496
00:24:45,230 --> 00:24:46,430
We're Gonna Get A Gun--
No.

497
00:24:46,610 --> 00:24:49,880
How Are You Ever Gonna
Rest Easy In Our Home, Hmm?

498
00:24:50,190 --> 00:24:52,560
How Are You Ever
Gonna Feel Safe?
Sten To Me.

499
00:24:53,310 --> 00:24:55,400
Okay, There's Something
That I Can Take

500
00:24:55,570 --> 00:24:57,860
So I Won't Remember This,
A Drug.

501
00:24:58,150 --> 00:24:59,470
We Do Not Need A Gun.

502
00:24:59,660 --> 00:25:02,840
Let's--let's Go Slow
Before We Go To Medication.

503
00:25:03,980 --> 00:25:07,190
Please. Nothing Has Changed.
I Don't Want To Feel It.

504
00:25:07,350 --> 00:25:08,540
I Want The Drug.

505
00:25:17,460 --> 00:25:18,470
Where's Her Family?

506
00:25:18,680 --> 00:25:19,830
Out Of The Picture.

507
00:25:21,080 --> 00:25:23,700
My Wife And I,
We Pretty Much Raised Her.

508
00:25:25,710 --> 00:25:26,600
Excuse Me.

509
00:25:26,770 --> 00:25:27,660
Can I Talk To You?

510
00:25:31,380 --> 00:25:33,870
What Kind Of Snake Oil
Did You Give That Girl?

511
00:25:35,160 --> 00:25:38,500
We Found It In Her Bag.
She's Alkaloid Toxic.

512
00:25:38,670 --> 00:25:39,770
This Isn't Mine.

513
00:25:41,490 --> 00:25:42,930
I'm Not Even Sure
What This Is.

514
00:25:43,100 --> 00:25:45,470
Well, That's A Damn Shame,
Because She's Your Patient,

515
00:25:45,630 --> 00:25:47,390
And It May Be
What's About To Kill Her.

516
00:25:54,590 --> 00:25:57,370
Come On, Vye, Open Up.
It'll Be Okay.

517
00:26:02,670 --> 00:26:05,550
Come On. I Got The Post-allan
Emergency Kit--roscoe's

518
00:26:05,710 --> 00:26:09,320
And Every Ashley-judd-shoots-
Her-cheating-husband Movie I Could Find.

519
00:26:10,520 --> 00:26:11,190
Oh.

520
00:26:12,710 --> 00:26:15,330
Oh, You Look, Uh, Good.
Well, I Shouldn't.

521
00:26:15,510 --> 00:26:16,950
I Had This Incredibly
Intense Thing

522
00:26:17,120 --> 00:26:19,100
With This, Uh,
Post-traumatic Stress Victim.

523
00:26:19,170 --> 00:26:19,860
Was--
Who's There, Vye?

524
00:26:22,580 --> 00:26:23,360
I Got It.

525
00:26:26,480 --> 00:26:29,210
We're Just Talking. Okay?

526
00:26:29,380 --> 00:26:31,330
Work Went Late,
And So He Came Here.

527
00:26:32,970 --> 00:26:35,520
Save These For Later.
You Will Need Them.

528
00:26:35,700 --> 00:26:35,960
Cooper--

529
00:26:36,130 --> 00:26:37,760
No, No, See,
This Is What I Was--

530
00:26:38,340 --> 00:26:40,590
Now Is The Giddy Updraft,

531
00:26:40,770 --> 00:26:42,730
Which Just Means You're Gonna
Have Farther To Fall.

532
00:26:42,910 --> 00:26:45,850
And I Can't Be The One
On Cleanup Detail When This Goes Bad.

533
00:26:45,930 --> 00:26:49,610
- Oh, So Suddenly You're A Relationship Expert?
- I'm An Expert On This Relationship

534
00:26:49,710 --> 00:26:52,520
<I>Because It's All
I Ever Hear About.</I>

535
00:26:53,140 --> 00:26:55,270
And You Know What?
I'm Tired.

536
00:27:15,150 --> 00:27:17,320
Oh, Come On.
You're Fantasizing
About Me?

537
00:27:17,510 --> 00:27:18,970
No.
It's Sweet.

538
00:27:19,310 --> 00:27:22,220
It's Not Sweet.
It's... Go Away.

539
00:27:22,400 --> 00:27:23,290
Is That What You Said
In Your Dream?

540
00:27:23,480 --> 00:27:24,830
I'm Not Talking To You
About This.

541
00:27:25,010 --> 00:27:25,940
You Like Me.
Wh--

542
00:27:27,280 --> 00:27:29,310
Why Do You Have To
Torture Me Like This?

543
00:27:29,480 --> 00:27:31,320
Do You Think This Is Fun?
Kinda.

544
00:27:38,720 --> 00:27:39,510
Hello.

545
00:27:42,530 --> 00:27:43,280
Oh, No.

546
00:27:43,830 --> 00:27:44,970
No, Sir.

547
00:27:45,150 --> 00:27:47,970
I Am Not Having A Child
Poke Around In Lady Town.

548
00:27:48,140 --> 00:27:49,260
I'm Not A Child. I'm--

549
00:27:49,340 --> 00:27:51,820
My Facial Hair Is Older
Than You.

550
00:27:52,150 --> 00:27:53,130
 Ll Take You.

551
00:27:53,290 --> 00:27:55,860
Mrs. Koster, I Can Assure You
That Dell--
Your Loss.

552
00:27:56,160 --> 00:27:57,410
I Don't Think So.

553
00:27:57,570 --> 00:28:01,150
You Know, Beethoven Composed His
First Symphony When He Was 5, 5.

554
00:28:01,550 --> 00:28:03,370
Picasso Mastered
The Human Form At 7.

555
00:28:03,530 --> 00:28:06,160
This Is What I Was Born To Do,
And Finally, I'm Doing It.

556
00:28:06,310 --> 00:28:07,620
I-i Would Have Rocked
This Pap Smear.

557
00:28:07,770 --> 00:28:08,960
I Guarantee
You'd Never Receive A More--

558
00:28:09,110 --> 00:28:12,820
A More Respectful,
Complete Examination Of Lady Town In Your Life.

559
00:28:12,970 --> 00:28:15,360
So Yeah, Your Loss.

560
00:28:23,070 --> 00:28:24,930
Go Ahead. Go Ahead. Go. Go.

561
00:28:31,950 --> 00:28:33,970
She's My Best Friend.
I Tell Her Everything.

562
00:28:34,130 --> 00:28:37,730
How Can I Not...
Tell Her About This?

563
00:28:39,750 --> 00:28:40,940
Sometimes
You Have To Disengage.

564
00:28:41,110 --> 00:28:43,410
Sometimes You Have To
Tell Yourself It's Better...

565
00:28:44,460 --> 00:28:45,960
Not To Get Involved.

566
00:28:48,760 --> 00:28:50,050
I'm Disengaging.

567
00:28:50,920 --> 00:28:52,510
Violet Can Do
Whatever She Wants.

568
00:28:52,670 --> 00:28:56,170
I'm Not Getting Involved,Not Any She Can Just...

569
00:28:56,940 --> 00:28:57,900
Suffer.

570
00:29:00,130 --> 00:29:00,680
Um...

571
00:29:01,930 --> 00:29:03,500
But We Were Talking
About You.

572
00:29:03,670 --> 00:29:04,860
We Were.
Yeah.

573
00:29:06,420 --> 00:29:06,770
Oh.

574
00:29:07,590 --> 00:29:08,190
Hello.

575
00:29:09,460 --> 00:29:12,490
Maya, Calm Down. Calm Down.
I'm Gonna Be Right There.

576
00:29:12,670 --> 00:29:13,110
Bye. 

577
00:29:14,230 --> 00:29:16,350
Uh, If Naomi Asks
Where I Am...

578
00:29:16,510 --> 00:29:17,420
Disengaged.

579
00:29:20,950 --> 00:29:21,820
Maya!

580
00:29:23,630 --> 00:29:24,350
What's Wrong?

581
00:29:25,490 --> 00:29:27,110
You Said Something
Was Wrong With You.

582
00:29:27,290 --> 00:29:28,050
Not Me.

583
00:29:31,190 --> 00:29:31,880
Ruby.

584
00:29:33,600 --> 00:29:34,440
She's...

585
00:29:35,040 --> 00:29:37,550
We Thought
She Just Had--had Gonorrhea.

586
00:29:37,740 --> 00:29:40,120
Wh-what?
You Said That You...

587
00:29:40,290 --> 00:29:42,690
<I>I Thought You Had It.
We Lied. It Was Her.</I>

588
00:29:42,980 --> 00:29:44,750
We Thought
She St Had Gonorrhea.

589
00:29:44,920 --> 00:29:48,190
but...now we think shi's pregnant

590
00:29:54,110 --> 00:29:55,650
Addison,
What's Wrong With Her?

591
00:29:56,380 --> 00:29:59,150
Ruby Has A Late Stage
Ectopic Pregnancy.

592
00:29:59,200 --> 00:30:01,420
It's Very Dangerous.
She's Bleeding Into Her Belly.

593
00:30:01,460 --> 00:30:02,690
I've Contacted Her Parents,
Though.

594
00:30:02,880 --> 00:30:05,740
Oh, But--but What Do I Do?
She's Lost
A Lot Of Blood, Maya.

595
00:30:05,900 --> 00:30:07,690
I've Got To Get Her
Into Surgery.
But--

596
00:30:07,850 --> 00:30:09,590
Now.
But What Do I Do?

597
00:30:19,960 --> 00:30:20,790
Mommy?

598
00:30:20,960 --> 00:30:23,630
It's Typical
For Victims Of Sexual Assault

599
00:30:23,810 --> 00:30:26,630
To Hide Detas
To Protect Their Partners.

600
00:30:26,830 --> 00:30:28,440
John,
Right After The Attack,

601
00:30:28,620 --> 00:30:30,330
Beth Started Worrying
About You.

602
00:30:30,510 --> 00:30:32,140
I'm Not The One
To Be Worried About.

603
00:30:32,740 --> 00:30:33,550
Beth's The One That--

604
00:30:33,750 --> 00:30:34,960
What Happened To Beth...

605
00:30:37,110 --> 00:30:38,230
Was Awful.

606
00:30:38,410 --> 00:30:41,900
But What She Did...
Beth.

607
00:30:42,690 --> 00:30:43,690
What You Did...

608
00:30:44,760 --> 00:30:46,500
Was Incredibly Brave.

609
00:30:47,400 --> 00:30:48,800
You Survived.

610
00:30:54,180 --> 00:30:55,790
I Survived.

611
00:30:57,980 --> 00:30:58,810
Whew.

612
00:31:00,930 --> 00:31:03,060
I Never Thought Of It
That Way Before.

613
00:31:08,150 --> 00:31:09,860
I Survived.

614
00:31:10,530 --> 00:31:12,740
I Believe That You Can
Get Through This,

615
00:31:12,920 --> 00:31:14,990
That You Have The Strength
To Get Through This...

616
00:31:15,480 --> 00:31:17,050
Without A Pill.

617
00:31:17,550 --> 00:31:22,050
What You Are Afraid Of Is Not Remembering
What Happened To You That Night.

618
00:31:22,110 --> 00:31:23,030
You Already Did That.

619
00:31:23,880 --> 00:31:25,720
And Look,
You're Still Standing.

620
00:31:26,780 --> 00:31:30,990
What You Are Afraid Of Is Not
That You're Not Strong Enough To Handle This.

621
00:31:32,330 --> 00:31:34,450
- What You're Afraid Of Is--
- That...

622
00:31:36,190 --> 00:31:39,840
John Isn't Strong Enough
To Handle This.

623
00:31:40,870 --> 00:31:42,480
Wait.
Are--are You Saying...

624
00:31:43,890 --> 00:31:45,960
You're Saying
That I'm Too Weak?

625
00:31:47,040 --> 00:31:48,560
I'm Saying
That You're Human.

626
00:31:50,030 --> 00:31:51,880
I'm Saying She's Your Wife,

627
00:31:52,650 --> 00:31:54,340
And You Couldn't Protect Her.

628
00:31:55,040 --> 00:31:57,030
And That's Not Your Fault.

629
00:32:03,860 --> 00:32:05,870
I'm Supposed
To Take Care Of You.

630
00:32:07,550 --> 00:32:09,580
John, Maybe This Time
You Could Let Beth

631
00:32:09,750 --> 00:32:10,710
Take Care Of You.

632
00:32:12,780 --> 00:32:14,410
And There's No Pill
For That.

633
00:32:25,820 --> 00:32:29,680
Nicole, I Need You To Tell Me
The Name Of The Person That Gave You This.

634
00:32:30,410 --> 00:32:33,680
Maybe I Just Took Too Mu.
I Won't Use It Next Time.

635
00:32:33,840 --> 00:32:35,850
I Don't Think You Understand
What This Guy--

636
00:32:39,280 --> 00:32:40,490
After Today...

637
00:32:44,730 --> 00:32:46,940
I'm Not Sure
If You'll Ever Race Again.

638
00:32:50,200 --> 00:32:53,780
No. I Did Not Work This Hard,

639
00:32:53,950 --> 00:32:55,830
I Did Not Give Up My Life
For This.

640
00:32:56,020 --> 00:32:58,220
Nicole, You Need
To Stay In Bed. Stop.

641
00:32:58,490 --> 00:32:59,510
Stop.

642
00:33:00,600 --> 00:33:02,110
Tell Me Who Did This
To You.

643
00:33:04,380 --> 00:33:05,050
I Didn't Know.

644
00:33:05,230 --> 00:33:07,890
You Knew Enough To Shop For Another Doctor
Who Would Tell You What You Wanted To Hear.

645
00:33:07,910 --> 00:33:10,890
She Was Gonna Lose Everything--
The Olympics, Her Scholarship.

646
00:33:11,030 --> 00:33:13,760
She Almost Died.
She Couldn't Miss That Meet.

647
00:33:13,910 --> 00:33:15,600
You Can't Allow For Weakness.

648
00:33:15,760 --> 00:33:17,440
She Was Gonna Break
Her Record.

649
00:33:21,540 --> 00:33:22,750
So What's Cami Like?

650
00:33:23,210 --> 00:33:24,990
Well, C-cami's Great.

651
00:33:25,520 --> 00:33:26,090
Oh, Come On.

652
00:33:26,940 --> 00:33:30,550
You Gotta Give Me
One Little Juicy Detail I Can Hate About Her.

653
00:33:30,550 --> 00:33:31,350
Um...

654
00:33:33,460 --> 00:33:35,130
Well, Sh--

655
00:33:36,280 --> 00:33:37,340
She's Young.

656
00:33:39,110 --> 00:33:41,110
Young Is Not A Flaw...

657
00:33:43,210 --> 00:33:46,030
Unless You're An Old Guy
Dating A Young Woman.

658
00:33:46,610 --> 00:33:47,470
Ouch.

659
00:33:47,820 --> 00:33:49,920
Okay, Her Flaws. Okay.

660
00:33:50,170 --> 00:33:52,580
Um...
Well, There's You.

661
00:33:53,340 --> 00:33:54,950
She's A Mess
When It Comes To You.

662
00:33:55,220 --> 00:33:56,200
Really?
Mm-hmm.

663
00:33:56,730 --> 00:33:59,510
See, I Have This--this File
With All Your Old E-mails,

664
00:33:59,670 --> 00:34:01,390
And She--she Found It.

665
00:34:01,390 --> 00:34:02,260
It Was Like, Kaboom.

666
00:34:03,920 --> 00:34:04,780
Kaboom.

667
00:34:05,760 --> 00:34:07,610
Yeah. Add That
To The Baby Fever.

668
00:34:09,970 --> 00:34:11,270
Baby Fever?

669
00:34:11,480 --> 00:34:12,520
Yeah. We're...

670
00:34:13,690 --> 00:34:14,820
We're--we're Trying
To Get Pregnant.

671
00:34:14,980 --> 00:34:16,060
You Know, Which Is...

672
00:34:19,480 --> 00:34:20,770
Finish The Sentence.

673
00:34:20,920 --> 00:34:22,340
No, I'm Sorry.
Why? Why?

674
00:34:23,320 --> 00:34:25,370
E's--she's Your Wife.
You're Talking To A Friend.

675
00:34:25,530 --> 00:34:26,630
So Finish Your Sentence.

676
00:34:26,780 --> 00:34:28,910
You're Trying To Get Pregnant,
And That Is...
We Don't Need To--

677
00:34:29,070 --> 00:34:31,540
Finish The Damn Sentence,
Allan.
You're Yelling.
You're Yelling.

678
00:34:32,980 --> 00:34:34,610
I'll Go.
No.

679
00:34:34,790 --> 00:34:35,630
- Violet.
- No.

680
00:34:39,600 --> 00:34:41,270
You Don't Walk Away From Me
This Time.

681
00:34:41,650 --> 00:34:44,290
This Time,
I Walk Away From You.

682
00:34:57,660 --> 00:35:00,630
I Think I Understand Beth
And Her Husband A Bit More...

683
00:35:01,540 --> 00:35:04,620
Wanting To Just...
Erase The Bad Stuff.

684
00:35:05,500 --> 00:35:07,680
Who Doesn't Want A Life
Without Pain?

685
00:35:08,840 --> 00:35:11,250
I'd Like To Think
That Pain...

686
00:35:13,100 --> 00:35:15,450
Is What Forces Us To Grow.

687
00:35:18,270 --> 00:35:19,900
Well, Maybe I Don't Want
To Grow.

688
00:35:21,550 --> 00:35:23,070
Maybe Growing Sucks.

689
00:35:25,360 --> 00:35:26,850
Maybe I Just...

690
00:35:28,700 --> 00:35:30,840
Oh, I'm Sorry.

691
00:35:30,840 --> 00:35:31,510
It's Okay.

692
00:35:31,520 --> 00:35:34,320
No, I Am Sorry...

693
00:35:35,710 --> 00:35:36,830
As In...

694
00:35:37,790 --> 00:35:39,400
I Am Pathetic.

695
00:35:53,530 --> 00:35:58,080
Ruby Dropped Her Crit To 26
Intraoperatively,But She's Gonna Be Okay.

696
00:35:58,790 --> 00:35:59,510
Maya...

697
00:36:00,640 --> 00:36:03,320
<I>Don't Ever Lie To Me Again.</I>

698
00:36:03,560 --> 00:36:05,000
I Didn't Know
What Else To Do,

699
00:36:05,680 --> 00:36:07,430
How To Get Her
To Come See You.

700
00:36:07,620 --> 00:36:08,470
She Wouldn't.

701
00:36:11,190 --> 00:36:11,880
Mom...

702
00:36:13,100 --> 00:36:13,990
I'm Not...

703
00:36:16,210 --> 00:36:18,240
Doing What Ruby's Doing.

704
00:36:18,410 --> 00:36:19,330
I Swear.

705
00:36:20,510 --> 00:36:21,580
I'm Still...

706
00:36:25,630 --> 00:36:26,560
I'm A Kid.

707
00:36:27,150 --> 00:36:28,330
Go Wait In The Car.

708
00:36:28,340 --> 00:36:29,700
- Mommy, I'm--
- The Car.

709
00:36:40,000 --> 00:36:40,830
How Could You?

710
00:36:42,060 --> 00:36:43,170
She's My Child.

711
00:36:43,320 --> 00:36:45,620
She Came To Me, Nai.

712
00:36:45,790 --> 00:36:48,540
Maya Came To Me.
I Couldn't Betray That.

713
00:36:48,710 --> 00:36:51,550
You Could Betray That.
You Just Chose Not To.

714
00:36:51,720 --> 00:36:53,420
Naomi, You're A Doctor.
You Know That's Not True.

715
00:36:53,590 --> 00:36:56,360
I Am Not A Doctor Right Now.
I Am A Parent.

716
00:36:56,770 --> 00:36:59,670
And She's A Little Girl.
And I Have A Right To Know.

717
00:36:59,830 --> 00:37:02,050
And You're Supposed To Be
My Friend.

718
00:37:05,490 --> 00:37:09,380
I...
Am Going To Walk Away Now

719
00:37:10,070 --> 00:37:12,560
Because I Need To Go Find
Ruby's Parents

720
00:37:12,720 --> 00:37:16,200
And Tell Them That Their
13-year-old Daughter Was Pregnant

721
00:37:16,240 --> 00:37:20,110
And Is Still Suffering From
An Advanced Case Of Gonorrhea.

722
00:37:25,780 --> 00:37:26,310
Nai...

723
00:37:28,090 --> 00:37:29,500
Nai, I Know You're Mad At Me,

724
00:37:29,680 --> 00:37:31,550
But As Your Friend,
I'm Telling You,

725
00:37:31,990 --> 00:37:35,560
Spend Some Time Talking
To Maya About Sex...

726
00:37:37,570 --> 00:37:40,390
So She Can A Stay
A Little Girl A While Longer.

727
00:37:53,090 --> 00:37:55,880
I Thought She Was Still
Into That Stupid, Uh,

728
00:37:56,050 --> 00:37:58,480
Little Mini-bake Oven Thing.

729
00:37:58,640 --> 00:38:01,680
Me, Too. Well, No, Not
The Mini-bake Oven,But, You Know...

730
00:38:01,860 --> 00:38:02,560
Well, You Had The Talk
With Her.

731
00:38:02,720 --> 00:38:05,220
What--what Happened When You--
When You Had The Talk?

732
00:38:05,860 --> 00:38:06,640
The Talk?

733
00:38:07,760 --> 00:38:09,280
You Didn't Have The Talk
With Her?

734
00:38:09,460 --> 00:38:11,730
What? It's--it's A Lot Harder
Than It Looks To Bring It Up, Sam.

735
00:38:11,900 --> 00:38:13,740
I Don't See You Having
The Talk With Her.
Me?

736
00:38:13,900 --> 00:38:15,140
I Don't--i Don't--
You--

737
00:38:15,560 --> 00:38:17,210
You Have The Right Parts.

738
00:38:17,380 --> 00:38:18,860
The--the Right Parts?
Yes.

739
00:38:19,030 --> 00:38:22,880
No, Y-you Have The Right Parts When It Comes 
To Explaining What Boys Want.

740
00:38:25,360 --> 00:38:27,630
Oh, God.
Oh, No.

741
00:38:28,400 --> 00:38:30,460
I Thought We Were
So Good At This,

742
00:38:31,380 --> 00:38:32,260
The Divorce...

743
00:38:32,440 --> 00:38:34,500
Yeah, We Were
Supposed To Be The Model

744
00:38:34,740 --> 00:38:36,520
For Screwed-up Parents,
Right?

745
00:38:38,320 --> 00:38:40,060
Maybe We Need To...

746
00:38:41,900 --> 00:38:43,510
Let It Hurt A Little More.

747
00:38:44,950 --> 00:38:49,760
Stop Tryingto Make It Look Like
We Got It All Together.

748
00:38:50,960 --> 00:38:52,220
Yeah, We Gotta Do Better.

749
00:38:54,420 --> 00:38:58,120
- Or We Could Buy A Chastity Belt.
- Yeah.Let's Get A Chastity Belt.

750
00:38:58,300 --> 00:38:59,900
Let's Get The Chastity Belt.
Yeah.

751
00:39:15,980 --> 00:39:17,420
Why Didn't You Check On Me?

752
00:39:36,130 --> 00:39:38,840
Hey, I Just Wanted To Thank You.
Awesome Week Of Gynergy.

753
00:39:38,850 --> 00:39:43,080
Dell, You Cannot Say "Gynergy"
If You Want To Work With Me.

754
00:39:43,500 --> 00:39:44,820
Got It. Ay.

755
00:39:48,220 --> 00:39:50,250
Hey, What Happened?

756
00:39:51,820 --> 00:39:52,560
Nothing.

757
00:39:52,970 --> 00:39:54,380
You Know, I'm Just Being Me.

758
00:39:54,900 --> 00:39:55,560
Yeah.

759
00:39:56,680 --> 00:39:57,620
Long Day.

760
00:40:00,140 --> 00:40:02,110
Listen,
About The Fantasies--

761
00:40:03,000 --> 00:40:04,120
Oh, Please. Don't.

762
00:40:04,310 --> 00:40:07,000
I Just Wanted To Say That I'm
Not Above A Fantasy Or Two...

763
00:40:08,810 --> 00:40:09,610
About You.

764
00:40:15,880 --> 00:40:16,880
Ouch.

765
00:40:22,500 --> 00:40:24,010
Come Here. Let Me See.

766
00:40:24,200 --> 00:40:25,680
Don't Be Scared.

767
00:40:26,050 --> 00:40:28,790
- I'm A Board Certified--
- Neonatal Surgeon.

768
00:40:28,790 --> 00:40:30,500
And That Helps Me How?

769
00:40:44,760 --> 00:40:46,420
you hit some one?

770
00:40:47,300 --> 00:40:51,160
***

771
00:40:51,400 --> 00:40:52,770
but this guy...he was a...

772
00:40:52,820 --> 00:40:55,840
- he deserves that...
- yeah it's not that,it's just...

773
00:40:56,700 --> 00:41:04,410
you hit some one with you fist like a cow boy,like...

774
00:41:05,390 --> 00:41:06,900
***

775
00:41:07,730 --> 00:41:11,740
yeah,yeah like a ***

776
00:41:19,940 --> 00:41:21,040
we were not...

777
00:41:21,300 --> 00:41:22,900
i am leaving, i'm hitting out

778
00:41:23,070 --> 00:41:24,130
what just happened?

779
00:41:24,440 --> 00:41:28,620
pete the cow bow,***,thank you for that.it'll helped

780
00:41:28,790 --> 00:41:29,580
helped for what?

781
00:41:30,270 --> 00:41:32,520
just this ***

782
00:41:37,480 --> 00:41:40,050
okay,she did not have to tell me that

783
00:41:51,660 --> 00:41:52,630
cow boy

784
00:41:55,080 --> 00:41:56,400
***

785
00:41:58,640 --> 00:42:00,450
it's great to each.
