Shaun?
Oh, hello, Dr. Glassman.
If you're here to
talk about our argument...
I am, kind of, in a way.
Working under Salen
was making me into a bad doctor,
so I quit.
I'm creating a spreadsheet
of residency programs.
I have 12 metrics.
Well, Shaun, that's a problem,
because there aren't
a lot of programs around
that are gonna take a
resident at your level.
And also...
You're somewhat vulnerable
because of the ASD.
I've already quit.
We got a plan, Shaunie.
We are talking to
an investigative reporter
for a story on the damage that
Salen has done to St. Bon's.
It'll put pressure on the Pension Fund
that's financing the hospital takeover.
The deal doesn't close for eight days.
We still have time to stop it.
We think you should apologize to Salen
and ask for your job back.
Apologize. Save your career.
She will not say yes.
Oh, she will say yes.
You're on the poster.
What's she gonna do,
drag you out of the hospital
kicking and screaming?
It'd be a PR disaster.
I have nothing to apologize for.
She does.
We agree, but if we pull this off,
it is only for eight days.
But what if you don't?
If we don't, then we rethink.
I will focus on the medicine.
We've got a morale problem
at the hospital.
Maybe it's just aftershocks from
what happened with the baby,
but I'm hearing a lot of complaints.
Even the board's unhappy.
Which is why I plan to replace
them as soon as the deal closes.
Well, good doctors are a lot harder
to replace than board members.
Any employees we lose, we'll find
others better aligned with Ethicure.
We've got a lot of great people at St.
Bon's,
and I'd like to make
an effort to keep them.
How's your morale?
I'm fine.
I know yesterday was tough,
the tracheal transplant.
I hope you aren't doubting yourself.
Shaun warned me. I didn't listen.
You took a risk,
and your patient is better off for that.
And now you and I are gonna make this
the most successful hospital
in the Bay Area.
No headaches, dizziness?
No. I feel fine now.
Blurry vision?
Dr. Murphy, why are you here?
I'm focusing on the medicine.
I don't have any patients of my own.
Probably because you quit yesterday.
Have you spoken to Salen?
This says you lost
consciousness while running
and hit your head.
Uh, yep.
And no. No blurry vision.
You recently flew in from London.
Perhaps your fatigue or dehydration...
It was three days post-flight,
and the liver function tests
are only slightly elevated
despite receiving a donor
liver six months back.
It doesn't seem transplant-related.
Well, it was a very high-quality liver.
From an even higher-quality person.
You're the donor?
Ry's been my best friend
since kindergarten.
I was about to die,
with my wife seven months pregnant.
He immediately stepped up. Total hero.
Definitely is.
We'll schedule a head CT
to look for damage from your fall,
as well as any reason why you fainted.
Great. I'm sure it'll be fine. Yeah.
If not, good news.
You get your liver back.
That's not how it works.
What are you doing here?
I work here.
That's not what I took away
from our conversation last night.
Last night, I wanted to quit.
Today, I don't.
You need to leave.
Now.
No.
It's not a suggestion. Goodbye.
I am on the poster.
You will not drag me out of the
hospital kicking and screaming.
It would be a PR disaster.
So I'm staying.
I have to go to work.
Synced & corrected by -robtor-
www.addic7ed.com
When did the bleeding start?
About an hour ago.
Any dizziness or nausea?
None. I told her that some
spotting was normal.
This is my last viable embryo.
I've had more miscarriages
than I can count.
I've done this five times already.
The baby is... Is fine.
You all have five kids at home?
You are experts.
No, we're not a couple.
I actually don't have
any children of my own.
Grace is my surrogate.
Is it typical for surrogates and
their clients to hang out together?
She has become more like family now.
That's a healthy heartbeat.
S-Something is wrong.
MRI abdomen and transvaginal ultrasound.
No intracranial bleed, no tumor.
I assume you know some of us
are going public against Ethicure.
Dr. Glassman and Lea told me,
but they think I should stay out of it.
What do you want to do?
Is it possible
to be sure what the right thing is,
but it's also wrong to act on it?
All too often.
And whatever happens,
I know you're on our side.
Scan seems to be clear.
Then why is he having a seizure?
Grace's scans look normal.
No placenta accreta or previa.
I love what she's doing,
carrying a child for a woman who can't.
I'd love it more if Grace
wasn't getting paid for it.
She created five families.
Do you really have a problem with that?
It's not just me.
Commercial surrogacy is illegal
pretty much everywhere but here.
It's exploitative.
Funny how everyone gets real concerned
about exploitation
when it's women's bodies.
Meanwhile, football players give
themselves brain damage every Sunday,
and it's glorified.
Point taken.
You know, it's not too late
to change your mind
about this Salen stuff.
You should join us.
Speaking of men telling
women what to do...
Look at this.
I've had to send children
to community transition care units
because of how she's
minimized pediatric beds.
That's his testimony?
It's the start of his testimony.
The plan being to bore
them into submission?
My plan is to let them know
exactly what she's done
and how it's impacted
the greater community.
Oh, it's the pizza guy.
Infant fatality. That's our plan.
- Let's stick to that.
- We can't prove that.
But what we do have
are doctors and nurses
and stories of systemic neglect.
It's not the pizza guy.
Don't worry. I tipped him.
I love your place.
Smart play.
That's what I'd do.
Yeah? What play is that?
Getting that investigative reporter
to write a takedown piece about me
and using that
to pressure the Pension Fund.
Dr. Wolke, Dr. Park,
it's time for you two
residents to get back to work.
- I'm not leaving.
- Me neither.
Gutsy, coming from a second-year
who already killed a patient.
And you really ought to take
lessons from your girlfriend.
She knows how to play the game.
Audrey, Lea, Aaron, I'm sorry,
but I have to terminate
your employment immediately.
You were saying?
Go.
That your plan?
Make us look like disgruntled
former employees?
You think that's gonna stop us
from going public?
No, of course not.
But... I think this research will.
Despite your generous salary,
you were a no-show for months,
making wine in your garage,
vacationing in Montana.
All after years of intervening
to excuse your protege
Dr. Murphy's erratic behavior.
You hired your boyfriend,
then fired him
once the relationship soured.
Classic sexual harassment.
That's not... H-He quit.
You secretly changed hospital metrics
to help your fiance.
Right now, you've only lost your jobs.
Go public,
and I release all this.
Cheat day.
J.L., Hawks, and Colson are out.
The reporter?
She'll still talk to us.
It's still a good story.
Just much shorter than planned.
Was she right? Are we wasting our time?
Probably.
The Pension Fund's annual
meeting is in two days, right?
Yeah.
We meet the reporter there.
Big public setting.
Denounce Salen
in front of the investors.
Create a viral moment.
That might do some damage.
She could ruin me in tech.
I'm in.
You're threatening to ruin their
careers? These are good doctors.
Who've decided to try to
interfere with my company.
You can't expect me to just accept that.
I've backed you at every step
because I believe a great
hospital could be profitable, too.
But blackmail is unacceptable.
Think big picture.
We just lost the president
of the hospital.
You're running this place.
Short-term.
The future is wide open.
For both of us.
Where's Dr. Lim?
She's no longer available.
But I'm the Chief of Surgery
and will be personally
involved in your case.
Unfortunately,
your imaging is consistent
with a bladder sarcoma
abutting your uterus.
Cancer?
But we did surrogacy testing.
It's small right now, but it will
continue to grow as the fetus does.
Oh, God.
And what can we do?
The safest option
is to terminate the pregnancy,
resect the tumor,
and begin chemotherapy.
Are there any other options?
There are a number
of chemotherapy protocols
that are safe for
second trimester fetuses.
But they'll all be far less effective
against the cancer than surgery.
I want to do the chemo.
Grace...
Are you sure?
Yes.
- So...
- I heard.
You're lucky to still have a job.
Well, I'm not sure if it's luck or you.
Salen suggested I learn
to play the game like you do.
She's right.
I didn't realize
being a doctor was a game.
Why are you obsessing about this?
We have a meeting.
I'm sure all of you have feelings
about what happened with our colleagues.
Shaun, if you want to talk...
Ryan has encephalitis.
Lea is okay.
I'm focusing on the medicine.
You said his head CT was clean.
Our scan was interrupted by his seizure.
I went back and reviewed the images.
There appears to be hypodensity
in the bilateral medial temporal lobes.
Interesting. Suggests HSV.
That's just artifact from skull base.
It's not encephalitis.
Clean CT plus clean blood test
suggests a cardiac problem.
I'm with Dr. Park.
Place Ryan on telemetry and...
You should trust me.
I told you not to
do that surgery yesterday.
I was right then, and I am right now.
No reason not to rule out
encephalitis, as well.
Start him on acyclovir in
addition to the cardiac monitor.
We could try Ifosfamide.
Lim and the others are speaking out
at the annual Pension Fund
meeting the day after tomorrow.
Please help me find
a chemo regimen for Grace.
Okay, Ifosfamide
can cause pre-term labor.
I'm gonna go with Adriamycin.
I'm gonna speak out with them.
That's gonna blow up your whole career.
Blow up your whole life.
Wouldn't be the first time.
Come with us. You're great at sales.
Help us persuade the Pension Fund.
Sometimes you got to stand up
for what's right.
What I do or do not stand up for
is my choice,
and my friends should respect that.
What have you come up with?
There are a few options...
Grace is crashing.
I'm going to test you for encephalitis
and place you on telemetry
to check for heart problems.
Okay.
Is your neck bothering you?
Y-Yeah. It just started
feeling a little weird.
Okay, can you take your gown
off your shoulders, please?
W-What is that?
Not encephalitis or a heart problem.
You had a uterine vessel rupture.
We were able to treat it,
but your cancer's progressing
quicker than we thought.
Our recommendation is to terminate.
We'll remove the tumor
and reconstruct your bladder.
But you said
there was a chemotherapy
that was safe for the baby.
The rupture made
everything more serious.
You need surgery now,
or the cancer might kill you.
If you don't want to terminate,
there is an experimental
cystoscopic surgery.
It should be able to clear
almost all of the cancer.
W-What...
What are the risks to the baby?
30% chance of miscarriage.
Gracie.
It's okay.
You should terminate.
You should do the surgery
that gets rid of all of the cancer.
I'd like to do the chemo.
You realize you probably won't survive.
As long as the baby reaches viability.
Gracie, honey, you don't
have to do this for me.
I'm not.
I went through
some of your recent cases.
W-Why?
Because of what Salen said.
You know she likes me.
What's the problem with her liking me?
Because of your paranoid reaction.
I reacted because it seemed like
you were reading something
into her comment.
Like you didn't trust me.
And now you're going through my files?
Apparently, I'm not paranoid.
Nira Joseph.
I didn't realize "playing the game"
is shorthand for losing
your entire moral compass.
Nira is half-blind because of you.
She had a tumor...
There is no mention in her file
of the procedure that
could have saved her sight.
A procedure you thought
wasn't a viable idea.
I didn't tell you to hide it.
You can't offer every patient
every experimental surgery...
Ah, especially not when "we're"
trying to win control of the clinic.
It was the right choice medically.
It was her choice.
Ryan's rash plus seizure and fainting
suggests an autoimmune disorder.
Makes sense. His ESR's elevated.
ESR's a nonspecific inflammatory marker.
Wouldn't matter
if it was through the roof.
Dr. Park,
are you taking offense at the diagnosis?
Salen fired our friends.
I didn't know about that in advance,
didn't support it.
And do you support it now?
It doesn't matter what he supports.
He's not the CEO.
No, he's just her bagman.
Salen came into this hospital
because it was going bankrupt.
And now it's become Salen's ATM machine.
That's an improvement?
You have been against her
from the moment she came in.
Just proven right.
You're not facing reality.
The takeover's happening.
Someone's got to keep
the hospital running.
You think you're being realistic?
You're being complicit.
We should start Ryan on
corticosteroids for the autoimmune...
Don't you see how being her
apologists is corrupting you?
Dr. Park...
You took a woman's vision away
to get your hands on the clinic.
Not fair.
And you stand by her
after she kills a child.
Dr. Park, do you have
an alternative diagnosis?
No.
Start Ryan on corticosteroids.
I'm done.
I'll finish up with my patients
and then submit my resignation.
If I get a job downtown,
this would be a good place
to meet for lunch.
They have great French pancakes.
Kind of eggy, but...
I should join you.
Lea, I'm the poster boy.
It made Salen take me back.
It could make the difference.
It'll make a difference, sure, but...
That's good enough.
You are so close to
finishing your residency.
One more year,
and you can go wherever you want.
Dr. Glassman,
Park,
Lim, they've stood up
for me so many times.
You've stood up for me so many times.
Now I want to stand up for all of you.
Okay.
Okay, can you make fun of my
beard or my eye bags or anything?
I hate this.
How many times did I say
I didn't want to get involved
in the Salen stuff?
But you still kept pushing.
I wanted you on my side.
You act like I'm scared of a fight.
I'm a Black woman
in one of the
top surgical residencies in the country.
Do you know how hard
I had to fight to be here?
I don't have the same luxury as you do.
I'm not scared.
I'm exhausted.
I never thought of it that way.
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
And I think I know
who Grace is fighting for.
She said she didn't have
any children of her own.
But you had to have given birth
before you became a surrogate.
We know what happened to Willem.
It wasn't your fault.
What kind of a mother loses
track of her baby at a playground?
A 19-year-old.
Who's overwhelmed.
I wasn't overwhelmed.
I wasn't paying attention.
I was arguing on the phone
with my boyfriend.
And I turned... I turned my back.
The crash was so loud.
So now,
I give babies to people
who actually deserve them.
Killing yourself
won't bring Willem back.
It'll let another baby live.
You have value,
not just in the children you carry.
I lost myself when Willem died.
This is what brought me back.
It is the only thing
that means anything to me.
You're being selfish.
This isn't just about you.
It's also about Amanda,
your friend, who loves you.
I'm trying to help her...
No. You're not listening to her.
She does not want the price
of her child to be your life.
You don't have to terminate.
Just let us do the cystoscopic surgery.
It could let Amanda have her baby...
...and you in her life.
Minute, please.
I'm sorry. That was unnecessary.
I'm sorry this is how it ended.
We're not done yet.
She'll destroy you.
Only if you let her.
You think I control Salen,
because we're dating?
That's insane and a little sexist.
Forget control.
How about taking a stand?
That's what I've been doing
and will continue to do from the inside.
You could've worked with me
to make things right.
Instead, you had to
burn the building down.
She lit the match.
You know that.
I feel a little sick.
Could this be 'cause of
the, um, autoimmune thing?
That's unlikely.
Oh. Your eyes are jaundiced.
Which means it is your liver.
I will need you to do a full-body PET,
CT scan.
Okay.
And you, as well.
Okay, Nira, we're all done.
I'm glad I had you
come in for a check-up.
Your vision's actually improved a bit.
You have 53%
of your left peripheral field.
That's great.
How are you, uh, doing these days?
I can't drive. I lose things.
I had to go part-time at the company.
It completely changed my life.
I'm so sorry.
No, the thing is, it needed changing.
I was working seven days a week.
My partner and I were about to separate.
I was watching my son grow up
through videos sent to me at the office.
Now...
I walk my kid to school.
My relationship is in a great place.
I'm happier than I've been in years.
It reminded me what was important.
You have liver cancer.
Your symptoms were from
a paraneoplastic syndrome.
The tumor put your
immune system in overdrive.
It started attacking unrelated organs.
D-Did I give him cancer?
Yes. There was probably a microscopic
lesion in the lobe you donated.
But it was to your benefit.
Your scans are clean.
So what's next?
Surgery?
It's metastasized.
We can resect the largest tumor
and chemo-embolize some others.
That'll give you
a few additional months.
Months?
I'm sorry.
Salen's gonna fire you and
then come after you publicly.
I don't care.
Well, you should care, Shaun.
Think about what she's gonna use.
Your outbursts in the hospital,
your low scores,
the complaint the nurse
made against you...
I am a good surgeon.
I don't believe I'll never work again.
You're an excellent surgeon,
Shaun. That's the point.
You can't risk that.
But you can?
Lea can? Dr. Lim can?
Yes, yes, yes.
We can. You're exceptional.
What you've accomplished is remarkable.
We can't risk that.
This is my decision.
I'm an adult, Dr. Glassman.
What are you gonna do
if you're not a surgeon?
That's always been
what's most important.
It's not what's most important to me.
Not anymore.
If I lose you from the hospital,
if I lose Dr. Lim and Dr. Park and Lea,
I don't want to work there anymore.
Okay.
Let's write that speech
to the Pension Fund.
I will do that alone.
Your speech at my
engagement party was terrible.
Cutting loop.
Debulking
further tumor from the bladder wall.
I see the deeper tumor fragment.
We've got significant bleeding.
Increasing irrigation.
BP's dropping, and baby's
in fetal distress, too.
Try bipolar cautery
on the tumor surface.
It's not working.
If we can't control this,
we're going to lose them both.
Got to open her up.
Heart and lungs sound good.
We're cleared for surgery.
Do you have any questions?
If it gives me a couple
more months, I'm all in.
Dom, this'll go great.
And then Alexa and
the baby arrive tomorrow.
We're gonna have an awesome
few days before I head back home.
Wait, I'm...
I'm so sorry, Ry.
You stood up for me
when I was being bullied.
You took me in when my marriage failed.
I tried to save you one time...
...and I killed you.
Dom...
You gave me eight more months.
I got to see the leaves turn
in Central Park.
I got to watch my wife give birth.
And I got to hold my baby girl.
Who you're gonna be
the world's best godfather to.
Or I'll come back and haunt you.
I promise I will.
Mom's mean arterial pressure's 50.
The tumor's stuck to the uterus.
We need to do an emergency hysterectomy.
There's still time.
She's going to bleed out.
We have to take her uterus.
S-Subserosal fibroids are adherent, too.
What if we treat the tumor like that?
Get deep to the tumor plane,
stop the bleeding at its source.
Good for mom, not for baby.
We could close the uterine wall
with three layered 3-0 sutures.
That could keep the baby safe.
Yeah.
Good thinking, both of you.
Let's get it done. Myomectomy scissors.
I'm gonna go public
about Nira's treatment
and the role Salen played in it.
It should make a big impression
on the Pension Fund's directors.
That could have real
repercussions for your career.
I have to make this right.
I'm not sure you can.
But it's a step in the right direction.
Speakers list for the Pension
Fund's annual meeting.
Glassman, Lim, that's hardly a surprise.
Murphy? Wolke? Park and Reznick.
Surgery go okay?
Those doctors speaking out
at the Pension Meeting,
I think they're right.
We should go meet with them right now.
I'm not hiring them back.
At least hear them out,
their concerns, their suggestions.
Let's come up with some compromises,
get them to agree
to not be at the meeting.
Marcus, you're being incredibly naive.
You may lose.
It's possible.
You'll lose more than this hospital.
I need to go get ready for tonight.
Your beard matches your eye bags.
I'm sorry.
What is this?
Oppo research.
Oh, Marcus...
What do you think you have here?
I wrote off a trip to Cabo,
had an affair with a state senator...
Oppo research on me.
I've made mistakes, personally,
professionally. They're all there.
If you're gonna
go through with this deal,
you're gonna have to destroy me.
Walk away.
You have every reason
to not want this deal.
The Board will not fight you.
I'm sorry.
Me too.
Well...
Good luck.
'Cause now this is all your problem.
I'm gonna sleep at my place tonight.
Okay.
You sent this to Nira?
Mm-hmm.
This is an admission of misconduct.
Well, you know me.
Go big or go home.
I hope you didn't do all this for me.
No.
I did this because of
who I am when I'm with you.
www.tvsubtitles.net