When I was 18, I wanted a tattoo
of a panda right
here, on my arm,
but, uh, my girlfriend at the
time talked me into a heart.
Stop moving. Yeah.
I don't know why I thought
a panda would be so cool.
Well, this tattoo will guide
the external beam radiation
to within less than a
millimeter of your tumor,
so, also cool.
Yeah, but three dots?
Three dots is so lame.
Why couldn't you give me,
like, a badass teardrop or a tiger?
I get that you're nervous.
Hmm.
When will you tell the staff?
I was kind of hoping
they wouldn't notice.
Four days in you're gonna
start vomiting constantly.
After two weeks, you'll be fed
through a tube in your stomach.
You won't be able to
swallow. There'll be hair loss.
Weight loss.
What I'm saying is, I
think they're gonna notice.
They're gonna notice, yeah.
I'll tell them.
Somehow.
Okay.
Hold. Don't move.
Imagine it's a panda.
So in the middle of stitching up
her arm, she asks for a mai tai.
I was like, "Lady,
"does this look like
a tiki bar to you?"
Hey, thanks, guys.
I would never have made it
from the Bronx without you.
Next time, drinks
are on me, okay?
Stealing snacks again?
No name, fair game.
Moonlighting before a double?
So? Like you don't.
Yeah, but I'm not
the department chair.
Later. All right.
Lauren?
Hey, do you know what
kind of Scotch Floyd drinks?
What? You guys are buds.
Yeah, it's just weird hearing
him being called Floyd.
Oh, yeah, right.
It's way more normal to call
somebody by their last name.
So, Scotch?
Uh, if he's paying,
whatever's in the well,
and if someone else is
paying, then top shelf.
Why? It's his birthday.
Oh, man. Well, good
luck. Wait, why good luck?
Well, it just sucks to start dating a
guy and then have it be his birthday.
Does it? Yeah.
If he's one of those guys
who loves his birthday.
I love my birthday.
Not like he does.
It's impossible.
So you're thinking I should get
something better than Scotch?
Yep. Good luck.
Thank you.
This is too much.
I don't even know how to...
Oh!
You got me a FloTech
Cell Sorter for my birthday?
No. Man, you shouldn't have.
I didn't. And yet, here it is.
I guess HCC decided to
upgrade our old cell sorter,
which, no surprise,
didn't need upgrading. Oh.
Maybe your girlfriend
pulled some strings?
I don't know. This machine
costs 100,000 bucks.
Which could have
been better spent
almost anywhere
else in the hospital.
Yes. Bureaucracy. Bureaucracy.
Here, help me get it to the OR
before someone else nabs it.
You're keeping it?
Well, possession's
9/10 of the law.
It's not, actually.
Well, then I'm invoking
the "finders, keepers" rule.
Just help me move it. Come on.
How do you... Do you know
how to... Do you know how to do...
It's broken.
Yeah, well...
Bureaucracy.
Oh, oh.
Keep walking.
I am still very angry.
Down three with seven seconds left
and Hardaway's sitting on a bench?
And then they
don't call a time-out.
He's our only
three-point shooter.
Well, to love the
Knicks is to suffer.
Would you like to
watch the game tonight
together?
I can't.
Okay.
I'm getting my one-year chip.
Chip? For being clean.
I see.
It's at the downtown Y.
You could come if you'd like.
That would be...
Strange to get a reward.
I mean, it's kind of a big deal.
I would think that the
real reward would be
not being an addict.
Okay.
So I guess you're not
coming. I have a better idea.
Uh...
Knicks game? Next week?
Yeah.
Patient.
So I'll see you next week?
Uh, Max.
Can I just get your
thoughts on a patient?
Yeah. Locally advanced
pancreatic cancer.
Amenable to surgery? Yes,
he's prepped and ready to go.
Great, then go for the
cure. There's a catch.
Cardiology work-up found a
left-ventricular ejection fraction of 35%.
That is a catch. 90%
chance he'll die on the table.
But a 10% chance he won't.
Technically. But those are terrible odds.
That's for him to decide.
I can't suggest he go
through with the surgery, can I?
Why not?
Because that's like me saying to
you, "Hey, let's scrap chemo and wing it
"with precision-targeted
therapy."
Well, some of those
trials show a lot of promise.
And some show it
makes the disease worse.
But we're not talking about you.
Right, but we have to give
your patient both options, right?
"We"?
A man named Daniel was
captured by Roman soldiers.
The general told
Daniel he could make...
Nurse, can you give us a
minute? Thank you, he's all yours.
The story was just getting good.
Rabbi Skillman, I'd like to introduce
you to our medical director, Max Goodwin.
Goodwin. Is that Jewish?
I believe my
great-great-grandmother was,
but I was raised nothing.
Then you're Jewish.
I'll take it.
So, Dr. Sharpe.
Do you have good news
for me this morning?
Lot of whispering going on.
I wish I did.
Okay.
It's what you
feared? His heart...
Work-up shows that it's
not pumping blood very well.
Hmm. The cherry
on the cancer cake.
There's a 90% chance
of dying in surgery.
Or a 10% chance of a cure.
Not great odds.
The other option is no surgery.
You can go home.
Spend a year of good-quality
life with the people you love.
We'll make sure that
you're comfortable.
Like any good conundrum,
I believe I'll need some
time to think about this.
Yeah, of course.
And if you have any
questions, I'm here.
Take all the time you need.
We just want to make sure
you really consider both options.
Okay. Hmm.
Amy.
I see your migraines
haven't improved.
And, uh...
Your triptans did not help.
No.
We can run a second MRI,
but I'm afraid we've exhausted
all the traditional treatments.
Is there anything else...
Find a better treatment.
Yes, Mrs. Chiang.
I'm starting to think that
stress could be a factor.
And we might think about
counseling as an alternative treatment.
I speak many
languages, Mrs. Chiang,
but Mandarin is not one of them.
My mom is just saying... My
daughter is here for migraines.
I have a colleague,
Dr. Iggy Frome...
And, uh... Ah.
He's a wonderful psychiatrist.
Okay.
"Dr. Ignatius Frome.
Chair of Behavioral Health."
Mom. It's just to talk.
One appointment can't hurt.
Okay, but what if
Dr. Frome could help?
We don't talk to strangers
about our problems.
What do we got?
"Failure to fly." Bowery
stop, attempted suicide.
Escort her out of here. Would
you give me the rundown?
Amy Chiang, 21.
Got lucky, landed on the track
bed so the train went right over her.
Left her with lacerations,
possible patellar fracture.
Amy, look at me. Can
you move your leg?
Got her chart.
Get ortho and prep
for surgery. Now.
You're not gonna believe this,
but she was here this morning.
Why? Seeing Dr. Kapoor.
First-generation
Chinese-American.
First to go to
college in her family.
Scholarship. Works full-time
at the family restaurant.
Grades started to slip. She
came in complaining of migraines.
Medication didn't work, at which
point Kapoor suggested stress
as a possible trigger, and
then referred her to me.
The next thing you
know... Only 21.
Possible undiagnosed
severe depression.
We saw this at the Chinatown
clinic. Called it "the F train disease."
Never heard of it.
Well, the F train runs
through Chinatown,
and a lot of women
would use it as a last resort.
Depression can be
hard to accept in some
Asian communities.
In many communities.
Yeah, well, stigma or
no, if we don't help Amy,
she will probably try
to kill herself again.
I've never seen
anything so beautiful.
What does it even do?
Oh, nothing. You know, just
separates the white blood cells
from the red blood cells
with the flick of a switch.
Best birthday present ever.
You really are a birthday dork.
My mom worked two
jobs seven days a week,
but every year on my birthday
she took the whole day off
and took me to the bookstore,
where she bought me as
many books as I could carry.
Correction. You are just a dork.
No way.
It's the wrong connector.
It's not compatible with
any of the machines.
Call an electrician.
No, we'd have to
upgrade the whole OR.
This is just $100,000
worth of useless junk.
Quality genes. I
bet he's smart, too.
You don't get abs like that
without crushing the SATs.
When I want input on
my choice of sperm donor,
I'll let you know. Right.
Has the rabbi decided
on the surgery yet?
I usually give my
patients a little more time,
you know, when it comes
to life-and-death decisions.
Well, you know, in poker they say,
"You think long, you think wrong."
Well, that's interesting,
because in oncology we say,
"Do the opposite
of poker players."
Well, let's see what
the patient has to say.
No. Max!
I think you're getting
too invested in this.
Really? Isn't this the same amount
of "too invested" I always get?
I take it, if you were the
rabbi, you would take the year.
I have my reasons. Well,
I respect those reasons,
except they're ridiculous
because a year is nothing.
A year is everything if it's
with someone that you love.
There's a year, and then
there's a year with cancer.
Believe me, most people
would take the surgery.
Max. Signatures. Dora,
my dear, how are you?
Uh, good, thanks.
Actually you're not. I'm not?
You have terminal cancer. What?
Uh, you're settling a debate
between Sharpe and me.
Oh, do I have to?
Choice one: get a surgery
that would cure you.
Right? Or choice two: go
home, do nothing, and die.
- Definitely the surgery.
- No, hang on.
Max is trying to sway the
jury. Here's the real situation.
Option one: have
a surgery so risky
you're more likely to
survive a plane crash,
or go home and have a
good year with your family
living in peace and comfort.
Definitely the year.
Can I be done now?
No. Yes.
It's okay. Just go. See?
It's all in the presentation.
He's doing the surgery.
It's a no-brainer.
I'm not doing the surgery.
The risk is too great, I...
I was prepared, but now...
90% death rate?
I'm a Jets fan.
Historically, luck has
not been in my favor.
Hey, hey, hey.
This is the path
God chose for me.
We're gonna have a good year.
You could take more
time to decide, if you want.
You can go home and talk it
over with the rest of your family,
your congregation...
I'm at peace with my decision.
I accept my circumstances
for the way they are,
not the way I want them to be.
We both do.
I want the year.
And New Amsterdam will be here
to support you every step of the way.
Thank you, Dr. Sharpe.
Now let's talk about
what comes next.
We're going to connect
you with staff members
who will discuss home
care and medication.
Rebecca's going to
be incredibly important.
And the focus of
this year is you.
Your comfort.
Mrs. Chiang. How is she?
Amy is stable. When
can I take her home?
Hi, I'm Dr. Frome. Dr. Kapoor
gave you my card earlier.
I just wanted to say I'm very, very
sorry about what happened today.
When your daughter
gets out of surgery,
we would like to discuss
inpatient psychiatric care with you.
She's not crazy.
She's a good girl.
No, no, we know
that. We know she is.
She just needs help.
We're going to go now.
Okay. We want what's
best for your daughter,
and I'm sure you do too.
But you're not the patient here.
Amy is.
Mrs. Chiang,
your daughter jumped
in front of a subway train.
She didn't jump.
I beg your pardon?
She didn't jump. She slipped.
Come here, baby. Come here.
Studies found that docs
working shifts of 30 hours or more
end up making 36% more mistakes.
I'm fine. I'm a
polyphasic sleeper.
That's not a real thing.
Me and Thomas Edison.
We thrive off of short naps.
Define "thrive."
You gave the subway jumper
20 milligrams of morphine?
Is she dead?
No, 2, 2 milligrams.
It's a typo.
I didn't submit it.
I was gonna proof it.
36%. Shut up.
Okay.
Hey, Doc. Hey. Thought
I was gonna miss you.
Everything all right?
Yeah, um...
I need to ask you a question.
And, uh...
This isn't me,
Dr. Goodwin, asking.
This is, uh...
This is me, Max.
What is it, Max?
That decision you made...
I don't think I
could have made it.
And you seem so
at peace, I mean,
real, in your bones, at peace.
You want to know how I can be at
peace when I know I'm going to die?
Yeah.
Do you know the story
of Abraham and Isaac?
No.
Okay, so...
Abraham and Sarah
have no children.
But when they're very old,
God gives them a son, Isaac.
And then God asks Abraham
to sacrifice Isaac. Kill him.
And he'll reward him
with as many children
as there are stars in the
sky and sand in the sea.
And Abraham, being a
good and faithful man,
takes Isaac up the
mountain to sacrifice him.
And God rewards him for it.
That's choice one.
But what if Abraham said no?
What if Abraham said,
"There's lots of stars in the sky,
"but only one Isaac, who
I waited 100 years for,
"and I'd rather spend the
time I have left on this Earth
"with him and Sarah,
reward be damned"?
That's choice two.
Two impossible choices.
So I took the one that
makes me happier.
I have a confession.
Wrong religion,
but I'm listening.
I have cancer.
I'm sorry.
The chemo starts tomorrow
and, uh, what I'm learning
is that I'm not a good patient.
'Cause I'm scared.
And I'm frustrated.
And I'm angry, you know?
I don't know what to do.
Cancer changes
everything and nothing at all.
Where is my sandwich?
I need a sandwich!
I need a sandwich.
Would you mind checking
it out? Yeah, not a problem.
How are you feeling, Rodger?
His asthma seems better.
Do you know how much
longer we have to stay?
I'm sorry, what?
When can we go?
Yeah, uh, since your
husband also has hypertension,
we're going to need to
watch his pressure overnight.
I'm afraid the recital's
gonna have to wait.
Is he gonna be okay? Absolutely.
Okay, you were right.
Polyphasic sleepers are real.
Yeah, you were right too.
I'm gonna hit the on-call
room and just crash for five.
What the...
Can someone get whatever
the hell this is out of my ED?
You better be
ready to party. What?
Uh, I thought
about what you said
and I decided to throw Floyd a
surprise party right after work.
Right. Great
idea. He'll love it.
Just a few more quick
questions. Cake or pie?
Neither. Cobbler. Peach.
Does he like karaoke?
Only if he can do power ballads.
Can't wait to see that.
You can't, really?
Are balloons too much?
Nothing is too much.
Thanks, you rock.
Dr. Bloom?
I could really use your
opinion on the patient in Bay 3.
Did you have a good nap?
Hi there, Amy. I'm Dr. Frome,
I believe Dr. Kapoor spoke
to you about me earlier?
Um...
Do you mind if I sit?
Thank you.
Okay, so.
I would like to talk to you
about what happened today.
You are very lucky to be alive.
You know that, right?
Okay, tell me if any of
these feel true for you.
Can't concentrate at school.
Chronic fatigue,
but you can't sleep.
You feel like a failure,
despite your many
accomplishments.
Feel hopeless.
I thought it was stress.
That's depression.
And millions of
people suffer from it.
I have a lot of good things in my
life. I shouldn't have depression.
Yeah.
Depression doesn't
work that way.
But the good news
is it's highly treatable.
How?
Well, the first step
is to ask for help.
I like to start
with talk therapy.
What if my mom found out?
Or my dad?
They'd think I was acting weak.
I think it's a good thing to talk
to others about our problems.
I'm on my parents' insurance.
Okay.
They would know I
was going to therapy.
They'd think I was talking about
them or telling family secrets.
They'd stop talking to me.
Amy... I can't.
I'm sorry.
Okay.
Amy shouldn't have to suffer because
her community is afraid of mental illness.
It is not about fear,
it's about shame.
No, it's about stigma.
You have to understand
that they are afraid
of what others think.
Yeah, well, who cares
what others think?
Look, we all want
what's best for her, okay?
But we can't fight every
cultural stigma in one day.
Told you it was
stigma. It's shame.
We've got a patient
that we want to help,
but we can't help her because of
all these stupid insurance forms.
You're right. See?
About what?
Downcode it. Are you serious?
I had to do it for girls whose parents
wouldn't allow them birth control.
Billed it as "round
ligament pain."
We would look incompetent.
But you'll help the patient.
You want us to
defraud the hospital?
Exactly.
Max.
What the hell did
you tell the rabbi?
I have no idea what
you're talking about.
After you talked to him,
he changed his mind.
You have just talked
him into a risky surgery
that will most likely
lead to his death.
Sorry, Jane? Give
us a second, please?
You're wondering why
I changed my mind.
I am praying it is
not because of me.
What can I say? You
made a good case.
This is a high-risk surgery.
And for me to tip the scales in
any way with my own baggage
is the definition of unethical.
Tough luck. You did.
Max. Rabbi.
Max, I make my own decisions.
Yeah, I could be
home with family.
But I'd still be a patient.
That's not the life I want.
But... If I do this,
tomorrow I'll be
better or I'll be dead,
but I won't be a patient.
Not sure that clears me of
the malpractice suit, but...
Max, go. I absolve you.
Wrong religion.
Now you're being picky.
Sorry. Rabbi?
Did Abraham actually
sacrifice his own son?
No.
An angel came down
and stopped him.
But he was going to.
And it was enough
to pass God's test.
And God rewarded him
with as many children
as there are stars in the
sky and sands in the sea:
the Jewish people.
Some things are worth the risk.
Why is there a cell
sorter in the hallway?
It won't connect to the
other machines. Bureaucracy.
Tell HCC to take it back.
They won't. It's like
we're working for the army.
Well, it can't live here. I
know. Can you take it?
And do what with it?
I don't know. But
it's my birthday.
Dr. Goodwin, Sandra Fall from
billing. Yes. You left me a message?
Yeah, and you
didn't call me back.
I knew there was something
I forgot to do today.
Um, are you aware that two of
your doctors are downcoding?
Downcoding?
Yeah, it's when doctors
bill for something small
but provide more expensive care.
Why would they do that?
Because if they were upcoding,
they could make
money, but downcoding...
Yeah, exactly. So they told
me to put down CPT code 90868
for transcranial
electrical stimulation
for patient Amy Chiang,
but that doesn't require
three weekly sessions
in the psych ward,
so I will also notify...
Okay, you got me.
I told them to do it.
I just hoped they
would do it a little better.
Uh, wait, you told your doctors
to extort money from the hospital?
Well, it sounds really bad
when you say it like that,
but, uh, we're just
trying to help a patient.
Yeah, and it's my job to make
sure the hospital has enough money
to help all our patients.
When is somebody gonna
get this thing out of here?
You bring up an excellent point.
So how do you intend to
make up the lost revenue?
Would $100,000 cover it?
You can do that?
Call therapy something else?
We want to get you the help
that you need any way we can,
so we're gonna
start therapy in here,
while you're in recovery,
three times a week.
And I will navigate your school
schedule and your work schedule.
Your mother will never find out.
But it's a lie.
On paper, yes.
And what will I tell my mother
when she asks about
the brain stimulation?
Well, you can tell her
it was very stimulating.
So then I will be
lying to my mother.
And to my father. It's...
It's for your mental
health. She'll know.
And even if she
doesn't say anything,
she'll judge me.
I can teach you some
coping mechanisms.
She won't love me the same.
Is there a coping
mechanism for that?
The downcoding will work.
But it's not gonna
help, not in the long run.
The stress of having
to lie to her family
is only going to
exacerbate her depression,
her sense of isolation.
Our only option is to
work around the mother.
I think that's the problem.
I don't think we
should work around her.
I think we should bring her in.
For therapy? Yeah.
They need to do it together.
The whole reason we are here is
because the mother is
against talking to anyone.
I know, but we have
to get her on board,
or we're gonna lose Amy.
Okay. Okay.
Rodger Conway's gone into A-fib.
What?
Sorry, I can get someone else.
No, just, just give me a sec.
No, we can handle it.
I'm fine. I'm fine.
SVT. Ventricular rate of 160.
Dr. Bloom? Uh, how's the
patient? Any chest pain?
I would ask him, but
he's unresponsive.
Okay. Uh, carotid massage.
He's a set-up for
carotid stenosis.
He'll stroke out. We
need a heavy hitter.
Okay. Okay.
What do you want
us to do, Dr. Bloom?
Bloom? Dr. Bloom, we
need your instructions. Yes.
Yes?
- BP's down to 95/50.
- Dr. Bloom.
Okay. Okay.
Okay.
Atenolol, 5 milligram, IV.
You mean adenosine.
No, I said atenolol.
Atenolol.
All right. Got it. Here.
BP's down to 90/50.
Mr. Conway?
Are you with us?
Still unresponsive.
The medication will
take a minute to work.
BP's down to 86.
He's about to convert to V-tach.
Blood pressure's still dropping.
We usually shock this rhythm.
Don't. No. This med will work.
We need to shock him now.
No, just wait.
Just stop!
He's back.
Normal sinus rhythm.
The medication worked.
What just happened?
You're okay, Mr. Conway.
It's okay. You're okay.
Okay, one last quick
question, and it's kind of funny.
How old is Floyd going to be?
I don't know. He's
not my boyfriend.
We just slept together
a couple of times.
There must be a
part of you that knows
that your daughter did not slip,
that she tried to
end her life today.
I know it's hard to accept.
When a child needs
help, one may think,
"I did a bad job as a parent."
One may wonder,
"Why I didn't see
the signs sooner?"
Our children aren't perfect.
And why should they be?
We are not.
He's a good man.
Does that count for something?
In here, no. But,
everywhere else, yes.
He was always going
to do the surgery, I think.
He just needed to
explore the alternatives
to know it wasn't for him.
Do you
resent him for it?
I love him for it.
Hi.
Just came by to check on you.
How you feeling?
Mmm. Like I've
been hit by an F train.
Whoa!
Solid. Solid jokes
are a very good sign.
I'm sorry I can't go
behind my mother's back.
You know...
You are obviously
a very, very loyal,
very caring daughter.
I see that.
And you're part of a very
tight-knit, close family,
and you care what they think.
I know it sounds
silly,
but the hardest
part of every day is
just getting out of bed.
I lay there thinking about
all the things I
have to get done.
I imagine it all in my mind.
And one by one,
I fail at everything.
I don't finish my schoolwork.
I'm late for work.
I say the wrong thing at home,
and then I think maybe
I shouldn't even try.
So I lay there for a while,
all the time wishing
that I could just tell my mom
how much pressure I feel
to make her proud.
Ma!
I told your mother how
we will bill your insurance.
She said it was quite clever.
I... Yeah, I would like
to, if it's okay with you,
see the two of you together.
I want you to get better.
I'm sorry.
I need help.
We all need help.
Ma.
Surprise!
Yeah, dawg! Yeah!
Did you do all this?
It's no big deal.
Thank you.
Seriously.
How amazing are you?
Ooh!
Paging Dr. Reynolds.
You are urgently needed
in the karaoke department!
How did you know?
Honestly, Bloom told me.
I believe I said
"urgently needed"?
Yeah. Yeah, come on!
Ooh, child, things
are gonna get easier
will get brighter
Ooh, child, things
are gonna get easier
will get brighter
Someday
We'll get it together
and we'll get it all done
Someday, when your
head is much lighter
Someday
We'll walk in the
rays of a beautiful sun
Someday, when the
world is much brighter
Ooh, child, things
will get brighter
Someday, we'll get it
together and we'll get it all done
Someday, when your
head is much lighter
Someday, we'll walk in
the rays of a beautiful sun
Someday, when the
world is much brighter
Brighter
Ooh, child, things
are gonna get easier
Rabbi Skillman's
surgery is looking good.
Yeah, I got a text
from Dr. Anders.
I'm so relieved.
Rolled the dice
and came up huge.
Maybe you should do the same.
Choosing a donor.
I still miss him.
His name was Muhammad.
Internal medicine.
One of the good ones.
We were completely out
of our minds for each other.
You know what that's like?
He asked me to marry him.
We were gonna have kids.
The whole thing.
You broke up?
Brain aneurysm.
All our plans, just...
And now here I am, freezing eggs
and asking strangers for help.
I feel like I'm...
I feel like I'm betraying him,
and I don't know
if it's worth it.
It's worth it.
All right, let's do it. Turn on the
mic now. Turn on the mic now.
Don't you forget about me
Reynolds.
We should stop him before
he moves onto prog rock.
Yeah, I didn't even know
he could go that high.
I mean, that is...
And would you cancel
my chemo tomorrow?
I wanna try
precision-targeted therapy.
Clinical trials?
Mmm.
Chemo's gonna take
the life out of me, and I...
I wanna keep
running this hospital.
I want to be there for
Georgia and the baby.
Max, we had a plan.
I know, but I don't
want to be a patient.
I just want to be myself.
It's too big a risk.
It's a risk I have to take.
Ooh, child
Ooh, child Things
will get easier