♪ You in the dark ♪
♪ You in the pain ♪
♪ You on the run ♪
♪ Living a hell ♪
♪ Living your ghost ♪
♪ Living your end ♪
♪ Never seem to
get In the place ♪
♪ That I belong ♪
♪ Don't wanna lose the time ♪
♪ Lose the time to come ♪
♪ Whatever you say ♪
♪ It's all right ♪
♪ Whatever you do ♪
♪ It's all good ♪
♪ Whatever you say ♪
♪ It's all right ♪
Sweetheart, go
back to sleep, okay?
Shh, shh. ♪ You in the sea ♪
♪ On a decline ♪
Shh.
♪ Breaking the waves ♪
What happened? Did
you have a bad dream?
Huh?
Oh, man, Tess.
You're killing me.
Abby?
Abby.
Yeah?
Paramedics are bringing
in a 22-year-old woman,
pelvic pain.
Okay.
You getting up?
Yep.
You want me to wake Malucci?
Nope. I'm up.
I'm sorry.
How long was I out?
About 20 minutes.
Oh, well, that must be
why I feel so refreshed.
So is this some
med-student hazing thing
or do you guys just hate me?
You're younger than us, prettier
than us, and skinnier than us.
We hate you.
Thanks for the candor.
Anytime.
Cold out here. I should
have brought my jacket.
So go back in.
We don't need you to
help us push in a gurney.
You know,
I never actually thought
I'd even get into med school.
I was just looking for a change.
You really wanna stop talking
before one of us hits you.
Do I tell you that enough?
I love you.
Hey.
I didn't know you
played basketball.
I don't, heh.
Hello, Tess.
Did you let your mommy
sleep for a change?
No, she did not.
Did I make you angry?
The flowers on your birthday?
No. They were beautiful.
They weren't animal
crackers, huh?
You heard about that, huh?
Are you still in love with him?
I don't know. You know,
I think I'm still too angry
with him to think straight.
I would think so.
Why?
No, it wasn't like that.
Doug didn't know I was
pregnant when he left.
He didn't come back
when he found out.
Well, it wasn't all Doug.
I could've gone with him.
He asked me to.
Why didn't you?
Pride.
I wanted him to
stay here for me.
I thought I should be at
least that important to him.
I still love my wife.
But it's time to
get on with my life.
Hey, let's help your
mommy get inside, huh?
Oh, yeah, here we go.
Like a cowboy.
♪ Da-duh, da-duh, da-duh ♪
Slide your bottom
down a little bit.
God, I hate these.
How many sexual partners
have you had in the past year?
One.
Do you use condoms?
Most of the time.
Do you think I'm pregnant?
No. The urine test
came back negative.
Wow, that didn't hurt at all.
Warm water. I know a few tricks.
I thought you guys
kept these in the freezer.
I gotta remember to
tell my gynecologist.
Cultures?
GC and chlamydia?
You think I might
have chlamydia?
We check everybody for
sexually transmitted diseases.
There's a purulent
discharge around the cervix.
I've been with my
boyfriend for over a year.
If he gave me
syphilis or something,
I'm gonna kill him.
We haven't made a diagnosis yet.
Okay, speculum's coming out.
I'm gonna move your
cervix. Tell me if this hurts.
Sorry. There's no
other way to do that.
I'll try to be gentle when
I examine your ovaries.
Okay, you can
put your legs down.
Everything seems
fine. It's probably PID.
PID?
Pelvic inflammatory disease.
We'll give you a shot
of antibiotics, some pills
and I'll throw in something
for the pain, okay?
You can go ahead
and get dressed.
Two-fifty of ceftriaxone
IM, a gram of Zithromax PO,
and 550 of Anaprox. Hang
on to her for 30 minutes.
Make sure she doesn't
have an allergic reaction.
You want me to get
Malucci to sign off?
I've seen more of these
than he has. Let him sleep.
I could find Weaver.
I wouldn't go there.
Her second double this week.
Been here since
yesterday morning.
Weaver's upstairs.
They had a code in CCU.
I heard Mark's
coming back today.
Thank God. If Weaver
gets any nastier,
I'm gonna have to
call Animal Control.
Amira.
Amira!
Frank.
Where's Amira?
Got off at 7.
Who are you?
Frank. Personnel sent me down.
Do you have any
experience, Frank?
Twenty-six years
as a Chicago cop.
In medicine?
Had my knee replaced
about six months ago.
What the hell are all those
people doing out there?
Sick, I guess.
Oh, thank you for that astute
and penetrating observation.
Why aren't they
being seen by doctors?
I don't know, I just got here.
No docs. Abby's down in Sutures.
Dr. Malucci's here.
I think he's asleep in Exam 1.
What about Kovac?
Foreign guy? Yes.
He and some nurse
came in together,
they took her babies
upstairs to daycare.
Dr. Chen? Dr. Carter?
Some people came in when I
did, I think they're in the lounge.
Okay, it's five after 7.
Is there some kind of
natural disaster that I'm
unaware of? An earthquake?
Or half of Chicago's
swallowed up by a giant seagull?
Could you stop yelling
at me? I was here on time.
Oh, Mark Greene called,
said he'd be in before 10.
Had to go by the mortuary.
Okay, hey, Lydia, do you still
have that rape whistle thing?
Get on the phone to everybody
who's supposed to be here,
and scream on their
machines that they're late,
and if they answer,
tell them they're fired.
Rise and shine!
Patients are waiting!
Dr. Malucci, if I don't see
you standing over a sick patient
looking compassionate and
engaged in the next 30 seconds,
you're gonna spend the next week
doing disimpactions
and yeast infections!
I'm up, chief. I'm up. I'm good.
I get called upstairs
for 20 minutes
and this whole
place goes to hell.
They're in the lounge?
Uh-huh.
She uses a whistle?
You okay, John?
Yeah. I'm fine.
You look terrible.
Thank you.
Dr. Carter, what
time do you have?
Five minutes after 7.
So why are you
two in the lounge?
The 7:00 shift starts at 7:00.
That means you're here in
time to be seeing patients at 7.
Is that clear?
Move it!
County's not paying
you to drink coffee.
Ooh, somebody woke up
on the wrong side of the coffin.
Today oughta be a lot of fun.
Chen, weak and dizzy in Exam 2.
And abdominal pain in Curtain 1.
Malucci, bleeding
hemorrhoids in Exam 8.
Oh, come on, chief.
Hemorrhoids in 8 and a
boil that needs lancing in 5.
Terrific.
I hope that tone of voice was
one of unbridled enthusiasm?
I can't wait.
Okay, and keep an eye
on your med student please,
for a change. Wh...?
Where is Abby?
PID down in Sutures.
You're supervising,
Malucci? Uh, yeah.
Carter, take the
pyelo lady in Curtain 3.
Kovac, rule out MI
or a nail through the
hand still waiting in tears?
Both.
EMS is bringing in a
terminal cancer patient
five minutes out.
Okay, that'll be us, Carol.
Let's get cracking people,
there's plenty more
where those came from.
Butt boil and hemorrhoids,
this is what I went
to medical school for.
Could've been worse. There's
an explosive diarrhea up there.
You okay, hoss? You
don't look so good.
So everybody keeps telling me.
I'm having trouble sleeping.
Well, try reading the
Annals at bedtime. That...
That usually puts me right out.
Hey, you want me to
dip a urine on our pyelo?
Yeah. Yeah, in
fact I'll be right in.
I just gotta use the bathroom.
You on all night?
I was supposed to be off today,
but I, uh, swapped with Cleo.
She's taking my Saturday night.
I got tickets for Rage Against
the Machine, my friend.
Right in the pit, baby.
Hey, lucky you.
I think Weaver's
got it in for me.
I don't know what I ever did
to Festus to get her so pissed.
Maybe it was calling her Festus.
Well, never to her face.
How's it going?
All right.
I couldn't wake her up.
BP is 85/60. Tachy at 122.
Mr. O'Brien says she hadn't
eaten in a couple of days.
Any fluids?
Little ginger ale.
She was operated on for a
bowel obstruction last month.
They said the tumor spread
to her liver and diaphragm.
She could be encephalopathic
from liver failure.
What does that mean?
Your wife's liver isn't
removing toxins from her blood.
That might explain
why she isn't waking up.
Okay, here we go. Gently now.
And one, two, three.
Carol, get a CBC, lytes,
liver panel and a PT.
Her resps are down to eight.
Mr. O'Brien,
your wife's breathing
is very slow.
We may have to decide
whether or not to intubate.
Oh, God.
Does she have a
do-notresuscitate order?
Yes. She doesn't
want any machines.
Is there any way
you can help her?
We'll give her some IV fluids
and see if that makes her
more comfortable, all right?
Carol, could you show
Mr. O'Brien and his family
to where they can wait please?
Sure. Let's go see
if we can find you
some crayons and some
coloring books, okay?
Bye-bye, Mommy.
Come on, sweetheart.
I brought her things.
That's my job when
we go to the hospital.
She likes to have
her things with her.
Okay.
There isn't anywhere to put
them in here, so do you think
you could hold on to
them for a little longer?
All right, sweetheart.
All right. Come on.
So Mrs...?
Wyatt. Wyatt.
How long have you been
experiencing the burning?
Couple of days.
It usually clears up
with cranberry juice.
Any fever?
101.4.
Open your mouth for
me, would you please?
Weaver sent you a
present: a wheezer.
Would you excuse me?
A history of asthma?
Since I was a kid.
Get him into bed. Give
him five of albuterol.
Be right back.
Could you sit up for me, please?
I want you to tell me
if this hurts you at all.
Oh! Oh! Yeah.
Looks like you've
got pyelonephritis.
Is that serious?
You're gonna be fine.
Frank said you had two
patients, need a hand?
No, no. I got this.
Have you ever been on steroids?
Last year. For a few weeks.
Give him 60 of prednisone.
Set him up for continuous
nebs after this one.
When was your last period?
About a month ago.
You sure? I'm just
waiting on labs.
I got 'em. Thanks anyway though.
Any allergies?
I get hives from sulfa.
Can you tell me what
inhalers you're using?
Ventolin and Vanceril.
Any chance you're pregnant?
No, definitely not.
You believe this
guy? Not you, you
I got scared when I couldn't
wake her up. Called 911.
You did the right thing
calling the paramedics.
She's dehydrated.
I tried to get her to drink
more, but sh-sh-she's so weak,
she can't swallow. She
can hardly hold a straw.
Labs are back.
Her liver isn't making
clotting factors.
What does that mean?
It's a sign of
severe liver failure.
Is there anything you can do?
No, not really. We...
We can only make
her comfortable now.
So this is it?
I think probably so.
Oh, boy.
W-where are my girls?
Oh, one of the nurses is
taking care of them in the lounge.
Do everything you can.
I-I-I don't want her
to suffer. Please.
'Course not.
Come back if you get a fever
or experience any vomiting.
And if you wanna wait a minute,
I can get you a list of
clinics that treat STDs.
Can I wait outside?
I'm dying for a cigarette.
Sure, but you are going
to quit really soon, right?
Absolutely.
Hey.
22-year-old with PID.
Gave her 250 of ceftriaxone,
a gram of Zithromax.
Need you to sign the chart.
Benton on? Kovac
has a hot belly.
No, Benton traded
with Corday again,
and Cleo just
happens to be off too.
Shocking. Mm-hm.
This date is wrong. Today's
the 11th, not the 10th.
No, I thought
tomorrow was the 11th.
Today's the 11th, all day.
Oh.
I was expecting today
to be a really awful day,
but it seems to be
turning out okay.
Venus out of alignment
with the ninth moon
of Jupiter or something?
No, nothing like that.
Ah, Jupiter only
has eight moons.
You want me to name those?
Who is this guy?
Ah, Frank. He's temping.
Eh, let's see. Ah, inner moons:
Metis, Adrastea,
Amalthea and Thebe.
Thank you. I believe you.
Your hemorrhoid
guy's complaining.
Says the suppository
isn't helping.
Outer moons: Io, Europa,
Ganymede and Callisto.
What's he going on about? Moons.
Saturn has 18 confirmed moons.
Do you want me to name those?
No.
Abby, your PID girl
collapsed in the bay.
What happened?
She's breathing, but I
can barely feel her pulse.
She needs a couple
of large-bore IVs,
two liters of saline, wide open.
Kathy. Kathy, wake up.
Maybe it's an ectopic?
No, the ICON was negative.
BP is 70 palp. Who's her doctor?
Malucci. I'll get him.
Mix up dopamine,
get an ultrasound.
Let's get her on the gurney.
One, two, three.
Pressure's 85 after two liters.
Up the dopamine to 12 mics.
HemoCue's 14.1.
Right adnexa's normal.
Left side.
There's a mass and
free fluid. Damn it.
What is it?
Tubo-ovarian abscess.
When they rupture
they get septic.
Want me to page GYN?
Uh, no. Dial 7614,
give me the phone.
Temp's 102. It's the infection.
Got 'em.
Hey, who's this?
Paula, it's Abby Lockhart.
I need to redline
a ruptured TOA.
Set up the O.R. and page
the chief resident, thanks.
What the hell is going on?
My patient had a
syncopal episode.
Dropped her pressure.
What patient?
Abby, what patient?
The PID I just
had you discharge.
Pressure's up to 100.
Good, let's move her.
Maybe it's a
hemorrhagic ovarian cyst.
No, crit's fine, mass is
loculated. She spiked a fever.
You picked up a
loculated mass? Yeah.
No kiddin'. I wouldn't know
one if it bit me on the ass.
♪ Da, da-da, da-da, da-da ♪
♪ Da-da, da-da-da Da, da-da ♪
You haven't gotten
your antibiotics yet.
I don't think so.
Sorry, I've been busy.
I wrote the order
45 minutes ago.
Yeah, you also wrote
for continuous albuterol
and steroids for this guy.
When can you do it?
When I'm finished.
Forget it. I'm gonna get
your antibiotics myself.
Hey, when did you get back?
Uh, 20 minutes
ago. Still holding.
Mark, I'm so sorry
about your dad. Thanks.
Are you okay? I tried
calling you a couple of times,
left messages, I wanted
to see if I could do anything.
I appreciate you calling.
Rachel ended up coming
up and we're just hanging out.
Yes. No, I'm trying
to find out how to get
my father into a VA cemetery.
Transferring me to
yet another department.
Didn't he want to be buried
next to your mother
in San Diego?
I don't know what he wanted.
He said he didn't
want to be any trouble.
Suggested I put him
out with the trash.
Oh, that was helpful.
Threw in a couple of harangues
about mortuary vultures too.
Another recording
telling me to hold.
You look beat.
Yeah, well, Tess
hasn't been sleeping.
Teething, probably.
Yeah, that's what Luka said.
Well, he sees them
enough to know.
Hey, don't give me a
hard time about that.
I'm struggling enough
with this as it is.
I think it's great.
I want you to be happy.
So why do I still
feel so... unsure?
Maybe you're just afraid of
making yourself
vulnerable again.
Carol, she's waking up.
Let me know if
you need anything.
Thanks.
Conni, could you
get Weaver for me?
Where am I?
You're in the
hospital, sweetheart.
No. No, I don't want that.
Mrs. O'Brien.
I'm Carol Hathaway. I'm a nurse.
We're giving you
fluid through an IV
because you stopped drinking.
That's why you
didn't wake up today.
I want to go home.
Please.
Honey, we need
to get you admitted
to the hospital so
you could feel better.
No. I want to go home.
Mrs. O'Brien?
You want to go home?
And you don't want to
be put onto any machines?
No.
Please, no machines.
Honey, they can help
you if we stay. No.
They'll give you
something for the pain. No.
Mr. O'Brien? Home.
Mr. O'Brien.
Conni, please start
her on a morphine drip.
I think that we should
explore home hospice care.
An ambulance could take
her home as long as someone
was there to take care of the
IVs and the pain medication?
It's clearly what she wants.
She's dying, she doesn't
know what she wants.
I think she does.
She was very clear.
Don't you think
she deserves to die
where she wants to, at home?
With her family? In her own bed?
All right.
Good.
Why don't you go tell her?
I think it'll help
calm her down.
Carol.
Oh, God, I really
didn't need this today.
Why don't you call
Social Services.
Maybe the husband's right.
And we could admit her for
a day or two, get her buffed...
No, Carol, please, not today.
She would go home eventually.
The woman wants to go.
We can't keep her here.
She wants to die.
I know it's not pleasant,
but we have to
respect her wishes.
Yes, but she is in
excruciating pain
and we didn't even try to
explain the options to her.
Just call and set it up.
All right.
This should take
about 20 minutes.
And you should start feeling
better in a couple of days.
I'm gonna have the nurse come in
and give you your prescriptions.
How are you feeling,
Mr. Papazian?
Are those steroids
and albuterol helping?
Yeah, I feel much better.
Yeah, it's amazing stuff.
You okay, Mrs. Wyatt?
Hard... Hard to breathe.
Are you having any chest pain?
No.
Has this ever
happened to you before?
When I... When I got Bactrim.
Bactrim?
I told you I was
allergic to sulfa.
Feeling dizzy...
Okay, just lie down. Lie down.
You need some help?
No.
Everything's under control.
How you doin', Mrs. Wyatt?
Not too good.
What happened?
Nothing.
Somebody hit the call button.
I did.
What? She was
having trouble breathing!
What happened?
Uh, she was
complaining of hives.
So, I gave her a subcu epi.
Where's all the
blood coming from?
She must've pulled out her IV.
Why would she pull...?
How the hell would I know that?
I want you to
start another line.
Just, uh, give her
50 of Benadryl,
125 of Solu-Medrol.
You just nodded off for a
second there, Mrs. Wyatt.
Good pulse, good respirations.
You want any fluids?
Yeah, why don't you
run a liter over an hour.
This isn't gonna be pretty.
Why was a critical patient like
this discharged from the ER?
She wasn't critical at the time.
Her vitals were stable.
I thought it was PID.
You didn't appreciate
the mass on exam?
No, I didn't.
Who was supervising?
You, Dr. Malucci?
Didn't you appreciate anything?
Uh... Uh, no. I... I didn't.
What were you
wearing? Oven mitts?
Actually, Dr. Malucci
never had a chance
to examine the patient.
I think you two
need a moment alone
to get your stories straight.
He didn't examine her
because I never called him in.
Have you recently
and unexpectedly
graduated from medical
school, Ms. Lockhart?
I thought my experience
in OB/GYN qualified me.
Obviously, I was wrong.
So you signed a discharge
order for a patient you never saw
who was examined and treated
only by a medical student?
This woman could have died!
And you're years away from
having the necessary experience
to make these decisions.
I know.
Oh, good!
I'd like a moment alone
to speak with Dr. Malucci.
Can I... Can I say
something? I, uh...
I think your cause
would better be served
by keeping your mouth shut.
When Residents arrive
here, we size you up.
We... have great hopes for you.
We want you to succeed.
But gradually, over time
and through interaction,
we form opinions.
Do you want to know
the staff's opinion of you?
You're lazy, sloppy.
And your careless attitude
towards your
responsibilities as a physician
endangers patients'
lives, as witnessed today.
In other words,
none of us thinks
you're much of a doctor.
Carter's all over the
place emotionally.
Depressed one
moment, elated the next.
Have you talked to him about it?
Yeah, I tried to ask
him how he's doing,
but he isn't very forthcoming.
Do you know if he's
he seeing anyone?
Let's get out of the hallway.
Haleh, can you give us a minute?
You mean a
therapist? I don't know.
Well, don't you think he should?
I'm not a psychiatrist.
Look, I know you think
it's none of my business.
But I got out the the DMS IV...
Oh, so now you're
a psychiatrist?
He has violent mood swings.
Sometimes he's deeply depressed
other times he's
manic and elated.
So you're suggesting
he's bipolar.
Do you know if
there's a family history?
He was almost killed.
He feels partially
responsible for Lucy's death.
My moods would be
all over the place too.
But are you sure
that's all it is?
Look, Dr. Greene,
I may be wrong,
but what if I'm right?
If we care about him,
don't we owe it to him to
at least try and find out?
How's she doing?
Breathing's agonal.
Resps are seven.
So she's not getting any better?
No. I'm afraid not.
We're doing what we
can to rehydrate her,
and we called Social Services
to help set up the hospice care.
Where are your daughters?
Down in the cafeteria,
getting something to eat
with some of the nurses.
She's been sleeping
so peacefully.
You should have
seen her two years ago.
She was so beautiful.
Alive and vibrant.
Always laughing.
I wish I could have it back.
The time I missed with her.
Traveling for work.
Late nights at the office.
All the weekends I
was prepping for trial.
When she was first diagnosed
I kept working.
Can you believe that?
Instead of spending time
with her, I kept working.
I'm gonna call
Social Services again,
find out what's keeping them.
Thanks.
She's not breathing.
Oh, God!
Shelagh?
Shelagh! Please,
the girls aren't here.
I-I-I didn't think it was
gonna happen this fast.
Conni, can ya help me?
Carol, she's a DNR.
That doesn't mean
we can't stimulate
her breathing.
Please, they didn't
get to say goodbye.
You want me to get Weaver?
No, I want you to get
Kovac. Tell him I need him.
And then go downstairs
and get the daughters.
Come on, Shelagh. Shelagh.
Come on, Shelagh Please, God.
Not yet. Please.
What happened?
End-stage ovarian cancer.
She stopped breathing.
Why are you bagging her?
Let's intubate. We can't.
She's a DNR.
Then let her go.
The daughters are downstairs.
They haven't said goodbye yet.
Please.
I-I thought we had more time.
Can't we use a nasal trumpet?
The children haven't had
a chance to say goodbye
to their dying mother.
It's not a ventilator.
Please?
Where are the trumpets?
I'll get it.
I'm in.
She's breathing.
What's going on in here?
We put in a nasal trumpet.
She's DNR. We didn't intubate.
We're helping keep the...
You resuscitated her.
She's your patient?
Yes, Dr. Kovac,
she's my patient.
Her daughters weren't
here to say goodbye.
Mr. O'Brien, will you
excuse us for a moment?
You deliberately
violated a patient's wishes.
No, I did what I
thought was best,
under the circumstances.
That's not your
decision to make!
I'm sorry, Kerry.
Damn right! You should be.
You're a senior member
of this staff, Carol.
We discussed this
earlier. We disagreed.
I listened to your
point of view.
I told you exactly
what I wanted done.
If you can't
respect my authority
then you shouldn't
be working here!
If she codes again,
I don't want either
of you to touch her.
Is that clear?
Yeah.
I'm sorry, Luka.
Luka, don't just walk...
Hey, Mark
Hey, what are you
doing down here?
I thought you were
stuck upstairs all day.
I came down to talk
to Kerry about Malucci.
What did he do this time?
I've just been through
the whole thing with her.
Can I tell you later? Sure.
Did you get your dad sorted out?
Yeah.
Where is he now?
He's, uh, actually,
in the trunk of my car.
I-I didn't have time to go home.
Where's Rachel?
Jen's parents,
being spoiled rotten.
I thought you might
like these back.
I don't feel comfortable
keeping them.
My father gave them to you.
Yes, and it was very sweet
of him but I just think it...
It's a bad idea.
I really think you should
give them to Rachel.
I was 12 once. I know
what they'll mean to her.
Hey.
Don't read too much into this.
Do I do that?
You do it regularly.
Mark, we've got an
acute MI coming in.
All right, I'll be right there.
Well, are you, uh,
still coming by tonight?
Where will Rachel sleep?
On the pullout
in the living room.
I don't get off till 12.
I'll leave the light on.
Okay.
You had no right to
put me in that position.
I know.
Kerry is my
superior. I work here.
I don't wanna lose my job.
You have every reason to be mad.
You took advantage of
our personal relationship.
I did what I thought was right.
Yeah, damn the consequences!
In this case, yes.
You had every right to make
that decision for yourself,
but not to make it for me.
You're really mad.
Yes, I am!
Why are you smiling?
I guess I thought I was immune.
Well, you are not.
Luka, I'm sorry.
Yes?
Really. It will never
happen again.
Good.
And thank you.
For what?
For helping her.
You're welcome.
What?
Nothing.
You sure?
Yeah.
"Good night, little house,
and good night, mouse.
Good night, comb.
Good night, brush."
Now can you see the mouse?
There's the mouse.
Hey, guys.
Your mom's ready to see you now.
Frank, could you take Jennifer?
Sure.
We'll be in in a minute.
Don't you want to see your mom?
She's going to die, isn't she?
Yeah.
It's not fair.
No, it's not.
I don't wanna only have a dad.
I wanna be a family...
like we used to be.
Come on. We should go.
You ready?
Hi, Mommy.
Hi, there.
How's my girl?
What are you doing?
Uh... just gathering
my thoughts.
Haleh said you'd been
in here for a while?
Yeah, I finished up
some sutures, and, um...
It seemed like a quiet
place to hang out.
Is that a problem?
No.
Some of us are just a
little worried about you.
Well, you don't need to be.
How are you? Fine.
You seeing anybody? Therapist?
No.
Need a referral?
Sure.
Yeah?
'Cause, uh, Nadio
gave me some names.
Yeah, that'd be great.
Might help.
Yeah, you're right. I'll go.
Okay.
Did Social Services
get your patient home?
No. She died.
I'm sorry.
She was end-stage.
I'm off in a couple of hours.
Would you like to
get some dinner?
Sure.
We don't have to.
Ah, no, that would be nice.
Excuse me, Miss Hathaway?
I'll find you when I get off.
I just wanted to thank you
for everything you
did for us today.
You're welcome.
Do you believe that
we have soul mates?
You know, that there's only...
one person we're
supposed to find?
O-Only one person
we can really love?
I didn't used to.
But I-I-I do now.
Sh-She was the love of my life.
And I'll never love anyone
again the way I loved her.
Carol, I need
some more atropine.
Carol!
Hey, Haleh, where's Mark?
Carol, is everything all right?
Where's Mark?
Exam 1.
Mark, I gotta go.
Tell Kerry I won't be
in tomorrow, okay?
Twins okay?
I'm gonna drop
them off at my mom's.
What? I'll call you
from the plane.
Plane?
Hey, Malik, where's Kovac?
Curtain 3.
Luka,
I can't have dinner
with you tonight.
Okay.
I'm so sorry.
For what?
I have to go find out.
Find out what?
If he's still in love with me.
Because... I'm still
in love with him.
I am.
I've been in love with him
since I was 23 years old.
He's... He's everything to me.
He's my life. I feel
complete when I'm with him,
and I feel empty
when we're apart.
He's the father of my children.
And he's my soul mate.
You'll find someone,
Luka. You will.
You're such a wonderful man.
She's out there, I know she is.
Someone who'll love you
the way your wife loved you.
You'll find her. You will.
You will find her.
♪ I had a good life ♪
♪ Before you came ♪
Seattle? Seattle?
Ramp 4. You better hurry!
They're already
in final boarding.
♪ I had my friends
And my freedom ♪
♪ I had my name ♪
♪ Still there was sorrow ♪
Seattle?
All right. Have a good
flight. ♪ And emptiness ♪
♪ Till you made me glad ♪
♪ Oh, in this love ♪
Fasten your seat belt,
please. ♪ I found strength ♪
♪ I never knew I had ♪
You almost missed it.
Yeah. I almost did.
♪ And this love ♪
♪ This love ♪
Dad, you're crazy.
This is your grandfather's
favorite spot in Chicago.
Right here.
It's beautiful.
Yeah.
Listen, I have to go to
San Diego next week
to, uh, bury his ashes
next to your grandmother's.
Can you come with me?
♪ Taking you home ♪
Sure. I-I'd like that.
You miss him, huh?
Yeah. I do.
It's kind of funny.
Why?
We didn't like each other
much for a very long time.
How come?
I can't remember now.
Probably mostly my fault.
I have somethin' for you.
These were your grandmother's.
Do you like them?
They're beautiful.
Can I put 'em on you?
'Kay, turn around.
Okay, let's see.
You... You look lovely.
Thank you.
Promise me you won't
grow up too fast, okay?
Okay. ♪ There were days ♪
♪ Lonely days ♪
♪ When the world
Wouldn't throw me a crumb ♪
♪ No, no ♪
♪ But I kept on believing ♪
♪ That this day would come Oh ♪
♪ And this love ♪
♪ This love ♪
♪ Is like nothing I
have ever known ♪
♪ No, no, baby ♪
♪ Take my hand, love ♪
♪ I'm taking you home ♪
♪ Where we can be with
the ones Who really care ♪
♪ Home ♪
♪ Where we can grow together ♪
♪ Keep you in my heart Forever ♪
♪ Oh, and this love ♪
Where are the girls?
They're with my mom.
♪ Is like nothing I
have ever known ♪
It's beautiful here.
♪ Take my hand ♪
♪ Taking you home ♪
♪ Yes I am ♪