To a degree,
medicine is a science.
- You spent six hours on a boat?
- Yes.
- And you talked about fishing.
- For six hours.
- Pretty much, yeah.
- Derek...
- What do you want me to say?
We went fishing, we
talked about fishing.
- I want the whole story.
- That is the whole story.
"She caught a fish and
cried," is not the whole story.
Except it is the story. It
is, in fact, the entire story.
- I'm ovulating.
- Ugh...
But I would argue
that it's also an art.
I mean, you stole my
best friend, and it's not OK!
It's not OK for the two of you
to hang out like I don't exist!
I am not hanging out,
I am trying to help her!
By hanging out with her!
- Are we gonna do this or not?
- I'm too mad
to even look at you.
Well, then, roll over.
Fine.
The doctors who see
medicine as science only?
You don't want them by your
side when your bleeding won't stop,
or when your child
is screaming in pain.
You look different.
You seem better.
- I feel better.
- Really?
Mm-hm.
So you have plans?
I think I'm gonna
explore the city today.
- Really?
- Mm-hm.
You know, I've never
had time to do it before.
Or the interest.
Hello?
Teddy, you're doing what?
The clinicians go by the book.
- The artists follow their guts.
- - Mm!
- Uh...
- Oh!
You're gonna make us late.
- OK.
- Mm!
OK. Go.
Go.
Nope!
The artists feel your pain.
And they go to
extremes to make it stop.
You sat here all night?
Um... Well, no.
Just flew in from Africa, so I
went to a hotel and took a shower,
got some sleep, and
came back really early.
Really, please,
go back to Malawi.
Extreme measures.
That's where science
ends, and art begins.
We can do this
another day, if you want.
No, no. I mean, no, we're
here now. And he'll be here.
Hey. Oh! Hey. My witness is
here. OK, let's get this thing started.
Teddy, you're not
seriously gonna do this?
Yeah, I am.
- Henry Burton.
- Owen Hunt.
OK, then. Will you be reading vows or
do you just want a standard ceremony?
Oh! Crap. Uh, it's work.
Um, I'm just gonna let it roll.
- Standard ceremony?
- Maybe you could
just skip to the end.
- Sorry. I'm just... I'm really late.
- Come.
Excuse me. Can you direct
me to the Space Needle?
It's your, uh, first
time in Seattle, huh?
- Um... sure, OK.
- You're just gonna
want to go west
on Union about eight blocks or so,
and then you turn north and you should...
Must be a bad accident.
Hey, that's not west.
You're going the wrong way.
I'll travel to Malawi every two
months for the next three years,
to oversee everything, and I
got a leading pediatric surgeon
to oversee the
day-to-day operations.
Dr. Robbins, I signed a contract
with a new Peds attending.
It's a year-long contract.
I can't eat that money.
- I just don't have it.
- Well, I don't understand.
So you're saying I can't...
Wh... I can't have a job here?
Dr. Robbins, you're back!
Now, that is the
reaction I was hoping for!
- Uh, excuse me, Dr. Robbins.
- So, Karev.
Tell me about this new Peds guy.
You're married.
You married that guy.
- So? You got married.
- To the woman I love!
- You don't even know this guy.
- Look, the man
needed insurance.
- Can we not talk
about this, please?
- Not ever, or not right now?
- I'm thinking not ever.
- What's going on?
Major Seattle area shooting. We have
reports that a gunman has opened fire
- on students and faculty
- Bailey? Bailey, fill us in.
We now take you live
to our on scene reporter.
Students and faculty
are still in the building.
I'm trying to get answers,
but what we know
so far is that a gunman
opened fire at Pacific College,
and that there are
at least a dozen...
I'm sorry? OK. OK,
there at least 20 victims.
I'm sorry. You can't be here. Clear
the area, please. Clear, please!
- Move back, people. Move, back up.
- Let's go. Come on.
He's bleeding out from his
chest wound. Pulse is thready,
and he's bled through the
dressing. We're going priority one.
V-tach on the monitor.
Any pulse with that?
No pulse. Starting CPR.
Let's get him to the hospital.
You need to crack his chest. You
need... Someone crack his chest!
There are 15 ambulances on
the way, maybe more to come.
First one is three minutes out.
People, people.
Our own trauma is fresh and
we are gonna have feelings today,
and there's no shame in
that. What I want to say is
what we went through six months
ago, they are going through right now.
Which makes them
our brothers and sisters.
Which makes them fellow
travelers. Which makes them our own.
So, to the very
best of our ability,
we are gonna do our work first,
and you're gonna
have your feelings later.
- Grey?
- I'm fine.
I'm fine!
Go to the pit and make sure
we're stocked. Call the blood bank...
- I'm fine.
- Call the blood bank.
Tell them to give us
all the O neg they have.
- All right.
- Look alive.
I got a cop, Michael Fazioli, 28,
GSW to the right upper arm and left leg.
- OK, this one's mine.
- - All right, I'm on that one.
- Chief Webber.
- Sarge?
All right, Kepner, get him to
trauma one. Get labs, trauma series
- and X-ray this leg and arm.
- OK.
This is the cop that
took down the shooter.
- You're kidding.
- No, he was on the radio,
he told me he landed a
shot, then he went down.
I've got conflicting reports about
what the shooter looked like.
If you could wake Faz
up and get him talking...
- Faz?
- Mike Fazioli. He's a good kid.
Great cop. One of ours.
- What do you have?
- Professor John Sturgeon, 48,
fell out a fourth story window, has an
open skull fracture and a blown pupil.
- He fell?
- He helped a dozen kids out the window
and up onto the roof. Then he
tried to go himself and slipped.
He's herniating. Get him to the
front of the line. Get him in the OR.
- You OK?
- Nothing about this is OK.
Two and three are open.
Fifteen year old, Kelly Keck,
GSW's to the leg and abdomen.
Abdomen rigid, systolic
75, last pulse 147.
- She's 15?
- Yeah.
Look what being
a genius gets you.
- Clear trauma three and page Stark!
- - Right away, doctor.
Jared Swork, 20 years
old, single entrance wound
to the left fifth intercostal
space, no exit wound.
Lost vitals in front of us. This
is the emergency thoracotomy
- we called in about.
- You did a thoracotomy
in the field?
No, I didn't.
I had to crack his chest.
- Cristina.
- Can you feel the lesion?
Yes, he's got a big
hole in his right ventricle.
But, as long as I keep my hand
here, I can feel a good heartbeat.
- Cristina!
- What? What?!
You're going to the OR?
She's got her hand
on the hole, Owen.
I'll be fine. I'll be OK.
- Can we stop in front of the...
- - Bring him to two.
This artery is in pieces.
- Vascular clamp.
- Here you go.
Your best move is
to amputate that leg.
You got no more
time to waste there.
- What? What?
- The artery's blown,
- the femur is shattered.
- Torres can fix that.
I'm more concerned
about the life than the leg,
- and I'm sure her
parents will be, too.
- Look, this kid is 15.
You can save this leg.
You can't just cut it off.
What I can't do is to spend
any more time arguing with you.
Would you maintain pressure
there? Prep the damn leg, Karev.
Freakin' do something!
Intracranial pressure's
getting higher.
Are we doing a
craniectomy or a craniotomy?
Craniectomy is our best bet.
Dr. Shepherd, the professor's wife
just arrived. Can someone speak to her?
I'll go. I'll be quick.
You paged me? Yang?
- I was at the scene.
- She was at the scene.
He's got a tear on
the right ventricle
and there could be torrential
bleeding once we get in.
So I just, uh, want
a little backup.
- Just a little extra backup.
- She's not sure
if I can handle it.
I'm ready. I'm
in. I'll go scrub.
All right. Let's get
this boy on bypass.
It's just crazy. We have so many
here, he couldn't tell me anything.
- Mrs. Sturgeon?
- Yes. Hi.
- Hi.
- Are you John's doctor? Is he OK?
He fell from a fourth story
window and landed on his head.
- So we're
taking him to surgery...
- Wait, wait, surgery?
We will be removing
the left side of his skull
to give his brain room to swell.
OK, I'm gonna come with you.
I need to come with you because
John doesn't like hospitals.
- You can't come into the OR.
- No, see,
John is afraid of doctors. OK?
So I have to be with him.
Please let me be with him.
Mrs. Sturgeon, I'm so sorry,
but you can't come into the OR.
I will come out and update you
every chance I get, though. OK?
- Just, uh... Excuse me. Hi.
- Yes?
Would you sit with Mrs. Sturgeon?
This is gonna be a long day,
and you all need to take
care of each other, OK?
OK.
You can put in a shunt
and then do a graft.
Do you even have
privileges here anymore?
Whether I have privileges
or not isn't the point.
- Karev's right.
- Karev is not
on this case anymore.
Dr. Stark, please, take the time to
do the graft, and you can save her leg.
I know very well what can
and can't be done, Dr. Robbins.
I have bigger fish to fry. And this
was very unprofessional of you.
I am all done engaging with it.
All right, get the hell
out of my OR, Karev.
I'm sorry, I'm unprofessional?
I'm unprof...? I...
Body block him, Karev!
Don't let him near that leg!
He's got some blood in his
chest, but the bullet's not there.
It's not in his leg or
in his arm. Kepner?
Uh... Uh...
We should put in a chest tube
and get more studies to see
what damage we're dealing with.
Is there any chance
we can wake him up
while we're waiting
for the studies?
I could reverse his pain meds,
but it would be a pretty
traumatic awakening.
- He'd be in a lot of pain.
- - I'm getting all sorts
of conflicting reports as to
what this shooter looks like.
Kids in shock, they don't remember,
but cops are trained to remember.
I don't know if there's a second
shooter, if this is some kind of plot.
But until I have a positive
ID, I've got nothing.
Believe me, Faz would rather feel
some pain if he can ID the shooter for me.
OK, I'll reverse the meds.
Kepner, let's set
up the chest tube.
Chief Webber? This
guy you replaced me with
- is a study in incompetence.
- Not now, Robbins.
No, yes now! Because
Dr. Incompetence is about
to hack off a
perfectly good leg.
Robbins, I'm pretty busy here.
What do you want me to do?
- Give me privileges.
- It's all hands on deck.
- Of course you have privileges.
- OK, thank you.
It's not an easy day to
be the man in charge.
- Torres, OR two,
right now! 911!
- What? Where are you going?
- I need scrubs.
- Uh, OK...
Bailey, can you take
over for me here?
This is, uh, Chuck
Fowler. He's 21 years old,
zone two injury of the neck
secondary to graze GSW.
He has a hematoma, and a CT
angio has been ordered. Thank you.
How you doing, Chuck?
Who walks into a classroom with an
automatic weapon? Who does that?
I don't know. I don't know.
OK, here I go.
I'm a wrestler,
man. I'm All-State.
Saw or no saw, you're
not getting past me!
Karev? You wanna tell
me what's going on here?
He's lost his mind, that's
what's going on here.
He's lost his mind and
he's destroying his career.
- That is what is going on here!
- Check it out, Torres.
Fifteen-year-old GSW to the thigh
with comminuted femur fracture.
Laceration is the
superficial femoral artery. Ha!
All right. What about her nerves?
Are her nerves salvageable?
Kid was moving her leg before
we put her under. They're intact.
She has a life-threatening
hemorrhage in her leg,
and multi-organ
injuries in her abdomen!
Abdominal bleeding is
under control for now.
Thanks so much, Dave. I
appreciate the support there.
Well, I can put in a traction
pin to stabilize the femur.
- Right?
- And then we can use a graft
- to restore blood flow.
- That's what I'm saying!
I have never experienced
anything like this
before in my life!
Dr. Stark, you're new
here. But, in this hospital,
we take shootings personally.
And I can save this leg.
- So are you gonna
work with me or not?
- No, no, I am.
Dr. Stark, I've spoken with Chief
Webber. This is my patient now.
What? This is...
This...
- Yes!
- Karev, you gotta go, too.
The pit's full of kids that need doctors
and we can handle this without you.
That's cool. My work is
done. Ha! All-State, baby!
See that bridging vein?
You'll have to compromise it if
you're gonna pull the skull flap up.
Mm-hm.
I'll be right back. I'm gonna
go update the wife again.
Dr. Grey, you're a
surgeon, not a social worker.
You can't spare
me for five minutes?
And we have a
patient on the table.
That's not the whole story.
Don't start this again.
The other part of the story is that
he's got a wife who is panicking...
- Fine. Go. Just let me concentrate.
- I'll be quick.
All right, he's ready.
I'm gonna push the naloxone.
He's gonna wake up and he's
gonna hurt. So talk quick, OK?
Ready.
Faz. It's Marty.
Can you hear me?
Oh, God, it hurts.
Oh, God!
Faz, I need you to describe the
shooter. Can you do that for me, bud?
Chief Webber, did you really
approve of Robbins storming my OR?
Stealing my patient?
Humiliating me publicly?
There are plenty patients to go
around, Dr. Stark. Jump in and find one.
I will not. What I will do is to go
back to my patient, in my OR...
Go be a damn doctor! People are
dying! Now go save a life, right now!
- I'm here
with Officer Murphy.
- Just hang on.
- I need the info... Excuse me...
- OK, I understand.
Dr. Hunt?
I'm free. Do you
need me? I'm free.
Dr. Hunt.
They just found another
classroom full of victims.
- We're getting
at least a dozen more.
- Crap.
- We're out of ORs.
- What?
We're out of ORs.
We're out of space.
And all other hospitals are at capacity.
If any of them need surgery, we're...
We're screwed.
Dr. Altman, we have
a GSW to the chest...
- Dr. Yang?
- Dr. Yang
was on the scene.
She performed an emergency
thoracotomy in the field.
- You all right,
Dr. Yang?
- Yes, sir.
- I'm staying, if that's OK.
- Dr. Yang,
can you tell me
what your patient was wearing,
or where his clothes are?
Uh, they were cut off at
the scene. It was, um...
a green hoodie, jeans.
Is he a redhead, about 20?
- Yes.
- Uh, why, sir?
Send me down any bullet
fragments you pull out of his body.
Chief, what's going on?
The patient's the shooter.
Send down any bullets
immediately. They're evidence.
OK.
OK, where were we?
You were about to
reconstruct the ventricle.
Right. Right, thank you. OK.
Hand me three-oh
Ethibond, please.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry,
but I can't, Dr. Altman.
- You can't
hand me the Ethibond?
- I can't...
She can't save this guy
is what she's saying.
He just shot up
dozens of people!
And this surgery is
gonna take all day.
- Dr. Avery...
- That's taking three doctors
and four nurses away
from helping other people.
People who didn't shoot up
a campus full of innocent kids!
Dr. Avery!
I operated on Iraqi soldiers
who blew up dozens of our guys.
I didn't like it, but I did it,
because I'm a doctor
and I took an oath.
You're not a jury or a judge.
If there's a life to be saved,
we save that life regardless...
I'm not doing this. No.
- Anyone else?
- I'm sorry.
Dr. Yang... are you staying?
Yes.
All right.
OK, great. Uh, three-oh
Ethibond, please.
Come on, come on, come on. Press
on the cricoid more. I can't see the cords.
- Come on, Faz, stay with me!
- Kepner?
His vitals started dropping.
X-rays were clear, no bullet,
so I did an ultrasound,
found blood in the belly.
We need all available
surgical equipment, all right?
Quickly. Good.
Chief, you should stay in that
trauma room. There are no ORs.
- Get the chief an
anesthesiologist.
- What?
I got a cop with blood in his belly. The
same cop that took down the shooter!
You're saying I have to operate
on him in the trauma room?
I'm saying it's your
best option right now.
Sir, his pressure's dropping!
Hunt, I hope you know
what you're doing, Hunt.
Yes, sir. So do I.
Kepner, lock him down in there and
get me a major procedures tray now.
- OK.
- Avery, is Altman done yet?
No. And while we've got a
cop bleeding out down here,
she's occupying a perfectly good
OR, going to extreme measures
to save the damn shooter.
I tried talking to her...
Altman's guy is the shooter?
Does Cristina know that?
- Yeah, so does Altman! I walked out.
- All right.
Go to the emergency
room. There is incoming.
Kepner, I need you to
go to Outpatient Recovery!
I need to get these
supplies to the chief.
No. You, take this to
the chief in trauma one.
Go to Outpatient Recovery
right now and oversee it.
- What am I doing?
- It's like
a mobile trauma unit.
It's like a MASH unit.
I'll be there in a moment.
- Wait! Where are you going?
- You were trained
for this, Kepner!
- Oversee it!
- Oh, God.
OK, coming through.
- I understand why
you're mad at me.
- No.
I even understand you
slamming the door in my face.
No! You will not hold me
hostage and make me listen to you.
I am rebuilding the leg
of a kid who's been shot.
That's... That's why I'm
here, that is the only reason.
No talking. None.
OK, if anyone's free, we
have an incoming patient.
GSW to the flank with
active hemorrhage.
Why are we still accepting
critical cases? I'm coming, Kepner!
Continue to debride out the devitalized
tissue and repair the injured vessel.
You're serious?
Do you want to take the
incoming GSW to the flank?
All right, then.
Um, there's enough
surgeons around
- if you have questions. Just take care of Chuck.
- OK, Chuck.
I'm gonna be doing a vascular
repair on you, in a freakin' mosh pit.
- Son of a bitch.
- ICP is still 45.
His brain is still swelling.
We're gonna have to
remove the other side.
You're gonna take off
both sides of his skull?
We're gonna leave this
strip here that covers up
the superior sagittal sinus.
Let's get the other side prepped.
Well, I'm gonna
go update the wife.
Since when are you so interested in
updating the wife in the waiting room
- than doing this?
- Since I was the wife
in the waiting room, Derek!
Honestly, do you think you
and Cristina are the only two
- who have ever
been through a trauma?
- Do not bring Cristina
back into this. You don't get to
act like a spoiled little brat in my OR.
Why is it OK for Cristina to do whatever
she wants, but it's not OK for me?
Because I'm not hiding
under OR tables or bartending?
- Meredith.
- Honestly, you and Cristina
are so busy
supporting each other,
have you even noticed that I
went through a trauma, too?
I was the wife in the waiting room,
Derek, and it's so hard to be the wife
in the waiting room. So
hard that I walked into the OR,
while the shooter had a gun to
you, and told him to shoot me instead.
That's how hard it is to be
the wife in the waiting room.
Excuse me. I'm gonna
go update my patient.
OK. OK.
I'm sorry. Let's continue on.
Dr. Shepherd is going to remove
the other half of your husband's skull.
If all goes well in the OR,
he'll then freeze the skull
to keep the bones from dying,
then he'll sew the scalp and muscle
- back over the exposed brain.
- I don't understand. I'm sorry.
- I don't understand.
- I know it sounds frightening
and extreme, and it is.
But Dr. Shepherd is very good.
And I'll come out and
keep you posted, OK?
- OK...
- OK.
I'm looking for
the Sackett family.
Anybody here for a John Sackett?
Excuse me, is anyone
here related to Jared Swork?
Yes! That's my son!
How is he? Is he OK?
Ma'am, would you
mind coming with me?
- Over there.
- Thanks, man.
My son was shot!
He wasn't the shooter!
No! No, my son didn't do this!
No, no, no!
- What the hell?
- Sloan, move on.
- I'm gonna kick your ass.
- Kick it later.
We got a kid in three
with a GSW to the shoulder
and we need this
space for incoming.
My name's not going on this
chart. That's a hack job you did.
Somebody get
Dr. Nelson here now!
- I'll get Grey, you get bed three.
- - Clean it and wrap it.
Right away, doctor.
She's got an intracranial
hemorrhage, her pupil just blew.
She needs burr holes
and a... and a trauma flap.
- We gotta evacuate that clot.
- OK, we can do that.
We can do that.
OK.
- I need some hands over here, Avery.
- - Yep.
- Arterial repair. Can you hold that?
- Got it.
You know Altman's
still in OR one?
So, you can't
choose who you save.
Yeah, that's
apparently the party line.
The shooter's sick. Nobody
does this in their right mind.
What's your point?
My brother just had a psychotic
break and tried to kill my sister.
And if he got hurt, even if
he got hurt hurting people,
I would want his doctors to do
everything they could to save him.
No matter what he did,
he's still my little brother.
Making the incision.
- Ready with the drill?
- Yeah.
- No, you're gonna do it.
- Mark.
She's your patient, Dr. Grey.
You're gonna save her life.
Ready?
Gently.
Right there.
Perfect. Perfect.
Damn it! He's crashing! I
need a crash cart in here now!
Hey, do not die,
Chuck! You hear me?
That shooter does not get
to win this. You come back!
Here we go!
Clear!
- Come on.
- Uh...
Come back right now, Charles!
- Come back to your body,
right now!
- Clear!
You bastard! You better
send this boy back right now!
Clear!
Sorry about the "bastard" thing.
There's something
you need to see.
What is that?
The Pacific College Alma Mater.
Thank you for
staying today, Cristina.
I know it can't have
been an easy decision.
You know what, though?
It was.
- How is he?
- He's decompressed,
but he's got a bad contusion.
Damn it. He's bleeding
too much. Vascular clips.
She is right there.
- Mrs. Sturgeon,
I'm Dr. Shepherd.
- Hi.
Hi. Your husband is in a
medically induced coma.
He'll have to stay that
way until his brain heals.
Hopefully, in a couple of weeks,
we'll be able to replace the skull,
- and wake him up.
- Wait, you're
saying that he lived?
- That he's alive?
- We have a long road
ahead of us.
But yes, he is alive. And I
can take you to him if you'd like.
- OK.
- OK?
Oh! Thank you.
It's OK. You can see him
in a few minutes, all right?
Excuse me, ma'am. Has anyone
talked to you about your son?
The police questioned me for hours,
as if I should have known something.
They found a suicide
note in his jeans.
And I didn't know anything.
My whole life...
Everything... I
ever knew... is a lie.
He's my baby.
All I want to know
is if he's alive.
Is that terrible?
All these people he hurt...
Does that make
me a terrible person?
Your son was shot in the chest.
Dr. Altman, who is a
very good heart surgeon,
is doing everything
that she can.
She's still in surgery,
which means he's still alive.
She'll come find you as
soon as she's out. OK?
OK. Thank you.
Thank you.
- He's fine.
- Oh, God!
- Oh, my God. You kidding me?
- It was touch
and go for a while,
- but he's gonna be fine.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
And, um... let's stop
meeting like this, Marty.
Oh, please, God.
Please, God.
This is... This is a huge victory. You
know, whatever else happened today,
we work together well.
So, thank you.
Thank you for coming
when I asked you to come,
and for fighting Stark
with me. Thank you.
- Calliope.
- Hm?
I am so deeply,
deeply, deeply sorry
for hurting you so
much. I am so sorry.
Because I am so
in love with you.
And I will spend the rest
of my life telling you that.
I'll apologize to you every
day if that's what you need.
But please...
Please don't walk away again.
I came across the world
to be with you. I love you.
Please.
You had to fly across the
world to get to me, Arizona,
because you flew a whole world
away without looking back. You just left.
And this might be news
to you. I think it kind of is.
But you're not the only one in this
relationship. There are two of us.
And you came back
today, but I didn't.
Whatever else happened,
that... that hasn't changed.
Hey.
You...
You've been holding
everybody up, even though...
You amaze me.
Mm...
I know you're mad at me
for taking Cristina fishing.
And I know you
think it didn't work.
I just heard she's in OR one.
- What?
- She's here.
I just took my kid to a
room. He was the last one.
- Besides this one.
- Mm-hm. Yeah, besides this one.
- Thirty-seven degrees.
- Should be any minute now.
We saw 26 patients.
Twenty-six victims.
And we had no casualties.
No one died.
I hate this place.
Surgery is extreme.
We cut into your
body, take out pieces
and put what's
left back together.
I was holding a grudge.
I can hire you back.
But you're gonna have
to work under Stark.
- Hey.
She's, uh, still sedated.
And she's just a kid.
She shouldn't
have a big ugly scar.
Do you mind waiting?
I'll be about another hour.
I love you.
So... yeah.
Just, uh, take your time.
I, um... I'll wait.
Good thing life doesn't
come with a scalpel,
because if it did, when
things started to hurt,
we would just cut
and cut and cut.
Hey, I'm really sorry I'm late.
You look exhausted.
I look handsome.
How about we get
you some insurance?
Let's have a drink
first. Toast the day.
- Henry...
- Because I've
never been married.
- Have you?
- No. Um...
But I wouldn't say
this is exactly...
Look, I know what this is. But
I say we raise a glass anyway.
There was no ring, right? No vows,
no photographer, no wedding cake,
which I was most disappointed
by because I love wedding cake.
I think we can at least
have a toast, right?
I spent the day in the OR
saving someone who
really, really is, um...
not a very good person.
Well, you saved me, too.
You saved my life this morning.
And that deserves a toast.
Even if it wasn't
a real wedding.
OK.
The thing is, what we
take away with a scalpel...
we can't ever get back.
You want to get a drink?
Yeah. I do.
Maybe not a real drink, actually,
because I'm trying to get pregnant
and supposedly alcohol will make
my baby have three heads and 16 toes.
Wanna get some crack cocaine?
So, like I said...
good thing.