The baby you have is the
baby you were destined to have.
What you thinkin', huh?
It was meant to be.
You gettin' tired?
That's what all the
adoption people tell you.
Anyway, I like
to think it's true.
But everything else in the world
seems so completely random.
You gonna talk now, too?
What if one little
thing I said or did...
Could have made
it all fall apart?
What if I'd chosen
another life for myself.
Or another person?
We might have never
found each other.
What if I had been
raised differently?
What if my mother
had never been sick?
What if I'd actually
had a good father?
What if?
Meredith.
Good morning, Mom.
Morning. Are you riding
with me or with your father?
Because if you're riding with
me, we have to leave now.
Don't wait. I'll go with Dad.
Who's coming with
me? Hiya, darling.
Hi.
Don't be late, either of
you. Sets a bad example.
I'm telling you...
It's true.
Oh, thank you so
much. You're welcome.
Okay.
All right.
I need you to sit right here
and wait until Mommy
comes out, okay?
Don't move. Here.
Play with your thingy.
And, I'm gonna just
be in the next room...
No, Mommy!
Yes. Sit right there.
Hey, pumpkin.
Hi, Daddy.
Hey, hey. Really?
Really? I mean, you couldn't
figure out anything else?
Well, Owen, if she's gonna
schedule staff meetings
before the day care opens,
what do you expect me to do?
I know, I know. Chief's here.
Okay, bye, guys.
I've been looking at
Seattle Pres's numbers,
and I think we can absorb
them the way we did Mercy West.
I want reports on
where your departments
can use extra residents
and equipment.
Congratulations on your
third Harper Avery Award.
Portal vein reconstruction,
pretty soon they're gonna
rename the Whipple the Grey.
Thank you.
Well, there's some
press here today, FYI.
Okay, let's go. Trauma?
Abdominal closure on an MVC,
and we will wait to
see what comes in.
Neuro?
I have a laminectomy.
Just one? You got a golf game?
You know what,
people? I keep saying it.
If you're not innovating,
be generating.
Cardio?
Yang is doing a solo
thoracic aortic aneurysm,
oh, and also, I'll be
checking in on my kid
with the artificial lung who
is waiting for a transplant.
Yeah, can I just say for the
record that he's my patient,
and I don't agree with
this method of treatment?
The FDA has not approved
an artificial lung on children.
Well, I got emergency approval.
It buys the kid more time,
it keeps him from being
sedated and ventilated,
I think it's worth exploring.
He should be sedated.
Let his body heal.
This is just too
risky. It's innovative.
Shepherd, this is what I'm
talking about. Let's hope it works.
Good work, Torres.
General, Dr. Bailey?
Uh, yes. Extended Whipple.
Speak up. I'm doing
an extended Whipple.
Owen. I got it.
Dr. Bailey, go on.
Um, 47-year-old male,
advanced pancreatic cancer
with invasion of the portal vein.
Well, what are you using
to graft the portal vein?
The...
Um, the jugular. I'll take that.
Excuse me? I'll
take your Whipple.
Send me the chart ASAP.
Okay. Well, I...
Neonatal?
A pyloric stenosis.
Actually, two pylorics and...
That's not a reflection
on you, Bailey.
She probably wants a surgery
to take her mind off of
all the Harper Avery fuss.
Now don't take it the wrong way.
I'm not.
Good.
Thank you so much.
Oh, my God!
When? Last night.
I mean, I kind of thought he
would, and then, sure enough.
Are you okay, April?
'Cause I know...
I mean, I knew this was
gonna be hard for you, but...
Oh.
You are going to
find someone, April.
And Charles is really into you.
Ugh! I know, I know,
but Charles is...
Hi.
Hey, April. Charles is what?
Nothing.
No, no, no.
I am thrilled. Have
you told anyone else?
Besides my parents,
no. You're my person.
Oh, God, this is so beautiful.
You guys, you're gonna
be, like, the next Shepherds.
Screw that. We're gonna
be the next Webbers.
Okay, how did he do
it? Tell me everything.
Okay, so last night, we
went out to dinner, and he...
Good morning.
Are you talking to me?
Jackson, don't feed the animals.
Every single one of
you can suck my...
Hey! How's everybody
doing this morning?
Everybody ready
to kick some butt?
Let's run the
board, guys. Avery?
Covering the pit.
Noble work. Yang?
Solo thoracic aortic aneurysm.
Huh.
Well, I guess that means
I'm doing Torres' post-ops.
Kepner?
Uh, I'm on Shepherd's
service. Good Shepherd.
Hey. I'm on bad Shepherd.
Maybe we're gonna
be the next Shepherds.
No, we aren't.
All right, guys. The day
is as good as you make it.
All right, let's get out there
and keep Seattle Grace
the country's best hospital.
Come on!
Yang, smile. Yeesh.
All right. Let's move.
Uh, can I speak with
you, Dr. Webber?
Okay, okay, okay.
I thought we had a rule
about this in the hospital.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I just... My God. You're
so hot in that ring.
I do look good, don't I?
Yeah. Hey, what did
your parents think?
I mean, what did your mom say?
Well, she loved it, of
course. And she adores you.
Well, finally. It took a while.
Well, you were a jerk
before you met me.
She didn't know there
was a good guy in there.
But I did.
Oh, I love it.
And I love you.
Have a great day.
Okay, come on, guys
and Allegra. Let's go.
He's so good with the
kids. How's he doing?
He's better.
Yeah. I think we're past it.
Really? Yeah.
That's great. Mmm-hmm.
I know. I've just
heard it can be...
A hard road, coming back.
I mean, who knows what
he went through over there.
Yeah, well... He doesn't
like to talk to me about it.
But he does skype with
some of his old buddies
that are still in Iraq, and,
this guy, Teddy, seems to
be helping him through it.
And he hasn't had another
episode since that one.
So anyway, he's good.
He's good. We're good now.
I don't know how you do it.
And then with the kids, too?
Well... You'll find out
soon enough, right?
Besides, you and
Derek will be fine.
You two are perfect.
All Ellis is saying
is that she wants
you to use your full potential.
Oh. Hi, honey. Hi.
Like that clinical trial
you used to talk about.
I'm about to have
a child, Richard.
I don't have time
for a clinical trial.
I think you should find it.
I think it'll do you good.
Good morning.
Mmm.
A clinical trial...
This elevator is not working.
What an ass.
We brought you a
cokehead found in an alley.
Presumed overdose.
Tried Narcan. No response.
Had to shock her
once in the field at 300.
BP is 80 over 60.
SAT's 96 on 100%.
All right. On my count.
One...
Stop. V-fib. Charge
the paddles to 300.
Clear!
There we go.
Ready? On my count.
One, two, three.
Avery, she's all yours.
All right, let's
get a tox screen,
an EKG, a CBC, a
CMP and an X-ray now.
Right away, Doctor.
Well, it's a stroke
of luck, actually.
I'm doing a surgery today,
and I'm planning to use
the new Grey technique.
So rather than a
boring press interview,
why don't you come
on up to the gallery,
take a few shots of
the technique in action...
And, we'll talk after?
I'll see you in the OR.
Great. Sounds good. Thank you.
- All right.
- Okay, thanks.
That was brilliant.
Why settle for another
boring press release, right?
So can I scrub in?
I would love to see the
procedure done firsthand.
Why? Your focus is cardio.
You're not gonna
get a cardio fellowship
scrubbing in on your
mother's Whipple.
That's true.
Cristina Yang is doing a
solo aortic aneurysm today.
That came in last night,
and had I been here...
Yeah, but you weren't
because you were too
busy getting engaged.
So, now that that's over,
what do you want to do?
Do you want to do
an aortic aneurysm?
Yes.
Do you want me to ask
Dr. Torres to give it to you?
No, Mother. I can get it myself.
There you go.
Dr. Bailey.
I am stoked for our Whipple
today. Are you stoked?
We, um...
No, we're not...
You gotta speak up.
We're not doing a Whipple today.
I had it taken from me.
Mandy. No.
Please don't call me Mandy.
We talked about this.
You can't let people
walk all over you.
You gotta stand up for yourself.
Not if it's Ellis Grey, I don't.
Ellis is operating?
Come on.
The next best thing to operating
is watching Ellis Grey do it.
We gotta get in on
that surgery, Mandy.
Remember what we say?
I don't remember what we say.
We create...
Oh. We create our own destiny.
Our own destiny.
That's right. Come on.
Chop, chop.
Hi there.
Oh, God.
What now?
Well, you OD'ed, your heart
stopped, but you're stable.
Can I get a name, please?
So you can call the cops?
I just need anything really,
so we don't mix up your
pee with somebody else's.
You have my pee?
Yeah. You were kinda
giving it away for a while there.
Spectacular.
Name?
Lucille. Okay.
Ball.
You're a funny lady.
Well, that's how
I make my living.
All right, Miss Ball.
We are gonna get you worked
up and send you on your way.
Hey, where am I?
Seattle Grace Hospital.
Oh, God.
Don't push. Theresa, don't push.
Kepner, what's happening?
She's dilated and effaced.
The baby started crowning
and then just stopped.
Okay, move.
Theresa, you're doing great.
Okay, Kepner, order
up a 3D ultrasound, stat,
and prep an OR for a crash
C-section. And page my husband.
Right away.
What happened?
He detached the connector
to the artificial lung,
and I had to clamp off the
cannula to stop the bleeding.
I told you this was a bad idea.
All right. Let's book an OR.
Let's get it hooked back up.
No, it's too dangerous. He
has to go back on ECMO.
It's not working, so he's worse?
Hold on. Everybody, stop.
Look at the Sat.
93? He's never been above
79. His respiratory rate's good.
Riley, is it hard for
you to breathe at all?
No, I can breathe.
Okay, hold on.
Blow in this, okay?
Oh! Wow!
What's happening?
He's breathing better
than he should be.
than he ever has.
So he can use it until
he gets the transplant?
We need to run
more tests, but...
From the sound of his lungs,
it's possible he may not
even need a transplant.
Are you serious? Well,
you know, we have to...
Are you serious? We
have to see the tests, but...
Oh, thank you! I
love you! I love you!
I think I do, too.
Okay.
Wait. What?
But why? Why can't
you do the surgery?
Uh, the Chief of
Surgery, Ellis Grey,
will be doing it.
I mean, I can. I
would. She just...
There's protocols, and she...
Think of it as a huge upgrade.
You just got handed
the keys to a Jaguar
and you've been
driving, like, a Civic.
A good car. A solid,
dependable car. But Dr. Grey...
Hello, Alex.
Mr. Taylor, Mrs.
Taylor, I'm Dr. Grey.
I'll be doing your
pancreaticoduodenectomy today.
I'll graft with a section
of your internal iliac vein,
a new technique of my invention.
By forgoing the
use of the jugular,
you'll have no visible
scarring on the neck.
Oh. Well, that's nice...
I'll gladly have you sign
these consent forms.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
I'll see you after we're done.
Jaguar. Doc... Dr. Grey.
Any chance I could
scrub in with you?
Alex, of course.
Love to have you.
See? You have to
speak up for yourself.
Can you explain anything
that woman just said?
You know, I, uh... Excuse me.
Here you go, sir.
Your heart stopped again.
Because of all the
cocaine you've enjoyed,
you're going to need
a surgical implant,
an AICD pacemaker.
If you have any questions
about this procedure,
here's an informative brochure.
She's a ray of sunshine.
She is.
I'm gonna go out on
a limb and assume
that you don't
have any insurance.
So is there somebody maybe
I can call, parents, somebody?
No. Parents are dead.
I'm sorry to hear that. Is it
from disease, family history?
My mother died of a stomach
thing. My father killed himself.
I am really sorry.
What's funny?
I do have a sister.
She's a half sister.
Okay. Nearby?
Very.
She's a doctor...
At this hospital.
What, are you kidding?
Who? Who? Who is she?
Hey, we've never met.
She doesn't know me.
And trust me,
she doesn't want to.
You paged?
Yeah, have a look
at her ultrasound.
That is a massive tumor.
What? Percy, shut up.
It's pressing up against the
neck. Is the airway secured?
I did an exit and trached her.
It's as secure as it can be for now.
Why can't I see my
baby? What's wrong?
Theresa, your baby has a tumor.
But Dr. Shepherd's here. He's
gonna take good care of her.
The Shepherds are the
best you and your baby
could hope for, okay?
They are an amazing team.
All right.
Wait. What's wrong with her?
What took you so long?
I wasn't standing around, Derek.
I had to make sure that the
mother wouldn't bleed out.
If we wait any longer, she
won't even be a mother.
It's pressing
against the trachea.
I need to make sure
the airway's secure.
The bleeders can't wait.
You have to work on
the neck as I operate.
It's gonna take us all day.
I'm sorry. I know
you weren't planning
on spending the
day with your wife.
I'll see you in there.
It's a beautiful
day to save lives.
Nice.
Oh, hey, darlin'. Hey.
What's up?
I have to steal a surgery
from Cristina Yang.
Well...
Yang's always
stealing surgeries.
That girl gives me the creeps.
I know. It's just...
Mom's operating today,
and I thought it would
be nice to go in and see it,
but she doesn't
want me in there, so...
Remember when you were
learning how to ride a bike
and you ran into the back of
the Richmonds' station wagon?
Vividly.
What happened after that?
I sat on the curb and
cried and bled all over you.
Well, after that?
You made me get back on my bike.
No.
Your mother made
you get back on,
and you learned to ride a bike.
She just wants you to succeed.
I know.
I'm doing a
proctocolectomy right now.
You want in? Single incision?
I probably shouldn't.
Yeah. Probably not.
How many aortic aneurysms
has she actually done?
Two, in the hospital.
She's probably done
more at home on cats.
Hey, does she eat
with anyone, ever?
No.
That's what happens to you
when you screw an attending.
You're a pariah.
Unlike your approach of just
never having sex with anybody?
No virgin jokes. Thank you.
Her and Preston Burke.
Really?
And apparently, it
was so scary for him,
he actually had
to leave the state.
I always say, never
mess with the crazy chicks.
She's probably gonna
go full-on Izzie one day
and shoot up the hospital.
What's Izzie?
Oh, it means crazy.
She was a girl in our class
who was sleeping with a patient.
And then she stole a
transplant heart for him.
What?
Until Meredith turned her
into her mom and got her fired.
Oh, my God, Mer.
You're so brave.
Hold on a second. How many
people washed out your year?
Two. Her and O'Malley.
007.
He failed his intern exam
and was never seen again.
Okay. Here I go.
Where are you going?
To get back on my bicycle. Oh!
Dr. Grey is gonna graft an
iliac vein to the portal vein,
but that man's got bilateral
deep vein thrombosis
in his femorals, and the
iliacs won't be usable.
I mean, she's gonna
look first, right?
Who's that woman
with Dr. Robbins?
I don't know. Some
ortho surgeon.
Oh.
I should've gone into
ortho. I liked ortho.
Why didn't you?
Well, when Ellis Grey
says you're good for cardio...
Excuse me, Dr. Torres.
I was wondering if I could
do the aortic aneurysm today.
This will be Yang's third,
and I've only done one.
So it's only fair...
Webber, I know how
many you've done.
And I know what my
residents need, okay?
My mother suggested
that I ask you.
Why don't you split it? You
and Yang can do it together.
Thank you.
Whatever Ellis Grey wants.
You know it.
Yang's not gonna like it.
Well, it's better than
kicking her off the case.
Bitch scares me.
Lucy.
You got some 'splaining to do.
I'm just gonna go.
No, you're not,
because if you don't get this
procedure, you're going to die.
Look, I get it. I
know. It is scary.
But I can tell you everything
that's gonna happen.
Yeah, I already
read the brochure.
Okay.
The automatic implanted
cardioverter defibrillator
is placed beneath the
skin below the collarbone.
The electrode wires... Wow.
Yeah, I have a
photographic memory.
Yeah. Okay. Well, you
should go to med school.
Right. Or I could
be a ballerina.
I'm serious.
Okay? You should see all
of this as a second chance.
People turn things around
all the time. You're smart.
You're sharp. You're beautiful.
You got a sister here
you've never even met.
You could have a
whole new family.
Let's start by fixing
your heart, okay?
Oh, okay.
All right.
It's gonna be okay.
What the hell is Meredith Webber
doing on my aortic aneurysm?
Uh...
Listen, if you tell Meredith
or Ellis or anyone...
That surgery is mine. You can't
just throw your girlfriend on it.
I swear, Yang.
I will fix it so you never see
the inside of an OR again.
I will bury you.
I'm not sharing my surgery.
Change the board and get her off.
Look, I didn't change
the board. Torres did.
Where's Torres then?
CSF is leaking. Let's get
some suction in here, Percy.
I need you to have lunch
with the president of the board
of the Bryson school tomorrow.
Why are you talking
about this now?
Because, Derek,
you're never home.
You're always spending
the night in that stupid trailer
on that stupid piece of land,
planning that stupid house
that you're never gonna build.
Pulse ox is dropping.
What did you do?
I didn't do anything. It's
invading the tracheal wall. Clamp.
Secure the airway.
We're losing her.
I'm working as
hard as I can, Derek.
You just pay attention
to what you're doing.
Do me a favor.
I'm going into surgery.
Yeah, just, tell Dr. Grey that
the patient has
a history of DVT.
And that the iliac veins may
not be suitable for grafting.
Wait. Wait. What? Why
didn't you say something?
Just... You're going
in there. Just tell her.
You tell her. He's your patient.
I'm not gonna tell
her she's wrong.
I mean, she took the
chart. She read it, right?
Yes. She knows what she's doing.
Well, just tell her.
Yang, wait.
When in the hell are you
gonna give Lucille Ball her AICD?
You have to do
it. I've got surgery.
I don't think so.
You did the consult.
Where's your wife? What?
She was supposed to put a
pacemaker in our OD girl hours ago,
and now she's trying
to pawn it off on me.
Hey. I have a surgery.
You're the cardio
consult. You do it.
Avery can do it.
I can't spare Avery.
I'm not giving up this surgery
to stick a pacemaker in a junkie.
Tell your wife to have
Meredith Webber...
Yang, just back off!
I'm sorry. I just...
I just got really...
Well, you won't need stitches.
This time.
I thought it was supposed
to be getting better.
Or are you gonna
hit another intern?
No.
Why do you keep helping me?
Why don't you just report me?
Because I'm a doctor.
Please don't tell my wife.
Well, you can finish the
rest of this. I have surgery.
Suction here.
So June sounds good. Have
you thought about where?
Oh. Meredith and I
thought about Hawaii.
That might be cool.
You know, have
everyone come out and...
Really, a destination wedding?
Alex, I'm running a hospital.
I can't just dash off to...
Retract that, please. Clamp.
You'll do it here. I'll
book the Rainier Club.
It's gorgeous.
That sounds great.
What the hell am I looking at?
The iliac veins are
completely thrombosed,
both of them. Unusable.
Completely unusable.
Did you know about this?
No.
Okay. Change of plans.
We'll use the renal vein.
Damn it.
Someone page Dr. Bailey, please.
I want her in here now.
Why aren't you doing a TEVAR?
I'm doing a direct
approach. It's cooler.
A TEVAR is safer.
It's far less invasive.
You go in through the femoral,
you don't have to crack the chest.
I already ordered the graft.
You two might have worked
out your surgical plan before this.
I did, and my surgical plan
didn't include this nimrod.
No, it just included hacking
up the patient like a psychopath.
Girls, don't make me come
over there and do it myself.
Shut up and work.
10 blade. 10 blade.
Avery.
Where have you been?
I'm booking an OR.
I'm gonna take my... That
girl up for her pacemaker.
Why?
Somebody made off
with an armload of drugs
from the dispensary,
codeine, morphine, Demerol.
Okay, why...
'Cause the dispensary was
accessed with your ID card.
That's why.
Damn it.
But you knew the
patient had thrombosis?
I...
I had... I did.
Speak up.
In the legs... Yes.
Did you look at his chart?
Of course I looked at his chart.
But there was no indication
that the thrombosis was this bad.
Why wasn't it in his chart?
Because I had chosen
to use the jugular.
They were in the
medical records.
And you didn't tell me
because I'd opted to
not cut the man's throat?
Well, that's...
It's a good plan...
But I ended up cutting
his throat anyway.
My procedure's a wash,
and the patient's been under
far longer than is optimal.
That's why I picked the jugular.
Is that right, Dr. Bailey?
Is that why you picked it?
Alex, where's my graft?
Here's the graft.
I'm just suturing.
Whoa!
Oh, my God.
I might have nicked the carotid.
You people are
trying to kill me.
Did you get the whole tumor?
I told you.
I'm not asking for myself.
I'm asking what I
should tell the mother...
Just go. I will
talk to her myself.
So we'll talk about
the preschool...
It's gonna be late.
I'm gonna stay
and look into
this clinical trial.
That's great.
One more reason for you
to stay out of the house.
That's fine.
It's fine. Maybe you'll be more
interested once the baby comes.
Right.
Everything's gonna be
different when the baby comes.
Well, a girl can hope.
Nothing's gonna change.
What do you think
is gonna change?
Do you even want a
baby? I didn't say that.
I'm not talking...
Yes, I want a baby.
No, I'm not talking about
a baby. This baby, with me.
Do you love me?
Do you?
Of course I love you.
Can you say it without
looking at the floor?
Less than three minutes
of circulatory arrest left.
You go over that, and
the organs start dying.
If Webber hadn't
taken so long...
I took the time it
needed. Two minutes.
- Done. Go back on bypass.
- Yes, Doctor.
Oh. Got a leak.
Okay, I'll find it.
I'll throw a stitch.
No, it's too risky.
The leak is behind the heart.
You need to do an internal graft.
Will you shut
up? I will find it.
Dr. Torres?
Webber's right, Yang.
Her way is safer. Let her do it.
5-0 prolene.
Move your hands.
Move your hands, please.
What are you doing?
Move your hands.
I got it. I found the leak.
Give me a clamp.
2-0 prolene. I got it.
Have you seen my wife?
As a matter of fact, I have.
She just threatened to quit.
Do me a favor. Wash your
laundry at home, not in my OR.
Well, there's two
sides to every story...
Yeah, I'm not
interested in your side.
Derek, Richard and I had
very high hopes for you,
but you have been nothing
but a disappointment.
You don't publish, you don't
teach, your attitude is terrible.
The residents have a nickname
for you, and it is not flattering.
What do they call
me? Get it together.
Because if it comes down to
a choice between you and her,
you need to be very clear
which one of you I will choose.
Trust me, you two don't
want to be the next Shepherds.
So I start to do the repair...
And she just stuck
her hand in? Yes!
Wait. What happened?
Yang's a freakin' maniac.
She's dangerous.
My patient's fine.
Awake, great vitals,
if you were interested.
Well, that's great
'cause OD girl bolted.
You had no business
shoving in there.
You had no business in that OR.
I wasn't about
to let that guy die
watching you jack around
with the internal graft.
That was the right technique.
Dr. Torres specifically...
Dr. Torres only sided with you
because you're the Chief's little girl.
She's a pathetic lackey.
Well, we'd all be working under
Dr. Preston Burke right now,
but you screwed us out
of that opportunity, literally.
What exactly did you do to him?
Because he left the
state to get away from you.
Good one.
If you want to get personal,
why don't you ask prince charming
what he and the virgin
Mary like to do in his office?
What? What are
you talking about?
What...
She's a lunatic. What
is she talking about?
You can't believe a word she
says. She's just... Come on!
April?
I'm sorry. I'm...
I'm sorry. I...
Oh, God.
Just shoot me now.
Tests are good. SATs are
great. He's breathing unassisted.
He's gonna be home
by the end of the week.
And he's been taken
off the transplant list?
Yep, yep. Two weeks
on your little thing,
and his lungs are
actually improved.
Well, good work.
Oh, amazing work. And
I didn't even want to do it.
It was amazing. You're amazing.
Well, um, we should
celebrate, sometime.
Yeah, we should. We
should go get drinks.
I mean, this is... This
is one to celebrate.
Dr. Torres, here are your kids.
Yeah.
Mommy.
Hi, baby girl.
Hi. Okay.
Well... Sometime.
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, sometime.
All right. Here we go.
Slow down, and tell me.
I can't.
I mean, I can't believe them.
I cannot believe them!
I heard what happened.
You did? Yes.
And you should be upset.
You should be
humiliated. Ellis...
You don't let Yang,
you don't let anyone
show you up in your OR.
Understand? Ever.
I shouldn't have been in
there. I wasn't prepared.
Then why in the
world did you go in?
Because you pushed me.
And you aren't mad
because I embarrassed myself.
You're mad because
I embarrassed you.
Ellis, what in the
hell is wrong with...
I want you to fire Mandy Bailey.
Tonight, Richard. I
want you to do it tonight.
What are you talking
about? What is this about?
She made a complete fool of me.
I had no idea, no idea at all.
I looked like a total failure.
Okay, look... Now
look, just hold on.
Now just...
Just breathe.
I was humiliated.
Okay.
In front of all those people.
I was just trying to
fix her stupid mistake.
I know.
I looked like a fraud.
But you know you're
not. You know that.
Like an idiot.
There was nothing to graft.
Okay, look, okay,
but you made it work.
You always do.
The patient is fine.
Look, you can't
control everything.
I know you want to.
But you can't, okay?
Is Meredith all right?
I don't know how to talk to
her, Richard. Will you talk to her?
Yeah, I will, I will.
She'll be all right.
I am horrible at
it. I am terrible.
I just want her to do well. I just
want her to do the best she can...
I know. I know you do.
And she'll be okay, okay?
I promise. Okay?
Thank you.
Okay. Okay.
Yang. Hey.
Thanks... For today.
Tell your wife
and get some help.
She'll leave, and I'll
lose my kids. She...
She's...
She's afraid I'm
gonna hurt one of them.
Aren't you?
Hey. Hey.
Hey. How are ya?
Okay. Oh, my gosh.
What happened to your hand?
Oh, I...
I... Some junkie
patient knocked me
into a tray of
instruments, so...
Oh, you poor baby. All
right. Let's get you home,
and I'll take a look
at it, okay? Okay.
Okay, let's go. Come on, Allegra.
- Come on. Let's go.
All right.
I need help.
She was just lying in the
street. I almost ran her over.
Okay, we've got this.
Pulse is v-tach.
Where's the crash cart?
360. Sir, step back.
It's all right. I'm a doctor.
Yeah, we're all doctors,
all right? Now move.
Clear.
Charge to 300. Clear.
Sinus tach. We got her.
Okay.
You know where I
can find Dr. Shepherd?
Which one?
Meredith.
No, Dad.
Don't come and clean
up after her again.
You do it every time.
And it's beneath
you, and it's pointless.
I can't do anything
right for her.
Your mother doesn't want...
And I finally figured out why.
She wants everyone
around her to be ordinary
so she can be extraordinary.
She wants everyone
around her small.
You stop it.
And that's what
she's done to you.
She has made you small.
And I'm not gonna
let her do it to me.
I don't know what's
wrong with me.
All I know is that the baby
is coming and I want it.
You know, it may change things.
You'll get happier.
We'll just take it one step at
a time. I want to make it work.
It isn't your baby.
It's stupid, I know, but
it's a brand-new shirt
and now it's got
junkie blood all over it.
Oh.
This is awkward.
Clear.
I've got a rhythm.
Barely, but...
Damn it. It's gone.
If you had just done
the damn surgery...
Asystole. Give her
1 amp of atropine.
I already did it,
okay? It's not helping.
Another, and an
amp of epi. Do it.
Go!
Move. Let's crack her chest.
Gown. What?
No. It's not
indicated. She OD'ed.
Okay, so she's gonna die
anyway. What has she got to lose?
Chest tray. WOMAN: Here you go.
Okay, let's do it. Betadine.
10 Blade. - On it.
Are you crying?
I screwed up.
I had a good thing.
She was a good person, but...
I had a chance to be better.
And I screwed it up like
I do every frickin' time.
What the hell is wrong with me?
I just lost my job.
Do you see me crying?
I have no earthly
idea what to do next,
but am I hiding in an elevator,
whimpering about it?
No.
Because what do we say, Alex?
What do we say?
We create...
Our own destiny. Our
own destiny. Uh-huh.
And that's exactly
what I'm gonna do.
You should, too.
Guys, you lost her.
Shut up! Shut up!
One more amp of
epi. Charge to 20.
Charging.
Charged.
Clear.
Charge to 30.
Ready? Go. Clear.
Sinus tach.
Wait. Wait.
Your life is a gift.
Accept it.
She's back. Okay,
we got her. We got her.
No matter how screwed
up or painful it seems to be.
Okay, now what do I do?
Okay, lick it, slam
it, and then lime.
Okay.
Fast, fast, fast, fast. Yeah.
Okay. That's good.
What?
We don't have to do that
thing where I say something
and then you say something
and then someone cries
and there's a
moment or whatever?
Oh, yuck.
Good.
It's just that...
Nothing is turning out
the way I thought it would.
It's like I don't even
recognize my own life.
I know what you mean.
Some things are
going to work out
as if they were
destined to happen.
Ugh! I gotta go get some
sleep. You gotta get some sleep.
You look like crap.
I look better than you.
Not possible.
Your mother says the
residents have a name for me.
I wouldn't know
anything about that.
What is it? What
do they call me?
Come on.
McDreary.
We call you McDreary.
You think that's funny?
It's apt.
McDreary.
Yeah, that's my life.
So how about tonight, you're
not McDreary? You're just...
You're just a guy in a bar.
And you're just a girl in a bar?
I am.
And I drink tequila.
Tom.
Here you go.
Cheers.
As if they were
just meant to be.