You're not in it alone.
Coming through!
It's a nice thought,
but pretty useless in an O.R.
Heads up!
Behind you!
Get her to CT.
Clear trauma
one, two, and three.
And let CT know
we'll be rolling
upstairs in a few minutes.
Uh, okay, these guys go straight
to the front of the line.
- Okay, Altman, take Parker.
- Got it.
Page everyone.
It's all hands on deck.
Come on.
Let's move. Move, move!
Hey, hey, hey, if you're gonna
be here, so am I, alright?
Give me privileges.
I can hop in.
Uh, okay, see if Altman
needs help with Parker.
After that,
go where needed in the E.R.
But, Ben, that's it.
I can't have you in an O.R.
Okay, let's move.
The better you are
as a surgeon...
...the more likely it is
that no one else
can do what you can do.
A good outcome, a loss...
100% of that
rests solely on your shoulders.
It's a ridiculous amount
of pressure.
- Schmitt.
- I'm sorry.
I just... I-I-I-I don't know
why I'm in here.
Oh, you were in the bar.
Uh, are you hurt?
No.
I'm j... Uh, no.
I, uh... But my friends.
Mm. I hear you.
But right now,
your friends need your help.
And mine, too.
So, look,
whatever we're f-feeling,
we put it aside
and we help.
Come on, let's go.
Let's go.
Let's go to work.
And I've seen
it shatter the best of us.
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 16  Episode 10
Title: "Help Me Through the Night
Shh.
He had a really hard day.
Yeah, and it just got harder
'cause now he's been kidnapped.
I didn't kidnap him.
I just didn't take him
to the hospital right away.
He wasn't ready.
I-I don't think
a Safe Haven volunteer's
supposed to make
that decision.
I just wanted him
to have one cozy night
before a social worker turns him
into a pile of paperwork.
Oh, my God.
It's the cops.
Okay, okay.
Wait, don't answer
the door.
Wait, wait!
Answer the door,
and tell them
that I brought the baby here
for a wellness check with Alex.
He's a peds doctor.
He's in Iowa.
Who is it?
It's Meredith.
Oh, it's Meredith.
Let her in.
You're not Alex.
Oh, yeah, he's, uh,
visiting his mom.
Well, Cristina sent
an obnoxious Irishman as a gift
and he stole
your husband's old job.
And who is that?
Oh, we already have
a bottle open.
Can you get her a glass?
Jo stole a baby.
I did not steal a baby.
Well, that's what I said
when I stole a baby.
Why are people
stealing babies?
He was left
at Station 19,
and they called me
to take him to the hospital,
and I... didn't.
Well, because you didn't want
him to go into the system
and have a miserable life
like you did.
Exactly.
She gets it.
But I'm a convicted felon.
She's a convicted felon.
- She's a felon.
- She's a convicted felon.
Oh, no.
Multiple traumas.
We should go back
to the hospital.
You know what?
I've had two glasses of wine,
- so I really can't.
- Don't worry.
We'll call on the way,
tell peds a Safe Haven's there
waiting for
a wellness check.
You can sneak him
into the nursery,
pretend he's been there
all night...
Like he should
have been.
Come on.
Hey, I just heard.
Is everyone alive?
So far.
Uh, do you know
if Maggie has been paged?
I kinda have a thing,
a personal... a talk thing,
need to... a girl talk.
Uh, girl thing.
Can you smile for me?
Ew, don't be that guy,
Tom.
No, I want to make sure
you're not having a stroke.
- Pierce quit.
- What? Why?
Dr. Mahoney to the E.R.
Hey, big trauma?
You should head upstairs.
Elliott Calhoun was just
transferred to the CCU on ECMO.
Go up there, sit with him,
hold his wife's hand, whatever.
His heart
still hasn't restarted.
I'm chief resident.
I-I should go...
He has a premature baby
and a hole in his chest.
You should go
where I say you should go.
We need more O-neg!
I need some
bandages over here.
Get his vitals
right away.
How bad is it?
Simms and Helm
got the worst of it...
Well, if you don't count
the couple who were in the car.
It's okay,
it's okay, it's okay.
Who is that?
Dr. Karev
is a Safe Haven volunteer,
and she is taking the baby
to the nursery.
Right, Dr. Karev?
Yep. Here I go.
So, how'd the ultrasound go?
Everything okay?
Everything is...
Yes. Uh, baby's healthy,
uh, great, developing.
Uh, Lincoln, Shepherd,
can you guys jump in here?
Not only are we swamped,
but we're short-staffed.
Well, not anymore,
because I've called in reinforcements.
Wha... Webber and Hunt were
fired from this hospital.
Lay off, Koracick.
Look, I don't care.
They are my students.
I hired them.
Okay, temporary privileges granted.
We need the help.
Everyone, gowns and gloves,
and keep up.
Blake Simms,
mid-face instability,
criked in the field.
Needs to head up to CT ASAP.
- Hunt, join Avery.
- Yep.
I should be in here.
In case there's any neuro.
Any other requests
from the peanut gallery?
Good. Moving on.
Taryn Helm,
hemodynamically stable,
tib-fib fracture,
but complains of pain
in the pelvis,
so we need a pelvic X-ray,
chest X-ray,
F.A.S.T. exam,
the works.
Webber,
Lincoln, Grey, go.
Where's Andrew DeLuca?
Uh, around here
somewhere.
No, with patients.
He's working.
- Oh.
- He's okay, Meredith.
Okay.
Casey Parker... he took
a nasty blow to the head.
He's got a palpable
scalp hematoma.
Did a bomb go off?
We're taking him up
to CT now.
Uh, uh, well,
you've got Shepherd.
And here I am.
♪ Before you do it again ♪
Hey, how is she?
Minor lacs and bruises,
but... neuro check's clear.
I'm okay.
I want to help.
Get cleaned up.
Then jump in wherever needed.
♪ You came in
and you took me by surprise ♪
- And, uh, what about you?
- What about me?
You good to operate
on your residents?
Wouldn't be the first time.
♪ Precious crimes,
my body's sinking ♪
- Thanks for coming.
- Oh, thanks for calling.
She seems okay.
She's not.
I mean,
she says she is, but I...
She's working through
a miscarriage.
She hasn't had time
to take a break yet.
I... I can't be there
in that O.R. with her,
so someone else who loves her
needs to be there.
In case she breaks.
Of course.
Thank you.
Warren.
Are you okay?
No.
But Miranda comes first.
♪ Mm-mm-mm,
mm-mm-mm, mm-mm-mm ♪
♪ Mm-mm-mm, mm-mm-mm,
mm-mm-mm ♪
There was a bomb.
No, Casey, it wasn't
a bomb. It was a car.
Stay nice and still, okay?
Are we in the green zone?
He was
in the military, right?
Mm.
Do you think he has PTSD?
We all do.
War. Life.
How far along are you?
Oh, um...
20 weeks-ish?
They're always a little off,
though, right?
With the whole
counting-from-ovulation thing?
When I hit 30 weeks,
I thought
I was gonna pop.
Temporal lobe contusion.
Yeah, explains
the PTSD exacerbation.
He needs to be in the neuro ICU,
closely monitored,
with q2 hour checks.
Dr. Shepherd,
I just stepped out for a minute
to prep the next patient,
and when I came back...
Hi, Doctor.
Oh, my God. Ah.
Chief, there seem to be
a lot of doctors in here,
and I don't want to get in
the way of anyone,
- specifically...
- You're in my way.
Move. Forward.
How are we?
- Oh, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- I'm fantastic.
Dr. Grey is here.
- Hi, Dr. Grey.
- Hi, Helm.
Jackson gave her
a whiskey sedative at the scene
to set her leg.
I just gave her a little bit
of fentanyl for the pain.
And the X-ray doesn't show
pelvic fractures.
CT showed an infrarenal
IVC injury with a clot...
That's near my kidney.
It also showed
a small retrohepatic hematoma
- by the IVC.
- Oh, no.
I'm bruised in the liver.
Doppler shows, uh,
vascular compromise to the foot,
which is probably due
to the fracture,
so I'd like to get her
to an O.R. ASAP.
We should put in
an IVC filter
to reduce the risk
of pulmonary embolism. - Mm.
But he just said
my foot could die.
Don't worry, Helm, we got you.
She's not wrong.
I can do the filter
while she's getting prepped
in the O.R. for her leg.
Okay.
Let's get to work.
Can I scrub in?
Sure.
Bailey.
Uh, you have full privileges,
so jump in wherever needed.
Uh, Ben called me.
He shouldn't have
done that.
But like I said,
jump in wherever needed.
Look.
Where are we
on Blake Simms?
Uh, doesn't appear to be any
traumatic brain injuries.
Leave that
to the expert, Red.
Yep, no epidural, subdural,
or subarachnoid hemorrhage.
How many of these
have you done?
Me?
I'm sure
it's in our records.
More than 20?
This is a rare injury,
the surgery extensive...
I have had
a long night, Tom.
I don't have the energy
to defend myself
to you. - I'm well aware
of your night, Avery.
It's just dumb luck those scans
aren't of you. Or Brody.
You're about to peel off
my protégé's face
and bolt his fractured facial
bones back into their place.
I want to make
sure that you're in
the right state of
mind to do that.
I'm good.
Go babysit someone else.
Okay, let's, um,
take him up to the O.R.
Brody, do you know
of any relatives
that we can
reach out to?
I didn't even know his first
name till I saw it on the scan.
His grandmother's local.
I'll call her.
Brody,
just get him to the O.R.
- Hi.
- Hello.
So, who do we have here?
Oh, Dr. Karev.
Jo Karev.
Nice to meet you.
But I meant the baby.
Oh, right, yes.
Uh, so, boy.
- Less than three days old.
- Mm-hmm.
Bottle feeding's
been good.
- He's sleeping well.
- Mm-hmm.
Good job.
Oh, there we go.
Okay.
Let's get that hat off.
Let's have a look. Shh.
- Normal chest contour.
- Okay.
Motor function.
Oh, yeah.
Does this hospital
have a baby hatch?
A what?
A baby hatch.
It's like a post box
but for babies.
That sounds not great.
No, actually,
they're brilliant.
Decorated like
a little nursery inside,
connect
straight to the E.R.
Mum puts the baby in.
A sensor notifies
the staff to come.
My last hospital had one.
They're safe and anonymous.
Where was
your last hospital?
That was in Switzerland.
Oh, you're him?
Him?
You're new guy.
New chief of peds guy.
Well, yes,
I suppose I am.
Oh, you're related
to the old chief of peds? Okay.
Yes. Wife.
I've heard good things.
About me?
Um, no,
but, um,
let's have a listen.
I got nothing.
- You?
- Nothing.
- Hey.
What are you doing
up here?
Uh, scrubbing in
with Avery on Simms.
Type III
Le Fort fracture.
- Ugh.
- Oof.
Yeah, it's bad.
And Koracick's leaning heavy on
Avery to get
the reconstruction right.
Well, making sure we get things
right is Tom's job.
Yeah, well,
being an ass about it isn't.
What are you two
looking for?
Parker's MIA
with a temporal lobe contusion
and a nasty episode of PTSD
about a really big bomb.
Well, if I were scared
about a bomb,
I'd be looking
for a bomb shelter.
Maybe check the morgue
and the basement,
and I'll meet you in security.
- Owen.
- Yeah?
Cut Tom some slack.
Umbrella filter
has been deployed.
She's got
the umbrella in.
Thank you, Helm.
You're welcome.
Are you gonna fix
my tib-fib, too?
I don't do bones.
Me neither.
And these are not
regular bones.
These are my bones.
Helm bones.
Helmones.
Helm-mouth.
I get it.
Dr. Schmitt,
let's prep her,
and let's remind Dr. Kim
and Dr. Lincoln
to check her neck for hematomas
and recheck her H&H.
- Mm, no, no.
- No Schmitt.
It's his fault
you left me.
- Helm...
- He got the love of my life fired.
Which is you.
Surprise.
I love you,
Meredith Grey.
And I know it's stupid
and I should get over it,
and I will
if I ever meet anyone else.
I'm starting to think
I never will.
I'm embarrassed now, so I'm...
I'm gonna go prep myself.
Thank you for that, Helm.
Thank you.
We'll have Dr. Kim
prep you, okay?
Kim's a traitor-lover.
Schmitt,
let's go downstairs.
Dr. Schmitt?
- Hey! Guys!
- Oh, my God. Levi.
Schmitt.
What?
What's happening?
You fainted in the O.R.,
Schmitt.
I'm doing
a full work-up.
I fainted and you're okay
being my doctor?
I couldn't really leave you
there on the O.R. floor.
They could take away
my license for that.
Your blood work
all looks good,
except for your cardiac enzymes
are slightly elevated,
which could indicate...
I'm having a heart attack?
That's very unlikely
at your age,
but I'm gonna do an echo
just to be sure.
I'm not even 30.
I take fish oil
every morning.
And, y-yeah,
I had double cheeseburgers
every day freshman year,
but since then,
I-I've been pretty good.
Okay, but you do need
to calm down, Schmitt.
Okay?
Is there anyone
I can call for you?
Well, I'd say my mom,
but she'd only panic.
Probably have
her own heart attack.
And then I'd say
Taryn Helm,
but she hates me
because of what I did to you,
and she's dying.
So then I'd say Nico,
but he's in the O.R.,
saving Taryn's life.
There's no one to call.
Take a deep breath,
Schmitt.
I gotcha.
Any updates?
We just finished
temporarily wiring his jaw,
and now we're doing
our coronal incision
to expose the superior orbit
and zygoma.
Alright, keep me posted.
Every update.
You know what, Tom?
You might as well
bring in a camera crew here.
Really great press.
Plenty of human drama
and vulnerability to exploit.
You'd love it.
- No?
- Okay.
Lap pads.
I do not miss that guy.
Nope. Suction.
Altman could do
so much better.
Meaning?
Are you serious?
Altman's a badass.
She's smart and skilled
and hot.
Koracick's just like
a creepy frat-house uncle.
She has done better, Brody.
She's with Hunt.
Periosteal elevator,
please.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
It's just the way
that he talks to her...
Yeah, don't worry about it.
Skin hooks, please.
Owen, these flaps
are coming along pretty nicely.
Speaking of which, how are you two doing?
You set a date yet?
W-We're...
We're not engaged.
- Really?
- Mnh-mnh.
Wow. I figured 'cause you have
two kids together,
you live together,
you marry everyone...
but... I guess you have been busy,
haven't you?
Okay, let's, um, take a look
at these fractures.
Sure.
Almost done here.
If you want to tap out,
it's cool.
I'm fine.
Your boyfriend
did just collapse.
Helm needed
a plate and screws,
so I'm doing
a plate and screws.
Me stopping to freak out
won't change the outcome
of Levi's condition.
And, plus,
Helm is Levi's best friend.
Fair enough.
She's hypotensive
and tachycardic.
- Page Bailey.
- Right away, Dr. Lincoln.
He's not in the morgue.
Did you check the exits?
Backed up all the tapes
half an hour.
I didn't see him leave.
Here's the basement.
I can do this without you
if you want to go.
He's a veteran
and he's suffering.
We send people overseas and we
ask them to give up their lives,
their health,
their families,
and when they come home,
we don't even give them
mental health care.
Owen.
And Riggs. And Megan.
And...
And me.
I can't imagine.
Do you think that Owen's...
God.
Forget it.
It's not appropriate.
Do I think Owen's what?
Mm, triggered.
PTSD is about patterns.
Owen has a history
of feeling trapped.
By fear of disappointing,
fear of hurting people,
trapped by obligations.
And I arrived here with a belly
full of a heavy obligation.
Honestly, Teddy, I don't think
that Owen is triggered.
I think...
he loves you.
Well,
he hasn't proposed.
And I feel really embarrassed
saying that out loud,
but it's, uh...
You know, it's... it's not like
I'm a stupid little girl
waiting for a ring
from a man.
- It's just...
- Hang on.
If he felt trapped
by an obligation,
don't you think
he would've proposed by now?
I really think
he's just...
trying to do things
differently.
You are incredibly kind,
Amelia Shepherd.
There.
Parker.
The hyperbaric chamber.
Bomb shelter.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
Talk to me.
We repaired her leg, and her
vitals just plummeted.
She's hypotensive
with a worsening base deficit.
Uh, did you check
her abdomen?
No.
Abdomen's distended.
Okay, prep for an ex-lap
and call Dr. Grey.
Okay.
I-I can assist.
Dr. Webber.
Look, I hired Dr. Helm.
I'm gonna help,
and you can't stop me.
- His heart.
- What is it? What's wrong?
It's coming back.
It's... It's beating.
His heart's beating.
Okay, uh, need to try
and wean him off
the pacing wires and ECMO.
Oh, my God.
Page Dr. Altman.
- Right away, Doctor.
- Oh, my God.
Parker?
We got incoming.
Lieutenant Parker,
permission to approach.
Hi.
I am right here,
Parker.
We're in a hospital.
You're at Grey-Sloan.
Hey.
We're safe.
Okay?
You want to come with me
and we'll get you some help?
Okay.
I got you.
I got you. Yep.
Here we go.
It's alright.
Oh.
Dr. Altman, Elliott Calhoun's
heart started beating again.
He's ready to
come off ECMO.
Whoa.
Parker, what happened?
He took a blow to the head
at Joe's.
Did you get into
a bar fight?
There was an accident
at Joe's Bar.
Casey and some
of the residents were there.
We are taking him up to the ICU
to monitor his contusion.
Damn it.
Grey needs me.
- It... It's Schmitt.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Schmitt was there, too?
What the hell happened?
Apparently,
it's cardiomyopathy.
I need to meet them
in the cath lab.
What about Elliott Calhoun?
Alright, why don't you prep him?
Clear an O.R.
I will go handle Schmitt,
and then I'll join you
when I can.
Page me with any updates
on Parker.
The rash is just
a little erythema toxicum, so...
But it's not remarkable.
Nothing to worry about.
So I think we can bring in
social services
for his placement.
Shh.
Maybe we can
wait for another couple of minutes.
What do you think?
Do you have kids?
Yes. Two.
Boys. Teenagers.
Hellions.
- You?
- No. No, not yet.
I'm just volunteering.
Oh, hello.
I was in residency
when my boys were this age.
All the pictures I have with
them, my eyes are half-closed.
I love my boys,
but sometimes I think
I probably missed
their perfect stage, you know?
Yeah, he's pretty perfect.
Don't know how you even
brought this guy in.
I think I would've
stolen him.
The subcostal incision
isn't enough.
Uh, can you visualize
the IVC?
I can't see from my side.
Okay, we need
to extend up to a sternotomy
to get better
visualization.
Clamp the IVC
from all directions
so I can isolate the bleed.
You want to crack
her chest, too?
No, but I don't want her
to die,
and this is the only way
we can get control.
You can do it
if you feel more comfortable.
Scalpel.
Get the saw ready.
Okay.
Very good alignment.
Dr. Hunt,
the E.R. is asking
if we can spare anyone
for an intake.
Uh, Brody, we got this.
But we haven't
closed the skin yet.
Dr. Avery is perfectly capable
of doing it, so...
Okay?
Thanks, Brody.
It's not her fault she didn't
know about you and Teddy.
Listen,
I want to marry Teddy, okay?
- It's just complicated.
- How's it complicated?
- I'm afraid.
- That you'll screw the whole thing up?
I am afraid
it won't be big enough
to make up for the fact
that I didn't do this sooner.
And I'm not talking about
the months
since Allison's been here.
I'm talking about years,
decades.
That is a lot of pressure.
But pressure or not,
don't wait too long.
If it's somebody you feel like
you want to be with forever,
that should include now.
What part of "updates
at every stage" was unclear?
Well, you know how it is
when you're in the zone.
Sometimes you just forget
everything else, right?
Fractures are reduced.
We're ready to reattach
the coronal flap.
I mean, unless you want to check
my handiwork first.
No need.
Alright.
We're ready for closure.
4-0 Vicryl, please.
Whoa.
Wait, Avery.
Koracick, look.
There is clear fluid
around the blood. Look.
CSF fluid's leaking
from his brain, damn it.
- You said scans didn't indicate...
- Well, it doesn't matter now, does it?
I got to find the leak
and seal it.
I said updates every stage.
If I hadn't shown up,
he'd be dead on your table.
Suture scissors.
Now, when I clamp
the intrapericardial IVC,
she'll flatline,
and then I have about a minute
to find the bleeding.
You'll have
less than a minute.
Alright, on my count.
1, 2...
3.
Starting cardiac massage.
Oh, man, I still can't see it.
It's too much blood.
Suction.
Do not die.
Do you hear me?
You are not dying.
You are not dying today.
Okay.
I will not let you.
No one is dying.
Ah, okay. There, there, there.
I found it.
Okay. 6-0 Prolene.
Okay, Richard, seconds.
Okay,
I'm repairing the IVC.
Hold it.
Richard.
Hold on.
We're gonna lose her!
Got it.
I'm releasing the clamp.
Good.
Okay.
Come on, come on.
Ah!
Ah.
She's back.
- Great job, doctors.
- Alright.
- Ah!
- Alright!
Okay. Okay. Okay.
You should so hate me
right now.
Schmitt, try and relax.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Schmitt!
I forgive you.
I have my license.
I have my job.
I forgive you.
But I need you to be quiet
and stay still
so Dr. Altman
can do her job.
Okay.
Dr. Altman, am I dying?
No, it just felt like it.
No blockages?
No, he didn't have
a heart attack.
It appears
from the echo and angio
that he has
broken-heart syndrome.
What's that?
It's when you have the symptoms
of a heart attack...
Chest pain,
shortness of breath...
But there's nothing wrong.
It's rare.
Comes from extreme stress.
No. Schmitt's as cool
as a cucumber.
No, I'm not. I'm the most
stressed-out person...
Oh, you're kidding.
I'm kidding.
Oh.
I'm glad
you're okay.
♪ The world was in my hands,
it was weighing on my... ♪
You may have gotten off
to a bumpy start,
but you're gonna be
just fine, buddy.
You got people
looking out for you,
people who love you.
Never doubt that.
♪ Here on my knees ♪
♪ Show me where to start ♪
Okay.
♪ And tell me how to stop ♪
♪ Let the strength of my heart ♪
Thank you, Dr. Karev.
♪ Be the weight of your love ♪
♪ When I fall apart ♪
You okay?
♪ I know I'll rise above ♪
When I signed up to volunteer,
I just wanted to heal me.
But I...
I fell a little bit in love
with him.
Is that weird?
Uh, you're asking
the wrong guy.
I'm in love with a baby
that hasn't even been born yet.
I went from being terrified
about being a father to...
I'm just sunk.
And, uh,
if this Safe Haven thing
is too much for you,
you are welcome to come hang
with our kid anytime you want.
As long as there's no
kidnapping involved.
Are you... I...
♪ Of your love ♪
Thank you.
Helm's gonna be okay.
You can tell her it was my call
to crack the chest.
What about, uh, Simms?
Linda said
they just closed,
and they are taking him up
to the ICU now.
And Parker?
They found him.
Shepherd's been
monitoring him.
She's optimistic,
and, uh,
his recovery will take awhile.
Anyone figure out
what happened to Schmitt?
Heartbreak syndrome,
apparently.
He'll need
a few weeks rest.
Bailey, everyone's fine.
Everyone.
Everyone I touched today,
everyone I held in my hands
or gave
to another surgeon
to put back
together again,
and fine.
I lose you and Grey,
Hunt, Karev,
but I made that fine.
I made that work.
But this... this...
This I...
I am not fine.
She isn't fine!
And I can't even
hold her in my hands
or put her
in someone else's hands
who could put her
back together again.
She just was!
Oh, God.
And now she isn't.
And I can't do anything
but just stand here...
Stand here and lose her.
Hey.
My heart was broken.
Mine too.
Taryn's out of surgery.
She's okay.
- Can I go see her?
- Yeah.
In a minute.
He did have facial fractures
we were able to fix,
and then we discovered he had
fluid leaking from his brain,
but Dr. Koracick
was able to get in there
and patch up the leak.
Dr. Tommy
operated on him?
Dr. Tommy is...?
Tommy.
Koracick.
- Oh.
Yeah. Yes.
Well, he's our angel.
When he offered Blake the job
to come out here,
Blake said no.
He didn't want
to leave me behind.
It's...
It's just been the two of us
since his parents died.
But Dr. Tommy
wanted him badly enough
he paid for me
to move to Seattle.
I know he must be beating
himself up that this happened.
I told him that it was
a freak accident,
but you... you know
how emotional he is.
- Koracick.
- Of course, yeah.
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah, s-super emotional guy.
So, um,
will Blake be okay?
There is
a slow recovery.
His trach should come out
in a day or two.
- As long as everything goes well...
- Lorraine?
Are these two men
bothering you?
No, not at all.
Um, can I go
in the room?
- Absolutely.
- Okay.
Dr. Avery,
lead the way.
Of course, yeah.
- Hunt.
- Mm-hmm.
That CSF leak,
that was a great catch.
I'm grateful.
Truly.
♪ All my life ♪
Hm.
♪ I've been searching ♪
Hey,
you and Avery got this?
Yeah. I got, uh,
something I need to do.
- ♪ When all this time ♪
- Oh.
♪ It was all ♪
♪ In me ♪
You're here early.
- ♪ I had lost my way ♪
- Got called in.
Me too. Same.
I have to say,
I kinda see it.
Really?
You have to say that?
Oh, don't be mad at me.
He's Yang's gift.
♪ All I had to do was try ♪
♪ Now I'm breathing ♪
Meredith. Huh?
Do you have a minute?
♪ In the sky,
I have spread my wings ♪
♪ No more will I cry ♪
He didn't die.
No. No, he did not die.
He just...
had a really
terrifying nap.
♪ Sending my help ♪
You saved him.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Oh, no, no, no.
This was all Dr. Pierce
and Dr. Altman.
I, uh... I just helped.
Well, you're the only one
that's here.
So thank you.
- Um, in here.
- This will work.
Give me this.
And this.
And...
Oh, my God, Owen.
What are you doing?
Teddy.
This ring was my mom's.
She gave it to me
the day that Allison was born,
and I've been carrying it around
with me in my pocket
ever since.
And I love you.
And there's no
perfect moment,
and I am not
a perfect man,
but the one thing
I know for sure is
you're the perfect woman
for me.
So, Theodora Grace Altman,
will you...
Owen, no.
- No?
- What?
Is it Tom?
Oh, my God, Teddy.
Owen, stand up. Get up.
Listen to me.
You are not obligated
to marry me.
You don't have to do this.
I want you to break the
patterns, not reinforce them.
I'm not repeating
a pattern.
I'm starting a new one.
Loving you,
loving our family,
with my whole heart,
every day.
That's my new pattern.
I love you.
Teddy, marry me.
Marry me.
Marry me, Teddy.
Hi.
Hey.
Uh, I have
to tell you something,
um, and I'm sorry
to do it at work.
I... It deserves
dinner and privacy,
but if I don't
spit it out...
Oh, it's okay.
What is it?
It appears...
We got news.
We're getting married.
- Oh!
- Oh, wow!
- Hey!
- Oh, my goodness!
- Congratulations!
- I, uh... Congratulations.
- Thanks, man. Aww, thank you so much.
- That's wonderful.
Oh! I know. Wonderful.
♪ It's a beautiful life ♪
- I know.
- Wow!
Congratulations.
Thank you so much.
♪ Miss you for always,
feel you on Sundays ♪
♪ Yellow and purple... ♪
So, you had something
you wanted to tell me?
Um...
I didn't want to know,
uh, but...
it's a boy.
Aah!
Careful.
Sorry.
What do you think
of the name Scout?
Like Atticus and Scout?
I know it's a discussion,
but I want it in the mix.
So cute.
Oh.
♪ It's a beautiful life ♪
♪ And I wonder
if it hurts or not ♪
♪ Hurts or not ♪
♪ I wonder if it hurts or not ♪
I, uh...
I'll understand
if you don't want me to...
Shut up.
♪ This isn't goodbye ♪
♪ Just until next time ♪
♪ Forever on our minds ♪
I forgive you.
♪ And even though we cry ♪
♪ It's a beautiful life ♪
You're my best friend
at this place,
and if I don't have you,
I'm done for.
Same.
♪ I wonder if it hurts or not ♪
I told Meredith Grey
I loved her.
You did.
I heard.
She didn't say it back,
did she?
No.
But you will find someone.
I promise.
Yeah,
it's easy for you to say.
You get to make out with that
every night.
Yeah. But it took me
my whole life to find him.
And, also,
for what it's worth,
I am amazing,
but I am no Meredith Grey.
Word.
♪ Oh, whoa, oh, oh ♪
Knowing
you're alone in the O.R.
can make you the best.
♪ Beautiful life ♪
But that attitude
can ruin your personal life.
Alright, I-I'm coming.
Hey. I turned off my
phone for a reason.
Okay, hey, hey, hey.
Elliott Calhoun's heart
started beating again.
Yeah. You did that.
You saved him.
Oh, God. Thank you.
Thank you, um...
Thank you for telling me.
I needed to hear that.
Hey, c-can I...
Could we, um, talk?
Yeah.
Look, I blew it, I think.
I think I made a big mistake
with Meredith.
I asked her
to take time.
I don't know. I...
I meant
some of what I said.
I-I-I wanted her
to see me.
I wanted to know
she respected me.
But I think
asking her to take time
might've had
the opposite effect.
You hurt someone
who's had more than enough hurt
for a lifetime.
I know. And I don't know
how to undo it.
Dr. Margaret Pierce?
Yeah?
You've been served.
That's why depression,
fatigue, and burnout
are so common
in our profession.
I'm being sued
for wrongful death.
Who's Sabrina Webber?
My cousin.
But if you're going to make
a life of this,
you need to learn to rely on
others whenever possible.
Get in here.
I had a miscarriage once.
I never felt so lonely.
Well, did... did you bring me the
doughnuts?
Did you bring...
And that if you break,
it's okay to let your friends
put you back together.
Sync corrections by srjanapala