I thought
you'd never get up.
Mmm. It's your fault.
You kept me up too late.
Mmm. Can you blame me?
Mmm-hmm.
You didn't tell me
this thing tonight
was such a big deal.
Is it?
"City honors Gaffney Chicago
Medical Center tonight."
It's all about
your Hybrid OR.
Mmm. They must be
desperate for news.
The city officials
are gonna be there.
And the board.
Let's not go.
Let's stay home and...
No.
I am so with you there,
but we have to go.
At least make an appearance.
Couldn't you go without me?
Uh, no, absolutely not.
There wouldn't be Hybrid OR
if it wasn't for you.
I just don't feel like it.
I want you there.
You're my girl.
Then honor my wishes.
I'm not going.
I saw Ethan and Vicki
at Gibson's.
So?
Ethan's old girlfriend.
Or maybe new girlfriend.
I mean, she's beautiful.
A doctor and a naval officer.
How do you
compete with that?
I'm not competing
with that.
Ethan can see
whoever he wants.
Okay. So you're dating?
That's beside
the point.
So you're not.
It's so hard to meet people.
Get down!
My gun!
There's been a shooting.
Oh, my God! April? Brett?
Dennis Mitchell, 28,
unrestrained
motor vehicle collision.
You're going to Baghdad.
April?
It's justice!
I'm fine.
Bitches like you
just want me to suffer.
You're the enemy!
It's justice!
Patient is violent
and delusional. GCS 15.
BP is normal.
I'm gonna kill them all!
Dr. Choi, I need you
in Baghdad now.
What about April?
I'll take care of her.
Okay.
Dr. Charles.
Now!
Are you two all right?
Yeah.
Well, you've
been through
enough this morning.
Go home.
Yeah?
Thank you.
Okay, Monique?
Well, the ED's short now.
We'll manage.
I didn't get a scratch
thanks to April.
I don't feel right leaving.
Okay, it's up to you.
I'll take care of her.
Okay.
Left arm's deformed,
probably a humerus fracture.
Dr. Choi.
Fifty of fentanyl
for the pain.
They had it coming.
It's justice!
Dr. Charles, help me out.
Five of haloperidol.
They'll learn.
They'll all learn!
Breath sounds
present bilaterally,
multiple lacerations.
Looks like a displaced
chin implant.
Let's get his clothes off.
Gonna need X-rays.
Displaced pectoral implant.
Clear.
He's had a lot
of plastic surgery.
Chest is clear,
humerus fractures,
get a CVC, BMP, UA tox,
and order a CT head.
Got it.
Also a liver panel,
cardiac enzymes, and EKG.
A liver panel?
Gotta cover
all of our bases.
Dr. Choi.
Get that feminoid
out of here.
You're the enemy!
Okay. I was gonna
take him to lockup.
Sorry, Kim.
He's not ready yet.
Bitch!
While he's still here,
can we grab a psych eval?
Yeah, knock yourself out.
But I'm keeping
a police detail
on this guy.
Let me know
when I can talk to him.
I'm so sorry, April.
It's terrifying
to be shot at.
I can't believe
you were hit.
I'm fine.
Will you sign me off
to go back to work?
Really?
I don't even
need stitches. I...
I'd feel better.
Okay.
Just take it easy.
All right?
Thanks.
When are we gonna do something
about all these guns?
You all right, Miss Curry?
Everything okay?
My PhD project.
Reprogramming human
pluripotent cells into
hematopoietic stem cells.
Previous data had showed
successful induction of cells
into monocytes,
but I re-ran
the single-cell cytometry
and didn't detect any
CD34-positive cells, so...
I did something wrong,
I don't know.
It doesn't corroborate.
I didn't sleep
at all last night.
Hmm.
Didn't or couldn't?
What difference
does that make?
Dr. Charles,
while we're waiting
to get Dennis Mitchell to CT,
you can talk to him.
Why don't you take a break
from that and come help me
evaluate this patient?
The shooter? What do you
need to evaluate?
He's crazy.
Maybe, but, um, well,
there are different kinds
of crazy.
With very different
legal implications.
Mr. Mitchell.
I'm Dr. Charles.
This is Student Doctor Curry.
You've had quite a day,
haven't you?
I bet you when you
woke up this morning
you didn't think
you were gonna end up here.
Does that feminoid
have to be here?
Excuse me?
Feminoid. Foid.
Tell her to get out.
Okay, you're gonna treat
Miss Curry with respect.
And you don't get to decide
who's in this room
or who isn't.
Do you understand me?
Okay, I'm gonna ask you
a couple of questions because,
well, 'cause I have to.
Um, just to check the boxes.
Have you ever been medicated
for your thinking?
No.
Have you ever heard voices
that other people don't?
No.
I do not hear voices.
Okay.
So, um, why don't you tell me
what happened this morning?
That Stacy got
what she deserved.
Bitch wouldn't even have
a cup of coffee with me.
Stacy?
They are in control.
They have sex
whenever they want it.
But no matter what I do,
they deny me.
Okay.
I deserve love.
But they won't
give it to me.
They only give it
to those shallow,
stupid alphas.
So besides being
a rabid misogynist,
what kind of crazy is he?
Well, he was using
certain buzzwords
that could be telling.
You know, Stacy, feminoid.
Made me wonder if he has
an online presence.
Could you check
that out for me?
Dr. Charles,
I am extremely busy.
Oh, okay.
Well, in that case, um,
I guess now
you're even busier.
Maggie.
Yeah.
I'm starting to think
that maybe this wasn't
a random shooting.
Could you look and see
if Mr. Mitchell
has ever been a patient
in this hospital before?
Sure thing.
Thank you.
Come in.
Dr. Manning,
this is Agent Lee.
I've been overseeing
Dr. Halstead's relocation
in Witness Protection.
I know who you are.
Well, I'll leave
you two to talk.
I know things have been
difficult for you.
You guys wouldn't tell me
where he was.
You wouldn't even
let me speak to him.
I'm sorry. That's
standard procedure.
Was it standard procedure
to take him away
on our wedding day?
It was for his own safety.
If it's any consolation,
Dr. Halstead did the FBI
a great service.
Because of him we were able
to bring some very bad people
to justice.
Why are you here?
The Burkes
are incarcerated.
We've determined it's safe
for Dr. Halstead
to return to Chicago.
Will's coming home?
Yes.
You should know there may be
a period of adjustment.
Meaning?
He's had a traumatic
experience
and he's been cut off
from his friends and family.
Some people
re-integrate easily.
Some don't.
Call me if you have
any questions.
Hey. You're working?
Yes, Natalie cleared me.
You should go home.
Ethan, I'm fine.
Leah? Talk to me,
what do we got?
Ivy Davis.
30 weeks pregnant,
pre-term labor.
All right. We're gonna
get you a doctor, okay?
Dr. Manning,
you're going to 6.
Page OB.
On it.
She can't have
this baby right now.
You have to stop it.
She has
a pre-existing aneurysm.
If she pushes,
it could kill her.
All right, help me
get her into the bed.
Why wasn't the aneurysm
treated earlier?
It's small.
She's not supposed to be
in labor right now.
We have a C-section scheduled.
But not for two more months.
Heart rate 97.
BP 128/73.
Shh.
It's okay. Breathe.
Let's start a magnesium drip,
embolus four grams.
Got it.
And 12.5 milligrams
of betamethasone IM,
and 100 milligrams
of indomethacin PO.
Ivy, we need to give you
this pill, okay?
It's gonna help stop
your contractions.
OB said that they'll be down
as soon as they can.
Okay.
Okay, hold on. You're okay.
You're doing great.
Just breathe.
Don't push, don't push!
No, no, no!
Dr. Manning, no pulse.
Bag her.
Ivy...
Still no pulse.
Ivy.
Ivy. Honey.
Asystole.
Take over compressions.
What is happening?
Honey, hey.
Her pupils are fixed
and dilated.
I am so sorry,
but her aneurysm
must have ruptured.
No, but she's still...
I'm sorry.
Your wife is gone.
But we need
to get the baby out.
It still has
a chance. Okay?
We got four minutes.
Start the four-minute clock.
Where is OB?
Can't wait.
I need to do
the C-section myself.
Angel, take over compressions.
Ivy. Ivy.
Honey.
Diane, get OB here.
Sir, I need you
to step out
so we can
deliver this baby.
Wait a minute.
Please save our baby. Please.
Get me a scalpel.
Scalpel.
Okay.
Suction.
She's cyanotic.
Ready to transfer.
Angel?
Sats at 78.
She's still unresponsive.
I might need to intubate.
Hold on.
Sats at 88 and climbing.
Heart rate 160.
She's coming around.
Call Neonatology.
Have them come meet us
in the NICU.
I'm on it.
Keep stimulating.
I want this baby
alert and moving.
Tell me.
You have a little baby girl.
We were able
to get her out in time,
but she does need
to go up to the NICU.
If you would like to spend
some time with your wife...
Monique can take you up
when you're ready.
I am so sorry for your loss.
Ethan! Ethan.
Hey.
Vicki.
I heard there was
a shooting
at the hospital.
They said
a nurse was injured.
It wasn't April, was it?
Yeah, it was.
She wasn't badly hurt.
Ethan, I...
Vicki.
It's over
between April and me.
Is it?
I mean, I know
it can't be easy.
You see her every day
and I completely understand...
It's over.
Okay?
Gotta get back to work.
Okay.
I'll see you for dinner.
Yeah.
Monique.
Did the shooter
Dennis Mitchell
look familiar to you?
I didn't really get
a good look at him.
Turns out
he was a patient here.
Oh, my God.
Maggie, I do remember him.
Yeah.
Your work-up
is negative.
He's cleared for you
to lock him up.
I'll call Burgess.
We'll get him out of here.
Dr. Choi, he was complaining
about his left hand.
Said it feels funny.
What do you mean funny?
It feels dead.
Pulse is diminished.
It's a soft sign
for a humerus fracture.
The artery needs
to be evaluated.
Can't release him yet.
Dr. Charles,
Dennis Mitchell
was a patient here.
Really?
Six months ago.
He came in with an infection
after some plastic surgery.
Monique was his nurse.
She asked to be replaced
by a male nurse
after Mr. Mitchell made a pass
at her insisting they go out.
Huh. Okay, thank you.
Yeah.
And order a CTA of his
left subclavian artery.
Hey, you do realize
it's upsetting to everyone
he's still in the hospital.
Can't help that.
It looks like you're
bending over backwards
to keep him here.
Are all these tests
really necessary?
He shot you, April.
He could have killed you.
I know that.
Don't tell me
how to practice medicine.
Okay.
Hey, Maggie, I just
heard about April.
Is she doing all right?
She said she's okay.
Back at work.
Yeah, what a thing
to go through.
Yeah.
Congratulations.
Front page of the Metro.
Wow.
Well, I'm sorry
we don't have any cases
worthy of your talents,
but since you're
still a trauma surgeon
on my service...
Kid in 5.
Goofing around
with a nail gun,
put one in his chest.
Hello, Mr. Bennett.
Hey, Davey. I'm Dr. Rhodes.
Am I gonna die?
No.
No, you're not.
No, your dad is right.
We're gonna fix you up
as good as new.
I thought the nail gun
was out of reach.
I should have
been more careful.
Really, he's gonna be fine.
So I see that Dr. Lanik
gave him some morphine.
How you feeling, Davey?
It hurts when I breathe.
My poor boy.
Well, that makes sense.
According to your X-ray,
the nail hit a rib.
A rib?
His vitals are fine.
There's no obvious blood
in his chest.
If you were an adult,
I would take the nail out
right here and now.
But given Davey's age, I would
rather do it up in the OR.
So it is serious.
Dad, I don't
want a surgery.
No, no, no.
I just think that Davey
would be more comfortable
if he were under
general anesthetic.
So as soon as an OR is open
and it's ready,
I'm gonna
take you upstairs,
all right?
And in the meantime, um,
I would try and stop
worrying so much, okay?
And you, I'm gonna
get you something
to make you feel
a little better.
So you hang in there, okay?
Dr. Charles, I, uh...
I have the stuff
on the shooter
that you asked for.
Oh, great.
Well, wait.
Where you going?
I don't know
how to work these.
Have a seat.
Okay.
Man, PhD and an MD
at the same time?
I mean, no wonder
you're exhausted.
I can only imagine.
Yeah, well, I'm used
to working hard.
Yeah, clearly. Show me.
Okay. So, um...
Dennis Mitchell has a history
on various message boards.
He calls himself
an "incel,"
an involuntary celibate.
Loser guys who think women
are unjustly denying them sex.
Yeah, ironically, the term
was coined by a woman.
She started a website
for lonely people.
Uh, this is
one of his first entries.
"I can't attract girls.
"My legs are skinny.
My chest is weak."
Then he posts pictures.
And, um, some guy named
Apeman writes back...
"Bro, this is fixable.
"Pectoral augmentation.
Calf augmentation."
Yep, then he spends
over $10,000 on surgeries.
Rhinoplasty, the chin implant,
it's unbelievable.
He thinks this will make him
more desirable.
Yeah. People who
don't feel loved
will do some crazy things.
Well, it didn't work.
This is him a month ago.
"No matter what I do,
"women deprive me of my right
to sexual pleasure.
"They are the enemy
and it's time to get even."
Then he posted this
yesterday.
I'm 28 years old
and I'm still a virgin.
Women treat me like I'm scum.
I will slaughter them.
I am the true alpha male.
And I will make them pay.
It's an epidemic.
Wait, what is?
Loneliness.
Despite the intubation,
she's still not oxygenating.
I'm hearing a grade 3
systolic ejection murmur.
EKG shows left ventricular
hypertrophy.
Samantha, transducer.
Tricuspid atresia.
And an atrial septal defect.
Do you want to
tell the father,
or should I?
I will.
We never should have
tried to have kids.
But Ivy wanted
a baby so badly.
And now she's gone.
I'm so sorry.
There is something I need
to discuss with you.
We've examined
your little girl...
Sophie.
We were gonna
name her Sophie.
There's a problem
with Sophie's heart.
It's missing
its tricuspid valve.
Normally the valve opens
and closes like a door.
But Sophie's door is closed.
So when she's a little bigger,
she'll need a surgery.
But in the meantime,
she needs an operation
called pulmonary artery band.
It's urgent.
Urgent.
Do we have your consent?
Yes.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Doctor...
Please save my little girl.
Natalie. Trauma 2.
You got a chart?
Just go in.
Okay.
Yeah.
Will?
Natalie.
Agent Lee said
you were coming back.
I didn't know it was today.
Yeah.
I have been so angry at you.
I don't blame you.
I'm sorry.
For everything. All of it.
I didn't know how I'd feel
when I saw you.
And?
Will.
I've missed you so much.
It was terrible without you.
I thought about this moment
every day.
You're really here.
All right.
An OR opened up.
What do you say we get that
nail out of your chest, huh?
I don't want an operation.
Can't you just give me
some medicine?
He's really scared.
You're gonna be asleep.
It won't hurt a bit.
I promise you.
I tell you what.
How 'bout if I'm
right there with you?
Mr. Bennett, I'm sorry,
but that's not...
I want my daddy.
I've heard of parents
in the operating room
with their kids.
It's not a common practice,
and really it's only while
the child's being put under.
Okay, that's fine. Please.
I am all he has.
It's just the two of us
since his mom died.
Yeah. Okay.
But just until he's asleep.
Okey-dokey, let's go.
Sophie did really well.
She'll need to stay here
for a couple more weeks
and then you can
take her home.
Until she's big enough
to tolerate the surgery.
She's so little.
Yeah, but she's
gonna be fine.
Is there anyone you would
like us to call for you?
Family? Friends?
My wife's family, I...
I still have to tell them.
Do they live close by?
Can they come be with you?
No, we just moved to Chicago.
Is there anyone local
who could help you
with the arrangements?
No.
I know hardly anyone here.
I'll get you some information.
Okay?
Thank you.
So we watched
the last video
you posted.
Where you said
you wanted revenge.
People should pay
for what they did to me.
What they did to you?
I'm sorry, Mr. Mitchell. Um...
So obviously, you feel like
you've been wronged.
What I'm curious about is
if you're experiencing any...
Any regret for what
you did today.
Yeah.
I have regrets.
I wish I'd killed them all.
You're disgusting.
You are. You're...
Miss Curry.
Pathetic, you're lonely...
Miss Curry, enough.
Nobody loves you, poor you.
That doesn't give you...
You shut up!
...the right to shoot people
except maybe yourself!
What the hell are you doing?
How could you take
his side in there?
"Obviously you feel like
you've been wronged?"
I'm not taking his side.
I'm trying to determine
if he feels remorse
for his actions.
I hate him.
Well, this isn't about you.
This is a hospital.
And that's a patient
who I'm trying to evaluate.
A task you just made
infinitely more difficult.
No, you are not trying
to evaluate him.
You just are trying
to find some excuse
so that he doesn't pay
for what he did.
So that he doesn't
go to prison.
Miss Curry,
what he did was terrible.
But as abhorrent
as we find his actions,
our job is to try
and understand
his mental state.
I don't know what
you want from me.
All right? I... I...
I am doing the best
that I can.
I...
Dr. Choi?
Mr. Mitchell's scans.
Call Vascular, tell them
we're bringing a patient up.
We need to take him
to surgery right now.
One of your pectoral implants
damaged the axillary artery
and you've developed
what we call
a pseudoaneurysm.
If it ruptures,
you could bleed to death.
Bleed to death?
Go.
Davey, can you count down
from 10?
Ten.
Nine...
Okay, Beth, why don't you
show Mr. Bennett
the waiting room?
Sir, let's have you
wait outside.
Just...
I'm in.
Sir?
It's okay.
Airway pressures are up.
Having trouble ventilating.
BP 88/60, heart rate 144.
What's going on?
No breath sounds on the left.
Tension pneumothorax.
What is that?
Get me a needle to decompress
and open a chest tray.
I'm guessing the nail poked
a small hole in the lung
and the pressure from
the ventilator is forcing
air into his chest.
We can deal with it.
What... What are you
doing to him?
Sir...
Dylan, I need you
to get out of here.
I am not leaving!
Scalpel.
Sir!
Tube.
No. No, no, no.
Sir, come!
No, take that out!
No, you are hurting him!
Stop! Let go!
You're killing him!
Marty, help me!
You are killing my son!
Come on, Marty...
Call security
and get him out of here.
He pushed
the tube in too far.
It caused a laceration
in the chest.
We need to open Davey up.
Hang a unit,
call the blood bank,
and page Dr. Bekker,
I need her now.
Watch his stats, Marty.
Pressure's good.
He's stable for now.
You allowed a parent
in the OR for a trauma case?
You can give me
the lecture later.
What have we got?
Chest tube lacerated
the left ventricle.
I've got my finger
in the dike,
I need you to sew.
Well, Daddy sure cocked
this up, didn't he?
Load up a 4-0 Prolene
with pledgets for Dr. Bekker.
All right.
Here you go.
Thanks.
Will.
Hey.
Sorry. Thanks.
Yeah, man. Sorry.
Oh, just a little
jumpy, I guess.
Welcome back.
Yeah, thanks.
Where were they
keeping you?
Phoenix.
Better weather
than Chicago, right?
I didn't get out much.
They kept me
pretty bottled up.
Hey. Just gotta
look something up
and then we can
get out of here, okay?
Yeah.
Mmm.
I missed that.
What are you doing?
Looking up funeral home
information.
This guy just lost his wife
and now their baby
is up in the NICU.
That's rough.
Yeah.
A single parent
with a newborn?
I know exactly
how he's feeling.
It's not easy.
ED?
I'll let him know.
Dr. Choi.
Vascular called.
They were able to stent
Dennis Mitchell's
axillary artery.
He's headed to the ICU.
Congratulations.
You saved his life.
April, don't you understand?
The first thing
I wanted was revenge.
But I couldn't let
myself go there.
Then I wouldn't be
any different than him.
He hurt someone I care about.
He hurt you.
Mr. Bennett.
Davey is out of surgery
and he's gonna be fine.
Thank God.
I'm sorry.
I am so sorry.
Hey...
You'll be able
to see him soon.
Thank you.
For everything.
You can give me
the lecture now.
Yeah, I could.
But your intentions
were good.
You couldn't know that
Dad would go mental.
Come with me tonight.
The board's gonna be there.
That means your father's
gonna be there.
Oh, I know. I've got
a mental dad, too.
So what?
It's uncomfortable.
Being around the two of you.
I know.
But you can't
avoid him forever.
You and I are a couple.
With a future, right?
Between you and Dr. Choi,
I've pulled
some overtime today.
Thank you.
Any time.
You're not putting him
on a psych hold?
Miss Curry, stop by my office
on your way out today,
would you?
Okay.
Just give me
a minute, okay?
Mr. Davis?
Here's some
funeral home
information.
They'll handle everything.
Thank you.
There's really
no reason for you
to stay here tonight.
Why don't you go home?
Try and get some sleep.
I don't want to go home.
You know, I...
I was pregnant
when my husband died.
Your whole world
falls apart.
The person
you loved so deeply,
shared everything with,
your worries,
your sorrows,
your joys...
Is gone.
And you feel so empty.
And alone.
But it will get better.
I promise you.
Oh, my God.
Oh, God.
In his twisted way,
with all his plastic surgery,
Mr. Mitchell was trying
to make himself worthy
of being loved.
And, well,
when he didn't get that love,
of course, he blamed others.
Of course.
Well, it's not atypical.
You know, men do tend to blame
others for their depression
and loneliness whereas women,
sadly, are more likely
to blame themselves.
Why are you telling me this?
You had a very strong reaction
to Mr. Mitchell today.
Yeah, I mean,
who wouldn't?
Fair enough, but it seemed to
really touch a nerve,
like it was almost personal.
Sorry, I have...
I have no idea
what you're
talking about.
I'm seeing this
extraordinarily talented,
brilliant, hardworking
young woman
who is putting an immense
amount of pressure on herself
to succeed.
You know, she's not sleeping,
she hasn't necessarily plugged
into a peer group for support,
you know,
she's doing it alone.
Elsa, for what it's worth,
I know a whole lot
about depression
and loneliness.
Okay?
Have you ever had any thoughts
about hurting yourself?
No, I... No, I've never...
No, I mean, how...
You have no right to ask me
a question like that.
None. I think maybe
you're the one
with the problem.
Not me.
Like, what kind of life
do you have?
What kind of friends?
You're here all the time.
You've been divorced,
like, 50 times.
Like, your last resident
hated you so much
she moved to Texas. I...
I think
you are the expert
on loneliness
and depression, okay?
See you, guys.
Good night, April.
Good night, Ethan.
Hey, Monique,
your shift is over.
Why don't you go home?
Monique?
I am so sorry
for what happened.
I'm so sorry.
Okay, okay.
Out. Everybody out now.
Come on.
It's my fault.
It's all my fault.
Your fault?
He could have killed you.
If I just had
coffee with him...
No.
Monique. No.
This had nothing
to do with you.
How can you
even think that?
'Cause I told him
to leave me alone.
I didn't want anything
to do with him.
So?
Guys should shoot us
for turning them down?
Come on.
You do realize
how crazy that sounds.
Don't you?
Oh.
Come here.
Is there someone at home
that can come and get you?
No.
Maybe a friend?
I don't have any friends.
Yes, you do.
Look at us.
You do.
Yeah. Come here.
I finally got Owen to sleep.
He's so excited
to have you home.
Well, not as excited as me.
Mmm.
We have to get the wedding
back on the calendar.
Yes, we do.
What is that?
Oh, careful.
Let me put this away.
It's a gun?
Don't worry.
Owen can't get into it.
You're carrying a gun?
After everything
that happened,
I thought we should
have some protection.
I can't believe this.
I have a permit.
I don't care.
You can't bring
that thing in our house.
Natalie, this is
for our protection.
Will, you used to hate guns.
That was before
I had one pointed
at my head.
I'm sorry.
But you cannot
stay here with that gun.
I won't have it
in this house.
We have a great reason
to celebrate tonight
and I am delighted to see
all the members of our board,
along with so many
of our generous supporters.
Gaffney Medical Center
is on the cutting edge
of urgent care,
due in large part
to the men and women
who are here tonight.
On behalf of them,
I thank you.
Congratulations
to both of you.
And to you.
Don't you two look beautiful.
I'm sorry,
but I have to steal
these two for a minute.
They're gonna try to
sneak in some questions
about the shooter.
But we're not here
about that.
We're here about you.
And your OR room.
Dr. Bekker.
I love that perfume.
Brings back
such nice memories.
Why don't we do it again?
That was
a very large check
I wrote you.
I think I deserve
more than one night.
I disagree.
Does my son
know about us?
Thank you.
Very nice meeting you.
I think we should go.
What, why?
Your father.
What about him?
The night that I went to
go see him to ask for money
for the Hybrid Room?
Yeah?
He's... He's now saying
the most hateful thing.
He's telling people
I slept with him.
Thank you.
Dr. Rhodes!
What did she tell you?
I can't wait to hear.
I should never have
made you come.