Previously on "ER.."
Oh!
I‐I'd invite you
back to my place
but, uh, I fear I'd be
taking advantage.
‐ 'I'm going to help you.'
‐ You have to help me!
I'm going to help you.
I'm going to help you, chase
but you got to
stick with me!
A delay in the vote at this late
there just isn't an option.
I can't support something
I don't believe in.
When I was talking
to Greg Powell
it got intense
'and, um..'
And I kissed him.
♪ It ain't no joke I'd like
to buy the world a toke ♪
♪ And teach the world
to sing in perfect harmony ♪
♪ And teach the world to snuff
the fires and the liars ♪
♪ Hey I know it's just a song
but it's spice for the recipe ♪
♪ This is a love attack I know
it went out but it's back ♪
♪ It's just like any fad
it retracts before impact ♪
♪ And just like fashion
it's a passion ♪
♪ For the with it and hip ♪
♪ If you got the goods
they'll come and buy it ♪
♪ Just to stay in the clique ♪
♪ So don't delay act now
supplies are running out ♪
♪ Allow if you're still alive ♪
♪ Six to eight years
to arrive.. ♪
Whoa!
Oh..
‐ Touchdown!
‐ Nice catch.
Hey, Dr. C,
how'd you get in?
I followed a snowplow
in from the Ryan.
What? Only one patient?
Yeah.
Bumsicle, defrosting.
'Yo, Jer!'
How much longer is Weaver
gonna keep you on nights, Jerry?
I believe her
exact words were
"until hell freezes over."
Yeah, I've been meaning to talk
to her about it again, actually.
You think I'd look good
in that cut?
Honestly?
No.
Carter, what do you think
the best approach
with Weaver is?
Contrition, indignation?
Begging.
Oh, I think I would
just appeal
to her innate sense
of fairness.
She has a sense
of fairness?
Yeah! Just remind her you've
been on nights now for, uh..
Four months.
And that you think that your
exemplary work history
and your many years
of loyal service
marred by only one
minor incident‐‐
Blowing up
the ambulance bay.
Makes it incumbent
upon her
to bring you back
to the land of the living.
I still say beg.
Hey, Anna's on?
Yeah, she's in exam
four, sleeping.
Hmm.
Yo, Carter.
'Nice throw!'
Carter?
Hey.
Hi.
What time is it?
It's 6:00. I didn't
mean to wake you.
I got to get up anyway.
No, no, catch
a few more minutes.
I'll go get us
some breakfast at Doc's.
What do you want bagel?
Coffee?
‐ Is it still snowing?
‐ Yeah.
Yeah, they said we might
get three more feet today.
‐ Wow.
‐ Maybe more.
Here. I brought
you a doughnut.
Oh, thanks.
How's Chase?
He's off the clonidine.
He's weak, but up and around.
Thanks for all your help
with him.
I was happy to.
What?
Well, I'll go get us
some breakfast.
‐ Scrambled eggs.
‐ What?
Scrambled eggs, please
with wheat toast,
a couple of blueberry pancakes
and an orange juice.
Coming right up!
Paramedics have a GSW, massive
blood loss. A few minutes off.
'They're having a hell
of a time gettin' here.'
They think they may lose him.
Rain check on that breakfast.
What do you got?
Multiple GSW to the chest,
abdomen and left thigh.
Estimated blood loss
is one liter.
Two liters saline in.
Abdomen is tense.
No bowel sounds.
Type and cross, and, uh,
get six units O‐neg down here.
‐ Are we still short?
‐ Yes. It's stuck at O'Hare.
We're runnin' low on blood.
With the storm and the flu,
nobody's donating.
Alright let's spin a crit.
Get a portable chest. Excuse me.
And a blood gas.
Did somebody use a machine gun
on this guy?
He's a security guard,
interrupted a rape.
Eight ET tube.
How long ago was he shot?
At least 20 minutes. We got
stuck, had to dig the rig out
in the middle of Halsted.
Hemopneumo. Chest tube tray.
Rape victim's
still on the scene.
Unit 57's got her.
An old lady,
must've been 70.
'Unbelievable.'
How's the old woman?
She's in rough shape,
but it looks like
he stopped her
from getting raped.
‐ I got the blood.
‐ 'They catch the rapist?'
No. But there's tons
of cops over there looking.
They think this guy
might've shot him.
Chest tube's in.
Okay. Good.
Let's call the OR.
And tell them
we're on our way.
‐ More blood?
‐ No. Save it.
Have Respiratory meet us
with a vent.
Maybe they'll finally
catch the son of a bitch.
About damn time.
If we get him upstairs
we can stop at the cafeteria.
Hey, hey, guys,
out of the way.
What do you got?
Multiple GSW
on his way to the OR.
He saved an old woman
from being raped
and got shot
for his trouble.
How'd you get in?
Oh, took the El.
Car was stuck.
‐ Whoa. No pulse.
‐ What?
Looks like
idioventricular rhythm.
Alright, take him back,
take him back.
Careful. Hey,
out of the way!
Listen, follow me.
We'll go around.
‐ Come on.
‐ Watch it.
‐ Whose patient?
‐ Mine.
Thoraseal's full.
Probably lacerated arteries.
Cynthia..
Hold on.
He was stable.
Yeah, well, he sure
as hell isn't now.
Careful.
‐ Thoracotomy tray!
‐ Let's get more blood in.
‐ How much?
‐ All of it.
‐ Should I order more?
‐ Yeah. At least four.
Somebody shut off
that damn alarm.
Rib spreader.
Come on.
Pericardium is tense.
‐ Incise. Release the tamponade.
‐ Ten blade.
Go laterally. Watch out
for the coronary arteries.
Suction. Come on, suction!
'Give me the pickups.'
‐ You're in my light.
‐ Four more O‐neg are coming.
Damn it!
Left ventricle's
shredded.
How many units in?
Three. The fourth one's up.
There's not
enough to sew.
Come on, we should still try.
'Call it, Carter.
Save the blood.'
He stopped an old woman
from being raped.
No good deed
goes unpunished.
‐ Time of death?
‐ 6:11.
Son of a bitch.
‐ 'Don.'
‐ Morning, Kerry.
Morning.
You're in early.
I was anxious to
hear the outcome
of last night's
SPG vote.
Well, after careful
consideration
and due in no small part
to your glowing
recommendation
the board will begin
negotiations with SPG
for an emergency department
management contract.
I'm sorry
to hear that.
You've placed me in a very
awkward position, Kerry.
I went to the board
at your urging.
Any misgivings
you had about SPG
should have been aired
weeks ago.
If we reverse
our position now
we are going to look
very foolish indeed.
I take it you have misgivings.
Yes, I do.
Well, the board
was anxious to know
whether the
senior ER staff
was supportive
of the idea.
You assured me they were.
If you were incorrect
in that assessment
and wish to go
before the board
and admit your error
that might carry
some weight.
So you want me
to fall on my sword
in front of the board
of directors.
It is your sword, Kerry.
So, my lease is up
February 1st..
Whoa, are you okay?
Oh, my God.
Yeah. Thanks, Mark.
Jerry, let's get some
mud mats down here
before someone slips
and kills themself.
Anyway, they want
me to move
or sign a new lease
for six months
and I was month‐to‐month,
but now they want me‐‐
Three patients?
It'll pick up soon
as it stops snowing.
Oh, yeah, all those
sick people
sitting around at home,
waiting around
just to rush in and ruin
our perfectly good slow day.
The 57's on their way
with a rape victim.
Anyway, um, it seems
silly for me to be paying rent
especially when I'm spending
every night at your place.
‐ What?
‐ Mark?
Jerry, get
some mud mats down
before somebody
kills themself.
Can I talk to you
a little later?
Yeah. Sure, okay.
And how much is your rent?
Well, $450 now but they
want to raise it to $500.
I could probably
help you out with that.
Oh. You know, I..
Do you want to talk
about this later?
No. I didn't mean
to make you fell uncomfortable.
You didn't make me
uncomfortable.
Okay, I'm gonna.. I have to get
these up to the lab.
Right.
‐ What?
‐ Nothing.
Uh, Randi called.
She's snowed in.
‐ Perfect.
‐ Uh, Dr. Weaver
Can I talk to you
for a minute?
Um..
I've been
working nights
for months now
and‐and while
I appreciate
that the accidental damage
that I inflicted
on the ER
cannot be dismissed
as inconsequential
nor insignificant.
I do, however, believe
that my eight years
of loyal service
along with my sterling
attendance record
and my seniority,
all demand
that I get my old
day shift back.
Is that it?
I'm also appealing
to your innate
sense of fairness.
Can you work
Randi's shift today?
Mm.. Pull a double?
‐ I'd love to.
‐ Fine. You're on days again.
Anybody see Carter?
He went over
to Doc's a while ago.
God, I'm starving.
Anna!
Breakfast is served.
Hey.. Oh, my God! John!
You okay?
You alright?
Oh, man, that smarts.
Damn it, Jerry, get
those mud mats out here now!
Ambulance is pulling up.
I'm never gonna get
my breakfast, am I?
Alright..
72‐year‐old‐woman,
respiratory distress, cyanotic.
She's unresponsive.
BP 90/70, pulse 56
resps 32, GCS ten.
‐ This one's mine.
‐ The snow's too deep.
We're gonna have to lift.
One, two, three.
Two large‐bore IVs,
ten liters O2 by mask.
Unable to intubate in the field
due to laryngeal edema.
Bastard tried
to strangle her
then pushed her down
a flight of stairs.
Head trauma,
multiple contusions.
There's a deformity
of the left hip.
Distal pulse is weak,
but present.
Decreased air movement,
stridor on inspiration
intercostal retraction.
‐ Pulse ox is 88.
‐ Let's tube her.
Caught her
in her parking garage.
Did the guard make it?
Guard died on the table.
'Son of a bitch.'
Uh, I can't see the cords.
Suction.
He gave up on
the magic marker
'used a knife
on her stomach.'
What do you want, doctor?
Um..
uh, blood gas.
CBC, chem‐7
type and cross for six
foley cath,
and dip a urine for blood.
Cross table C‐spine,
chest, pelvis and left hip.
‐ 'Let's do it.'
‐ Another one?
Damn it. I don't believe this.
‐ How's the hangover?
‐ Painful.
No hard feelings,
I hope?
No, of course not.
I'm really sorry.
There's a novelty shop
down the street from my flat.
You know, magic tricks,
rubber bugs, black soap.
I love that sort
of thing, don't you?
‐ Not really.
‐ Oh. Sorry.
Why are you so late?
It's not like you.
Oh, Carla wants to put
Reese into a day care.
He's not even a year yet.
I'm afraid you won't
get sympathy from me.
My mum gave me
to a nurse after I was born
and went away on holiday
in southern Spain
for three weeks.
It was nannies after that
and boarding school
by the time I was five.
Anytime,
Dr. Benton.
This colectomy is not getting
any younger.
Okay.
So anyway,
I'm on the phone
with this
nanny service.
450 a week, after taxes.
That's two‐thirds
of my take‐home.
You got any lunch plans?
I doubt I'll have time.
I'm buying.
Ah, it's a mess out there.
Schools are closed,
but we still got to work.
Honey, we always
got to work.
'Well, now..'
Pretty slim pickings.
‐ Any pedes?
‐ Not a one.
Uh, give me time to work
on my dictation.
'Do you have my X‐rays, please.'
What's going on
over there?
Uh, another of those
elderly rape victims.
The cops might catch
the guy this time, though.
They've got him cornered in a
warehouse down by the river.
I hope those dogs
tear him up good.
Yeah, no kidding.
‐ Hey.
Uh..
‐ You okay?
‐ Yes.
'No.'
I mean..
He's your best friend, right?
Mark? Yeah. He's..
I don't understand.
We have great times together.
We laugh.
'We have..
We‐we enjoy each other.'
I sleep over there every
single night, but he's..
I know that I make him happy.
I know I do.
I can tell, but..
He just keeps giving me
these mixed signals.
Well, I mean..
We have, um, uh..
I mean, you talk
to him about that?
Yeah, I talk about it
to him lots of times
but he just avoids it.
I mean..
we usually end up
having sex instead.
Is it me?
Does he think that maybe I'm not
good enough for him? Is that it?
Or is he just..
Is he just..
Scared 'cause he cares so much?
Okay, let's bag her.
Babinski's downgoing.
Pulse ox is coming up.
X‐rays.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
Guys, it's getting crowded
in here, wait outside
and we'll let you
know how she's doin'.
Uh, hip's dislocated.
Should we pop it back in
before we take her up to CT?
Yeah, we can get
post‐reduction film
after the non‐contrast CT.
Thanks.
‐ Vitals?
‐ BP's 110/70, pulse 88.
‐ Ready?
‐ Yeah.
Call CT to tell 'em
to set up a vent.
Okay, let's go.
Send a blood gas from CT.
And repeat a chest X‐ray
when she gets
back here, okay?
How's she doing?
Well, her vitals
are normal.
They put
her hip back in.
I'll get our stuff
back to the rig.
Yeah. Yeah.
You okay?
Yeah.
Hey, Connie, what do you do
for child care?
I got a sitter.
It was a nightmare.
Used to run up
my phone bill.
Eat me out
of house and home.
Eight bucks an hour.
‐ Eight bucks?
‐ My sister's paying ten.
Well, I finally gave up.
Put them upstairs
in day care. They love it.
Yeah, but, aren't they sick
all the time
being around
those other kids?
‐ Sure.
‐ Builds their immune system.
You know, there's a girl
in my building she baby‐sits.
I don't think
she's that expensive.
You want me
to give call her?
Need a baby‐sitter,
Peter?
Carla wants to put
Reese into day care.
And you're uncomfortable
with that?
Listen, Jerry, do you have any
more dictations for me?
You know, my mother
raised us at home.
You're the product
of a bygone era.
It's time to join
the modern world.
Listen, I'm doing these in
sutures if anybody needs me.
'Oh, Dr. Ross.'
Pedes is on the phone,
they're short staffed.
Wants to know
if you can come look
look at a newborn
up in the OB.
Yeah, fine. Thanks.
See you later.
Doug.
‐ Doug, come on.
‐ Is that the guy?
We were talking.
He was upset.
Another elderly
rape victim came in.
I was trying
to calm him down.
Was that the guy?
Yes, that's the guy.
I'm not seeing him
or anything.
No, you're not ready to
commit, that's fine.
You want to screw
firemen, fine.
Just don't humiliate me
in front of my friends.
Humiliate you?
What about the surgical tech
in the on‐call room
or the pedes nurse,
in the parking lot.
How about the drug rep with the
fake breasts and the big hair?
Ancient history.
I'd have to do
the entire bulls' line‐up
on the dammit mid desk
before I began to be equal you.
Is that what this is about?
This is about getting even
for things I did
a long time ago?
No. This is about me
needing some time
and you being really pissed off
that things aren't working out
as you planned.
I've spent years
years of my life,
changing to fit your needs
working around your schedules,
your insecurities
your inabilities to commit.
'Well, you know what, Doug?'
'It's not all about you.'
I know that may come as a shock
but a relationship
is give and take.
Two people as equals
and right now, I need something.
'So you can grow up
and accept it'
or you can go on being
the same selfish
self‐centered bastard
you've always been
and refuse to give me
the one thing
One thing I've ever
asked you for.
Mark, we're precariously
short of blood.
I'm going to ask
the staff to volunteer
rotate our people
upstairs to donate.
We don't have very many
patients anyway.
Sounds smart.
The board voted yesterday
to begin negotiations
with Synergix
to take over the management
of the ER.
Congratulations.
‐ That's what you wanted, right?
‐ Yes and no.
I've had disturbing reports
from other hospitals
about their cost‐control
techniques.
Uh, Mark?
Did you talk to Anspaugh?
He felt that if all
the ER attendings
opposed the decision
that would go a long way
toward scuttling the deal.
Won't that make us
look ridiculous?
I mean, we recommended
it, right?
Yeah, but then the heat
doesn't fall on any one person
if we all go to
the board together.
I've started contacting
the other attendings
and I was hoping I could
count on your support.
Well, show me the statistics
and I'll let you know.
‐ Good, thanks.
‐ Mark.
Cops caught that rapist.
GSW to the chest.
Paramedics
are bringing him in.
‐ Here?
‐ That's what they're saying.
‐ Tell 'em we don't want him.
‐ Let Mercy take him, or Rush.
Malik, prep trauma two
and alert surgery.
Come on, people.
There's no evidence
of penetration.
Thank God for small favors.
Who does something
like this?
I don't know
but if they find the guy
that did this
they should take him out
back, shoot him
and toss his body
in the dumpster.
‐ Hey.
‐ 'Hey.'
How's it going?
Great.
Really?
Cynthia cried on my shoulder
for about an hour.
What's that all about?
Her lease is up.
You want my opinion?
Not particularly.
Fine.
How's Carol?
She talk to you about it?
‐ About what?
‐ Nothing.
Um, we have a nasty
MVA on the Kennedy
and a family in a minivan
hit an overpass
and that, um,
rapist is here.
You should talk.
Two IVs in, no pulse
large‐caliber GSW
to the chest
multiple contusions,
canine bites
an open fracture
to the left femur.
Damn, he's just a kid.
Yeah, 19.
Name's Jack Miller.
We'll leave him
on the paramedic gurney.
‐ Who's up?
‐ Carter.
No breath sounds.
‐ This the rapist?
‐ One of you guys get him?
Nah. He was hiding there in the
crawlspace. Dogs found him.
'Too bad they called
the dogs off.'
Yeah, another 20 minutes
would have saved us all
a lot of trouble.
Got a rhythm
on the monitor.
‐ Should I setup another drip?
‐ Nope.
What's going on,
Dr. Carter?
PEA?
Yep. What's the differential?
Hypovolemia, hypoxia,
tension pneumo
pulmonary embolism
pericardial effusion,
tamponade.
How's the old lady?
She's going to be fine.
Chuny?
Bradycardic 48.
What do you want to do,
Dr. Carter?
Let the bastard die.
He's a patient.
Like every patient
he gets our
best effort.
Dr. Carter?
Amp of epi, IV push,
and a milligram of atropine.
You heard him.
Let's go.
What about an airway?
Yeah, he needs one.
Well, let's put one in.
Mark, that MVA is here.
Mother's in trouble.
I'll be right there.
Malik, you're with me.
Thank God.
Call me if you
need anything.
She was throwing up
last night.
No. Only a little bit.
I ate some saltines
like my sister told me to.
‐ That usually works.
‐ Do you throw up often?
I always eat the saltines
and then it goes away.
Last night, she ate
a whole thing of Cherry Garcia.
Robert!
Cherry Garcia's
my favorite, too.
Are you
having them again?
Have you had
these pains before?
Sometimes it'd hurt
a little bit
but it goes away.
These just keep
coming back.
Coming back, how often?
When? How many?
Eight...times?
During.. Kathie Lee
about eight or nine times.
Okay, I want you to
just lie back
and I'm going to take
a quick look, alright?
‐ Am I okay?
‐ You just relax.
Legs apart.
Good.
Okay.
Alright.
She's seven centimeters.
I'll get the fetal monitor.
Just keep breathing.
Weak pulse.
No breath sounds
on the left.
Neck veins are dilated.
Tension pneumo?
Sounds about right.
32 French.
‐ What are you doing?
‐ Central line.
This guy's going
to need volume.
Victim's coming to.
You guys want to talk to her?
Whoa.
Damn it.
He's losing
a lot of blood here.
Want me to go get Mark?
No.
He's bleeding out.
He's already lost a liter.
He needs blood, Carter.
How many more units
of O‐neg do we have?
This is it...
four units.
Alright,
let's auto‐transfuse him.
‐ What?
‐ You're kidding?
‐ 'Use his own blood?'
‐ 'Hook up the cell saver.'
The guy needs a transfusion.
And he's going to get one.
There's not enough. It's all
over the floor, Carter.
‐ This'll be fine.
‐ He needs blood, Carter.
And he's going to get it.
Hook it up to the central line,
wide open.
Shootin'.
AP pelvis next.
Call me when you're ready.
I'll be next door.
How's he doing?
He has a massive hemothorax
from the gunshot wound.
Possibly to
the pulmonary artery.
We auto‐transfused him
from the Thora‐Seal.
BP's up to 80 palp.
No kidding? You
auto‐transfused?
I've alerted the OR.
And I think
he's stable enough to travel.
Then let's
send him up.
‐ Anna, you coming?
‐ No. Thanks. Carter's got it.
Overweight 62‐year‐old
shoveling two feet
of wet snow.
I can't imagine why
he's having an MI.
Word on the grapevine
is you're mustering
opposition to SPG
among the ER
attendings.
I have to do
what I think is right.
The board has approved
the deal, Kerry.
Yeah, maybe
they can be dissuaded.
Come back here.
Come here. Come here.
I've put months of work
into this already.
Whatever concerns you had
you should have addressed
to me weeks ago.
You should have
been more forthcoming
about the
cost‐containment strategies
you've utilized
at other facilities.
We're a public company.
Whatever we do
is clearly spelled out
in our literature
and our prospectus.
Did you happen to read that?
Yeah, I had trouble
finding it
buried in all
the rosy profit predictions
and glossy photographs
of satisfied patients.
Come on. You're the one
struggling to turn this ER
into a cost‐effective
operation.
Are you telling me
you couldn't anticipate
what's necessary
to make it profitable?
I'm willing
to make hard choices, Ellis.
I'm not willing
to endanger patients.
Are you questioning my ethics
as a physician?
I'm not sure. Maybe.
‐ Kerry.
‐ Hang on a second, Carol.
You used me, Ellis.
That's what we've
been about, right?
You used me
to get this deal.
Well,
I don't like being used.
You underestimated me once,
and you were right to
but don't
underestimate me again.
I'll see you at the board.
'Are you okay?'
The patient, Carol.
27‐year‐old woman,
35 weeks.
Seven centimeters dilated,
fully effaced.
‐ Get her up to OB.
‐ Well, she won't go.
She's scared they're going
to take her baby away.
What?
She's retarded.
She wants
to leave AMA.
I've been treating her
at the clinic.
I think she'll stay
if we keep her down here.
I...I'm going home.
'You can't go home, Mary.
You're having a baby.'
Robert,
where are my shoes?
Mary, hi.
I'm Dr. Weaver.
Where are you going?
Mary, why don't
you sit down here
and let Dr. Weaver
examine you, okay?
'Mary, if you go home'
it could be very bad
for your baby.
I know you love
your baby very much.
You don't want anything
bad to happen, right?
So let me take a look
and we can talk about
'what we should do.'
Please? For your baby?
Good. Jeanie, let's get her
on a fetal monitor.
That's so we can check
your baby's heart.
Do you know
if it's a boy or a girl?
‐ A girl.
‐ How exciting.
And why
are you afraid
to go upstairs
to have your baby?
They'll take her.
Why are they going
to take her, Mary?
That's what
Judy said.
‐ Who's Judy?
‐ 'Her sister.'
Nine centimeters.
Do you live with your sister?
No. We live at
5214 East Chestnut.
Well, we don't take babies
when they have such nice parents
so why don't you
stay here with us
and we'll make sure
everything's going okay.
When did it
stop snowing?
Oh, I didn't
know it had.
Only the finest
culinary offerings
from the third‐floor
vending machine.
Tuna or cheese?
'I didn't know
if you were one of those'
truly fanatical
vegan people
or whether
a little bit of seafood's
'allowed to pass
your lips every so often.'
‐ Cheese, please.
‐ Ah! A true believer.
I must say I do enjoy a good
hunk of rare meat
every so often.
How long has it been
since you've had something
really juicy, Peter?
Oh, I don't know.
Uh...six years.
I thought as much.
Egg?
No.
Pity.
No, I...I eat eggs.
I just, uh...I just..
I've, uh...had a thought.
I have no family here..
...no ties... no time.
You have the baby,
but not much else.
'And with
our schedules'
it makes it almost
impossible to date
or even really meet someone
much less anything
approaching a real relationship.
So, uh...
I was thinking.
We're both adults...
attractive.
We, uh...
we enjoy each other.
Why not?
I won't disappoint.
I've made you blush.
Whoo!
I, uh...
I don't think I'd...I'd..
...I'd be comfortable
with that.
That's a pity.
Heard
the rapist made it.
‐ Good job, Carter.
‐ Has anybody seen Doug?
I'm gonna need
a pediatrician
to check out a newborn
in a couple of minutes.
I think he's still up at pedes.
I'll go page him.
I'm around if you
can't find him.
‐ Thanks Anna.
‐ You ever get anything to eat?
I lost my appetite,
thanks.
Excuse me, I'm looking for
my sister, Mary Cochran.
She's having a baby.
Hi, yes. She sure is.
I'm Carol Hathaway.
Come with me.
Is she alright?
Oh, she's doing great.
Not long now.
Can I see her?
Uh, sure. I have
to ask her first.
Hi, Mary. How you doing?
‐ I'm back.
‐ She's crowning.
Keep pushing.
Four, five, six, seven
eight, nine, ten.
Good. Now, don't push.
This is hard.
You're doing great.
He's ROA.
How you doing,
Robert?
Not going to
faint, are you?
I'm okay.
Somebody get Robert a chair
just in case he feels
like sitting down.
Your sister's
outside, Mary.
Judy?
Yeah. She wants to know
if she can come in.
‐ Yes.
‐ Carol, can you give me a hand?
Yeah.
Alright, Mary,
just one more time.
Mary, I'm here, honey.
'Let's give it everything
you've got, okay?'
One, two..
...five, six,
seven, eight, nine..
There she is.
I see the head.
Look at all that hair.
Oh, wow!
Looks like you might
need someone
with pediatric experience
in here.
Oh, look.
She's beautiful.
Okay, Mary, this
is just the last little bit.
She's out.
Oh...oh, my God.
Welcome to the world,
Madison.
Is she okay?
'Yeah. Ten fingers..'
...and ten toes.
Okay, dad,
get in here and cut the cord.
Come on, Robert.
You can do it.
There?
That's the spot, there.
Go ahead.
Good.
So sweet.
Hello, baby.
Hello, little baby.
'Ten units
Pitocin, IV.'
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Thank you
so much.
You're welcome.
Is the baby
okay mentally?
Well, it's too soon to tell
but she's seems
fine, alert.
There's no reason to think she
won't be perfectly normal.
When do the
social workers come?
They don't.
We don't call social services
when there are two
loving, adult parents.
You seem very nice
so I hope you won't
think me rude
but do you have
the training
to make
that assessment?
Well, they're doing fine
with the baby
they have
their own apartment
and Robert works.
Robert is the janitor
at his uncle's
muffler repair shop.
Neither of them drive
because they don't read
well enough top pass the test.
They have their own apartment
but I do their bills
and remind them to do
their laundry every week.
They are sweet, loving people
but they can't care
for an infant.
Do you think you're qualified
to make that assessment?
You know, I wish
that I weren't.
I can't tell you how much
I wish that I weren't.
Mark, did you get a chance
to look over
those Synergix reports
I gave you?
‐ Not very encouraging.
‐ So you're with me?
Sure. Whatever
you think's best.
Would somebody please
answer the phone?
ER.
The board finance committee
meets next Tuesday.
Can I count on you
to be there?
Yeah, as long as I don't
have to say anything.
Why isn't anybody
answering the damn phone?
Where is Cynthia?
Cynthia left hours ago.
She seemed upset.
‐ She left?
‐ Yeah.
Jerry?
‐ Jerry!
‐ What?
Answer the damn phone!
Blood's finally here
from O'Hare.
Blood bank's restocked.
Peter.
'Hey.'
Hey, I was looking
for you upstairs.
Yeah, a I had a hot appendix
turned out
to be unrefrigerated,
three‐day‐old pizza.
Do you have the forms?
Hold on.
Hey, where's Reese?
He's in the car.
You left him
in the car?
Yeah, he's with a friend.
Dafina? Carla, she better not
be smoking.
Peter, the forms,
did you sign them?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I've been working all day.
I need those forms today
so Reese can start on Monday.
‐ Monday?
‐ Yes, Monday.
Are you going to sign them?
I don't know. I was trying
to check out other alternatives.
‐ Forget it. Just forget it.
‐ What?
‐ Just forget it.
‐ Carla, Carla, look, look.
I'm not convinced this is
the best thing for the baby.
Thanks for the vote
of confidence, Peter.
Carla, I think I deserve more
than one day to make up my mind.
Fine. Take a week, a month...
hell, take six.
Just let me know
when you've decided
what's right for my life.
You know, it's not
just your decision to make.
Peter.
Wait! Where do you think
you're going?
To see my son.
He's in the car, right?
Peter, get back inside.
What? Is Dafina in here
smoking again?
Look, come by later.
You can see him then.
'Hey.'
Peter Benton,
Roger McGrath.
Roger McGrath,
Peter Benton.
Roger, will you put Reese
in the car seat, please?
Peter, I been meaning
to talk to you about this.
He works with Chandra
over at the CTA.
He's steady and smart
and...Reese loves him.
All in.
You take care now.
If you want to talk
about this later
give me a call, okay?
Hey, Scoot.
Hey, Chase.
You asked me
to drop by today.
Oh, right.
Right, right.
How you feeling?
I've been better.
Nothing some crank
and a half gallon
of Stoli's wouldn't fix.
That was a joke, Scooter.
That's not very funny.
Listen, can you hang out
for a second?
There's a patient
I don't want to miss.
‐ Hey, Anna.
‐ Hi, Chase. How are you?
Oh, great. Never better,
thanks to you.
Your cousin there
did all the work.
'Hey, John,
when do you get off work?'
I could take you and..
...Anna out to a great dinner.
Uh, actually, I've got to..
Maybe some other time.
Take care.
Trouble in paradise?
Something like that.
You going to go
after her?
If you don't, I will.
Mark, have you seen Carol?
Yeah, she's down the hall.
A retarded couple had
a baby this afternoon.
She's teaching them
how to change diapers.
No kidding.
A little girl,
six pounds, seven ounces.
Name's Madison.
Seems fine.
Good for her.
Listen, uh,
Cynthia left early.
Chuny said she was upset.
I'm going to talk to her.
I know what I'm doing, Doug.
If you say so.
Hey.
We saved that rapist today.
'Hell of a world, huh?'
Yeah. I'll see you later.
Anna!
What the hell's
the matter with you?
Go back inside, Carter.
You're going to freeze
your ass off out here.
I don't understand. This
morning, everything was great.
I'm tired.
I was on all night.
Let's just call it a day, okay?
Is this about that rapist?
You know what this is about,
Carter!
No, I don't.
Why didn't you use
the blood on hand?
It's all we had.
So?
We used six units
on that guard this morning.
We were short then
and you didn't even blink.
'Why not use the blood
on the kid?'
I thought auto‐transfusion was
the best course of action.
Oh, please.
We could have done
a thoracotomy.
'We could have
pumped in blood'
'on the rapid infuser.'
Yeah, well, he lived.
He's in recovery.
Dumb luck!
You are one of the most
aggressive physicians
I have ever seen in trauma
and you auto‐transfuse him?
You didn't want to waste
the blood on the kid.
You didn't care
if he lived or died.
It's my trauma,
it's my call.
Would you have
done it differently
if the patient
hadn't been a rapist?
Come on.
Every case is different.
Did you withhold treatment
from that kid?
No.
John, did you
withhold treatment?
No.
Fancy meeting you here.
Hey.
'Listen, um..'
...you feel like any darts?
Just darts?
Yeah. Just darts.
I mean, if that's okay.
Don't know what you're missing.
I've got
a pretty good idea.
As long as I'm not
being...unappreciated.
You know, darts
usually involves wagering
of a rather
substantial nature.
Alright, um...
a penny a point.
I've withdrawn
the contract.
I called Anspaugh
and told him
that Synergix is
no longer interested
in managing county's
emergency department.
Why would you do that?
I only wanted the contract
if it meant working closely
with you, Kerry.
Apparently, that's
not possible anymore, so..
You are a smart, beautiful,
sexy woman
and I don't want
you believing
that I used you,
because I didn't.
'And I never
underestimated you.'
Never once.
You underestimate yourself.
Take care.
So you fold under.
You fold up.
And you fold over
just like that.
Okay?
Now you try.
'Fold up.'
Fold it over.
That's good.
Try it again.
Looks like
they're doing great.
Yeah.
So why is it
so hard for us?
I don't know.
I didn't mean to push you.
Take as much time
as you need.
I'll wait.
Hey.
How long you been
sitting here?
About an hour.
Give or take.
I wanted him to die.
I saw what he did
to that old lady..
...and the others before
and I wanted him to die.
I didn't think
he should have that blood.
I mean if someone
had come in
and they...really needed it..
If some little kid
had been hit by a car
or some old guy
had been accidentally shot.
'If someone like that
had died'
'because we wasted
the blood on that guy..'
I don't know.
It was my decision.
And I made it.
And if he had died,
I don't know how I'd feel.
But I can't say that I'm sorry.
I mean, was that wrong?
Anna, are you sure?
No.
I'm not sure.