This patient
harms herself
to get attention.
I'm not available to give you
the kind of care you need.
But I want you.
Where's Ramona?
Check the front.
Tell security.
Did you snow him to
force him into surgery?
Why would I do that?
I think you're
suffering from PTSD.
That's why I keep pushing you
to talk to Dr. Charles.
What's going on?
Something's off.
I don't have
the bandwidth to worry
about anyone else.
I need some space.
The drug we're testing,
any idea how it might affect
a patient with an LVAD?
If there's a patient suffering
any adverse reaction,
it needs to be reported.
If we can keep
from getting caught,
your mom may not ever
need a transplant.
Will, I do not want to
put you in this position.
You let me worry about that.
Hey, Sabeena.
I haven't seen you
around the ED lately.
Haven't seen you
around the trial office.
Though, I don't blame you.
I have been a little hard
on you lately.
I had it coming.
It's true.
Last round of follow-ups
going okay?
Everything looks good.
A few more left to go,
and we're done.
That's great.
You know what
that means, right?
Kender starts the first stage
of data analysis.
Wait.
Is there still a chance?
You and me?
Just a slight chance.
Well, in that case,
you better get to work.
Come on, get upstairs.
Move it.
Course guide.
Going back to school?
Got my interview for
Med's Nurse Practitioner
program today.
Squeezed in
under the deadline.
I'm sure you'll do great.
Are you okay?
You haven't
seemed yourself lately.
No, just been working
some late nights.
You know how it goes.
Okay.
Great, thanks.
Will! I need
a little help.
Where should we go?
Treatment Five.
What's going on?
I think Mom's
in liver failure.
Do you think this
is from the trial meds?
I don't know.
Hey, Carol.
Does your belly hurt?
Yes, it does.
Okay. Let's get you
into bed.
Okay.
Come on, Mom.
Hey, Carol.
Hi, Crockett.
Hi, how you doing?
Okay. Thank you.
Come on.
Okay.
There you go. Easy.
Yeah. Thanks, guys. Oh!
Yeah. Jaundice, edema.
I think you're right.
Hi.
Liver failure?
How's her cardiac
function been?
You know, pretty good.
Yeah?
Yeah.
On just the standard meds?
Why? Shouldn't it be?
It's just, you hadn't
been responding before,
but it looks like
they're working well.
We'll need to do
a full workup.
Okay. I'll get a liver panel,
CBC, CMP, and coags.
Thanks, April.
And we'll need a list
of her medications as well.
Okay.
This could be
a drug interaction.
We have to rule
everything out.
You're right.
But this doesn't
look surgical.
I'll take it from here.
You never know.
Could be an obstruction,
gallstones.
I better stay on
just to be safe.
Hey...
Yeah.
Um, I really appreciate
everything you're doing
to help.
And I promise, as soon
as this becomes surgical,
I will call you, okay?
Whatever you want.
I'll see you, Carol.
Thank you. Bye.
Hey, Maggie.
Morning, Sharon.
How's it going?
Okay.
It's just that tomorrow's
Vanessa's last day here.
I didn't handle things right.
Well, it's not an easy
situation.
I know. But I'm thinking,
maybe if I told her
the truth...
I don't like leaving things
the way that they are,
with the two of us at odds.
I don't know, Maggie,
once you take that step...
I know.
Morning, Dean.
Hey.
So, uh, I have to ask.
Have you sat down
with Dr. Charles yet?
Mmm.
Actually, he referred me
to a veterans' therapy group.
Went last night.
Really?
Yeah, yeah.
It was something, man.
The stories you hear,
the things people
have been through.
There's a deep well of pain
out there, man.
I can imagine.
Bet you had
some stories, too.
Oh, well, nothing worth saying
compared to what I heard
last night.
And I wanna thank you
for leaning on me.
Last night was inspiring.
I'm sorry.
Am I interrupting?
No, ma'am.
We have an 18-year-old
in Treatment Six.
And a few weeks ago,
she was diagnosed with
a cranial hemangioblastoma.
Eighteen, that's tough.
Yeah.
Do you two mind
taking a look?
Of course.
Thank you.
Mindy, is this the first time
you've passed out
since your diagnosis?
I just got dizzy for a second.
It's not a big deal!
Yes, it is.
When they diagnosed
her last month,
they said the tumor
was small.
Does this mean
it's growing?
Well, possibly.
Or it could mean
there's a bleed.
Either would be a reason
to recommend surgery
to remove it.
I'm not doing that.
But, sweetie,
if it's getting worse...
No!
No one's digging
through my brain!
She's spent the last month
glued to her computer,
reading horror stories
about brain surgery.
They're not just stories, Dad.
People come out changed.
They stutter,
they have seizures,
they forget everybody's names.
I play the piano.
What if I can't
do that anymore?
Uh-uh. No way.
Okay, before we
go any further,
why don't we get a CT
to see what
we're dealing with?
Then we can talk again
and come up with a plan.
Yeah, yeah.
We'll be right back.
Excuse us.
Her oncologist wanted
to remove the tumor
back when she was
first diagnosed.
But you can see there's
no talking to her.
Is there any way that...
Can we make her do it?
Uh, I'm sorry, but no.
She's 18 years old.
She has the right
to make her own decisions.
But she's still a kid.
She doesn't understand
the consequences.
We're at our wits' end.
We don't know what else to do.
Look, I see
how distressing this is,
and understandably so.
But there is one thing,
as parents, you can do.
Tell us.
You can apply for temporary
power of attorney.
This would give you
the ability to make
medical decisions,
should she
become unconscious.
You can do it
with her consent.
But using it to get
a procedure she doesn't want
would still be circumventing
your daughter's stated wishes.
With the goal
of saving her life.
Okay. Can we discuss it?
Of course.
Uh, in the meantime,
I'll order a CT.
Mom's going up
for her echo now.
Are those her labs?
Yeah. It is
acute liver failure.
Oh, God.
And look at this.
Hepatitis C?
She must've been carrying it
a long time asymptomatically.
Which means
something happened
to push her over the edge.
Do you think
it's a drug interaction?
I'm not sure what else
it could be.
We have to take her off
the trial medication.
That's our only choice.
Oh, God.
I know. I'll put her back
on her old cardiac meds
until we get
her liver failure
under control.
And then what?
I'll find something.
Thanks.
Yeah.
I found her
sitting on a bench.
She said that
she wanted to talk to you.
Wow.
Thanks, Mags.
Yeah.
Hi, Dr. Charles.
Ramona, how you doing?
Good. Very good.
You gave me a real scare,
running out of here
like you did last time.
I'm glad to see
you're okay.
I'm sorry, but there's
no reason for you to worry.
So, um, what's going on?
What can I do for you?
Actually, I just wanted you
to know that I'm fine.
Oh. That's great.
And you know what?
I really appreciate you
letting me know. I do.
Yeah. I just got
a new apartment,
and I'm working.
I'm just temping now,
but I think they'll
keep me on full-time.
Wow. Things are
really looking up.
They are.
So, I thought,
if you had a little
free time,
maybe we could get
a cup of coffee.
You know what?
I am in the middle
of my workday.
But I really would like
to hear about what's been
going on with you.
So, um, what do you say...
I don't know,
let's make an appointment.
Meet in my office
and have a proper chat?
I just thought
we could hang out.
Probably better
that we make an appointment.
I tell you what.
Call me anytime.
Okay? I mean it.
If you don't get me,
leave a message.
I'll call you
right back. Okay?
Okay.
Great.
Really good
to see you, Ramona. Really.
It's good to see you, too.
Dr. Marcel, incoming.
What do we got?
Baghdad.
Twenty-six-year-old male
in respiratory distress.
Status, post double lung
transplant eight days ago.
James?
You know him?
Yeah. I was his surgeon.
Hillary, hey,
what happened?
He started having trouble
breathing the day after
we got home.
His pulmonologist said
to continue taking his meds,
but he just kept getting worse
until today, he got a fever.
Yeah, okay. All right.
James, we're gonna take
good care of you, bud. Okay?
On my count.
One, two, three.
There we go.
James, on a scale
of one to ten,
how hard is it to breathe?
Eight. Maybe a nine.
O2 sats 85 on 12 liters.
And he's tachycardic at 106.
Deep breaths for me, James.
Yeah. Major consolidation
in both lungs.
Let's order cultures,
lytes, CBC with diff,
cyclosporine level,
and get him up
for a chest CT, stat.
Got it.
Let me see your hands, bud.
Is he rejecting the lungs?
No. He's immunosuppressed,
so, he shouldn't be.
But he's definitely got
a bilateral pneumonia.
The question is why.
James? I wanna get you
on a BiPAP machine to help
you breathe. Is that okay?
Okay. You hang in there
for me, okay?
I'll check back soon,
all right?
So soon after surgery.
What do you think happened?
Yeah, I'm not sure yet.
But I do know when
it goes this bad this fast,
surgeon error is always
at the top of the list.
You find anything yet?
There's not a single case
of liver failure
in the entire trial.
If it is a contraindication,
then Kender needs to know.
Yeah.
I guess I should
go find Dr. Virani.
Uh...
I need to let her know.
No. She's not in yet.
Don't worry. I'll handle it.
No, I stole the pills.
I gave them
to my mom illegally.
I need to be the one
to tell her myself.
Sure.
Hey, James. Hillary.
Dr. Marcel. Have you
figured out what's going on?
So, I've looked at the labs,
the scans.
The only reason
I can come up with for getting
a pneumonia this fast,
was that something
must've gone wrong during
the transplant surgery.
Wrong? What do you mean?
Well, the lungs
could've mismatched,
a stitch could've come loose.
I'm really not sure.
So, what do we do now?
How do we fix this?
Honestly, the options
are not good.
As you can see, the pneumonia
has already caused significant
damage to both lungs.
At this point, we need
to put you on ECMO,
a machine that oxygenates
your blood for you.
For how long?
It's hard to say.
But if we end up
having to search
for a new pair of lungs,
it could be several
more months.
Wait. Are you saying that
these lungs can't be saved?
I'm not saying that.
But it is possible.
I'm so sorry
this happened. I...
Look, I promise you,
I'm going to do
everything I...
I'll give you some space.
James' new X-ray.
Lungs are just
getting worse.
Damn it.
When I was
on the COVID ward,
I saw a lot of films
that looked just like that.
Is it possible
he's infected?
No. The donor was negative.
And James tested negative
when he came in today.
I understand. But maybe
it's worth retesting him.
No. The truth is,
you were right.
My head has been completely
out of the game lately.
And because of that,
I may have cost
this man his life.
If there's any donor tissue,
we could check,
just in case...
April, I appreciate
everything you're doing.
I do. Now, please,
call the ECMO team.
And let's get
this man hooked up
before his lungs
completely fail.
Hey, Irma.
Hey!
Can you look up
the records of
an organ donor?
I need to know if there's
any lung tissue
you can test for COVID.
Sure, I'll check
for you, April.
No, no lung tissue.
Okay. Thanks.
But we do have
some deep washings.
Can you test that?
Sure.
But I'd need a doctor's order.
Here.
Really, April?
Come on. You gonna make me
go back upstairs?
Okay, "Dr. Marcel."
I'll call you
when it's ready.
Thank you.
All right.
You know, it's wonderful that
you're doing so well. Really.
I guess what
I'm curious about
is what happened
in the last four weeks.
Oh, God. The self-harming,
I mean, the poison?
It all seems
like a bad dream now.
I realized stuff like that
was crazy.
Wow.
That is great.
You know,
that's a huge step.
Really.
Any insights into why
you were doing that stuff?
What do you mean?
As I recall,
we were talking a lot about
your family, all right?
And in particular, your dad,
and how you thought
that your relationship
changed as you got older?
Dr. Charles, you always
come back to that.
My father.
I mean, I thought
we were just gonna
hang out and catch up.
Isn't that kinda
what we're doing?
Okay. My father molested me
when I was little. A lot.
I wished every day
that it wouldn't happen,
but it would,
and there was nothing
I could do about it.
Ramona, I am
so sorry to hear that.
It's okay.
You know what?
It's not okay.
I mean, I can't imagine
how difficult,
how awful that must have been
for you to go through that.
It was.
But it's all
in the past now.
You know,
in my experience,
recognizing that
something like that happened,
as crucial as it is,
and then processing it,
are actually
two different things.
Okay, look, no.
I have processed it.
That's what
I'm trying to tell you.
I completely understand
how it might feel...
No. Okay, see, we don't
need to talk about this.
You and I can just be friends.
Regular friends.
Ramona, I am absolutely
100% here for you
as your doctor.
Okay. Stop! I don't
need a psychiatrist!
Ramona...
Ramona, sit down.
Why won't you listen to me?
I am fine!
Ramona.
Okay. Yeah. Bye.
Maggie, I've got some orders
for Treatment Two.
Okay, sure. Oh, wait.
Mmm-hmm.
Can we meet up
at the end of the day?
Did I make a mistake?
Uh, no, it's just we use some
different abbreviations here,
and the doctors
are sticklers on it.
So, I thought
we could just meet up
and go over them.
Yeah. Yeah, sure.
All right. Yeah. Right.
Nat. Your mom's EKG.
She developed
a long QT interval?
Exactly, but there's
an upside to that.
She's now a candidate
for biventricular pacing.
The cath lab?
But she's still
in acute liver failure.
Yeah, but it's a heart issue,
nothing to do with the liver.
It's a major procedure,
and she's extremely sick.
Yeah. If we don't
try something,
she could go into a dangerous
arrhythmia at any moment.
But it's not a cure,
and she still needs
a heart transplant.
That's right. And this is our
best shot at keeping her alive
until she gets one.
I don't know, Will.
There are so many
potential complications.
This is your mom. I'm not
leaving any stone unturned.
Okay. Let's give it a try.
I'll set it up.
Lead's in
the coronary sinus.
Just putting in the wire.
These veins
are extremely tortuous.
I'm getting a lot
of resistance.
How about
a venography balloon
to anchor you in?
That'd be great. Susie?
I'm on it.
Carol, how you doing?
Oh, I'm great.
Good.
Shouldn't be much longer.
We're just grabbing
an extra piece of equipment.
Okay, Will.
Just take your...
Carol?
Her pressure's dropping.
Heart rate's up to 180.
What's happening?
She's in SVT. Bag her.
Carol? Carol!
She's unresponsive.
Looks like tamponade.
The wire must've perforated
her heart. 60cc syringe.
Mom? Mom!
Syringe.
She's gonna arrest
if you don't get in there now.
I think I'm in.
No. Nothing.
Angle it deeper.
Charge to 200.
Hold up!
I've got blood.
Rhythm's back.
Heart rate's down.
Pulse is strong.
All right, set up
for continuous drainage.
Hey, Vanessa brought
her parents in and wants them
to meet everyone.
Oh.
And this is our
charge nurse, Maggie.
Sure.
She keeps the place running.
Maggie, these are my parents,
Kent and Bea.
Hi.
Hello.
Nice to meet you.
Your daughter is great.
She just loves
working here.
She can't stop talking
about the patients,
how much
she's learning...
Okay, Mom.
What?
You do.
Okay.
Ah, parents...
Such an embarrassment.
Ugh, come on!
Let me show you where
the ambulances come in.
So nice to meet you.
Likewise.
Dr. Choi!
Dr. Archer!
She's not waking up!
Mindy?
What's going on?
The bleed must've gotten
much worse,
faster than we expected.
What can we do?
You can use
your power of attorney.
Say the word, and we'll
take her right up to surgery.
But I'm sure we'd all
rather have Mindy
make this decision.
How?
We can drill a hole
in her skull right here
to release the pressure.
Then when she wakes up,
we can explain the situation
and get her consent.
Let her make the choice.
Okay.
Dr. Choi, a minute, please?
All right.
Nancy, get the drill.
High-flow O2,
elevate her head.
We both know
she needs this surgery.
This is our chance.
Did you do this?
What?
Sedate her
to override her wishes?
I am trying
to save this girl's life.
I'm about to drill
a hole in her head.
Am I gonna see blood?
Drill the hole, Doctor.
Nancy?
Okay.
All right.
Keep her still.
Yeah.
I can't...
Ready?
Yeah.
Okay.
She's waking up.
Mindy, you're okay.
Do you want me to
set up a drain
for the rest of the blood?
Yeah.
Hey, Mindy.
Huh?
Hey, you're okay.
Ramona,
it's Dr. Charles again.
I don't know
if you got my last message,
but I think it would be
a really good idea
for us to continue
our conversation.
So, I hope you call me back.
At least to let me know
that you're doing okay.
Okay.
Come in.
Hey.
Hello.
Almost done, huh?
Yes.
Good.
We never ended up
looking at interactions
with Hepatitis C, did we?
Of course not.
You know we screen all
Hep-positive patients out.
Right.
Though, if we knew
there was a definite
contraindication with Hep C,
that would be
good to know, right?
I suppose.
Why are you
bringing this up?
There is a patient
who's on the drug
who was not screened.
Did they slip
through our protocols?
No. It's not
that she slipped through.
It's that she's not
part of the trial.
Are you telling me
our drug went
to an outside patient?
Will, this is
a massive breach of protocol.
Who did this?
What's important
is that...
Dr. Halstead.
There's a very
sick woman...
Who gave
an unauthorized patient
our trial drug?
Me. I did.
I can't believe you.
You swore you would never do
anything like this again.
Sabeena, the patient
was out of options...
Stop making excuses!
I trusted you,
and you betray me like this.
Who's the patient?
She's Natalie's mother.
That explains it all,
doesn't it?
You realize you have
quite possibly
compromised the trial,
not to mention your career.
You can leave.
Okay. Thank you so much.
Why isn't Mr. Barton
on ECMO?
I ordered a culture
of the lung donor's washings,
and told the ECMO tech
to hold off just...
That man in there is dying,
and every moment counts.
I know, but I just heard back
from the lab...
April, for you to ignore me
because of something
you think
you saw on an X-ray
is absolutely inexcusable.
Dr. Marcel, it's positive.
There were traces
of COVID DNA in the lungs.
I have COVID?
No,
you do not have COVID.
The lungs you were given
had been infected with COVID.
Even though the donor
tested negative?
He must've
already recovered.
But not before
the virus caused
widespread microscopic
damage to his lungs.
None of which was visible
at the time of the transplant.
But it made them
very susceptible
to pneumonia.
So, this wasn't
anybody's fault?
Just bad luck?
It was.
But the good news is
Dr. Marcel might be able
to save one of the lungs.
But this would be
a very risky surgery.
And even then,
I won't know until
I'm in there,
whether you'll have
enough functional lung
left to survive.
I could die?
Yes, you could.
So, if you'd rather
me not perform the surgery,
I can get you on ECMO
and we can start looking
for a new set of lungs.
Hey, it's okay.
James?
I trust you.
Okay. Then we're gonna
get you up there right now.
All right?
Right now, the drain
is keeping the pressure
from building up.
But she can only
stay on like this
for so long.
Are we talking days? Weeks?
Depends on several factors.
Whether the tumor
continues to grow,
or whether the bleed
breaks through the clot.
But she will eventually
need the surgery.
So, I suggest...
Give me a minute
with her. Okay?
Hey.
I don't need another
lecture right now.
I know you think
I'm being stupid.
Oh, come on.
Are you kidding me?
Sometimes, being scared
is just about the smartest
thing a person can be.
Listen, I was a doctor
in Iraq. All right?
And, uh,
we were in a town that
was considered friendly.
And I'm just standing there
in the middle of the street,
and all of a sudden,
we start taking fire,
seemed it was coming
from every direction.
And right off the bat,
I'm hit.
My left thigh,
blood pouring out
everywhere.
And so, I hightail it
to some stairwell.
All right? It was hidden,
it was relatively quiet,
and all I wanted to do
was just sit there
and wait for
the shooting to stop.
I couldn't stop the bleeding.
I tried, couldn't stop it.
And after a while,
I started feeling woozy,
started getting cold.
And I knew
I was gonna die right there.
All I could hear
on the other side
of that wall
was shooting, all right?
So, somehow,
I just forced myself
to run out of there,
run right through the middle
of that firefight.
I'm running and running,
and somehow,
by some miracle, I made it.
Leaving that stairwell
was the hardest thing
I ever had to do.
But it was what I needed
to do to save my life.
Do you understand?
So, as scary as this is,
if I'm there with you
the whole time
during this surgery,
will you take
that chance, too?
It's really my only chance?
Yeah, it is.
Okay.
Okay. Okay.
Looks like
you may have picked
the right man for this job.
Yeah.
Ramona, I'm so glad
that you...
Okay, Ramona?
Don't do anything.
Don't move.
I'll be right there.
I'm on my way.
Hey, Ramona.
Any way I could
get you to, um,
step back onto the balcony,
so, we could chat a bit?
I keep wondering,
would it make
any difference
if I jumped?
Oh, it would make
a great difference to me.
I can tell you that.
Hey. Easy, easy! Easy, easy.
Ramona, it's okay.
I just wanna talk.
When I came
to see you this morning,
I just wanted to
talk to someone
like a normal person.
Just have a conversation.
Yeah. Okay.
I just want a normal life.
Yeah.
So, Ramona, a normal life,
what does that
look like for you?
It looks like
not feeling like a freak.
Like, not being
totally alone all the time.
Yeah.
It looks like having
maybe someone who...
Who you could trust?
Yeah.
Somebody who always
has your back, no matter what.
Yes!
Ramona, look at me.
Look at me.
You can trust me.
I absolutely have your back.
And not just me,
there's so much help
for you out there.
I'm scared.
Of course you're scared.
You've been through
something awful.
To really look at that,
it's gotta be scary as hell.
But you know what?
I know that you are
brave enough to do that.
You do?
I do.
And I also know
about a safe place
where that could happen.
What kind of safe place?
It's a place where
there are women
who have been through the same
kind of thing that you have.
What would you think
about maybe letting me
take you there?
I got you. I got you.
I got you.
It's okay, it's okay,
it's okay. I got you.
It'll be okay.
He opened his eyes.
Does that mean
he's gonna be okay?
It means he's waking up
from anesthesia.
What matters is
if he's able
to follow commands.
Hey, James. Hey.
Squeeze my hand.
Give it a good squeeze.
Come on, give it
everything you got.
There it is.
That's good, right?
Oh, my God,
thank you both so much.
Hi.
Hey, April.
Look, I'm sorry about
getting upset before.
I shouldn't have.
You saved his life.
I'm just glad it worked out.
Yeah.
Hey, I never asked.
How'd your interview go?
Oh, my God!
Hey.
So, the pacer's
not gonna be enough.
Gift of Hope's got her
at the top of
the transplant list. Okay?
Hopefully, a new heart
will come up soon.
Oh, um,
you know, I never did get
to talk to Dr. Virani today.
You know what?
She never came in.
Oh.
Yeah. So, maybe, you can
track her down tomorrow.
Okay. I really hope
you don't get
into any trouble.
I wouldn't worry about that.
Thank you for everything
you did today.
Sure.
Thank you.
Yeah.
She looks good.
Yeah. I think it's gonna be
a quick recovery.
Dean, that story in Iraq.
I had no idea you went
through anything like that.
Yeah, didn't we all?
Not like that. I didn't.
Yeah, okay. So...
Wait.
That story,
did you make it up?
No. I did not make it up.
Actually, I heard it
from one of the guys
in my vet's group.
I mean, it's not exactly
the same story,
but it's close.
Anyway, that reminds me,
my group's about to start.
So, I better get a move on.
I got your page.
Hey.
Yeah.
Look, Natalie,
if you and Will
are getting back together,
just tell me.
This not knowing,
it's driving me crazy.
No, Will and I
are not getting back together.
Okay, then what?
I mean,
you've been keeping secrets,
shutting me out.
Something's going on.
What?
I stole meds
from Will's trial.
My mom was so sick,
and nothing was working.
I was desperate.
I wanted to tell you...
Oh.
...but I felt so guilty,
and so afraid.
And now, my mom
is dying in there,
and she needs a new heart,
and I don't know what to do.
Oh, honey. Come here.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
It's okay, Nat. It's okay.
It's okay, it's okay.
Okay. Yeah.
There you go. Thank you.
Hey, you want to talk to me
about abbreviations?
I'll call you right back.
Yes. I wrote them
down for you.
Cool.
Your parents, they seem
like really nice people.
Yeah, they're great.
Well, you know, parents.
Sure.
Yes. I get this.
Anything else, Maggie?
No. That's it.
Okay. Yeah,
I'll see you tomorrow.
See you tomorrow.
It looks nice.
I think
you're gonna find this
a pretty special place.
Hey, Daniel.
Ramona, this is Dr. Garner.
Oh, please, call me Anne.
It's nice
to meet you, Ramona.
Your room is ready,
and there's breakfast
in the kitchen
if you're hungry.
So, would you like to come in
and meet everyone?
Mmm-hmm.
Okay.