House?
Oh, my God!
What the hell?
Gotcha. Did you
actually wake up early
and hide under the bed just
to scare the crap out of me?
Set an alarm and everything.
It's like dating a 10-year-old.
God, I hope not.
Now that we're down here...
Hold that thought.
Seriously?
I have to pee.
I'll wait. I brought a book.
Didn't know what time
your alarm was set for.
House?
You know, you could rent
this space out down here.
In Japan, that would
be like a deluxe...
House, shut up.
There's blood in my urine.
You really don't
have to be here.
You're my girlfriend.
I'm being supportive.
I'm mainly talking about them.
Well, given that there's almost
certainly nothing
wrong with you,
and my patient definitely has
something wrong with him...
That can't wait an hour?
Afraid not. He's...
Chase?
Sixteen-year-old
male spit up blood
during a pick-up
basketball game.
ER couldn't find the source
in his lungs or GI tract.
See? Serious.
Could be vasculitis,
bronchiectasis, inhaled particles.
What about angiodysplasia?
Ready when you are.
Get them out of here.
My urethra is not for
public entertainment.
But it is good-time adjacent.
Feed the kid a camera, check
his gut for angiodysplasia.
All right, scoot up here.
I'm missing a watch. If you
could keep your eyes open while...
Okay. You, too.
This little camera
transmits images
to the data recorder
so we can see if you've got any
vascular malformations
in your GI tract.
Your records show you've lost
some weight over the past year.
Was that
intentional? Not really.
Well, he's been eating less
since he quit the swim team.
You have to get
up early for swim.
It wasn't fun anymore.
I need to talk to your
son about sexual activity.
Generally, it's less
embarrassing for everyone...
We're leaving.
Actually, I've only ever...
How long have you
been cutting yourself?
Those are from a layback
grind that went wrong.
Came off my skateboard,
straight into a fence.
So, no to cutting but yes to
appetite and sleep changes,
and you quit something
you used to enjoy.
How long have you
been depressed?
Imaging showed no
sign of upper GI issues,
but the kid did admit
to being depressed
and to smoking pot
to take the edge off.
You are very pleased
with yourself, aren't you?
His marijuana could be laced
with formaldehyde or lead,
which could cause a
pulmonary hemorrhage,
which could make
him spit up blood.
Yes. Yes, I am. It
was a good catch.
Run a lead level and
push five liters IV fluid.
Feel free to tip
your other server.
Cystoscopy was clean,
cytopathology was normal...
Why do you have my lab results?
I don't. If I did, I'd
know you were fine.
Unless the blood
came from my kidneys.
Come on.
Your hypochondriac mom had
a brush with mortality last month.
It's understandable that
you're worrying more than usual.
Worrying that you
might turn into her.
You're right.
Odds are this is nothing.
Meet me in the cafeteria in 10.
There'll be a corn dog
with your name on it.
I mean an actual corn dog.
They fixed the deep fryer.
I need to schedule
an ultrasound.
My dad's head is
still in one piece,
so I'm guessing you
didn't mention the pot.
What'd you tell them? The truth.
You had a minor
chemical exposure
and we can't be 100%
sure how it happened.
Thanks for covering.
I know what it's like to be 16.
You also know what
it's like to be depressed.
You figured out my deal
after only a few minutes.
I've been fooling my friends
and parents for months.
It's my job to notice things.
Maybe talking to your parents
would make things better.
I've tried.
They take it personally
that I'm not happy,
and then I end up having
to make them feel better.
They don't get me.
No one does.
In med school, it seemed like
everybody else could handle the pressure.
I couldn't.
I ended up hurting myself.
Stupidest thing I've ever done.
You've got red spots in your
eyes. They weren't there before.
You have nice skin.
Thank you. Shut up.
Sorry, just thought it would
be rude not to comment.
Just treat me like
any other patient.
Right.
Are you sucking in your stomach?
No.
Now hurry up before I pass out.
Wilson?
Ultrasound isn't definitive. We
should run other tests before...
Stop talking like a doctor
and tell me what you see.
There's a mass in your kidney.
We still don't know why
Ryan coughed blood,
and now he's got small
hemorrhages in his eyes.
Sounds like an
acquired coagulopathy,
which gives us a
pretty wide differential.
Gets a lot narrower if we
factor in his depression.
Oh, don't do that.
Mood swings can be a
symptom of physiological illness.
Not talking to you.
Mood swings are also a
symptom of adolescence,
along with emo music
and masturbation.
More importantly,
his weight loss
and sleeping issues
started a year ago.
Infection makes the most sense.
He shoots hoops at school,
showers in the locker room.
I'm thinking staph or... - Damn.
You don't think...
Not talking to you.
Everything okay with Cuddy?
- She's fine.
She's just too
stupid to accept it.
Start him on
nafcillin for staph.
All that's in the First
Mutual safety deposit box.
The retirement accounts...
You're freaking out
because of one ultrasound
performed by an
incompetent bonobo monkey.
As demonstrated by my sitting
here calmly, going about my business.
Calling in a lawyer,
drafting a will.
Okay. I hacked into
your on-line schedule.
Look, tests always
show something.
Mass in your kidney could be a
complex cyst, it could be benign...
I'm a single mom.
I need to set up a
trust, appoint a guardian.
It's silly that I haven't
done it before now.
But you're doing it now
because you think you're sick.
The freaking out
can at least wait
until after the
biopsy this afternoon.
The biopsy's not till tomorrow.
It's the first opening
in the schedule.
For the Dean of Medicine, the
first opening in the schedule is...
Oh, look. Now!
My worry isn't any more
important than anyone else's.
Actually, it is.
But I'm not sick, right?
Good point.
I want my stuff, asshat.
I told you, man, I
don't have it here.
Hey, guys. Everything okay?
On my way out.
I'll see you later.
You want to tell
me what's going on?
My friend gave me some
leftover Klonopin he had
when he switched
to seizure meds.
I sold them to Roid
Rage for 80 bucks,
but I landed in here
before I could deliver,
and now he's gonna
rip my arms off.
How often do you sell drugs?
It was a one-time thing.
I needed the cash, I had the
pills, so I thought, "Why not?"
It was a bad idea.
The pills are at my house. I
could have a friend go get them.
Give the thug his money back.
One time only.
I mean, if you're
okay with this.
You have three kids of your own.
It's not even a question. Of
course, I'll be Rachel's guardian.
And House is cool with this?
I mean, you guys...
We've only been
together a few months.
It seems like a lot longer.
Probably because you've been
talking about him for 10 years.
And by "talking," I
mean ranting about
wanting to smash his teeth in
with a stapler for being such a jerk.
People change.
WILSON: I'll get it.
That better be her.
Rachel Cuddy, you were supposed
to be home half an hour ago.
Don't blame me.
He's the one who
wouldn't run any red lights.
Mouth on that kid makes Mel
Gibson sound like Nelson Mandela.
Where'd she learn that?
I don't know why you're
here, but I didn't do it.
What's the problem, Officer?
She was shoplifting
down at the mall.
Are either of you
this girl's father?
Nope. But since her mom died,
she's my favorite tax write-off.
Officer, you have my
word, it won't happen again.
Because next time
she won't get caught!
It's no big deal.
Good for you.
You could have just
assumed he was a drug dealer,
but instead you
took his word for it.
It's nice to finally
see someone have
a little faith in
humanity around here.
Why would you do that?
Ryan, you okay in there?
I'm not sure.
I think I just peed blood.
Looks like peeing
blood is the new black.
Peeing blood after
a night on antibiotics
means we can move
on from infections.
Scoping showed no sign
of a bleed in his bladder,
which points to
a kidney problem.
Probably some kind of mass.
A kidney mass wouldn't explain
the coughing blood
or the hemorrhages.
Antiphospholipid syndrome,
on the other hand...
Makes sense. But
doesn't rule out a mass.
You think it's cancer?
Mass doesn't have to be cancer.
It could be a renal hematoma.
But the patient doesn't have
any other abdominal trauma.
He's not talking
about the patient.
Cuddy has a mass on her kidney?
It's probably just a complex
cyst or angiomyolipoma.
It's a mass, not a mystery.
They'll do the biopsy, then
you'll have your answer.
Just have to wait.
Patient admitted to using pot.
Who knows what else he's doing.
This could be
heroin-induced nephropathy.
I thought you trusted this kid.
And then you pointed
out how sweet that was.
If it were heroin, he'd be
going through withdrawal.
Antiphospholipid
syndrome's a better fit.
Start the patient
on plasmapheresis.
While he's doing that, can I at
least search his house for drugs?
Have I ever said
no to that question?
What are you doing here?
Pie-eating contest.
Cuddy's biopsy is in an hour. You
should be keeping her company.
Okay, you've been worried
that your relationship is getting
in the way of your diagnoses,
you're protecting your patient.
Either that, or you're an ass.
Three, I hate the
smell of death.
The chances of Cuddy
having renal cell carcinoma...
I'm talking about
our relationship.
She needs support and comfort,
both things that I
famously suck at.
Which will inevitably lead to...
You know what's
good for that? Practice.
Doing it, I don't know, once.
I'm not gonna act like there's a
crisis before we know there is one.
There's no proof that there's
anything wrong with her.
There's no proof she's being
stalked by ninja squirrels either,
but if she's scared of them,
as her boyfriend, it's your job
to figure out how to
help her feel better.
You're right.
House told me to
keep you company.
Nurse told me to
give you antibiotics.
Tell House I'm fine.
Hmm.
Tom Cruise got married.
Do you want me to quote from First
Corinthians? Because I can do that.
As a Jew, I'm gonna
have to decline that offer.
Don't know what you're missing.
Saint Paul was
really on his game.
He'll show up eventually.
You don't actually believe that.
But I do.
All these years,
he's never stopped
trying to annoy me for
more than 15 minutes.
Now he can't even
walk into the room.
"Love hopes all things."
What is it with
you and this kid?
He's doggie-paddling in a sea of
misery. I remember what it's like.
How far do you have to reach
back for that memory? Last night?
Sometimes I hear you in the
living room watching TV at 3:00 a.m.
That's when classic Doctor
Who comes on the BBC.
Yeah, if only they
had some device
that allowed you to record
them, watch them another time.
I'm just saying, don't think
fixing this kid is gonna fix you.
Yeah.
We're on our way back.
Our patient lost all
feeling in his right arm.
Look at this.
Chase?
How'd it go with Cuddy?
Good thing I brought my ax cane.
House, help me!
I'm coming.
House, please!
Looks like we've got company.
House!
No!
Are you okay?
I was sleeping.
What could go wrong?
Patient lost feeling in his arm
while on steroids,
rules out autoimmune.
So what causes bleeding, kidney
problems and unilateral numbness?
And a complete absence of any
record of Cuddy's kidney biopsy.
She must've put it
under a false name
so I couldn't rush the results.
What if we had it backwards,
and it's not a bleeding
problem, it's a clotting problem?
And there's no patient file
created in the last two days
for anyone having
that procedure.
She backdated the
file? That's very clever.
Hands off. She's mine.
Clots could explain everything,
including the numbness.
We should do an angiogram
of his brain, see if we can find it.
House. We're worried, too.
How sweet.
I'm not worried. I just want to get
the results so she can stop worrying.
Okay. But in the
meantime... Do an angiogram.
And you two go to pathology
and look at Cuddy's slides.
You just said you didn't
know which sample was hers.
I guess you're gonna
have to look at them all.
Bigger question, what's
the deal with Taub?
Just because House is too
distracted to notice your distraction,
doesn't mean we didn't.
Clots, angiograms, I'm focused.
The kid scratched out
the faces of half his class.
You don't think that's a
problem? It's not our problem.
Why is it anyone's problem?
I violently executed my
10th grade geometry teacher
about five different
ways in my mind.
I didn't want to kill anybody.
I just wanted to
torture them slowly
in my basement,
preferably with acid.
You guys ever think about
what you might do to House?
Maybe it's no big deal.
Unless it is.
Somebody shot House.
What are you doing?
Pie-eating contest.
I was going to send
Chase to tell you
what the obvious
right thing to do here is.
But then I realized
if you were too stupid to
know how stupid that was,
you might miss the irony.
You have to be with her.
Yeah, I get it.
She needs artificial support
for an artificial problem.
She's fine.
Chase did an excellent job.
She doesn't sleep with Chase.
We don't know that.
Hey, eating pie in here.
House. I'm not gonna
tell you a third time.
Do not screw this up.
Because I really don't
want to clean up the mess.
He was referring to the pie.
Fourteen patients
with kidney biopsies.
I tabulated them against
their urinalysis results.
Six men, three diabetics, one
LCDD, one kid, two seniors.
And, by default, one Cuddy.
The biopsy was inconclusive.
The mass is near the
center of her kidney.
They couldn't get
a readable sample.
Means they'll have
to remove the mass
to know if it's cancer or not.
File says they're doing
some imaging now.
Give the surgeon a better
idea of what he's dealing with.
Can we order pizza?
There's nothing in the fridge.
At least, not anymore.
What's happening
with the patient?
Angio showed a clot in a branch
of his middle-cerebral artery.
We started him on
streptokinase to break it up.
Although maybe we should've
just played a few rounds
of Savagescape 2: The Revenge,
because that's obviously the best
way to make someone feel better.
You keep talking like Wilson,
your face will freeze like that.
However bad you think
you're gonna be in that room,
not being in the room is worse.
When she breaks up with
you, you're playing by yourself.
Honey, I'm home.
Just in time. The
pot roast is ready.
It smells wonderful.
I cured all my patients, so I came
home to spend time with Rachel.
And how was your day today?
It was great, Ma. I got
100% on my spelling test.
And 170 on my LSATs.
Your LSATs? You're
eight years old.
We've been studying together.
It was supposed
to be a surprise.
Well, that's wonderful.
I think Rachel deserves a treat.
No, thanks, Daddy. It
might spoil my appetite.
Well, who could that be?
Delivery for you, Mrs. House.
Happy 29th birthday.
I'm not 29.
You're not limping.
This isn't possible.
None of this is possible.
A girl can dream.
You run out of sugar?
I got your scans
back from today.
Yeah.
Okay.
What's going on?
Imaging shows enhancing masses
across multiple lobes
of Cuddy's lungs.
That's what kidney cancer
looks like when it metastasizes.
She's dead.
What's up, losers? I hope
you're enjoying being alive.
Today's lesson,
natural selection.
Excellent system, made
us who we are today.
But then we invented seat
belts and grocery stores.
Things that keep idiots
and weaklings alive.
And let's be honest, most
of you don't really deserve it.
Here's to the natural order.
Yes!
Whoo!
Copied from his flash
drive. Do I go to the cops?
Yes. "Officer, I'd like
to report an assault.
"The victim was
a pile of leaves."
It goes on. He talks
about bombing his school.
Which you know because you stole
his flash drive and
broke into his house.
How's that gonna play?
Ryan's not responding
to streptokinase.
We don't have very long before
the damage becomes irreversible.
So we either up his dosage, or go
into his head and get the clot out.
Where's House? FOREMAN:
Hopefully with Cuddy.
She did just get some
pretty awful news.
I called her. She doesn't
know where he is, either.
Have you seen House?
No.
He left my place last night after
you called. No one's seen him today.
Any idea where he'd be?
No.
And you're not
worried about that?
He's not good with bad news.
Yes, I'm worried.
But this isn't about
House, it's about Cuddy.
She's the one who could be dying
and he's trying to
make this about himself.
I'm not playing.
Okay.
She still believes
he'll show up.
He'll either get over himself
and be who she needs him to be,
or he won't.
We'd like to do an embolectomy.
We'll run a
corkscrew-shaped instrument
into Ryan's brain
and pull the clot out.
Okay. Have you
talked to him about it?
Yes. But I wanted
to see you alone.
I saw some videos that
Ryan made a few weeks ago.
He's blowing up pipe bombs and
threatening people in his school.
Oh, God!
He was probably
just messing around.
Our son wouldn't hurt anybody.
I'm not so sure.
I know this looks bad,
but Ryan's a good kid.
He's had a rough couple of
years since he started high school,
but I really think
he'll come out of it.
He needs help.
Maybe he does.
But this gets out,
he'll be suspended,
maybe expelled.
How about you focus
on keeping him alive.
What are you gonna do?
What do you think I should do?
So you can do the opposite?
There are kids all
over the country
doing dumb,
potentially violent things,
but the percentage
of them who would
actually kill anybody
is minuscule.
So I shouldn't do anything?
Hmm, while the odds are
low, the fallout could be huge,
tens or even hundreds of lives.
So I should call the cops.
Of course, over-identification with
the subject could skew the calculation
towards being extra
protective or alternatively...
You suck at this.
Hate the statistics,
not the statistician.
Give me a little more dye.
There's the clot.
It just disintegrated
when you touched it.
What was that thing?
I got a great idea
where we should go.
I don't want to hear it.
You're gonna love it.
Australia's Finest. It's a
great karaoke bar in Newark.
I hate karaoke.
They've got every song
by every Aussie artist,
Midnight Oil, Men at
Work, Olivia Newton John.
I do a mean version of Physical.
And the barbecued
shrimp is amazing.
What about the fries?
Hot, salty and delicious.
Talking about food
made me hungry.
You had candy in
my other dreams.
Means you're stressed at work.
All dream symbols mean
you're stressed at work.
Or castration anxiety.
No.
I was hoping you'd figure
out a way to handle all this.
Maybe you can't
because you're still a child.
I can do better.
Might be too late.
House?
I should have been here.
I'm sorry.
I knew you'd come.
What was that thing?
And why did it just dissolve
in the middle of surgery?
And why is his
liver shutting down?
That thing in his brain goes
away, the kid slips into a coma.
We've started him on lactulose,
but at the rate his liver
function is declining,
he'll be dead in a day.
Should we page House?
He's busy.
House can't do
anything for her now.
We need him. By his own logic...
Patient's blood
tests were negative
for barbiturates
or acetaminophen.
He's not on a high-protein diet.
House couldn't concentrate on
the case before she was dying.
You think he's gonna
get in the game now?
If you don't make it,
I won't sleep with anyone
for at least a month.
Make it two.
Bitch.
AIP can cause
uraemia, tank the liver.
It causes abdominal cramping
not abdominal bleeding.
Because fucosidosis
was such a brilliant idea.
Guys.
Type 2 citrullinemia fits.
There are no signs of
hyperlipidemia or pancreatitis.
Those can take years to emerge.
Closest we've gotten.
Start him on IV sodium benzoate
to reduce the ammonia
levels in his blood.
Run a genetic test
for citrullinemia.
Hi. Hi.
Guess who doesn't have cancer?
Me.
Also, you.
Actually, you for sure. Me...
House...
The tumor was benign.
It was an oncocytoma.
They got it out, you'll be fine.
Then what was in my lungs?
Well, once they
ruled out cancer,
I remembered that your
mom was allergic to antibiotics,
so I had them test your blood.
Your IgE levels
were through the roof.
Because the lung masses
were an allergic reaction.
So, now that you're
off the antibiotics,
your lungs should
clear right up.
And I brought you something.
Say hello to your tumor. Oh!
Wait.
There are so many things
that I could be afraid of,
and most of the time I manage
to lock them up behind doors.
Then this happens.
All those doors just burst open.
You just figured something out
about your patient, didn't you?
Go. Do what you do.
Take him off the meds.
He's got a staph infection.
You treated him for staph
three days ago. It didn't work.
Bacteria already in
his system responded.
But once a door's been busted
open, more just keep coming.
Oh, he's talking
about an abscess.
I got that.
For the cheap seats,
an abscess is a gooey
little cream puff of infection
that probably burst
when your little pride
and homicidal joy
took a hard foul.
It's good news.
If we can find the door.
I think I know where it is.
What if these aren't
from skateboarding?
The kid has been blowing
up PVC pipe bombs.
If he got hit by shrapnel, the
body walls off the foreign object,
which, because it's plastic,
doesn't show up on imaging,
and provides a perfect
home for bacteria.
Antibiotics attacked the infection,
causing pieces to break off.
Some hit the liver,
one lodged in his brain
and dissolved when
Foreman touched it.
Once we drain the abscess,
and remove the shrapnel,
the antibiotics
can do their job.
He'll be fine.
Which just leaves, what
are you gonna do now?
All right. I put the rest
of the soup in the freezer
so you'll have some for later.
Thanks for everything.
Yeah.
Here you go. I got it.
Okay.
Are you gonna tell Mom?
So she can show up
here to take care of you
by harassing the housekeeper
and criticizing your bathrobe?
Yeah. I think I'm
gonna wait a few years.
Okay.
Oh, and I moved your sleeping
pills back in the medicine cabinet,
because I just worry. Rachel
always calls them candy.
You took Vicodin.
When you came to my
hospital room that night,
you were stoned.
How did you know?
How did I not know?
How did I make myself forget
for months that you're an addict?
My subconscious
was trying to tell me
you could never get
through this without drugs.
It was a one-time thing.
It's not about the pills, House.
It's about what they mean.
I was scared because I
thought my girlfriend might die.
No.
You don't take Vicodin
because you're scared.
You take it so
you won't feel pain.
Everything you've ever
done is to avoid pain.
Drugs, sarcasm,
keeping everybody at arm's
length so no one can hurt you.
As opposed to
everyone else in the world
who goes looking for pain
like it's buried treasure?
Pain happens when you care.
You can't love someone
without making yourself open
to their problems, their fears.
And you're not
willing to do that.
I came to be with you.
But you weren't
with me, not really.
I wanted to be.
Well, that's not enough.
I can do better.
I don't think you can.
You'll choose yourself over
everybody else, over and over again,
because that's just who you are.
I'm sorry.
No. No, no, no. Don't. Don't.
I thought I could
do this. Don't.
Please don't.
Goodbye, House.