Previously on The Resident...
What you're talking
about is torture.
All I'm talking about
is this man, who will die
unless Rob Spiro tells
us where he's being held.
- I want no part of it.
- It has to be done.
There's a way we can keep an eye
on each other's
surgical practices.
An Ortho-Spine Surgery Center
for comprehensive spine care.
Logan Kim. Exec VP of Red Rock.
I'll be overseeing the
day-to-day operations
- of the hospital now.
- I took an oath.
I get that you would've
made a different choice.
- The right one.
- For you.
But I don't want to be
the kind of doctor you are.
Hawkins is a whistle-blower.
He's a threat to the hospital.
I'll handle it.
Last night I took my date
to that new five-star
place on Peachtree.
You went to Manny's?
Oh, I hear it's so good.
Well, it was... until my ex
- and her girlfriends
got seated next to us.
- No.
Those ladies had words for me.
Rongeur.
- BP is dropping.
- I'm almost done.
Just give her
another liter of LR.
She's moving. I'm
gonna bolus the propofol.
No, that'll drop her pressures.
Just hang on, I'm
almost finished.
- Damn. Tube's out.
- Uh, reintubate.
There's no time. I'll bag her.
- Her pressure is falling fast.
She's gonna code, what do we do?
Uh...
- 911, what is your emergency?
- My patient.
We need to get her
to a hospital right now.
♪ ♪
What the hell happened?
A 53-year-old female.
Lost her airway midway
through operation
in an outpatient
spine surgery center.
- Did they send operative notes?
- Yes.
Her name is Lynette Hughes.
She went in for
a spinal fracture.
That's minor.
Let's take a peek.
Okay. One, two, three.
There we go.
Okay, very gently now...
One, two, three.
Bloody hell.
Whatever they started
to fix, they didn't finish.
All right, start her on
IV vanc and cefepime.
Let's get her to CT now.
And my client will stay outside
until you can
assure they will have
absolute privacy and security.
I can't clear half the
ER for one patient.
- No matter who they are.
- Everything all right?
No. I need to speak to
his supervisor immediately.
- That'd be me.
- And Dr. Feldman
will tell you the same
thing that I told you.
What he said.
Phoenix on the move.
But... who's the patient?
Can you direct me to "Phoenix"?
ER bay four.
I'm on my way, too.
They called you?
I am the admitting
resident. Yes.
Any idea who the patient is?
No. Sounds like
they're a big deal.
Not to me. I've been operating
on big shots since
I was a resident.
Athletes, celebs, heads
of state... it's all the same.
Gentlemen, allow
me to introduce you
to Princess Nadine.
Your Highness.
Just Nadine's fine.
My mom's Pakistani but she
married a king while abroad.
Pretty sure they sent me to
the States when I was a kid
so they could have "alone time."
Nadine fainted while
jogging a few hours ago.
No past medical history.
I forgot my water bottle.
Probably just dehydrated.
But Amir's my head of security
and he said we had to come in.
Her head has been
hurting for weeks.
It comes and goes.
- You speak Urdu?
- Some.
Yeah, there's
overlap with Hindi.
Anything you tell us would help.
Yeah, we'll keep
it confidential.
Well, I was running
through Piedmont Park,
and then... I don't
know, it was like...
the ground beneath
my feet just disappeared.
She's lost
sensation in her feet.
And she's had recent
headaches, dizziness, fevers.
- More than just dehydration.
- No question.
My money's on a stroke or bleed.
Eh, it could be cardiogenic.
Or vascular.
Get a noncontrast head CT stat.
- I'll ultrasound her carotids.
- We should also do
a spinal tap...
Rule out meningitis
and encephalitis.
Page me when
the results come in.
Let's get her settled
in one of our VIP suites.
Thank you. And the princess
has requested that Dr. Pravesh stay
on her medical team
while she's at Chastain.
Thank you.
We good?
You tell me.
You've already established
a connection with the patient.
I think you should stay on.
Incredible.
We can see her perfectly.
And... she looks just like you.
Is she sucking her thumb?
Yes.
Movement is a very good sign.
Mm. Your last
trimester has begun.
Soon that little blob will
be crying in your arms.
Have you decided on a name?
Not yet.
For now, let's just
call her Michelle.
- Obama?
- You know it.
Oh, all right.
Let's have you sit up.
Lost my breath
there for a second.
That's common
during pregnancies.
Why don't I give a
listen to your heart
and lungs while you're here?
Have you felt like this before?
Sometimes when I'm lying down,
my chest gets a little tight.
I did hear some atypical sounds.
It's probably
nothing, but I'd like
to order some more
tests just to be safe.
We'll order a few
labs, get a chest X-ray,
and an echo to make sure you
and your little queen are okay.
She does look like
me, doesn't she?
Yeah.
We suggest branding this
product by branding you.
That face says strength,
confidence, compassion.
Which one's your favorite?
It's a tough
choice. I like 'em all.
We think the third one
shows more... authority.
- In the eyes.
- Exactly.
Am I interrupting?
Yes.
I've been looking for a
new post-workout shake.
This one come in mocha?
Uh, we want you and the product
to be camera ready
for the press ASAP.
Yeah, okay, I'll-I'll get
back to you guys later.
That was... That was good.
Thanks, that looks great.
Why are you here?
For the meeting.
For... what meeting?
This one.
Dr. Bell, we have a problem.
A former patient
is suing Chastain.
Hospitals get sued all the time.
That's why we have lawyers.
This is different. The
patient has named
Dr. Hawkins in the suit.
And he just walked in our door.
Rob Spiro was
admitted one month ago
after he was injured
during a failed robbery.
And we saved his life.
That's not what he says.
I can't believe
they let him out.
Once the depositions are over,
he goes back to
prison to await trial.
It's just for the day.
Spiro claims that
after his surgery,
Hawkins withheld
pain medication.
He tortured Spiro
to extract the location
of a man he abducted.
And you believe
that kind of criminal
over our top resident?
- A judge might.
- Judges...
almost always side with the
doctors in malpractice suits.
And that's if the
patient isn't a murderer.
I can assure you, this suit
is not gonna cost
Chastain a dime.
Any judge would
throw it out in a second.
We've worked too hard to
improve Chastain's image
to let anything threaten it.
Any association with Spiro
is bad for this hospital.
You'll be in the
deposition, naturally,
and I'll be joining you today.
Well, be my guest.
Bell has no idea this gives us
the perfect way to
get rid of Hawkins.
Spiro's out for blood.
And we're gonna give it to him.
♪ ♪
Hawkins...
Don't worry, you'll be fine.
Red Rock's lawyers
will be here soon.
You haven't always
been on my side.
I am this time.
Gentlemen, we're
ready for you now.
- Where's Levin and Sutton?
- Levin is sick.
Sutton was unavailable.
We're familiar with the case.
Shoot, I forgot my pen.
Dr. Hawkins, Mr. Spiro
was in a lot of pain
when he came out of
surgery, is that correct?
Yes, that's normal
for a major operation.
According to his
electronic medical record,
Mr. Spiro's morphine
was stopped at 8:32 p.m.
Yeah, it's typical for
morphine to be withdrawn
if it's depressing a
patient's respiratory drive.
That's not the case here.
You stopped the
morphine to coerce
a confession out of my client.
Gonna perjure
yourself, you little bitch?
What did you tell them?
I said Mr. Spiro was lying.
That I provided him
the standard of care.
Is that true?
The less I tell you the better.
He confessed the
location of a hostage.
If you hadn't done what you did,
another one of Rob's
victims would be dead.
But if they find out,
you'll never practice
at Chastain again.
Or anywhere else.
Does anyone else know?
Conrad, who else knows?
Just Devon.
Nadine, once the
lidocaine takes effect,
you shouldn't
feel a thing. Okay?
Amir. Give the man some space.
How are we doing?
Prepping the lumbar puncture.
So, just a few more questions.
There's a chance your
symptoms may be caused
by an infectious disease.
Any travel outside
the U.S. recently?
- A trip back to the Middle East?
- No travel.
I haven't been back
home since I was six.
I spend most of my time in a
campus practice room anyway.
- You're a college student?
- At Emory, yeah.
I'm a music major.
Mom and Dad
insisted I go to college,
even though what
I really wanna do
is be a professional deejay.
Sweet.
- Do you make your own mixes?
- Yeah.
I love taking old
songs, classics,
adding new beats, loops, hooks.
Totally reinventing them.
Making them my own.
Okay, Nadine.
All set. You ready?
As I'll ever be.
All right.
Hmm. You see that?
Your heart is enlarged.
It's not pumping as
vigorously as we would expect.
You have a condition called
dilated cardiomyopathy.
It explains the
shortness of breath.
Most likely brought
on by the chemo
that treated your breast cancer.
But my baby's okay?
Yeah.
But pregnancy is
hard on the heart.
The longer you're
pregnant, the greater the risk
that you develop
congestive heart failure.
There is another option.
Induce an early delivery.
My baby's only 28 weeks.
How early are we talking?
Ideally, we would want to wait
as long as possible to induce.
The sooner we do it,
the more risk to the baby.
What kind of risk?
Like underdeveloped
lungs with increased risk
of respiratory distress and
some serious infections.
So what's best for my
baby could harm me,
and what's best for me could...
It's not an easy choice.
The health of my
baby comes first.
I'm carrying her to term.
We've got a problem.
I'm not getting a signal
from the right L5 nerve root.
Must be a screw
abutting the nerve.
Retractors?
Whoever started putting in
this hardware blew out pedicles
and left her with a
spinal pseudarthrosis.
I see the screw, right
there, but it's deep.
Poor woman should never
have been operated on
at a spine surgery center.
They thought she only
had a spinal fracture,
but once they opened
her up, they found
spinopelvic disassociation.
Got it.
Those centers aren't
prepared for things to go wrong.
And when they do,
patients can be hours
from a hospital
and die as a result.
She's one of the lucky ones.
- Nerve signal is back.
- Okay.
Great. We can start to repair
and fix the spine to the pelvis.
It was awful.
My own doctor,
trying to hurt me.
I swear to God, I...
I've never felt pain like that.
Thank you,
Mr. Spiro. That's all.
Don't you have
any more questions?
We're good.
All right. I'll begin
deposing staff.
What the hell was that?
I thought it went well.
Those Red Rock lawyers
are barely a day
out of law school.
They didn't ask one
substantive question.
Conrad deserves
an actual defense.
I'm bringing in
our old legal team,
wherever the hell they are.
No, you're not.
You want Conrad to go down.
Every year,
whistle-blowers like Hawkins
cost hospitals millions.
He discovered that a
drug was killing patients.
And good for him, but
what about next time?
He won't hesitate to
take sides against us.
He is our number
one diagnostician.
He's about to
become chief resident.
Long-term, I guarantee a
whistle-blower is a liability.
Well, then, why
not just fire him?
Why go through all that?
We both know his
father's a powerful man.
Former chairman of the board.
I want Hawkins gone,
but we can't get rid of
him without good cause.
I want it done clean
without any blowback
from Marshall Winthrop.
So you're using Spiro's lawsuit.
A criminal.
I won't support this.
You clearly still
don't understand
how things work around here.
You seem confused,
so let me help.
Red Rock gave me authority
to do whatever's necessary
to protect Chastain's
bottom line.
So if Hawkins isn't
gone by end of business,
then today will be
your last as CEO.
It's him or you.
This is a new low
even for Red Rock.
- You think they'll really do it?
- Of course they'll fire me.
Have you met these people?
The only way I stay on as CEO
is if I let them end
Conrad's career.
You can't let them
get away with this.
What am I... What
am I supposed to do?
Report Red Rock
to the state board.
- Take it to the press.
- Yeah, but then say what?
I have no proof. I'd
be out of my office
before anybody even
returned my calls,
and then I'd be
the whistle-blower,
and then they'd move
to destroy me, too.
Then what now?
I don't know.
I-I make Red Rock
think I'm on their side.
Show I'm being
cooperative. I, uh...
I don't know, best-case
scenario is I can figure out a way
to save both of us.
How's your pain level, Lynette?
If I say zero, can I
pack a bag to Vegas?
Push, push, push.
I have Nelly tickets and a
date with the penny slots.
You just went through a
grueling spinal repair and fixation.
I think you're stuck
hanging with us
for a few weeks.
Squeeze my fingers.
W-Weeks?
The surgery center people
said I could be home by tonight.
Well, they were wrong.
And the surgeons
who actually fixed you
want you to stay fixed.
Somebody order an angel?
Lynette, this is my dad, Kyle.
- He's a volunteer here at
Chastain. Yeah, we have
angels like him to
keep patients company
- during their stay.
- Anything you need,
I'm your man.
How about a cigarette?
No can do.
Smoking constricts
your blood vessels,
which keeps your surgical
wounds from healing.
And means you'd
be here even longer.
Well, buckle up, honey.
If I don't get my nicotine,
I'm more than a handful.
Still going, huh?
Yeah, they're... about
to depose the staff.
That is where I'm gonna
build the tennis court,
and this what I'm thinking of
for the interior.
Are you gonna stay in there?
Yeah, I cleared my schedule.
Thanks for having my back.
How would you
describe Dr. Hawkins?
Caring.
- Smart.
- Handsome.
We heard he can be a
rule breaker. Is that true?
- Never seen it.
- Define "rule breaker."
Well, I saw him cut in
line in the cafeteria once.
At any time, did
you see Dr. Hawkins
go into Mr. Spiro's room alone?
- Nope.
- No.
I was in the OR all day...
Where I should be right now.
Mr. Spiro wasn't even
one of my patients.
Can I please go?
We got nothing.
Conrad is well-liked
and respected.
Nobody is liked by everyone,
especially doctors like Hawkins.
What do you expect me to do?
If I were you, I'd
think of something.
Hurry, please!
Help her! Please, hurry! Hurry!
Nadine, try to relax.
We're gonna check
your heart and lungs.
BP 210/140. Sats in the 80s.
Okay.
Crackles two-thirds
of the way up.
Override a nitro spray bottle.
Then call Radiology
for a portable X-ray stat.
What's happening to her?
She's got fluid in her lungs.
It's making it hard
for her to breathe.
Give her 40 of furosemide IV.
Okay. All right, Nadine.
Open wide.
Okay. This will help you breathe
while we figure out
what's going on, okay?
I don't get it. Her
head CT was benign.
CSF is clear. Cultures negative.
No pulmonary or cardiac issues.
Is it renal?
Her creatinine was normal.
Besides, that wouldn't
explain her syncope.
So what are we missing?
I got to go.
We're not done here.
We still don't know
what's wrong with her.
She could decompensate
at any point.
You will figure this out.
Keep me updated.
It's not my fault.
- What?
- Rob Spiro.
I tried to stop you.
What does that have
to do with anything?
Because you're
taking it out on me,
and Nadine will
suffer because of it.
I have other patients,
including ones in the ICU.
And you were the one who
didn't want to work with me.
Because you tortured a man.
Rob Spiro is a murderer.
And we're doctors.
We're supposed to be the
ones who are helping people.
- And I did.
- You break rules,
ignore protocol.
That is who you
are, and it is wrong.
We have been over and over this.
A man is alive
because of what I did.
Oh, you didn't do it for
him. You did it for you.
You're damn right I did.
Had to make a
choice I could live with.
I got to go.
So, we'll start you
on a cardiac
regimen, oral diuretic
and a beta-blocker.
And then we'll see
you every few days
to monitor you and the baby.
Sounds like a plan.
And I have faith that
God's watching over us.
Adaku, we want
to make sure that you
understand what all this means.
If the strain on your
heart becomes too great,
we may need to perform an
emergency cesarean delivery.
But even that might
not be enough. I've seen
women your age end up
with a device implanted
to take over the
function of their heart.
Tethered to a battery pack.
Waiting for a transplant.
But I feel fine now.
Cardiac issues can escalate
quickly for pregnant women.
Worsening heart failure...
could kill both
you and the baby.
We're here to support
whatever you choose
if you are sure
that you want to try
carrying this baby to term.
Maybe I should take a minute.
Add a thyroid panel,
ABG and BMP.
You ran those two hours ago.
Two hours ago, she
wasn't on oxygen.
- Run it again.
- Yes, Doctor.
You all right?
I got to make sure
you finish school
so you can start deejaying
sold-out clubs around
the world, right?
I like the sound of that.
And you can have a disguise,
like that guy with
the mouse mask.
And hey, you already
have a code name.
Phoenix?
Okay, you'll think
of a better one.
All I ask for in return are
backstage passes... for life.
All right, I'm gonna go
check on those tests.
Wait.
Um... before you go,
could you pass me the, um...
the... the...
the... the Ras?
Juice?
Yes. Sorry.
I couldn't think of the word.
Thank you.
Has that happened before?
Forgetting English
words for things?
A few times. It's weird, huh?
How long has it been going on?
A couple weeks.
Why?
Nadine forgets words in her
primary language, English,
but her secondary language,
Urdu, remains intact.
Could have a number of causes.
But it happened when she sat up.
So you think she's experiencing
positional cerebral
hypoperfusion?
That's why I ordered
an angiogram.
Look. The blood vessels
in her brain have narrowed.
- She has Moyamoya.
- Which would explain
why she lost all
sensation in her feet
- while she was jogging.
- And why
her symptoms only occurred
when she exerted herself.
Moyamoya can be
unremitting and progressive.
She could die of strokes
before she turns 30.
Unless I perform
a cerebral bypass.
Time to get our
princess to my OR.
The first time my dad
busted me, I was 16.
But instead of grounding
me, he bought me a pack.
Said fathers and daughters
should smoke the same brand.
- He gave you cigarettes?
- He'd smoke 'em with me.
- Oh.
- Playing slapjack
on the front porch like a
couple rowdy old drunks.
Till he passed away
a couple years ago.
What did he die of?
Heart attack.
You know, more people
die of heart disease
from smoking than cancer.
- And still, you smoke?
- I know
- it doesn't make any sense.
- No.
The right thing to
do is to quit, but...
I can't.
You know, that's the
definition of addiction.
It's in my family, too.
I, uh...
I was a drinker and, you know,
eh, drugs when I was younger.
My daughters... They
grew up seeing that,
and one of 'em became an addict.
Oh, that doesn't sound good.
Oh, God.
Can you read that thing?
No, but I-I...
I-I... I think I can find
someone who can.
Um, I'll be right...
I'll be right back.
Uh, excuse me? My...
Hey, uh, can I just...?
Hello. Hey, could
you just help...?
You got to be kidding me.
Uh, hey, I-I need a doctor.
Hey! Angels will not be ignored.
It's my patient.
- Y-Your patient?
- Yes, yes.
Her mon-monitor
thing... It-it's beeping.
Could you... could
you check on her?
I think you might be
getting a little carried away
- with your role here.
- Okay. I'm a Nevin.
- All right?
- A who?
Yeah, th-that's it!
I want your name,
Scott, and your badge
number, right now!
- I don't understand.
- I know.
- It is a lot to process, but...
- No. I don't understand
who comes up with these names.
Mora-maya?
- Moyamoya.
- Okay.
It means "puff of
smoke" in Japanese,
because of the way it
looks on the angiogram.
- Mm.
- Nadine, if we don't operate...
it is fatal.
I've faced a lot of
threats in my life.
Kidnapping,
poisoning, assassination.
I'm not gonna let a puff
of smoke take me out.
Then we'll prep you for surgery.
I want my day in court.
I'm sorry, Dr. Feldman.
They've decided
not to depose you.
But Dr. Hawkins is one of
the best doctors at this hospital.
He...
A patient came in
hypertensive last week.
Hawkins realized it
was pheochromocytoma.
Who else makes that call?
And not only is
Conrad a great doctor,
he makes great doctors.
Dr. Pravesh used
to train under him.
Total rising star.
Oh, Pravesh isn't
Hawkins' intern anymore?
No, he requested a new resident.
Why?
When did he put in the request?
About a month ago.
Wasn't that around the time
they were both treating Rob Spiro?
Yeah.
Why?
They say a cerebral bypass
is like landing on the moon.
Cain only gets one shot.
Oh, I like that music.
The patient requested it.
Yeah? Who's the artist?
Her.
♪ Swingin' ♪
♪ Don't count me out,
'cause I'll come back... ♪
Show angiogram.
This area lacks
adequate perfusion.
I'll need to reroute
the circulation by
performing the
anastomosis right here.
Show vitals.
♪ Can't feel my
hands, but I got you... ♪
Pressure's stable.
All looks good.
It's exactly what
I like to hear.
Stopping the blood
flow to the brain.
Nurse. Pig clips and hemostat.
♪ And I know in my soul that
I'm onto something good... ♪
Middle cerebral artery clamped.
Dr. Chu, the clock, please.
30 minutes starting now.
Let's dance, Princess.
♪ To you ♪
♪ Don't count me out,
'cause I'll come back. ♪
You've been wasting our time,
and I'm fresh out of patience.
I need a CEO who will
get things done at all costs.
Clearly, that's not you.
I think you should
question Dr. Pravesh.
We were all under the impression
that he's one of
Hawkins' most loyal allies.
Why talk to him now?
Because I've recently discovered
that may not be the case.
I think he knows what really
happened with Rob Spiro.
Let's put him under oath.
Occlusion time is
approaching 30 minutes.
Cain needs to finish soon or
risk permanent brain damage.
He's throwing the last stitch.
Let's hope this works.
Prepare to unclamp.
Dr. Pravesh?
They've decided to depose you.
Now.
Pressure's rising.
Elevate the head.
Push the mannitol.
Her brain is
swelling too quickly.
The edges of her skull
are lacerating her brain.
We're losing
neurological function.
I'm enlarging the craniotomy.
She's my patient.
I'm not going anywhere.
Taking down the anastomosis.
Swelling is coming down.
Time to redo the bypass.
She doesn't have time
for him to redo
an entire bypass.
But we still need to restore
blood flow in her brain.
And complete the
surgery quickly.
Are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
Omental transposition.
Yeah, well, you better
lose the suit, buddy.
I save your patient, then we go.
Step aside.
Two Chastain OGs to the rescue.
- No need. I've got this.
- Uh, sorry, brother, but
the princess does not have
time for you to play hero today.
Project abdomen.
I see a vascular-rich piece
of omentum we can use to
place on the brain. 10 blade.
♪ Underneath it all... ♪
I'll need a piece at least
20 by ten centimeters.
♪ ♪
Metz.
Harvesting the omentum.
Taking that piece of tissue
from her abdomen and laying
it on her brain can stimulate
the growth of new blood
vessels, restoring perfusion.
Won't this increase
the risk of hematoma?
You're right, but
we're out of options.
♪ Underneath it all... ♪
Laying the omentum down.
♪ With the whispers closing in ♪
- ♪ To lives we all defend ♪
- ♪ We all defend ♪
- ♪ And now ♪
- ♪ And now... ♪
Show vascularization
over the next 90 days.
- ♪ It all ♪
- ♪ No one knows... ♪
Devon?
♪ No one knows your name ♪
♪ Knows your name ♪
♪ No one loves you now ♪
♪ Loves you now ♪
♪ No one feels the same ♪
♪ Feels the same... ♪
Yes, yes, yes.
Let there be blood.
♪ Underneath ♪
♪ It all ♪
♪ Underneath it all... ♪
I'm sorry.
It's not your fault.
Got to see a patient.
Deep breaths, deep breaths.
Hold on.
- What's going on?
- She's in A-fib.
I'm getting her back into sinus
rhythm, and you're interrupting.
Hey, hey, man, I really
don't like your tone.
How about a little
bedside manner?
Lynette has been through enough.
Dad, I appreciate the passion,
- but take it down a notch.
- This...
this is what I'm trying to say.
She gets panic attacks,
so maybe we can all
relax one damn minute.
Panic attacks. What
do they feel like?
I don't know, it just
feels like my heart
is beating out of my chest.
What if they aren't panic
attacks but A-fib as well?
- Her past EKGs were all normal.
- An EKG could miss it.
- If she's been having A-fib
for some time...
- There could be a clot.
Shocking her could
dislodge it, 'cause a stroke.
You want to do rate control.
20 milligrams IV Diltiazem.
Try it.
- All right.
- Oh, my God.
Breathe. Come on, breathe.
♪ ♪
So, I hear Adaku decided
to continue her pregnancy.
Risk her own
health for her baby.
She and I are
practically sisters,
yet I have never
understood her faith.
Have you tried?
You believe there's
some all-powerful being
who can heal us if
we just ask nicely?
The fact is that faith
is good for patients.
Those who believe
they'll be okay
- generally have better outcomes.
- That's no guarantee.
Surgeons or God... everyone
needs someone to believe in.
She has a long road ahead.
Even if everything goes right.
All the more reason you should
support her on her own terms.
Even if she finds faith in a
place you don't understand.
Lynette's stable.
It was the right call.
You all right?
Devon's about to be deposed.
I'm gonna go talk to him.
And say what?
That sometimes telling
the truth isn't enough.
Sometimes you have
to fight fire with fire.
Devon has to do
what he feels is right
no matter the consequences.
That's what I
tried to teach him.
Now we have to
respect his choice.
Dr. Pravesh,
let's cut to the chase.
Did you see Dr. Hawkins
go into Mr. Spiro's room?
I did.
- Alone?
- That's correct.
I understand you recently
asked to be assigned
to a new resident. Why?
Dr. Hawkins and I disagreed.
About what?
Too many things.
Like the treatment of Mr. Spiro?
Yes.
Because Dr. Hawkins
tortured him?
Dr. Pravesh?
Please.
They need an answer.
Do you have any
reason to believe
Dr. Hawkins withheld
pain medication
to elicit a confession?
Dr. Pravesh, just
tell them the truth.
I know you're one
of the good guys.
Dr. Pravesh,
just tell the truth.
I know you're one... I know
you're one of the good guys.
Mr. Spiro was in
respiratory distress.
Pain medication
needed to be withheld.
This man is alive today
because of Dr. Hawkins.
Why are you lying, huh?
Why are you lying!?
♪ ♪
Why did you lie for me?
I didn't do it for you.
These patients need you.
And I had to make a
decision I could live with.
Ah, you and I
are very different.
I respect that.
Me, too.
And I think this hospital
needs doctors like both of us.
♪ ♪
Your intracranial
pressures and post-op labs
are trending in
the right direction.
Thank you.
Dr. Pravesh, have you ever
saved a princess before?
It was a team effort.
The king will want to thank you.
I expect he will
be calling shortly.
Well, what do I call him?
Your Majesty.
♪ ♪
Okay,
maybe I lost my
cool, just a little.
Well, I'm glad you did.
Now I understand why
they call you an angel.
Nah.
The truth is...
I love this job.
Sometimes I feel like
it's the only thing I got
to hang on to.
- Mm.
- And I know what it's like
when things don't go your way.
Damn!
- Yeah.
- How did you get that?
I gave my kidney
to my daughter.
At least I tried.
The younger one?
Jessie. Yeah.
She struggled with addiction.
Opioids.
She, uh...
she didn't make it.
Oh, I'm s... I'm so sorry.
When we lost Jessie, I...
I don't think I could've
made it through
if it hadn't been for Nic.
She's the best
thing about Chastain.
You sound so proud of her.
Yeah. Well...
She's the best
thing about me, too.
♪ ♪
I'm scared.
Me, too.
Dr. Hawkins survived the day.
I can't say the same about you.
- Hold it.
- Sorry, I got
to make this quick.
Oh, it will be.
What is this?
My resignation as CEO.
Just finish packing and go.
Oh, I won't be leaving Chastain.
I'll be staying on
as chief of surgery.
Red Rock won't see it that way.
Well, then you'll need to find
yourself some better lawyers,
because my surgical
contract is bulletproof.
You just try getting rid of me.
♪ Do you really even like me? ♪
♪ Are you really even trying? ♪
Today Red Rock asked me
to turn against one
of my own doctors.
♪ Are you really even trying? ♪
And tomorrow they'd just
ask me to do something worse.
♪ You are so dead to me ♪
♪ Without this hurt,
without this curse ♪
♪ What would you mean to me? ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ You fled on me ♪
♪ Tellin' me to quit so easily ♪
♪ You bled on me... ♪
There's a bloodbath coming.
I don't even want to be
up there when it happens.
But down here, I can survive.
What's gonna happen to Conrad?
Red Rock has eyes
and ears everywhere.
Conrad still has a
target on his back.
♪ You fled on me. ♪
As do we all.
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH