I feel like I've been through a war.
Parasites.
My brother had parasites in his brain.
An epic, epic war.
I know,
but the good news is that we won.
- Archer is nearly himself again.
- Nearly?
What? What? Is something wrong?
No, no, no. Oh, God, no.
No, no, no. Everything is fine.
All parts are working.
- Okay, my brother, my brother.
- Okay, sorry.
It's just that it's, um...
- It's good. We're really good.
- Yeah?
You know, I think he's my boyfriend.
- What?
- You know, he sleeps over every night.
And he calls constantly.
He's been talking lately. Addison,
I think I have a man.
Archer is committing.
All right, I'm getting
another bottle of wine.
NAOMl:
Yes, please.
MAN:
Easy. I just got stitches.
Archer?
[KISSING]
Archer. Archer. Shame on you.
How cou...?
- Is this your wife? Are you married?
- God.
No,
- but he has a girlfriend who is here.
- Oh, damn it.
Look, I'm sure
you're a very nice person,
but a little old
to be getting felt up in the foyer.
But now, it's all the best. Bye-bye now.
You.
You've got to get that lipstick
wiped off your face.
Is this pre- or post-sex?
I hope you used a condom, you whore.
[PHONE RINGING]
I'm in trouble, right?
Hey, Dell, can I call...?
Yeah, is she...? Uh...
Is she okay? Uh-huh.
Okay. Great, l...
I'll be right there. Thanks, bye.
Addison, anything to eat?
Hey. I'm edible.
Hey, what are you doing here?
Hi.
Okay, you two. You just do whatever it is
the two of you do. I gotta go.
[MOUTHS]
I'm not done with you.
[GROANING]
Come on. Come on. Bear down.
One more big push.
It's a fast labor.
I thought I could do this solo.
You're doing great.
Come on, Leanne. You're almost there.
Good, good, good.
I can see his head.
All right, great. The baby's coming.
Come on, Leanne. Come on.
[YELLS]
[BABY CRYING]
You did it.
Matthew. He's here. He's here.
I wanna hold him.
Can I hold my little boy?
Come on.
- What's wrong?
- It's not a boy.
- What, the ultrasound was wrong?
- It's a girl?
I'm not sure.
I know this is impossibly hard.
And we don't have all the answers yet.
But your baby has something
like a penis.
There's also a vaginal opening.
DELL: The baby's heart and lungs
and brain are all very healthy.
And that's important
for you to understand.
But what is it?
We'll run some genetic
and hormonal tests.
I'll consult with my colleague,
Dr. Bennett.
She's an excellent endocrinologist.
We're gonna get you answers.
Okay, what about until then?
I mean, what do we tell people?
I mean, what do we...?
What do we call him?
He's Matthew.
He's supposed to be...
He's supposed to be Matthew.
Why'd you go to Seattle?
I'm sorry. It's just...
It's running through my mind on a loop
like a song I can't stop humming
so I have to ask.
Seattle.
- Why'd you go?
- Archer's surgery.
Look, Naomi likes to pretend
like she has it all together, but...
She's an lvy League-educated doctor
with the best shoe collection I've ever
seen, so she does have it all together.
Usually.
But Archer getting sick...
You thought
she'd need a shoulder to lean on.
Yeah.
Okay.
Is it okay?
I think it's great.
You've managed the impossible,
you know.
You've maintained a good relationship
with your ex.
Which is why I like you.
I like you too.
- You want to go again?
- Yes, please.
Hey, Violet.
- Hey, Sheldon.
- Now, I was wondering.
I run a couples therapy group
and my co-leader's down
with a stomach bug.
And I think it's very important
that we have a male and female therapist.
You know, role modeling,
communication modeling.
And I wondered if you'd like to fill in.
I know, not such a great idea,
considering the...
No, no. I think it's good.
I like working with couples.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah. What time?
Our conference room at 1.
- It's lunchtime.
- Okay. See you then.
Violet.
How is it? The baby.
- It's fine.
- Good.
- That's good that it's fine because...
- Sheldon.
I would really appreciate it
if we didn't talk about this right now.
Because I don't know if I can handle it.
Okay? But I'll see you later.
Hey, Pete.
PETE:
Oh, you've got that look.
That
it's-impossible-to-decipher-Violet look.
I've just given up. I'm going with cool.
Not cold, just cool.
- Hell, I'll go with cold.
- Yeah.
Therapy should be interesting.
You and Violet are in therapy?
No. No, we're doing therapy together.
It's a couples group.
You're leading it? As a couple?
- Yes, we are.
- Good luck with that.
[CHUCKLES]
You should have seen the look
on their faces, Naomi. It was awful.
- Like this is their fault.
- Hey.
- Are you okay?
- What? Huh?
No, what, uh...?
Yeah, what do we tell them?
Well, I wish I had a good answer.
But the baby does have
11-beta-hydroxylase deficiency.
- What is it?
- It is an enzyme deficiency
that causes an overproduction
of testosterone in the baby in utero.
That's why the baby has both male
and female sex organs.
Karyotype is XX.
- So the baby's a girl?
NAOMl: No. It's not that simple.
Yes, genetically, it is a girl,
but about 30 percent of these cases,
these kids orient towards male.
So we can't tell the parents
what sex the baby is?
They'll have to choose and then
we can surgically correct the genitalia.
Wait, you said
there's a 30 percent margin for error.
Postoperative healing is faster
and it leaves the genitalia functional.
I'll support it with hormone therapy.
What if they choose wrong,
the baby orients the other way?
Exactly. We should have them choose
the gender now, but not do surgery.
Let them raise the baby
as a boy or a girl
and then when the baby becomes
an adolescent, it makes up its own mind.
That's the problem, leaving it an it.
Every sleepover, every swim party or
locker room is gonna be cause for panic.
Well, maybe it should be whatever it is
and never lop off any body parts.
And I was worried I'd be missing
all the fun. Lopping off body parts?
NAOMl: Intersex baby.
- Can of worms.
Some people think gender is hardwired,
so whatever you do,
not gonna change the outcome.
Me? I find it freakish. Lop away.
NAOMl: How was your first day back?
- It's perfect now.
Good morning, Dr. King.
Move in with me, Cooper.
Charlotte.
I know you care
about Violet and her baby.
And I understand
why you wanted to move in with her.
But you can still be there for both of them,
without living at her place.
Violet's afraid to be alone.
- So I need to be there for her.
- I'm your girlfriend.
And I am here for you.
And living with Violet?
It doesn't change that.
My patience only goes so far.
So it's a boy,
but it could also be a girl?
My God.
What are we supposed to do?
How do we decide?
Well, the odds say that your baby
will most likely identify as a female.
So we can do corrective surgery and
give the baby the appropriate genitalia.
You want to take my baby, my son,
and cut off his penis?
Alternately, you can choose a gender now,
raise the baby,
and then when he or she matures,
you reevaluate.
And hide this for his entire childhood?
MITCH:
I mean, what would we tell him?
How do you even begin
to explain this to a little kid?
Well, that not everybody's the same.
That it's okay to be different.
But it's not okay. Kids are cruel.
One kid sees him in the bathroom,
everyone's talking. Teasing him.
I mean, that's what kids do.
That's not the life we want.
We need to make this right.
We need to put this behind us,
behind him or her,
and make it right.
But what's the best way?
ARCHER:
I like women. I like a lot of women.
But I am not married to Naomi
- and she is not the mother of my children.
- Naomi sat by your side
while you had surgery.
She held your hand.
You're upstairs sticking your tongue
down her throat, seeing her every day,
letting her believe
that you two have something together.
Well, I thought I was dying.
You are...
You are asking me to lie for you.
You are making me feel dirty and cheap,
and I'm 10 years old again telling mother
that I went out with ice cream with Daddy,
when really I'm sitting in his office while
he's screwing his secretary down the hall.
I'm too much of a snob
to screw secretaries.
- You think this is funny?
- No.
I think that you're one to talk.
I remember something. You doing your
husband's best friend behind his back.
That was once. I slipped once.
Okay, so you're like an alcoholic.
You're on a program now.
- God me grant the serenity.
- You're so mean when you know I'm right.
You know what? I am mean when
I want you to mind your own business.
- I won't keep your secret for...
- Yes, you will.
Montgomerys look the other way
when it is none of their business.
CHARLOTTE:
Now, there's a sight for sore eyes.
I got patients lined up
waiting for you to get back.
- Well, that's me. Money in the bank.
CHARLOTTE: I like money in the bank.
What? I like your brother.
He's my golden boy.
Beverly. You okay?
Oh, yeah, yeah. I'm fine. I just...
- I had to see you.
- This is the fourth time this week.
I checked your schedule.
You have an opening.
- Beverly.
- Oh, come on, Pete. Just a quickie.
Okay.
I feel like Paul doesn't share
much of himself with me either.
He hardly wants to have sex anymore.
I get home from work. I'm tired.
And you don't seem that interested.
But when I ask you what's going on,
you won't talk to me.
I wanna know what's going on with you.
Up here.
GREG:
See, there's your first mistake.
Thinking much of anything goes on
for us guys. Up here.
You know what I think, Greg?
I think we guys like women to think that.
Maybe we think it ourselves, but part
of that is that we don't look at ourselves.
Don't ask ourselves
what we're thinking or feeling.
VIOLET:
Exactly.
I mean, the truth is,
all of us have things going on inside.
I mean, right now,
everyone in this room,
Sheldon and me included,
have a thousand things going on.
And the trick is to open yourself to that.
And to share it.
Well, that's not to say, of course,
that there aren't pieces
you wanna keep to yourself.
You don't wanna lose yourself
in a relationship.
No.
No, but the beauty of good communication
is that when you share,
share what you're thinking,
good or bad, you both feel better.
Maybe help each other.
SASHA:
Ryan and I used to have that.
Back in high school, when we met.
We talked about everything.
RYAN: And now
all you wanna talk about are the kids.
SASHA:
That's not true.
But I'm there with them all day.
You don't wanna know about that?
That's my world.
I know it's hard here in the group,
but talking?
It really will make things better.
Beverly,
I love seeing you,
but this has got to stop.
I can't stay away. Whatever you do,
whenever you put your hands on me,
I swear,
- it's magic.
- It's not magic.
- And it's not...
- Hey, I've been reading up a lot
on reiki therapy.
Healing hands.
It supposed to be incredible. Let's try it.
I'm not a specialist at reiki.
I can't do that.
Pete, you can do
whatever you want to me.
As a doctor,
I can't keep pretending this is okay.
Come on. Just one more time.
It's been taken care of.
You can just file it over there. Thank you.
- Hi.
- Hello.
You know what? We haven't been
speaking for two weeks and I miss you.
Don't treat me
like the pervert next door.
If you lived next door
we wouldn't be having the problem.
I wanna get past this. We need to.
What is it gonna take for you
to forgive me?
I don't know, Cooper. I'm working on it.
We walked past your wall of pictures.
All those kids.
Happy and sweet and normal.
And that's what our baby should be.
And surgery can do that.
Surgery can give your baby
gender-distinct genitalia, yes.
And we can know?
We can stop saying "it"?
MITCH:
Great, so let's do that.
Can we do it soon?
I can book an OR for tomorrow.
Afterward, we'll supplement with estrogen
so she'll be as healthy as possible.
No.
No, no, no. That's not what we want.
It was clear to us
from the second we saw his face.
He's Matthew.
But only 30 percent of these babies
orient toward male.
MITCH:
You said you don't know.
We know.
LEANNE:
He's our son.
You're gonna give us our son.
[SIGHS]
I just saw Ryan and Eleanor
in the stairwell.
- You mean Ryan and Sasha?
- I mean Ryan and Eleanor.
They were communicating. Lip to lip.
- Did they see you?
- No, they were too focused.
I can't believe this.
Maybe it's a cry for help.
An affair in the stairwell after marriage
counseling is a cry for help?
Haven't been able to communicate
in their own.
So they do this awful thing
where they could get caught
because they wanna force
the communication.
Only, we can't tell on them.
It's not like they disclosed this in session,
I don't think the waivers apply.
I'm not suggesting outing them.
I'm saying we get them to tell.
How's exposing an affair
going to improve communication?
So we let the secret keep festering
until it poisons every aspect of the group?
Lt'll become the 800-pound gorilla
in the room.
As therapists, we need to acknowledge
that gorilla and take steps to deal with it.
We don't know what they feel.
We don't know what they think.
They could be in love.
- Could be a one-time thing.
- Which is why we need to talk to them.
Look, what I think, as bad as this is,
getting them to confess could be
the breakthrough the group needs.
NAOMl: I was surprised that you changed
your mind about doing the surgery.
Well, I can help them, Nai.
You know, the Thompsons,
they are desperate
to change their situation.
For them and for the baby.
And you made a very good case.
That surgery is the only way
to really do that.
I did. But a boy?
- The odds are stacked against that.
- Gender's not my choice. It's theirs.
And they want him past this.
They want him better, and I can help.
Hey, speaking of better,
I was thinking of borrowing Archer
for a few days.
A weekend in Palm Springs.
You know,
sleeping late, getting massages.
- Nai.
- What?
Do you think that's a good idea?
A trip? With me?
No. No, I mean just,
you know, health wise.
Oh, he can go back to work,
- but going to a spa is strenuous?
- No, no, no. But I mean, you know Archer.
I mean, he's gonna wanna play golf,
tennis. He'll push himself.
- You don't want me to go.
- No. No, I do. It's just...
- Why rush it?
- Because
I want to go away with my boyfriend.
Like a woman.
Like a woman with a lover.
Lover.
Lover, I like that.
That's a lot better than boyfriend.
He's my lover. What do you think?
- Lover.
- Yeah, no. Yeah, it sounds stupid.
It sounds like a soap opera.
- No, no. It's not...
- Paramour.
Arch, come on, we're gonna be late.
You really need to learn how to knock.
I'm sorry.
No. It's just what I get.
- Hey, you okay?
- Don't touch me.
- Because my sister walked in?
- No. We just...
We never should have...
I never should have done...
Where are Archer and Addison?
Addison's waiting for him at the office.
It's his first day back.
He's got a lot of work
to catch up on, so...
Charlotte's probably holding his feet
to the fire.
- Hey.
Where's Archer?
Oh, he got stuck at the office.
I don't think he's gonna make it.
Aren't we celebrating his first day back?
- Well, maybe I should call him.
- He was with a patient when I left.
I'm gonna get a drink.
MAN: What can I get you?
- Scotch, neat.
What, uh...?
- How come you're not with them?
- I decided I liked the quiet.
Yeah. Me too.
MAN: Here you go.
- I thought you'd be in a great mood.
Archer's back at work.
Things are back to normal.
Yeah, you'd think.
What?
Can I tell you something?
And you can't tell...
You can't tell anyone.
Anything.
- Addison.
- Never mind, forget it.
Oh, hey, don't do that.
Don't shut yourself off from me.
You don't need to see my crazy.
You don't think I have crazy?
Do you feel left out?
No. I feel
broken.
Archer's cheating on Naomi.
Which is wrong on so many levels,
but mostly because he's gonna hurt her.
He will and there's nothing...
I just, I can't...
[ADDISON SIGHS]
It's okay. You're okay.
What do I do?
People make their own choices.
You can't do it for them.
NAOMl:
Yes, well, that is...
- But... I don't think...
- Sorry I'm late.
Hey. Oh, you're here.
You wanna talk about this?
- Will it help?
- No.
Then what's the point?
- Addy.
- Don't.
Don't be this guy, Archer.
Don't be this limited, short-sighted,
not-good-enough guy.
- Please.
- Look, I like Naomi. I really do.
It's just...
I'm sorry.
Don't apologize to me.
Apologize to her.
You know, I hated him.
I hated Dad for years.
Past tense. "Hated."
Do you love him now?
- Now he's your hero?
- I am him, Addison. I am him.
Like father, like son.
Whatever he passed down to me.
I'm missing a gene.
You don't think I wanna be better?
You don't think I wanna be
a good man in a storm?
- I don't have it in me.
- That's a cop-out.
Maybe it is.
But it's honest.
Do you usually do this?
Have us come in alone?
Sheldon's never done this before.
Well, sometimes I find things
that are best served outside the group.
What's going on?
I saw you in the stairwell yesterday.
- Oh, God.
- It just happened.
After the first session,
Ryan and I, we started talking
and it was easy.
Everything you said about communication,
that we couldn't do with our spouses,
the two of us could.
Are you gonna tell?
You can't do that, can you?
You might think that keeping this a secret
is a good thing
and that holding it in is better.
But I think it would be best
for both of you to go home.
Talk to your spouses
and work together
to try to figure this out.
VIOLET: You came to the group
to work on your marriages.
To make things better.
Is that still what you want?
To work on your marriages?
We wanna be together.
And if telling our spouses is the first step
to a new life together,
we'll do it.
And instead of wanting to save their
marriage, they're just willing to walk away.
NAOMl:
Well, maybe it's a good thing.
- If it's not working, why force it?
- I don't know what's worse.
To be faithful in a loveless marriage
or to cheat to find true love.
ADDISON: What are we talking about?
- Keeping secrets.
Well, it's tough.
- Keeping people's secrets.
- That's why it's better not to.
I mean, if you care about that person,
you just tell them.
- Bottom line.
SAM: Yeah, especially in a marriage.
The bond between a husband
and wife is sacrosanct.
Like the bond
between a parent and a child.
VIOLET: How is the Thompson baby?
- I'm operating today.
The parents want a boy.
I think it's important to respect that.
- What about what that kid wants?
- He's young to make that decision.
I hope you make the right one.
SAM:
Are you hungry?
Frustrated.
Charlotte acts like I'm cheating on her.
I mean, here I am trying to be
the good guy, all I get is guilt.
I'm really not the person
you should talk to about this, Cooper.
Talk to her.
WOMAN [OVER SPEAKER]:
Dr. Klass, call Recovery.
Charlotte, we need to talk.
Charlotte. Stop. Hey.
Hey, stop treating me
like I've done something horrible.
Like taking care of my friend
is cheating on you.
- You don't know...
- You don't know.
All I've ever wanted to do
is make you happy.
I can't do that if you're shutting me out.
Please.
NAOMl:
Addison?
Addison.
ADDISON: Oh, hey.
NAOMl: You ready to do this?
Hey, I'm sorry we left so early
last night. It's...
I just... I think Archer's just so glad
to be healthy again that we...
[LAUGHS]
I'm sorry, never mind, I know.
Some details
I just have to keep to myself.
Oh, I asked him about going away.
And we're thinking
maybe next weekend.
Oh, and I came up with a name
for him. Beau.
He's my beau.
You know,
it's simple and it's a little old-fashioned.
But still, I think it's better than boyfriend.
I can't do this.
NAOMl:
Addison. Addison.
Is something wrong?
It was gonna be hours.
I can't do this.
I'm sorry. I can't do the surgery.
- Is the baby sick?
- No, no, no. The baby is fine.
That's just it.
The baby is fine.
But you, Naomi,
we all want to change the baby.
To a him. Into something that he's not.
So you just want to leave him a freak.
- He's not a freak.
- Well, he is if they don't do the surgery.
Please, you've gotta do this.
Give us our son.
I can't. I can't do it. I won't.
Okay, well,
if you want a boy,
you can still have a boy.
You can take him home
and call him Matthew.
And love him and accept him
for what he is.
And raise him
so that when the time comes,
- he'll make the choice that's right for him.
- And meanwhile,
what? Our kid should hide?
Be embarrassed? Humiliated? What?
- We could protect him.
- What do you think it'll be like
- to be a 6-year-old boy with a vagina?
- Imagine being a 20-year-old woman
without one.
We'll find another surgeon.
- Someone who will do this.
- No.
She's right.
We need to think about this.
It is too important
to just hurt him this way.
Him. That's right. Him.
That, in there, our baby, it's a him.
And leaving him like this, it's not right.
I don't wanna make a mistake.
Look, well, I can't. I can't do this.
All right, I can't do this.
I can't take that home.
And hope it turns out right.
I can't. I can't...
I can't change that diaper
every day and...
I can't do this.
- I can't. I can't.
- Mitch.
Mitch.
Did yesterday's session
bring up anything?
Ryan came to me.
He said he wanted to talk.
I was surprised. It had been so long.
And he had this look on his face.
And he started to tell me
all the things that were wrong
and how he was feeling.
And I guess
it's not all him. It's me.
It's us.
We talked for hours.
And then
we had sex.
- Oh, Sasha.
SASHA: We did.
We can talk about it.
For the first time in a long time,
we had sex and it was great.
Something about it felt new
and better
and different.
I guess because I felt
like he was there.
Ryan, I know
that this might be uncomfortable,
but it might be helpful
if you could tell us how you feel.
Well, it wasn't
what I thought I'd be saying.
But we talked
and I remembered what we had.
And what we can still have.
I had an affair.
What the hell just happened
back there?
I don't understand what happened.
You agreed to do the surgery...
- This isn't about the surgery.
- Well, what is it?
I thought
that he could be a different person.
After everything he went through,
after almost dying.
I thought
he could be a different person.
I wanted to believe that so much
that I almost cut into a baby
to convince myself
that people can change.
That I can change them.
But I can't.
Archer's cheating on you.
And I'm sorry. Nai.
Who was it? Someone I know?
SHELDON:
This may be hard to hear, Paul,
but sometimes an affair
isn't moving away, it's reaching out.
For the wrong thing.
It's reaching out towards someone
who seems like an answer.
But they're not.
They're a crutch, a way to fill the void
of something that's missing.
The person that you really love.
The person I really love?
I thought I'd lost that with Sasha.
I was in the same boat you are.
Maybe we all are in the same boat.
But isn't it...?
Isn't it worth another chance?
I think I made a mistake, Paul.
- I don't care.
VIOLET: But you should.
Because if you want anything
to change, you have to work at it.
You haven't shared yourself
and I understand that.
How can you share yourself
if you don't know what you think
or you don't know what you feel.
And it makes you feel pathetic
and crazy and bad.
And you think that if you share that,
then they might decide
that you're as crazy as you feel you are.
But we're... All of us, we're human.
We make mistakes.
I have.
I know Eleanor has
and I bet you have too.
But if you can talk to her about this,
if you can open up with her,
then I really think you can work
through this and make things better.
You know what?
I'm done.
I'm afraid that Carol will leave me,
just like Paul did.
When you come home at night
and you talk about
how great the guys are you work with,
I feel small.
Insignificant.
I know who I am and what I am.
But it scares me
that you'll realize you could do better.
You should have talked to me.
Because I want you.
I love you.
This has got to stop.
When I'm with you, what you do to me.
These days, it's the best I ever feel.
- Look, Beverly...
- I want to try this new herb.
Red clover.
It's supposed to put years on your life.
And take years off your face.
Bev.
- I know what you're gonna say.
- You have cancer.
I know that.
Stage two lymphoma.
God, I know that.
You don't have to say it.
PETE:
I do.
I love that you come to see me.
You're one of my favorite patients.
But I've referred you to the best oncologist
in town and you won't go.
You have to go.
I tried. I made it to the waiting room.
But those people are so frail.
I mean, they're bald.
Or worse, bad wigs.
Chapped skin.
- I can't be like that.
- They're sick, like you are.
But they're getting the right treatment.
They are trying to get better.
- What if they don't?
- Then they don't.
But their eyes are wide open.
They know they can't cheat fate.
They're fighting.
The way you should be fighting.
I don't want to be the one
who dies.
Then be the one who lives.
He's gone.
I'm sorry.
I'm going home to New York.
Are you saying goodbye to Naomi?
Don't tell her about Charlotte.
That would hurt her.
Archer, you leaving without a word?
That will hurt her. Don't do this.
Bye, Addy.
I love you.
I wanted to see how you were doing.
Mitch is gone.
But I don't know
how I'm gonna do this alone.
I went with blue.
Matthew.
Mitch was so excited.
You know,
I know you want to save him
from all that he'll go through,
but I think you're doing the right thing.
I hope so.
You do not get to cut and run
because you're afraid of not knowing
what comes next.
There are people that love you
and that need you.
Why are you here yelling at me?
Because it is not okay to just walk away
and pretend like it doesn't matter.
I mean, to have something incredible
and not even see
what is right in front of your face.
Your wife loves you.
And you have a healthy child who,
yeah, has some issues, but so what?
Everybody has issues.
You need to be there for them.
- Love them.
- Well, I don't know if I can.
Grow up.
God, be a man.
You need to not hurt the woman
who loves you.
Well, nice surprise.
I slept with Archer Montgomery.
I just thought you should know.
No. No.
You don't get to just walk away from me
after telling me that.
How dare you? How dare you do this?
- That's just the way I am.
- Oh, that's crap.
You did the one thing
you could to push me away.
To make me make the choice
and not you.
Guess what, Charlotte? That's not
gonna work. I'm not going anywhere.
You wanna sleep with some guy
to hurt me? To make me back off?
Too bad. I'm here.
I'm storming the freaking castle for you.
And you so underestimated me.
What? You thought I was so weak
that I'm gonna walk away
because my pride got wounded?
You are mine.
And I'm not walking away
because you're scared.
God, I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry.
This one,
I can overlook.
This one.
But you have to think long and hard about
testing me because next time, I'm gone.
You'd better dig deep, Charlotte.
Dig deep in your soul
and grow the hell up
and be in this relationship.
Right now.
Okay?
I wanted to thank you for what you said.
- I don't think I got through to Paul.
- You got through to Greg and Carol.
And we saved a marriage. Maybe two.
Trying to figure this stuff out
is hard, Violet.
I mean, they come to us,
they're on the brink already.
If we turn two out of three,
I say we won.
It was a shock.
I mean, the pregnancy.
It was unplanned.
And I don't often do unplanned.
So this whole thing
is unfamiliar territory for me.
And I'm just trying
to roll with it the best way I can.
I know, Violet.
And I don't expect you to confide in me.
But if you do need me,
I'm here for you.
[MOANING]
SONYA:
You taste good.
Really good.
SAM:
Oh, Naomi.
What's wrong?
What did you just call me?
What?
You just called me Naomi.
No, I didn't.
- No, I didn't.
- You did.
You warned me.
I thought...
I really thought Archer had changed.
Or that he could.
I'm sorry.
I know he's your brother
and I know I shouldn't...
It's not right to say it.
Say it.
I hate him.
Me too.