Bell, yank that sucker,
so we can get out of here.
Oh, the appendix hasn't burst.
That's good news.
Slippery little fellow.
Did you guys know this is
my first surgery with Dr. Bell?
No kidding.
We have to get a photo.
- Make it quick.
- Get in, Chu.
That is totally inappropriate.
- Go back to your stations.
- Oh, we're just having fun.
He's out cold, he'll never know.
Wait, I'm gonna
take a quick selfie.
Get closer together.
I wish we could do
one without the mask.
Quit clowning, Chu.
Just one more.
I think we got it.
I'm going to send
this to my mother.
You'll get us all fired.
Cameras aren't allowed
in the OR.- -
He's waking up.
I need to up the sevo.
Oh, my God. Did
you hit an artery?
- On an appendectomy?
- You're losing blood fast.
I'm hanging two liters of
normal saline wide open,
Call for four units of
blood and 2 FFP stat.
I'm giving him Trendelenburg.
Packing, suction.
You have to clamp something.
He's lost at least
two liters already.
Come on, come on.
We just lost the
pulse. P.E.A. arrest.
All right, pressure, Cheryl.
I'm starting compressions.
CPR isn't gonna put
all that blood back
into his body.
Don't die on me.
It's no use.
He is so dead.
Time of death: 12:03.
Dr. Bell.
Oh...
Well, I think we can all agree
it was the misdosed sevo...
that led to this
unfortunate situation.
What? You're kidding, right?
The patient woke up,
his arm hit my hand.
You left the blade in the
field. You nicked the artery.
- You all saw it.
- Well, you never should've okayed
him for surgery in the first
place. His INR was abnormal.
The upper range of normal.
That's never gonna fly.
You know, I'm-I'm flashing back
to the time when
you tore through
that old woman's oropharynx
on a routine intubation.
Did that fly? I covered for you.
Not this time.
I'm chief of surgery, and he's
at the end of a 30-hour shift.
What did you see?
Well, w-we're all on
the same team here,
right?
Maybe he had a heart attack.
Yes. There's some family
history of heart disease.
Uh, yes.
His left main clogged.
Sudden cardiac event.
We tried CPR.
He was unresponsive.
Yeah, that works.
Well, that's right.
That's exactly right.
There was no
way to prevent this.
Who are you calling?
I'm erasing the photos,
Doctor.
♪ ♪
♪ Last night took a "L,"
but tonight I bounce back ♪
♪ Wake up every morning,
by the night I count stacks ♪
♪ Knew that... was
real when I hit ♪
♪ It bounce back ♪
♪ You ain't getting checks ♪
♪ Last night took a "L,"
but tonight I bounce back ♪
♪ Boy, I been broke as hell ♪
♪ Cashed a check
and bounced back ♪
♪ D-town LAX, every
week I bounce back... ♪
- That's handicapped, pal.
- Yeah, whatever.
♪ Last night took a "L,"
but tonight I bounce back ♪
♪ If you a real one, then you
know how to bounce back ♪
♪ Don't owe nobody, owe nobody ♪
♪ Always, always on
the job, I got no hobbies ♪
♪ Got the city, city with
me 'cause I'm homegrown ♪
♪ Vibin' out more than
my phone, though ♪
♪ Leave me 'lone, me
on my own, though. ♪
This bone here is the acromion.
We have 206 bones,
and I can name each one.
Here is the clavicular head.
The sternum.
I got to go.
No. Stay. It's early.
I don't want to be
late on my first day.
You're gonna be
an amazing doctor.
I know.
♪ I want what I want,
not what I need ♪
♪ Even if it kills
me, I'll be free ♪
♪ I want what I want,
not what I need ♪
♪ The American dream ♪
♪ I want what I want,
not what I need ♪
♪ Even if it kills
me, I'll be free ♪
♪ What I want's
just what I want ♪
♪ The American dream... ♪
Every doctor needs one of these.
It's part of the uniform.
- This is insane. I can't...
- Well, you have to.
It can't be returned.
I had it engraved.
"Dr. Devon Pravesh."
Keep it to remember this day.
Your first as a doctor.
♪ I want what I want,
not what I need ♪
♪ Even if it kills
me, I'll be free ♪
♪ What I want's
just what I want ♪
♪ The American dream ♪
♪ What I want's
just what I want ♪
♪ The American dream ♪
♪ The American dream. ♪
Wow.
That's him.
Dr. Randolph Bell.
Chief of surgery. He's a legend.
Thank you very much for coming.
I really appreciate
you taking the time.
And, Dr. Shore, thank you...
Excuse me, Dr. Bell?
I just wanted to say
that I really admire you.
And you're the reason
why I chose this residency.
Well, you made
the right decision.
Good luck to you.
Thank you.
Okay. So that's pretty much it?
Did you see that?
I feel like I just got
blessed by the Pope.
Oh, my supervising
resident just texted me.
Oh! A winky and a smiley face.
- That's got to be good, right?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Um, hey, man.
Know where I can find
Dr. Conrad Hawkins?
Namaste.
You found him.
Take off that tie. You're
not at Harvard anymore.
What are you into? White, black?
Brown?
Men?
- I-I don't understand what you...
- Oh...
"I don't understand."
Were you affirmative
action at Harvard?
I read your file, bro.
Yale, then Harvard.
Let's go.
19 first authors.
Step 1 score: 267.
- I got 280 by the way.
- Dr. C.
Top of your class,
followed all the rules,
and you think that puts you
at an advantage. It doesn't.
It just means you
have more to unlearn
than the guys who
weren't paying attention.
Over easy, no cheese,
- no mayo, breakfast sandwich.
- Good man.
Second year.
I broke him.
Now he's a doctor.
You're not.
You got your little
white coat, though.
Your stethoscope, your penlight.
You're all ready to
play doctor, right?
No, no, no, no.
It's not like that.
We're not laughing together.
Everything you thought you
knew about medicine is wrong.
All the rules you
followed, we'll break.
I have only one rule.
Covers everything.
I'm never wrong.
You do whatever
the hell I tell you.
No questions asked.
Do you want me to speak now?
That's a question.
No, no, no, no, no,
no, no. Don't do that.
Don't do that. Eyes on me.
My last resident
had an attitude, too,
and you know where he is now?
He's teaching
eighth grade biology.
I cut him. Do you
know what that means?
It means I can end your career.
Just like that.
Remove you from this residency
at any time, for any reason.
And if I do that, no other
residency will take you.
All you'll have left
from that fancy Harvard
medical school degree
is a mountain of debt.
Now, let's meet
your first patient.
This is Dobroslav.
He's Croatian,
speaks no English.
He has severe cauda
equina syndrome.
What are we worried about?
- Early paralysis.
- Hey, man.
What's the first
sign of paralysis?
- Anal tone.
- Stick your finger up his ass.
Normal procedure
is to get an MRI.
Thank you so much for telling
me about normal procedure.
An MRI would take
hours and delay
steroid treatment and surgery,
both of which might
save Dobroslav.
A loose rectum means
his legs may give out soon.
Tight means
there's no paralysis.
So we need to know
exactly how tight it is up there.
Good afternoon, we need
to explore your rectum.
How tight would you say it is?
Compared to your prom date.
Stay like that until you
can answer the question.
Excuse me, nurse? Devon.
Nic.
I need a new resident.
- Mine's impossible.
- You got Conrad.
Yes, I did, and I need
someone else, like, now.
Let's say your car has a rattle.
So you take it to a mechanic
and this guy's kind,
polite, eager to help.
For two days, he runs
every test in the book.
And then he calls you and says
it's gonna set you
back a thousand bucks.
So you max out your credit card
and on your drive
home, guess what.
What?
You hear the same rattle.
Or you could take the
same car with the same rattle
to another mechanic.
And this guy is rude,
uh, dismissive, arrogant,
but he tightens a
bolt, fixes the rattle,
charges you five
bucks. Problem solved.
This is nothing like that.
No, because your
car can't end up dead.
Watch and learn.
Conrad's the guy
who tightens the bolt.
Four heart failure disasters.
Two went straight to the unit.
One is dry and cold.
Now a new admission shows up
with a bewildering
array of symptoms.
You'd probably diagnose her
by the type of dirt on her shoe.
Could you possibly
do a quick consult?
I'm slammed.
Ah.
I took that photo.
Mrs. Robinson, we're going
to get you back to your room.
Right.
"No gamers, no
slackers, no doctors."
That's pretty clear.
What did you do this time?
Tell me about the new admission.
Alopecia, discoid rash,
rising urea nitrogen...
Lupus.
HR to Dr. Shaw.
♪ Feeling fallen like a stone ♪
♪ You ask your mother ♪
♪ "Is it true?" ♪
♪ Stays to listen... ♪
You think you can just kiss me?
I will do whatever it
takes to get you back.
♪ It's following me ♪
♪ It's following me... ♪
Take off your shirt.
My shirt?
If we're gonna do this,
we're gonna do it my way.
♪ We're the last to know ♪
♪ We're the last to know... ♪
And your pants.
♪ It's no fun,
you're the last one ♪
♪ You're the last to know ♪
♪ You're the last to know. ♪
Nic.
Not funny.
Acute leukemic on chemo.
Fiancé called because she
was shaking uncontrollably.
Uh, she spiked a fever
this morning, 100.8.
Also, there was some vomiting.
There's no blood in it.
Last chemo was a week ago.
Hey.
You're here.
I was scared.
Ah, you're running a fever.
It's just another infection.
Chemo is still crushing
your immune system.
We'll get you started on broad-
spectrum antibiotics again.
Acetaminophen to
get your fever down.
Get cultures from
both arms. Urine.
She'll need a head CT.
- Okay.
- Don't worry.
We'll get this under control.
Get you both back home soon.
You're in good hands.
Guess where he
went to medical school.
I think he went to
Harvard Medical School.
Was it Harvard Medical School?
I'm pretty sure it was
Harvard Medical School.
Lily means a lot to all of us.
She's been in and
out of the ER so often,
we're all invested, but her
diagnosis is a tough one.
I'm giving you a gift.
From now on, she's your patient.
But if you screw this
one up, I will wreck you.
- I got it.
- Hey, Conrad.
What's wrong?
Your appendectomy patient
who had surgery last night...
What about him?
Conrad, he's dead.
What the hell happened?
HODAD happened.
What was it this time, Bell?
Pulmonary embolism?
Undisclosed heart condition.
Tragic situation, and
naturally I covered for you.
You need to consider a change
before you kill
any more patients.
How dare you?
Go be one of those
celebrity TV doctors.
You look the part.
Make a lot of money,
wear nice clothes.
You'd be great at it.
You watch yourself, Conrad.
You know, I'm remembering
a pretty, young resident
that reported a fatal chemo
overdose a couple years back.
That good deed...
that led to a lawsuit
that cost the hospital millions.
You tell me, Conrad,
where is she today?
With cutting-edge research.
At this moment, our
patients are involved
in over 100...
Not here.
♪ Gonna be here all my life ♪
♪ But I don't know
what else to do... ♪
How'd you get that
cheeseburger, Chad?
Delivery app.
It looks like you haven't
been following your diet.
Diets don't work.
Have you been
taking your insulin?
I don't want a lecture, Nic.
I'm here 'cause
my toe's killing me.
Severe gangrene.
♪ All I know ♪
♪ Hear me on the radio ♪
♪ But I keep thinking
the time will go... ♪
The toe was already
dead. I just touched it.
He broke my toe!
His toe fell off.
Chad, buddy, we are
amputating the whole foot.
You knew this was coming. Devon.
What do you think
they got for dessert?
You can't keep me here!
- You need to settle down.
- Calm down.
- Get me out!
New admission.
21-year-old girl,
history of IV drug use.
Likely endo.
She was trying
to steal Dilaudid.
Now she wants to leave AMA.
She's been spiking
fever, vomiting.
- She's using again.
- Hey, hey.
She took all my money
and spent it on oxy.
Oy, listen to me.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Please, stop.
Hey, hey, hey. See these?
See these? These
are Osler's nodes
caused by bacteria
swarming in your blood
and moving throughout your body.
Classic for endocarditis,
an infection of the heart valve.
Happens to drug
users all the time.
If you walk out of here
without any antibiotics,
this will kill you.
If you give us a chance,
we can save your life.
I'll stay if you give me
three milligrams of Dilaudid.
Two.
If you calm down and you
get back in bed right now.
Chloe, baby!
- Get a crash cart.
- Chloe, baby!
- I'm not getting a pulse.
- Code Blue in ED alpha!
- Get them out of here.
- No, no!
- Baby, no! No!
- You need to give them space.
Start compressions.
You're running the code.
I've never run a code.
- Do you want an amp of bicarb?
- He's in charge.
Page Anesthesia.
What is the first question
you ask in a code?
Rhythm.
What's her rhythm?
P.E.A.
- Should we shock?
- No, we can't. Her rhythm's not shockable.
Get me one of epi.
Make those compressions
harder and faster.
Prepare to intubate.
It's been 24 minutes.
- It's time to call the code.
- No!
This is my code. You
gave me this code.
She's 21 years old.
Harder, man. You need
to feel the ribs crack.
That's enough.
No. Move.
I'm not giving up.
I said that's enough.
We got a pulse.
You saved her life.
Her end tidal CO2 was less
than 15 for the entire code.
- That doesn't necessarily mean that...
- Yes.
Yes, it does.
She's been without oxygen
to her brain for 26 minutes.
Congratulations, you got
her heart beating again,
but she's brain-dead.
You came in here all
bright-eyed and bushy-tailed,
ready to save lives, but
today you didn't save a life.
You saved a brain stem
because you didn't listen to me.
Now the repercussions
on Chloe's family
will be catastrophic.
There's no way
they'll accept this.
Chloe looks alive. They'll
think she can wake up.
So they will hover over
her, tend to her for days,
weeks, maybe years,
waiting for a miracle to happen
that's utterly impossible.
What was rule one, Devon?
Do whatever you tell me to do.
No questions asked.
All we want to do
is help our patients,
but what they don't
teach us in medical school
is there are so many
ways to do harm.
As you can see, the
Titian is an amazing piece
of medical technology.
We've nicknamed
it the "Hand of God"
because it does what no
human hands could accomplish.
Even yours?
Yeah, even mine.
The finest surgeon in the world
would benefit from the Titian.
It's capable
of movements that are incredibly
steady and precise,
virtually eliminating
human error.
Chastain Park Memorial
is the first hospital
in the country
to have this miraculous machine,
thanks to Dr. Bell,
who spearheaded
this fund-raising campaign,
and, of course, to you,
our very generous donors.
Thank you.
"Serious complications
may occur,
"up to and including death.
Individual surgical
results may vary."
I've trained for
months to do this.
Results will not vary.
Until Bell gets his hands on it.
Over my dead body.
I'm sure HODAD
could manage that.
I heard a nurse call him HODAD.
What does it stand for?
Hands of Death and Destruction.
You're kidding. Does
that mean everyone knows
about his complication rate?
All the nurses,
some of the doctors.
The ones who pay attention.
Poetry.
But none of the
patients. They're clueless.
You've got the best
hands in the business,
but he's still the most
requested surgeon
in the hospital.
Have you seen
his reviews online?
He has got five stars.
Top patient review:
"McDreamy is real."
- You want to hear yours?
- Don't care.
You got one star.
"Steer clear of Dr. Okafor.
She told me my uterus sucked."
It did suck.
I just had hernia
surgery with Dr. Bell.
The man has magic hands.
Dr. Flores, dial 182...
Hey.
Randolph, I'm so
glad you're here.
Where else would I be?
You better finish up
those smoked oysters.
There's no food after midnight.
All right. They're
absolutely delicious.
This whole VIP
floor is spectacular.
It's nothing more than
you deserve, my friend.
If it hadn't been for
your generous donation,
there would be no
new cancer wing.
- Well...
- So...
I hear you're gonna
be the first patient
to benefit from the Titian.
Yeah, it's quite the honor.
I hear the damn thing
practically operates itself.
Have you met your
surgeon yet, Dr. Okafor?
Nope, not yet.
She's Nigerian.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, here on a visa.
Very promising young resident.
What do you mean,
"young resident"?
Well, second year, I believe.
Randolph, I spoke
directly to the CEO...
I mentioned you...
But she told me
that Dr. Okafor was the best
possible person to remove
my prostate with the Titian.
She'll be fine,
I'm fairly certain.
I want you.
You're the chief of surgery.
Don't you think I
deserve the best?
Yes.
And I'll make sure you get it.
Thank you.
You have a visitor
in the main lobby.
Lisa brought this
back to you, baby,
your honey bunny.
I'm so happy
you're with us again.
I'll be right back, my darling.
Dr. Pravesh,
I never thanked you
for saving my daughter's life.
Thank you.
You're wonderful.
I'll be in the cafeteria
if she wakes up.
You okay?
Nothing like this has ever
happened to me before.
They'll do an
investigation, right?
Are you kidding me?
The hospital will
probably give you a medal.
Every day Chloe's in the ICU,
they bill thousands of dollars.
It's a huge payday for them.
Medicine isn't practiced
by saints, Devon.
It's a business.
Yeah, but this, all this,
just isn't what I imagined.
Then you're lucky.
When I was 13, my mom
went in for her routine physical.
They did some tests, and they...
they found something
small on her lung.
So they cracked her chest,
and her lung collapsed.
She got pneumonia,
and five days later,
she was dead.
She was 38 years old.
I'm so sorry.
This happens all
the time, Devon.
Medical error is the third-
leading cause of death
in the United States after
cancer and heart disease.
They don't want us
talking about that.
But you still show
up here every day.
'Cause it's personal to me.
And there are
still plenty of good
doctors and nurses
trying to do the right thing.
I'm just trying
to be one of 'em.
Lily.
You look like
you're feeling better.
Yeah, yeah. Conrad's
a miracle worker.
Well, good. Let's
get you back in bed.
You need to stay warm.
Where's your fiancé?
Oh, he... he left
a few hours ago.
I was still in the ER.
I bet he's just exhausted.
- He'll be back tomorrow, I'm sure.
- No, he won't.
I got diagnosed a month
after I got engaged.
It's not his fault. He
didn't sign up for cancer.
I mean, maybe if I
just let him go sooner...
I was selfish.
Didn't want to die alone.
Do you have to go right away?
No.
No. We can talk.
Come on, man.
Status?
We pushed adenosine
six milligrams, then 12.
She's still tach'ing
away at 180.
- Try verapamil.
- That won't work,
Dr. Bell, she's gonna
have a heart attack.
I think her heart's had
enough AV blockade.
Oh.
Normal rhythm.
- Her heartbeat is back.
- Ice water stimulus.
Prompts vagal tone,
restores normal rhythm in SVT.
Called the Diver's Reflex.
That was my next step.
Two in one day would
have been a bit excessive.
Tightening the bolt.
You saved my life, Dr. Bell.
Thank you so much.
Nothing to it.
I don't have time to give
updates on how the surgeries
went one by one. Are
the families all assembled?
Dr. Okafor, you have to
talk to them each individually.
- There are rules about this.
- I get it.
Luis is doing fine.
He's in recovery.
- Oh.
Raj is in the ICU.
It's touch and go.
- Oh.
Prescott's dead.
What? Huh?
Dr. Okafor! A word.
Sorry, I'm on my
way out. I need to rest
for the first robot
prostatectomy tomorrow morning.
Well, that's actually
why I'm here.
The patient has requested
a last-minute
change in the lineup.
The lineup?
Lyle's always been my patient.
He's asked me to step in.
Does he have a death wish?
I hear you're applying
for an O-1 visa.
You'll need a letter
of recommendation
from your supervisor.
- I believe that'd be me.
- Dr. Bell,
you have never
touched the Titian.
It takes many hours of
practice to be proficient.
You cannot do that surgery.
As in, it's literally
impossible.
You have no idea what's possible
for a surgeon with my
experience and expertise.
The surgery is first
thing tomorrow morning.
There isn't enough time
to bring you up to speed.
I have to draw a line
here. This can't happen.
It's too risky for you
and for the patient.
Oh, then, I'm afraid you'll
be heading back to Abuja.
And as you know,
immigration to the States
has become quite difficult.
We're shutting our doors.
Given the political
unrest and the quality
of health care
available in Nigeria,
you might want to reconsider.
If I help you,
you'll get your visa.
If I don't, you won't.
Your call.
Start with a simple maneuver.
Four-millimeter incision
on the ventral surface.
Slow and steady.
I've got it.
What the hell's wrong
with the machine?
It would be better,
for everyone, if I do this.
No. The patient asked for me.
I'm always there
for my patients.
Just put that plum
back on the table,
and let's get on with it.
Round 11.
Oh, for crying out loud!
This is a new low even for you.
Is your pride really worth
more than the life of a patient?
Get out.
I can't stop this train wreck,
so I just wanted
to let you know,
I've arranged for a
very wide audience.
What are you talking about?
The hospital's gonna
stream the robotic surgery live.
Not just to the donors
who are watching here,
but to thousands
of viewers online.
Unless, of course,
you want to step aside.
Idiot.
I'll do no such thing.
The more witnesses the better.
This is going to be a
flawless presentation.
Do you think you can sleep?
Uh, yeah, I think so.
Hey, can I ask you something?
Of course.
What are my odds?
I mean, is there a
chance I can survive this?
I looked at your chart, and
you're on an intense protocol.
The next few
months will be rough,
but you can beat this.
How are you feeling, Lily?
A bit weak all of a sudden.
Your blood pressure is low.
80/40. It was
120/90 a minute ago.
Lily. Lily!
Lily.
Lily!
Where's Conrad?
He's in the ER.
Why? What's wrong?
Lily's BP is 70/38 and dropping.
Can we please get
rapid response now?
Get a CBC, CMP, LFTs, lactate.
Is the IV wide open?
Systolic's fluctuating,
but it's not good.
We're three liters in
already. It's sepsis.
You want to give
norepi peripherally?
No. Get a central line.
No. You've never done
one. We wait for Conrad.
We can't. She'll die.
Prepare the iodine swabs.
We need norepi and vaso on
the table. Get pharm here now.
I want 12 leads
on her at all times.
Call for an
ultrasound as backup.
Scalpel.
Have respiratory
on page, please.
Oh, good. Her
pressure's crashing.
- We need a central line now.
- I can see that.
Go on.
Do it.
- Conrad, seriously...
- You heard me.
She's right. You
should do it, not me.
Then why are you here?
Premed, med school, MCATs.
Was that just for fun?
Come on. Be a doctor,
or go be something else.
Her stats are slipping.
Pressure's 70/38
and dropping fast.
Okay.
Keep going.
So far, you haven't killed her.
Start at five micrograms.
Titrate up as needed.
Don't look at him.
I'm right, and you know it.
What next?
When her pressure levels out,
wean her off the norepi
and then drown her in fluids.
Congratulations. We
just busted your cherry.
We are moments away
from the maiden
voyage of our new Titian.
And after having spent
considerable time working
with it, I can definitively say
this is a miraculous machine.
And we expect it to
be particularly useful
for radical prostatectomies,
which is what we're doing today.
Tell me this isn't happening.
Oh, this is happening.
The man is insane.
Only upside is this
should be a career-ender.
I can't watch.
I can't look away.
The prostate has to
be carefully peeled
off the bladder.
The risk of rupture
and bleeding is high
in unskilled hands.
How is this possible?
As you can see, the robotic
instruments are smaller
than your fingernails.
But that blade
is sharper than a #11.
This represents
the union of human ingenuity
and cutting-edge technology.
Man and machine are melded,
working as one.
Where's Chloe's family?
They just left
for the first time.
The mom was sleeping in
there in case she woke up.
You're done.
You can go home.
Hey!
I want to show you something.
Annabeth. Five. She had cancer.
I was a first
year, just like you.
I gave her too much potassium.
She died.
From me, not the cancer.
If it were easy, everyone
would be a doctor,
because this is the
best job in the world.
Despite everything.
Because of everything.
I'll see you tomorrow.
♪ ♪
♪ Lay my heart down ♪
♪ Laid it down for you ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Put my arms out ♪
♪ Put 'em out to you ♪
♪ Oh, Lord, I was
reaching for ya ♪
♪ Reaching for ya ♪
♪ Oh, child ♪
♪ Reaching for ya,
reaching for ya ♪
♪ Oh, but you ♪
♪ Will never know this love ♪
♪ Will never know this pain ♪
♪ Never know the
way I feel for you ♪
♪ You will never
know this touch ♪
♪ Will never know this shame ♪
♪ Never know the
way I want you to ♪
♪ You will never know ♪
♪ My love ♪
♪ You will never feel ♪
♪ The way I do ♪
♪ You will never know ♪
♪ My love ♪
♪ You will never
feel the way I do. ♪
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH