Previously on ER:
Is it okay if I stop
by the apartment?
Sure. You've got
some stuff in the closet.
Where have you
been? I was worried.
I wanted to say thanks
for suggesting I look
into the transfer
program. I'm going for it.
You're one of those
smart girls, aren't you?
You just noticed?
Why do you do that? - Do what?
Drink in front of me. You never once asked
was that okay or did that bother me...
You used to have a problem.
You're much better now.
My father died.
Luka.
Is the stroller in the car?
No, it's down here
in the living room.
Can we carry it on the plane?
No.
We're gonna have
to check it at the gate.
"And all through the house
not a creature was stirring...
not even a mouse."
Mouse.
Okay.
Hey, the flight's
at 10 tonight, right?
I'm gonna run errands.
Dry cleaners, bank.
It shouldn't take long.
No, sweetheart, you stay
here with Daddy, okay?
Let Daddy finish the book.
- Joe, let's go.
Look at the tree, huh?
Help me how to count
how many Santas we got.
- You okay?
- Yeah, are you?
Yeah.
I'll be back in an
hour or two, okay?
Bye.
Mama, mama, mama.
I saw Frosty the
Snowman on TV last night.
- It's December 6.
- I know.
By the time the Yuletide gets
here, you're already sick of it.
We work for the County,
they all gotta get equal time.
Christmas, Hanukkah, Kwanza.
Why can't people agree on
one date and be done with it?
Damn, what a messed up board.
Messed up floor. It's
like Calcutta around here.
Calcutta on a bad day.
We signed in 142
on the night shift.
- That's a new record.
- You must be proud.
I'm too tired to go home. I'm
gonna sleep in the call room.
Poor kid's a zombie.
A hundred and forty-two, huh?
Hey, we keep this thing
cranking, we could hit 300.
Yeah, that'd be
quite a milestone.
- Forget it.
- Never had over 250 in a 24-hour period.
Dream big, Frank.
We have to sign in, what, 14
patients an hour for the next 12 hours?
Never gonna happen.
Bet you 300 bucks we hit that
mark by the end of this shift.
- Too rich for me.
- No, you guys could split it.
Put up a hundred
each against my three.
- I'm in.
- Oh, Lord, when is he gonna learn?
Looks like I'm gonna be able to get the
wife that toaster she's been hinting for.
Frank, you romantic fool.
- Admin sent this down.
- Oh, put that by Trauma.
New portable CT scanner.
That's the holiday gift for the ER, in
lieu of the T-shirts we normally get.
Oh, too bad. I
love those shirts.
Hey, guys. Everybody
see my memo?
I saw your memo.
- What memo?
I'm going around to
all the departments...
and I'm doing blessing
ceremonies and memorials.
And today is the ER's turn.
Well, you know, that sounds
nice and very cleansing, but no.
- We're busy.
- It's not really our thing.
Yeah, why don't your try Oncology.
They love all that touchy-feely crap.
Come on, guys.
This could be cool.
Enlightening. Gratifying.
Don't shoot the kid down.
How open-minded
of you, Dr. Gates.
Thank you. I do my
best, Miss Dupree.
Good, so I'll see you all later.
- Are you and her...?
- Wait a second.
Are you banging the chaplain?
- Pratt?
Hey, Pratt.
Yeah? SAM: Melissa Tanner, 61.
Restrained driver, TC
in respiratory distress.
- You're on the chopper today, huh?
- Logging hours, part of Transpo training.
- She's unresponsive.
- What's this scar?
Looks like a thoracotomy.
Sats are dropping.
All right, 100 percent
non-rebreather and a portable chest.
- Morris? MORRIS:
What do we got here?
That's her son, Lowell.
Down syndrome, facial
lac, a few contusions.
- Found walking on the scene.
- Is Mommy okay?
- Yeah, we're helping her now.
- Need me?
No, I got this.
Push some charts.
Harold?
Who are you
supposed to be, Merlin?
- I need a ladder out in the bay.
- You need a ladder for what?
Holy cow! Is that
what I think it is?
It's not a cow, no.
What is this?
We had a dress rehearsal
for a hospital holiday pageant.
Surgery got the Nativity scene.
- Congratulations.
And this camel they got from
somewhere bit Lucien on the leg.
Well, why the hell
did you bring it here?
Oh, we were just
down the street.
Well, we need to take a culture.
You need a shave.
There might be an exotic organism
that needs targeted therapy, so...
All right, let's
give this a shot.
My dad raised horses.
Allow me.
Okay, buddy, this
won't hurt. Just a little bit.
No, this will be easy. Come on.
Hold it. I'll
get it. I'll get it.
All right.
Let me just... All right.
Come here.
You know, I'm starting to think
this is not such a good idea.
Well, we've gotta
get a swab, Tony.
All right.
Easy there, big fellow.
Oh, Harold, can you grab my
phone from my back pocket?
Sure thing.
We'll still have noon
conference, Neela.
Make that fat embolus
presentation without me.
You have it on
your laptop, right?
"Missed call. Abby."
Yeah, but I left it at home.
Okay, well, you go home
after morning rounds and get it.
Sorry about this.
Hey, Neela. I left a
message on your cell.
I was just wondering if
you were home right now.
Luka's father died and
we're flying to Croatia tonight.
I left a few things
in the closet...
so I thought I'd just
come by and pick them up.
All right, talk to you later.
Thanks for helping sell
those guys on the ceremony.
- Oh, I'll proselytize for you any day.
- Nice to know I have an acolyte.
- Pulse ox down to 84.
- No pneumothorax.
- Any rib fractures?
- Don't think so.
Intubation tray.
Hey, mind if I try?
I need 10 supervised...
- No, this isn't a good teaching case.
- Patent airway, shouldn't be tricky.
She's had thoracic
surgery with lousy reserve.
- Once we paralyze, every second counts.
- Give Sam a try.
Here.
Suction. PRATT: Twenty
of etomidate, 100 of sux.
Oh, guys, this CT is cool.
- Hey, what's up with her kid?
- Oh, just a few scratches.
Whoa, noncontrast
scan in 15 seconds.
- She's out.
- Go, go.
How about we fire this baby up?
- Quiet, Morris.
Got it. GATES: Nice.
We're not radiating every
patient because we got a toy.
- Good breath sounds.
- End-tidal is yellow.
Good, let's call for a vent.
Hey, Morris, see if you can
get the history from her son.
Kid doesn't say much.
I talked to him on the chopper.
Call for a portable chest.
- Okay, 151, 152, 153.
- What are you doing?
- Just tracking the census.
- Sam, how's my mommy?
She's doing better. We're
helping her breathe right now.
Do you know if your
mom takes any medicine?
Lots of pills. She's sick.
Do you remember when
she had an operation?
How about the
name of her doctor?
It's okay.
The husband's number was
in her wallet, so I'll call him.
- You're gonna call my dad?
- Mm-hm.
Continuous NG, recheck lytes,
write the order, then go get your file.
Oh, will do.
I'm gonna be upstairs in my office
while my anti-camel drip kicks in.
I'm running home.
Be about half an hour.
Dr. Zelinsky will start up any
consult orders you might need.
You mean Harold?
Please hurry back.
The husband of the woman we
choppered in is on his way here.
- Okay.
- Hey, Sam.
Coming to my séance?
I'm off shift. I'm pretty beat.
- That's too bad.
- Yeah.
Plus, to be honest, my relationship
with religion's kind of complicated.
So is mine.
But you know, it's not
exactly a religious ceremony.
Well, I was raised in a
pretty strict household.
A lot of talk about sin and damnation,
and it never did that much for me.
Do you believe in God?
Some days, it's tough.
And other days?
Other days, I thank
him for showing up.
Or her. Or whatever.
Well, if you change your
mind about our get-together...
we'll be here.
I hear you've been
riding rigs all over town.
- You never asked me.
- I go where they tell me, Zades.
Wish I could get into that
paramedic conference.
What? Sternback's case review?
Yeah, I hear it's interesting.
He goes through every
tough ambulance run.
Yeah, you can learn a lot.
So you coming or not?
- Can you get me in?
- I got connections.
- Let's go.
- Yeah.
- Hi.
- Abby.
- I didn't know you were coming over.
- I left you messages.
Oh, no problem. I just
need to pick up my computer.
- You're watching TV?
- Yeah, I was just checking the weather.
- What's going on?
- I was running a few errands.
And I remembered there was a
coat I left here that I wanted to pick up.
I had a drink.
You had a drink?
Yeah.
What are you doing?
Oh, jeez.
Just forget it, I'm gonna go.
- Abby.
- Yeah.
I'm just gonna go, okay?
Is this what's been going
on these last few weeks?
What's been going on
the past couple of weeks?
The way you've been acting? At
Ike's, how far away you seemed?
- That time you asked to...
- Sometimes you are such a child.
- Stop it, I'm trying to help you.
- I don't need it, really.
You've gotta stop this. Think
about Joe, think about Luka.
And I really don't expect you
to even begin to understand this.
- If you love them, you'll do something...
- If I love them?
Please, I'm your friend.
Are you about to lecture me
on love with your track record?
Don't.
Because I'm thinking right now, Ray
is really wishing he didn't meet you.
You don't live here anymore.
Get out.
She has end-stage emphysema.
Used to smoke three packs a day.
She still tries to sneak
one every now and then.
Yeah, we noticed
the scar on her chest.
Yeah, she had lung reduction
surgery about 10 years ago.
It worked. I mean,
it worked for a while.
But she's been on home
oxygen 24/7 for almost a year now.
I... We didn't realize.
We thought maybe her lungs
were bruised in the collision.
No.
She shouldn't have been driving.
She knows that.
I offered to hire a driver.
Well, the ventilator's
helping her to breathe.
No, no, she's a DNR.
She does not wanna be
kept alive by a machine.
Well, we can take off the support if
that's what you and your son decide.
- He didn't say anything about it.
- My what?
Your son. Lowell.
He's right there
in the next room.
I don't know who that is.
So you thinking of
making a change?
Maybe.
Had enough, huh?
I don't know.
I was a traveler for a long
time before I got to Chicago.
Been a nurse at County
for over four years now.
Kind of weird for me.
I used to be wired for change.
Whoa, hold on!
Hey, you okay, Sam?
Yeah. You?
Banged up my knee.
You all right?
I think.
There's a kid.
Hey, Zadro!
Stay in the car.
Evie! SAM: Hey, I'm a nurse.
I'm gonna help you, okay?
- Evie! ZADRO: Hey,
honey, what's your name?
Oh, God. EVIE: Evie.
Where do you hurt, Evie?
- Evie.
- Down there.
No obvious head trauma.
- Did that car hit her?
- I'm all right, Mom.
- Where's Nina?
- Who's Nina?
My dog. JOYCE: Is she okay?
A broken bone in her
pelvis. Everything else, good.
- Her neck? ZADRO:
Bruised it on the way down.
- You breathing okay?
- Yeah.
Sats are good. BP 118 over 76.
Hey! Stay there, sir!
Is that brother drunk?
I bet his dumb ass is drunk.
- Evie.
Nothing but liquor stores
and churches around here.
Hey, Sam, go check
him. I'll call for backup.
Excuse me, coming through.
Excuse me. VAN: Asshole.
- You hit a kid.
- Been drinking?
Hey, come, on, back off, okay?
- You hit a little girl.
- What is your name, sir?
Del.
Del, do you remember anything?
Do you know what happened?
When?
Here you go.
Oh, thank you.
Mind if I...?
Oh, no.
Thanks.
What's his name?
His name is Lowell.
Lowell.
Look, I'm sorry you
had to find out this way.
That your wife had a
kid with someone else.
Oh, no. No.
No, that wasn't it.
Melissa and I were...
We were in our 40s.
We thought we were past
our having-children time.
Then she got pregnant.
That was in 1983.
I knew something
was wrong right away.
I could tell by the looks
on the doctors' faces.
They told us about
Down syndrome.
We realized how
hard it would be.
We weren't ready for it.
I convinced her that
it would be better...
That it would be
better for all of us...
What would?
Giving him up?
Do you know why he
was in the car with her?
Hey, Pratt.
You seen Skye?
You should ask him.
- What? ABBY:
She's not in her office.
She's not on today. What's up?
Luka's father passed away.
What? Oh, I'm
sorry to hear that.
Yeah, so we're leaving
for Croatia tonight.
I need to take a
leave of absence.
- Hey, you okay?
- Yeah.
- You sure?
- Yeah, I'm sure.
I mean, his father just
died. Give me a break.
All right. Well...
fill out the paperwork.
And I'll tell Skye about it.
Thanks.
- A little oxygen in your nose.
- Okay.
- I think the girl stopped moving.
- I saw her get hit, it was bad.
- You think she could die?
- No.
- Go help with the girl.
- Paramedics are with her.
This jerk's feeling no pain.
He's concussed. He's not drunk.
- Come on, that girl needs you more.
- Hey!
Why don't you back off and
let me do my work, okay?
- Okay. EMILIO:
Give her some room.
Yeah, thank you. VAN: Cool.
Hey!
- Little drunk bitch!
- Hey.
Hey, Zadro!
Frank? I need two more charts.
- You're pathetic.
- No, no, it's the funniest thing.
As I was getting my coffee, I noticed
that Conchita has carpal tunnel.
From working the register.
Yeah, and Bheru here has a
bad back from lifting heavy boxes.
I'm thinking I slipped a disk.
- Bring it on, we haven't even hit 200.
- Are you serious?
Yeah, give me your card and
PIN. I'll save you a trip to the ATM.
It's not over till
it's over, Frank.
A fool and his money
are soon parted, Morris!
Labs are back.
Vitals are stable.
Yeah, everything looks good.
No serious injuries, Lowell.
Mommy was taking me
to a new place to live.
You know, your
mom's not doing well.
- She needs air.
- Yeah.
She's getting sicker.
Mommy comes every Thursday.
But she's too sick now.
Is my dad here?
I heard he's coming.
Which one is he?
I can find out and
I'll bring you to him.
No.
No, you don't you
wanna meet him?
He didn't want me
when I was a baby.
Well, you know, dads
can change their minds.
- Really?
- Really.
Yep.
My dad was kind
of like your dad.
Did he change his mind?
I like to think he did.
- Oh, hi, Abby.
- Hi.
- Sorry, do you mind? I have to...
- Yeah.
What are you doing?
Oh, you haven't heard?
We're doing a memorial
and blessing ceremony.
- Who's bringing the Kool-Aid?
- It's nothing scary.
Don't worry.
You should come, check it out.
I don't think so.
Oh, everyone could use
a blessing now and then.
Or a memorial.
Abby, do I piss you off?
- Excuse me?
- I was wondering.
No, you don't piss me off.
I don't know you, really, so...
If there was ever anything
you needed to talk about...
Why would I need that?
It's kind of why I'm here.
Okay.
You know, there's this story...
I know, I know, bear with me.
It's about this little boy
who asks his mother...
"Do you think I can pick
up that big rock over there?"
And she says, "Yes,
I'm certain you can lift it.
If you use all your strength."
So he goes over and
he tries to lift the rock.
He tries a bunch of times, until
finally he says, "I couldn't do it."
So she goes over there.
And together,
they lift the rock.
Wow, that's great.
And she explains to him...
that sometimes using all your
strength means asking for help.
The floor's under control.
We got no incoming traumas.
- Want us to round up the troops?
- Yeah, let's get while the getting's good.
- Sorry.
- Sorry, Neela.
No, it's my fault. My
mind is somewhere else.
Oh, me too.
I heard about
your father. Sorry.
Thanks. Yeah.
Just when I thought he was
out of the woods for a while.
Have you seen Abby today?
Something the matter?
She was just supposed
to be home a while ago.
She must've gotten caught
up with something here.
Yeah, maybe she got
caught up with some work.
The names of those who've
passed on while under our care.
We take time
from our busy day...
to pay respect to the
mothers and fathers...
husbands and wives,
sisters and brothers...
sons and daughters
who are no longer with us.
Think of one patient who's
changed you in some way.
Hold them in your memory.
Were they inspiring?
Funny?
Courageous?
Did they challenge you?
Teach you something
about yourself?
Were they searching
for something?
Was their heart
filled with love?
As you hold them in
your mind, ask yourself:
"Which of their qualities
can become part of my life?"
Sorry, multiple trauma rolling
in. I waited as long as I could.
- Another time. PRATT:
Gates, Morris, let's go.
Two ORs on standby.
- Page Dubenko.
Yeah, I got it. What is it?
Blunt trauma. Auto versus peds.
You said you'd be back an hour
ago. I didn't know where you were.
Well, here I am.
There's no way.
Anatomy is distorted.
- I thought her breathing was okay.
- It was.
Gonna grab the fiber-optic scope.
- I'll bag her.
Is there a problem? What
are you doing? Tell me.
- Joyce, wait outside.
- No, I need to be here.
Just give us a
few minutes, okay?
You said it was a scratch.
There's more
swelling in her throat.
So she can't breathe?
We're helping her.
Would you like to sit down?
- Sorry.
- Oh, God.
Oh, my God.
My baby.
My baby's hurt?
God. No. Oh, God.
You're Lowell's dad?
Yeah.
Have the balls to go in there.
I don't know what to tell you.
- What's going on?
- Nothing!
- If you don't wanna come to Croatia...
- No, that's not it.
- Then what?
I just have a lot to
deal with it. That's all.
Since I got back, you
haven't seemed happy.
You avoid me, hardly
touch. Do you think I'm blind?
- Don't be ridiculous.
- Am I?
Look, you were just gone
forever. It was a lot of stress.
- Taking care of Joe and supporting us.
- Supporting us?
Yeah, there were bills to
pay. All we had was my salary.
- So you're mad I wasn't working?
- No, that's not it, no.
It's just hard for me
to just turn it back on.
Turn what back on?
When did it turn off?
I know you. I know
when something's wrong.
- Do you still love me?
- Of course, I still love you.
- Why would you ask me that?
- Why do you think?
Just talk to me. Hey.
Look, I have to go and
finish my leave request.
And then we'll go to Croatia and
then everything will be different.
Okay?
You can't just hide
forever, you know. You can't.
- Hey, what...
- I'll see you at home.
- All I can see are arytenoid folds.
- Sats are way down.
- Let's do a surgical airway.
- She's too young to crike.
Formal trake? Prep the neck.
- Will take too long.
- Twenty minutes.
She doesn't have 20
minutes. Jet ventilation?
- Requires a regulator.
- Release valve.
By the time you get
that, she'll be traked.
- I can do it with a cannula.
- Get out of here.
- Will take me 30 seconds.
- Fine.
Lost the pulse. PEA.
I'm starting compressions.
Are you sure he
wants to meet me?
He was asking the same question.
Will...?
Will you come in with me?
That's not a problem.
Someone's here to see you.
Hello.
My name is Pierce.
My name is Lowell.
Lowell.
Lowell, I'm your father.
Nice to meet you.
Okay, Morris, steady the hub.
Nasal cannula at 15.
Okay, 10 blade. - Tip suction.
Okay, when I cover the open prong,
she's gonna get a blast of oxygen.
Hold CPR.
That's hot.
- One second on, four off.
- Where'd you learn this?
- Transport.
- Got a pulse.
- Gates needs a surgeon now.
- I got it.
- BP 110 over 60.
- Big epidural, he blew a pupil.
Heart rate's dropping.
- Atropine?
- Two amps.
- He needs the OR.
- He'll never make it to the OR.
- Seventy over 50.
Dopamine.
- Hey, what about a burr hole?
- We need a drill.
He got kicked in the head.
Can you show me bone windows?
- He's seizing.
- Four of Ativan.
- Looks like a circular skull fracture.
- Brilliant, prep for a cut down.
Sorry your thing
got interrupted.
Life in the ER, I guess.
We'll finish later.
Why did you tell
me that story before?
I like it.
I thought you might too.
Hey, Frank, did that fax
come in yet for Melissa Tanner?
Greg, thanks for taking care
of this thing with Skye for me.
Let Luka know we're
thinking about him.
- Okay.
- Fax is right here on the chart.
- That the DNR?
- Yup.
"No intubation, no CPR."
Is her husband comfortable
honoring her wishes?
Yeah. So I guess we extubate.
And she's gonna
die in a few hours.
Lowell needs to understand that.
It doesn't seem right.
Kid's never had a real family.
And on the same day that
they finally get together...
he's gonna lose his mom.
Makes me wanna call my folks.
You okay?
My mom died when I was a kid.
Breast cancer.
We were close.
And I lost her pretty early.
I don't know why I'm
even talking about this.
Must be that time
of year, you know?
I'll go talk to them.
Heart rate's down, 20.
Start pacing him. You
know he's gonna arrest soon.
Elevating the fragment. Suction.
- What the hell is all this?
- Draining an epidural bleed.
You did a burr hole?
We didn't have to. JARVIK:
Heart rate's 80, bounding pulse.
Mayday hits a
three-pointer at the buzzer.
You people are crazy.
I'm gonna go and help
Dubenko with the trake.
I'll be right back.
Heard you were a
seasoned pro out there today.
You'd think that.
I hit somebody.
How is that? How are you?
Yeah, I've had worse.
- Harold, what's next?
- Chuny, I got this.
A vertical incision
through the third and fourth.
- You bitch!
- Remember the girl you're worried about?
- We're trying to save her now.
- Yeah, plenty of doctors.
- You messed me up. DUBENKO:
This is a sterile procedure.
- I need you to step back!
- Hey!
Let go! Get off me!
- Hey, let go of me!
- Stay down!
- Stay there! Don't move!
- Get off me!
Get off me!
Not so tough now, are you?
Lowell, a long time ago...
your mom decided she didn't
wanna be put on a breathing machine.
- She wants to die?
- Not exactly, no.
And son, living
on the machine...
she wouldn't...
She wouldn't be able to
do things that she loved.
She wouldn't be
able to visit you.
And she'd be stuck in a bed,
unable to walk or talk or eat.
She'd just get
sicker and sicker.
Mommy?
Are you sure you
don't want the machine?
She doesn't want it.
That means in a little while,
we're gonna pull out that tube.
Okay.
And she'll probably die
not too long after that.
Could she get better?
I don't think so, Lowell.
But she might.
Well...
Lowell, we'll pray for that.
We'll pray for that.
Mommy, you don't
have to die today.
And we're gonna
go on the airplane.
Can you say airplane, huh?
- Hey.
And the propeller.
Yeah. Put it here.
Where's Niko?
He went to buy a
present for his wife.
And are we ready to fly now?
Ready to fly.
We're gonna fly.
Where are we gonna
put Joe in the airplane?
On a window seat, huh?
Joe. Come.
Luka, I need help.
I started drinking again.
When?
The night Joe got hurt.
And I...
I can't stop.
I thought when I came back...
we just needed to get
used to being married again.
But then things didn't
get better and I thought...
- So, what do we do?
- I need to fix it.
I need to go somewhere.
A facility with
professionals and get better.
And I need to believe it this
time, and I need you to believe it.
And I need you to help me.
So...
So take Joe...
go to Croatia for your
father while I do that.
- You want us to go without you?
- Yeah.
- You're his mother.
- I know that.
I know that.
But I haven't been
a very good one.
And I honestly don't think I
can be until I deal with this.
Can't we do this together?
This is how we do it together.
You have to help me do it alone.
That's it?
Is there anything else?
What do you mean?
That you wanna tell me?
You know, I just...
I was out of control.
I got out of control and I...
I did some things.
What kind of things?
Things I'm ashamed of.
Okay, just tell me everything.
Luka.
And after all this, after
everything, you don't wanna tell me?
Not tonight.
- It's my fault, isn't it?
- No, don't, please don't.
I should've come home earlier.
- I shouldn't have left.
- No, I should've been able to handle this.
- I broke my promise.
- Don't do that, okay?
Don't. I screwed up.
I screwed up because I
couldn't keep it together.
- This is my fault.
- I'm so sorry.
And please don't.
Don't. Just don't.
I'm sorry.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Neurosurgery finished with
the driver from your MVC.
- He's waking up.
- Oh, that's good to know.
Nice move in there. You okay?
Oh, yeah, I'm fine.
I did a little cage fighting
back in medical school, so.
It showed, good thing Harold
was there to save your ass.
Is that what happened?
Come on, Harold.
Seriously, thank you.
And I don't care what
anybody says, Gates.
- I think you're a half-decent guy.
- Sam, is that a new patient?
- No.
- Damn.
With 15 minutes to go,
the patient count is 263.
I need another two nurses here.
Food poisoning at
the Christmas potluck.
Hallelujah!
And now take a deep breath in.
And blow it out.
Good. Good.
Well, that's good.
Hi, Mommy.
Hi, baby.
I love you.
I love you too.
I couldn't forget him.
I never knew how to tell you.
Don't worry about anything now.
He's our son.
I'll take care of him.
Ha...
Ladies and gentlemen.
The official census
for the past 24 hours...
stands at 299.
Triage is empty.
Which means, we will
each be $100 richer...
in 10, nine, eight...
seven, six, five...
four, three, two...
Ah! Son of a bitch!
Lily, make a chart for Frank!
You have a serious
gambling problem.
Three-view hand x-ray,
ibuprofen and an ice pack.
Three hundred!
Yes, yes, yes, it's me!
Julia's ready, we
moved to Trauma 2.
Water is the source of all life.
It's used in healing
rituals all over the world...
in almost every faith.
Water is an element of
cleansing and purification.
Today, we use sterile saline.
It's what we work with.
And water doesn't get
much cleaner than that.
Earlier, we talked about
what our patients do for us.
How they affect us.
Stay with us.
Now we'll honor
what we do for them.
And pay thanks for the
abilities we've been given...
hoping that we may continue to
use them to serve our community.
So let's each dip our
hands in the water.
May we all have the strength,
dexterity and sensitivity...
to carry out the
mission of healing.
And may our hands be blessed.
We have our dead.
And we have let them go.
Now, let's turn our attention
back to the work of the living.