Previously on "ER.."
We'd be better
off as friends.
Mark, thanks again
for dinner last night.
God forbid you should listen
to me and learn something!
‐ Yes, I was engaged once.
‐ Hmm.
To a really lovely man
and he was killed in a..
...freak horseback
riding accident.
Shh, shh, shh.
'You know you bring a child
into this world'
and you think that
they're helpless
but actually,
I think it's us.
I think we're the ones
that are helpless.
'Hey, Carol, what time's
that big do at your mom's?'
'Right after church.'
I promised her
we'd be there
for Christmas caroling
with Uncle Ted.
That the old guy
with the banjo?
It's a family tradition.
You know, kind of like
going to mass on Christmas Eve.
Nah, I told you, if I go,
I feel like a hypocrite.
All that kneeling
and standing‐‐
‐ You could just sit there.
‐ Yeah, yeah.
Everybody looks
at me with the dirty looks.
Like I'm a pagan.
You are a pagan.
Oh, what a glorious day.
Did you see the sky?
Oh, yeah,
it's like a painting.
Makes you glad
to be alive.
Unless you're being persecuted.
Persecuted?
He's upset about Dr. Lee's
new charting system.
What new charting system?
Each patient
gets two charts.
One for the doc,
one for the nurse.
That way we get to do our notes
the same time you guys do.
Orders get in quicker,
patients get meds faster.
Oh. Docs don't waste time
chasing down charts.
So what's the problem?
The problem is
that someone
has to keep track of twice
as many charts as normal
thereby doubling his workload,
not that anyone cares.
Good morning, gang.
‐ Oh, my God.
‐ Oh.
Amanda, what have you done?
Assorted Christmas nibblies..
...some dried fruit, mixed nuts,
some little chocolate reindeer.
‐ Oh, don't mind if I do.
‐ Oh, oh.
Just wait.
First dibs go to Jerry.
I think it's only fair,
since he's the one
bearing the brunt
of the new charting system.
No. No, thank you.
I'm not hungry.
Oh? Well, as you wish.
But seriously, Jerry
if you find yourself
in the weeds, call me.
I'll make sure you get
the support you need.
‐ Alright?
‐ Sure.
Excuse me.
That's a Christmas
card image.
‐ Hey.
‐ Surgeon wrapping a book.
What is it,
something educational
for one of your nieces?
No, actually, it's for you.
It's T. S. Eliot.
You know, you said
you liked him, so I, uh..
...got it last month
when we were still, you know..
Peter, that's so sweet.
Yeah.
Um, I can't think
of a more thoughtful gift.
Thank you.
Oh, please. Forget it.
Listen, um,
I was wondering
if we could, uh, finish
our work‐ups around noon.
'I, uh, I need to get out
of here early tonight.'
Have you got big
Christmas Eve plans?
Yeah. My sister's
hosting a dinner.
Carla's gonna bring Reese by.
I haven't seen him all week.
Oh, don't worry.
I understand.
I absolutely hate being
away from my family
during the holidays.
In fact, I'm so desperate
not to be alone
this Christmas Eve
that I...I bought a ticket to
the surgeon society gala.
Oh, golly.
Yep. And you won't believe
who's sitting next to me.
Hey! There she is.
So I checked around.
We definitely have
the coolest table
and, uh, it's
really kinda lucky
that we were both able
to make it tonight, huh?
A little trouble
in paradise, huh?
Anyway, so, um, tonight's
dinner is semiformal
so any slinky
black number will do
although, if I may voice
a personal preference
something short and off
the shoulder would be ideal.
Peter, by the way,
that reminds me.
I have about a week's worth
of charts to review
and I'm really trying
to get outta here early
so I need you to cover
my teaching rounds.
Whoa, whoa. That's gonna
mess up my morning.
Well, look at it this way,
I get to have a life
and you get to earn
a special place in my heart.
Jerry, do you know
a garage that's open?
My piece of crap car
died on the Dan Ryan.
On Christmas Eve?
Good luck.
Lydia, is that, uh..
Christmas card from Jen.
My ex‐wife sent you
a Christmas card?
‐ No, she sent one to me.
‐ You?
Yeah, Jen and I have exchanged
cards for years.
Christmas, birthdays.
I was just reading
the newsletter.
Merry Christmas from the Simons.
What?
That new house they bought
sounds amazing.
I know.
5,000 square feet.
Six bedrooms, three baths.
Yeah, sounds just like Jen
to be bragging about her house.
Yeah. I wouldn't call it
bragging exactly.
More like
sharing good news.
Yeah, Jen made partner.
Partner? Jen made partner?
The firm even
bought her a new Beemer.
I love those convertibles.
Oh, you know what?
Mack's Garage on Wacker is open.
They'll tow your
piece of crap car.
Thanks, Jerry.
"Dear Dr. Carter, I'm sure
you don't remember me
"but I wouldn't be around this
Christmas if it weren't for you.
"You're a lifesaver,
the Lord's instrument on Earth."
Pacer pads?
Third drawer on the left.
"May God bless you and keep you.
Merry Christmas,
Emily Ropella."
Do you remember her?
Not a clue.
That's a nice card though.
Does it bother you that the Lord
gets all the credit?
One can be called worse things
than an instrument of God.
So you believe in..
I give him the
benefit of the doubt.
‐ You?
‐ I don't know.
Sometimes I can't help
but think
that God is just
this comforting illusion.
We all want everything
to mean something
so we create this all‐knowing
puppet master in the sky
when really everything
is just arbitrary
in life, death,
natural disasters..
Oh!
Ow.
The master is displeased.
I'm so sorry, Peter. I can't
believe he foisted this on you.
Ah, there's no use
in worrying about it now.
Well, look,
I'll start on the pre‐ops.
That should save
you some time I guess.
Whatever.
Hello, Mr. Gardner.
I have the results
of your MRI.
Great. So how's it look?
Good news.
It appears the cancer
hasn't spread
beyond the capsule.
Great. So, uh, does this mean
I can hold onto my prostate?
Well, I'm afraid not.
Dr. Romano does
want to continue
with the radical
prostatectomy
tomorrow morning
as scheduled.
But with the surgery
you stand an
excellent chance
of beating the cancer.
It really is
very good news.
Is, uh...is Dr. Romano around?
He's in surgery.
Is it something
I can help you with?
Well, he had mentioned
uh, that the operation
could result in
my losing sexual function.
I take it that's
still the case.
Well, we'll try our best to do
a nerve‐sparing procedure
but there is that
possibility, yes.
How strong a possibility?
Well, according to
Dr. Romano's notes
as high as 75% to 80%.
80%.
Has Dr. Romano
discussed your options
about having children
in the future?
Uh, no.
Well, you might
want to consider
paying a visit
to a sperm bank.
That way, if there
is a loss of function
you'll still be able
to father children
through alternative means.
Right.
Dr. Lee.
‐ You startled me.
‐ Uh, sorry.
Dr. Anspaugh would like
you to call him.
Is there something wrong
with Dr. Greene's locker?
Well, I found it ajar,
so I thought I'd better shut it
before something walked away.
'Thanks for the message.'
Sure.
I've got super ventricular
tachycardia.
It happens all the time.
Rate's 160. BP's 100 palp.
Just cardiovert me at 50
and I'm on my way.
Alright, let's put him
on a monitor
and get a strip.
I'm...trying to tell you
I got SVTs.
Uh, just cardiovert me at 50.
It works every time.
Okay, I appreciate
the tip
but I need
to examine you myself.
I'm just trying
to save some time here.
Uh‐huh. You stop talking.
Would you tell him
that I have SVTs?
I've got SVTs!
‐ Ah, let go.
‐ I got SVTs.
I heard you!
I need to examine you myself.
I'm going to be
late for work.
Let go.
Are you, uh, one of
Santa's helpers?
Argh. The helpers just
pass out the goody bags.
I'm an elf, a singing elf.
‐ You're part of a choir?
‐ There's four of us.
But thanks to
super doc here
it looks like the elf tones
are going to be a tenor short.
‐ Here you go, Dr. Greene.
‐ Says I've got SVTs, right?
I knew it!
You want to shock me
at 50 now, smart ass?
Got an 18‐year‐old kid
flatline.
Alright.
How long down?
Unknown. Mother
found him in his room.
We've been working
on him for 15.
Gave him two rounds epi,
two of atropine.
Any signs of life?
Got him back once,
then we lost him again.
Alright. Let's get him
on a monitor.
Carter, you might
check ventilation.
‐ What can I do?
‐ Rectal temp.
Great.
Alright, on my count.
Watch your hand, there.
One, two, three, go.
Alright, any signs
of drugs, suicide?
No. He told his mom
he had a killer headache
went for a nap,
never woke up.
Sounds like
a subarachnoid hemorrhage.
Killer headache
is right.
Monitor's up.
‐ No femoral pulse.
‐ Asystole.
No spontaneous
respirations.
No response to pain.
Anybody got any good news?
Pupils are..
...fixed and dilated.
No corneal reflex.
He's only 18.
Alright. Well, Zadro
got him back once.
Maybe we can do it again.
Start with a high dose epi
put him on a pulse ox
an end title CO2 detector.
‐ Paddles, please.
‐ Alright, crank it to 50.
‐ Let's go.
‐ Let's start at 20.
20? Why?
Why? Because I said so,
that's why.
Oh, that's mature.
Charged to 20. Clear.
‐ How'd we do?
‐ No change.
Uh, 50.
Do I hear 50?
Okay, let's go to 30.
Oh, for crying out loud.
Mark, why not
just go to 50?
Because he has
a sensitive rhythm
I don't wanna
overshock him.
‐ Alright, charged to 30.
‐ Clear.
‐ Anything?
‐ Nothing.
Uh, you know,
I don't want to question
your medical genius, doc,
but can we go to 50
while I've still got
some hair on my chest?
‐ Let's go to 50.
‐ It's about time.
‐ Charged.
‐ Clear.
That did it.
Back to normal sinus.
Watch him for 15
and then let him go.
Thanks for nothing,
Dr. Mengele!
Time?
12 minutes.
Alright, let's
check his rhythm.
Still no pulse.
Asystole.
‐ Keep at it.
‐ Ten of epi on board.
Dr. Ross, the boy's
mother is out in chairs.
She'd like to
talk to someone.
Alright. Carter,
you want to do that?
Don't get her hopes up.
Alright, give me another epi,
seven milligrams.
Mrs. Richards.
My son?
Hi, I'm Doctor Carter.
Your son's heart
stopped beating
and we are doing everything that
we can to get it started again.
We are giving him medicine,
and we are doing CPR.
Why would his heart stop?
He's 18‐years‐old.
There's a sign that he
had a brain hemorrhage
which could have caused
the cardiac arrest.
How?
He's the picture of health.
It could be
a weak artery.
Possibly something
that's been there since birth.
The thing is,
he's been down a long time..
...and the longer that
he goes without oxygen
the less likely it is
that we can
bring him back.
And you and I might need
to have conversation‐‐
Please, don't give up on him.
He's all that I have.
Please.
Okay.
I'll be back.
Alright, hold it,
hold the compression.
‐ Any sign of a rhythm?
‐ Flatline.
Alright. Let's call it.
Not yet. Keep bagging.
You got some reason
to keep flogging this kid?
Yeah, he's 18..
...he's his mother's only child,
and it's Christmas.
You're looking for a miracle?
He's been down for 40 minutes.
So what's five more?
Okay, doctor, let's go.
I'm resuming chest compressions.
Let's keep bagging.
Let's give another round
of high‐dose epi.
Start a dopamine drip wide open.
Get those paddles ready.
Paddles won't work,
he's in Asystole.
He could be in fine V‐fib.
Charge to 300.
‐ No, no, no. 360.
‐ 'Charging.'
Alright, everybody let's hold
a really, really
positive thought.
‐ Ready.
‐ Clear.
‐ Was that a beat?
‐ 'Oh, my God.'
A few agonal beats
does not a rhythm make.
Let's slap some pacer pads
on him right now.
Alright, here you go.
Can you roll him?
‐ Set it at 80.
‐ You're on.
It's not capturing.
Dial up the gain.
Come on, we just got
to get it to capture.
He's throwing PVCs.
No, hold that Lidocaine.
Maximum gain.
Come on. Come on.
‐ We got it.
‐ 'He's got a rhythm!'
'Take a carotid.'
‐ 'Pulse?'
‐ Strong at 120.
‐ BP is 100.
‐ Okay. Let's send him to CT.
Find out where this
bleeding is coming from.
‐ How did you do this?
‐ I am but an instrument‐‐
‐ Way to go, Carter.
‐ Yeah, nice save.
Hope he's got some brain left.
‐ Do you want contrast?
‐ No, but call respiratory.
Make sure they got
a vent in the scanner.
Well, it looks like
we got our miracle.
If he wakes up..
...even if he does, he'll
probably have brain damage.
Carter..
...you'd better
prepare the mother.
Yes, ma.
Of course we're coming.
Uncle Ted wants Doug
to play "Silent Night"
on the tambourine?
‐ I think he'd love it.
‐ Hmm.
Yeah.
Hey, do you have any,
uh, videotape
left in the video cam?
Yeah. Yes, I am coming to mass.
Nope, he's not.
But, um, you know what?
We should probably
respect his choice.
It would be lovely if we could
all go together, I know.
Jerry, if anybody needs me,
I'll be out at the roach coach.
Okay. I'll be here suffocating
under a mountain of charts.
That's odd. I could swear
I had my gloves in my pocket.
Dr. Lee took 'em.
What'd you say?
I saw her
at your locker earlier.
That is ridiculous,
Jerry.
What's ridiculous?
Jerry's accusing Amanda
of stealing my gloves.
I'm telling you,
she had your locker open
and she was
very suspicious.
Hey, Jerry, I know you're angry
at Amanda for
the new chart system
but to accuse her
of being a thief..
No, you didn't see
how weird she was acting.
Can it, Jerry.
Peter, I finished the work
on Landis. How are you doing?
Two more pre‐ops,
then on to post‐ops.
So you may make
your dinner after all.
‐ Yeah.
‐ Lizzie.
What'll it be..
...goose in chestnut sauce
or roast loin of venison?
We gotta call in
our entrees.
Dr. Romano, Mr. Demisa's
coming back in
with postoperative pain.
Demisa?
Oh, what a pain in the ass.
Oh, Peter, you,
uh, you assisted
on his gastroplasty,
didn't you?
‐ What? Uh, yeah.
‐ Great.
When he comes in,
you take him.
Uh, Dr. Romano, I'm already
piled up with work here.
I'm trying to make it home
to my family for dinner.
What can I say, Peter?
Sometimes being
a resident just sucks.
So what'll it be?
Mother Goose or Bambi?
Are these leads on?
The leads are on.
Nothing in the alpha, theta,
or delta frequencies.
He's brain‐dead.
Well, maybe he can be
an organ donor.
Not too likely.
He has type AB blood
and that's what,
two percent of the population?
I doubt you're gonna find
many compatible candidates.
It's worth a try.
Sure, it is.
Talk to the mother.
If she won't go for it,
see if you can persuade her
into pulling the plug.
So much for my miracle.
Dr. Corday, the fertility clinic
just called.
Your patient David Gardner
is having an MI.
His EKG was normal
this morning.
Um, is he upstairs?
They're taking him
to the ER.
Uh, okay.
Hey, I just took
an unusual complaint.
An elf with an attitude
claims you tried
to torture him
with the cardio version
paddles?
Uh, we differed
over treatment strategies.
I wouldn't quite
call it torture.
I know. I read the chart.
He's clearly a nutcase.
I just want to make sure
you were alright.
I'm okay.
Although, to be perfectly honest
I could have
handled it better.
I'm a little off
my game today.
Blame it on the holidays.
Is it a rough time
of the year for you?
Not usually.
My ex‐wife,
she sent out this newsletter
saying how happy she is.
I can't help but seeing it
as her way of saying
"Hey, look how well
I traded up."
‐ I got it.
‐ Thanks.
Yes, it's a tough
time of year for me too.
Really?
This is the first Christmas
since my brother
committed suicide.
Oh, geez.
I‐I‐I'm sorry.
Yeah.
It was one of those
apocalyptic cult things
you know, the guys
with the sneakers?
Oh, yeah.
I thought that was
a couple of years ago.
Well, he missed the big event
so he decided
to follow on his own.
Wow. I'm sorry, I..
...I got to say, you're handling
it better than I would've.
Well, I credit that
to my Grandma Lee.
She always said,
"Whatever life throws at you
"you have to greet it
with a smile.
"there's nothing
as contagious
"as a positive attitude."
You know, I think
we'd all be better off
if we followed
grandma's advice.
‐ Here we go.
‐ Coming through.
Okay, let's take him
into trauma one.
Mr. Gardner.
Mr. Gardner, how are you?
My chest feels tight.
I can't breathe.
Is this.. Is this
your patient?
Yep. And he's hyperventilating
like crazy.
Okay, hook him up to a 12‐lead
EKG. And a pulse ox.
Start a line.
Let's get a mask on him.
We need to get your breathing
under control
so concentrate
on the breaths.
Okay. Let the breath
out slowly.
Slowly.
Monitor's up.
Alright, yep,
pulse is up to 99.
That's a good sign.
You're gonna be fine.
Breathe in on
the count of five.
One, two..
Oh, my..
You‐you're David..
You're David Gardner, right?
That‐that trumpet soloist?
'I saw your guest performance
with the Chicago Symphony.'
Oh, I'm sorry.
I‐I'm Kerry Weaver.
Season ticketholder.
‐ 'Oh.'
‐ 'Breathe out.'
I just loved your
featured performance
in "Mahler Two."
It‐it‐it gave me shivers.
'Slowly..'
'Uh, where‐where do you
go next?'
B‐Boston.
‐ Ah, the BSO. Yes.
‐ Breathe in.
‐ I got the 12 leads.
‐ Breathe out.
'David, your heart
looks just...fine.'
Okay, we'll run a few tests
just to make sure
but I think that you were just
having an anxiety attack.
Are you a little nervous
about playing for Ozawa?
‐ Huh.
‐ Breathe in.
So how long
have you had the pain?
Ever since the surgery.
Uh, wish I'd never had it.
They told me that stapling
my stomach would help me reduce?
But I haven't lost a pound yet.
So, have you been sticking
to the all‐liquid diet?
Yes.
What'd you have today?
A little blended tea.
What was in it?
Bacon and eggs.
Mr. Demisa..
But I blended it up!
What else did you have?
A smoothie.
And what was in that?
Low‐fat milk..
...some butternut squash
'sweet potato pancakes,
a honey‐glazed ham'
and a caramel‐orange
buche de Noel.
That's a full
Christmas dinner.
Oh, also,
I'm a little backed up.
W‐what do you mean
a little backed up?
Um, constipated.
Okay.
He probably busted a staple.
Set him up for
a Gastrografin X‐ray
and give him a laxative.
Ooh! I like
the chocolate ones.
If that's alright.
Dr. Carter,
I was talking to Steven..
...and he moved his arm.
He's having
involuntary muscle spasms.
I think he was trying
to tell me something.
Mrs. Richards, I'm afraid
that's not possible.
'We did a test
on Steven'
to, uh, check
for brain activity.
We didn't find any.
Well, then..
...it'll take some time, and..
Time isn't going to help.
Steven is brain‐dead
with no possibility
of recovery.
I know this is
a really difficult thing
to think about right now..
...but one way to salvage
something positive out of this
is to donate Steven 's organs.
No, I.. I can't let you
take out his organs
when his heart
is still beating.
Mrs. Richards,
if that's the case
I'd ask you to consider signing
a do not resuscitate order.
That way, if
Steven's heart fails again
we won't subject him
to overly aggressive procedures.
'By prolonging his life
in a vegetative state.'
I can hope for
a miracle, can't I?
Well, who do we have here?
Uh, Mrs. Hutton fainted
while shopping at Lakewood Mall.
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that,
but don't you worry.
We're gonna have you
back on your feet in a jiff.
Alright.
Have you been
hitting the nitrous?
Come on, Lydia.
You got to greet life
with a smile.
I do?
Yeah. A positive attitude
is contagious.
So, Mrs. Hutton, why don't you
tell me what happened?
I went to Field's
Night Before Christmas sale.
It was crowded, it was hot,
it was stuffy. I passed out!
‐ Very nicely put.
‐ Thanks.
Why don't we order Mrs. Hutton
some cardiac enzymes,
CBC, and a chem seven?
Hold it!
How much do those things cost?
Gosh, I don't know.
You won't tell me?
No, I mean I‐I really
don't know. Please sit up.
‐ Oh, I got your number now.
‐ Excuse me?
You think you're pretty smart,
don't you, doctor?
Sweet‐talking me into buying
all those expensive tests
I don't need.
Okay. Ahem, I'm just trying
to make a diagnosis.
Well, I'm trying to survive
on social security.
'We can't all make
a doctor's salary.'
I'm sure your insurance company
will pay for the tests.
Oh, so that's your racket.
'Ripping off
insurance companies.'
'It's crooks like you that
keep my premiums so high!'
Give me another doctor!
Um, Dr. Greene's the best
doctor we have, ma'am.
'Well, I don't like
the look of him.'
The way he smiles,
the way he talks.
I want another doctor!
Any doctor,
as long as it isn't him!
Mr. Gardner,
your labs look stunning.
We should probably wait
on the cardiac enzymes
before letting you go.
Well, at this rate
I might as well
check in for the night, huh?
Well, it would certainly
save you the drive in
for surgery tomorrow.
No. No, the less time
I spend here, the better.
No offense.
None taken.
So how you feeling?
Oh, like an idiot.
Here I thought I was having
this big heart attack.
Turns out I 'm just
a nervous wreck.
You know, if you wanted to,
you could postpone surgery.
No. I have to be
recovered by January 15th.
I'm doing a televised special
with the Boston Symphony.
‐ 'Dr. Corday?'
‐ Well..
I'll have to mark my calendar.
Symphony fan?
I know very little
about orchestral music.
So what do you like?
‐ Well..
‐ Thank you.
I'm..
I'm embarrassed to say.
How bad can it be?
I'm in a disco
phase at the moment.
Yes, well..
I can see why
you would be embarrassed.
‐ You paged me?
‐ We've got a problem.
‐ He's stuck.
‐ Stuck?
He's wedged in so tight
I can't get him out.
Alright, so, what do you
expect me to do?
Could you help me
get him out?
Uh‐huh. I don't have
time for that.
Just call maintenance.
Have them take the chair apart.
‐ Uh‐oh.
‐ What now?
I have to go to the bathroom.
Uh, you're gonna
have to hold it, sir.
‐ Help!
‐ Help me get him out, please?
‐ Please?
‐ Alright. O‐okay, okay.
Come on.
Come on, grab his arms.
Oh!
Alright, on my count.
One, two, three.
What a waste.
Why did I do it?
Oh, why did I do it?
I know.. I know better.
You were trying
to save a kid's life.
I let that instrument of
God stuff go to my head.
Maybe it is all arbitrary.
I mean, what did this kid do
to deserve a brain hemorrhage
and why does it blow
on Christmas Eve?
What's the point?
Doug, I got the test back
on the teenager in one..
'Mm‐hmm, and?'
A little Christmas
present from the stork.
Alright. Well, I 'd better
go and give the good news.
‐ Oh, my God.
‐ Here.
Oh, Dr. Weaver.
Dr. Weaver, you
have to read this.
‐ Read what?
‐ XXX sex fantasy.
Excuse me?
I found it in one
of Dr. Lee's charts.
It's her handwriting.
"I took MG's
gloved hand and placed it
"on my heaving,
pink‐stippled breast."
Why am I reading this?
Don't you get it?
MG is Mark Greene.
Come on.
What about the glove reference?
Whose gloves are missing, huh?
Jerry, you have
completely lost your mind.
Oh! You found my notes
on Mrs. Condrell.
I've been looking up and down.
‐ Mrs. Condrell?
‐ That psych patient?
It's a sad case.
She's psychotic,
extremely hyper‐sexual
and she has these
obsessive fantasies
about Merv Griffin,
of all people.
Anyway, thank you.
Jerry, next time you wanna
make an ass out of yourself
leave me out of it, okay?
Could there be a mistake?
No, there's no mistake, Laura.
You're pregnant.
Oh, God.
Now what do I do?
Well, is there anyone you
can talk to, your mother?
No way. She'll kill me.
What about your dad?
‐ No.
‐ Thanks.
I had to sneak out
even to come here.
Mm‐hmm.
Are you gonna tell them?
Not if you don't want me to.
I don't.
Well, you have some choices.
You can have the baby, keep it.
Have the baby,
give it up for adoption
or you can have an abortion.
I can't have a baby.
There's no way.
Can you help me?
Yes, I can. Be right back.
Stephanie, can I..
Thanks.
Hey, Carol?
We got a pregnant
13‐year‐old in there
who wants to have
an abortion on the holidays.
‐ God. 13.
‐ Mm‐hmm.
Think you can arrange it?
Merry Christmas. Yeah.
Yeah. Can you
take it from there?
Sure.
Carla, look. Uh, yeah,
I know his bedtime
is at 8 o'clock but
I'm getting slammed here.
I might not be able
to make it until then.
Yeah, I know. Listen,
listen, listen. Okay, okay.
It's Christmas Eve. I'm just
trying to see my son, alright?
Okay. Thank you so much.
Oh, yeah, I promise.
I will. Yeah. Bye.
‐ How's it going
‐ Don't ask.
Did you call the ER for Demisa?
Said he's still on the toilet.
Lizzie, if you're ready,
we can go together.
Um, look, I have a couple of
patients to finish with, okay?
Is Peter trying
to ruin our evening?
No, not at all.
‐ Um..
‐ It was a joke.
Look, I 'll see you there.
Peter, I wasn't able
to finish these dictations
so I left them for you,
they need to be in by 8:00.
Appreciate the help.
See you later.
16‐year‐old, unconscious
history of biliary atresia.
‐ Hepatic coma?
‐ Yeah. Looks like it.
She was doing fine
until six months ago.
What medication is she on?
Ampicillin, tobramycin,
vitamins A, D, and K.
Skin's jaundiced.
Same with sclera.
‐ Her breath smells sweet.
‐ Fetor hepaticus?
‐ Yep.
‐ What's that?
Liver has shut down.
Let's dip a urine.
It's getting
a little crowded in here.
Why don't you deal
with the parents, please?
Start lactulose, 30cc's per MG.
We'll give her some medicine
to clean her blood.
Why don't you come with me?
She's bleeding inside?
Her liver failure is
causing her blood not to clot.
Oh, God.
Is, uh, she on
the transplant list?
She's been status 2A
for six months
but we haven't been
able to find her a match.
Why not?
‐ What's her blood type?
‐ AB.
What are you doing?
Are you hiding back here?
Exactly.
I tried your grandmother's
greet them with a smile
approach on a patient
and she threw me out.
‐ No.
‐ Yep.
I've decided
to restrict myself
to the unconscious
for the rest of the day.
Now, now.
Tell you, there's
something about me
that just brings out
the worst in people.
I've noticed that.
I'm like a magnet
for negativity.
People get too close
I'll pull the positive
right out of 'em.
‐ Oh, my God.
‐ What?
I suddenly
feel depressed.
‐ Low blood sugar?
‐ No, it's definitely you.
Hey, shut the hell up.
‐ I'm trying to sleep here.
‐ Ooh.
Oh, another satisfied customer.
Two kids come in
on Christmas Eve
one ends up brain‐dead
the other needs a liver
and they both have AB blood.
Tell me that's not a godsend.
It's not. The mother
won't consent till‐‐
She will when I get
through with her.
Where's his mother?
She's not here.
‐ Is he throwing PVCs?
‐ Yeah.
Why didn't you call me?
Let's get the pacer pads on him.
‐ Can't. DNR.
‐ What?
His mother said you
talked her into it.
There goes your godsend.
Did she say where she was going?
Not to me.
If she comes back,
keep her here.
Laura, Dr. Sarafini
can take you.
What's wrong?
'I just keep thinking..'
...it's a mortal sin.
‐ Do you believe that?
‐ Doesn't matter what I believe.
What do you think?
I don't know.
Is there someone
in your family you can talk to?
‐ A sister maybe?
‐ No.
What about your mom?
She'll kill me.
Look, Laura, this isn't
gonna be easy.
But it is a very big decision.
And I don't think
you're sure of what to do.
I think you really need
to talk to someone.
Can you call my mom?
Yeah, I can.
I'll call her, I'll call her.
She's not back yet?
Nope. He just
went into V‐tach.
'Dammit!'
I got a thin pulse.
Give him another 50 of Lidocaine
and get the paddles ready.
I take full responsibility.
Yeah, and I'll lose my license.
What are you doing?
I'll code him myself
if I have to.
You can't code him
against his mother's wishes.
You wanted a miracle?
These two kids
arriving on the same day
is as close as it gets.
That's what you want to believe,
she may not see it that way.
I'm willing to bet she does.
You're only thinking
of yourself.
And a dying 16‐year‐old girl.
Charging at 200.
Move 'em.
Move 'em!
‐ Clear!
‐ You're both crazy.
Back in sinus.
Oh, now you did it.
Page me if he goes south.
I'm going to find his mother.
So which section
of the orchestra
are you going
out with now?
No, I've been unattached
since I started
the tour six months now.
That's a long time
to be on the road.
Yeah, it sure is.
Swarms of groupies
in every city.
Well, a classical soloist
doesn't quite lead
the life of a Rolling Stone.
But if I had known I was
gonna lose my prostate
I would've made more
of an effort, believe me.
Are you still anxious
about the surgery tomorrow?
I was never all that anxious
about the surgery, per se.
It was more the..
What?
You really want to know?
Yes.
Well, I..
I went up to your clinic
to deposit my..
...DNA..
...and, of course, they
directed me to the cubicle
where they'd set out the..
...the specimen jar and the..
...men's magazine..
...and I...and I
just kept thinking..
Well, this is it. This is
my...my last sexual experience.
And I..
Well, you know the rest.
Must be the first
time in history
that somebody's had
performance anxiety
while by himself.
David, would you like to grab
a bite to eat somewhere?
Yes, Elizabeth,
I'd like that very much.
Alright, Mr. Demisa.
We got your X‐rays back.
They're clear, so you are..
Mr. Demisa?
Mr. Demisa!
Takata, you seen
our 400 pound patient?
‐ Uh‐oh.
‐ What?
I'm missing five
patient dinners.
‐ Oh, dammit.
‐ Mr. Demisa?
Mr. Demisa?
'Mr. Demisa!'
‐ 'Over here.'
‐ What is it?
Cake crumbs.
Looks like German chocolate.
Mr. Demisa? Oh, dammit.
Mr. Demisa?
Alright, he's unconscious.
He vomited. There's at least
a half a gallon here.
Okay..
No bowel sounds,
abdomen's rigid.
He really did it this time.
‐ He blew a staple?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Need a gurney!
‐ Prep an OR!
Get an X‐ray and page Romano.
Tell him to get
his ass back here.
Mrs. Richards..
I'm sorry to bother you.
But an extraordinary
thing has happened.
A 16‐year‐old girl
with the exact same
rare blood type as Steven's
came into the ER
in liver failure.
Now, I can't help but to think
that if God meant
for Steven to die tonight
at Christmas..
...then it must be
so that this girl can live.
I'm sorry.
But I can't think about another
child's problems right now.
All I want is for my son
to die peacefully..
...and to be buried whole.
Excuse me.
Lots of free air
under the diaphragm.
Yeah. He's perfed his stomach.
‐ Still no Romano?
‐ I paged him five times.
‐ Alright, who's on call?
‐ 'Guthrie. Just started a AAA.'
BP's dropped to 80 palp.
We can't wait much longer.
He's got a fever.
Alright, give him
a gram of Cefotaxime
500 of Flagyl and hand me
a scalpel. Let's move.
You're starting
without an attending?
He's septic.
I don't have any choice.
We keep him on the table,
he's going to die.
'What the hell?'
Hey, Carol. Hey.
You see there's a priest
in there with that girl?
Uh‐huh.
Well, he's gonna pressure
her into having the kid.
Well, maybe he's
gonna counsel her too.
How'd he find out about it?
She asked me to call her mom.
‐ The mom brought the priest.
‐ Well..
‐ I wish you'd told me about it.
‐ Why?
Because I would've tried
to keep him out of there.
Are those baked beans?
Yeah.
And French fries.
‐ Huh.
‐ Phew, that's rank.
What's this?
Coleslaw.
Ah, here's a good one.
What is that? Mystery meat?
What the hell
do you think you're doing
operating on my patient?
Saving his life! You jerk.
Get me a gown and gloves, now!
Peter, get your hands
out of my patient.
Okay, give me
a little suction here.
Sucker's clogged.
Yeah, it's a cranberry.
Let's go, Shirley! Gloves!
Where the hell is she?
‐ Who?
‐ Who do you think?
What'd you do, give her extra
work to hang her up here?
I have no idea what
the hell you're talking about.
‐ Step away.
‐ Fine.
'Who gave you permission
to start without me?'
He was going into septic shock.
You are a resident, Peter.
You don't take a piss
without getting permission.
And where the hell's Lizzie,
off doing your scut?
She left an hour ago.
What the hell did you use to
make this incision, a chainsaw?
‐ He's been drinking.
‐ What?
He's drunk.
Go. Call Anspaugh. Now.
Retract the bowel.
Retract the bowel please.
Dr. Romano, have you
been drinking?
Are you questioning
my surgical fitness?
How many drinks have you had?
Go to hell.
Dr. Romano, I 'm going to have
to ask you to step back, please.
‐ Sponge.
‐ Dr. Romano!
Touch me again, Peter,
and I'll deck you.
‐ Give me the sponge.
‐ Look, you're drunk.
Alright, Shirley, get me
some clean gloves and a gown.
Coming right up.
Hey, who ordered
all this stuff?
‐ What is it?
‐ Uh, pizza, beer, brandy.
Whole bunch of spices.
Ah, the provisions have arrived.
How much do I owe the man?
$212 plus a tip.
What's goin' on?
Staff Christmas party.
I didn't know there was one.
There is now. My treat.
Alright.
You know what?
It's really crowded.
Can we maybe take this
stuff into the lounge?
Grouch.
Thanks, guys.
Remember to punch out
before boozing. Thanks.
What do you need
brandy and spices for?
Hot toddies.
The Sultan of Johor's favorite.
Ah, well, if it's
good enough for the sultan.
Yeah, make mine a double.
Jerry, where's my lab coat?
Uh, it was here a minute ago.
Now where'd it go?
You know what? I don't even
wanna hazard a guess.
That's a wise choice, Jerry.
I admit it. There's no
such thing as miracles.
You don't really believe that.
I don't know what I believe.
I was so sure that I was right.
That I had the big
kahuna on my side.
‐ That's pretty arrogant, huh?
‐ Very.
What's going on?
Apparently, Mrs. Richards
bumped into the Mikamis
in the hallway,
and they got to talking.
She consented to
the liver transplant.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Wait. Before you go
giving him too much credit
there's something
you oughta know.
What?
I introduced them.
What do you know?
You're an instrument of God.
Oh, please.
Sorry.
How sorry?
Well..
Huh..
Not sorry enough
to go to the mass tonight
if that's what you mean.
Hmm.
You know what I
don't understand is..
...how I can care
so much for an hot‐tempered..
...pig‐headed heathen.
I prefer pagan.
Heathen.
Just finishing up
my disciplinary report
recommending that your residency
be terminated for operating
without an attending.
You turn that in,
I'll be forced to defend myself.
Ah, good luck, Peter.
I mean, I'll have
to turn in these labs
showing that your blood
alcohol level was .12.
You shouldn't have
even been driving
let alone operating on someone.
Don't bluff me, Peter.
You didn't draw my blood.
Not from there.
Mark, look here. Gotcha.
Amanda, these hot
toddies are delicious.
‐ I want the recipe.
‐ 'Not a problem.'
Hey, Jerry, you want to try
one of Dr. Lee's hot toddies?
No, just give me a beer.
"Depart, O Christian soul,
out of this world.
"In the Name of God the Father
Almighty who created you.
"In the Name of Jesus Christ,
who redeemed you.
"In the Name of the Holy Spirit
who sanctifies you."
♪ Joyful and triumphant ♪
♪ O come ye ♪
♪ To Bethlehem ♪
♪ Come and behold Him ♪
♪ Born the King of Angels ♪
♪ O come
let us adore Him ♪
♪ O come let us
adore Him ♪
♪ O come
let us adore Him ♪
♪ Christ ♪
♪ The Lord ♪
♪ O sing
choirs of angels ♪
♪ Sing in exultation ♪
♪ O sing on
ye citizens ♪
♪ Of heaven above ♪
♪ Glory to God ♪
♪ In the Highest ♪
♪ O come
let us adore Him ♪
♪ O come let us
adore Him ♪
♪ O come
let us adore Him ♪
♪ Christ ♪
♪ The Lord ♪
Merry Christmas, Amanda.