Previously on
"Grey's Anatomy"...This dissection is
routine for me at this point.
I need to know what happened.
Dr. Schmitt started
the dissection
instead of waiting.
Time of death, 1:19.
Why aren't you in pre-op?
He has a low-grade fever.
- Dr. Grey, he's hypotensive!
- Jo, you're right.
I've been holding on to
a fairytale.
We don't have to get married
now. I just need her, right?
What happened?
The heart is a match for Farouk.
It's a beautiful
and healthy heart.
It's perfect.
How are you holding up?
If Farouk dies,
I go with him.
- She is not alright.
- What's happening, Owen?
Nobody bloody move.
Take the cooler. Save Farouk.
I gave Noah Young the drugs
that he needed to die,
and I promised him that
I would give the same drugs
to three
other dying soldiers.
Move, before
it takes us both!
♪♪
Is that it?
Yeah.
You're sure?
I've never been more sure
about anything in my life.
And Heather knows?
She does.
We made a plan, and I can
take better care of Danny
from the other side.
I feel good
about my life...
...and I feel good
about where I'm going.
I did my best, and...
I think
that's pretty damn good.
Yeah.
Hey, Dr. Hunt?
I don't want to abandon
the guys in my unit.
They need your help, too.
We...
We need your help.
Please.
♪♪
Here! I'm here!
The vagus nerve
is the longest and most complex
of the cranial nerves.
It transmits information
to or from the surface
of the brain
to tissues and organs
elsewhere in the body.
Wait! Stop! Stop!
Wait, wait!
♪♪
When a body sustains
an extended period
of stress or trauma,
the vagus nerve
becomes hyperactive.
We think of stress and trauma
as primarily emotional...
Why didn't you wait?
...but the real impact
is on the body.
That's not
the Webber Method!
When the vagus nerve
is triggered,
it fights to slow the heart.
♪♪
Blood pressure drops,
and you can experience nausea,
tunnel vision...
...ringing in the ears,
low blood pressure,
an irregular heartbeat.
And when the mind suffers,
the body suffers,
and it can be difficult
to undo the damage.
♪♪
There was an accident.
Yeah, I heard.
You okay?
I will be
as long as the heart is.
♪♪
Ndugu?
The heart's bruised.
It must have hit the side
of the cooler when the car --
Can you still use it?
♪♪
Page Dr. Pierce.
Please page Dr. Pierce
to OR 3.
♪♪
Owen.
Owen, can you hear me?
Hayes, I already
have the meds. Okay?!
Aah!
It's me. It's Amelia.
Link is here, too.
There you are.
You were in an accident.
Do you remember?
They gave you morphine on
the way here for the pain.
You're in trauma one.
I know your leg hurts, but can
you wiggle your toes?
Feel anything?
Good. Okay.
Can you feel this?
A little.
Good. That's good.
We are gonna get you scanned
and we're gonna get you into --
Amelia. Amelia.
Teddy. Farouk's heart?
Teddy's okay.
She's outside.
Farouk is in surgery.
They got the heart here in time.
Okay. Hayes?
I haven't seen him, but
I will see what I can find out.
Amelia.
Don't tell Megan
that I'm hurt, okay?
Owen --
Please.
Not until after
Farouk's alright. Please.
Teddy.
Do you need to sit down?
Is he...?
He's in a lot of pain,
which right now
is a good thing.
Preliminary assessment
shows extensive fractures
to the left leg.
His neuro exam?
He's conscious,
and he's following commands.
His motor and sensory exams
seem to be intact.
Will he walk again?
We'll know a lot more
after a scan.
Teddy, he's alive.
He's still here.
You can go in and see him.
Has anyone
checked you out yet?
I'm fine. I'm --
I-I just, um...
I just...
I think I need a minute.
I-I'm not sure I...
I just --
I-I need a minute.
You got it.
You should get
checked out, Teddy.
He got me
out of the car first,
and I went to call
for help and...
and then I-I heard
the car fall,
and I rode all the way here
with Farouk's heart in my hands,
and I --
I thought Owen was dead.
And it's just -- I feel like
my insides are like, lead,
or like, you know, like --
like ice, and I just --
I just need them to thaw
before I-I go --
before I go inside
and see him.
You've gone hard.
Your nervous system
is protecting you.
But he is alive.
And he needs to see you.
I know that.
♪♪
Hi, Teddy.
I thought you were gone.
Me too.
Can you come over here,
please?
Hey.
I'm still here.
I love you.
I know.
Dr. Radford to 2-6-2-2.
Hey.
I think we just do a pan scan
and cover all our bases.
I don't want to take a chance
of being blindsided in the OR.
Couldn't agree more.
No one likes being blindsided.
Link?
Dr. Goldberg to the ICU.
Link, are you alright?
Link, Owen means a lot to me,
to everyone,
so whatever is
going on with you --
I have work to do.
I'll, uh, meet you
in radiology.
This is not about
the Webber Method, Bailey!
It's about one surgeon --
one surgeon who overstepped.
If we canceled
a teaching method
every time a surgeon
made a mistake, there wou--
A preventable mistake.
It was preventable.
I am suspending
the Webber Method
immediately
and indefinitely.
You absolutely will not.
I won't accept it.
Now, you may be
the chief of this hospital,
but I'm the chief
of chiefs.
I will call
the medical board, Richard.
You want to pull rank on me?
I will report you!
Bailey!
There should have been
an attending
in that room!
I am done arguing!
Schmitt, stop wasting water.
Your hands are clean.
♪♪
I don't know.
I don't think so.
If we don't do this,
we have to put him back on ECMO,
with risks of him bleeding
or throwing a clot
causing a stroke, or worse.
I don't know if he could
survive long enough
to get another heart.
And if this heart fails
because it was bouncing
around a cooler,
he goes into
immediate cardiac arrest.
You called me here
for my opinion,
and I think you need to wait
for a new heart.
Okay, everyone.
Let's incise the right atrium.
Dr. Ndugu --
Dr. Pierce,
I know the risks,
but it is a miracle that Hunt
and Altman and Hayes are alive.
It's a miracle that this heart
is in front of us right now.
And it is a miracle that
we have the privilege
to see if it will beat inside
Farouk's chest, bruised or not.
So I'm gonna take the miracle
and trust my gut.
And I'm asking you to help me
do this quickly and well.
Okay.
Scalpel.
♪♪
What do you mean he lied?
He had a bowel obstruction
and he tried to hide
the pain from us
until it got so bad
he nearly perfed.
He was septic.
I almost lost him on the table.
What an idiot.
"Idiot" doesn't begin
to describe it.
"Megalomaniac" maybe.
Hey. You know what?
I've got a crazy idea.
Yeah?
There's a jet leaving
for Seattle,
a critical care transport.
I'm not -- I'm not working,
so I wasn't gonna go,
but now I'm thinking...
I don't know --
I hitch a ride
and take you out
to drown your sorrows.
Seriously? You hate this idea?
I love this idea.
Okay. In that case,
I gotta go.
Hey. Hayes,
what happened to your head?
There was, uh...
There was an accident.
What kind of accident?
My whole life...
My whole bloody life
flashed before my eyes.
I saw Abigail and...
my boys and...
It was just a lot.
It was a lot.
Have you been checked out?
I'm fine. I'm fine.
Well, I'll be the judge of that.
Let's go inside. Come on.
♪♪
Pupils look good.
Was there any
loss of consciousness?
No.
I'm alright, Grey.
Scale of one to ten,
how bad does your head hurt?
It doesn't hurt.
Just let me take
your blood pressure,
and then we can agree
that you're okay.
What's your opinion
on mercy killings?
Whoa.
You've gone dark.
No, I'm serious.
What is your opinion
on mercy killings?
And not on me.
I believe in
death with dignity,
if that's what
you're asking me.
No, I'm asking what
you would think of a doctor
who took that decision
into his own hands,
who killed a man,
a man who wanted to die,
a man who was gonna
die soon anyway.
I would say
first do no harm.
Yeah.
That's what I thought.
Something
you want to tell me?
Listen.
Altman and Hunt
were in that car with me.
Hunt was hurt.
How badly?
Bad enough he might need
a great general surgeon.
I came
as soon as I heard.
What are
we looking at?
L1 burst fracture.
We'll need to go in
and remove any bone fragments
before stabilizing it
with a cage.
Open femoral fracture
needs a wash-out,
and we'll use a nail
to fixate it.
Left leg also has
a tibial plateau fracture.
We'll have to wait a few days
for the swelling to go down
before repairing it.
Is that a splenic lac?
Yeah,
looks like a Grade One.
Let's monitor it
with labs.
Yeah, the leg's
in much worse shape.
You think he'll be able
to walk again?
The sooner we get in,
the sooner we'll know.
Shepherd?
There is some retropulsion
into the spinal canal.
But he's got some movement and
feeling, which is a good sign,
but we'll have to get in quick,
and we'll need to be perfect.
Perfect
or he's paralyzed?
Yeah.
Okay. Whatever OR
you need, it's yours.
What about Schmitt?
What about him?
He's the best resident.
Can we have him?
Schmitt's unavailable.
Do you want me?You want to be
our resident?
Well, I'm just saying,
if you need hands.
Mer, we got him,
but if that changes,
you'll be our first call.
Okay.
Our patient is awake.
I have to go yell at him.
I'm here
if you need me, okay?
Total room disinfection
in process.
You're supposed to be
writing an operative report.
Hey, I don't know what you think
you're scrubbing in on,
but don't.
You're in no condition.
Total room disinfection
in process.
Look, a surgeon
who's never lost a patient
hasn't done enough surgeries.
It happens,
even to the best of us.
Take a break, Schmitt.
Take a walk,
feel your feelings...
and then write that report.
I'll start on
your burst fracture,
and then Link and Nico
will start in
on your femoral fracture.
The other way around.
Femoral fracture first,
then spine.
We always start
with the spine.
Yes, when the spinal fracture's
more unstable
with motor and sensory deficits.
In this instance, the leg is
shattered with an open wound
and he has decreased
PT and DP pulses,
so it takes priority
if he wants to keep it.
We could
actually compromise here.
We position Hunt on his side,
we both go in laterally --
you in through
the lumbar spine,
and I'll go in through
the side of the femur.
We do the repairs
simultaneously.
Owen, the risks here are
you lose your leg
or you lose the ability
to use your legs.
I really think
that we want to --
- Where's Hayes?
- Hayes?
Yeah.
I need to see him.
We need to get you into the OR
as soon as possible.
Owen, listen. You can talk
to Hayes after your surgery.
No, no. No. No. I need to talk
to Hayes, and it can't wait.
I will see if he can
meet you in pre-op.
Okay.
And we will go in
simultaneously.
♪♪
Okay?
Ndugu.
We know anything yet?
I'd like to give his mother
an update.There's no way to know
just yet.
We still have a couple
more vessels to anastomose.
But for what it's worth...
I have a good feeling.
♪♪
Dr. Sellers.
Dr. Mari Sellers. 4-6-1-9.
My God. Look at you.
Could have been much worse.
Yeah.
Could have been me.
Thank you, Hunt.
I don't know
what else to say.
Thank you.
You could thank me by
forgetting what I told you.
If I do that...
then I'm an accessory
to a crime.
Hayes, Noah was dying.
You know that.
He qualified for
physician assisted death.
Then why do you want me
to forget about it?
'Cause his friends
don't come from states
that allow
death with dignity.
I made him a promise,
and he made them a promise.
So you stole drugs and plan
to pass them out like candy?
I plan to show
those soldiers
the respect
that our country hasn't.
I plan to keep my promise
to those men, okay?
You saved my life, and I need
to spend what's left of it
looking after my boys.
I can't go to prison.
That's not gonna happen.
You stole life-ending drugs
that you plan to dispense
to men who do not qualify.
Come forward,
tell Bailey what you've done,
what you plan to do next.
The longer you hold
this secret inside,
the worse it's gonna get.
Tell the truth
so I don't have to.
I fell off of a cliff
so you didn't have to.
If not prison,
I'd almost certainly
lose my license
to practice medicine
for knowing about this
and failing to report it.
Hayes, come on.
Hunt, I'm grateful to you
for getting me out of that car,
but I can't make you
any promises.
I need to
think this through.
Hey. Farouk's heart?
We don't know yet.
Okay. Thank you.
♪♪
Hey.
I'm sorry.
No.
No, I'm not sorry?
I'm not interested
in your apology.
I'm honestly not
super into it, either.
Dr. Bartley worked two years
on this protocol,
and you nearly ruined it.
S-Stupid.
Way worse than stupid.
David, you were septic.
You almost died.
We don't have another patient
with Parkinson's
who will volunteer to let us
experiment on his brain,
and even if we did,
the FDA only approved you.
You're it.
Our time is
a non-renewable resource.
I have children
here in Seattle
that I am missing days with
that I will not get back.
So if you pull a stunt
like this again, I will quit,
and if I quit,
the FDA will kill this project.
And then I will have wasted
two years of Dr. Bartley's time.
We'll get over it,
but you won't,
because you will die
with Parkinson's.
Understood?
Understood.
♪♪
Yeah.
I'm walking out, too.
But only 'cause
I need more coffee.
♪♪
Hey. Bailey told me
what happened.
She thought you might
still be in here,
so she sent me
to take you home.
Levi, it's the worst,
and we've all been there.
Levi, your hands!
Levi. Okay.
You need to stop --
Levi!
Megan.
I wanted to give you an update.
Your mother said you were here.
I came here to pray,
and I don't pray.
But I came here to pray because
no one will tell me anything.
No one's told me anything
for hours.
I haven't seen Teddy.
I haven't seen Owen.
I haven't seen you.
No one will give me
an update.
How bad is it?
Megan,
I need to know your plan.
What plan?
I need to know your plan
for how not to kill yourself.
Maybe it's medication.
Maybe it's inpatient treatment.
Maybe it's just
talking to your family,
letting them know how you feel
and then letting them take over.
Whatever it is, I need to know
your plan for living.
My wife died a few years back.
Did you know that?
No.
I tried to move on.
I couldn't.
I blamed it
on my son's panic attacks,
but the truth is...
I'm not over Abigail.
I don't know
if I'll ever get over her.
I desperately don't want
to leave my boys,
but I'm desperate
to see Abigail again.
What I'm saying is,
I know how it feels
to want to live
and not want to live.
I know the depth
of that grief.
I know the impulse
to want to leave the planet.
But if I'm gonna
give you more bad news,
I need to know that I'm not
handing you a bottle of pills...
that I'm not
taking you out.
I took a sedative.
That helped.
You can watch me
call my therapist.
And I'll e-mail my psychiatrist
and CC you.
Just please --
If you'll please just tell me.
Tell me everything.
There was an accident.
Car went off the road.
The heart was bruised.
Ndugu thinks
it's still functional,
so they're working on Farouk
right now.
Owen was injured.
His injuries are not
life-threatening,
but his leg was shattered.
He is also in surgery.
Wow.
When it rains, it pours, huh?
Yeah.
♪♪
Alright.
Let's make that call.
Have you got your phone?
Yeah.
♪♪
Hey.
How's it going?
Ahh.
I can't imagine Owen Hunt
unable to stand
over an operating table.
Is that where we are?
Eh, I don't know.
It's slow going.
Heard about Schmitt?
No.
He had a tough loss.
Young guy in his 20s.
He bled out
in Schmitt's OR.
And I should be comforting him,
but I am just so angry
because he was at the
anastomosis with the stapler
and he didn't wait
for the attending.Oh.
Put too much traction
on the IMA,
and it avulsed
at the aorta.
Just hubris.
Just...pure and simple.
I wouldn't have waited.
If you had been teaching
this way when I started, I...
would have been drunk
on it.
Cristina wouldn't have waited.
Alex wouldn't have waited.
O-Okay. I got it.
Thanks.
I'm just saying --
No, you're saying
that Bailey was right.
You're saying we should kill
the Webber Method completely.
No, that's not
what I'm saying.
I'm...
I am just saying
that I am...
sorry for Schmitt.
♪♪
Exposing the endplate.
Drill, please.
Hold the drill for a second.
Nico's checking his anastomosis.
Tell me when.
Strong signal.
The primary repair worked.
I'm not seeing any other
neuro-vascular issues.
More irrigation,
please.
Shepherd, go ahead.
Can we clear the gallery,
please?
What?
I need to focus.
And I -- I'm asking
to clear the gallery.
Can we clear the gallery,
please?!
♪♪
Rongeur.
Now to clean some
of this dead tissue.
Nice work, Nico.
Now I need you to --
Debride and then do
a wet-to-dry dressing.
I got it.
Owen,
we are almost done.
♪♪
Nurse Kaiser to the OR.
- Oh! Sorry!
- Whoa. Whoa. You okay?
Um, I need your help.
It's Levi.
Our friend needs our help.
- Oh, my God.
- Levi. It's been hours.
You have to stop.
Uh...Schmitt.
I heard what happened, man,
and I've been there.
The first patient I lost,
I went running.
I went running
for five hours
until my legs gave out
and my friends found me
collapsed on the side of
the street, unable to move.
I get it.
I know how you feel.
But you have to stop, okay?
Um, listen.
Step back.
Look, um...
It's gonna be okay.
You have to
step back, though.
And the water
will turn off.
Just step back.
I've got you, buddy.
It's alright.
- No!
- It's alright. It's alright.
- Levi.
- It's alright.
- Watch out!
- It's alright. It's alright.
Levi.
It's okay.
Alright.
- It's okay, Levi.
- You're okay. You're okay.
- It's alright.
- You're okay.
- It's okay.
- Let him up.
It's okay.
I'll get him
up to the ICU.
When do you want
the first post-op labs?
As soon as he arrives.
And I want them doing
regular neuro-vascular checks.
Got it.
Dr. Rymock to the Psych Unit.
Dr. Rymock,
call the Psych Unit.
You spent the day
punishing me
because you saw me
kissing someone else?
You brought all of that --
all of that into Owen's surgery.
You don't think maybe
a conversation
before we're cutting into
someone I love?
Are you kidding me?
You think you get to be upset?
Are you serious?!
I'm over here
pining for you, Amelia,
head-over-heels,
can't-think-straight pining,
because you told me
you loved me.
You told me
over and over and over.
We were building a life
together,
and suddenly, you say,
"No, thanks."
And while I'm torturing myself
trying to convince myself
that I don't need to be married,
I just need you.
Since when?
Since now. Since today.
And I came to tell you this,
but instead, I find you
kissing someone else
in the hospital where I work!
You -- You just moved on.
You just --
You just moved on
like the last year and a half
didn't matter.
Okay. I am not a person
who just moves on.
I had to think and process
and go through
every scenario in my head
and every feeling in my body,
and it was exhausting.
And you know that I spent
a year in A.A. meetings
trying to figure out
what I needed,
and you did not want to hear
that I was losing myself
in something that I did not --
that I could not want.
You demanded
that I marry you,
and now once again,
you want to gaslight me
into thinking
that I played you?
You keep using that word --
"gaslight."
That's when you pretend that
someone else's experience,
their -- their, uh, reality
isn't real, right?
Like when you pretend that
we didn't make
an amazing baby together,
raise four kids, or love
each other really damn well.
When you pretend that
we weren't in love
because you're ready to move on
with some random woman.
They're non-binary.
Oh. Okay.
T-That makes it better.
Congratulations.
I hope you're really happy.
♪♪
Okay, everyone.
We're gonna try
to get this heart going.
If it doesn't beat,
I need everybody ready
to go back on bypass.
Okay.
Taking off clamp.
♪♪
Here we go.
♪ I hear...
You're gonna go home,
and you're gonna sleep
and hydrate and eat if you can
and cry if you can,
and, little by little,
you will feel like
you can breathe again.
I have to take this.
Don't wrap it too tight.
Hey.
Don't leave him alone.
Call me if you need me.
Yeah.
♪ In the air
What happened?
You okay?
♪ Nothing is clear
Hey.
What happened to him?
Levi? What --
What is going on here?
- Let's, um...
- Yeah, yeah. I got it.
♪ Ahh-ahh
Let's take a walk,
Nico.
Yeah?
♪ These secrets
sound like sirens ♪
What's going on?
Alright, man.
We are done here.
Everything's
gonna be alright.
♪ Sound like sirens
♪ But they never come
♪ Ahhh
♪♪
♪ Ahhhh
♪ Stand on edges
where fear is proud ♪
♪ They don't like to be found
His heart is beating,
and it's beating well, Megan.
♪ Shadows flee
in the blackest night ♪
♪ Without me
they won't survive ♪
♪ Ahhhh
Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you.
♪ Ahhhh
Dr. Ndugu made sure
the graft was perfect,
and he'll be up any minute.
What -- What about, uh, Owen?
Is he out of surgery yet or...?
We will get an update to you
as soon as we can.
Right now, I just want you
to take this in.
Farouk's heart
is beating in his chest.
He's okay.
And it's okay to --
to take in the miracle.
♪ These secrets
sound like sirens ♪
♪ But they never come
♪♪
Dr. Bailey,
can I have a word?
Yeah, just let me --
Oh, your head.
Uh, any update
on the Hunt family?
Farouk's heart transplant
was a success.
Oh. And Owen?
I, uh...
I haven't heard.
Well, I need him
to be okay.
That family
has been through so much.
They've lived
lives of service.
The mother was an Army nurse.
Did you know that?
No.
Whole military family.
Owen Hunt is one of
the best men I know.
He cares and he fights
and he...
He's gonna be okay.
I'm just gonna decide that
right now.
Owen Hunt is gonna be okay!
You hear me?
Oh, this day.
Did you hear about Schmitt?
Dr. Bailey.
I have to give you my notice.
What?
I'm sorry.
My kids,
they're not thriving here.
They're not happy.
We have to go.
W-Where?
Back to Ireland.
O-kay.
I...I...
I d-- I don't suppose
there's anything I can...do
to convince you to stay?
Support for the boys.
No. I'm sorry.
The decision's been made.
Um, my -- hmm...
...head of trauma
is still in surgery
and could need
months of recovery,
uh, so can you at least give me
until he's well?
I mean, at this rate,
I'm hemorrhaging surgeons.
I just can't.
I truly am sorry.
I've loved my time here.
But I got to do
what's best for my family.
I'll hand off my cases.
This will be my last shift.
I'm sorry.
♪♪
So, are we celebrating
with drinks at Joe's
or pajamas in bed?
Grey-Sloan Memorial.
How can I...
What --
What was that look for?
"Take in the miracle."
You're a person
who takes in miracles.
I didn't know that
about you.
What, you don't?
I take in science,
data, reason...
calculated risk.
And today, you jumped in
and had my back
when I decided to leap.
You were right there --
every stitch, every move.
Meaning?
Meaning we both
showed up.
We were a team.
Owen and Teddy and Hayes,
they're alive,
and they kept
that heart alive.
The two of us,
we were a team.
We gave that boy a heart.
So call it a miracle --
Or skill, precision,
hard work.
Okay. Either way.
That boy's brand-new heart
is beating in his chest.
His heart is beating
in his chest.
Hmm.
Pajamas.
We're definitely celebrating
with pajamas.
Meredith!
Hi.
I thought
you'd never get here.
What do you mean?
I'm right on time.I know.
How you doing?
Bad day, huh?
Yeah.
What's up?
My friend got into
a car accident.
Oh, no.
Yeah.
My other friend quit.
Oh, no.
And then my favorite resident
flamed out.
Geez. This place really falls
apart without you, doesn't it?
Well, I got us
a reservation
at a nice restaurant
not too far from here.
I thought that might be
your reaction,
so I also got a hotel
with amazing room service.
Yes, better.
Much better.
Hey.
Hi.
Fries?
Yeah. Please.
♪ Strangely, there's
nobody else around ♪
How did the surgery go?
Uh, well, the patient has
a long road to recovery,
but he's alive
and he's not paralyzed.
And he is my ex-husband.
And, uh, the surgeon
who operated with me
is my son's father,
so, you know...
family reunion.
Got it.
Oh. Got it.
So he cleared the gallery
because I came in?
He saw us kissing.
My life, uh, is...
...messy.
And I would
totally understand
if you don't want anything
to do with that mess.
♪ Hear your voice
Tell me, is your type
always hot, square-jawed men?
Lately,
it appears my type
is hot, square-jawed you.
Touché.
What about you?
Do you have a type?
No, but I'm sharing my fries.
That's not a small thing.
♪ I still see you
♪ The sunlight on your face
in my rearview ♪
Is that your kid?
That's Scout.
His dad sends
a goodnight photo of him
every night that he has him.
Even if we're fighting.
He's a good man.
I hate that
I broke his heart,
and I hate that he made me
break it all over again.
♪♪
You want me
to grab you a drink?
Yes.
But, no,
because I don't drink.
♪♪
Thank you.
♪ When you go away
♪ I still see you
Thank you.
I don't want to feel
all this again.
Then don't.
Helpful. Thank you.
I'm saying, don't.
I'm saying
life is hard enough,
and sometimes on bad days,
we kill people
and wash our hands
until they bleed.
Maybe don't suffer
any more than you have to.
Is it that easy?
Maybe.
Amelia is a good mom
and a great surgeon
and a decent human being,
I guess,
but she doesn't want
what you want.
And you -- you are...
Atticus Lincoln.
You are the best ortho surgeon,
the best bartender,
the best father I know,
and you're also just, like,
really hot.
I'm serious!
You're the hottest guy
that everyone knows.
Let's just not pretend
that that's not true.
There are other women
who would...
love to love you, Link.
I am a catch.
There's no denying it.
You already mourned her.
You already suffered,
so maybe just...
...don't suffer anymore.
♪♪
♪ There's nothing left to say
♪ No breath in your lungs
♪♪
♪ Standing in flames
♪ The wreckage of us
♪♪
♪ Caught in this war
This is a bad idea.
Is it?
♪ It's a dangerous love
♪ Mmm-mm
♪♪
♪ Ooh-ooh
♪ There's nothing left to say
♪ Your heart turned to stone
♪♪
♪ It's too late to save
♪ You're already gone
Recent studies suggest
that when we experience
physical sensations
related to intense emotions,
it comes back
to the vagus nerve.
♪♪
♪ Mmm-mm
♪ Ooh-ooh
We think of the pain
of a broken heart
as being
outside of our control.
♪ Ooh-ooh
♪♪
But science suggests that
if we laugh instead of cry...
if we sing instead of ache...
we might just heal faster.
♪ Ooh-ooh
Ahh.
Okay, okay. Hey.
Okay. Here.
Press this if you need
some more, okay?
Yep.
Give it a second.
Okay.
Okay. Okay. Phew.
The surgery?
It went well.
I'll walk?
Yes.
It'll take time, but yes.
Ohh.
Bailey just stopped by
to check on you.
She told me
that Hayes quit.
Says he wants to
go back to Ireland.
What happened
in that car, Owen?
Of course,
when we're hurting...
What are you
not telling me?
...sometimes it's just easier
to keep hurting
than to try to heal.
♪♪