Previously on ER:
- Sending me to Africa?
- You can use a change of perspective.
Mouthwash? You
got to be kidding me.
You're a weird dude, Pratt.
- Debbie and Dakarai, huh?
- Yeah. They're an item.
We're on our way to Dumtala Camp
to help sick people. We're here to help.
They do not hurt doctors. One
never knows what might happen.
Janjaweed.
Welcome to Darfur.
Your government promised $50
million in aid only to pull it away.
Yeah, well, we got our own
problems. You ever heard of Katrina?
If the U.S. does not lead
the way, who else will?
Without international intervention,
nothing will change here.
Zahra, ask him if he's
been taking the amoxicillin.
Listen, even with intervention,
a year after us being here...
the world will be screaming
for us to get out of Sudan.
Oh, Pratt, I expected so
much more from you. Ah.
- Why? Because I'm black?
- No, because you are smart.
Yeah, well, I'm also American.
I did not realize these things
were mutually exclusive.
- He says, yes, he's feeling better.
- Okay, good.
Listen, all I'm saying is that it's
a lot more complicated than that.
We been too quick getting in
the middle of other people's fights.
Fine. When the solution does come
to Darfur, it is not going to be quick.
Yeah, well, where I'm from,
gangs, they get into it all the time.
All the cops can do is step
back and wait for it to end.
Step back and wait?
That sounds like an excellent foreign
policy while people are suffering.
Dakarai, stop
ragging on my country.
There's plenty of Americans
helping. You see me here, right?
Yes and quite frankly, I'm
beginning to wonder why.
- What?
- She says the baby wasn't moving.
Okay, just show me where.
And you are moving
pretty fast for an isolationist.
They told you a brother was
coming, you expected Marcus Garvey?
We don't have more in
common than you and Carter.
I don't. In fact, I think Carter
is more African than you are.
How long has he been like this?
Um, has he had
a fever? Diarrhea?
Baby no cry.
Yeah, he's too sick to cry. Listen,
we need to bring him back with us.
Look, your baby needs medicine.
We have to get him to the hospital.
Where is that other doctor?
- Tired.
- Tired?
Okay, wait right here.
Dakarai, what are
you doing, man?
Whoa. What the
hell? You all right?
- Varices.
- Varices?
Getting worse.
You told me your IV was
for a little stomach virus.
Scarring in my liver.
Schistosomiasis
when I was a child.
Damn. Well, congratulations.
You just became the proud
winner of a bed in tent number three.
Rashida Fallad.
She's 26 weeks pregnant
and she has hepatitis E.
Hepatitis E? I thought
our water was clean.
They go outside the camp, drink from
other sources. It shouldn't be long now.
I think you're overreacting.
Mortality rate for hep E isn't high.
It is in pregnant women,
especially in Darfur.
Over 30 percent of people
who contract the disease will die.
Rashida.
The encephalopathy is worse.
She's pretty jaundiced.
Scleral icterus.
She's in hepatic coma.
Ask her if, um, she's
been eating or drinking.
Tell her we've been giving her antibiotics
and glucose through an NG feeding tube.
What did she say?
She wants to know if...
her daughter will die
today or tomorrow.
Tell her I'm not sure.
She wants to know
if we need the bed.
No. No.
Got a minute?
Mm-hm.
So this baby I brought in
yesterday, she's not doing so good.
I'm having trouble finding an IV
site and this kid is getting pretty dry.
- Stop trying to be so tough.
- I am tough.
- I'm just trying to look out for you.
- I don't need a wife, already had three.
- Steven, you feeling any better?
- I don't want to be babied. I'm fine.
- Stay in bed a little longer.
- I'm ready to work.
- You have paracentesis. Don't be an idiot.
- Sound medical advice.
She has no bedside manner.
- Talk to him.
Stay in bed until I
sign off on your chart.
When?
- When I get to it.
- This is why people hate doctors.
- He needed a paracentesis?
- Took five liters off his belly.
- Five liters?
- Had him on Lasix all night.
We have to limit his sodium.
That man shouldn't be working.
He shouldn't even be here.
- Dr. Dakarai is very committed.
- Uh-huh.
This is Mahdi,
his mother, sister.
I'm Dr. Carter. Can
you tell her that we're
gonna try to give
some fluids to her baby?
Dr. John, they're bringing
a man from outside.
They say he's been shot.
Okay, 20 gauge on the femoral, I
want you to call me if you need me, okay?
Ishaak. PRATT: What?
His name is Ishaak.
Why won't you get this treated?
- What happened?
- Two GSWs, chest and leg.
I'm going to help. - We got it.
- We handle gunshots differently...
- We know that. Get back in bed.
An entrance wound, right chest.
Okay, belly seems clear.
Ishaak, you left the compound.
Just to the perimeter,
to help a family get water.
He's got strong carotid.
Okay, try for the BP.
Men on horses. They shot me.
Let me guess, Janjaweed.
Through and through left calf.
One hundred over 60.
- Why are you always where the trouble is?
- I try to help.
- Ishaak is a sheik.
- Like, with a harem?
No, like a leader.
He is recognized as someone
the other IDPs can look up to.
Trying to make a difference,
get people together.
- Yeah, well, he should stop that.
- Why say such a thing?
It's making people
wanna kill him.
Give me two liters
of saline, wide open.
Okay, I got a good vein in the
antecube. I'm going in with the 18.
Ishaak, we need
to move you to town.
You need more surgery
than we can do for you here.
I... I can't breathe.
Do we have the oxygen extractor?
- Yeah, on its way.
Treating a man with a gunshot
wound? Ishaak Alazhari?
I'd have to check with the
doctors. You can't just come in.
As long as there is
no violation, we'll leave.
Officer, please, please, wait
outside. I'll look around for you.
- We'll look for ourselves.
- You cannot be here with those weapons.
You know the agreement the
Alliance has with your government.
We'll go where we need to
go, do what we need to do.
Look, the NGO rules
apply, even in Darfur.
Debbie.
Ishaak, this is oxygen.
This should help you breathe.
- How are you doing, man?
- Feeling pain when I breathe.
This man's been shot.
- Yeah, that's right.
- He's bleeding internally.
He needs immediate care and
transport to a surgical facility.
- Did you report this to my office?
- Come on. He can do that later.
Without a form eight,
he's got no right.
He's gotta fill out a form?
It's not gonna help
much if he's already dead.
- Come on. PRATT: Wait
a minute. Take it easy.
What's the matter with you?
What are you doing? Are you nuts?
- He'll die.
Guilty, form-eight violation.
Requires gunshot injuries...
- He's here now. Please, don't do this.
- If you are going to do this...
- Steven! PRATT: You
can't come in here... Unh.
I'll send you a document
re-clarifying the regulation...
so this does not happen again.
Good day, doc.
Okay, okay. Let's see.
Damn.
How does that feel?
Feels like I got hit in
the head with a rifle butt.
Better to be hit with
one than shot with one.
- You want something for the pain?
- No, I'll be fine.
I've had hangovers
worse than this.
Perhaps you should
drink less mouthwash.
What's gonna happen
to the guy they took?
They'll probably bring him back
when they are finished interrogating him.
- He could be dead by then.
- Oh, yes, I'm sure they are aware of that.
Hey.
- You should go back to the compound.
- No, I'm okay.
It's almost quitting time.
He's bradycardic, 58, 0.5 epi.
He's already had two doses.
He's not responding.
Because he's
hypoxic and acidotic.
All right, give him another
bolus and find me a bag mask.
Nope.
He'll turn around once
the antibiotics kick in.
I can bag him through this.
By yourself? All night?
- It could take days.
- Pulse is down to 50.
I'm doing compressions.
Are we just gonna watch him die?
No, that's what his mother does.
We have other patients.
That's messed up.
Would you please tell
her that we're very sorry.
Tell her that I know how
difficult it is to lose a child...
that my own son died when
he was very young in a hospital.
She finds it hard to believe that
babies die in Western hospitals.
You should not have
let them take him away.
- We didn't have a choice.
- Hey.
- Ishaak's wife, Sittina.
- Hi.
You treated my husband?
Tried, but they took him,
he didn't fill out some form.
No, they took him away
because he tells people the truth.
That it is not safe to
go back to their villages.
- The people listen to him, he's... Ah.
- Whoa.
You okay? Maybe
you should sit down.
Are you having
contractions? How far apart?
She's eight centimeters.
One hundred percent effaced.
She's definitely
having this baby tonight.
It'll be dark soon.
- Take her to the residential compound?
- She can't have it here?
She can, but we can't stay with her.
There's electricity back at the compound.
The only place I am going is to
the police station to get my husband.
Do you want the police
to deliver your baby?
- Unh. But Ishaak...
- Let's worry about the baby.
Ibrahim, bring the truck.
- Here we go.
- I'll grab the OB pack.
- Passing through.
Here we go.
I got it.
Go ahead.
Okay.
You're late.
It's cinema night. We're
moving to the rec room.
Gregory wants us to
watch Deuce Bigalow again.
Keep everybody in there
for a little while, all right?
- Is everything all right?
- Yeah, it'll be fine.
They turn the generators
off in the compound at night.
The only power in the
clinic is used for cold storage.
She would have to deliver
the baby alone in the dark.
Try and relax, huh?
You okay?
She's progressing very well. She
can start pushing within the hour.
I'm talking about you.
I am tired. Been
on my feet all day.
- You are not tired?
- I'm tired.
Tired of you lying to me...
ignoring a life-threatening
illness which needs to be treated.
Hey, hey. I promise...
if I get any worse, I will do IV
diuretics and sodium restrictions...
- and I will dry out my ascites.
- It's not good enough.
You need the procedure.
Carter, what is it he needs?
A, uh, transjugular
intrahepatic portosystemic shunt.
Well, interventional radiology is hard to
come by if you don't have x-ray machines.
You need to go to
Khartoum, Nairobi.
When I'm in bed, who's going
to take care of my patients?
Don't know. Who's gonna take
care of them when you're dead?
Long day, huh?
Only thing longer than
the days here are nights.
I'm okay, Carter. Really.
You could have fooled me.
This is nothing.
It's my weekly ritual.
Only way to get through the
suffering that surrounds this place...
is to allow myself a good
cry every now and then.
Feel better already.
So this has nothing
to do with Steven?
Steven makes me angry,
he doesn't make me cry.
You tell me, you're a doctor.
What happens if he
doesn't get treated?
His condition is
gonna get worse.
It's already worse.
It's the police.
- Hide her.
- What? Where?
- What's going on?
- It's the police. Gotta hide her.
- Unh, unh!
- Whoa.
Contraction? DEBBIE: Where?
Let's go to the bathroom.
Are these the men
that took my husband?
- I don't know.
- Unh. Ask them.
- I want to know what they've done.
- Keep her quiet.
Okay. Just breathe.
What's going on?
He is searching
for Ishaak's wife.
I told him come in the
morning, search the camp.
He thinks we brought her here.
No, we don't treat patients here.
- I told him that.
Now he wants to
search the house.
No. A housing
unit, that's off-limits.
It's off... Hey,
come on, you guys.
You know what time it is?
Everybody's sleeping inside. Okay.
Hey, hey, hey.
- They're in the house.
- No!
Shh. You have to keep her quiet.
I can't. She's in labor.
Try to breathe through
the pain, Sittina, good girl.
Breathe, breathe, breathe.
Shh, shh, shh, shh.
Hey, what's up, fellas?
Whoa, whoa. Sorry, I'm next.
And I don't think it's gonna
leave a scar. Thanks for asking.
Look, I've been standing
out here for 20 minutes, okay?
Pratt!
All right.
What the hell are
you doing? Get out!
Get out!
Your superiors are
gonna hear about this.
Something is wrong.
- Hang in there. You're doing great.
- I feel the head.
- I see thick meconium.
- Deceleration. A long one.
- How low?
- Low.
I think the occiput's posterior.
We don't have time
for this baby to turn.
- Prep for c-section?
- Are you out of your mind?
All, right, Sittina, your baby is
showing signs of very serious distress.
Vaginal delivery is too dangerous.
We need to do a cesarean.
No, please, unh, save it.
I'm gonna put some
anesthesia in your back.
- You'll lose feeling from the waist down.
- Okay, come on.
Oh, Ishaak.
Aah! Ishaak!
Give me more counter pressure.
- Yep.
Debbie, can you get a blanket?
Okay, I got it.
Unh, here we go.
- Got it.
- It's a girl, Sittina.
Allah has blessed
you with a healthy child.
Get my husband.
Yeah. DEBBIE: Okay.
Oh, oh.
- There's blood in the pelvis.
- Try uterine massage.
I am. I got no suction, I can't
see where she's bleeding from.
Oh, Ishaak.
Give me some sterile
four-by-fours and keep them coming.
If they find out who
we are, they will kill him.
- Who you are?
- We helped to form the HRD.
What's she talking about?
HRD. It's a human rights
group based in Khartoum.
Human Rights for Darfur.
They will kill him if
they know. Please.
Oh, man, she's bleeding out.
This was a bad idea. No blood,
no pressors, no pit, not Methergine.
What are we supposed to do
now? She needs a hysterectomy.
Bring her to the
hospital in Al-Fashir.
It's too late to drive.
She'll have to go tomorrow.
Because of a bunch
of thugs on camels.
And they also have
trucks and guns.
Lots of guns.
Okay, I can tie off
the uterine arteries...
buy us time. Give me O chromic
on the longest needle we got.
Not enough time. Couple hours,
the uterus will become ischemic.
That is the best
chance we got right now.
I grew up in Detroit, I can
be in Al-Fashir in two hours.
You didn't wanna bring her.
- I made a mistake.
If we'd left her, she'd never
be able to deliver safely.
- This baby would have died.
- Slow down, Pratt.
Okay, the uterine
artery is tied off.
- Only chance she's got, you know it.
- She may not survive the trip.
Yeah, but she's
dead if she stays here.
If she dies making the
journey, well, at least we tried.
Okay.
Okay, I'll go with you.
No, John, you and Debbie
should go to the police.
Find Ishaak. You have a much better
chance of getting him out of there.
He and I, we'll close and then
we will bring her on to the hospital.
- All right.
- Okay.
We'd like to see
Ishaak Alazhari.
No, you can't see him.
Why not?
He's under arrest.
On what charge?
He's been shot. He
needs medical attention.
I'm a doctor. I would like to
evaluate his medical condition.
How's she doing back there?
She is breathing.
What the hell is that?
Janjaweed. Let's go back.
Oh, we got a traffic jam.
If we stop, they will take the
truck, leave her to die, or worse.
Okay, all right,
then we don't stop.
Just cover her up and hold on.
- Now, hold on, Dakarai.
- But...
Hold on!
Get down, Dakarai.
Did you tell him that
we work for the Alliance?
- Dumtala camp.
- Mm-hm.
All right, look, is it money?
Because I can get some.
- You must leave now.
- No, I would like to speak to your boss.
Very busy.
Should I tell him you walked in on this
American woman while she was bathing?
Or should I tell the consulate that an
American woman's privacy was violated?
How much money?
Ishaak? Ishaak, can you hear me?
I need to see him.
No, I need to go in there.
Not responding.
He's dead.
The tire is flat.
Yeah. I think they hit the
oil pan and the radiator too.
She's getting pretty hot.
What is that? Lasix
for the ascites?
Prozac. Keep driving.
How fast can a
horse go with a rider?
I don't know, maybe
30 miles an hour.
Okay, well, we've been going 45 miles
an hour, maybe 40, our tire blew out, so...
- It's more like 50.
- Okay, good.
We've done enough time.
For what?
To change the tire.
Maybe somebody in that
village can help us out over there.
Maybe. Aah! If there
was somebody living there.
Lord.
You all right? DAKARAI: Yes.
What...?
The people we treat every day...
it is places like this
from which they come...
before the Janjaweed
burned them out.
Huh.
- Agonal respirations and a thready pulse.
- He's alive?
- Barely. Ready to lift? One, two, three.
- Don't tell the police.
Zahra, get an IV started
and get him back on oxygen.
- What can I do? CARTER:
Transfer O-neg from the fridge.
And when she's done, you
can squeeze in a liter of saline.
He's got decreased
breath sounds on the right.
Possible hemo-pneumo.
He's gonna need a chest tube.
Where do you keep them?
- We don't.
Uh, we're gonna
have to improvise.
Get me a scalpel and a
curved Kelly and a NG tube.
When the blood compressing his lung is
removed, his pulse should get stronger.
- Bleeding?
- It should stop.
If it doesn't?
Why don't you see if
you can radio Dakarai?
They should be in
Al-Fashir by now.
Do we have any extra water?
No.
- What about saline?
- Four liters.
All right, toss me one.
I gotta say, this is the first time I've
ever given a bolus to a truck before.
Take it easy, man.
We just wanna get her to
the hospital. Tell him that.
I'm trying.
Aah! PRATT: No.
Oh, man.
His friends will
not be far behind.
If you try and save him, we
will never get away from here.
There is nothing you
can do for him now.
Come on, get up.
Come on. Watch your step.
- Okay.
- All right, go.
- Aw, damn!
- What?
The engine is seized.
We're gonna have to hoof it.
- Gotta walk from here.
- I can't.
- Why the hell not?
- I don't think I can walk.
- And I will only slow you down.
- I can't leave you here.
- You have to.
- No way.
Why don't you
leave me the rifle...
and perhaps I can occupy his
friends while you get to Al-Fashir.
How far away is
the city from here?
It is still several miles.
But you can get there.
- You really think she's gonna make it?
- She will die if you don't.
You ever fire one of these?
- I've never held a weapon.
- Just point and shoot.
Okay, Sittina, we're gonna go
on foot patrol from here on in.
I'm gonna give you a little
something for the pain, okay?
Wha...? What the
hell is she saying?
She called us angels.
I said there are no angels here.
Speak for yourself.
You ever been to
Mozambique, Sittina?
Yeah, they got
great beaches there.
White sands, cool waters.
Yeah. Definitely gotta
get me to Mozambique.
Okay, either those are the
good guys and we're saved...
or the bad guys and we're dead.
Either way...
I'm done walking.
Very sick?
That's right.
- I tell him faster.
- Good.
You English? James
Bond, 007? Do-doo-do-doo?
- No.
- Do-doo-do-doo?
American "Rambro"?
Yeah, "Rambro."
Good stuff.
Help me. Please. Please.
I need a doctor. Please.
Please.
She needs saline, blood,
antibiotics and a surgeon.
Hurry.
Good stuff.
Yeah.
Ishaak's doing much better.
Bleeding stopped.
Good.
Keeps asking for Sittina.
No word yet.
Did you try the radio?
They stopped answering
the radio hours ago.
- Still...
- There's no signal, John.
And they haven't resorted
to sending smoke signals yet.
Okay.
Sorry.
Come on.
Let's go introduce
him to his daughter.
Whoa. Stop! Stop! Stop!
Dakarai.
Come on, let's go.
Go.
We had hoped to be back in
our village before the child came.
To be born in this place...
it wasn't what we
wanted for our child.
Now I can only hope that
before she's grown up...
we can go back to our village.
Ahem. We tried calling
the hospital in Al-Fashir...
but we haven't been able
to find out anything yet.
She's there. I'm sure of it.
Dr. Carter.
Greg, you gave us quite a scare.
Van broke down.
Turns out even in Africa
cabs won't stop for a brother.
Sittina...?
She'll be okay. They're
working on her in town.
She should be ready to
come back in a few days.
- Allah is with her.
- You guys fixed him up pretty good.
Nice job.
Greg, where's Steven?
He couldn't keep going.
And Sittina, she...
Tell me.
I left him on the road.
- Where?
- At a burned-out village.
I went back for him, but
by the time I got there...
I could tell the
Janjaweed had been there.
They torched the truck.
Here, his medicine.
- We need to go out and look for him.
- No, it's too late.
It'd be dark by the time we get there.
I'll take you first thing in the morning.
Debbie.
We didn't have a lot of options.
I mean, if we'd stayed, we'd all
be dead. He made me keep going.
You did what you had to do.
So did Dakarai.
Can you work?
- Yeah, in a minute.
- Okay.
Did you name her yet?
Yes. Amala.
That's beautiful.
It means hope.
After they had burned the truck,
I saw no reason to stick around.
Anyway, it was safer to walk,
especially after all of your driving.
Ah, I'm glad you
made it back, brother.
- You all right?
- I am now.
Why didn't you go to
Al-Fashir, you dummy?
They could have
treated you there.
Maybe next week, huh?
Ibrahim, let's take
him to the clinic.
Tell Zahra to get him started
on lactulose and saline.
He's one stubborn
son of a bitch.
I know the type.
You know, Carter, I got
my own way of being.
But it damn sure doesn't mean
I don't see or feel everything...
that's going on around me.
To tell you the truth, I never wanted
to be around this type of suffering.
I mean, who would?
I'm glad I came here.
I'm glad you came too.
Because I am not gonna
take the blame for that van.
Oh, gee, thanks.
That's okay. They'll take
it out of your paycheck.
What do you mean? We
actually get paid for this?
Whoa. Hey.
Okay, where are we going?