The timing was good.
I just got a job transfer.
Gretchen will start
at a new school.
We're gonna start a whole
new life. It's very exciting.
In college, my dad
majored in cheerleading.
That was a joke.
Gretchen's got a
great sense of humor.
I'm laughing on the inside.
Soon, you'll be laughing
on the outside, too.
Dr. Park?
Moebius syndrome
is the paralysis
of the sixth and seventh
pair of cranial nerves.
The seventh pair
controls facial expression.
Luckily, in Gretchen's case,
we haven't found any
limitation to the sixth pair.
I'm a lucky girl.
We'll be taking two slivers
of muscle from your thighs,
along with their nerves
and blood supply,
and transplanting
them into your cheeks.
There will be
considerable recovery time
before you'll be
able to smile at will.
Maybe three months.
So what do you say?
Are you up for this?
Can I sleep on it?
See what I have to live with?
Nobody knows when I'm joking.
Sorry, Dr. Andrews.
Yes, I am very up for this.
Ah, okay. Great. So, unless
there are any other questions...
Do you want to be a comedian?
People getting your jokes
must be very important to you
if you think it's worth the risk
of dying during elective surgery.
Hmm.
I apologize for Dr. Murphy.
He's still learning that
silence is the right choice
when you have
nothing useful to offer.
We are required
to have an honest
risk-benefit discussion
with our patients.
We are giving a lovely
young girl a smile.
That's a simple equation.
Well, it's more than
the smile or the jokes.
She can't express
any emotions at all.
No one can tell if she's
happy or sad or scared.
Anything.
She's never had
much of a social life.
Ever since her mother died,
she's been completely withdrawn.
All I wanna do is bring my
baby girl back into the world.
Don't worry, Mr. Milman, we'll
take great care of her, all right?
Lucy has a post-op
infection of unknown origin.
Infusing 900 milligrams
of clindamycin.
It's terrible, isn't it?
Yes, it is.
Have you been
changing your dressing?
Every day.
- Soaking it in clean, warm water?
- Yes.
Taking your antibiotics,
one pill three times a day?
That's a no.
Lucy, I know I gave
you a script for antibiotics
along with one for pain meds.
Why haven't you been
taking your antibiotics?
Did you have a bad
reaction to them or...
I never filled my prescription.
I didn't think it was
necessary until it got really bad,
and then I was too
weak to go myself,
and I didn't have anyone
to pick it up for me.
Okay, mystery solved.
I'm sorry. I know it was stupid.
Very stupid.
Okay.
Hey, Shaun.
- Oh, hello.
- Haven't seen you in ages.
What's... What's new?
- I'm buying an apple.
- I can see that.
- Here, I'll... I'll get it for you.
- No, thank you.
- Thank you, Shaun.
- Yes.
What else is new?
You didn't want to be friends.
Mmm.
Yeah, no, uh, we...
We're colleagues.
You know, we're...
Whatever we are, we can
still talk. We should talk.
I have a new friend. Kenny.
Here you go.
Thank you, Debbie. Kenny,
huh? That's, uh... That's great.
Do you have a new friend?
- No.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
We can talk, you know?
We can talk about sports.
We can talk about
weather. We can talk about...
Debbie?
Why would you wanna
talk about Debbie?
Debbie was flirting with you.
She was?
Yes, I noticed her
exhibiting two typical signs.
- Not the trifecta, though?
- No, not the trifecta.
And one atypical sign.
I think she's just
trying to be friendly.
She gave you an
extra dollar in change.
And the fact that you didn't
notice means you like her, too.
Maybe she's just bad at math.
My dad said that
you're on the spectrum.
That's why you said that
about people getting my jokes.
People always get my jokes.
Then you're very lucky.
That was a joke.
I see what you did there.
Yes.
They call me
"Resting Gretch Face."
"Shaun the Moron."
Not very witty. No, I'm
obviously quite smart.
I drew this to their attention.
I'm on a spectrum, too.
It's somewhere between
inscrutable, unapproachable,
and actively scorned.
I don't want to be
more approachable,
and I prefer people not reading
my emotions. They're mine.
But that's what
you do with friends.
You really think this
surgery's too risky?
Possible complications
include embolism, hemorrhage,
collateral paralysis, asymmetry,
brain damage, and stroke.
It's also expensive and
medically unnecessary.
Okay. Look straight ahead.
There's a two-hour wait in
the ER, and what are we doing?
Treating a woman because she
wilfully ignored doctors' orders.
I know what a parasite
looks like, and it's not Lucy.
So this is a mom thing with you.
Growing up with a whack
mother means that you can identify
any and all problem
personalities.
And that is the sole upside to my
miserable childhood. Thank you.
Well, at least you had a
mom. Mine died when I was six,
and Dad instantly
married a child-hating bitch
with a butt-load of debt.
Morgan, I'm sorry. I...
I didn't tell you to get sympathy.
Just that I know parasites, too.
Got you booked first
thing tomorrow morning.
Dad.
- What? Too soon?
- It's...
You're nervous.
I get it.
If you have any more
questions, feel free.
I've changed my mind.
I'm not having the surgery.
Murphy.
Hello.
Gretchen's father is very upset.
Seems you talked
her out of the surgery.
No, I didn't talk her out
of it or talk her anywhere.
I just gave her the
list of potential risks.
Embolism, hemorrhage,
collateral paralysis, asymmetry,
brain damage, and stroke.
- "Stroke"?
- Yes. There was a case in Brazil
- in 2004, and the patient suffered...
- Uh... Uh...
It seems that you don't believe
that restoring this girl's smile
is that important.
Smiles are overvalued. There
are studies that support that.
And there are
studies that don't.
When we smile, we produce
endorphins. They make us happy.
They make other people happy.
When we see smiles,
our basotemporal lobes are
activated, and we duplicate what we see.
Murphy, smiles are contagious.
You see?
I feel good. You feel good.
Everybody likes smiles.
I don't.
In any case, your
smile wasn't sincere
since it didn't demonstrate
the Duchenne marker.
There was no involvement
of the orbicularis oculi
muscles around the eyes,
which means you didn't
release endorphins.
You know, if you can talk her out
of a surgery she's wanted for years,
I'm pretty sure a conversation
with someone objective
can talk her back into it.
Get Park, come
with, and keep quiet.
Okay.
Dr. Kalu.
Remember me?
Fish girl?
- Uh, hi. Celez, hi.
- Yeah.
Yes, of course I do.
Hope it's okay that
I requested you.
I'm glad you did.
How are you doing?
Ooh, that's what
you're going to tell me.
I've been wearing the, uh,
tilapia skins for five months.
I'm getting really tired of being
followed home by stray cats.
How's the pain?
Compared to what
it was? Nothing.
- Uh, any fever, itchiness, or swelling?
- Nope.
Well, it looks very good.
But...
How much longer?
Um...
How do you feel about tomorrow?
- Seriously?
- I never joke about tilapia.
What's the matter?
I... I just wasn't
expecting that.
I...
I'm afraid of how
I'm going to look.
You're going to look beautiful.
Tomorrow.
I know Dr. Murphy informed
you about the risks of this surgery,
and some risks are
significant, and some just aren't.
This is as close to risk-free
surgery as we can get.
It'll give you a smile.
It'll let you laugh.
No.
Dr. Murphy didn't
talk me out of it.
He inspired me.
He helped me realize that this
could actually make me stronger.
I don't wanna run
from it anymore.
She's lying.
She's a smart,
sarcastic young woman,
not exactly someone who's
prone to inspirational stories.
Why would she lie
about changing her mind?
Well, when I was a cop,
I had a lot of people change
their minds about testifying in court,
and it always came down
to one of three reasons.
Fear, confusion, or
they were paid off.
- She doesn't seem confused.
- And I don't think she's afraid.
So Gretchen was paid off?
I admit the
analogy isn't perfect.
It's close enough.
Guess who's back in the ER.
You're happy, so I'm guessing
it's a non-compliant patient.
You misjudged Lucy.
She made an honest mistake
forgetting her prescriptions.
You called her, didn't you?
She didn't spontaneously
remember. You had to remind her.
Is that a mom thing, too?
Gretchen.
Are you worried that your
dad can't afford this surgery?
The insurance
company is paying for it.
Dad, I know it isn't.
It's elective.
It's medically unnecessary.
No one can put a
value on your smile.
Not bullies, not an
insurance company,
not even Dr. Murphy.
In my opinion, this surgery
is medically necessary.
Gretchen, sweetie,
my first memory of your mother
was of her smiling at
me from across the room.
And because of that smile,
we ended up with you.
And my last memory of her
is that radiance lighting
up the world one last time.
I mean, we never had much money,
but as long as I had
that smile, it didn't matter.
I love you, Dad.
And that's why I can't let
you give up everything for this.
- Lucy Callard?
- I'm here.
Um...
Lucille Elizabeth Callard?
Yes, that's me.
A Dr. Browne called me
to pick up my prescriptions.
You're the victim of
identity theft, Lucy.
There's an impostor using your
name and medical ID to get benefits.
Did you have your
purse stolen recently?
Six weeks ago.
And you had your driver's
license and credit cards replaced,
but not your health
insurance card?
Is this why the pharmacy
refuses to fill my prescriptions?
I'm on pain meds for
postherpetic neuralgia.
It's getting really bad.
Once the impostor filled her
prescription for pain meds,
the pharmacy must have thought
you were overfilling opiates.
Oh! It always flares
up when I get upset.
Don't worry, Lucy.
We'll get you your meds.
We... We can't.
We're already
treating Lucy Callard.
Nice game, Tony.
- Hi, Jim.
- Marcus, hey.
- You coming or going?
- Neither.
Fifteen-year-old girl
with Moebius syndrome.
Your company denied coverage.
No respiratory issues,
deformities, pain.
She doesn't even drool.
- She's fully functional.
- She can't smile.
That's a function.
Marcus, I think it's wonderful
you wanna give this
little girl her smile.
But if we paid for
everything wonderful,
we'd go bankrupt. And
then who are we helping?
We all know doctors cheat
diagnoses to get coverage.
Deviated septum gets
you a free nose job.
Migraine gets you botox.
Do you really want
me to play that game?
This isn't a game for me.
We're a reputable company
with very high standards.
Very high bonuses that get
even higher with your denial rate.
I was gonna suggest we end this
before we say something we'll regret,
but I believe that
just happened.
Gretchen's socially
isolated, depressed,
and that's only gonna get worse.
What if she slashes her wrists?
You'd prefer to cover that?
Are you threatening me
with a teenage girl's suicide?
And God forbid something
does happen to her,
'cause I'll make sure
that this conversation
is part of the permanent record.
Dr. Andrews said
smiles are contagious,
and I'm testing that hypothesis.
Well, I'm not sure your
study will prove anything.
It might have something to do with
the lack of the Duchenne marker.
Oh. Yes.
But here you go.
That wasn't a smile.
Sure, it was.
I want to show you something.
You need to follow me.
Okay.
The impostor has poisoned
the real Lucy's medical record.
We have to go through
every medication,
every notation, every test
to determine whose is whose.
Doing that with zero tolerance
for errors could take six months.
Well, the paperwork is
our problem, not hers.
Not if the confusion results
in a harmful treatment
or incorrect diagnosis.
Well, we have to do something.
This poor woman
is in serious pain.
So we treat her.
Just be clever about it.
Shaun. Shaun, I've
already had two iced coffees.
Debbie. Hello, Debbie.
- You flirted with Dr. Glassman.
- Oh, my God.
So I have a new friend,
and he needs one, too.
- I'm so sorry.
- Okay, look, Dr. Glassman,
Debbie's facial proportions
are close to optimal, okay?
0.38 vertical and
0.48 horizontal.
- I'm so sorry.
- So you should find her attractive.
- Thank you?
- Shaun. I'm so sorry.
And I think you're both Jewish.
Tribal commonality is highly
conducive to social bonding.
Shalom.
Bullies can't put a
value on your smile,
nor can Dr. Murphy,
but it seems the
insurance company can.
They've agreed to pay $43,750,
about 85% of the entire cost.
I can cover the rest of that.
I swear.
Oh, sweetie, please,
let me do this for you.
Okay.
"Jane Doe"?
That's the only way that
we can treat you right now.
Go home and get some rest.
The records department
will call you to sort all this out.
A year ago, I was
playing tennis.
And then the shingles hit,
and I was laid up for six weeks.
And I've been on
pain meds ever since.
I lost my job. My husband
treats me like I'm an old lady,
and my daughter thinks I'm too
medicated to be around the new baby.
Maybe I'll be better
off as Jane Doe.
The impostor returns.
Lucy? Lucy, can you
squeeze my fingers?
"Lucy"?
She's in septic shock.
Order a lactate
level, blood cultures,
and a broad-spectrum antibiotic.
I'll tell Melendez we've
initiated the sepsis protocol.
We should report her. She's
a criminal and a flight risk.
And very, very sick.
We should put
someone outside her door
and arrest her
when she's stable.
We don't report patients
we find with drugs
or non-violent people with guns.
We do report people
who steal from us.
What would happen if
people who needed our help
thought they would be arrested?
If they thought they would
be arrested for stealing an ID,
maybe they wouldn't steal an ID.
I don't remember anything
in the Hippocratic Oath
about checking payer
sources before treatment.
Strongly suggesting there
was no health insurance
in fourth century BC Greece.
We have a duty to treat, and
we have the right to get paid.
But first things first. Oh, God.
Really do not wanna be sued
by either one of these women.
Maintain the pretense,
and as soon as she's stabilized,
we're gonna press charges.
Dr. Park, pull the
muscle, please.
We don't want any excess
gathering in the suture line.
Thank you.
Okay, remove retractors.
Ready?
Are you sure you don't
want something for the pain?
No. No, I'm good. As long
as you keep talking to me.
Especially if you share
something, uh, very painful.
- Painful?
- Mmm.
Okay.
Like the time I mistook
my biology teacher
for my girlfriend and
picked her up in the hallway.
Yeah. Twirled her around three
times before I realized my mistake.
That kind of painful?
You may have to dig
even deeper than that.
How about
the time I finally found
myself in the perfect situation?
You know, work, friends, future.
Something I never
really had before.
Maybe that's why
I screwed it up.
You're not responding to
the antibiotics like we'd hoped,
Lucy.
You know, don't you?
When the real Lucy Callard
showed up, it kind of gave you away.
Is there anyone we can contact?
Do you have any children?
A son.
But he'd be so ashamed of me.
- Where is he?
- College, first one in our family.
I had to choose between
premiums and tuition.
Your son is very lucky to
have such a loving mother.
I just wish you'd
got your antibiotics
when you got your pain meds.
I didn't get either medication.
Are you sure?
Because the real Lucy was
having problems with the pharmacy.
I didn't wanna risk
using the card again.
Is she okay?
Maybe it's time to move on,
take the lesson with you,
find new friends.
I went to Denver for
an interview last week.
And?
And we're done.
Really?
Take a look.
Hey, trust me.
See? Beautiful.
The kid, college, it's just
a convenient sob story.
Why would she lie
if she may be dying?
Here's what we don't
know about fake Lucy,
whether her story is true.
Here's what we do know.
She's a liar who just
found out she's busted.
Speaking of lies,
that shingles virus that
the real Lucy had last year?
According to Dr. Spindler
at Santa Clara General,
she had it the year before, too,
and, according to Dr. Millhouse
at SF Muni, the year before that.
She wasn't denied the pain
meds because of her impostor.
She was denied because
she is a garden-variety addict.
Well played, sir.
Dr. Park says the
surgery went well.
- It's been too long.
- What has?
She should be breathing
on her own by now.
Even after prolonged anesthesia,
it should only take
60 to 90 minutes.
Is she okay?
Mmm. She should have
protective airway reflexes,
motor activity, and a
return of consciousness.
I need to page
Dr. Andrews, stat.
- What's going on?
- Something bad.
Gretchen's glucose
is within normal limits,
and her electrolytes
are also normal.
And we've ruled out
hyper and hypothermia.
That doesn't leave much.
What about hypoxia?
She's maintained normal
oxygen as well as end-tidal CO2
throughout the entire case,
and we've given
her reversal agents,
which we will repeat.
Do you feel bad?
It's okay.
You told them it
was close to risk-free.
They knew there were
risks, and I told them, too.
Get a CT. Rule out clots,
hematoma, bleeding, and stroke.
WBCs and lactate are rising.
O2 sat and MAP are falling.
Sepsis protocol isn't working.
Multiple organ dysfunction
syndrome. Medications?
Add another antibiotic, uh,
continue crystalloids,
increase her vasopressors?
- Low-dose steroids?
- Give them all a try.
And intubate her
and insert a Swan.
And, yes, I understand
this is out of our own pocket.
Mmm.
Um, do anything
exciting for Purim?
Purim? Uh, no. Yeah.
You know, the usual.
Ate a little matzo
and celebrated our
exodus from slavery,
which I think is
Passover and not Purim.
Mmm.
Truth of the matter
is, I'm only half-Jewish,
so only half the knowledge.
The truth is, I'm
not Jewish at all.
Ah.
Yeah.
Yeah, my first husband was.
So I guess we have our lack
of Jewishness in common.
You know what, Debbie?
I think I should get going.
Okay. Well, it was nice, uh,
finally meeting you officially.
Same.
Oh, no, look at that.
A 1975 300D, one of the
most perfect Mercedes ever,
just got a little less perfect.
I beg to differ. If you're
looking for perfection,
you look no further
than the 1967 280SE.
- Cabriolet or coupe?
- The coupe, an all-time classic.
Well, an owner of a 300SL
Gullwing might argue otherwise.
- A Gullwing?
- Yeah.
Can I get you another coffee?
Yeah.
- Iced, large, black.
- That's it.
I know.
That's a little bit
unsettling, Murphy.
Hmm.
Okay.
Why are you studying the
current of ions during electrolysis?
Uh, it's not the chemical
kind of transference,
it's the doctor-patient kind.
I'm dealing with a
personal situation.
I don't think the
Internet is very helpful
for solving personal situations.
True.
But I can't exactly ask
Claire for her advice,
and I barely know
Park. And Morgan...
Morgan would be bad.
Very bad.
I'm a person.
Yeah. No, no, yeah, of course,
Shaun, I'd, uh... I'd love your advice.
Okay.
Uh, so I think Celez, my burn
patient, has feelings for me,
and I may have
feelings for her, too.
But there's a good chance
her feelings aren't real,
and if they are real, then
they may not be permanent.
You know, it's kind of
textbook transference.
She's grateful, and
she's vulnerable.
And all I've ever known in
my life is unrequited love.
From Claire and from my parents.
And that makes
me vulnerable, too.
You should call in sick.
Uh...
Lea says calling in
sick is all you need
to gain superior
wisdom and knowledge.
She was right.
The CT showed no abnormalities,
and the reversal agents have
been repeated without effect.
So what else could it be?
Anoxic brain injury,
a complication of anesthesia.
Unfortunately, we believe
your daughter is brain-dead.
What?
All for a smile.
I made her think she wasn't
good enough the way she was.
I should have listened to you.
Yes.
There's just no predicting how
individuals will react to anesthesia.
Huh.
Park. You just walked
out on that man.
The last thing a grieving
family member needs
is to see their doctor tap out.
Maybe she's still
under anesthesia.
Succinylcholine. It's
one of the anesthetics
- Gretchen was administered.
- Yeah.
Now, what if she has a plasma
cholinesterase deficiency?
It'd mean her body couldn't
break down that specific drug.
Complete deficiency
is extremely rare.
I've never personally seen it,
and I don't know anyone who has.
Yeah, but if she does have
it, she's just gonna wake up.
Should I tell her father?
No, not yet. No way we're
letting him grieve twice.
Your labs are not improving.
Your organs are shutting down.
You're running out of time.
I'd like to stop
calling you Lucy.
You're welcome, Beatrice.
What are you doing?
Corneal reflex.
It's mediated by the nasociliary
branch of the ophthalmic branch.
What does it mean?
It means we were wrong.
She's gonna be just fine.
Thank you, Doctor.
Thank you.
Thank you. Oh.
Thank you, Dr. Murphy.
Honey, you're gonna be
okay. You're gonna be just fine.
I was drawing a bath, and
I leaned over to turn it off,
and I dropped the pill bottle.
- And before I could fish it out...
- All the pills were ruined.
So you need a refill?
My pain has made me so clumsy.
Lucy, you're a liar
and a cheat and an addict.
We know about the
frequent prescriptions,
the multiple doctors, and
the ever-recurring shingles.
You have a serious
medical problem.
Let me help you.
- Three months?
- Hopefully.
But we might be able to
give you a pretty good idea
of what you're gonna look like.
Those things by your
ears are neuro-stimulators.
When we activate them,
instant smile. Sound good?
Dr. Murphy?
It's your mother's smile.
She seemed like a good template.
Hmm. There is no Duchenne
marker. Her smile is not real.
Thank you.
But all the other ones are.
All the other ones are.
I spoke with Jim Ransler,
who made it very clear that
we owe him big time for this.
Don't worry, Marcus.
I can handle him.
I'm very impressed.
It was all very
presidential of you.
You really went
above and beyond.
Yes, I did.
I thought I was saving her
life. Instead, I nearly ended it.
Celez, hi.
This is the
brilliant Dr. Murphy.
He'll be assuming
your care from here on,
though I don't expect
you'll need much.
I understand.
I don't think you do.
You see, doctors aren't
allowed to date their patients.
What are you doing tomorrow?
Uh, I'm calling in sick.
I think you may still
have some friends here.
Guess there is one
upside to all this.
If she hadn't bought the
stolen insurance card,
the real Lucy wouldn't
be in rehab right now.
You were surprisingly nice.
I told her what she
needed to hear to get help.
Trust me, I get it.
Too soft, people
take advantage of you.
But with your badass upbringing,
no one messes with you.
Upsides everywhere.
I mean, you have way
more street cred than, say,
someone whose mom's a
Johns Hopkins cardiologist,
whose dad is a pathologist,
and whose parents have been
happily married for 37 years.
Coming from
privilege, zero respect.
It must be really
hard to overcome.
- I'll call a code.
- No.
There's nothing left to save.
Time of death, 8:14 pm.
I'll notify her son.
We're gonna show
you that we're tough
Y'all gonna stand
We'll get back up
Yeah, we're gonna
show you what we've got
Oh, hey. Um...
My homies decided to pop by
and play some Texas Hold'em,
so I'm gonna have to take a
rain check on that pizza night.
You got a 70-inch
flat-screen, too.
Uh, no. I borrowed yours.
Makes no sense for us
both to have one, right?
Plus, my homies got to
watch March Madness.
- Okay.
- Oh. Um, sorry, amigo.
It's four-player Texas Hold'em.
I don't like poker anyway.
Hey, Shaun.
Look, you're a great guy, um,
but you got a few,
like, quirks, you know?
And that... It doesn't really
jive with this kind of face time.
You get what I'm saying, right?
I love you, man.
I once drove a
300SL... Thank you.
A 300SL Gullwing.
- On the road?
- No.
For 200 feet at the
Concours d'Elegance.
Oh, in Pebble Beach?
That's just as cool.
- The car show, you know it.
- Of course, yeah.
This year they're featuring a
Rollston coachwork display.
Including the Mercedes SS?
- I don't know.
- Ah.
But we should find out.
Wanna go?
I couldn't.
Yeah, no, I... Why?
No reason.
I just... I just thought that I
should make that my first response
before I accepted.
Can I get you anything else?
No, thank you. We'll
just take the doorstop.
I'm sorry. Um...
Well, you can
bring the doorstop.
Aaron?
Sorry. Um...
The thing...
The thing that tells
you how much to pay.
The doorstop.
Uh...
Could you call a...
- Can you call an ambulance, please?
- Mmm-hmm.
Thank you.