I found a clinical trial.
Precision-targeted
immunotherapy.
It's led by Dr. Panthaki
at St. Simon's.
He's highly regarded.
And, unlike radiation and chemo,
it comes with no
debilitating side effects.
That sounds perfect.
It's exactly what he wanted.
All right. Dr. Sharpe
gets it done.
Which is the difference
between me and this trial.
Because precision
therapy might not work.
Your objection is noted. Again.
Yes, radiation
chemotherapy is challenging,
but it's... It's brutal.
It's hitting yourself with a
brick over and over again
and hoping the cancer
dies first. That's the point.
The cancer dies.
Radiation and chemotherapy work.
Precision therapy is like
gambling your life on a lottery ticket.
People said the same thing
about bone marrow transplants.
They also say it
about lottery tickets.
Enough.
Is this what you really want?
She's right.
Chemo and radiation, they work.
They do the job.
But they'll break me.
No matter how strong I
am. I'll lose my hearing.
My sight.
I'll lose my mind.
They don't always come back.
And I have so many things
that I need to do.
So let's get in the trial.
Uh, so? What?
Sorry, I didn't see you there.
You know what, an email would
have covered it, maybe even a text.
But now we're here in person
you should definitely be groveling.
Evie and I were up
all night. You stallion.
Fighting. Look, I'm not
trying to be a jerk here,
but telling Evie
that we used to...
I know. It wasn't cool.
I said I know.
What you should be
saying is, "I am sorry."
I am. I'm sorry.
You don't sound sorry.
Look, can we just not
have this be a thing, okay?
You know what, you're the one
who said that we can be friends.
This doesn't feel like friends.
Early morning
rush started early.
You got some nerve.
It's French vanilla.
Like hell it is.
Eh, maybe hazelnut?
You're mothering
me or babying me.
Whichever one it is, stop it.
Are you okay?
You're doing it again.
What do we got? This
is LaDavius Powell,
45-year-old man with new
onset right-side abdominal pain.
No meds, no past medical
history, allergic to Cephalkem.
Cephalkem? Fancy penicillin.
Bay 23, step lively. Cephalkem.
Sarah Madsen, 36-year-old
woman, found down on the sidewalk.
Unresponsive, hypotensive.
BP 90 over palp, heart rate 120.
Said New Amsterdam
was her hospital.
Okay, looks like previous heart
surgery. Find her medical records.
Drew this in the field.
Why is the blood so diluted?
No idea. No sign of bleeding.
The blood's gotta be going
somewhere. Page Dr. Sharpe.
We gotta get on this or
she's not gonna make it.
Maximus, today is one of those days
that makes it all worth it, you know?
It's one of those days you jump out of
bed excited because you just know...
It's gonna be one of those
days. Yes! Yes, in a big, big way.
Are you feeling it
too? I am feeling it.
I got a meeting with the nurses'
union about insurance and birth control.
So not so much. Nah, it'll
be good. What do you got?
Me, I have a transitioning
teen coming in with his parents.
And you know how society
is not kind to trans teens.
Bullying, cultural stigma, hate
crimes, which all leads to depression,
which way too often
leads to suicide...
Sorry, this is your happy day?
No, no, my happy day is what happens
when these kids get to feel heard.
Today I get to help somebody
find out who they are.
I get to help somebody
find their voice.
Happy day indeed. Indeed.
Yeah, so I'm good with
the whole voice thing,
like, got it, found it.
Fine with it. I've got
other issues here.
Oh.
Okay.
Uh, what are they?
Exhibit those. Parents.
All right.
Jillian, Grant?
Care to elaborate?
Well, Dr. Frome, Shay says
he's ready for top surgery.
But we... They
won't let me get it.
I mean, how's that
for withholding?
Shay, that's not fair.
We have concerns.
See, Doc?
Issues. I mean,
help me out here.
Nuclear Medicine,
please call extension 29.
We could do a
sit-in. At shift change.
Bigger. Picket HCC's offices.
Bigger. You want to keep
your birth control coverage?
Then kick 'em where it
hurts. Excuse me, Max,
can I have a word
please? All right.
Keep thinking.
Kick some ass for
the working class!
Did you hear from Dr. Panthaki?
No, this isn't about the trial.
Dr. Bloom asked me to
consult on a hematology patient.
Turns out that she was a heart
transplant recipient here, 27 years ago.
And?
Her file says that she received
her heart from a "Luna Goodwin."
Your sister.
She's fading fast.
We've already infused
two units of packed red cells
with a pressure bag but
she's still net negative.
I would give her a plasma expander,
but her hematocrit's already in the toilet.
I mean, that's just gonna
make it crash even more.
The usual
production-destruction algorithm
doesn't seem to apply to her.
Let's order up two more
units from the blood bank
and let's get a second
large bore IV line.
Give me a little
Trendelenburg. How can I help?
That's where all the blood
is going. Sarah's right thigh.
Why is she bleeding in the first
place? There's no localized source.
No cuts, lacerations,
blown arterial aneurysm?
No, every organ just
seems to be oozing blood.
Elevated PTT? It's barely
out of the normal range.
Yeah, but put that together
with why she's bleeding so much.
Acquired hemophilia?
Her clotting factor eight isn't
working. That's why she's bleeding.
Rare, but it would
explain it. That's good.
I'm really thirsty.
Uh, uh... She's thirsty. Can
we get her some water, nurse?
Ah, let's hold off on
that. Uh, Ms. Madsen, I...
I had a heart transplant. At
my last check-up my doctor said
that my cyclosporine
levels were low
and I've been worried that
my body's rejecting my heart.
Could that be causing this?
That wouldn't explain the bleeding.
But it might explain why the
bleeding's been making you so sick.
How sick am I?
I'm afraid acquired
hemophilia is quite serious.
But we're gonna fix it, okay?
Uh, nurses are gonna
take you up to ICU right now.
We're gonna start treatment
and you're gonna do great.
Thank you.
Are you okay?
Uh, once the bleeding is stabilized,
get me a transvenous heart biopsy.
Tell me everything
you can about that heart.
Max.
You type so fast!
Like Matthew
Broderick in WarGames.
No idea who or what that is.
Boom. Now you're on Twitter.
See? That's me right there.
@ShayMyName2018?
Yeah. Silly name, I know.
You have 27,000 followers?
Yeah. Crazy, right?
They've been following me since
the beginning of my transition.
It's a... It's a real
community. They support me.
Keep me real. I had no idea.
Yeah, they can't wait
for me to get top surgery.
Now we're just waiting for
Dr. Frome to, you know, do his thing.
You don't understand.
We love Shay.
We have been supportive of
his transition from the beginning.
The new haircut,
the new clothes.
Even the hormone blockers.
We never pushed back, not once.
But surgery? It's so permanent.
Well, you know, um...
Top surgery is the most common
gender-confirmation surgery for trans men.
Having a body that
doesn't reflect your gender...
That can be deeply unsettling.
Of course. We know.
It's just... Okay,
I'm just gonna say it.
He's not even old
enough to drive a car.
He's not old enough to
get into R-rated movies,
and he's not old enough to decide
on his own to get permanent surgery.
It's okay, it's okay. This is exactly
where we can talk about all of this.
So why don't you guys
tell me a little bit about Shay
before he came out?
It was hard.
He was anxious all the time.
Sometimes he had
trouble getting out of bed.
What about after he
started to socially transition?
He started smiling.
Making friends.
And when he started
the hormone blockers,
he said he felt like
himself for the first time.
Yeah.
My baby was 14, and he
had never felt like himself.
And we're grateful he does.
But when we said no to
surgery, you know what he did?
He threw a GoFundMe on Twitter
to ask his followers
to pay for it.
And they did.
We're proud that he is
a voice for a community.
But he's just a kid.
Our kid.
Please tell him
he can't do this.
All right, I understand
that you are overwhelmed.
But the positive changes
in Shay since transitioning
are undeniable.
And emotionally,
I gotta say, I think the
emotions that matter most here
are his. So...
I am going to approve a
medical evaluation for surgery.
My son has been
sober for a year.
Oh, that's terrific.
He has shown great strength.
More than I knew he had.
I should have had more faith.
It's never too late. Peanuts?
Barbecue or Tangy Fiesta?
Tangy Fiesta.
I would like to
give Rohan a gift.
Show my support. Yeah.
But recently my gifts have
been completely misunderstood.
I hear that, and families
see agendas in everything.
What you thinking?
An apartment.
Just a small one.
Nothing too fancy.
Yeah, you wouldn't want
to spoil him with a fancy one.
I have been a doctor
for the last 40 years.
I've had more money
than I know what to do with.
It's a beautiful idea.
Use your money to help
someone you care about.
What else is it for, right?
Hey. Hey. Thanks for coming.
Is that her? MAX: Mmm.
She had the transplant here.
She's been coming back ever since.
I didn't even know
Luna was an organ donor.
It probably wasn't the easiest
thing for your parents to talk about.
My parents didn't even
take me to the funeral.
They just kind of shut the door.
Hey.
Have you told her who you are?
No, she has enough on her mind.
It's not about me.
Isn't it?
Luna's heart
is beating.
Right over there.
And the amazing thing is,
she gets another chance.
Thirty years ago, the doctors
here let Luna's heart stop.
Not this time.
Hey. Uh, Evie.
Sorry to bother you.
Slogging through the
madness of malpractice claims.
Oh, not my department, I hope.
I always hide the
bodies when I'm done.
I... That was not
even a little bit funny.
Okay, uh, listen.
The other day when I mentioned
that Reynolds and I, we...
We kind of had this, uh,
fling?
That was, uh...
That was bad form.
To bring that up. I mean,
I totally betrayed the
sisterhood of
sisters.
Or whatever.
I think you and Reynolds
are perfect for each other.
I mean, that's why I
introduced the two of you, so...
Let me bail you out here.
Oh, great, please hurry.
I know Floyd had
a life before me.
I'm glad he did.
I just need to know
if you two are over.
Oh! Oh, we're over.
We are the very
definition of over.
I like Floyd.
But I've made bad bets before.
So if you really are a card-carrying
member of the sisterhood of sisters,
you won't let me do it again.
Because I do not have time.
So are you and Floyd done?
Evie.
It is not something that you
have to worry about. Okay?
Then I won't.
Okay.
That looks fun.
This infusion replaces the clotting
factor that your body is destroying.
So you can just replace
it? It's that simple?
Unfortunately, it's
not simple at all.
Uh, but it's very doable.
It's been done
successfully many times.
We need to infuse the factor
at the exact same rate that
your body is destroying it,
which is an incredibly
difficult rate to find.
But again, doable.
Too much factor and
your blood will clot.
You could suffer a stroke.
Or a heart attack.
Too little and you could
start to bleed again.
Which we won't let happen. I'll be
doing a blood test called the PTT.
I'll be drawing it from the
central line every 20 minutes,
and then based on the results,
I will adjust the rate of infusion.
Will that take a long time?
Yes, it will. Hopefully not.
It's not something that
we can definitively know.
Yeah, but however
long it may take,
I will be here by your side
night and day
till we get it right.
Why me?
Excuse me?
Well, um, you're the Medical
Director of the entire hospital.
You're dropping
everything for me, Dr., uh...
Uh... Goodwin, Max.
Um...
Just an interesting case.
Dr. Goodwin, Dr. Sharpe.
Could I have a minute?
Excuse us.
I, uh, got the results
from Sarah's heart biopsy.
The heart muscle showed both
fibrosis and T-lymphocyte infiltration.
It's Grade 4.
Well, it doesn't get much worse.
Okay, so we up the
cyclosporine dose.
Why would we...
If we up the dose
and we add pulse steroids. And
we look for an anti T-cell agent...
That's out of the question.
Look, the stress from Sarah's
hemophilia has ravaged her heart.
So un-ravage it. I gave you a
whole cardio department, use it,
because we sure as hell
aren't going to just sit here
while... What? Max.
Luna's heart is dying.
It's gone.
That's my sister's heart.
We have to save it.
No.
We have to save Sarah.
And the only thing that's
gonna do that is a new heart.
Because the old
one is out of time.
The waiting list for heart
transplants isn't short,
but the good news
is you're at the top.
And priority goes to
the most severe cases
that can withstand a transplant.
Wow. That's, uh, great. Also...
Totally terrifying.
Right. So...
OTF gets us a heart,
we fix the hemophilia
and you walk out of here.
That's the plan.
I like the plan.
Me too, so...
Hang in there.
Question.
Sorry, this is kind of weird.
No. I'm your doctor,
you can ask me anything.
Did you have a sister?
You're Luna's brother.
How did you know?
Your sister gave me her heart.
My folks told me all about her.
Her family.
When you said your name, I...
It didn't seem, uh, fair to
say anything. You
need to focus on you.
And, uh, really,
we are strangers.
I mean, we've never
even met before.
Yeah, we did.
You don't remember?
Sorry, no. Where did we meet?
We met in Cold Spring.
Wow. I haven't thought
about Cold Spring in years.
We used to go there on the
weekends. There was this dock.
My sister and I would jump
off and we thought we were,
you know,
cliff divers. We loved it.
Yeah, I know.
That's, uh...
That's where I saw you.
At Luna's funeral.
No, I...
I didn't go to the funeral.
You did.
It was in Cold Spring a
week after the transplant.
After the funeral, I, uh...
I saw you on that dock.
Skipping stones.
Well, you were trying to
skip stones. You were...
You were really bad at it.
So I went up and I asked
you how the stones were going.
You said... I'll never forget.
Your sister promised to teach
you the next time you came.
It was the first time it hit me.
I was only here 'cause
another girl wasn't.
So I showed you.
You taught me
how to skip stones.
Yeah.
I got Mad Libs.
I just... I couldn't believe
they still publish these.
See anything you like?
My patient needs a study
that's going to deliver results.
I'm more intrigued
by what I don't see.
Definitive conclusions.
Well, my sample size isn't large
enough for that kind of certainty,
but I like where we're heading.
Strong words
from someone failing
more than he succeeds.
It's cancer. I'll take
any wins I can get.
And each success gets
me a little closer to a cure.
You know what they say. Close only
counts in horseshoes and hand grenades.
And a couple other things.
You must know your
reputation precedes you.
My reputation for
exceptional results?
Your reputation for
exceptional charisma
and aptitude for salesmanship.
And I am immune.
Because I have
the same reputation.
I'm only paying
attention to the numbers.
You got your file upside down.
Made you look.
What would you say
to somebody who says
you sell quixotic hope in
lieu of medical certainty?
I'd say that someone is right.
Clinical trials are
riskier than chemo.
They're also the only way to
find a treatment better than chemo.
Yeah, they're
quixotic, and, yeah,
most of the time it doesn't
work. But when it does,
it's gonna change the world.
But it may never work.
Even Don Quixote hit
a couple of windmills.
He lunged at one and then
promptly fell off his horse.
How soon will you know
if my patient's eligible?
Max Goodwin.
You're treating your boss.
No, I'm treating my patient,
who also happens to be my friend.
I have to warn you, I don't accept
patients based on prominence.
The integrity of the
study is too important.
Of course.
And at first glance,
this is not a great fit.
That's not a "no."
Give me a beat, let me
get into it. I'll get back to you.
Thank you for your honesty.
And you for yours.
Even though you
were a little bit mean.
Okay. This is you.
Do you mind if I Insta this?
What the heck. Yeah.
Just no video, okay?
All right, so. Do you see the
dark spots here on the ends?
Those are your
epiphyseal plates.
That's the stuff inside your
bones that does all the growing.
Now, looking at this, we can estimate
more or less how much more growing
you are going to do.
So how tall am I gonna be?
I'm pleased to report, tall.
Not NBA tall. But,
you know, top shelf tall.
#Topshelftall...
Yes, you are in very good health,
Shay. All the doctors here agree
that you will be a prime candidate
for top surgery in about a year.
A year?
Yeah. I mean, I know you were
hoping for something a little sooner,
but, uh, we have to take medical
into consideration. It's surgery.
Now you sound
just like my parents.
Listen, you've only been on
hormone blockers for about six months.
We need to see how it
affects your breast tissue
before we can decide which
surgery will be right for you.
So a cisgender doctor gets
to tell me what's right for me.
Okay. Got it.
Got it.
All right. I hear
that you're upset,
but I need you to hear me when I tell
you that I want you to have the surgery.
I said so to your parents.
Screw this, and screw you.
Okay.
Okay, thanks.
Bye.
What's wrong? Oh, I'm fine.
Please, what's the
matter? Nope, it's nothing.
Honestly.
My dog, Gertie, has cancer.
I'm so sorry.
Is there anything
to be done? No.
I mean, surgery, but...
It costs more than
I make in a month.
I'm gonna have to put my little girl to
sleep unless I can come up with $2,000.
I'm sorry.
You do not need to
be thinking about this.
I'm fine, thank you.
Hey, Becky, I'm gonna take five.
Okay, we're starting to back up down
here. Turan, help me clear some space.
What do you got? Got an
upper GI bleeder in curtains.
Waiting on GI.
Hemodynamically stable?
Yes. Then send him home.
He can get a scope
as an outpatient.
And a weak and dizzy in
Bay 13. I'll meet you there.
Surgery cleared him for
conservative treatment.
Okay.
We're gonna treat you
with medicine, Mr. Powell.
No surgery. So we'll get you out
of here real soon. Sound good?
Sound good? Mmm-hmm.
And we'll give you
something for the nausea.
Start Cephalkem, and when he
can eat and drink, he can go home.
Casey, did you
give Mr. Powell...
Levofloxacin plus metronidazole.
Just like you said.
Right. Just like I said.
Great.
Need me to make
any other adjustments?
No.
Thank you again, Dr. Kleinman.
I know that this is moving fast,
but Sarah Madsen's case is
the definition of time-sensitive.
Mmm-hmm. I've spoken to one
of your reps over at OTF already
and they have agreed to move
Sarah to the top of the transplant list.
Mmm. We have a viable
donor in our ICU right now,
a brain-dead MVA, actually.
And so go ahead and
say the word, and we...
I'm going to stop
you right there.
Okay?
I'm certainly impressed
with your due diligence.
Your patient's hemophilia
is too compromising.
She isn't healthy enough
to receive a new heart.
I'm very sorry.
No, so, uh... Wait a
minute, wait a minute.
On paper, yes.
I see what you see.
But, this woman...
This woman, she can do this.
Believe me. Will you tell her?
Her INR and creatinine
clearance are normal.
Hepatic function excellent.
Her kidneys are fine.
Right, and she has never shown
any signs of bone marrow suppression.
Dr. Goodwin,
this isn't personal.
OTF has strict requirements
to ensure healthy organs
are not placed into bodies
that cannot support them.
Plain and simple. Sarah
Madsen does not qualify.
No, wait, wait, wait.
Sorry.
There has gotta be
something that I can do
to convince you to
give Sarah this heart.
She needs to complete
three normal-range PTT tests
in a row. Consider it done.
She's not gonna make
it, Max. Yeah, well,
it's gonna be hard...
She could barely pass
one PTT three hours ago.
The chances of her passing three
in a row before her heart gives out?
So... You said that passing
one of these tests would be hard.
It will be.
Well, I freaking
hate failing tests.
Oh, yeah, like you'd know.
My wife seems like
this cool New York chick.
"Oh, I'm a social worker.
"Look at my cool haircut."
Okay. Okay, you know,
you dye your hair purple once,
you never hear the end of it.
But she is a nerd.
She has never failed a test.
Not once in her whole life.
The X means a failed PTT, so...
We'll try again.
Hey.
Hey. Forget it.
What? Wait.
We, uh... We need to talk about
what happened with Mr. Powell.
What I did with Mr. Powell.
That was, uh...
That was unacceptable.
Are you
angry? I'm not angry.
Why are you standing there with
a face like I just kicked your dog?
It's just my face.
Hey, I am trying
to apologize here.
Okay, I'm sorry. I...
I do apologize, okay?
You came through huge for me
today, and if you hadn't, then...
I would never have
forgiven myself. Okay?
It won't happen again.
You know I'm not that kind of
doctor... It's happened before.
What? I correct your EMRs.
Put patient notes
on the right charts.
Pull doubles when you
leave holes in scheduling.
Okay, well, that's just paperwork.
That's not exhaustion. That's normal.
Okay? So once or twice I
screw up some red tape...
It happens all the time.
And it's been getting worse.
No. That can't be right.
Dr. Bloom...
I think you may need help.
I'm just tired, okay?
Just an RX from
Dr. Sleep and I'll...
Mr. Powell could have died.
Gladys, yes, I knew
you'd come around.
This falafel is a revelation.
Something may have
happened on the Internet.
Okay, well, the Internet
is a big place, Gladys.
Might want to be a
little more specific.
"Dr. Frome blocked
my top surgery.
"Dr. Iggy Frome hates
the trans community."
What? What is that?
Tweets. Tweets?
"What a typical
white cis-male move.
"Dr. Frome's nothing
but a transphobic loser."
What? Give me
that. Let me see that.
And there are so many more.
Like, hundreds of them.
Before you say anything,
I would like to pretend
that earlier never happened.
Ella. Uh, cappuccino,
extra dry. Coming up.
Uh, you have any
nice evening plans?
What is this? Please.
Oh.
Oh, Dr. Kapoor,
I can't take that.
For Gertie. No. No.
I can't. That's too much.
I was told to use my money
to help people I care about.
What else is this for?
Please.
Thank you.
Dr. Stiles to the Trauma Center.
I picked a bad time
to start failing tests.
I'm not giving up. Are you?
You need to know it's okay.
What's okay?
That I'm gonna die.
No.
No. See, I'm a maestro at this.
So you're not gonna...
Right after my transplant,
my dad asked me what I'd
want to do if I could do anything.
I said I wanted to be a pirate.
So my parents sold
a car, got a loan,
and we spent a month
on a boat in the Bahamas.
It was insane.
We couldn't afford it.
But at the end of that trip
I wasn't a sick kid anymore.
You know why I
wanted to be a pirate?
Me neither.
I never did before the
surgery. I always thought
maybe it was Luna.
I have to tell you,
Luna's heart didn't always
have the best taste in guys.
But it skipped a beat
when she met Andy.
It's like she picked
him out just for me.
Me and Luna learned
what it felt like to be in love.
I have a job where
I help people.
I've been all over the world.
I ran a half-marathon even
though people told me not to.
Last year I won a
watermelon-eating contest.
Which is a real
thing and I love them.
That's why it's okay.
If it's time for me to go.
Your sister...
She gave me a beautiful life.
It's the other way around.
There's a rhythm
in rush these days
Where the lights don't move
and the colors don't fade
Sometimes there's
things a man cannot know
Gears won't turn and
the train won't leave
I will stay with you tonight
There is a truth
and it's on our side
Dawn is coming open your eyes
Look into the sun
as the new days rise
There's a rhythm
in rush these days
Look into the sun
as a new days rise
You just lost a follower.
Okay.
I saw what you
said about me online.
I was, um, surprised.
My husband read those tweets.
My co-workers. My friends.
And if you google me right now,
that is the number
one thing that pops up.
Shay, I'm not here to shame you.
I'm not here to yell at you. But
I would like you to look at me.
Please.
Do you really think
that I'm anti-trans?
I knew it would make
people upset when I posted it.
But I did it anyways.
I don't even really
know why I posted it.
Yeah, social media's weird.
You know, it's like,
we're not even us
when we're on it.
It's like we're the thing
that we wish we were.
Or even worse,
we're the thing that we
think others want us to be.
Yeah, I scrolled
through your tweets.
It's powerful stuff.
I guess.
No, no, it's easy to see why
you have so many followers.
It's pretty intense.
I think it was your GoFundMe
campaign for your surgery
that really put you on the map.
You got a lot of followers
that are very excited about that.
So...
The rush for surgery,
the anger when I
advised you to wait...
Do you think maybe that's really
more about you being scared
to let your followers down?
They're all counting on me to
get it, and I told them I would.
I mean, now if I
make them wait, it's...
Let 'em wait. I mean...
Shay, I'm not... I'm not telling you
anything you don't already know.
How and when you
transition is about you.
You're not gonna let some
troll bully you out of a choice.
So you can't let
the fans do it either.
Even the ones that mean well.
And, dude, I'm telling you,
you are going to have exactly
zero problems helping
people understand.
You are extremely
gifted at Twitter.
As my Google hits would prove.
And, hey, in a year,
if you want the surgery,
I'll be right there with you.
Doctor.
You all right?
It's not something you
have to worry about.
Come on, Sarah. Just one more.
You can do it, Sarah.
Sarah.
You're a very good brother.
Nobody has ever said that to me.
Sarah.
You did it.
You did it!
Um, um... Can I get
the transplant team?
Now! Max.
Okay, we gotta
get... What? What?
Here, listen to her.
Listen.
Luna.
She did it.
Come here.
Hello? Sharpe?
Panthaki. Got good
news and good news.
Dr. Goodwin is a
candidate for therapy.
He'll be thrilled to hear it.
What's the other good news?
I'm on my way to your office.
You are?
I have to pick up his cell samples
and give you some paperwork.
Oh, well, I'm sure we can
have someone pick that up.
It's too risky.
See, this paperwork includes two
tickets to see Lauryn Hill at BAM.
Hey, if I was off-base
here, I apologize. I just, um...
I was just thinking about
what to do with the extra ticket.
Well, I might have a suggestion.
Dr. Mendez, ER 1.
Dr. Mendez to ER 1.
How's she doing?
Really well.
Thanks to you. Good.
The next few weeks are
critical, so stay close to her.
And keep us informed.
My wife is an optimist.
And the minute she found out
that it was your sister,
she had me arrange this.
It's her way of
thanking you both.
Oh, I've just come
from the land of the sun
From a war that must be won
In the name of truth
With our soldiers so brave
Your freedom we will save
With our rifles and grenades
And some help from God
I want to see my family
My wife and child waiting for me
I've got to go home I've
been so alone, you see
You just can't believe
the joy I did receive
When I finally got my
leave and I was going home
Oh, I flew through the sky
my convictions could not lie
And I want to see my family
Max?
Oh, my God.
Max.
Max! Hey!
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God.
Help!
Somebody!
Anyone!
Oh, my God.
Anyone...
Help!