Previously, on
"The Resident"...
Dad,
what's going on?
I think I have a little flu,
that's all.
I need to get you
into the OR immediately.
I'll do whatever
you say.
You put a patient
at risk of getting COVID.
He won't get COVID
because my OR is spotless.
This is day five
with the same mask.
I've put in an emergency order,
and it turns out
this shipment
is on its way.
You said
Red Rock wouldn't pay.
They won't.
But they did.
Don't worry,
I'm not expecting anything...
You may now enjoy your first kiss
as husband and wife.
I feel like we've done
the research,
and the results
are in.
Sex is better
when you're married.
Was there a concern
that it wouldn't be?
No, I just didn't think
it could possibly get
any better, but it did.
Nice recovery.
We need to get going.
Five more minutes
in the love bubble.
Fine, five more minutes.
But then you gotta
get your ass out of bed.
You've got that meeting.
♪ Taste of romance ♪
♪ Taste of romance... ♪
Had we recklessly hopped
into bed two years ago,
who knows where
we'd be right now?
Agreed.
And we'll restrain ourselves
in public
to keep this...
Whatever this is...
Uh... private?
Agreed.
♪ Run your fingers soft... ♪
Are you just going to agree
with everything I say?
Please don't tell me
you're losing your edge,
Andre Jeremiah.
Oh, please.
Losing my edge
is the last thing
you have to be worried about,
Mina Okafor.
♪ The current in your head. ♪
♪
Dr. Voss,
how would you describe
Logan Kim's performance
as CEO during the pandemic?
Reprehensible.
He tried to coerce our surgeons
to perform elective surgeries
while they were prohibited
for the safety
of staff and patients,
all in the name of
the bottom line.
Logan did everything
he could to keep Chastain afloat.
Unfortunately, not everyone was
willing to follow his lead.
Thank you, Dr. Cain.
I've never thought much
off Logan Kim.
He's a garden-variety
company man.
I don't really have much
to say about him.
Except, when the pandemic hit,
we needed PPE.
He promised he'd bend the rules
to find the money, and he did.
It's the one time
he earned my respect.
- Hey.
- Good to see you, man.
- You, too.
- You just get back?
- Yeah.
How was the memorial?
It was sad, but it was nice
to see my relatives.
Now it's time
to move forward.
- How's your mom?
- Um, up and down, you know.
But how about you guys?
How was the honeymoon
in, uh, Key West?
It must have been
awesome.
Did you waste
away in Margaritaville?
Yes.
Yeah, we did,
- and it was awesome.
- Excuse me. I need some help.
My boss is sick. Please come
outside, it's an emergency.
We were on our way
to a fundraiser,
I insisted we stop.
She's burning up, coughing.
Can't keep anything in her.
Doctors, I have too much
to do today to be sick.
I need you all to work fast
and get me back out there.
Now.
Let's get her into the ER.
Syncopal episode,
incoming to a trauma bay.
Devon,
it's Congresswoman Randall.
♪ ♪
*The Resident*
Season 04  Episode 02
Episode Title: "Mina's Kangaroo Court"
Aired on: January 19, 2021
How long have you had
that pain, Congresswoman?
Please, call me Nichelle.
A few days.
Started with the fevers,
diarrhea.
Which is why you collapsed.
You're severely dehydrated.
Do you think I have a flu,
or is it something I ate?
It's not COVID.
I was vaccinated.
James mentioned a cough
as well.
Anything else we should know?
Underlying conditions
you're aware of?
Medications you're currently
taking?
She hugs or shakes hands
with everyone she meets.
And she works too hard.
Because of Governor Wayne's
tragic fishing accident...
May he rest in peace...
I am running in
a special election to be
the first Black female governor
of Georgia.
So, yes,
I hug the people.
Push. Push.
Push, push, push. Good.
James, call the office.
I do not want
any of the staff
coming down here.
"Loving mankind is not enough.
You have to love
the individual."
Best speech at the convention.
Thank you.
I hate to interrupt
Dr. Hawkins' fanboy moment,
but has there been
any recent travel
not related to the election?
I-I went to a yoga retreat
in Kentucky,
of all places,
along the Ohio River.
Okay. There's a fungal infection
that's common
in that region;
It's called histoplasmosis.
It might explain your symptoms.
We'll look into it.
But don't worry, it's
treatable. We'll send out for cultures,
get you on antibiotics
and antifungals
just to cover our bases.
If it is histo, we'll get you
back on the campaign trail ASAP.
But we are gonna
admit you.
We gotta be safe.
And for the record,
Congresswoman...
Uh-uh. Nichelle.
I insist.
Conrad. I insist.
- Is the congresswoman okay?
- Yeah.
Well, on the off chance
she needs an organ,
I'm happy to donate.
By the way, your husband
over here geeked out on her.
Wow, "husband."
I don't know that
I'll ever get used to that.
And the congresswoman's husband,
Tom Randall,
is at a golf tournament
in Hawaii.
He won't be here
until tomorrow.
Ooh, Tom Randall is my top
fantasy dinner party invite.
Falcons' greatest quarterback,
Hall of Famer.
Denied a Super Bowl victory
by the worst call in history.
Wow, you are a big
Tom Randall groupie, huh?
Everything will be ready
in about five minutes.
Meet you guys down there.
- You stabbed me in the back.
- I told the truth.
The truth you knew
would get me fired.
No. I told them
you did a good thing.
You listened to your
better angels
when you got us that PPE,
so I appealed to theirs.
Well, you're gonna find yourself
- incredibly disappointed.
- Let me explain something to you.
I know what I stand for.
I know what I'm fighting for.
You could have actually
done some good here.
You could have stood
with me.
But you let Red Rock infect you.
So I did you a favor today.
I saved you
from a disease.
Getting fired can be
a beautiful thing, trust me.
Now you and I have that
in common.
Hey.
Hang on tight, Dr. Hawkins.
It's going to get...
even uglier around here.
Trust me.
These were our
colleagues and our friends.
Health care workers who died
in the line of duty from COVID.
I hope we never have to
put another face
or name on this memorial.
You know,
I was with Nurse Garner
when he passed away.
Heartbreaking.
Such a lovely man.
I-I had to go out and tell
his enormous entourage...
Wife, kids, parents,
siblings, friends... I...
It's a life cut short
but certainly well-lived.
And you know, I don't know
if I was...
if I was feeling envy or...
or jealousy,
but I-I mean, I just,
I have to admit I...
I wish I had even a small part
of what he had.
In the very distant future,
when you're on your deathbed,
I and every one
of your friends here
who you haven't outlived...
will be at your bedside.
Well, I appreciate it.
I've just come to regret some of
the bridges I've burned,
the people I've hurt,
that's all.
Figure out who's worth
fighting for
to get back in your life
and get after it already.
Sat's 85.
You're not getting enough
oxygen. We need you
- off the phone...
- Senator Buxton,
I'd like to put you
on the phone
with one of your constituents.
Her name is Bianca.
She is a hardworking young woman
who can't afford childcare.
Yeah, tell her what you just
told me.
Sat's down to 83.
Nichelle!
I don't feel right.
What's happening?
Devon?
Devon.
Devon, give me the mask.
Let's get another X-ray, okay?
She's a little wheezy.
How about some nebs?
Mr. Mullins here came in with a
few weeks of worsening dyspnea.
And look at this.
Right axis deviation.
Right heart strain pattern.
And evidence of pulmonary
hypertension on bedside echo.
Also complained of
some dizziness,
so I sent him through
the answer box, which...
Fine. CT scanner.
His head CT revealed
some old ischemic strokes.
But the reason
I called you is...
Proximal filling
defects in the pulmonary artery.
It's consistent with
thromboembolic
pulmonary hypertension.
- Uh, what's that?
- Uh, blood clots
in the artery that leads
from your heart to your lungs.
That's why you're
having trouble breathing.
Based on these images,
these clots could be
a few months old.
They could
have started last April.
That's when he had an urgent
spine surgery here
followed by COVID-19.
Oh. This sounds bad.
What happens now?
Well, based on your husband's
hemodynamic instability,
we should plan for surgery
to remove the clots as soon
as possible.
Then he'll be able
to breathe comfortably again.
I knew he looked familiar.
I butted heads with Cain
months ago over this guy.
He reclassified his elective
spine surgery as urgent.
Which means if Mullins got COVID
here at Chastain...
He's another Cain casualty.
And we both know that that
surgery wasn't truly emergent.
Well, we suspect.
We don't know for sure.
Okay, in Mina's kangaroo court,
Barrett Cain is sentenced
to death.
All right, I'm gonna
find out for sure.
- You okay?
- Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine.
You froze up before,
and then you took off
like a bat out of hell.
Yeah, I'm just fried.
It's jet lag.
Multiple small nodules
with surrounding
ground glass opacities.
It's consistent
with histoplasmosis.
And a lot of other types
of infections
- and inflammatory processes.
- Yeah.
Histoplasmosis is one
of the great imitators.
All of her test results
and symptoms
could mimic something else.
Her diagnosis
might not be straightforward.
- And she might not have histo.
- True.
But until we have something
more definitive,
we stay the course.
Have you heard anything
about who might be
replacing Kim as our CEO?
- Come in.
- Well, have you?
Not a word.
What are you doing?
Who's he?
My former stepson Jake.
My first wife's kid.
I was with Donna for six years.
Gosh.
We've been out of touch
for a long time, and
I reached out
during the pandemic, and, um,
you know, didn't...
didn't hear anything back, but,
just, I'd like to try and...
to reconnect with him.
I was with him
from when he was six
till just about 12, and...
Oh, God, we had fun.
And he was angry and-and...
and hurt
when I divorced his mother.
Then Donna threatened to kill me
if I reached out to him.
Said I'd done enough damage
by abandoning them, and...
Oh, I shouldn't have
listened to her.
Tread lightly.
And good luck, Randolph.
Hey. Bianca.
Not sure if you're aware
of this,
but HR can help you find
affordable childcare, okay?
Um, great. But my name's not
Bianca and I don't have kids.
We need help!
What happened?
She fell.
And she's in a lot of pain
and she's having even
more trouble breathing now.
Please,
you got to do something.
- We're gonna get you on the bed.
- We got you.
We got you.
Nichelle, try to relax.
Try and relax. Try and relax.
- Bilateral crackles.
- Sats in the 80s.
Something's not adding up.
We'll run some more tests
and I'll order a chest CT.
Well-well, could it be the meds?
As I told Nichelle,
very unlikely.
Shingles. I saw a dermatologist.
They put you on an antiviral?
- Yeah, ten days ago.
- Good.
- She's gonna be okay, right?
- Yeah.
If it's not a fungus,
we'll figure out what it is.
She's stressed
about the special election.
Mr. Randall
didn't want her to run.
And that's why
he's not here?
Tom Randall cares
about Tom Randall.
He puts in time for her
if there's a camera.
Nichelle cares about everybody.
Atlanta needs her.
Georgia needs her.
You know, I couldn't imagine
what we'd do without her.
Is he off his call yet?
I'm sorry, Mr. Yorn
is on a different call now.
Of course he is. When do you
suppose he might be available?
- Check back in an hour.
- That's what you said an hour ago.
Tell you what,
why don't you have me paged
- when he's off the phone?
- Certainly.
- Mr. Mullins.
- Hey.
I have a couple of questions
I'd like to ask you
- before we prep you for surgery.
- Yeah.
Have you continued to experience
acute onset bowel incontinence
post the discectomy
Dr. Cain performed
back in April last year?
Or was it only before surgery?
Say what?
Were you having difficulty
controlling your bowels
after the operation
or was it only before?
Neither. Um, I've never
had that problem.
Did Dr. Cain check
your rectal tone back in April?
Oh, uh, no.
Uh, I think I'd remember that.
Sure.
Of course you would.
All right. I'll see you
in the OR.
And we'll get you back
on your feet before you know it.
Okay.
Ben Mullins.
Remember him?
He's back
with chronic thromboembolic
- pulmonary hypertension.
- And you're telling me this because...?
Because the clots could be
the result of COVID.
Which he most likely
contracted here
after you conned him
into thinking
- his discectomy was urgent.
- I did nothing of the kind.
I know you fabricated
his symptoms
to justify the surgery.
Mullins was never incontinent.
He doesn't even remember
you checking his rectal tone.
I know I may look like I have
stupid written on my forehead,
- but I see what's going on here.
- Even if I did what you are
accusing me of, there are plenty
other white surgeons out there
who did elective surgeries
during COVID.
Why come after the only
other prominent Black cutter?
There are plenty of brothers
I left behind because they
weren't ready for the fight.
Not once did it ever occur to me
to pick them off.
But you're that one rising crab
in the barrel
who pulls the one
above you right back in.
No.
You got me wrong, bro.
That's not my M.O.
I don't want you gone, Barrett.
I happen to find strength
in our all-too-small
brotherhood,
but I'm about pushing
each other to excel,
to be more prepared,
to be more skilled,
so our talent
cannot be discounted.
It doesn't matter
if we're better.
We're always gonna
be discounted.
It's about the money.
Money's the one thing
they can't ignore.
Which is why I'm gonna continue
to do whatever it takes
to be the top earner.
That's the way
the game is played.
Playing the game doesn't mean
you have to lose your soul.
You do you, and I'll do me.
Let the cards fall
where they may.
Devon.
Thanks.
What's up?
Nichelle and James
seem concerned
that she's taking
the antifungal meds.
It's a little weird.
When James asked me
if she was gonna be okay,
he looked like I'd look
if I thought I might lose Nic.
So you think there's something
going on between them.
Hey, what's up?
So, Cain lied
on Mullins' file.
Said he was incontinent
to justify the surgery,
- but he was not.
- That's it.
We have what we need
to get rid of him.
When you say "get rid of him,"
it means to potentially
destroy his career.
- Absolutely.
- Yeah, I-I need to sit with it.
I can't imagine why.
He's a proven menace.
- It's complicated.
- No, it's not.
It's simple.
Cain is dangerous.
He shouldn't be allowed
to practice surgery.
We can make that happen.
It is incumbent
upon us to do so.
Like I said,
I need a minute.
All right?
All right.
Nichelle, I'm gonna follow your
lead and speak truth to power.
- Conrad...
- I don't think you're telling me
everything I need to know.
And I'm worried that
whatever you're holding back
is putting you at risk.
It's okay.
You can tell me.
I can't feel my legs.
Can you feel that?
- You feel that?
- No.
Lesions in L3-L4.
That's the cause of the lower
extremity paralysis.
Histo only causes spinal lesions
in the immunocompromised.
Which the patient is not.
We're dealing
with something else.
My gut says infection, but our
work didn't turn up anything.
I still think she's not
telling me something.
And it may end up killing her.
Well, I'll leave the detective
work to you two smarty-pants.
Right now, our future governor
needs a spinal decompression
so her paralysis
doesn't become permanent.
Hey.
- There you are.
- Hey.
I have, uh, concerns
about this bypass thing.
- Okay.
- So, you're telling me
you're not just gonna run
my blood through the machine
but you have to...
have to stop my heart, too?
Yes. The bypass
will act as your heart and lungs
- while we remove the clot.
- Okay. So,
what happens
if my heart doesn't, um,
start back up again?
Oh, well,
in that very remote possibility,
we would do everything we can
to get your heart beating again.
- "Remote possibility."
- Mm-hmm.
That isn't reassuring, okay?
I don't know if you've noticed,
but, uh...
but remote possibilities
tend to happen
- to me.
- Hey.
Forgive him.
It's just been a rough year.
First it was
the emergency back surgery
and then his COVID infection,
and now this.
I must be
the unluckiest man alive.
- Mr. Mullins?
- Sweetheart?
- - What's going on?
- He may be having a stroke.
- Excuse me. I'll up his oxygen.
- Oh.
All right, his pupils are
still reactive, but he's lost
tone on his left side.
He needs a head CT.
We need to page Cain.
Hey.
Holy crap.
What are you doing
lurking out here?
Well, I-I was actually
lurking inside.
Just out of sight.
I didn't want
to throw you off your game.
The bouncer told me
you come back here between sets.
Just thought I'd
come see what you were up to.
Seriously? 20 years go by,
and you just thought
you'd come see what I'm up to?
What do...
what do you want, 'Dolph?
So, how's-how's your mother?
She's doing well.
She... Over you, finally.
Listen, I've got
a lot of friends inside,
so if we could just get to it,
whatever it is?
Yeah. Of... Yeah. Of course.
Uh, like a lot of people,
the pandemic has forced me
to reevaluate things,
and I realize I've...
I put my professional
and financial life
ahead of my relationships,
and I'm-I'm so sorry for that.
I've seen a lot of people die
this year, Jake.
Some alone.
Others surrounded by loved ones.
Oh.
You're here because
y-you're scared of dying alone.
No.
- That's not why I'm here.
- But it's totally on brand.
Oh, that's not entirely fair.
We had a lot
of wonderful times together.
I-I... And I-I blew it.
There's no way
around that. I-I...
I cared for you, and I blew it.
No, if you cared for me,
you would've stayed in touch.
Go find somebody else
to hold your hand while you die.
I already mourned losing you.
Ben Mullins has
a clotting disorder
that is threatening his heart,
lungs and now his brain.
This is your fault.
I know the hierarchy
between you two is fluid,
but I will not be spoken to
that way by a resident.
Two things, bro,
Dr. Okafor
is no ordinary resident,
and she happens to be right.
- This is on you.
- No, it's on the patient,
who was advised
of the risks.
And last time I checked,
I didn't unleash a pandemic
- on the world.
- Mm-hmm. Deny it all you want,
but you will be held responsible
for this.
Logan Kim isn't here
to protect you anymore.
Hey.
Let's just, uh,
take a breath, all right?
He had a stroke in his
nondominant frontal lobe.
All right.
Well, looks like we can
proceed with the surgery.
The blood thinners he's on
should be adequate
to treat the clot,
but we need you to be on standby
in case there's
hemorrhagic transformation
and the vessel bursts.
Always here
when you need me.
You'd both do well
to remember that.
Dr. Voss?
Kit, what's going on down there?
Better if I show you.
Nichelle has something
on her skin
that looks like shingles.
You have shingles, too.
- Why?
- I don't know. Coincidence?
It's a symptom of something
you and Nichelle caught
when you were
out of town together.
- I'm guessing nowhere near Kentucky.
- I'm her driver.
- All right? That's all.
- Yeah, no, of course.
That being said, she's gonna die
unless I get the truth.
We were in the Caribbean.
Jamaica.
Are the meds you're taking
for the shingles working?
Not really. Why?
Because I know what you both
have now, and it's not shingles.
All right.
A massive clot removed
and a beating heart.
I say it's a beautiful day
in the OR.
Intracranial pressure
is rising.
- Pupils are blown.
- He's brain-hemorrhaging.
And herniating.
He doesn't have much time.
- Somebody call Cain.
- He's already here.
Elevate the head,
reverse the blood thinners,
prep for a craniotomy.
Incision.
Intracranial
pressure is up to 60.
I know how high it is.
Ready to enter the skull. Drill?
Blood pressure's rising fast.
What's going
on up there, Cain?
I stopped the bleed,
but he's still herniating.
- How is that possible?
- He's bleeding
from a place where I can't see.
Other side of the brain.
- Ultrasound?
- Aren't you supposed
to drill a hole
in the other side of the skull?
No, he doesn't have
the time for two craniotomies.
I'm gonna pass the needle
from this side of the brain
to the other
to remove the blood.
You can't blindly poke
a needle through the sides
- of his brain. You'll kill him.
- I don't blindly operate,
and nobody asked
for your permission.
Yo, have you ever
done this before?
Nope. Never.
We need to stop this.
If we do, the patient will die.
Listen to your mentor, Okafor.
Stay in your lane.
Blood pressure's dropping.
Time to go to work.
BP stabilized.
You're going to protect Cain.
He's done so much harm.
Yeah, but in his mind, he's just
doing whatever he can do
to survive in a system
that's been rigged against us.
So you think systemic racism
excuses his behavior?
No.
But it does explain it.
The frustration,
the-the pain, the anger
that builds up,
knowing that in this country,
your life can go south
at any moment
just because of the melanin
in your skin.
Now, I was raised not
to let the unfairness
of discrimination consume me.
But if Cain wasn't taught that,
can you blame him
for how he turned out?
I mean, what else do you expect?
I wasn't born in this country,
so my experience and history
with racism is different,
but this is
a mistake.
I believe
Cain can be redeemed.
You're wrong.
People don't change.
Okay, well,
here's the bottom line.
I've listened
to your input, Mina,
but at the end of the day,
it's my decision
whether to report him or not.
Not yours.
And I need you to respect that.
Are you asking me as m...
As my colleague or my boyfriend?
- Does it matter?
- What you do matters to me.
- How did it go with Jake?
- Not well.
- Oh, I'm sorry, Randolph.
- You know, I've always
felt guilty about leaving him.
And...
He needed a father.
And I'm not so sure
about the choices he's made.
- Can you do anything about it?
- No, he's...
He's a grown man, he's moved on.
And I think my chance to have
any positive impact on him
- has passed me by.
- You can't give up
so easily, Randolph.
Put up a fight.
Oh, I have to hang up.
It's time to ambush
the CEO of Red Rock.
- What?
- And your lunch
is at 12:30 and...
Sir, I'll call security.
It's okay. Dr. Voss
isn't here to hurt me.
Although, given her mastery
of the spine,
I'm sure she could.
Listen, I'm sorry you got
the cold shoulder all day,
but my assistant,
she's a bit overprotective.
All will be forgiven
if you answer one question:
Who's replacing
Logan Kim as CEO?
Chastain isn't
getting a new CEO.
I don't understand.
Someone has to be in charge.
Who's gonna
run the hospital?
Dr. Voss expects
you'll be up
and walking again soon.
She said I had lesions
on my spine.
Please tell me you
know what I have.
We do.
You have a parasitic worm
called a Schistosoma.
And your spinal lesion biopsy
confirmed it.
They're usually found in places
like the Middle East,
Southeast Asia, the Caribbean.
The Caribbean?
Do you have any idea
how lucky you are
that we had the time
and the patience
to figure out
what was going wrong with you
before your organs failed,
despite...
- Devon.
- No, no, no.
She needs to hear this.
You lied to us.
We have sick people out there
who need our attention,
but we were stuck here wading
through your nonsense.
Let me talk to her.
We put you on antiparasitics
for the next four weeks.
James is on them, too.
Keeping secrets from
your doctors can kill you.
I don't want you to think
I'm just another politician
who had an affair.
- I am not here to judge you.
- Well, that's what
people do unless
you give them context.
You know, I represent
the district I grew up in
in Atlanta.
I love my people.
And I've been able to
make a difference where change
is hard to come by.
At first,
my husband understood that.
When we met,
he was an NFL megastar
and I was a judge
in small-claims court.
Now no one asks him
about football.
They ask him what it's like
to be married to me.
And his ego
can't handle that.
But James...
Yeah?
He'd love to tell people what
it's like to be married to you.
Yes, sir.
He's a good man, my James.
While my husband might not
sleep with me anymore,
but he will do
a press conference tomorrow
and say, "My wife is stronger
than half the men
I played football with.
No bug's gonna stop her."
But if I was outed as unfaithful
to Atlanta's favorite son,
I would never make it
to the governor's mansion.
You know we're duty bound
to keep
your personal life
confidential.
I know.
But it will get out eventually.
Can you ask James to
come in here?
She almost died
keeping a secret.
Anything you want to tell me?
After the memorial,
I went to the hospital
where my dad died.
I found the resident
that took care of him.
It was a good guy,
reminded me of you actually.
They were understaffed,
too few vents.
One nurse for every
ten patients.
We have one nurse
for every two patients.
They intubated him.
He was stable until,
like, 2:00 a.m.
His sat dropped,
heart rate started to slow.
Ten minutes went by.
And when they finally
got to him, he was gone.
Cardiac arrest.
My father, he died alone
because his public hospital,
in a poor brown neighborhood,
didn't have enough resources
to save him.
I'm so, so sorry, man.
When the,
when the resident was...
When he was rereading his notes,
he started to cry.
And I said to him,
"Hey, l-look, we all have
that patient we know
we could have saved."
And he said to me,
"If only it had just been one."
There had been dozens.
We'll continue to monitor him
but, uh, his prognosis is good.
Dr. Cain said the same thing.
He stopped by.
His words were
such a comfort.
We are indebted to him, to all
of you, for saving Ben's life.
Mrs. Mullins, there's something
you should know.
You went behind my back
and told the Mullins about Cain.
- I explicitly told you not to.
- Oh.
Now they're suing.
You weren't listening to reason.
I was listening to my gut.
Which tells me to believe
in Cain's redemption.
You don't get to override that,
Mina.
Barrett Cain broke the first
tenet of our profession,
"do no harm."
He shouldn't be allowed
to practice medicine.
I did you a favor.
I did us all a favor.
You didn't do anybody
a favor.
You just carried out
your own verdict
in Mina's kangaroo court.
And you
disrespected me.
If you're looking for me
to apologize,
that's not happening.
You know, by my count,
it's been nine
consecutive nights of
soul-stirring sex
- and unparalleled conversation.
- Mm.
And, though I will deny
ever saying this,
my back hurts.
Are you suggesting
we take a break?
- Yes.
- Agreed.
Two nights.
Three.
Agreed.
Rest your back
and reconsider your actions.
Yeah.
And you reconsider, too.
New driver, huh?
Can't move forward
without change.
But good news.
Senator Buxton freed up
some federal money
for our childcare needs,
so not a bad day's work.
I'll mention that to Bianca.
Trust me, somewhere
in Atlanta there is a girl
named Bianca with two kids
who can't afford
to take care of them.
Thank you for everything.
Best of luck to you, Conrad.
Best of luck to you, Nichelle.
Oh, what the hell, man?
How do you go from absent
ex-stepfather
to shameless groupie...
I'm here because
I want to be here,
and because there's something
I need to say to you.
You needed a father,
and I dropped the ball.
You're a very
talented musician.
- Thanks.
- You know,
having said that, I know
it's-it's hard to make a living
in the music business no matter...
- without a lot of luck.
- Okay, this is priceless.
You know, I don't know how you
supplement your passion,
but I'd... I would like to help.
The thing is,
I don't need your help.
I play music to relieve stress.
I'm a surgeon.
Plastics and ENT.
I...
I googled you.
I use Wong,
my mother's maiden name,
for my medical practice.
She is the one who put me
through medical school.
Don't do that.
- What?
- Smile
like you had any influence on
my decision to go into medicine.
I'm glad Devon finally
opened up to you.
You're a good friend.
Oh, it's devastating.
- I hate that he's going through this.
- Mm.
Promise me,
let's never run for office.
Or become sports icons.
And let's never, ever
keep secrets from each other.
Right. No. Never.
What is it?
You look adorably insane.
Well, in the spirit
of excellent rules
for a healthy marriage,
there's something
I have to tell you.
Okay.
I'm pregnant.
What? How?
Four years of medical school
and you still don't know
how this works?
I didn't know
we pulled the goalie.
We didn't. I know.
It's-it's...
it's crazy.
♪ If you wake up
without any reason ♪
Holy crap.
Yeah.
♪ Late at night
and I'm not there ♪
Oh, my God, you are gonna
be the best mother ever.
And you're gonna be
the best dad.
You are gonna be the kind
of mother who makes sure
her kids have an even better
life than she did.
- Oh, God, I hope so.
- You will.
Our kid will be kind and brave
just like you.
♪ I'll keep knocking
on the door... ♪
A baby?
Oh, my God. It's never
gonna be the same again.
No, it's not.
It's going to be better.
♪ You are, you are ♪
♪ You are someone special. ♪
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
Sync corrections by srjanapala