You okay?
I'm thinking.
Thinking's not gonna
get you to the top.
Mom, you're supposed
to be encouraging me.
No, I'm supposed
to be coaching you.
The slower you go, the
more tired you're gonna get.
There's a hold about a
foot above you on the left.
I know.
Nice grab!
Keep going. You're
almost there, babe.
I can't. My calf's cramping.
You need to get off your toes.
Get on the ball of
your foot. I can't.
Yes, you can. You can
get all the way to the top.
It's okay. I got
you. You all right?
Looks like you were wrong. Yeah.
But you did awesome. That's
the highest you've gotten.
I'm proud of you.
I don't feel so good.
Okay. Come on down.
Mom?
Mom, are you okay?
Oh, my God.
Whoa! Did you see
that? You all right?
My arm. I think I
broke it. Don't move.
Oh, Jane, I'm so sorry.
What happened?
Did the rope break?
No. My hands, I can't move them.
She's been to an ortho, two
neuros and an immunologist.
None of the treatments
have had any effect.
You think it's over?
It's getting worse.
Last neurologist found
intermittent numbness in both arms
as well as the hand paralysis.
I meant the game. You think
he's gonna keep all four of us?
He said he would. No sign of
upper motor neuron involvement.
He lies.
My ears are burning.
Tell him you're
done firing people.
Well, if I lie, that would
be little reassurance.
Dr. Kutner, who told you
that it would be a good idea
to put up superficial representations
of a hypocritical season
celebrating a mythical figure?
It wasn't me.
He lied.
Homey knows better,
Hymie doesn't care,
and Huntington's would
have done a better job.
I don't have Huntington's.
That you know of.
Why would you...
Because I got sued when
I called you "honey buns."
Am I fired if I put up...
The point of the
game was to scare us.
Telling us it's
over isn't scary.
Therefore, he has no reason
to say that unless it's true.
Good. Then, can we
do a Secret Santa?
I liked you better 15 seconds ago
when you were afraid for your job.
So, who's sick?
35-year-old single mom.
It's an odd
presentation of paralysis.
Is there any history
of drug use? No.
She says there's no history.
She's not a liar.
Okay. This is gonna
be a tough case.
I have almost no knowledge
of alien physiology.
Everyone lies. But there's
an exception to every rule.
Actually, there isn't. That's
kind of what makes it a rule.
The patient's mother died of
breast cancer when she was seven.
She never even knew
her mom was sick.
She promised herself she would never
hide anything from her own daughter.
Oh. I didn't know
she'd promised.
And we're not her daughter.
The patient inherited the
BRCA1 mutation from her mom.
She had a prophylactic double
mastectomy 10 years ago.
She lied about it. She told
her co-workers. She told her kid.
She lied to the world.
Reconstructive surgery is
designed to convince people that...
She didn't get
reconstructive surgery.
Okay. We can rule
out breast cancer.
Actually, I was gonna rule it in.
Paralysis could be paraneoplastic.
Even the best surgeon can't
remove every cell of breast tissue.
MRI what's left of her chest.
Set the machine to scan for irony.
I'm gonna go re-do
the patient history.
Your mom tell you about
all the drugs she does?
She smokes pot once in a
while, but not in a long time.
What about you?
How would that make her sick?
Are you a doctor?
I'm 11.
That's not an answer.
That's an evasion.
Drinking? You
ever sneak a drink?
I don't do any of that
stuff. It's bad for you.
I understand why you don't
want your mom to know.
But I'm her doctor, so...
No, I would tell my mom.
And I would tell you. Why?
Because she would
never lie to me.
What's her favorite
way to have sex?
I don't get what sex has
to do with breast cancer.
Are you a doctor?
Did you go to med school
since the last time I asked?
You just think we've
got to be lying to...
White lies? What are those?
Those are lies we tell to
make other people feel better.
I don't lie.
Rationalizations?
What are those?
Those are lies we tell to
make ourselves feel better.
No. We don't...
Lies of omission?
Saddle, bronc or doggie?
That's sex talk.
She used to like being on top, but
now she likes to be on her stomach.
That way she doesn't have to
see them looking at her scars.
It's child abuse.
Honesty?
There's a reason that
everybody lies. It works.
It's what allows
society to function.
It's what separates
man from beast.
Oh, I thought that
was our thumbs.
You want to know every place
your mom's thumb has been?
I'm sorry. I missed rehearsal.
Am I taking the truth-is-good side?
Don't you usually
take that part?
Lies are a tool.
They can be used
either for good...
Wait. I've got a better one.
Lies are like children.
They're hard work but they're worth it
because the future depends on them.
You are so full of
love or something.
When you care about someone...
You lie to them.
You pretend that their constant,
ponderous musings are interesting.
You tell them they're not
losing their boyish good looks
or becoming worn out and...
I stand corrected. And may I say it's
been a real pleasure chatting with you.
Axilla is clean. Surgical
margins look clear.
No lymphadenopathy, no
masses, no nothing. It's not cancer.
We need a new theory.
You catch her lying?
Not yet.
Wouldn't no have
been a shorter answer?
Wouldn't you not talking have
made this a shorter conversation?
Kid says Mom's a slut.
She called her mom a slut?
No. I called her mom a slut.
She jumps anything
with a pole and a pulse.
Not that I'm judging, here. Given her
medical history, I'm actually impressed.
Maggie already admitted to
having multiple sexual partners.
Which is why we already
tested for, and ruled out,
syphilis and any other STD that
could have caused her symptoms.
STDs aren't the
only risk in risky sex.
The problem in sleeping with
strangers is, they're strange.
We'll follow up with
any recent partners.
Send Foreman and
Taub. They're better liars.
More likely to get to the truth.
You think I drugged
her? Use a coaster.
We're not cops. Legally, we
don't care one way or another.
But we need to know the
truth so we can help her.
I'd known her for less than an hour
and she offered to take me home.
There was no need to drug her.
Not that I would.
She's gonna be okay, right?
As long as she doesn't have to
pick up or hold anything, yeah.
Sorry. I just had the floors
done. Reclaimed pine.
You always this thirsty?
I don't know.
Water's supposed to
be good for you, right?
Dehydration,
anxiety, aggression.
I'm not aggressive.
Spastic chorea
in his right hand.
What about my hand?
How much do you weigh?
About 180, 190?
180. What is this?
If you took what she did, it
could take longer to hit you.
It might affect you differently.
But you didn't give
her anything, right?
She was really drunk.
I just gave her some E
to help enhance things.
Have any of it left?
Is my hand gonna be okay?
There's nothing wrong with it.
We lied.
I've had a sore throat
for a few days now.
My stomach's also
been bothering me.
I think my glands are swollen.
Saint Nicholas?
Patron saint of children.
Also seamen, merchants,
archers, prostitutes and prisoners.
Mmm. He must have
been pretty hard working.
Or just a credit hog.
Open wide.
Say, "Ah." Ah.
You have strep.
Is it contagious?
Only for the next 24 hours, as
long as you take the antibiotics.
How contagious?
Take a personal day.
I can't.
I'll write your pimp a note.
My pimp?
You get tested for
AIDS every three months.
And your necklace.
Prostitutes wear
religious symbols?
I think they just like kneeling.
You don't have the skin of a
seaman, the fingers of an archer,
the clothes of a merchant
or the attitude of an ex-con.
So, that just leaves one left.
Mmm, two, actually.
But I'm not a child, am I?
You owe me 50 bucks.
Then you owe me
half a lap dance.
It's for the nurses' holiday
bonus. I know you got the memo.
I got the memo last year. I
want to hire 40 more fellows.
You already fired
the ones you hired?
They work better
when they're scared.
You were right. Guy
slipped her Ecstasy.
He have any symptoms? No.
Kutner's starting the
patient on hemodialysis,
and Thirteen's in the lab trying to
figure out what the guy put in the drugs.
See? Clear, simple
statement of facts
describing their cooperation
with absolutely no attitude or fear.
Something's got to be done.
Oh, yeah.
How are you feeling?
I still can't move my hands.
It will take a few more hours to cycle
all your blood through the machine.
What just happened?
Nothing. What's wrong?
What do you mean?
The lights just went out.
Didn't they?
What did you do?
Is this from the drugs?
Most of the drugs should
be out of your system by now.
And our drugs
wouldn't... I can't see.
Do something!
I can't see!
Nothing in the
Ecstasy except Ecstasy.
Well, that never hurt anybody.
Can't make them
blind days later.
Do you spell "Homey" with a "Y"?
I want to be respectful.
You're actually gonna
let us do Secret Santa?
Not just you guys.
I like presents, too.
Pick a name.
Why are you doing this?
See, this is why no
one likes your people.
The notion of picking one time of the year
to be decent to other people is obscene
'cause it's actually
validating the notion
of being miserable
wretches the rest of the year.
So, you think this is the part
of the year that's screwed up?
On the other hand, you are now a
team. You've got to work together.
And the simple fact is, giving
people crap makes people like people.
So, spend 25
bucks. Learn to love.
Blindness could be a
complication from the hemodialysis.
No, the dialysate
composition was within range.
Sweet. Interesting.
The dialysate composition just
indicates... Indicates nothing.
I was referring to his
reaction to the name he got.
I was pleased. I thought
it'd be fun to buy for...
Means there's someone here
it wouldn't be fun to buy for.
I wonder who. Pick a name.
Then go check out
the patient's house.
Interesting.
We're wasting time
going to the home.
Kearns-Sayre Syndrome
fits the symptoms.
No family history of
Kearns. Go to their house.
She would have told us if there
were any other drugs. You met her.
She couldn't have been more
candid. You're absolutely right.
Go to their house... MS or a
vascular problem fits better.
They could affect
hands and eyes.
Fine. Do an MRI, check for MS.
And a fluorescein angiogram of her eyes
to see if we missed a bleed somewhere.
Oh, and whoever goes to their
house, get me their computers.
You talk to your kid about sex
so she'll think you're being
open about everything.
It keeps her from asking questions
about things you don't want to talk about.
That's right. Her honesty
proves just how dishonest she is.
Yes! Exactly who I wanted.
This is gonna be fun.
The dye may sting when
it enters your bloodstream.
Are you scared, Mom?
Yeah.
Are you? Yeah.
Are they?
They don't look scared.
Either they're confident
or they just don't care.
We're confident.
Okay if I shift you a bit? I
need to get you into position.
Your boss is weird.
Yeah, he is.
He thought he'd get information
you may not have been telling us by...
Being a jerk?
You'd be surprised
how often it works.
Choroidal flush looks good.
Why would people
lie to a doctor?
Dozens of reasons to lie.
Only one reason to tell the truth.
You're never even tempted?
I mean, lies do sometimes
smooth things out, make life easier.
Yeah? Your life easy?
Not even close.
Dye's reached the retinal
capillary bed. No leakage.
That's good, right?
It means it's not a
vascular problem.
But? A vascular
problem we could fix.
They look worried now, Mom.
What's with the Secret Santa?
You trying to bring
them together?
Want to drive them apart.
With gift giving?
Conflict's built
right into the name.
Santa's about sharing.
Secret's about withholding.
Aside from the Trojan
horse, gifts don't usually...
What did you get your wife
for your final anniversary?
Uh, a sweater. She hated it.
She loved it.
Then you didn't buy it.
I gave her some cash and...
Gifts allow us to demonstrate exactly
how little we know about a person.
And nothing pisses
off a person more
than being shoved in
the wrong pigeonhole.
Nice.
I'm thinking of spending a few
extra bucks on my Secret Santa.
Bad idea.
You mind if I tell House you asked
them for the key instead of breaking in?
Yes. I do. Just another
5 bucks. 5 will be 10.
The key's proof she
doesn't have anything to hide.
The key is proof I didn't do
exactly what House told me to do.
And what do you
care if it's another 15?
I'm gonna tell him. Who
are you so anxious to please?
Not you.
You really think you're gonna
prove people are capable of honesty
using a mother and daughter
you've known for one day?
I'm not the one who's based his
entire worldview on the proposition.
If I'm wrong, so
what? If he's wrong...
So, you've got
Huntington's? Nope.
But House said that...
If I wanted to talk about
it, why didn't I bring it up?
Fluorescein angiogram was
clear. No leaks. No lesions.
Definitely not a
vascular problem.
Someone get their
birthdays out of the file.
Have you tried leaving it blank?
Tough to get into the head of
someone who actually trusts people, huh?
Found both computers in
an office on a desk they share.
No sign of macular
degeneration or optic neuritis.
Her eyes are completely normal.
Except she can't
see out of them.
So she says.
You find anything on the MRI?
No sign of plaques. It's not MS.
We haven't found anything
abnormal on any tests.
Except she can't see
or move her hands.
So she says.
You can't lie about
flaccid paralysis.
Maybe she's not
lying. Her brain is.
What if it's a
conversion disorder?
Lacks personal boundaries.
Promiscuous. Inappropriate
obsession with truth telling.
Certainly sounds
like a psych case.
Cool. I'll set up a psych consult
and start her on anti-depressants.
No.
Her mind is tricking her body.
We need to trick her mind.
Or even better...
You don't need her. I know.
Then this serves
no medical purpose.
You have a genetic
defect, choose to ignore it.
This woman has a genetic defect,
chooses to butcher
herself to be safe.
Yet, what you claim to be
fascinated by is her honesty.
Interesting.
You claim to want the truth.
And then you screw with people
who actually live by it. Pathetic.
Hey, I gave you
credit for interesting.
You're protecting her because you're
jealous she did what you couldn't.
I need you.
I'm not lying to her.
Fine. Keep your mouth
shut. I still need you.
If it doesn't work, you've
got to hold the kid down
until someone else
finishes lying to Mom.
That does actually
serve a medical purpose.
Jane.
I have to lie because
she trusts me?
If you show doubt, the
placebo treatment won't work.
If it's just depression,
that's good news, right?
There are a lot of
great medications.
Why can't we just give her those?
Why do we have to lie to her?
Because we might be wrong.
Those medications
take a long time to work,
and since your mom's
condition's declining,
there's a chance the drugs won't
tell us anything until it's too late.
My mom's not depressed.
Maybe she's hiding it from you.
No.
She wouldn't.
She's doing what
every good mom does.
Protecting her child from bad news
that she can't do anything about.
My mom's never lied to me.
If you don't know how to lie,
you don't know how to tell
when you're being lied to.
Maybe you're right.
I know I'm... I was lying.
I know how to lie.
I just won't do it to my mother.
You like foosball?
Until the treatment of your
infectious paraparesis takes effect,
Jane can't come
back into the room.
I've already been inoculated.
Can she have it already?
Don't worry. It's a
very effective treatment.
You should be feeling
better in a matter of minutes.
Don't you think Jane
deserves a few secrets?
Some personal space?
Room to make her own mistakes?
She makes plenty of mistakes.
Only difference is I'm there
to help her through them.
But she's got to know you're
looking over her shoulder.
It's got to stifle her.
I think the world
would be a better place
if everybody always acted like their
mom was looking over their shoulder.
I want to go see my mom.
She's sleeping.
Why don't we just double
the amount we can spend?
Nope. Can't afford another 25?
If we allow people 50,
people will spend 60.
Ah! So, you can't
afford another 35.
You must really like who
you got. Or really dislike.
My mom always
gives the best presents
to the teachers I get
along with the worst.
No. No.
How do you know no?
I know you didn't get House.
I know he didn't get House.
You gave them all
your name? Mmm-hmm.
I figured I could sow some dissension
and get a few ties and sweaters.
What happens when they find out?
It's Secret Santa.
They'll argue about what
to do with that information.
The ties are less important
than the dissension.
We still have to buy him
something. Not a chance.
We weren't supposed to discuss
this. We're not supposed to know.
He's not supposed to put
his name in there five times.
He wants presents. It's sad.
It's pathetic.
I'm still buying him a present.
No, you're not.
Fine.
What's wrong?
I think it's getting worse.
I can't breathe.
I need a nurse in here!
Her lymph nodes are cutting off
her airway. We've got to intubate!
The swollen lymph nodes
were cutting off Maggie's airway.
We shrunk them with alcohol and
she's breathing on her own now.
Well, that sucks.
Four thousand, three
hundred saved emails
and not a single mention of
"lesbionic," "Sanchez," or "mangina."
Swollen lymph nodes
means it wasn't psychological.
Who's that from?
Santa, obviously. As
you know, I worship him.
Oh, wait. I meant Satan. I
always get them confused.
What is an "alpine butterfly"? And
why is she learning how to do one?
House, we already have a full
history. You don't need to waste time...
It's just a climbing knot.
But what does she use it for?
- Try "bondage."
- I did once.
But she just tied me down and whined about
how hard it is to be Dean of Medicine.
Gyms aren't exactly pristine. Could be a
fungal infection. Seriously, who's it from?
No fever. No
elevated white count.
That's funny. Friend sent
her a Garfield cartoon.
That cat sure does love lasagna.
House, stop obsessing.
If it weren't for my obsessions, we
wouldn't know that she has sarcoidosis.
Eighteen months ago,
she sold her Stairmaster.
It was only two months old.
Now, either she needed the cash, or
climbing stairs was getting more difficult.
Twelve months ago,
she canceled a hiking trip.
Now, either she just wanted
to sit home and watch TV,
or walking was
getting more difficult.
She's been suffering joint
pain for the last two years.
Pull my ribbon. If
you know what I mean.
ACE levels are too
low for sarcoidosis.
That's not what I meant.
Could just be an inactive phase.
It's not Christmas yet.
I remembered. I'm not
a Satanist. I'm a Druid.
No lung involvement. Yet.
We'll need a bronchoalveolar
lavage to confirm it.
That's a shame. I was gonna
surprise her with one for Christmas.
Wow!
Now, either that cost
more than 25 bucks,
or I'm seriously starting to doubt
Steve Jobs' business strategies.
Thanks!
Last round of saline,
Maggie. One more big breath.
You've got to get the liquid to go
all the way into your lungs, okay?
Here we go.
The gift could
be from a patient.
Who sent it to the wrong doctor?
House obviously gave
the present to himself.
They're arguing right now.
I've been looking
for this all morning.
Did you look in the
box on my desk?
Oh, by the way, your mom
called. Your dad's dead.
You left the present
sitting on your desk?
It wouldn't have been as effective
sitting in a closet in my home.
They're gonna know
it's from you. No.
They're gonna guess
that it was from me.
They might even be 90%
sure that it was from me.
But all that means is
they're 10% percent sure
that one of the other
guys is screwing them over.
Have you ever considered
channeling your powers to,
I don't know, bring
peace to the Mid-east?
I couldn't do that.
But if they ever got it,
you could screw it up.
Yeah. That's more
where my powers lie.
The gift could be
from Wilson. It's House.
Why do you have a
problem with him speculating?
Because that's what
House wants us to do.
Lungs are pristine. No
infiltrates or alveolar hemorrhage.
Maggie, I'm gonna remove the scope.
I need you to cough for me, okay?
A little harder.
Great.
Maggie? Open your eyes.
Why aren't you saying anything?
What's wrong?
Maggie tested
negative for sarcoidosis.
But she's bleeding
into her eyes, now.
Have her platelets dropped?
Plummeted. New labs
show they're under 40.
She'll bleed out of every
orifice if we don't find the cause.
Could be splenic
sequestration, tuberculosis.
Gaucher disease, TTP.
Hemolytic-uremic
syndrome, sepsis, lupus...
Listing all the possible
causes is only impressive
if you can do it
reverse alphabetically.
We need to know why her
platelet machine is broken.
Go to the factory. Do a
bone marrow aspiration.
I'm your Secret Santa.
You're not supposed to tell.
But you got a present already,
which means you have
more than one Secret Santa.
Or somebody else
wants to make me happy.
Merry Christmas.
On the one hand,
you should be in bed.
On the other hand, I told you
to rest. So, I see your dilemma.
Hey, I don't think
resting is the problem.
Can strep cause this?
Clap on.
Trust me, first place I went.
No rash on my labia. Do
you need to take a look?
I'm saving my money
for a Red Rider BB gun.
Darker shade of lipstick?
I'm not wearing any.
You tell your
mother what you do?
It doesn't matter. I'm curious.
I don't need to break her
heart just so I can feel righteous.
Do you do a donkey show?
I'm not curious. It matters.
It's a donkey or a mule.
I can never remember.
Wow. That is a creepy smile.
I bet the donkey's
is even creepier.
Do I have to explain... Nope.
That's my job.
Contagious ecthyma.
Any contact can cause rashes,
flu symptoms, sore throat.
Has there been
contact?
Okay. Antibiotic cream for you
and a love glove for Francis.
You'll both be fine.
You should come and see
the show. I think you'd like it.
Sorry. I hate Westerns.
So, they really never lie?
Doesn't seem like it.
Admirable.
You tell Cameron everything?
No.
You think she keeps secrets?
If I knew, they wouldn't
be secrets. I hope she does.
People have a right to a little
privacy, even from the people they love.
Did you buy House a present?
Why would I? To screw with me.
Then, I'm gonna say yes.
No, wait. Stop. Stop.
What's that smell?
The bone is smoking.
Her bones are
harder than the drill?
We ran a full body bone scan to
find the cause of hardening in the hip.
No hot spots anywhere.
Tracer could have been inactive.
So, I screwed up the test?
There are so many ways
that could have happened.
Maybe it was inactive,
maybe it didn't fully circulate...
It circulated. The
camera picked up.
Hey, hey. It's Christmas.
Why are you guys fighting?
Why do you think
there are no hot spots?
I did not screw up. The
density is consistent.
Just means the density was
consistent. Doesn't mean it was cold.
It's possible all she
has are hot spots.
It's consistent because her
entire skeleton is turning to stone.
Good for an aspiring superhero.
Fatal for a human hoping
to make it to Kwanzaa.
It's got to be from a carbonic
anhydrase type 2 deficiency.
It has free will.
It doesn't have to be
anything it doesn't want to be.
I meant if it's not CA-2, well,
none of the other causes of
osteopetrosis are treatable.
You're right. It's got to be.
Go run her blood and hope that
your sunny optimism isn't misplaced.
They accused Kutner of screwing
up a test because they hate him.
You're surprised?
That's the sort of
crap that happens
when you mess
with people's heads.
One day, he will
screw up a test.
And if they don't accuse him of that
because they like him, someone could die.
Where are we going?
Nowhere. I just
know it hurts you.
CA-2 deficiency's a genetic
disorder that scrambles proteins.
If the blood test is positive, you'll
need a bone marrow transplant.
"Transplant" sounds like a
euphemism for "slim odds."
Slim but not none.
We're gonna need to
test Jane for a match.
Don't you have donor banks?
Jane is your best bet.
The procedure is perfectly
safe. There's no risk.
No risk?
Any surgery has... Then,
don't tell me there's no risk.
You're gonna tell me
there's no pain, either?
The testing will hurt a little.
I'll be fine.
If she doesn't do this
and you don't make it,
she's gonna spend the rest
of her life blaming herself.
Mom, please.
Find someone else.
Let someone else take the risk.
Donor bank turned up a
49-year-old man in Cleveland
who's a five out
of six HLA match.
First flight out of
Cleveland leaves at...
Why is a 49-year-old Cleveland
man a closer match than her daughter?
He may not be. Maggie
didn't let us test her.
Why not?
Pain, danger, risk of...
Only reason to
give multiple reasons
is you're searching for what
the person wants to hear.
House.
You're wrong about
sainted Mommy.
Don't care. You can forget the donor
bank. There's no CA-2 deficiency.
Best we can do is
make her comfortable.
Is that from Taub?
Yes.
Yes, it is.
Merry Christmas.
Who's gonna tell the
patient she's dying?
I will.
And nobody leaves here
until we find out what killed her.
Whatever she has is fatal.
Makes no difference if it's
disease number 58 or 907.
Are you guys mad at me?
No. You had no choice.
Of course I had a choice. You had
no choice once I made my choice.
And now, I'm choosing
not to be mad at you.
Why?
Because it will
drive House nuts.
Do you think that will make
your lives better or worse?
I told my mom I don't
care what she thinks.
I want you to test my marrow.
I can't be dying.
Sure you can.
You're wrong.
You don't even know what I have.
What you have is one last
Christmas with your daughter.
One last chance to
give her a present.
The truth.
It's inexpensive, highly valued.
Never have to stand in line to
return it the day after Christmas.
What are you talking about?
A mother who's going to die
doesn't refuse a donor
test because it might hurt.
She refuses when she
knows it won't match.
Which tends to happen
when mother and daughter
aren't mother and daughter.
I can do DNA tests if you'd
rather keep lying to me.
I never wanted kids.
I loved them, but
with my genes...
I knew this woman,
a drug addict.
She got pregnant, didn't
want to have an abortion.
But she also didn't want her daughter
to ever know who her real mother was.
What she was.
I promised never to tell.
A promise to an addict is worth
more than a promise to your daughter?
It'd be cruel to tell her.
Right. She lives a lie.
You get to die a hypocrite.
Mom? The doctors told
me what's happening.
It's gonna be okay, sweetheart.
I promise you.
Doctors can be wrong.
There's still a
chance I can beat...
You really believe that?
I do.
No, Mom. You're dying.
Nobody can help you.
It's not gonna be okay.
That was cold.
Yeah.
What did you get for Christmas?
I got a watch, a vintage LP,
and a second
edition Conan Doyle.
And if that wasn't bad
enough, my patient's dying.
Christmas deaths in a hospital.
There's nothing more depressing.
No one ever wants to
go in the patient's room.
Even the candy stripers
leave them alone.
But I saw something amazing.
Pure truth.
She told her mother
that she was dying.
Stripped her of all hope.
That sounds horrible.
It was like watching some
bizarre astronomical event
that you know you're
never gonna see again.
You tell people the cold, hard
truth all the time. You get off on it.
Because I don't care.
She cared.
And she did it, anyway.
She did it because she cared.
The angels of Christmas have finally
given House a present he can appreciate.
Oh, don't ruin it.
Don't pin this on Christ.
He's got enough nails in him.
Patient had to die...
Why don't you take off that hat?
It's Christmas. It's a reindeer.
It's a moose, on a Jew.
Who cares?
Things have their place.
You wouldn't hang dreidels
from a Christmas tree.
You could.
Things don't care.
No, they don't.
Happy solstice, House.
God rest ye merry gentlemen
Let nothing you dismay
Remember, Christ, our savior
Was born on Christmas day
To save us all
from Satan's power
When we were gone astray
Have you people
no holiday spirit?
Bring me the
eggnog of good cheer.
House, if you have
something to say, say it.
If you don't, give us a chance
to get home before Santa.
Scrooge.
Give the patient risperidone.
That's an anti-psychotic.
She's dying. She's not crazy.
I am gonna perform
a Christmas miracle.
Oh, tidings of comfort
and joy Comfort and joy
You said all the other causes
of osteopetrosis are fatal.
Except for the one we discounted
early because it was impossible.
When a fetus forms,
it's just a mass of cells.
Breast tissue covers
extensive portions of the body.
As the fetus develops,
most of this tissue recedes
remaining only
in the fun places.
But sometimes,
extra breast tissue
is left behind in places
where it doesn't belong.
Risperidone does
a lot of things.
One is it makes breast tissue
swell so we can find it more easily.
You're telling me I could
have breast cancer?
Somewhere not in my breasts?
That doesn't make sense.
Taub's parents have a
winter condo in Florida.
They're still New Yorkers.
Actually, my
parents... Don't care.
I told a parable.
Now, I'm gonna raise the dead.
Give me that syringe.
That's got to be a fat deposit.
Yes, I could be wrong.
If I am, she's
dead. So, shut up.
What's that?
Risperidone also
causes galactorrhea.
What's that? Galactic?
Open your mouth.
Relax. You've had it before.
I am not...
Milk?
Ew!
We'll cut out your mom's
tumor and start her on chemo.
All the rest of your
symptoms should go away.
I love you.
I know.
Have a wonderful life.