Everybody wants
privacy for themselves.
Do you have any
idea how many places
I've been looking for
you? What the hell, Alex?
You can't call? You can't
text? What happened?
For other people, not so much.
They said that the
trial was canceled.
- You said you were
taking a plea.
- I did.
Are you in hiding?
Are you evading the
law? Are you on the lam?
Alex. I can help you, but,
I mean, I have kids here.
Stop it. I went down
there. I talked to the D.A.
I have to advise you, Dr. Karev,
that talking to you without
your lawyer present just isn't...
- She's on her way. Should we wait?
- We should.
But... if you just want to
tell me what it's about...
Wait! You can't just go in!
- Mr. Kirby, I'm sorry.
- Can I talk to you?
- Have you... Did you guys talk?
- What are you doing?
I'm dropping the charges.
What? You can't do that.
- Well, I am.
- No, he's right.
They're not your charges
to drop. They're the state's.
- Really?
- Really.
Okay, then...
if you put me on the stand,
I'm gonna have to tell the truth.
We had a fight, both of us.
And I was just as much
to blame. I started it.
The only reason I
let it get this far is...
pride, I guess. I didn't want...
Anyway, you put me
up there, I'll say that.
You're tanking this case.
Has something happened?
Has he threatened you?
Absolutely not.
No, he's... great.
- DeLuca.
- This case is a slam dunk.
- It's a slam freaking dunk.
- I'm sorry to waste your time.
Okay.
- So, Andrew
called off the trial?
- Yeah.
- For you?
- Why?
- No clue.
DeLuca. DeLuca, wait!
So, you called a meeting,
and they ignored it?
How many attendings
didn't show up? A few?
Five? The entire staff?
Well, it was mostly
the department heads.
It was just their way
of sending a message...
Oh, you're going to have to
send a message right back.
I know that. I know.
I am handling this.
I know you are, Dr. Bailey.
But I am a dragon.
I'm your dragon.
And you should feel free to
unleash me, should you wish to.
Call me if you need backup.
I'm a dragon, too.
Dr. Reynolds, extension 2216.
Ohh!
Boy, am I glad to see you.
- Mmm.
I didn't expect
you till tonight.
Well, I took an early
flight to avoid a storm,
moved up a couple
of bladder repairs.
Making hay while the sun shines.
- How are things here?
- Oh, fine.
I have a bowel resection later.
How are things with Dr. Minnick?
Good. Good.
You know, just the
usual bumps in the road.
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah.
Well, I better get going, okay?
I'll see you tonight.
Metabolic panel showed slightly
elevated AST and ALT levels.
CT showed no stones, but
there was wall thickening.
Well, CT can miss gallstones,
especially if the
gallbladder's opacified.
In that case, the study
of choice is ultrasound.
Oh, I get a star? What did I
do? Play nicely with others?
The stars are the surgeries
I've chosen to teach in today.
Yours is first up, Dr. Grey.
No.
- No?
- No.
Okay. What is it?
What's the excuse?
The surgery too
delicate, too dangerous?
There is no excuse. Just no.
Let's go, Edwards.
Hey. So, what's the
fallout from last night?
So far, nothing. Why?
What have you heard?
Well, Minnick's car is here, so that
means she obviously wasn't fired.
- You know what
Minnick's car looks like?
- So? That... That's not weird.
- Hey, did you hear about Alex?
- No.
- Yeah, Andrew told me.
- Did he tell you why?
- No. He wouldn't say.
- "Why" what? What's up with Karev?
He's not in jail.
There's no trial.
- Yeah, Andrew
dropped all the charges.
- Really? Why?
- Well, I don't know. We just said...
- No idea.
What happened last night? Do
we have all the attendings with us?
Uh, well, Hunt... I'm not
sure where he stands yet.
Well, what about Riggs?
Uh, Riggs, we can ask after
he's done talking to your mom.
- What, after he's done
doing what?
- Talking to your mother.
- My what?
- Your mom,
your mother, the one
that raised and fed you?
How could Riggs be talking
to... My mother is in Hawaii.
What is he talk... What are
you... What is he talking about?
No. I met her at the coffee cart
this morning. She's really nice.
Why is no one making any sense?
Maggie, your mom is here.
- My mother is here!
- That's what I've...
- Okay.
- Mom!
Maggie!
What are you doing here?
What's going on? Are you okay?
What kind of welcome is
that? Let me look at you.
Where are your manners?
Introduce me to your friends.
Yeah, Pierce... manners.
Arizona and I are
already old friends.
Oh, yes, yes. Mrs. Pierce and I
go way back to the coffee cart.
Not "Mrs." Diane.
- Diane.
- But who is that?
Is he the one you like?
- Mom!
- What? Look at him.
Okay. Everyone, thank
you. You can go now.
Go now.
- Yeah, well... I have things to...
- Yeah.
- Lovely to meet you. Bye.
- Thanks. Bye.
I just want to introduce myself,
Diane. Dr. Jackson Avery.
Oh, so, you're the
famous Jackson Avery.
Yes, and he's very busy, so...
- Are we all set for 2:30?
- We are. Yes.
What is happening at
2:30? What is happening?
Just a little consult.
Wait, what? You're not
getting plastic surgery?
It's not a dirty word, Pierce.
Mom, why? Why would you do that?
I don't know, I might want to
have a few things spruced up.
And you said
Dr. Avery is the best.
She's right. I'll see
you this afternoon.
Mom, what is going on?
I just spoke to you two days
ago. You said nothing about this.
I knew you'd try to talk
me out of it. So... surprise!
Come on, give me the tour.
I've only seen this
place on video chats.
Mom, I have
surgery in 20 minutes.
I wish you had told me
that you were coming.
It's okay. I have my book.
Just put me somewhere
and I can take care of myself.
Okay.
Wilson, what do we have?
Trauma Two. One! Trauma One.
I said, "What do we have?"
Oh, a patient. A trauma
patient in Trauma One.
Sorry. That's all I know.
Wilson, how many
hours you been working?
I'm fine.
You did a full shift
before going to Tri-County.
That was an all-nighter.
Did you work yesterday?
- I just need some coffee.
- How many hours?
- Thirty... something.
- Okay. Go home.
No, no. I'm okay, I'm okay.
No, you're not. And
I'm not gonna risk
you making a mistake
'cause of exhaustion.
Okay. I'm going.
Is that razor wire?
I'm staying.
Home, Wilson.
Okay. Gently. On three,
guys. One, two, three.
What have we got?
Fifty-year-old female found
down, wrapped in barbed wire.
Vitals: BP ninety over
sixty, tachy at one-twenty.
Non-responsive at the scene.
Trauma panel, chest
film, and cross-match her.
Keep her on high flow O-two.
Someone get a core temp.
Hey. I have a few minutes
before my lap chole.
- Oh, I gave that to Lawson.
- What? Why?
When Dr. Minnick approaches you
to observe in your O.R. and teach,
she's not asking
you for permission.
Wait, she told on me?
Bailey, who is this woman?
Dr. Minnick is the residency
director now. Period.
And you're the chief of general
surgery, so I need you to get in line.
Bailey, I'm not
going to get in line.
I do not support this, at all.
It's unfair and it's unnecessary.
You're pushing Richard
aside for no reason.
And a lot of us feel this
way. I think you need to listen,
and hear what
people are saying...
You're saying you won't
let Minnick into your O.R.?
I think a lot of us are. Yes.
Then you no longer have
an O.R. You're suspended.
Effective immediately.
Go home, Dr. Grey.
Bailey took out Grey.
Winter is coming.
Okay, set up a central
line and page RT.
Core temp's thirty-two.
She's hypothermic.
Let's start infusing warm saline
at a rate of one-fifty and
grab a warming blanket.
This poor woman. Has
she been conscious?
Not since they got her, no.
She's lucky her...
Careful. Okay, somebody
call maintenance.
We're gonna need wire cutters
and heavier gloves to free up this leg.
That razor wire
was just everywhere.
I would have helped her myself,
but I was afraid I'd lose a hand.
Can you tell me anything
about her medical history?
God, no. She was very private.
I mean, like really,
really private.
Annie and her husband
never said hi, never waved.
Right after they
moved onto our road,
they started to build the
wall around their place.
Not a fence, a
wall. Like a fortress.
- They seemed a little...
- Private.
Nutballs.
I tried to bake cupcakes, bring
them over, say hi, welcome.
- She didn't like that either?
- Her husband just yelled,
"We have guns."
He died a while back.
I only see her when
she gets her newspaper.
Six-thirty sharp, every morning.
But yesterday, the paper
just sat there for hours.
Finally, I peeked over
the fence, thinking,
"Grace, you're gonna get
your dumb head shot off."
There she was, tangled
in all of that razor wire.
Well, one thing's for sure.
She'd be dead right now if
it weren't for you finding her.
There's evidence of early ulceration.
She's been down a long time.
The blood flow's been
compromised. Page cardio.
We need a vascular consult, 'cause
she's in danger of losing this leg.
Right away, doctor.
Okay. Push five of Haldol.
Ow!
The rumor mill is...
The rumor mill is churning.
Why? What's it say?
- That you suspended Grey.
- Dr. Grey got herself suspended.
- What about Karev?
- What about him? He's in jail.
You really don't have a
line to the rumor mill, do you?
Charges got dropped.
- No jail.
- No jail?
Who...
Wait. Why are you smiling?
- What did you do?
- I might have told DeLuca.
Well, Karev was
gonna take the plea.
Yeah, but I wasn't supposed
to say anything to anyone!
And you didn't. I did.
I told DeLuca. DeLuca
took it from there.
But why would he
do that for Karev?
Come on, now. It's for Wilson.
Why would he do it for Wilson?
Woman, are you blind?
Blind... Why would...
Pain Management, O.R. Recovery.
Neighbor says she was putting razor
wire on the fence around her place.
- Fell off a ladder
and got tangled.
- My God.
Who needs razor wire?
What's wrong with people?
Every time she moved,
she injured herself more.
She's lucky she
didn't sever her aorta.
Hey. Word is Bailey
just took out Grey.
- What?
- They fired her?
No, suspended. And
apparently, Shepherd, too,
'cause she's just, like, gone.
Yeah, well, we sent a
message. Bailey sent one back.
- She took out our power hitter.
- Who, Shepherd?
- Grey.
- What makes Grey
our power hitter?
She was the one we didn't
think Bailey would ever take out.
Yeah, I'm just saying we're
all pretty powerful hitters here.
Look at the hospital sign.
Grey seems untouchable.
Well, I mean, if we're talking about
big names and power hitters, then...
I'm just saying.
This is getting scary.
Oh, my God. Is that razor wire?
Ma'am, you have to hold still.
- Max her out
on the midazolam drip.
- No!
Copy that.
She's gonna tear herself to
shreds. We have to stop her.
How?
Ma'am, I know it hurts,
but if you don't lay still, you're
gonna hurt yourself a lot more.
Please. What's her name?
- What?
- Her name, what's her name?
Annie Banks.
Annie. Annie. Annie. Annie.
Shh!
It's okay, I got
you. Annie. Annie.
Annie. Annie. Shh!
It's okay. I got you.
Annie, it's okay, it's okay. Look
at me. It's okay. I've got you.
I've got you.
- Okay, can I get a hand?
- Uh, right. Yes.
What is it?
I can't tell where to start...
- Just start.
- Okay.
Hi. Where you going?
To try to get my job
back. Why are you home?
- Oh, I just lost mine.
- What?
I threw down with Bailey
over Richard's replacement,
and she suspended me.
- What the hell?
- I know.
I've a meeting with Bailey right
now. I'm gonna tell her it's not cool.
Don't say a thing.
You just worry about
getting your job back.
Go cut open some little
kids. It's been too long.
Are we both ever gonna
work at the same time again?
Go.
That is a nasty
intraperitoneal bladder rupture.
- I'm so glad you're in town.
- Hmm.
Well, anyone could
repair a ruptured bladder.
Well, yeah, absolutely.
But it's just the hospital...
Are you here to put
a halt to this stuff?
A halt to what stuff?
You know, the Dr. Webber,
Dr. Bailey, Dr. Minnick... stuff.
Now, how is any
of that my business?
- 'Cause Dr. Webber's
your husband.
- Yes, he's my husband.
And he has his job, and I have
mine, and Dr. Bailey has hers.
And you have yours.
You should keep your mind on
these scans, and not on my marriage.
Yeah. Right. Yes.
Dr. Adele to the NICU.
- Riggs. Hey.
- Ohh!
You're not gonna take the
razor wire lady from me, are you?
- Who?
- You didn't hear about it?
She fell into a big batch of
it. It's like a cocoon of death.
Apparently, her vascular
damage is through the roof.
No, no. I wanted to
apologize for my mother.
She can be so...
No worries. Come
on, she's a hoot.
- Right. A hoot.
- Yeah.
Have you seen Dr. Webber?
No, why? Do you
need him for a consult?
No, I need to introduce
him to my mother.
I need to prepare him
or warn him or something.
Do you think she considered
that? That this might be a thing?
That my mother meeting my
birth father might be a thing?
I mean, what if he wasn't ready?
What if he hadn't planned, or-or
run through enough
scenarios or-or...
read enough books on the topic?
What if it doesn't work?
What if they hate each other?
Do you think she
thought about that?
Can I say a thing?
No.
All right. I better
get to the ER.
Wait. Say your thing.
It'll be okay. Whatever
happens. You're their kid.
And she was like
that as a little girl?
- It's you! And you. I
can just hear her now.
- Hey! Well, there she is.
- Yes!
I was just sitting here and
in walked your... Richard.
- So, you met my mother.
- I did.
- We've been having
the nicest chat.
- That's so great.
Well, I just came to take
you to your appointment,
so, if you don't want
to be late, we should...
Oh, well, all right, then.
I'll see you tonight, I guess.
See you at eight.
Okay. Bye.
- What is happening tonight?
- We're going to dinner.
Acosta's. Reviews
are through the roof,
an amazing wine list,
and it's on the water.
Mom, I know
Acosta's. I live here.
He seems every bit
as nice as you said.
He is.
What's wrong, Maggie?
We have to go, if you
don't want to be late
for your butt lift,
or whatever it is.
Oh, just stop it, Maggie, now.
I will need your court papers,
dismissal of charges, whatever.
I need all that
paperwork for your file.
You can start back
as soon as I have it.
Thank you.
Promise me that you are the Alex
Karev who heals small children.
That you have left behind the
Alex Karev who beats people up.
I've got my head on straight.
I want my job back.
I just want to work.
Promise me.
I promise.
Don't scare me like that again.
You need something else?
You suspended Meredith...
for backing Webber?
I just don't understand
where it's coming from.
Webber was the program
since I've been here.
Really, Karev? The second
I give you your job back?
Look, since you've been here.
Get out of my office
before I change my mind.
Go!
Just promise me you won't
turn her into a fish-lipped monster
with an immobile forehead.
- That's not something I do.
- I'm just reminding you
that you swore a sacred
oath as a physician
to give sound, medical counsel to
women who are already beautiful.
To you. I'm not
worried about you.
I want to feel beautiful naked.
Ew, Mom!
Go. I'll text you when I'm done.
All right. Well, firstly, I do
agree with your daughter.
You look terrific. But that doesn't
mean there aren't some things
that you might like to change.
So I'd like to start with
just a brief conversation
so that I can get
a better sense...
I always taught my daughter, if
she wanted to know something,
don't ask the internet.
Find the smartest
person in the room.
And if they're not
smarter than you,
find another room.
My doctor at home
is not the best.
Maggie tells me you are.
Well, that's very nice
of her. Thank you.
Can you get rid of this?
Well, let me take a look here.
It's mostly just vascular
repair. I'll look for organ damage.
I'll take care of the limb. I'm
worried about that right leg.
- She tore it up pretty badly.
- Mm-hmm.
Did Shepherd get canned, too? I
mean, this place is coming apart.
Shepherd didn't get
suspended. She's taken a leave.
- Everything all right?
- Yeah. Yeah.
No. She left. She left work,
she... left me.
Where'd she go?
- Grey's house?
- Edwards, I think.
What are you gonna do?
She's good to go.
What can I do? You know,
go over there and drag her out?
I've said what I can,
I tried. She doesn't want
to... doesn't want to talk...
- Damn it.
- Look, she'll come around, mate.
No, no, it's the razor wire.
DeLuca.
Dr. Burks to Oncology.
Oh, so now my
fetoscopy's in O.R. Three?
I'm glad, glad I
checked the board.
You would have figured it out
if you had walked into O.R. Two
- and found a bowel obstruction.
- You do this everywhere you go?
- Do what?
- Turn the place against you.
People don't like change.
Mmm. I know. People like people.
So first you try and
oust Richard Webber,
and then you get
Meredith Grey suspended.
- Suspended?
- Yeah!
I mean, you really don't want
to make friends here, do you?
I... I didn't come
here for that.
Well, then you're
doing a great job.
Meredith Grey? How about
a little heads up next time?
No. Better yet, no
more suspensions.
I am doing my best here,
but you are not helping.
Well, I can't just
allow insubordination.
No, you can't make my job even
more difficult than it already is.
I'm still moving forward, but I'm
up against very strong opposition.
Yeah, I've seen that for myself.
Look, the residents are happy.
The attendings are not.
If I am seen as the person who
came in and tanked Meredith Grey,
that's not gonna be
good for the program.
- It'll slow down my progress.
- It's a new system.
- You can have all the time
you need. I don't need time.
I need to stop being blocked.
My job is hard enough. Look...
I have to win people over. Just,
please, don't suspend anyone else.
Vascular Surgeon to O.R. Two.
Two-oh Vicryl. Have you done a
Connell technique yet, Edwards?
- Like to try it?
- I would love to.
Uh, that's a very
complex repair.
The idea is to see what
the resident is capable of.
It's not like
Dr. Minnick is in here.
Dr. Minnick is the
residency director.
Suction, Kepner.
More distal, Edwards.
I'm sorry. Are you really
okay with all of this?
Let it go, April.
Good, good. Now, go under
again, and that should cinch it up.
- Where do you want me?
- Left arm.
Just missed the brachial artery.
She's losing her leg, huh?
Yeah, her foot's already
developed gangrene.
The wire disrupted
the popliteal artery.
Did a number on her
abdominal wall too.
Can I get a three-oh
nylon, please?
Yeah, you should
close up the subcue first.
We going with the
Minnick method here?
By necessity. I cut up
my arms pretty good.
So, why the change of heart?
- What?
- Karev.
Why'd you let him off the hook?
Is it okay if we
don't talk about that?
It's just... it's my personal
business. I don't...
Of course. Sorry. Of course.
So, what's the deal with
this lady anyway, huh?
What do we think she's
got behind that wall?
Meth lab? Hmm? Puppy mill?
Think she's a nudist?
Maybe she's the
tinfoil hat lady.
You know, maybe
she's just stubborn
and locked herself away,
and it's gonna cost her a limb.
Right.
That's not a great look.
Well, Diane, our
initial biopsy results...
They show inflammatory
breast cancer.
- We need to confirm, but...
- Breast cancer?
But... but there
are no lumps. I...
I understand. It's...
a particularly
aggressive form of cancer
that presents as external skin
reactions more often than lumps.
- Dear God.
- I am so sorry.
Now, you'll have to
have a full work-up,
at which point we can
discuss our options.
I'll be able to refer
you to local specialists.
You're in Hawaii, I believe?
I know a terrific group of
oncologists out there on the Big Island,
and I'll be more than happy
to travel to you for surgery.
That's if... if you'd like.
You would?
You're Maggie
Pierce's mom, so, yes.
Would you like me to
grab Maggie for you?
Oh, no. No, don't. No.
Not while she's working.
I'll tell her tonight.
What are you calling this again?
This is called inflammatory
breast cancer or IBC.
It's a local form
of the disease.
Maggie's gonna have
a million questions.
Will you help me tell her?
- Can you do that?
- Of course.
Absolutely.
Um, I'm sorry if I pushed.
What's between you and
Dr. Webber is none of my business.
You don't owe me an apology.
You owe Dr. Bailey one.
We were taking a stand
for Dr. Webber. I don't
understand why you...
Dr. Webber doesn't need
you to fight his battles.
What you did stands to
hurt this entire hospital.
Your first priority needs to
be this place and its patients.
You should not be proud about what
you did, you should be embarrassed.
Hi! How are we doing in here?
Annie, the injuries caused
by the razor wire were deep.
Some of the cuts compromised
the blood flow to your right leg.
Unfortunately, we... we had
to amputate below the knee.
How'd they find me?
Well, a neighbor called 911,
and then the firefighters
broke the gate down.
Listen, they saved your life.
Damn razor wire. I
got most of it down.
Then I fell off the ladder
into the whole mess of it.
- You were taking it down?
- Yeah.
My husband and I,
we didn't trust people.
There's just so much
bad stuff out there.
Started with locks,
alarms, and cameras...
And then the wall. It
felt safe, you know?
It was him and me
against the world.
But then he died, and...
It just felt more like a prison.
Every day I'd...
get the paper, and I'd
think about going farther.
But I never could.
So then I thought,
start with the wall.
Just take the stupid thing down.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry
about your leg.
I feel like one of them animals
that chewed its leg
off to get out of a trap.
But I got out.
I finally got out!
Thanks.
- Hey. You got a minute?
- No.
Look, you never gave
me a chance to say...
Don't. Okay? Don't thank me.
I'm not. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry I hurt you. I'm sorry...
It was a misunderstanding.
You got the wrong
end of me overreacting.
I'm glad you're okay,
and I'm really sorry.
- Are you serious?
- Yeah.
I gave you every
chance to say that.
For months, you could
have just said that.
I said it that night.
Oh, yeah, because you
didn't want me to tell the cops
that you beat me up.
You came to me
in my hospital room
when I was jacked
up on painkillers
afraid I was never
gonna see again.
You tried, and then you
never talked to me again.
I saw you almost every day. I
worked for your friends every day.
I knew what happened that night.
I knew what you were thinking.
I knew why you hit me. If
you would have just treated me
like a human being, if you
would have just talked to me,
maybe we could
have avoided all this.
- I didn't think you'd listen.
- Yeah? Well,
I'm a pretty good guy!
Why'd you do it?
- I don't
have to explain myself...
- Just tell me.
Jo's been through enough.
She doesn't need to
live her life being scared.
Yeah, well, Jo would say she's
pretty good at taking care of herself.
Yeah, well, should she have to?
- Hi.
- Your mom's in the kitchen.
She what? What? You met my mom?
- Yeah.
- She met you.
- She met you without me.
- We did more than meet.
I mean, she folded laundry, put
the kids to bed, and fed me lasagna.
God. I am so sorry. I'm so
sorry she's been in the way.
Are you kidding? I'm in love
with her. The woman's incredible.
Maggie! Oh, good!
I'm going to binge watch
TV. Tell her she can move in.
Mom, I really wish that you'd...
Hey, Maggie. Hey.
I invited Dr. Avery.
Of course, you did.
Because who doesn't invite
their plastic surgeon to dinner?
Come, have
something to eat, honey.
Mom, we have plans with
Richard Webber. You made them.
I know. I thought we
might postpone that.
I thought it would be nice to
have a quiet dinner at home.
- Is that okay?
- Why not?
- Are you upset with me, Maggie?
- Am I...
Yes, Mom. Yes.
You show up here without warning
for plastic surgery that you don't need.
- You embarrass me
in front of my friends.
- When did I embarrass you?
Then you make dinner
plans with Richard,
and you blow them off like
they don't mean anything.
- Oh, he'll understand.
- You talk to Meredith
without me.
You talk to Richard,
you talk to Jackson.
I mean, you two go way back.
Uh, Dr. Avery, I am sorry.
You don't get to apologize
for me to my friends.
This is my life that
you've walked into.
You can't just come in and
rearrange things without asking me.
When did you become so selfish?
I am not the one who
destroyed our family.
Who moved to
Hawaii to make soap,
without thinking about who you
were leaving behind or hurting.
And now you come here and you...
You are the one who is selfish.
You only think about yourself.
Maggie, if I could...
I think you should go, Jackson.
I'm so sorry that Maggie's
being so very rude.
I'm being rude? You
just kicked my friend out
of a house that wasn't
even yours to invite him to.
God! Mom...
I have no idea who
you are anymore.
Guys, I'm here if
you need anything.
Thank you.
You are right.
You don't have any
idea who I am anymore,
because you haven't
taken the time to try.
The moment I left your father,
it was like I could finally breathe.
Now, I know that's not something
you want to hear, but it's true.
I...
I have finally become the
person that I always wanted to be.
I want my mother back.
I'm sorry you don't like
who I've become, but I do.
And I'm not apologizing
for that. Not anymore.
- Where are you going?
- I'm going to the hotel. I...
- Mom. I've an early
flight in the morning.
You have a great life here.
You call when you're
ready to share it with me.
- You wanted to see me, Chief?
- Sit.
It is obvious that you
don't support my decision.
I just... I just think that
Dr. Webber is the backbone of this...
Save it. You're not gonna win
a loyalty contest against me.
You support Dr. Webber. I
get it. That's your business.
But my business is making
sure this hospital runs,
and right now, some people
are making that very hard.
So it is tough
decision time, Kepner.
Congratulations.
- On?
- Getting your way.
I'm pretty sure the chief is starting
to think I'm not worth the trouble.
- She is a smart lady.
- She could fire me.
- I wouldn't cry.
- No, you'd be terrified.
Because then you
would have to face it.
- Face what?
- If Bailey fired me,
you and I would be an option.
We could date. We could kiss.
We could... actually
be something.
So screw you.
- You think this tie is too much?
- No.
That's a nice place you all
are going to. No, this is good.
You know, I worked
with April all day today.
She could not shut up about
Grey getting suspended.
Well, I don't blame
her. It's outrageous.
You think it was the right call?
I think Bailey had to
send a clear message.
To me. About me.
Well, I think she's...
Actually, I don't
want to get into it.
We're in it.
You're on Bailey's side on this.
Richard. You're going to
have a lovely dinner tonight.
Don't ruin it. We can
talk about this later.
This is from Maggie. She
has to cancel dinner tonight.
So...
I guess we can
talk about this now.
- Why?
- We have pizza and beer.
I have shows with swords
and dragons and decapitations.
We also have gossip.
Come in. Where's Warren?
He's married to the chief.
- So...?
- So, he is not to be trusted.
- I didn't invite him.
- Yeah.
Edwards wants to have some
weird sort of strategy session.
Listen, Bailey called a meeting
with the attendings last night,
and no one showed up.
Not a single one. So Grey isn't
the only one trying to get Minnick out.
Yeah, but we're residents.
It doesn't really concern us.
It only concerns us.
This is our education, we
worked hard to get here,
and they're obstructing us.
Look, Kepner, Avery, and
Robbins are all with Grey.
- Karev probably will be, too.
- Karev?
Karev is in prison.
What?
Why did she leave, though?
Because I'm terrible, and I
exhausted her with my terribleness.
Now she's gone, and I
can't make it up to her
and I feel awful. I
love my mother. I do.
But for her to just barge in
here like that with no warning...
And she was weird.
She was. She was, she was
flighty and nervous and weird.
God, I couldn't
wait for her to go.
She makes some
good lasagna, though.
Are you seeing this?
Bailey hired an
interim chief of general?
Bailey replaced you? With who?
Kepner?
Kepner.
Amelia.
Every day you
don't open the door,
it gets a little
easier to stay inside.
I can't pull you out anymore.
No one can open
this door but you.
And I want to be
here. I will be. But...
Amelia.
Tell her I'm not
gonna wait forever.
We have to keep
something to ourselves.
Or else anyone can get to us.
They'll see the stuff
we don't show anyone.
So we build the
walls high and wide.
And we lock the gates.