Morning.
I have to pick up
Owen at Helen's
before work.
Yeah, I get it.
You know, um...
Last night was...
It was really great.
Yeah, it was.
Huh.
I don't think I've
seen this one before.
Helmand Province.
That was our last
deployment together.
Wow.
Jeff looks so young.
Hey, we're good, right?
Of course.
Okay.
Good.
Bye.
See ya.
This is what I always
carried in the field.
Gear for fluid resuscitation,
hemorrhage control,
airway management,
basic meds,
including OTCs.
Always have lots of Pepto.
Oh, and tape.
Can never have too much tape.
Yes, sir.
It's, uh, a lot
to take in.
I know. When do you deploy?
Um, twelve weeks, sir.
Look, nothing really
prepares you for war.
But a day in Chicago,
the number of gunshots we see,
the Navy sending corpsmen for
a rotation in the ED
is a pretty good primer.
What's that, sir?
Is it a quick
reference guide?
Case notes from the field.
Things I thought
I shouldn't forget.
Dr. Choi,
we got a drive-up and drop.
Corpsman, with me.
Sir.
All right. I got you,
buddy. I got you, okay?
Hey, what's your name?
Marco.
Marco. Marco, okay.
Okay, you stay with me.
We're gonna take care of you.
Single GSW.
Left flank thoracoabdomen.
No exit wound.
Weak pulse.
Corpsman, cut his shirt off.
Yes, sir.
Hey, hey. Corpsman,
what do you hear?
Come on. Hey.
I have weak breath
sounds on the left side.
Means the lung
is collapsed.
Air leaking out is
pressurizing his chest.
He's got
a tension pneumothorax.
Breath sounds
unilateral and tachycardic.
Needle the chest.
Hold the pressure.
Yes, sir.
In.
Okay. Breath
sounds improving.
Good.
Bring in a board.
All right.
Easy, easy, easy, easy.
All right,
let's move him
on my count.
One, two, three.
Jeff, let's get an
AP chest X-ray and
prep a chest tube.
Got it.
He said, "I'm only 18."
Welcome to Chi-raq.
All right, now, try to
stay off the hoverboard
for at least a week,
Hudson, okay?
Yeah?
Of course.
Bye. Thank you.
Hey, Gayle.
Taking your daily lap
around our gorgeous grounds?
Anything to get out of
the pediatric
ICU for a minute.
I swear, if I hear
another monitor beep,
I'm gonna nosedive
onto Michigan Avenue.
And how is little
Timmy doing?
Hey, cutie.
He's had a good month,
thanks to Dr. Rhodes.
I hoped we'd finally
get to go outside today.
He's a little wheezy.
Probably best we
head back upstairs.
Okay.
Dr. Manning?
It was nice
seeing you, Gayle.
You, too.
Right away.
Hi, I'm Dr. Manning.
Hi. My daughter, Alicia,
she stopped nursing.
She's only three months old.
Okay. Well, don't worry.
We'll figure out
what's going on.
Why don't you
follow me into the back?
I'll take the paperwork.
You guys want to
go in the back?
Yep.
All right.
Okay, I got
a new favorite,
Capgras Syndrome.
The belief
a familiar person
has been replaced
with a duplicate.
That's cool.
That was an
unenthusiastic response,
even for you.
Sorry.
It's the new
pathology resident, Mark.
Hmm?
He's in my head.
What's going on?
He's pushing really hard
to get drinks after work.
Hang out on the weekends.
Mmm-hmm.
Be pals.
It's uncomfortable.
Why? Are you worried
something bad will happen
if you become friends?
What? No, it's just
I'd rather be colleagues.
I've got enough friends.
Is there a limit to
the number of people
you can let into your life?
Maybe. Yeah.
What is all this?
Nothing. We're just talking.
Okay.
I've gotta get back.
Are we still on for dinner?
Yeah, sure.
She's gurgling a bit,
but there's no
obstruction in her throat.
She doesn't appear
too dehydrated, and
her membranes are moist.
When did she
stop nursing?
Yesterday.
I'm gonna
put this up, okay?
I wasn't too worried at first.
My boys were
both finicky eaters.
But when she wouldn't nurse
at all today, then...
Any fever or vomiting?
No, none.
Um...
She's been a bit cranky.
She's been napping
longer than usual,
but that's about it.
Mama, I'm thirsty.
Okay, baby, we will
get you a drink
as soon as we speak
to the doctor, okay?
All right?
No, no, no. I'm so sorry.
Um, we go to the park
every day.
They're exhausted.
My husband will be
here to help any minute.
Don't worry about it.
Uh, let's get a CBC, CMP,
an abdominal
ultrasound and a babygram.
Yes, doctor.
Uh, a babygram?
Uh, an X-ray
of her entire body.
So, this could be serious.
There's no way to
know for sure just yet,
but I want to
cover all our bases.
I should've
brought her in sooner.
It's just with my
husband at work...
Look, you are
juggling three kids, okay?
I get it.
I only have one,
and it's a handful.
I will fill you in as
soon as we know anything.
Thank you.
No, Nina, I've ditched cable,
cut up my credit cards,
and have nothing left
to sell on Craigslist.
Yet, I'm still in
the hole each month
when the vig is due.
Easy there, Vegas.
It's med school loans
and malpractice insurance,
not a note from a bookie.
Either way, I'm broke.
Had to post an ad
for a roommate.
Here, look at this.
Come on,
it'll make you feel better.
What is it?
Molluscum contagiosum.
It's a type of pox virus.
It's a nasty one, actually.
Mmm.
Even so, stunning, right?
It's like 10 pounds
of raspberry rock candy
pressed into a five-pound bag.
Come on, you must
have a day off, right?
Go then.
It's summertime,
the animals are
really playful, you know?
Elephants are my favorite.
They're so soulful.
Okay, you sold me.
Yeah.
This Saturday,
I'm at the Lincoln Park Zoo.
Okay.
BP 126 over 82.
Heart rate 74. Sats 100%.
Hi, Mr. McGregor,
I'm Dr. Halstead.
I understand you fell,
hurt both wrists.
Yeah, just a
moment of clumsiness,
you know.
But they feel
better already now.
Don't be modest.
He's here. Let him help.
MR. McGREGOR: I put my
hands out just trying to
catch my fall, you know?
Mmm-hmm.
Yeah. Fifteen years
on the street.
I guess I'm not as fast
as I used to be. Yeah.
AP and lateral X-rays
of both wrists.
Okay.
Have you fallen before,
Mr. McGregor?
A few times.
So much action
in the city nowadays.
You stop paying
attention for a second,
bam!
Face plant.
Right.
Pretty big guy,
Dr. Halstead. Football?
Baseball.
Just a fan now, though.
Cubs or Sox?
Southside pride.
Sox all the way.
Ah! I'm a Cubs guy.
I won't hold it
against you.
Hmm.
Love Wrigley.
The way the ivy creeps along
the outfield wall.
You know,
perfect stripes mowed
right into the infield grass.
Breathtaking.
Mmm-hmm.
Do you stay
near the ball park?
During the season.
Sure, why not?
You know, it's fun
seeing the players
in person,
they're larger than life.
Moises Alou.
Sammy Sosa.
Oh, yeah? Wow.
Must be really exciting.
Oh, yeah!
Mr. McGregor,
after your X-rays,
I want to run an EKG.
It'll determine if
a cardiac event caused
your fall. Sound good?
Sure, yeah.
All right.
We'll see you soon.
You know, they haven't
had elephants
at the Lincoln
Park Zoo for ages.
Mmm-hmm.
You think he really met
those baseball players?
Not recently.
Alou and Sosa's last season
with the Cubs was in '04.
So, I guess maybe Mr. McGregor
could have seen them
outside the park, but...
Maybe not.
Unfortunately, homelessness
and mental illness
often go hand in hand.
I'll page Dr. Charles
for a consult.
Okay.
How's Marco doing, sir?
Bullet looks to have
lodged in the midline
between the spine and heart.
May even be touching
the aorta. Bad spot.
You get a lot like him?
The drive-up and drops?
Yeah.
Easy way to get
your boys patched up
without having to
answer any questions.
Hey, Marco.
A trauma surgeon is
gonna come see you.
She'll decide how
best to proceed.
You cutting me open?
Probably.
If the bullet shifts
inside you, it could
do a lot of damage.
No, man.
Not "whatever."
Lot of you guys
come in here and
don't make it out.
If you do,
make it mean something.
I ain't afraid.
Okay.
He's saying that...
The usual.
Revenge.
Timothy Williams,
eight months old.
Diagnosed with
Hypoplastic Left
Heart Syndrome.
Bryan, can you
tell us what that is?
I know.
It's a congenital
heart defect.
Left side of the heart
can't efficiently pump blood,
so the right side has
to pump it to the lungs
and the rest of the body.
Correct.
Now, Tim is on
the heart transplant list.
But he's developing
fluid around his lungs,
a pleural effusion.
He requires
a thoracentesis
to drain it.
The patient is sedated,
and the ultrasound shows
the fluid
surrounding his right lung.
Lidocaine is injected
just below
the surface of the skin,
forming a wheel.
We go through the wheel,
and into
the pleural space,
staying above the rib
because the blood
vessels are below.
If you go too far,
you puncture the lung.
Once you're in,
aspirate the fluid.
Give us a minute.
Gayle, John.
I think it's best
that Tim not leave
the PICU going forward.
No more trips downstairs.
You mean keep him
on the vent.
He's not oxygenating well.
His lungs are very congested.
Hon, he's gonna
get a heart soon.
Listen, everything's gonna
be okay. You hear me?
Mmm.
I'm gonna check
the transplant list.
See if there's
been any movement.
Thanks.
Hi.
My husband, Andre,
took the boys
to get some food.
He'll be back soon. Any news?
The blood tests and
babygram were okay.
Nothing abnormal
in the abdominal
ultrasound either.
Thank goodness.
Dr. Manning.
May I take a look at her?
Yeah.
Thank you.
Do you have any family history
of neuromuscular disease?
No, none.
Her deep tendon
reflexes are diminished.
She's floppy.
Her muscles
are losing tone.
What is it?
What do you see?
Uh, a baby's natural
position is to flex the legs.
And when straightened,
there should be
some resistance.
Let's get a CT
of her head.
I want to make sure that
there's no
swelling in her brain.
"Swelling in her brain"?
I don't know that
that's the case,
but we just have to check.
If the CT comes back negative,
then we will do
a lumbar puncture
to test her spinal fluid.
Why?
That'll let us know if
she has an infection.
My poor baby.
Just hang in there,
okay?
We'll know more soon.
That is one sick baby.
What do you think
is going on?
I have no idea.
Surgeon ordered a chest CT.
I'll let you know what's up.
Then what happened?
So they were all looking at me
and clapping, right?
So I started dancing, too.
We partied all afternoon.
Uh, sounds like a blast.
You know, there'll probably be
another fiesta next week.
Families rent that
restaurant for them
all the time.
You should check it out.
All-day party
would do me good.
What was he
telling you about?
A quinceañera he
attended last week.
Didn't miss a detail
about the people he met,
the clothes they wore,
the venue.
I mean, he really
thinks he was there.
But he wasn't.
I know the place
he was talking about,
or I knew it.
It closed 10, 11 years ago.
It's a Starbucks now.
Schizophrenia?
Some kind of
delusional disorder.
I mean, he also admitted
that he binge
drinks sometimes.
Even though he's sober now,
could be
alcoholic hallucinosis.
I'm gonna order
an antipsychotic,
see if we can
narrow this down.
Well, for being
homeless the last 15 years,
he seems pretty okay with it.
Lucky guy.
"Lucky guy"?
Everything okay there, Doc?
Money problems.
Pretty embarrassing.
Kind of all-consuming,
actually.
Buy you lunch?
I'd rather you
write me a check.
Get in line there, amigo.
Her lips are turning blue!
What's happening?
She is in
respiratory distress,
unable to
contract her diaphragm
and chest muscles enough.
I need to intubate, now.
Broselow tape.
Okay.
Mr. and Mrs. James,
I'm gonna need you to
step outside, please.
Sats are falling.
Heart rate's stable.
Pharynx is collapsing
around the scope.
I need crike pressure!
Suction.
Sats still falling, 40%.
Heart rate's dropping.
It's at 60. Atropine?
Not yet.
It's been a minute.
Heart rate 30.
O2 sat is zero.
We're running
out of time.
I got it! I'm in!
Give the Atropine.
Right away.
Point five IV push.
Sats coming up.
Heart rate 130. Sats 99.
How long did it
take to intubate?
Almost two minutes.
Pupils are fixed and dilated.
Call PICU for a bed.
Got you.
I have to go
talk to the family.
Want me to join you?
No, no.
I got this, but thank you.
Okay, well, uh,
how about Thursday?
I'm busy Thursday, too.
Pretty busy week.
Run something by you,
Dr. Charles?
Shoot.
I was speaking
with a colleague
this morning.
My age,
intelligent, compassionate,
a great person, but shy.
Asocial?
Uh...
Not a loner per se,
but comfortable being alone.
Recently, he's been
presented with an opportunity
to expand
his social circle.
He wants nothing
to do with it.
So, what are you thinking?
His reaction.
Actually his
overreaction screams
Avoidant Personality Disorder.
Hmm.
This is a colleague?
A close one.
Probably why
I never noticed that
he meets four of
the seven APD criteria
outlined in the DCM.
The psych fits, doesn't it?
Clinically. Yeah, I guess.
Well, I'm gonna have to
talk to him about this,
but I don't want him to feel
criticized or rejected.
Excuse me,
I've got some reading to do.
Do you think "cat lover"
means "cat" or "cats"?
Does it matter?
Good point. Pass.
What's cosplay?
Oh.
Yeah? Okay, another pass.
The roommate search
is not going well.
Well, you're trolling
the Internet.
What do you expect?
It's the hospital
community page.
I don't know,
someone like me.
Oh, you mean, like,
a slightly anal,
overly stubborn,
rule-breaking, control freak?
Oh.
Good luck.
Really? When I'm
already down?
Mr. McGregor's EKG
and troponin
results are normal.
Cardiac event
didn't cause his fall.
Stroke?
Maybe. Or a bleed.
Either way, it could
affect his balance.
Let's get a CT.
So, what does that mean?
There could have
been a brain injury
due to lack of oxygen.
We're running
a cerebral flow study
to make sure that blood
is reaching her brain.
This isn't happening.
Yesterday,
I was singing to her
in the bathtub.
And now, she's hooked up
to all these
machines and nobody...
Dr. Rhodes!
Code Blue.
No pulse.
All right.
Start compressions.
Get him off
the vent and bag him.
0.07 milligrams of epi.
He's in v-fib.
Charge to 15 joules.
Charge 15.
Charged.
Hold compressions.
Clear.
We're back in sinus rhythm.
We have a pulse.
My God.
This is the floor
where babies die.
He's fourth on
the organ transplant list,
but he doesn't have time.
If, by some chance,
four hearts do
become available,
one still has to
be an HLA match.
I know the odds seem bleak,
but children under a year
have to receive organs
from similarly-aged donors.
The pool of
recipients is smaller.
Yes, but so is the
pool of donors.
Ms. Goodwin, I can't perform
another thoracentesis.
His lungs are too weak.
Without a transplant,
he's gonna die.
I'm contacting
the other doctors
on the donor list.
I'm pleading my case,
and it's...
Okay.
I have a contact
at Gift of Hope,
a friend of a friend.
Hold on.
I will do my best
to get Timothy pushed
to the top of the UNOS list,
but you know how delicate
these matters are.
Thank you.
Dr. Rhodes?
Be careful.
Hey.
Still no sparkly
on the finger.
Does that mean
you made a decision?
Not yet.
April, the guy
proposed two months ago.
You owe him an answer.
I know. It's complicated.
He told me
I could quit my job.
I'm worried that means
he thinks I'm a housewife.
I'm not a housewife.
In his house, no less,
the one he shared with his ex.
It's a huge decision,
and it's all happened so fast.
And, of course,
then there's the TB.
Mmm.
I mean, the whole thing
just really makes me anxious.
What?
What are you thinking?
Anxiety is a
powerful emotion.
Would you say that
you feel more nervous
about the situation or
fearful of the future?
I don't know.
Both, I guess.
How've you been sleeping?
You waking up at night,
or any earlier
than you'd like?
What?
Oh, my God.
You're shrinking me.
Three weeks in psych,
and she's Freud.
What?
She said "anxious"
and "worried."
Those are emotions
that convey distress.
You know,
Meigs Field is beautiful
down the river.
The sun reflects off
the water with the blues
and the greens,
and the luminescence...
How you doing there,
Mr. McGregor?
Hey, Dr. Charles,
how are you?
Who are you, um...
Who are you talking to?
It was the nurse. Yeah.
She mentioned how
she walks her dog
along the lakefront.
Took off from there.
Let me tell you something,
Doctor.
There was a time
I used to hate hospitals,
but that's before
I noticed the details.
The staff floating
through the halls
like angels...
There. Do you see that?
White light surrounding.
Oh!
Beautiful aura.
Yeah.
You know,
I missed the beginning.
You were talking
about your favorite spot.
Where was that?
South End Meigs Field.
You excuse me
one second?
Absolutely.
I'm here if you need me.
Mr. McGregor get his
antipsychotics yet?
Yes. Two milligrams
of Risperidone.
Little over three hours ago.
You'd think it'd
be making a dent
in his symptoms by now.
Not really happening.
Give me a shout
when the CT results
come in.
You got it.
Hey, can I talk to
you for a second?
Sure.
Not here.
What? No! No!
Absolutely not.
I'm still working
on a diagnosis.
What you're asking
me to do is premature
and completely unethical.
Natalie, please.
You're running
a cerebral blood-flow test
for Alicia.
You clearly think that
brain death is a possibility.
A possibility.
But I will not get
those test results back
for another few hours.
So, all I'm asking
is that you speak
to Alicia's family
about organ donation.
Look, just let me
run an HLA test.
Just to see if she's a match.
Just in...
Should the worst happen.
Okay.
You know that...
If I do that,
I'm insinuating to her parents
that she's definitely gone.
You are putting me
in a terrible position.
You're right.
When Tim was born,
he wasn't breathing.
I performed his first surgery.
When he came to,
I was the first person he saw.
And he put his hand
around my finger.
Please, Nat.
I can't lose this kid.
So, it's about
2:00 in the morning,
pitch black out.
We start taking fire.
Small arms.
Just a few bad guys.
One of our guys drops
into a wadi for cover.
Wham!
Gets hit right
in the foot.
Oh, man.
When I get to him,
he's writhing in agony.
I shine my light
on his boot,
see two tiny
puncture wounds.
So, what was going on?
Slowly, I light up the wadi,
and right there,
staring back at me,
is a cobra.
Get the hell out.
Hood flared.
Ready to strike again.
Man, that's insane.
We just heard.
Our banger, Marco?
CT showed that the bullet
isn't in the midline
or touching the aorta.
It's in the left
paraspinal muscles.
Surgeon gonna
go in and get it?
No. Says it's harmless.
Safer to leave it in there.
Should be as good
as new in a few days.
And back on the street.
Yeah.
Snakes here, too.
Organ donation?
So, Alicia's brain dead?
The test results
have not come back yet.
Then why are you
even here asking us
to cut up our baby?
No, that's not
what I'm saying.
Have you given up on her?
No.
No, I swear I'm doing
everything in my power
to diagnose your daughter.
I don't believe this.
Alicia's life is
hanging in the balance.
Our baby girl!
Andre, just...
No, she's saying
that there's no hope.
But there is.
Alicia is still alive.
She's supposed
to be our doctor.
Mr. James, please.
I know that this is
difficult to process,
but the reality is,
we don't know
what the test results
are gonna say.
And right now,
there's a baby
fighting to survive.
A baby just like Alicia.
What would it require?
We already have
Alicia's blood.
All I'm asking is that
you allow us to test it.
Alicia's a match.
Yeah.
I know this wasn't easy.
Thank you.
You know, as a doctor,
you want to do everything
in your power
to save your patient.
And I am.
But it's just now...
If I save my patient,
it means yours won't make it.
Mr. McGregor has
a pituitary tumor.
A big one.
Yeah, it appears
to be pressing
on the optic chiasm.
Which, if his vision
is impaired,
could explain why he fell.
How long do you
think it's been there?
Based on the size,
a decade. Maybe even longer.
Huh.
Meigs Field,
torn down in '03.
In '04, Sammy Sosa
and Moises Alou
were still
fixtures at Wrigley.
Yeah.
The restaurant
where the quinceañera
took place
was still
open for business.
All the while,
Mr. McGregor's tumor
is likely growing,
putting pressure
on his optic chiasm.
He's still really
congested.
So order a chest X-ray
and give him
5 milligrams of Lasix
to try and clear
some of the fluid.
Dr. Rhodes, it seems like
he's getting
worse pretty quickly.
Is he gonna make it
to the transplant?
Do you know what
we did last month?
We bought a car seat.
We were so sure
that we were
gonna beat the PICU,
finally take
our baby boy home.
The fight is not over yet.
The important thing
for you right now
is to try and stay
in the present.
What do we got?
Joy Billings,
44-year-old female.
Triple zero.
GSW to the chest.
18 gauge IV in the right AC.
No drugs given per protocol.
Baghdad's alive!
Down time?
Roughly eight minutes.
What happened?
Watching TV with her kids.
Rival gangs
start blasting at
each other outside.
Stray bullet
ripped into the house.
All right,
let's move her
on my count.
Ready? One, two, three.
Call the blood bank, get a type...
Police get the shooters?
Yeah.
Buddies of the kid
from this morning, Marco.
Breath sounds bilaterally.
She's lost a lot of blood.
Trigger the MTP.
Hang blood on
the rapid transfuser.
Maggie, need a
trauma surgeon now.
She's in the OR.
Three minutes.
That's too long. Chest tray.
Yes, Doctor.
You're gonna cut her open?
First incision.
Second incision.
Corpsman,
I need you to take over
so I can
cross-clamp her aorta.
Yes, sir.
Back and forth
as if
you were clapping.
In.
Hold compressions.
Resume compressions.
Milligram of epi.
Hold.
Resume.
Beat, damn it, beat.
Come on.
Asystole.
Beat.
Beat!
Time of death, 15:42.
And Marco is gonna go home.
Dr. Rhodes?
Is there a donor
in the hospital
for Timmy?
We heard a rumor.
It's her child,
isn't it?
Her little girl?
They're the only
new patients
on the floor.
We've been here
for eight months.
We know everybody else.
It has to be her.
I'm sorry, Gayle.
But the HIPAA regulations
won't allow me
to discuss another patient.
Hi.
The spinal tap
was clean.
I've ruled out all
the common causes.
We must be looking
at something rare.
Have you had any
foreign visitors?
Anyone outside of your
normal social circle?
No.
Has your house been sprayed
with pesticides?
No, none of that.
Nothing. No.
I'd like to reach
out to toxicology...
Would you look at them
over there,
watching like vultures?
Why don't they show
some damn respect?
Andre.
My fault, son.
I shouldn't have shouted.
Mr. and Mrs. James,
I'm so sorry
that you're going...
Those, um...
Those grass stains.
When you take
the boys to the park,
what do you do with Alicia?
I lay her down
on her stomach
for tummy time.
You know what?
I'd like to consult
with Infectious Diseases.
Excuse me, please.
Pupils are reactive.
Mr. McGregor, can you
follow the light
with your eyes?
How about now?
Mr. McGregor,
how many fingers
am I holding up?
Three.
Okay.
And now?
One.
Good job.
I'll be right back.
Legally blind?
No, he can detect
sharp lights
and block images.
Probably how he
made out my size earlier.
But anything more
than a few feet away
is likely just a blur.
His pituitary tumor,
is it operable?
I'll have neuro consult,
but I suspect
it's a prolactinoma.
If so, medication alone
should shrink it enough
to ease the pressure
off the optic chiasm.
So, he's gonna get
some of his sight back.
Fifteen years.
Homeless, essentially blind.
I mean, that's a crap hand.
He should be pissed.
Yet, he's happy as can be.
Crazy I got
this patient today.
My experience,
we get the patients we need.
You've created a monster,
you know that?
Turns out the English language
is primarily
comprised of buzzwords
for borderline
personality disorders.
And now that I know them,
I can't have a conversation
without immediately
seeing the psych in people,
which is clearly
an impulsive reaction,
which, by the way,
could also suggest
a borderline
personality disorder.
I mean, I can't even
not analyze myself.
And now I'm using
double negatives.
You're a first-year
psych resident.
Compulsive diagnosing
is par for the course.
My first year,
I was convinced
that a friend of mine
had dissociative
identity disorder,
because suddenly he would
only listen to Euro disco.
Really.
My advice.
Think less, listen more.
You'll be just fine.
Sir...
Just wanted to
thank you for today.
My pleasure.
I'm spent.
Not gonna be easy
over there.
You'll get through it.
The medicine, sure.
The rest...
Well, I just hope
I can handle my emotions
as well as you.
Good luck.
Botulism?
Isn't that a food thing?
I'm still
breastfeeding.
Most cases actually come from
contaminated soil.
It can be absorbed
through the skin.
The park. Tummy time.
Is it treatable?
Yes. Yes.
We will start
Alicia on an antitoxin
that will provide antibodies
to stop
the disease's progress.
But what about the vent?
The neurotoxin
from the bacteria
is what caused
the muscle weakness.
I believe she will
make a full recovery.
Thank you so much, Doctor.
Thank you.
Hey.
What's it this time?
Gout.
Oh.
May I?
What do you think?
An explosion of
brilliant crystals.
Like Hawaiian shave ice.
Hmm.
I know how you pathologists
love food references.
Yes, we do.
Yeah. Uh, okay.
No, I understand.
Thanks for your time,
Dr. Laurel.
Damn it.
It's gonna come through.
How do you do it?
They're just babies.
Well...
On rough days, I call Helen.
Ask her to watch Owen
for a few extra hours
while I do
something to decompress.
A good meal, a long walk.
Just something to
let my emotions settle.
I find a safe space.
See you tomorrow.
Night.
Hey. How'd the rest
of your day go?
Not so sure I want
to talk about work.
Yeah, I may have
overstepped a bit earlier.
So you were analyzing me?
Unintentionally, though.
Ugh.
I'll make it up to you
with burgers at Au Cheval?
And you can tell me all about
how the Bears are doing.
But you know
nothing about football.
Exactly.