Previously, on
The Good Doctor...
Shaun, I have cancer.
I have to undergo brain
surgery, which is really scary.
To be clear, Jared, I
don't want you here.
- I fought for my job.
- You compromised your integrity.
My former mentor
is head of the surgical residency
program at Denver Memorial Hospital.
A surgeon needs to communicate.
Can Dr. Murphy do that?
Can he do that under stress?
Can he do that
knowing that a human life
literally hangs in the balance?
- Shaun?
- If Shaun proves anything
less than excellent,
I will resign my position
as president of this hospital.
I know why Caden has DIC.
It was my mistake.
I have to tell Dr. Andrews
about the mistake I made.
Shaun, you can't.
I'm not gonna ask him
to lie to save my job.
It's up to Shaun.
Hello? Yes, of course.
Dr. Murphy, the
President will see you now.
Hello. I'm Dr. Shaun Murphy.
I'm a surgical resident at San
Jose Saint Bonaventure Hospital.
So, what did Andrews
have to say to you?
Shaun.
You've exceeded my expectations
in terms of expertise
and technical execution,
but your communication
skills are sorely lacking.
That has to change if you wanna
stay here at Saint Bonaventure.
He told me I
exceeded expectations.
Great.
- Sounds, uh, sounds great, Shaun.
- Yes.
I think you should have
gone to your review.
Since it's my last day,
not much opportunity
to make use of feedback.
Dr. Andrews could
have some wisdom
that you could use in
Denver at your next job.
Even if I did care
about his opinion,
it was made pretty obvious
by the fact that we're here.
This is Glassman's project.
Andrews thinks
it's a money trap.
How'd your review go, Claire?
Went well.
Andrews said I connected
nicely, and I cared about people.
Interesting.
I'd have thought he'd want
you to be more aggressive.
I think you need to be
more assertive, Dr. Browne.
Okay.
No.
What'd he say about you?
Figure out how to be a
little less self-centered
and realize you're
part of a team?
You're sometimes overbearing.
Often egotistical.
You need to be
more of a team player.
Melanie Arnott.
The patient has
pulmonary hypertension.
The only treatment
is medication,
which reduces the
lung blood pressure,
but not enough. Her heart's
failing due to the extra strain.
That is a factually-correct
diagnosis. What about a fix?
Isn't it just a transplant?
Nope.
There's nothing inherently wrong
with Melanie's heart. It's healthy,
it just needs a
little bit of help.
So, we're gonna leave
her current heart inside,
and slot in another
one to support it.
A piggyback transplant?
Nice, huh?
- Do you live in a tent?
- Uh, yeah.
I lived in a tent, too.
It wasn't very good,
so I moved to a bus.
You should move to a bus.
You will be much less likely to
develop ulcerative tinea pedis.
Very early stages.
Just keep it dry and clean,
and we'll give you some...
Would you rather we
continued to discuss this inside?
We are discussing
things with the patient
that are potentially
sensitive, so I...
We're done with the patient.
Did Andrews happen to speak
to you about communication?
Yes. I'm trying very hard.
It's definitely something
you should work on.
Things might be different...
More difficult for you now
Glassman's not around.
Dr. Glassman is still around.
He's alive and he
is not going to die.
He's meeting his
oncologist today.
You... you didn't go with him?
No. That would be stupid.
I am a resident.
I don't know as much
about brain cancer
as a double board-certified
neuro-oncologist.
True. But this has gotta be
challenging for him, emotionally.
I can't help him, emotionally.
Excuse me. Please.
Thank you for
keeping me waiting.
We doctors are busy,
important people.
Yeah, we doctors are.
So, pre-op, clearance,
surgery, radiation and chemo.
We're gonna have a lot of fun.
I hope you don't mind
if I start with pre-op.
Did you change the
policy on pot use?
Are you using again?
Should I worry?
I'm clean. I miss
it, but I'm clean.
They test me every week now.
Good.
I think you had me reinstated,
as your last official act before
they booted you as president,
because I am the
best oncologist around
and you would like to
get the best treatment.
Yeah.
So, I'd like to
ensure that the brain,
in this instance, my brain, stays
as dry as possible during surgery,
maintain minimal swelling.
I would still like to be able
to swing my nine iron
when we're done here.
Of course, it's also possible
that you had me reinstated
because you'd like an oncologist
who thinks they owe you,
and you wanna push them around.
Look, Dr. Blaize, I am
like any other patient,
entitled to have a say
in my own treatment.
But unlike any other patient,
I have spent my entire adult
life digging into people's brains.
So, if you think I'm gonna sit
around and watch, you're mistaken.
Well, if you think you
can operate on yourself,
I'd happily add you to the
list of potential surgeons.
Today you're gonna be waiting.
And waiting.
Test, test, test. You've
had them all before.
I want them again, my versions.
You free all day?
Yeah, sure.
I'm free.
Sir?
We're going to need
you to give those back.
What's your name?
I'm Harry. These are my meds!
Those pills are for people
with chlamydia, Harry.
No. You're all the same.
See, I know better. That's why
I have to hide out on the streets.
I had to move next
door to Mr. Googly-Eyes.
I... I trust him!
He's my friend!
I trust him.
- I trust him.
- Okay. Okay.
- Disorganized thinking...
- He's always watching me.
Paranoia and delusions.
I think you have
schizophrenia, Harry.
Do you have chlamydia as well?
Harry? Harry, are you okay?
That smells very bad.
I get that this
is rare, exciting.
The sort of surgery you
guys must jump at doing.
I... I just... I wanna
make sure that we don't...
They're not.
I have three months left. This
will give me at least 10 more years.
Should give you
10 more years, yes.
Elliot, I understand
your concerns, but...
And Dr. Melendez is one of the
best cardiac surgeons around.
Dr. Andrews told
us all about you
when he convinced me to
come here for surgery instead of...
You spoke to Dr. Andrews?
And they've both already spent
half the morning raving to the press.
Well, it's... That's very kind.
You spoke to the press?
You spoke to the
patient? My patient?
As I explained to
Elliot and Melanie,
the press attention is a necessary
element for funding this surgery.
But as you didn't explain to them,
it's simultaneously a vanity project
to create buzz for
your new presidency.
As I didn't explain to them,
this surgery can change the way
our entire hospital is perceived.
I'm hoping this
"buzz," as you put it,
will help us establish a
Surgical Center for Excellence.
It'll be a nice
feather in the cap
for whoever replaces
me as chief of surgery.
Okay. Swill your mouth
out with alcohol now.
- Never said no to that.
- You will have to spit.
Oh, well.
Over here.
Are you having trouble
with your neck, Harry?
It's stiff.
A stiff neck could be an early
indicator of bacterial meningitis.
There are many possible
explanations for a stiff neck,
most of which are much more
likely than bacterial meningitis...
If the abscess has invaded
the meninges of his brain,
it could be exacerbating
his paranoia.
We need to bring him back to
the hospital for a lumbar puncture.
Come on, Shaun. There's
nothing to lose by trying.
I have something to lose.
It's not my last day
at Saint Bonaventure.
Dr. Andrews won't be happy.
Look, it's my responsibility.
If anything happens,
I'll take the blame, okay?
Okay.
It's probably best that Jared
isn't here on his last day.
It's gotta be awkward.
I mean, how do you
say goodbye to someone
who must have meant
that much to you?
What Jared and I had is over.
It was never all that
much of a big deal, anyway.
You worked with
him for over a year.
You were sleeping with
him for most of that time.
For me, anyway, you can't sleep
with someone and not feel anything.
And for you... You're way more
decent and caring than I am.
Hey.
Melanie has an aortic aneurysm?
Two hearts beating into that.
Yeah. Not so good.
We could reinforce the dilated
aorta with an endovascular stent.
But we can't attach
the donor heart's aorta
to an aneurysm
over a metal tube.
Why not resect the dilated tissue
and re-approximate the artery ends?
Great.
Except the wall's
inherently weakened.
How long do you think
it'll take to dilate again?
It was nice while it lasted.
I'll let Andrews know.
I didn't wanna say
anything, I'm not entirely sure,
but you suggested
resecting the dilated tissue.
What if we resect the
entire abnormal segment?
Shorten the ascending aorta...
You were very right
not to be entirely sure.
You need to have enough
aorta to plug in the donor...
Actually, a version of
that could maybe work.
We'd reduce the risk of the aortic
aneurysm if we used a Teflon graft.
I, um...
I didn't know
you lived in a tent.
Yes. We got to travel lots.
We saw all of Natrona
County, Wyoming.
What was your favorite part?
My brother.
He took care of me.
He knew I needed help.
Now I'm fine on my own.
Mary had a little lamb
Keep still.
Little lamb, li...
Don't you want to help Glassman
the way your brother helped you?
I can help people with medicine.
And you can help Dr. Glassman
just by being there, with him,
letting him know
you're his friend.
He knows I'm his friend.
I don't have to be
there to tell him that.
Okay, Harry,
we're done, but you have
to stay here for a while.
Got a minute?
I get it.
It's your last day, you hate
me, wanna prove me wrong,
prove that you're a better
doctor than I gave you credit,
and leave here with a victory.
It was my medical opinion that
he could have bacterial meningitis.
And if you're right, then
I owe you an apology.
But if you're wrong, then I
will be on the phone to Denver
and I will make your life
infinitely more complicated
than you think
you're making mine.
You don't seem disappointed.
You think I like passing up
on a once-in-a-lifetime surgery?
I think you don't
mind telling me
that a surgery I publicly
supported can't be done.
I spent half a day with my team
trying to figure out a
way to make it work.
We think there's a way to do
this surgery by using a Teflon graft.
A modified David Procedure.
We cut out the entire
aneurysm segment and replace it.
The dilation starts
above the aortic root.
That leaves enough room
to plug in the donor heart.
That's a great idea.
Isn't it?
There's two hearts, not one.
There'd be about a 20% chance
the graft would blow
at the suture line.
It's not worth it.
Whose idea was it?
It was a joint thing. We
were all talking, and we...
Come on, Claire. You
know that's not true.
It was Claire's idea.
That's very gracious
of you, Dr. Reznick.
I thought we talked about this.
Andrews was right.
I did think Harry
had meningitis,
but maybe I only
really believed it
because I wanted
to prove him wrong.
If this test is negative, we've
wasted the hospital's resources
on my self-indulgent,
pointless gesture.
Your results are ready.
We've wasted hospital resources
on a self-indulgent,
pointless gesture.
Don't worry, Jared.
You're young.
There's still time for you to fulfill
your potential somewhere else.
I think, one day, you're
going to be very happy.
I can unload the
mobile clinic by myself.
I haven't been assigned
anything else to do.
- I'll help you.
- Do something else.
I'm sure there's better ways
you could be spending your time.
I'm halfway through a chapter
of my book. It's very good.
But you shouldn't be
alone on your last day.
Seriously?
You're worried about
me being on my own?
The guy going to a new job?
Not the... Not the guy facing death.
- Not the guy who mentored you for...
- He is not facing death.
No, but he's facing...
He's facing death, Shaun.
That's all he's thinking about in
every one of those waiting rooms.
Are you scared?
And you think by...
by separating yourself
you'll make it easier?
- It does.
- For you, Shaun, not for him.
I'm going to finish my chapter.
How's everything going?
Pretty good.
"Pretty good"?
It's your first week
running a major hospital.
How "pretty bad" has it been?
You heard about the
piggyback surgery falling through.
Read your draft press release.
When does that go out?
Soon as Melendez
informs the family.
You know, I was sure
he'd seize the chance
when Dr. Browne came
up with a potential fix.
He's arrogant, always just does
stuff, knowing he'll find a way.
You assumed he'd
make the call you wanted.
It is his call.
What would
Dr. Glassman have done?
He held on to the
presidency long enough,
he must have been
doing something right.
Don't buy into his
fuzzy warmth, Marcus.
He was a manipulator.
He manipulated the board
into hiring Dr. Murphy.
And he always found a way to
do exactly what he wanted to do.
Sitting around waiting for
tests is a waste of my time,
much less yours.
I know. I told Jared that.
I wanted to read my book,
but he kept saying that I
should just be here with you.
But then I realized that I could be
here with you and also read my book.
I want you to stop doing that.
Harry has kaleidoscopic
disintegration.
We thought he had schizophrenia,
but he does not. He
has a brain tumor.
Thanks. Shaun,
is everything okay?
I have a solution. I
need to find Jared.
Can I ask you something
important really quickly?
- I need to find Jared.
- This is about Jared.
How is he?
Is that your important question?
Well, it, um... It's
just... It's his last day.
No, I'm sorry. You should go.
Um... Just...
Say hello to him for me, okay?
Hello.
Also, your day is not over.
Harry doesn't have
schizophrenia, he has a brain tumor.
- Did you go and see Glassman?
- Yes, that's where I got the idea.
Harry's tumor won't kill him,
but removing it might change
him back to who he was before.
I was hoping Andrews
wouldn't bother
following through on
his threat to call Denver.
I do this, Shaun, and I really
don't leave him any choice.
We need to bring Harry in for
an MRI to confirm the diagnosis.
You need to help me find
him because I can't do it alone.
Have you told the piggyback
patient the surgery is off?
- Not yet.
- How come?
I haven't gotten around to it.
Is it because you're wondering
if you made the right call?
I'm not gonna do it.
The Teflon graft
isn't worth the risk.
- That's a judgment call.
- Yeah, my judgment.
- Your judgment's biased.
- And yours isn't?
Of course mine is.
But as you've made quite
clear, mine doesn't matter.
You're biased because if this fails,
you will publicly pay a huge price.
And if it succeeds, I
will reap a huge windfall.
And I think both those scenarios
are deeply unpleasant to you.
But the only issue
that matters is
are you surgeon enough to
pull this off? I think you are.
Am I wrong?
Get out of my office.
Hello. I'm Dr. Shaun Murphy.
Have you seen Harry?
He lives in a tent.
- He's about 6' tall with red hair.
- No.
He said that he lives in a...
- Have you seen a guy named Harry? No?
- Haven't seen him.
Hello. Harry?
Hello. Have you seen
Harry? He lives in a...
We need to find
Harry. You don't...
Have... Okay, you
don't understand.
Okay.
Okay, we...
We need to find Harry. Harry!
Harry!
Ah!
- Shaun.
- Okay.
Hey!
What the hell is wrong with you?
We need to find... Hello? Harry!
Okay.
- He's...
- We need to find him. We need to...
- Shaun, it's okay.
- It's not okay.
- No.
It's not okay. We
need to find Harry.
- We need to find him.
- Shaun.
Okay, please be... Can
you please be quiet?
We found an issue.
An aneurysm near your heart.
So, we can't do the surgery?
We have a solution.
It's an addition to what
we had originally planned.
A Teflon graft.
It's finally time to prepare
you for your surgery, Melanie.
Thank you.
Nurse should be by shortly.
The surgery...
It was already
complicated, and now...
How confident are
you this graft will work?
There are always risks.
But I believe I
can make it work.
Thank you.
That's it, Shaun.
Keep holding it. Good.
- Hold. Hold. Okay.
- Good. Keep your eyes closed.
- Feel the scalpel, Shaun.
- We need to find Harry.
- No.
- Hey, Shaun, it's okay.
It's... It's not okay
- We need to...
- Hey.
- We need to find Harry.
- Hey, Shaun.
- We need to...
- Shaun! Look over there. Look.
Remember Harry
said he had a friend?
Harry.
Harry and Mr. Googly-Eyes.
Yes.
Yes. Harry! Har... Harry!
- Harry!
- What do you want?
This is... This is my
home. My home! Go away!
We're not coming
in, Harry. Okay? We...
We made a mistake, and we
want to run an MRI scan on you...
Always mistakes. Always
blaming others. You see?
I knew you were a
doctor. I knew it. I knew it.
We think you have a brain
tumor and we can help you.
- If we can just get you back...
- Didn't I say, "Go away"?
- If we can just...
- I said go away.
- Edward Austin Thomas.
Harry is not who you really are.
You are Edward Austin Thomas.
You live at 3458
Brookland Avenue.
I have a neurological condition.
I will always have it.
You have a neurological
condition, too,
but yours can be cured.
You just need some surgery,
then you can be Edward
Austin Thomas again.
You're not a doctor, are you?
Let's go.
Knife.
Another thing about being president,
it's always your ass on the line,
but ultimately, you're
just a bystander.
He has a wife and daughter.
And I checked out the
address, and it all adds up...
You had to mess with me.
You didn't care that it might
mean the end of your career?
Didn't care what happened to Shaun,
dragged him along? Unforgivable.
Your day's over.
And I'm making
that call to Denver.
The reason we're here right
now is because of Shaun.
Not me.
Shaun believed there was
something wrong with the patient.
Shaun communicated with him,
connected with him,
got him to come in.
And whether he's right or not, I
couldn't be prouder to back him,
because he sticks to his gut,
and he fights for
what he thinks is right.
Excuse me, please. I
have something to say, too.
Edward has a right
parietal brain tumor.
Find Dr. Lim. You can
have OR number two.
There she goes. What's left?
Replace the damaged
segment of aorta with a graft,
then plug the donor
heart into the aortic stump.
Exactly. 3-0 Prolene.
Damn. Give me a pledget.
The aorta wall's too thin.
It's like sewing tissue paper.
I can't anchor the graft here.
We're going to replace the whole
ascending aorta, not just a segment.
We're building an entirely
new aorta of Teflon.
But you'll be plugging the
heart directly into the graft.
That's even riskier.
That's true.
Get me three Teflon grafts
and some monofilament sutures.
Now we just have to
wait to see who wakes up.
Edward or Harry.
Flush it.
- No leaks.
- Put your back into it, Park.
This needs to hold a
systolic pressure of 180.
Good.
Okay, let's plug the donor
heart in, see if this thing holds.
They're connected.
Let's take her off bypass.
We have a heartbeat.
Two heartbeats.
- Who wants to do the closing?
- I'll do it.
The Teflon graft was
my idea. I'd like to finish it.
What we've accomplished
tonight is the type of radical surgery
that we plan to do
more of at this hospital.
I love Dr. Glassman,
you love Dr. Glassman,
we all loved Dr. Glassman,
but now is the time
to build on his legacy.
Now is the time to
take Saint Bonaventure
to the forefront of the
medical profession.
I'd like to introduce you
to Elliot Arnott, Melanie's son,
and the phenomenal surgeon
who masterminded this surgery,
Dr. Neil Melendez.
He wouldn't take the medication.
He just became more
erratic, more disruptive,
and eventually,
for Hannah's sake, I, um...
I had to ask him to leave.
I didn't have a choice.
You couldn't have known it
was the wrong medication.
We were making him worse.
That's true.
He doesn't blame you.
That's kind of
you to say, but...
I know he has a distrust
of doctors, not of you.
- Where am I?
- You're in a hospital.
You're okay.
Eddie?
Mary.
Oh... My lamb.
Daddy.
Shaun.
I meant what I said to Andrews.
He might never fully appreciate
what you accomplished out there,
but I did.
I know.
Thank you, Shaun.
Thank you, Jared.
Do you have my book?
Yeah.
I said goodbye to Jared.
He has to go to Denver,
and I have to stay
here, with you.
No, you don't, Shaun.
It's not up to Jared,
it's not up to me,
it's not up to anyone
to tell you where to be.
I've got a long
journey ahead of me.
And in the end,
I've got to take it alone.
Yes. I understand.
I'm going with you.
Jared.
I missed having you
around as a colleague.
But I...
I also miss what
we had together.
You know, I th... I think
we made a mistake.
I made a mistake.
And I'd like you to stay.
No.
It's hard saying goodbye,
but it doesn't
mean it's a mistake.
Yeah.
I think you'll be okay.
I'll be okay.
I think one day we're both
going to be very happy.
Hey.
I wanna wake up
Where your love is
'Cause your love Is
always waking mine
I wanna break down
Where your heart gets
So torn It's almost
breaking mine
I wanna tell you
What my truth is
But it's buried down inside
Mmm, mmm, mmm
It's buried down inside
Aren't you gonna say hello?
Hello.