Mmm.
It's a big day.
Yeah. I'm excited about it.
Really? Mmm.
You finally gonna tell
Cristina that you're pregnant?
What are you talking about?
Today is the last day
of your first trimester.
I'm talking about
the plane crash.
The judge could
have a decision today
about whether the
hospital is at fault or not.
Well, that's not gonna happen.
The lawyers moved
for summary judgment.
Well, that is a formality.
Then it's gonna go to trial.
It's gonna take
months for a decision.
Maybe not.
Meredith, your first
trimester is over.
Let's focus on that.
Try and relax a
little bit. Enjoy it.
Tell your twisted sister.
She'll be happy for you.
The big day is here,
the day you're
gonna hear the news,
the test result.
Is the biopsy
malignant or benign?
Am I gonna live or die?
You just want to know.
Breakfast for two? Oh!
Even if the news is scary.
God. Oh, my God.
What are you doing?
I'm sorry. I thought you
were Cristina, and you're not.
Definitely not.
No.
Because then you can move on,
whatever that means.
You didn't? Yeah.
I did.
It's...
It's not funny. Oh!
I know. I know.
God. It's not.
It's hilarious.
It was humiliating.
If you wear pants, it
doesn't happen as much.
I just got up.
I was looking for a glass for
water 'cause I'm hung over.
And why are there no
glasses or mugs or anything?
You're pretty loud
for a hung-over girl.
The Chief of Surgery
just felt me up.
And I had to sleep on
your living room floor
because you have no furniture,
and now I have a neck ache.
Being your friend is
basically ruining my life.
I've heard that before.
You're a douche. Get a couch, or
I'm never drinking with you again.
Look, if you're
thirsty, all you gotta do
is stick your face
under the faucet.
Okay.
I'm going to the hospital where
there's food and paper cups.
Sir. From my mom. Cookies.
Oh, you know, that's not...
And there's a message
that I am supposed to read
to you, make sure you get it.
"Richard, I am in town
doing a case at Seattle Pres.
"Left you several messages
and wasn't sure you got them.
"I just want to make
sure you're okay.
"I'm worried about you, baby."
To be clear, that
was her and not me.
Well, please tell her I'm fine.
Oh, no, you gotta
take the cookies, sir.
That's such a nice gesture,
but I'm trying to avoid sweets.
Uh... Would you like them?
Um...
I can put them in the lounge,
and everybody can enjoy them.
That's a fine idea.
Morning.
Hey, I heard there might
be a judgment today.
I hope it works out for you.
No, you don't.
A judgment comes
down that quickly,
it means the
hospital's negligent.
It means you did
something wrong.
Which you did.
Well, you've obviously
been thinking that for a while.
I'm glad you...
Finally got it out in the open.
And for the record,
I really do hope it
works out for you.
I heard your girlfriend
did a little panty dance
in the kitchen this morning.
She's not my girlfriend.
Look, I know it's weird.
She's hot and
she's always around,
but I don't even
think of her like that.
It'd be like you and I
sleeping together. Ew.
I'm trying to eat my breakfast.
Did you hear your husband
accidentally copped a feel?
Yeah.
Oh, and he's not my husband.
That's why he's sneaking
in at the crack of crack.
You are a messed up broad.
Dr. Webber rejected
my mother's cookies.
That sounds dirty.
She's worried about him.
She wants me to assess his
mood. She thinks he's depressed.
Well, his wife died a month ago.
Isn't he supposed
to be depressed?
Of course, but, like, normal
depressed or too depressed?
I mean, he's fine.
He's back at work.
Nah, but he's not operating.
Maybe you should hold him.
And I'm done.
Enjoy the cookies.
Thanks.
So what do you mean,
he touched your boobs?
Like...
He's not a 13-year-old girl.
He's the Chief of Surgery.
Well, I'm sorry that
I don't know how
the Chief of Surgery
touches boobs.
But was it, like, a glancing
thing, like side boob?
Heather. Show me what happened.
No. Was it... Look.
Was it like this?
No, it was like a
move up the front.
Yes.
Ahem!
Murphy, let's go. We
got a facial reconstruction.
I gotta go, too. I'm
working with Dr. Shepherd.
I think he's back for
real today, operating.
I think we're all
happy about that.
I've got post-ops with Yang.
I'm on Grey. With Grey.
"On Grey" sounds...
Dr. Avery, I'm just on scut. If
you don't mind, can I tag along?
I don't know. Um,
sure, I guess. Come on.
Quick question about the case.
That was good.
You like that, throwing
Murphy on my service?
And made me beg to tag along.
Now you understand that
it's in both of our interests
to keep this thing
quiet, right? Relax.
Do you really think I
want anyone to think
I'm getting surgeries because
I'm sleeping with my boss?
I want to get them because
of my awesomeness.
Well, that's true, because
you are extremely awesome.
Hmm.
And that is how... Oh,
what were you saying?
They invented the
shunt. That is fascinating.
Yeah.
Hey. Hey.
So I think our big
mistake last time was,
we tried to get
you back too fast.
So this time, baby steps. Mmm.
Torres... Who's the patient?
I'm the patient.
That's right. Now...
This is the same muscle movement
you use with the
Leksell Rongeur.
Basically, the same motion
as hitting a ping-pong ball.
So that is what
you're gonna do today.
For how long?
How long did your last
meningioma removal take?
It was eight hours, I think.
Well...
We're gonna play
ping-pong for eight hours?
Not me. I've got
surgery. Well, then who?
Morning. We back in the saddle?
What?
You're gonna love this one.
What, MVC, GSW?
Better. Stripper pole.
Vitals stable in the field.
Has abdominal tenderness
from a crush injury.
She slipped. Make
sure she's all right.
Off a pole? It was
our anniversary.
They installed it
right in the bedroom.
I wanted it to be a surprise.
It was. I thought I
was getting an iPad.
Mmm.
Hey. Where'd you
get the cookies?
Webber didn't
want the pity cookies
from his girlfriend
about his dead wife.
He's not operating, so
Jackson's "mommy" was worried.
Whatever. These
cookies are awesome.
What about Jackson?
Are you still pining
over Jackson?
No. God. No.
Why? Is he seeing someone?
April, April...
Jackson is like a cookie.
People want to lose weight,
they don't eat the cookie.
But then they get so hung
up on not having the cookie
that their whole life
is about the cookie.
My whole life is not
about the cookie.
Mmm-hmm.
Is your whole life
about the cookie?
What do you mean?
You and Owen, are you
guys a thing again or...
I don't know.
All I know is,
having sex with a man
who used to be your husband
is way more fun than
when he is your husband.
That's all you know?
That is all I know.
Unless there's something
else you want to tell me?
No. Nothing I can think of.
Okay, then.
Okay.
Hey, Cristina.
Ah! Whoa.
Nice shot, Dr. Shepherd.
You put a little something
on that backhand?
Seven serving two.
Hey, Derek. Answer your phone.
We're in the middle of a game.
Well, you know
what? Not anymore.
The lawyer called, and they
need us at the courthouse. Now.
Did I miss it?
Damn it. I'm sorry. I got out
of the OR as fast as I could,
but I didn't think it was
gonna happen today.
Oh, God. Was it bad?
It wasn't?
We won.
He said the airline company
had a history of mechanical
problems with the plane.
It was in public record, and
the hospital should've known.
He found the hospital negligent.
So we won.
When's he gonna tell us
about the award? I mean...
I hate to be all
about the money...
He already did.
He's giving us $15 million.
Whoa!
Each.
So what happens now,
the hospital hands us
a check for $15 million?
Well, their insurance
company does,
and it'll probably take
some time to get through
all the bureaucratic
rigmarole, but, yeah.
Pending appeal,
the insurance company will
issue each of you a big check.
In the meantime, I have
a ping-pong ball to hit.
Yeah, I gotta get back, too. I
have James Leggett's surgery.
Oh. How is James?
Well, that's right.
You and Mark did his
original cranial expansion.
Wait. Wait. Wait. Wait. Wait.
Why is everyone rushing off?
This is a momentous event.
Shouldn't we do
something, like celebrate or...
Okay, maybe "celebrate's"
too strong a word.
Dinner. We should
have a dinner. Come on.
We've been sitting in rooms
with each other for months
talking about this,
and we just won.
What's wrong with
sitting in one more room
with food in front of us?
I'm gonna do a quick exam.
I don't know what happened.
I was doing a sexy flexy,
next thing I know,
I was on the floor.
A sexy flexy?
It's a move. I could
do it perfectly in class.
Uh. Uh. You have a
bruise near your tailbone.
You must have landed
on a hard surface.
I landed on my husband.
And there was
nothing hard about him.
Leonard Olsen, 67,
came in via EMS.
His wife was on a
stripper pole and fell on him
while trying to execute a
move called a sexy flexy.
His physical exam indicates
possible internal injuries.
So why don't you get
Mr. Olsen's past medical history
while I order a scan?
See that?
Your face?
Now imagine how I felt.
We could buy a house.
We have a house. We
could buy another house.
We could buy five houses.
We could buy five houses
with yards as big
as football fields.
We could buy the team
to play on the football field.
Who would play against them?
Well, we'd buy
another team. Mmm.
I just wanted a house.
Mo' money, mo' problems.
Mmm.
I should've been
on that damn plane.
James was born with
Crouzon syndrome,
a genetic disorder characterized
by the premature fusion
of certain skull bones,
resulting in... A
weird-looking face.
James. Fine.
A tall, narrow head, wide-set
eyes and a small midface.
Now over the years, Dr. Sloan
has operated on James
five separate times to...
Try and make me less
weird-looking. James.
What? Even Sloan
said I was weird-looking,
and you worshipped him.
My mom thought Sloan
walked on water. No pressure.
Dr. Sloan was great with him.
I really can't
believe he's gone.
I know, and I know that this
isn't easy, trusting the new guy.
You were Sloan's guy.
That's all we need to know.
The only person who liked Sloan
more than my mom was my dad.
Again... No pressure.
I got it. Okay.
I know that Dr. Sloan's plan
called for this final operation
to consist of simply moving
the upper jaw forward.
I am recommending a
monobloc advancement,
which means, Dr. Edwards?
Cutting into your skull and
moving the whole midface
forward in one block.
Excellent job, Dr. Edwards.
Thank you, Dr. Avery.
Uh, if this is a
better procedure,
why didn't Sloan suggest it?
For one thing, Dr. Sloan
did not anticipate
that James'
forehead would still be
this disproportionately
underdeveloped.
Hey, everybody. Sorry I'm late.
What's up?
Dr. Avery was just
explaining the new plan.
Mark had a plan.
And I have a different plan,
which gives James a
more normal appearance.
But Mark knew
James for 16 years.
You've known him
for, like, uh, 16 minutes.
You know what? If Mark was here,
then I would be glad to
have this argument with him.
He was a plastic surgeon.
This is not your
area of expertise.
So if you want me to walk you
through my thought process,
I guess I can do
that as a courtesy.
What I'm not gonna do is
stand here and argue with you
about this procedure.
This is what I'm doing.
You'll walk me through your
thought process as a courtesy?
Are you kidding me?
I'll wait. All right.
I'm just not ready for
Callie's dinner tonight.
It's too weird. I know.
How long do you think till these
parasites are hitting
us up for a lung?
Dr. Grey. That was fast.
Glad you're back.
I have a patient.
She's a 19-year-old college kid,
nauseated with a
distended stomach.
And she says there's no
way that she's pregnant.
Oh, everybody always says that,
and then they always
end up pregnant.
Okay, but if the
pregnancy test is negative?
Okay, I will come with you. But
I am not taking point, you are.
Yeah, you know, that
really is a problem,
people claiming not to be
pregnant when they really are.
You know?
Of course I know.
Her boobs got huge
about two weeks ago,
and she's eating
everything in sight.
But she didn't
tell you? No, but...
She knows I know.
So you know she knows
that you know? Mmm-hmm.
She'll tell me when she's
ready to be happy about it.
Congratulations.
Taylor?
You're not pregnant.
Of course she's not pregnant.
Taylor knows better
than to bring boys home.
She knows she needs
to focus on her studies.
Get your hair out of your mouth.
Taylor, do you mind if I
take a look at your stomach?
Of course you can take
a look. You're the doctor.
Does that hurt?
Have you been constipated?
I don't know.
Speak up. No one can hear
you when you're mumbling.
Yes. Yes, what? Yes,
you're constipated?
The doctors aren't mind readers.
Okay, she's not constipated.
Okay. She's just throwing up.
Mrs. Lanz, do you
mind if we step outside
while the doctor
examines Taylor?
Taylor doesn't mind
if I stay. Do you?
Oh, it'll just take a second.
Wow.
That was awesome.
So...
You need to talk to the
patient, not the mother.
If the mother interrupts
you, you stop her.
So, let's start again.
Robbins is concerned.
Yeah, well, she shouldn't
be. I've thought this through.
I've got a solid plan.
So did Sloan.
I did James' first
surgery with Mark
when we still lived in New York.
Yeah, I know. I've read
through Sloan's notes.
How old is James now? He's 16.
When you're 16, you're worried
about your SAT score, your future.
Yeah, well, so am I.
This is gonna improve his
appearance by 5% to 10%.
But at what cost? It's riskier.
It's complicated recovery time.
I would stick with Sloan's plan.
Oh, hey. Hey.
I got a message about a consult.
Oh, yeah. Chest X-ray came back.
Turned out to be heartburn.
Oh, God. There's...
Why is she coming over here?
She's on my service. Relax.
Dr. Yang, I did
orthostatics on 21-14.
Hey, you know, uh,
you know, your hair and hers...
You know, from behind kind of...
Yeah, no. Totally
honest mistake.
Yeah.
Okay, these results are
weird. Schedule a tilt table test.
Mmm.
I said, "Relax,"
not make it worse.
Grabby. Just grabby.
What?
Are you trying to see if it's
really me or some intern?
I'm relieved.
I heard about the judgment.
Yeah?
It hasn't really sunk in yet.
Hey, will you come to
this thing with me tonight?
Uh, depends. What's the thing?
Oh, it's dumb.
Callie wants to have
a survivors dinner.
It sounds morbid
to me, actually.
But if you come,
it could be fun.
I mean, I could get drunk
and dance on a table.
Promise.
That's... I...
Shepherd doesn't want me there.
Why?
He blames me. And I get it.
I'm the bad guy.
And I don't know if I
want to be forgiven.
Don't play martyr.
I'm not. I'm... This is...
I am partially responsible.
So if Shepherd doesn't
want me around...
Okay, you know what I
think? I think Derek Shepherd...
Mmm. Mmm.
Let's just leave the case and
the crash in the past outside
and just be here right now.
Just you and me.
Okay.
So now what?
Now...
You take your shirt off.
Okay.
You can take off your pants.
Bailey said I would find
you here. What is this place?
Well, it's my hall of horrors.
At least that's what
Adele used to call it.
Malignant teratoma
resected from a liver in 1985.
This thing is 27 years old?
It was the first
in my collection.
I'm cataloging it,
and then the medical waste is
gonna come and take it all away.
I remember this guy.
This is the guy who
swallowed all the pennies.
This was my intern year.
That's Ron Newsome.
He swallowed these
scissors a year later.
And why do you want
to get rid of all this stuff?
What do you want, Grey?
I came to ask you if you would
like to scrub in on a surgery.
A very cool case,
a 19-year-old girl
with an unknown
mass in her abdomen.
I'm busy.
Richard, I'm worried.
No need to worry.
I've heard you
haven't been operating.
I'm fine. I don't
need your help.
I need to be left alone.
So please let me
do what I'm doing.
Okay.
You called Shepherd on me?
He's not on James' case anymore.
He's a trusted colleague
and a respected surgeon...
And I'm a plastic surgeon.
Hey, quick question
about the sitter for tonight.
Yeah. Hold on for one second.
Well... I don't know
about the dinner.
It just, it feels weird.
We're doing the dinner, okay?
Um. Curly hair can't sit.
So I was gonna...
So I was gonna call art student,
'cause she's fun
and Sofia loves her,
but unibrow cleans.
What do you think?
I think that you should
learn their names,
and you should call Claudia
because Kelli has
only sat for us once,
and I don't want Sofia
with someone new.
Great. Claudia is... Okay...
Unibrow. Right.
Yeah. This is why I
went to Derek, okay?
Mark knew James. He was
with him from the beginning.
And you're just
the new babysitter
who doesn't know where
we keep the extra wipes at.
I waited around here for
you to insult me again?
I'm sorry. It's been
a weird morning.
But Mark was so
invested and so...
I was coming to tell you
that I changed my mind.
I'm now doing the
procedure Sloan's way.
Oh, great. Thanks.
Sorry.
Your husband's
scans show that a rib
punctured his
diaphragm when you...
Landed on him.
We're gonna need to operate,
but I'm confident we
can fix the problem.
Oh, thank God.
I feel so terrible.
Here you go, Sheila.
This will make your ride to
radiology more comfortable.
Mmm-hmm.
Now about that X-ray,
is it okay if I have
metal on my... Cookie?
I'm sorry. I don't
understand. Oh.
You bedazzled your vagina?
It's called vajazzling.
All the stars are doing it.
Oh, it's a butterfly. Look.
That's the body and
those are the wings.
That's game.
You win again, Dr. Shepherd.
Wait. Just stop.
Great. This was fun.
I think you're letting me win.
You're a smart man.
I am. So am I.
That's why I'm
absolutely letting you win.
Whupping your ass
wouldn't be a smart move,
especially since you're a
competitive guy who likes to win.
Do you know who else is
a competitive guy, Ross?
A neurosurgeon.
I thought you had
what it takes to be one.
Mmm. See? I am a smart man,
and you are now goading me.
But you won't like
it when you lose.
Oh, when I lose?
You'll be angry and
never want to see my face.
That won't help me on
my quest to become you.
Yeah, I've told you, it's
creepy when you say that.
Sorry. It is what it is.
I need a real test, Ross, okay?
Dr. Ramsey has a Chiari
decompression tomorrow,
and I'm sure she needs
someone to help assist.
If you beat me in this
game, I will put in a...
One-love.
Is that for me? Thanks.
Catherine, what
are you doing here?
I'm taking you to lunch.
We have reservations
at The Firefly.
I don't have
surgery until later on,
and I couldn't
just sit in my hotel
knowing that you're
five miles away
and I haven't laid eyes on you.
Well, I've... I've been busy.
I haven't had time to check...
Richard, Jackson told
me you're not operating.
I'm worried about you.
You look thin.
Are you eating?
Are you sleeping?
Look, you're not my wife.
So you don't get to...
My wife died.
While I was carrying
on with another woman,
my wife died, Catherine.
So what I'm eating and how
I'm sleeping is not your concern.
I haven't returned your calls
because I don't want to go to lunch.
I don't want cookies.
I don't want you here.
If you'll excuse me now,
Grey and I have a surgery.
So what's the
plan for the house?
I'm sick of sitting
on the floor.
Nice!
Shepherd scores.
Ah, waiting out Yang.
She's gonna break down
and furnish the whole house.
What? It's genius.
Yes! You got it, Shepherd.
Wilson, your friend's choking.
You want to make
this interesting?
A hundred bucks says Shane wins.
You don't have 100 bucks.
I won't eat for a month.
Hey. Who's, uh... Who's winning?
He's got Shane on the ropes.
Please. Shepherd's meat.
Watch Shane's dead ball.
Ah!
That's my wrist in there.
Wilson, it's not too
late to back down.
I'm a gentleman.
I'll let you walk away.
Ah, damn it! Ah!
Ouch.
Five hundred bucks.
Okay, how about we take a break?
Let me take a
look at that wrist.
The wrist isn't the
problem. It's his feet.
They're not as fast as
mine 'cause he's an old man.
Sorry, Dr. Shepherd. I don't
know where that came from.
I occasionally get carried
away while engaging in athletic...
Okay. Nine-eight.
Let's go, bitch.
Whoa. Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Okay, boys, I trust that you
remember, this is not Wimbledon,
but a hospital
conference room table
where you are working on
strengthening your muscles
so that one day soon,
you can operate again.
Also, respond to my e-mail
about the dinner tonight,
and let everyone know
you're very excited about it.
What if I'm not?
Come on, Derek. If
you go, everyone will.
Play is continuous.
What dinner?
They won the crash
case, 15 mil each.
Oh!
Hey, Dr. Yang, congratulations
on winning the case.
Are you gonna spend
some of that money
on furniture for the house?
Why? It's not my house.
Yeah. You're a genius.
My turn.
You need to forgive Owen.
For what? You're
holding a grudge.
You make it sound like he stole
my lunch from the refrigerator.
Derek, we won.
We get to move on.
And we have to let
Owen do the same.
He put us on that plane.
You know what?
You were chief once.
You make a bunch of decisions
based on what you know at the time.
Forgive him.
It's not that easy.
I know.
Forgive him anyway.
Let's go.
Wilson, you're working,
not playing ping-pong.
Five hundred bucks.
Let me know how it goes.
You are gonna do great.
I'll come back tomorrow
after volleyball practice.
Hey.
I know.
My girlfriend's hot.
You're wondering how I do it.
No. No.
Yeah.
Sloan... Telling me
I was weird-looking.
He wasn't being a jerk.
It was just that surgery was
only gonna take me so far.
I was never gonna look
completely normal, so...
I was gonna have to develop
some moves to get the women.
So he gave you a couple of tips.
Getting women was
kind of his specialty.
Nah. Sloan said his moves
would never work for me.
I had to come up with my own.
So I blind them with
my amazing personality.
They don't even notice
the weird-looking face.
Well, it looks
like it's working.
I do all right.
Although not being
weird-looking would be cool, too.
Again, no pressure.
Let's see what we
can do about that.
Whatever happened
to just regular old sex,
without poles or vaginas
dressed up in rhinestone?
When did just plain old
"get naked" become boring?
Antibiotic lavage.
And I suppose men do it,
too, bedazzle their penis?
I'm really trying
not to think about it.
Somebody look that up.
On it.
Just foolish.
Idiotic.
Kepner, you ever
vajazzled yourself?
Oh, right. Jesus isn't
a fan of the vajazzle.
Boki?
Feel good being back in the OR?
Grey, let's focus
on the patient.
Opening the stomach.
Babcock clamp.
Here you go.
Lap pads.
Whoa.
Look at that thing.
Well, would you
look at that. A bezoar.
It's a giant hairball.
Like, from eating your hair?
Like, from eating your hair.
I used to eat dirt.
I haven't in years.
Excuse me.
Mmm. You got here
just in time to lose.
Final point, advantage Ross.
Ah, Shepherd's got this.
Double or nothing.
What's the matter, you scared?
Fine. You're on, 1,000 bucks.
Whoo! Shane! Come on, Shepherd!
You got it!
Ah, yes!
Damn it.
Yes! Oh, yeah.
One more game.
No way. I won it. I get to
assist on Ramsey's surgery.
Get on that phone right
now and you call her,
or I swear to God, I'll...
Sir, again, I don't know
what came over me.
What I meant to say is,
I'd appreciate the opportunity.
Yeah. Fine. One more game.
This time, I play with
my dominant hand.
Oh, yeah. It feels so good.
A thousand. I'll
get it to you later.
I gotta go to the cash machine.
Oh, I'm headed that way
myself. I'll come with you.
Uh-huh. Ah, ah, ah.
It's too cool to let it
go to medical waste.
How are you gonna
throw all this stuff away?
You know what I see
when I look at the scissors
Ron Newsome swallowed?
I see the Thanksgiving
that I didn't take off
so I didn't join
Adele in London.
The teratoma kept me
from our anniversary party.
Black tie.
She planned the whole thing.
I got there in time for dessert.
All this stuff that I saved,
that I'm so proud of...
Just reminds me of my failures.
So...
You must be happy
about the judgment.
What are you gonna
do with all that money?
It's blood money.
My sister's dead. It's...
Meredith,
it's a good thing.
Haven't you suffered enough?
Haven't you?
Well, it's just a bruised
tailbone. You can go home now.
And your husband
shouldn't be too far behind,
just maybe a couple of days.
Thank you.
No driving for him,
though, for at least a month.
And that goes for
sexual activity, too.
Uh, and...
So stay off the pole.
You just got back
from your honeymoon.
You come talk to me
after 45 years of marriage
and raising three kids.
You get tired.
You just want to
sit in front of the TV
and say it's done, it's over.
But you know what?
I'm not doing that.
I'm trying. At least I'm trying.
She's sorry. She
didn't mean to judge.
And the worst part is,
he looked embarrassed for me.
I mean, that hurts.
That hurts more than
a bruised tailbone.
I mean, I survived
45 years of marriage.
Is it so wrong for me to want
to celebrate my
anniversary with a little sex?
Well, is it?
No, it's not. No, no.
It's not. It's a good idea.
It's not. I said no.
So I'm gonna teach you two
how to prep for a monobloc.
Wait. What? No, no, no.
You told me that you
were reverting to Mark's...
Yes, but I'm just not
comfortable with that.
Well, you can't just
change your plan in surgery.
I didn't. I spoke
with Dana and Phil
and Dr. Jovan, the plastics
attending who's overseeing me.
Dr. Avery, Mark had a very good
reason for wanting
to do a simple jaw...
Of course he did. But
Mark is not here anymore.
So I need to do what I
think is best for my patient.
So...
I'm going to begin by shaving a
short strip along the coronal incision
instead of cutting
off all of his hair.
Hey. Maybe he can't
get it up anymore.
Maybe that's why he
looked embarrassed.
Or maybe, like the woman said,
he was just embarrassed for her.
Oh, come on. They're sweet.
You just got back
from your honeymoon.
I'd think you of all people
would appreciate an older couple
with a healthy sex life.
No, I do appreciate
a healthy sex life.
It's just...
Okay, look, I had sex
once on my honeymoon,
one time, the very first night.
We arrived in the Bahamas,
and my husband
wanted to have sex,
not in our well-appointed
suite, but on the beach.
So off to the beach we
went, where we had sex,
and I got sand
up in my... Cookie.
Ew.
Yes, a vagina full of sand
that gave me a
bad, bad infection,
requiring a trip
to the local doctor,
who confirmed the infection
and also diagnosed a few
sand flea bites on my buttock.
Yeah, his word. Buttock.
He also went on to
say that my buttock
would become very itchy,
and he was right.
So a painful infection
and an itchy buttock
are what I had on my honeymoon.
So, no, no, I am not a
fan of the beach or the pole
or anywhere at this point.
I am a fan of a bed.
Oh, that's right.
Go on, friend. Laugh.
How's everyone's dinner?
Good. Good.
Yeah. It's good.
Good.
How'd the surgery with James go?
Uh...
Jackson didn't listen.
He went ahead with the
monobloc readvancement.
Really?
How long did that take?
Five hours. Yeah.
I stood there, you know, just to
make sure he didn't mess it up.
Ma'am?
Uh, perfect.
Okay, very good.
I'd like to make a toast.
Callie, no toasts.
You know what? Let's just
get this dinner over with...
Arizona stood for five hours.
- That's not the point.
- Yeah, I know.
Do you realize
how big a deal it is,
you standing for five
hours isn't the point?
Do you know what
else happened today?
Derek played ping-pong.
And lost.
And wanted to keep on playing
'cause his wrist wasn't sore.
What are you doing?
Oh. Sorry. I'm just
quick texting Owen.
Sexting.
No, she's trying is
what she's doing.
Yeah. You just divorced the
guy, and here you are texting him.
Mer's right. I'm sexting.
Oh, well, even better.
Mark would've loved that.
Sex was the thing he loved
more than anything else.
And we're all
having it, so that's...
- Well, we're trying.
- Yeah, okay.
We're...
Don't you see that?
We're all trying.
We're trying to move
on, which is progress.
And it feels weird.
And sad and wrong,
but it also feels exciting.
I miss Mark...
And Lexie. And I'm...
Heartbroken that
they're not here tonight.
I'm heartbroken, but...
I'm also grateful...
That all of you are.
And I'm gonna celebrate that.
And we are gonna toast.
Come on. Toast. Pick
up your glasses and toast.
Oh, no, thank you.
Yes, she's having champagne.
Grey, we're all having champagne.
No, I can't.
Just try. Try.
Come on. Just try.
Is it too much
to ask you to try?
I can't because I'm pregnant.
What?
Aww.
And I'm happy,
so let's celebrate.
Oh, my God.
Well, congratulations.
Congratulations.
Cheers.
I should've been
there, Catherine.
I know.
I failed her.
When she needed me
the most, I failed her.
Richard... No, I...
I feel like I can't grieve.
Like I lost the right to grieve
when I started seeing you.
But you are grieving, baby.
And you shouldn't
have to do it alone.
I would like to just
hold your hand.
Could you let me do that?
Could I just hold your hand?
Well, the good news is,
the surgery went great.
The bad news is,
you're just gonna
be another pretty
face from now on.
Thank you so much.
Yeah, well, Dr. Sloan
did most of it.
I just took us
into the end zone.
Yeah.
You know Jackson
told me he thinks James
may not even need
another major surgery?
Really? Jackson told you that?
Did Jackson have his hands
on your boobs when he said it?
What are you talking about?
You made fun of me
for sleeping with Karev.
Called me a skank,
made this "I don't
wanna be like Leah" thing,
and now you're
sleeping with the boss.
How'd you know?
Oh, well, I didn't.
Now I do.
Everything looks good.
So... You're gonna have to learn
how to stand up for yourself.
I know it's not
gonna be easy, but...
Your mom makes
me want to eat my hair.
I just found out it was hair.
I don't understand.
It's a condition
called trichotillomania.
And it makes you
want to pull out your hair
and, in some cases, eat it.
So we're gonna set
her up with a therapist
who's gonna help her to... No.
Here's what's gonna
happen, she's just gonna stop,
like I did when I
stopped eating carbs.
You just decide and that's it.
This is not like you
not eating carbs.
It's a medical condition, and...
You're gonna take
me to see a therapist.
Hey.
Hi.
I am kind of sleeping
with Stephanie.
I was hoping that you wouldn't
have to find out about it at all.
But of course, it's
probably gonna get out.
So I just wanted to make sure
that you didn't have to hear
about it from anyone else.
Okay.
Okay?
I miss you.
I feel like we were friends,
and now everything is just so...
So we can still be friends.
You know what I'm
thinking about right now?
Kissing you.
Standing here looking at you,
and all I want to do is kiss you.
So, no, I... I'm...
I'm not ready to
be your friend yet.
You sure?
Yes.
Yes, I'm sure.
Thank you for telling me.
Okay.
I just checked in on your wife.
Medically, she's fine.
Otherwise...
Your wife is horny, Leonard.
All there is to it. She wants
some sex. She needs it.
Oh.
Is the equipment working, sir?
Yes. Good, good. Then use it.
You're married.
If I were married, I would
be doing it all day long.
Just...
Do it.
Slowly.
Okay.
I got you a couch
with the money I won.
This is such a girlfriend thing.
Okay, I think what
you want to say is,
"Thank you for the
awesome couch."
Okay.
But we're not doing it, if
that's what you're thinking.
Why would we do
it? That's disgusting.
You're like my brother.
We drink beer and hang out.
Okay.
I mean...
I've never really had
a friend who was a girl
who didn't want to
do it, so it's weird.
Except Mer, and she probably
wanted me at some point.
Wow. You really are a douche.
Just shut up and drink.
Hunt, come over here.
I can't.
It's not your fault.
I know that. We're
moving forward.
Just please come over
here and have a drink.
Shepherd, I...
Cristina.
Tell your husband to come
over here and have a drink.
No, no. He's not my husband.
I mean, I don't
know what you are.
I mean, I don't know
what we are, but...
You know, it doesn't matter.
All that matters now is
that I'm drunk and happy,
and I want you to be here.
Drunk and happy with me.
Plus the bathrooms lock, so...
Whatever you're doing,
just... Let somebody else do it
and come on over
and have a drink.
They say ignorance is bliss.
Another time.
Enjoy your party.
Because once you know
about the tumor or the prognosis,
you can't go back.
So where are we at?
The insurance company
found a loophole.
Apparently, there's a rule that
no more than two attendings
are allowed on a medi plane.
So when Dr. Robbins took
Dr. Karev's place on the flight...
Anyway, they say
they aren't gonna pay.
Okay, so who pays?
We do.
The hospital.
We don't have
that kind of reserve.
No, we don't.
So?
We go bankrupt.
The hospital closes its doors.
Will you be strong
or will you fall apart?
It's hard to predict.
So don't worry about it.
Enjoy the time you have
before the news comes.
Around the mommy.
Yep. Ignorance is bliss.
Baby!