Every surgeon is trained
to look for problems.
To look at a person and
say, "What's wrong with you?"
Where am I supposed to be now?
You can come with me.
Cross.
Drunk or deranged.
Find out which.
Sir. Hi.
Uh, can I help you?
I don't know.
You guys called me.
We're trained to foresee
the ugliest possible outcome.
She actually said...
Steph said I'm not as
good a surgeon as she is.
Is that true? Of course not.
Yeah, but is that
the perception?
Do attendings just automatically
go to anyone but me?
I think you're amazing.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God! Mr. Jaffee!
When your job is to
make people better,
you're automatically inclined
to look for the worst in them.
Wilson, I have three kids.
Three.
Do you have any idea
how little sleep I get?
Mr. Jaffee?
Are you sure you
don't want to just sleep?
You cannot keep this up.
Grey is killing you.
I know, but I can't
think of that right now.
'Cause right now, I'm in a bed.
A comfy, comfy bed...
With you.
Did you just fall asleep?
Got it!
Wha...
Hello? Uh-huh.
Of course it is.
Yeah. Of course it is.
This is ridiculous.
No, absolutely.
Absolutely I can.
Uh-huh. No, of course.
Who's Mr. Jaffee?
Simon Jaffee.
End-stage renal disease.
He's been on dialysis
for the last 18 months
waiting for a transplant donor.
Why so long?
Antibodies. He needs
a six-antigen match...
An impossible
match until tonight.
We've been looking forever.
It's like finding
the Holy Grail.
Blake, when was Mr. Jaffee's
last round of dialysis?
Oh, um, looking...
He was at the dialysis
center two days ago.
Electrolytes and renal labs
were within expected limits, so...
I've been on his case
since I was an intern.
I'm so sorry, Dr. Grey.
I will catch up.
It's okay, Blake.
Do the best you can,
and ask Wilson if you
have any questions.
There are my girls.
Mr. Jaffee, it's so
good to see you.
Where are the grandkids?
I haven't even called them yet.
I wanted to wait until I
knew it was a sure thing.
So...
Is it true?
It's true. We
found you a kidney.
Thanks again for breakfast.
My pleasure.
This was his last
night in my house.
You just made the man pancakes.
Because I am a benevolent
leader and good host.
And I've been waiting for
this thing to resolve itself.
It has not.
This job is stressful.
I need to go home at night
and be alone with my husband.
Well, I agree with
that, but... Whoa!
Miranda, he's my friend,
all right? And he's my boss.
I'm your boss,
too. And his boss.
I'm all your bosses.
If you want your wife back,
take care of your business...
Today.
So, I'm just wondering if
maybe we should rethink
the resident-rotation system.
I mean, make sure
that our residents
get an equal opportunity
on every specialty.
Isn't that happening?
Well, there's a danger
that our residents are being
monopolized by a single attending.
She's talking about
Blake. You know what?
This is not your busi...
Isn't Blake with Grey?
Yes, and she has
been since she got here.
I worry she's not
getting a full education.
And Grey is...
She's running her ragged.
Residency runs you ragged.
We've all been there, Torres.
You know this as well as anyone.
No, but this is different.
This is different.
I think it's personal.
Is it that you want to spend
more time with your girlfriend?
Amelia, could you please...
I mean, you are
saying that it's personal.
Hey, hey. All right. All right.
Has Blake expressed
this concern or just you?
Okay. She's...
Blake stays with Grey.
We don't have a policy
to move around residents
to accommodate
your personal lives.
No, that's not
what I was saying.
If Blake has a problem,
she comes to me.
All right. He has
already been seen.
I know the doctor is...
Hey, all.
I was just wondering if
someone could tell me
where I can get some scrubs.
Uh, third floor by
the dispensary.
Cheers.
You're Dr. Pierce,
right? Mmm-hmm.
Yeah, I just wanted to
say I'm super excited,
and I can't wait to get started.
Great.
Go get 'em.
Okey-dokey.
Yep.
Who was that?
Oh.
Oh, hey.
I found you.
Pulled a night shift.
This is a nice way to wake up.
I could get used to this.
How's your day?
I had to listen to Torres go
on and on about her girlfriend,
who Meredith's got basically
chained to her service.
I don't know how
she even looks at her.
Mmm. I'm sorry. You were saying?
Was I?
Gary, this is Dr. Karev.
Uh, Gary Walton, 14.
Complaining of abdominal pain.
How's it going, Gary?
This ball looks like a cherry.
Do you like cherries?
Gary was born with some
intellectual disabilities.
Well, I'm more of
an apple guy myself.
But, uh, do you like cherries?
I love cherries.
Loves these stupid things. And
that's probably why he ate one.
Joel!
He did, actually. He
swallowed the other one.
Is he gonna be okay?
Here it is on the X-ray.
I can show you where it is.
Gary, you want to show
Dr. Karev what you showed me?
Gary. What'd you do that for?
It looked like a cherry.
Well, I bet it didn't
taste like one.
It's in my tummy now.
This doctor says
he needs surgery.
Endoscopic surgery just
to remove the ball, right?
Whoa, whoa, whoa. I think
Dr. Spencer jumped the gun a little.
Gary's body has
its own exit strategy.
Gary, you're gonna poop it.
Oh, ho, ho! That
is going to hurt.
Joel!
Well, maybe it'll keep him
from doing crap like this.
Well, so don't
worry. No surgery.
Oh, good. Thank you.
Uh, we'll just keep
him here overnight,
and, uh, we'll make sure
everything comes out okay.
Gary, want to sleep over?
Yeah!
Okay.
Can I stay with him?
Uh, absolutely.
Uh, you're not gonna
eat this, are you?
No. All right.
Spencer, I need you
to do hourly checks.
Yes, sir. Oh, uh, just
steer clear of the mom.
She's a doc knocker.
A what?
A mom who's up for more
than your bedside manner.
Know what I mean?
Really?
She just seems like a
concerned mom to me.
Her kid's...
Just trust me.
Keep a buffer
between you and her,
a stool, portable
X-ray, anything.
I hate guys like that.
Just 'cause he
has a hot girlfriend,
he thinks everyone
wants to bone him.
Mr. Jaffee, we've
almost got the all-clear.
We just need to
take you upstairs
for a pre-op chest
X-ray and an EKG,
and then we're good to go.
So, you're gonna
need to lose the hat.
He, uh, won't
take it off. I tried.
Look, my late wife
gave me this hat.
You know, I caught 22
prize-winning bluegills in it!
It goes everywhere
I go. It's good luck.
And we found you a kidney,
so the hat's done its job.
Yeah.
Well, can't I just keep it?
Hand it over.
Okay. But, uh...
Oh, my God.
Yeah, that showed
up a few months ago.
Charge to 100. Press sync.
Clear!
What do we have? Here you go.
What are you doing?
Cardioverting, 150. Clear!
Who are you? Get
away from my patient!
Found the scrubs, by
the way. Thanks for that.
Hey! Your patient?
Charge to 200.
Hey, I'm in the middle of doing
something here! She's hypotensive!
I can see that! Clear!
Riggs?
Hunt! Do you know this person?
What the hell are
you doing here?
Hey, I'm trying to do
my job! Everyone stop!
Who gave you privileges here?
Well, you did.
When you hired me, right?
You hired someone for my
department without telling me?
Shoot. Riggs.
Uh, no, I was going to tell you.
You'll like him. I promise.
I'd like to have
decided that for myself.
Oh, but he's great.
He was in line to be
chief of cardio at Duke.
He's done incredible
amounts of relief work...
And you hired him here
without any discussion,
without asking a single...
Hunt, it's not your department.
What's your problem?
Look, Pierce, I'm sorry,
but he was available,
we had an opening,
and I made a call.
And I'm the chief.
Now, kindly go
away. I'm operating.
Well, thanks for having my back.
Huh? Right. No problem.
So, how long have
you had this lump, sir?
Oh, not long.
Um... Seven, eight months now.
And you never had it treated?
Well, it was just a little
bump at first, you know?
I thought it was a bug bite.
And then I thought
maybe it was a cyst.
And then I was afraid.
That they would kick
you off the transplant list.
I already called the grandkids.
Maybe I should've waited?
This is not a plastics
case. I think it's a tumor.
That's what I was afraid of.
I mean, if this is cancer, there's
no way he's getting that kidney.
Yeah, it's likely invaded
locally, the tumor.
Uh, it's possibly metastasized.
Sorry.
Hey. Did we get the pet scans?
I thought we were
waiting on neuro
and ortho consults.
Okay, we need to run oncology
staging on this mass right now.
Pet scans ASAP
with renal precautions.
And why are these
consults taking so long?
I'm sorry. I pushed.
They were busy. That's fine.
Just, uh, let me know
when we get them, okay?
Okay.
Why is she going easy on you?
What'd you do?
I have no idea.
Okay.
Hey. Oh.
Um, any interest in trivia
night at a lesbian bar?
I'm not sure I know that
much about lesbians.
Funny. You're funny.
Uh, listen, I'm just trying
to dip my toes in the pool.
Mmm. You know, the dating pool.
It's been a while, and I
need, like, a wingman.
Or wingwoman. Whatever.
Because women don't
buy drinks for sad loners...
I have a date with
Jackson tonight.
Oh, that's great!
Ah! I know!
He, uh, asked me
to dinner to talk,
and I'm trying really hard
not to get too excited about it.
Oh, but that's a start, so...
Yes, yes, it's a light
at the end of a
long, dark tunnel.
I'm so glad, April.
I'm so... Sorry, I...
Yeah. No.
Got a sec? Hey. What's up?
Uh, well, uh, listen.
You know, uh, Miranda
and I were talking,
and she... Well, both of us,
we were wondering if
tonight you might, uh...
Ah, I can't do anything tonight.
I'm going to dinner with April.
April? Really?
Yeah. I asked her.
You know, I figure we're
in a pretty good place,
and now we can actually talk...
That's fantastic.
About divorce. So...
Well, that's, um...
Damn.
I'm sorry, man. I
wish there was...
Yeah, I do, too. Thanks, man.
Another night, though?
Another night.
All right. Um, good luck.
Yeah. See you at home, buddy.
Yes, you will.
I finally pinned down
Dr. Torres and Dr. Shepherd,
and they're looking
at Mr. Jaffee's scans.
Okay, great. Tell
them I'll be right there.
How do you do that?
How do I do what?
Work with Blake after...
I mean, how are you doing that?
Oh.
Well, I thought that I could
treat her like any other resident.
But that was really hard,
because I wanted to
punch her in the face.
Like, a lot.
So now I'm trying
something different.
I am keeping her on a
short leash at a distance
so at least she can't
hurt anyone else.
I just don't think
I could do that.
Well, she's here. She's
not going anywhere, so...
Mrs. Brown? I'm Dr. Pierce.
I'm the chief of
cardiothoracic surgery.
And this is doctor... Dr. Riggs.
Hi. Well, I'm glad to
see you awake, Loretta.
You gave us a bit
of a scare, there.
When can I go home?
Uh, I'd like to run
some more tests
to determine whether
you'll need surgery.
We've called your family.
They're on their way.
Dr. Riggs, do you
think I need surgery?
Your echo shows a
reduction in blood flow
through one of the
valves in your heart,
so we just want
to make sure that...
I'd like to keep you overnight
to run some more tests.
And I'll take it
from there, okay?
Dr. Riggs?
You're gonna be
well taken care of.
It's your first day.
Might want to get your
feet wet before you dive in.
Mmm.
My feet were pretty
wet when I got here.
Then you can get me
a cardiac-gated CT,
and do a risk stratification.
Page me with the results.
Yes, ma'am. Thank you.
Well?
Osteosarcoma.
It involves the frontal
and the occipital bone.
It's locally very aggressive.
It's a lovely tumor.
It's almost cute.
Just plopped there. "Hello."
He's waited 18
months for this kidney.
We finally have one,
and now he has cancer?
What if he didn't? Didn't what?
Have cancer. His tumor
has gorgeous margins.
It's like a ripe,
juicy piece of fruit
that's hung low on the branch.
I could reach in and pluck it.
No cancer, no problem.
You can do that? No.
Even if you can
remove it... Oh, I can.
Well, he's left with a
gaping hole in his head.
No skull, no skin to cover it.
I fix brains. I give you
your soft, gooey center.
The hard candy shell
is your department.
No, there's no way to close it.
Not even a rotational flap.
There's nothing
to work with here.
And a wound that size,
when his immune system
is already compromised,
that could kick him
off the transplant list.
We have less than 24 hours
before we lose the kidney.
So, Wilson and
Edwards, I need ideas.
Crazy ideas, smart ideas.
Give me anything that
will close Mr. Jaffee's head
so he can survive this surgery.
Go. Hit the books.
Find me something.
On it. Absolutely.
Dr. Grey?
Should I look too, or...
Blake. No, you should, um...
Go monitor the donor. Do that.
Make sure the brain-dead
guy is still brain-dead.
Got it.
What are you doing? Excuse me?
"Monitor the donor?"
You've got Blake doing
scut that an intern could do.
She is here to
learn. And, well...
Listen, Callie.
When I teach her, you
say I am beating her down.
When I'm nice to her,
you say I'm neglecting her.
No, no, no. You're
neglecting your responsibility.
And if she were
any other resident...
If she were any other resident,
you wouldn't be talking
to me right now, Callie.
I'm done talking
about your girlfriend.
This is your problem.
It's not Blake's,
and it's not mine.
That's...
Ah! Oh!
Oh, I didn't mean
to startle you.
Is he okay?
Listen, you have nothing to
worry about. Gary's gonna be fine.
I imagine it's
not the first time
he's done something like this.
You're right. You get it.
You know, it can just
be so hard sometimes.
You know, he's a great
kid, but he can be a lot.
Well, you're doing a great job.
He's a great kid. Thank you.
Thank you so much. You know,
you're so nice, and so helpful.
Thank you.
Oh, uh, that's... It's
not a problem at all.
Oh, um...
Uh-oh. Um...
Ma'am... Ma'am!
It's Elaine.
Oh, uh, Elaine, ma'am, I...
'Cause I have
the other patients.
But I'll... Uh, bye.
Yeah, bye. I'll see
you in an hour?
Finally. God, what took so long?
Whoa. Relax. This was
nice of me, remember?
I didn't know you were
gonna make the food.
She's cranky.
Bailey hired a new cardio
guy without telling her.
That's jacked. Who is this guy?
It just means I'm gonna have
to train another alpha male
not to pee all over the place.
Mmm. I hate it when they pee.
Derek peed a lot.
Oh, come on.
We're not like that.
When you got here,
you peed everywhere.
It was disgusting.
You had to be trained.
Nobody trained me.
We trained you. It was
subtle. You didn't notice.
Is that why you
made me get the food?
Not even that.
It's the patients.
It's the way that they always
look to the man in the room first
no matter who
is talking to them.
Yes. That's a thing?
Not for you.
And then there's
the whole other thing.
You know, I just... I thought
I was done with that here.
This guy just comes in.
He's taking consults without
even talking to me about it...
What whole other thing?
That?
Come on, is that a thing?
Of course it is.
Here? Yeah, here. Anywhere.
Ask Edwards. Ask Bailey.
I can't believe that.
That's 'cause
it's not your thing.
Okay, tell me what
you said to him.
How did you fight for our love?
Well, um...
What? I, uh...
What did you say?
Well, I started to, and...
Look, I would
have, but he told me
he's talking to
April about divorce,
and so... He's coming back here?
Do you get how serious this is?
Oh, I am off my game. Ugh.
I hired a new cardio surgeon
and forgot to tell Pierce.
That's all the more reason
for us to use this time
right now while we have it.
When he's out at
what is bound to be
a very, very long
dinner. Oh, no, no.
He could come back here
any minute in the middle of stuff!
Okay, this is our
window, Miranda.
He's asking for a divorce.
There's no telling when
we're getting our sofa back!
Oh, yes, there is.
It's when you tell
him to get the hell out!
When you get him to say,
"Thank you for your hospitality.
"It is time for me
to leave your sofa."
Miranda, come... No.
You don't get
it until you get it.
Oh, that was delicious.
Yeah, their pumpkin
ravioli never disappoints.
This has been really nice.
Yeah.
We've somehow managed to
finish our meal without actually...
Talking. Right. Talking.
Do we need to, though?
I want to.
If you do.
But it...
It's been so nice just
having a meal with you.
We really should, though.
We should talk.
Yes. Yes. We should.
Damn it.
I'm... It's all right.
Duty calls. It's fine.
I want to keep
talking, though. I do.
Um...
Tomorrow night?
Tomorrow night. Okay.
Help. Help!
Someone, please.
Do something. Dr. Hunt?
I can't find her.
Find who?
Dr. Hunt. No, do something!
Dr. Hunt. Dr. Hunt, Dr. Hunt.
Are you okay? God.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I was just sleeping.
Sorry. You can go.
Are you sure that... Get out.
Here?
Dr. Grey said monitor.
I am monitoring.
Any luck?
With the hole in
Mr. Jaffee's head? Nope.
3D printing will take too long.
A custom-based cranioplasty
won't work, so I'm...
How's the Holy Grail?
Can we not call him that?
Sorry. Just...
He was someone's
family member, you know?
Someone's husband,
someone's dad.
To someone, he was everything.
And now he's
everything to Mr. Jaffee.
But after all this
time and waiting,
we probably won't
even get to use him.
He's everything, and
it doesn't even matter.
It means nothing.
I know.
It doesn't seem fair.
He's everything.
Pardon?
He's everything. Oh,
my God, he's everything!
A skull transplant?
Skull and scalp, actually.
Our kidney donor is a
perfect match for Mr. Jaffee,
which means that he's also a
match for the skull and scalp.
Lower risk of rejection.
He's everything.
We'll have all the
vascularized bone
and skin that we
need from the donor.
Have you done this before?
I haven't. It's been done once.
It's a complex surgery,
but I think it'll work.
Same donor, same surgery.
Well, I'll start on the tumor
while you two start organ recovery.
Let's go get our kidney.
Hey. Um, come out for
a drink with me tonight?
It'll be fun. It's trivia night.
It can either be fun
or it can be trivia night.
Come on. Broaden your horizons.
Plus, I don't really
want to go alone...
Uh, Robbins. Huh?
Did you know that Henri Giffard
built the first powered
airship in 1852?
Um...
Uh, no.
I did.
And I'm free tonight.
I'm always free
for trivia night.
Hmm.
Riggs, what happened?
Her heart's failing.
I've asked for a balloon
pump to buy us some time.
What she needs is a
valve replacement, stat.
Even better. Call up for an OR.
Let's prep her for a sternotomy.
Krista, not a sternotomy. Keep
prepping for a cath procedure.
No. No?
No. I need to open her up.
She won't survive
being open that long.
I'll never get a catheter all
the way up into the heart.
Riggs, I am doing
this procedure.
And you will be doing
the wrong procedure.
Prep for a TAVR. WOMAN:
Right away, Doctor.
My name is on her chart.
I want to be in that room so
that if something goes wrong...
Don't worry, Riggs. If
she dies, it'll be my fault.
My wife's dying?
Uh, Mr. Brown. Hello.
We're taking Loretta
up to surgery right now.
Okay.
We're going to do
everything we can.
Hang in there, Gary.
How long ago did
the light stop blinking?
It stopped? I'm not sure.
I might've missed
the last couple checks.
Tell me what's wrong here.
The ball came apart?
Yeah. The ball came apart.
And the ball had
little blinking lights.
So what is missing?
I don't...
A battery. Right.
Now the battery is
all the way over here.
Now, if the acid from the
battery eats through his intestine...
It'll perf his bowel.
Well, could we get it
with an endoscope?
Well, we could have.
But now, thanks to you,
I have to open him up.
So notify Karev that I'm
taking Gary to surgery,
then you get a front-row seat
to how bad you screwed this up.
All right. See you in there.
You won't, actually.
I'll be in the donor's OR.
Making sure that the kidney
doesn't grow legs and walk away.
What?
Grey has me babysitting
the kidney until she needs it.
Oh, come on. Callie.
That is...
Grey. Yeah?
Blake is a third-year resident.
She should be in our surgery.
The skull transplant.
That is the learning
opportunity here.
She deserves a chance to see it.
Callie...
Callie, we talked about this.
Blake needs to be
where I need her to be.
You don't need
her with the donor.
You just want her
there. What for? Why?
Why are you doing this?
What, do you just
want her to sit there
and think about what
happened to Derek?
Callie, stop. No, I am sorry,
but I can't just stand here
and... You're embarrassing me!
Nobody asked
you to say anything,
so just shut up
and stay out of it.
All right.
Now, I need you to... Hold on.
I don't need her
to fight for me,
but Callie is right.
I'm here to learn.
I want to learn, but
you have to teach me.
Don't go easy on
me. Don't expect less.
Treat me like
any other resident.
Treat me worse. I don't care.
Hate me, yell at
me, I can handle it.
I will handle it.
You told me not
to quit, and I didn't.
But you are right now.
And if you can't do
what you are here to do,
then please let me go.
Are you gonna do something?
I'm thinking.
Let's prep for a sternotomy.
Let's open her up.
Good choice. - I know.
Come on. You
can say I was right.
You weren't. She won't
survive a six-hour procedure.
It's her best shot.
Listen, I get it, okay?
I'd hate me, too,
the way I was hired.
Bailey should've told you.
10 blade.
Bailey is the chief.
Yeah, but it was
pretty messed up.
I mean, you and I should've
had a proper sit-down.
I agree. Saw, please.
You'd have seen me in my suit.
It's nice.
I mean, it's probably
wrinkled, but it's clean.
No, it's definitely,
definitely clean.
You would've asked
me where I'm from.
Australia. Retract.
And you'd guess
wrong. New Zealand.
A common mistake.
Seattle when I was seven,
then med school, fellowship.
The Middle East for a long time.
Prepare to make a
large aortic purse string.
Why?
Just do it.
Why the Middle East?
Relief work.
I like the pace, the
people, improvisation.
I once re-inflated a
collapsed pulmonary artery
on a dirt road with a
straw and a set of car keys.
Oh, you'd like that story.
Yeah, you'd be
asking me all about it.
You'd be so impressed.
You'd be thinking,
"Wow! He's so innovative. And
he's quick. I should hire him."
Would I? Mmm-hmm.
Oh, yes. At this point, the
interview's going very well.
Take this.
3-0 prolene.
But the kicker is
when I ask about you.
How you landed a
fellowship at the age of 25.
How you made chief
of cardio at an age
when most of us are still
starting out in our specialties.
I'd ask about some of your
twenty-odd published
papers that I've read.
Mostly, I'd like to know what
the hell you're doing right now.
Trans-aortic valve replacement.
By not putting her on bypass,
I turn your six-hour
procedure into...
Into a one-hour
procedure. Brilliant.
Bloody brilliant.
Look, it may seem like
Bailey hired me on a whim,
but I don't do
anything on a whim.
I like to choose the
people that I work for.
When...
When Wilson told
me that you lied...
About, uh, being sick...
I believed her.
Mmm-hmm.
You didn't think that
that... That that was what?
That I sided with her because...
No.
Good. Good.
I mean, it crossed
my mind, but no.
It crossed your mind?
Yeah, of course it did.
I mean, it's always a
possibility. It's always there.
But it wasn't.
With me you have to know...
Hey, Dr. Shepherd...
We are good.
Blake.
Okay. MEREDITH:
Where are you going?
You want to stand in the corner
while I attach the Holy
Grail of kidneys, be my guest.
No, no. Okay.
So let's give Wilson a
break, and step on in here.
I've prepared the
vessels for anastomosis,
and I like an end-to-end
with the internal iliac.
Give me some
room here. Get back.
So, wanna tell me why
you missed the checks?
Dr. Karev warned me
to steer clear of the
kid's mom, and I didn't,
and she sort of jumped me.
She's a doc knocker.
That's a thing?
It is very much a thing.
How did he see that?
I swear I just saw
a nice, scared mom.
Let me tell you what Karev saw.
A concerned mom with a
kid who takes a lot of energy
and a husband who only
looks up from his phone
to contradict
everything that she says.
A mom who was
presented with a doctor
who was only interested
in her son's well-being.
Made her feel
good, taken care of.
Suction.
I didn't see that.
Of course not.
You've only been a
doctor for five minutes.
But you'll learn.
People aren't always
who you think they are.
You learn to see
through it. You learn fast.
Oh. There it is. Right there.
You want to get it?
Chief.
Looks like both of
Mr. Jaffee's transplants
were successful.
Oh, great news.
Oh, Dr. Riggs.
How you settling in?
Well, you'd have to ask
Dr. Pierce that, I think.
Well, have you met everybody?
Um... Dr. Nathan Riggs, this
is Grey, Shepherd, this is Hunt.
Nice to meet you. Riggs.
Hunt! Hey.
Yeah, we, um...
Dr. Hunt and I go back a bit.
Oh! Oh, I didn't realize. - No.
No, you didn't.
Maybe you should've asked around
before you decided to bring a
complete stranger into the hospital.
All right, Owen, why
don't you and I just...
Did you think this
was how it was done?
Didn't you think for one second
that, as chief of this hospital,
it is your responsibility
to vet your people?
'Cause this, this is
a bad call, Bailey.
This is a really bad call.
And it was thoughtless,
and it was reckless...
Hunt.
Why don't we go to my
office and talk about this?
What's done is done, right?
What did he say? Nothing.
Whatever this is...
He's not talking.
Meredith...
I made a promise to Cristina
that I wouldn't let
you go dark and twisty,
that I'd be your person
if you needed one.
I don't want to talk.
Okay.
You don't have to.
But just tell me,
do we hate him?
We hate him.
Okay, then. We hate him.
So, um, how'd it go last night?
It didn't.
I mean, dinner was
great. It was fun, actually.
But when it was finally
time to have the real talk,
April got paged.
Honestly, I think we were both
trying to avoid the subject, but...
Yeah, I need to
have sex with my wife.
And that can't happen
with you in my house.
Now, you're in a
bad place. I get that.
And I will do anything
I can to... I will.
But I need you off my sofa.
I mean, it's for the
good of the hospital...
Totally get it. Okay?
I'll see you. All right.
I mean, how did he seem to you?
Riggs? Yeah.
I don't know. Smart,
capable, charming. Ugh.
I think Bailey was right.
Owen wouldn't tell you anything?
He just shut me
out. I don't know why.
And then...
I'm afraid I
might've been racist.
God, I hate this day.
Okay. Okay, back it up.
Oh, good. I can
talk to you about this.
I am worried I offended Edwards.
I need you to tell me.
Why me? 'Cause I'm your sister?
Yes. Or because
I'm your "sistah"?
No. This is exactly
what I was worried about.
Okay. What do you think you did?
I don't think I did anything,
but I think she thinks I did.
Amelia, use your words.
Did what?
Sided with Wilson over
her because she's black.
Which I didn't do. I think...
God, I hate that this is
even an issue all of a sudden.
Well, it's not an issue for you.
And it's not all of a sudden.
I mean, okay, it's not
Mississippi Burning or anything,
but it is all over.
It's when people
assume I'm a nurse.
Or when I go to
get on an airplane
with my first-class ticket,
and they tell me that they're
not boarding coach yet.
It's like a low buzz
in the background.
And sometimes you
don't even notice it,
and sometimes it's
loud and annoying.
And sometimes it
can get dangerous.
And sometimes it is
ridiculous, like right now.
But it's not funny.
I mean, if I'm doing it
and I don't even notice it...
Then notice it.
Look, did Edwards
tell you that she's okay?
Yes.
Okay.
Then don't give
her the extra work
of having to make
you feel good about it.
Right.
Okay, but how do I
know that she's really...
Because she knows you, okay?
So listen to the words that
are coming out of her mouth
and believe them.
This is not a small thing.
And I'm glad that you feel like
you can talk to me about it,
but I don't speak
for all black people.
I am not the
spokeswoman. No one is.
And it is kind of annoying to
be asked questions like I am.
But, uh, one piece of
advice that I can give you
that I think we
would all agree with
is that if you feel
uncomfortable having done it,
check your white privilege,
and don't do it again.
But I don't think you're racist.
You don't think?
Girl, get in the car.
Okay.
He had so many
grandkids I lost count.
I'm not exaggerating.
Seven.
He had seven
grandchildren from six kids,
who he raised on his
own after his wife died.
Are you okay?
I treated Mr. Jaffee for years,
and I finally get
him what he needs,
and you just come and
take it and run with it.
And I helped you all day.
He was my patient.
That's all.
Jo.
So, you want to grab a drink?
Yeah.
I would love that, actually.
Okay.
So, um, we've got
science covered.
I'm strong on history
and geography.
How's your popular culture?
I just want to get a sense
of our strengths here...
Richard, I'm sorry.
I'm here to...
I wanted to have...
I'm trying to...
I'm here to meet girls.
I don't care about trivia.
I don't even like trivia.
Oh.
I see. That's...
And then you offered to come,
and I didn't know how to say no.
And I just... I didn't want
to go it alone, honestly.
It's just it's been a long time,
and I'm rusty and nervous.
And I feel like I
lived an entire lifetime
since the last time I dated,
and I don't even
know where to start.
You need a wingman.
What do you like?
Glasses?
Cardigan. She has a nice laugh.
You into tattoos?
Not that many tattoos.
Well, you know, I'm just
trying to get a sense of
what we're after here.
Glasses is cute.
I'll be right back.
Sit up straight.
Hello, ladies.
It's hard to fight
against certain biases.
It's important to
keep an open mind.
It's how we learn.
It's how we grow.
Hey.
It's how we move forward.
Dr. Grey, right? Yep.
Yours is easy to remember.
It's on all the
hospital stationery.
What's the story there?
That's too long a story to tell.
I was actually headed
across the street.
I was gonna grab a
drink or something.
Are you headed that way, or...
I'm a friend of Owen Hunt's.
Until we don't.
I see.
So, no.
Until we let our bias take over.
Until we succumb
to what feels right or good
or satisfying in that moment.
Because even then,
deep down inside,
we usually know
we're going to regret it.