Big Eye, this is Cobra Zero Six.
Just entered Indian Country,
approaching way point four.
Request confirmation to
engage target on first approach.
Roger, Cobra Zero Six.
Big Eye waiting for
confirmation as well.
If we wait any longer, Big Eye,
we're not gonna have
any choice in the matter.
I can't exactly
do a U-turn here.
Roger that, Cobra.
Hold for confirmation.
Captain Cooper, are you okay?
What happened?
You weren't answering.
Because the damn comm
cord got disconnected!
You spend a billion
dollars on the avionics
and don't bother to check
the comm connection?
No, I checked that
twice before you got in...
And the next time you
ask us to test a prototype,
it'd be nice if your directional
gyro didn't spin like a top
when I'm supposed to
be 500 feet off the floor.
I'm sorry.
I'll go review the simulation, see
if I can figure out what went wrong.
Who is this man?
Come on, take a shot.
I'm not gonna fire you every
time you get a wrong answer.
Neville Chamberlain.
You're fired.
Does this man look like he's ceding
Czechoslovakia to a fascist dictatorship?
It's Buddy Ebsen, the actor.
He's dead. Why are we...
Buddy Ebsen was the original tin
man in the Wizard of Oz, for a day.
He was diagnosed allergic to
the aluminum dust in the makeup.
His lungs failed. He nearly
died. Question is, why?
Didn't you just say
he was allergic?
You may not have legs, but you
got ears. I suggest you use them.
I said he was
diagnosed allergic.
Since we are currently short
exactly one interesting patient,
we are gonna figure out what really
happened to Buddy Ebsen in 1938.
Now, on one hand,
he's not getting deader.
On the other hand, your
jobs hang in the balance. So...
House?
I want seven alternate
diagnoses when I get back.
Did you forget how
to count to three?
I get a budget for three.
Doesn't mean I
can only hire three.
Actually, that's
exactly what it means.
I cut the permanent
salaries by 10%.
Over three years, that'll more than
make up for the breakage on the 27
that I'm gonna weed out
over the next few weeks.
There's 40 people in there.
Row D, you're fired.
I didn't actually
count all the resumes.
This is stupid. You can't
manage that many people.
You're just gonna keep
weeding them out arbitrarily?
Sure, and having
them sitting in my office
schmoozing about their
favorite Algerian surfing movies
is a much better system.
Wait a second. Were
you in Row D? Yes.
My apologies. My boss says
I'm being arbitrary and stupid.
Row D is not fired.
Row C is fired!
What? WOMAN: Great. Thank you.
See, that was not arbitrary.
Well, I'd love to chat,
but I've been paged.
That's interesting.
Apparently, I paged myself.
If you have a resume
there, I'm not interested.
But I wouldn't mind hearing
how you got my pager number.
It's not a resume.
$50,000.
Does One-Eyed Nicky want
me to run that to Jimmy the Nose?
It's for my medical bills.
I need you to find out
what's wrong with me.
Insurance is usually
cheaper than that.
Cash means there's
something to hide.
I'm a captain in the Air Force,
about to start a new assignment.
NASA's astronaut
training program.
I discovered salt
and created FM radio.
Something is wrong
with my eyes, my ears...
Well, if it's fixable, the
Air Force will do it for free.
If not, it doesn't matter.
There are a hundred
applicants ready to take my place
who don't need to be fixed.
I need to do this off the books.
I did the research. You're
the best, you break rules,
and you don't care about
anyone except yourself.
Well, let's say that's true.
You get a new job.
Hospital gets a
nice wad of cash.
What do I get?
I crashed a flight simulator
because I started
to hear with my eyes.
The aluminum could
have been tainted...
Don't care. New patient!
30-year-old female
with synesthesia.
New rules.
You generate a lab
report, you shred it.
X-ray, you melt it.
No notes, no records, nothing.
As far as you're concerned,
the patient is Osama Bin Laden
and everyone not in this room
is Delta Force. Any questions?
We're protecting
Osama Bin Laden?
It's a metaphor.
Get used to it. Any
more questions?
And you're not even
gonna tell us her name?
You think her name might be
connected to what's wrong with her?
Here's Osama.
Now, you all have numbers, so
we're gonna do this alphabetically.
8, 15 and 5.
Is the synesthesia new?
Yes.
Any history of similar
symptoms or psychiatric...
No, nothing.
Are you on any prescription
meds or use any other drugs?
No. Should we trust her answers?
What, you think I'd pull you off
Buddy Ebsen just for a junkie?
Can we trust your answers?
You gotta trust someone, right?
No.
Has anyone close to you been sick
lately? A family member, co-worker?
No, not that I'm aware of.
Two down. Kitty Carlisle?
Do you spend much
time above 20,000 feet?
Why would you ask that?
People who fly are
immobile for long periods.
Could be a leg clot that embolized
to the brain through a PFO.
That's an unusual choice.
Well, like you said, you wouldn't
interrupt Buddy with anything that wasn't.
The patient is a frequent flyer.
13, 32, 39, get Osama an
EEG, MRI and angiogram.
How many of you think
that Oswald acted alone?
If, by alone, you mean that
he was unaware that the CIA...
Oh, shut up.
Split yourself into two groups.
Test her blood. Test her stool.
Who likes the designated hitter?
You're wrong. You're
lucky you're not fired.
Two more groups LP and cultures.
Who doesn't know what
a designated hitter is?
Okay, here's her address.
I want you to break in and
find out what she's hiding.
Why don't we just ask
the patient for the key?
Well, if you can find out what
she's hiding just by asking,
we'd have to redefine hiding.
You want to live in this
country, learn the language.
What do you want
the rest of us to do?
30 people for three openings
and I want you to wash my car?
This is not why I busted
my ass in med school.
We spend a half an hour
cleaning the car. Big deal.
It's demeaning.
Work is demeaning?
We're too good for this?
Oh, don't give me that
honest day's labor crap.
We all went to med school so we
wouldn't have to do an honest day's labor.
What about an
honest hour's labor?
In exchange, we
get a shot at learning
from one of the best
diagnosticians in the world.
No, we don't.
If we did, we'd be one of the ones
drawing blood or checking for toxins.
We're done.
He's just not gonna cut us loose
until we've dusted his
shelves and starched his shirt.
I'm out of here. Who's with me?
Are we sure he wasn't joking?
Maybe this is just a test.
Everything's a joke and everything's
a test and he wants us to do it.
Come on, get up here.
Well, I could try, but I
pulled a muscle in 1987.
I didn't waste two years repeating
medical school to be arrested and deported.
Why'd they make you repeat?
Not enough gym credits?
According to the
state of New Jersey,
medical schools in my country
suffer from not being from this country.
You know, if you get it open, you're
gonna have to come down and let me in.
Or, you could
just wait out here.
This is a competition.
Change your mind?
No.
Then why are you here?
Never intended to quit.
Then why did you... Intended
to get everyone else to quit.
Get off the car.
I need to clean it.
We need to clean it.
I stole his keys. We'll
take it to a car wash.
He's got people breaking
into a woman's apartment.
Obviously, respecting personal
property isn't one of the rules.
I told the super I was
worried about my niece.
She hasn't been
answering the telephone.
Nice guy. Two daughters
in Mount Holyoke.
No evidence of clots, and other
than elevated red blood cell count,
the blood work was unremarkable.
You got a problem with
the naked female form?
Not at all.
Maybe she's just not used to seeing it
spooning with the naked dolphin form.
That's not a dolphin,
it's a porpoise.
There is a difference, you
know. Salary, for one thing...
You want us to
give you a minute?
High red blood cell
count likely means...
Carbon monoxide poisoning.
There are a lot of different
explanations for elevated red blood cells.
Yeah, well, which one fits best
with the damaged flue
that your competitors found
in the gas fireplace
in Osama's cave?
Car's clean.
Did you just see a blond
guy with a pretentious accent?
Can't see an accent.
Good point.
Can I have my car keys back?
Give me the car keys, put the
patient in a hyperbaric chamber
and no more prime
numbers for you.
Thank you.
The high pressure and oxygen will flush
the carbon monoxide from your system.
This much oxygen for
too long can have some
toxic effects, so
we'll do this in cycles.
Can I talk to you a second?
You're working that thing all
the time. Is everything all right?
We're supposed to be watching
her heart rate and blood pressure.
Yeah, I was until you
pulled me over here.
I'm sending out a
consult on another patient.
Okay.
What? I'm not quitting my old
job until I'm sure I've got a new one.
I didn't say anything.
You had a look.
Yeah, I did. Sorry.
Hey, I think she's
having a heart attack.
No, I just feel a little funny.
Tachyarrhythmia.
Call the code!
Nothing.
V-fib. Where the
hell is... Clear!
Are you crazy? You can't use
those! We're in a hyperbaric...
Clear!
She's on fire!
Her heart's beating.
And we are so fired.
We've started her on
nitro and blood thinners.
Electrolytes and post-arrest
EKG were normal.
The attack was not
caused by the procedure.
So, what does cause synesthesia,
high red blood cell
count and heart attack?
Aren't we gonna discuss what caused
the sudden appearance of burnt flesh?
He brought charged paddles
into an oxygenated room.
And you didn't stop him.
Means either you thought it was a chance
worth taking, making you a hypocrite,
or you thought he'd fail,
making you a cutthroat little pixie.
What causes...
Takayasu's syndrome.
Not without a rash and a
fever. It's gotta be Whipple's.
No way. You ever see
Whipple's without abdominal pain?
Stop it!
This argument is distracting
every male and lesbian here.
You're both right.
In the sense that you've
convinced me that you're both wrong.
What about cardiomyopathy?
Structural abnormality
causes the heart attack
and throws clots to the
brain, leading to synesthesia.
How old are you?
I'm 21, unless it's relevant.
Okay, Scooter.
Do a transoesophageal echo.
And since the positive divisors of
26, are 2 and 13, have them assist.
The rest of you,
go to the cafeteria.
Document 10 things that
can cause infection, each.
I wouldn't. Someone named 17 thinks there
could be lysteria in the cream cheese.
17's a stupid number.
What's Chase doing here?
You saw Chase?
Last night. Outside my office.
That's interesting.
It's more curious
than actually...
Chase took a job at the Mayo
Clinic in Arizona a week ago.
Interesting.
It wasn't Foreman or Cameron you
saw, but Chase, the one you fired.
Not interesting.
Someone who looked like someone
I used to know walked by my office.
It's always interesting when
repressed guilt starts unrepressing itself.
The only thing I
feel guilty for is this.
We're gonna feed this
endoscope down your esophagus,
try to find where your
heart might be damaged.
It's gonna feel uncomfortable,
but just keep swallowing,
I promise you'll be fine.
She's ready.
Go ahead, take a whack.
Right, so if we don't find
anything, House blames me.
Or you find something
and get a gold star.
Why don't you wanna do it?
House isn't gonna be impressed by a
gray hair doing his ten-thousandth echo.
So, you're just
being altruistic?
That makes you
suspicious, Doctor...
Call me 13. I'm
not getting invested.
Her heart's structurally sound.
No clots, no valvular defects,
no wall motion abnormalities.
Got that from
structurally sound.
What did she say?
Structurally sound.
I assume you're not all walking
with me to tell me you found nothing...
It showed a
short burst in the...
Okay. Who's next?
It showed a short
burst of atrial flutter.
I ran a rhythm strip twice
and got the same result.
Stop.
Okay, here's how
we diagnose in transit.
I lead, you draft, I move, you
move, I stop, you stop. Got it?
Flutter could mean
hormone overproduction...
Wait a second. Why did you
do the test? I gave it to Scooter.
- We didn't think it mattered.
- It doesn't.
It matters that you let her.
Okay, 10, 24, 39, run a TRH
stimulation test for hyperthyroidism.
That could cause
another heart attack.
Proving her first attack
was caused by her thyroid,
which is kind of
the point, right?
Uh-uh, uh-uh, uh-uh.
I ride alone.
The hormones
stimulate your thyroid.
Don't worry if you get
flushed or you start to sweat.
It means the thyroid's working.
And, if you want, I
can remove that mole.
I'm a plastic surgeon.
You're allowed a little vanity.
I'm fine with the way I look.
Good for you.
Although, I do find it a bit odd
that someone so self-assured
doesn't want her doctors to
find out what's wrong with her.
What are you talking
about? Why else am I here?
You're jerking us around. You're
handcuffing us with all these restrictions.
I'm feeling warm.
Her pulse is 120. Stop pushing.
If House thought this would handicap
us, he wouldn't have taken the case.
Or maybe that's
why he took the case.
He wants to see if we can
get it out of her on our own.
What did you find at her home?
You were in my home? Nothing.
Travel pictures, yearbook, her
name on an employment slip?
We weren't checking
for that stuff, okay?
Obviously, House
didn't want us to.
You're gonna... You're
gonna out me, aren't you?
You're gonna ruin everything.
Nobody's trying to
do anything, just relax.
This is not a normal response to
the test. Pulse and BP are too high.
Get away from me.
Get away from
me! Don't touch me!
Paging me during Judge Judy,
not the best way to win my affections.
She had another
episode of synesthesia.
It set off a psychotic attack.
And now she ran in there, and must
have jammed something in the handles.
So, you call me?
The guy with one good
leg and zero leverage?
We break that door down, security
shows up and her name goes in a file.
Luckily, violence
is not the last resort.
Extortion is. So, go
ahead. Extort her.
If you don't open this door,
we're gonna break it down.
Clever.
An appeal to her deep concern for hospital
property. Let's see how that works.
If you don't open this
door, you're going to die.
Go away!
Well, you seem
to be getting to her.
She doesn't care if she dies.
You think she wants to die?
No, but I think she only wants to
live under certain circumstances.
Open up, or I blab
your secret to everyone.
You don't know anything.
I do.
No!
Anybody think that
a sedative might...
I'm trying. Okay!
Who's that?
Who is she?
Osama Bin Laden.
Is she okay?
She's stable. Who is she?
What did House tell you?
That she is on the run from
an international crime syndicate.
That's what he told us.
House may be your
boss, but I'm House's boss.
You wanna work here,
I better be okay with it!
Honestly, he didn't tell us anything
about who she was or what she...
Her name's Greta Cooper.
Wants to be an astronaut.
Doesn't want NASA to know her brain's
getting her ears confused with her eyes.
I went through her mail.
You're a virus, House. Now
instead of one liability, I've got 20.
Apparently only 19.
Which number was it?
From now on, everything
you do gets charted.
With pen, on paper,
in a binder that says,
"Princeton-Plainsboro
Teaching Hospital" on the cover.
Mom!
If you wanna run something
through the labs, I get a copy.
If you do scans, I get a copy.
If you think about doing
scans, I get a copy.
You know my current thoughts,
right? I don't have to put those on paper.
Three issues.
One, number 10, you're fired.
She told you?
Well, it had to be someone
who went to her home.
Number 26 is half asleep.
Missed his afternoon nap.
Obviously, he
doesn't feel guilt.
Number 2 is here on a
visa, she can't jeopardize.
You can't know.
And that chick's been
pointing at you since I walked in.
Issue two, what
causes synesthesia,
high RBC, tachyarrhythmia
and panic attacks?
Slight glucose elevation.
That says thyroid.
Baseline thyrotropin's 1.1.1.3.
Whatever. Her thyroid's working.
What about her liver?
Original ALT levels weren't
abnormal, but were near the edge.
She has patient data
on her PDA. I do not.
I saw the lab values. You said
we couldn't write anything down.
I also said I wanted answers.
Liver cancer's the most likely.
Paraneoplastic syndrome.
We need to do an MRI.
Which brings us to issue three.
You're saying we
can write stuff down?
To you, I'm
saying, you're fired.
To everyone else... But
you said specifically...
I hate tattletales.
She tattled on 10.
Now, you've tattled twice.
Issue three...
Come on, let's go.
Issue three, how do we do
tests when we can't do tests?
Dr. Cuddy didn't say we can't do
tests, she said we have to chart.
If we chart, we won't
get consent, so we can't.
The patient's life may
depend on her consenting.
Her dreams depend
on her not consenting.
So, how do we do tests
when we can't do tests?
You've got an hour.
How do you scan a liver
without scanning a liver?
And what's Cameron doing here?
Interesting, so you're
seeing Cameron now.
No, not interesting,
because not seeing. Saw.
My patient won't consent
to MRIs or ultrasounds.
You've dealt with more liver
cancer than anyone else here.
So, you want me to share the secret
scanning techniques I learnt in Nepal?
Unfortunately, the monks
made me swear a blood oath.
Where was she?
In the lobby.
I guess, we could palpate
the area around the liver.
Which won't work unless the
tumor's enormous, which you know,
which means you're here because
these visions are freaking you out.
Did...
She had blond hair. Why
would I hallucinate that?
Yes, yes!
Why are you merging
Cameron and Chase?
We should find out before the next
time you see her, when she'll be black.
Because, of course, it's
scientifically impossible for a person
to go back and visit
somewhere they worked.
No. But since
she's not a dead cat,
it is scientifically impossible for
her to be in two places at once.
Physics joke. Don't
hear enough of those.
She just called me from Arizona.
Notice the area code, 480.
They put an offer on
a place in Scottsdale.
Do you want to talk or should
I? I guess we could both talk.
Although, they're engaged,
and if you're staying in touch,
you might wanna buy them...
Maybe it's not repressed
guilt, maybe it's just panic.
Right now, you've got enough
fellows to build a railroad,
but you're gonna have to narrow that
room full of numbers down to three people.
Any chance you could turn this creative
brilliance towards my patient's liver?
I think you're gonna
choose people
for reasons that have
nothing to do with their skills.
I think you're gonna choose people
just because you can't stand them.
Because if you like
them, well, that's just
stressful.
Stress.
I like it.
We need to stress
the patient's liver.
You mean make her sick?
I mean, make her
sick in a specific way.
If her liver's given to malfunctioning,
we make it malfunction.
Are we on the other
side of wrong here?
Don't we have an ethics board
that we should consult, or...
I fired you.
No, you didn't.
He fired you, you're number 6.
No, I'm not. I'm number 9.
I approve of your shamelessness.
You're still fired.
So, how do we stress her liver?
Lying and paperwork, I get.
Shutting down organs, I think...
We could give her intravenous vitamin
D and stick her in a tanning booth.
If she goes into a coma, we
know it's a metabolic problem.
Nice.
But vitamin D's metabolized
by the liver and kidneys.
It wouldn't tell us
which one's screwed up.
We could get her wasted.
Give her shots of tequila and measure
how long it takes for her to pass out.
If it's too fast, then we know
her liver is not processing alcohol.
Means it's shot.
I like you, number 9.
You wanted to see me?
You a Mormon?
You're wearing a ring
from Brigham Young.
Or did your folks
just do the lawns?
The Church has a very progressive
attitude towards racial equality.
Don't care. Actually,
I'm thanking God.
You're the only
non-drinker we got.
We need a control group
to establish whether the liver's
deterioration is within normal range.
Got a big drinker, a medium
drinker, now I got a no-drinker.
Just do an MRI.
You really think the guy
who created heaven and earth
cares what you put
in your digestive tract?
Her dream shouldn't
outrank my religious belief.
Why not? Her dream
might come true.
All life is sacred, right?
We're not saving her life.
We're doing a diagnostic test.
Not even a real diagnostic test.
Well, that fake test
might really save her life.
Would you pull an ass
out of a pit on the Sabbath?
Would you or would you not pull
an ass out of a pit on the Sabbath?
Fine. I'll do it.
Good.
Why'd you have to pick tequila?
I assume a single malt
would've worked just as well.
Wasn't our choice.
Okay, two minutes,
then round number five.
So, tell me about
the magic underwear.
Is that why you're here?
I'm the big drinker,
doing my part for science.
The interesting question
is why your religious beliefs
are suddenly less
important than her dreams.
You're reversing your argument?
I know what I believe.
I'm just not quite
sure what you believe.
Well, LDS doesn't try to
dictate every detail of our lives.
When a situation isn't clear, we're
encouraged to make our own decisions.
But your judgment was to say no.
You used my judgment.
You made a good argument.
Rational arguments don't
usually work on religious people.
Otherwise, there would
be no religious people.
You're an atheist.
Only on Christmas and Easter.
Rest of the time, it
doesn't really matter.
Where's the fun in that?
A finite un-mysterious universe?
It's not about fun.
It's about the truth.
The truth is we're having
this debate because
you wanna figure
something out about me.
What have you got so far?
Greta! Greta!
She can't breathe.
We need to intubate.
No!
At least oxygen.
NASA will need to know why!
I checked the tests you ordered.
Did you just see Foreman?
You measured the
density of her teeth.
It's a shortcut test
for hypocalcaemia.
You had to have just passed him.
So, you suspected hypocalcaemia
from her complete
lack of broken bones?
Is that why you also
ran three tox screens?
Patient might have
been sneaking uppers.
He was in a white coat.
Did you hire him back?
Foreman is running the diagnostic
department at New York Mercy.
Have you been drinking?
She was having
trouble breathing.
Refused oxygen and intubation.
So you put her on a treadmill?
Records will show that we gave her oxygen
as a part of a routine cardio stress test.
She gets to breathe, your
boss gets her paperwork.
Whose idea was that?
It was a joint decision.
It never is.
So, how old were you
when your brother left home?
Why do you think that I...
Why aren't you answering?
Did your mother
initiate the divorce?
We should probably focus
on what's wrong with her lungs.
Are you Wiccan?
She really can't breathe.
Okay. Hold still.
What are you doing?
Auscultatory percussion.
If you have a
good ear, you can...
You didn't have a lot of friends,
because you chose not to...
You can hear
while you're talking?
You can detect not only structural
details, but small, deep masses.
Game's over.
You either have lung
cancer or tuberous sclerosis.
We need to cut you
open and biopsy.
That'll
leave a scar.
NASA doctors will
see it. They'll know.
I never opened for Springsteen
or slept with Barbara Feldon.
You can live for years
without dreams. Without lungs...
Find a way.
Okay.
As long as you keep saying
it strongly, you won't die.
Find a way.
How do we force a
patient into surgery?
Texas bag scam? Saratoga Wire?
Paris Exposition Trick?
The problem's not the
surgery, it's the scars,
and we have a plastic surgeon
here who can hide them.
Not that well. NASA's
gonna check every cranny.
I say we just put ether in her
oxygen and do what we have to do.
She'll sue.
For what?
Making it harder for her
to lie to the government?
We don't need to hide them.
We give her elective
cosmetic surgery.
The incisions will give
us access to her lungs.
And she's got an innocent
explanation for the scars.
You mean, like, liposuction.
No, no. Those incisions
are too far from the lungs.
We don't subtract. We add.
Turn her Bs into Cs.
It's myth that fake hooters blow
up at high altitude. She'll be fine.
Just think of it as one
giant rack for mankind.
I fought for years
to be taken seriously.
Trust me, you'll be taken more
seriously. Just sign the form.
This'll make me a joke.
There's gotta be another way.
I've known a few
people who had dreams.
One thing they all had in
common was they got laughed at
and they didn't care.
You bumped a
splenectomy for a boob job?
Would you condemn
this woman to a life
where people look at her
face when they talk to her?
If you don't explain this,
I'll cancel the surgery.
Can I explain why you're here?
I think I just told you why I...
I scheduled a diagnostic patient
for a boob job. Which is ridiculous.
So, obviously you
had to confront me.
With you so far.
But I'm gonna give you a reason.
Not a good one.
No. Not even
close to a good one.
But here's the drag
from your point of view.
My explanation will make sense.
Not to the board, not
to a judge, but to you.
So you'll let me do it.
Then, you're gonna have to sit next
to me at the administrative hearing.
Don't you have
better things to do?
It's in the best
interests of the patient.
Trocar's in, you're good to go.
Deflate the lung.
There, a cyst.
Cysts, I count three of them.
Probably the same, if
not more, on the left lung.
Okay, so what's been working
overtime to kill Miss Bin Laden?
We know her name now.
Yeah, but I forgot it.
Say the magic word and get
immunity from the next challenge.
Alveolar hydatid disease.
Hits all the organs.
She'd have had
multiple seizures by now.
Pulmonary Langerhans'.
Doesn't explain
the red blood cells.
Come on!
Cysts, synesthesia, heart
attack. You guys have gotta...
Von Hippel-Lindau syndrome.
Raises red blood cell count,
causes masses on the organs.
If one of the masses is
a pheochromocytoma,
it could cause neurologic
episodes and a heart attack.
Do you see a blonde guy who still
has peach fuzz standing up there?
Yeah.
This is a closed procedure.
Gallery's off limits.
Not to the surgical staff.
Are you gonna hire
that guy instead of us?
Not a chance. I love you guys.
Please dig out the cysts, histology
to confirm Von Hippel-Lindau.
Don't forget her chesticles.
Calling Arizona was
a very nice touch.
You do have residual...
Not only do I not
have residual feelings,
I didn't even have
primary feelings.
You freaked... You lied!
Because you knew it meant...
It meant nothing!
I saw him 'cause he was there.
Did Cameron follow her bashert
to the surgery department?
I think Chase followed her.
She's been a senior attending
in the ER the last three weeks.
A blonde senior
attending, to be accurate.
And Foreman, is he
back in neurology?
He's at New York Mercy.
He's been there a month.
Did you see Foreman?
No.
Doctor Chang to OR.
So, I'm cured.
You're fine for now, but Von
Hippel-Lindau is a genetic disease.
There's no cure.
Greta, you need to
come clean to NASA.
You said you got all the cysts.
They could re-emerge.
I'll go to radiology clinics.
I'll get regular screenings.
If something happened
while you're up there,
you'd be playing
Russian Roulette
- with other people's...
- Relax.
She doesn't have to
tell, and neither do you.
Turns out the NASA doctors even know
where the hyphen in Von Hippel-Lindau goes.
You called them?
I'm not an idiot.
Those shuttles fly
over New Jersey.
So, here we are. The big moment!
Which of you gets to live
to be abused another day?
And which of you goes home and rationalizes
being fired as character building?
The following numbers,
thanks for playing.
21, 19, 8, 34,
17,
29, 5,
36, 2.
The rest of you, 8 a.m. sharp.
I'll be in sometime
between 10:00 and 3:00.
Oh, and 26, stick
around a while.
I did nothing wrong.
Lots of people
did nothing wrong.
Other people screwed
up, I never even...
Other people took chances.
26?
Buddy Ebsen actually
was allergic to...
Yeah, I know. How old are you?
21.
You don't think it's relevant.
I'll likely have less time to
use the skills you teach us,
but I don't think that's
significant to you.
How about the fact that you
never went to medical school?
Which is why you let the
unlucky number do the trans echo.
At least you're
ethically unethical.
30 years I worked in the Columbia
med school admissions office.
Audited all the classes,
most of them, more than once.
I just never got a diploma.
You had to know I'd
find out sooner or later.
I know you break rules.
I thought maybe
you'd break one for me.
I can't hire you as a doctor.
But you can still tell
me what you think.
You could also fetch me coffee
and pick up my dry cleaning.
Until I can decide
whether or not to keep you.
So, I'm playing this whole
game to be, like, your secretary?
Assistant sounds
marginally less demeaning.
It's not my dream job.
Actually, it is. It's just
not your dream title.
Three weeks.
For someone who never misses
something small, you missed something big.
You're an idiot.
The hair, where
I'm working, or both?
The hair makes you
look like a hooker.
I like it.
Pulling pieces of windshield
out of car accident victims,
and reattaching fingertips
sliced off cutting bagels?
At least Chase's move
is only one step down.
I can do good here.
Get it out of my system.
Why'd you rat your
patient out to NASA?
I don't know who's been gossiping
about ethics instead of sex,
but I hope they've
already been fired.
Which number was it? Greta.
Number. No number, the patient.
How do you think she
got your pager number?
She came into the
ER, didn't want to talk...
I didn't rat her out.
You lied?
I suppose I should tell her
that before she keys my car.
Why lie?
I had to stop
some leaky faucets.
What did it matter?
It was no one's business.
Right.
She's gonna be the
safest astronaut up there.
Certainly more vigilant than the
guy next to her who's got no clue
about the aneurysm in
his head ready to pop.
Right.
You got a better reason?
You couldn't kill her dream.