Dean Archer, my senior
medical officer in the Navy.
Why don't you shadow me to
get the lay of the land?
It's an ED, I think
I know the lay.
There is one thing
I need to be clear about.
In this ED, I'm in charge.
The trial needs a chance to
prove the drug can work.
I can help you start sorting
through those files.
Thanks, April.
Wouldn't it be great
if the boys could
grow up together?
They wanna adopt Auggie.
See how happy
he was today?
It's okay, baby.
He should be with his brother.
Auggie's gone, huh?
Mm-hmm.
Took off with the Carters
this morning.
I'm heading over to
the Med thrift shop to donate
the stuff he left behind.
Must be hard right now.
Mm, he's with his brother.
He's safe, he's happy.
When Ben and I took him in,
that's all we wanted for him.
And you'll stay in contact?
Yeah, we're talking about
heading out to California
to see him this summer.
It'll be here
before you know it.
Yeah.
Morning, Dr. Manning.
Good morning, Dr. Marcel.
How's your mom recuperating?
Any problems with the LVAD?
She's feeling great.
Yes?
She wanted me to
express her gratitude.
Oh, well, you know,
I hear it's important
to impress the mom
when squiring the daughter.
I so wanna make out
with you right now.
Oh.
But not here.
Perhaps another time
then, milady.
Hey, Will. Do you have
any updates on
the clinical trial?
I have some
free time now.
Well, last few days I've just
been combing through data.
Kind of a one-person job.
Maybe I can search
the recent patient files,
see if any of them
are good candidates?
Sure. That'd be great.
Ramona Davis, 30 years old.
BP, 122 over 80. HR, 115.
SATS, 100%.
Ramona, what happened?
My foot, it's excruciating.
Dispatch told us
she called 911 after
shooting herself in the foot
with a nail gun.
How'd you get that gash
on your head?
She was passed out
when we found her.
Yeah, 'cause it
hurts like hell.
Okay, well, we're gonna
take good care of ya,
and then give you
something for the pain.
One, two, three.
Thanks, guys.
Okay. Breath
sounds bilaterally.
Ramona, can you move your head
up and down, side to side?
Good. C-spine's clear.
Let's get a head CT
on the books.
Wait a minute,
where where am I?
You're at the hospital,
Ramona. You had an accident.
No, no, no, which...
Which hospital?
Chicago Med.
I was supposed
to go to East Mercy.
Don't worry. We're gonna
take good care of you here.
Need to get that shoe off
to get an X-ray.
No, don't, don't. Don't.
Ramona, we're just trying to
figure out the best way to get
this all...
No, I said don't touch it!
No doctor at Chicago Med
is treating me!
Okay, ma'am, please.
No.
All right.
No!
I need restraints.
It's okay, it's okay,
settle down.
I was nailing down
some lattice!
I thought I was aiming
the nail gun at the ground.
I shot myself.
It was stupid.
Can I... Can I go now?
Yeah, but you you told us
that you fell and
you hit your head.
To knock yourself out,
you gotta assume that's gonna
be a pretty serious bump.
But I'm sure they can
figure it out at East Mercy.
So, you wanna go to East Mercy
because you think that
you're gonna get better
treatment there?
Yeah, they don't tie you
to your bed.
Huh.
Well, look, if you think
that you can
calm down a little bit,
I don't see why
we can't take those off.
How does that sound?
Okay.
Great. Great.
Can you send me
to East Mercy now?
Ramona, we are required
to make sure you're stable
before we transfer you.
There is a nail in my foot.
It is not going to kill me.
No, but let us do
a CT, okay?
Make sure there's no serious
injury from your fall,
and then we'll send you
on your way.
If that's what
it takes, okay. Okay.
I'll let radiology know.
But no one touches the nail.
Yeah. You're welcome.
Thank you.
Hey, care for a cup?
They poured me
an extra one by mistake.
Thanks, but I'm trying
to kick caffeine.
Oh, more for me then.
Scheduling, huh?
Yeah.
More 12-hour shifts.
I liked to stick to
eight hour shifts back
when I was running Milbrook.
Keeps the troops fresh.
Yeah, we tried that.
But I found this
is better for patient care.
Less handovers.
Well, sure as long as you
don't burn your team out
in the process.
Well...
Huh?
Specifically, if they're
not drinking caffeine.
Hey, I've been meaning
to ask you. How are you
adjusting so far?
It's a good fit.
And, uh, you and me?
I'm good. I'm good
with the chain of command.
Dr. Choi? I could use
another set of eyes.
I just sent you the deets.
Yeah, sure.
We should grab a drink
after work, hm?
Aye, aye, Captain.
Is that right?
Yeah.
Mr. and Mrs. Campos?
Hi, I'm Dr. Choi.
Louisa, please.
And this is Hector.
I hear you're having some
trouble breathing.
Patient's reported
a fever that spikes up
and down erratically,
a sustained period
of shortness of breath.
Looks like your ears
are swollen. Does it hurt
when I touch it?
It's pretty itchy too.
Yeah? Okay.
Can you tell me when
was the first time
you started feeling sick?
About three days ago.
He works at a meat-packing
plant out in Cicero.
They've had a bunch of
COVID outbreaks in the past.
I was worried that
there might be another.
I'm just... I'm so relieved
that that test
came out negative.
It's a good start.
We're supposed to see
our granddaughter
in two weeks.
She's turning one.
We still haven't met her
due to social distancing.
Sure.
His lungs sound congested.
How are his sats?
89 and trending lower.
All right. Let's up him to
high-flow cannula.
Okay.
What do you think
this might be?
Hard to say. Perhaps
some kind of pneumonia.
But let's grab a chest X-ray
and a CT to rule out PE.
Also, a CBC, BMP, blood
and urine cultures as well.
Roger.
We'll figure out
what's causing this, okay?
Excuse me.
Thank you.
This here is a subdural
hematoma with mass effect.
So what?
Ramona, you have a bleed
in your brain from
where you hit your head.
Not gonna stop on its own.
It requires a craniotomy.
It's a pretty
significant surgery.
We had a deal.
I get the scan that
you wanted, you let me go
to the hospital of my choice.
If you don't treat this soon,
you will die.
So let me go treat it.
Ramona, could you give us
a second? Dr. Halstead.
Okay. What is with her
and East Mercy?
I have no idea, but I think
we gotta let her go.
Wait, what? This bleed in her
brain is a ticking time bomb.
Which is why we have to
do it right now.
Right, she's clearly not
gonna change her mind.
So, the sooner we
get her over there,
the sooner she gets
the treatment she needs.
All right, I'll arrange
the transfer.
I'll set up the ambo
and forward her scans
over to East Mercy.
Natalie?
Darby!
Hi! I haven't seen you
in, like, forever.
Yeah.
It's been over
a year now.
Wow. Our kids go
to preschool together.
Oh.
How's Owen been doing?
He's driving his
grandmother crazy.
How's Sebastian?
Driving me crazy.
I forgot you worked here.
I would have
asked to see you.
You're in good hands
with Dr. Archer here.
If you don't mind me asking,
what brought you in today?
A pain you would not believe.
Like someone's stabbing me
with a harpoon.
Well, I don't see
anything here that's acute,
but I would like to send you
to get a CT scan
if you don't mind.
That should give us
a clearer picture.
Sure. CT away.
Okay.
Hopefully we can get
the kids together soon.
Yeah.
See ya.
Hey, Dean?
About that ultrasound.
Mm-hmm?
So, I'm not trying to step
on any toes here,
and maybe you didn't want
to say anything in front
of the patient,
but I was seeing some swelling
around the gallbladder.
Well, perhaps but the
bile duct was still
normal-size in character.
There's no evidence
of stones or fluid
around the gallbladder
and only a mild amount
of thickening.
But the gallbladder wall was
inflamed. And it's not normal.
And it could still be
causing her symptoms.
Why don't we wait for the CT
scan before jumping to any
conclusions, okay?
Um, excuse me?
Where can I put this
for donation?
Leave it on the counter.
Okay.
Thanks.
Um, this baby blanket.
How much is it?
Five dollars.
Oh, too much.
Here. And I'll keep this.
I've changed my mind.
Okay.
Hi. I couldn't help
but overhear over there.
It's big for a baby blanket,
but it's teddy bear-soft.
How much is it?
I'm on a tight budget.
No, it's a gift.
You mean it?
Yeah. Please.
Thank you so much.
My pleasure. I'm Maggie,
by the way.
Tionne.
Is this your first?
Mm-hmm.
You have kids?
I... Tionne...
You're bleeding.
Oh, my God.
I got you. I'm a nurse over at
Med around the corner.
Get me an ambulance, please.
I can't afford
a fancy hospital
like Chicago Med.
It won't be an issue,
I promise you. Just hold
on to me, okay?
We'll figure it out.
Tionne stopped hemorrhaging
once we arrived.
How are you feeling otherwise?
Fine, till today.
This will pinch.
All right, Tionne, I wanna
give you an exam.
But first, I wanna do an
ultrasound to see where
your placenta is.
Did your doctor tell you
your placenta's low?
No, I don't got a doctor.
I have no insurance.
All right, I'm gonna press
this down on your belly
and take a look, okay?
All right.
Well, let's look.
Okay. Well, your placenta
is covering your cervix.
Tionne, it's probably what
caused the bleeding.
Is the baby okay?
It appears so, yes. But I'm
gonna take a look inside now
and see what's going on. Okay?
Okay.
Thank you.
Tionne, you're bleeding
heavily again.
We need to get you
to the operating room.
The operating room?
Yes, you need surgery
to deliver your baby.
Cut me open?
It's what's best
for your baby.
Okay?
Tionne, is there
anyone that we can call?
Someone that should be
here with you right now?
My mom's taking care of
my grandma downstate.
She can't get here
till tomorrow.
Can Maggie come with?
So someone's there for
the baby while I'm asleep?
You're gonna be fine, Tionne.
Okay.
This picture
is showing some
bilateral infiltrates.
I'm confused.
Does he have pneumonia or not?
Certainly not full-blown
pneumonia at this point, no.
Do you see the tips of
his fingers and toes?
How blue they're getting?
The scans show he has a lot
of inflammation in his body.
It could be affecting his
circulation.
If I don't make it through
this, give my cross
to the baby.
Hector. Don't talk like that.
Yeah, okay.
Let's up his oxygen,
get a mask on him.
Hey, Hector.
If I had to guess, you've got
some kind of infection.
So, we're gonna start you
on some broad
spectrum antibiotics,
see what effect they have.
And in the meantime,
we'll take a closer look
at your blood,
try to get our arms around
what's going on. Okay?
It's okay, go on.
Something's not
adding up, Dr. Choi.
His symptoms say
pneumonia for sure.
But he's not producing
a steady cough and his
white count's totally normal.
And then there's
that crazy ear thing.
Sorry to be a buttinski,
but I love a tricky diagnosis.
Do you mind if I take a look?
Sure.
Thanks.
You think maybe
it's an HIV-related syndrome?
Let's test to
definitively rule it out.
Also, scan his legs, see if
there's any signs of a DVT.
Well, you'd have seen them on
the scan if it was a pulmonary
embolism, no?
No, I think young Driskell
here is on to something.
His inflammation of
the ear cartilage, yeah?
Dr. Choi thinks it's most
likely a rash or a reaction
to the infection.
Or it could be the key
to this whole thing.
You know, they say if you hear
hoofbeats, think horses.
But if I were you,
Dr. Driskell, I'd be
on the lookout for zebras.
Maybe sarcoidosis,
or peripheral vasculitis.
I'm gonna hold off
on that, Dean.
Give the antibiotics
a chance to take effect.
Occam's Razor and all.
I want to check off
all the boxes before
we go hunting for zebras.
That's certainly
a viable strategy as well.
Dr. Archer?
CT just sent over the scans
you requested
for Treatment-Four.
Thank you.
Uh-huh.
And I apologize
if I overstepped.
Okay, could you
hold on, please?
Dr. Charles, wait.
I am on the line with East
Mercy. There's a problem.
I'm not treating her.
Ramona Davis has been
trouble for a long time.
Frequent flier?
Yes.
Every two, three weeks
for the past year.
She shows up,
insists that only I treat her.
She's obsessed with me.
Last week she came in,
she claimed she'd lost
feeling in her hands,
but it was clear she was
making it up.
And was this the first time
it seemed like she was
faking symptoms?
The first time I called
her on it. She flipped out.
Accused me of malpractice,
threatened to sue me,
the hospital.
It got pretty intense.
You know, that might explain
why she showed up
with a nail in her foot.
I mean, if she had actually
made it over to you today,
there's no way you could say
she was making that up.
Excuse me, Dr. Bridges.
Look, I've gotta run.
I hope Ramona gets the help
she needs, but I can't be
the one to give it to her.
Completely get it. Thank you
for your time, Doctor.
I'll cancel the ambo.
So, if you're right and she
injured herself with the nail,
then you can put her
on a psych hold.
But even on a hold,
she could still
refuse surgery.
Yeah, she still has
decisional capacity. Right?
Okay, but we gotta
convince her to stay
and have the surgery.
Her life is at stake.
Dean? Darby says you're
discharging her?
I wrote her a script for
extra-strength PEPCID.
See how she fares.
You mind if I take
a look at the CT?
See. Nothing here
tells a different story
than the ultrasound.
It still seems to me that
the gallbladder's infected.
Well, I disagree, and I'm
just trying to spare
the patient an operation.
Well, what if it's
an operation that she needs?
Maybe a second opinion from
a surgeon is warranted?
Well, I also happen to be
a board-certified
surgeon myself.
But thanks very much for your
input, Dr. Manning.
Excuse me.
Thank you.
What doctor refuses
to treat a patient?
My dad was a doctor,
and he went out of his way to
help anyone who needed it no
matter what.
You know, I can't speak
for your father,
but I know plenty of doctors
who decide not to engage
with patients,
you know, for
a number of reasons.
Like what?
Well, for instance, let's say
if a doctor feels that
there's a lack of boundaries.
Boundaries? Between
Dr. Bridges and me?
Listen, Dr. Bridges made
it very clear to me,
it's important to him
that you get the
medical care that you need.
He did?
Yeah.
Well, I...
I do know that doctors won't
operate on their loved ones.
That's right.
It's considered
an ethical issue
if a doctor is too close
to their patient.
Of course. Dr. Bridges
has feelings for me.
It all makes sense now.
In any case, how about
we get you the surgery?
Okay.
Great.
Is there anybody
that you would
like me to call, or...
But could you
call Dr. Bridges,
and let him know that
I'm getting the operation?
I'll be happy to do
that for ya. Oh, and
how about
I tell the surgeons
to take that nail
out of your foot,
while they're at it?
What do you say?
Okay.
Great. Okay.
I'll be back in a bit.
Ultrasound for Mr. Campos
came up clean. There's
no evidence of DVT.
Dr. Choi!
My Hector can't breathe!
Sats in the 70s.
Please.
Heart rate's dropping too.
BP 97 over 68.
Hector! He's not
protecting his airway.
We need to intubate.
20 of etomidate, 100 of sux.
He was all right a minute ago.
Oh, my God.
Please don't let him die!
Why is this happening?
Baby's not coming,
I need to extend
my hysterotomy.
When I say now, Maggie,
give me fundal pressure.
Got it.
Now.
All right, see.
There we go.
Suction.
All righty.
Okay, buddy.
I got him.
Here we go.
There.
Heart rate is 140.
And get ready to rotate.
Huh.
Is that a dimple?
Unfortunately, yes.
So, your gallbladder
appears to be inflamed
and I suggest we remove it.
Better safe than sorry.
Now, it's a relatively
simple procedure.
I'll go in with an
itty bitty little scope
and just slide it
right out of there.
You'll barely
notice the scars.
And this pain will go away?
Possibly, if the gallbladder
is the issue.
Which I believe it is.
Okay, then. I'm here
already so...
Let's do it.
Okay.
We'll get you upstairs
in a jiff. All right?
Thank you.
You bet.
Doc...
Have them set up for a
laparoscopic cholecystectomy
pronto, would you?
Yeah.
Great.
Boy, boy, boy. You two
must be pretty pleased
with yourselves, aren't you?
Excuse me?
Yeah.
The only way a patient can get
a second opinion in the ED
is to ask for
a doctor by name.
So?
So Darby's never even been
a patient here in Med.
There's no way she'd know who
you were. Unless somebody
slipped her your name.
Dean, I understand
you're upset. Okay? No one
likes to be disagreed with.
You went behind my back.
Regardless of how this played
out, Dean, I'm involved now
and I happen to agree with
Dr. Manning's diagnosis.
Okay. You also happen
to be in cahoots.
I'm sorry. Cahoots?
You guys are
having an intimate
relationship, right?
Aren't you?
We are professional
colleagues. And that is
all that should concern you.
This morning, I saw
the way you two were
looking at each other.
Okay, forget that guy.
Mm-hmm.
You okay?
Yeah.
All right, I'm gonna
head upstairs.
You page me if you need me.
Okay.
Just forwarded you
a new patient chart
from Sunday.
Stage two heart failure,
might be a good
candidate for the trial.
All right. Let me take a look.
Sabeena. Nice to see you.
I have a meeting upstairs.
Can I borrow you for a moment?
Sure. Be right back.
Good news. We're closing
enrollment on the trial.
Turns out you're such
an effective recruiter,
we have more than enough data
to work with moving forward.
Well, that is good news.
Kender's CEO
asked if you golf.
I do not golf. But give me
a week and I'll figure it out.
I expect nothing
less from you.
This patient I sent you
might be perfect.
Dr. Virani just told me
we're closing admissions.
So you can stop
looking for candidates,
but refer that one to
cardiology. Thanks anyway.
Bone marrow biopsy
came back negative.
We CAT scanned his brain,
abdomen and pelvis.
All totally normal.
No evidence of malignancy.
Maybe we should be looking for
autoimmune issues.
Perhaps, but his
ANA is normal.
You can't rule out
an autoimmune
disorder entirely,
but a tissue biopsy suggests
it's not sarcoidosis.
So, in other words
we still don't know anything?
You might wanna get
Infectious Disease on this.
Thanks, Doc.
Ethan, if you don't mind,
I've been giving your
case some thought,
and based on the
symptoms that your
patient's been exhibiting,
I think he may have some rare
auto-inflammatory syndrome...
It's called VEXAS.
VEXAS? Never heard of that.
Yeah, it's a genetic mutation.
They've only diagnosed,
like, 25 cases.
Symptoms include
blood clots, fevers,
inflammation of the cartilage
and lung tissue.
It would certainly
explain the crazy
constellation of symptoms,
but I'm still not
looking for zebras yet.
You know what,
I'm sorry for getting
in your face over this.
But I just don't wanna
be doing to you what
was done to me.
What are you talking about?
Uh... Some doctor sticking
his neck in, questioning
the care I'm giving.
Who?
I was just double doc'd by
Manning and Marcel.
They sent my patient
up to surgery against
my medical advice.
Okay.
Yeah. And they're
secretly dating,
which frankly raises
ethical concerns.
I didn't know. But, plenty
of doctors have
dated in the past.
I admit I have myself.
It's never really been
an issue before.
Well, but you can see
how it would be, right?
Let's say they made
a mistake with this patient,
it could make them susceptible
to a malpractice suit.
And you gotta believe that the
hospital would want cover over
something like that.
I hear you, Dean,
but honestly,
I've got bigger issues
to deal with at the moment.
Well, it's your ship.
Here he is!
I'm Dr. Watkins, Tionne.
Meet your baby boy.
Oh, my God.
He's so beautiful.
Yes, he is.
I can't believe he's mine.
When can I take him home?
I want to keep him under
observation for a few weeks,
on account of how
early he was.
You should also know that
he has a birth defect.
Spina bifida occulta.
What does that mean?
His vertebrae didn't
fully form in utero.
There are small gaps
in between the bones
of his spine.
Is he going to live?
Oh, yes. I know it sounds bad,
but I've seen many babies
born with spina bifida
who grow up to be just fine.
How did it happen?
It could've been
a number of things.
Your genetics.
Something about the
environment you were
living in during pregnancy.
Your nutrition.
Something I ate?
Well, more like an
insufficient amount
of folic acid.
That's a nutrient that's found
in vitamin B rich foods.
How was I supposed to know?
Most women don't.
They find out
from their doctor.
I can't believe it.
I hurt my baby.
No. I promise you, Tionne.
I'm so sorry.
Please forgive me.
How're you feeling?
I'm fine. I don't see
what the big deal was.
Did you talk to Dr. Bridges?
You know, I did. We were
able to have a nice
long talk this time.
And, you know, he told me
about your dad.
I was so sorry to hear that
he passed away last year.
What did he say about me?
Well, really, we mostly talked
about your dad.
You know, and how rough
that must've been on you.
I mean, I know how hard it was
on me when my dad died.
Yeah.
It was terrible.
He...
He was a wonderful man.
Yeah. And, you know,
Dr. Bridges said that
he was actually
the one who tried to save him.
Right? And that's how
you met him?
I really don't wanna
talk about this.
Where's my stuff? I wanna
call Dr. Bridges,
let him know I'm okay.
I totally get that it
makes you uncomfortable
to talk about Dr. Bridges and
your dad, really I do...
Okay. Okay. I see where
you're going with this.
My father and Dr. Bridges have
nothing to do with each other.
Dr. Bridges cares for me.
So much so that he
wouldn't even treat me.
You said so yourself.
Well, no, you actually
said that. I just confirmed
that it would have been
an ethical issue if
Dr. Bridges
had feelings for you.
But wait, are you
saying, Ramona,
that you don't feel like
your father cared for you?
I want to talk to
Dr. Bridges right now.
Ramona, I'm so sorry. But...
Dr. Bridges doesn't
wanna talk to you.
But you said that he wanted me
to get the care that I need.
He does. Because he's
your doctor. But
that's all that he is.
Ramona, I'm really
worried about you.
And particularly, the
circumstances surrounding
your injuries.
Right? And which is why, I
wanna hold you here at
the hospital for a few days,
because, well, frankly, I'm
concerned that you're a danger
to yourself.
My injuries? You've seen
the nail in my foot.
You think I put it
there on purpose?
This is outrageous. Get me
that walker in the corner.
Listen, I can understand why
you're upset, really, I can.
But there's something
important going on here.
And we're gonna have to talk
about it, sooner or later.
If you won't get it, I will.
No, Ramona. Ramona,
you need to stay in bed.
Ramona! Ramona!
I will sue you!
I will sue this hospital!
Walter!
You stop!
One second.
Ramona. Get back into bed.
No, stop! No.
Miss?
Soft restraints, please.
No, let go of me. Let go
of me! You can't do this!
No, let go of me!
Okay.
Stop! Please!
Two of Ativan.
No!
Hey, Nat.
Hey.
So, you and Crockett?
Dean told you.
Yeah.
All right, look.
He was about to send
a patient home with a
severely infected gallbladder.
Okay? We wouldn't have
known about it, had
I not sent Crockett in.
It was the right thing to do.
Sure.
But being right about the
medicine doesn't excuse
the way you went about things.
Fine. It won't happen again.
And listen, if you and
Crockett are seeing
each other outside of work,
then you'll need to go
to HR and declare
that that's the case.
What? Oh, come on.
Did you declare your
relationship with April to HR?
No, we didn't, and we
probably should've.
But, April and I were
never in a position to
double doc anybody.
But HR? Really, Ethan?
I'm just trying to protect
you and the hospital
from any legal recourse.
Okay? So, please,
take it seriously.
Oh, my God.
Tionne Marie Jefferson?
Perfect, thank you.
You're welcome.
Madeline.
Are you here to see
Tionne Jefferson?
She put in a request
with the charge nurse.
Why? Is she giving
her baby over to DCFS?
Maggie, you know I can't
reveal those details.
I am so annoyed with
him right now.
With Ethan or Archer?
Both, I guess.
But, mostly Ethan.
You don't want to go to HR?
It's a violation
of our privacy, Crockett.
Yeah, okay. Then forget it.
Well, Ethan's not just
gonna let this go. So...
Right. Okay.
So we go to HR. No big deal.
Right?
I mean, unless you have
reservations.
No.
It's just the whole
going public of it all.
You know, I can just hear what
people are gonna say. It's...
Oh. So that's
what this is about.
You're worried about
what other people think?
No.
But you do have reservations.
Okay. Your call, Nat.
I'm gonna get out
of these scrubs.
Ethan.
I checked in with the lab,
saw your patient's bone marrow
samples there for testing,
so, I asked the tech to go
ahead and take a look
at those myeloid cells.
See if your patient
has VEXAS after all.
Hector's not your patient.
But see, I thought you
said that it wasn't
such a big deal
about Manning
and Marcel before, so...
I didn't think it was
an issue that they
were in a relationship.
Not that it's okay to
start running tests
on other doctors' patients.
It's a little hard knowing
which rules to follow when
some of them aren't enforced.
You're being disingenuous.
You're right. Anyway,
I'm just letting you know,
you might hear something
about this VEXAS.
Dr. Charles. There you are.
I was just on my
way to see you.
Ramona. Shouldn't
you be in bed?
I slipped my restraints.
I really needed to
talk to you. I have
a confession to make.
Okay.
You were right. I did shoot
myself with a nail gun to see
Dr. Bridges.
Uh-huh.
There's something
wrong with me.
I know that now.
Well, you know, sometimes
being honest with yourself,
that can be very freeing.
It's just a lot, you know,
to lose your dad.
And it's so helpful to find
people who know
what that feels like.
Right, like Dr. Bridges?
No. No, I was
talking about you.
I am so lucky to have met you.
You don't need to be
nervous around me.
I am very comfortable
around you.
And I'm pretty sure that
you are going to be the
best doctor I've ever had.
Ms. Davis, there you are.
Hi, Ms. Davis.
You gave us quite a scare.
Let's go back upstairs.
Yeah.
Really good idea for you
to get some rest now,
okay, Ramona?
I will make sure
that I look in on you
tomorrow, okay?
Good night.
Goodbye, Dr. Charles.
I really can't wait.
Okay. There.
I saw that DCFS was here.
You thinking about...
Giving your baby up
for adoption?
I don't deserve him.
Tionne, there's no evidence
that you're responsible
for your baby's birth defect.
But I could've been.
I made so many
mistakes in my life.
What if I mess up again?
What if I can't take
care of him right?
You can. You're not alone.
You got family.
And there's support groups for
new moms in your situation.
I can put you in touch.
I been planning,
I can get him what he needs.
But maybe what he really needs
is a better mother.
I gave my baby
up for adoption.
I was 16.
It seemed like the right thing
to do at the time.
But there was this voice
in the back of my head that...
That told me not to do it.
And I ignored it.
And that voice, now,
is all that I hear.
You love that little boy.
I can see it.
And I think that's
all that matters.
All I'm saying is that...
Make sure that whatever
decision you make,
you don't end up living
a life of regret.
Hey, Dean.
You were right. Genetic
sequencing found that
mutation. It's VEXAS.
Hot damn.
I've already
started treatment.
Just, amazing catch, man.
Thanks. Thank you. And...
Again, sorry for overstepping.
No, no need.
All right.
Maggie. I heard you
came back today.
Is everything okay?
It is now.
I'm thinking about
reconnecting with my daughter.
Wow. Is that even
a possibility?
Mm-hmm.
There's a program
affiliated with DCFS that
helps birth parents track down
the children they
put up for adoption.
I spoke to Madeline Gastern
and it may take a while,
but I might be able
to make it happen.
Sharon?
Well, that's a big
move to make.
Are you sure about this?
There's a wound in my heart
that won't heal.
And Auggie leaving
has only made it worse.
I have to do something.
I understand. But it's been
over 20 years.
That child is a
grown woman now.
All the more reason to do it.
She and I can finally have
all of our questions answered.
But, have you considered
maybe she hasn't been
asking those questions?
Look, I'm not saying
don't do it.
Just be prepared, Maggie.
She may not want to reconnect.
Crockett.
Yup.
Hey. You headed home?
Hey.
Yup.
Here.
A consensual
relationship declaration?
What, are you, gonna start
a bonfire or something?
Look. Everything I said
earlier was coming
from a place of fear.
Okay? I don't have
reservations about us.
And the last thing I wanna do
is break things off. So...
Hm.
You want to know how I feel?
Of course.
You got a pen?
Yes.
Can you turn around?
Okay.
You are too much.
You know, people
are gonna talk.
So let 'em.