Previously on
"Grey's Anatomy"...
What if it wasn't
ridiculous? What?
What if you try to
cure Alzheimer's?
Should I anticipate any goodbye
e-mails from you? I don't know.
Tessa's like Seattle royalty.
Man, I grew up on her stories.
I do have
another story to tell.
"Tessa and the Rising Sun."
I'm sorry. I can't.
You don't consider
me part of your life.
Of course you're
part of my life.
You took the Boston job
without even talking to me.
I love cardio. But
I love you more.
Guess I'm not sure
that I respect that.
♪ I'm up, I'm here,
I'm out the door ♪
One of the greatest
frustrations surgeons have
are the unrealistic
expectations of our patients.
Whoa.
♪ Don't you wanna go with me
Whoa!
Whoa! Whoa!
No!
No. No, no, no!
Whether they're acutely ill or
they've been sick for years...
No, no, no, no, no.
No, no.
Oh, my God. No.
By the time they're
on the surgical table,
they're hoping for a miracle.
Thanks for the ride. Get out.
I'm late. So am I.
But often, surgery is just
the beginning of the healing,
rather than an end.
Because for weeks
or months post-op,
people have to learn how to live
without the part of their
body we've just removed.
- You're late.
- Not as late as you.
And that's not always easy
and it's never painless.
So, surgery is not
the happily ever after
our patients hope it will be.
Like everything else in
life, it's an evolution.
Now, remember what
I said to you.
You're going to take these gifts
and go visit your
old daycare teachers.
They're gonna be very
excited to see you.
Do you remember
where you're going?
Mom, I'm not a baby. Same, Mom.
Okay.
Hey!
Look who's here!
Hi. Big last day.
Yeah, we're trying to forget
all that and act like everything
is super normal.
How are we doing?
Not great.
- How's the new place?
- It is great.
It is weird to live alone
when I don't have Scout,
but I feel very grown up.
Do you have any surgeries
I can watch today? Zola...
I might have a
very excellent one
with Uncle Winston in O.R. two,
if your mom says it's okay.
Mom, please?
Okay, if anyone asks, I
don't know where you are.
Link! Hi. Hey.
Do you, uh... Do you have a busy
schedule today? Actually, no.
I've carved out my whole
day to catch up on charting.
I am buried in... I need you
to pick up a cake by noon.
This bakery's across
town. It's for Meredith.
Does she like faraway cake?
It's her favorite.
It's the triple berry
with the buttercream.
I would do it myself,
but the baby that I delivered
two weeks ago with
the malformed heart,
he's having heart surgery today,
and his parents are very
attached to me, and...
And... and you love
me, so please help.
That is true.
I do love you. Thank you.
You're all rounding with
Doctors Ndugu and Pierce.
They are breaking
new surgical ground,
and it is a privilege
that they have invited...
Sorry. My car broke down.
Had to get a ride
with my sister.
Yeah, my car got towed
and it's also my house.
Do you know who else
wasn't punctual?
Taryn Helm wasn't punctual,
despite being an
excellent surgeon,
and now you can find her
throwing her life away
bartending across the street.
There's a surgeon
bartending at Joe's?
Why?
Because she burnt
out, that's why.
So, hydrate and sleep
and lean on your friends,
and take a break and
get a good therapist.
And be on time,
unless you want to
wind up like Helm,
wasting your talents,
your family's investment,
and your futures.
Does she know you're throwing
shade behind her back?
Dr. Joseph to L&D.
Dr. Earl Joseph to L&D.
Meadow, Will.
Um, we're a teaching hospital,
and these are our first years.
Is it okay if they stay?
You can say no.
Uh, i-it should be okay.
Baby?
Dr. Kwan.
Arlo Fischer, delivered by
Dr. Wilson two weeks ago,
and diagnosed with truncus
arteriosus and VSD.
He's been listed for a
transplant for heart failure,
and he was placed
on ECMO a week ago.
Arlo's deterioration is
sending him into organ failure.
We got a call from UNOS last
night that there is a match,
but the procurement
team reported
that the donor
heart muscle is weak
and not suitable
for transplantation.
But Dr. Pierce
and I believe
that we can still
make use of the heart
if we transplant only
the two major arteries.
So, it's a partial
heart transplant?
Has that ever been done before?
No, this will be the first.
I don't understand.
Why can't we just
wait on another heart?
Meadow, it could take months
to find another match.
Arlo cannot stay on
ECMO for that long.
Baby, she's saying partial
is better than nothing.
We know this is frightening,
but if this works,
these valves will grow with
him for the rest of his life,
and he won't need
a heart transplant
or any other
additional surgeries.
Ifthis works. What
if it doesn't work?
He dies? My baby dies?
We're gonna give you some
time to think about it.
We really do
believe that this is
Arlo's best option
at this point.
I can stay.
Yes, Of course.
Thank you, Doctor.Yeah.
Come in.
Hey. Hi.
Heard it's your
last day. It is.
Thanks for coming.
I went by the house.
It's nice to see
it's still standing.
There's a giant hole where
the attic used to be.
They've spent the last two
weeks stabilizing the place,
but everything still
reeks of smoke.
It's... How are the kids?
Zola's excited to start
at her new school.
I think Bailey and
Ellis are sad to leave.
I called, you know?
I know.
This has been a lot.
A fire, living in
a hotel, moving.
No, I know it's been a lot,
but what... what was your plan?
You were just gonna leave
and not call me back?
And you're gonna move
across the country
without a conversation?
I-I-I-I don't get
that. I don't.
I didn't know what to say.
I moved here to be with you.
Yes, I took a job,
but I moved here
to be with you.
You didn't say it back.
I didn't say what back?
You s...
What?
I said, "I love you."
You were standing
exactly in that spot
where you are right now.
I said, "I love you."
You didn't say it back.
You had just taken a
job at my hospital.
I thought... I had hoped
that we were gonna pick it up
right where we left off.
But you seemed to
want to take it slow.
So, it did not occur to me
to confer with you
about me moving.
Okay, so wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait, whoa.
This... So, this is on me?
This whole thing, it's my fault?
That is not what I just said.
I-I didn't do and say
exactly what you thought
I should do and say on
exactly your timeline,
so this whole mess is my fault.
That's what you're saying?
That is not what I said.
No, no. Nope.
I can't.
So essentially, we will
take out the truncus
and the malformed artery,
replace it with the donor
aorta and pulmonary trunk,
and then use their
walls to close the VSD.
So it's like gutting
the inside of a house
without disturbing the frames.
Can you not use the word
"gutting" when talking
about a tiny baby heart?
Mm, cosign.
I don't like the verbiage, but
it is a pretty apt metaphor.
Do we get to scrub in?
There will only be room for
one of you at the table.
We are operating on a heart
the size of a strawberry.
The vessels are half
a centimeter wide.
My hands are the smallest!
You will not be stitching.
You will be observing.
But whoever does the
best vascular anastomosis
in the skills lab wins the spot.
Dr. Kwan.
Yeah?
Uh, don't do your
finger agility exercises
in front of the
patients, alright?
Oh, it's a technique
I use to disengage
from the emotionality.
To stay neutral.
Y-You know, when...
When the mother
started crying, I was...
It's smart. You just can't
let them see it, Kwan.
Understood.
Richard!
Just curious how it's going.
The search for the new chief.
It was easy a few years ago
when we were at the
top of our game. Right.
But we've got a lot of
interesting applicants
we're sorting through, yeah.
I mean, Grey-Sloan
is not an easy place
just to step right
into.
It's got its own history,
its... its own quirks,
its own personality.
Well, that it
does.
Yeah. I mean, it... it wouldn't
be the... the worst idea
to look closer to home.
Someone who's been here,
who... who understands
our history,
the issues, and... and
our past and our needs.
Altman, I think
you're onto something.
T-There's no extra pay involved,
but there's lots
of free pastries
and we could use your expertise.
I-I'm sorry, there's
no extra pay?
No, the search
committee is voluntary.
But we'd love to have you.
We're meeting in the second
floor conference room
from 4:00 to 6:00 on Monday.
Okay, got it. Thank you.
I will...
join. Great.
Yeah. Thank you.
Okay.
Meadow, I got a page.
Is everything okay?
I can't do it.
I-I can't kiss him goodbye
for what might be forever.
She wants to wait.
W-We want to wait
for a whole heart.
An infant donor heart
could take up to six months
to find a match.
But we got this one.
This one was a match
and it came in days.
But it was damaged. I know.
But we could get another match
in the next couple of days.
It could happen.
I know that it's hard, and
I know that it's scary,
but Dr. Pierce is
as good as it gets
and she is not a risk taker.
She doesn't do
experimental surgeries
for practice or for glory.
She is suggesting this
because she believes
that she can save Arlo's life.
I don't know how to
love my son this much
and send him in for an
experimental surgery
that might kill him.
I-I can't do it.
If he
dies in that surgery,
I won't ever be okay again.
Tell Dr. Pierce
thank you, but no.
The surgery is off.
Ow! Damn it.
You know what?
Screw this.
What? Should I go
after her? - Shh.
Some of us are trying to win.
I hate this stitch.
Oh, you have to kinda twirl
your wrist like, um...
Here.
Right.
Yeah.
Oh, no. It's Tessa Hobbes.
Who?
I have no idea.
Done.
Tessa. What happened?
I'm so sorry.
She came in with
severe abdominal pain.
She's a bit hypotensive.
Take her to CT.
I-I picked up my groceries.
Tessa, we said no heavy
lifting, three months.
It was just a grocery bag,
and I was feeling so great.
And then there was
this sharp pain,
like something tore.
And then she drove herself here.
Wh... You drove yourself?
Well, in retrospect, I can see
that might have been a bad idea.
Tessa, which area hurts exactly?
All of it. The
entire abdomen hurts.
Here... touch right there.
Ow! She's tachycardic.
We should take her
straight to the O.R.
No, her blood
pressure's holding.
Get her to CT first
and then call the O.R.
to be on standby.
Skip the line.
I'll call ahead.
I really think we
should just take her
straight to the O.R.Go!
I'll call Marsh.
Someone page Chief Grey!
Are you Dr. Hellum?
Who's asking?
Mika Yasuda, first
year surgical resident.
It's Helm, and I'm
no longer a doctor.
Cool, 'cause I'm barely a doctor
and I'm desperate for a win.
Could you possibly teach me
how to do a perfect
microvascular anastomosis?
There's a contest and if
I win I get to scrub in
on a partial heart
transplant on a newborn.
A partial heart
transplant doesn't exist.
I know, but it is about
to, and I-I need this.
I need a win because I, uh...
I don't have anywhere
to sleep tonight,
and Seattle is
outrageously expensive,
and being a surgical
resident is exhausting...
to the point
of nearly impossible,
and I just really need to give
myself a reason to keep caring.
And if Blue wins, I
cannot take the gloating.
Blue? Like the ribbon.
And this is a nickname
he perpetuates.
Wow. That is arrogant.
Right?
20 bucks.
My house was towed this morning,
so I don't have 20 bucks.
But if I win this contest,
I will barback for you
on Friday night for free.
You've been a barback?
No, but I've been a cater waiter
and I'm excellent
at chopping limes.
Give me it.
♪ I love you far
♪ You know I'm never right
I was treating myself to
champagne and fruit salad
because that's
what I was craving,
and I had plenty to celebrate.
Now, okay, wait, wait.
And then
the groceries came.
They left them on
the front stoop.
It didn't even o-occur to me
not to bend over
and pick them up.
It's routine.
It's muscle memory.
Dr. Griffith, the ring
around your necklace...
Are you engaged?
I-I was. I was engaged.
Now I'm not.
Heartbreak is the worst.
It is.
If I die today, I might
even miss heartbreak.
Please try not to die today.
Yeah, I'll do my best.
Oh, wait. I need my purse.
Right now? Yes, where is it?
Uh, it's downstairs
with your clothes.
I can get it after
we're done here.
Okay.
Hey, what happened?
Schmitt said her abdomen is
distended and she's tachy.
She's getting more hypotensive.
Okay, well, you two
need to go book an O.R.
I don't care if you have to
kick someone out to do it.
Tessa takes priority.
I don't get it.
She did this for groceries?
Well, I don't think she
did it on purpose, Nick.
I think she probably lives
alone and is set in her ways,
and I'm sure it's a lot for
her to change and ask for help.
Hello?
We're here, Tessa.
Please stay very still.
I'm afraid. This is all wrong.
I-I don't want to die.
I still have something to say.
Tessa, you're not
going anywhere today.
We've got you.
She's bleeding out.
We're gonna need
some help in here.
blood in the O.R.
Tessa, we're gonna
take you upstairs.
So on a scale
of one to better?
We're better. I think.
I think we're better.
But you're not sure?
I am sure that we
are both excited
about this partial heart
transplant on an infant,
which is a stroke-of-genius idea
that we came up with together.
And that is because in the
O.R., we're good together.
In our chosen field of
study, we are so good.
Are you rehearsing
a speech you plan on
giving him later?
Maybe a little.
So the two of you haven't
really spoken since the fire.
Oh, we said some things.
We needed a cooling-off period.
It's best that we
haven't talked about it.
A-And, you know,
we'll talk again soon.
As soon as we change
medical history.
I have bad news.
Oh, no. The baby?
No, he's stable.
But his mom's too scared.
She wants to call it off.
I can't talk her into it.
That would be unethical.
But you think she's
got this one wrong?
Without this surgery, the
baby has days to live.
She had a 30-hour labor and
she did it without any meds.
Meaning? She's a warrior.
She's strong in her convictions,
and she seems sure
of what she wants.
Let me talk to her.
You can't.
I'm not her doctor.
Let me talk to her.
You're a neurosurgeon,
so do you think Arlo needs...
No, no, no. No.
No, I'm not here as
one of Arlo's doctors.
I'm sorry, but if you're here
to try to talk me into...
I'm here because I had a baby
who only lived for 43 minutes.
He had a condition
called anencephaly,
which is when the baby's brain
does not develop typically,
and, uh, we discovered it
when I was 6 months pregnant.
We didn't know.
We didn't know until he was born
that there was anything wrong.
I gave birth to Christopher
knowing that he would
be an organ donor,
uh, because there was
nothing that we could do.
There was no surgery
that we could try.
And, um, I think about
him a lot these days
because he has a brother
now, named Scout,
and as Scout grows up,
I cannot help but think about
who Christopher would have been.
And, um...
what I do know is
if there had been a chance
that Christopher
could have lived,
if there had been any hope,
if there had been any surgery
and it meant that
he might live...
I would take the shot.
I knew it.
I knew we should have taken
her straight to the O.R.
We needed the CT to see
if we could operate...
My gut doesn't lie.
And I should have fought for it.
We should have brought
her straight here.
Yeah, I'm number one.
Ew, someone likes himself.
No, my sample is
literally number one.
But yes, I intend to win.
What is that face?
Is that good?
It is if you want
to go home early.
I knew I shouldn't have
practiced on bananas.
What about fruit says
"baby veins" to you?
This is all good work.
Number one's sutures are
particularly precise.
But with perfect
alignment and tension,
the winner is number three.
That's me!
Guess we gotta call
you Red today, huh?
Hm.
Scalpel.
I thought you would win.
Your stitches are
typically excellent.
I know.
Better than Yasuda's.
I tanked the contest
because babies scare the
crap out of me.
Didn't want to be
anywhere near that table.
Why are you scared of babies?
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
You gotta tell me. Come on.
Okay, but you owe me one.
Owe you what?
Whatever I decide.
Fine.
When I was 5, my dad
took me into the backyard
where my mom had just
given birth to my brother
in a kiddie pool.
Now, you've done an OB rotation.
You're acquainted with
all the blood and placenta
and the literal horror movie
that is human child birth.
And I'm sure it's all very
beautiful in its own way,
but I was 5.
And before I could fully
process what I was seeing,
my dad handed me
a pair of scissors
and told me to cut
the umbilical cord.
Wait, you were 5?
Yeah.
What, you think this is funny?
This is trauma.
This is... This
is crystal-loving,
weed-smoking, latter-day
hippie-style trauma.
Shh!
Sorry to shush you, but my aunt
is making history right now,
and I think we should
all be paying attention.
♪ I've had my heart
get swallowed ♪
♪ And dragged
down to the deep ♪
♪ But I made it to tomorrow
♪ So I believe
♪ After all these
years of trying ♪
♪ Weighing on
these tired bones ♪
♪ If there's something
I'll take with me ♪
Starting compressions.
♪ Let it be hope
Come on, Tessa.
♪ Yeah, let it be hope
♪ Yeah, let it be
♪ Let it be hope
♪ Let it be
Come on, Tessa. Fight.
Mer.
Meredith, let
Griffith take over.
♪ After all these
years of trying ♪
♪ Weighing on
these tired bones ♪
♪ If there's something
I'll take with me ♪
♪ Mm-mmm
♪ Let it be hope
♪ Yeah, let it be hope
♪ Yeah, let it be
♪ Let it be hope
♪ Yeah, let it be hope
Griffith,
it's time to stop.
♪ Let it be hope
Oh, God.
Oh, my God. No.
♪ Let it be hope
Time of death 12:21.
Chief Grey, I'd like
to close her up.
I'd like to pay
her that respect.
Can I help? Yeah.
That was so incredibly stupid.
That did not have
to end that way.
I hate this day.
I hate everything
about this day.
Me, too.
I-I'm a... I-I'm a
transplant surgeon.
I-I wait. I'm trained to wait.
I attach, I perfuse, I
wait for the organ to take.
For it not to be rejected.
For it to pink up.
For blood to flow.
Because that's how
humans respond.
They're not machines
with an on/off switch.
And I'm a grown
woman with a big life
and a big career and three kids.
And this move is what
my daughter needs.
I want you in my life if
you want to be in my life.
But if I have to choose,
I'm going to pick me.
I pick my kids, and I
pick what's best for us.
And I am not going to
beg you to love me.
I'm sorry I was
emotional earlier.
Be sorry when you stop
feeling the losses.
This was my last surgery here.
I thought for sure I
was going out on a high.
I know that sounds shallow.
No, it's devastating,
on every level.
How's your grandmother?
Awful. It's awful.
She exclusively calls me
by my mother's name now,
which I can handle. I
didn't know my mother.
But my sister, she
remembers my mother,
she remembers that I killed her.
She was 6 when it
happened and...
she's never forgiven me for it.
And every time my
grandmother calls me
by my mother's name,
she hates me more,
and I don't know why I'm
telling you this, Chief Grey.
Well, because you know I know.
And I don't work here anymore,
so you can call me Meredith.
I have Tessa's book, Meredith.
What? She wrote her last book.
She saved it on a thumb drive,
and she brought it
here to the hospital,
which means after
she felt her pain,
the first thing she did
is go to her computer
and save her book.
She wanted me to give it
to her publisher in Boston,
and, um, I know you're...
You're going there today.
♪ Your color's fading
♪ 'Cause I kept you waiting
♪ It's a wild, wild world
I'm so happy she got to
write her last story.
♪ And you're a
wild, wild girl ♪
Chief Grey? Meredith?
♪ Our sun's still shining
♪ But it seems half
the size I'm sorry.
♪ And it's a wild, wild world
My mentor once told me you worry
when you stop
feeling the losses.
♪ Before my time runs out
[ Sighs ] Let's go inside.
♪ What if I run away to Mars?
♪ Would you find
me in the stars? ♪
The heart is completely
pumping on its own.
♪ Would you miss
me in the end? ♪
It worked?
So far, yeah. So
far, it worked, yeah.
♪ If I run out of oxygen
♪ When I run away
Amelia, thank you.
♪ To Mars
Echo looks great.
VSD is closed.
Outflow from the new
arteries looks good.
It sure feels like we
saved that baby's life.
Are you taking in the miracle?
That is exactly what I'm doing.
That was beyond my
wildest imagination
of what my day would be.
And not just this
day, which was awful
because my house-van got towed
with my whole life in it.
That was beyond my
wildest imagination
of what any day of
my life could be.
The way that you saved
that tiny baby heart.
I will never forget it.
Did you say house-van?
Yeah, you sleep in a van?
Oh, well, I can't afford
to get it out of impound,
so not tonight.
Anyway, thank you.
♪ Would you find
me in the stars? ♪
Aunt Amy, how did you do it?
How did I do what?
How did you stop caring
what other people think?
My mom, your sisters, they
talk about you like...
Like... like you don't
give a flying crap
what anybody else thinks
and, like, they're a
little jealous of that.
And I want to know
how you did it.
Because I wanted to fight
for a patient today.
My gut told me everything
she needed and I didn't do it
because I was worried about
what other people would think.
I-I was worried about
getting in trouble.
You want to know the truth?
The truth is I care deeply
what other people think.
And then I do what I
think is right anyway.
But I learned that the hard way.
I had to live a lot of life
before I became
the kind of person
I like and respect.
My patient died today.
I should have fought.
The good news is...
you let that pain soak in...
next time, you will fight.
Did you ever find a
place to live, Shep?
Uh, yeah, I found a youth
hostel with a roach problem.
And please don't call me Shep.
Then don't call me Aunt Amy.
Is that it?
Straight from the oven
from the faraway bakery.
You are truly, madly,
deeply the best.
Wow, it's so much bigger
than I thought it would be.
I know. It barely
fit in my car.
Wait, what do you mean bigger?
Did you check it?
I gave them your name,
they gave me a cake.
Well, there's no
time to take it back.
What do we do?
Oh, hey.
Oh.
Top of my class. What?
I was top of my class at an
East Coast boarding school
where my classmates were
doing designer drugs
and cheating their way
to a passing grade.
I was top of my class.
And I didn't even
drink in high school.
Well, this is sparkling cider.
Then I was second in
my class in undergrad,
but that's because I had
a brutal case of mono
my junior year, which
took me out for weeks,
but in med school, I was
back up to number one.
And I completed my
cardiothoracic fellowship
at the Mayo Clinic
before coming here
and training Cristina
Yang as a heart surgeon.
I have an inarguable pedigree
and I find it insulting
that you invite me to sit
on a panel to choose a chief
without stopping to consider
offering me the job.
Teddy, this hospital just
came out of a shutdown.
Dr. Bailey and Dr. Grey
both quit the job
that you're talking about,
and their pedigree is
quite similar to yours.
I didn't consider
you for the job
because it is a flailing program
with a huge amount of stress.
But by all means,
if you want it,
it's yours.
Really? Is that a yes?
Can I think about it?
What is going on here?
Oh, crap. She's
here. Surprise!
Surprise!
Aw, Come on, people. You
can do better than this.
Okay, ready?
Surprise!
Well, this is very thoughtful.
And ridiculous because
I'm only going to Boston,
and you know I'll probably
be here next week.
For God's sake, Grey, will
you just let us toast you?
To Meredith Grey!
♪ Been swimming
through shadows ♪
You know, once upon a time...
♪ Moonrise
you were the bane
of my existence.
But, no, you grew up to become
one of my greatest
points of pride.
I'm...
♪ We keep run, run,
running from the cold ♪
To... Wa...
♪ Keep my eyes wide open
Okay, go. Go.
Dr. Grey, what Dr. Bailey
is trying to say is...
this place won't be
the same without you.
♪ On my, my way
♪ Oh, you gotta keep
on feeding that fire ♪
♪ Oh, you gotta keep on
dancing through the night ♪
♪ Hey, let it fall
To Meredith Grey.
Hey. Hear, hear.
♪ Hey
Mom. Yes?
It was amazing. Was it?
Aunt Maggie was amazing.
Of course she's amazing.
I think I might want to change
from neuro to cardio.
Will you be mad?
I will absolutely not be mad.
Did you talk to Nick? I did.
We have a plane to catch.
Should we go?
♪ Chasing the light
Dr. Marsh.
Helm.
Hey.
What are you doing behind a bar?
Living my best life.
What are you doing atthe bar?
Uh, yeah, well, it was
a bit of a rough day,
so I decided to call it early.
Actually, can I have a
whiskey rocks, please?
Thank you. I don't get it.
Isn't Dr. Grey leaving today?
Isn't her party,
like, right now?
Yeah. Oh, my God.
You are such an idiot.
Wow.
I don't
work there anymore,
so I'm just gonna
tell you the truth
instead of pretending to respect
your awful decision making.
She's Meredith Grey.
She's impossible,
and she's perfect,
and she's brilliant,
and she cares.
And she can be mean sometimes,
but only when she needs to be,
and she can be selfish sometimes
because she has
earned that right.
And for some stupid
reason she's into men
so she never fell
in love with me,
but she fell in love with you.
And you're here?
How stupid are you?
He's still going strong.
I am in awe.
It really is a miracle.
Yes. Yeah.
It is... It's a miracle
of science, Winston.
Specifically, it's a miracle
of cardiothoracic surgery.
We did a thing that no
one else has done today,
and... and we saved
that baby's life.
And if it worked
like I think it did,
this miracle of science
is going to save
thousands of babies'
lives.
That has to make you see
that you can't just change
your field of study at
this stage of your career.
You told me that you
didn't respect my choice...
You said you didn't respect me.
I didn't say that. And
then there was a fire.
You know, it was a lot.
I gave you time, and
I gave you space,
but for two weeks
now, I've been waiting
for an apology that hasn't come.
And now you're doubling down?
You're... There's
no apology coming
because you meant what you said?
I think you'll reconsider...
Yeah, changing my job
to protect my marriage.
It's not a job.
It's nota job.
It is a gift.
Alright.
And just like that
the feeling is mutual.
What feeling?
You told Kwan that his
strategy to disengage
emotionally from his
patients was smart.
What feeling?
All this time, I don't... I
don't know how I missed it.
Winston, what feeling?
The disrespect.
You're cold.
And I don't respect it.
Bailey, w-w-where's Meredith?
She's one of a kind.
That's what I was trying to
say. She's one of a kind.
A firecracker.
Yeah. Any words at all, really.
Look, she's, uh, on
her way to the airport.
But look, there's
cake if you need some.
You look like you need some.
Well, fine. More for me.
This is the final
boarding call for Flight 623.
Any remaining passengers,
please proceed to the
gate at this time.
♪ Hold steady
♪ This heaviness
♪ Will break
Come on, come on, come on.
♪ Through the ground
♪ Take cover
♪ What's underneath
Oh, come on.
Oh, my God.
♪ Will find a way out
Alright.
Zola, you can sit here.
Guys, we're gonna sit here.
Go right in there.
♪ Living in the lost
I'm never
gonna make it.
♪ Falling through the motions
like a sinking stone ♪
Okay.
♪ Living in the lost
♪ Seeking out the silence,
but you're never alone ♪
♪ Living in the lost
Who wants to read the new
Tessa book?
Oh, Zola, I know these are
a little young for you,
but this is the last one ever.
That's the book?
Yes,
I got an advanced copy.
Hold on, guys.
Hi. We're on the plane.
I love you.
I fell in love with you
the first day I met you.
the second day I met you.
And I have loved you
every minute of every day
that I have known you.
Meredith?
Um, I...
I can't quite hear
you. Meredith?
We're about to take off,
so I'll call you
when we get settled.
Meredith...
Meredi...
"I've flown rockets
and slayed dragons,
I've saved lives and
I've had my life saved.
I've been through broken
bones and a broken home
and the death of people I
love, but I'm still here."
"I never chose the
safety of what was known
when there was the possibility
of more to be discovered."
Hey.
Could I stay at
your place tonight?
"I've had adventures that
most people only dream about."
♪ Nocturnal
"And I've had losses that
I still dream about."
♪ When the days and the
nights blend into one ♪
"And if there's one
thing I've learned
in all my adventures, it's
that there's no such thing
as a life lived
happily ever after.
Unless the happily means
simply that we're still alive.
That the sun is
rising on another day.
Because with every sunrise
comes the possibility
of happiness
and also the possibility
of heartache."
Uh, what
are you doing here?
Grey gave me a key.
She said there's a
hole in the attic,
but if I don't mind overseeing
the repairs, I can stay here.
"And sometimes it's all
rolled up together."
Yeah, my Aunt Amelia
told me the same thing.
"I came to understand
as a very young child
that when the
imagination is limitless,
life's possibilities
are endless."
When I got kicked
out of my residency,
it also ended my relationship.
Had my dream job, was
planning my dream life,
and then I didn't, and I wasn't.
"But I learned
that the hard way."
It's not that I
don't feel things.
It's that I don't want to put
you through any kind of rebound.
♪ Keep reaching and seeing if
I can just break my way out ♪
I-I mean,
I could be down for a rebound.
Did you
really just say that?
Um, okay, w-what I'm saying is,
you know, as long as
we call it what it is,
then no harm, no foul, right?
Apparently we live together
so that's a really, uh...
terrible idea.
Yeah.
♪ Oh
♪ Nocturnal
"I learned it through
yearning and frustration
and ache and longing
and sometimes desperation
for a life different
than the one I was living."
♪ Turned purple
♪ All the air that I
had gone from my lungs ♪
♪ Eyes are closing,
head spinning round ♪
"I learned to stretch
my imagination
and spread my wings,
and to allow for all the
options life had to offer."
♪ Oh
"Not only the ones I
could see with my eyes.
I stretch for the ones I
could feel with my heart."
♪ Lost or found,
who am I now? ♪
Wow.
This is amazing.
♪ Before I hit the ground
♪ Who am I now?
What are you doing here?
Uh, Dr. Pierce gave me a key.
She said I could stay
if I fix up the
hole in the attic.
Same. Same.
"As long as the sun
rises on your life..."
Then I guess we should
have brought sleeping bags.
"there will be new
dragons to slay."
So, who wants pizza?
"So the end of my story is
not any kind of ever after.
Because I'm still alive.
I'm still here.
And the sun still
rises on my life."
♪ Break my way out
♪ Oh
Captions by VITAC...