Most people believe
that who they are today
is pretty much who they
will still be in the future.
Hi!
How was your flight?
Ah, it was fine.
Thanks, Meredith.
I mean, Maggie.
Maggie. Sorry.
Someone didn't sleep
on the plane.
Oh, I couldn't.
I've rewritten my talk
at least 20 times.
Meredith is so sorry
she can't be here.
Babysitter got the flu.
Oh. Well, I'm glad
you're here.
Our minds trick us into
thinking our entire history,
every choice,
every change and chance,
has led to this specific
moment...
What we call "Now."
You seem good. Chipper.
Ah, I put my blood, sweat,
and tears into this PATH pen.
I can't wait to
share it with the world.
Mm.
You're... You're jumping too far
on the last one.
I don't need your help.
♪ It's a new day ♪
♪ Whoo-ooh-ooh ♪
Come on!
No, wait your turn!
Yeah, cut it out, lads.
Come on. Don't make me
regret bringing you. Let's go.
Just missed it.
Come on, guys.
So close.
Liam, look after your brother,
please, will you?
Seriously, Dad?
Come on.
Dr. Hayes.
I really hope I wasn't
supposed to bring my kids.
No, their, uh, their
aunt lives down here.
- So...
- Oh.
..it's a chance for them
to see family.
Well, I am heading
to something called
Heart Valve Happy Hour.
Want to join?
Is it as dire
as it sounds?
Worse, somehow.
But free booze.
Maybe I'll see you there.
Great.
♪ That tomorrow
will be brighter ♪
"It is a curiosity that has
driven humankind
since the discovery of fire..."
No. No.
Oh.
"...since the harnessing
of fire... "
No.
Yeah. Okay.
"...since the taming of fire."
Yes!
Oh, no turn down service needed.
Thank you!
Richard. It's me.
Aren't you going
to invite me in?
I'm not sure I believe
you're really here.
You here to buy
the convention center?
Stop me from presenting?
I'm here to stop
the foolishness!
Richard, you said
you wanted an apology.
Well, I am sorry.
I am so sorry.
Truly, for everything.
I regret my behavior.
Thank you.
You don't have anything
to say back to me?
There's nothing between
Gemma and me.
Mm-hmm.
I know what I saw.
Well, something...
almost happened.
W-We went to breakfast,
and she kissed me.
Oh, Richard!
But I stopped her.
But you didn't tell me.
I... I didn't,
and I'm sorry.
Oh, Richard,
we can fix this.
You know we can.
There are things in this world
you can't control, Catherine.
And I'm one of them.
I don't want
to control you.
You bought my hospital,
for God's sakes!
Because of your temper!
Worst investment
I ever made.
It's just
hemorrhaging money.
The foundation board thinks
it's a sign of my dementia.
I look like a fool.
No, stop.
I'm serious.
Oh, me too.
This is funny.
This is not funny!
You had a fight with
your husband
and purchased an entire
hospital to get back at him.
Pac-North has
my name on it!
My name!
I mean, the worst place
I ever worked in my life!
Oh, dear Lord.
Do you think
there's a couple
who ever had
such an expensive fight?
No.
Well, maybe
Anthony and Cleopatra.
Ah.
Come here and kiss me,
Cleopatra.
Ohh.
- Mm.
- Mm!
- Mm! Mm! Mm!
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 16  Episode 19
Episode Title: "Love of My Life"
Aired on: March 26, 2020
Sync corrections by srjanapala
Hey. How are you?
Hi! Welcome to
Heart Valve Happy Hour!
Oh. Wow. Yes.
Thank you.
Uh, best party
of the year.
Hey! Teddy!
Oh, my God!
You always see people you know
at these things,
but they're never
people you like.
- Aww.
- Here. I ordered one for you.
Ooh. Thank you.
Wow. They really splurged
for the reusable straws.
- I'm so glad you made it.
- Mm.
Evelyn rescued me.
She's with Allison
while Owen's at work.
You know, and for the first time
that I can remember,
no one
in a 50-mile radius
depends on my breasts
for survival.
Mm. Cheers.
Yes. Thank you!
I know these things
are kinda lame,
but I kind of
enjoy them.
'Cause it's like
summer camp.
For people who like
to cut into other people.
I never
went to summer camp,
but this is what I imagine that
the Olympic Village is like.
Yeah.
Assembling the greatest
talents in the world,
putting them
in one building.
Professional by day, but
screwing each other by night?
Y-Yeah, I meant the "gathering
of the best of the best" part.
Is that what
the Olympic Village is like?
Totally.
Oh, my God.
What?
Wow.
I mean, he's...
Do you know him?
Yeah.
Uh, no, no.
I mean, not really.
We... Uh... Sort of.
He was one of
my residents at Tufts.
I-I doubt
he even remembers me.
God, he is so hot!
Am I blushing?
Maggie Pierce.
Olympic Village.
Find out if he's single
and get yours.
No, I don't do that.
You don't have sex?
I don't have sex
with strangers.
You just said
you know him.
Also...
he's behind you.
What? No. No.
- Mm-hmm.
- Maggie Pierce.
Hi...
..you.
You don't remember me,
do you?
She remembers you.
Eh, no. Yeah.
Dr. Winston Ndugu.
We worked together at Tufts.
- We did.
- Yeah.
You know, I just remembered
my key isn't working,
so I-I'm gonna
go get a new one.
Three years
I've been coming here,
and this is the first time
I've seen you.
What... are you
stalking me?
Not stalking you.
But... seeking?
Yes.
I'm gonna be a little forward now.
Is that okay?
Mm-hmm.
I have had a crush on you
since my first day of residency.
But you were my chief,
even though I'm older than you,
which just made me
crush harder.
So, I bided my time.
But then you went
and moved away to Seattle,
right before I became
an attending,
and I never got my shot
to ask you out.
But I see that somehow
you aren't wearing
a wedding ring.
So, hopefully,
I still have a shot.
Which is just
my long way of saying
I'd like to
buy you a drink.
♪ I'm gonna live it
like I own it ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Big city, bright lights ♪
♪ Yeah, I like it ♪
♪ Can't wait to see
where it goes ♪
♪ Ain't nobody
gonna kill my vibe ♪
♪ I'm gonna live it
like I own it ♪
♪ Ain't nobody
gonna kill my vibe ♪
♪ I'm on fire ♪
♪ I'm gonna live it
like I own it ♪
Okay, we only have 36 more hours
to get to know each other,
so I'mma do
a lightning round, alright?
Don't think. Just answer.
You ready?
Ready.
Favorite snack food?
Pretzels.
Wow.
Failed your first question.
How can I fail at naming
my favorite thing?
Because pretzels are
only the favorite snack food
of prisoners who haven't
had snacks in years
and don't remember what snacks
are supposed to taste like.
Okay. Well, I don't fail tests,
so give me another one.
Favorite movie.
"Amélie."
Why?
Because it's about
hope and resilience.
Perfect day off.
Okay, sunrise run.
Spend the morning
at a museum,
the afternoon in a park,
evening cocktails
by a body of water.
A nice dinner,
and then...
ice cream while
walking through the city.
Bed early, with a book.
So, your perfect night
is a romantic comedy.
Okay.
No, I didn't say who
I was doing all of that with.
Well, who are you
doing all that with?
Me.
So, you like
being alone?
I do.
To a point.
Favorite movie.
"Ghostbusters."
Perfect day off.
Wake up...
well after sunrise.
Roll over to
the beautiful heart surgeon
in bed beside me.
Do that thing to her
that makes her lower back arch.
Okay.
No more lightning round.
Who is your favorite person
in the whole world?
My mom.
She was my protector.
She was
this fierce mama lion.
She didn't let anyone
mess with me.
Including my dad.
She died...
..about two years ago.
Ovarian cancer.
Oh, my God.
Yeah.
It happened really fast.
My mom died
two years ago.
Breast cancer.
No, actually, it was
three years ago.
God.
I can't believe
it's been that long.
There's nothing worse
than watching
the woman who protected you
from the world
get sicker and sicker
and you not be able
to fix her.
Okay, so...
do you do this?
Do you have
med conference flings?
I can't say that I've never
hooked up at one of these.
But I've never done this.
What's this?
Falling this hard
in one night.
Me neither.
These conferences
are all the same.
Yep. Just
a sea of desperation.
Sales reps trying
to unload their equipment
before it becomes
obsolete.
Or banned.
Wow. Really sounds
like your scene.
If you hate it so much,
why'd you come?
Well, I'm the new guy.
And Bailey asked me
to come represent peds.
Didn't seem like an invitation
I should turn down.
The boys get to see
their aunt, so...
Which is your sister or...
- Sister-in-law.
- Mm.
Evening, doctors.
Dane Pinetti.
I'm with Wilkes and Boon.
Teddy Altman.
Grey-Sloan. In Seattle.
You look like a man
in need of something.
Do I?
And what might that be?
Hmm.
Not quite sure what
to make of this.
Well, you, uh...
you click the little part
at the back,
and you write
with the front.
Mm.
It's called a pen.
Courtesy of Thrivea,
who make erectile
dysfunction medication.
They do?
You don't even know
what your own company makes?
My friend said
a company at a convention
was paying 500 bucks,
and all I had to do
was hand out pens and smile.
That might not sound
like much to a doctor,
but to a starving artist,
that's rent.
Oh. No wonder no guys
want these pens.
What kind of artist?
Apart from starving?
Mixed media.
A lot of multiple exposures
and instant film transfers.
Mm.
That doesn't make any sense
to you, does it?
No, the individual
words do...
Just not when you
put them together.
So, what are you
drinking?
I'd like to.
But these are not gonna
hand themselves out.
Well...
I go through
a lot of pens.
So, how about that drink?
Watching the debates...
They said just
a couple more minutes.
Okay.
This is happening.
Are you sure they don't need
a few more, like, years?
Babe, this is...
A hysterectomy
on a 33-year-old.
They're removing
an important part of me.
And if you say
"Not a big deal,"
I am going to kill you...
In front of our sons...
And it will
be your fault.
I was gonna say "routine,"
but...
The surgeon we found...
She's done more of these
than I can even count.
She's minimally invasive,
fast recovery time,
low post-op
complications.
You're in amazing hands.
She's great, really.
Or I'll bleed out
or she'll cut into my bladder
or I'll get a horrible
infection and die.
Well, in that case,
me and the boys will move on.
Don't get me wrong...
It'll be a tough couple of days.
Then single women will start
showing up with casseroles.
I mean, I won't even have to
try. They'll feel so bad for me.
- Ohh.
- I mean... surgeon.
Sexy widower.
Single dad.
I mean, I'll be... I'll be
batting them away, honestly.
Uh-huh. Right.
I hate you.
I love you.
Mrs. Douglas at school
had skin cancer,
and she's fine now.
That's
a different cancer.
Oh.
But that's really nice
to hear, honey.
Hey, could you boys
go find Mommy a ginger ale?
- It'll make me feel better.
- Okay.
Mrs. Douglas is the one
who accused him of
writing swear words
on his desk.
She's a monster.
I need you
to listen to me.
The nurse should be
here by now.
If this doesn't work...
It has to work.
It's the second
clinical trial we've tried.
We're at the end of this.
I'm not gonna be okay.
I've seen people bounce back
from far worse than this.
It is likely that you're gonna
be doing this alone soon,
so I need you to listen.
No.
I'm not.
Make sure the boys know
it's okay to cry.
To feel it.
To feel everything.
I don't want them
locking this up
and letting it
eat away at them.
Don't be strong.
Be a mess.
Let them know that
it's okay to fall apart.
Please don't do this.
And promise me that you're gonna
let the boys see my sister.
♪ ...glory, Lord ♪
I know she's crazy,
but she's not a bad person.
And she loves them.
And whenever you have
trouble with them,
just call your mother.
You are proof
that she knows
what she's doing.
And it's okay
if Austin quits piano.
Yeah.
I told him that he'll get better
if he keeps practicing,
but... I think
it's hopeless.
And... And... And keep an eye
on Liam's temper.
'Cause I think
he gets it from me.
And we've both seen
the mess that can cause.
♪ And it feels like glory... ♪
And it's okay for you
to fall in love again.
You have my permission.
I don't want that.
Which is why you need
to hear me say that it is okay.
You don't need to
beat yourself up or feel guilty.
♪ There'll be oceans
to wonder for miles ♪
You deserve to be happy.
♪ There'll be flowers
and roses so ♪
Bright side, you won't
have to work for it.
Sexy widower,
surgeon, single dad.
You'll be
batting them away.
♪ Let them notice ♪
♪ It's in your heart now ♪
♪ And it feels like ♪
♪ Let them notice ♪
♪ It's in your heart now ♪
♪ And it feels like glory,
Lord ♪
Okay, lads.
That's everything.
Can we stay?
A little longer?
That's creepy.
Oh, no, Austin. Here.
It's okay.
We can stay
as long as you want.
I want Mama.
Me too.
Come here.
Mm.
Did you order these?
Guilty.
Do you always sell this hard
to everyone here?
Well, not everyone here
works for Catherine Fox's
flagship hospital.
Maybe you should
take up your business with her.
You know how hard it is to get
face time with that woman?
Mm.
Listen, this is a really
exciting opportunity.
Wilkes and Boon is
looking to expand R&D
beyond our laboratories.
We want to partner with
the right hospital
and develop side by side
with you.
That actually
could be something...
I know all about
your devices.
I know about
the c-30 power morcellator.
Do you know about
that one, Dane?
Of course. It's our most
popular model on the market.
I bet you'll say
it's magic.
What is it?
It allows for minimally
invasive hysterectomies.
Its little spinning claws
chop up fibroids,
make them disappear.
But there's a problem.
This fibroid...
isn't a fibroid.
It's cancer.
But there's no way
of knowing that before you cut.
And along comes
your morcellator, and...
What... the hell, man?
What started out
as nicely contained,
easily removable
has now spread
countless cancer cells
all throughout
the patient's body.
Cancer that metastasizes
and grows and can't be stopped.
Less than 1% of benign fibroids
turn into uterine sarcomas.
My wife was
one of those 1%.
Her name was Abigail.
Your device took her.
It took the mother
of my sons.
And you still sell
the thing,
even though you know
it can kill,
and you pay
to suppress the proof.
So, no.
I don't want your drink.
And you're lucky
I haven't already put that pen
through your throat.
O-Okay.
Apologies, Dr. Altman.
♪ Lazy days, dreaming
in the midday sun ♪
♪ Miles away, you're thinking
about the things I've done ♪
Teddy?
♪ Time to hit the road again ♪
..been
a second explosion, uh,
here in Manhattan
at... at the Trade Center.
We are getting reports
that a part of the tower...
T-the second tower,
the one a bit further
to the south of us...
Has collapsed.
We... We are checking on that.
But obviously, people were,
uh, already at work here
at the Trade Center
when this happened.
We... We don't know how many
people have been hurt...
Claire?
Uh...
- Hey!
- Hi.
Uh, may I?
Oh, yeah. Please.
Um, of course.
Hi.
Uh, whiskey, please,
and another glass of wine
for this one.
How are you?
I'm... I'm good.
It's so good to see you.
Yeah, you too.
I can't believe
we haven't run into each other
at one of these things
before.
Oh, yeah,
I've been practicing in Germany
for the past couple years.
That's exciting.
I'm in North Carolina now.
Which is fine.
Clara and I...
That's my wife.
We are Claire and Clara.
I know.
We have a small practice
in, uh, her hometown.
Wow. I never thought
you'd leave New York.
Neither did I.
But, you know,
after 9/11, I...
there was just
too much grief there.
In the marrow
of that place.
Mm.
I never saw you again
after she died.
Where did you go?
Afghanistan.
You enlisted?
I know. It's crazy
when I think about it now.
You were practically
a socialist when I met you.
I can't argue that
or totally explain it.
I mean, the closest
I've come
to making any sense of it
is that I-I...
I wanted to support
the soldiers
who were trying to get
the people that killed Allison,
and I-I know that
it's not a straight line,
but at the time,
it was...
Mm.
There wasn't much
that made sense.
It's hard to explain
to people who weren't there.
I miss her.
You miss her?
Every day of every week
of every year of my life.
I don't know why this stuff
always happens to me.
Never to you guys.
Only to me.
I swear to God...
Here's another.
Thank you.
This guy was
clipping his toenails...
Oh.
...on the subway
at rush hour.
Only in New York.
Alright,
I gotta go to bed.
Early morning
layout meeting tomorrow.
Boo.
It's only 10:00.
I'm not superhuman
like you two.
I can't survive on
three hours' sleep
and then do surgery
for 12 hours.
16.
Exactly.
Mm.
Please don't stay up
too late.
I need this booty rubbing up
against me in bed.
♪ Till I'd passed
and left them alone ♪
I will be soon.
Okay.
No!
I got nothing.
Must be vascular.
Oh, yeah.
That's me.
Okay.
- I'll see you later.
- Mm.
Please be careful.
Uptown is scary
this time of night.
Alright.
Look after my girl,
Altman.
I'll try.
- Night, babe.
- Bye.
♪ For the prettiest girl
in the room ♪
♪ And God help you
if you are a phoenix ♪
You okay?
Yeah. Just, uh...
Just tired.
You have to
work tomorrow?
Yeah. All day.
Bummer.
I was gonna see if you wanted
to come to work with me tomorrow
and have fancy breakfast
at Windows on the World.
You just said you have
a layout meeting all morning.
So I could have breakfast
with you.
I had a baby.
Congratulations!
Thanks.
- Uh, pictures, please.
- Oh. Yeah, here.
Oh, my goodness!
She's perfect!
Look at those cheeks!
Ohh!
What's her name?
Allison.
That seems odd.
What?
To name your daughter
after...
My best friend?
It's been almost
20 years, Teddy.
You can admit it.
Admit...?
When Allison first told me
that she met this amazing girl
and wanted her
to move in...
I remember thinking,
"She's not a lesbian. Perfect."
In fact,
she made me promise
that I wouldn't
like you better than her
since we're both doctors.
The last thing I expected
was for the two of you
to get together.
Tell me again.
You were wearing
your flowered dress
with your combat boots,
and you were riding
a bike.
The one with the basket
in the front...
..and it was filled
with fake birds.
Oh, my God.
I'm so embarrassed by me.
Shh. I'm telling it.
- Okay.
And then you almost hit me
because I was
crossing the street
and I was looking
at a map,
and then I looked up,
and I said...
"Get those birds
out of my way, Pollyanna!"
I was stressed.
I was a first year attending.
You were mean.
And beautiful.
And I feel desperately
in love with you on sight.
You did not.
Okay, I kinda
hated you at first.
You were in the bike lane.
I know. I'm sorry.
But I bought you
a bagel anyway.
I'm so lucky you did.
Allison.
Mm.
I can't...
I can't keep doing this.
Kissing me?
No, I just...
I can't keep sneaking around
and lying to Claire.
She's our best friend.
Oh.
I know.
Oh. I know.
I'm an awful person.
No.
You are the best person.
I'm telling her.
I'm telling her tomorrow.
Then what?
W-We all come home
to the apartment that we share
and help her pack up
and move out?
Or we could move out.
And then she's stuck
with three shares of the rent?
You're right. I know.
But I can't keep
lying to her, either.
I love her.
And I love you more.
Don't say that.
Okay, say it again.
I love you more.
- Mm.
- I love you more.
How long did you know?
I suspected for months.
Mm.
Did you ever stop and think
about what it would do to me,
or did you just not care?
No, it tore me up,
Claire. I...
But not enough to stop.
I requested her phone records
after she died.
I kept trying to imagine her
in those last minutes.
"What did she do? What did
she see? Was she in pain?"
So I got
her phone records,
from that... that clunky
little Nokia she had.
And I found out that
you were the last person
she tried to call.
At 8:57 a.m.
On September 11, 2001.
Allison Robin Brown tried
to call you, Teddy Altman,
as the Twin Towers
fell around her,
as she...
As she fell
out of the sky.
Not me.
Not her parents.
You.
That's how I found out.
She was
the love of my life.
And you were
the love of hers.
Take care, Teddy.
There was this one time
you let me scrub in
on a piggyback transplant.
Oh, my God.
I was so nervous.
I was afraid I was gonna drop
the donor heart on the OR floor.
This is so crazy.
'Cause that is how I felt
every single time I saw you.
Except in the OR, because
in there, I'm a superhero.
But in regular life,
I am a neurotic mess.
I do not see that.
I guess...
I'm not.
With you.
I mean, at least not
for the last few hours.
Mm.
For the last 12 hours?
Is it morning?!
Oh, my God!
Oh, look.
The sunrise.
It's time for your run.
Which talks
are you going to?
Um..."Bioethics
in Crisis Zones"
and "Innovations in Pathology:
Presenting"...
The PATH pen!
That's Richard's talk.
And Richard is...?
My biological dad.
Remember? I told you.
Oh, right. Yeah.
Richard.
So, is it gonna be weird
if I meet this man
on what amounts
to our first date?
Yeah.
Incredibly weird.
But everything about this night
has been weird.
Weird and...
Mm.
...perfect.
Conference.
Advancement.
Mm-hmm.
Expanding our minds.
- Right.
- Mm-hmm.
Surgical.
Innovation.
Technology.
Mmmmmmm.
Hi there.
Mm.
Good morning, Cleopatra.
Oh. There's coffee.
Mm.
You know,
maybe it's okay
that we fight
like cats and dogs.
Maybe
if we stopped fighting,
that's when we need
to start to worry.
Now...
healthy cells
never stop dividing.
It's not until they're harmed
in... in some way
that growth stops.
But cancer cells...
they keep growing even if
the conditions aren't ideal.
Baby, please tell me you're
not comparing us to cancer.
Okay, the problem isn't that
cancer cells keep growing.
It's that
the good cells... stop.
♪ All these places... ♪
Catherine,
you are a genius.
Ohh!
You have to make
that presentation
in a couple of hours.
You better hurry up.
Okay, I'm going
as fast as I can.
♪ I can make my first steps ♪
♪ As a child... ♪
Hey.
Do I smell like sex?
I mean, I took a shower,
but I just...
I'm not sure
I got it all off.
Do you really want me
to smell you?
I just never knew
it was possible
to like someone so much
that you know so little.
♪ Roof of my mouth
as I lie to you ♪
You know what? I'm, um...
I-I'll catch up to you, okay?
♪ ...doesn't mean ♪
♪ I didn't enjoy it
at the time ♪
Claire,
I owe you an apology.
No, you don't.
I had too many free drinks
last night.
It was 20 years ago.
Bygones.
It's not bygones.
I mean, not even a little bit.
And... we both know it.
I met the father of my daughter
in Afghanistan
after Allison died,
and he saved me
from a grief so huge,
I probably
would have let it kill me.
And for years, I loved him
so much, I felt guilty.
Guilty for loving him
half as much as I loved Allison.
Guilty because he was
with someone else.
And guilty because...
...because maybe
I wasn't capable
of letting someone
love me fully.
And Allison
did love me, yes.
But she loved you,
too, Claire.
Allison was in love
with the both of us.
And at the time,
I didn't believe it.
I...
I thought no one could love
more than one person at once.
I... I thought...
I thought love couldn't
be divided like that.
But now I do.
I believe it.
And I am sorry
for the lies,
and I'm sorry
for the betrayal.
I was a bad friend,
and I was selfish.
And I never, ever meant
to hurt you.
♪ I promise
I'll do anything you ask ♪
I could never stay mad
at anybody for loving Allison.
She's Allison.
Ah.
Honey. I think
I've cracked it.
That's great, dear.
Alright. Okay.
So, here we go.
Um...
"Thank you very much.
I can't tell you what an honor
it is to be here."
Well, wait.
Why don't you make it funny?
Make a joke of it.
Oh. That's a good point.
That's a good point.
Joke. Yeah. Okay.
Um...
"Also, I can't tell you how many times
I've rewritten
this presentation."
Nervous?
Energized.
Break a leg.
Okay.
Look at you.
Come back to Boston.
What?
With me.
Come back with me.
You want me to...
move back to Boston
to be with you?
Yes.
Or I'll move to Seattle.
I know. It's crazy.
But this happens,
right?
I mean, sometimes you just
meet somebody and you know.
And, look,
after my mom died,
I-I've been a little bit...
you know...
seize the day.
"O Captain! My Captain!"
- "Dead Poets Society."
- It's my second favorite...
So, I'm... I'm a person who...
I need time
to make decisions.
I need to weigh and measure
and make spreadsheets.
Got it.
- Okay. Okay.
- Okay.
Take as much time
as you need.
Get a focus group
together.
Do a
study. Write a paper.
Okay.
I just don't think that
I'm gonna feel
any differently about this
in a few hours
or a few months.
But...
you do you.
Over three decades
as a surgeon, teacher,
and chief of surgery
at Seattle's Grey-Sloan
Memorial Hospital...
Jackson!
Nothing's showing yet.
I know, Ma. Calm down.
You said this was
gonna work.
Will you sit down,
please?
I'm working on it.
Our next speaker has
built a sterling reputation.
In Washington and abroad...
How do you know
how to do this stuff?
Everyone knows
how to do this stuff, Mom.
..and his medical judgment
is second to none.
Please join me in welcoming
my colleague and friend
Dr. Richard Webber.
Whoo-hoo!
I think I just heard
Auntie Maggie say "Whoo-hoo!"
Me too.
Oh, did it start?
He's going on
right now.
I'm sorry.
Thank you so much, Cynthia.
I can't tell you what an honor
it is to be here.
Also, I can't tell you
how many times
I've rewritten
this presentation.
I've worked hard...
He looks good.
..to develop the PATH pen...
I'm just pointing it out.
...but...
that's not why I'm here anymore.
Because this morning, with
my brilliant wife's help...
What's that?
...I have figured out...
...how to cure cancer.
Now, good cells need
favorable conditions,
nurturing
and loving conditions.
What is he doing?
What is happening?
I don't know.
Think of everything
in... in your life.
Every moment, every cell,
every atom
as having a simple positive
or negative charge,
which is just... you know...
good or bad, right?
Something is wrong.
Um...
Okay, uh... let's see.
Uh-huh.
Ah. Okay.
So, um, now,
it's not fair to blame
the environment or toxins
o-or... or family history.
Um...
cells need apologies.
Dear Lord.
- He's drunk.
- They need to know on an elemental level
that we are sorry.
What's
Uncle Richard saying?
I don't know.
Will you go grab my phone?
Um...
Okay. Um...
Uh...
Circle!
I-I need the circle!
No.
Here we go. Where...
Okay, I'm...
I need a... circle.
Ah.
So, um, if we divide
a circle into fourths
and then we remove
one of those fourths...
We have to get him
down from there.
I'll call for
a gurney and oxygen.
...now a third of...
Of the remainder.
Um... you see?
Okay, a-and then
all of the pieces will continue
to make... make the whole,
eh, if the whole
is filled with...
With, uh, evidence.
Now, this evidence that
we're talking about is...
Richard,
Richard, Richard.
Richard. Okay?
We're gonna take you home.
You're not feeling well.
Uh, you know what?
I'm... I'm fine.
You're... You're...
You're embarrassing me.
I'm... I'm sorry,
ladies and gentlemen.
But the historic
illusion of, uh...
Please, Richard.
W-Who are you?
It's me.
It's... It's Maggie.
Um...
Um, oh... oh... but...
Oh, yes. Yes.
- The... The historical illusion that...
- Okay.
Dr. Webber.
Get your hands off of me!
Oh!
- Uh, if... if...
- Somebody please call 911!
I think he's
having a stroke.
And can somebody turn on
the lights?
I have to finish my...
My presentation.
- I-I gotta finish this.
- Oh, my God.
♪ Like that ♪
♪ With the holes ♪
Maggie.
What's happening?
I don't know.
I'm not sure I really
believe you're here.
There's coffee.
Oh. That's a good point.
♪ ..with the holes? ♪
♪ With the holes ♪
Sync corrections by srjanapala