♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
I couldn't sleep.
I kept trying to tell myself
that it was from something
other than Sam,
but, I mean, come on.
How can I ignore the fact
that my bed is half empty?
It's like this space
that I can't occupy.
You know, it's his space.
Sam's space. He belongs there.
Anyway, so I'm up, flipping
around through the channels,
and I came across
this documentary.
What about?
The history of shin-kicking.
I had no idea that
this existed as a sport.
I mean, for 400 years
men have been kicking
each other in the shins.
Like, professionally.
What was so captivating
about it?
Ha, ha. I don't know. I--
uh...
I couldn't sleep.
You, uh, all right there?
Yeah.
No.
Sam and I broke up.
What?
I lost my boyfriend
and my baby in one day.
And I haven't
been sleeping much.
I'm sorry about you and Sam.
Really. Uh...
But you didn't lose your baby.
Someone else got theirs.
You'll get yours. I mean,
adoption's always on the table.
Well, I'm not really interested
in being picked over again.
Well, there's
always surrogacy.
I can get you a great donor egg
and a healthy surrogate.
I'm tired.
All right, I know it's hard
to think about now,
but you do have options.
Why not surrogacy?
You get your baby and someone
else's boobs take the hit.
Heh. Because I've already jumped
through a thousand hoops.
I don't think I can make it
through a thousand more.
All right, tell me something.
Take my mind off this.
Well, I'm staying sober.
I don't miss Ryan any less,
but I'm sober.
He'd be proud of you.
I'm proud of you.
I overslept.
Turned your alarm off.
Why?
You think I didn't hear you two
giggling with the TV on
past midnight?
The cartoon channel was playing
a pokémon marathon
that Mason
had never seen.
The rise of darkrai.
You had no business
keeping that boy up so late.
He is off from school today.
You are not.
Where's Mason?
He's in your office.
Did he eat?
Yep.
I can crack an egg.
He's nervous about
his spelling bee.
I promised to--
I quizzed him on the way in.
His toothbrush
looked a little ragged,
so we stopped
and got a new one.
Erica will be by
in a little bit to pick him up.
Don't get used to it.
My partner and I
were following a car
that had just been involved
in an armed robbery.
All of a sudden, the guy ditches
it, takes off. So I went.
I cornered him,
I drew my weapon,
and he made a move
for his waistband.
I saw a flash, I reacted,
I shot, and I killed him.
And it turned out
he was unarmed, right?
Yeah. But the guy
just robbed a gas station.
With a gun. So I assumed that--
of course. Of course.
And now how do you feel?
Like I followed protocol.
That's not exactly
what I'm asking.
What I'm asking is how you
feel about what happened.
Look, what I did?
It's part of the job.
Having to discharge your weapon
isn't usually part of the job.
Are you sleeping at night?
You know, I appreciate Joe,
you know, sending me
to somebody that he trusts.
But, um, I just--
I wanna get back to work.
That's tricky, getting back to
work after something like this.
It can also put a lot
of stress on your home life.
How are things there?
You want me to say
that my home life sucks
because nobody else
gets me except other cops?
I wanna know how
you're handling it all.
Huh.
In my job, I see things.
Things that, um...
I can't describe them
to my wife.
And when I get home,
sometimes they're
still in my head.
And you can't talk to anyone
at work about this, either?
You're not the first cop
I've dealt with.
I know what it's like.
So you can talk to me.
How you guys doing in here?
Give us a couple minutes?
I'd love to, Shelly,
but I'm on the clock.
I gotta get this kid home,
so let's go.
Thanks, doc. Really.
Yeah.
Aaron and I were starting
to make progress.
Well, I appreciate you
stepping up here, Shelly.
These in-house counselors,
they're looking
to cover their own asses.
I'm just not sure
he's ready to go back.
You don't get over
what he did in a week.
He did his job.
No, he killed someone
in the course of doing his job.
It's not the same thing.
A cop shoots an unarmed kid,
everyone
starts asking questions.
I'm less worried
about how it looks
than about where
his head's at.
Well, if you say so,
Shelly,
I'll make sure
he sees a therapist.
Heck, I'll even drive him
down here once a week,
after we restore him
to active duty.
This ia investigation hasn't
wrapped, and they catch wind
of you not signing off
on this kid right away...
You get my drift?
I think so.
You want me to say
it's all right for him
to go back to work even though
I'm not comfortable with it.
I want you to help
the kid out.
Dragon. D-r-a-g-o-n.
Dragon.
On fire.
Okay, Coop. Retrieval.
Okay, retrieval.
R-e-t-r-e-e--
Retrieval.
R-e-t-r-i-e-v-a-l.
Gosh.
The new and undisputed
spelling champion
of the kitchen is Mason.
Milkshakes before noon?
It's a special flavor
Cooper made.
Marshmallow cream,
caramel syrup--
- No, no, no. Secret recipe.
- Secret recipe.
You've gotta try it.
Mm-hm.
It's sweet.
It's delicious.
- Delicious. D-e-l-i-s-h-o-o-s-h.
- Errh.
- Oh, my god! So sorry.
- Whoa.
Aah.
Are you okay, mom?
Well, it looks like
she will keep her finger,
but your mom
might need stitches.
Stitches. S-t-i-t-c-h-e-s.
Stitches.
I'll do it.
You guys clean up.
Wah.
Sam wouldn't even smile
at me this morning.
I saw him draw
his shades the other day.
All of them.
Your lives are very intertwined.
It's bound to be unpleasant.
Ugh. I just wish
I was sleeping.
When Pete first left,
I wasn't sleeping.
And then I started
sleeping sideways.
I don't know.
It was oddly comforting.
What do you do
when the one person
who can make you
feel better
is the one person
who won't talk to you?
Hell if I know.
Unh. Unh.
You go to hell!
Ah, that must be my patient.
- You're in the hospital.
- We're gonna take care of you.
Go to hell!
All of you go to hell!
I am not supposed to be here!
I have important people--
we found him on ocean Avenue. He
was yelling at a fire hydrant.
People are waiting to listen
to what I have to say.
That's enough.
It's okay, you can let him go.
Mr. Bauer. Sounds like
you're having a hard day.
I have a knife. I have
two knives. And I will stab
every person in here
who's looking at me right now.
I will stab you.
Mr. Bauer, you know better
than to talk that way.
You're scaring everybody.
What would your mother say if
she heard you talking that way?
Could I get ten milligrams
of haloperidol, please?
Don't you come near me.
Don't any of you come near me.
I am the only one
that's gonna come near you.
Because I wanna help you.
Okay?
I know it's frustrating.
I know it's very confusing
being in here,
but I'm gonna give you
some medicine
and you're gonna feel
much better soon.
Okay?
Everybody else
is going back to work.
Here it is.
Can you do that yourself?
There you go.
Good. There you go.
Thank you. Thank you.
Good job.
You're gonna feel
much better soon.
Good job.
Any weakness in your hand
before today?
It's just an old habit.
It's like a tick I picked up
in middle school.
And the glass? Seemed like
you couldn't grip it.
It was just wet.
It just slipped.
Have you been having
any headaches?
Dizziness?
I'm a single mom.
I work 50 hours a week.
I get headaches.
I'd be happy to check you out.
I appreciate it, but i--
you know,
I have my own doctor.
Who has probably never given
you a complete neuro workup.
We can get you over
to St. ambrose.
I could give you
an mri.
It would take an hour
or two, tops.
I don't have an hour.
You never know with these kind--
look, I know
it's what you do,
but I just don't like
being poked and prodded.
I didn't mean it like that.
No, it's cool.
Just let it go,
heh. Okay?
Done.
Great. Thank you.
Hi. Dr. Turner?
Hello.
I'm Scott Becker.
I brought in the guy
you talked down yesterday.
Oh, yeah. Hi.
Hi.
What you did for him, that was--
that was really impressive.
Thank you.
Yeah, I see a lot
of doctors here,
but what you did was, um...
You're different.
I'm starting to sound
ridiculous,
so I was wondering
if you'd be interested
in going out
with me sometime?
That's very sweet.
That was a tiny bit patronizing.
Still, why don't you say yes?
I guarantee
you'll have a good time.
I am sure you're great,
but this is just not
the best time for me right now.
But, um, thank you.
Really.
Hey, fellas.
Hey, Sam.
I heard about you and Addison.
I'm sorry, man.
Yeah.
You guys--?
We broke up.
Oh, man. You okay?
I'm fine. I'm fine.
It was amicable, adult.
It made sense.
I had a dream last night
that I ran her over.
Flattened her.
Like in a cartoon.
That's adult.
You know, adult breakups
are myths perpetrated by women
so they can have their cake
and eat it too.
The mature way to do things
is just untangle and move on.
Good luck selling your house
and finding a new job.
I've done this before, okay?
With Naomi.
She's my ex-wife.
She used to work here.
How'd that work?
Got involved
with her best friend.
Who? Addison?
Mm-hm.
Oh, man, you are a glutton
for punishment.
The thing is we broke up over
a baby that doesn't even exist.
Is she even gonna have one?
- Mm-mm. You better ask her.
- Hey, hey, come on.
Right now this is a baby-free,
estrogen-free zone.
Look, I spent the whole weekend
just sitting around.
Sitting around.
We need to go out.
Let's go out.
It's not a bad idea.
Have some drinks.
Right. Some drinks.
I won't talk about Violet.
Don't talk about Addison.
You don't talk about babies.
Done.
All right. Bring it in.
I guess I'm just
a little bit excited.
Look, maybe the glass did
just slip out of Erica's hand,
but she was flexing it earlier
as if it were weak.
And?
And when I tracked her eyes,
the right one was lagging
behind the left.
These are serious
neurological symptoms.
It could be a lacunar infarct,
onset of Ms.
Is there a reason
you're having this conversation
with me instead of her?
I offered to do a workup.
She shot me down.
Maybe Cooper can convince her?
Telling Cooper
will only have him jump
to the worst possible
conclusion.
So you just wanna turn
a blind eye to this
and hope that nothing
serious is going on?
That's your call.
But if Erica strokes out
and drives Mason off the side
of the pch,
what do you think
you'll tell Cooper then?
He shot and killed a man.
He's a good kid.
I'm not making a value judgment,
I'm just saying he couldn't
possibly be ready
to go back to work.
If every cop with PTSD
was benched,
there wouldn't be
any police left.
Well, strip all
of that away, okay?
Joe asking you the favor,
the fact Aaron is on the force,
what would you do?
I'd want him to get some help,
work through the trauma.
Exactly. You have an opportunity
to step up for Aaron
in a situation where he might
not be able
to step up for himself.
Or I could push the point,
keep him off the force,
and destroy his career.
That's what your buddy
wants you to believe.
I've been around enough cops
to know he's right.
So you just check the box,
you put Aaron out on the street,
and hope he's stable
enough to keep it together?
Joe said he'd make sure
he gets some help.
Ah. Does the police department
seem like the kind of place
where therapy's encouraged?
Look, Violet, with all due
respect, I'm not being naive.
Okay? But I know Joe.
And I have to make a choice:
I trust him
or I put the kid in a position
where he could lose everything.
Shouldn't you be asking
if the kid loses more
by going back to work too soon?
Not gonna do this. It's lying.
Okay.
It is.
And I just busted Cooper's butt
over doing something like this.
Yeah, you did.
Not to mention that the
patient specifically said
she did not want this
to happen,
which makes it against
the law and unethical.
Why do I feel
like there's a "but" coming?
This is Dr. Charlotte king. I'm
chief of staff at St. ambrose.
We have a patient, Erica Warner,
who just arrived in our er.
She was seen in your clinic
a few months ago.
We need her medical records.
No, not everything,
just her most recent
head ct and mri would be useful.
She's in a medically induced
coma, no next of kin,
so you're gonna have to wait
on the consent forms.
Look, we can debate this
or we can do the right thing
and save this woman's life.
Courier's fine. Thank you.
I was completely clear,
completely clear with Addison
that I did not want a kid.
Were you expecting her
to give up?
Hey. No Violet. No Addison.
No babies. Shh.
All right.
Look, Sam was a good soldier
and we just-- we know what
happens to the good soldiers.
- Yeah. What?
- What's that?
- They-- uh--
- Ha-ha-ha.
They go missing.
Good soldiers go missing,
and then their brothers
have to go and get them.
I need another drink.
What is going on?
Yeah, like Sam needs
another office romance.
- Well, you know how-- hey. Ahem.
- Hey.
I've been looking for a drink,
she goes right to Jake.
Can I get you anything?
No, I'm fine right now.
Well, if you need anything...
I-- no, I need something.
Impressive.
Actually, she was.
Oh.
For real?
Really? Really?
I gotta have a life outside of
work.
Apparently.
We need to hang out
with this guy more.
Okay, okay. I'm a married man,
but I'm just saying,
that pretty young lady
over there just smiled at me.
All right.
Oh, no, no.
- She's looking at Sam.
- Mm...
Oh.
Yes. She most definitely was.
Yes.
I think I'm gonna
go over there.
Really?
Yeah. Why? Why not?
You haven't picked up a girl
since middle school.
Oh, come on. I'm sure
it's just like riding a bike.
Don't tell her you
just learned last year.
My brothers, let's mock him
on the way out of battle,
not on the way in.
Okay.
Thank you. I think
I'm gonna be fine.
Go get them.
Who's gonna get
the next round?
I guess it's me.
Hi.
You drinking bourbon?
Rye.
You drink rye on the rocks?
It's an old-fashioned.
Oh. Doesn't that usually have,
like, a cherry in it?
If you're a teenage girl
or you take pride
in sullying classic drinks.
Maybe I'll try one.
Don't. They're serving swill.
I'm in from out of town on
a conference. Wanted to go out.
And I'm already regretting it.
Yeah, this really
isn't my kind of place, either.
So, what kind
of place do you like?
Quiet. Good music.
And a great cocktail.
Those places do exist
in L.A.
Mm.
If you have time.
Well, how about my room?
It's quiet,
I have great music,
and I have a killer
bottle of bourbon.
Unless, of course, you're
a cherry-in-the-old-fashioned
kind of guy.
Are you really a doctor?
Yes, I am.
What kind?
I'm a heart surgeon.
Oh. The last guy I met
said he was a big
television producer.
Okay.
Turns out that he's the guy
who got the writers
their frappuccinos.
So...
Well, I don't know.
How do you want me
to prove it?
How can I prove it
to you?
What muscle is this? Ha-ha-ha.
Ha, ha.
Yes.
Well, that is the bicep brachii.
Good.
Mm-hm.
There we have the
pectoralis major.
Uh-huh.
And down there, we have
the transverse abdominis.
I could play
this game all night.
Right. Me too.
I mean, I actually know
all of the names
of all the muscles, so...
That was too much, wasn't it?
Yeah.
I know, it felt weird
coming out of my mouth.
Wasn't that our floor?
Mm.
Whew. You're hot, you cook,
are you married?
No.
Ha, ha.
You wanna get married,
or could we just pretend
it's our honeymoon all morning?
I was kidding about the married.
Ha, ha.
Oh, no, I knew that.
I know.
I should probably
get going to work.
Do you wanna
hang out again?
Yeah.
No.
So, what? You are married?
No, i'm-- I just...
I just got out of something.
Ahem.
And you're stuck on her?
She is stuck in my head.
I'm not stuck.
You know, I'm not the guy that
just leaves without calling.
I mean, I always call.
I've always called.
But I just--
you seem really great.
And I just-- I kind
of wanna know,
you know, what would happen
if I decided to
do things different
than I've always done.
Because what I've always done
doesn't seem to work.
Again, it's too much.
I have something on my mind.
Me too.
You first.
No, you go.
Ahem. Am I like...? Um...
If I wasn't your husband
and you saw me at a bar,
would you hit on me?
Ow. I'm serious.
Let me guess.
The bachelors' night with
the boys got you all nostalgic?
I do not miss being a bachelor
and I love being married.
There was a lot of attention
being doled out,
and none of it
was coming my way.
Do I not give you
enough attention?
That's not the point.
What is the point?
I'm not sure.
Cooper, you are
a handsome man,
and if you didn't have
a ring on your finger,
you'd have to beat
those hussies off with a stick.
Thank you.
Hmm.
Would you have sex
with me?
I am not one of those hussies.
Damn it.
You think we have enough space
in the loft?
What do you mean?
Mason's been spending
a lot of time there
and I was thinking
he may want it to be
more than just a weekend
thing at some point.
I was looking on the Internet
and there are these partitions
we could install
in the living room maybe.
We could build Mason his own
man cave. He would love that.
So you're pretty into Mason
these days--
Are you feeling
like a hussy now?
Don't push your luck.
We've gotten threats.
The stuff in the papers?
Everyone's trying
to twist this around
like Aaron's
some rogue cop.
That must be hard.
Yeah.
We'll be fine.
Do you wanna know what he did
that day before the shooting?
He drove a kid from corner
to corner to find his mom
because she left in the middle
of the night to buy drugs.
That didn't make the papers.
He's a good man.
He doesn't deserve this.
No, sissy. Can you, um...?
I need a moment alone
with Dr. Wallace, okay?
Okay.
So...
What have you decided?
I'm sorry. I don't think you're
ready to be back on the street.
I am ready.
I am. Please let me
get back to work.
It must feel like the whole
world is watching you,
maybe even against you,
but you can't worry about sissy
or Joe or anyone else.
You've had a major trauma,
and I think it's important
that we continue
to talk about it.
No, no, no.
You don't understand.
You know, growing up, the cops
in my neighborhood were jerks.
Just because they could be.
You know? And I thought...
I thought I could be
a better cop.
A better person
than that.
See, I don't know how to sit
around my house.
I know how to be a cop.
Okay, I wanna get you to the
point where you can do your job
and still have a healthy outlet
for your emotions.
How is that possible?
Without work to keep my focus,
all I do is sit around
and I replay that night.
And, uh...
And what do you see?
I see his face.
That's natural.
You didn't have a choice.
It's okay to let yourself
off the hook, Aaron.
Is it?
You can talk to me.
I see his face,
Dr. Wallace.
It was dark.
There was a shadow.
I got spooked.
And when I opened my eyes,
he was on the ground.
And I told the investigators
he reached, but, uh...
It's okay.
I was scared.
And now I can't get
his face out of my head.
I am sorry.
I am so, so sorry.
I just spent two hours
on the phone
trying to convince Aaron
not to quit.
I said I needed more time
with him.
Shut the door.
I thought you'd do right
by him.
You thought
I'd rubber stamp him.
You knew that his story
was bogus.
This guy Aaron shot?
He was 19 years old.
But you probably read that,
right?
You know what
you didn't read?
The first time he comes
into the system, he's 11.
Beats up an old man
at a bus stop for $9.
Nine bucks, Shelly.
Three years in juvie,
where he distinguished himself
by his ability to make shanks.
He almost killed a kid
in there.
Now six weeks after he finally
gets out,
he robs a liquor store.
The list goes on.
You think that justifies
my lying to protect Aaron?
You think you're protecting him
by keeping him off the street?
I'm telling you,
the only way this kid makes it
is by putting on his uniform
and getting back out there.
No, you are wrong, Joe.
He is not doing well.
None of us are doing well,
Shelly. That's the joke.
It's a brutal job,
and we do the best we can.
But if we were to stop
and think about what we do
and why and try
to make some sense of it,
you'd have a line of us
outside your door a mile long.
Well, then maybe
I should have a line.
Aaron doesn't go back
to work until I say so.
What am I looking at?
A gliosarcoma.
Neuro docs
go their entire careers
without ever seeing
one of these,
and I sniffed it out
while suturing a hand.
Well, congratulations.
What does it mean?
These things are nasty.
They are the only tumor
that can actually push out
of the brain through the skull.
If the cells come into contact
with any other part of the body,
the tumor grows there,
making them nearly inoperable.
How long?
I'd need updated scans
to be sure,
but we're talking
a few months.
This specialist
gives her six to nine.
Is there anything
you can do?
No.
Hey.
I called you last night.
You left bonky bear
at your place.
I know. I saw.
I was out with, uh--
Jake and Cooper.
We were trying to get Sam's
mind off of Addison.
Mm. How did that go?
It's Sam. I mean...
I know.
Addison is not a bastion of
mental health these days either.
The next two people who get
together at this practice--
should be fired
immediately.
So how was it?
What do you mean?
Last night.
The boys' night out.
Oh. Oh, it was good.
Fun. Yeah.
What?
What did you think I meant?
Nothing.
What did you do
last night?
Violet, that's--
no, no, no. What?
Were you with someone?
Oh, god, you were with someone.
Oh, wow.
Go ahead.
With what?
With your objection to me seeing
other people
while we're separated.
How old was she?
Violet--
no, really.
Was she a waitress or a girl
that goes to the club--
stop deflecting.
I'm not deflecting.
Congratulations on your--
whatever it was.
So you're okay
if I see other people?
We're separated, right?
Okay. I'll bring back
bonky bear tonight.
Okay.
Did you know the guys
went out last night?
Really?
So Sam could get
his mind off you.
That's why
he didn't come home.
I was up all night again.
I did not hear the garage open,
I did not see the lights go on.
I feel like Pete
is using this separation
to have the bachelor party
that he never had.
You know, he wants
to sow his wild, old oats.
He told you that?
Yeah.
I pretended not to care.
Do you?
Well, I don't want to.
I mean, intellectually,
I understand where Pete
is coming from, but emotionally,
I haven't processed him
being with other women yet.
Does he think our marriage
is over?
Maybe he has a different idea
of what separation is.
You know?
You prefer sleeping sideways.
He prefers sowing
his wild, old oats.
Look, a part of me hopes
that Sam moves on.
You know? I mean, I wonder
if I held him hostage, you know,
with all the baby stuff.
You're trying to be happy.
Maybe Pete is too.
Hey. What's up?
I know about the tumor.
What?
I know.
How?
I just-- I know.
You've no idea
what you're talking about.
I do.
You need help.
No, what I need
is time, and I'm not
gonna waste it
chasing some cure
that doesn't exist.
You have to tell Cooper.
I don't have control
over this thing,
but I have control over
when I tell Mason
and destroy his childhood.
He won't say anything.
He won't have to.
He'll just look at him
like a kid whose mom
is dying and Mason will know.
Look, I understand that.
I do.
But you are family
to Cooper now.
He needs time to prepare.
You need to listen to me.
You're gonna keep
your mouth shut.
Because if you mention one word
of this to Cooper,
I will take my son
and disappear,
and Cooper will
never see him again.
Nice.
Hey, come here. Ahem.
Put your two fingers
over the seam
and let your wrist
roll over it.
Got it, dad.
Teaching him the curve, huh?
Yeah.
Used to be enough to take
my mind off of things.
Yeah, well, silence
has a way of eating at you
until there's nothing left.
I think what
you need to consider
is whether you can keep
this one inside
and still be the man
and the cop that you wanna be.
If I rat myself out,
I'll be letting everyone down.
Look, Joe would never
talk to me again.
Yeah, maybe.
My father
was a brilliant surgeon,
one of the best in his field.
And I wanted to be that too.
For him.
But I failed in the worst
possible way.
Imagine trying
to be a world-class surgeon
when you can't stomach
the sight of blood.
Coming to terms with the fact
I wasn't gonna be the person
he wanted me to be, it was hard,
I won't lie to you.
But I'm better for it.
Yeah, well, I wouldn't know
how to do that.
Well, I do. If I don't sign off
on your psych eval,
you're off the force.
At least for a while.
It'll make getting back on very
difficult. Maybe impossible.
But if I do it
it's not the best way.
Because at the end of the day,
you're the one
who has to live with it.
You still sulking?
I'm not sulking.
Too much energy.
I am too far past exhaustion
to sulk.
Looks like sulking from here.
You know what you are?
You're a peddler.
A baby peddler. It is.
Is that right?
And you're probably here to give
me some sort of pep talk where,
to summarize, you'll tell me
to get back on the horse.
You're a peddler.
Ha, ha.
Are you getting back together
with Sam?
Why would you ask that?
Well, you gave Sam up
because you wanted a baby,
and if you're not
getting back together,
then a baby is still
what you want.
Give me your hand.
What?
Until you have a baby,
I consider you my patient.
Give me your hand.
Okay.
I have heard every word
of this before.
And I have told women when
it's time to throw in the towel.
And you are not there yet.
You're not even close.
If you want this,
we can make this happen.
I know you felt alone
in this before,
but you don't need
to feel that way anymore,
because you've got me.
I will always be there,
Addison.
You say that
to all your patients?
Not all of it.
I just almost
fell asleep.
You've got some balls.
I came for Aaron.
Well, you've already
done enough for him.
He's giving himself up.
Know what that means?
If he's lucky enough
to somehow avoid prison,
he loses his badge,
his pension,
and everything
he's ever worked for.
He'll be lucky to wind up
flipping burgers
at some fast-food joint.
You screwed him.
And you screwed me.
We've been friends a long time.
Not anymore. The next time
you need a cop, don't call me.
This is the right thing to do,
whether you see it now or not.
You stealing supplies?
Oh, hey.
What are you doing here?
I-- ha, ha. I was gonna say that
I was here to see Mr. Bauer,
but really I was hoping
to find you.
That's very sweet.
I'm assuming you're
not being patronizing.
Mm-mm.
Um, I was wondering,
is it too late
for me to take you
up on your offer?
Um, I need to finish
stealing supplies
for my rig
and take a shower.
Give me an hour?
All right.
Will you help me
find a surrogate?
Absolutely.
So they really called you "bus"?
Um, my brother is older,
and he and his friends
used to play tackle football
out behind our house,
and I always wanted to play,
as the younger brother,
but, you know, my mom said,
"you're too young
and you're gonna get hurt."
So one day I went,
I put a bucket over my head
and I just ran out
on the field
and I said,
"I'm gonna bus them.
I'm gonna bus them up."
Ha, ha.
And so the name "bus"
was born.
I broke my collarbone
that day.
Needed to have surgery.
How old are you?
I'm 29.
- Comrade. C-o-m-r-a-d-e.
- Comrade.
Did I get it?
Sorry.
Uh, yeah.
Knocked you out again.
All right. I don't think
I can take any more tonight.
Why don't you get washed up
and we'll watch a little TV,
okay?
What's going on
with you?
Usually you love to watch me
get thrashed by an 8-year-old.
I'm just... I'm tired.
Charlotte,
what's wrong?
I love you.
So do I.
Hey. Tonight's my night.
Yes, I just--
could we go somewhere to talk?
Just you and me?
Where's my dad?
Uh...
He'll be back in a minute. Um...
You want another word?
Sure.
Uh...
The word is acceptable.
Acceptable. A-c-c-e-p-t-a-b-l-e.
Acceptable.
How have you been?
Okay.
You?
I haven't been sleeping.
Me either.
I mean, the winner was literally
hobbled by the end.
And he did this all for 50 bucks
and a boot filled with beer.
I mean, the guy is either
a glutton for punishment
or he just really likes
drinking beer out of a boot.
Which do you think it was?
I don't know. Ha, ha. Both.
I guess if you want something
badly enough,
then maybe getting your shins
pummeled is a fair price.
I want a baby.
I'm gonna have a baby.