When life forces us to
do something impossible,
an explosion happens
inside the body.
The rush of hormones
blast through us,
- making us stronger.
- What the hell?
Making us faster.
Biology overrides fear, and that
makes the impossible, possible.
Okay, so either this is
a drill, or it's a real fire!
If it's a real fire, then it
probably has something to do
with the guy, so I vote drill.
Despite that large boom
you just heard? Really?
All right, fine. It's the guy.
The bad, escaped rapist guy!
Why? Why?
Oh, door's unlocked!
Well yeah, a fire would
override a lockdown.
I gotta go find Stephanie.
Just be careful!
The entryway is closed, ma'am.
I just watched an
explosion up there!
And I already reported it.
The hospital is on lock down.
- Did you see that?
- Something exploded up there.
- This entrance way
will remain closed!
- East South,
possibly in the South
wing, four, five floors up!
- That's right near the NICU.
- And the CCU, Yeah!
- We have to get in there!
- We need to get in there!
- Hey!
- They won't let us in!
They're clear to come
in. I need their help.
- There's a lockdown!
- I ordered the damn lockdown!
Fire in the hospital
trumps rapist on the loose.
They are cleared!
- There's a rapist on the loose?
- Where have you been?
We have a multiple-alarm
fire on floors five and six
from the service elevators east.
We are concerned about the
structural damage on that floor.
We're diverting all
incoming traumas.
Patients in immediate or impending
danger need to be evacuated first.
Unaffected areas, the ER, radiology,
nursery, daycare. They stay put.
We have to prioritize.
Firefighter Carroll here will be
directing you to the most urgent areas.
And, uh, the woman with her arm
in the air, over there is Dr. Kepner.
She is setting up
the holding area,
- Outside by parking lot one.
- By parking lot one.
Take evacuated patients
to her. She is in charge.
And if your patients can walk,
they can transport themselves.
Okay, thank you, Dr. Grey. Do not be
a hero. If they can walk, let them walk.
Carry the rest. The
elevators are not working.
- Do not try and use them.
- Work fast, but work safe.
Our man's still at large, so we're
maintaining security at the exits,
and we're keeping
active sweeping.
Because just one hospital
emergency wasn't enough.
Lord, don't make me have to
tell Catherine Avery I burned
- her hospital to the ground.
- Edwards!
Stephanie!
Edwards!
Go, go, go, go. Stephanie?
Maggie! Hey, take
this to Kepner outside.
- Right away.
- I've been texting you. Are you okay?
They're trying to
contain it near the CCU,
but I heard it spread
to the O.R. floor.
- I just figured I'd help
with evac.
- Have you seen Nathan?
No, no, and don't go thinking
he's been burnt to a fiery crisp.
- I'm sure he's fine.
- No, I'm not, I'm just,
I need to speak with him.
- So if you see him,
please let him know.
- Yeah.
I'm legit! I swear!
High alert in progress,
sir. I need to see some I.D.
I don't have it. My
wife has my wallet.
Look, our baby's
upstairs for observation.
- Please.
- Is there a problem?
You gotta help me.
I've looked everywhere.
I went... I checked the
cafeteria, the gift shop.
- I tried looking outside,
looking there.
- What are you looking for?
My daughter, Erin.
She's missing again.
Help!
Help me!
Stephanie!
Help!
- Erin!
- Stephanie?
Erin! Erin, where are you?
Don't do that! I
thought you were dead!
I thought you were gone!
- Stephanie?
- Yeah? Erin, uh, hang on!
Hang on!
- I don't like this.
- Don't worry, uh, Sondra.
You'll be fine, all right?
You're just gonna get a
bit of fresh air, all right?
Okay, we got Mr. Pruitt downstairs
safe and sound. Who's next?
Okay, these two very capable
doctors are going to carry you down.
Carry?
Yeah, you're gonna have
your own personal escort.
- Down four flights of stairs.
- But a smooth ride, I promise.
- Like Cleopatra.
- Exactly!
Okay, hurry up!
Okay, this place is full.
- We got to move quick.
- Yes, sir!
Come on, let's go.
Oh. Just finished alerting
all dispatchers to divert
their traumas. Do
you need hands here?
Absolutely.
Hey, you guys seen
Edwards anywhere?
- I'm looking for a missing girl.
- We don't have eyes
on Edwards yet?
- No,
I've been looking everywhere.
- Is she missing?
Yes, yes. The rapist
guy in the hospital.
That's her patient. She's
with him somewhere.
- What?
- I gotta go.
Did you alert police
about Edwards?
No, no, good idea.
Can you do that?
- I...
- Thank you!
- We need all hands on
deck, Avery! Let him go.
Doctor Webber, there's a
protocol when it comes to this.
- You can't just...
- I am looking for
a missing girl.
And yes, the police
are also looking for her.
Then maybe we should let the cops
do their jobs. We focus on patients.
Okay, listen. She
likes to run and hide.
She has brownish
hair. Her name is Erin.
- All right,
we haven't seen her yet.
- Grey! Doctor Webber...
Look, I'll be fine, Dr. Minnick.
Would you let the police know we
have a resident missing? Will you?
Okay, the kids are asleep,
so it should be easy.
Ellis is just getting over a
bug, so when she wakes up,
just take her temp.
We are gonna be on
the road for the next
several hours, but
after that texting is best.
Hey, uh, you might
wanna eat something.
What's gonna take hours?
Owen, there's been an
explosion at Grey Sloan.
What? What do you
mean, an explosion?
So it looks like the
helipad there is off limits.
How many casualties?
Are there people hurt?
- Why didn't you wake me?
- It only affected a few floors,
and they have got it covered.
Look, I'm the head of
trauma. I need to be there.
Okay, no. We have to go. It's
gonna take a few hours to drive
to Madigan Army Medical Center.
And we have to be there
when your sister lands.
Yeah.
They suggested you might
want to bring photographs
- or keepsakes if you have any?
- Right.
Right. Right, because
she might not remember.
You know what? You stay
here. I'm gonna go to the house
- and see if I can find an album.
- No, no,
I know where everything is.
Erin, don't be
scared! Just hang on!
All right, Erin?
Okay.
Fire extinguisher. Fire extinguisher.
It's a lab. It's a lab. It's a lab.
There has to be a fire
extinguisher somewhere.
Is he gone? Is that man gone?
Uh, yeah, yeah. He's very, very
gone. You keep your face low, okay?
You keep your face low and stay
as far away from the fire as you can!
I can't. I can't.
My leg, it's stuck.
Okay, don't worry. Uh,
I'm coming, don't panic.
- Oh, God! Just... Okay.
- Ow, ow!
Move it off! Please!
No, no, honey, it's keeping
all the blood in your leg.
It hurts.
Yeah, I know. I know it hurts.
But I can't... I can't move it until...
I figure out how to fix your
leg. And I... and which I...
How the hell am I
gonna fix her leg?
- Stop it! You're scaring me!
- Sorry!
Okay.
Okay. You... You lucked
out, missy. 'Cause I am...
the best surgeon in here.
I do this kind of
stuff in my sleep.
Okay. All right. We're
gonna figure this out.
Okay? Right? Just
you and me. Right?
- We'll figure it out.
- Okay, okay.
- Right? Just you and me.
- I really want my mom.
Yeah, I know. I know. I do, too.
Okay!
God! Hey, it's okay, it's okay, it's
okay. I got you. I got you, okay?
- All right? Lie back.
- Okay.
Just lie back.
Relax as much as you can.
You know, when I was a
kid, I was in the hospital a lot,
and, uh... they would have to...
- Ow, ow.
- Oh, it's okay! I'm sorry.
They would do a bunch of stuff
that hurt me too. And I hated it.
I hated it. So, do you
know what I would do?
Ah!
- What?
- I would clench my fists.
Real tight, tight as I could.
- Mm-hm.
- Sometimes, my, uh, nails would
dig into my hands.
And I would even break the
skin sometimes, but it helped.
The more I thought
about my hands,
the less I thought about
anything else. And sometimes,
I would just scream my head off.
And it would drive my doctors crazy,
but it made me feel better.
- Okay. Okay.
- Okay?
All right, Erin.
Look, what I'm about to do
is really going to hurt, Erin.
It's going to hurt a lot, and so,
I want you to clench your fists.
Clench them real tight,
as tight as you can for me.
- Okay.
- And if you need to scream,
- you just go ahead and scream,
okay?
- Okay.
Okay. Here we go.
I want patients organized
by condition and severity.
The temp CCU area needs
ventilators and crash carts on standby.
And please check everyone
for smoke inhalation.
- Erin! Erin! Where...
- What's going on?
Oh!
What... We don't
know! A fire, explosion.
But there're no kids out here. How
are my PEDS patients or the NICU?
Listen, the fire is on the
south side, about four floors up.
The kids should all be okay.
What happened with Jo's husband?
- You never called me back.
- Yeah, uh, the trip was a waste.
Okay, I'm looking for
this little girl. She's eight,
she's super smart, she
keeps ditching her parents.
- Look for her!
- All right!
Hey, what do we have?
CCU patient, one day status
post CABG. She's stable.
She just needs to stay
on her heparin infusion.
Are you okay?
Yes. Yeah, yeah. Not a
big fan of fire. You know?
If I'm being honest, it's kinda
my worst nightmare, actually.
Okay. Well, just, like, imagine
that it's a parking lot barbecue.
The smoke, the burning burgers,
Okay. All right, you know what?
Just take a minute. Okay?
Just take a minute. We...
No, no. I'm good. I'm good.
- You sure? Okay.
- Burnt burgers. Right? Burnt burgers.
Oh, Pierce! Can you
come take a look?
- Hi.
The chest sounds good.
Those handsome boys
treated me like a queen.
Good. I'm glad to hear it. We're
gonna get you set up in triage.
We're gonna get you attached
to an EKG machine. Okay?
Hey, you didn't happen to
see Jackson in there, did you?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
Right when the alarms went off.
And then he took off, running after
Edwards, like he was
fireproof. He's not back yet?
- No! Of course not. Typical.
- Typical?
Yeah, he ran into a burning
bus once to save a child.
He's the kind of guy that
runs into a fire, apparently.
- I'm sure he's fine.
- Yeah. Me too.
It's okay. Good. Erin, I
just wanna... loosen this.
And see if there's
less bleeding. Okay?
Look, less blood.
- No blood?
- No blood. Good girl. Okay.
All right. This is heavy.
Scootch on out. Scootch out,
scootch out this way. Don't
bend, don't bend, don't bend.
Go this direction. Keep
going. There we go. Okay.
Let's get you out of here, okay?
Hang on. Let me help you up.
Okay, okay. Don't
put any weight on it.
Lean on me. Good girl. Good
girl. Good girl. Hang on. Okay!
- How do we get around it?
- We can't... We can't.
Hang on, hang on.
Hold on, hold on.
Okay. All right, so...
I'm gonna pick you up,
and I want you to take a big,
deep breath, okay?
The biggest breath
you can, and then hold it.
One, two, three, jump!
Good! Keep that leg straight.
Okay. Good girl, good girl. All the way.
Okay. All right. Here we go.
We can't go down there.
There's the roof.
Okay. All right, come here.
Put your arms around me,
- tight as you can. Okay?
- Okay, okay.
We have to go up. Come on, Erin.
One step at a time.
Okay. One step... at
a time. There we go.
Steph!
Edwards! Stephanie!
Ma'am, can I help you?
Let me help you walk.
-I don't need any help -Ma'am,
did you just have surgery?
For God's sake. I'm not a
ma'am. My name is Cheryl.
And surgery would
be better than this.
Being sliced up and gutted
would be better than
this. It's just kidney stones.
Okay, look, no. We gotta
get you out of this hallway.
There's way too much smoke.
All right? I'm gonna pick you up.
- Is that okay?
- No way! I'm perfectly capable...
of walking, and...
- I'm sure you are.
- It's just kidney stones!
Do you not hear the alarm?
The fire is on the floor above us.
Yeah, I was midway through a
lobectomy when the alarm went off.
I'm not leaving a
patient open on the table.
Okay, glove me. What
the hell are you doing?
Well, you're right. You can't
walk away from the patient.
And it'll be quicker if the
two of us work together.
This floor is supposed to be
clear. You need to evacuate.
Sir, I have a man's
lung in my hand.
- We're working
as fast as we can.
- How long you need?
- Fifteen minutes.
- Fifteen, no more.
Sir? We're looking
for a missing girl.
She's eight years
old. Her name is Erin.
- We've all got our eyes
out for her. Okay. Thank you.
Bovie.
All right. Let's get her
on a morphine drip.
All right, you're
gonna be all right.
- We've been looking for you!
- You scared the crap out of me!
- I need some O-two.
- Yeah, of course you do.
That's what happens when you
don't listen, and instead you inhale
- an entire hospital full
of smoke!
- Ah, what the...
- Stupid heroics!
- Look, I was trying to help her.
You are a surgeon,
not a firefighter!
I wasn't trying to
fight a fire! All right?
- I was trying to save Edwards!
- Don't yell at her!
She is the mother of your child!
- Okay.
- And what would
I have told Harriet?
- I'm fine, April!
- Breathe.
You know, Megan used to
call me Eeyore during the war.
She said the war made
me grumpy and too serious.
Go ahead. You can say it.
- What?
- She was right.
Wouldn't war make anyone grumpy?
Not her. No, she
was... She was happy.
She was always smiling
and joking and laughing.
I don't know what to say. I
mean, how do I even... How...
I don't know what to... I
don't know what to say.
You will... when you see her.
You'll know what to
say when you see her.
They found her ten miles
from where I was stationed.
She was right
there the whole time.
Owen, your sister is alive. And
that doesn't feel real, right now,
but it will... when you see her.
- Almost there. Oh. You okay?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Almost there, almost... Almost
there. Okay, stay there. Good.
No. No. No. No! No! No!
- What?
- No! No!
- My key...
My keycard! I don't
have my keycard!
I can't... I can't get
out without the card.
- We can go down.
- My card...
We can get through
the fire. We can make it.
So we're stuck?
No. No, we're not stuck.
We are... we're
gonna sit right here
and put this over our heads,
and we're gonna be just fine,
I promise you. Come on.
No. That's pulling the
covers over your head.
My mom said, when things
get scary, you don't do that.
You turn on the lights
so the scary goes away!
Listen, your mom
is right, usually, but...
I'm a doctor. And I know that,
in this case, this blanket is
our best chance. Okay? Okay?
Okay.
All right. Come on. Let me help you.
Lean on me, lean on me, lean on me.
Good girl. There we
go. There we go. Okay.
Okay, hang on. Okay.
No. The scary will get
you. The scary will get you.
No, no, no. No, no, no.
Don't worry about me.
Don't worry about me, okay?
I've got a lot of ways
to keep scary out.
Is that my card?
That's... that's my
card! That is my card!
No, Stephanie! Don't leave me!
- No, it's okay! It's okay!
- Don't leave me alone!
I'll be right back. I'll be right back.
Keep your face covered, okay?
All right? I... Erin, I'm
gonna be right back.
Fists, fists. Good, good!
No!
No! No, Stephanie! Stephanie!
No, don't go. Don't leave me.
Stephanie, no!
Stephanie, come
back. Come back...
No! No, Stephanie!
Stephanie, come back!
Stephanie! Please...
Stephanie!
Let's get out of here.
Whoa!
I found him in O.R. Two.
O.R. Two? We evacuated
that floor ages ago!
Yeah, I was in the
middle of a thoracotomy!
Hey, Maggie, can you take over for
him there? You need some oxygen.
Not until my patient's stable.
You inhaled a lot of smoke.
Put this over your face.
Thank you.
- Wait, come here.
- Okay.
- Stay here. Stay here. Don't move or walk.
Help us! Help! Help
us! Somebody help!
Here! Help! Help!
Stephanie! Stephanie!
Oh, my God!
Wait, Erin. Wait, no.
No. No, no, no, no, no, no!
Don't. No, don't! Don't.
Erin! No! Erin! Don't! Hey!
Erin, stay with me. Erin!
No! Stay with me, okay?
Stay... Somebody help me!
Somebody help me, please!
Somebody help me!
Put your mask back on.
And... And no, no
one has seen Edwards.
But that doesn't mean that...
Hey, Chief! Any word on Edwards?
No one's seen her
since the lockdown.
I told Minnick to tell the
police that she was missing.
Minnick! What did the
cops say about Edwards?
- Oh, my God. I forgot.
- You forgot?
There were patients. I forgot.
I saw Edwards earlier,
before the alarm.
She was... she was
with a liver lac patient.
- That's him. That's the guy.
- Where?
- What?
- Where did you see her?
It was a hallway,
just a regular hallway.
Where's radiology on
this thing? When I saw her,
we were close to there. I
had no idea who she was with.
If I'd realized, I could
have done something.
Which way were they walking?
It's just... You know what?
It's easier if I show you.
- I can just walk you right
in there.
- Benjamin Warren!
Absolutely not!
You're a civilian,
and the fire is not
completely contained.
We are wasting time out here!
Agreed. If it helps
find this guy sooner?
No, we're seeing
sporadic flare-ups inside.
Giving a criminal the perfect
opportunity to escape the premises,
no questions asked?
-This isn't about protocol. It's
about -MIRANDA: Oh, hell, no!
- Capturing a dangerous predator.
- You coming or what?
- I have
a radio on me.
- Damn it.
You heard 'em. Move.
Roll up, guys, we're
going in with 'em. Okay.
It was right in here.
Yeah, this is it. This
is where I saw her.
They were...
They were... they were
headed in this direction.
And... they must've
gone in here.
Hey...
if she was near the
explosion when it happened,
could she... Could
she have survived it?
Would depend on her
proximity to the blast.
- Captain, over here.
- Yeah?
We got a casualty.
We have an adult.
Can I borrow your light?
Help me!
Please...
somebody help me!
Stay with me. Stay with me.
No, no. This is too
tall to be Edwards.
It's blood. It is, It's blood!
It's blood over here.
Edwards!
- Edwards, you all right?
- I'm fine! I'm fine!
She needs an IV access,
and a... and an Ambu
bag and a freaking gurney!
All right. On it. Let's go.
Did you take the scenic route?
They were on the
roof. The patient coded.
She needs as much O-neg as
possible and get her typed and crossed!
Hey, get her to Trauma
One. Edwards, we got this.
- You can get down.
- No, ma'am.
She needs to go
straight to the O.R.
-Nope, O.R. floor is inaccessible
-She's not gonna make it.
She needs to be
treated here, now!
Edwards, you're
injured. You need...
She needs blood
and a defibrillator now!
I deep-fried a rapist, I... I
dove through a wall of fire.
I did not do all of that so
that this little girl could die.
Okay? Should be... I
saved her. I saved her.
I saved her. I saved
her, Doctor Bailey.
We need to finish
saving her, right now!
And I need you to
get out of my face!
Doctor Bailey!
You heard her. Get out of
her face. This ER is now an OR.
She's back in sinus.
Pressure's holding at 70.
Yeah, this leg
is still cyanotic.
Should we amputate?
No, we save the
leg. We save the leg.
This son of a bitch does
not get to cost this girl her leg.
- Doctor Bailey, please.
- We'll need to do a graft.
Okay, let's throw a shunt in
and we'll get that leg a chance.
All right, how is she?
We're prepping to do
a graft to save her leg.
You need to be lying
down, Stephanie.
- Let me take a look
at these burns.
- No, not yet, not yet.
Okay, look. You need to
at least be hydrated, okay?
Will you stay there? Let
me just take care of this.
You get the proximal
end? Oh, yeah. I got it.
We need to isolate the distal.
How's she doing? BP's
steady, SATS are 97.
Which means
she's finally stable.
Uh-huh.
She's gonna make it
through this and keep the leg.
Oh, my God.
You got her back, Edwards.
Now, you need to get
yourself back. Okay?
- Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
- You did...
Gurney!
Let's get her on a
bed right away! Okay.
All right, her adrenaline
faded. Pain probably set in.
It's the body's way of
protecting itself from the pain.
- Got her head?
- Yep.
Okay, -RICHARD:
Let's get back to work.
- Hey.
You okay?
- Yeah, I think so.
- You sure?
Yeah, look, I'm
sorry if I scared you.
I was fine. I'm fine.
It's just, you're gonna
need to breathe when I...
when I tell you what I
have to tell you, so...
Take a deep breath for
me, so I know that you can.
What do you mean? What
do you want to tell me?
Take a deep breath for me.
Okay, so remember the dream...
where they come back to us?
Hm?
Derek forgets his keys
and Megan goes for...
For coffee. Yeah.
What... What about it?
Nathan, they found
Megan. She's alive.
That's not funny.
The Army called
Owen this morning.
That's... not funny.
Okay.
Shh. Shh.
Okay. Shh.
Major Hunt, Dr. Shepherd.
I'm Lieutenant Hill.
This is Colonel Turner.
Glad you guys could
make it on such short notice.
So, if there's anything you
need, don't hesitate to ask.
- Appreciate it.
- Absolutely, ma'am.
If you'll just walk this way. I
know it's hard to know exactly
what to expect, so
you should be prepared.
She may not know who you are...
She may not trust where she is.
She could be fine, or she
may communicate in extremes.
There could be yelling.
So, it's best to avoid
any potential triggers...
Sudden movements, sudden
noises... Anything like that.
And why did it take
us so long to find them?
I was sidetracked
by treating patients,
which is my job. I
was doing my job.
Right, that
protocol states that,
I'm sorry. If anyone could
follow protocol around here,
Edwards would be
perfectly fine right now.
I'm sorry, what?
She was supposed to be in counseling.
But, Doctor Webber over here decided
she should be
able to work today.
If you hadn't completely
undermined me...
- If I hadn't complete...
- Then a little girl would
be dead!
Doctor Minnick...
I don't believe that there's a place
for you in my hospital any longer.
Doctor Bailey, hold on.
It's Chief Bailey, and
I am not holding on.
She is holding on. She
is... is clinging to these
procedures and protocols,
and cannot see when
to let go in order to save
the life of a
patient. A child! I do!
I know! Because I was taught
right! Doctor Edwards certainly knew,
because she was taught right.
This is not some factory
that turns out surgical robots.
We make doctors.
Thinking, feeling,
human doctors.
And we will teach them right.
- Hey. You're not going home?
- Uh, nope,
incoming's two minutes out.
Hey, well, look, I just wanted to,
um, say, I'm sorry about earlier.
I yelled at Jackson
and I shouldn't have.
Well, he was an idiot
and he almost died, so...
Well, I just meant that, you
know, he's your baby's father,
and I went too far.
I was just mad because he
and I had been talking earlier
- when the alarms went off...
- Maggie.
What?
Jackson, he, uh... He likes you.
I know him, so I know
what that looks like.
And, he likes you. He
has feelings for you.
No, he doesn't. Why
would you even...
Because I have a feeling
that you like him, too.
So, you know what?
You should just tell him.
I gotta get out there.
- Hey. Long night?
- Yeah.
You want to go back to
my place? Sleep it off?
Or maybe do some other
stuff before we sleep it off?
And by other things, I mean sex.
You wanna go have
some overly tired sex?
I shouldn't. I have to pack up.
- Pack up what?
- I just got fired.
What...
I'm so sorry, but you
know I'm gonna have to do
this again today, right?
Mm-hm.
It's looking good, it's looking good.
Edwards, I can turn up the morphine.
You don't need to
be in this much pain.
Not yet, not yet.
- How are you feeling?
- I've had better days.
- Your burns are severe.
- Mm-hm.
But we are all with you. We
are going to get you back.
But it'll... It'll be a while
before you step in an OR.
Okay. Actually, about that...
I've spent my whole
life in hospitals.
My whole life. And I... I
think I need to see everything
that's not the
inside of a hospital.
I need to travel and...
and explore and... and hike
and... and breathe. And breathe!
Okay.
Breathe... breathe...
Real air. So deep.
I want to breathe it all in. Away
from the monitors and the blood
and the... and
the sterile gowns.
Away from saving other
people's lives. I want my own.
It's time... It's time
I lived my own.
You changed my
life, Doctor Webber.
You have... You,
you taught me how...
You taught me how to take
my past and find my path.
Thank you. Thank
you. I think I found it.
- Which means?
- Which means I quit.
Mmm. Okay, DeLuca. Turn that
morphine up as high as it'll go, please.
- Nathan, are you okay?
- Where was she?
- I don't know.
- Well, who had her? Is she hurt?
I wish I knew more.
Do we know for sure it's her? I
mean, have they confirmed that?
Apparently so. I... I'm not
really sure how it works.
Well, where is she now?
They're taking her to
Madigan Army Medical Center.
Owen and Amelia
are on their way now.
- Tell, Pierce I... I had to go.
- Okay, wait.
- Are you okay? Can you drive?
- And someone needs to contact
my patients, tell them
that I finished surgery.
Don't worry, we'll take care
of it. Are you okay to drive?
- Do you want me to take you?
- Megan is alive?
Megan's alive.
- I'm sorry.
- No. Don't do that.
- No.
- Don't do that. Don't apologize.
If this were Derek, I
would already be gone.
- Okay, I can drive.
- Get out of here! Go!
Yeah, okay. I can drive.
Nobody wakes up thinking,
"My world will explode today.
"My world will change."
Nobody thinks that, but
sometimes it happens.
Sometimes we wake
up. We face our fears.
We take them by the hand.
And we stand there,
waiting, hoping, ready...
for anything.