I'm sorry, Nat,
I just gotta do
something quick for Jay.
I'm gonna be
a few minutes late.
Thanks.
Hey, why didn't you call 911?
We called you.
Hi, Ray.
So, what made you fall?
I took one look
at that carburetor.
Can you tell me
how old you are?
62.
What month is it?
Come on, Will.
Ray, what month is it?
It's... It's, uh...
I can't remember.
Your eye movement's
a little sluggish.
I need to get you
to the hospital for an MRI.
Happy to do it,
first thing tomorrow.
Ray...
So, he's got
a bridge game today
with some friends
that, um, hasn't seen
in a while.
Look at your father.
He could be having
a stroke right now.
If he is,
and we don't get him
to the hospital, he could die.
I'll get you in and out
in an hour.
Really? An hour?
Promise.
Fine, get my stuff.
All right, come on.
Okay.
All right, there we are.
An hour.
Em, you sure you should be
going to Vegas?
I mean, you did meet in AA.
Ethan, Bernie has a lead
on a really good job.
I mean,
we're gonna buy a house.
Look, I know
you're worried about me,
but everything's
gonna be okay.
Em, he has pancreatitis.
You have to keep
his drain clean.
Check his glucose
every four hours.
It's a lot of work.
I know.
Well, if we're gonna
get to Omaha by dinner,
we gotta hit the road.
Drive safely, okay?
We will.
And, Bernie...
Don't worry, Doc.
I'll be checking my glucose.
Oh, thanks for everything.
Call when you get there?
I will.
Thanks for your help.
Yeah, of course.
See you at work.
Yeah.
Hey, haven't seen
your big, red shadow today.
Yeah, he's running
a little late.
Oh, hey, um...
Yeah?
Have you noticed Will
acting a little weird lately?
He is getting married
in a month.
Makes most men act
a little weird.
Yeah, I guess.
Heard Emily left.
Oh, yeah.
So?
So now what?
Nothing.
Really?
Yeah.
Emily was the only thing
keeping you two apart.
She actually just made
our problems more obvious.
Really, there's nothing left
between me and Ethan.
If you say so.
Dr. Choi,
there's a patient
in Treatment 4
that's insisting to see you.
You know him?
Don't think so,
but I'll check him out.
All right, then.
Mr. Patrick,
hey, I'm Dr. Choi.
What brings you in today?
Uh...
I was looking
for Dr. Ethan Choi.
Is that you?
Yeah.
And why are you
looking for me specifically?
Do you recall
seeing my wife here
a year ago?
Megan Patrick?
I'm sorry,
not off the top
of my head. Why?
'Cause you're the doctor
that killed her.
I don't care
what you remember.
Just give me the facts.
I understand, but first,
I just want you to know
that I realize you've been
through something
truly awful...
Sit down.
Just tell me what happened.
Okay, Mr. Patrick,
but I have to look up
her chart.
Go ahead, go ahead.
Man, those vanilla lattes
never get old, do they?
Why do people think drinking
black coffee makes them cool?
We don't. We are cool,
so we drink black coffee.
Is that my dad?
I do have one final question.
Yes?
How you feeling?
Second trimester,
and a lot better.
Thank you.
You look fantastic.
Hey, Dad.
Thank you.
Connor, hello.
Hello, Dr. Bekker.
You are a little far
from your office, aren't you?
Didn't you hear?
I have a seat
on the board now.
I guess we'll be seeing
more of each other.
Great.
Hey, Ms. Garrett.
Yes?
Can you tell me why
my father has a seat
on the hospital board?
Well, it's the least
we can do after
he donated all that money.
The money for...
Wait.
Is he the principal donor
for the Hybrid OR?
Nice having a rich dad.
Unbelievable.
He is always trying
to undercut me,
trying to have some kind
of power over me.
Um...
Wait a second, did you know?
You knew
and you didn't tell me.
So instead, you lie to me,
to my face for weeks?
I didn't lie.
I just didn't mention it.
No, Ava, that is a lie.
That's great.
Thank you very much.
Your wife was admitted
to the ED at 7:12 a.m.
Her blood pressure was 104/62,
heart rate 87.
Dr. Manning, you're going
to Treatment 3.
Monique, go with her.
Claire Burton, ran her bike
into a car on Michigan Avenue.
Vitals stable.
Can't get any answers
out of her,
but she definitely
looks pregnant.
Claire, I'm Dr. Manning.
Do you remember me?
I used to eat
a lot of carrots...
Dr. Charles.
...but, you know, they don't
really help your eyes.
I don't really
need them anyway...
She manic?
Yes, bipolar.
I treated her a few months ago
for morning sickness.
All right,
let's move her on my count.
Ready, one, two, three.
Anybody we should call?
Oh, my gosh.
As far as I know,
boyfriend's out
of the picture.
Sometimes, if I look at
something for too long,
I feel like all that energy
is gonna turn into a laser
and just burn a hole right
though whatever it is
that I'm looking at.
I heal a lot faster
than others...
Claire, does it hurt anywhere?
Two Haldol, please.
A lot of times I try
not to look at anything
but myself.
Claire, Claire, can you
tell me if anything hurts?
Every single molecule
on my skin is something...
She'll calm down
in a couple of minutes.
I'm right outside.
Okay, thank you.
...and I just heal.
Does anybody know
what happened to my bike?
This, it's just
a little bit of a cut.
Maybe, I could just
get my bike and go.
What are you doing?
Ray's gonna be here
any minute.
Our tail has him
seven minutes out.
You need to call off the MRI.
What are you talking about?
That bridge game is the summit
between Ray and his crew
that we've been waiting for.
This is where he's going
to incriminate himself.
So I'll do one test
and send him home.
Listen, you work for us,
and I am telling you
to call it off.
I work for the hospital,
and he needs an MRI,
so he's gonna get one.
We can make your life
very hard.
Make sure you get him home
for that meeting.
What's going on?
I just got a weird vibe
from Dr. Choi's patient.
I'll check it out.
Yeah.
O2 sats, 86%.
You need my help?
No.
We're fine in here, thanks.
All right.
Yeah, something's up.
Ethan wouldn't even
let me in the room.
Okay, I'll call security
and have them
keep an eye on them.
Derek Glenn, 35, MVC,
BP 110/60,
heart rate's 120,
left upper quadrant pain.
Why the hell is he in my OR?
It's not a treatment room.
I was told to park him here
because all the other rooms
are full.
All right.
Let's get an ultrasound.
Hey there, Derek.
Can you tell me
where it hurts?
Right here.
All right.
Is there anyone
you need us to call?
Already called my wife.
Good.
Well, it looks like
you've got some free fluid
around your spleen.
That usually indicates
a small tear,
which we do sometimes see
with blunt trauma.
Now, the good news is
90% of these bleeds
stop on their own.
So for now, I'd just like
to get a scan to confirm,
and then we'll keep
a close eye on you to make
sure that you're stable.
That sound okay?
Yeah, sure.
Good.
Let's get him a CBC, CMP,
coag panel,
type and cross
four units of blood,
and set him up for a CT.
We will get you all set up,
and then I'll be back
to check in on you soon, okay?
Look, about this morning...
I don't want to hear it.
So what if your father's
the main donor?
This Hybrid Room
has been a godsend.
That's not the point.
You're saving lives with it.
Who cares where
the money came from?
I do, and you should know me
well enough to know
that I don't want
to be beholden to my father.
Connor...
You should have told me.
How many more damn papers
do I got to sign?
That's it.
We're gonna get this
done right now.
About time.
Let's get this done
fast, okay?
It's a head MRI.
It takes as long
as it takes.
Let's lay you down.
All right.
Ray, I got to see
some more patients,
but I'll be back
before you're done.
Yeah.
What was her normal dose
of Quetiapine?
It was 800 milligrams,
but I cut it in half
to be safe for the baby.
Huh. That might explain
the onset of the mania.
Well, the standard of care
is to cut the dose in half.
There's actually been
some new research,
a couple of new papers,
both suggesting...
Dr. Charles,
I can't keep up with
every psychiatric journal.
Of course you can't.
And more,
I didn't have a choice.
I did what I had to do.
Dr. Manning.
What's wrong?
Your placenta
must have abrupted
from the accident.
Call OB, we need to get her
upstairs for a delivery.
Delivery, did something happen
to my baby?
Is he gonna be okay?
What's wrong with my baby?
Everything's gonna be fine.
Let's get you upstairs,
and then we'll figure out
what happens next, okay?
Are you sure
I didn't hurt the baby?
Are you sure?
What if I hurt it?
Your wife was given
antihistamine, steroids
and epinephrine,
but progressed
to cardiac arrest.
I performed CPR with ACLS
for 35 minutes,
but she never
regained circulation.
And at 9:17,
she was pronounced dead.
Mr. Patrick,
I assure you,
we did everything we could.
No.
I can only imagine
the pain you felt.
She couldn't breathe.
Do you know what's that like?
I want you to know
how it feels.
This is your...
Mr. Patrick!
There's a toxic spill.
Evacuate the ED now!
Code Orange!
Everyone, out, right now.
Get your patients out
right now!
Code Orange!
Get out! Everybody, out!
Go, move!
This is Maggie Lockwood.
Toxic exposure in the ED.
I repeat,
toxic exposure in the ED.
Get the hospital
on bypass right now.
Start the internal
disaster protocol.
Everyone, out now! Move, move!
Dr. Rhodes.
Ava, get me a gurney.
They're all in use.
What's going on?
Toxic spill.
We need
to get you out of here.
No, that's too dangerous.
What are you doing?
This room has
positive pressure ventilation.
We're safe as long
as we stay in here.
What happened?
Why did we stop?
What's going on?
I don't know.
Move! Move! Move!
Everybody, out!
Moving out the truck!
Head trauma, GCS 9.
We just got her,
so she needs a full trauma
workup when you land.
35% TBSA second
and third-degree burns.
Take him straight
to the burn center.
Maggie?
Yeah.
Have you seen Natalie?
Don't worry.
I saw her take a patient
upstairs before the spill.
Dr. Choi.
You need to sit down.
I'm okay.
But we have more patients
in ambulances,
so we need to triage into red,
yellow and green,
and get the sickest ones off
in the first wave.
Make sure
everyone's showered
and deconned.
You got it.
How long till you can detox
my ED?
Depends on the floor plan,
ventilation, size of spill.
I'm sending Squad in now.
Soon as they
get us the samples,
we'll take them down
to the lab and try
and ID the toxin.
And what about Mr. Patrick?
We're looking into him now.
Background, employment,
family,
anything that'll give us
a lead.
We already have
12 hospital staff and patients
in respiratory distress.
We need to figure this out,
and fast.
Got it.
Easy, easy, easy.
Okay?
Yeah.
Why are we here?
What is this place?
Uh... Orthopedics.
They're renovating
the rehab floor.
I'm supposed to have my baby.
You said I was bleeding.
Emergency exits are locked.
I was thinking maybe
a Code Orange.
Would explain why
the elevators were down.
Oh, there's a lot more blood,
a lot more blood.
Her bleeding's much worse.
Call Labor and Delivery.
Worse?
What does that mean?
Is my baby dying?
No. We need to lay you down,
okay? Come on.
He's dying, isn't he?
My baby's dying.
Come on.
No, he's not.
Come on, let's lay you down.
Just lay down right here.
You're all right.
There you go.
Dr. Charles.
There's no signal.
I can't find a signal.
Oh, my God. I killed him.
Just stay right there, okay?
We have to figure out a way
to break open these doors.
We need to get her upstairs.
Natalie, we're not
getting through those doors.
We're gonna have to do
a C-section.
This is all my fault.
I killed my baby.
His pressure's dropping.
Derek, are you feeling dizzy?
A little. What does that mean?
That means
you're still bleeding.
The tear in your spleen
isn't clotting like I'd hoped.
He's got
a lot more free fluid.
Hey! Hey!
Cruz!
I need to get
this patient upstairs.
Sorry, Doc, I can't open
these doors until we get
the place clear.
Just to get a couple units
from the blood bank.
Even if I wanted to,
all of the stairs
are locked down
so the gas can't spread.
Emergency exits, everything.
We'll get you out
as soon as possible.
All right.
We need to keep
his pressure up
until they get us out of here.
I'll hang a bag of saline.
I got it.
April, we need
more oxygen masks.
Fire brought out
everything they could find.
All right, see how many
nasal cannulas we have.
The worst patients can always
double up.
Ethan, you need to sit down.
I'm okay. I'm fine.
I'll be okay. Don't worry.
Okay, you let this nurse know
if you feel any nausea,
dizziness or problems
with your vision, okay?
Hey, Will!
Where's our dad?
He's safe.
He's still upstairs.
Then go and get him
out of there.
I can't.
They've locked down
the entire hospital.
You're a doctor.
You go find whoever's got
the key and you get him
the hell out.
Look, guys,
I'm sorry, but it just
doesn't work like that.
Will, you said
it'll only take
an hour.
Yeah, and it should have,
but we're having an emergency.
Dr. Halstead!
Guys, I got to go.
Ethan! Ethan, breathe.
Ethan!
Talk to me, Ethan.
Talk to me.
Get him on O2!
Mask!
Here you go.
Ethan.
Hang in there, Ethan.
How's he doing?
Not good.
We'll get him through this.
He was trying to keep me safe.
Back there in the ED.
That's why he didn't let me
in the room.
Yeah.
I've never done a C-section.
I haven't even seen one
in years.
We're gonna figure it out.
But we don't have any
instruments or emergency
supplies or pain meds.
There's got to still be some
supplies on this floor.
What if we just held pressure?
I mean, whatever's happening
in the hospital right now
can't last forever.
We have to do this now.
We don't have a choice.
Listen, whatever doubts
you may or may not have
about your previous treatment
of this patient...
I led her to believe
that she could go through
with this pregnancy.
She can't take care of a baby.
She can't even take care
of herself.
You were in a very
difficult situation...
If I operate on her in this
hallway and she dies,
that's my fault.
Okay.
Okay, look. Um...
I am going to find a signal
and get an ob-gyn
on the phone.
But no one can get down here.
No, no, so she can talk us
through it on the phone.
Together.
Okay?
Please tell me
you found something.
Jacob Patrick is an engineer
at a textile factory.
He has access
to numerous industrial toxins.
We're hoping to have it
narrowed down soon.
Please keep me posted.
I will.
You can't be serious!
Until an ambulance shows up
with more,
there's nothing we can do.
What's going on?
Ethan and Mr. Patrick
and both in bronchospasm
and in need of racemic epi.
The problem is
there's only one dose left.
Which, obviously,
we should give to Ethan.
Who's doing worse?
That's the thing,
Mr. Patrick is.
You're not really thinking
of giving it to him?
I'm following protocol, April.
Whichever patient
has the greatest need
gets treated first.
He came here
on a suicide mission.
I'm sorry.
Give Mr. Patrick the epi.
This is wrong.
What's happening?
The bleed isn't stopping.
I'll hang some Ringer's.
I'm gonna embolize it.
What?
We're just putting a wire
into his groin.
It's a simple procedure.
Not without nurses or techs,
let alone anesthesia.
No, we can twilight him
with Versed.
Look, we don't have a choice.
We need to close off
the vessel,
and frankly,
I'm not interested
in your opinion.
All right,
the guys inside checked.
They can't find any more doses
of racemic epi.
We have to do something.
His airway's almost closed.
I mean, we could try
methylprednisolone.
It's not great,
but it's better than nothing.
Okay, where can I find it?
In the respiratory
therapist carts.
All right,
what does that cart look like?
We're wasting time.
April!
Hey, you can't go in there!
Give it to him now.
That was incredibly stupid.
Let's hope this works.
All right, come on.
Let's get you decontaminated.
Do you have reception?
I've got one bar.
It's ringing.
I'm not cutting
until you get someone.
Cutting melon,
cutting chicken,
cutting me, cut the baby.
No one's gonna hurt the baby,
Claire.
Her Haldol's wearing off.
Is someone answering?
Uh, yes, this is Dr. Charles.
I need an OB immediately
to talk me through
an emergency C-section.
They're getting Dr. Grant.
Come here and put her
on speaker.
I can't.
I'll lose the call.
I'll drop the call.
Dr. Grant, thank God.
I have a woman, 36 weeks,
abrupted placenta,
already lost a couple units
of blood.
Some lidocaine,
which we've administered.
A scalpel and a few clamps.
Okay, okay, here we go.
Dr. Grant says to start
the incision three centimeters
below the umbilicus.
Okay, here we go.
Come on.
Damn it.
The pressure's still dropping.
I can't get the wire in there.
The anatomy's too challenging.
Hang 500 of albumin.
We'll hold pressure
until we can
get him out of here.
He won't make it that long.
There's nothing else
we can do.
We can remove his spleen.
We can't open him up.
He'll lose too much blood,
and we don't have
any to give him.
I'm a universal donor.
That's insane.
The surgery
will take too long.
Well, then do it faster.
Ava, what are you
trying to prove?
I'm trying to save his life.
If you do this,
you both are gonna bleed out
before I'm done.
Unless you have a better idea,
I suggest you stop making
excuses and get started.
How's your breathing?
Good? All right.
Will.
Be right back.
Congratulations.
They called off Ray's meeting.
You screwed it up.
He was sick.
What was I supposed
to do?
What I told you to do,
stay out of the way.
I didn't know
there was gonna be
a toxic spill, Jay.
This is why
we don't take chances,
and you needed to listen.
He could have had a stroke.
I wasn't gonna let him die.
I took an oath.
PD's narrowed down
the possible toxins.
We hope to have
an answer soon.
Look, I understand
you're upset, April.
Ethan is dying,
and you didn't fight for him.
I did what I was obligated
to do,
and Dr. Choi would have done
the same thing.
Can you see
the splenic artery?
Not yet.
I'm still getting through
the mesenteric fat.
Just keep going.
Ava, you've probably given
a pint by now.
I'm doing fine.
You're gonna run out of blood
before we even get there.
If I stop transfusing now,
he'll die.
This is crazy.
Okay, tell Dr. Grant
I'm through the uterine wall
and ready to deliver.
Through the wall.
It's a baby. Through the wall.
Yeah, she's through
the uterine wall.
Hold on.
The placenta's in the way.
I can't see the head.
Ask Dr. Grant if I should
extend the incision
or reach through the placenta.
Well, can you reach around it?
Is there any room?
Ask Dr. Grant.
Yes, Dr. Grant,
Dr. Manning
wants to know
if she should extend
the incision or go through
the placenta?
Dr. Grant says
that she totally
trusts you to make that call.
No, she needs to tell me
which way to go.
Make the call, Manning.
Manning, make the call.
Dr. Grant says that without
being there to assess
the position of the placenta,
there's no way
that she can make
that determination.
You need to decide.
I'm going through
the placenta.
Hold on, it's too high.
I need you to come over here
and push down on it.
Here?
Yeah, I think so.
Okay, I'm sorry,
but you're gonna feel this.
Get out of me! Help!
Did you get the baby?
No.
Maybe I should do
the incision.
Stop! Get off me! Stop!
Okay, okay, Hold on.
How about now?
Yeah, okay. I think...
Yeah, there it is.
Okay, push again. Push again.
Get off me!
I got it.
The baby...
Push. Push. I got it.
I got him.
Keep pushing.
How's the baby?
I got it.
He's not breathing.
His trachea's blocked
with secretions.
What do you need?
An aspirator.
Something to get
the secretions out.
All I got is IV tubing.
Give it to me.
He's okay.
You did it.
Yeah.
Baby greens,
baby carrots, baby teeth...
Baby single parents,
baby teeth,
baby blankets, warm blankets,
fuzzy blankets.
The artery's almost impossible
to get to.
You okay?
Yeah.
Ava.
You need to sit down
before you pass out.
I'm okay.
Hey! Hey. Hey.
I'm not taking out the tube
till you're done.
All right, stay with me
just a little bit longer,
okay?
Hold on for me. Stay with me.
And...
All right. And...
All right. We did it.
Ava? Ava!
Ava. Hey, Ava.
Oh!
Okay. Okay.
There we go.
Did we do it?
Yeah.
Yeah, we did it.
Coming through.
Any changes?
Nothing.
All right, keep him going.
Word is we should have an ID
on the toxin soon.
He's in v-fib.
April, start compressions.
I need these cuffs off.
Monique, charge to 200.
Bag.
Clear.
Continue compressions.
Charge again.
Clear.
Still no pulse.
Charge again.
Clear.
Continue compressions?
No, he's gone.
Time of death, 12:12.
They identified the toxin.
It's cyanide.
Oh, God.
Ethan.
Okay, let's go everyone.
Let's go.
We got the all clear.
Let's get everyone inside.
All affected staff,
go to Trauma 2 and 3
and we'll triage from there.
Let's go.
Give a dose to everyone
who's affected.
What is it?
Hydroxocobalamin.
It helps counteract
the cyanide.
I got the hydroxocobalamin.
Think it'll work?
As you know,
there's no antidote
to cyanide.
But it's the best chance
we got.
Dr. Grant, how's Claire doing?
She and the baby
are both stable.
You did a nice job.
Well, I couldn't have done it
without you.
I don't follow.
The phone call
with Dr. Charles.
Thank you for getting me
through the C-section.
I wasn't on any phone call.
Dr. Charles, you lied to me.
Yes, I did.
You tricked me into doing
a surgery that endangered
both Claire and her baby.
What you did was reckless
and unprofessional.
You had no right
to manipulate me.
Can I show you something?
She looks good.
Yeah.
Meds kicked in.
Listen, you were
trying to solve
a very tricky problem,
and most doctors would have
tried to talk her out
of this pregnancy.
But you, you saw the woman,
not the mental illness.
You have excellent instincts,
Nat.
Just gotta trust them.
We've got a room
for him in ICU.
We're moving him upstairs.
I'll make sure they call
if anything changes.
Thank you.
Ms. Goodwin, you were right.
He would have done
the same thing.
His pressure's going up.
I think
the medicine's working.
All right,
get him upstairs.
Two units of PRBC are up.
What happened?
The surgery got
a little complicated,
but you're gonna be fine.
In fact, your wife is waiting
for you in the ICU.
They're gonna get you up
to her,
and I'll be there to meet you
in just a minute.
Here you go.
You know I hate peanuts.
Well, as long as
you're not allergic, right?
What you did back there...
You were incredible.
Derek's alive because of you.
So thank you.
Wait.
About your father...
No, forget it, Ava.
I had no right
to get upset
with you like that.
I'm sorry.
No, Connor.
It was me.
I was the one who asked
your father to donate
to the Hybrid Room.
What, you?
You were taking that job
at the Mayo Clinic.
I didn't want to lose you.
Will, are you all right?
That's blood.
Were you exposed
to the cyanide?
Maybe.
Let's get you back inside.
Come on, let's go.
April, the ICU just called.
Dr. Choi's improving.
Oh, thank God.
Go on, go up there.
I'll cover your patients.
Okay.
Hey, you know
what I said earlier,
about there being
nothing left between us?
I was wrong.
I knew that.
Hey, you're up.
Yeah.
So, it turns out
it's not cyanide.
It's an ulcer.
Did you know
this was happening?
I had no idea.
What is going on, Will?
Are you stressed?
No.
Really?
Because I have to say,
you've not been
yourself lately.
Natalie, most ulcers
are bacterial.
They're not stress-related.
I know that.
With the way
you've been acting,
it's not...
There's nothing going on.
I'll go get your antibiotics.
Thanks.
Yeah.
Is there something
you're not telling me?
No.
Everything's fine.
Okay.
Vicki?
Hey.
I got a call
from the hospital.
Apparently,
you haven't updated
your emergency contact.
Are you okay?
I will be.
Are you back in town?
Couple of months now.
I'm back at the VA.
I should have called...
It's okay.
Glad to see you.
So, how was Germany?
It was good.
I've had enough bratwurst
to last me a lifetime,
but my skiing has vastly
improved, so...
That's good.