Previously on ER:
I'm not saying he's not a great
guy. He is. But do you know him?
Under what circumstances would a prisoner
be transferred from one state to another?
Your ex?
- I'm gonna be the new ER chief.
- When I withdrew, I hoped they'd pick you.
I'll make sure you work
harder than any other volunteer.
No more going out for
doughnuts and chasing skirts.
Gotta stay in the
game, K.J., or they win.
Would you like to...?
Here's to discretion.
- Propriety.
- Maturity.
Well...
How's it going, Louie?
I got two more sidewalks to
clear and a Furby doll to find.
Hey, Louie.
No way.
- Merry Christmas, buddy.
- Thank you.
- Hey, Doctor Kovac.
- How's your mom doing?
One more treatment,
then she's out.
Well, maybe this
will cheer her up.
Thank you.
Ho-ho-ho.
I want one.
You look like
you've been naughty.
No? There you go.
Ho-ho.
Well, look what the
reindeer dragged in.
This is for you, Frank.
The last time I got a
present in this hospital...
was when that
helicopter fell on Romano.
- For you.
- Oh, wow, a neon stethoscope.
Thanks, Santa Kovac.
What about me?
♪ NSYNC's greatest hits. You
didn't. I mean, I was hoping you didn't.
I love this love. Bears
tickets. Thanks, man. Just one?
- Looks like it's you and me, man.
- Okay, and now the bonus.
Since it's Christmas Eve, we
only need skeleton crew tonight.
So I'm letting three support staff
and one resident home with pay.
- Well, I did the manual disimpaction.
- I did a pelvic on a 300-pounder.
I débrided maggots out of a
diabetic ulcer, you wankers.
This is gonna jinx us
into a night of trauma hell.
Okay, Rock, Paper, Scissors.
Neela and Morris, you first.
No, no, this is sheet metal.
Morris, you're out. Pratt.
- Ray.
- All right.
You suck.
Thank you, thank
you and thank you.
Michael and I are going to Jamaica
and I have tons of packing to do.
Somebody giving lap
dances? I wasn't even invited?
Santa's sending people home.
♪ NSYNC. I didn't
know you were gay.
- Evil elf.
- It's the thought that counts.
Maybe you could think
about calling Jodie back?
- Get her off my back.
- She did not call again.
Eight times.
Look. Is there any way to,
like, change the main number?
Maybe you could work from
somewhere with a different extension...
like Cambodia.
- Hey.
- Ah! Hi.
Hi. Sorry I'm late. I had to pick
up the cake for the Christmas party.
No problem. Come here.
Oh, wow, that's for me?
Yeah. Open it.
- Now?
- Yeah.
- I can't.
- Oh, tomorrow morning, then.
Okay.
- Are we spending Christmas together?
- That's what you said last night.
No, I didn't.
You probably don't
remember other things either.
Shut up.
I never said anything about us.
We should.
We should?
Okay.
- I should change.
- I'll help.
Is Alex playing hockey again?
They don't just move you
from another state for no reason.
Make sure that coach doesn't
bench him, because he's got skills.
Are you listening to me?
Yes. I need to see him, Sammy.
- Steve.
- It would really help me right now.
I wanna know why you
were moved to Illinois.
It's nothing. Listen...
Do you still have the
guitar that I gave Alex?
- Yeah.
- The DVD player, camcorder?
Yes.
People might come
looking for those.
People with warrants.
Unbelievable.
You are such a piece of crap.
- I'll explain everything to Alex.
- No, you won't.
Don't call and don't write.
I've changed, Sammy, I
really have. God is helping me...
- Hell of a job he's doing.
- He's making me see things...
- that I've done wrong. Sam, please.
- Merry Christmas, jerk-off.
Tamara Gordon, 30, altered, restrained
MVC with passenger space intrusion.
Tachy to 110, good
BP, sats 97 percent.
Frontal hematoma,
breath sounds clear.
- I'm Dr. Kovac. How are you, Tamara?
- I'm okay.
Do you remember what happened?
- Other driver skidded on black ice.
- Let her tell me.
Tamara? Tamara?
She's seizing.
- Two of Ativan.
- Could be an intracranial bleed.
Let CT know we'll be up
there as soon as seizure stops.
I need background
singers for the party tonight.
I'll do it.
I want someone to have
my back, not stab me in it.
Baby, I got your back.
I'm looking for somebody
who can "sing" sing.
I can "sing" sing.
Seriously, I got
soul. I'm super bad.
Haleh takes her Christmas
gig very seriously.
I grew up in a Baptist church.
I'm holding auditions in the
lounge. You are welcome to sign up.
- And so are you, Dr. Weaver.
- Yeah.
For the 10th year in
a row, I think I'll pass.
Seventy-five-year-old
male, cough times two days.
No significant history,
afebrile, vitals normal.
- Exam?
- Good breath sounds, unremarkable.
- X-ray?
- Normal heart, lung fields clear.
- Your dispo?
- I was about to send him home.
But he started complaining
of severe epigastric pain.
Did you check an
amylase and a lipase?
Yeah. Not back yet.
All right. Let's see
how he is doing.
Doc, am I gonna lay here all
day just like a piece of herring?
Well, I sure hope
not, Mr. Goldstein.
I'm allergic to pickled
fish. Dr. Clemente.
Oh, doc, do I look
pale? I feel like I'm pale.
You know, let me check you out
so you can go home right away.
See if my cell count is back
on my lizard breeder's LP.
- Sure. RAY: Pupils
equal and sluggish.
Tamara, you were in a car
accident. Do you know where you are?
- A hospital?
- Heart rate's 127.
Okay. Hang a liter of NS.
Tamara, can you
tell me today's date?
- Chest wall stable.
- Christmas Eve.
Good.
December 24th. Chicago.
Breath sounds okay.
Nineteen eighty-six.
Still postictal.
Tamara, do you have any
medical disorder? Seizures?
Tamara?
Tamara? Tamara?
She's not responding.
Could be a subclinical
seizure. Another two of Ativan.
Radiology says CT's
negative. Sats only 86.
- Okay, crank up the O2.
- Guys, she's hyponatremic.
Hypertonic saline, 25 cc's.
I don't keep that in here.
Go to the drug lockup.
- Go get it, then.
- I can't leave, I'm the only nurse.
- Guys, she's going apneic.
- Bag her through it.
- You guys need an extra hand?
- Where are the other nurses?
We're a little light. Seems
Santa sent half of them home.
Hey. You're out of here?
I'm a little nervous.
It's a honeymoon.
You're gonna have fun.
I'm not worried about that.
- Right, you hate to fly.
- It's not that either.
- I've got my Xanax and sleeping mask.
- So, what is it?
We're stopping at his parents'
for Christmas dinner before we go.
Ah. Do they know you're married?
- I heard Michael tell them on the phone.
- And?
Then I heard a dial tone.
- We need to confer.
- Confer?
I have some department chief
business to go over with you in lockup.
I'm checking LP
results for Clemente.
Clemente can wait.
- You guys seem cozy.
- Yeah.
- We're spending Christmas together.
- Really?
Look up. You got to kiss.
- Kiss?
- Britney and Madonna did it.
Perverts start young these days.
Hyponatremia is the
condition in which...
the sodium concentration of
the blood is abnormally low.
It does weird things to the
fluid balance of the body...
that can cause serious
problems, like seizures.
How did she get this?
Well, a lot of
things can cause it.
- Any vomiting, diarrhea?
- No.
- Do you take diuretics, laxatives?
Okay. Creatinine's normal.
Kidneys seem to
be working all right.
How long before I can go home?
Oh, you're not going home.
I mean, at least not tonight.
But I'm fine.
You need to be admitted.
I got two kids who are expecting
gifts under the tree tomorrow.
I understand, but we need
to work this up to find out...
why your sodium is so low. So
that this never happens again.
No. I can't do this to my kids.
So whose kitchen are
we dirtying up tomorrow?
Mm. I don't know. I hadn't
really given it much thought.
- Guess what I got you.
- Give me a hint.
Um...
- It's small.
- Small.
A necklace.
It's not jewelry.
Hey, our hyponatremia
lady is signing out AMA.
- She can't.
- Maybe you wanna come and stop her.
Okay. I'll be right out.
- Luka.
- Yeah. What?
You're gonna
love what I got you.
- You didn't get me anything.
- I did.
- No, you didn't...
- I did too.
- Keep guessing.
- All right, not jewelry. Spark plugs.
- Right.
- A glass frog.
- How did you know?
- Not even close?
- Listen, page me when you have a clue.
- Okay.
Just come over when you're done
with your mother's. I don't care how late.
You know, I got
a stocking for you.
Actually, I have two. They're
fishnets, and I'm gonna...
I gotta go, I'll call
you later. You're late.
I got tied up.
- Uh-huh. The phones still work.
- I had to drop my kid off at a friend's...
- and take care of personal stuff.
- Get in line. My linebacker called.
He was supposed to spend
the weekend. I think he's flaking.
- Linebacker, huh?
- He plays for Cincinnati.
- Our ice skater's back from Radiology.
- All right, I'll pick up her films.
Six-year-old female, GSW to abdomen.
Shallow resps, tachy at 150, BP 50 palp.
- Access? EMT:
I/O in the left tibia.
- It hurts.
- Please, you gotta help her.
Good breath sounds.
How'd this happen?
We were buying garlands
and a bullet came through.
- There's a dead guy at the scene.
- Mommy.
- Seven hundred cc's en route.
- What's her name?
- Danielle.
- Danielle, we're gonna fix you up, okay?
- Lost the carotid. No pulse. NADINE:
Does that mean...? Is she dying?
Satinksy.
Cross-clamping the aorta.
Four hundred cc NS bolus and
call for two more units of O-neg.
- Cordis introducer.
- Chest is dry.
Hold compressions.
Still no pulse.
Another epi, get
ready with atropine.
CBC, trauma panel,
type and cross for four.
Belly's full of blood.
Notify the O.R.
- Subclavian's in, treat it easy.
- Check for pulses with compressions.
She's got a carotid.
She needs a Foley.
O.R.'s ready.
I've got blood bank. Two units?
Make it four. Tell
them to rush it.
Hey, Chuny, page Olivia Evans.
She's at the social worker party.
See if she can come
down for this woman.
Eight candles.
And we get gifts with each one.
What the hell is Kwanzaa anyway?
Some made-up thing like Flag Day?
Who are you calling
made-up, fat boy?
Her husband is
okay with her leaving?
I get the impression she
generally makes the decisions.
I never heard that one before.
Repeat electrolytes
aren't even back yet.
- How about the UA?
- Well, it's normal.
But we still don't
know what the cause is.
Mrs. Gordon, you understand you'll
be leaving against medical advice?
Honey, why don't you go get
the car? I'll meet you out in front.
It's okay. Just go.
- You shouldn't go home yet.
- But I feel much better.
Hyponatremia is serious. You
need to stay here and be monitored.
I thought you had fixed
me with that saline stuff.
- No. The fix could be temporary.
- If your sodium falls again...
- you could have another seizure.
- Or worse.
It's Christmas.
Severe hyponatremia can cause a coma,
permanent brain damage, even death.
We got an MVA rolling in.
Ray, I'll meet you in a second.
Okay.
We need to figure out
why this is happening.
That's the only way
for us to help you.
You can't help me.
Three months ago, I went to
the doctor for a stomachache.
I walked out a cancer patient.
Ovarian.
I'm sorry.
Had already spread to
the liver and the lungs.
Five-year survival,
less than 5 percent.
All the more reason for you
to stay. You can't fight this...
if you don't take
care of yourself.
I don't wanna fight this.
Treatment means surgery,
chemo, months in a hospital bed.
I don't want that.
I don't want my kids
remembering me...
as this weak, bald, dying woman.
I can devote my
remaining time...
to some futile fight...
or to my family.
I'm choosing my family.
What does your husband want?
He doesn't know.
Look, after the
holidays, I'll tell him.
But right now, I'm going home.
- I already told you. It happened so fast.
- So no license plate, nothing?
- No.
- Why don't you give her a break?
- We'll call you if anything changes.
- Sure.
Thanks.
He asked me if I saw the
guy's face, and I didn't, so...
It's okay. It's okay.
They're stabilizing her. We
wanna get her to Surgery.
Oh, good. That's good.
And here are her things.
I told her Santa wouldn't bring her
anything unless she wrote it all down.
We're doing everything we can.
Neighborhood's
always been dangerous.
When I moved to New York, I
asked my mom to come live with us...
but she wouldn't.
Do you want me to call her?
Arrange to have her meet you here?
Her diabetes, she
can barely walk.
Well, is there someone
else? A friend or family?
My husband.
He's flying in tonight, but
he doesn't know about this.
Is there anything I can get you?
I should try Jason again.
Maybe I can catch
him on the layover.
Thanks.
This is Dr. Kovac from the ER
looking for a repeat sodium level...
- on a patient, Tamara Gordon.
- Dr. Kovac, are you auditioning today?
I'm not sure yet.
Hey, schizo. Mickey
Goldstein's labs are back.
What about you,
Dr. Clemente? Are you a singer?
Very nice. Abby's short on baked
goods, maybe you can help her out there.
Okay, good news.
All your blood tests came
back completely normal.
Yeah, bad news. I feel like
there's a truck parked on my spleen.
You can go home
now. Merry Christmas.
Wait a minute. What
about this terrible cough?
Don't worry. It's
probably just a little virus.
A virus? Well, can a
virus cause chest pain?
- What chest pain?
- A terrible massive pressure right here.
- Oh, the pain.
- Why didn't you tell the other doctor?
It just started a
little while ago.
You still stuffing that suit?
I went to buy
some kente cloth...
but the salesgirls used
it all to wipe themselves.
That's why I kicked your ass.
How did you guys get
started in this, anyway?
Some employee complained that our
company only celebrates Christmas.
So the boss decided to
throw a PC holiday party...
to show how we all get along.
That sounds like a plan.
Santa, how do you handle
one of those on your lap?
Oh, we break out the
big Santa for that one.
- That's enough.
- Maybe I should bring a leg tomorrow.
- If you don't stop, I'll shove a leg up...
- Eve.
You're a real nutcracker.
You wanna help
me jingle my bells?
Instead of pissing all
over everyone, piss in that.
I'm in too much pain to walk.
I need a urine sample now.
- Crit's 31.
- Hold compressions.
- Got a weak pulse.
- That's what I wanna hear.
Let's get a BP.
All right. Tube
position looks good.
- What's the delay?
- Surgery's here.
- Where's Dubenko?
- On vacation.
- I'm Dr. Albright. I'm covering for him.
- Bullet in upper quadrant.
Cross-clamp the aorta
for traumatic full arrest.
You told us an hour ago you were
redlining this patient to the O.R.
We got a team,
scrubbed and waiting.
- She hasn't been stable enough to move.
- We had no pulse.
Be discriminating
when you say "redline."
We hear it, drop everything,
and run to the O.R.
- You don't redline a pulseless patient.
- Important thing is she has a pulse now.
- So let's go.
- She's bradying down.
And we just lost that pulse.
Resume compressions.
You have a real
three-ring circus in here.
Dr. Albright, I don't think we've
met. I'm Dr. Weaver, chief of staff.
Oh, Dr. Weaver. I'm the
surgical chief resident.
Just got back
from a VA rotation.
Good for you. Epinephrine, 0.2.
Type-specific blood is up.
- Hang a unit.
- Call us when you know what's going on.
- I know what's going on.
- We can't hold the O.R. for a dead kid.
- She's not dead.
Uh-huh.
- What the hell?
- She's a bitch, but she's right.
Let's get the mom in here.
All right. I'm going
with an atrial line.
Fourteen-gauge
and four more units.
- Hey.
- Merry Christmas, doctors.
- Merry Christmas.
- You letting them go home?
- You saw her sodium level.
- She needs to be home.
She could develop
central pontine myelinolysis.
- She could start seizing again.
- We'll recheck her level in the morning.
She promised to come back
after her kids opened their presents.
You're not gonna believe this.
Joe just called. He wants to
spend Christmas at his mother's.
- That could be fun.
- Without me.
Well, maybe it's
a family tradition.
- You can spend New Year's together.
- I guess.
Isn't this cute?
Ray Charles, Stevie Wonder,
Roy Orbison, together at last.
What did you just say?
My bad. Roy Orbison wasn't
blind, he just wore the glasses.
You sit down. I'm not
gonna tell you again.
- You're ruining our performance.
- No, you guys sound great. Keep going.
And don't yell at me again, or you
won't see any gifts under the tree.
Oops! My bad. You
won't see them anyway.
Ho, ho, ho, you piece of crap.
Resume compressions. Another
atropine and stand by with epi.
She's had eight
rounds of meds, Pratt.
Bring her mom in.
Five more minutes. Cardiac line might
help us catch up with her blood loss.
I'm getting her now.
No, I'll go get her.
- Mrs. Hopkins.
- Is she okay?
I'll let you guys talk.
Would you like to come
in and see your daughter?
Are you finished?
- How is she doing?
- Danielle's condition is very serious.
But you're helping
her. I can see that.
We've given her fluids.
We've given her medicines.
We've even opened up her chest, but
her heart's just not beating on its own.
What are you saying?
- Nadine, please...
- No. Just go back in there and help her.
It'd be good for her
to have you there.
Just hearing your voice.
Okay?
Sats are not coming up.
- It's getting harder to bag her.
- Up the rate. Watch her pressures.
It's okay. You can get close.
Hey, sweetie.
You have been so strong today.
Is she responding
to the calcium?
We've given her medications
to try to restart her heart...
but nothing's working.
She's lost too much blood.
They've been working
real hard to keep you here.
Remember how I told you
God does things for a reason?
Well, maybe he just wants
you with him real bad right now.
I want you to know...
I want you to know
that it's okay to let go.
You see, God doesn't want you to be
in any pain, and neither does Mommy.
Daddy and I, we
love you so much.
We will always love you.
So don't be afraid.
Don't be afraid.
It's all right.
- Rate's coming up.
- She's got a pulse.
Epi infusion, 0.1 cc per kilo.
- What's happening?
- Her heart's beating.
Package her up. Let's go.
- I want her fired. SAM:
Things got a little out of hand.
- She poured pee on me.
- At least it was your pee.
You think that's funny?
These guys saw it.
Saw it? We can still smell it. What did
you have for lunch? Asparagus fries?
We didn't see it, Santa.
No, but you heard it.
Yeah. And it sounded
good, you fat bastard.
- Dr. Clemente.
- Yeah, what's up?
Nice going, Santa.
That nurse boss you got there
threw urine on me. I want her fired.
- Eve did what?
- Yeah. These guys were out of control.
Eve told them to be quiet,
but they wouldn't listen.
So she pours pee on me?
- I want her fired.
- Oh, crap.
Hey, you listening to me?
Dr. Clemente?
- Your East Coast squeeze is here.
- Just tell her I'm with a patient.
She's kind of a looker...
- in an interstate off-ramp kind of way.
- Please, Frank. Please, please.
Hey, I need some help with
this. Where are you going?
Take it to Kovac.
He's the boss, right?
I talked to the cops. The
store owner ID'd the kids.
He's seen them around before.
They're gonna pick them up.
You're supposed to be holding
a room open for my GSW.
Tell her this kid can't wait.
Yeah, I don't care.
The kid can't wait.
Her chest is open.
She's got a pulse.
Two minutes and that's it.
O.R.'s full. They'll
take her soon.
Now. They'll take my child now.
Move her to another hospital.
- She's not stable enough.
- Call Shriners, Children's.
If they don't call back within 2 minutes,
I'll take her up myself. I promise, okay?
What did...? How did it go?
- Remember Debbie Allen from Fame?
- Yeah.
Well, Haleh makes her
look like Mother Teresa.
Next!
- You punched a patient.
- He's lucky I didn't have a gun.
- You can get suspended.
- He's a moron.
He's a moron who
wants to call his lawyer.
Good, I'll punch him too.
Now, keep the splint dry.
Watch for any pain,
numbness, discoloration.
Remember, just because
Santa's reindeer can fly...
- doesn't mean you can, okay?
- Eve.
I'm busy. Walk with me.
- Eve, hold on.
- What?
You need to go over
there and apologize.
You want me to say sorry to some
jerk who was teasing blind kids?
I want you to apologize so
we can salvage this situation.
- And if I don't?
- You can lose your job.
You may have gotten a gold star
and become chief of the department...
but I hate to break it to you.
Only the nursing
supervisor can fire me.
Okay, well, you got no signs of
ischemia, or LVH or arrhythmias.
So, what have I got?
You've got absolutely
nothing wrong with you.
- What about the headache?
- What headache?
- The terrible pounding between my eyes.
- Pounding?
- Yeah. It keeps me awake all night.
- Mm-hm.
- And it's worse during the day.
- Right.
- I'm starting to smell something.
- Yeah, I smell something.
- Yeah, me too.
- What is that?
- Bull crap, maybe?
- Oh, jeez.
First you say it's your stomach,
then your heart, then your head.
Look, I just can't go home.
Well, you got no choice, okay?
I need these beds
for really sick patients.
Look, I need this bed.
Yeah, well, you've
wasted enough tax dollars.
Just go home to
your wife. Just go.
My wife died about
four years ago.
So you're tired of
spending Christmas alone...
watching Miracle on
34th Street by yourself?
Yeah, especially
in living color.
- Right.
- How long you gonna keep me waiting?
I got a patient here, okay,
Jodie? Please, do you mind?
Yeah. You're signing him out.
No, I'm not signing
him out. He's really sick.
He's got Ohniatis
Muchgotow. He got it in Brazil.
- Right, Mickey?
- Yeah, right, Brazil.
I never heard of that.
Because you're an ICU nurse, that's
why. And this is a toxicology problem.
In fact, he needs to be
admitted and watched tonight...
and especially tomorrow.
Haleh. Haleh, please.
- Yeah. I've called you 20 times.
- Right.
And I haven't answered
you back for a reason.
- What's up?
- That's why I'm here.
- Because I wanted to see you in person.
- Breathe normally.
Okay, go back.
Go back to Jersey.
Go back to your husband.
Just leave me alone.
My husband is not gonna
find me, so just relax.
Your husband's a cop,
okay? Don't tell me to relax.
Dr. Clemente, do you need me?
Haleh, yes, I do.
Mr. Goldstein needs to be signed
in and needs to be observed for...
- Systemic Ponderosa.
- What?
- What? You heard me.
Just write it down. I'll
explain it to you later.
Jodie, please.
Come on. Hurry up.
Have you witnessed
violent behavior before?
I never said she was violent.
Angry?
She's very good at her job.
- Today was just a hard day.
- Ms. Taggart...
Look, I don't feel comfortable
evaluating her. She's my boss.
That's part of management, Sam.
That's what everyone tells
me, but I don't understand...
why you can't just bring her in here
instead of talking behind her back.
I will talk to her, but we
believe in 360 evaluation here...
from supervisors,
peers and subordinates.
So I expect you to
be honest with me.
After she punched Santa and poured
the urine on him, what did she do?
She went to lunch.
Okay. Thank you for
your time, Ms. Taggart.
So, what happens now?
Well, this is grounds for
immediate termination.
Oh, come on. You can't
fire Eve on Christmas Eve.
Look, it was good between us,
okay? Actually, okay, it was great.
But that was for a while.
God, you look good.
You're married, which is something
you deliberately omitted when we first met.
- You knew.
- No, I didn't know.
Okay, at first, at first...
Okay, but you know what?
It doesn't matter now, because
I can't stop thinking about you.
Jodie. Jodie.
Jodie, stop it, stop it.
I want you to hop on the first
plane and get the hell out of here.
Before your husband
puts a bullet in my ass.
Just tell me the truth.
- Don't you miss it?
- Nope, not at all.
You never think about it?
You never think about us?
No, I don't think about us.
See, I think that whenever I
called, you wanted me to call.
- That's such bull.
- I think...
that whenever you heard my
voice, you sprung to attention.
Oh, come on.
Don't be ridiculous.
And you went into a room and
you saluted your little soldier.
- Big soldier.
- I know.
But, see, I'm here now, baby.
- Systolic's up to 83.
- The art line's a little hinky.
If the waveform looks
blunted, try repositioning.
This is probably
a waste of time.
But it's good for Residents and
students to get a look at young organs.
This is a child.
Keep that in mind.
I'll see you. They're
taking her up to Surgery.
Anesthesia will have some
more questions for you.
Danielle's a fighter. They're
gonna take good care of her.
- Nice work.
- Thanks.
- Hey.
- Hey. Is she gonna make it?
Not sure yet. Did they
find those shooters?
Still looking. I'll come back
later. I need to go out for a while.
Where are you going?
Come see.
When they find these jerks...
the cops should make them come
here, make them see what they've done.
- What's all this?
- It's a vigil for Danielle.
- But she's not dead.
- They're praying to keep her that way.
- Really?
- Really.
Not bad, Olivia. Not bad, baby.
Pratt. Our little girl bradied down
in the elevator, lost her pulse.
- Brought her back to Trauma 1.
- Tell them to keep praying.
Hey.
I just can't believe it.
On Christmas.
Yeah, I know. I'm so sorry.
I just tried so hard, you know.
Now it's all nothing.
You're gonna be fine.
Don't talk like that. You
know how hard it is out there.
Yeah, but you're experienced.
Hospitals are always looking
for good nurse managers.
What?
What are you talking about?
My boyfriend just dumped me.
Oh.
Wait a minute. What did you...?
Am I getting fired?
I didn't say that.
Answer me. Am I getting fired?
I gotta get back to work, okay?
What? Ugh.
Of course. What did I expect?
Come on. I'm setting
up a new life here.
I want as little drama as possible.
You can understand that, can't you?
Bobby hit me.
- What?
- Broke a rib.
I'm sorry, I didn't know,
but you didn't say anything.
Look, why didn't
you go to the police?
He is the police. All they would have done
is come over, give Bobby a high five...
and then had a beer
with him. I left him.
Vic, I'm not going back.
Now, I'm at the Marriott.
If you wanna call me, do.
And if you don't, then you
can have a nice holiday.
At least she's saving on long distance.
- Come on, Frank.
- Was that Jodie?
- How do you know her name?
She calls Frank about eight times
a day and I talk to her about three.
- That's great.
- Must have been.
- Your fly is down.
- Hey, Abby.
There's a snowplow
accident coming in.
I'm making Croatian bread and
a turkey. What are you cooking?
Cooking? Do you have amnesia
from the last time we dated?
I thought that little girl
was gonna die hours ago.
I guess she's not
ready to go yet.
- Is that them?
- We got confessions.
Thanks for bringing them.
- Hey, what are we doing here?
- Taking us to the morgue or something?
Somewhere even better. This way.
- What happened?
- She was fine until we tried to move her.
Holding compressions.
She's down on the
right. Tension pneumo.
Chest tube tray and
14 French for Dr. Pratt.
- I got the heart.
- What's happening?
Her lung collapsed. We're
inserting a tube to reinflate it.
- Nadine?
- They found them?
They're outside. Is it
okay if we bring them in?
I don't wanna be in here for
that. I need to see my daughter.
Go through there and wait in the
hall. I'll come and get you in a minute.
- Hey, nice shot, guys.
- We didn't shoot no girl.
You didn't mean to. Your bullet
went through that guy and landed here.
- No, dog.
- Yeah, dog, right into her belly.
Ripped through her liver, her
intestines and her spleen too.
Took out countless veins and arteries,
caused her abdomen to fill up with blood.
- We had to crack her chest open.
- Yo, get us out of here.
No, no, stay. Admire your
work. You know, your one shot...
is probably gonna kill this little girl.
And if she lives, well, think about it.
What if this was
your sister lying here?
Have to have her intestines removed and
crap into a bag for the rest of her life?
- Answer me.
- Come on, man.
While you're in jail, I want you to
remember what you did to this little girl.
And for what? A dime bag? Because
somebody looked at you wrong?
Let's get them out of here.
Her name's Danielle
Hopkins. She's 6 years old.
Hey. You got me fired?
I have nothing to do with you.
Check with the nursing supervisor.
She said I had to clear out within
two hours. You know it's Christmas?
You'll be missed.
- Bite me.
- Don't make me call security.
No, it's fine, I'm leaving on my own.
But I tried to do something good here.
I tried to elevate
this stupid ER.
Instead of getting praise, I
get fired on Christmas Eve?
- Screw yourselves. You all suck.
- Come on, calm down.
Oh, you, behind my
back, trying to get my job.
Merry Christmas, Judas.
They've controlled the
bleeding. Vitals are good.
Looks like she's
gonna pull through this.
Always wanted a girl.
Thought it would
be easier, safer.
Those guys are gonna
pay for what they did.
I don't want them to
pay. I want them to stop.
We turn our backs on these
kids, we don't educate them...
and then we wonder
why this happens.
People have choices.
Some people don't know they do.
- Is it over?
- Not bad for your first shift.
- You cleared the board and an employee.
- I had no choice.
Yep. I gotta go get
Henry. I'll see you at Ike's.
Hey, what's up?
Nothing.
I'm gonna go play my game.
Thank you so much for having
a play date on Christmas Eve.
I can take them on
New Year's if you want.
You know, Sam, I don't think so.
Why, what's wrong?
Is there a problem?
Alex keeps telling
Willie his father's dead.
- That's not true.
- And now he's telling Willie...
his dad's gonna die too.
I'm sure he's
just joking around.
Sam, Alex needs help.
Until you get that for him, I'd
prefer he not hang out with Willie.
- Heather...
- I'm sorry.
Anything I can do?
Thanks, I got it.
Alex?
What's up?
Why did you tell Willie
that your father is dead?
Hey. Answer me.
I don't need him, so
that's like being dead.
Come on. Your dad has problems,
but he loves you, you know that.
- I know you love him.
- If he loved me, he'd call.
He can't call you, Alex.
- But he misses you.
- No, he doesn't.
You're just lying for him.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- What's this?
- Part of your present.
Open it.
Wow.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
This... This beats
what I got you.
Open yours.
- A compass?
- I know it's corny, but...
it seems we always
find each other.
It's beautiful.
Can we talk?
Yeah, sure.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Maybe go outside for a minute?
Okay.
- I don't know how to say this.
- What?
Well, It's just that these past
three weeks have been really...
You know, I couldn't
have imagined it better.
- For me too.
- Yeah. And I haven't laughed so much...
or felt so good in a really long time. I
don't wanna do anything to ruin that.
- Hey, you won't, I promise.
- Look, Luka.
Yeah?
Oh, man.
- What?
- I'm pregnant.