Doctors practice
deception all the time.
We give vague answers
to hard questions.
We don't talk
about post-op pain.
We say you'll experience
some discomfort.
John Driscoll. White male, 62.
Alzheimer's diagnosed
eight months ago.
Patient number one
of Alzheimer's
NGF Clinical Trial.
If you didn't die,
we tell you the
surgery went well.
But the placebo has to be
the doctor's greatest deception.
OK, you're gonna hear a...
little drilling sound.
How you doing, John?
- OK.
- Great. You're doing great.
All right. Envelope, please.
Half of our patients,
we tell the truth.
The other half, we pray
the placebo effect's real.
OK, John, we're gonna
insert the probe now.
And we tell ourselves that
they'll feel better anyhow,
believing help's on
the way, when, in fact...
we're leaving them to die.
You have to say something.
Words. Make words.
- Holy crap.
- Yup.
- A baby?
- Growing like a weed. In my uterus.
Not like a weed.
Like a mighty oak.
We're gonna be great parents.
- Mark, you don't have to do...
- Are you kidding?
That's my kid in there.
I'm a dad.
We're parents.
Of a baby.
- OK! You're in.
- Should we get married?
Oh, no.
I mean, I'm all for raising
a baby with you, but...
there's a line.
You're right. That's good.
'Cause I'm in love with
Lexie and it would be...
Oh, my God... Lexie.
What am I gonna tell Lexie?
OK, you think about that.
Are you ready to talk now?
I want to say some not nice
things, and I want you to listen
without saying our relationship
is over or walking out.
OK.
I'm mad that you slept
with someone else.
And I know that we
were broken up, but still,
you slept with someone else.
And I'm even madder that
that person has a penis.
And I know you're
bisexual. I know that, but...
Would you rather I'd slept
with a busty redhead? 'Cause...
You have to give me a
chance to process this, OK?
- I'm processing!
- I didn't plan this.
OK?
I... I didn't plan any of this.
But there's a...
mighty oak or whatever
showing up in our lives
in about seven months.
So now I have to plan.
And I don't know how long I
can wait for you to process.
But I...
I want you in my plan. I want
you to be a part of my plan.
So... Are you in? Are you out?
Oh, God...
I'm in.
I'm in. But you have
to give me... You...
I'm just... I'm still
so mad at you,
so you have to give me a minute.
OK.
By injecting methylene blue, it's
easier to identify the structures.
What do you see, doctor?
Gall bladder, cystic duct,
common bile duct.
Yes. Misidentification
of the anatomy
is the main cause
of biliary tree injuries.
Today we're trying
this new technique...
Put those things away, people!
No texting in my OR.
Save that for the drive home.
Um... Actually,
we're not texting, sir.
Dr. Bailey's performing a
Toupet procedure right now.
There wasn't enough room in her
OR so we're just following it on Twitter.
Twitter?
What the hell is a Twitter?
I booked the OR, I read up on the procedure...
I know this thing better than my own name...
I pre-rounded on the patient
and her pre-op labs are all done...
Quadruple bypasses
are exciting, right?
First assist gets to sew
all the grafts onto the heart?
Plum job!
- I want it.
- It would be an honor.
I know. You're thinking
whoever does this gets a leg up
in the race for chief resident.
But you wanna know a
good way not to get it?
That's to bug the crap out of
me before my day even starts.
I'm sorry. I'll back off.
Actually, I'll go
to the skills lab
and practice my grafts.
And you just let me know
if you need anything at all...
Yang took the chart. She
took the chart? What...?
- What did Arizona say?
- Well, she said she's in.
- That's good, right?
- I'm still hedging my bets.
I'm not gonna move back in with her until
I know for sure she's not gonna bail again.
- Hey, you got
dinner plans tonight?
- No.
I'm cooking for you
tonight. Your place.
I rocked a lap chole.
So, when are you gonna tell her?
Not until after my
home-cooked meal.
Mark, you do not
have to do this.
I'm giving you a Get Out of
Jail Free card. No hard feelings.
You can be the cool uncle
that hangs out on Sundays.
I'm not the cool
uncle. I'm the dad.
You love Lexie, and
the last time a Sloan kid
appeared in Seattle,
she dumped you.
Now if you were
the cool uncle...
I'm not the cool uncle!
Don't ever say that again!
- OK!
- This is my kid. I want this kid.
- Cool uncle...
- Well, so tell her.
Do not wait until this kid
comes out looking all Sloan-y.
- You didn't say
goodbye this morning.
- I had a surgery.
- I didn't want to wake you.
- No. You were starting
your clinical trial
and you feel guilty
that I'm not on it,
- so you snuck out.
- You're right.
But I don't feel guilty
and I didn't sneak out.
Patient number two, Daniel
Cobb, admitted and in a room.
His wife has some
questions for you.
I... can't believe...
He picked you for this
thing instead of me?
Well, Dr. Shepherd didn't
wanna leave anything to chance.
- Now you can both go to hell.
- It was open to all
the residents.
Karev just did a better
job of pitching me.
It was open to all the
residents except for one!
- You having a good day, Daniel?
- Yes, I am, Dr. Shepherd.
Give me that new wonder
drug of yours, I'll be even better.
If it came down to how much I
liked the patient, you'd be a shoo-in.
Now, if Daniel gets the drug,
how soon will he stop
slipping in and out of things?
Well, at this stage we don't know
any more than you do, Mrs. Cobb.
That's why we're gonna
do a two year follow-up.
And the idea that his condition
could be reversed altogether,
is that completely
out of the question?
'Cause I just read that when the
drug was used on rats and monkeys
there was some
reversal in tissue damage.
That's rats and monkeys. It
can be different for humans.
Well, I don't want to rule
out a reversal altogether,
but right now we're trying
to stop the progression.
All right, Dr. Karev is gonna
take you down for an MRI later.
So if you have any more
questions today, page him.
I'm feeling better
already, Dr. Shepherd.
- Here we go!
- Here we go.
A clinical trial's a little
different than a regular surgery.
You can paint a rosier picture.
I didn't want to give
them false hope.
You didn't give them any hope.
Look, if Mrs. Cobb thinks this is
gonna give her husband a better
chance, she'll be a better caregiver.
And in the end, he has a
better chance of success. OK?
- Yes, sir.
- Good.
- Is that all you're having?
- Yeah, I think so.
Chief, this is my
milk shake time.
Milk shake time is not a thing.
You didn't bother to tell me that
you were broadcasting surgeries.
Oh, I didn't think
it'd be a big deal.
Well, it is. What if
something goes wrong?
Look, the patients who want to
do it sign a comprehensive release.
And the nice thing is,
most of them want to do it.
They're excited about
being on the cutting edge.
Until they code on the table
in front of the whole world.
In which case I'd stop tweeting.
In the meantime, residents
from all over the country
get to see a surgeon's
decision-making process.
They get to ask questions
live. It's a great teaching tool.
No, it's lawyer bait.
Shut it down, Dr. Bailey.
Sir, if you understood
it, you'd be on board.
- I understand it fine.
- Uh-huh.
- I understand it, Dr. Bailey.
- If you say so.
I do say so.
Don't give me Bailey-eyes.
I'll look into this Tweeter
thing. But no promises.
Does this mean I get to
tweet in the meantime?
No, it means give me
a chance to look into it.
Hi. What's going on?
How's your day going so far?
Good. I've got a CABG later
this morning with Avery and Yang,
who have officially entered
into the rabid dog stage
in the race for chief resident, which
could be a good thing or it could be...
a bad thing, which... You really aren't
interested in my day at all, are you?
I might be having
Mark Sloan's baby.
Oh, good Lord,
he got to you, too?
Callie is pregnant
with Mark's kid.
It's while we were... you know.
I love Callie, and Mark, you know,
is human and clearly has good genes
because he's both
pretty and smart.
And I want to have
a kid, but with Callie.
I'm not sure that I want to
have Callie's kid with Mark.
Can you say something to me that'll
make me wanna have Callie's kid with Mark?
Um...
I gotta go.
What happened?
- I might be miscarrying.
- You're not miscarrying.
- Then it's an ectopic.
- Could it be a blighted ovum?
It's not a molar
pregnancy, is it?
Wow. We got a lot
of doctors in the room.
Who the hell are you and
what are your credentials?
Lucy Fields, Harvard MD,
Duke OB-GYN resident,
and now a Maternal-Fetal Medicine
fellow at Seattle Grace Mercy West.
Damn good at my job.
Who the hell are you?
We're related to the...
- situation.
- Lesbian lover, baby daddy.
Ah. And everybody's
a little wigged out.
OK. So...
There's your baby.
There's the yolk sac...
Looks good. You're good.
- I'm bleeding...
- It's not uncommon.
Happens in around 30
percent of all pregnancies.
- It's probably fine.
- I don't see a heartbeat.
- Where's the heartbeat?
- It's probably too early
for that.
I'll do blood work, but I'm
pretty sure everything's OK.
Just take it easy for the next
few days. Drink a lot of water.
- No tampons, no intercourse.
- Sing it.
Call me if the bleeding
gets worse or if there's pain.
Otherwise, go live your life.
All of you. While you still can.
Martha Elkin, 75, multivessel coronary
disease confirmed by angiography.
Here this morning
for an off-pump CABG.
That's just doctor speak
for a quadruple bypass.
- Thank you.
- Pre-op labs and
X-rays were normal.
OK, you're ready
to roll, Martha.
My husband went
down for some coffee.
He wanted to know how long
I'd be asleep after the procedure.
Well, Martha, it's hard to tell.
Every patient
reacts differently,
but we'll keep him posted.
Most patients wake
within 90 minutes.
Oh, that's helpful, dear.
He'll be glad to know
that. We're both so nervous.
Well, some anxiety is
completely normal, but...
let me reassure you...
Dr. Altman is an
incredibly talented surgeon.
You're in the
very best of hands.
Martha, I'd like to give you
my cellular telephone number.
Now, you or your husband,
if you have any questions,
if he gets a little worried
or wants an update,
then he can call this number.
I'll even make sure to
have a nurse answer
- if we're in the OR.
- Oh, you're wonderful.
You all are!
This is the finest patient
care that I have ever seen.
I feel like a VIP.
Well, it's just what we do.
Hey. How long you
gonna be in there?
I've gotta put on a localizing
frame. At least an hour.
- An hour?
- Yeah, give or take.
Dr. Shepherd wants me to
be as thorough as possible.
No! I'm not doing
this without my wife!
- Sir...
- No!
- Mr. Cobb,
your wife is right here.
- That's not my wife!
- Mrs. Cobb... Look, it's your wife.
- That's not Victoria.
Daniel... Daniel,
Daniel, Daniel... It's me.
You're not Victoria.
You're not my wife.
You're not Victoria. I want
Victoria! I want my wife!
- It's Allison.
- Get away from me!
- Sir, who is your wife?
- I don't know.
- Sir...
I told you. It's
Victoria. I want Victoria.
Is she here?
- No.
- Do you know where she is?
- I... I don't know.
- OK. OK. I...
Well, I'm gonna go
find Victoria for you. OK?
I'm gonna go look for her. I'm
gonna find her and bring her to you.
- You sit tight. I'll find Victoria.
- OK... OK.
Do you know who Victoria is?
Victoria is the woman he loves.
They met at the home last year.
One day he asked me to wheel
her towards him and that was it.
I watched him fall
in love with her.
- Well, Ben and I watched.
- You're Victoria's husband?
Until she leaves me.
She's not gonna leave you, Ben.
We'll see.
Victoria was diagnosed
with vascular dementia.
It's not Alzheimer's,
but it might as well be.
She's like Daniel.
When she's lucid, she
knows I'm her husband.
When she's not, I go from
being her husband to...
somebody that gets to hear
about Daniel all the time.
Daniel can still be
in the trial, can't he?
This doesn't mean
he can't do it?
No, he can still do it. The rule for
the study is we need his consent.
Once we have it, it's OK
if he's not always lucid.
You don't have any
more openings, do you?
Unfortunately, the trial is
only for Alzheimer's dementia.
There's no chance?
I'm sorry.
This is seriously jacked-up.
Mayo Clinic says "Good luck".
Cleveland Clinic sent you a
whole bunch of smiley faces.
And there's a resident from Sydney,
Australia joining us for the first time.
- Yay, Sydney.
- Turn it off, Grey. Chief's orders.
But this is Mr. Windsor's
third operation.
Everyone wants to
know how it comes out.
Until I get the OK from the chief, we're
not even gonna tweet the time of day.
It's not like the chief even reads
tweets. It's not like he'll know.
Drop it, Kepner.
I understand. He's the boss.
And I'm sure that
he's got his reasons,
but you've also got
3,000 residents out there
who have been by
your side this whole time.
Through a couple of very
difficult, time-consuming,
life-threatening operations.
And now to tell them,
"forget it," just like that?
It's like...
It's like turning off
the TV when Clarice
is knocking on the
door of the house.
It's silencing the lambs!
And the lambs wanna
scream, Dr. Bailey.
The lambs wanna scream.
- The man would never know.
- No. No, the man would not.
Wanna know what's really
fun and not at all depressing?
Alzheimer's research.
Callie's having my baby.
- What?
- Right?
Best news of my life.
At least it would be,
except for the fact
that Lexie wants a baby about
as much as she wants a root canal.
I guess I could tell her
I'm the baby's uncle.
But I don't want to
be the cool uncle.
The cool uncle's only
cool until the kid's like nine,
and then the cool
uncle's just creepy.
I'm the dad. I want this.
And I want Lexie.
What do I do? You're
the man with the answers.
What do you think?
How can Meredith and I try for
months and not have any luck,
and you look at somebody
and a baby appears?
The Sloans are
unusually fertile.
You're the classic
example of failing up.
Not exactly the advice
I was looking for.
Well, you got it. Cheers.
- Is she OK?
- Yep.
- Maybe.
- I said yep. Yep is not maybe.
- It's yep.
- She paged us.
I paged you. Callie
hasn't left the exam room
since you were last
here. Two hours ago.
What if it is a molar pregnancy?
Or fetal demise.
Or an infection?
She doesn't seem to want to leave
the exam room until we rule out,
- what, everything?
- Well...
- Callie.
- I'm bleeding!
I don't wanna take any
chances with this baby!
All right, what if
we run a culture.
Just in case. Can't hurt, right?
- Sure. Can't hurt.
- Good idea?
He followed me
through a snowstorm.
- Sorry?
- In college.
Daniel saw me in
the student union
and he followed me to my class
in a snowstorm.
Introduction to French Poetry.
It was in this big lecture
hall and he sat there
for an hour and a half,
twice a week for five months,
just trying to get up
the nerve to meet me.
That was 40 years ago.
Please...
give my husband the drug.
- Mrs. Cobb...
- You could do it
if you wanted to.
You know that you could.
No, I couldn't. It's
completely random.
The computer decides.
We don't even know if he's getting
the drug until we're about to inject it.
Then change it if you need
to. I need my husband back.
I need Daniel back.
I'm sorry, I just...
Even if the drug worked,
it's not gonna reverse things.
But I can live with that.
I can live with what
we have right now.
I can live with being
a part-time wife.
But I cannot live...
with losing my
husband all the way.
So...
for God's sake...
give him the drug.
Please.
Day one and this
thing already blows.
We got one guy begging
us to get his wife on the trial.
Then this other guy's wife wants
me to steal the drug for her husband.
Well, you're the one who wanted
in on the trial of the century.
With peds, the problem's
right in front of you:
sick kid, worried parents.
Here, you got a sick parent
who doesn't even
know they're sick.
Well, about five years ago,
I was visiting my mother.
And she starts telling me how
she thinks she's got herpes.
And how she doesn't want to go
to the hospital and get checked out
because she's afraid
everybody will know.
So, I realize that
she thinks I'm her best
friend from med school,
and it's 35 years ago.
So... I had to just sit there
and talk to my mother
about her possible herpes
for two hours. Two
very long hours.
I couldn't cure her Alzheimer's,
but at least I could give her
what she needed in that moment.
- Advice about herpes?
- Advice about herpes.
You may want to put
all that away, Mrs. Elkin.
They're gonna come take
you to the OR any minute.
- I don't think
it's such a good idea.
- What? The surgery?
Well, it's risky, isn't it?
I mean, it's a five percent
chance of mortality?
Yes, but...
that's a 95 percent
chance of success.
Those are good odds.
I've had such a wonderful life.
My friend, Donna, she had a
big operation like this, and...
she was never the same.
Nursing home. Couldn't
even feed herself.
It was terrible. The poor kids,
it was so hard on them.
Such a burden. I don't want
to do that to my children.
I know it's scary.
And it can go wrong sometimes.
But you could
have 20 more years.
You could go to
this baby's wedding.
Are you sure you
want to give that up?
If you walk out of here right
now, you could have a few months.
Maybe a year.
But you'll always be wondering
when you're gonna go.
And your family...
they'll always be
watching you, terrified.
Don't give up on yourself.
Let us help you.
- Will you be there?
- Every step of the way.
OK. I'll do it.
You'll be great.
Unbelievable. You think you're
gonna be able to do the grafts
because the patient's
requesting you?
Altman doesn't exactly
fall for that kind of crap.
Believe it or not, not everything
I do is about competition.
Yeah, as if.
911 means you're dying!
Somebody has to be dying!
Well, what if the
baby was dying?
There's nothing
wrong with the baby.
Or you. You can't page me in a
panic every time you have a feeling!
Don't yell at me!
I am a hormone casserole.
My body is not my own.
And something feels wrong.
- Is it muscular?
- No, it's a feeling in my gut.
- In your uterine gut?
- No, my metaphorical gut!
Thanks.
Arizona says she's still in, but
she said that before, and then...
she left.
I don't think she's
going anywhere.
She loves you, Torres.
What about Lexie? What
are you gonna do about her?
She's your soul
mate or something,
and she's gonna
freak the hell out!
Everything in my life
is always a disaster!
I really don't want
this to be a disaster!
I don't even want
to move or breathe.
I don't wanna do nothing!
What if I do something
and it messes this baby up?
Martha Elkin's blood
pressure was slightly elevated,
but I let her rest and I retook it and
it's fine, so it should be no problem.
And Tweedle Dum is here, too.
Charts are updated.
Have you decided who's
gonna be first assist?
Why would I decide now?
Patient care has never been better.
I mean, once I choose,
one of you is just
gonna be skulking around
like a surly teenager.
OK, this should
be an easy choice.
I have been practicing these graft
attachments every day for a month.
- Some of us
don't need to practice.
- Sure, Yang.
You've got more experience
overall, but these last couple months
you haven't exactly logged a
lot of hours in the OR, have you?
That's not...
You really had to go
there? You're that insecure?
No.
Just that much of an idiot.
Damn it.
Can I help you with
something there, Chief?
I'm trying to look at
Bailey's teats on the Internet.
- I think you mean
"tweets," sir.
- Whatever.
No, not whatever.
It's important you get
that one right. Let me try.
Bailey's putting her
surgeries on the Internet
for the whole world to
see. I told her I'd look into it,
but I think it's
a terrible idea.
I dunno. Might be a good
way to reach students.
Or it might be Bailey bragging
to the world about Bailey.
This thing isn't
designed for medicine.
It's designed for gossip.
For now. But look at GPS. It
was designed for the US military
to keep an eye on
foreign troop movements.
Now it's in everyone's car.
You know, you go out. You
never have to get lost again.
Yeah, I don't go out.
Let's save that
conversation for next time.
There you go.
Bailey's Twitter page.
Looks like she's tweeting
a surgery right now.
What?!
So that's why we also had
to do a left hemicolectomy.
Um...
Here's a question from...
Dr. Bailey, I specifically told
you not to tweet your surgeries
- until I looked into it.
- I'm sorry, Chief,
I misunderstood.
I thought you said I could
tweet until you decided.
Don't play dumb. That's not
what I said and you know it.
Put away that little toy.
He's hemorrhaging.
The blood's coming from... I
don't know where it's coming from.
OK, hold on. Let's see...
Yeah, we've got a
pseudoaneurysm in the splenic artery.
How did that... What happened?
Pancreatic enzymes are
leaking into the abdomen.
They're dissolving the
blood vessels. Clamp.
You need to get the
spleen out of there.
I'm already on it. Clamp.
Anyone see any more bleeding?
No, but what's left of the
pancreas is still leaking.
We need to take
out that whole thing.
It's one thing to live
with half a pancreas,
but to remove the whole
thing... His life's gonna be hell.
Grey, put that damn thing away!
This is exactly what
I was talking about.
- Grey...
- It's Walter Reed.
They suggest an islet
cell autotransplant?
That's for pancreatitis. You
don't do it with trauma patients.
What is it exactly?
You isolate the cells
from the pancreas
and inject them into the
liver. They trick the liver
into acting like a pancreas
and making insulin.
Yeah, when it works. You
need an awful lot of cells.
You know, just because
it isn't done for a trauma
- it doesn't mean...
- I know. But even if we wanted to,
we don't have the
equipment to extract cells.
You need a Ricordi chamber.
We don't have it, but
Northwestern does.
How do you know?
They can get it on a plane and
have the equipment here in six hours.
- It's too late. He's too unstable.
- OK. Hold on.
Denver... Tacoma
Methodist. Yes! They've got it.
Tacoma...
We take out the pancreas.
I get on the helicopter
to Tacoma with it.
I'm back in 90 minutes.
You manage in the meantime.
- Let's do it.
- OK. Tell them.
She's wigged out, OK. Now she
won't say anything. I think it's my fault.
- What did you do?
- We were busting
each other's balls,
we both wanted the same surgery,
and I may have said something
about her... flaming out.
Hey. Hey.
- I want Owen.
- Go find him!
What the hell...?
He's gonna be running
around for the next hour
while I sew grafts on
a quadruple bypass.
Owen's at the dentist.
He'll be hard to find.
- You are evil.
- He started it.
Now this is the
hard-core machine.
- Highest resolution there is.
- Thank you.
Now, it's almost impossible to find
a heartbeat until the eighth week,
even with this thing.
In fact, I don't even have moms
come in until the eighth week
because they come in,
they don't see a heartbeat
and they freak out and they
camp out on my exam table all day.
But since you've already
camped out here all day,
it can't hurt to have
another look, right?
- How's he holding up, Dr. Knox?
- PH is good. He's normothermic. Stable.
Um, uh...
A resident at Hopkins wants to
know why they don't normally do
islet cell autotransplantation
in a trauma patient?
But we're not tweeting, so...
Um...
In a trauma, the pancreas
is usually too damaged.
- You can't get enough cells.
- OK.
Um...
I got another
question. From Emory.
Go ahead.
Will you use the portal vein
to inject the islet
cells into the liver?
Yes, but it's a little tricky.
The portal vein is
partially dissolved
because of the enzymes.
Cool! Good answer.
Oh, this is a message for you.
It says, "Hi, Chief Webber.
Dr. Neil Lefkoff.
University of Miami.
I was a resident at Seattle
Grace eight years ago.
It's a pleasure to be
scrubbing in with you again, sir".
Neil? Really?
Well, I'll be...
OK, we've placed the Octopus
Tissue Stabilizer. Now what?
Dissect out the
LAD, nick the artery,
put in a shunt and put the
graft in distal to the blockage.
OK, good. Go for it.
Dr. Avery. Nice of
you to finally join us.
And, before we had these machines,
we used to mince up the pancreas
and spin it ourselves. Dr. Ellis Grey
taught me how to do that 20 years ago.
- She would take the...
- OK, slow down, Chief.
I can only do 140
characters at a time.
She had this trick where
after the final washing, she...
Oh, man, what was
it? It was classic Ellis.
What... What was it?
Forget it, put a pin in it.
Anyway, she would take... We'd
put the minced up pancreas...
- Nice. What do we do next?
- Check the flow in the graft.
All right, Mr. Cobb.
Everything is looking good.
- How's he doing?
- Stable. Not acidotic
or hypothermic.
- How many cells did you get?
- Three hundred thousand.
- Is that enough?
- Normally you want
about a million,
but it's better than nothing.
- Nothing?
- Just give me a minute.
- This was a bad idea.
- Callie.
That was stupid. She said it's
too early, she can't find it yet.
Doesn't mean a dead baby, it
just means it was really stupid.
Shut up.
There.
Oh, my God.
- OK, we're almost there.
- Can I have the envelope?
OK, Daniel, I'm gonna
insert the probe now.
Very good, Mr. Cobb.
Honey?
Hey, how you feeling?
I'm OK. I've got
a slight headache.
Where's my Victoria?
Can I see her?
Oh.
Mrs. Cobb, he just
came out of surgery.
Look, this doesn't
mean it's not gonna work.
We won't know that for a while.
When he acts like this,
you just need to tell yourself
this is not your husband.
But he is somebody
who needs your help.
So whatever you can give him.
Daniel...
I'm gonna call Victoria...
and get her here as
soon as I can. OK?
Thank you.
Karev.
I couldn't have done
it any better myself.
You reassured her. You got her
to focus on what was important.
- I'm off the trial.
- What?
It's too depressing. I can't
handle this for the next two years.
- You just handled it.
- No. That was Meredith talking.
She told me what to say. She's
been saving my ass all day.
You need to get over this thing where
you're just thinking of her as your wife.
Because your wife is the only person
twisted enough to handle this crap.
Oh, that said, I'm in the
race for chief resident.
And so far, I'm kicking ass.
So I'd appreciate it if you mentioned
to Dr. Webber that I prioritized
the patient's needs
over my personal gain.
Take care of her.
Any time, Martha, any time.
Bite me, Yang.
Chief, I just wanted to update
you on Anthony Windsor.
- Anthony...?
- Windsor.
- Our pancreas patient.
- Oh, yeah, right, right.
- What's all this?
- This is Ellis Grey's
old journals.
I'm trying to find the
answer to a thing...
Well, anyway, the islet cells
have started producing insulin.
It looks like the
transplant's gonna take.
That's great, great.
Excellent work, Dr. Bailey.
OK, sir, I'm doing a robotic
subtotal gastrectomy tomorrow.
Now, I know you wanted time...
That's fine.
Absolutely. Tweet away.
Yeah! Yes, yes...
There it is! OK...
She would add
heparin and aprotinin.
Now when you're
tweeting tomorrow,
tell everyone that Ellis Grey's
trick was to add those, OK?
- Make sure you tell them that.
- Yes, sir.
What are you doing?
Is that one of my boxes?
Don't get up. You rest.
You shouldn't be lifting
any heavy things. I got this.
No, I'll get up if I want to. Are
you moving my stuff back in?
- Callie.
- I haven't said
I'm moving back in yet.
I... We're not together.
You can take those
back to Mark's place.
Shut up. Just shut up.
You don't get to tell me
that we're not together.
We are together. Because
I love you and you love me,
and none of the
rest of it matters.
We are together.
And if you ever sleep
with anyone else again,
man or woman, I will
kick the crap out of you.
Now you sit your
ass back down there
because that's my baby in there,
and I don't want anything
happening to my baby!
Your baby, huh?
Our baby.
There was a heartbeat.
- Mm-hmm.
- And it was...
We're having a baby.
Do I still have to sit down?
Because I'd rather rip your clothes off.
I'll do the ripping. You rest.
Doctors practice
deception every day.
On our patients.
On their families...
I'm putting in tarragon.
Not that I have any idea
what tarragon tastes like,
but I think when
people use tarragon,
it makes them seem like
they know what they're doing.
Basil can't do that.
Anybody can sling some
basil around the kitchen.
- Callie's pregnant.
- Oh, my God!
That's great. She loves babies.
Did they do a turkey baster
thing or something? I mean...
Wait a minute. OK, so wait...
Arizona just got
back, and they...
were they doing...? Wait,
was this before they...?
I saw the heartbeat today.
This is my kid.
This is a part of me.
Please, is there any
way that we can...
How the hell...
did you get me in
this position twice?!
It's...
unbelievable.
You are unbelievable!
But the worst deception
we practice is on ourselves.
My next Alzheimer's
surgery is tomorrow at seven.
Put your name on the board.
Which is why sometimes it
takes us a while to realize...
that the truth has been in
front of us the whole time.