Kerry. I'm gonna put a fresh
towel on the sink for you.
Okay, thank you.
What time does your shift start?
Uh... 9.
Oh. Yeah, you better hurry up.
Do you want some coffee?
Sure, thanks.
Okay.
That looks good on you.
What? My blouse.
Oh, yeah. It's not too long?
No.
It's a good thing I have
a 40-gallon water heater.
What?
You take long showers.
I'm sorry. Oh...
No. No. So do I.
Sometimes I have to stand
under there for 20 minutes...
just to wake up when it's cold.
Especially in winter.
Is it cold outside? Low 20s.
Do you want a bagel? No, thanks.
You know, I gotta... I'll
get something at work.
You okay?
Yeah, um, I got it. I got it.
No, I... I meant about us.
First time can be a little...
No. It's just...
It's just different.
That's true.
But good. Really?
Yeah.
I'll see you at work.
Yeah. Okay.
I'll see you later. Mm.
Hey, um...
I'm sorry, but I... I
know this is understood,
but I just...
This is just gonna
be between us, right?
Of course.
I'll get the door.
Open a GAI-50 and a
TA-55 on the resection.
No need, Peter.
I gave it to Henderson. What?
Page us if the CAT
scan shows free air.
Come on. Let's go.
Where are we going?
I got a chore for you.
You know what?
I'm a little busy.
Yeah, so am I. Let's go.
So, Peter...
how is this, uh, per diem
situation working out for you?
Could be a lot better.
Really? What's the problem?
Where are we going?
Are you, uh,
dissatisfied in some way?
Besides being grossly underpaid?
Ah. Well, would a
$10,000 a year raise
and a limited benefit
package help?
What? Okay. Let's
make it 20,000.
Final offer. And you'll have
to take on administrative work.
You're serious? Yeah.
Look, you've been, uh...
You've been doing your penance,
working hard, displaying
dedication and groveling.
I'd be a complete sadist if
I didn't ease up eventually.
What do I have to do?
A little of this and that.
It won't take you more
than a few hours a month.
What's in it for you?
Okay, fine, forget it.
Go back to Surgery.
Hey, I'm just asking.
Whoa. Do you want
the bump or don't you?
Sure.
So we have a deal?
Yeah.
Okay. Let's go.
This way, please.
Sorry for the delay.
Dr. Benton had to finish
a complicated surgery on a
gunshot wound to the abdomen.
Come on in, Peter. Don't be shy.
Come on, come on.
Okay. Now, as you are all aware,
we at the county level
are very concerned about
the declining numbers
of minority medical school
students and faculty physicians.
Not only here in
Chicago, but nationwide.
The medical school is
committed to addressing this issue.
As part of that
commitment, I am appointing
a Director of Diversity
for the medical center:
Dr. Peter Benton.
Dr. Benton's bio and
résumé can be found
in your handout materials.
So... he's all yours.
Dr. Benton,
is your appointment
the direct result
of the investigative report
about the declining numbers
of African-Americans being
admitted to medical school?
I, uh...
Well, I mean,
you know, it, uh...
It-it could be a part of it.
How can you ensure
minority representation
at the medical school in this
post-affirmative action era?
- Is he drinking?
- Just water.
He had a little rice
three days ago.
Did you start an IV?
We can't without a court order.
Call Dr. Samson.
Dr. Samson doesn't
work here anymore.
What? Dr. Miller
treats your cousin now.
Fine. Call him.
Well, that's probably not
necessary since you're here.
Why's that?
I think he's just lonely.
Can you get me a, uh...
A protein shake or something?
Huh.
Hey, Chase.
It's John.
You mind if I sit down?
Hey, I'm, uh, sorry
that I haven't been
around here very much.
I've been busy.
For a year?
You're right.
You're right. That's
not an excuse.
Hey, your speech sounds good.
You been, uh...
getting around much?
No.
Here you go.
Oh, thank you.
You know, you gotta
eat something, Chase.
No. Why not? What's the matter?
Come on. Just take a sip. No.
Just take a little sip. No!
Maybe later.
Go away.
Okay, let me know if
this hurts. Ow! Hell, yes.
Ha. Wuss.
You want another
beating, keep talking.
I'm sitting right here.
This is his sparring
partner, Walter.
Lip lac and a
possible broken jaw.
Aren't you guys too
old to be fighting?
Never too old to
defend a lady's honor.
Was this was over a woman?
Grace is in all her steps
Beauty in her eyes
In every gesture
Dignity and love.
Yeah, don't let him fool you.
He stole that from a book.
At least I know how to read.
Yeah. With your lips moving.
Lip...? Okay, okay, okay.
Let's start with, uh, 6-0 nylon.
And let's try and keep
these kids apart, shall we?
Hey, Mark.
Morning, Kerry. How's it going?
Uh, well, ahem, snow blower
blew a rock into a guy's larynx.
I had to trache him.
No. I meant with you.
You know, first day back.
So far, so good.
Good. I'll let you
know in four hours.
We getting a little backed up?
Three patients waiting
for a surgical consult.
Who's on the service?
Peter. But she's stuck
in a press conference.
Who? Peter.
She's been in for an hour.
Who's "she"? What?
Wait, I mean... I mean, who's
giving a press conference?
Oh, I don't know what it's
for, but I heard Peter's in it.
Kerry? Yeah.
Can you call Radiology?
They sent this guy
back without his films
and they won't take him down.
Is there any bone exposed?
Yeah, I have to rongeur
it, and I need the x-ray.
How did it happen? I
don't know. They just lost it.
No. The finger.
I don't know. He won't say.
Habla usted inglés? No.
Chuny already tried.
Looks like some kind of saw.
What did he say?
I told you.
Did someone bring him in?
I think he took a cab.
What cab company?
Nobody saw him arrive?
Malik was out there. Why?
Okay. We should
put a call in to OSHA.
OSHA?
They monitor workplace
safety requirements.
He's probably illegal, and
he isn't saying anything
because he doesn't
wanna lose his job.
That's his choice, isn't it?
Until someone
gets seriously hurt.
I'll call, find out where
they picked him up.
I just need you
to call Radiology.
I gave you a promotion.
What are you crying about?
You should have
talked to me first.
I did. I said a
little extra money
for added responsibility.
I don't like being used.
Everyone is used, Peter.
It's what makes
the world go round.
The only reason you gave
me that job is because I'm black.
Well, you're discounting
your finely honed
public relations skills.
I don't want it. Sure you do.
Nope, I don't. You
should have thought of that
before your press conference.
Yes. I need a minority
to be the Director of Diversity.
But it's not gonna
require any real work.
It'll get you that much closer
to a full-time faculty position.
So please get over
yourself. You know what?
You can find somebody else
to be your little poster boy.
Well, I... I... The truth is
I don't have anyone else.
Which is a perfect example
of why the diversity issue
needs your immediate attention.
You don't even believe that.
Actually, I do.
But it doesn't really
matter, does it?
It's on your shoulders now.
Excuse me. I have a meeting.
Time's up, Peter.
Did I misread the schedule?
What schedule? You
canceled six elective cases
in the past week. They were
not canceled, rescheduled.
Which means canceled.
One had a fever, another
had a family emergency.
All of them happen to be
the more complex procedures.
If that's true, it's simple
coincidence, I assure you.
Look, I've been completely
slammed by this review.
Nothing seems to be up
to standard at the moment.
And I have every confidence that
you'll get them up to standard.
But I also need an
associate chief of surgery
who actually performs surgery.
I do.
I will, gladly, once I get
out from under all of this.
No. Today.
You're covering the ER.
Robert, they're
coming on Monday.
You only have to go
down there if they page you.
Are you married?
No.
Oh, a cute girl like yourself?
Well, he didn't
crack your skull.
What?
There's no blood
behind your eardrum.
He didn't crack your skull.
He couldn't crack a smile.
You know, I'm a big
proponent of marriage.
Of course, you gotta be
married to the right person.
Oh, is that a proposal?
Well, we have to get
to know each other first.
We're gonna have to wait
on the x-ray of your hand.
But I don't see any other
injuries. Anything else hurt?
Nothing I want to talk
about in mixed company.
Well, I'm a nurse.
Just the same, if
I'm gonna talk to you
about my private parts,
I'd prefer to do it
in a social setting.
Does it hurt when you pee?
Yeah. How did you know?
Do you have an
enlarged prostate?
It's large enough.
Well, it could be prostatitis.
I'm gonna need a urine sample.
You're gonna have
to hold it a little lower.
I am going to show
you to the bathroom.
You know, actually,
it feels more like, uh,
something you pick up.
Pick up? Yeah, a burning.
I got it once before when
I was stationed in Korea.
From... sex?
Well, I didn't get
it from dancing.
Abby, we need you.
Grab 100 of mannitol.
Gunshot wound to the head. Okay.
I'll be right back. Pee in that.
From here?
80 systolic after two liters.
What do you want for labs?
Full trauma panel.
Get a C-spine.
Cross him for four.
On my count. One, two, three.
Sinus at 65.
Rate's coming down.
What is it? Fifteen-year-old
with self-inflicted gunshot to
the right temple at close range.
Pupils are fixed and dilated.
Was there a suicide note?
No. His friend claimed they
were playing Russian roulette.
God. Guy's behind us.
Bullet blew through this
one and grazed his cheek.
No response to painful stimuli.
Smell alcohol. He
could just be drunk.
Dropped his systolic to 70.
Bradying down to 50.
Amp of atropine. Open
the fluids. Pump in O-neg.
What are you doing?
Massive blood loss. That
could be the cause of his low BP.
Or he could have
blown out his brain stem.
Crit's 39.
Doesn't sound like blood loss.
So do you want O-neg?
But if you wanna
try transfusing him...
Uh... Yes. Hang two
units on the rapid infuser.
I'll put in a central line.
What? Nothing.
Is this the other guy?
Yeah.
Superficial
abrasion, left cheek.
Cranial nerves intact.
You were playing
Russian roulette?
What?
They were playing
Russian roulette.
It was his idea.
How old are you? Why?
How old are you?
He wanted to play.
Mark, I got this. What, 20?
Nineteen. He's 15
years old. He's drunk.
I could smell the
alcohol across the room.
He came over that way.
You didn't give
her anything? Who?
Your friend.
He brought a case of beer
along with his dad's gun.
You made him hold
the gun up to his head.
I didn't make him do
anything. Hell, I went first.
It w... It was his idea,
but you went first?
Yeah. Better odds.
Better odds? That's
the point of the game.
The g... It's not a game!
She blew his brains out!
Who's "she"?
What?! You said "she."
He! He's dead.
He loaded the bullet. He
knew what could happen.
Where are the police, huh?
Why aren't they
arresting this idiot?
I didn't kill him.
The hell you didn't.
Did you call it?
Yeah. After six units of
blood and 45 minutes of CPR.
I should never have started.
You wanted to make sure.
Rubbish. You would have
called it from the beginning.
Yeah, but I'm lazy.
Mark, please.
You wanted to give it a
chance. No big failure.
All right. I'm going
back upstairs.
Later, gator.
Hey. Are you taking it easy?
Yes, Mom.
Sour milk? Yeah. It came back
from the dry cleaners
like that. Smell.
It's fine. Right?
So anyway, he's not psychotic?
Uh, no. Sociopathic, maybe.
But, no, I can't hold him.
We'll leave it up to the police.
Thanks.
Any time.
So, Elizabeth?
Yeah?
Is Mark doing okay?
Very well.
There's no change
in personality or...?
He's a little tired. Why?
Uh, have you noticed that
he's mixing his pronouns?
Uh, mixing? How?
Well, like, saying she
when he means he.
Uh...
Well, it's nothing
that I've noticed.
Has he said anything
to you about it?
No, I don't think he realizes.
Well, maybe you've misheard.
Yeah. Maybe.
Dr. Weaver.
Yep. Starting my shift.
Okay.
You wanted to see me
before I started my shift.
Right. Well, uh...
I've been thinking about it.
And the fact that you told me
that you claimed responsibility
I... I... I think is
a positive sign.
Therefore, I... I feel that I...
I can't, uh, summarily
dismiss you.
But...? What chip are you up to?
What? Your AA chip.
Oh, uh... How many
days of sobriety?
Two hundred and forty.
Okay, give it to me.
It's, uh... It's at home.
All right.
Well. You're starting over.
Day 1. Another 90 days,
another 90 meetings.
And I need documentation.
And you'll go back to not
administering or distributing
any Schedule II narcotics
or benzos until further notice.
But that's it, Carter.
Even the smallest infraction,
and you no longer work here.
Is that clear?
Understood? Understood.
Good. Thank you.
Don't make me regret it, John.
How you doing, Mr. Nicolaides?
Call me Walter. Walter.
I'd be doing a whole lot
better with a sponge bath.
You want a bath?
Yes, please.
Malik.
Come here.
Yeah. What?
Oh, no.
I-I'm fine. Really.
I was just kidding...
Okay. Never mind.
Whatever. Jeez.
Boy, you're a real
firecracker, aren't you?
That's me. Nurse Firecracker.
Mm. Married?
None of your business.
Mm. My second
wife was a spinster.
Married her when she was 32.
Well, just waiting for
the right guy, I guess.
Yeah. Damn right.
We were married
for another 32 years
before she passed.
Yeah, but don't you worry,
because feisty gals like you
always take a little longer.
I wasn't the one who
was brought in for fighting.
Oh, well, Earl started that.
He was...
flirting with my Victoria.
Who's Victoria? My lady friend.
Are the two of you intimate?
Well, I...
still get up a full
head of steam,
if that's what
you're driving at.
I see.
Uh, tell me... Walter,
have you been experiencing
any burning when you pee?
I mean... it was cool at first,
but then my
girlfriend went to work,
and it just stayed... like that.
Have you taken any
drugs lately, uh, Gary?
Little coke.
Okay. That'll do it.
Have you tried masturbating?
No. I'm a Christian.
Oh. Well, too bad.
Sometimes that helps.
Guess we'll have to drain it.
How?
With a needle.
Do you have a men's room around?
Yup. Down the hall to the left.
I'll check back.
- How you know she's gay?
- It's obvious.
Are the fibroids
actively bleeding?
Crit is down to 28. I mean,
why risk multiple transfusions
if she's not gonna
use it anyway?
Use what? Her uterus.
Oh, come on. Come
on. You can tell.
Check her out.
These files are Dr. Benton's
on the med school
admissions committee.
He doesn't have a box
anymore, so they came back.
A hysterectomy is the
safest way to go, man.
Dr. Weaver?
- Uh... lounge.
- Fine, fine.
I mean, I... I'll just make
sure she understands the risks.
Hey, Malucci. Be careful.
I don't want a lawsuit.
Hey. I'm the king
of couth, chief.
Great. Storm's back.
Snowing again.
Is this my hand x-ray?
Does it have your name on it?
Yes. Then it's yours.
Uh, Orbie Coronado
from OSHA called back.
Said thanks for the address.
Said someone from
the INS may be calling.
Wait a minute. I didn't
want him to call the INS.
Is that my patient?
They've been having problems
with furniture
sweatshops in that area.
Call back. I need to
find out what he said.
That's great, Kerry. Hey.
We have a responsibility
to report unsafe
working conditions.
You don't know that. He
wouldn't even say how he cut it.
He was scared. Scared
of getting deported.
Nobody's getting deported.
Why the hell not?
If he's illegal, he's illegal.
Who's paying for him?
Shut up, Frank.
Hi. Hey.
Hey, I heard you got stuck
with a couple of grumpy old men.
Well, horny old
men is more like it.
They both have chlamydia.
How old are they? Late 70s.
Seems to be going
around their nursing home.
Nice to know there's more
than shuffleboard in our futures.
Do you want Mr. Baker,
20-year-old sickler in crisis?
Better not. Why not?
Because I'm back to
not pushing narcotics.
You told Weaver? Yeah.
She was okay?
Well, not okay,
but she let me stay
with a few...
reinforced restrictions.
Good for you.
I guess. No, I mean it. Really.
No. Thanks for the push.
Carter. Wound check in 5 has...
I'm coming. I'm coming.
He's getting difficult.
Both EKGs are normal.
Cardiac enzymes are normal.
I just talked to
his cardiologist.
He said he should
have a treadmill test
and maybe an angiogram.
Probably meant as an outpatient.
He didn't say that.
Well, that's what he meant.
Keep taking your
medications as directed
and come back if
there are any problems.
That's it?
Make sure you see your
cardiologist when you get home.
You're not gonna
admit him? Nope.
Georgia, honey, it's all right.
I want him checked
in. This isn't a hotel.
Told you we shouldn't have
gone to a county hospital.
Georgette. I want
a second opinion.
Okay. Here's your
second opinion.
Your husband's overweight.
He suffers from stable angina.
He needs to stop
drinking and smoking.
He needs to lay off the
pizza, burgers and fries,
and get some exercise.
Otherwise, all the second
opinions in the world
are not gonna keep
him from dropping dead
in the next two years.
I'll clear the Trauma rooms.
Notify the ICU. I'm
calling the blood bank.
Can I get eight units of O-neg
and every bag of Ringer's?
Carter, what's going on?
Rescue's bringing in multiple
victims of a basement fire.
Smoke inhalation
Crush injuries...
How many? They
were too busy to count.
Call the O.R.? Yeah,
and the burn unit.
ETA? They're rolling in.
Mark, you got this? I'll
take the one on the end.
Partial burn to the
right arm and face.
What happened? A raid.
Bunch of workers got
trapped. BP 120/60.
Pulse, 92. Better
keep her on O-2
and check the
carboxyhemoglobin level.
Give 0.5 of albuterol.
Mark, I thought you were off.
Not anymore. You
need to take it easy.
Not much chance of that.
Why don't you go triage?
See you in O.R. We'll
flush out the joint upstairs.
I just threw her in the
front seat as I pulled out.
Any burns? It's
a superficial lac
to the right calf and groin.
What's she saying? She's
saying she wants her mom.
Smoke inhalation
with pleuritic chest pain.
Malik, I need a blood
gas on this guy right away.
- Portable chest?
- Yeah. Get me a 12-lead.
Got an INS officer
who crushed his pelvis.
Any shortness of breath?
Did they get out? Who?
Well, we only got
half of them out.
They had the windows
barred shut. What place?
Oh, we got a tip on
an illegal sweatshop.
Uh, we went to case
it. It just started burning.
Sats are down to 82.
Dr. Weaver, his
pulse ox is falling.
Put him on 15 liters.
Open an intubation tray.
He needs a trauma
consult now. Move.
Sorry, doc.
Decreased breath
sounds on the left.
Carter...
can you take this?
Possible pneumothroax.
Yeah. Trauma 2.
Luka? Thirty-year-old male,
full-thickness burns
over most of his body.
BP, 100/70. Pulse, 120.
Where should we go?
Just get him out of the hallway!
How much fluid in?
One liter Ringer's
and 10 of morphine.
Give another round of both.
I need a sterile
gown and gloves.
Do you know each other?
They work together.
Mark!
Mark, what's open?!
I don't know. Try
the Suture Room.
Suture Room. Go!
He needs an NG tube and a Foley.
Dr. Weaver, we're
out of I&D kits.
Use suture-removal
kits for débriding.
CBC, chem panel
and cardiac enzymes.
What do you got?
Possible electrical burns.
She may have
touched a hot power line
while she pulled some
rubble off her daughter.
She doesn't know
what happened to her.
How old? Five.
First name, Araceli.
Haleh, call Dispatch.
See if they have a
20 on a 5-year-old girl.
Good air entry,
scattered rales bilaterally.
Put her on a pulse ox.
Got an exit wound here.
Here's the entry.
She's burned from
the inside out, huh?
What was the voltage
on the line? I don't know.
Get on the phone with the
commander and find out.
Pulse ox, 89.
Put him up to five liters.
Just take it easy. Take
it easy. Just lay back.
Cálmate. Cálmate. Just lay back.
Titrate another 10 of morphine.
You got about 20 percent
partial-thickness burns.
He needs a chest tube.
Lily, I need to prep
for an escharotomy.
That doesn't sound very good.
Can you set up a fiber-optic
laryngoscope? In a sec!
I need it now! Go, go. I got it.
Carter, can you help
me prep the chest?
Hurry, I'm losing pulses.
How fast do you need the fluids?
I'm estimating 92 percent
surface-area burns.
Start Ringer's at
1700 cc's per hour.
Setting at 91 on 15 liters.
Okay, switch him to
humidified O-2, non-rebreather.
What?
He's asking how bad it is.
Tell him very serious.
"Am I going to die?"
Most likely, yes.
Probablemente sí.
His finger's swollen.
I can't get his ring off.
Get the ring cutter.
I'm in.
No persistent pneumo,
good tube position.
He's still hypertensive.
Do you know how it started?
Paint thinner.
I think someone kicked
over a space heater
when they were running out.
Where's that
crit? Working on it.
Borderline widened mediastinum
and a left pleural effusion.
Might be his aorta.
All right. Chest
CT. Let's move him.
Hold on. Crit's low at 31.
You want to take
him up to the O.R.?
No. I... I don't want to
open him if I don't have to.
It could just be an
intercostal artery.
Fine, fine. We'll do a
transesophageal echo.
Somebody call upstairs,
tell them we're on our way.
Neck is swollen.
So are the upper extremities.
Mamá. Mi hija.
Where did you find her?
She came in with Morales.
Sats are dropping. 86.
Put her on high-flow
O-2, open saline, 80...
High voltage fried
every cell in its path.
Look, her CK is over 2000.
Cómo está mi hija? Mamá.
No me dejes.
Está bien.
Did you check her out?
She's fine.
She has a non-displaced
fracture of the tibia.
Mamá. She's okay. See?
Pulse ox dropping, 82.
Okay, let's intubate.
Abby, take her out.
Abby, out.
She wants you to take
care of her, Abby. Abby, go.
Mamá. Okay.
Twenty of etomidate. 100 of sux.
Mamá!
8-0 ET tube.
Relax, relax, relax.
Whoa. Whoa, whoa.
Okay, okay. Carter,
hold him down.
Hold on. Watch the drape!
Relájate. No!
Sats are down to 78.
He's getting hypoxic.
All right, push some Versed.
What?
The Versed! Right
there on the Mayo stand!
Come on! I can't.
Why not? I'm not allowed to.
Carter, push the damn Versed!
I got to get this tube in him.
Carter, where are
you going?! Hold on.
Inflate the tube. Bag her.
Her complexes are widening.
Dave, go push some
Versed for Benton, will you?
I'm busy. Sats
are still dropping.
I got this. Go ahead.
I'm not a nurse.
Give her 10 units
of insulin and D50.
Come on, just do it, will you?
You do it. Dave, go.
What? Now. Help Benton.
You've got a run of six.
Get a repeat potassium.
She's in V-tach.
Crash cart! Charge to 200.
Got a weak femoral pulse.
Get an amp of bicarb. Clear.
Still V-tach. Charging, 300.
Pressure's 60 palp.
Clear!
Pressure's 92/62. Pulse, 110.
Repeat crit is 28.
I can't isolate the aorta.
You got to go in now.
Oh, not blind, I don't.
Ah, come on.
Come on.
Okay. There.
There's extra lumenal fluid.
He's torn his aorta.
No kidding.
Set up a thoracotomy tray.
Call the perfusionist.
I'll scrub in.
Scrub fast.
How much blood?
Eight more units. Type-specific.
Clear.
Still in V-tach.
Three-sixty. 100 of lidocaine
and an amp of calcium.
Clear.
What happened?
Lost the pulse.
Damn it. She's in
V-fib. Let's start CPR.
I got it. Benton's
taking your patient up.
You get the chest tube in?
That's not all.
Clear.
You had to intubate, uh?
ARDS. His sats were
low after thoracostomy.
I'm taking him up to SICU.
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm not allowed
to push controlled substances.
He was about to arrest. Part
of my diversion agreement.
You know what? Sometimes
you make exceptions.
No exceptions.
Then you don't
need to be in there.
What? If you can't
treat a patient,
you don't need
to be in the room.
I didn't set the rules this way.
Sometimes you gotta
use your own judgment.
It's not negotiable. If I push
the Versed, I'm out of here.
How long has it been?
Eight months? Yeah.
This is ridiculous. I'll
talk to Weaver. No, no.
Dr. Benton.
Post-intubation film.
I'll handle it. It's,
uh, you know.
It'll just piss her off anyway.
Yeah, well, you know what?
I'm pissed off. You
should be pissed off.
Well... it's my problem.
No, Carter. It's
everybody's problem.
Listen just don't talk
to Weaver. Please.
Swelling of the upper airway.
We'll intubate after
the escharotomy.
No. No.
When... When is he going to die?
In about a week. From infection.
Your body won't be able
to keep the bacteria out.
You'll also get, uh,
major fluid imbalances
and possible kidney failure.
We'll have to put a tube
down your throat
to help you breathe.
Can you find his wife?
Does he have a number?
No. She's...
She's in Guatemala, and
there's no phone there.
He has $520 in a
little box by his bed.
He lives in a garage
at 395 Landale Street.
"Can you get it to her?"
Can you get her the money
and tell her what
happened to him?
Yeah.
Sí, Ernesto.
"Can you tell her I love her?"
Yo la quiero mucho.
"I love her very much."
Okay, 30 of etomidate,
six of Pavulon.
Clear!
Fine V-fib.
Charge again. 360.
Potassium's 7.5.
Pulse ox is 60.
How long has she been down?
Twenty-five minutes.
Clear!
Asystole.
How much atropine
has she been given?
Two amps.
When was the last epi?
Uh, about three minutes ago.
Okay, that's it.
Time of death, 12:16.
There was too much
internal injury, chief.
Yeah.
There's more. Rescue found a guy
trapped inside with
a blunt head trauma
and blown pupil.
All right, let's go.
I'll clear the room.
I need better exposure.
Get a large Deaver in here.
That is a large Deaver.
Then give me more retraction.
I can't maintain his
pressure much longer.
Metz. LISA: We need
the pump in O.R. 4.
Where's the bypass machine?
Open hearts going in two O.R.'s.
First one will be off
the pump in 30 minutes.
I need it now. Right now.
These are my last two units.
DeBakey.
Lisa, you go in there, you
tell them we have an unstable
patient on the table. I did.
The pump's not available
for... Now it's 29 minutes.
Pressure's 80. You've
gotta cross-clamp him.
No, if I... I do that,
I'll cut off circulation
to his spinal cord.
Or you could let him bleed out.
I will not paralyze this man.
You want to kill him?
I can't isolate the aorta.
Find Romano. We can't wait!
Lisa, now! Go!
Carter, I've got to go home.
Girl in Exam 1 needs
a leg-burn débridement.
Uh, Burn Unit's full. Does
she needs admission?
No. Give him Thermazine
to use at home.
Boy or girl?
What? You just said "him."
Carter, I'm really tired.
So much for a
four-hour shift, uh?
See you Monday.
Have a good weekend.
It's none of your business.
It is when it
affects patient care.
Dr. Carter did what
he was supposed to do.
The guy's sats were dropping.
This one needs a tetanus
booster and dressing.
There was an unnecessary
delay. If I need a resident...
Peter, you are a
surgical consultant!
You do not dictate ER policy!
This is not policy,
Kerry. This is punishment.
Peter, we're not gonna
have this conversation.
This one needs Xeroform
and a tube-gauze dressing.
In a second. Fine.
What do you have
against him? What?
Oh, yeah. He made a
mistake. He got through it.
Peter, for the last time,
the terms of Carter's
diversion program
are not your concern!
You know what,
Kerry? It's time to let up.
He's been clean now
for what, 8 months.
Has he?
Tenth unit's up.
Proximal aorta is dissected.
He's taching at 120.
Darn it. There's a
traumatic pseudoaneurysm.
Where the hell is Romano?
I paged him three times.
Did you check his office?
The staff lounge
and your cell phone.
Get the Resident on
call. The Resident?
Yes! Just get him.
BP's 70 and dropping.
Okay.
Well, give him two more units.
This is all I've got.
So call the blood bank.
They're out of
A-positive. I told you.
Then get O-negative!
For God's sake! Just
keep transfusing him!
Don't you understand
I need more time?!
You've got to
cross-clamp him now.
Do you want the
Zanger or the Crawford?
Dr. Corday?
Dr. Corday... what clamp?
The Crawford. Crawford.
We'll establish
proximal control.
Open a 20mm Dacron.
Okay. We'll maintain
blood flow to the spinal cord
by sewing his intercostal
arteries into the graft.
BP's down to 60.
Okay. The clamp's on.
Dr. Babcock, I need another
hematocrit. Eleven blade.
Okay. Pressure's up to 80.
Better work quick.
I'm okay. I'm okay.
Collateral flow should
reduce the risk of paralysis.
Okay, cut.
3-0 Prolene.
Hey.
Boy.
Days like today, you
look down at your watch,
and suddenly your shift is over.
What are those?
Med school applications.
Oh, yeah? Where
are you applying to?
Why the two separate stacks?
Interviews. No interviews.
You have a special,
uh, secret formula there?
GPA times competitive
factor plus MCAT scores.
Over 25, you get an interview.
You don't read the
letters of recommendation?
After the interview.
Poor kids.
I don't know if I
would have made it in,
if I had the interview with you.
How'd you get on the committee?
I'm busy, Carter.
Did you talk to Weaver?
Yep.
It was nothing.
I mean, it was a
slip. Not even a slip.
You know? I threw them up.
Urine output 75
in the last hour.
Hemoglobin's 10.8.
Less than 100 cc's
of chest tube output.
Is that good?
All good.
Just need to do a
quick neuro check.
For what?
To check sensation.
Ow.
What's so funny?
Let me see you wiggle your toes.
That's excellent.
Lizzie, you called for me?
Yeah. Over an hour ago.
Well, I'm here now.
What's so emergent?
Will you excuse me?
We had a little trouble
with an aortic graft,
and I...
I wanted a second pair of hands.
Do I need to worry
about another lawsuit?
Uh, no. No.
Things got hairy for a moment,
but I pulled him through.
Well. That's your job, isn't it?
Yes, it is.
And I am now late for
dinner. Thank you, Elizabeth.
Thank you.
It's a good thing
they didn't frisk me.
It's chocolate.
Go away.
There's a reason I didn't
come to see you, Chase.
I thought about coming...
but I didn't.
And I didn't...
because I was afraid.
And I was afraid because
I didn't want to ad...
When I got stabbed
last year at work,
a friend of mine got
killed. And I, um...
ended up addicted
to painkillers.
And it caught up to me.
And I started to, um...
shoot morphine
and Demerol and fentanyl, and...
And whatever else I
could get my hands on.
And I don't know what would
have happened if I hadn't got busted.
But I did, and I went to rehab.
But I wasn't like
any of those people.
I mean, I got into this
because of an injury,
because of circumstance.
Because a near-death experience.
And they...
Anyway, it wasn't me.
I mean, it was me, but
it... It wasn't... Anyway.
I did the program.
Mm, I pretended
that I bought into it.
I did everything that I
was supposed to do.
Except...
believe that I
had anything to do
with what had happened.
And then...
I almost relapsed.
Or I guess I...
I guess I did relapse. Anyway...
I didn't come to
see you, Chase...
because I didn't want
to admit to the fact that..
I was just like you.
In fact, the truth is...
there's not a day that goes by
that I don't think
about getting high.
It's the first
thing I think about
when I wake up in the morning.
And it's the last
thing I think about
when I go to bed at night.
And I think about it all day.
I'm a drug addict.
Tsk.
Did you bring any french fries?
Huh.
Did the mom say anything
about any relatives in Chicago?
No. How about in Guatemala?
We didn't have time to ask.
All right, thanks.
Hey, um...
What's gonna happen to her?
Put her in a group home for now.
Will she be deported?
Not unless we know
she's going back to family.
If we don't find anyone, she
becomes a ward of the state,
and then we look for a
Spanish-speaking foster home.
You okay?
Yeah.
♪ Drawn to the violence ♪
♪ Of change ♪
♪ Charmed by The
sentimental brave ♪
♪ I hear the door slam ♪
♪ I look the other way ♪
♪ I hate the small talk ♪
♪ And the empty days ♪
♪ Silver lining ♪
♪ I bathe in your light ♪
♪ I'll always believe in ♪
♪ Your place in my life ♪
♪ Silver lining ♪
♪ I know that I'm right ♪
♪ I'll always believe in ♪
♪ Your right to shine ♪
♪ Scared of the things ♪
♪ That people say ♪
♪ Knowing my confidence ♪
♪ Might fail ♪
♪ I feel the world's weight ♪
♪ Upon my breaking back ♪
♪ I see uncertainty ♪
♪ And the visible cracks ♪
♪ Silver lining ♪
♪ I bathe in your light ♪
♪ I'll always believe in ♪
♪ Your place in my life ♪