Previously on The Resident...
Today is the day we introduce
3B Life to the American public.
So you are Bell and
Cain's new partner?
They're the new
partners. I'm the founder.
- You should call me.
- Okay.
I've just been hired
as the new team doctor
for Georgia FC.
This will remain
at St. John's unless
there's another hospital
I decide to call home.
What would be the terms?
Chief resident.
- Good to have you back.
- Cheers.
I told you the table-side
Caesar was a bad idea.
You know that little asterisk
they put on the menu?
"This contains raw egg"?
Why did I ignore it?
'Cause you love to live
life on the edge. Like me.
I really wanted to be with you
your first day back at Chastain.
I know, but it's only one day.
And we have so
many more to come.
Unless you continue
to ignore the asterisk.
All right.
Kitchen's stocked.
Bananas...
- rice...
- Applesauce, toast.
Yes, I'm well aware
of the BRAT diet.
Have a good first day back.
Be with you in spirit.
All right. I love you.
Oh, nice. My little BRAT.
Now go. I'm gonna be sick again.
- Stay out of trouble.
- Call me if you need anything.
♪ I want what I want,
not what I need ♪
♪ Even if it kills
me, I'll be free ♪
♪ I want what I want,
not what I need ♪
♪ The American dream ♪
♪ I want what I want,
not what I need ♪
♪ Even if it kills
me, I'll be free ♪
♪ What I want is
just what I want ♪
♪ The American dream... ♪
- Hey, Pravesh?
- Hmm?
- Does that guy
look familiar to you?
- Oh, no. No, no, no.
- Why?
- I don't know, I...
I think he used to work here.
You know, it's just
really hard to remember,
you know, with all these faces
just coming and
going around here.
Oh, yeah, yeah. You boys done?
- Hmm?
- Oh, wait. I do
remember that voice.
Dr. Conrad Hawkins.
The man who went up against
Red Rock and lived to tell the tale.
Oh. Oh! Oh.
You miss all this?
You have no idea.
How do you feel about getting
your footsies wet in the ER?
- We could use the help.
- Ah!
Wet footsies. I'm in.
Psst.
Good to see you, darling.
Dr. Hawkins.
Welcome back.
Thank you.
Nice to be back.
♪ ♪
Let's go.
Brought Hawkins back?
Uh, hey, let me call you back.
He signed a lucrative deal
with a national sports franchise.
- He's still a whistleblower.
- I'm aware.
Risk versus reward.
I made the call.
It's insanity.
Turns out he's a rainmaker.
And Red Rock likes the rain.
Yeah, I'm well aware.
Remember who you're talking to?
Now, careful now... Barrett.
Proceed with caution.
I should have been informed.
Leaving me out of
the loop on Hawkins is
a sign of disrespect to
the surgeon who's made
more rain for you and
Red Rock than anyone else.
Not as much as you used to.
Your billing is moving
in the wrong direction.
Pair that with the expensive
neuro center we're building
on your behalf,
by my assessment I'd say...
you got to hustle up.
Hustle up?
What exactly are you implying?
Everyone has an expiration date.
Everyone.
♪ ♪
I'm game.
I'm game, too.
Even though most people
don't normally do it this way.
That's true. When
most people start out,
they only show each
other their best qualities.
And hide their worst, pretend
to be someone they're not.
It could be months before you
find out who you're really with.
Years.
We will lay it all on the table
next to these inedible eggs
and DOA flapjacks.
A breakfast interrogation.
Won't be my first time
on the witness stand.
- Oh.
- Mm-hmm.
- Well, let's start there,
why don't we?
- Okay.
Oh, hey, uh...
Just checked on that
outside hospital
hernia transfer.
His incision was oozing.
I interrupt something?
Enjoy your meal.
Uh...
where were we?
I was about to ask you
about your worst breakup.
Yeah.
No.
No, we're-we're not going there.
- What?! We're just...
- N-No.
Sorry. Not-not a chance. The...
I-Is...? Whoa.
Is that my pager? I think...
Oh, look at that.
Saved by the pager.
- Did you just page yourself?
- Excuse me?
- What? Huh?
- What do you mean? Who does that?
- Okay.
- Listen, got to go.
Catch you later.
Incoming Bay Six.
- Hmm.
- All right, let's do this.
♪ ♪
Doug, I'm Dr. Hawkins.
So what's going on?
Uh... it was Taco Tuesday.
I do it up real
nice for the kids.
Queso, green chilis.
I was cleaning the table
off, and I looked down,
and that's when I saw it.
Saw what?
Drool.
I was in the middle
of a photo shoot
when it got real bad.
Well, it's not uncommon
for flashing lights to
trigger a headache.
Your pupils are pinpoint.
That means smaller than normal.
I know what pinpoint
means, thank you.
How long will it take
me to get normal?
I'm tip-top from
top to tail, baby.
Then why are you here, Raj?
Look, I get the runs,
like, every 20 minutes.
All right, I was on
a date last night.
Had to get off to the john
before the food even arrived.
We were supposed to go
see a movie after. Forget it.
We might as well watch it
on my phone in the bathroom.
All right.
So you pull me into
the ER for what appears
to be a drooler, a
headache, and diarrhea.
So we threw you
some softball cases.
We just don't want
to lose you again.
Don't fly too close to the
sun on your first day back.
Mm-hmm.
I could use a little sun.
Mind if I join?
Hawkins is back in action.
What a lovely sight.
They should be landing soon.
54-year-old woman, Jet
Ski collision with a motorboat.
Propeller lodged
in pelvis. Pulse: 126.
Got it. Voss, you're with me.
Careful not to disrupt
the propeller blade.
Roger that.
- What's her name?
- Becky Copple.
Becky, we're gonna
take care of you, okay?
What have we got?
55-year-old male, same accident.
Hit his head on
the deck. No LOC.
GCS 14 on scene for confusion.
I'm fine. Just
please save my wife.
Becky, do you
know where you are?
Hospital.
BP's 75/40, pulse in
the 140s, 02 sat 99%.
She's cold and clamped
down, going into shock.
No, she's in shock. Hang
two units of O neg now
and activate massive
transfusion protocol.
Dr. Feldman, can you
put in a central line?
Oh, there's blood in her pelvis.
The propeller could
be tamponading
a more catastrophic bleed.
Becky, can you
wiggle your left toes?
Great. How about your right?
I... I...
can't move my leg.
What's going on?
Ah, pupils are
equal and reactive.
This shouldn't need stitches.
How you feeling?
Ah, just-just a headache.
Maybe my eyes
are a little bit blurry.
Okay, possible concussion.
We'll run some tests.
Hey, I got another patient.
- I got to go. You good?
- Good.
- Sure?
- Mm.
- John?
- Squeeze my fingers.
- Ah.
Squeeze my fingers. Good. Good.
So you live here in Atlanta?
Yeah, we do, but we spend
most of our time on the road.
- Oh, yeah, why's that?
- Uh, well,
Becky and I started the Copple
Foundation about 15 years ago.
All right, push on the gas.
Push on the gas. That's good.
Yeah, we, uh, serve the causes
that we're most
passionate about.
Health care is one of them.
And that is why we
know this man so well.
John.
I'm so sorry to hear
about the accident.
Thank you, Logan.
I'm, uh...
Becky's hurt really bad.
I assure you
she-she's in the hands
of our absolute best.
As are you.
Thank you.
I'll be right back.
John and Becky Copple are among
the biggest donors to Red Rock.
Most notably, our
new neuro center.
You gave me a reason
to bring you back.
Let's make sure that I continue
to feel good about my decision.
Okay?
BP's up to 100/60. Pulse
has come down to the 90s.
This is our window to move her.
Hang another unit of blood
and let's bring the
cooler with us to CT.
And then to the OR to
remove the propeller.
Come on, people, let's move.
Wait, wait. Wh-Wh-Where-where
are they taking her?
Imaging. Just
part of the process.
It was my idea to go Jet Skiing.
Becky loves the outdoors.
I hate the sun.
It's one of the few things
we don't have in common.
But this boat came
out of nowhere.
And we crashed at full speed.
I just wish I had gotten
the worst of it and not her.
I can't lose her.
I just...
I-I don't even know what my
life looks like without Becky.
I understand.
But if we don't take care
of you, then you can't
take care of Becky, so how
about we focus on you for a minute?
Deal?
- Deal.
- All right.
I'm seeing on
your medical record
you had a brain tumor
removed eight years ago?
I did. Yes.
It was a benign growth.
- Hmm.
- Why?
Just want to get a CT to
make sure everything's okay.
- Sound good?
- Let's do it.
So, thanks to ads,
point of sale displays,
strategic partnerships...
Oh, Randy, there
you are. Have a seat.
The lovely Andrea just
came to the interesting part.
You gentlemen remember
our first quarter projections.
Well, this is our
actual revenue.
50,000 units sold
in the first month.
100 last week alone.
- Those are real numbers?
- Mm-hmm.
I mean, I knew we
were doing well, but...
We can barely keep
up with demand.
Well, then, I say we
increase production,
with a larger facility.
We could expand
to other regions.
- Mm-hmm.
- You know,
we should put some cash into R&D
and lay the foundation
for a whole new line.
You'll all be
parking your yachts
next to mine before
the year's out.
You know, maybe you
can quit teaching Pilates.
Or, hell, she could
buy the studio.
Hell, she could buy Pilates.
I don't think that's possible.
Uh, with the fortunes
we're gonna make, it is.
L-Listen, listen.
I-I-I have been here before.
All right? I mean, we are
playing with the big boys now.
And with profits this
promising, competitors will be
trying to buy us for a
nickel and a rubdown.
But I think we can all agree
that the real winning formula
is not just what's in this
little bottle. No, no, no.
No, it's-it's the
people in this room.
All y'all, the-the men and
brilliant lady right here,
united, working together.
We have struck gold, my
friends, and I don't know,
but anybody here want to
let 'em take away our gold?
I'd like to see 'em try it.
That is one enormous fracture.
The propeller sliced
through her sacroiliac joint.
Explains why she
can't move her leg.
Her pelvis has been completely
separated from her spine.
And it's torn
through her internal
iliac artery.
The damage is so extensive
- because this
propeller is cupped. So,
the plan is, we
remove the propeller,
stop the bleeding before
she exsanguinates.
Then, if we succeed,
reattaching her pelvis
to her spine will not
be a walk in the park.
I'll prep the OR.
What's the story?
TBI.
History of a benign brain tumor
that was successfully removed,
but it's regrown.
Well, hopefully
it's still benign.
I'll send it to pathology
when I take it out.
I'm gonna need to review his
prior scans and path reports.
- Mm-hmm.
- There's also
an associated hemorrhage.
- Is he symptomatic?
- Headache, blurry vision.
And it's only gonna get
worse the longer we wait.
We're gonna have to operate
soon. Any there any issues
- that might complicate
his surgery?
- Eh, mild hyponatremia.
That's likely related
to dehydration.
Otherwise, labs
were unremarkable.
All right. I'll take
him to my OR.
Sir, you need to
stay in your bed.
And keep your pants on.
L-Look.
Fasciculations?
- When did it start?
- A few minutes ago.
- Let's get another
full set of labs.
- Right.
We'll check for any
electrolyte abnormalities.
Should I, uh, cancel
Waffle Wednesday?
Maybe just reschedule
till next week.
- A - little help over here!
Respiratory distress, Bay Eight.
- Pravesh.
- Stay there.
Get me an intubation kit.
She started to wheeze and
couldn't clear her secretions.
We tried BiPap and
she became altered
and we couldn't get
her sats over 72%.
Mild crackles bilaterally.
Increase the PEEP.
PEEP is up to 15.
Okay, that bought us some room.
But she's still
skimming the treetops.
All right, let's get a blood
gas and a chest X-ray.
And write her for broad-spectrum
antibiotics with cultures first.
Once we get the gas, we'll
put her on ARDSNet protocol.
If her oxygenation
is still tenuous,
we'll start inhaled epo.
Good plan. But this is strange.
I mean, she came in with
a headache, for God's sake.
And now she's very
close to max vent settings.
We need to figure
this out. And fast.
Can I talk to my wife?
We need to get you
both in ORs ASAP.
No, no, please. I just...
- I need a sec.
- We have to be quick, though.
Hold up, hold up.
I know what you're gonna
say. We're in good hands.
We're both gonna be fine.
You love me.
I was gonna lead
with "I love you."
But, yes, all of that.
Then I'll see you tonight.
Make sure we're in a
recovery room together.
In our 20 years of marriage,
we've never spent a night apart.
We wouldn't want to
break a streak like that.
Well, you've got two softies
who'll do our best
to make it happen,
but right now we got to go.
I love you.
- I love you.
Hey.
How you feeling?
Better. Thank you.
It's so quiet. Where are you?
Our supply closet.
Oh, it's our supply closet now?
Well, we-we share it
with Jess and Irving,
but it's mostly ours.
You okay?
Nic,
I just...
I just want to say
thank you for...
for being there
and for, for never doubting
that I would be okay
and for helping me.
Helping me find
my way back here.
You don't need to thank me.
Yes.
I do.
Hey.
You'd do the same for me.
But you need to
get back to work.
People are gonna
think you lost your mind,
talking to yourself
alone in a supply closet
on your first day back.
That's fair. That's fair.
I'll get home as soon as I ca.
I know you will.
I'll see you tonight.
Again?
Unfortunately, Raj's bathroom
situation has escalated.
But all of his stool studies
have come back negative.
Mr. Corson's pants
are back on, but he's
still having fasciculations,
and he's started
to act confused.
What?
Pravesh. What's up?
MUDDLES.
I haven't heard that term
since I was in medical school.
Meiosis, urination...
Diarrhea, diaphoresis...
Lacrimation, excitation of
the central nervous system,
salivation.
Yeah, so, if you add
Doug, Cynthia and
Raj's symptoms together,
it is textbook
organophosphate poisoning.
How do three patients who
have nothing in common
get exposed to a
toxin that's only found
- in pesticides
and chemical weapons?
- I don't know.
But they're all showing
different signs of exposure.
If it is, we need
to treat them fast.
Organophosphate poisoning
can progress rapidly.
Hundley, push atropine
and one gram of 2-PAM
- for all three of them.
- On it.
Dr. Okafor,
why don't you give
that propeller blade
a nice, big tug.
It's not budging.
It's stuck in the SI joint.
You have to pull
with more force.
Put your back into it, dear.
Okay, it's not working.
Step aside.
I've got Excalibur.
Damn.
- It won't come out.
- Mm-hmm.
Allow me.
Ortho isn't just
about brute strength.
Sometimes you have to
think outside of the box.
Hammer, please?
And then use brute strength.
Get ready.
Suction.
- Retractors.
- Sutures.
What are the odds
a benign brain tumor regrows?
Well, it's rare,
but it can happen.
Don't worry. I'm
here to deal with that.
We're gonna proceed
with the craniotomy
- to remove the tumor.
- Copy that.
I'll get scrubbed up.
Thank you, Dr. Cain.
You're welcome.
John, I'm gonna
administer the propofol now.
Start counting
backwards for me from ten.
Just breathe.
What'd you give him?
Just relax. Just breathe.
What did you give him?
I haven't given
him anything yet.
You must have done something.
He's tach'ing away in the 150s.
His BP shot up to 180s.
- It hurts!
- What?
- Where do you... Where does
it hurt? Tell me what hurts.
- It hurts!
- What's-what's hurt? What hurts?
- My stomach!
Your stomach?
Abort the surgery!
Dr. Austin, you're
on the left pelvis.
Dr. Okafor, you're on the right.
Fasten this obtrusive
instrument on each side.
Now for the most
critical part of the surgery.
We must bring her pelvis
and spine back into alignment.
- We're gonna
reduce her SI joint?
- Correct.
You will both push your side of
the pelvis towards one another.
How hard do we push?
It must be equal pressure.
And what if one pushes
harder than the other?
Then her pelvis will be
misaligned from her spine.
We could crush her sacral
nerves and leave her paralyzed.
You must be perfectly in sync.
I know I can count on you both.
We got this.
On three?
One, two, three.
Slowly.
A little more pressure
from you both.
Feeling some resistance.
I'll adjust.
Stop.
How did we do?
That's anatomic.
I've never seen a
more perfect alignment.
Game, set...
Match.
My patient is stagnating in
the ICU after an aborted surgery
because something you missed.
We don't know that yet.
Then what do you know?
- You're the internist
here, right?
- Mm-hmm.
In the great ecosystem
of this hospital, a flea.
You had one job:
to make sure my patient
was tuned up for surgery.
So let me give you some advice
upon your fresh
return to this hospital.
Go do your one job
so my patient doesn't die.
What the hell happened in there?
I'm replaying it in my head.
This, uh, acute
abdominal pain with nausea
and hemodynamic
instability in the OR
but with absolutely no prodrome.
Could he have thrown
a clot to his bowel?
I thought about that,
but nothing on imaging.
And his lactate is flat.
So what's your plan?
Uh, reexamine head to toe.
Rerun labs. Get to
the bottom of this.
Listen, let me know
how I can help you.
They-they took your head.
You figured out how
to grow another one.
But don't think for a
second they're not looking
for any reason to
bring the ax down again.
Who's "they"?
Kim did the firing,
but he and Cain are a team.
There's no way Cain
didn't have a hand in it.
And Cain doesn't care that
you brought in Georgia FC.
For him, getting rid
of you is personal.
Be careful.
Buy you coffee?
No.
Please?
Thank you.
Fine.
Uh, one almond
milk latte and one...
- Large coffee.
- Thanks.
What do you want
to know about him?
AJ seems amazing,
but I have been conned before.
So, woman-to-woman,
off the record,
jump in or run like hell?
All three patients
have stabilized.
Cynthia just got extubated.
- So you were right.
- Yeah.
But how do three
people with no connection
end up with the same
rare poison in their system?
First, we find out. Then
we call County Public Health
and stop whatever caused this.
So, you live nearby in...?
- Savannah.
- Chamblee.
Sandy Springs.
Any recent exposure
to chemicals?
- No.
I bought a can of body spray.
Has anyone sprayed insecticides
near your home or your garden?
I don't have a garden.
Not that I'm aware of.
No.
Any vitamins or supplements?
Yeah.
Yeah, I just picked
up a new one.
Um...
3, uh... 3B something.
3B Life.
That's it.
Hey, fingers crossed, I look
just as good as that doctor
on the label when
I'm his age, right?
Three different patients...
All with organophosphate
poisoning.
All on 3B Life.
Well, maybe they use
the same cleaning supplies
or pesticides.
We did extensive
patient histories.
You can't possibly
know everything
that they came
in contact with...
Yes, but, right now,
the only link that we do
have is your supplement.
- How widely was it distributed?
- Wide.
Okay. We need to call Public
Health and warn them about it.
That's ridiculously premature.
You can't call the
CDC on three patients.
Dr. Bell, I know that you
have a personal stake in this,
- but we have to...
- Okay.
Maybe, maybe they have
other things in common.
And if we act too quickly,
we'll destroy the reputation
of a good product
that is helping people,
not to mention me.
Yeah, but if we wait,
people could die.
So, beyond an acute
cholinergic crisis,
people could have serious
long-term disabilities...
I don't need to be educated on
the effects of organophosphates.
Okay, Dr. Bell, we just
need to do the right thing.
I can only see you
when I turn to look at you.
When you stand to the right
of me, I can't see you at all.
Must be because of the tumor.
The bleeding is
causing some swelling,
and that is what's
affecting your vision.
Well, will it get better?
I-I can't go blind.
We're giving you some steroids.
We're gonna
decrease the swelling.
Now, if we can get
that tumor out soon,
- then you should regain
your vision.
- "If"?
- Let's get it out now.
- Yes, I know.
I am of the same mind.
But your labile blood
pressure and heart rate
haven't been responding
to the treatments.
And I can't risk sending
you back into surgery
unless Dr. Hawkins
can come up with a plan
to make sure that
you're safe in the OR.
- What's the plan?
- Yes, Dr. Hawkins.
What is the plan?
John, I know you've been
scanned and examined up and down,
but do you mind if I
take one more look?
Did that start to hurt
after the accident?
No, actually.
That pain has been
on and off for a while.
Sometimes it hurts
so bad, I feel like
it's gonna rip right through me.
Like today in the OR.
And then...
all of a sudden, it gets better.
Now...
I'm gonna untie your gown
so I can get a good listen...
to your lungs.
What?
What's wrong?
There are blisters
on your shoulder.
I did not see that earlier.
Why the hell didn't
you see that earlier?
That's your job. Didn't you
do a full physical examination?
They-they weren't
there this morning.
I'm sure. I would know.
I've had them in the past.
That's why I hate the sun.
And when we were outside, I
was covered from head to toe.
Hyponatremia.
Recurrent abdominal pain.
Blistering skin lesions.
Blistering.
Blistering, blistering,
blistering skin lesions.
I need a urine sample.
Right now.
There's got to be a mistake.
I don't know.
It doesn't make sense.
We ship out hundreds
of thousands of units
and only three people get sick?
Well, it's not just three.
No, I just found out
that two more patients
have been diagnosed with
organophosphate poisoning
- over at Atlanta General.
- Oh, my God.
They're stable. They're
getting treatment,
just like the ones
here at Chastain.
Are they on 3B?
They're on supplements.
But if I ask for specifics,
the doctors there will make
the same connection that we did.
Then we test the facility,
- we prove it's not us.
- Agreed, but...
Zip is gonna start talking
about an exit strategy.
- Wait, what? It's too soon.
- No, Andrea,
there's a chance, no
matter what the percentage,
that 3B is the culprit and
that we're dead in the water.
I can't believe
this is happening.
I-I...
I have to call the partners.
Your post-op CBC is stable.
No more bleeding.
Distal pulses are strong.
Becky, can you wiggle your toes?
Looks good.
Recovering from major
surgery is challenging,
so we will be
monitoring you closely.
Thank you.
And what about John?
He didn't have surgery yet.
Why?
We don't know.
But we do know his
doctors are working on it.
What does that mean?
Will he be okay?
Can I be with him?
First, you must get well.
Then you can be strong for him.
When he had brain
surgery eight years ago,
I held his hand all night.
Like I could keep him with
me, just by physically holding on.
And it worked.
Well, as soon as we can,
we'll get you two
back together again.
And now we have
urine in the sun.
Dr. Hawkins, I'm starting
to lose my patience.
Just wait.
I am not gonna stand here
and stare at another man's
urine with you while John's tumor
continues to swell.
We don't have time for this.
It was time well spent.
What-What's happening?
John, this urine changed color.
That explains what
happened in the OR
and gives us a
diagnosis: porphyria.
Porphyria's when you have an
excess of the chemical porphyrin
and it builds up in your organs,
and when that happens,
certain stressors, like...
the intense lighting in
the OR, triggers a crisis
that causes things like
blisters, stomach pain,
and even organ damage.
You got all that from my pee?
Combined with your exam
and history of previous
stomach pain and skin blisters.
But yes,
when the porphyrins turned
your urine dark in the sun,
my clinical suspicion
was confirmed.
So I've had this my whole life?
Incredibly rare, easily missed,
but the good news is...
we can treat you.
We'll be sending
confirmatory labs of course,
but I am confident you
will be back in the OR soon.
Which Dr. Cain and I
will be prepping for you.
I made a list
of all the meds that can be
fatal to a porphyria patient.
Avoid these at all costs.
I haven't had a porphyria
patient since residency.
Yep, this is a unique
case. That's exactly why
I made a list for everyone.
Propofol for
anesthesia, that's safe.
Morphine's okay. Just let
me know before you give
- any antibiotics.
- Dr. Hawkins is right.
We all need to
review the drug list.
And the reason John
crashed in the OR before
was because of these intense
lights, so we got these filters.
We'll still be able to see, but
they change the wavelength
of the light that
hits John's body.
Avoiding a porphyric crisis.
What the hell happened?
She came out fine
after the surgery,
then she went into V
tach and lost her pressure.
Hold compressions.
Checking a rhythm.
Damn, she's still in V fib.
We need to shock again.
Charging to 200.
Clear.
Restart compressions.
I'll take over.
Code labs are back.
Hemoglobin is stable.
She's not losing blood.
But her calcium is under five.
That's not doing
her heart any favors.
Okay, we need more calcium.
One gram of
calcium chloride, now.
We ordered it hours ago. There's
a calcium chloride shortage.
Take it from the crash cart.
She should have
received more calcium
with her blood transfusions.
This is what happens
when drug companies
discontinue products that
save lives but don't make money.
Calcium chloride is in.
Continue compressions.
30 seconds to the
next pulse check.
Hope this works.
Bull's-eye.
Time to remove the tumor.
How are the lights?
Sufficient. My patient's
hemodynamic instability
is no longer distracting me.
You might want
to follow that lead.
Forceps.
His wife Becky just coded.
They're still working on her.
Get this to path.
It's been hours... why is he
just getting to the tumor now?
It's a delicate surgery.
Dr. Cain is in the middle of
a very complicated surgery,
and with the added
precautions for the porphyria...
John's a lucky guy.
♪ ♪
I can see you.
All of you.
Surgery went well.
Your tumor's gone, and your
preliminary path looks benign.
And we have a plan to manage
your porphyria moving forward.
Today you received
Chastain's finest,
as promised.
But Becky...
where is she?
She sustained serious
injuries in the crash,
but, like you said before,
John, your wife...
she is strong enough
for both of you.
She survived a very
grueling surgery.
But hey, don't worry,
we will make sure you
do not spend tonight apart.
Your streak will be intact.
♪ ♪
So now what?
I don't want to give up.
What if I'm wrong?
What if my supplements
are hurting people?
Look... you and I don't
know each other well,
but you have shown me so far
a woman who doesn't
half-ass anything.
So I believe that
you know your stuff.
And I believe
that you will do
the right thing.
I know it's not the 3B.
- I know it.
- Actually, you don't.
I see a future
- buried in lawsuits.
- Oh, please, do not use
- the "L" word.
- Okay, once we test
the manufacturing facility...
We'll already be on
60 Minutes by then.
I know you're both concerned
about your own liability.
- If...
- We poisoned people?
Yeah, I think we might be a
little bit concerned about that.
Okay, but let's remember that
I'm the reason that we're here.
My product, my
skill, my judgment,
that's... that's
what got us this far.
So I ask that you trust
me to see us through this.
Please.
How many units have we sold?
Enough that a recall
costs us millions more.
All to protect a brand
that we don't even know
will be worth anything
when this whole thing is done.
It's time to walk
away from the table.
I agree, I agree.
We got to protect
ourselves, cut our losses.
I-I think we should
declare bankruptcy.
Liquidate the assets,
make sure there's
nothing left to sue for.
Okay, everything I have is in
this company... don't do this.
It's over.
Okay?
I'm sorry.
Maybe next time, don't make
your supplements out of fertilizer.
You have no idea what
you're talking about.
You're just a fat cat who
came along for the ride.
And I appreciate the cash,
but do not speak to me
like that again.
I am just fine to go it alone,
if that's what I'm up against.
There's another way.
I'll buy you out.
Both of you.
Take on all the
liability myself.
You sure you have the
cash for that suicide mission?
I'll figure it out.
50 cents on the dollar
for all your shares.
Hell, I mean, if I can get
some of my money back
and, uh, dodge this bullet,
I don't care how you do it.
I'm sold.
Okay.
But make it fast.
Why... did you...
Why... why did...
Well, because, at this point,
they think it's a coin
toss that 3B's at fault.
They're panicking.
And I think the odds are
slightly better than that.
You know, yeah, it's...
kind of betting the farm, but...
it's a chance to get
full ownership back
for the two people
I care most about.
Wow.
Thank you.
No, don't thank me.
Just...
Just pray we're not wrong.
Otherwise,
I just made the biggest
mistake of my life.
And we're both ruined.
♪ ♪
Where's your friend?
She's going through
some things right now.
Hmm. Are you looking
for her red flags?
Well, it's early.
You know?
She's looking
for your red flags.
What'd you tell her?
You mean what didn't I tell her.
You know, you are
enjoying this a little too much.
Mm-hmm.
I led with "compassionate."
Closed with "brilliant."
That she would be wise
to hold on and not let go.
♪ We're gonna rise,
hear the calling... ♪
And I told her about your cats.
All five of them.
The woman deserved a warning.
♪ We're gonna rise above... ♪
♪ We're gonna rise,
hear the calling ♪
♪ We're gonna find
that we belong ♪
♪ We're gonna rise
above where we've fallen ♪
♪ We're gonna rise... ♪
Hey.
Ah...
Mm...
You do not look or
smell like a 12-hour shift.
My new office has a shower.
Ooh. I remember that shower.
How are you feeling?
So much better.
You survived.
Yeah, and my patients did, too.
Really?
This amazing couple,
20 years together,
never spent a
single night apart.
Wow. That is amazing.
Something to aspire to.
No way.
- No way, right?
- No.
I mean, I love you, but...
time apart is healthy.
We've got, like, a
thing that works for us.
- It works beautifully.
- Mm-hmm.
Which requires the
occasional night apart.
Handful of nights;
rare exceptions.
Mm, a few handfuls.
Easy, now.
Tonight is not one
of those nights.
♪ We're gonna rise,
hear the calling ♪
♪ We're gonna find... ♪
How many handfuls?
♪ We're gonna rise above... ♪
I know you're not asleep.
♪ We're gonna rise... ♪
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH