Can't keep me here.
I need to go!
You've got to let me go.
My kids are coming
home from school.
I meet them at the bus
stop at 3:30 every day.
Relax. It's only
10 in the morning.
My icebox is empty.
I've got nothing
to cook for dinner.
You're in the hospital, ma'am.
We're going to take care of you.
I could get some ground chuck.
But they want 69 cents a pound.
Peter!
Have ya heard of such a thing?
I remember paying
29 cents a pound.
Where have you been?
Don't even think about T-bone.
I had to put a Swan in
upstairs. This the consult?
Mrs. Howard.
So, what's the problem?
Nursing home sent her in
because she's not eating.
Doesn't sound surgical.
Could be. You took out
her gallbladder last month.
But there's macaroni and cheese.
Hello, Mrs. Howard.
Oh, so nice to see you.
I'm Dr. Benton.
I know. I never forget
a handsome face.
Simon?
She's afebrile. I've
ordered a hemogram...
Simon! Simon!
Simon!
Who are you? CARTER: Simon!
Are you Simon? No?
Yosh, you seen a little guy
running through here alone?
Sorry.
Hey, Carter.
Lose something? Simon.
Where's his mom?
Mom went to the cafeteria
to get some chocolate milk.
But Simon's not
getting any treats
until he lets me draw his blood.
I don't want you
to take my blood.
We're only gonna
take about this much.
If you sit still,
this won't hurt.
I don't want a needle.
How about a papoose?
I think we're okay.
You sure? Hate for
you to lose him again.
Will you just
hold his arm still?
Okay.
Be brave and do not move.
Good one at the wrist.
Antecube looks better.
No!
Want to try an arm board?
No. Let's take a break.
Abby, I need another nurse.
You okay here? Go.
He kicked me in the face.
We need some Haldol.
Careful. He bit a
nurse's finger in Psych.
What's he doing down here?
He cut up his face.
You want some help?
Yeah.
Hey! Man, what'd
you do that for?
It was an April Fools' joke.
April Fools'?
Was that Haldol?
The board is full,
gurneys are lining the halls,
we got another 30 in the rack.
We desperately need
to clear out the rooms,
and you're wasting your
time on April Fools' pranks.
No more shenanigans
for the rest of the day.
Have I made myself clear?
Yes, ma'am. Uh-huh.
Dave!
Yeah.
How much did you give him?
Ten milligrams.
Okay. I want you to take a nap.
I'm fine.
What did I just say?
Go take a nap.
Before that?
No more fooling around.
That's right. Now,
get back to work.
Malucci!
It wasn't me, I swear.
What?
Nothing.
What's the matter with him?
Ten of Haldol.
Oh, yeah?
Hey.
Dr. Carter.
You were supposed to
get this after we took blood.
I'm sorry. I can
get another one.
No. That's okay.
You want another chocolate milk?
No, really... I don't mind.
Be a good boy,
Simon. I'll be right back.
You know, I didn't
call you down here.
The nurses did.
They said you were
having some trouble.
Not me.
Well, he's ready now.
Malik, can you give me a hand?
Yeah, sure.
It's better if you
don't hold onto him.
Yeah. We tried that once.
Ended up in the closet.
Trust me.
Purple and a red top.
Okay, Simon. Are you ready?
You might want to give
Simon here a, uh, friendly hug.
Keep blowing bubbles, Simon.
Blow right through
the pain, okay?
Fine.
Good. That's it.
Good boy.
What do you want for the labs?
A CBC, lytes, BUN,
creatinine and glucose.
Okay. We are done.
You were very brave.
Let me hook you
up with a Band-Aid,
and you are good to go.
Thank you.
No problem.
So how's your internship going?
It's good. Yeah?
I haven't seen
you around lately.
You been busy?
Yeah.
I should probably
get back upstairs.
Nice to see you again.
You too.
Is this the trauma?
Yeah. Eddie Palcynski, 32,
single gunshot
wound to the belly.
Hypotensive initially.
I take it he's not
an innocent victim.
Tried to hold up a liquor store.
It wasn't me. That
other dude had a knife.
Any pain in the chest?
Just my stomach.
What happened to you?
Chased his partner.
Did you get him? Not exactly.
No, you actually
would have had to run.
Heard you had a GSW.
Right upper quadrant.
Can you get this? No problem.
Need a hand?
Take a look at that arm injury.
You just need a Band-Aid.
Yeah, over your mouth.
Officer?
Be good, they'll
give you a lollipop.
On my count. One, two, three.
Where is my purse?
I've lost my purse!
Hey, who's got the screamer?
Dr. Finch. Benton
cleared her belly.
Can we put her in a room?
If we had one.
Nurse, I need my
wallet and my car keys.
Nice outfit you
got there, Randi.
Thanks, Dr. Carter.
I can't go anywhere
without my keys!
You look nice too.
So are you Dr. Carter
now or Mr. Hyde?
Oh, I'm sorry about that.
I guess I just needed
a cup of coffee.
And I suppose seeing, uh,
Miss Bubbles had nothing to do
with your sudden
mood change? No.
No? Come on. You've been
moping around here for days.
And then the
minute she shows up,
you turn into Mr. Congeniality?
I was just being friendly.
I was!
Did somebody order a school bus?
Grace Linden.
Stuart's having
an asthma attack.
Get a gurney and
a hand-held neb.
You use an inhaler?
Empty. How long's he been bad?
About 10 minutes. There
are fumes on the bus.
Exhaust fumes?
No, something else.
Some of the kids
are throwing up.
We can't bring them in.
It's a HAZMAT situation.
Until we know there's
no contamination
you have to wait outside.
In the cold?
A gram of cefotetan
and repeat the CBC in pre-op.
What's this?
Small-caliber
gunshot to the liver.
I want four units of
type-specific in the O.R.
Thought Benton was on.
Yeah. You need something?
How long's the case?
Couple of hepatic drains,
couple of sutures
and we'll be done.
Sounds quick. Should be.
Hope so. Mm-hm.
He needs 125 of Solu-Medrol...
We are walking.
We are not talking.
Let's get him into a
gown and bag his clothes.
Okay. Can you hop up here?
Stu, Stu, stupid!
I think you broke your
ass. I can see the crack.
When the hand goes
up, the mouth goes shut.
Arms up.
You guys on a field trip?
Art Institute.
Oh, yeah? The Gauguin exhibit?
We never made it.
Hey, nice rack, Stu.
Make 'em bounce.
Okay, that's enough!
Hey, doc, you do liposuction?
Toby, next time it is
you, me and the principal.
Keep moving. We are walking...
Don't even listen to them.
Anything else?
Some number-one
chromic on a liver needle.
Lizzie, I heard you're
doing an ex-lap on a GSW?
You heard correctly.
Sure you can still
reach the table?
Least I can see the table.
Well, I was gonna offer
to assist after my AV shunt
but not if you're gonna
go prenatal on me.
Actually, if you
really want to help,
you can order me some
pizza and ice cream.
Think you need it?
Razor wire.
More like a cyclone fence.
It's pretty deep.
We can help you.
I need to use the toilet.
We're gonna move
you to a quiet room.
I need you to
spread your fingers.
Dr. Weaver, we got
a status asthmaticus.
Chuny, can you help her
with the bedpan, please?
He needs continuous nebs.
Where do you want to put him?
One second.
Sit up for me, Stuart.
Hey, your guy is seizing in 2.
Okay.
Cock your wrist back like this:
I'll go by myself.
Can't keep me
here or where to go.
Stand up.
You can let me
go if I want to go.
Hold your hands like this:
A prisoner I'm not.
I'm gonna press down.
Just keep them up, all right?
Let me go. I don't
need to be here.
Hey!
This is not right.
Drop the gun, ma'am.
Can't do this to me.
Drop the gun,
ma'am. Drop it now.
Just leave me alone!
Everybody calm down.
Put it down now and
no one will get hurt.
Leave me alone!
Just leave me alone!
Drop the gun.
Leave me...
10 blade. Set up a cell
saver and try for a pulse ox.
Central line is in. Two
units on the infuser.
Rib spreader.
We asked three times.
Yeah. She didn't respond.
Asystole.
Start internal compressions.
How'd she get your
gun? I don't know.
What are you gonna say?
Put the suction on high.
We'll talk about it.
Right atrium is
completely shredded.
We should figure it out.
Aortic root is blown away.
Guess one shot wasn't enough.
Come here.
Another amp of epi.
Side-biting clamp and pick-ups.
I need a cordis
introducer for the atrium.
I need a lap pad. Let's go!
Hope they get
their story straight.
It's okay.
All clear. No carbon
monoxide, no flammables.
The kids smelled something?
Maybe, but it's gone now.
Probably just mass hysteria.
That's it?
Kids smell nail-polish remover,
pretty soon everybody
thinks they're sick.
Do we need to scrub them down?
No one's contaminated.
All right. Let's split 'em up.
Who had vomiting?
Me. So did I.
Luka, postural
vitals and a pulse ox.
Okay. Come with me.
What's your name?
Emily.
Are you still nauseated? Yeah.
Any stiff neck or double vision?
No.
Are you really a doctor?
When I'm not out
fighting crime. This way.
All right, guys. Let's go.
We like it out here.
They say fresh
air's good for you.
Put out your cigarette.
You got a spare ashtray?
Come on.
Beck's suture.
Fifth and sixth units are in.
How's she doing?
Heart's empty. Not so good.
Looks like hamburger in here.
Officer Kimball, did you
discharge your weapon?
Go with Detective Westland.
Satinsky.
Officer Grant, you're with me.
Push another atropine.
I need the names of
the treating physicians.
Dr. Weaver.
12 French Foley.
Let's move, people.
And Dr. Benton.
Okay. Inflate balloon.
Did you witness the shooting?
We both did.
B-E-N-T-E-N?
O-N.
Okay. Hold compressions.
Still asystole.
Is she gonna make it?
Not if you don't
let us do our job.
Let me know if she expires.
Resume compressions.
You want some more blood?
How long has she been down?
Half an hour.
All right, let's get,
uh, two more units,
and I need some
more 0 silk. Come on.
I'll get some.
Deep breath.
Excuse me.
Once again.
Is that stuff still in my lungs?
I don't think so.
Everything sounds good.
What kind of chemical was it?
We don't know.
Well, then how do
you know it's safe?
Because your
oxygen level is normal
and your lungs are clear.
Do you think it
could hurt my baby?
You're pregnant?
I think so.
Laura Beckton, 23. Put
her car into a hydrant.
She's altered. No
response to verbal.
This is a crime scene.
We have a critical...
Gotta go around. Let us through!
I can't.
BP, 120/85. Pulse, 90.
What's with all the cops?
We had a shooting.
Let's get X-ray down here.
Laura, open your eyes.
Pupils are equal and reactive.
Let's get a portable
C-spine, chest and pelvis.
Head CT to follow.
Looks like Peter's
patient didn't make it.
What patient?
Little old lady from the hall.
That's my patient.
Cop shot her.
What?
Feeling better?
Starting to. Did that lady die?
Think it'll be on the news?
Yeah.
She could have
blown my head off.
Weren't you scared?
A little.
Then why'd you
get in front of me?
Guess I wasn't thinking.
I was really scared.
Me too.
You're still wheezing.
Have you had a cold?
No.
Well, something
triggered your asthma.
Think it was the fumes?
Maybe. I don't know.
You're not sure?
I'm just trying to help.
It was the fumes.
Where'd they come from?
You know, anything that
you tell me is a secret.
Another 4.0 proline.
Shirley, can you
rub my back for me?
Excuse me?
Yeah, just above
the waist on the right.
Oh, yes. Yeah, that's it.
Okay. Release the vessel loop.
Oh, yeah. That's it.
I'm sorry. This
must be the day spa.
I was looking for the O.R.
Everything's under control.
I hope so. You've been
in here long enough.
I've repaired the liver, the
diaphragm and now the IVC.
Uh-huh. What about the
defect to the ascending colon?
Where?
Little lower.
Yeah, right there.
I hadn't fully run
the bowel yet.
Or maybe this is too big a case,
given your delicate condition?
We were doing perfectly well
until you came in, thank you.
Are you crying?
No.
We don't cry in the O.R.,
that's what the
ladies' room is for.
I'm not crying!
Good. Then you
won't mind if I scrub in.
Where's Malucci?
He's with his new fan club.
As if. Find him.
Right now?
No, sometime in
the next two weeks.
Don't be so snippy.
Some kids on the bus
had a can of solvent.
They were huffing?
Trying to get high.
I've got a pregnant girl.
What were they using?
I don't know.
They held a rag
over my patient's face
and forced him to take a hit.
Tox screens are negative.
Solvents. They don't show up.
We need to find out.
I know where to start.
Don't implicate Stuart.
He's afraid of payback.
Tell him.
Dr. Dave was talking to me
and he fell asleep in the chair.
Now he's drooling.
Okay, Mr. Gunderson, you
need to change into a gown.
The doctor will be
in to examine you.
Just have a seat on the bed.
Dave.
Dave. Dave!
I'm good.
No, man. You gotta
stick it up his butt.
Okay, guys. What
were you sniffing?
What? On the bus.
You smell something
on the bus, Eric?
Yeah, Mrs. Linden's farts.
We found chemical
solvents in your bloodstream.
Some of your
classmates are really sick.
Can I get another Band-Aid?
I need to know what it was.
Butane, paint thinner, adhesive?
Okay, fine. We'll do more tests.
Bo? Come here.
What kind of tests?
Just lie still, man.
We take the blood and label
it with radioactive hydrogen.
Then we re-inject
it into your body
and do a nuclear scan.
Really?
It's the only way to
identify the chemicals.
It was spot remover.
What kind?
Carbon tet.
Carbon tetrachloride?
Order liver panels
on all three of 'em.
Got it.
We gonna be okay?
I hope so.
Hey, can I help you?
Yeah, I'm looking for Rena.
She's just finishing
up with a patient.
Dr. Carter, right?
Yeah. Have we met?
No. I'll let her
know you're here.
We didn't have... We didn't...
Dr. Carter?
Yeah, hi. I...
Don't worry about it.
This is always falling apart.
Okay, actually,
it goes like this.
Are you sure you're a doctor?
I was a surgical
resident for a year.
I guess it's easier
taking things out
than, uh, putting it back in.
I was waiting and I
accidentally eviscerated this guy.
I heard about the
shooting. Are you okay?
Yeah.
Did you need something?
I've been doing some
thinking about you and me.
And I realize that
I may have been...
Stupid?
I was gonna say wrong.
But maybe I was
a little of both.
Look, I enjoyed the time
that we spent together.
I'd like to do it again.
So I was wondering if you
would have lunch with me.
What about the age thing?
Not an issue.
Anymore.
You dropped your spleen.
Right. So is that a no?
I'll think about it.
Okay.
I was just up at grand rounds.
Why didn't anyone get me?
There wasn't any
time. She arrested.
She wasn't that
agitated when I left.
What did she want with the gun?
She didn't want anything.
She was altered...
Dr. Benton, the cop is
still waiting for his sutures.
Yeah. I'll see you.
Got the film.
I have to get out of here now.
You need to sit down.
You were unconscious
from a car accident.
I'm gonna be late. For what?
For my gynecologist.
They have to harvest
my eggs by 6:00.
Are you on fertility drugs?
Yeah. I had 10 days
of FSH injections.
And yesterday they
gave me Beta HCG.
Look, I'm ovulating now.
There's only a two-hour
window to retrieve the eggs.
I don't think that's
gonna be possible now.
Why, did I damage my ovaries?
Head CT looks normal.
We think you may have had
a small blood clot in your brain
which caused you to pass
out and crash your car.
But I'm okay now?
We need to give
you blood thinners
to prevent more clotting.
I'll go to the clinic
and come back.
You need heparin now,
which means you can't
have an invasive procedure.
When I come back,
you can do whatever.
I have to harvest these eggs.
Hold on. Who's
your gynecologist?
Her name is Dr. Alexander.
Let's call her and
maybe she'll come here.
What is taking so long?
Have a seat.
Did you do the test?
You are pregnant.
I knew it.
What about the fumes?
Shouldn't be a problem.
Good. I want a healthy baby.
Have you thought
about your options?
What do you mean?
Can you take care of a baby?
Well, there's daycare
in high school.
And my mom can help
out until I'm in ninth grade.
Does your mom know?
Maybe you should tell her.
No. Don't tell her.
She'll freak out completely.
It's a big decision.
No, it's not.
All my life I wanted a baby.
She's a good cop. Saved
my ass a couple of times.
No one ever wants
to draw their gun.
She was forced to make
a split-second decision.
Was she?
She followed the guidelines.
Mm. They teach you to
shoot little old ladies, huh?
She could have shot anyone
in that hallway. You know that.
All I know is that an
elderly black woman is dead.
No, man.
Lisa's not like that at all.
I would have done
the same thing.
Yeah, well...
Hold still.
You don't know her.
You can trust her.
She's a good person. She...
Look. She's been raising
two kids on her own
ever since her husband died.
She's had it rough.
I'm telling you,
this investigation
goes the wrong way,
you could ruin
a good cop's life.
She was trying to protect
you and your patients.
That's all she was doing.
You might wanna consider that,
maybe talk to these detectives.
I know she's in the
middle of a procedure.
Page Dr. Alexander.
Have her call Dr. Greene
at County General.
Hold on, Malik.
Yeah. The patient's name
is Laura Beckton. Thanks.
Robert Borsellino? Yeah.
This is Bo? Yeah.
We need a ProTime,
type and cross for four.
You gonna admit him?
Pedes ICU.
She's in seventh grade.
They're emancipated
for a reason.
When they're pregnant,
you can't tell her mother.
She'll have to eventually.
Yes, she will.
Don't you think it's
better to tell her now?
Well, yeah. I do.
So you'll talk to her?
What?
Maybe she'll listen to you.
What room? Exam 2.
I don't need this. I can
just go home and rest.
What we need is
to find your parents.
They don't get back till 8 or 9.
They have a cell
phone or a pager?
No. Don't even bother.
We really do.
Well, what is it?
You're in liver failure.
How'd that happen?
You need to huff pretty much
every day to hurt your liver.
People drink every day.
This is worse.
We have to start
looking for a donor.
A donor?
You could die if you don't
have a liver transplant.
Is this another one
of your scare tactics?
No.
Mark, Laura's crashing.
I'll be back. What happened?
She slumped over,
stopped breathing.
I should have heparinized.
Pavulon and sux. Let's paralyze.
I don't think you have to.
Number 8 ET tube, suction.
No muscle tone
in the legs either.
Blood clot knocked out
the corticospinal tracts.
She's a quadriplegic.
How about TPA? Maybe
we can bust the clot.
Not after a car crash.
Pulmonary contusions.
She could bleed into her lungs.
Dr. Greene? I took a message.
Dr. Alexander can
come see the patient.
Forget it. She stroked out.
And you also
heard Officer Kimball
ask the woman to
drop the weapon?
Yeah.
What happened next?
Mrs. Howard was startled,
and she raised the gun.
Pointed at anyone in particular?
There were patients around,
but, no, no one specifically.
Okay.
We'll notify you if we
need anything else.
That's it?
Yeah.
Something you'd like to add?
Yeah, they could
have grabbed the gun.
What makes you say that?
She was a frail, frightened,
demented elderly woman.
She didn't know
what she was doing.
She still could have fired.
Maybe.
But?
They didn't need to shoot her.
Was she huffing?
No. No.
I've talked to her about drugs.
But you never know.
I don't think she does drugs.
I shouldn't have let
her go on that field trip.
Why? She's been sick.
She tells me she's been
throwing up every morning.
Could that be gallstones?
My mother had them.
Do you know when
was her last period?
I don't keep track.
She has a boyfriend?
Is she pregnant?
Oh, that little slut.
Mrs. Perault. How
could you be so stupid?
What? This is your mother?
Yes. I'm her mother.
If you're gonna sleep
around, use a condom!
He didn't want to.
No need to shout.
Who is the little bastard?
You're getting an abortion.
I am not. Yes, you are!
Leave me alone.
Why don't we all calm down.
You can't take care of a baby.
You can't even
take care of yourself!
Get her out of here.
I need you to step outside.
I need you to mind
your own business.
Mrs. Perault.
Told you not to tell
her. She's a psycho.
She is not leaving
here pregnant!
Yes, I am. I'm having this baby.
And I'm gonna be a much
better mother than you, you bitch.
You doing your homework?
No, that lady brought it in.
What lady?
The really cute one
with the curly hair.
She works in Pediatrics.
Oh, yeah. Rena. Yeah.
Hey, we found out exactly
what caused your asthma.
You tell them I told you?
Didn't have to. They told us.
They told you, or you asked?
Either way, it's not a problem.
They think I squealed.
Bo is gonna kick
the crap out of me!
Don't worry about Bo.
Everything is
gonna be all right.
No. It won't. They saw me naked!
They just saw you
from the waist up.
They're gonna make
fun of me forever.
Listen, I knew a boy
who was a little husky.
He didn't have many friends
and all the kids used
to make fun of him.
So he spent most
of his time studying.
And he went on to college
and he became a surgeon.
And at his high-school
reunion, he took out his scalpel
and he cut the
tongues off of every kid
who ever made fun of him.
That supposed to
cheer me up, doc?
Okay. Help me immobilize
the small intestine.
Pancreas is fine.
Uh-oh. Take a look at this.
It's a hematoma of the duodenum.
Yeah. The bullet went
through the medial aspect
of the second portion.
You're kidding.
Have you known me to kid?
Okay, open a
pancreaticoduodenectomy tray.
He needs a Whipple.
That's a five-hour procedure.
I'll call in Peter.
No, no. It's my
patient. I'll finish.
No, no, no. No need
to torture yourself.
I just need a bathroom break.
A bathroom break?
Well, I am seven
months pregnant.
Should have considered
that before you started.
I'll be back in five minutes.
Fine. Shirley, call in
another scrub tech.
I need an extra pair of hands.
Okay. Forget it. I won't go.
Go.
No! I won't!
Bovie, pickups.
Shirley, can you crawl between
my legs and insert a Foley?
All right, all right, go
on. Go on. Get out.
Go on. Get out
of here. Go ahead.
Don't you need a
cable or something?
Nope. It just sends it
right to your phone. Done.
Okay, okay. Call me.
Okay.
Papa Roach. That is so cool!
Stuart, do one
for me. Blink-182.
Looks like he's found
some new friends.
How'd you do that?
Well, I guess it's a
little late for lunch.
Well, we got busy
with all these kids.
How about dinner?
I'll probably grab a Happy
Meal on the way home.
Okay, I deserve that.
Now you can forgive me.
I don't know.
Come on. I'm starving. You,
me, a couple of big steaks.
I'm a vegetarian.
Or Brussels sprouts.
It's a school night.
No, seriously.
I've got a midterm tomorrow.
Well, I can help you study.
Might have to
pull an all-nighter.
So is that a yes?
Excuse me.
So where and when?
Let me think about it.
I'll call you when I know
something more specific.
I thought you were
over this age thing.
I am.
So, what was that about?
Do you know Abby?
No, but she seems nice.
She's nice. Yeah.
No, she's just...
She's always had
this thing for me.
You used to go out with her?
She's got some issues.
She gets a little weird
around other nurses
and stuff, so it's probably
best not to let her on...
Let on about us.
I'll meet you down
here after your shift.
Yeah. Sounds like a plan.
Okay.
When you have a chance,
her family wants to talk to you.
Peter.
Hey.
Mrs. Howard's sodium was 172.
What?
She was delirious because
of profound dehydration.
Did you check her
mucous membranes?
I examined her abdomen
for post-op complications.
That's it?
Well, didn't you examine her?
I shotgunned her labs
and gave her to you.
Come here.
This whole thing
was preventable.
If I had recognized the
problem and started an IV
hell, given her
a glass of water,
she might still be alive.
You don't know that.
It takes time to make a
diagnosis when we're busy.
She wouldn't have
grabbed the gun.
No reason for them to shoot her.
You'll see a tube in her
mouth hooked up to a ventilator.
Well, she's not breathing?
The stroke affected
the part of her brain
that controls breathing.
Will that get better?
We'll have to wait and see.
Here.
You can sit down.
Laura? It's Greg.
I'm right here.
God, she's only 23.
How could she have a stroke?
We think the fertility
drugs caused the blood clot.
Fertility drugs?
The injections.
What are you talking about?
I talked to her gynecologist.
Your wife was trying
to be an egg donor.
She was selling her eggs?
There was an infertile
couple willing to pay $80,000.
We have this, uh,
little hardware store.
Bills are stacking up.
Business is down...
We're about to
file for bankruptcy.
I guess she was trying to help.
I'm sorry.
You didn't have
to do this, honey.
You didn't have to do this.
Is Dr. Carter around?
He was here a minute ago.
Will you tell him I'll be late?
There's a new
admission to the PICU.
No problem.
Hi. Hi.
I'm Rena. Abby.
You're Dr. Carter's friend?
That's right.
I hope you don't mind me
spending time with John.
Why would I?
Well, he told me.
Told you what?
About you and him.
Me and him?
I don't want there to
be any hard feelings.
I understand how some
relationships take longer
to get over than others.
He told you we
had a relationship?
I find his honesty refreshing.
He's different than most guys.
Oh, yeah.
He's special.
Good view of the
heartbeat. There's the head.
"It's time to
explore new places.
"Even though Taureans
cringe at the thought of change,
trust what lies ahead as a
once-in-a-lifetime opportunity."
That's so perfect. What?
My horoscope. What's your sign?
I don't know.
Well, when's your birthday?
Looks like you're
about 10 weeks along.
So when will I have it?
November.
Early Christmas present.
Oh. Look, how cute.
Babies are a lot
of responsibility.
I know.
It's hard work getting up
in the middle of the night.
It's easy if you love them.
How old was your mom
when you were born?
Sixteen.
Maybe if she had
waited a couple years,
she would have
been a better mother.
I'm way more mature
than she was at 16.
I'm gonna have a social
worker stop by to see you.
Good. I need to sign up.
For what?
Money. When my
friend Gina had her baby
she started getting
a check every month.
Your wife wanted...
Randi, any word from the O.R.?
They're still working.
No, no! I said no!
We won't harm her in any way.
Stay the hell away from my wife!
Dr. Alexander, Mark Greene.
Could you keep her
out of here, please?
What are you doing?
Discussing his wife's condition.
Right now you're a
consultant. Talk to me first.
I couldn't find you.
I was reviewing her
records when he walked in.
No, you were twisting his arm
because you want
to harvest the eggs.
I was presenting
it as an option.
He'll never let you do it.
She's already given her consent.
He just lost his wife.
Leave him alone.
Dr. Greene, she's gonna
need a lengthy hospitalization.
And then round-the-clock
home nursing care.
That's a tremendous
financial burden.
Thanks to your fertility drugs.
I don't think so.
I've been doing IVF for 12 years
and I've never seen this happen.
She must have a protein S
or an anti-thrombin deficiency.
Those are pretty
rare conditions.
Not as rare as a vascular
occlusion from FSH.
I'll send up the labs.
There's an hour left
to retrieve the eggs.
It's a 10-minute procedure
but it'll give them a
nice financial cushion.
Why don't you try
and calm him down,
discuss the situation.
Mm-hm.
Another Vicryl.
Why don't you go take a nap?
Because I've got my second wind.
Well, it's about time.
I'm happy to close.
Be my guest.
Skin stapler.
Dr. Greene called again.
He'd like you to phone
him when the case is over.
Oh, how sweet.
You are one lucky lady.
Couple of ABDs.
You gonna write post-op orders?
Yes. Leave the clipboard for me.
Okay. Here we
go. One, two, three.
ABG in 20 minutes.
I'll meet you in Recovery.
His brother's in
the Waiting Room.
Can you talk to him?
Yeah.
Hey, Abby. Can you update
the tetanus on my foot lac?
Sure, why not?
You okay?
Oh, yeah. I'm peachy.
What's wrong?
I don't know, maybe I'm
still getting over our breakup.
You talked to Rena.
Yeah.
I'm sorry. I panicked. I...
What did you say to her?
Nothing. No, really.
Really. Against
my better judgment
and everything I
hold sacred in life
I covered for you.
So you owe me one.
Thank you.
Sure.
Also, I told her I dumped you.
Ha. You dumped
me? She believe you?
Of course she did.
Why wouldn't she?
Well, it's just... You'd
never dump me.
I would dump you
like a bad habit.
Oh, no.
I definitely think
I'd dump you first.
In your dreams, maybe.
I would dump you.
No, you wouldn't.
You're acting crazy now.
What's that?
Pulse ox came off.
That's it for the right side.
She in any pain?
No.
Left ovary looks good.
She wrote children's books.
Did you know that?
Those were our bedtime stories.
I still can't believe
this is happening.
She's had dementia
for such a long time.
I know.
Usually she's forgetful
or thinks she's
still living at home.
But she's never been
agitated or violent.
I can't imagine her
fighting with the police.
So you're sure it's
nothing from the surgery?
No, no. Dementia is
a progressive illness.
Over time there's worsening
psychiatric symptoms.
You know, it's been so
hard to watch her deteriorate.
Even little things
can lead to agitation.
Sleep deprivation,
a bladder infection.
Actually, we think
it was dehydration.
From not drinking enough?
There's too many people
at that nursing home.
They weren't even
giving her water.
I never should have
moved her out of the house.
It was too much for you.
I could have done it. I
could have cared for her.
I was the one who
put her in there.
This is not your fault.
Thank you, Dr. Benton.
I know she appreciated
your kindness.
I was looking
everywhere for you.
Is that Dermabond?
How's he gonna get it off?
Maybe he'll find some acetone.
Carter, could you pitch in
with some chart reviews?
It's okay.
I promised Rena
I'd help her study.
Tutoring?
Yeah. It's a
midterm, right? Yeah.
Family Studies. Psychology.
Good night, Dr. Carter.
Randi, could you
call up to the O.R.?
Again? Yes.
Don't bother.
I thought you'd never get out.
Neither did I.
How are you?
If I don't get off my feet,
my ankles are going to explode.
Did your patient make it?
Yeah. How was your day?
The usual.
You save any lives?
I hope so.
Oh, thank you. That's wonderful.
Dr. Corday, your
dinner has arrived.
"Nice work, Mom."
It's from Robert.
Maybe we should have
someone taste it first.
I'm so hungry.
Pepperoni pizza.
And ice cream.
Cherry Garcia.
Oh. Let's go with
the ice cream first.
Oh, I had the most
difficult case today,
and I got through it.
Mm. Mm!
That's good. Have some.
Mm.
Now that it's over, I'm thinking
why do I have to prove that
a pregnant surgeon can...
Can be competent?
I don't know.
I can operate until
the day I deliver.
But what the hell for?
So, as of now, I'm
officially on maternity leave.
I'm going to rest,
I'm gonna take care
of myself and my baby.
Oops. No napkins.
If I should call you
up Invest a dime
And you say you
Belong to me...
Mark, can I just sleep here?
I don't think I have
the strength to move.
I don't think I have the
strength to carry you.
Keep it coming. Sorry.
I can't see me
Loving nobody but you
For all my life
When you're with me
Baby, the skies'll be blue
For all my life
Me and you And you and me
No matter how
they Toss the dice
It had to be The
only one for me is you