Previously on ER:
My car's up the
street. You want a ride?
- Dr. Romano, you're back.
- Hide your wild enthusiasm of my return.
I find overt displays of
emotion embarrassing.
Did you think about me? - Yes.
Okay. What did you think?
- Where am I going?
- Home.
Give this to Abby
when you see her.
On any given day, this Emergency
Department will treat 300 patients.
Another 40 will leave
without ever being seen.
In order to not get buried, you have
to maintain adequate patient flow.
This all starts with the nurses.
Treat them with respect,
they'll get you through your shift.
Treat them as your personal scut
slaves, you'll be lucky to get out alive.
Triage is our first line of defense.
Patients are signed in and vitaled...
by whoever's working the cage.
- The cage?
Like a shark cage. You can see them
circling around, but they can't get you.
- When is Kovac getting here?
- Flight should land at 7:30.
What about Carter?
Can you rack this?
Triage nurse starts the chart,
which is then racked at Admit.
- Put your name in for the lottery.
- Once the patients are brought back...
their name is put on the board, along
with time, location and chief complaint.
Dr. Pratt is also a second-year Resident.
Pratt, this is three of our new R-2s.
- Sofun, Morris, Cooper.
- Welcome to the zoo.
What do I give a
10-year-old with road rash?
Acetaminophen's easy on the stomach,
but ibuprofen's better for inflammation.
Med students work up patients
and present them to Residents.
You can mentor, but ultimately every
case has to be looked at by an Attending.
I know my rights! This
is assault and battery!
- I'm coming back for you, bitch.
- Yeah, yeah...
- bring me a latte when you do.
- Dr. Lewis is one of our Attendings.
We usually we have two working.
They have to sign off on every case.
Don't remind me.
Second-year Residents?
- Cooper, Sofun, Morris.
- Grab a chart.
Abby, could you set up
the airway box in Exam 3...
so they can practice
assembling laryngoscopes?
Mm-hm.
Nursing orders go there.
Clerk orders go here.
These are two of our clerks, Jerry
and Frank. Please don't feed them.
When you're done, the discharge
rack is over here. Any questions?
Yeah, why is the
board see-through?
- So we can see through it.
- Remind me not to get sick anytime soon.
- The ambulance pick Luka up yet?
- An hour ago. They should be here soon.
- He need a bed down here?
- No, no, they got one for him upstairs.
Have you seen the schedule?
- No.
I'm only working four
shifts in two weeks.
- I only got three.
- How many do I have?
- Two?
- We're starting a petition.
We got more beds, but fewer nurses.
Romano's cutting senior nurse hours...
- so he can bring in cheaper travelers.
- You need to talk to him.
You lost the Triage lottery,
Abby. You got the cage from 9 to 1.
Come on, no way. I lose every time.
- Abby.
That's, like, statistically impossible.
- Abby!
What?
How you doing, Luka? - Okay.
Welcome back, man.
Africa agrees with you.
- I need you to help me with a GI bleeder.
- Two minutes. Let me say hi to Luka.
Sir, you have to stay in bed.
Here, lie down. Lie down. I
need sedation orders over here.
I think Mrs. Dunn's in labor.
- She's only 36 weeks.
Explain Braxton Hicks
contractions to her.
Her water broke.
Please, I need a nurse!
- Did you nitrazine it?
- No, I was helping her to the bathroom.
- Page OB and call an Attending.
- Please, somebody, help me!
- Hi.
- Aah!
Okay, breathe. Don't push.
- It's too early.
- No, 36 weeks...
is what we start
calling "normal term."
All right, try and relax.
I'm gonna do a quick exam.
I need a fetal monitor and an IV.
- Okay. I got it.
Oh! Lewis needs
that in Curtain 1.
- Thank you. MALIK:
You're welcome.
- Show me how to set the slit-lamp?
- Yup, just one second.
Luka.
Hey, I think this old
lady stopped breathing.
Dr. Romano, hi.
How are you today?
- I'm busy.
- How's the stump feeling?
It's suffering from delusions of
grandeur. It still thinks it's an arm.
- What's that? DOCTOR:
Your new prosthesis.
Okay. I'm sorry. I just
assumed as a prosthetist...
that you would have some
rudimentary knowledge of medicine.
- I have a degree in bioengineering.
- Well, then you have a vague...
civilian concept of what
doctors do. I'm a surgeon.
That's why I was specific
about needing a Utah Arm.
Your hospital insurance won't
cover a myoelectric device.
I lost my arm on the roof
of this damn hospital...
- trying to save a patient's life.
- They require proof you can't get by...
- with a traditional device.
- What do I do?
Am I supposed to just duct-tape
a coat hanger to my stump?
I can prepare another
letter to insurance.
I've got two letters for you and
the insurance company, F and U.
- It's hurting my arm.
- A little bit longer.
Why can't I just have my prescription
filled without being tortured?
- How much longer? My back's killing me.
- I'll let you know.
- I don't wanna miss my turn.
- Then you should sit down.
Okay, put this in your mouth.
Be a good girl, Ilanna.
Open your mouth.
I think it was a black widow.
Darren, don't touch that.
- Hey. Hey, hey.
- Darren, stop it.
- Give me that.
- Is it almost my time?
No.
Tell her.
Tell the nurse what you ate,
Lisa. Well, go on. Tell her.
Maybe you should,
Mrs. Brandenburg.
I brought my own urine
sample to save time.
- Could I at least get a sandwich?
- How did you get back here? Security!
Hey, wake up!
She's getting worse.
- Do you have asthma, Elle?
- No.
- Anybody sick at home? Any fevers?
Okay, deep breaths.
- How long have you had that cough?
- Since we went camping.
Uh, a few weeks, maybe.
She lets herself get rundown,
and she doesn't eat enough.
What's that?
The oxygen level in your
blood is a little bit low...
which can happen with
infection. Frank, what's open?
- Curtain 1.
- Okay, I'm taking this one back.
Come on, Elle. Gonna put you
in a bed, get you some oxygen...
and that should
make you feel better.
Oh, Dr. Lewis. This is Mrs.
Ryser and her daughter, Elle.
Shortness of breath,
sats are 86, bibasilar rales.
Yeah. Can you grab a Resident?
I think an Attending
should take a look at her.
Hi, I'm Dr. Lewis.
Come on this way.
The rest of her vitals okay?
Tachy at 116. BP's 98/52.
- A & O times three.
- What are rales?
It's the sound fluid makes
when it's in your lungs.
That doesn't sound good.
It's probably just pneumonia.
Great. She never dresses warm enough
and she's always going out with wet hair.
- Mom, please. LEWIS:
All right, let's get a chest.
- I'll be back to do a full exam, okay?
- Thanks.
- Are you coming back?
- Yeah. And don't worry.
The only thing you can catch
from wet hair is split ends.
Yeah, send her up for a
chest and draw a CBC.
- How's Luka?
- I haven't had a chance to get upstairs.
If you do go upstairs, let me
know and maybe I can come.
- Okay.
- Have you talked to him?
- Luka?
- No, Romano. We gave him the petition.
You better do something or you're
gonna have a mutiny on your hands.
As soon as I can,
I will. I promise.
Frank, where'd they send Kovac?
- Five West. He looks good.
- You saw him?
Just popped my head
in to welcome him back.
Wouldn't hurt you
to do the same thing.
Hi, could I get an update
on a patient, please? Kovac.
K-O-V-A-C.
- Right, malaria.
- He's still spiking on quinine...
but lucid between fevers. And
he's asking for a meatball sub.
- Either he's delirious or hungry.
- Never mind.
- Hi.
- I'm Gillian.
- Abby.
Oh, you're Abby? John
talked a lot about you.
John...
- Carter?
- Yeah.
I'm sorry. Who did
you say you were?
I'm sorry. You don't
know. I'm Gillian.
I was working with Luka
and John in the Congo.
Oh, I have something for you.
Um, John asked
Luka to give you this.
- He wrote me a letter?
- Now, there's a lost art.
Well, it's hard to find a phone
and when you do, they seldom work.
- Where do I find Dr. Magoo's?
- You don't. It burned down.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Nance, I'm taking my break.
Am I interrupting? Your
assistant wasn't at his desk.
We're in the
middle of a meeting.
That's why you haven't returned
my pages. I'm Dr. Romano.
Jeez. I'm sorry.
Let me get that.
- Okay. Stop. ROMANO:
You know what?
I'm not good at using this thing.
Maybe if the hospital's workers' comp...
had covered a myoelectric
arm, it would be better.
- Robert...
- What do I have to do?
Pay for it myself? That'd
make a good news story, huh?
Amputee surgeon has to pay for his arm
to work in the hospital where he lost it.
It's not the place or time to discuss this.
- You're right.
I've got a lot of patients
in the ER. That's
where using this
hook really gets dicey.
Wish me luck. Hopefully I won't
take someone's eye out with this thing.
We're staging a walkout.
Meeting at Dunkin' Donuts to plan.
- What?
If we don't take a stand, they're
gonna replace us with part-time nurses...
- so they don't have to pay benefits.
- Yeah, they're welcome to replace me.
- Is anybody working here today?
- Talk to Dr. Romano.
- I will.
- A joker just fainted in the waiting area.
Took a header into an end
table. There's blood everywhere.
Abby?
Why... Why are
you telling me this?
Well, according to my
watch, your break is over.
That's right. Leave
me to pick up after you.
Hey, wait. Hold up,
hold up. Hold up.
Sorry. I just ran down from CT.
- You're Pratt?
- Yeah.
Nick Cooper, second-year
Resident. Friends call me Coop.
Plastics or Head and Neck for
an unstable mandible fracture?
Call them both.
Take whoever is first.
- What do I tell the other?
- Patient left.
They'll be happy. It's one
less consult for their team.
- Cool.
- You new guys got to start picking it up.
It's only 10:30, we're
already 20 patients behind.
- I got six.
- The other two are slow.
Morris has an LOL with abdominal
pain and altered mental status.
It's a big workup, possible LP.
Sofun's still getting the lay of the land.
- They're killing me.
- Don't worry about it.
Look, we'll blast through
these. Let me see what you got.
Epistaxis and vertigo.
Nasal pack for the nosebleed,
Meclizine for the vertigo.
They're out the door in 20.
How's it going?
Oh, uh, rather deep. I
used a 4-0 Vicryl subq.
Nice. What was that
that you were just saying?
- Nothing.
- I heard you talking to him.
It was a prayer.
He's not dying.
- It wasn't for him. It's a private prayer.
- Oh, something like:
"Please, Lord, don't let
me kill somebody today"?
Somewhere along those lines?
Neela, I need you to run down to Medical
Records and get Mr. Perkins' old chart.
If you can't find that...
Cardiology should have his
last EKG on file on the fifth floor.
He's got anemia and renal insufficiency,
so print out his BUN, creatinine...
and CBC trends for the last two years.
- Okay.
Hey there.
Don't forget.
Dinner tonight, 8:00.
Oh, they have a dress
code, so wear something nice.
How nice?
I'm wearing my
little black dress.
- I think I'm in.
- You think?
No, no. I'm in.
Hey. How come I wasn't
invited to this party?
- Hook up the Thora-Seal.
- I got it.
Okay, what's next?
Um...
- You want 0 silk?
- Yes, 0 silk.
Girl's in 2's x-rays.
You better check it out.
Not good. COOPER: Who is it?
- Tachypneic girl in 2.
- Huge heart.
Call Cards. She's in failure.
I don't think this is normal.
Maybe it's a brain tumor.
I've tried everything.
I can't stop drooling.
I'm out. A nurse will be
with you in one minute.
Hey, what about that sandwich?
What about it? Where's Amanda?
She's supposed to relieve me at 1.
The nurses are over at Dunkin'
Donuts plotting some kind of a coup.
- Hey, did you sign this?
- No.
- Smart girl.
- Should have.
I want everyone on this petition
in the lounge in five minutes.
- They staged a walkout.
- They're on a break.
- For over an hour?
- Well, page them.
Anyone who's not back
in five minutes is fired.
- You can't fire nurses. ROMANO:
I can if they walk off the job.
I'll go get them.
- Hey, you got a hook. Suits you.
- Shut up.
- Nobody's called my name yet.
- They will.
Would it help if I gave
a stool sample too?
No, just...
- Are you a nurse?
- Check-in's at Triage...
- What happened to you?
- Somebody shot me.
All right. Okay,
sit down, sit down.
I need a gurney. What's your
name? What's your name?
- Bobby.
- Okay, Bobby. Okay.
- Don't let me die.
- I won't. I won't. I won't. Okay.
- Who shot you?
- I don't know.
- Dumped by a homeboy ambulance.
- You're gonna have to hold still.
- We need to tube him.
- Well, get that line in, and I will.
Uh-oh, Bobby? Bobby?
Bobby, open your eyes.
No radial pulse.
Got a carotid, but it's weak.
Get him on the monitor.
Get that blood up
and page Surgery.
Twenty of etomidate,
120 of sux. Suction.
- BP, 64 systolic. Pulse is 60.
- Saline and a mg of atropine.
Penetrating trauma with
impending arrest. Crack him.
- No, not yet. Tube. Come on.
- I'm prepping the chest.
All right, I'm in the
hole. Bag him up, Abby.
Where's Lewis?
Abby, crash cart, now!
Sorry, I had a hot MI.
What are you doing?
Talk to Abby. I'm
putting in a chest tube.
He was talking,
now he's arresting.
Good breath sounds,
airway secure, hypotensive.
Okay, run the code, Pratt.
What are you gonna
do, crack him by yourself?
Get Corday and order
some more O-neg.
Okay, Lisa, can you
follow my finger, please?
Lisa, can you follow my finger?
Don't stare.
Excuse me.
Morris? Work the
kid up in Curtain 2.
- Pressure's only 60 systolic.
- Vasculature is collapsed.
- Cutdown tray.
- Femoral cutdown.
- Who are they?
- Med students.
That makes three of epi.
- Good breath sounds with bagging.
- Hook up a Cell Saver.
- How much O-neg?
- Four units.
He's only got a faint carotid.
- Come on, man. Stay with me.
- Another two units of blood.
Let's follow his
chest tube output.
- There he goes again.
- Hey, I have an idea.
How about a thoracotomy?
"Wow, that is just so
crazy, Abby, it might work."
There's only 300
cc's out the chest.
V-fib.
Charge to 200. ABBY: Look out!
- Prep for a thoracotomy.
- He's already prepped.
Ten blade, now.
First incision is in the fourth intercostal
space from the lateral sternum...
- to the posterior axillary line.
- Clear.
What's Carter mean
by "unfettered"?
- He means... FRANK: It
means she's been dumped.
- Did you get rid of those nurses?
- They went to Nursing Administration...
saying something
about hiring a hit man.
- Hell hath no fury like an RN scorned.
- Whose patient is this?
- She's mine. ROMANO:
Well, get her back in bed...
and use restraints
if you have to.
It's okay. She's harmless. Can
you sign off on a wound infection?
- No. Go away and take her with you.
- No, seriously. She's cool.
I'm Nick Cooper. Coop.
I'm a new Resident.
I didn't realize who you were.
Do me a favor would you, Coop?
Air Rescue's bringing in a bad MVA.
Go up on the roof. Wave in the chopper.
Stand in the middle of the
landing pad so they see you.
You're Rocket Romano. You were
a surgeon. Used to be chief of staff.
I still am a surgeon.
Yeah, you got scalpel
attachments for that bad boy?
- I'm right-handed.
- Lucky.
- This guy's 10 days...
- Let's get a few things straight.
One, we don't offer
remedial medicine here.
Two, you don't talk
to me. I talk to you.
- Three...
- Should I be writing this down?
Stay out of my face!
Thirty again.
Clear.
Fine V-fib.
- More like coarse asystole.
- Resuming compressions.
Units five and six are up.
- How long's it been?
- Thirty-five minutes.
- Should be able to shock him into sinus.
- Hold CPR.
- There's nothing to shock.
- High-dose epi might coarsen his rhythm.
- He's been down too long.
- He's young and healthy.
- With fatal wounds.
His hilum and aorta
are cross-clamped.
We've replaced his volume and
maxed out on atropine and epi.
- He walked in here. He was talking to me.
- That's it.
Time of death: 1336.
Abby, can you try
and locate the family?
I was coming down the ladder and
I stepped on the cord to my sander.
I only fell about 3 feet, but I
twisted my ankle pretty good.
And my collarbone's killing me.
- Well, let's take a look.
- Okay.
Heard about your run-in with Dr. Romano.
Someone should have warned you.
- He's quite a character.
- That's one word for him.
- What were you sanding?
- The hull of a boat.
- Fiberglass?
- Yeah.
Are you all right?
Hey, Coop, you ready
to present some cases?
His asthma is acting up.
- All right, give him
an albuterol treatment.
Then come find me. We
have to clear this board.
So, what's the story?
Call Respiratory to
set up nitric oxide.
Give her more Lasix and
start an isoproterenol drip.
- Wait. What?
- She has primary pulmonary hypertension.
You're kidding. Can you even
diagnose PPHN from an echo?
If you know what to look for.
We'll cath her in the
lab to be 100 percent.
Tough break.
Seemed like a nice kid.
Yeah.
Hennesy in Exam 3
needs a Foley and an IV.
CBC and chem panel
on Gininni in Curtain 4.
And that scalp-lac kid in the
Suture Room needs a setup.
- Am I the only nurse working today?
- Close. Romano fired six.
Oh, so that leaves four
of us for 35 patients.
Looks like you dodged a bullet.
Hey, I'm sorry about the
thoracotomy on that kid.
- Didn't seem to make a difference.
- Maybe if we'd done it sooner.
- You reached the parents?
- No.
Oh. Hey, you know, for what
it's worth, I think it's Carter's loss.
What?
Do you know where my parents
are? They went to talk to the doctor.
They said they'd only be a few
minutes, but that was a while ago.
Uh, why don't you hop back
into bed and I'll find them.
- Okay.
- I think he's getting even tighter.
- Try not to talk. Slow, deep breaths.
- Epi. Epi.
- Subq epinephrine?
- Uh, point three.
- His nebulizer's dry.
Okay, we'll try five
of albuterol this time.
Push it.
Little stick here, Coop.
Too much.
- Too much.
- We gave you 0.3.
You said push it all.
You gave 1 milligram?
- That's over three times the dose.
- I'll get an Attending.
No, no, no. He can handle it.
- V-tach.
- Crash cart.
- What the hell happened?
- Too much epi.
Has he got a pulse?
Can you hear me?
- Charge to 300.
- No, no, no. It's stable V-tach.
He only needs 50. Do
you want some Valium first?
- This could be uncomfortable.
- Just do it.
- Charged to 50 for synch cardioversion.
- Clear.
Aah! Jeez!
- V-tach.
- Let's try 100.
Valium. NEELA: Charged.
- Valium.
- Clear.
Aah!
Okay.
Congratulations.
You just saved
your first Resident.
You can't just sit here.
The union steward said
to stay the entire shift.
But we're getting slammed. I
mean, we'll work it all out tomorrow.
I'm sorry, Abby.
Think how you're gonna feel 10
years from now when they replace you...
with minimum-wage grads
right out of nursing school.
Abby, Lewis is yelling for you.
Are you nurses? ALL: No.
How come you're still working?
I'm an LVN. They don't
get no cheaper than me.
Pratt needs a chaperone
for a pelvic in 3.
If you could cath
the little boy in 4.
- Done deal.
- You still with us?
Okay, I also have a guy
in 2 that needs something...
- I can't read.
- What's that say, "nipple lips"?
I got a Resident who needs a
holding help for a spinal tap...
- on the dirty old man in Exam 3.
- He died.
- For real?
- Real dead.
Do you think you could cover
for me for, like, five minutes...
so I could go up? I gotta
deal with the nursing situation.
- I haven't seen Luka yet.
- I haven't stopped for six hours.
I had to use a patient's urinal.
And that Carter letter, I'm sorry.
- I know that was pretty harsh.
- How did you hear about this letter?
- Jerry.
Excuse me, Dr. Romano, if we
don't get some help down here...
- patients will die.
- We called the registry.
Someone from the service
should be here soon.
Edna's down from Geriatrics.
Edna?
Hey, excuse me. Excuse me. Hi.
There is a drunk in Exam 4
that needs two more of Ativan.
I'm sorry, dear. He's a putz.
Who, the drunk?
That Carter boy. It's too
bad you didn't dump him first.
- You've gotta be kidding me.
- The big man, he let me read the letter.
The guy in 3 needs another
bolus and an emesis basin.
And call the lab and ask
why it's taking over two hours...
- to get a set of electrolytes.
- Malik can do this. Hey!
- Okay. Did you hear about my letter?
- What letter?
Oh, yeah, I need a phenytoin
level on my seizure guy.
And your girl in Exam
2 needs 20 of Lasix, IV.
Oh, Elle. I told her I was gonna
find her parents. How's she doing?
She has primary pulmonary hypertension.
Won't live to see her 21st birthday.
Other than that, she's fine.
- Are you sure?
- Ninety-eight percent.
They won't be certain until
after the cath on Monday.
Her parents don't want her
to know until after the tests.
- Not gonna tell her for three days?
- It's awkward.
It's not awkward. It's stupid.
She already senses something's
wrong. She deserves to know the truth.
After the cath, she'll know and
then it'll all be downhill from there.
Just stay out of it. It's
the parents' decision.
Excuse me. Hi, I'm sorry.
We got turned around.
We were going to the children's
ward to visit a classmate.
Okay, go back to the elevator.
Go up to the third floor, take a left...
- You know what? I'll show you.
- Thanks.
- Are you a nurse?
- Yes, I am a nurse.
Who here wants to be a nurse?
- Hey, you know boys can be nurses too.
- I want to be a doctor.
Me too! Me too!
- Robert.
- To what do we owe this royal visit?
Do you know who that was
in my office this morning?
- Let me see. Do I care? No.
- That was totally inappropriate.
Yeah? I'll tell you what's
inappropriate, Kerry.
The hospital boning me with a
prosthesis with a limited functional field.
I'll have peripheral
neuropathy, overuse syndrome...
Did you fire six nurses today?
It was the only
good part of my day.
- How'd you like me to fire you?
- Well, I've got a handicap, remember?
- Somehow I don't think that's an issue.
- You guys have an audience.
Fire anyone else, even a
candy striper, and you're gone.
Consider this an
official reprimand.
You are one Grade A bitch!
You know that, Kerry?
No, Robert, I'm your boss. And
as long as I am, you're my bitch.
Now get your ass back to work.
Fecal impaction in 4 needs some
good old-fashioned finger digging.
Enjoy.
Jerry! Show them how to
get to the Pedes playroom?
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
- What is that?
- This is human blood.
Hi, Elle. Feeling any better?
- Yeah. I can finally take a deep breath.
- That's good.
They had a heart
doctor come see me.
Mm-hm.
Why?
I thought it was my
lungs, not my heart.
Well, your heart...
Your heart and your lungs are
connected, so it only makes sense...
that Cardiology would
come and take a look at you.
I'm sure Dr. Lewis
was just being thorough.
So was it okay? My heart? My
parents were acting a little weird.
Well, all parents are
a little weird, right?
I'm sure they just want you to get
better. I'm gonna go find Dr. Lewis...
and see if she's
heard anything, okay?
Hey. PRATT: Hey.
These are my parents.
Mom, Dad, this is Greg.
How you doing?
- Nice to meet you.
- They were downtown, shopping.
Really?
And now they wanna
join us for dinner.
- I hope you don't mind.
- Come on.
It's... It's okay.
How you doing?
- Nice to see you.
- Sit down, Greg.
Thank you.
Much better. The
medicine's working.
Dr. Lewis, I heard there
was a PPHN in here.
Cardiology said I should listen
for a tricuspid regurge murmur.
A what? Is that what I have? There's
something wrong with my heart?
This is not a good teaching
case, Neela. Come with me.
No, I want her to stay. I wanna
know what's wrong with me.
Okay, I'll be right
back, all right?
- I've never seen a PPHN before. I...
- She's not a PPHN.
She's a girl who's about to find out
she's going to die a slow, horrible death.
She hasn't been told yet?
There are extenuating circumstances
which you don't know about. Excuse me.
What are you doing?
He... He wasn't eating it.
That doesn't mean you
get to. What's his story?
Um...
Forest Herman. Just snoozing
off pain meds for lower-back pain.
Mr. Herman, I'm
Dr... Mr. Herman?
- Tell me he's sleeping.
- Not unless he's taking a dirt nap.
Wait, I feel a pulse. It's
weak. Get a crash cart.
- Bag him. What'd you give him?
- Just Demerol for back pain.
Somebody page Corday.
Okay, what did I
do? What did I miss?
While you were stealing his tuna
fish, he was bleeding out from a triple A.
He's drifting down.
You want more blood?
Yep, hang it. This man
needs vascular right now.
Get his pressure up, they can
do an endovascular procedure.
He probably won't
survive an open wound.
I paged them. They
were unimpressed.
Right. Let's page Dr. Dorset again.
Tell him Dr. Corday needs him. Badly.
I tried to get you a room
with a fireplace by the pool...
but the guys from Coldplay rented
out the whole top floor for a party.
I can walk.
I know, but hospital policy
says I have to do the driving.
Where are your parents?
They disappear every half-hour.
My mom pretends they're
making phone calls for work.
But when they come back,
I can tell she's been crying.
So either the stock
market crashed...
or there's something wrong with me
and no one is willing to talk about it.
So, what, am I dying?
Do I have cancer or something?
Okay, Elle...
the doctors still have
some more tests to do.
- But so far...
- Abby, I need to talk to you.
We're on our way upstairs.
Oh, okay. Hey, Malik, can
you wheel Elle to Three South?
- Yeah.
- I need help with the code.
This is wrong. You know it.
We're teaching her not to trust us...
exactly at the time she
should be trusting us the most.
Abby, what is wrong
with you today?
You practically start a
thoracotomy on your own.
Now you're talking to my
patients when I asked you not to.
Somebody should.
It's not your call. You're not
her doctor. You're her nurse.
When I ask you not to
do something, don't do it.
Mind if I watch?
- You should be at home in bed.
- Unit six type-specific is up.
Pressure's down to 80/40.
Shouldn't we start pressors?
- You wanna kill this guy. He's not stable.
- He was. Your service didn't come down.
Those bastards hate
to leave the hot tub. You.
Grab some Betadine, scrub
this guy like a sweet potato.
Ectopy.
- Kick that tray over here.
- You don't wanna do this upstairs?
Love to. Didn't leave
enough gas in him to get there.
- Scrubbed.
- Nicely done.
Maybe you can detail
my Jag after work.
Ten blade. Drape this
area here and here.
Suction to Lewis. You wanna try a little
more teaching, a little less standup?
Are you serious? My
name's on this chart.
It's like we say upstairs, "What
happens in the ER, stays in the ER."
- Thanks. ABBY:
His BP's still 50.
Cover your eyes, kids. This
is gonna be some badass juju.
Midline
transperitoneal incision.
There.
Pull down a bit, Dr. Corday.
You know, it really is like
music when we work together.
You boys remember
the Law of Laplace?
Stress on the arterial wall is pressure
times radius, divided by wall thickness.
You two have just
been nurse-slapped.
- You know what it means?
- It means this man's about to die.
Anyone can rip a man's heart
out. But fixing it without looking?
That's why I get the big
money and all the hot chicks.
Right-angled retractor.
Is this where I get to make a joke
about this man bleeding to death?
Only if you're qualified.
I got the supraceliac aorta in my
hand, meaning we have proximal control.
- Don't try this at home.
- Or anywhere near this hospital.
You need a clamp?
I think it's best if I just pull a Dutch
boy, keep my finger in it. Let's roll.
- How wicked was that?
- Guy's got balls the size of my head.
- I want the blue one.
- Hey, you know what?
A medical student was crushed to
death working on this computer last year.
- I can believe it.
- You save any lives today?
- Nope.
- She saved one.
Hey, I'm Nick Cooper.
My friends call me Coop.
- Michael Gallant.
- Good to meet you.
- So did I miss anything good?
- Yeah. Dr. Kovac is back.
- He's upstairs. He's doing better.
- Abby got a Dear John letter from Carter.
And she gave it to you?
- Not exactly.
- What's it say?
I imagine it's private.
Yeah, you're probably
right. What's it say?
"Dear Abby..."
Has anybody not
read this letter?
I haven't.
What, you pulled
this out of the trash?
- I...
- You guys are pathetic.
You're not the only one
who got a letter today.
We all got 90-day suspensions.
- I hate my job.
- Don't worry, dear. It'll get better.
I hope you don't mind, Greg...
but we went ahead and ordered
something that's not on the menu.
Oh, no, this is
okay. It looks good.
Okay. Okay. Sorry.
So, Greg, what do
your parents do?
Well, my mom passed
away when I was 12...
and my father and I
never kept in touch.
Well, that's unfortunate.
Family is such a
valuable part of one's life.
It's important to have roots.
Jing-Mei is going to China with us.
She's going to rediscover her ancestry.
No, I'm not. Mom,
we talked about this.
It's difficult to know where you're going
if you don't know where you came from.
What's that? Confucius?
Common sense.
- Lizzie, burning the midnight oil?
- Not if I can help it.
- How are you doing?
- Very well, thanks.
So is this where all
the cool kids hang out?
Not if we can help
it. How is our triple A?
- Not dead yet.
- Well, that's encouraging.
Thank you for coming
down so quickly.
And?
And what?
This is where you
say, "I owe you one."
- What do you want?
- Foot rub.
I'll settle for coffee.
I have to be home in an
hour, and nothing fancy.
No coconut-frosted double
javaccino or anything like that.
All right.
- Good night, Robert.
- Elizabeth.
Whoo.
- Okay, okay, how bad was that?
- What, the jellyfish or the ambush?
I'm so sorry.
- You know, they caught me off guard.
- Uh-huh.
You know, if it's any
consolation, they didn't hate you.
Is that what they were saying?
They're just old-fashioned.
- Taxi!
Meaning?
Meaning they want me to be
with someone more traditional.
You know all that talk
about going to China?
They just wanna
find me a husband.
Well, just tell them to relax, all right?
It's not like we're getting married. Taxi!
Oh, come on.
What?
What are we doing?
You're kidding, right?
We're dating. You
know, we're having fun.
Neither one of us is
ready to settle down, right?
Right.
What, did I say something?
Nope.
- Then why are you mad?
- I'm not mad.
I'm sure you'll find
yourself a new bang buddy.
Good night.
Thank God I got you a decaf.
He left.
- What are you doing?
- I needed to stretch my legs.
It's good to see you.
You look great.
You look like hell.
Too much partying on the plane.
So...
- So...?
- So I met Gillian.
- She seems...
- Yeah, she is.
Must be nice having
a private nurse.
She give you your letter?
Did you read it?
- No.
- Well, you're the only one.
I think he wanted to try
and explain why he stayed.
He saved my life.
It's different over there.
Changes you.
I think Carter found himself.
I didn't know he was missing.
- He's gonna be okay.
- I don't wanna talk about Carter anymore.
I think it was
doomed from the start.
I'm glad one of us had the
courage to put it out of its misery.
It feels strange to be here.
I think maybe I've changed too.
Well, change is good, right?
I think I'm way overdue myself.
I hope he hasn't talked
you into helping him escape.
Nope.
You need to take these
and get back in bed.
You're still warm.
I'll stop by tomorrow.
- Okay.
- It was really nice to finally meet you.
- You too.
I'm glad you're back.
What are you doing up?
Come on.