When you become an intern,
there's a ceremony where
you get your white coat.
Like magic...
You're a doctor.
My parents came to my
White Coat Ceremony.
I can still picture
them, so happy...
So proud.
Hey, we need to get
the board together, and...
Congratulations.
They say your life
flashes before your eyes
right before you die.
The important moments.
The moments that tested you.
The moments that
made you who you are.
April, you're getting married.
Unless I'm not.
I just heard.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
I don't know about my
life flashing before me.
I was thinking
about my white coat,
and how I'm glad I
have it on me now.
Will you overhead page
- Richard Webber for me?
- Right away.
It's the moment my life started.
Seems fitting it should
be on me when it ends.
Dr. Richard Webber,
please call the ER.
Baby's sleeping.
Okay, we should get started. Oh.
Bailey, we have some board
business that we need to...
I'm not going anywhere.
Me and this baby got
Bailey business to discuss.
Don't we? Yes,
Mr. Derek Bailey Shepherd.
Yes, we do.
What does Zola think of him?
Oh, she wants to take him
to day care for show and tell.
Where's Richard? I paged
all the board members.
Well, Avery should be here, too.
Yeah, well, he was
being a hero last night.
He dislocated his shoulder
saving a kid from the bus crash.
What bus crash?
She had a baby. She
doesn't know things.
So tell me.
A church was evacuating some
people, and their bus overturned.
Good news is everyone survived
and there are no major injuries.
And the bad news?
Everything else.
The blood bank is flooded, and
the ER looks like it was ransacked.
So we need to close the ER?
We're dangerously low on meds.
Personnel can't make
it in due to the flooding.
So we need to close the ER.
But can we do that?
You are the board.
I am telling you that
ER cannot open today.
What do we need?
I mean, I can try to
coordinate with our suppliers.
I had a baby. I'm not dead.
If they have it,
then we want it.
In the meantime, let's make sure
that our inpatients
are taken care of
and discharge who
we can. Like me.
No, you just had a
major abdominal surgery.
You're gonna stay right here.
All right, airport's
just reopened.
I just put Dr. Boswell in a cab.
Who's Dr. Boswell?
She's the woman Arizona
slept with last night.
What are you doing?
We're closed to
incoming traumas, guys.
Tell that to them.
There was a mudslide
near Madrona.
A bunch of cops and firefighters
got hurt doing evacuations.
There are also a bunch of
civilian casualties as well.
What about Seattle Pres?
They're worse off than we are.
All right, let's do it.
Help me get this sling off.
Get me every suture
kit, laceration tray,
foley, and chest
tube that you can.
We're gonna come down.
We're sending a triage down.
What?
My shift is over. I was gonna
go home and go to sleep.
I'm so tired and hungry.
My teeth have stuff
growing on them, and...
Can you pretend you
didn't hear any of that?
Yep.
Yeah, yeah.
Coming through. Straight ahead.
Wait, wait. Wait.
Okay, I'm not doing
it in an on-call room.
I'm a grown-up with a house.
Your house has a
tree in the middle of it.
Wait, wait.
Did you have sex
with Leah in here?
And Heather?
Oh, God. I don't
think I can do this.
Yeah, I can.
No. No, no, no. I need this.
We're here. We're ready.
Let's just do it. Two minutes.
No one's gonna die
if we don't answer
our pagers for
two minutes, right?
Right.
Crap!
Now I'm thinking
about dead people.
Lenny Shulte, captain
of ladder company 54.
Unconscious at the
scene with a GCS Of 13.
BP's been constantly
dropping. Last was 85 over 60.
I can't get a good breath.
Increase his O2 to 10 liters.
Can you tell me if anything
fell on you, on your chest?
I don't know.
Last thing I remember, helping
the old lady out of her house.
Did she make it? I'll check.
5818 Shore Drive. And my
guys, I got 12 guys out there.
Turn him. Turn him!
Okay, looks like
he aspirated mud.
Let's get him into
trauma room one.
Let's get a chest X-ray
and start him on antibiotics.
Let's go!
Go! Coming through.
Owen and I...
I don't even know
what to call it.
Ended it? Broke up?
I feel like I'm gonna die.
You always end it, and
then you start it again.
Yeah, but this is different.
Okay.
I'm gonna go to sleep.
Just for, like, 20 minutes.
Okay.
Oh, Robbins cheating on Callie?
Oh! Did not see that coming.
I know.
And Bailey is a good name.
But two Baileys? You don't
think it's gonna be confusing?
No, because if I say,
"Bailey peed on me,"
I think it's safe to assume
that I'm talking about my son.
Very good. Seriously,
wake me in 20?
Okay. Thank you.
I feel like I'm gonna die.
Dr. Bentley to
ICU on four north.
Shepherd?
Yeah, Lydia Ashford. Injuries
to the upper extremities.
My house.
And she's worried
about her house.
Wait. 5818 Shore Drive?
Yes. Is it gone? I don't know.
Karev, Kepner's in trauma one.
Get her to tell her patient
5818 Shore Drive made it.
Kepner!
Tell your guy 5818 is out.
I could've done that.
I'm sorry, but I need a
neuro consult in bay seven.
The guy's unconscious,
but he's stable.
Okay.
Look what I found
in outpatient surgery.
Ross, stay here. I paged Brooks.
Have her get Mrs. Ashford
a pan scan of the head,
neck, chest, and abdomen.
Well, I can take her.
No, have Brooks do it.
Uh, the mayor's on the phone.
He wants to know about
casualties from the mudslide.
I told him it was soon to tell,
but he wants to
hear it from you.
Okay.
Hey, go find Dr. Webber.
I'm supposed to give Dr. Brooks
a message from Dr. Shepherd.
Is that life-threatening?
Because not having
enough general surgeons
in here right now is
life-threatening. Go find Webber.
Have you seen Dr. Webber?
Last time I saw him
was after surgery.
He went to go check
on the generator.
Where's that? How
the hell should I know?
Lidocaine and a bunch of 4x4s.
Can you take that to Hunt?
I got paged by Shepherd.
Uh, he wants you
to go find Webber.
Are you sure? He
just paged me 9-1-2.
That's our special little code.
It means more emergent
than 9-1-1. Get it?
All I know is they
need Webber here
and Shepherd
wants you to get him.
Apparently, he went to
deal with the generator.
And I'm walking toward the car
and suddenly the hillside just goes...
And I'm falling.
I see my squad car
coming down on top of me,
so I managed to
roll out of the way,
but my leg was caught under it.
Can you salvage it?
I think so. We'll
get ortho down here.
I'm gonna take a look at that
nasty laceration on your neck though.
It's a lot of embedded debris.
Hey, Tilden? Everyone
make it out of the mud?
Everyone's accounted for except
Lauenstein, Phil G, and Brian.
Brian's my fiance.
Don't worry. You know
him. He's gonna be fine.
Look, he's probably
giving himself a mud facial.
You know, look
good for the wedding.
Yeah, well, if he had cold
feet, he should've just said so.
Okay.
Dr. Webber?
Dr. Webber!
Oh, crap. Dr. Webber!
Oscar Hallis. Shepherd
says he's probably concussed.
We're gonna do a head CT.
I'm more concerned
about infection.
That is a nasty cut on his leg.
Well, Dr. Wilson's
irrigating it with saline.
But we couldn't
find any bacitracin.
We're gonna hang
some ampicillin.
No ampicillin!
He's allergic to penicillin.
How do you know?
What the hell?
Military trick.
Someone triaged him at the
scene, probably whoever dug him out.
Substitute cefazolin and keep
a close eye for allergic reaction.
All right. Get some cefazolin.
We don't have it. Well, find it.
People, check your
patients for vitals
written in Sharpie
on their bodies.
Someone at the scene
knew what they were doing.
Might've just
saved this guy's life.
Sharpie here, too.
And it indicates he's
getting worse fast.
His BP was better
in the field. Crap.
Okay, we need to
stabilize his pelvis.
Okay, you're gonna
need to pull harder.
Talk to me, Murphy.
Aaron Garcia. CT showed
an open book pelvic fracture
on a liver lac with
hemorrhage. Harder, Murphy.
I'm afraid if I pull too hard,
I'm gonna make it worse.
You can't... Move.
Can't make it worse.
It's already as
bad as it can be.
All right, I need to
get this guy upstairs
and put on an ex
fix immediately.
Murphy, book an OR.
And ask Bailey to scrub in.
What do you need Bailey for?
He has a liver lac. I
need a general surgeon.
Well, I'm a general surgeon,
and it's all hands on deck.
Get me Bailey!
Dr. Mahoney to the
ER. Dr. Mahoney...
Do you have cefazolin?
Yeah, they were
hoarding it in OB.
Bastards. Give me some.
Ha! I'll trade you
for a chest tube.
And a granola bar.
I don't have a
granola bar. Liar.
You've got granola-bar
breath. Do you want the cef?
Fine! Yeah.
What is going on out there?
Huge mudslide. Gotta go.
Lot of crush injuries.
Super cute baby.
I thought the ER was closed!
Where's Brooks?
She was busy, so I went
ahead and did the scan.
It shows a small
subarachnoid hemorrhage.
Her exam? Neuro
checks have been stable.
All right, tell Brooks I
want her to continue on
with Q 1 hour
neuro checks. But...
Don't argue with me.
Just find Brooks. Yes, sir.
Mrs. Ashford, how
are you feeling?
My house. 5818.
Crown molding in every room.
All right, right now
I'm worried about you.
Your fingers are crushed.
I need an ortho consult, please.
- On it.
Okay, I need you to
look up here for me.
Crown molding in every room.
Okay.
How's he doing?
Captain Shulte has decreased
breath sounds on the right,
worsening tachypnea and
persistent sats in the 80s.
Took me forever
to find a chest tube.
I need a list.
Who's still missing?
Okay, Lenny, something
in your chest cavity's
preventing you
from breathing well,
so we're gonna
insert a chest tube
which should help
you breathe better.
Is there anyone that
we can call for you?
Call Marla,
but don't let her come
up here. Road's not safe.
Guys, you're gonna
need to go. All right.
Okay. Come on.
Hang in there, Lenny.
Okay, you're gonna feel
a little snip. Here you go.
Got a chest tube. APRIL:
Too late. Already got one.
Okay, let me help.
Okay.
Oh, God! Oh, God, it's poop!
Oh, jeez. I'm sorry, sweetheart.
The tube is in a good position.
I suspect a
diaphragmatic rupture.
Lenny, I believe your colon has
been pushed up into your chest.
Now the risk of infection
is extremely high.
Now if I'm right, we're gonna
need to open you up. All right?
Give me the chart,
please. Here you go, Doctor.
All right, let's get an X-ray
and prep him for surgery.
I'll scrub in with
you. Call Bailey.
Ask her to man the ER, please.
Go.
Dr. Trask to OR two.
Dr. Bailey.
You smell like feces.
I know.
So why you standing next
to me if you smell like feces?
Dr. Hunt would
like you to take over
in the ER while he
goes up to surgery.
Tell Dr. Hunt I'm about
to go in with Torres
on this gentleman's
broken pelvis,
so I can't man the ER.
Where's Dr. Webber?
I don't know.
Okay, well, find him.
Someone needs to
find Richard Webber!
Coming through!
Webber's pulse is thready.
Systolic's 80. Brooks
has massive head trauma.
Pupils are unresponsive.
Let's get her on
her side. Ready?
Move over here.
One, two, three, go.
Get her for a CT, Ross?
Ross! Let's go. Go!
V-tach. Give me one of
epi. Come on. Come on.
Charge to 120. MAN: Got it.
Clear.
Okay, charge to 200. Clear.
Charge to 200. Clear.
I know you guys are freaked out,
but we have patients,
so you need to focus.
Figure out who Ross
and Brooks were covering.
Uh, Ross was doing neuro
checks on crown molding.
No breath sounds. So
I can take over those.
Allergic guy is awake, and
his head CT came back clear.
Last time I checked his
BP, it was good, like...
Like 115 over 70. I
wrote it down somewhere.
What the hell?
Well, the electronic charts
are still down, so I'm winging it.
Let's charge him again.
Crap. I know I have it.
Clear!
Give him another epi.
Come on.
Oscar, I'm Dr. Karev.
Glad you're awake.
Your head CT is clear, and we're
gonna have plastics sew up your leg.
Awesome.
All right. BP looks
good. 115 over 85.
Our electronic charts are down.
Hope you don't mind
a temporary tattoo.
Go for it, doc. I
already got one.
I'm gonna scrub in.
They wanna take me back.
Look, I know Heather's a friend,
and if you need
more time, I can...
No. I'm...
I'm fine.
Good. Go help prep the patient.
I know that you wanted Bailey
but she's working on Richard.
Callie, we should...
Should what?
Not sleep with other people?
Respect our wedding vows?
We should put our
problems aside right now
because this guy deserves that.
Well, thank God you
found them, Ross.
Let's just hope you
found them in time.
Damn it. Subdural.
Oh, God.
Let's go.
Line's in. Swan, please.
Okay, let's hook him back up.
Labs.
Okay, troponin?
Elevated at four.
Crit? Fine at 40.
Potassium's 4.5. Bicarb
18. Everything else is normal.
Lactate. Two.
No, that can't be right.
He should be acidotic.
His girth is increasing
as we stand here.
Look, it says... I know
what it says, but it's wrong.
Redo it.
All right, charge again to 200.
Clear.
Karev? What's going
on with Richard?
Echo shows very little heart
activity, and CVP's elevated.
Yang's about to set
up for a balloon pump.
All right, if we're sending
him up to surgery,
let's make sure we have an
adequate blood supply for transfusion.
On it.
If you need to go deal with
more dire patients, I get it.
Go. I'm fine.
Actually, you're not, Sasha.
It's important that we go ahead
and debride and clean out this wound
as soon as possible
to prevent infection.
Sasha...
Are you supposed to be
walking around on that thing?
I can't sit still.
I'm waiting on plastic
surgery to sew me up.
That's this guy.
You mind if I sit here?
That kind of looks
like Brian's handwriting.
Yeah, I know. My glasses
got knocked off in the slide.
I could barely see a
thing, but it could've been.
But was it his voice?
I can't remember.
I'm sorry, Sash.
I was kind of out
of it, you know?
I'm sorry.
Just a little discoloration
in the tissue.
I'd like to run a few tests just to make
sure there's nothing to worry about.
I'm just gonna
numb you up, okay?
Yeah, go ahead.
I'm telling you,
that's his writing.
We need blood, Mer.
There's no time to screen,
type, or cross. All right?
I need all the O-neg I can get.
Okay, but wait. Tell
me what's going on?
And staff, lab
techs, scrub nurses.
I need ETAs on when
you can get people in here.
Page me when you can.
Alex, pick up the baby.
Mer, I don't have time.
Alex. Pick up my baby.
No, the baby is for you, so
that you can stop freaking out.
Now just relax and
tell me what's going on.
Webber and Brooks are
down. They were electrocuted.
It's bad, but we're
dealing with it.
I just need you to
get on the phone
and help us get
those supplies, okay?
Okay. Okay.
Here.
Your turn not to freak out.
Okay, forceps. Metz.
I have a status update
on Dr. Webber. Okay.
Dr. Yang is attempting to place a
balloon pump, but he keeps coding.
She's placing one
bedside without fluoro?
She could rupture his aorta.
Do you want me to get
Dr. Yang on the phone?
You just said that she's
threading a balloon pump.
She is, but... How is she
gonna talk on the phone?
I didn't mean... Retract her.
No. No, no, no.
Okay, let's run the bowel.
The abdomen's fully
contaminated. Just run the bowel.
We're gonna resect
this and get out of here.
Let's get ready to pack him.
Come on, Lenny.
It's too quiet. Talk.
You're doing good.
You are not going
to rupture the aorta
because you are Cristina Yang.
Attach this to the console.
You are the star of your class.
I always knew it. I said
it to anyone who'd ask.
"Look out for Cristina
Yang." I said it to Webber.
"Cristina Yang is good.
"Cristina Yang would
not rupture an aorta.
"Cristina..."
Oh, God, you did it.
Oh, dear Lord. He
has a steady heartbeat.
Praise Jesus. You
didn't rupture his aorta.
Secure this device and
get him up to the ICU.
We just bought him some time.
Hug me back, Cristina Yang.
I know you are not a hugger,
but right now I need
you to hug me back.
Hey, Mrs. Ashford.
Did you find out?
Press against my hands
with the bottoms of your feet.
Find out what? About my house.
It has the most
beautiful crown moldings.
Now with your hands.
I'm sorry. I haven't had
time to ask about your house.
How's your vision?
Any blurriness?
My vision? I don't
care about my... Stop.
Stop this nonsense.
Just call somebody, please.
Find out about my house.
Ma'am, this isn't nonsense.
I'm trying to help you,
and I have about
20 other patients,
so checking on your house is
the last thing on my mind right now.
People got injured badly,
so you need to stop
worrying about your house,
and you need to tell me if you are
experiencing any blurriness of vision.
His lactate is six.
Six?
He has an acute abdomen.
Get me an OR, and a good staff.
I'll take Linda, if she's
available. Norman.
Are you out of your mind?
Norman's MIA. Okay, Anna, then.
I'll make some phone calls.
You're not opening him up.
The electrical injury may have
caused intra-abdominal tissue damage
and likely progressing
because of his heart failing.
He barely tolerated
the balloon pump.
I need to get in there and
debride the dead tissue.
There's no way his heart
can handle the anesthesia.
His lactate is six.
He needs sustained cardiac ICU.
He's gonna die if
we don't do anything.
We're not doing nothing.
We're gonna let the
balloon pump work.
I am the attending...
And keep his fluids tight.
You are a fellow. I
make the decisions here.
Well, I own this
hospital. You work for me.
He's bleeding
through the packing,
and there's still
stool coming out.
Damn it. We need to take it
out and resect more intestines.
How's his INR?
The last one was six.
Okay, give him factor
VII, FFPs and platelets.
Faster, Kepner.
He's having arrhythmias.
Talk to me. Uh, I
can't get a pulse.
I think he's in PEA.
Starting compressions.
I know this is difficult,
but Brooks is our patient.
I'm telling you this to
remind you to be her doctor,
not her friend right now.
There are decisions
to be made in there
that will affect not only
her ability to be a surgeon,
her speech, her ability
to function, her life.
But those decisions
are ultimately mine.
I will not make them lightly.
But I will make them quickly,
and you need to do exactly
as I say. No questions.
Can you do that?
I think so.
That's not good enough.
Yes, sir. I can do it, sir.
I'll take this to the labs, and
Dr. Avery will let you know the results.
Thank you.
Hey. Heard you were
looking for this guy.
Brian! I was so worried.
Get over here and
give me a kiss, you jerk.
Baby, I'm all
muddy. I don't care.
Are you okay?
I knew that was your handwriting.
What are you talking about?
On Oscar.
Didn't you pull him out? No.
Someone triaged a
bunch of guys at the scene
and wrote vitals
down with a Sharpie.
Yeah, I wish that was me.
I was just sitting in an air
pocket, twiddling my thumbs.
I actually think I'm having
some trouble moving.
I think I broke some ribs.
Let's get those checked out.
Yeah.
I heard Lenny was in
surgery. How's he doing?
I don't know.
PH is down to 7.12.
Come on, Lenny.
He's been down 20 minutes.
Did you say yes?
Sir? To Matthew.
I helped with his proposal.
Oh.
Yeah. Yes. I said yes.
Good.
I like him. He's a good guy.
I mean, these guys...
These first responders,
they're all good guys.
Hate to give up.
Damn it, Lenny.
Time of death, 15:56.
It's Dr. Karev. The firefighters
are asking for an update.
Chaplain's on his way
to tell Marla and the girls.
She's gonna wanna
come in and see him.
Absolutely.
Let's bring her in.
Full lights and sirens.
On it.
Lauenstein's still missing.
We gotta bring him back.
We gotta do that for Lenny.
If I could walk, I'd
be out on that pile.
Excuse me.
Kelly clamp. Suction.
Guys, he's almost lost
his entire blood volume.
If you don't get control up
there... It's already done.
I controlled the bleeding
using a pringle maneuver.
Wow. Cool.
Don't be so impressed.
It's fairly standard.
Yeah, I know, but
you did it so well.
I was wrong before, Murphy,
when I implied that Dr. Robbins
wasn't a real general surgeon.
She is. She's an
excellent general surgeon.
It's okay. We've all said
things that we shouldn't have.
Oh, Owen.
Oh, no. You're not
gonna "Owen" this.
No personal relationships. This
is professional. This is Dr. Hunt.
What is going on?
Dr. Webber has an acute
abdomen. He needs surgery.
He barely survived
the balloon pump.
His lactate is six. And holding.
So what if it's holding?
Something is dead inside of him.
It's not gonna get undead.
It is way too risky,
and you know it.
I would rather take the risk
than just wait for what
we know is gonna kill him.
Stop. Stop.
What does his healthcare directive
say about extraordinary measures?
Whoa. I smell dead people.
And spiders. Dead
people killed by spiders.
Okay, let's find
his personnel file.
Okay, I got it.
"Webber."
Oh, no.
What, he doesn't have
a healthcare directive?
No. He has one.
I don't understand.
Richard designated you as
his medical power of attorney.
But he can't make me next of
kin without talking to me first.
He did.
After Adele died, he
revised his directive.
But... Meredith, I
know this is a shock,
but we don't have much time.
Right now, you need
to make a decision.
His heart is too weak,
Meredith. His heart can take it.
You trust me, right? You
named your baby after me.
Hey, hey! No
personal relationships.
The amount of electricity
he had in his body
should have killed him
instantly, but it didn't,
which tells me that the heart
damage isn't as bad as you think.
He coded four times.
And we got him back!
And now you just sound idiotic.
Dr. Yang! No, seriously.
You sound like a family member
who googled "electrocution"
and is trying to
remain optimistic.
Well, I am optimistic.
Well, Richard should have
made Bailey his family member,
because that is how
she's acting right now.
- I wish he would've.
- Well, he didn't.
He put Meredith down.
Why would he do that?
And she knows as well as I do
that electric shock can
cause death of tissues
which could start a whole
inflammatory cascade
unless I debride
what's been damaged.
Well, he'll have to handle it
for a day to let his heart rest.
And then... He can't handle it?
Okay, now you
sound like an idiot.
Letting that tissue die is like
taking a gun and killing him.
Why wouldn't he tell me?
I don't know, but he didn't.
And it's on you, so
you have to decide, Mer.
Yes. Meredith, please.
Damn it.
Just damn it.
It's massive.
But we can just
evacuate it, right?
It doesn't change our plan?
Do what we can
and hope for the best.
Can you see her vital signs?
Yeah. Bad.
At least Shane's happy.
Heather's out of the competition.
That was mean, even for you.
It was a joke. I'm trying
to lighten the mood.
Our friend is dying.
You don't even like her.
Oh, my God. Just
ignore her, Steph.
Well, she usually does.
We should get back.
I like Heather.
I know.
You know what I was thinking
before you guys came in here?
I was thinking I wish my
mother were here to see my kids.
I was wondering if she'd
make a good grandmother.
But you know what that is?
That's delusional thinking.
Because my mother would
make a horrible grandmother,
because she was
a horrible mother.
So, I'm delusional and hormonal.
And I can't trust my
delusional thoughts.
I have to rely on the labs.
So we need to run
the lactate again,
and if it's above six, we're
going to do the surgery.
And if it's not, we're not.
Hey, where's Brian?
Who's Brian? Bed three.
Broken ribs.
Dead fiance.
Him. He left. One of
his friends is still missing.
All right. Listen up, guys.
You wanna do something
for your friends
that are hurt? Sure.
How about donating some blood?
- We can do that.
All right, just line up
behind these doctors,
and they're gonna help you out.
That way they're tied to the
table and they can't take off.
Okay.
I'll give some blood.
I'll help the blood
bank staff get set up.
Were you out at the pile? Yeah.
Do you know if 5818
Shore Drive is still standing?
It's my patient's house,
and she's worried.
Sharpie lady's
here? Sharpie lady?
I was evacuating her when
the mudslide happened,
and she runs back in her house.
I lose it on her,
'cause I'm thinking
she's looking for her
wallet or something,
and I'm like, "Lady, that
crap can be replaced."
And she comes running
out with a Sharpie
and immediately starts digging
guys out and taking their vitals.
That's why her
fingers are crushed.
I feel kind of bad
for yelling at her.
Yeah.
What's wrong?
Crown molding's a badass.
Yeah. Okay.
Hi.
I was just thinking
about when Richard
caught me living
in the limb room.
I was a resident.
Before George, anyway.
I was in there
one night, and he...
Richard walked in on me
dancing in my underwear.
I was so embarrassed.
I mean, he was the chief.
Are you okay? No. No, I'm...
No, I don't dance in
my underwear anymore.
Lactate's nine.
Go.
Hey.
You agree with
Meredith's decision?
I think it was a coin toss.
You gonna be in
there with Bailey?
Yeah.
Okay, if he has abnormal
bleeding, give him factor VII.
He responds to it well. Okay.
And make sure his
pulses are checked hourly.
That is really important.
You wanna write that down?
No, I think I...
Let me put that in your phone.
You're a challenging person.
I know.
The swelling is bad.
Shepherd's had to open up
a bigger chunk of her skull.
There's no way she's getting
out of this without major deficits.
What are you doing?
Heather's hemorrhaging.
Yeah, I heard.
She could die. All right,
look, don't go there.
She's my age, my class.
Her locker's right next to mine.
I use her deodorant without
telling her, and she could die.
I know. It sucks.
It all sucks.
Wait, wait. This is bad.
We shouldn't. Yeah.
But I want to. Okay.
Wait.
Did you have sex with any
of my friends in this closet?
Uh...
Okay. No. This isn't
happening. I gotta go.
Whoa...
Oh! Hey. Hey.
I was just gonna
get some lidocaine,
but I'm not gonna slip
on a used condom, am I?
Screw you. Yeah.
Did you hear the news about
me being a big slut got out?
Yeah.
It's mortifying.
But I mean, I think that
we're gonna be okay.
I think it's gonna
make us stronger.
Like a bone.
Sometimes you have to...
You have to break it in
order for it to heal correctly.
And I think that
maybe Callie and I...
That's what I was
gonna tell Callie.
Like, an ortho metaphor?
What do you think?
I think you should stick to
"I'm sorry I'm such a slut."
Yeah. Good call.
Hey, Mrs. Ashford.
You wanna press against my
hands with the bottoms of your feet?
I heard you're kind of a hero.
Oh, my God. Okay.
Mrs. Ashford. I could
use some help over here!
You're gonna be good, Dougie,
okay? You're gonna be fine.
Douglas Lauenstein, multiple
crush injuries, BP 105 over 72.
Get him up to trauma three. Hey,
where do you think you're going?
Sash, we got him.
He was still in the rig.
Is he gonna be okay?
Yeah, he's gonna be okay,
but I gotta head back out.
We're trying to
stabilize the area,
make sure we don't
lose any more houses.
You're not going anywhere.
You're still bleeding.
Well, just patch me up.
No, I already did that.
Well, maybe this guy can help.
All right, Sasha, we just
got your studies back,
and this is
necrotizing fasciitis.
It is aggressive, and we need to
get you up to surgery right away.
How did I...
The water and the mud
that you were stuck in,
both of those are
breeding grounds
for this type of
bacteria. Well, wait...
It's a flesh-eating
bacteria, Brian, all right?
What's most important
is that we get her prepped
and ready right away. Let's go.
A doctor puts on his
white coat to save lives,
defy death,
but once he takes it
off, he's vulnerable,
just like anybody else.
Human.
Ma'am, I'm Dr. Kepner.
I worked on your husband.
Would you like to see him?
Okay.
We're all gonna die.
We don't get much
say over how or when.
His ring.
Thought you'd want it back.
I'm so, so sorry.
But we do get to decide
how we're gonna live.
So do it.
Decide.
Is this the life
you want to live?
Is this the person
you want to love?
Is this the best you can be?
Can you be stronger?
Kinder?
Be a good friend. Tell me
I made the right decision.
More compassionate?
You made the right decision.
Damn it. There's blood
in the temporal horn.
I have to do a
temporal lobectomy.
Dr. Shepherd.
She'll have motor and
memory deficits if you...
I'm trying to save her life.
This is my fault.
Shane.
No, I did this.
You didn't do anything.
This is not your fault.
This just happened.
Now I can't have you in here
if you can't hold it together.
Can you be in here?
Decide.
Yeah.
Dissectors.
Breathe in.
Tell me again.
Breathe out.
You made the right decision.
And decide.
10 blade.