Hey.
Thanks for coming.
Hospital food, I know.
But the French toast
is surprisingly good.
Not at all.
Let's do it.
Okay. But first...
I have a little
something for you.
What are these?
Airline tickets to Honolulu.
For our wedding.
Where you wanted to go
first time around, remember,
but we couldn't afford it?
Danny,
that is so sweet. Thank you.
I don't know what to say.
How about..."Aloha."
Honolulu! Take that.
Whoa.
What?
What's this?
Um, Robin gave it to me.
I don't really need it
but, you know,
it makes her happy,
so I'm going to do it.
Come on, French toast.
Come on, Waikiki!
Finally you're going
to learn how to surf, right?
Remember you've just had
abdominal surgery
so be patient. It takes
a while to recover.
You need to be ambulatory.
Walk every day.
But don't push it.
Got it.
Great to see you two
back together.
I like to think it was
because of Bernie and me.
Whatever.
You know, when you go through
something like this,
makes you appreciate
everything you have.
Good friends,
a wonderful woman,
a brand-new baby.
Not to mention a wife
and teenage daughter.
Ethan.
I know, I know.
But we're working
something out.
I promise, I'm going to
take good care of your sister.
I look forward
to hearing your plans.
Connor...
Look, I hope you know
I did everything I could
for your father.
I do.
I'm here for you.
If there's...
If there's anything I can do.
Thank you.
Hey, Nina.
Are you doing the autopsy
on my dad?
Yes, um...
Before I start, maybe you
want some time with him?
Yeah, please. Thank you.
I hated you.
I blamed you for Mom's death.
I blamed you for...
So many things.
Maybe I was
seeing it all wrong.
You weren't the best dad.
But maybe if I'd been
a better son...
You'd have been
a better father.
Oh, man, I...
I'm sorry.
Remember our
cochlear implant patient,
Peter Rush?
Yeah. Usher syndrome.
Why, is he back?
Is his eyesight worse?
Yes, but that's not
why he's here.
It's his wife, Bonnie.
This way.
Okay.
Hello, Bonnie.
Who's that?
Dr. Manning.
Sorry. I don't see too well.
No need to apologize.
Congratulations
on your marriage.
So what seems
to be the trouble?
She says she doesn't
need to be here. There's
nothing wrong with her.
I made her come.
Her heart doesn't sound right.
"Doesn't sound right"?
I had my head
on her chest.
I heard it.
May I?
You heard right.
Sounds like a systolic murmur.
Do you ever feel dizzy
or out of breath?
Yes, you do.
Let's get her
on the monitors.
Need a CBC, BMP, cardiac labs,
a D-Dimer, chest x-ray...
And a 12-lead EKG
and a cardiac echo.
Right.
She's saying sorry,
he was right.
We'll be back
when we get the results.
Dan.
I got a patient of yours,
Delmar Brendl.
Oh.
Yeah, he won't let me treat
him unless you're in the room.
Hey, Del.
Dr. Charles, I'm fine.
I really don't need
to be here.
He was found at the bottom
of his stairs of
his apartment building.
I didn't get hurt.
But he couldn't get up.
The manager called
the paramedics.
Well, Del's been
a patient of mine
for a couple years now.
I'm treating him for
generalized anxiety disorder,
panic attacks, and making
some real progress.
Mr. Brendl, why weren't
you able to get up?
I don't know.
My right leg is a little weak.
And my left.
And my left arm.
Anything else bothering you?
You mean
like the headaches?
But everybody
gets headaches, right?
Do me a favor.
Put your feet up.
Flex your foot like you're
stepping on the gas.
The other side.
Your left side's weaker.
Yeah, I know. I told you that.
It's no big deal.
Monique, let's get
a 12-lead EKG, CT head,
CTLS spine and...
No needles. I hate needles.
And cardiac labs.
You can totally do this, Del.
Gonna be over in a flash,
I promise you.
Ow, that really hurts!
I haven't done anything.
Here. Del,
Del. Look at me.
Right here, all right.
Doing great.
In through the nose.
Out through the mouth.
Gonna be fine.
When we woke up,
I looked over and Henry
had this rash all over.
Okay if I look in your mouth?
Sure.
Ahh.
It's clear.
Any trouble breathing?
No.
Mr. Kupfer puts out
a star for Christmas.
Yes he does, Joanie.
Honey, give us a second.
We're talking to the doctor.
It's Alzheimer's.
Well, your rash, it's hives.
Pretty sure you're having
an allergic reaction.
To what?
He doesn't have any allergies.
People can develop them
at any age.
April, let's give Mr. Wilks
50 milligrams of Benadryl IV,
150 milligrams of Zantac IV.
Also, let's get a CBC
and BMP and send a UA
for tox and EO's.
Standard blood
and urine tests. Fist.
Let's see
if the antihistamines
get rid of your rash,
make you feel better.
I'm afraid your husband's
going to be here
a few hours.
Oh, I'm not his wife.
Joanie's my wife.
Am I sick?
No, honey, you're fine.
It's Henry.
I'll check back
in a little bit.
Excuse me.
Dad.
Hi, honey.
Hey, I need to talk to you.
Shoot.
Wedding in Hawaii?
Right.
Dad, do you really think
this is a good idea?
Oh.
Honey, it's what
your mom always wanted.
Yeah, I know, but...
Oh, trust me.
She was delighted.
Delighted.
Yeah, of course she was.
I mean, she wouldn't want
to disappoint you.
What do you mean?
Mom is thrilled
about the wedding,
but... She's not well.
She can't handle
a trip to Hawaii.
She's gonna have
a couple mai tais
and sleep the whole flight.
Then once we get there
she's not lifting a finger,
'cause it's first-class
all the way.
You have my word on that.
Charles.
Mr. Brendl's cardiac labs
came back negative.
But his head CT showed
a frontal mass
with focal edema
and midline shift.
A tumor?
Very possibly.
Neurosurgery and Neurology
want a stat MRI.
I mean, he's really
claustrophobic.
The CT was bad enough,
now with all the banging?
He'll jump out of his skin.
Ingrid, got your text.
What is it?
I just got some news, Will.
Tim Burke,
he's out of prison.
Already?
He only got
a two-year sentence.
Model prisoner, no priors.
He's out on parole.
Should I be worried?
Will, you are responsible
for his father
and his brother
being incarcerated.
This is hard for me
to say, but...
I think the safest thing
would be for you to relocate.
Out of state.
The purpose of the Glenn
procedure is to improve
Sophie's oxygenation
and reduce pulmonary
artery pressure.
Any questions?
No.
The operation
is not without risk,
particularly in light
of Sophie's previous surgery.
Each time you open the chest,
it becomes more difficult.
We expect Sophie's adhesions
to be extensive.
But we're optimistic.
She's a strong little girl.
Ah. Okay, thank you.
Hey, you're doing great.
They're great surgeons,
Phillip.
Sophie's in the very
best hands.
You know, it might just be
because you're here, but...
I just think that everything's
going to work out.
Yeah.
Oh!
It's terrible!
Oh, God, that was terrible.
That was terrible.
The banging. Oh, God.
Just get me out of here, man.
You did great.
Absolutely great.
Del, this is Dr. Abrams.
He is a neurosurgeon.
Best one in Chicago.
If not the entire
United States.
My mistake.
Surgeon?
Yeah,
you have a tumor.
A frontoparietal convexity
meningioma.
I have a tumor in my brain?
That's where the weakness
is coming from.
But Dr. Abrams is
pretty sure that it's benign.
And operable.
Okay.
Okay, just knock me out
and let's get it over with.
Here's the thing.
Because of the location
of the tumor,
it's going to have to be what
we call an "awake procedure."
Awake?
Yeah,
not the entire procedure.
You'll be anesthetized,
but then at a certain point
we'll have to lower
the sedation so I can monitor
your motor functions.
So I'll just
be lying there awake
with the top of my skull off?
Yeah, more or less.
I know it sounds extreme,
but it's actually
remarkably common.
No, forget it.
I'm not doing that.
Okay.
Um...
Wait here,
I'll be right back.
Sam!
Dan, he said no.
I'm not going to
twist his arm.
I'll talk to him.
Look, the guy's
a terrible risk. What if
he flips out in surgery?
He could herniate.
If he does that,
I'll calm him down.
Really? I'd say
you've done a piss-poor
job of that so far.
Sam, come on.
If you don't operate,
that tumor's going to
kill him.
All right, if you
get him to agree,
page me.
Looking for a job?
No.
Just curious.
There's a lot of jobs
for ED docs out there,
you know?
Well, hey, nice to know
you're wanted, right?
Let's go.
Bonnie, Peter.
This is Dr. Latham, our chief
of cardiothoracic surgery.
He's made a diagnosis.
Your cardiac echo shows
a condition which is...
Why don't you let me sign?
With your permission,
of course.
You know ASL?
I try to learn
a new language every year.
This year it's Hindi,
last year ASL.
It's an elegant language.
Correct me if I make
a mistake.
Okay.
Your cardiac echo shows
a condition associated
with hearing loss.
Mitral valve prolapse.
Is it serious?
The leaflets of your
mitral valve
bulge when your heart
contracts, allowing
blood to leak back
into your atrium.
I can repair with
minimally invasive surgery.
She's asking if she
really needs it.
She doesn't feel that bad.
It's better to do it before
you feel really sick.
There's less risk.
Yeah.
And you're in danger
of getting endocarditis.
It's a heart infection.
He's asking if he can
go ahead and
schedule the procedure.
Mr. Wilks' test results.
Wife's got Alzheimer's
but, hey, why should that
slow you down?
Go out,
get another woman.
Have her come live with you.
It's really nice, Ethan,
when we actually agree
on something.
Yeah.
Hey, Mr. Wilks.
How are you feeling?
Better, thanks.
I see your hives are fading.
And as I thought,
your blood work is normal.
I do recommend
you see an allergist
to figure out what you
were sensitive to.
I will.
I will start your discharge.
While you're waiting,
I'll get Joanie a bite.
Pick me up something too.
Okay.
Come on, Joanie.
How about some scrambled eggs?
Scrambled eggs!
Yes!
Dr. Rhodes...
Sophie just went up
for a pre-op.
Good.
Yeah... Oh, can I ask
you something?
You've known Natalie
for a while.
I mean, yeah, we've worked
together for a few years.
So...
What do you think?
Will she like it?
Um...
It's a very nice ring.
Yeah, right, well...
I'd only propose
if everything goes well.
Right.
Thanks, man.
Will, I need you.
They're bringing in
Sydney Hawkins.
Your kidney recipient?
Yeah.
You're going to Baghdad.
Sydney Hawkins, mid-30s,
kidney transplant. GCS 15.
BP 102/66. HR 98.
Sats at 95.
Complaining of flu-like
symptoms, edema, and lower
left quadrant abdominal pain.
Maggie...
I'm sorry.
Sorry for what, Sydney?
I... I'm nothing but trouble.
No, you're not.
Don't say that.
On my count.
One, two, three!
Four liters nasal O2,
stat chest x-ray, CBC, BMP,
cyclosporine
and renal ultrasound.
Right.
Get a non-contrast CT
abdomen and pelvis.
Take a look
at her kidney as well.
She seems pretty uremic.
Sydney Hawkins.
Looks like she might be
rejecting my kidney.
Maggie, I'm so sorry.
Help, help!
Henry can't breathe!
Somebody!
He was just eating
a sandwich and suddenly...
He's having an allergic
reaction. I've got to look
in your mouth.
All right, tongue's swollen.
He's got hives in his mouth.
Epi?
Yeah,.3 milligrams IM
and 125 of Solu-Medrol
IV stat.
Let's get him on oxygen.
Another round of epi.
Sat's at 86.
He's tripoding.
All right,
he's in anaphylaxis.
I've got to intubate
before his airway closes.
Twenty of etomidate,
100 of sux.
I'm in.
Bag him.
Eighty-nine.
They're coming up.
BP and heart rate are okay.
He's stable.
Oh, thank God!
My God, what...
What could've caused this?
What did he eat?
It was a roast beef sandwich.
Wait, where's Joanie?
Where is she?
Hey, did you see a woman leave
this room just a minute ago?
Yeah. She's headed outside.
Joanie!
Oh, my God!
Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Lots of cars.
Let's get you
where it's safe.
Oh, honey! Honey!
Oh, honey.
Are you okay?
I'm okay.
Okay.
Connor.
Hey, Nina, what's up?
Your father didn't have
a history of diabetes, did he?
Hmm. No, why?
He died from
an overdose of insulin.
Insulin. That doesn't
make any sense.
It was synthetic.
Someone in the hospital
gave it to him.
I have to label his death
suspicious.
So were they able
to determine your father's
cause of death?
Uh...
No, not yet.
Such a sudden arrhythmia.
I'd have to guess
it was a pulmonary embolism.
Dr. Rhodes...
She's bleeding.
Suction.
Suction. It's coming
from her right atrium.
The adhesions from the sternum
must've torn it open.
Damn it.
Let's do a sucker bypass.
Sats are down to 52.
Eleven blade
and an aortic cannula.
And...
I'm in.
Sats are up to 76.
Eighty...
Prolene stitch
for the SVC cannula.
Time to
wake him up. You ready?
Yes, sir.
Lighten his sedation.
Maggie?
Mmm-hmm?
Sydney's scans came back.
There's a tumor on her kidney.
That's what's been causing
her kidney failure.
A tumor? Cancer?
It looks that way.
We'll know more
after the biopsy.
Oh, God, I gave her
a bad kidney.
No. No, they examined
your kidney thoroughly.
There was no sign of a tumor.
Sydney clearly developed it
after her transplant.
As if her life
wasn't hard enough.
Well, let's hope
they get it all
and she recovers.
Sydney?
Do you understand
what's happening?
They're trying to
make me well.
That's right.
We're all just trying
to make you well.
Thank you.
Go ahead.
I've excised
the misshapen
section of the valve.
I'm starting now
to reconstruct.
Surgery's going well.
No surprises.
What were we thinking?
What's going on?
Bonnie and I,
we talked about
having a baby.
So stupid.
Me going blind.
Bonnie with her heart.
Her heart's going to be fine.
But what's next?
You know, Peter, none of us
get any guarantees in life.
I mean, we all
just face what comes.
I look at you and Bonnie
and I think you two do great.
I think you two can handle
almost anything.
Mr. Brendl,
can you hear me?
Who's that?
That's Dr. Abrams.
You're in surgery, Del,
and it's going great.
I need to map different
pathways in your brain,
so I'll be touching
certain areas
and asking you to respond
to my questions.
Count to five for me.
One, two...
So the top of my skull is off?
A portion of it, yes.
We talked about that, too.
Continue counting.
My brain is just exposed?
Del, you've got this.
Deep breaths, okay?
In through the nose.
Out through the mouth.
Three, four...
No, I want to stop.
Make him stop.
Del, it's okay.
You're doing great.
You got me into this.
Get me out.
Stop squirming.
No, no, no!
Del, look at me.
Right here, right here.
His breathing is too shallow.
He's retaining CO2.
His brain's going to swell.
Get me out, get me out!
Either you do something
or I'm going to re-sedate
and end this.
Please, please,
I can't stand it!
Okay, Del.
I need you to tell me,
how are your feet?
Can you feel your feet?
I can't, I can't!
Dan!
Del, I'm touching
your right foot.
Can you feel me touching
your right foot?
Yeah, I can feel it.
Can we please stop?
Okay, great.
Now how about your knee?
I'm squeezing your right
kneecap, can you feel that?
Yeah, I can feel it.
So your feet,
your stomach, your legs,
your hands are all okay,
right?
I'm okay.
Yeah.
You're doing really,
really well.
I mean, you're answering
my questions.
I think that that means that
maybe you can answer some of
Dr. Abrams' questions, too.
What comes
after three?
After three... After three...
You know this one.
Four.
You're so much stronger
than you think you are,
you know that?
What did FDR say?
FDR?
Come on, we talk
about this all the time.
Roosevelt.
"You have nothing to fear..."
"...but fear itself."
That's right.
Raise your right index finger.
That's a lot of narrowing
in the right branch.
And the left as well.
We need a new plan.
There's no way to anastomose
to the trunk of the artery.
We need to attach
further up the right side.
But if we don't attach
to both sides, she'll only
oxygenate half her blood.
It's a lot better than none.
She'll never sat above 75
for the rest of her life.
She'll be in heart failure
by the age of 30!
Which can be controlled
by medications.
Connor...
I won't let this girl die
because we tried to bite off
more than we can chew.
I know this is
a difficult time for you.
You've suffered a loss.
But I've seen you do
things in the OR
that I did not think possible.
This is not the time
to back away from a challenge.
All right.
Two anastomosis sets.
Let's move it.
So what are you saying?
We think it was
the roast beef sandwich
that you're allergic to.
That's what kicked
off the attack.
Roast beef?
I've eaten roast beef
my whole life.
I like roast beef.
Have you been
in the woods recently?
Woods? Yeah, I...
A month ago I went
fishing in Kentucky.
Any tick bites?
Yes. He called me and said
there were ticks everywhere.
A bite
from the Lone Star tick,
which is common
in the Southeast
like Kentucky can cause
a sensitivity to meat.
You'll need to confirm
with an allergist,
but in the meantime it's best
that you stay away from meat.
Oh, God.
Mr. Wilks, we were very lucky
with your wife today.
Has this happened before?
She can wander off.
We have to keep
an eye on her.
Yes, you do.
If you find you can't manage,
you know there are facilities.
Oh, Joanie was in one.
Nice place.
But she was depressed.
Missed her house,
Roxanne and me.
She's a lot happier now.
We missed her, too.
I know that look.
You don't approve
of how we live.
I doubt you have any idea
what it's like
to, little by little,
lose someone
you care deeply about.
If it hadn't been for
Roxanne's love and support,
I could never
take care of Joanie.
It's not a perfect situation,
but it's the best we can do.
Excuse us.
You're gonna be okay.
Unusual arrangement,
but, seems to work.
I guess.
People can live
any way they want.
I'm glad to hear
you say that.
Emily called.
Yeah?
She and Bernie have a plan.
They'd like to discuss it
with us over dinner.
What is this plan?
I'm going to let
Emily tell you.
I informed Ms. Rush
that her surgery went well
and that I anticipate
that she'll only need
to spend another three days
in the hospital.
Oh, Dr. Halstead.
Mr. Rush asked me to tell you
that they've decided
they will try to have a baby.
Ah! "A lovely couple."
Thank you for asking
me to consult.
Thank you.
A baby?
They didn't think
they could handle one.
Looks like
they changed their minds.
I guess when you've
already been through
so much together...
Nothing much scares you.
Yeah.
Snip.
Time on pump?
Three hours 14.
Should we take
her off bypass?
That should do it.
Pressure's good.
Normal rate and rhythm.
Sats are at 88.
She's going to make it.
Close, if you don't mind.
Not at all.
Hey.
What is it?
I've decided I'm not
going to relocate.
Why?
I'm tired of being afraid.
I don't want to run away.
I'd like to think
that you were staying
because of me,
but that's not
the reason, is it?
Natalie?
My loss.
Be safe, okay?
I was able to completely
resect the tumor and
as I expected, it's benign.
Dr. Charles, I couldn't
have done it without you.
Thank you.
I'm the one you should be
thanking, but so be it.
You should be
proud of yourself.
The inspirational speech
you gave that nutcase?
The FDR quote?
That was a dreadful clich,
but effective.
Yeah.
All right, Daniel, I'll bite.
What's the problem?
Well, um... Fear.
I think I'm having
a really hard time
facing the fact that I'm going
to lose somebody that I love.
And?
And what?
Who doesn't have
a hard time with that?
Shrinks.
Have to make a meal
out of everything.
Hey, honey. It's Dad.
Um, I think I'm going to need
your help with something.
Emily, there's more blankets
for the guest room
in the hall closet,
and pillows.
Thanks.
Hmm.
Ethan. Do you want
more chicken?
No, thanks.
Jamie, did you put out
fresh towels for
Emily and your dad?
Mom...
Sorry, the bed's only a queen.
The king wouldn't fit.
It's okay.
I'm used to the couch.
You and Emily should sleep
together so she can
keep an eye on you.
Oh! Did you remember
to take your stool softener?
Oh! No, I didn't.
I'll clear.
Oh, Jamie can do that.
Honey, I'll take the baby.
No, sit. I'm fine.
Okay.
I'll help him.
So... You're not
judging, right?
No, no.
Hey, didn't I tell Emily
how happy I was for her?
Living together with
Bernie's wife and daughter?
I just couldn't tell
how sincere you were.
Okay.
This might actually
be the best solution.
Emily's always had trouble
with stability...
Bernie's family seems
pretty stable.
Look, what can I say?
Everybody's happy.
So... Why shouldn't I be?
I have something to tell you.
What?
I'm late.
"Late"?
My period.
Maggie.
They got the path results
back on Sydney.
The tumor is malignant.
Oh, my God.
There is another issue.
Pathology says it's not
primary kidney cancer.
What do you mean?
The tumor is actually
breast cancer.
Metastatic breast cancer.
Sydney has breast cancer?
And it spread?
Actually...
She doesn't.
You're saying that I have
metastatic breast cancer?
When was the last time
you had a mammogram, Maggie?
I don't know.
I... A while.
You're going to have
a mammogram.
Today. Now.
Come on.
No.
One second.
Maggie...
You don't have to
worry, Sydney.
You're going to be okay.
Thank you.
Sharon, I can handle this.
Come on.
We did it.
We saved that little girl.
Yeah.
We're a great team.
Connor...
I'm so sorry
about your father.
But...
Now there's nothing
keeping us apart.
What?
He's gone, you're free.
No, Ava...
No, no, look. Listen to me.
We can be together now.
I think that you and I
are way past that.
We're not. We'll start over.
We'll just...
Ava, stop!
Okay? We're finished.
That's it.
You ungrateful prick.
Rot in hell.
Oh, my goodness.
This is so beautiful.
Thank you!
Oh, my goodness gracious. Oh!
Well, it's not...
Not quite Hawaii,
but it's close, right?
Yeah.
Oh, my goodness,
look who's here!
What are you guys doing here?
Hi, Mom.
Oh, my God!
Congratulations, CeCe.
Congratulations for what?
Mrs. C!
I am so happy
to finally be
at your wedding.
Wedding? Now?
If you'd still have me?
Come on, wed me.
I'm like... Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
Caroline, this is Keoni.
Hi, Keoni.
Welcome.
Thank you.
In the Hawaiian language,
the Hawaiian word
for love is "aloha."
You will share these leis.
Exchange them,
in the spirit of your aloha.
Sophie should be able
to leave the hospital
in about a week or ten days.
And after that,
she'll begin to thrive.
Hit her milestones.
Crawling, walking, growing.
Natalie...
You've helped me so much
through a very difficult time.
I'm glad I could.
There's something
I want to ask you.
Dr. Manning, can I...
Will you give me a second?
Yeah.
What is it?
Tim Burke's out of prison.
And I advised Will
to relocate, but he won't.
Because of you.
Will loves you.
He is brave, and devoted,
and you will never find
another guy like him.
You would be a fool
not to take him back.
Natalie. What are you...
Agent Lee told me
what was going on.
Will, I am so sorry.
Whoa.
Natalie!
I got you.
Natalie? No!
Natalie!
Natalie, come on. Wake up!