Previously on The Resident...
Does she know you're in
love with her? I'm her mentor.
To be anything else would cross
a line that I would never cross.
That must be hard on you.
You might be a
genius at medicine,
but when it comes to love,
these unexpected Raptor feelings
- is too much.
- He's my mentor.
Nothing more.
- Turn off all his morphine.
- You can't be serious.
Then we add a dose of Narcan.
What you're talking
about is torture.
What I'm talking
about is this man,
who'll die unless Rob Spiro
tells us where he's being held.
- I want no part of it.
- It has to be done.
C-Could you slow down?
I'd like to make it to the
conference in one piece.
We will. But riddle me this.
Why is there an illicit bag
of trail mix on my
leather upholstery?
Okay, first, you wouldn't
let me choose the music.
The driver picks.
Everybody knows that.
And now you're
saying I can't eat.
What part of
"leather upholstery"
does not compute?
For the record, you
could've stayed at Chastain.
Oh, and miss your presentation?
Over somebody else's dead body.
Look, as your mentor,
it's a privilege to
ensure that your debut
at the Society of
Georgia Surgeons
is filled with all the pomp
and circumstance it deserves.
This weekend's
gonna change your life.
The hell?
I told you to slow down.
What happened to this kid?
Unclear.
Someone said he collapsed
while walking at the mall.
Hold compressions.
Let's check for a pulse.
No cardiac activity.
Been over 30 minutes, no pulse.
Time of death, 14:20.
You know, there's
nothing but brush out here.
You keep pacing like that,
you're liable to start a fire.
Wow.
Looks like somebody's
got the Halloween spirit.
That's up year-round.
Giant homemade voodoo
doll to ward off evil spirits.
Some folks think we're
cursed around here.
All right, lay it on me, my man.
What's wrong with my baby?
Your radiator hose burst.
Ooh! Hello. Um, we have
a medical conference to get to.
How long is that going to take?
Good mechanic
can fix it in a day.
You got a guy?
Aren't you our guy?
Best I can do is find you a
shop in the city, come get you.
That's three hours away.
We don't have that kind of time.
So, since he can't
get the job done,
let's call Chastain
and have Bell send
- the Red Rock chopper.
- That's a solid backup plan,
but it shouldn't be necessary.
I got this.
- Okay.
- Look,
we're here. You're here.
Why can't you
just do the repair?
I don't work on cars like this.
Really?
Your customer reviews
online say differently.
Well...
it ain't gonna be cheap.
it's good that
money isn't an object.
So I'm assuming
you can give us a ride
in that big old rusty,
sexy truck of yours.
- He's weird.
- Mm.
I usually avoid weird people,
especially on Halloween.
So you want to stay
here till it gets dark?
I'm sure it gets real
fun out here after dark.
- Good point.
- Yeah.
A morgue assistant
dressed as a ghost?
Is that good thinking?
Boo.
Are you gonna
finish the paperwork
or... what?
Sure thing.
- It's a terrible idea.
- It's a great idea
and you're gonna love it.
Okay, can someone
please tell Conrad that
leaving a bowl of candy out
for the trick-or-treaters
was a bad idea?
Yeah, well, the first
kid's just gonna steal it all.
Thank you.
I don't want to come
home to a TP'd house.
Kids are unforgiving if they
think you're not into Halloween.
Why do I get the
impression that you were
one of those unforgiving kids?
You just got to show people
that you're in the spirit.
Wow. Tough crowd.
You guys are no fun.
Hey, Pravesh, could
you please tell me why
your dead patient
is currently sitting up
in his body bag?
- Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Bring in the crash cart. Let's get him up
- on the monitors.
- I'll bag him.
Hang a liter of saline wide open
and draw a trauma panel.
I'd say this dude
looks like he's alive.
He had no pulse,
asystole in both leads
and an ultrasound
with no cardiac activity.
Well, there's
definitely activity now.
Your patient just came
back from the dead.
Happy Halloween.
♪ ♪
Tell me you understand
pronouncing a live
patient dead is a big deal.
Remy had no pulse,
no heart sounds,
no spontaneous breaths
or pupillary light reflex.
I followed protocol.
Clearly, your protocol was off.
And what about your protocol?
You tortured a patient.
What we're gonna
talk about right now...
is your screwup.
Are we good here?
Yeah.
Just trying to figure
out what happened.
They're taking Remy to the ICU.
- I think it's Lazarus syndrome.
- It fits the profile.
Spontaneous
return of circulation
- after CPR fails?
- It does happen
once in a blue
moon when pressure
builds up in the
chest during CPR.
Yeah. There's no explanation
for it. I've seen it one time,
and it looked just like this.
So I didn't screw up.
No. You still screwed up.
- You put the guy in a damn
body bag. Just dial it back
a little bit. It's a
mistake, all right?
Okay. You know what, you
guys? Just have fun with this.
Good luck.
But now that he's alive,
you get a second chance.
So, what caused him
to nearly die to begin with?
Do you idiots want me dead?
I don't want the black doctor
on the billboard out there.
Trauma bay 11.
Or the Indian kid.
30-year-old male.
Sudden onset headache.
BP 210/90.
History of a arteriovenous
malformation.
Okay, BP is high.
One, two, three.
Okay. Good luck.
Perhaps you don't know who I am?
We know who you are, Hades.
You're hard to miss
on social media.
Good, then I shouldn't
have to reiterate
that I don't want the
brown guy touching me.
"Feldman"? I don't think
you'll be touching me,
- either.
- Hmm.
Hold on there, cupcake.
- What're you doing?
- I'm starting an IV.
Then I'm going to
put leads on your body
for the cardiac monitor.
And I'm going to
attach a pulse ox.
All right. You know what?
You don't want to be
treated, that's fine by us.
Let's go.
I wouldn't mess with
them if I were you.
Look, I was diagnosed
with the AVM when I was a kid.
Doc said I should
call an ambulance
if I ever got a severe headache.
- We'll be back.
- Just you and the girl will do.
More proof
that evil doesn't always come
in a mask on a movie screen.
Guys like him spew
hate on a regular basis,
- and ignorant people eat it up.
- Despite that,
we have to do our jobs
and treat him like
any other patient.
- Or not.
- No, you're right.
And that being said, a
headache in someone
with an AVM could
indicate a sentinel bleed.
But he needs an MRI
to confirm because he's...
First, we need to get
his BP under control.
Hypertension could
cause his AVM to rupture.
Which is what I was just about
to say if you'd let me finish.
I'll start a nicardipine drip.
And I will schedule an MRI
and get him sent to the ICU.
I'm gonna go check
on my Lazarus patient.
And I'll come with.
Make sure he doesn't
die on us again.
Um... it's Halloween.
Where is everyone?
Shouldn't there be little
kids in annoying costumes
asking for wrapped sugar?
Well, look at all the businesses
that have closed down.
You can't trick-or-treat
if there's nobody to
give out the candy.
All right, looks like we're
definitely getting a room.
- Get something to eat?
- Yeah.
Uh, excuse me?
Okay. Well, service needs work.
Go at it. You just have to
tug down.
♪ ♪
Side-eye alert.
Where are we?
Hey.
You need to order and leave.
Why?
And what happened to your arm?
I'll order you two specials.
To go.
- We need to see Hades right now.
- Visiting hours just ended.
You'll have to come
back tomorrow.
I don't care. Like it or
not, we're gonna see him.
Why don't you go
- make that happen.
- That won't be necessary.
Dr. Randolph Bell,
CEO, Chief of Surgery
here at Chastain.
Zeke Metcalfe.
As I was telling these folks,
- we need to see Hades.
- I understand,
but we can't have
people visiting at all hours.
Our patients need
their rest... It's my job
to make sure they
get what they need.
And Hades needs me.
His health is complicated.
If anything comes up, our
staff is capable of handling it.
Yeah? You mean like the
black guy on the billboard?
'Cause if that's the case...
can't say I trust
your judgment, Doc.
My judgment is not the issue.
Your compliance is. I
don't like to call the police,
but when a situation
warrants, I do.
You tell me.
Does this situation
warrant a call?
Okay.
We'll play ball for now.
We'll be back first thing, hmm?
Without the guns.
Georgia might be open carry.
Chastain is not.
You think you're something, huh?
You got that fancy suit.
You got these
walls to protect you.
But let me give
you the brass tacks.
If anything happens to Hades,
I'm gonna hold you
personally responsible,
and there won't be anyone...
or anything that'll stop
me from getting to you.
- I see Hades has landed.
- He has an AVM,
which may or may
not become emergent.
If he dies at Chastain,
there's no telling what
his followers will do.
Yeah, they're a violent bunch.
Sounds like you need
a surgeon to perform
- a flawless AVM resection.
- Preferably before it ruptures.
I'll do it.
He's a racist who
incites violence
against people
who look like you.
- Why volunteer?
- Because my heart can find
the compassion in
all human beings,
no matter our differences.
Just get him out
of this hospital...
alive.
Well, if it isn't
the poster boy.
Am I supposed to be impressed?
Hey.
Tell me, how does it feel
knowing that you're
only filling a quota?
Chances are your
AVM is bleeding.
Without surgery, you
can die at any time.
Might want to be nice to a
man that could save your life.
I will be, once I meet
the real American
who should have your job.
I've met my share
of people like you.
Weak, ignorant, false
sense of superiority.
Many of them tried
to take me down,
but all their efforts
ended up the same.
- Yeah? How's that?
- The look.
A pained expression when
they realized I was smarter
and more talented
than they ever would be.
Hey, I know my rights.
I want another surgeon.
Cool. I have no problems
learning about your
death on the news.
Wait, please!
Don't listen to him.
To who?
To Hades.
Listen to me. Douglas Atwater.
I-I-I'm begging you.
Help me, please.
We were able to
get you off the vent,
but you have what we
call dilated cardiomyopathy.
This puts you at
risk for arrhythmias...
which can be fatal.
And if you had
one earlier today,
that could explain why
you lost consciousness.
The tests also revealed
that you have liver damage.
He wants to be discharged.
Well...
that would be a mistake.
Okay, we know our rights.
You can't keep him here.
Isn't that right, Remy?
Uh...
Bro, i-if you won't
discharge me,
I'll just leave on my own.
Hey.
You are very sick, Remy.
Technically, you
already died once today.
You leave this hospital,
and you could actually die.
Remy, we already
ran some basic tests.
Why not just stick around for
all the results to come back?
You have to pay for them anyway.
Okay, fine. But after that,
then we're out of here.
Did you see the track marks
on their arms?
I think they're addicts.
We need to see what drugs he's
taking before we move forward.
Wait, you're speculating.
He needs a cardiac cath
to figure out what caused
his cardiomyopathy.
Might even need
a liver biopsy, too.
Did you hear them?
They want to leave.
It's hard enough to get them
to wait for Remy's test results,
you want to recommend
invasive procedures?
In this situation,
it's called for.
He has life-threatening
conditions
that need to be worked up.
Remy doesn't want to be
bombarded with tests right now,
so we build up some trust
first, and then we go from there.
Understood?
I was diagnosed with multiple
personality disorder as a kid.
Hades... the man
you've been speaking to...
- he takes over my body.
- You lost me at multiple
personality disorder.
- It's-it's a real thing.
- It's not.
It is. A do-doctor in
Oregon diagnosed us.
- I can get you his number.
- A doctor in California says
that yogurt treats brain
tumors. Doesn't make it so.
You-you have no idea of the
hell that Hades puts me through.
He makes all of our decisions.
He insults me. He suppresses me.
I lose control every
day, but right here,
right now I am winning.
I have an opportunity
to get what I want,
and I want you to operate.
And you're willing to sign
a consent for surgery?
Yes.
Okay.
The car won't be finished today,
but we can still make it
to the conference on time
if we leave early tomorrow.
♪ What's the use ♪
♪ Of my crying ♪
♪ If you don't care anymore? ♪
Here's your food.
I suggest you check into your
hotel room and eat upstairs.
Hey, let's-let's hit pause
on the dramatic
heads-up for a minute.
- Let's talk about that arm.
- It looks inflamed,
and has grown past the
bandage. Have you seen a doctor?
We don't have
doctors in this town,
so I drove three
hours to Atlanta
and got a prescription for
penicillin that isn't working.
There must be some reason
why the antibiotic isn't working.
Sonya.
Everything okay over here?
We're okay, Phil.
Hey, listen,
Phil, we are okay.
All right? We don't
want any problems.
You don't like black
people. We get it.
They're not racist.
That's not why
you're not welcome.
We want you to leave
because you're doctors.
Boone spread the word
you're from Chastain.
Which means you work for
Red Rock Mountain Medical.
The company that
bought our hospital
and shut it down
because no one here
could afford
their inflated bills.
I was a nurse anesthetist.
Best damn job I ever had.
I took care of their
electrical, top to bottom.
Did it for 30 years.
I used to make good
money at my pharmacy.
Now there's no one
here to write prescriptions.
All the doctors left
when the hospital closed.
Leaving us to
care for our elderly
and mentally ill on our own.
We had nothing to do with that,
so if there's any
way we can help...
- Like looking at the arm.
- Look, eat here if you want,
but please, just leave me alone.
He's in V-tach. Move.
Get a crash cart in here now!
- Wait, what's happening?
- His heart
stopped beating again.
I need one of epi
and charge to 200.
Charge.
- Clear.
- None of that is gonna work.
Bella, please, we are trying
to save Remy's life. Okay.
Charge again.
Clear.
Stop! You can't
save him, but I can.
Remy needs some of my blood.
Because he's a
vampire and so am I.
Let's start him on 300
milligrams of amiodarone.
- And get another EKG.
- Right away.
He doesn't need that.
He needs blood.
You guys don't
get it. This is why
we didn't tell you how we live.
The media just
spouts so many lies.
We're not here to judge you.
- We just want to help.
- In order to treat
and diagnose you correctly...
Remy, tell us about
your vampirism lifestyle.
We...
feed on a limited amount
of one another's blood.
Al-Always safely.
Okay. So...
what does that do for you?
It gives us energy.
Vitality.
Imagine the most
alive you've ever felt
and multiply it by ten.
And since we share blood,
it's like we share one essence.
Our connection...
is both physical and spiritual.
Remy, we still don't know
what caused you
to collapse earlier.
The answer could
be in your blood.
- You need more extensive tests.
- No, he doesn't.
- We've been safe.
- You love Remy.
We can see that.
Regardless of how safe
you are, you're sharing blood,
which means you're both at
risk for blood-borne illnesses.
If Bella's in danger,
there's no question.
Do the test.
I won't let you take any risks.
I hear you met Hades
and Doug.
Word travels fast.
Don't often see DID
patients around here...
Dissociative identity disorder...
Whatever they're calling
multiple personality
disorder these days.
Why bother renaming
something that's pure fiction?
I don't believe that... I mean,
I've seen a handful of cases
- during my career.
- Well, if it does exist,
it's not because of anyone's
childhood or their mommy.
I think it's a cagey
form of manipulation.
How can you say that
with so much certainty?
I mean, don't you
think we should look
at our patient's
psychiatric records to see
what a doctor who has a
degree in that area has to say?
I heard the words
"we" and "our."
Are you tagging
yourself on to my case?
Who do you think
scheduled the MRI
that's currently in progress?
Well, now we have confirmation
that the AVM
needs to be excised.
It's hemorrhaging
into the temporal lobe
and the surrounding tissue.
What's this, next to the AVM?
Looks like mesial
temporal lobe sclerosis,
inflammatory scarring.
People with sclerotic tissue
are more prone to seizures,
but in this area of the brain,
it presents as
personality changes.
Doug is having seizures that
are manifesting as Hades?
Yes. It's not DID.
It's temporal lobe epilepsy
as a result of sclerotic tissue.
Which means I can
literally cut out Hades.
I can get him into
the OR tonight.
You're talking about removing
a portion of this man's brain.
You know as well as I do
there could be serious
consequences to this.
We need a second
opinion, a neurology consult,
and more than anything, we
need to see his psych records.
Nevin, I like you
most of the time.
But you're a nurse practitioner.
Don't ever question me.
And with one delicate
stroke of the scalpel,
I can and will, single-handedly,
free you from the evil
that has hijacked your life.
Thank you, Dr. Cain. Thank you.
It's my pleasure.
Oh, you're so pathetic.
Did you really
think I wouldn't fight
my way back to the surface?
You need consent to operate.
I already got the
consent from Doug.
Oh, yeah, that shadow of a man?
I'm revoking it.
I'll go to another hospital.
Get my discharge papers.
Hi, Remy.
All of your hepatitis
panels and the HIV test
- came back negative.
- So we added on
some additional studies
looking at your iron levels.
You have hemochromatosis.
It's a condition
where the body
stores too much iron.
Excess iron poisons
organs, which, for you,
- caused heart and liver disease.
- Okay.
Is it treatable? Tell
me it's treatable.
It is. We reduce the
iron levels in your body
and, because
blood is rich in iron,
the best course of action is...
bloodletting.
We'll need to do a
phlebotomy tonight.
And every week
for the next month.
It will give your body the
best chance to recover.
Wait. You're-you're
talking just a little.
Like, drops, right?
Remy will need to give a pint
each time. And in order
to maintain control
over your disease...
you can't take in
any excess iron.
It's not their call.
We need to discuss
this. Leave us alone.
Uh, my bad.
Look, even the
Raptor is a little rattled
this Halloween evening, right?
Yeah. It's okay.
But we'll get a
good night's rest.
Tomorrow, this town
will be far behind.
And the next phase
of your career begins
with this speech.
You sound so sure.
Let me break it down
to you, Miss Cleo style.
Your speech is going to be fire.
You're going to receive
countless fellowship offers,
and in five years you will
no longer need a mentor,
and we will be...
something else.
Something more.
But I will still consider
myself the better.
And you would be wrong.
Oh, we'll see.
Okay.
Um, thanks for everything.
- Night.
- Good night.
I don't see discharge papers.
That's because you're
not going anywhere.
At least not till I say so.
Yeah. See, no one... Let
alone someone like you...
Is gonna keep me
here against my will.
I agree.
You know what?
Which is why your will
- needs to be taken.
- What is that?
Little dose of ketamine.
What the hell did you just do?
What people like
you do to others.
I'm taking away your right
to be treated like
a human being.
Is this it?
That does it for the day.
Do you need anything else?
No. You're free to go.
I told you if anything
happened to Hades
you'd see me again.
That black doc... He
took him into surgery
against Hades' will.
If he dies
or he wakes up
as anything other than himself,
you and that doc
will pay dearly.
Dr. Cain.
Don't worry, I've got consent.
- There's my AVM.
- From what I understand,
you had consent.
Put the scissors down.
Now it's time to cut out Hades.
Are you removing
the sclerotic tissue?
Think about what you're doing.
You're better than him.
You're better than this.
I'm better because
I can do this.
What are you doing?
Let me go.
Somebody! Help!
She's missing something crucial.
Go ahead and cut.
Here we go.
No. No! No!
Mina. Mina!
Mina, I'm coming!
♪ ♪
♪ Yes, there she is ♪
♪ Is she following me? ♪
♪ If I'm at a movie show ♪
♪ And I'm in the second
row, well, there... ♪
She doesn't have a heart.
What?
Wh-What?
Mina! Mina, are you okay?
I do have a heart.
Of course you do.
Your actions not only
put Chastain in jeopardy,
you put my life at risk as well.
I did what I had to do.
And I live and breathe
for risks like this.
No one has to break the law.
And just to be clear,
that's what's happened.
Chastain's not going
down for what you did.
You're on your own.
Actually, I'm not.
Excuse me?
In case you hadn't
noticed, I can do...
whatever the hell I want.
I'm a cash cow for Red Rock,
which means when you
sold Chastain to them,
providing cover for me
became your number-one job.
So, if and when the time
comes for you to explain
what happened here
today, I have no doubt
that you will find
the right spin.
Because without me,
there is no Red Rock.
There's no Chastain.
Or you.
All right.
How we doing?
Have you made a decision?
Yes. Remy doesn't
want treatment.
We're leaving now.
We are who we are,
and you'll never understand it.
Remy, I know
that it is difficult,
but you have to
face the fact that
vampirism will
cost you your life.
- We don't believe that.
- Actually, Bella,
I-I do believe it.
I've always known
I'm not a vampire.
Wait, what are you saying?
You've been lying all this time?
To-to make you
happy, to keep you.
Uh, fake fangs? No problem.
A night in a
coffin? No big deal.
I drank blood because I would
do anything to make you happy.
I know I'll never get
another woman like you.
I'm-I'm "swipe
left." I know that.
I can't believe it.
You're a liar.
I-I know. I'm-I'm sorry.
I... I don't want to lose you,
but I have a life-threatening
condition now.
I have to stop being a vampire.
Many couples have different
belief systems and are happy.
No.
I could never be
with this man again.
Two people this
fundamentally different
cannot remain together.
No way.
I'm sorry, man.
Coming. Coming!
Hey. We got a medical emergency.
Sonya. Looks like they
need our help after all.
Who are you? What are you doing?
Get off of me!
Someone help, please!
What's wrong with her?
Based on the mixed
delirium, the blisters and ulcers
on her arm, Sonya
has necrotizing fasciitis.
- What the hell is that?
- It's a flesh-eating
disease caused by
the same bacteria
that causes strep throat.
We need to surgically
remove the infected tissue now.
Surgery? Just where do
you plan on doing that?
At a hospital. You
got one sitting there
- across the street.
- It's been closed for months.
Then we open it.
Nec fas spreads within hours,
leading to sepsis,
amputation and then death.
Look, you feel betrayed
by doctors, right?
Fine. We get it. But
you need to get over it
and trust us, or Sonya
here is going to die tonight.
We're with you.
All right, let's get moving.
So how'd you sleep?
- Blissfully.
- Like a baby.
Hmm. Some people,
when they come to this
town, have strange dreams.
Well, I have them, too.
I think it has to do with
Red Rock Mountain Medical.
When they left, they disposed
of all kinds of medications
by putting them down the drain.
Each year, the EPA finds
pharmaceutical-grade
chemicals in the groundwater.
The drugs could eventually
contaminate the
drinking water, too.
Low doses of antibiotics
in the water supply
can make superbugs
resistant to all antibiotics.
Which may be why penicillin
did nothing for Sonya.
And psych meds in the water
have also been known
to cause strange dreams.
Mina, are you sure
you slept okay?
We should focus on the work.
You sure this is necessary?
We hate the idea of
her going to Chastain.
I know, but Sonya
needs to be hospitalized.
I'll go back with her.
I'll make sure she gets
the best care, okay?
I don't know what we'd
have done without you.
Hey, all of you chipped in.
This is a hell of a town.
A town without a hospital.
If we have another
medical emergency...
Get your water checked.
And then you sue the
hell out of Red Rock
- when you get the results.
- You're suggesting
we sue the hospital
that employs you.
- Yup.
- Yeah.
Your car's good to go.
Well, that is music to my ears.
What do I owe you?
The repair is on the house.
Appreciate that.
You know I want to hear
your presentation, right?
Yeah, I do.
My baby is yours.
You treat her nice,
she'll be good to you.
Oh, no, I can't drive your
car. You love that machine.
True, but I know
she'll be in good hands.
Besides, you're a queen.
You need a proper chariot.
♪ If I gave you my
heart and my soul ♪
♪ Would you even take it? ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm
saying I'm over it ♪
♪ No, I don't care
if you break it ♪
♪ The light coming from
the crack in your door... ♪
We both know there's
something going on.
♪ Oh, tell me, what are we... ♪
Let's talk about
what's bothering you.
Okay.
Look, I'm grateful for
everything you've taught me.
But there are some lessons
that I don't want to learn.
What lessons?
I think you know.
You cross lines that
I would never cross.
You're talking about
the hostage situation,
the man I got released,
who's safe with his family?
No, I'm talking about the
patient that you tortured
to get the information
that you needed.
The ends don't
justify the means.
So we have different
styles and boundaries.
No, it's more than that.
We are very different people
with different beliefs.
And neither of us are
ever gonna change.
♪ Every single step ♪
♪ And untruthfully,
stupid for loving you ♪
♪ Darling, just save it ♪
♪ But I'll follow you ♪
♪ Crawl, is it obvious ♪
♪ Please say it's obvious... ♪
My bad.
Forgot to tell you.
Don't look at the
person in front of you.
It'll psych you out
for no good reason.
♪ I mean it ♪
♪ Don't get me wrong ♪
♪ But you've been
here way too long ♪
♪ Still feel you in
every single breath... ♪
You got this.
There is no one in that
building who can touch you.
Remember who you are.
I'm Dr. Mina Freaking Okafor.
When I first stepped
out on that stage...
I wasn't worried about
the people in the seats.
I couldn't even see 'em.
Because in my mind,
there was only one person
I wanted to hear me
speak in that room.
So I imagined that
person was there,
cheering me on.
♪ ♪
Doug's psych records.
You should have waited for them.
You would have made a
different decision last night.
Actually, Doug's last
psychiatrist didn't agree
with the DID diagnosis, either.
He also believed that it was
the temporal lobe epilepsy.
Right, but after treating
him, he had a different opinion
on the seizures.
Look at the doctor's note.
Hello, poster boy.
I was right about the seizures
creating an
alternate personality.
I was wrong about which one.
Doug was the
alternate personality.
And now he's gone,
and I am unchained.
And there it is.
That pained expression
when you realize
you're not as smart
as you think you are.
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH