I had this memory
game when I was a kid...
A bunch of cards
facedown in rows.
Each card has a picture.
You turn one over, look at it...
Then you turn it back over.
Then you have to try and remember
where its matching card was.
I have to get on a plane.
Dr. Grey, Dr. Grey,
you were on a plane.
You were in a plane crash.
Can you tell me what you...
Derek!
Meredith, get up!
Sometimes you have no idea.
Where... Where's my sister?
My sister... Where is Lexie?
No, no, no, no.
Where... where... where's my
husband and... and... and Cristina?
Lay back and
relax. I have to get...
All right. I have
to get to my sister
and my husband. All
right. Hold on. Hold on.
I... my sister. Hey,
you can't go in there.
Don't tell me where I can go.
There's an infection and
I need to see him. Move.
And other times, it shows us
exactly what we need to see.
Doctor, we've got them.
We're taking care of them.
Hey.
That's your mama.
Hey, honey.
Okay, okay.
Okay, okay. You sit here.
Mama's here, baby.
There we go.
Mama's here. No.
The cards seem completely
out of order and random,
but you keep turning them over.
And the more cards you see...
You get a sense of how
everything fits together.
Hey.
They're taking us home
tomorrow on a plane.
And I said no planes,
but we don't have a choice,
because of Mark
and Arizona, so...
So I told Bailey
to just sedate us...
Sedate all of us.
And we'll never
know it happened.
Right?
Cristina?
Oh!
I wish they had put me out, too.
Yeah, I know what you mean.
All I keep thinking is,
we're gonna crash
on some tropical island
and get attacked
by a polar bear.
Now... I don't know
what you mean.
You should watch more TV.
I don't even know how
you can think of leaving.
Because it's Harvard.
Meredith, because you don't
turn down an offer from Harvard.
You have two, maybe three
surgeries left on your hand before...
You know what? Maybe
they have doctors there.
Maybe one can help me.
With Mark in the condition
he's in, and Cristina?
I'm not saying we
leave tomorrow.
They're just looking for a time
frame. Well, I'm sorry, Derek.
I know you really want to go.
But I can't even think about it.
This is not about
me. This is about you.
You're at the
beginning of your career.
It's you they want.
I don't know. I'm not the
same man that they hired.
Don't say that. 80%, Meredith.
Don't say that!
Shh.
We stay here, we work here,
we move into that beautiful
house that you built us.
That was our plan.
That was before you
got a job in Boston.
And that was before
our plane crashed.
Mmm. Blowing off Harvard. Wow.
You're blowing off Hopkins. Wow.
No, I'm postponing
Hopkins till Robbins is better.
Avery did the same
thing for Sloan.
And I stayed.
And you stayed because
you have no place else to go.
Oh. Wake me up in
ten for Chunky Stu.
You just ate. Stuart.
Short-bowel syndrome kid.
I'm doing an intestinal transplant.
He puked on me the first time
we met, so I call him "Chunky Stu."
Ugh.
Arizona hated it, but
Stuart thinks it's hilarious.
How is Arizona's infection?
Is it getting any better?
Don't know. I haven't seen her.
What do you mean?
You're running her service.
You really think she
wants to talk to me?
I mean, what am I
supposed to say to her?
"Hey, remember the time
that I quit and you got pissed
"and took my seat on
a plane that crashed,
"and now you're trading in your
wheelie sneaks for a peg leg?
"Sorry. My bad."
How are we doing here?
Hey, Jackson, you're
talking to Sloan, right?
Keeping him updated. Yeah.
Not about work stuff, though.
He doesn't need that
kind of pressure right now.
What is wrong with you two?
I just said that...
No, I'm just saying, they're
fine. They're gonna be fine.
Arizona's not gonna lose her
leg, and Sloan is coming back.
They're coming
back. So let's act like it.
They're gonna be fine.
We're all going to be fine.
How long are we
saying that this is okay?
As long as she needs.
I, for one, find it refreshing.
They say, if you don't
have something nice to say...
She never has
anything nice to say.
Come on, Yang. I'm
wide open. Just hit me.
I said no more damn restraints!
Look, she is clearly a danger.
She doesn't even
belong on this floor.
She is violent, uncommunicative,
and I'm worried...
She communicated.
She just hasn't talked yet.
Look, there is nothing
physically wrong with her.
She belongs up in psych.
I am the chief of
surgery and her husband.
Don't tell me where she belongs.
Well, with all due respect,
sir, that is exactly why
you shouldn't be
making this decision.
Okay. Okay. It's
time. It's time to get up.
They are gonna take you upstairs
and they're gonna pump
you full of antipsychotics.
And you're gonna go
slack-jawed and cuckoo's nest
and you'll never be you again.
Cristina, please, I am
begging you. Please.
You have to say something.
Cristina, please.
Do you hear me?
Say something, please.
Derek.
Derek, you're
gonna be just fine.
Nurse, could you move
that in here, please?
How salvageable is
that hand do you think?
I'm a surgeon.
What was that? Did you get that?
No. It's all right.
We're gonna take
good care of you.
There was damage to
the second metacarpal,
but the first M.C.P. joint
was completely crushed,
so Boise did an X-fix. I
revised it to an internal fixator.
And then I removed
a lot of scar tissue
so there wouldn't
be contractures.
Smart.
Oh, thank you. Thanks.
Did you see how I, uh...
No, no, your work is great.
Um, Derek, it's the nerve
damage that I'll concern myself with.
Mmm-hmm.
And it looks like
a pretty easy fix.
You know, that'll get you
your prehensile strength back.
That'll get you this back.
Which will get me
back into the OR.
That's the hope.
Well, that's the
point. Isn't it?
Of course. But your
hand was badly damaged.
And I think conservatively, I
can get you back to 80% function.
Meredith, I can teach, consult.
I just may never
do another surgery.
Oh, don't talk like that.
Meredith...
I'm alive.
We survived.
Zola has both her parents.
I know.
That's enough.
Meningioma. Patient
is female, 44 years old.
It's a tricky spot. It's right
up against the sagittal sinus.
Which is why I suggested
Dr. Ramsey see what you might do.
No radiosurgery. I'd cut it out.
Right, but with two
draining veins in the way,
it might be safer to
see how she responds...
This woman's gonna
live for another 40 years.
The tumor can recur too easily.
You need to dissect the
two draining veins clear
and approach it
from this direction.
You get it all, she's cured.
Well, that's much
sexier, isn't it?
That's why we keep him around.
Thanks, Shepherd. I'd be
happy to have you join me...
Or if you'd like to observe.
I... Probably have a
class to teach. Good luck.
She's right. You're invaluable.
Mmm.
Great.
Hey, Dr. Shepherd.
This is pretty cool.
Dr. Ramsey's got a meningioma
invading the sagittal sinus.
She was gonna
do it radiosurgically,
but decided to go
after the whole thing.
Oh, is that so? Yeah.
She just freed the
first draining vein.
Yeah, I got it, Ross. Thanks.
There's bleeding
on the sinus. Suction.
Cottonoids.
Okay, let's put the
head of the table up.
No, no, no, no.
Get the head down.
B.P. is 90 over 50.
Co2 is down to 22.
All right, get the head
down. Move it down.
She's sucking in air.
You have an air embolus.
Boki, bulb irrigate the field.
Make sure no more air
gets in there. Seal it off.
Thank you,
Dr. Shepherd. That was...
All right, you have a hole in the
sinus you need to take care of.
Yes, yes.
You have to carefully reapproximate
the edges of the patch graft.
I'll just seal it with a clip.
No, don't. That could
occlude the sinus.
There. See? Bleeding stopped.
B.P.'s 210 over 130.
Venous infarction.
Ventriculostomy tube now.
She's coding.
It's not your fault. You didn't
force her to try your approach.
If she couldn't pull
it off, well, then...
I could've pulled it
off had I been in there.
Well, you'll be back
in there. No, I won't.
I will be the former
neurosurgeon,
Derek Shepherd,
research librarian.
Shut up. Mark, the
guy gave me 80%.
Well, get back to 100%.
It's not gonna happen.
Don't give me that crap.
You love a hopeless case.
It's true. It's the only
reason we're still friends.
I'm glad you're doing better.
Me, too.
You will be, too.
100%, you'll see.
Yeah, coming along.
X-ray shows excellent alignment.
I heard Schachter
moved your surgery up.
Yeah, couple days.
Well, fingers crossed.
Oh, sorry.
That was...
No, it's okay.
It's fine. I get it.
So I had a look at
Schachter's plan.
He's opted for an
end-to-end repair.
What'd you think? It's good.
Oh, it's great. He's
amazing. He's the best, right?
But? But nothing.
It's just that I've...
I've been in there.
I've seen the amount of gap in
the nerve, and I know it's messier,
but I thought a nerve
graft might be better.
That's all. I'm sure he's
thought of it already.
He's the best.
Well, that would
be... Be much riskier.
You're right, it is.
But it could mean
a full recovery.
You could use your own A.I.N.
for the graft. I've used it before.
It's practically gift-wrapped
for a median nerve graft.
Yeah, but if the graft doesn't
take, we shorten the nerve more.
I could lose more
function than I have now.
You're right. It's stupid. That's
why Schachter's not doing it.
He's smart not to...
Which is why you should.
What?
I want you to do the surgery.
No.
Okay, graft, please.
Here you go, Doctor.
Perfect. This looks...
Perfect.
It's Arizona. There's a problem.
Watch that line. Hold
her. Get some restraints.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Send... Damn it!
- All right, I got it.
- I've got it.
Two of lorazepam now! Now!
There's the restraints.
Calm down. Easy.
Calm down.
Okay. Okay.
The combination of extreme
exhaustion, dehydration, and exposure
seems to have
put her in a state.
What do you mean?
We think it's
reactive psychosis.
She's unresponsive, and then
when we go to examine her,
she becomes... Violent.
I'm here, okay?
I wouldn't do that.
It's all right.
All right. All right. All right.
Cristina. I'm gonna help you.
Cristina, I am gonna help
you. I'm gonna help you.
I'm here. Cristina,
I'm here. I'm here.
Cristina, I'm here now.
It's okay. I'm gonna help you.
Shh.
We're all going to be fine.
How long are we
saying that this is okay?
As long as she needs.
I, for one, find it refreshing.
So she doesn't speak at all?
She hasn't yet.
She just stares...
And breathes.
It's kind of weird, but the way
that they talk about her around here,
it's like she's a
legend, you know?
Mmm. And now
she's like an end table.
Shane, that's horrible. Stop it.
Sorry.
I'm gonna take a
leave of absence.
I think three years ago, I
said I was gonna figure out
how to make a
great roast chicken.
Still haven't done it.
I just like how a house smells
when there's a chicken in the oven.
You're gonna feel stronger
in a couple of days or weeks.
It takes as long as it takes.
And we have all
the time in the world.
When you're back on your
feet, you'll go back to work
at whatever pace you want.
You'll go back into the OR,
and you can do your magic.
You won't have to deal
with patients or families.
I'll take care of all of that.
You ready to get out now?
I can't.
What?
I can't get out.
Are you... You
can. I'll help you.
I stayed awake for four days.
I remember...
Every single minute
of those four days.
The fire went out. It
was really, really dark.
There were so many stars.
I remember getting the
bugs out of Arizona's leg.
I put leaves on it,
trying to keep them out.
And Mark...
Mark just kept dying.
It was so annoying.
I kept trying to help him, but
he just kept trying to die on me.
I just wanted to lie down...
And sleep on him
because he was warm.
And I wanted to sleep.
Meredith was asleep.
Everyone was asleep.
Arizona got the
last of the water,
and I remember
drinking something bad.
It might have been
the fuel from the plane?
I drank...
My pee.
The noises...
The animal noises...
Fighting and growling right...
Next to us, right there.
I kept waiting for them
to come and kill me,
but they didn't.
And then I realized...
They were fighting over Lexie.
I tried to keep them
off of her. I tried.
But I couldn't get out.
I can't get out.
You're out now.
I've got you. You hear me?
I can't get out.
Don't you see?
I'll never get out.
You okay? Yep.
You sure you know
what you're doing? Yes.
It's one highway all
the way to Minnesota,
through Montana,
cross one of the Dakotas,
I can't remember which.
No, I meant by leaving.
Are you sure
you're okay with it?
Are you sure it's
the right thing to do?
Meredith, not you,
too. Owen just tried to...
Well, yeah, because I'm worried
that you're just running away.
Well, yeah, I am. I'm fleeing,
like Bambi from a forest fire,
and so should you, 'cause
horrible things happen here.
No, something horrible happened,
and we should stick together.
You know what? We
have stuck together.
And we've grown together,
like two gnarled trees
twining around each
other, trying to survive.
Survive what?
Cristina, this is life.
Bad things happen. It's hard.
You find your people,
you find your person,
and you lean on them.
God love you, Mer.
You know, so many horrible
things have happened to you,
and maybe you're okay
with it, but you shouldn't be.
Go to Harvard,
anywhere except here,
seeing your dead sister
around every corner.
Hey, your mother died here.
Your husband was shot
here. George died here.
It's my life, and you
were here for it, too.
I mean, now you sound like
the same scary loner bitch
who rode in here on a
motorcycle five years ago.
Like the past five years
has never happened?
Well, you know, a part
of me wishes it hadn't.
Oh, okay. Well, then
you should just go then.
And you should
not look back. Go.
Meredith...
No, you know,
Cristina, you're right.
I'm not your person. And
Owen isn't your person.
Your person is you,
and it always has been.
What the hell did they
do to this guy out there?
Hold my hand.
He's bradying down.
Charge. Clear.
Yeah, I got a pulse.
Clear.
I flew to Boise.
I was there, but they
wouldn't let me in.
They said I wasn't family.
It's not fair.
You don't deserve...
You deserve better.
Shh.
Stop it.
I'm here.
I'm not going anywhere, Mark.
I love you.
I love Lexie.
Loved.
I'm sorry.
Callie? Callie.
Go home.
No, I'm all right.
No, you're not.
You've been up for
the past two nights
bouncing between
Arizona's room and here.
I just need some
coffee. Can you, um...
Can you stay with him
while I run to the cafeteria?
I'll stay with him all night.
I just feel like we're
losing him, Derek.
Usually when I talk to
him, I sense that he's there,
that he's listening, but
I think he's giving up.
I'm so scared the second
I leave this hospital,
I'm gonna get a phone
call that he's dead.
That's not gonna happen tonight.
Promise? Mmm-hmm.
If he starts going south,
I'll tell him to cut it out.
He idolizes me. Mmm.
He'll do whatever I say.
Thank you.
You heard what I told her.
Don't make me look like an ass.
Pull it together.
A lot of people counting on you.
Damn it. I knew I
shouldn't have gone home.
Is he okay? Did he code?
Just come see.
Oh, God. Where
the hell is Shepherd?
Avery, tell me what's going on.
Torres.
Where you been?
Pretty amazing recovery, right?
Yeah. His stats are good?
He's being weaned off pressors?
Yeah, B.P. is 110 over 60.
And he's making inappropriate
sexual comments to Brooks.
It's fine.
No, it's not.
But right now I'm really,
really enjoying it, so...
You think it's the surge.
Mmm. It might be.
I don't. I don't think it is.
What's the surge?
In many terminally ill patients,
they have a final
surge of energy.
They get better
before they get worse.
But this is not that.
But in a little while, he'll
do what all patients do.
He'll have epiphanies,
he'll tell you what really
matters in life, ask for his family.
The man is telling dirty
jokes. It's not a surge.
No, I don't think so either.
Uh, I have a facial lac. Oh, I
had a consult this morning...
Breast augmentation, "B" to "D."
Did you tell her her breasts
were beautiful the way they are?
No, I still think that's weird.
Well, I know you
do, but you're wrong.
You tell her she's
beautiful just the way she is,
and if she believes you,
you've saved someone
an unnecessary
surgical procedure.
And that is definitely
not how I talk to a patient.
No, but it's how you
talk to a woman, Avery.
We're in the business of making
people feel better about themselves.
Again, sometimes when you talk,
I feel like a male prostitute.
She's a person on the
precipice of change, Avery.
She's scared and she's worried.
God, the things we
worry about. So pointless.
And we get to help take that
worry away. It's why we're doctors.
It's actually why we're people,
but somehow we forget
that all that matters is people.
And whether we walk away
leaving them better or worse
for having met us.
We control that, Avery.
I want you to promise
me something.
If you love someone,
you tell 'em.
Even if you're scared
that it's not the right thing,
even if you're scared
that it'll cause problems,
even if you're scared that it
will burn your life to the ground,
you say it, and you say it loud.
And then you go from there.
Hey, where's my kid?
I want to see Sofia.
Avery, why don't you run up to
day care and bring her down here?
I can't bring a
baby in the I.C.U.
No, but you can sneak one in.
Come on, Avery. Grow a pair.
You know what?
Forget it. I'll do it.
Whoa, no, no, no.
All right. I'll get her.
I'll get her. Yes!
My man!
Is this what I think it is?
There's no way to know.
We'll just take it
as it comes. Okay?
Um, can we talk? I'm leaving.
No. Actually, I've gotta
grab Sofia for Sloan.
He needs to see her.
But I can call you later.
Uh, no, Jackson. I'm leaving...
For home... Moline.
My flight's in a few hours.
What do you...
I... I don't have a
job here anymore.
My contract actually
ended a few days ago,
but I stuck around, waiting
for Sloan to get better,
and he's better, so...
All right, I've gotta get Sofia right
now. Okay? But can you just wait?
Just wait for me at Joe's. We
can have a drink. We can talk.
Just... Okay? Just
wait for me at Joe's.
Okay.
All right.
Don't tell Callie. She's
about to operate on Derek.
Okay.
Derek doesn't need to
go in this surgery worried,
so don't say anything to him.
They can reschedule
the surgery, Mark.
I'm sure they'd want to. No.
That surgery's gonna get Derek
back into the OR where he belongs.
Nobody's got better hands
than him, except maybe Callie.
Have you looked at her
hands? They're beautiful.
Sofia has her hands.
Callie...
Really doesn't even
know how good she is.
Sometimes you wish people...
Would just see
themselves the way you do.
Listen to me.
This the surge talking?
No, this is you.
This is all you.
So keep going... 'Cause
I'm not going anywhere.
The extensive bone injury
along with the degree of
soft-tissue infection is troubling.
No matter what we do, it's...
If the infection goes to the
bone, it'll be hard to treat.
And eventually, you're
looking at bone loss.
I'm gonna have to say...
Officially, I'm
recommending amputation.
Show me those.
Show them to me.
I withhold consent.
Before you drug me or sedate me,
I give nobody permission
to cut off my leg.
And certainly not some
yahoo in dump truck, Idaho.
I want to go home to Callie.
She'll know what to do.
Just take me home.
How's that? Yeah.
Does that feel all
right? Does that hurt?
It doesn't hurt.
And anything that doesn't
hurt feels good. Thanks.
Is the infection
better or worse?
Don't worry about
that right now, okay?
Just...
Try to feel good.
Hey.
Sorry I haven't been around.
I just wanted to let you know that
I gave Chunky Stu, sorry, Stuart,
his intestinal transplant today.
It went great. He's...
He's responding well. Oh.
And I know that you
like to do that thing
where you bring
him his favorite food
in a couple of months
when he can handle solids,
so it's Hawaiian pizza.
I just thought I
should tell you.
Thank you.
I feel like crap.
It should've been
me on that plane.
If I could trade places
with you, I would...
I would let you.
I had that thought a lot, too.
And I didn't like
myself for it, but I did.
I kept thinking about
my wife and baby
and how you had
no wife and no baby.
You had no one.
I only went on that plane
because I was pissed at you.
So I kept wondering...
I'm only here because he's
so selfish and thoughtless.
And no matter how hard
I tried to make him better,
he's still a horrible person.
So now...
I keep wondering...
Why this would happen
to someone like me
instead of someone like you.
So I guess I'm still
pretty pissed off.
Would you get out
of my room? Please.
Hey. Look who's here.
Hey. We just had lunch.
And now it's back to
the crayon mines for her.
Goodbye, sweetie. Bye.
Bye, baby. I'll see you tonight.
Okay. Crayons. Crayons.
You need to take
her to the park more.
She goes from that
apartment to the day care.
She's indoors all day.
Okay. Yeah.
We should... We
should get a house.
Whoa. Slow down.
Then she could have a
yard and she doesn't...
Have to be inside all the time.
Hey.
Hey, hey, hey.
Hey. What's wrong?
Do we have a plan yet? Do we?
We are waiting for
the infection to improve,
and then we will know
what options we have.
Well, if the vancomycin
isn't working,
then put me on
colistin. It'll be stronger.
I understand that
it's hard to just...
No, you don't.
You don't, because you know
what your life is going to be.
You know if you're going to...
Take her to the park.
Or if you're gonna stand
at an OR table again.
You will. Of course you will.
I know. I know
what my options are!
And the longer we wait, the more
that my vascularity diminishes,
the more the nerves die, the
more the muscle atrophies,
and then there's
only one option left!
Okay, we are so far
from that happening.
Do something, Callie!
You need to do something.
Please. Please
don't give up on me.
Arizona, I'm not.
Promise... promise me...
You won't let them take my leg.
I promise.
I do. I promise,
okay? I promise you.
It's all right,
sweetheart. It's okay.
This is a good plan.
You're not her doctor.
Oh, I'm not saying I'll do
the surgery. Carlson can do it.
There is a real possibility
she may lose her leg.
You need to help her
prepare for that. No, no! No.
An intramedullary
nailing can save the leg.
Define "save"?
Her leg will never be the same.
A prosthetic can give
Arizona a better quality of life
than years of rehab
and chronic pain.
I don't need to tell you this.
No, in fact, it's
pretty condescending.
Or the surgery will
make her infection worse
and increase her risk of D.V.T.
I'm sorry. I'm
sorry. It's her leg.
I'm risking it. I am doing it.
You are not doing anything.
She is your wife,
not your patient.
She's not, though.
She's not my wife!
I...
I don't know who she is.
Did this happen with Cristina?
It's like you're looking at
her, but there's nothing inside?
I feel like she's
just this shell.
All the Arizona's
been scooped out...
And she's just this shell now,
and I want her back.
And I don't think I'll ever get
her back if we cut off that leg,
so I'm going to save it.
I've made a plan to save it,
and you're gonna get on board.
And then we'll work out a
plan to get Cristina back,
but you need to help me now.
I don't think I'm ever
gonna get Cristina back.
You gonna use a free flap to
cover the open fracture site?
Yeah.
Where are you thinking
about pulling it from?
There we go.
That's from Mark.
He's still doing great.
He said to tell you,
"Good luck tomorrow."
Hey, it's still way
down. Looks good.
And I haven't eaten
since breakfast.
Okay, your surgery's
not till noon tomorrow.
Carlson doesn't
care if you eat now.
Well, I'm just... I'm gonna be
an unbelievably good patient.
Mmm.
Oh.
Oh, okay. I have to go.
'Cause you're an
unbelievably good doctor.
Say more. Come here.
My wife is the doctor
that's going to fix
Derek Shepherd's
million-dollar hand.
She's that good.
Okay, stop. You're
freaking me out now.
You...
Are outstanding.
And I love you.
I love you, too.
I brought you a piece
of Chunky Stu's pizza.
He's eating tonight,
thanks to you...
Us.
He's out of the woods, so...
I'm out of here.
Uh, I'm going to Hopkins.
I've really been busting my ass
to make sure
everything's run smoothly,
and now I'm done.
So just...
Goodbye.
I'm sorry this happened to you
and I'm sorry that it
made you hate me.
It's Arizona. There's a problem.
What? She's crashing.
Crashing? She's... Temp's 104,
serum lactate is six.
She's in septic shock.
Shut up. Shut up. Shut up.
Do you have her on pressors?
I've got her on pressors,
triple antibiotics.
I've got her on
aggressive I.V. fluids.
Did you give her
supplemental oxygen?
I intubated her. She's crashing.
Do you...
Did you start her
on hydrocortisone?
Yeah.
Do you have her on pressors?
Yes, I told you. Yes.
Look, she's still deteriorating.
She's dying.
It's the leg.
Cut it off.
Go. Just do a good job,
please. Do your best.
Callie, what do you
need? What can I do?
Nothing. I'm fine. I'm...
I'm fine, really.
I know.
Okay.
"In the event that my
heart stops beating
"and I stop breathing, I
want to be resuscitated."
Well, don't go crazy, but...
If you can get me
back, yeah, get me back.
Initial here.
"In the event that I
am close to death
"and life support would only
postpone that moment of my death,
"I, A, want to
receive tube feeding,
"B, I want tube feeding only
as my physician recommends,
"and C...
"I do not want tube feeding."
Initial one.
This section specifies a
time of withdrawal of care.
"Life-sustaining care
shall be withdrawn
"if signs of recovery are
not seen after a period of..."
Thirty days.
You've reached Cristina
Yang. Leave a message.
Hey, so I haven't
called because...
Well...
Neither have you, so...
You were right...
About all of it.
You were right.
Crash cart!
This is a place where
horrible things happen.
You were right to go.
You're probably
escaping disaster.
Clear!
Will you take her, please?
Take her.
Look at me. I
practically grew up here.
Ten blade. Here you go, Doctor.
And you're right.
It's hurt me...
In ways I'll probably
never get over.
I have a lot of
memories of people...
People I've lost forever.
But I have a lot of
other memories, too.
This is the place
where I fell in love...
The place where
I found my family.
This is where I
learned to be a doctor...
Where I learned how
to take responsibility
for someone else's life.
And it's the place I met you.
So I figure this place has given
me as much as it's taken from me.
I've lived here as much
as I've survived here.
It just depends
on how I look at it.
I'm gonna choose to look at it that
way and remember you that way.
Hope you're good.
Bye.
Hello?
You are my person. You
will always be my person.