Previously on The Resident...
- First husband.
- You mean best husband.
I got to say, my new
assistant was right.
I'm proud of him.
He's a good son.
That scotch is from my
mom. She and my dad
crossed paths and
they reignited their spark.
The greatest
betrayal of Austin's life
was when his birth
parents abandoned him.
Threw him away like trash.
At work, we go back to
what we always were: friends.
- Her kidneys are failing.
- This time I'm here.
For her. For you.
- Here we go.
- Bring it on. Mm. Uh...
Jel-Jelly... Octopus. Octopus.
Looks like a mouse to me.
Oh, come on, guys.
It's an elephant.
Respect the trunk.
Okay. I see it there.
Wait, who was that?
Work.
You need to calm down. I promise
I will tell you
the second I hear
from the transplant coordinator.
Okay. It's just that
they called me 24 hours
after my first blood test, so...
Nic, his test was
yesterday. All right?
Like the man said, calm down.
That's my girl.
Look, I'm Jessie's father.
I will be a match,
and I will donate
my kidney to her.
Well, I'm already scheduled
for my second round of testing,
just in case, so...
I just wish neither
of you had to do this.
I know, honey. But...
in good news,
you have two shots
at a new kidney.
Come on, girl.
Come on. Come on,
you're onto something.
Come on. Come on, come on.
Come on.
I found our guy!
Found our guy.
About a hundred yards
northwest of where
the river bends.
Copy that. Air unit en route.
Fritz. Hey.
You're gonna be all right, huh?
Fritz...
I got you.
County Search and Rescue.
Update on the information
that the sheriff has been notified.
My name is Dr. Conrad
Hawkins. You know what day it is?
How'd you find me?
Your friends called
Georgia Search and Rescue.
- I'm a volunteer.
- I got lost. My friends.
Well, I got you
now. You're safe.
He's alive. We're gonna
need to fly him out of here.
Hang with me. We're
gonna get you to Chastain.
♪ ♪
21-year-old male lost in
the wilderness for 72 hours!
Let's get him to bay seven.
I thought you were off today.
I am. Picked up an
extra volunteer day.
Glutton for punishment.
And why were you
out there, my friend?
I asked my fraternity
brothers to go camping.
Figured we'd
throw rocks at trees.
Drink beer. Forget
about the world.
One, two, three!
Instead, they turned it into
this messed-up intervention.
- They were mad at me.
- Why?
Because I started
dating Jonathan.
All right. Relax.
Relax. Relax. Just breathe.
He took a fall, he's hypotensive
and severely dehydrated. I gave
him two liters of normal saline
in the chopper.
This is why God invented hotels.
Nobody needs to
sleep outside. Ever.
Gave him a Chem 8 en route.
His hemoglobin's 6.5.
Why is he so anemic? I'm
only seeing cuts and scrapes.
Could be bleeding internally.
Type and cross him
for four units of blood
and let's get him to CT.
What, haven't you heard?
Chastain's almost out of blood.
There's only a few units
left in the whole hospital.
Get whatever you can.
He's gonna need it.
How is it possible that
Chastain is out of blood?
Last night there were
car pileups, stabbings,
and more than the usual
amount of gunshot wounds.
Well, why don't we just get
some from another hospital?
There's a national shortage.
Happens a lot. I'm no help.
I donated last month and
you have to wait 56 days.
I'm out, too. Conrad and I
donated together last week.
It wouldn't help today, anyway.
It takes at least 24 hours
to test and process blood.
Who is that with Dr. Austin?
I don't know her.
Well, he certainly does.
Well, that's a big improvement.
Way too long bored
off your ass in a hospital
will do that for you.
No. A necessary
surgery for a pheo
and an aneurysm
will do that for you.
When are we supposed
to let you out of here?
Tomorrow. Can't wait.
I already missed the
Braves' spring training
and the season opener.
Ugh, you and your sports.
No, I can't miss another
game in their VIP suite.
The Braves' VIP suite?
That's an upgrade.
When we were married,
you could barely see the game
from our seats.
"Is that it there? That
tiny green square?"
I'm telling you,
you'd like it now.
Champagne...
an outdoor patio with servers
who bring food
right to your face.
Come with me this weekend.
I'm not sure that's a good idea.
But it might be.
You're not wrong. It might be.
All right.
Doing okay, Fritz?
How did I end up here?
I started off the school
year in our fraternity house.
I'm an orphan, no family.
- Those guys were my family.
- Well, that sounds pretty great.
- We all need to find our people.
- They were awesome.
Didn't act like I was
different from them,
with their normal
homes, normal families.
We were homies.
Until you met Jonathan.
Yeah. Until Jonathan.
I imagine he must
have been pretty special.
Long hair. Acoustic
guitar. Vaped cloves.
Wow, come on, man.
I know, I know.
But I liked him so much.
So much that I kind of
stopped hanging with my bros.
Oh, it happens.
We all get wrapped up
when we're in a relationship.
Yeah, well, I got
a little extreme.
I ignored them until Jonathan
ghosted me for a barista.
So then I had no
boyfriend and no homies.
That's why I asked
them to go camping.
I thought I could get
back in with them.
But the moment we
got to our campsite,
they unloaded on
me about everything.
So I walked off.
Ended up getting lost.
You find anything?
No major bleeding.
Does have a grade II
splenic lac, but it's stable.
That still doesn't explain
how he lost so much blood.
Two to three liters, at least.
It doesn't make sense.
Those the test results?
His anemia's critical. His
body's starving for oxygen.
- His organs are shutting down.
- He needs blood.
And we don't have any units
that match his blood type.
We need to figure
this out. Fast.
♪ ♪
Seems like Chastain's
always trying to squeeze blood
- out of someone.
- It's necessary.
In the United States,
a patient needs
a blood transfusion
every two seconds.
And the shortages are only
becoming more common.
Whatever. I'm just here for the
free cookies and orange juice.
If I save a baby along
the way, well, good for me.
Thank you for your donation.
Man, you're good at
dealing with those patients.
Eh, she likes to feel needed.
Look, I know we're just
colleagues, which I respect,
but am I allowed to
ask about your sister?
Of course. I don't
have an answer.
Are you okay?
Well, I found out my blood's
a match, waiting to see
if my father's is. I got
my CT this morning.
Should get results soon.
Who's going with you... Conrad?
He doesn't know about it.
It's fine. I don't
want to talk about it.
Absolutely.
Not my business.
We're giving him
supplemental oxygen,
but his O2 sats keep going down.
Why is it so hard to breathe?
These are normal
red blood cells.
These are fragments of
cells that have burst open,
and these are cells
that are sickled.
That combination is making
it so you don't have enough
red blood cells to carry the
oxygen throughout your body.
But I've never been diagnosed
with sickle cell disease.
That's 'cause I think
you've got a sickle cell trait.
It's usually asymptomatic
unless there are
major bodily stressors.
Like in your case, severe
altitude and dehydration.
Dr. Hawkins. The
blood bank just called.
They have one unit of
blood available for our patient.
Tell them to send that now,
- but that's still
not gonna be enough.
- Okay.
Could we get a little help
with transport in here?
We're gonna take a little
trip down to the basement.
All right. Here we go.
Contacted Atlanta General.
We're all in the same boat.
Postpone elective surgeries,
- encourage employee donations...
- Dr. Bell!
Dr. Bell! 911! 911!
My mom is in the ER!
I repeat, my mom is in the ER!
That's all you, bro.
So how long has
this been going on?
Well, redness and
swelling for a few days.
I thought it was age or
weather or something.
But then I slipped in
the shower and twisted it.
And now it's really bad.
Go ahead, Dr. Bell.
We're all adults here.
We all know you
two did the deed,
- so just don't make it weird. Just examine her.
- Grayson? Grayson?
Please? Thank you.
Grayson.
Uh-huh. Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
Your mother is gonna
need a specialist.
Who's the ER
ortho consult today?
Right here, just finished.
Hello.
- Morning.
- I'm Dr. Kit Voss.
Vivian Betournay.
Nice to meet you.
I, uh, slipped in the shower.
I'll have handrails put in.
- I know a guy.
- Y-You know my assistant,
um... Vivian is, um,
Grayson's mother.
- Mm.
- Dr. Voss is one of our
very best physicians.
Thank you, Randolph.
Let's get an X-ray, and
then I'm going to need
to get an arthrocentesis.
Fritz...
this hyperbaric chamber
is gonna pressurize,
just like when a submarine
dives underwater.
Increasing pressure's
gonna allow extra oxygen
to dissolve into your blood.
How long will I be in here?
Till we can get more
blood for a transfusion.
This hood is gonna
give you pure oxygen.
Nurse Robert will stay with you.
There's a tech outside,
page me if anything changes.
You good?
All right, I'm gonna
take that as a yes.
Dive time.
Ready?
Take him down to 60 feet.
- Who's coming tonight?
- Anyone who wants a beer
and to complain about Chastain.
It keeps us sane.
- Irving?
- Always.
- Conrad?
- Not unless Nic comes
and she has a lot with
her sister right now,
- so probably not.
- Hmm. Raptor.
Unclear. Maybe he'll bring
that woman from this morning.
Are you here for Mr. Harper?
Shira Smook, anesthesiologist.
Just came over from
Coburn Civic Med.
Mina Okafor, surgical resident.
Devon Pravesh,
intern. By the way,
I called the blood bank
about Mr. Harper's surgery
and they still have ten
units of type A positive.
Are you sure it wasn't a typo?
Type O, typo.
Sorry, bad jokes, they keep
the lambs from screaming.
- Everybody needs something.
- Exactly.
I'll be in Mr. Harper's
OR with you, Dr. Okafor.
- I'm looking forward to it.
- Mr. Harper does not. He wishes
he were anywhere else but here.
- How am I looking, doctors?
- We had hoped
the bowel obstruction
would resolve on its own.
Unfortunately, it has
become emergent.
You need an operation.
So, no way I'm gonna
make it to the
convention this weekend?
It's nut looking good.
Sorry.
Where's your partner in crime?
Grayson went to get snacks.
Have my results come in?
Vivian...
you have gonorrhea.
Remember, I'm the knee patient.
The knee? Uh, my vagina is fine.
The disease can travel
through your bloodstream
and infect your joints.
Although gonorrhea
is transmitted
through sexual intercourse,
it can be asymptomatic
until it shows up elsewhere.
As it did here.
Bright side, all you
need are antibiotics
and a washout in the
OR under mild sedation.
Well, I would rather have
the traditional gonorrhea,
you know, the vagina kind.
That never gets amputated.
You know, for the
record, it's been, uh,
it's been more than
six months since I was,
- uh, with her...
- I'm sure you're fine.
I could run a test.
No...
Lindsay.
Here you go.
Dr. Bell.
Brett.
How can I help you?
I'm getting out tomorrow, right?
Yeah, I hope so.
I'm sure you want
to get away from
all these doctors.
To tell the truth, I'm
not actually trying
to get away from
all the doctors.
You know... Kit and me...
Things are looking up.
Oh, really?
I know, right? Later-in-life
romantic reunion?
We should be a Hallmark movie.
We've got plans this weekend.
So... if you can
spring me early...
- I'll check your chart.
- Thank you.
I told you you
didn't have to come.
Oh, I'm happy to be here.
This is tough stuff.
I've seen other people navigate
the organ donation process.
It's... a lot.
Nic Nevin?
We reviewed the images
from this morning's CT scan.
It shows that you have
an arterial anomaly
- with your kidney.
- What kind of anomaly?
An abnormal additional artery.
Now, it's not dangerous
and it doesn't affect
Miss Nevin's day-to-day life,
but it does disqualify her
from being a donor. I-I'm sorry.
There are other ways. I
can start making some calls.
See about getting Jessie into
a different transplant program.
Yeah.
Thanks for coming.
Hi.
Your assistant's mother
has septic arthritis.
I've scheduled her
a washout in the OR.
Well, thank you very
much for taking care of her.
I checked Brett's chart
and he's happy to be
going home tomorrow...
with you.
Brett wants us to try again.
Oh. And do you want that?
I'm leaning in that direction.
Well, I just... it sounds like
you'd be very happy with him.
I'm leaning.
I'm not there.
Interesting.
Dr. Bell!
Dr. Bell.
Did you give my mom gonorrhea?
What, you gonna hit me?
No.
No, I'm a... I'm a pacifist.
Here, wait, let me...
So, Dr. Pravesh will take
you to pre-op in about an hour
and I will meet you
in the operating room.
I-I guess there's
no way that I could
stay in costume for the surgery.
- Is there?
- It's not sterile.
- Okay. Would you mind, then?
- Yeah.
It's a shame,
I-I was really looking forward
to the convention this year.
Is it a, um...
squirrel convention?
No, no, no, no.
There's rabbits, too,
and, um, chipmunks.
Uh, the occasional weasel.
Almost all the rodents
are represented.
Yeah, people-people
think it's a sex thing,
but it's not.
I'm sorry you can't go.
Well, it's the one time
a year when I actually
get to be with people who are...
you know, like me.
Dr. Okafor?
I just came from blood
bank, they're down
- to four units of A positive.
- Oh, don't worry.
One of those is
ours. I put one on hold
- for Mr. Harper's surgery.
- Okay, good.
Then... we don't need to
throw in the bowel just yet.
Throw in the bowel? That...
that really is terrible.
Well, thanks.
Okay, this one laughed at that.
- Mm-hmm.
- Oh, come on. She's funny.
Uh-huh. I see what's happening.
You know, I may just be a
guy getting out of a squirrel suit,
but I'll tell you this:
that doctor was
flirting with you.
- No, she's not.
- Oh, no, I agree
with our patient...
Her joke was a flirt joke
and your laugh...
was a flirt laugh.
- No, it wasn't.
- Uh-huh. I approve.
You know, look, we're
all weird in our own way,
but if you can find someone
whose weird matches your own,
I say go for it.
Well, I do not approve.
At least not until she
comes up with better jokes.
All right. Lay back.
Okay. Ow.
Thanks for the latte.
Thanks for being here.
Look.
Things are about to get tough.
We don't know when or
if Jessie's getting a kidney
and dialysis is hard even
when there are no complications,
and there are almost
always complications.
Are you trying to scare me away?
No, I need to make sure
that you're not gonna run
when things get harder.
Jessie didn't even finish rehab,
I'm just...
I'm worried this is
all too much for her.
Nic, I...
Why don't we just put
all this aside for a minute?
Hmm?
What about you?
I'm fine.
- Let's just focus on Jessie.
- No.
You're not fine.
That's why I'm here.
I knew that you'd
put everything aside
to take care of your
sister, like you always do.
Of course I would.
What else would I do?
Are you sleeping? At all?
You were still awake when
I went to bed last night,
you were the first one up.
Plus Conrad. Jessie said
you're having
problems with him, too.
Look...
your sister got here
because of her bad decisions.
Addiction is a disease.
She didn't ask for this.
Neither did you.
And I'm here for you, too.
So I want you to
just hang in there
until we get my results.
If I'm a match...
we're golden.
Should I bring the
patient back up?
No, we take him
out of the chamber,
he won't have enough
circulating oxygen to survive.
Hey. Hang on, I'm coming in.
Oh, God, it hurts!
Talk to me.
Abdominal pain.
And his pressure just dropped.
- Where is the pain, exactly?
- Left upper quadrant.
Okay, give him 50 of
fentanyl, set up the ultrasound.
Fritz? Keep breathing.
In...
out.
Push another 50 of fentanyl.
There's free fluid
around the spleen.
His injury's getting worse.
He's gonna bleed
out. Page Dr. Austin.
We need to get this
spleen out of Fritz now!
It's a little tight in here.
What, you couldn't find
a less convenient place
for surgery, Dr. Hawkins?
- Was the surface of the sun
already booked?
- Give it a minute,
it grows on you.
Ah, the best filtered
air outside of an OR.
Nurse Pund.
You turn that Bovie on
in here, we could all go up
like Roman candles.
Pop, pop, pow.
In this chamber, you
can't use anything
that could cause a
spark, so no Bovies.
And no defibrillators, either.
If he codes, we can't
shock him back to life.
No worries. These magical
babies will make sure
nothing happens to our
forest-wandering friend.
10 blade.
That's Chastain's last bag.
Okay.
So we can't lose
any blood at all.
There's a small perf
in this dead bowel.
Mr. Harper's going to
have significant discomfort
from the peritonitis.
I'll make sure we
have the pain meds.
How much longer
you think it'll be?
Maybe about 20
minutes until we close.
Great, his backup
IV line just blew.
I'd hate to start another one
- if it's just going to be...
- Don't say it.
In vein.
Fine, you don't appreciate
a pun, I can respect
that, not everyone does.
All I'm saying is,
if he really needed to
squirrel away some nuts...
What's that sound?
I've-I've never heard
Dr. Okafor laugh before.
It's unsettling.
Yes, it is.
I was not expecting that.
If I'd known nerve blocks
killed all feeling
so effectively,
I would've gotten one when
I married Grayson's father.
- You don't feel this at all?
- No, nothing.
Here we go, then.
How is Grayson? Seemed
a little upset earlier.
Well, you know,
I'm sure it's not easy
watching your parents fall apart.
- Do you have children?
- Two.
I'm not with
their father either.
Well, that's how it goes.
That's not always how it goes.
You're young. You don't know.
At first, you're in love
and planning for the future.
Next, you're having your
cheating husband's STD
drained from your knee.
- Could be worse.
- There is no way.
The gonorrhea could've
infected your eye.
Pus literally dripping
from your eyeball
and running down your face.
Oh! You win. That's
disgusting. Oh, my God.
Ugh, more than anything,
I just can't believe
that I'm here, at my age.
I'm right there
with you, sister.
Was your marriage
as bad as mine?
Marriages, actually.
Two. And no, they weren't.
At least, the first one wasn't.
He was actually a decent guy.
Should've held on to him.
Maybe I should have.
Maybe it's too late now.
Well, a smart surgeon
like you... I'm sure
you have other options.
I think I do.
Hey. I dropped
Jessie off at dialysis
a while ago, what's going on?
You're not a match.
Did you bring my meds?
Dr. Kennedy to triage.
Those anti-craving strips
aren't working
anymore. I-I just...
Still want to use.
So bad.
That'll get better, Jess.
I'll up your dose. You got this,
- I promise.
- Nic, if I couldn't
stay off drugs when
my life was good,
how am I supposed to do it now?
- Dad's pulling the car around.
- Great.
These short gastrics
are killing me.
Can we call the
blood bank again?
I just touched
base. Still nothing.
He's getting acidotic.
There's not enough oxygen
- delivery to his tissues.
- I need more hands.
Hawkins, get Okafor in here now.
I'm on it.
- Take them down to 100 feet.
- That's pretty deep.
I'm buying us some time.
I'm sorry, but we're just all
out right now. If you could just
have a seat, we'll be
with you. Thank you.
Uh, if you're here about
one of the transplants
that got pushed, nothing I can
do about it, we're out of blood.
No, no, um, I was here this
morning about a kidney donation.
- Last name?
- Nevin.
- Jessie?
- Yeah.
Sorry, nothing I can do
until the donor calls back
- to schedule his follow-up.
- The donor?
Uh, Kyle Nevin. We
can't move forward
with the intake
until he does that.
- Kyle's a match?
- Right, but like I said,
we can't move ahead until
he calls for the follow-up.
- Is there anything else?
- No, thanks.
- Fogarty clamp.
- He's not clotting.
Pressure's dropping.
His organs are shutting down.
Would it help if we dive deeper?
No, increasing the pressure
can only do so much.
If we don't get real blood
into him, he's gonna code.
- He's dying
right in front of us.
- Take me down
- as fast as you can.
- They're at 100 feet.
If I drop you down
that far too fast, it'll put
- too much stress on your body...
- Do it anyway.
♪ ♪
- More bicarb.
- It won't work.
Without more blood,
he's going to die.
I'm O negative, universal donor.
- Sylvie, help me out.
- Didn't you just donate?
Another bag. That was only half.
Oh, okay, this
isn't the military.
Blood needs to be
screened for HIV,
- hepatitis...
- I'm clean. Trust me.
Chu. Hold up.
Now, I don't doubt
that your blood is clean,
but if he dies right now,
we are all legally protected.
Whereas if we put
your unprocessed blood
in him and then he dies...
So don't let him die.
All right. You heard the man.
Let's save this kid's life.
Knock, knock.
- Hey.
I heard the surgery
w-was a success.
How do you feel?
It's not my finest moment.
I-It could happen to anybody.
And, FYI, I got
tested, I'm clean,
so neither one of us
gave the other gonorrhea.
I know that.
It was my jackhole ex-husband.
But I get to tell him
that he has gonorrhea,
and that will be very fun.
Hey.
How about you?
Are you seeing
anybody right now?
Well, complicated, but no.
Really?
Well, you should...
'cause you're a decent guy.
And not awful in bed.
I started seeing
someone a few weeks ago.
He's sweet
and kind.
We're taking it slow...
Thank God... so no sex yet.
He's a lucky man.
You were good for me, Randolph,
at least for my ego.
It's only a matter of time
until you find the one.
I don't know if that's in
the cards for a guy like me.
How you feeling, Hawkins?
If Fritz is good,
I'm feeling fine.
Fritz's "friends" are here.
Well, go.
We're almost done here.
Hey, yo.
Respect.
I'm, uh... feeling light-headed,
yet relaxed.
Like you've just
had a stiff martini?
Exactly.
Nitrogen narcosis.
Good ol' martini effect.
You know, I've
always heard about it.
I've never felt it.
It's fascinating, Mina.
Not at all unpleasant.
Gases at high pressures can...
cause temporary
disruption to nerve signaling,
impair judgment
and delayed response times.
It's rare, but it can
happen to anyone.
So, it's like you're drunk?
Yeah, pretty much.
All right, Okafor, I'm
gonna need you to finish
closing up.
Thank you, Chu.
Whew.
So...
you were with a
woman this morning.
Uh, well, sometimes I'm
with women in the morning
and also the evening.
Wait, are you trying
to take advantage
- of my inebriation?
- Mm. Perhaps.
Only if it's working.
Cute.
Well, that pretty
lady you speak of
was a liaison to
an adoption agency.
- Are you adopting a child?
- No.
No, I looked up
my birth parents.
Get this.
Bio Mom is a doctor.
What are the odds?
Turns out that was the problem.
She was in med school
when she got pregnant.
She wanted to
focus on her career,
so they decided to give me up.
Where are they now?
Right here in Atlanta.
Together, married,
three grown-ass kids.
The ones they didn't give away.
I guess old August Jeremiah
just showed up
at the wrong time.
Ooh.
Uh... Hey, hey,
hey. Shh, shh, shh.
- Jessie's sleeping...
- You haven't changed a damn bit.
It's not that you can't
give Jessie your kidney,
it's that you won't!
- Nic, it's complicated...
- Why can't you, for once...
For once... do something
that is not selfish?
There's a reason they don't
hand out kidneys to addicts.
They use again, they destroy
- perfectly good organs.
- She is your daughter.
- Okay, so maybe in-in
six months, a year...
- She might not last that long.
That's exactly my point!
Who's it gonna help if she
has my kidney inside of her
and she OD's?
Wow.
- I'm sorry, I...
- You didn't...
you didn't come here
to help either one of us.
You came here to
make yourself feel better
for being a crappy
father our entire lives.
- That's why you're here.
- That's not fair,
and that's not right.
Get... out.
And don't come back.
Get out.
Is someone here
to see Fritz Rawlins?
Is Fritz okay?
- He will be.
- Look...
we weren't trying to make
him run away from us.
Yeah, we just wanted to get
some things off our chests, like how
it wasn't cool when he dropped
us to hang with Jonathan,
- so we told him that.
- And he got mad.
And then we got mad,
and then it got ugly.
Yeah, Fritz stomped
off, said he had to pee.
I-I guess we
should've been clear.
It's not about him
being with Jonathan.
I mean, we don't like him.
The guy's a schmuck...
Dude's a part of
our rival fraternity.
Fritz could do way better.
But we just missed our homie.
I'm pretty sure he
missed you, too.
Come on. I'll take you to him.
- Come on.
- Thanks... thanks, Doc.
Hey, Dr. Bell. I, uh...
I just wanted to
make sure we're chill.
You know, after-after our beef.
Can I still work here,
even after I almost hit you?
You know, Grayson, during the
course of your employment here,
I've had multiple
reasons to fire you.
Mostly for inappropriate
suggestions
of a personal nature, and for
your seeming inability to speak
in any manner that
even remotely resembles
the English language.
But...
defending your mother...
I'm not gonna fire you for that.
You're the dopest, Dr. B.
I'll s-see you tomorrow.
No, uh... seriously,
look at you.
I mean, you're-you're
literally giving your blood
to help other people.
My pops would never do that.
He's only in it for himself.
That's why I liked the idea
of-of you hanging
out with my mom.
You're not like that.
I don't think you
know me very well.
I think I do.
You're one of the good ones.
You just keep it way deep down,
so people will think
you're a hard-ass.
Can we get a needle in this kid?
Oh.
- Hey, sleepy.
- Hi.
Apparently, dialysis makes
me take three-hour naps.
Where's Dad?
Right on schedule.
It's just you and me now, huh?
It's just us.
Good.
I like it better
that way anyway.
All right, Mr. Harper,
you're up for a milligram
of hydromorphone.
You don't need all of this.
Go ahead.
Go ahead what?
You took advantage
of my altered state,
and now you want to explore
the information that you gathered.
Oh, please. You
wanted to tell someone
about your biological parents.
Will you contact them?
I don't know.
I understand why
you would be upset.
I'm not upset.
I'm not angry, either.
Every day, I choose my
career over my personal life.
It must be in the DNA.
But if you wanted
to be angry at them,
that'd be okay with me.
Are you still drunk from
the hyperbaric chamber?
Maybe.
I can be angry for you.
Thank you.
Dr. Voss. Look, I
wanted to thank you
for taking care of
Grayson's mom.
And for your discretion.
Eh, what's a little
"gono-knee-ah" between friends?
- I, uh...
- And I liked her quite a bit.
- I understand the attraction.
- Well, to be clear,
that was... a
temporary situation.
Well, I certainly know
my way around those.
Um...
Look, I want to tell you...
you're not gonna screw it up.
Whatever you end up
doing, it'll be the right thing.
It'll be the good thing.
And if you don't
lean in that direction,
I'm here for you.
Okay.
Have a good night.
Y-You, too.
♪ Leaving on a midnight
train to Georgia, woo ♪
♪ Woo, I'd rather
live in his world ♪
- ♪ Live in his world ♪
- ♪ Than live without him
in mine ♪
♪ Her world is his,
his and hers alone ♪
♪ He kept dreaming ♪
♪ Dreaming... ♪
Here without Nic?
And eating carbs.
- Mmm.
- Who are you?
I'm just hanging with my homies.
Oh, you invited her.
- You must like her jokes
after all.
- You know,
some of them are just okay.
Uh, and I think
you wanted to see
if you are... weird
the same way?
Mina Okafor
is your wingwoman.
You could do much
worse, my friend.
♪ Back to the life ♪
♪ He once knew ♪
♪ Oh, yes, he did,
he said he would ♪
♪ Oh, oh, he's leavin' ♪
♪ Leavin' ♪
♪ On that midnight
train to Georgia ♪
♪ Yeah. ♪
- Hey.
- Hey. I've been thinking
about this all day.
- Alec, it's late.
- I know. Just hear me out.
I've got a way to help Jessie.
But I got to know:
how far are you willing to go
to save your sister's life?
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH