Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
We're live. Naïma?
Twenty-two-year-old male,
gunshot wound to the abdomen.
GCS 15.
Dr. Choi, GSW!
On it!
BP 100 over 50.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
wait a second. Wait a sec.
Get this one up to surgery.
All right, let's go.
Okay, here we go.
Dr. Choi, you're good?
Good.
All right, Monique,
seven treatment
rooms on the east side,
four trauma bays on the west.
Bays three and four combine
to treat gunshot wounds,
a place affectionately
known as Baghdad.
Four thousand
shootings in Chicago.
Some days, we get a dozen.
Drug dispensers
are in the north
and south end of the ED.
Extra gurneys,
isolations suites
in the ambulance bay.
Uh, band-aid, wound dressings,
gauze, and extra weaponry
are in the supply
closet next to the elevator,
which brings us right here
to the command center.
Deer in the headlights.
Nursling?
Mmm-hmm.
Monique Lawson.
She's got her
Pediatric Advanced
Life Support certification,
and is doing her ED
check-off skills training
with yours truly.
Be careful, she bites.
Monique, Doris, move.
I hardly slept last night.
I couldn't stop thinking.
I mean,
so many people coming in
with horrible injuries.
And this isn't
even a busy day.
I just hope I'm up to it.
Quick, nurses' credo?
"Cure sometimes,
treat often, comfort always."
Uh-uh.
Don't kill your patient.
Because that's
the doctor's job.
I heard that.
Maggie,
what you got for me?
Alzheimer's patient,
here from
long-term care facility.
Hypotensive and high fever,
in Treatment Two.
Any family?
Advance directives?
No, surrogate
just passed away,
and no one else
was designated, so it's
going to be our call.
Okay, and you need to be
initiating catheter duty.
Patient in Treatment Six.
Have a stab at her.
Wait, we need to page Will.
What is it?
This is Bella Rowan,
Dr. Rowan.
She was Will's teacher,
his mentor.
Okay.
Lungs are wet.
Does this hurt,
Dr. Rowan?
Okay. All right,
all right.
Who are you?
I'm Dr. Halstead.
Oh...
I'm gonna help
Dr. Manning here
take care of you.
Is that all right?
Oh, good.
Okay.
Gotta... Gotta go.
Why is that?
Miss my bus.
Oh...
Where are you going?
What?
Okay, okay, okay...
Tell you what,
Dr. Rowan...
We promise to do our best
to get you out of here
so you can catch that bus.
How's that sound?
Good.
All right.
I'll be back to check
on you in a few minutes.
I'm pretty sure she's got
aspiration pneumonia.
Yeah.
You start antibiotics?
Vanc and Zosyn, plus Levophed
to maintain her pressure.
Metabolic panel,
urine analysis,
and blood cultures
are all pending.
She's obviously
been sick for days.
Why did they wait so
long to bring her in?
I'm sorry, Will.
Dr. Halstead,
I came as soon as I heard.
I was an OR nurse
under Dr. Rowan
when I was starting out.
How is she?
Not good,
and we're playing catchup.
All right,
let's put in a central line
and get a chest X-ray,
and I want to keep close tabs
on her volume status.
Please keep me
updated every 20 minutes.
Of course.
Hey, we went to
Joe's last night.
My sister loves stone crab.
It was nice.
I mean, there were
a lot of years when Claire
wasn't speaking to me.
I'm sure she had
very good reason.
Well, she can tell you
all about it herself.
What do you mean?
She wants to meet you.
She wants to have
you over for dinner.
By "meet,"
you mean "grill"?
Make sure I'm
worthy of a Rhodes?
No, that's more my father.
Claire's not like that.
She's happy if I'm happy,
and I'm happy.
I'm not sure if I'm
ready to meet the family.
Good morning,
Dr. Rhodes.
Robin.
Leah.
Dr. Bardovi, are you
ready for your first
coarctation repair?
I've been
studying cases all week.
Good.
'Course, there's nothing
like watching the maestro.
I will catch you
at lunch, maestro.
We'll continue this
conversation later.
Let's go.
Patient's 13.
Pretty late to get
a coarctation diagnosis.
His dad's an oil worker.
He did a stint in Nigeria.
Nobody there caught it.
Knock, knock?
Dr. Rhodes.
Mitch, how are you doing?
This is Dr. Bardovi.
She's gonna be
assisting me in the surgery.
Brandon, how are
we doing this morning, bud?
We are both looking forward
to getting on
the other side of this thing.
Ain't that right, buddy?
Uh... Yeah, sure.
Hey, are you guys gonna
have to saw me
open to do this?
Yes. Yes, we are.
I'm not scared.
I'm just wondering if
Halloran's gonna have
a cool scar after
the battle of Madigan.
Halloran?
It's a character
in some dumb online
game that he plays.
Dad, it's not a game.
It's fan fiction.
I published a chapter today,
and my followers are
gonna wanna know
what happens to Halloran
after he slays
the High Locust.
That's you.
All right, then.
Well, I am honored.
And yes,
Halloran's gonna have
a pretty gnarly battle scar.
Sweet.
Well, at least one
of us isn't nervous.
So, coarctation repair.
It sounds complicated,
but it's actually
a relatively
simple procedure.
I'm gonna make an incision
in Brandon's left chest.
We'll place him
on partial bypass,
and then resect, or cut out,
the narrowed
portion of his aorta,
and place a graft.
Now I know all this is a lot,
but any questions, feel free.
Yeah, I was doing
some research online,
and it seems that
Brandon's chicken legs
and his puny size
are because of his condition.
I mean, any chance
that that'll change?
Obviously, Brandon's health
is our primary concern,
but yes, he may grow
at a more rapid rate
once the blood flow
issue is corrected.
Good. Okay.
All right, Brandon,
see you on the battlefield.
Dr. Reese?
You didn't answer your page.
Oh. Sorry.
I...
I was just...
Uh...
When Jason Wheeler jumped,
do you think he was scared?
Was...
I mean, was he at peace?
Right before he stepped off,
was there a moment of regret?
I just can't stop
thinking about him.
Yeah.
But, see, I don't want to,
and then I feel
guilty because I don't.
The thing about suicide,
it's never really
a lone act.
It tends to leave a lot
of victims in its wake.
I'd be lying
if I said I'd been
sleeping too well recently.
But, um, you and I,
we've got work to do.
Excuse me.
Sean Adams,
former naval aviator,
now flies for
a private charter company.
He was doing his
pre-flight check
and felt faint.
Co-pilot brought him in.
Says it's not the first time.
Now, I checked Mr. Adams out.
Can't find anything wrong.
Probably just
dehydrated and overworked.
Says he feels
fine and wants to go.
So, why are we here?
Charter company
wants a psych evaluation.
Uh-huh.
Co-pilot says he's also
been acting different.
Doesn't go out
with the boys anymore,
naps a lot,
seems to be
low energy. Huh.
Sounds like depression.
Possibly.
In any case,
the company won't let him fly
till you sign off.
Why don't we
have a little chat?
Thanks.
Code Blue!
Unresponsive two-year-old.
Quick, what do we do first?
Check pulse,
start compressions.
There is no pulse.
Compressions at what rate?
150 beats per minute.
Good.
You got a team behind you.
What's next?
I tell them
to start bagging.
Pulse check.
Okay, but there's still
no pulse.
Patient's dying.
What now?
Use the paddles
to do a quick look.
Shows v-fib.
She's coding, so?
Need to shock at
four joules per kilo?
Well, move then.
You're losing her.
Charge to 28 joules.
I'm shocking the patient.
Great.
You just killed me.
I did?
Mmm-hmm.
You forgot to yell
"clear" before shocking.
Just one of
those minor details.
Reset. Let's take it
from the top.
Come on.
It just seems like
everyone's overreacting.
But you can see
their point of view.
I mean, people put
their lives in your hands.
And I'm fine.
I've answered your question.
I know what today is.
I know where I am.
Aside from lack of energy,
your co-pilot
says that at times
you seem mildly confused.
I have no idea what
he's talking about.
Maybe he's
the one that's confused.
Mr. Adams, I imagine
there's a lot of pressure
at your job.
I used to land F-14s
on an aircraft carrier.
That's pressure.
Have you ever had thoughts
of hurting yourself?
What? No.
Let's see here.
Are you on any medication?
You mean do I take
anything that might
affect my performance?
No.
I take a statin,
like 10 million
other Americans.
And no, I don't drink,
if that's your next question.
All right, Mr. Adams,
well, thank you
for your time.
Getting a little
ahead of yourself.
Don't you think?
Well, he is exhibiting
signs of depression,
and there is a high rate
of suicide among pilots.
Dr. Reese, trust me,
I understand
what's on your mind,
but suicidality should not
necessarily be
a default diagnosis.
So what do you think?
I think that Mr. Adams
is linear, lucid.
I mean,
he's certainly
not confused.
Are you gonna
sign off on him?
Well, I didn't say that.
I mean, I thought
he was a little defensive
around the medication issue.
Well, the man has to
prove himself to keep his job.
That would make me defensive.
And you know what,
that could be
all there is to it.
But, look, he's a pilot.
Let's just take
the extra step.
You know, run a tox screen,
make sure he's clean.
Okay.
To your point,
depressives
often self-medicate.
So, I'm not ruling out
the diagnosis.
Dr. Rowan's LFTs are high,
her creatinine's
through the roof.
Kidneys are struggling.
White cell count's high, too.
Multiple organ failure,
impending respiratory failure.
We need to intubate her.
What, at her age?
Nurse!
No, Will...
You know what this means.
She might never get off.
What if we
bridge her with BiPAP?
That'll take
the stress off the lungs,
until the infection cools.
We'd still wind up
intubating her,
and we'd have lost time.
Dr. Halstead,
there's a Mr. Sherwood here
from the nursing home.
He wants to know
how Dr. Rowan is doing.
I'll be happy to tell him.
Sherwood, is it?
You mind telling me
how you and your staff
let a textbook case
of aspiration pneumonia
go unattended?
I don't think that happened.
You don't?
Then how was she
allowed to aspirate
in the first place?
Dr. Halstead...
'Cause I...
I visited her every month.
I knew she had
trouble swallowing.
Your staff knew
she had trouble swallowing.
Okay. I promise you.
I'll look into this.
I'm sure you will.
Oh, you better.
I mean, that Dr. Rowan
should come to this,
all because you denied her
the most basic...
Hey!
Dr. Halstead.
Thank you, Mr. Sherwood.
Will...
They're criminals.
I mean, we should call IDPH,
have their license revoked.
You've all achieved
something very special today.
Now you're physicians,
doctors.
In a few months,
you'll begin your residencies,
caring for people in need.
If you take one thing
away from me today,
let it be this.
Treat the patient,
not the disease.
I brought you
some Vitner's.
Ah!
Triple cheese.
Thanks.
Dr. Rowan?
I'm really sorry, Will.
I know how hard it'll be...
No.
No, if we can get
her temp down
and her sats up,
I think we'll
be over the hump.
Hmm.
Okay.
I just remember
when my grandma got sick,
how tough it was for my mom.
The options, decisions.
Seeing my grandma so ill,
it was awful.
Yeah, I hear
what you're saying.
But, Nina,
she can beat this.
Dr. Rowan gave me so much.
Getting her through this,
it's the least I can do.
Enter the patient's
first and last name,
select an urgency level,
pick your labs,
and then hit submit.
Okay.
Excuse me.
Yep.
I'm looking for my husband,
Sean Adams.
He's in Treatment Four.
I'll page his doctor.
Thank you.
How's it look?
Systolic's still 50
higher in the arms,
but that's not uncommon
right after surgery.
It should come down
in the next 24 hours.
It looks like Halloran slayed
the High Locust after all.
Hey, so how much longer
before he's up
and running around?
Well, over
the next few months,
you should see
an increase in energy
and some improvement
in muscle development.
Oh, thanks.
I can't tell you,
I've been
dreaming about the day
I could get out in the yard
and toss
a football with my son,
like my dad did with me.
Well, hopefully,
that'll happen.
Right now, why don't you
just let him get some rest?
See, Mr. Adams,
as part of our evaluation,
we run a toxicology screen,
and I'm happy to say
that yours was normal.
I told you
I don't take drugs.
However,
we did find something else.
Profound anemia.
Anemia?
It could explain
your feeling faint.
Okay, I guess
I gotta eat more steak.
It's actually more
serious than that.
We need to transfuse you
with several units
of blood right away.
We also need to find out
what's causing it,
so I'd like to admit you
for a battery of
scans and tests.
I've got my own doctor.
I'll make
an appointment with him.
Mr. Adams, we don't want you
to leave in this condition.
You're not well.
I feel fine.
Sean, are you sure
about that?
Yes, and a car ride home
and sleeping in my own bed
isn't gonna hurt me.
That may not be true.
I emphatically recommend
that you take
Dr. Choi's advice.
As far as
the psych evaluation goes,
am I in the clear?
Well, not listening
to your physician isn't
the greatest sign to me.
Well, you're not
the only psychiatrist
in Chicago.
I'll get
a referral from my primary.
Sean...
Viv, we're going.
Hand me my clothes.
Please get me
whatever paperwork
I need to sign,
so I can get out of here.
I'll be back shortly.
Something's just
not right with him.
I agree.
But is it physical or mental?
Your guess is
as good as mine.
Unfortunately, we have
no grounds to hold him.
I'll get the paperwork ready.
Okay,
so your patient is in SVT.
What do you do?
Cardiovert at seven joules.
Right.
So, she's back in
sinus rhythm. What now?
Check her vitals,
establish IV access,
provide fluids if her BP
drops below 75 systolic.
And? The adenosine?
You got a dose?
Um...
Adenosine is scratched out.
Calculate then.
Your patient's gonna
revert back to SVT.
Come on.
Um...
It's a life-and-death
situation here.
6.5 milligrams of adenosine.
It's 0.65,
not 6.5. Here.
Oh, I'm sorry.
What happened?
He can't feel his left arm.
All right,
left BP is 80 over 30.
Check the right. Sats at 70.
Hey, Brandon,
can you squeeze my hand?
No. No, I can't.
Okay.
Right arm's 150 over 100.
What's going on?
All right, legs are cold.
We need a CT angio now!
Got it!
Dad?
What is happening?
Brandon's not getting
blood to his left arm,
but I need
a picture of it to see.
It's possible that the graft
we put in has become occluded.
Occluded? What does that mean?
The first surgery
may not have worked.
So you have to
do it again?
It may be more
complicated than that.
She's in v-fib!
Paddles. Start compressions.
Will, I'll break her ribs.
Charge to 200 joules.
Start compressions now!
Are you sure? I...
Out of my way.
No, Will.
Are we charged?
Two hundred joules.
Holding the CPR. Clear.
One milligram of epi,
charge to 200 again.
Two hundred.
All right, clear.
Pulse is good.
Hey.
Dr. Halstead
decided to intubate.
You know, this woman
is the reason I
stayed in nursing.
My first year as
an OR nurse, I actually
thought about quitting.
You?
Oh,
I had a rough time.
There was this
surgery I scrubbed on.
I think it was
a vascular case.
The resident asked
for a 10 blade scalpel.
It slipped out of my hand,
dropped in the incision.
Oh, my God.
It didn't hurt the patient,
but that resident
reamed me out.
Dr. Rowan stepped in,
called him out,
said everyone in
the OR deserved civility.
Everyone.
Bella Rowan.
Wonderful woman.
Extraordinary teacher.
Sean. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Help, someone!
Help my husband, please.
Okay, hey,
I need a gurney here.
Mr. Adams,
can you hear me?
What's wrong with him?
Unresponsive, has a pulse.
Get him in a room.
Bring it over here.
Let's transfer on my count.
Ready, one, two, three.
Here we go.
All right,
he's not breathing.
Get me a laryngoscope
and a 7.5 ET tube.
I got it.
Sean!
Trauma One to prep.
We'll take care of him.
He's totally flaccid.
Don't need drugs.
Monique, you start the IV.
Okay.
Sean...
Okay, you stand right here.
He's got
a massive upper GI bleed.
His stomach's
filling with blood.
I'm in.
April, listen to his lungs.
Yep.
Good breath
sounds bilaterally.
Hang two units of blood
and get another four ready.
What's going on?
Why is this happening?
I don't know,
but we're gonna find out.
Hang saline.
Saline's up.
All right, stay on it.
Got your page.
Dr. Rowan's latest labs.
I am so sorry.
She's in acute renal failure.
Hyperkalemic and
still acidotic.
All right, we'll start her
on low-flow dialysis.
It should correct her
electrolytes and pH.
Will...
I won't stand by
and let her die.
Tell April to call renal.
Graft occlusion is
a possible outcome
of any vascular surgery.
It's nobody's fault.
Okay, so there are
two options, right?
We could either...
Just let me handle this, okay?
Mitch, a moment?
Uh...
What is it?
So the CT
revealed that the graft
I placed in
Brandon's chest kinked,
causing re-coarctation
or essentially
a narrowing of his aorta.
Like before?
I'm sorry.
So... So what?
We're just back
at square one?
Yes, but this time,
things are more complicated.
Now, I can repair
the graft by placing a stent,
and we would do
that in the cath lab.
But the stent will cover
the opening of his
left subclavian artery.
That will cut off
circulation to his left arm,
meaning Brandon
will lose that arm.
Lose his arm?
Mmm-hmm.
No. No, he can't.
He can't. There must be
something else you can do.
I'm sorry, but no.
I'm afraid this is
our only viable option.
Oh, God.
Hey, look, Mitch,
why don't you go be
with your son, okay?
We'll take him up
to surgery soon.
I'm very sorry.
Pardon me,
Dr. Rhodes.
I know you must've
had a very good reason,
but you didn't present
the other option,
the carotid
subclavian bypass.
Wouldn't that
preserve Brandon's arm?
Dr. Bardovi,
20% to 30% of young patients
will stroke out
and possibly die
when you clamp their carotid.
It's too big of a risk.
Okay, but still...
What was that all about?
Look, this boy's father...
I know the type.
I grew up with one.
He wants his son to
be something he isn't.
He'll choose the bypass.
It's too dangerous.
But it's his decision,
not yours.
I already opened
Brandon up once.
I'm not gonna do it again.
I'm not gonna risk
this boy's life
just to save his arm.
Huge gastric ulcer.
That's where all
the blood was coming from.
Were you able to
stop the bleed?
Yeah, GI cauterized it,
but that's not the headline.
Sean's endoscopy shows
chronic caustic
esophageal erosions.
And his chest X-ray...
Pneumonitis.
Yeah.
This is a pattern
suggestive of ingesting
some sort of hydrocarbon.
Isn't that in
cleaning products?
And lighter fluid,
motor oil, gasoline.
Extremely toxic.
So we must be talking
about low doses over
a long period of time.
So I was right.
We should be
concerned he's suicidal.
Why assume he's
doing this to himself?
Well, what, you think
someone's poisoning him?
I don't know.
It's possible.
I had a case where
a wife was slipping
something into
her husband's food.
So you think
it's his wife?
You know,
hydrocarbons are
extremely noxious,
so he would've smelled it.
Not necessarily.
They're all over
any aircraft hangar.
With constant exposure,
he could be nose blind.
I don't know.
Suicide? Attempted murder?
I think it might be
something else altogether.
I just
checked in on Dr. Rowan.
I heard
you ordered dialysis.
She's in renal failure.
That's the appropriate
treatment.
I understand
the medicine, Doctor.
Even if you dialyze her...
I am.
Even if you dialyze her,
she's unlikely to
come off the vent.
That means
she'll be bedridden.
Eventually,
she'll need a tracheostomy.
You've already
broken her ribs.
Now she'll have bed sores,
a feeding tube.
Shouldn't quality of life
be a consideration?
Remember that
ballplayer I told you about?
He was a pitcher
with one arm.
He was one of the best.
All right, so,
you know, we can be strong.
We can do this.
The important thing
is that you're gonna be alive.
And healthy.
We'll figure out the rest,
okay? Together.
Mitch.
Yeah.
Guys, if you can
hold on for a second.
Yeah.
Can I have a word with you?
Your dad
will be right back.
So, I've been thinking
about Brandon's case,
and there is
something else we can try.
Wrong angle.
You need to go
in perpendicular,
or you'll stay
in the cortex.
Okay.
You're too shallow.
You need to keep on drilling
until you hub the needle.
Not like that.
Who taught her
how to do an IO?
An orangutan?
Okay. She'll get there.
We've all gone through this.
Just take it slowly.
Go ahead.
There you go.
White board says
carotid subclavian bypass.
It's just, I thought...
I presented both options
to the patient's father.
As I suspected,
he chose the carotid
subclavian bypass.
And you're gonna do
a great job, Dr. Rhodes.
You're an exceptional surgeon,
and it is an honor to be...
Dr. Bardovi,
you don't have to do that.
You're a fine surgeon,
and trust me,
I'm a less-than-perfect
teacher.
Mr. Adams,
can I ask you...
You ever find yourself
doing something
that you know you shouldn't,
but you just can't stop?
I have no idea what
you're talking about.
My wife would say that
I watch too much football.
I'll tell you
my dirty little secret.
I went through
this phase where I would
come home every night,
cut my nails every night,
like down to the quick.
Couldn't stop.
On some level,
I must've been
satisfying some urge,
but my hands were bleeding.
It wasn't good.
And the point of this?
The point is that
I understand
compulsive behavior.
You know, it's not rational.
You can't explain it.
You just...
You just do it.
Yeah, but eventually,
like with me,
your fingers bleed,
or something similar.
And it just starts
to cost you too much,
and you wanna stop.
I mean, you realize
that it's interfering
with your life,
and you just really,
really wanna stop.
Sean, I think you
have a compulsion,
and you're tired,
and you're also
getting scared.
I mean,
who wouldn't be scared?
All that blood?
All that vomiting?
Yes.
I'm tired.
Mr. Adams,
we think you're ingesting
something very harmful.
Can you tell us
what it is?
Mr. Adams,
please, we can help you.
Gasoline.
I'm sorry? Say again?
I drink gasoline.
Is my husband crazy?
Why would anyone
drink gasoline?
I know it's very
difficult to fathom,
but I'm quite sure
that your husband
is suffering
from a psychiatric
disorder known as pica,
which involves the compulsive
consumption of non-nutritive,
and sometimes even
hazardous substances.
For some,
it's paint chips.
For others, dirt.
For your husband,
it's gasoline.
Why?
There's no unified
theory as to the cause.
All we know is
that it manifests
itself as a compulsion,
an irresistible urge,
against one's
conscious wishes.
Can he stop?
Probably not on his own,
but if he'll allow us,
we can help him.
Okay.
We'll do whatever it
takes to get him healthy.
Before we discuss
the course of psychotherapy,
I'd like to talk to
you and your husband
about repairing
the physical damage.
Of course. Yes.
He could've killed himself.
Sometimes we
get a win, right?
Sometimes we get a win.
If you take one thing
away from me today,
let it be this.
Treat the patient,
not the disease.
Good. You haven't started.
Just finished the line. Why?
You were right.
We shouldn't do this.
What changed your mind?
"Treat the patient,
not the disease."
Our patient
wouldn't have wanted this.
April,
10 milligrams of morphine,
and hang a drip, please.
Dr. Rowan,
I'm going to extubate you.
I promise
you won't feel any pain.
I'll let you two
be alone with her now.
Okay, going to start
the carotid anastomosis.
Everybody get ready.
We're going to
clamp the left carotid.
Carla, tell me if you see
any change on the EEG.
Right.
Peripheral cross
clamp times two?
Carotid is cross-clamped.
Brain waves look good.
Okay, 11 blade,
followed by 5-0 PROLENE.
Let's sew this
graft in quickly.
Brain waves
flattening on the right.
He's impending infarct.
We only have
four minutes of hypoxia
before deficits occur.
Do we unclamp him?
We can still call this off
and take him to the cath lab.
It's safer.
Dr. Rhodes.
No.
This kid's
not losing his arm.
Coming around
the front wall now.
Left side brain's 50,
right side's 70.
Dr. Bardovi,
follow me. Eyes on the field.
Dr. Rhodes, you need
to get those clamps off.
Thank you, Marty,
I'm almost there.
Left side's 30,
right side's 50.
Okay. Done.
Coming off cross clamp.
Cross clamps are off.
I've reestablished flow.
EEG is normalizing.
You have
a good wave pattern.
He's good.
Nice work,
Dr. Rhodes.
Okay, everyone, let's
get set up for the stent.
Good night.
How could you
do this to us?
Excuse me?
My husband told me.
He'll lose
his pilot's license.
We'll lose everything.
I'm very sorry.
I had no choice.
I am legally
obligated to report him.
It's his life.
I called the FAA.
I had to.
Every time he gets on a plane,
he puts his own life
and the lives of all of
his passengers at risk.
I know this wasn't
necessarily the win
that you were looking for,
but at least
we saved a man's life.
See you in the morning?
I heard
the surgery went well.
Yeah, thankfully.
Yeah, don't worry,
I won't tell anyone.
Tell 'em what?
That you were scared.
Oh, that's
what you think, huh?
Yeah.
Oh, man, you're
definitely a Charles.
You're very perceptive.
I was,
after that first time.
I was afraid.
I was afraid
I was gonna lose him.
I have fears of
my own, you know.
Cholera? Typhus?
Yeah.
And relationships.
There are a lot of pitfalls
in dating a surgeon.
It's crazy hours,
stress of the job...
Great case, Dr. Rhodes.
Very impressive.
And thanks for
the vote of confidence.
Fawning women
falling at your feet.
Yeah, I don't know if I can
compete with all of that.
You don't have to compete.
I'm all in.
So, your sister...
Is she a red or
white wine drinker?
Um... White.
Not chardonnay.
Sauvignon blanc.
Will?
Hey.
I'm so sorry for your loss.