.
Previously on
"New Amsterdam."
You want Dr. Shinwari
in your ED.
Are you talking
about a bribe?
I could lose
my medical license.
I could go to jail!
I gave Chance everything.
I just want him to get better.
You know,
all I've tried to do
is create a place
where people can heal.
I think I've been
successful with that.
I have never replaced
a successful medical director.
As you know,
I've been seeing someone.
Ah.
♪
So we're adults.
The fact that we can
come together like this
is a testament to that.
Claude and I have talked,
and this thing has happened,
and we agree the only way
to move forward
is to face
this situation head-on.
I'll admit,
I was a bit thrown
when I learned
you were sleeping with my wife.
But I--I've processed.
And I believe that
we can push through this
if we have no more secrets.
No more secrets.
The weird thing is,
I get what she sees in you.
You know, not--
not like that way, but,
you know?
Yeah, I do. I do.
Of course, and I feel
the same way about you, Claude.
But it's--
it's complicated.
I--I'm sorry we didn't--
we weren't more clear
when we were setting
our relationship ground rules.
We agreed that
we didn't want to know
who the other person
was seeing, but
we--we didn't really
lock down the part about, um,
getting involved...
with colleagues.
You want to say
something, Floyd?
No.
Well, I actually, uh, I just
hope that we can maintain
this level of honesty, uh,
and harmony.
Harmony.
Yes.
Harmony's a good word.
Excuse me, I'm so sorry,
but there's only
one quiche left.
They're super big.
Anyone want to share?
Okay, which thalamic nucleus
is primarily responsible for
processing input associated
with the activation
of Pacinian corpuscles
in your left hand?
Right VPL nucleus
of the thalamus.
Yes.
And where would
we most commonly find
the Morgagni hernia?
Left side or--
Right.
But you're not playing fair.
Welcome to
American medicine, baby.
Do you know which part
of the vertebral column
will show secondary curves
with concavity backwards?
Hmm? Hmm?
Cervical and lumbar.
And no more questions.
I want my breakfast.
You're gonna nail
this review.
What?
Nothing.
I'm just grateful
for these days,
this moment.
None of it possible
without you.
You have to put all
the donuts right here, huh?
Just, like, staring at me.
Thank you.
Oh, Dr. Frome.
Hi.
Hi, Dr. Fuentes, how are you?
Uh, Veronica.
Oh.
I, um, I was gonna call you
because I wanted to discuss
this whole
not seeing patients business.
Oh. Okay, yeah.
Because if you're going
to remain at New Amsterdam--
Oh, um, I'm sorry.
Hold on, back up.
You have to see patients.
Otherwise, I don't really
see a way forward for us.
Okay, um, Veronica--
Could I get, um,
a coffee, black.
I'm--I'm the chair
of the department.
And as the chair,
I--I have residents
that I'm overseeing 24-7.
I'm--I'm training them,
I'm shaping them, you know?
I don't--I don't have time
for patients.
Every other
behavioral health chair
in the city still practices.
I don't know that
that's true.
Thank you so much.
Thank you, thank you.
By abdicating, you are not only
hurting our bottom line,
you're damaging
the reputation of the hospital.
You're in a position
of prestige,
and prestige
is what we must lead with.
So let's get some patients
on the books, yeah?
But, um--
First thing after lunch?
Look, I'm not saying
it's a bad thing.
Well, it doesn't sound good
if it kept you up all night.
I'm just saying that
there's a lot of things
we never discussed.
There's a lot of boring,
traditional relationship stuff
that we kinda skipped over.
You mean like dating.
Yeah, I mean,
in less than 24 hours
we went from being
friends and coworkers to--
To mad lovers
moving to London.
Yeah, which is
pretty awesome.
I know, but it does leave
some unanswered questions--
It does.
Like, um,
will I ever get
to meet your parents?
I mean, do you even
have parents?
Exactly like that.
I do have parents,
who divorced, thankfully,
when I was in med school.
Dad is, let's just say,
not a nice guy.
Drove my mom pretty much
all the way to Arizona,
where she married a guy
who is also a nice fella.
Uh, anyways,
we won't be visiting my dad
or Arizona any time soon.
Oh, wow.
Yeah, enough of that.
Can I ask you something?
Always.
Um...
what do you want Luna
to call you?
Oh, um, I don't--
what would you like her
to call me?
I don't know.
Last night,
as I was tucking her in,
she asked me if you were...
her new mommy.
Georgia is her mommy.
She never even knew Georgia.
And if you're gonna
be living with us--
♪
You okay?
Help me!
Rob, are you good?
Hey.
Whitaker! Unlock it. Whitaker!
Whitaker's in back.
You okay?
I'm fine.
You sure?
Whitaker! I can't--ah!
My God.
Whoa.
Help!
We need a stretcher over here!
I'll take Kerry.
Go, go, we got the patient!
Whitaker's down!
Just keep breathing, Kerry,
come on.
Whitaker, you with us?
Yeah, I'm good.
Where are we?
Respirations rapid
and shallow.
Okay, let's set her up
for a full trauma eval.
We're gonna take
good care of you, okay?
I'm okay.
No, you're not.
You need a head CT
and you need that lac sewn up.
I want to stay with Ker--
Go.
Pedestrian struck
by ambulance.
Lower body injury.
Vital signs stable.
Okay, let's get her
to Bay 23.
Okay.
Kerry, what happened?
We were driving crazy fast.
Another car was coming out.
Transport patient
from the ambulance crash.
Severe laceration.
Get him to Trauma One.
What the hell
happened out there?
Another car cut them off.
Kerry, Ker, we're gonna
take care of you, okay?
Hey, STAT page?
Trauma One.
Can you--
Yeah.
Okay.
Rob! Rob, go get your head CT.
Go.
Forceps.
You good?
Give us a little room.
Yeah.
Can you see?
Yeah, there we go.
We're clear,
stanch the laceration.
Tachy at 144, 96 over 51.
Floyd, look at this.
Oh.
Bleeder's not our only problem.
Suture.
This puncture happened
in the crash,
but we need to know
what put him in the ambulance
in the first place.
Whatever it was
must have been bad.
Moreland was
tearing down that road.
Respiratory rate's 13.
Can you ask him?
No, Moreland's in CT
and Whitaker's in surgery.
Dispatch report.
On it.
♪
Promise me
that you'll save her first.
Hey, how are you?
Luna, say hi to your mom.
Give me a clue. Anything.
The report's missing.
Somebody tore it out.
Look, I know this isn't
where your head's at right now,
but you need to call
your union rep.
Police are gonna have questions
and you need to be protected.
When I was carrying
Whitaker in,
people were looking at me
like I'd killed--
Don't. Don't.
I need to be fired, Lauren.
The police should
put me in jail.
Robert,
you drive an ambulance.
There's not a single
human being who's needed one
who wished the driver
had gone slower.
Tell that to the man's family.
I met his wife, his grandson.
Okay, listen to me.
Two of the best doctors
at this hospital
are doing everything
they can for him right now.
And Whitaker
is gonna pull through.
Because that's our job.
And your job is to
stop blaming yourself, okay?
Another car cut you off.
This is not your fault.
Wasn't a car, Lauren.
I got around the car.
It was me, I--
Okay.
I was going too fast.
This was all me.
We did all we could.
He's gone.
Hey, it's okay.
.
Oh, Max, hey!
Listen, I, um, I know things
are a little crazy
around here right now.
Yeah, beyond.
I have this thing
I need you to submit me for.
It's a little time-sensitive,
so I put stickies
everywhere you need to sign.
For the NAPA Prize?
Why is this time-sensitive?
They've been trying
to give it to me for years.
Yeah, and you've been
making fun of it for years.
Yeah, which was
incredibly immature of me.
I believe you called it
a spiky, ugly little award
that was ironic
in its Freudian obliviousness.
Yesterday it was oblivious,
today it's prestigious.
What changed?
Uh, our new medical director.
Veronica wants this?
Yeah, she says that I'm, uh,
bringing down the department
by not practicing,
and that I'm lowering
the prestige of the hospital.
I thought I would
throw her a little bone--
You know what this is?
This is retaliation
for me hiring Wilder
without her sign off,
and now she's putting
the squeeze on you. I'm sorry.
I'm trying to think
of a way to neutralize her,
but I can't--
Yeah, okay, but Max, I, um,
I can't go back
to seeing patients.
I'm nowhere near ready.
Yeah, it's okay.
Take your time.
Okay, thank you.
All right.
Thank you.
Welcome.
Mr. Newbounde.
Hi, you must be Alijah.
I'm Dr. Sharpe.
This is my colleague Dr. Kao.
They say she had
a small stroke,
that maybe it was
because of her sickle cell.
This stroke
may have been small
but the next one may not be.
We are very sorry
to have to tell you this,
but we found a blockage
in your basilar artery,
which supplies blood
to the cerebellum.
This is the area of the brain
that controls your motor skills
and cognitive functions.
Uh, what does that mean?
Alijah's sickle cell anemia
is restricting
the blood flow to her brain.
But with proper testing,
we can prevent another stroke.
Tell me, Mr. Newbounde,
has Alijah ever had
trans-cranial
doppler screenings?
Of course, we relied on them.
I was taking her to get 'em
once a year until last March.
Why did you stop?
The program was discontinued.
It was? Where?
Here.
Hey.
Hey. Where you heading?
OR, to plate a broken bone.
I'll take her.
No, it's okay, I got it.
Uh--
didn't you just lose someone?
I need you prepping
for the M&M.
M&M?
There's nothing to review.
The guy was basically gone
when we got him.
Just let me take care of her.
Prep for the M&M.
Last time I checked,
Dr. Reynolds,
you were still my deputy
and I was still your chair.
Harmony, right?
Dr. Reynolds, do you mind
if I walk with you?
Be my guest.
Um, I need your take
on something.
Every department
has its strengths
and weaknesses, right?
But yours seems
a bit top-heavy.
I beg your pardon?
Well, you and Dr. Baptiste,
both excellent surgeons,
and two of our highest-paid,
and yet,
you often share patients.
Can you explain that?
I mean, is that
really efficient?
It is, if you're trying
to save a patient's life.
Oh, okay.
Well, Dr. Baptiste
had some thoughts on this.
I just wanted
to check in with you.
Oh, you spoke to Baptiste?
I did, yes, this morning.
Well, what did he say?
Oh, I mean,
I can't divulge the contents
of a private conversation
with you.
But I will tell you that
he had some pretty bold ideas
on how to rebalance
your department.
Did he?
Mm-hmm.
And I'm sure you'll
have ideas as well,
so let's set up
a time to chat, yeah?
I know we can cut
the suit to fit.
Right.
I understand, thank you.
Where's Moreland?
Uh, he's waiting
to talk to the police.
Well, he's gonna
talk to me first.
Max, you understand
this isn't his fault, right?
He's one of us. Max--
Where's the dispatch report,
Rob?
It should be
in the ambulance.
Yeah, should be,
but it isn't,
because someone tore it out.
Okay, look, anything
you want from the report,
you can get from 911 dispatch.
I just called 911 dispatch,
and the patient that
he picked up, Mr. Santangelo,
who is now dead,
didn't call 911,
he called
the non-emergency line,
'cause he had a fever,
and his wife was concerned.
The man didn't even
need an ambulance.
That's why you took
this report, isn't it?
You were driving like a madman
with a non-emergent patient,
whom you knew had no business
being in your vehicle!
Keep it.
Or give it to the cops.
I'm sure they'll
want to read it.
.
Even if he was
driving recklessly,
there's no way
they're gonna hang him.
When a cop goes down,
who's the first on the scene?
Paramedics.
The blue line covers them too.
No, he shouldn't need cover.
He's never done anything
like this before.
Well, that may be true,
but he killed a dude
with a runny nose, Laur.
And he almost killed
his partner.
Who's side are you on?
There are no sides.
It's just what happened.
Well, I want to know
why it happened.
Uh, Lauren.
Did you get my message?
Uh, I didn't know
you left me one.
I did. I wanted to thank you.
Mm, for what?
For your donation.
The donation you made to
the Dean's discretionary fund
a few months back?
I came across it
in the financials.
That was very,
very generous of you.
Are--are you not comfortable
discussing this?
No, no, um, I just--
money stuff, I like
to keep things confidential.
Oh, yeah, no, no,
of course, of course.
Yeah, it's a--
it's a family trust,
so you know, we make donations
like this all the time.
It's nothing special.
Oh. Well, if that's the case,
you might consider
a second gift
to the hospital's endowment.
A second, um--
uh, I don't know, uh,
I'd have to talk to my mother
and my sister and--
Mm-hmm.
And the lawyer.
Uh, I don't make
these decisions alone, so.
Is--is Dr. Shinwari involved?
If so, I'd like to extend
my gratitude to her as well.
No.
I mean, she doesn't know
that we do this.
Mm.
And I'd like to
keep it that way.
Gotcha.
Okay, well, have a think
about the endowment.
Your money would go
much further there.
And it wouldn't
have to be a lump sum gift.
We could work out
a quarterly situation.
And Leyla doesn't have
to know about that either.
Dr. Ketner.
Helen. Good morning.
I understand that
we're no longer offering
doppler screenings.
Can you tell me why?
No funding.
Since then?
Since you
reallocated the money.
Since I reallocated it?
In the early days
of the pandemic.
No, no, no.
Listen, it's not possible.
There's no way
that I would cut a vital test.
No one was coming in
for any tests then,
so you asked if we could
move some money around
to treat the effects
of long-term COVID.
But I--I didn't mean--
I didn't realize that it, um,
that it never came back.
A lot of tests
never came back.
Whole departments
But this test
saves lives and...
Yeah. Hey, come in.
Congratulations, Dr. Frome.
I think.
Dr. Fuentes just called.
She wanted us to know
that you are being awarded
this year's NAPA Prize.
Yes! Oh, what?
So it happened. I got it.
I got the award? And she knows.
Yes.
Oh!
Why do you look so excited?
I thought you didn't want
anything to do with
the NAPA people?
I mean, you said
their hearts were...
both: Black and rotten.
Yeah, I know what I said.
But she sounded happy about it?
About the--she was happy
about the prestige of it all?
She did.
In fact, I mean, she suggested
that you make a point
of mentioning the award
to all of your new patients.
Which surprised me,
because I didn't know
you were seeing new patients.
She still wants me
seeing patients?
She wanted me to confirm that
they were on your schedule
for today.
No.
Oh--
oh, God, no.
No. No! No!
That's--
Iggy.
I--my--my--oh,
I can feel my throat
closing up, literally.
Okay, okay.
Now, just--just breathe.
Oh, God.
You are so good with people.
You are so empathetic.
No, no, no, not right now.
I would be damaging
to them, Gladys.
I'm--I'm--I--
watching your shrink
pass out from lack of oxygen,
that's not--
that's not helpful, mm-mm.
Is--
is this still about Chance?
Yeah.
Yes, it's about Chance.
It's about Chance.
It's about everybody.
It's about everyone
who's ever sat on that couch
and made their nightmares mine.
I took them all on
and made them mine.
I took them all on, and I--
I just was starting
to feel like--
I just was starting to have
dreams of my own again,
you know, and I--
and not confuse everything.
Okay.
Yep, Iggy, just breathe.
Yeah.
It's okay.
Mmkay, okay, all right.
Yeah, it's just--okay.
Mm.
So, what do you think
you want to do?
I don't know, I don't know.
Okay.
I don't know. Um, I, uh--
I think, uh...
Resign.
Floyd, you need something?
I'm here to see my patient.
Did you do the work
for your M&M?
Yes, I did.
What have you done
for Ms. Perez?
Nothing, because
she's stable.
For now.
Which, last time I checked,
that was a good thing.
I need to put that plate in.
And I told you not to.
Oh.
She can't breathe.
Collapsed lung and
internal bleeding.
All right,
she needs an OR now.
Dr. Baptiste, Ms. Garcia's
heart rate's plummeting.
Better tend to your patient,
doctor.
It's okay, it's okay.
So what's the emergency?
Mr. Santangelo lived
on the Upper East Side.
What were you doing 40 blocks
outside the hospital
jurisdiction?
Is that why you were
driving so fast,
just to make up the miles?
This is me now, Rob,
not the police.
And you need to tell me
why this happened.
We were ordered
to make the pickup.
What? Ordered by who?
Our battalion chief.
Why?
Why were you driving
1,000 miles an hour
for a man with a fever?
Hey, look--
we were told
to ignore jurisdiction.
Grab any patient we could
anywhere in the city,
then drive bat out of hell
to make the drop
so we can get back out
onto the street
as soon as possible.
That's insane.
Why would he tell you
to do that?
Private ambulance companies
are killing us, Lauren.
This is how you compete.
Your chief, he's done.
It wasn't his idea.
Oh, yeah? Then whose was it?
Dr. Fuentes,
your new medical director.
.
You're coming to me
for money.
Uh, yes, I realize
that we started off
on the wrong foot,
and I am sorry
about that, but--
You thought I was a superfan
trolling the halls.
Yes, well,
obviously, I've been
making tons of mistakes lately,
but I'm here to own them.
I, um--
I cut funding
off the doppler screenings
for our sickle cell patients.
It was the peak of COVID
and we were moving fast--
obviously too fast--and I--
um--
okay, look,
I take every part of my job
incredibly seriously,
but the part that I view
as more than a job,
as, um, as a higher duty,
is taking care of children.
And I have let one down.
In the ICU right now,
I have a patient
who may never walk again,
and she is 14.
She had a stroke, a stroke
that may have been avoided
had I have not
ended the program.
So I have come here
to ask you--
to beg you for the money,
so that I can reinstate
the program,
so this can never happen again.
You know how bad
the financials are, right?
And that's why
the board brought me in.
Yeah.
But I hear you,
and I appreciate
you taking responsibility.
I don't think every program
is worth keeping.
But this one sounds
like it might be.
So I will find a way
to get you that money.
Um--
thank you. Thank you.
I don't have a lot of friends
around here,
and even though you're leaving,
I--I hope
that I can count you as one
until you're out the door.
Absolutely.
Thank you.
Yeah, of course.
So the source of the blood
in her lungs was her leg.
She had a fractured rib.
I fixed that.
Now I'm onto the leg.
She has osteoporotic bones.
That's why there are
two fractures,
and that's why
the screws will never hold,
and why I didn't want you
taking her to the OR.
Which is why
I'm trying something new,
expandible pedicle screws.
They'll never hold
without cement.
Hey, nurse,
could you bring me the cement?
I'm sure your
novel surgical technique
will impress
our new medical director.
As opposed to you
trying to impress her
by sending me to do
a completely unnecessary M&M.
Hope that helps
your rebalancing.
Who don't we do this
together, Dr. Reynolds,
since we're so good at sharing,
and save the rest
of this discussion for later?
Nurse, scalpel, please.
You're not resining.
I am.
I mean, I think I am. I guess.
I don't know, what other--
what other options do I have?
Iggy, we just blew through
all our savings
driving across country,
living in an RV for months.
I know, I know,
and the odds of me
actually getting a job
at any other hospital
where I don't have
to see patients, is
slim to none, at best.
And I'm--
I don't--I mean,
I don't know what to do.
Martin, I'm asking you
to tell me what to do.
I don't know what to do.
Trust your own words,
all right?
All you ever say is
how much you love this place.
I do.
I do love it.
But I can't--I can't--
I can't see patients anymore.
I can't.
Can't now or forever?
I don't know.
I don't know, I don't know.
I don't know the answer
to that question. I--
and I just--
seeing a patient, I just--
I--my heart begins to race,
and my--my palms get sweaty,
and I--
I can't do it. I can't.
I just envision
all of the people
that I'm gonna hurt
because I'm not ready.
And I'm not willing to do that.
Okay.
Resign.
Are--are you sure?
I mean, if you're not
completely on board, I'll--
you know, say the word,
I'll figure it out.
We'll figure it out.
That's what we do.
Hand this in.
What about the money?
Babe, you're going through
something really big.
The money isn't as important.
If we need to move, we'll move.
If the kids
need to start new schools,
they'll adapt.
We'll all adapt,
'cause that's what
families do for each other.
I love you.
Yes.
I told them to drive faster.
Someone died!
What kind of
insane, reckless--
Dr. Bloom, are you aware
that the majority
of paramedics in this city
work for private
ambulance companies?
So what?
I mean, we have a contract
with the fire department.
Which I told them
we'd terminate
unless they got competitive.
So you blackmailed them.
Great.
Max, the private
ambulance companies
all have backroom deals
with the private hospitals.
They are strongly encouraged
to only pick up
insured patients,
the big ticket procedures,
the money makers,
which leaves the uninsured,
the homeless,
and the poor for us.
We are a public hospital!
That desperately
needs money to survive, Max.
So I incentivized the chief
by making him realize
that a win for us
is also a win for him.
Mm, well,
killing our patients
isn't exactly a win.
I am truly sorry about
what happened this morning.
But accidents can happen
at any speed.
So what exactly did you say
to the fire chief?
I mean, how far are they
supposed to just drive around,
just scooping up people
who don't even need them?
They have a daily quota,
and they're incentivized
to meet or exceed it.
You know, the NYPD
tried a quota system
and, uh, it led to
the mass incarceration
of Black and brown people and
nearly tore this city apart.
And I believe you are
out of here in two weeks,
so none of this
is really your problem anymore.
.
No, listen, hey!
Your issue--
In the scrub room.
Sorry, young brother,
but it's my job
to make the hard decisions!
Guys--
My issue is that because
you're threatened
by me and Lyn,
you're trying to edge me
out of my job.
Guys, stop this, now.
And because you're
the woman's new flavor,
you think you can talk down
to me in front of my team?
Floyd is not anybody's
new flavor.
I was making
a medical decision--
Stop it! Both of you!
If you think
yelling our business
all over this hospital
is going to help anything,
you're wrong!
Oh, and now you want to help.
'Cause falling in love
with another man, this man,
was not part of our agreement.
You opened the door, Claude.
You're the one who wanted this!
You're the one who wanted more.
More of you.
I just wanted
to make you happy,
'cause you sure as hell
weren't happy with just me!
That's not true.
That's how it felt.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry for all of this.
As soon as you saw
she was my wife,
you should have declined
the deputy chair.
I broke it off, Claude.
I thought that was the solve.
But I love her.
And I know you do too.
How did we think that
we could just have breakfast
and everything would be cool?
Sure, we could pretend
that it's cool,
but it's not.
Not for me.
Me either.
Same.
I'm sorry
I wasn't upfront day one.
I'm sorry I started something
I couldn't handle.
And I'm sorry
for caring so much
about both of you.
The clients are nervous.
How much are they getting
for their return?
Are they overpaying? You know?
My wife,
she doesn't think about this.
All she cares about is
getting to the theater on time.
And the crazy part is
we've already seen "Hamilton."
I don't get
what the big deal is.
So we're a few minutes late.
So what?
If I don't take care
of the clients,
then I'll be out of a job
and I don't have any money
to buy any damn
"Hamilton" tickets anyway.
Right?
Right.
♪
♪ Walking on the rooftops
♪ Talking of time
♪ With our eyes a-glowing
♪ Like the city lights
♪ She stands on the ledge,
she says, it looks so high ♪
Hey, uh, Louis.
It's Lauren Bloom.
I'm wondering, um,
if we were to make another
donation to New Amsterdam,
a different fund,
how complicated would that be?
Just, uh, give me a call
when you get this, okay?
Thanks.
♪ Feels like
a long way down ♪
♪ Like a long way down
How you doing, baby?
Weird, but okay.
Along with
her physical therapy,
I want you to resume
the regular doppler screenings.
Where?
Here.
We're bringing back
the program.
Um, will you
excuse me one moment?
There she is.
Dr. Sharpe, they shut down
the makeup place.
I had an appointment
for the wig room.
I came all the way
across town for this.
Hang on, everyone, please.
Please, what's happened?
The aesthetics clinic's
been shut down.
Yeah.
Shut down?
The entire wig and makeup
program?
Since when?
Since just now.
They told us to close up and
another clinic was taking over.
What clinic?
Doppler screenings
for sickle cell patients.
♪ Feels like
a long way down ♪
♪ Oh, feels like
Mm, you're right.
I am out of here in two weeks.
But in that time,
I'm not just gonna lay down.
I'm not gonna stop
trying to make things better
for our patients.
I'm stunned.
Trying to compete with
private ambulance companies
is stupid.
It's a losing battle,
and it's a dangerous one.
So I'm starting our own.
I'm sorry, you're what?
I've ordered a fleet
of new ambulances,
which is gonna save a ton
of money in transport fees,
expand our jurisdiction,
and help control the influx
of patients in our hospital.
I did it. It's done.
Good.
I like it.
I'm just pissed
I didn't think of it myself.
It's almost mercenary.
I think I'm starting
to rub off on you.
Not gonna touch that one.
But I'm glad
you like the idea.
Goodnight.
Max.
I heard about
what happened to Georgia,
and I just wanted
to say that I'm so sorry.
That would destroy many people.
And I--
I just wanted to say
that I think it's beautiful
that you found a path forward.
For both yourself
and your daughter.
♪
You brush?
Now, we're gonna rinse.
Good rinse. Whose cup is that?
Luna pup.
Yeah, that's Luna's cup.
Whose cup is that?
Dada pup.
Daddy's cup.
And whose cup is that?
Helen pup.
Yeah, Helen's cup.
Hey, can I ask you something?
Yeah.
I was thinking, because
we're gonna be a family,
maybe we could give
Helen a new name.
You know, a special one.
What do you think?
Because--
'cause it can't be "Mommy."
Why?
Because Mommy's in heaven.
♪
And Helen--
Helen's right here.
Do you know
what they call mommies
in England, where Helen's from?
Yeah.
You do?
"Mum."
You like that name?
Yeah.
Mum.
♪