Mom?
Oh, did I wake you?
What are you doing?
I'm making you breakfast.
Where's the coffee?
How are you feeling?
Sleeping okay?
Like a baby.
No nightmares?
No.
It would only be natural.
Mom... I see worse
stuff at work every day.
Today's the big day, right?
The test?
No. Find out about your job.
Mom, they suspended me.
I might not get my job back.
Those eggs done?
No, still too runny.
I like them runny.
Another couple minutes.
What test?
Medical school
admissions test, Mom.
I thought you gave up on that.
No.
Hmm, big commitment.
Here we go.
Perfect.
Hmm... doctor...
That would be something.
I could do it.
I know you could.
I could.
I said so.
Why do you always do that?
Do what?
Make me feel
like I'm incapable, stupid.
I said I thought
you could do it.
I just wish that for once
you would believe in me.
I believe in you.
You're always criticizing,
belittling, making me feel
like I can't do anything.
That's not true.
Why didn't you ever tell me
I could be a lawyer or a
pilot or a damn astronaut?!
You wanted to be an astronaut?
No, but I wanted
you to tell me I could.
Fine. Go be an astronaut.
I'm your mother.
I love you, whoever you are...
doctor, nurse, housewife...
Oh, right... housewife.
You hold you back, not me.
You're the one that always
quits everything,
always frightened that
you're not good enough.
I finish things.
Ballet, cheerleading,
uh... the flute.
I was 13.
Business school...
your own wedding.
I finished nursing
school, didn't I?
Right.
Exactly.
You've got a great
job you're good at,
so why is the grass
suddenly greener?
You have a good life.
I'm proud of you.
Why aren't you
proud of yourself?
Carla! Carla!
Hey, Carla.
I was coming to see you.
I didn't know you had
to be to work this early.
I don't.
Look, uh...
Carla, I'm sorry
I haven't called.
This... lot of stuff came up.
Uh-huh.
I just had a lot of stuff
going on, you know?
I had minor surgery
and all this other...
Sorry to hear that.
Are you okay?
Yeah, it was just my appendix.
I mean, I'm still a
little sore, but I'm okay.
How about you? You okay?
Peter, what do you want?
Well, we need to talk.
Uh-uh.
I told you that I was
pregnant weeks ago, okay?
Then nothing... no phone calls,
no coming by to
see how I was doing.
Silence.
I got the point.
It's cool, I got it.
Look, I wasn't trying
to make a point.
Look...
Carla...
I realize there's going
to be a baby here.
He's going to be as
much my responsibility
as he is yours.
I just needed some time
to think about this thing.
I mean, no, it's not the
way I would've planned it,
but I'm not going to let you
go through this
thing by yourself.
You going to marry me, Peter?
That's not what I'm saying.
So what are you saying? What?
You're going to stop
by every so often
and change a few diapers,
bounce the baby on your knee
for a couple of Kodak moments?
The child's going to
need a good school,
a nice place to live.
And you're saying I can't
provide those things?
I'm saying I can help, Carla.
Money.
So that is what
this is all about.
Yeah, that, among other things.
The child's going to
need a man in his life.
Well, who says that this baby
will not have a man in his life?
So what are you saying?
You seeing somebody else?
Peter, you know, you and I...
We've known each
other for a very long time.
I never expected
you to marry me.
I never expected a
damn thing from you.
You care about you.
And that is the way
it has always been.
But, you know, it's
comforting, really.
It's one of the few
constants in my life.
You don't have to
worry about it, Peter.
This baby's going to be fine.
Plenty to eat, nice clothes,
good man around to call Daddy.
I'm going to take
care of all those things.
You go back to
worrying about yourself,
because that's what you do best.
Dr. Benton! First day back, huh?
How's the incision
healing? Any discharge?
It's fine, Carter.
You know, you really
shouldn't be back on your feet
for extended
periods of time yet.
Did you finish that whole
course of antibiotics?
You don't want to
develop resistance.
Peter, how's the scar?
Is it itchy yet?
I made a Rocky-Davis incision,
running stitch,
McBurney's point.
You know, when the
hair starts to grow back,
that's when the
itching gets worse.
You going to show
us your scar, Peter?
Come on, let's see.
Yeah, come on,
let's take a look.
I did it one-handed, you know.
Come on, Carter, stop.
Carter, Carter!
You know, that's really a shame,
because it's a great job.
Good thing I took pictures, huh?
What is that, a mole?
Yeah, a big one, too.
Good morning, everybody.
What are you doing?
Ooh, yikes, what is that?!
That's Benton's appendix
in a jar on my mantel.
Wow! They really
shaved him good.
Somebody got carried away.
Dr. Carter, you're
still backed up.
Okay, on my way.
Carter looks beat.
Yeah, he was on
again last night.
Surgical interns
are still covering
all Dr. Gant's shifts.
What is that, like
a 90-hour week?
More like 95.
Thank God for Pediatrics.
Jerry, what is that all about?
Oh, nurses and management
are still at the table.
Their contract
expires at midnight.
Mark, paramedics are pulling
up with a 35-year-old female...
Respiratory failure.
Duty calls.
Hey, lunch?
Only if you're buying.
Carol finds out today, right?
Yeah, the investigation is done,
and nursing has the report.
You've seen it?
No, and I haven't heard anything
on the grapevine either.
How's she doing? She okay?
Yeah, she claims she's fine.
Okay, thanks. Nothing yet.
They're still at it.
Oh, man, I do not want
to walk a picket line.
Not in February,
that's for sure.
Hey, we stand firm.
That's easy for you to say.
You've got a husband with a job.
Believe me, they'll settle.
They can't run this
place without us.
That's what the air
traffic controllers said
before they started
parking cars for a living.
One, two, three.
37-year-old Down's patient.
Her mother found her in
bed in respiratory distress.
Resps shallow at 30.
BP's 100/50.
Mom said she had
a respiratory infection
a couple of weeks ago,
never fully recovered.
Where's the mother now?
She went to gather
up some of her stuff.
Said she'd follow in her car.
Two-plus pitting edema.
Hi, Louise.
I'm Dr. Greene.
You having a little
trouble breathing?
Mm-hmm.
We'll make you
feel better, okay?
She's sweet,
scared, held my hand
all the way over.
Louise, can you tell
me what day it is?
No, you can't tell me?
No. Okay.
Dr. Doyle, why don't
you take a listen,
tell me what you hear?
Chuny, come hold Louise's hand.
You bet.
CBC lytes, EKG, chest film,
O2, six liters by mask.
Hi, Louise.
My name's Chuny.
S3 gallop and mitral regurg.
Indicating?
Possible cardiomyopathy,
probably from that viral infection.
Hey, Mark, I think she's
trying to say something.
Hey, Louise.
Louise, you need something?
Huh?
Louise, what's wrong?
Where's my mom?
Your mom?
Your mom
is coming real soon, okay?
Don't you worry.
So you can just relax.
You're doing great.
Okay?
Human Resources, Carol,
reviewed your incident report
in the ER procedures,
and they passed their
recommendations,
along with mine, on to
the Safety Committee.
And?
And they agreed with
us... That your mistake
was a result of systems problems
and not of negligence.
There will be a written warning
placed in your
file for one year,
and the three weeks you
missed due to your suspension
will be deducted from
your vacation time.
And that's it?
You preferred a public flogging?
You can start back today.
You don't have
to start back today.
No, thanks, I'm okay.
I, uh... I'd better
get back to work.
La Bohème? Don't say it
like it's a new strain
of resistant bacteria.
What is it, like
five hours long?
Forget it, really. I wouldn't
take you now if you begged me.
It's just that I've never
been much of an opera fan.
Now, if you had
Marcus Roberts tickets,
I would be there in a flash.
I got it, Greg.
You don't want to go, fine.
Is La Bohème the
one where they, like,
lop off all the nuns'
heads at the end?
It's set in Paris.
They're star-crossed
lovers and artists.
Artists?
Jeanie, hang on a
second. Look, I'm sorry.
If you really want
to go... we'll go.
Don't do me any favors, Greg.
I-I'd love to go.
What time's it start?
I just thought we
could do something
spontaneous,
something romantic, fun.
Opera?
I have to get
back to my patient.
Jeanie, let's hang
out anyway, okay?
Look, we'll order take-out.
The Bulls/Warriors
game is on channel nine...
You think you're
charming, but you aren't.
Good-bye, Greg.
Lunch, then?
At least let me buy you lunch.
Hey, Jeanie?!
That's one big, boggy heart.
God, it's taking up
most of her chest.
EKG shows ST and T
wave changes and PVCs.
What do you want to do?
Get an echo and page Cardiology.
Okay.
Mark, Louise's mother's here.
Hi, Mrs. Cupertino.
I'm Dr. Mark Greene.
How's Louise?
Not good.
Her heart isn't pumping well,
and her lungs
are filling with fluid.
Can I say hello?
Yeah, sure.
Hello, Louise.
It's Mommy.
Hi, Mommy.
You okay, baby?
You're not scared, are you?
Oh, baby...
I, uh... I brought
some of her things,
uh... just to make
her feel more at home.
I'll just put this quilt on her,
make sure she's good and warm.
Mrs. Cupertino,
can I speak to you for a minute?
She had trouble
understanding me earlier.
Can she communicate?
Oh, yes.
She likes to talk.
Is she suffering from any
dementia or Alzheimer's?
No, no, she's a good girl.
Okay.
Echo's on its way.
Is she competent to make
her own medical decisions?
No, I'm her guardian.
Louise can't make
decisions on her own.
You are aware that
Louise's condition
is very serious.
I'm worried that Louise
may need a heart transplant.
Is she already on
the UNOS waiting list?
The list? No.
She's not?
They wouldn't do it.
Wouldn't do what?
Put her on the list.
They wouldn't put Louise
on the heart transplant list?
No. Why not?
My daughter is mentally
retarded, Doctor.
Peter, sorry to
keep you waiting.
Welcome back.
Thanks.
We've missed you.
I was surprised
not to see my name
on today's schedule anywhere.
How are you feeling?
Well rested?
Yeah.
And mentally?
Feeling sharp?
No postoperative depression?
No.
No depression of any kind?
Dr. Hicks, if you're asking
if I can perform my
duties adequately, I can.
I'm asking how you are, Peter.
I'm fine.
Okay, then.
Let's see what we've got.
There's two portacaths,
a circumcision
and a nevus removal.
A mole?
UNOS can't refuse
to put her on the list
just because she has Down's.
I'm sure there are other
mitigating circumstances.
She's a retard, so
why bother, right?
Dr. Kayson, do
you know Dr. Doyle?
Echo shows left
ventricular dilatation
with an ejection
fraction of 18%.
There are also signs of
wall motion abnormality.
I'm worried about her breathing.
We've given her 40 Lasix,
and she's still struggling.
I'd like to try a vasodilator.
Sure, do whatever you
can to make her comfortable
before you release her.
Release her?
Louise will be much happier
at home with her mother.
She needs a heart
transplant, right?
That would be the standard
operative course, yes.
Louise's mother told us
that she's not on
the transplant list.
That's correct.
UNOS can't refuse
to put a dying patient
on the list because of
a congenital birth defect.
UNOS didn't refuse
to put her on the list.
We did.
Cardiology?
Hospital Transplant Committee.
She was evaluated
and we chose not to
submit her name to UNOS.
That's a death sentence.
She's a 37-year-old
Down's patient.
She's lucky to have lived
this long.
Down's patients can
live into their 60s easy.
That's extremely rare.
What are you, an intern?
First-year resident, yes.
Why don't we just step in here?
Dr. Kayson,
Dr. Doyle, I think
is just expressing a frustration
that we probably all feel.
It seems that Louise would
be an obvious candidate
for the UNOS transplant list.
I'm a cardiologist.
I'd like nothing better than
to give her a new heart.
If you have a problem
with the decision,
take it up with the
rest of the committee.
Short of that...
send her home.
Nice guy.
Yeah.
Carol? You back?
Thank you, Jesus.
Hey, y'all, Carol's back.
Carol!
You're back.
Yeah, starting now.
Man, did we miss you.
We didn't think we
were going to make it.
Hi.
They dock your pay?
No, just some vacation time.
It's been a disaster
around here without you.
A complete zoo.
Hey, I didn't do that bad a job.
Oh, no, girlfriend, you
did worse than bad.
If you need to call a
union meeting, Haleh,
do it after work, please.
No union... Carol's back.
Oh, thank God.
We'll talk to you at lunch.
Yeah, we'll catch
up later, girl.
See you.
We're glad to have you back.
Thank you.
You okay?
Yeah, you know,
I'm sorry to disappoint
everyone's expectations,
but I'm fine.
Oh, it started a few
hours ago after breakfast.
It's a sharp pain?
No, sort of all over.
I just started my morning walk.
Any recent illness?
I take digoxin
for atrial fibril...
I never say that word.
Fibrillation?
Anything else?
No.
What did you have for
breakfast this morning?
Oh, the usual...
Three fried eggs,
bacon, glass of buttermilk,
toast and jam.
Oh, the American Heart
Association breakfast.
Don't lecture me, Doctor.
My mother had the
exact same breakfast
every day of her life.
Died last year at 96.
Car accident.
Vitals?
130/90.
Heart rate 110, resp 24.
Did Dr. Weaver get a CBC?
Yep, crit's 53,
white count's 12.2.
You drinking enough
fluids, Mrs. Jarnowski?
Is that what's wrong with me?
It's too early to tell.
Um... chest film?
Not back yet.
Okay, I'm going to call for
another surgical colleague
to come down and take a look.
Her breathing's improved.
Hi, Louise.
You feeling better?
For you.
Oh...
She likes to share.
Malibu Barbie was
my favorite, too.
I was kind of partial to Ken.
Ken?
You don't like Ken?
Too pretty.
I'm with you,
Louise... Ken's trouble.
Louise, can you
hold on to her for me
while I do my work?
Okay.
Thanks.
She misses her friends.
Since she got sick
and had to move
back into the house,
it's been hard for her.
She had her own place?
Uh-huh, an apartment
above the garage,
and she had a job at the Jewel
helping people
with their groceries.
Father even let her
be an altar girl at the church.
Everybody loves Louise.
Excuse me, Dr. Greene...
got that list from upstairs.
Thanks.
Transplant Committee?
Yeah.
Who are the bastards?
Excuse us.
Doctor, your attitude
can get in the way
of achieving your goals.
What? You're not
going to vote for me
for Homecoming Queen this year?
Like that, you mean?
Recognize any names?
One.
Hey.
The vanquished
return victorious.
Hi, Doug. You miss me?
You have no idea.
I hear they clipped you
for some vacation time.
I never take it anyway.
I have a couple
of years saved up.
This place is a mess.
How you doing?
No complaints.
Today's the 20th, isn't it?
I think so.
MCATs are this
afternoon, aren't they?
You going?
Got to work.
With all that saved-up
vacation time?
You know, it was a stupid idea.
I mean, four years
of med school,
if I ever get in,
all that debt.
I'd be about 50 by
the time I got out.
What's the point?
Well, I could bring you coffee
in the middle of the
night to the med library,
and I could teach
you how to cheat
on the biochem exams.
Doug, they need
you upstairs in Pedes.
Mm-hmm, okay.
Think about it.
Carter, where you been?
Getting some food.
You don't have a
spoon on you, do you?
On me? No. Anspaugh's
in with your patient.
Anspaugh? Why?
Said you paged him.
No, no. I paged Dr. Hicks.
Well, you got Anspaugh,
and he dragged down
all the surgical rounds...
What do you hear, Edson?
Rales at the base of the lungs.
Dr. Anspaugh, I'm sorry to have
dragged you all the way down here.
I actually called Dr. Hicks
just for a consult.
Dr. Hicks is in surgery,
and we were on the prowl
for an interesting
teaching case.
I heard that you had
a surgical abdomen.
Yes, at least
that's my suspicion.
Pain vague and diffuse,
very little tenderness
to palpation.
The, uh... chest films
show bi-basilar effusions.
Rales heard on auscultation.
Would you consider this
a surgical patient, Dr. Edson?
No, I'd bet on CHF.
Yeah, yeah, but, uh...
I was more concerned
with... with the CBC.
Previously diagnosed
atrial fibrillation?
Her diet?
I'd assume that she, uh...
went into fib or
ate a salty meal
and that was enough
to push her into
congestive heart failure
as demonstrated by the
rales and chest effusions.
The diffuse abdominal pain
is probably due to congestion
in the liver, secondary to CHF.
In other words, boys and girls,
congestive heart
failure, secondary to a-fib.
Wouldn't you agree, Dr. Carter?
Yeah, yeah, that
sounds about right.
Is Dr. Pomerantz available?
And you are?
Mark Greene from the ER.
She knows you?
Yeah, Steph, I do.
It's okay. Hi.
Hi. You got a minute?
Sure.
Just move those.
Put them anywhere.
What can I do for you?
You're on the committee
that evaluates prospective
transplant patients?
Yeah.
I have a patient dying
downstairs... Louise Cupertino.
Dr. Kayson tells me
that she was denied
access to the UNOS list.
Yeah.
Kayson says he wanted to do it,
so it doesn't sound
like she was excluded
for medical reasons.
What do you want, Mark?
There are five people
on the committee.
Kayson's already a "yes."
If I can get you and one
other person to sign on,
Louise can get a new heart.
Our decisions have
to be unanimous.
But I'm the one that
turned Louise down.
Why?
Do you know how many
people die each year
because an organ doesn't
become available for transplant?
3,500.
She had a job, an apartment,
a mother who loves her.
Is her life somehow
less valuable
than a businessman
with a wife and kids
and a two-pack-a-day
cigarette habit?
Don't patronize me, Mark.
I agonized over this.
Louise has an IQ of 40.
She can't comprehend
the surgical risks.
Yes, she had a job, sure,
but she was always late.
Do you know why?
Because she doesn't
know how to tell time.
How is she going to
adhere to the rigors
of the posttransplant regime?
Her mother will make
sure she gets her meds,
get her where she needs to go.
She's a 120-pound
eight-year-old, Mark.
We do the operation, and
assuming she doesn't die
for lack of postoperative care,
she's in a state
home in two years,
and her mother is adamant
she not end up in a home.
Those are all bureaucratic
perfectly logical reasons
we give ourselves so
that we can sleep at night.
Louise can make people smile.
She can laugh, cry,
touch or hold someone.
I have an eight-year-old,
and if she never
grew a day older,
I would still cherish every
moment we spent together.
It's not our place to decide
whether Louise lives or dies.
She has as much right to
be here as you do or I do.
Nina, don't let her die.
I'm freezing.
I thought you liked picnics.
I love picnics.
I'm just not used to
breathing on my sandwich
to try and thaw it
out so I can eat it.
Where's your sense
of spontaneity?
This isn't what I meant.
Your sense of romance?
The dip is frozen solid.
It's pâté.
It's a brick.
Okay, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
I was wrong.
You're very romantic.
You're very spontaneous,
and you're very crazy.
So please put your parka
on before you freeze to death.
I'm fine.
You can't be fine. It's
ten degrees out here.
I think we should
start sleeping together.
What?
Sex.
I think we should have some.
In fact, I think we
should have a lot.
Are you sure?
Hell, yeah, I'm sure.
This isn't a joke, Greg.
No, it isn't.
Jeanie Boulet...
would you please sleep with me?
Hi. How's she doing?
Her breathing's worse.
The resp's up to 36.
How's the pain?
It hurts.
It's bad.
Hi. Who are you?
Her daughter, Yolanda.
She's so stoic,
if she says it hurts,
it must be awful.
Okay, let's take a look.
Oh, God!
Ooh.
Uh... okay.
I need to order a repeat
CBC and a blood gas.
You want me to page
Dr. Anspaugh again?
No. God, no.
Uh, call Dr. Hicks.
Don't page her... call her...
And when you get
her on the phone,
tell her that I need her
down here right away.
My fiancée's been
begging me for years
to get this thing taken off.
Betadine.
I'm not very religious,
but her family...
Oh, boy!
They wouldn't even
consider letting us get married
if I didn't convert.
Whoa!
Whoa.
Stuff's cold.
I probably wouldn't
have started dating her
if I'd known this was
going to be part of the deal.
Lidocaine. You'll
feel a small prick
in the area that I'm
going to anesthetize.
Please, do not move.
Oh, good, you
haven't started yet.
I have three eager students
visiting today from Evanston.
I thought they might
enjoy watching you
perform a circumcision.
Don't mind us, sir.
I'm converting to
Judaism for my fiancée.
She must be quite a girl.
Dr. Hicks, you've got a
phone call from the ER.
Peter, make them
feel welcome.
You're in very capable hands.
Number 15 blade.
I'm Dr. Ross from the ER.
Someone page me?
I paged you.
Hi. Samantha Ewing.
I got a CF kid up here.
Jad Heuston. Know him?
Yeah.
He's been on respirator
last couple of weeks
at his mother's request.
I know. I'm the one
who put him on it.
Yeah, well, today's
his 18th birthday,
and he wants off.
So why page me?
He wants you to
be the one to do it.
Hi, Norma. Hi, Katy.
Happy birthday, Jad.
Jad's first act as an adult
was to sign a DNR
and demand we remove
him from the respirator.
I've explained the
dangers to him,
but he's insistent.
You still sure?
I've explained to him
that with the advanced
nature of his disease
and the number of weeks he's
been dependent on the machine,
he's unlikely to live more
than a couple of minutes.
I was hoping you
might talk him out of it.
What's his tidal volume?
350. PCO2 38,
pO2 120.
This is what you really want?
Okay, then.
You said your good-byes?
Yes.
Okay.
All right, buddy.
You know the drill, right?
I'm going to count to three.
And you're going to
take a deep breath,
and you're going to blow
out while I pull, all right?
Can you give me a hand
with this, please?
I love you.
All right, here we go, buddy.
Okay, on three.
Ready?
One, two,
three... blow!
Blow, blow, blow.
Okay.
Is he going to be okay?
Good afternoon, Doctor.
What could be so important
to call me off
the surgical floor?
64-year-old woman,
onset of abdominal
pain five hours ago.
Pain was vague and diffuse.
Belly wasn't too tender.
She takes Digoxin
for a previously
diagnosed atrial fib.
Rales, chest X ray
show basilar
infiltrates bilaterally.
Dr. Anspaugh came
down for a consult,
and he diagnosed
congestive heart failure
with diffuse abdominal pain
due to congestion of the liver
secondary to the CHF.
We gave her 40 of Lasix.
That's a good story.
What's the problem?
I think Dr. Anspaugh's wrong.
Page Dr. Anspaugh, please.
I think he's still eating
lunch in the lounge.
Get him quickly.
You have a better story?
Mm-hmm. Her abdominal
pain is worsening.
Her resps are up to
39, and she's acidotic.
When she came in
here, she was dehydrated,
so why was there
fluid on her lungs?
And the pain isn't
really explained
by congestive heart failure.
It doesn't all add up.
And what is your thinking?
I'm thinking that
she's suffering
from atrial fibrillation,
which puts her at risk
for developing clots.
And she threw an embolus,
and it's blocking
her small valve.
What the hell is
going on in here?
Dr. Carter believes you have
diagnosed this patient incorrectly.
He what?
Her pain is worsening,
her resps are up to
39, and she's acidotic.
CHF made sense at the time,
but I believe she has
ischemic small bowel disease,
secondary to an embolism
in the mesenteric artery.
Pretty good story,
don't you think?
Damn it!
I diuresed her.
All right, normal saline,
200 cc's per hour.
Call the OR, book a room.
We're moving her right now.
What's happening?
Your mother needs
immediate surgical attention.
An operation?
Yes, but she's going
to be just fine.
Dr. Anspaugh, can I assist?
Assist? You're going to do it.
Perform an embolectomy?
You're damn right.
You're the only one
around here today
that seems to know
what the hell they're doing.
It's going to fall.
It's not.
Yes, it is.
No, it's not.
Hmm.
She looks like
she's feeling better.
Yeah. She ate a little bit.
Seems to be breathing okay.
Who's her friend?
That's my brother.
I had my mom bring him down.
I figured Louise could
use some company.
Hey, Jimmy.
Say hi to Dr. Greene.
That's my boss.
Hey, Dr. Greene.
Hi, Jimmy. How are you?
What'd they say?
Good.
Come here.
Psych feels that she's incapable
of handling the post-op regime,
and they don't think
the mother's going to
be around long enough
to get her through it.
That's a lot of crap.
She could go to a group home.
Jimmy takes classes
out at Glenkirk, and they
have a great program.
Mom doesn't want her in a home,
and she has guardianship.
I've called Loyola and Rush.
They both have
transplant centers.
Maybe we can get
them to get her on the list.
Mark?
Dr. Doyle, this is
Dr. Pomerantz from Psych.
She's the one who
evaluated Louise.
Hi, Louise. Hi.
How are you doing?
Mrs. Cupertino.
She's doing better.
She's out of heart failure.
You need to fill this out.
What is it?
Transplant Candidate
Registration Form.
I can't get her on
the network without it.
Kayson filled out most of it,
but I need today's history
so that I can rank her.
So you have to
get this back to me
as soon as you can, okay?
Nice meeting you, Doctor.
Nina?
Thank you.
Jad... why don't
you come and go?
You take off during the day.
You do whatever
the hell you want to do
and you come back at night.
We hook you up
with I.V. antibiotics.
We get PT to pound
your chest in the morning.
No, thanks.
You'd be a lot more comfortable.
You might even...
you know, squeak out
a couple extra
weeks out of this thing.
I said, no, thanks.
All right.
This is my beeper number.
That is my home number.
You call me anytime,
day or night, all right?
Let's go.
Thanks.
Where are you going?
Anywhere but here.
Whoa!
Sorry, Dr. Ross.
I raided the cafeteria.
Bought every piece
of cake they had.
Ladies, here's your cake!
What's going on?
The nurses got
their new contracts.
Did they get everything
they asked for?
Current employees are protected,
but the hospital won the
right to replace existing RNs
with unlicensed
technicians through attrition.
Technicians?
It's the wave of the
future, I'm afraid.
Come on, Doctor, dance.
No. No, thank you.
I'll get the next song.
Have you seen Carol?
Hathaway?
She changed her mind
about working today.
Went home before lunch.
I'm starving. Want
a piece of cake?
No, thanks.
Hey.
I just dropped off
all the paperwork
with Nina Pomerantz.
Louise should be on the
transplant list tomorrow.
All we have to do
is wait and hope.
Where's your brother?
In the lounge, watching TV.
She won't sign the release.
Louise's mother...
She won't sign the
surgical release.
Kayson was just down here.
She doesn't want Louise
to have the transplant.
Kayson explained to her
that Louise will die
without the operation?
Twice. Then I tried.
She wants to take her home.
Ms. Cupertino...
you don't want Louise
to have the operation?
I was, uh... 41
when Louise was born,
and I knew right away
that something was wrong.
I couldn't see Louise,
but I could see the doctor.
He was frowning and
snapping his fingers
over the little bassinet.
And, uh... they took her away
before I ever got a
chance to see her,
and I thought maybe she'd died.
Maybe that umbilical
cord had gotten wrapped
around her neck.
Nobody told me
anything, and then...
then they put me in another room
with mothers with their babies,
and I waited there for hours
until the doctor finally
came back and...
he looked very sad.
And he told me
Louise was Mongoloid.
And he said that
I should put her
in a state hospital and
never ever see her again.
She will die
if she doesn't
have this operation.
We all die, Doctor.
Louise has been
the light of my
life for 37 years.
God blessed me with
this... this wonderful girl,
and I wouldn't change a thing.
I'm not going to be
here much longer, and...
I'm her whole life, just as
she's always been mine.
There are group homes...
Places where she
can make friends,
enjoy life, even if it's
only for a few more years.
I went to a home 20 years
ago when my husband died
and I was afraid that if
something happened to me,
who would... who would
take care of Louise.
And there were women
there like her with Down's...
wandering around half naked.
They didn't even
know their own names.
I couldn't put Louise
in a place like that.
You want to save people, Doctor?
If my daughter dies, you lose.
But I'm not afraid of death.
Jesus is there waiting for us
to hold us and
bring us into the light,
to show us the
kingdom of Heaven.
And if Louise dies before I do,
I know where I'll see her next,
with angels where she belongs,
because she's an angel...
my angel.
Something new?
Mesenteric embolectomy.
Who's doing it?
Dr. Carter.
Dr. Carter?
Just rolled the woman into 3.
Sweet God in Heaven,
I hope somebody's helping him.
We're putting in a
portacath... a catheter used
to deliver chemotherapy.
Should you pursue
a career in surgery,
you'll perform this
procedure dozens of times
in your first year of residency.
And this can be done
in the patient's room,
but you need to check
the position of the catheter
with the fluoroscope.
Does everyone know
what a fluoroscope is?
This is a fluoroscope.
Dr. Benton, can I steal Debbie?
We can use her in OR 3.
What's going on?
Dr. Carter's performing
a mesenteric embolectomy.
By himself?
Anspaugh and
Hicks are supervising.
What's the score?
Bulls are down by one.
Oh, that was a nice shot.
So I let a kid with CF
leave the hospital today.
He's 18 years old.
Went off to die
with his girlfriend.
Didn't want any of my help.
Is there anything you
could have done for him?
No, not really.
I spent the day
trying to get a CHF
patient with Down's
on the UNOS list
for a heart transplant.
Any luck?
Mother wouldn't sign
the surgical release.
Fine couple of
doctors we are, huh?
Remember when we were
going to change the world?
No, I was always
in it for the money.
All right.
I'll see you later.
You want to grab a pizza?
No, I can't.
I got to be someplace.
Anybody I know?
No, just helping
out an old friend.
See ya.
Hi.
Are you ready to go?
Go where?
Dinner at Morton's
and then La Bohème.
I already told Kerry
that we couldn't
use the tickets.
I told her you were wrong.
But I'm not dressed.
We'll stop by your place.
We'll be late.
If we miss a little bit,
you can tell me what happened.
What about the basketball game?
Taping it.
You know, Greg,
you don't have to
prove anything to me.
I don't?
I mean, this has
all been pretty fast.
You know, we can slow it
down, make sure it's right.
So this means
we don't have to go
to the opera.
No, seriously.
Can we just slow it down?
Sure.
Okay.
Hey. What are you doing here?
Waiting for you.
You been waiting long?
Uh... a while.
Ah.
So you took it, didn't you?
Ha-ha, yeah, I did.
And?
Well, I knew a lot more
than I thought I would.
There were a lot of
people taking it... kids.
I felt about a
hundred years old.
They all seemed so
confident and smart.
I guessed a lot.
I bet you did great.
Thanks.
Was your day okay?
Oh, you know...
just saving lives, as usual.
Have you seen my mom
lurking around here at all?
No, I banged on the door,
and nobody answered, so...
Well, you want to come in?
I'll make you some
coffee, burn some eggs.
No, I can't.
I'm up early. I'm
going to go home.
Okay.
All right.
See you tomorrow, then.
Yeah.
Doug?
Mm-hmm?
I know everyone's
worried about me,
but I'm fine.
I mean, I was
scared in that store,
but I'm okay now.
So why'd you go
ahead and take it?
The MCATs?
Mm-hmm.
For me.
Just wanted to see
if I was good enough.
You are.
I love this place.
You should.
You're a wonderful surgeon.
You belong here.
You know, you were
right this morning.
I haven't slept much
the last few months
since Gant's dying.
And before that, me
almost killing that baby
and then Keaton not
recommending me, and...
Six months ago, I
thought I was invincible.
And now I don't even...
I don't even know.
I guess life isn't working out
the way I thought it would, huh?
You're not responsible
for Dr. Gant's death, Peter.
Yeah, but I could
have stopped it, maybe.
You know, told him
he was doing well...
Encouraged him.
You know, Dr. Hicks,
I wish I could tell you
that it was all intentional...
That it was a part
of some master plan
that I had going on, but...
truthfully, I never even
thought about Gant.
I mean, he was just an intern,
and I was more involved
with my career, my... ambitions.
We all have to find
our own way, Peter.
You're not invincible.
You're a young doctor,
learning, making mistakes,
saving lives.
It takes a lifetime.
You just have to have faith.
Go home.
You've got a busy day tomorrow.
More circumcisions
and portacaths?
No, I've signed you up
for a lap chole at 6:00
And I'd appreciate
if you'd assist me
on a splenectomy at 11:00.
Thank you, Dr. Hicks.
You're welcome, Peter.
See you in the morning.