Previously, on
"The Resident"...
Governor Betz has got to be
feeling the pressure
to meet with you.
- So far, no word.
- You're really worried about this.
- You talked to your sister?
- You're worried?
- A little.
- She wanted this. She chose it.
Did she understand
what she was choosing?
- Want to dance?
- Yeah.
I'm grateful
you're always there
for both of us.
I love you guys.
Come and meet my hospice nurse.
This is Jana ya.
She takes care
of dying folk like me.
I'm not just here
for your mother.
I'm here for you, too.
Which do you think is better...
Side-by-side stroller
or front-to-back
Splash Mountain style?
Side-to-side doesn't come
in fire engine red,
and I'm not about to be
strolling through Piedmont Park
in pumpkin spice orange.
Is the stroller for you,
or is it for the twins?
Hey, if I'm spending what I'm
spending on a glorified wagon,
don't I deserve the color
of my choosing?
Ah.
This next chapter looks good
on you, AJ.
Thank you, my brother.
And what about
your next chapter?
What's the status
with you and Cade?
We're having fun.
She's... really great.
Hmm.
You know, it's funny.
I thought you and Billie
would end up together.
But I adjusted
and I told myself I was wrong.
But then I saw you and Billie
dancing at the wedding.
Cade wanted
to be at the wedding.
- She just had to work.
- Ah.
Yeah, that explains everything.
I've practiced medicine
in many places,
but never in a place like this.
Closest I got was residency.
Our ER had a jail ward.
Challenging, pretty rewarding.
Hey.
Jana ya.
- Hey.
- Oh.
Thank you so much
for agreeing to see Bobby.
You have no idea
how much this means to me.
They aren't taking
his symptoms seriously,
and I had nowhere else to turn.
Well, prison clinics are
notoriously short-staffed,
and sadly,
the people they house...
They aren't top priority.
What kind of symptoms
is he having?
Well, he was in terrible pain
during visiting hours.
They won't let me examine him,
so I don't know what's going on.
How come they won't let you
- help your own brother?
- Only outside
specialists like you guys
are allowed to.
And just so you know,
Bobby was convicted
of something that he didn't do.
Now he's alone on death row.
He doesn't deserve this.
Yeah. We will make sure
that Bobby gets the care
he needs, right?
We're gonna figure out
what's going on.
Thank you.
Once they're asleep,
go for a walk
or take that yoga class
in the park.
I know, Padma,
but that's why AJ hired Serena,
so you can have time
for yourself.
All right, okay.
I'll talk to you later. Bye.
Still doesn't want to let them
out of her sight?
Apparently not.
Doesn't she trust
the new babysitter?
No, it's more than that.
She can't relax with them
or without them.
I wish she wasn't so alone.
AJ's been amazing,
but at the end of the day
they're not a couple, you know?
Look, Padma is strong.
Having two kids is a lot.
She just needs some time.
She's going to be okay.
- I know, let's hope.
- All right?
Everyone looks amazing.
Such a beautiful wedding.
Not gonna lie,
you really missed out.
Who's that?
That is Bell's stepson Jake.
He's awesome.
He's a plastic surgeon,
has an amazing voice.
He asked me to accompany him,
but, uh,
I just didn't feel like it.
- Right.
- No, I didn't.
Aw, look at their dresses.
They're so adorable.
Mm-hmm.
That is not what it looks like.
Everyone was dancing together.
Hell, I also danced with Conrad.
And he looked at you like that?
Mm-hmm.
I've known Bobby for ten years.
He's one of my favorites.
We play hoops, lift weights.
He's always asking me
about my kids,
telling me the crazy things
he learns about
in those books he reads.
But he also killed a woman
for her wallet.
Smashed her with a brick
until her brain exploded.
Everyone in here deserves
decent medical care.
So do your best in ten minutes.
Hey, Bobby,
you've got visitors.
I'm Dr. Austin,
and this here is Dr. Hawkins.
We're here to examine you.
I've examined him,
I know what's wrong.
He's got a case
of "desperate for a field trip."
Jana ya asked us to see you.
Hey, man, your sister
was my rock
when my mother was dying.
She was our hospice nurse.
And I'm telling you,
I don't know
how I would have managed
without her.
You and me both.
She's taken care of me
my entire life.
Now she's stuck
visiting me here.
People cut her when they hear
her brother's a killer.
Her reward for being the only
one left who believes in me.
What the...?
Grand mal seizure.
Protect his airway.
You, call 911, now!
I want to believe Governor Betz
called this private meeting
because he's ready to listen.
What he's thinking about is his
rich donors who want a tax cut.
Randolph, we're not gonna get
anywhere by attacking him.
- He holds the power over Chastain's future.
- Okay.
If we do this right,
we enter as enemies
and leave with the governor
on our side.
- Let me do the talking.
- Okay.
All you see here is
the CEO's arm candy.
The intense pain comes and goes.
So you're on vacation?
The trip of a lifetime.
We saved our money for ages
so we could take a year off
from the Tate.
- That's where we work.
- And travel the world.
Camping out, cheap hostels,
- railway passes made it all possible.
- Yeah.
So when did
your stomach start hurting?
It was about two weeks ago?
Yeah?
Ibuprofen did the trick
for a bit, till it didn't.
So your blood pressure
is slightly low,
and your heart rate is high.
Why haven't you seen a doctor?
In this country?
Yeah, we can't afford it.
I only came now
'cause I thought I was dying.
We wanted to wait
until we got home to the NHS...
Our National Health Service,
which is entirely free.
You know, we complain about
waiting a bit in England,
but if we had to pay
actual money to see a doctor,
there'd be bodies
in the streets.
Corpses in the canals.
Cadavers in the...
Um, castles?
It bloody kills!
- Wh-Where am I?
- Bobby,
you passed out at the prison.
You're at Chastain Park
Memorial Hospital,
and we're going to take care
of you here, all right?
- Bay 12.
- Bobby Purcell.
He's an inmate
at the Georgia State Prison.
He's presenting
with acute onset hemiplegia
after having a seizure.
His sats and BP are low.
- He aspirated, as well.
- Let's load him with AEDs.
You go ahead.
I paged Billie
for a code stroke.
- What do you need?
- I'm concerned about stroke,
seizure
and aspiration pneumonitis.
And time of symptoms onset?
- Uh, 30 minutes.
- He's still in the window for TPA.
- Page me when you get a head CT.
- Okay.
His sats are improving.
Yeah, looks like we can hold
on intubation for now.
Let's order a full panel
and a tox screen
so we can figure out
exactly what's going on.
Push, push, push. Good.
- Jana ya.
- Bobby, hold on. I'm here.
- Squeeze, squeeze, squeeze, squeeze, squeeze.
- How is he?
Better but still unstable.
- Let-let me know what I can do.
- Yeah. We'll come get you
- after we get a head CT, okay?
- Hey.
Let's get you settled
in the waiting room, all right?
You couldn't be
more prepared if you tried.
There's so much riding on this.
If Betz slashes our budget,
- we'll be a third-rate hospital.
- Right this way.
All the hard work we've done to
make Chastain a great facility
that serves rich and poor alike
will be gone.
Kit, you got this.
It's a one-on-one. It's private.
It's low pressure.
It's a perfect scenario for you.
From your lips.
- Dr. Voss!
- Dr. Voss! - Dr. Voss!
- Dr. Voss, over here!
- Excuse me, Dr. Voss!
If we could just
ask a brief question, Doctor...
Anything to add, Governor?
- Dr. Voss!
- Excuse me, Kit.
Dr. Voss, welcome.
Thank you. I thought
this was a private meeting,
- not a media event.
- Oh.
I think it's good
to pull the curtain back
for the people of Georgia,
don't you?
And you are?
Randolph Bell,
a surgeon at Chastain.
One of our finest
and a former CEO.
Here to give you more
information about the effect
of budget cuts
on our surgical floor.
Well, I'm glad
you could join us, Dr. Bell.
Here. Help yourselves.
There's coffee and tea.
I got rid
of the espresso machine.
It's not really my style.
Well, I'm sure
we'll muddle through.
How's the pain now, Claire?
The pain comes and goes.
Maybe it was just a cramp.
Ah. Kidney stones, actually.
They're some of the most painful
little things in the world.
But why aren't
the pain meds working?
The stones have become
too large,
and they're stuck
in the ureter.
And if we do not get rid of
them, you will feel a lot worse.
Hello.
Um, this is my colleague
Dr. Devi,
and I have discussed your case
with her.
Oh, I'm so sorry
you're going through this.
We are going to have to do
a procedure
to break up the stones
to make them easier to pass.
- Procedure?
- It's noninvasive.
You'll be out of here
shortly afterwards.
It'll still cost
an arm and a leg.
I'll wait till England.
Listen, it is dangerous to fly
with kidney stones this large.
You could have an attack,
and they'd have
to divert the flight.
Claire, you're suffering.
W-Whatever the cost,
we'll deal, yeah?
Even if it means
selling the car.
I think
we'll be selling the flat.
Baby brother.
- Jana ya.
- Are you okay?
Oh, I was so worried.
It was touch and go,
but these docs kept me kicking,
much to Leo's dismay.
- Glad you're okay, Bobby.
- Well,
- what do you think happened?
- His head CT
is negative for hemorrhage.
Start him on TPA?
I suspect you suffered
a transient ischemic attack.
What is that?
That's when parts of your brain
don't get enough blood.
Right, it's usually
temporary and resolves
on its own, which is why you're
getting your strength back.
- But why did it happen?
- Mm.
That's the question
we're facing.
Bobby had leukemia as a child.
Our mom was always working.
Jana ya saw me through it,
cared for me,
even though
we were both just kids.
It was so long ago, but could
the leukemia be related?
We'll look into it. I want
to check your neck, all right?
It's all yours.
I hear a right-sided bruit.
Oh. That's when
there's some kind of obstruction
inside the artery in your neck.
Could be high-grade stenosis?
But that wouldn't
cause headaches.
It may be responsible
for the TIA.
Let's get an MRI and find out.
Governor, I know
you and I are both committed
to the same thing...
The well-being
of the people of Georgia.
But can I just say
I love your accent?
Is that inappropriate?
Where are you from?
I'm Georgia born and bred.
I've lived in
Atlanta for 40 years.
I care about the people here
as much as anyone.
I'm certain
a conscientious person
like yourself wants
to understand
the effect your budget cuts
will have on our patients.
Yeah, sometimes
we all need tough love.
I-I campaigned on lower taxes.
Chastain Park has got
to operate within its budget,
without help
from public funding.
But, Governor Betz,
we are a public hospital,
which means
we require public funding,
something Governor Randall
understood when she instituted
a sales tax
to help cover our expenses.
Well, that sales tax
must now foot the bill
for more pressing issues.
- More pressing than health care?
- Crime.
Crime is soaring.
We need more cops on the streets
to ensure law and order.
Well, you know, you're talking
about taking away
hundreds of millions of dollars
being used to save lives.
There's no way
Chastain will be able
to provide
the most basic level of care.
Well, for basic care,
you bill Medicare and Medicaid.
I bet you know all about that.
Well, maybe not as much
as you do.
I mean, you made your fortune
running one
of the largest hospital groups
in the country.
Yes, and we maximized profits
without sacrificing
patient care.
Is that what you call
Medicare fraud these days?
You billed for home health care
visits that never happened.
You subjected patients
to dangerous
and invasive procedures
they didn't remotely need,
overdosed people on chemo.
Medicare paid for all...
Just remind me, how much did you
scam the taxpayers for?
Wait. I remember.
- $1 billion.
- Lies. It's all lies.
All right, we're done here.
But it's in the public record
and deserves more attention.
All right, turn the cameras off.
No, in fact, your hospitals
committed the biggest
Medicare fraud in history.
They got caught
and had to pay a huge fine
while you walked away
with a $300 million parachute
that you used to finance
your campaign for governor.
Governor, what do you
have to say about these allegations?
I don't have
to put up with this.
But we're pulling back
the curtain, right?
That went well.
That had to happen. Right?
Yeah.
Find me every ounce of dirt
on that Dr. Bell.
I'm gonna destroy him.
It's just hard to imagine
he committed this kind of crime,
but his DNA was all over
the scene and murder weapon.
It's not always easy to know
what people are really like.
What's that supposed to mean?
I saw Irving's photos
from the wedding.
And?
There's one of you
slow-dancing with Billie.
And the look on your face was...
It feels like
there's something between you.
We're friends, good friends.
Is that all?
We share something that's...
It's-it's hard to describe.
I guess...
it's a sense of what we lost.
That's it?
Yes.
Truth is important to me.
Bobby's labs came back.
There's nothing remarkable.
Well, maybe
we'll find some answers here.
- Wow.
- Looks like a mass
traveling along his carotids
into the skull base.
A carotid body tumor.
I've never seen one
this extensive.
It's spread to his lymph nodes.
They're usually detected
early when people get
the proper care,
but now it's compressing
his vessels and cranial nerves.
That explains the TIA,
aspiration,
difficulty swallowing,
even his hoarse voice.
This would be an extremely
complicated resection.
The tumor is entangled with his
internal and external jugulars.
We'll have to talk to AJ,
but surgery could cause
irreparable disability,
- even death.
- We haven't even talked
about his execution
being scheduled for next year.
Does it make sense
to put him through something
this dangerous
and invasive right now?
He'll likely die before the
year is out without the surgery.
But recovery is long
and difficult
with months
of chemo and radiation.
It could ruin
the time he has left.
Surgery gives Bobby a chance
at a better life,
no matter how long.
Well, it's his choice to make.
Isn't it?
Thank you for meeting me,
Donald, on such short notice.
Yeah, sure. What can I do
for you, Governor?
Well, Jerrod mentioned
we need some help.
And you are in a
perfect position to provide it.
I don't follow.
How long have you worked
at Chastain?
Not long.
Uh, this is my second week.
And have you had a chance to
work with Dr. Randolph Bell yet?
No. I-I hope to.
So, let's make that happen.
Does this have anything to do
with what happened this morning?
- 'Cause I saw the video...
- Well, let's just say
that there have been
some concerning reports
which put Dr. Bell's competency
in doubt.
Now, I'm sure, as a scrub tech,
patient safety is
your first priority.
I've only heard good things
about Dr. Bell.
I wish I could say the same
about you, Donald.
Jerrod filled me in on what
happened at Yates University.
How he helped that little mess
of yours go away.
For now.
What is it you need?
They got caught
and had to pay a huge fine
while you just walked away with
a $300 million golden parachute
that you used to finance
your campaign for governor.
Any calls or emails?
Letters laced with anthrax?
Not yet.
Dare we hope something good came
of that rant?
At least the problem's
in the public eye now.
Maybe Governor Betz
will feel the pressure.
No, you had him.
I just charged in there,
I'm sorry.
Couldn't stop myself.
You spoke from the heart.
There was never any chance
of winning the governor
to our side.
He brought me there
to humiliate me.
I'm proud you stood up to him.
And a little scared
of what may come at us next.
- Yeah, I really put my foot in it.
- All right, Attila.
Don't you have an army
of kidney stones to conquer?
Yeah, I think
I can probably get that right.
Dr. Bell? Sorry to bother.
Uh, I'm the new scrub tech.
I just wanted to say
I look forward
to working with you in the OR.
- Great. What's your name?
- Uh, Donald Killian?
I look forward to working
with you also, Donald.
This is quite comfy.
It feels like I ended up in
some weird science experiment.
So there you see
the kidney stones.
And we position
the head of this machine
so that the crosshairs
are right above the stones.
How does it work?
Well, shock waves... they move
through the water, and
they break up the kidney stones.
2,000 shock waves, each
a fraction of a second long.
Shattering them into fragments,
which will then pass
on their own.
Ah, the NHS might be free,
but these American gizmos
might be worth the price
of admission.
Well, spending big on technology
does have
the occasional benefit.
Our uncle
died of something similar.
Bobby, I'm so sorry.
I should have caught this.
Carotid body tumors
are very rare.
And Bobby had a constellation
of symptoms.
This isn't on you.
How long do I have?
Given where the cancer
has spread, a few months
if left untreated.
Surgery and chemo
could buy you some time,
but it's complicated.
Side effects, huge risks.
I appreciate the efforts
and care.
It means a lot to me.
But I'm done here.
Don't say that.
I live alone in a cage
for a crime I didn't commit.
We're gonna keep fighting
to prove your innocence.
I gave up on that long ago.
Now we move on.
Both of us.
I won't suffer anymore,
and you'll be free
of the brother who shamed you.
I have never been ashamed
of you.
This is a blessing
and a relief in some ways.
Ending it all soon
is a welcome way out.
I am so sorry.
He didn't kill her.
- The DNA evidence...
- Yeah, I know.
Case closed.
But I will never believe
it's right.
You mentioned earlier
that your uncle died
of something similar?
Um, a neuroendocrine tumor.
Seems like cancer runs
through our family.
Have you been tested?
No, I haven't had symptoms,
so I never thought to go there.
We can run a genetic test on
you and Bobby, cross-reference
the disease markers,
and if they match...
Keep an eye on you,
we can catch anything early.
Yeah. At least
something positive can come
- from all of this.
- Yeah.
As soon as she feels better,
and she will soon,
you can get out of here.
But have her stay hydrated for
the remainder of your travels.
I'll make sure of that.
This has been one part
of our adventures that will not
make the photo album.
- Mm-hmm.
- Hello.
Dr. Pravesh tells me
you reside in England.
- Oh, yeah.
- How is our soggy little island?
Oh, thanks to global warming,
less soggy than you remember.
This is my wife
and our CEO, Dr. Voss.
And I told Dr. Voss about your
anxieties over American billing.
Have a look.
My team spoke
with your insurance, and
- it looks like they'll cover the majority of it.
- Wow.
This is an incredible relief.
Thank you.
Oh, excuse me. Hello.
She's become more hypotensive
with a low-grade fever,
and she's sweaty.
- Looks like an underlying infection.
- Or sepsis.
Could be a number of things.
- Everything okay?
- Aziz,
c-can you get me some water?
There seems to be
a complication, something new.
Claire, we're going
to get you on more fluids.
We're gonna start
you on antibiotics and send off
a set of cultures just
to figure out what's going on.
If I ever caught you looking
at Nolan like that,
I'd spontaneously...
- Nolan?
- No?
Oh, really?
That's where your mind goes?
- I don't know. Dr. Paul Chu?
- Hmm.
George Clooney in his ER days.
- That's more of my sweet spot.
- Oh. Touché.
Jessica. Just
who I was looking for.
- Donald, hi.
- Hi.
Oh, Irving,
this is Donald Killian.
He's been making my life
so much easier
- since he joined the team.
- Happy to hear that.
- Keep up the great work.
- Thank you. -
You know, I haven't had a chance
to work in Dr. Bell's OR yet.
- Mm-hmm.
- And I'd love the opportunity.
I see you're scheduled with him
tomorrow, and...
Yeah, Dr. Bell's
pretty particular.
He's kind of a creature
of habit.
- Have you worked with Dr. Sutton?
- No.
She's lovely to assist.
I can arrange that.
Yeah, okay. Um,
you know,
if you're ever busy or tired,
you keep me in mind
for Dr. Bell's cases, too?
Yeah, sure. Uh, how about we go
check out Dr. Sutton's schedule?
I hear you've got
quite the photo collection.
It seems that way. Uh...
I hope I didn't get you
in trouble.
I always thought there might
be something between you two.
Billie was Nic's best friend.
Which explains what exactly?
You know, it's possible for us
to care about each other
and be friends without...
- Benefits?
- Dr. Feldman?
Discharge papers
for your patient in Bay 11.
Just in time.
Thank you very much.
You okay?
What were you looking at?
Ah, just photos
from the wedding.
Well, it was a lovely wedding.
And dance.
I woke up a little confused.
Yeah, I'm confused, too.
Well, you seem really happy
with Cade.
Am I wrong?
Are you happy?
Yeah, we're happy.
Then I'm not confused.
I got to go.
I want you to be happy.
Hey, uh, Dr. Hawkins, yeah?
James Yamada.
I look forward
to working together.
See if the man lives up
to the legend.
Oh, hope I don't disappoint.
I've got great news,
Chief Sutton.
That killer place where
all the chefs go after work?
I scored reservations.
It's harder to get than tickets
to the Super Bowl.
Oh, um... well, unfortunately
I'm working late, so...
It doesn't open until 10:30.
Look, they have this, uh,
Spanish octopus with jalapeño.
I know it sounds kind of weird,
but it's... it's incredible.
Oh, and a-a drink
called Vieux Carré with...
Unless I'm overstepping
and there's someone else.
- Is it Hawkins?
- I'd love to go.
- Yeah?
- Mm-hmm.
Okay.
- Great.
- See you later.
- This is incredible.
- Wild.
What did you find?
Brother, you are not going
to believe this.
I thought
it was a contaminated sample,
so I ran his genetic test again.
Oh, my God. Bobby has chimerism.
That's right. Two sets of DNA
as if he's two different people.
- I never thought I'd see a case of this.
- You and me both.
Only a hundred cases
have ever been recorded.
Bobby was convicted
with DNA evidence.
- DNA that may not have been his.
- Jana ya might be right.
He could be an innocent man.
Like the chimera,
the mythical beast with
the lion's head, goat's body,
and serpent's tail,
except in your case
- it is not a myth.
- In medicine,
chimera refers
to having two sets of DNA.
How's that possible?
Did you have
a bone marrow transplant
to treat your leukemia?
- Yeah, I did.
- When he was ten.
My childhood friend
was my donor.
- He saved my life.
- Well, it's quite possible
that your childhood friend
committed a murder,
and you took the fall.
Bobby, you
must have acquired his DNA
when his bone marrow started
making blood cells in your body.
Cells which have his DNA.
So it was Martin's DNA found
at the crime scene, not Bobby's?
Yeah.
For 15 years
I dreamed of a miracle.
But this...
Do you know where Martin is?
In prison
for armed robbery.
We are going to appeal and win
and get your life back, Robert.
But is there time?
If we do the surgery,
it's possible.
Then I'll do it.
Please.
Save my life.
It hurts!
Claire, hang in there.
We're taking you to surgery.
Her pain is getting worse.
What is happening?
We'll know more in the OR.
We think it has something
to do with her infection.
Repeat labs just came back.
Lactate is sky-high.
Cultures show florid gram
negative bacteremia.
The antibiotics aren't working.
She's in refractory shock.
Well, that's probably what's
causing her acute abdomen.
- We have to hurry.
- We got her from here.
I'm waiting for you, Claire.
I love you so much.
Let's find you a place
to sit, okay?
Come on.
Looks like I got my wish
sooner than I thought.
No offense,
but I asked for Jessica.
I know,
but she's tied up in OR Four.
- I promise to do my very best.
- Your name again?
Donald.
This is a tough one.
You better keep up.
Hope the damage isn't too bad.
Me, too. We just told her
she'd be leaving here soon.
Retractors.
- Dead bowel. She's ischemic already.
- How the hell
did that happen so quickly?
- Pressure's dropping fast.
- She's too sick.
- We don't have that much time.
- We're gonna have to do
a colonic resection.
Stapler to me.
You heard
about Bobby's chimerism?
Dr. Austin told me.
- I can't believe it.
- Nah, it's unbelievable.
He survives this surgery,
he clears his name.
You said
the truth was important to you.
What did you mean by that?
Losing Nic crushed me.
I'm just...
doing my best
to figure out things as I go.
I get that.
I think we both have
to be honest with each other.
And transparent.
I have been,
and I totally agree.
I see the tumor
eroding into the lumen
- of the carotid artery.
- It's also
invaded
into the intracranial space.
This tumor is way more extensive
than we expected.
Don't tell me it's inoperable.
It might be.
Wait.
Let's try and debulk
as much of the tumor as we can
- and reconstruct the carotid artery.
- To do all that,
we'd have to stop the blood flow
to the brain.
And finish everything
in 20 minutes,
or else risk a fatal stroke.
Sounds impossible.
Bobby was given a second chance.
We have to give it a shot.
Clamping.
Time starts...
...now.
Hey.
- Coffee?
- No, thanks.
How you holding up?
Nauseous, a little numb.
How bad is this?
The doctors are working
very hard, but it's serious.
I wish I had better news.
If she doesn't make it...
...I'm not sure I will either.
- Hey, what's the update?
- Still working
- on the anastomosis.
- We had to remove
more of the bowel.
It's taking longer than expected.
V fib! She's coding!
- I'm starting compressions!
- Prepare to shock!
On it.
Clear!
- Again!
- Charging! Clear.
This tumor
is too damn hypervascular.
I can't see a thing.
Increase suction.
Hang another unit.
They still have
to do a carotid reconstruction.
If they don't,
Bobby could end up brain-dead.
But if they continue...
Brain death versus fatal stroke.
We're not going to make it.
It was impossible to begin with.
Let's try COOL AID.
I'm not sure
a therapeutic hypothermia alone
is going to cut it.
What if we couple it with
systemic induced hypertension?
Plus an infusion of Ketamine.
That could buy more time.
So we make him sicker
to make him better?
I love when a medical
and surgical mind meld.
Let's start reconstruction.
Four of pro line to me.
Activate
Triple Neuroprotection.
Prepare the infusion.
Get cooling blankets,
ice packs, alcohol rubs.
Anything that can bring
his temperature way down.
Let's move.
Mr. Has an?
Despite our best efforts,
we were unable...
What happened?
She developed ischemic bowel
in the setting of shock,
and in the OR,
just too much was necrotic.
She must have already been sick,
and no one recognized it.
And maybe
when she first came in,
the tachycardia, which we
thought was due to her pain...
Or the slightly low blood
pressure, which we thought was
because she hadn't had
anything to drink.
It was sepsis all along.
And by the time we gave
antibiotics, it was too late.
The kidney stones must have
masked the earlier signs.
Which progressed
into an acute abdomen
- needing surgery.
- It was my fault. I...
I should have seen
the signs earlier.
Even if you had, it would
probably have been too late.
Claire avoided American
health care because of the cost,
and it killed her.
How are you feeling?
Still here... thanks to you.
And my voice...
It's back to normal.
I have more good news.
Rebecca's already working
on a petition for a new hearing.
So she can present
the new evidence to the judge?
I look forward to hanging out
with you on the outside, Bobby.
Well, that outcome was better
than we had any right to expect.
Patients pull off miracles
when you give them
a reason to live.
And now he has a good one.
Yeah, but the wheels
of justice are slow,
and his expiration date
is short.
Well, we gave him some time.
There's hope.
Spontaneous Triple
Neuroprotection in the field?
Dr. Sutton,
you are quite the powerhouse.
Oh, it was a team effort,
but you're not wrong.
Hey, I was thinking
maybe we could grab a drink
at the tiki bar first before
hitting up the restaurant?
That sounds like
just what I need.
Great. Uh, shall we?
See you tomorrow?
Yeah. Have a good time.
You deserve it.
Who's the new guy?
Just met the dude.
James, uh, Yamada,
interventional cardiologist
from Boston.
Oh, so he specializes
in placing stents?
Apparently he did
a thousand of them last year.
Whoa. At $13,000
per procedure. Wow.
That explains the brand-new
red Porsche in the parking lot.
You're cool with them together?
Eh, she can do better.
No doubt. Look,
I just want her to be happy.
Me, too.
He missed it.
She got worse
and died on the table.
Oh, you really think
there's enough for a lawsuit?
Yeah, no doubt about it.
Well, it sounds to me
like there's a lot more
where that came from.
I asked around.
Um, Dr. Bell seems to have
some skeletons in his closet.
What kind of skeletons?
It might take me a little while
to find out.
They don't tell the new guy
their secrets right away.
Well, we will take
whatever you can get, Donald.
Bell, you picked
the wrong enemy.
Captioning sponsored by
20th CENTURY FOX TELEVISION
and TOYOTA.
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org