Previously on ER:
- I don't know what to do.
- Go to your car and follow me to Chicago.
Welcome to County, Dr. Lockhart.
Eight years of school.
So close to the finish.
You gonna throw
away your future?
I'm not sure it's
the future I want.
You don't work here anymore.
- When are you coming back?
- I'm not sure.
I've gotta rest.
Get back into work.
John.
Kem?
Can't sleep?
You'll get cold like that.
He'll come back.
We won't have any idea when.
Sleeping in one morning or on our way
home from a movie, he'll just show up.
Well, we'll deal with that.
- I don't know why you'd want to.
- I can think of a reason.
This place is too small.
- Maybe you should both live with me.
- What?
My apartment has two floors.
Alex can sleep downstairs.
Luka...
if we move in, it's gonna
be because we want to.
Not because you think
we need to be protected.
- Hey.
- I need to take a shower.
Hey.
Scrambled or fried?
Poached.
Poached?
Hello?
- What? Hello? WOMAN:
This is Neela's mother.
We're on the way
in from the airport.
Hold on a second.
It's for you.
Hello, Neela?
- You didn't tell your parents?
- I was waiting for the right time.
- When?
- My wedding day.
Hey, you know, you can
just put those anywhere.
They phoned Michigan.
The department head
told them I wasn't there.
- Those are still dirty.
- I'm totally screwed.
- What are you doing?
- Getting out of your way.
- Oh, please don't leave me.
- Neela, they're just your parents.
You think you've seen trauma at
work? You don't know the Rasgotras.
I know this may not
be the best time to ask...
but how long do you think
you'll be needing my couch?
Damn it.
Mom. Dad.
You remember Abby.
You look like hell.
Yeah, The Searchers
was on channel 9 last night.
It's tough to sleep in the
middle of a John Ford movie.
Talk to Jing-Mei?
Yeah, she's gonna start
seeing a physical therapist.
Pratt keeps calling, wants
Weaver to put him on the schedule.
- Doesn't even have his stitches out yet.
- Kyle Skinner, 23 years old.
- Found altered by his mom.
- He's had skin grafts.
- His headache's worse.
- Looks like dehiscence with cellulitis.
- What happened to him?
- Iraq.
He was a HEMTT driver in
the Sunni Triangle near Fallujah.
- One, two, three.
- Any meds? Allergies?
- Just Vicodin when he hurts.
- Lungs are clear.
What's the differential for altered
mental status with fever and headache?
This guy's a setup for all kinds of stuff.
But I'd go with meningitis all the way.
- Uh, Dr. Carter? KYLE:
Take me home, Ma.
All right, CBC...
blood and wound cultures,
LP, ceftriaxone, and a head CT.
- Roll him over.
- Easy, man.
We're gonna fix
you right up, okay?
No, you won't.
Head and shoulder in 3, Harold.
- Herman.
- Howard.
Ha. There is a God.
Took me five minutes to
track down a strep culture.
What are you waiting
for on this ankle sprain?
Needs a wrap, as soon as I
swab my football player's throat.
How many patients do you have?
- Ten.
- Twelve.
Can't be efficient if you get hung
up doing jobs other people can do.
- Sometimes it's easier...
- Your job is to move patients...
not wrap ankles or go
on hunts for strep cultures.
Learn to delegate to
nurses and med students.
Go see the migraine in 1.
Abby, your med student ordered
a bolus on the dehydrated kid.
- My med student?
- Penny Nicholson.
Dr. Weaver told me
I'd be shadowing you.
I need you to cosign the order.
Weird. Last week someone
was cosigning for me.
- Nice to be the boss.
- Sam, can you prep my forehead lac in 2?
- Yeah, I'm on my way.
- And can you do a throat swab...
- for the guy in Sutures.
- Fine.
- Something the matter?
- I'm getting slammed here.
In the time it took you to ask me,
you could have swabbed him yourself.
But you can do a setup
for Dr. Tiger Beat over there.
- That's my patient.
- It's okay, Sam. I'll do it.
- Thanks, Haleh.
- No problem.
Haleh, I think you might
have been off a decimal point...
- on my pyelo patient's dopamine.
- Excuse me?
I noticed it was running
at 3 cc's instead of 30.
I caught it early, but next time
maybe you could double-check.
Double-check the concentration
before you mess with the IV pump.
I mixed it 10 to one.
- Don't we always mix it one to one?
- No, you always mix it one to one.
- I always mix it ten to one.
- I didn't realize.
If you concentrate the drip...
- the bag will last longer.
- Sorry.
I'll go turn down her rate, make
sure her BP hasn't hit the roof.
Um, you know, nurses really are
the backbone of a place like this.
It's good to get
on their good side.
Thanks. I'll keep that in mind.
So when are you going
to tell us what's going on?
Ajay, relax.
I don't know if I
wanna be a doctor.
What?
I'm not sure I'm good at it.
Of course you're good at
it. You're good at everything.
Some send their children to medical
school, get a Nobel Prize on the mantel.
- Ajay, please.
- Why does she punish us?
I'm not trying to punish you.
I'm trying to figure things out.
- What's there to figure out?
- Like how I want my life to be.
- Neela, you're not a child anymore.
- Then stop treating me like one.
What about your
brothers and sisters?
Don't you think they
want to go to university?
We don't make enough
to pay for all that.
You promised to help out
once you began your Residency.
I'll help soon enough.
You'll have to wait a little.
Is that what you're going to tell
them? Their futures have to wait?
Because their sister is not
sure what she wants to be?
I'll have a job soon
and I'll send money.
- What job? Where?
- Here at the hospital, I hope.
- That's possible?
- I've talked to my supervisor.
She's trying to arrange it.
- Starting when?
- I'm supposed to discuss it today.
If the third neb doesn't
break her, call her up.
- Call her up?
- To Medicine, to be admitted.
- Call the Resident.
- Should I write this down?
- What year did you say you were?
- Labs are back on your guy, Dr. Lockhart.
- Something wrong?
- I heard what you did.
- Um, excuse me.
- Changed the bedpan in 2...
- and dug out the earwax in 1.
- Et tu, Chuny?
Acetaminophen
level on pharmacy girl.
- What, so now I'm the bane of all nurses?
- Anything else?
- You can stop the Mucomyst.
- Yes, doctor.
- Abby?
- What?
Anterior glenohumeral dislocation.
I was hoping you could take a look.
- Did you try to reduce it?
- The girl won't let me.
She's crying a lot.
Hi. I'm Dr. Lockhart.
- Are you her mom?
- I'm her aunt.
She cannot move it. I
tried to fix at home but...
- Okay. What's her name?
- Marta.
Marta, I'm gonna show
you a trick with a sheet...
that's gonna make your
arm feel much better, okay?
- She doesn't speak much English.
- Um, okay.
All right?
- Three of Versed, 50 of fent.
- You sure you wanna use both?
Yes. Can you hook
up some blow-by?
- Blow-by?
- I'll get it.
- You don't think the Versed is enough?
- I think it will be too painful.
Marta.
Uh... Sheet. Okay?
Here you go.
- Versed's in. ABBY:
Penny, come here.
I'm not really familiar
with this technique.
It's okay.
All right.
- Go ahead with the fent.
- O2's not ready.
Fifty of fent sounds like
a lot on top of the Versed.
- That's what I was saying.
- Listen, team.
We're shoving a bone
back into its socket.
- You'd want all the meds in the hospital.
- It could suppress her respiratory drive.
I'm aware of that, Howard.
That's why I asked
for oxygen. Okay.
On the count of three, I want you
to lean back as hard as you can.
This is gonna go fast.
Okay, one, two, three.
- Cool.
- We can go now?
Um...
There's a cut here too.
We should clean that out.
Ceftriaxone's in.
The CT shows a sinus
infection that's spread to his brain.
We can isolate it with a tap but he
has to go up to the O.R. for drainage.
Hold still, Kyle. Little pinch.
- When was he wounded?
- In February.
- Okay. One more minute.
- I've been with him the whole way.
Finally got him home
on Tuesday and now this.
Yeah, fluid's cloudy.
That means an infection, right?
Almost done. You okay, Kyle?
- Yeah.
Okay, we are done.
- You want me to run those to the lab?
- Yeah.
Stay there while they
do the Gram's stain.
They like to lose
things up there.
Okay, you can sit up now.
Why don't you try and get some
sleep, and I will be back in a little bit.
- Can't sleep.
- I will see what I can do...
- about moving you to a...
- Doesn't matter.
Try to get some rest, huh?
In my dreams, I'm still
the guy I used to be.
But I always wake up.
Did you get a history?
No hablo, and they didn't
have any paperwork, so...
And no address and
no phone number.
- Okay. ROSARIO:
She better now. We go.
Get a guard over here, okay?
- Hi.
- Feels good, gracias.
Okay, but I'm gonna
give you a complete exam.
What for?
Hermanos?
Sisters, three.
See there?
- Qué pasó?
- The girls play crazy sometimes.
Okay. Los pantalones.
Can you take them off?
- Why you look at her legs?
- Everybody gets a full exam.
We don't have time.
Marta, vámonos.
Ma'am, you can't leave.
Ma'am, you don't want
to do that. Stop them.
- What are you doing?
- Calm down, ma'am, calm down.
- Calm down.
- Get away from me.
Take her to the conference
room. I'll get the girl.
Marta. Wait, wait, wait. Okay.
- Slut, puta!
- Okay, listen, listen.
Tranquila. Tranquila,
okay? I'm not gonna hurt you.
I'm not going to hurt you.
Okay?
Okay.
I wasn't aware that
there was a dress code.
I just don't want you to create
any discomfort with the patients.
The patients, or
the other doctors?
- It's the jewelry, isn't it?
- No.
Fingernails, tattoo, the hair?
It's the whole package.
Okay. I'll talk to my band mates
and see if I can't pull it back a little.
- Band mates?
- It appears we've hired...
the love child of Ozzy Osbourne.
- So did Kem get back okay?
- Yep.
- Have you heard from her?
- She sent me an e-mail.
- Dr. Weaver.
- She and I are just sort of...
taking a little time
to... How's Henry?
He's pretty great. Thanks.
Your folks are back in Chicago.
- That's great. Where are they?
- They're across the street. Dr. Weaver in?
Yes, she is, just
down the hall there.
Hi, Dr. Carter.
How is everything?
Um... Nice to see you, Neela.
- Wait, what's she doing here?
- I'm not really sure.
- I am not a victim!
- Whose patient is that?
- I did the H and P, waiting on a doctor.
- Okay, ma'am. You need to settle down.
- I am the solution to the problem!
- Hard restraints.
I am not the problem!
Actually, right now you are.
- He forgot to write it down.
- He's lying.
- He wouldn't let me take it.
- You're a liar.
- You a liar.
- You are.
- Dr. Weaver, do you have a minute?
- Malik, take his temperature again.
I decided not to do my
internship at Ann Arbor.
I know. Your department
head called me.
He wanted to know if we detected any
psychiatric problems during your rotation.
- What did you tell him?
- I lied.
I didn't wanna be there. I'm not
even sure I want to be a doctor.
So, what can I do for you?
Give me a position, a job, any kind
of job, just until I get myself refocused.
- But you don't want to be a doctor?
- No, what I meant...
I have no idea what I meant.
I just... I need some work.
Oh, I'm sorry. I can't...
Can't really help you.
I'll take anything. I can stock
supplies or be a candy striper.
Neela, can I give
you some advice?
Go back to Michigan
before it's too late.
Está bien? Does that hurt?
Well...
your aunt has to
answer some questions.
Why do you call her mamacita?
Is she your mother?
You said she was
your aunt, right?
What?
She... She keeps us.
She keeps who?
You and your sisters?
Not sisters. Only girls.
Is mamacita the one
that's been hurting you?
You can tell me.
Okay.
It's okay. You're safe
here. Who's hurting you?
Marta, who hurt you?
Los hombres.
Military medical record on Kyle Skinner.
His mom had someone drop them off.
Yeah, thanks.
Coffee break?
No, I put vodka in
here on special days.
I wasn't trying to be
a hero this morning.
I asked you to
move in because I...
I love you.
I'm in love with you, and I...
I thought, I don't know,
maybe you feel the same.
Did you just say that?
I've spent too much
time wasting time.
So whenever you're
ready, just let me know.
You guys doctors? My
buddy needs some help.
Herm Bullard. I'm a marine
biologist over at the aquarium.
Hey, over here. HERM:
There's been an incident...
- during a tank cleaning.
- What the hell is that?
Ginglymostoma
cirratum, a nurse shark.
Damn fish just latched onto me.
- We need them disconnected.
- You think?
It's important that neither Mr. Fahey
nor the shark be damaged in any way.
- I'll get a gurney.
- Wheelchair.
Keep pouring water on
him, Mort. He's suffocating.
Chuny, I have a patient in Sutures.
I need you to help me get a history.
Last I checked, an H
and P was a doctor's job.
She's in trouble, and my
Spanish is not very good.
- The one with her aunt?
- Not her aunt.
Chuny, can you change
the pressure dressing in 1?
- Security has her in custody.
- I'll be over there in a minute.
- He'll only live for 30 minutes like this.
- What?
- Not you, Mort, the shark.
- You're just making it worse.
Get me three grams of Unasyn IV.
- Can you feel this?
- Clem, go get the tank from the truck.
He's got a mouthful
of subcu fat.
Is that something
I can live without?
- Is that my subcu fat...
- Hey, watch it.
Okay. You don't have a job here,
so we are taking you to Michigan.
- No, Dad.
- It's a good hospital.
- Dermatology is a lucrative field.
- It's not what I want.
What do you want?
To be like this man?
- Ajay.
- I don't know.
- That's what I'm trying to tell you.
- I've heard enough.
Ajay, will you go get us a cab?
Excuse me?
We are getting your
things. We rent a car.
And then we go.
And that's final.
He doesn't get it, Mom.
You think he doesn't
get it? We get it.
- You're the one that doesn't get it.
- Don't you start in on me.
Neela, when I married your
father, I was younger than you are.
Sure, I loved him. But do you think I
didn't have grander ideas for my life...
than running a curry
house in Southall?
Then let me find my own path.
Passing up the opportunity that you
have been given is not the way to do it.
- I've worked hard for it.
- So have we all.
All those years at the restaurant,
saving, planning for your future.
- I just need some time.
- Sorry, love. Time's up.
I've always done
everything you've asked.
Everything. Even the damn viola.
I had to learn to play
the sheet music perfectly.
I was never allowed
to play what I wanted.
- You wanted to play rock music.
- Or to improvise, or be creative.
- You can't improvise the viola.
- You can try.
- So you want to be a musician now?
- No, Mom.
I want to improvise.
A man abducted her
from a bus stop in Mexico.
When did this happen?
You were 12? How
old are you now?
No sé.
So, what happened
after the man took you?
They made me dañada.
Damage girl.
What is "damage girl"?
The men, they hit her,
or do what they want.
Anything they want.
When's the last time
you spoke to your family?
Once, a long time ago, she
snuck off and called her parents.
She told them she didn't
know when she'd be home.
She told them not to cry.
Okay, Marta.
We're gonna help
you now, all right?
Okay?
My name's not Marta.
My real name is...
Tesoro.
- We are going, Ajay.
- Good.
- Home. Neela's staying here.
- What?
I love you, Mom.
Get in the car, Ajay.
I hope you know that we
can't help you anymore.
I'll find a job. I'll send
something for Rajiv when I can.
When you were little, you used to tell me
that you always dreamed of being a bird...
so that you could
fly far, far away.
Well, you've finally
done it, haven't you?
I called the factory where
Tesoro's parents work.
- Did you talk to someone?
- Through a translator.
- Secretary gave us this number.
- Great. Get Chuny for me, will you?
She's a real piece of
work. Asking for asylum...
saying she's as much a victim
of the Lenones as the girls.
- Lenones?
- Organizations of traffickers and pimps...
that bring these girls in
and set them up in houses.
- You've seen this before?
- A bit.
She'll be put in custody and
we'll search the apartment.
- What about the girl?
- All the girls we've put into foster care.
Children's Services and
the INS will get into it.
- She needs to go home to her parents.
- Yeah.
- Hey, where are your folks?
- Gone.
- Are you crying?
- No.
I'm sorry. I'm off at
8. We can talk then.
- I'll wait around.
- You're waiting around for three hours?
I've got nothing better to do.
Okay. Hey, you don't
speak Spanish, do you?
Punjabi, French, a bit of Farsi,
smattering of German, some...
All right, all right, all right.
Hi.
- How's your shoulder?
- What happens now?
Maybe you can go home to Mexico?
They don't love me.
They don't want me.
Of course they do.
No more.
Wanna call them?
I have a number
where I think they'll be.
- Maybe we should try.
- Too long now. I'm gone too long.
Let's try it.
It's ringing.
Hello?
Mama?
- Get any sleep?
- What do you think?
So your mom says that
you don't want the surgery?
It's relatively minor. They're just
gonna touch up your cheek implant.
A drop in the ocean,
right? Whatever.
Okay.
You a Democrat?
Yeah, most of the time.
People rag on this war.
I say it was a good thing. Gave
a lot of people their freedom.
- Well, it's good that you feel that way.
- Where the hell would I be if I didn't?
- I hear you got engaged.
- I was.
Her name's Karen.
- What happened?
- She tried to come see me at Bethesda.
I wouldn't let her.
You think she would've
given up on you that easy?
Karen's a good
girl. She's the best.
Sometimes things happen that
even the best people can't get past.
Maybe in a few years I
won't think about her anymore.
What kind of shark was it?
- A nurse shark.
We got a few of
those working here.
It says here they
adapt well to captivity.
Sounds like a nurse to me.
- Not all of us.
"They tend to move slowly within a
relatively small range during the day."
- Hey, easy.
- Watch it.
Nobody has any
work to do today, huh?
- Want me to take a look at that?
- This? It's nothing.
Why don't you take off early?
We got things under control here.
I got some follow-ups
to do. And my vet guy...
I'll take care of it.
Okay. Thank you.
Nineteen-year-old attacked in
Grant Park. Complains of belly pain.
I'm Dr. Lockhart. Can
you tell me your name?
Good airway, sats 98,
pulse 133, BP 104/58.
- They hit us.
- Who hit you, honey?
- They hit us with a tire jack.
- Initial GCS 15, mental status is waning.
- Help my boyfriend. Help Zack first.
- Wait here, I'll check the other.
Blunt trauma to head and torso.
Agonal on the scene, LMA placed.
Sats 78/100 percent. Pulse
thready and irregular, 120.
- Flail chest.
- God, are they gonna be okay?
- Give us room to work.
- Pupils are fixed and dilated.
We were sitting in the grove, a
bunch of us. I'd never been there before.
- Belly's tense.
- Four guys came from nowhere.
Just started beating them,
just because they were kissing.
I'll take this one in T-2. You
and Haleh with the other in T-1.
This guy's less critical.
- Shouldn't I...?
- Just go.
- Curved Kelly.
- Sats are 72. Heart rate's dropping.
- Sure the ET's in good position?
- Put it through the cords. 36 French.
- What do you hear?
- Distant breath sounds.
- Whoa!
- Okay, I'll tighten up the clamp.
- Hook him up. Get the Cell Saver.
HemoCue's 5.2 after
two units of O-neg.
Hang another two on the
rapid infuser. Start another PIV.
- He's too clamped down.
- Well, set me up for a subclavian.
- I'll do it right after this. Ten blade.
- Sats down to 68.
- It's getting harder to bag.
- Bradycardia at 47.
- Mg of atropine, amp of epi.
- There's blood in the ET tube.
Well, suction it. Open
platelets and FFP.
I'm in.
- Any blankets in here?
- Check in the warmer.
- You guys okay?
- Lost the pulse.
PEA. Starting compressions.
Sam, get Kovac in here.
- Sats are down to 82.
- I got a good look at those guys.
- I can tell the police.
- The grove always seemed safe.
Tom, we're inserting a
tube to help you breathe.
- Twenty of etomidate.
- Abby's asking for you.
This guy needs to be tubed now.
Where's Howard? He can help.
- Stuck in CT with a kid in status.
- Meds are ready.
We're gonna send you to the O.R. so
surgeons can stop the bleeding, okay?
- Zack. How is he?
- He's gonna need another crit.
- He's out.
- They'll be able to fix it, right?
The surgeons, they'll stop the
bleeding. That's what you said.
- They're gonna do everything they can.
- What's that mean?
Tube.
It's really tachy, 145.
What do you mean,
"Everything they can"?
Okay, page Corday again.
You can't just kill people
for kissing in the park.
- Robert, don't go in there.
- Hold compressions.
Still PEA. Rate 38.
- What's happening?
- Let them work.
Resume compressions.
How long since the last epi?
- About 30 seconds.
- Atropine?
- Just pushed it.
- How much fluid?
Liter of LR, seven units of
O-neg, and another two going in.
Can I switch out?
My arms are tired.
- Maybe the meds aren't getting in.
- We got good flow through all the lines.
No pneumo, no tamponade,
temp's okay, tube's good, got bicarb.
The obvious cause is hypovolemia.
We're slamming fluids in.
- Can you check the pupils again?
- Tox screen's back. Negative.
- Thoracotomy?
- Not with blunt trauma.
Fixed and dilated.
Should I put in a central line? You
think that would make any difference?
- Haleh?
- You have three IVs with good flow.
Yeah, but if we had central access,
maybe we could get the blood in faster.
- Sam?
- Maybe. I don't know.
Okay. Two liters out of the
chest. Two liters out of the chest.
If anybody has any opinion
about this, please speak up.
It's your call, Abby.
You're the doctor.
Hey, Dr. Carter.
Patrick.
Hey, I'll get you an iced
coffee and a BLT right away.
Maybe something else today.
- Holding compression.
- Junctional rhythm: 24.
- No pulse.
- What's our time?
Forty-two minutes.
You have anything
you wanna say to him?
Zack, thank you.
You made me strong.
You let me see who I was.
And to know that it was okay.
Come on, Robert. Let's go
talk to the police now, okay?
I didn't know I was gay
until they became my friends.
Four fifty-three p.m.
Guide wire back. Run the
FFP and platelets up here.
- My guy died.
- Can you throw in a femoral line?
Tell the O.R. if Corday isn't
here soon, I'll bring him up myself.
- Hematoma on the left. Try the right.
- Could've used a little help in there.
- BP's dropping, 55/44.
- Narrowed pulse pressure.
- Muffled heart sounds.
- Pericardiocentesis needle to Abby.
Raise the head of the bed.
- Lost the pulse.
- Okay. Mg of epi. Have atropine ready.
- Angle the needle.
- I know.
Ectopy on the monitor.
I need another syringe, quick.
Carotid's back. Good job, Abby.
- Sorry, I was going to Grand Rounds.
- Trauma, bleeding into the belly.
Complicated by a bloody
pericardial effusion and tamponade.
Set up Room 5 for an ex-lap. Tell
Dr. Edson he's gonna have to do it.
- Two hundred and fifty cc's out.
- Right. Let's get him upstairs.
Systolic's up to 88.
- Nicely done.
- You left me alone in there.
We had two traumas.
Last week I had to get
approval for everything I do.
Suddenly, I'm supposed
to run a code by myself.
- Welcome to internship.
- I was tentative and unsure.
- I was asking nurses for advice.
- They respect openness.
They respond to being
treated like team members.
- You always did.
- Luka, the boy's dead.
And I don't think he got
the best possible care.
We gave the best possible care
to the one I thought we could save.
And we gave the
next best to your guy.
- What?
- He had coded when they brought him in.
He had barely any vitals, and he was fixed
and dilated. The guy was already gone.
- So, what? I never had a chance?
- He never had a chance.
You'll have one sooner than you want.
15 minutes, an hour, tomorrow maybe.
You still here?
- I'm addicted to this zombie game.
- You missed that guy.
- Which one's that? "Pain Killer"?
- No.
- Hello again.
- I thought you went home.
There's something I meant to do.
- Everything okay, John?
- I just gotta talk to this guy.
- Can we talk, please?
- Just one minute.
- I thought you were gone.
- Call Karen. Okay?
Bad things happen to everybody.
But you two have to at least
take a shot at getting through this.
So... call her.
You can live through this.
You can live through all this.
- But you may never get over losing her.
- Dr. Carter.
- Okay, you guys. Let's take a walk, John.
- Call her. You hear me?
- Yeah, he hears you.
- Let's go to the lounge.
Call her.
- Is he all right?
- Yeah, he's fine.
The lady from CPS is here.
- Thank you.
Hi. I'm Dr. Lockhart. You're
from Children's Services?
- Marie Barclay. Here for Marta Delgado.
- Her name's Tesoro.
- They told me Marta.
- No. So when can she go home?
We'll be in touch with
the Mexican Consulate.
They'll locate the family, we'll
send someone to pick her up.
- The family's very poor.
- We'll figure it out.
- And how long will that take?
- Well, she'll be placed in foster care...
until the INS clears her. Once that
happens, should be a few months.
- Like two?
- Six, eight months at the most.
Of getting bounced around
between foster families.
- I don't think she can take it.
- We'll do our best to look after her.
Sorry. Okay, I'll go
get her. Just wait here.
I have a conference
soon. Will it be long?
No, I'll make it quick.
- The train station?
- She'll need ID for the airport.
- Do you have money?
- Do you know what you're doing?
I'm calling her parents to tell
them she'll be there in two days.
There's all my cash. Take this cred...
Don't take that one, take this one. Okay.
- I can't just whisk her away.
- Do you have something better to do?
- I go? ABBY: Yep.
Honey, you go now. Okay?
- Your name?
- Abby.
Muchas gracias, Abby.
Okay, you gotta run.
And don't take her through
the bay. Take her out the front.
I don't know what happened.
You had a rough time.
It's not hard to understand.
I guess I just thought
it would help somehow.
Help what?
- What else is going on?
- Nothing.
No, I'm fine.
Looked bad all day. I wasn't
the only one who noticed.
Well, I did get hit in the
head by a psycho patient.
You can talk to me, John.
I've been having
trouble sleeping.
I keep having these dreams.
And I miss her.
And I miss the baby.
And I miss all the stuff that I
thought we were gonna have.
And I don't know how
to get any of it back.
Here's your ticket.
Chicago to L.A...
L.A. to San Diego,
then a bus to Tijuana.
This envelope has $200
in it. It's yours. Keep it safe.
The train leaves from Track
11 in five minutes, okay?
Okay, good luck.
You need to get
on that train now.
It's all right. You can do it.
It's simple. Tickets. Money.
- Dr. Lockhart, I'm still waiting.
- Oh, yeah. I'm sorry. I feel terrible.
When I went to get
Tesoro, she wasn't there.
- I think she ran off.
- Was anyone watching her?
- I have a nurse looking for her right now.
- I have to call my office.
- You people need better security.
- We say that every year.
- Hi.
- Hey.
I lost my cell phone.
There's a meeting over at St.
John's if you want me to go with you.
Yeah. No, that's all right.
Just a little slip.
All the crap I used to give
you. I'm kind of a hypocrite.
No. We're all hypocrites.
- Need a ride home?
- No, I took the train.
- See you tomorrow.
- Yeah.
Hey. What do you want me to do
with the med records on the vet guy?
Um...
I'll take them. I'll have
them sent up to the O.R.
Luka.
- I thought you were still on.
- For a while, yeah.
Uh, you know what you
said earlier over on the steps?
Me too.
So come on by later and
I'll make you some eggs.
Okay.
Hey.
Hey, Kem. It's John.
I know that you're sleeping. I
just wanted to hear your voice.
- No family?
- College student from Milwaukee.
Haleh, if you ever think
I'm doing something wrong...
You did everything you could,
Abby. It was a good code.