Hey.
Hey, I'll be right there.
Take your time.
You mind if I get
a drink of water?
No, no. Not at
all, help yourself.
Not exactly beach reading, huh?
Do you understand
any of that stuff?
Well, most of these
I can get through.
But that one, I can't
get past the dust jacket.
Where's Ted? Laid off.
Company's going
with per diem workers.
You don't have to pay
overtime, health insurance.
Wow, that sucks.
I don't mind. Really. I'm not
a 40-hour-a-week kind of guy.
Uh, if I could just
get you to sign...
Right. Um...
Hang on one second. I
wanna show you something.
You're gonna laugh,
but I swear this guy, James
Sidas, looks exactly like you.
Wait, hang on a second.
This guy is you. I saw a
profile Nova did on you.
You're like the youngest
guy to ever graduate MIT.
Standards were lower back then.
You got an IQ of 178.
Published three
books and 35 papers,
all before the age of 18?
Yeah.
Sorry, I really
need to get going,
so if I could just
get you to sign off...
All right. I'll trade you.
I'll sign if you'll sign.
I'm not that guy any more.
Come on, man. This is
the most exciting thing
that's happened in
this place in years.
Come on, don't be like that.
I'm paying you a compliment.
It's not that. I'm...
My hand's not working.
Hey, hey. Whoa, whoa. You okay?
No.
$2.32. Put it on
Dr. Wilson's tab.
I don't know who Dr. Wilson
is, and we don't have tabs.
Do you know who I am?
No. Good.
But, sir...
I got it. It's all right.
Thanks.
Although, I should make
it clear that for two bucks,
all you get is top
half, over the clothes.
Any plans for turkey day?
Going to my sister's
for dinner. Why?
Just making
pleasant conversation.
I heard tell of
folks doing such.
How about we talk about this?
Fifteen-year-old, recurring
migraines and blurred vision.
Great. Really?
Sure. There's no point
putting a band together
if we're not gonna
play any gigs.
Hold on. Take this instead.
I was expecting more resistance.
That was the old me. New me
is static guarded and friction free.
Enjoy your drumstick.
Ready to save some lives?
Thirty-two-year-old courier,
ataxia, anemia, mild cough.
CT was clear, tox
screen negative.
What are you so excited about?
Why wouldn't I be?
Got all my starters back,
plus a couple of first-class free
agents. I feel like Mike Tomlin.
Probably not as much as
you do, but you get the idea.
Ataxia and anemia, could
be viral, maybe West Nile.
No fever, lymph glands were
normal. Anybody seen Wilson?
Hyperbilirubinemia?
Yeah, like that's a real thing.
Meningitis.
Anemia's a stretch.
Page Dr. James Wilson at 558.
What about sickle cell?
The guy's white.
Whites can get it.
Come on. We get the tennis
elbow and all the money,
let them have sickle cell.
TTP is a better fit.
He's right.
What, you thought I wouldn't
agree with him? Ever?
Well, you didn't agree with him.
That's why he dumped
you. Oh, sorry, it was mutual.
We're cool, okay? Nobody's
angry, nobody's hurt.
Sounds passionate.
TTP makes sense
to me. Not to me.
What if he had a history of...
One big happy family. TTP it is.
Confirm with a blood smear
and ADAMTS13 antibodies.
Dr. James Wilson,
please dial 558.
Can you cure it?
TTP isn't completely curable,
but the symptoms are manageable
with the proper treatment.
Is this the treatment?
No. First we need to do a blood
test to confirm the diagnosis.
But he's gonna get better?
Honey, that's what she's saying.
I'm gonna be okay. Don't worry.
How can't I worry?
You're in the hospital.
I'm gonna be fine.
Are you sure everything
was fine before?
I mean, given your
educational background,
you'd think you could at least
find a job with a medical plan.
We have money. Don't worry.
It's not that.
It's just I want to make sure
we have all the
information we should.
My husband wouldn't lie.
It's okay, baby. He's
just doing his job.
He just wants to make sure I'm not
a secret drug addict or an alcoholic.
Or hiding a history
of mental illness.
I work as a courier
because I want to.
It's easy. I don't
have to think.
It's too hard to think?
No. Just unpleasant.
No matter what I did, it
really wasn't good enough.
Then I met Dara.
She didn't care how smart I was,
or what I might
accomplish in the future.
It was the first time in my
life that I was really happy.
So I decided I would
rather be happy than smart.
You all right?
Sorry. I know you're
not okay. I mean...
She left.
Went back to Chicago.
Any chance of reconciliation?
No.
You sure you don't wanna
grab a drink after work?
I figured we could talk about
the perils of dating doctors.
I wasn't dating Cameron.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to...
I know what you're
doing, and I appreciate it.
But I've got it under control.
That's what you said
about the Dibala incident,
and obviously you didn't.
And talking about it obviously
made things so much better.
Didn't you think there was
something weird about that guy?
Not really. In fact, he
seemed pretty normal.
That's my point.
Guys with IQs off the chart
are usually completely abnormal.
Speaking of House,
why did you come back?
I mean, you must have
taken a major pay cut.
Life's too short to
worry about money.
Your wife feel the same way?
She's happy to cut
back on some things.
Like sex.
Why'd you come
back? Why wouldn't I?
Like Foreman said,
nobody's angry, nobody's hurt.
Schistocytes.
That means TTP.
Which is what we thought it'd be,
remember? This is a good thing.
This is an easy thing, and House
doesn't take cases that are easy,
which means it's not TTP.
And he wants to see how long
it takes us to catch up to him.
Schistocytes suggest TTP.
Good, now what?
Normally we'd try
plasmapheresis,
but the patient has an
albumin colloid allergy.
So?
So that means we have
to give him a splenectomy.
Yes, it does.
Wilson? MAN: No.
Do you know where he is?
Not in here.
You're sure you want
us to take out his spleen?
Is that what a splenectomy is?
I thought it was an
ice cream treat. Yuck.
So you do really
think he has TTP.
You're not just testing us.
Yeah. Like I have
time for games.
So, why did you
really take this case?
Isn't it obvious? I'm
fishing for a dinner invite.
Missed you at
breakfast this morning.
And lunch.
I had a dentist appointment.
You know where
Cuddy's sister lives?
You see, this is why I don't
answer your urgent pages,
because they're
not urgent pages.
I've decided what I'm gonna
do about Cuddy and Lucas.
I'm going to break them up.
Of course. It's given
me a purpose in life,
a goal, a raison d'être.
Albeit a selfish,
mean-spirited, childish raison.
I think of it more
as benevolent.
There's only two possible
outcomes for their relationship,
they split or they
stay together forever.
If it's split, then the sooner it
happens, the better for everyone.
If it's stay, then my
meddling won't matter.
In fact, if they survive it,
it might even make
their bond stronger.
How you manage to
elevate your narcissism
to beneficence is masterful.
And I've decided to do
it at Thanksgiving dinner,
just 'cause I'm sentimental.
Dinner's at Cuddy's sister's,
which brings us back to...
House, don't.
I fished for an invite. Cuddy
wasn't biting, so I'll have to crash.
I have no idea where
Cuddy's sister lives.
Ask and thou shalt receive.
You can't honestly think
I would help you with this.
Not help me, help
Cuddy, remember?
If you don't get it, I'll be forced
to use more nefarious methods.
Happy holidays.
Ah.
Looks great.
So, he's all better?
Probably be on
some long-term meds,
and he's about
10 ounces lighter,
other than that, he
won't even know it's gone.
Did you hear that, honey?
You're gonna be just fine.
When can I get out of here?
If everything checks
out, less than a week.
Good. 'Cause those boxes
aren't gonna deliver colors.
Colors?
Green and orange
and ceiling.
Mr. Sidas, do you know
where you are? Chewing.
Jimmy?
Shirt.
He's stroking. Call
the cath lab, now!
Oh, my God.
Blood flow's restored, appears
to be no permanent damage.
Good news is it turns
out to be an exciting,
action-packed thrill
ride of a case after all.
Bad news is we took
out his spleen for nothing.
Thank God he's still got
his appendix and tonsils.
So what looks like
TTP, acts like TTP,
tests like TTP, but isn't TTP?
CNS Vasculitis,
explains the ataxia
and anemia, maybe the stroke.
CT would have
picked up something.
Hi, I'm Greg House. I'm a
friend of your sister, Lisa.
Could be DIC.
Lisa Cuddy.
Sorry, wrong number.
You gonna ask?
I'm sure he's got a
perfectly logical explanation.
Can't be DIC, no hemorrhaging.
And I'm calling all 12 Julia
Cuddys within 100-mile radius.
See? Completely reasonable.
Acquired pancytopenia?
WBC's normal.
Hey, Julia. You're
Lisa's sister, right?
Are you sure? You are number 12.
Maybe she got married
and changed her name.
Otis Campbell.
Probably kept her first name.
The mnemonic for toxins.
"O" for organophosphates,
"T" for tricyclics, "I" for insulin...
Or as I remember
it, "Moist Place."
That's "Place" spelled with
two "L"s and a silent "B."
Except the tox
screen was negative.
Standard tox screen. Unstandard
toxins don't show up on it.
Well, you two do an unstandard
tox screen. You two search his home.
Otis Campbell's gotta
be hiding somewhere.
Smartest guy in the world
and this is the best he can do?
Maybe he's doing what he loves.
Delivering boxes was
a childhood dream.
Soda, processed cheese,
marshmallow spread.
Nothing in here is
capable of going bad.
Ibuprofen, eye
drops, cough syrup.
You want to come over
for Thanksgiving dinner?
You never asked me
over before, why now?
Just never thought of it. But
now that we're both on the team...
And my wife left me?
Is that a bad reason?
No, but I'm okay.
On both the food and friends.
Mice.
Leptospirosis could explain
the ataxia and the anemia.
But not without a fever.
You have someone to talk to?
Yeah. Who?
What, you want names?
Look, you lost
a friend, I get it.
But I'm not Kutner.
Good. 'Cause Kutner never
used to come over for dinner.
I'm going to pretend there's
something interesting over here,
so you'll shut up.
Actually, there is. He's got
sketches of atomic structure.
This one is full of math proofs.
They're all old.
Nothing since '96.
This isn't some
homework assignment
his parents forced on him,
this is passion. Why would
he want to stop doing this?
Marriage destroyed his soul?
Ooh.
Or maybe it was just the booze.
Thank you, Doctor.
You've been wonderful.
As have you, Diana. Be well.
Thank you.
You're helping. Voluntarily.
He's done six already.
I figured you might
be getting backed up
with the holiday season and all.
So which one of us slipped through the
wormhole into an alternate dimension?
I have always loved
to travel. And paint.
Lucky number seven.
House, I know you're
trying to be nice.
But I also know you're doing it
because you have an agenda.
Wow. Sexy and smart.
Lucas is a lucky guy.
The question is, is this a
bad agenda or a good one?
Either you're trying
to screw with me,
or you're trying to show me
that you've really changed.
So which is it?
I'm dying to know.
What are you doing
for Thanksgiving dinner?
Peace in our time!
Only cost me 45
minutes of clinic duty.
This is a three-hour drive.
Have you considered the
possibility that this is a fake address?
You think she'd send me to a
vacant lot for Thanksgiving dinner?
If she's smart. She is.
That's why I ran it through
Motor Vehicles. Good as gold.
This cannot end well.
Don't want it to end well.
You should come as my date.
You're not gonna
want to miss this.
The unstandard tox screen
was as clean as
the standard one.
But we found vodka
stashed away in his place.
What's with the ties?
Makes me look adorably
non-threatening. Party or party-hearty?
Liver failure would
explain all the symptoms.
Party.
So, the guy's a brainiac and his
secret drug of choice is booze?
It's kind of pedestrian,
don't you think?
Talk to him, he's
a pedestrian guy.
With pedestrian alcoholism. Liver
biopsy can wait until after Thanksgiving.
Yes, assuming the biopsy
is going to tell us exactly
what we expect it to tell us,
it can wait till
after New Years.
On the other hand, Taub and
Thirteen can do the liver biopsy today.
Why us?
Juniority. Welcome back.
What do you want us to do?
Same as me. Have a
happy Thanksgiving.
I'm not an alcoholic.
Yes, you just hide vodka
around the house for fun.
I drink, just not a lot.
Since when do you drink at all?
I have one shot when I get
home from work, baby. That's it.
So why lie to
your wife about it?
Because it's not important.
What difference does it make?
That you drink every
day, by yourself?
I have one lousy drink, okay?
Have you ever seen
me drunk? Ever?
No, but you've obviously been
drinking enough to hurt your liver.
My liver is fine. Hold still.
There we go.
This test is a waste of time.
Hey. This wine?
All right. Very good.
There, we got this...
String beans?
Julia?
No, I'm the house sitter.
They're in Hawaii for the week.
Happy Thanksgiving.
Happy Thanksgiving, you guys.
Cheers. Cheers.
You must be Dr. House.
I was told I should offer
you a turkey sandwich.
Tuna salad. Closest
thing they had to turkey.
Thanks. But I'm hoping
I can still get out of here
and catch the tail end
of dinner with my wife.
Anything?
No cirrhosis, no
scarring, no infection.
Blood panel?
Elevated albumin, 7.2.
That's it? Everything
else is fine.
So it was a waste of time.
Unless, it's not his liver
that's elevating his
albumin, it's his kidneys.
Renal failure.
Explains the anemia.
If he developed hyperkalemia,
that would explain the
ataxia, but the stroke...
Ischemic encephalopathy.
Nice.
Except now we have to
stay and test his kidneys.
Key under the mat.
There's no key under the mat.
Oh, right.
You need to replace one
of your kitchen windows.
I helped myself
to your wine cellar.
I'll leave a buck
on the way out.
You're not right for her.
And you are?
Less wrong.
Ah.
But then I started thinking...
What was I saying?
You were saying it's late and...
She invited me. She
didn't know if she should.
She was trying to figure
out if I really have changed
or if I'm still the same
old SOB I've always been.
But she always gave me a chance.
Eight hundred and
thirty-two chances,
and I used up every one of them.
Eight hundred and thirty-two's
her limit, make a note.
How about a cup of coffee?
It's just instant, but...
I'm pathetic.
I don't deserve her.
Okay. Okay. All right.
Here.
Maybe you should crash here.
It's a sofa bed.
I love her.
Patient's liver is fine, it's
his kidneys that are shot.
And where the hell is House?
He left a message on the
machine. He's not coming in today.
So what causes kidney failure?
Rhabdomyolysis.
No edema.
I trust you had a
wonderful Thanksgiving.
I don't remember.
So I guess I did.
Multiple myeloma. No bone pain.
You got drunk alone?
No. That would be a sign
that I need to talk
to you about this.
Polycystic kidney disease.
No UTIs or flank pain.
Well, what if his cough
is more than just a cold?
He hasn't been
coughing. It's in his history,
and we found a new bottle of
cough syrup in his medicine cabinet.
Cough could mean
Goodpasture Syndrome,
affects kidneys and lungs.
Start him on
immunosuppressors and dialysis.
We'll do it right after
we run it by House.
He's not answering his pager.
Looks like he's
leaving it up to us.
Us. Not you.
And since we don't disagree,
you can save your
fight for another case.
How long do I have
to be hooked up for?
Four to six hours a day
until we see an improvement.
What if you don't?
Then we keep doing it
until he gets a transplant.
You were sure it was his spleen,
and then you were
sure it was his liver,
which he told you it wasn't,
and now you're
sure it's his kidneys.
It's definitely his kidneys.
We just don't know
why it's his kidneys.
Any word from Cameron?
Nope.
I started seeing a
counselor after my diagnosis.
She's really good.
Why does everyone assume that
everyone works in the exact same way?
We pretty much do.
Our egos want us to think
we're all snowflakes, no two alike,
but really, we all
want the same things,
love, forgiveness, chocolate.
Well, what I want is for
everyone to leave me alone.
How do I get that?
What did you say
to Lucas last night?
I know there were
a lot of consonants.
I don't remember how I got
here, never mind what I said.
Well, I just talked to him.
And he said he
thought it'd be better
if we stopped seeing each other.
Said he didn't realize how much
there still was
between you and me.
And he didn't want to get
caught in the middle of us.
I was drunk.
Whatever I said,
he can't really...
I've had enough, House.
I actually felt bad
about scamming you,
but then you lived down to my
expectations, and then some.
There is no us.
There never will be.
It worked.
Please tell me you're talking
about a medical procedure.
They split up this morning.
You're the very
first one I've told.
And you think she'll start dating
you? I'm sure she hates you.
But her eyes say,
"How will I ever pay you
for that tennis lesson?"
What a shame.
They'll get over it.
I meant for you. I'll get
over it faster than they do.
I can't believe that
Lucas fell for my
"I'd never say this
because it's so personal
"except that I'm drunk"
profession of love.
Second oldest trick in the book.
You're right. It's his
fault because he's stupid.
He certainly is.
You're stupid.
Well, I'm rubber
and you're glue...
He's not pedestrian,
he's stupid.
Or at least stupider than he
should be. He's a DXM junkie.
Dextromethorphan.
As in cough syrup?
He wasn't taking
it for his cough.
It's cheap, available at
your corner drugstore,
and taken in high
doses, it's a dumb drug.
Dumb drug? He
obviously hasn't...
He's smart compared to you,
he's a moron compared
to what he was.
Robotripping lowers the IQ,
it also causes brain damage.
Unless taken with the
proper amount of ethanol,
about one drink per day.
He wasn't abusing the booze
and taking the cough
remedy medicinally,
he was abusing the cough meds
and taking the booze medicinally.
Bravo.
Why would you do that?
If you had a gift, why
would you just throw it away?
I didn't throw it away. I
just turned it down a little.
When my brain was on low, everything
didn't seem so miserable any more.
Life was bearable.
I thought that I did that.
You do.
Long-term abuse of DXM
explains all your symptoms.
Even, oh, sweet
irony, your cough.
Whole bowel lavage,
activated charcoal.
We get all traces of
it out of your system,
you'll be the unhappiest
little courier in no time.
I don't think I
can live without it.
You'd be surprised
what you can live without.
Make him a genius.
I can't believe it. He looks
so much better already.
We were thinking
about calling GQ.
Lavage has removed all
traces of DXM from his body.
You're drawing
again. What is it?
Just doodles.
No, it's not. Come on,
Jimmy, I want to know.
This is a toroidal
helicon plasma device.
It determines the
amount of energy
expended by the
subatomic particles.
I'm thirsty. Could you get
me a juice or something?
Yeah. Of course.
I'm so happy, Jimmy.
I told you.
You know what the difference
between her IQ and mine is?
91 points.
In relation, she's closer to
a gibbon than she is to me.
Having sex with her
would be an act of bestiality.
I assume you didn't marry her
for her skill in
Applied Physics.
I just wish she could spell it.
You really think
you'd be happier
with someone who
could spell better?
No.
That's the problem.
I'm the one who's a jerk.
But I owe her everything.
I want to want to be with her.
And when I'm clear, I...
I can't.
Fainting, dizziness,
shortness of breath?
Sometimes.
Is the wait always this long?
Only on days that end in
"day." Diarrhea, weight loss?
A bit.
Don't you ever shave?
Yeah, once a week.
How about you?
Stomach pain, tenderness?
Every now and then. Are you
this rude to all your patients?
Oh, yes, don't
think you're special.
So we got a lot of vague,
unverifiable symptoms,
yet all the physical
signs are perfectly normal.
What do you think I
have? I'm not sure,
but I think it's a lame job.
What?
You're a rat. Insurance
company sends you out
to check on the
quality of medical care.
That's ridiculous.
Is it really?
'Cause you seem
a lot more interested
in asking questions
than answering them.
Handwriting in your medical
records is obviously not a doctor's,
'cause I can almost read it.
And when you went out for a
urine sample, I looked in your purse.
Found the list of questions
you were supposed to memorize
before you came to the
clinic. I was looking for gum.
You're an ass.
Put it in your report.
I'll tell you what. I'll
give you 20 bucks
if you'll pretend that I'm not
when we leave this room.
Remember, first ice, then heat.
If you have any problems,
don't hesitate to call me.
Thank you, Dr. House.
Wait a second. Where's Cuddy?
Gone for the day.
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Sorry, can't remember if I've
mocked you yet for being a male nurse.
I think this counts.
Fair enough.
That isn't the man I married.
Yes, he is. He's just
smarter. Give him some time.
I'm sure... He hates me.
His body is going through
withdrawal. He's adjusting.
Maybe he never
loved me. Not really.
Maybe we never really
had anything at all.
Somebody help!
I can't feel my legs.
Anywhere. Nothing.
We have to talk about this.
It's late. I'm tired.
I know it's a big pay cut,
but I'll always have the
chance to make money.
I won't always have
the chance to do this job.
That's what you think?
That it's about the money?
So it's that I didn't consult
you before I took the job?
That was offensive, but
it's not about that either.
So then...
Can you give
me the first letter?
When we got married,
you were an intern working
30-hour shifts, doing grunt work,
and we both put up
with it because we knew
that it was leading
to something better.
In your private practice, you
are the boss. You call the shots.
But now, you're 40 years old,
you're still doing grunt work.
That's what this is about?
You think I'm a wuss?
He made you miss
Thanksgiving dinner.
Vitamin B12 deficiency
gives us anemia, numbness...
Not a stroke.
If he has a vascular
malformation...
Anemia's not macrocytic.
Sorry to inconvenience you.
Dying patients can
be so thoughtless.
Don't.
Great comeback. Is that
Oscar Wilde? Come on, people.
Bone marrow malignancy.
Wouldn't produce schistocytes.
Lupus. HOUSE: Gee,
thanks for coming in.
ANA was negative.
What about you?
You got any predictable
drivel you'd like to add?
I think they've given
you enough already.
At least they're trying, not
just sitting there like roadkill.
Give me something!
Give me something or
I'll get your ex-smarter half
on the phone and ask her.
House...
You're going to be
pressing charges?
Against the ottoman
I tripped over?
Against Chase.
I'm pretty sure the
ottoman was acting alone.
You free for dinner
this weekend?
At least three other
people saw him do it.
Mass hysteria. Either night?
I can't have doctors
punching each other out.
Oh, my God, who got punched?
And more importantly,
for Chase's sake,
I need to know if he's
able to handle himself
or if I should be
getting him some help.
Chase couldn't have
punched anyone.
He was with me when I
tripped over the ottoman.
If you're not planning on eating
this weekend, maybe a movie?
I'm not doing this, House.
It's not fun anymore.
Just do your job.
I need your help.
What happened to your face?
I was mowing the lawn
when the phone rang.
You're a computer. I'm gonna
feed you data, and you analyze it.
What are you gonna feed me,
20 years of medical
knowledge, too?
It's not gonna work.
I know. But I don't
have anyone else to ask.
It's lonely, isn't it?
It's not that bad.
Then you're not that smart.
You ever try to kill yourself?
Not quickly.
I did.
Twelve years ago, I jumped off
the top of my eight-story building
into a dumpster bin
the day before pick-up.
I broke my collar bone,
my leg and three ribs.
When I was in the hospital,
they put me on narcotics
and suddenly
everything was just better.
I didn't feel
isolated or lonely.
That's where I met my wife.
She was so happy and dumb.
And I was
smart and miserable.
You tell me who the genius is.
I fell in love with her
buzzed out of my head
and I knew I wanted
to stay that way forever.
Enjoy.
Easier on your
conscience if I die an idiot?
What's a conscience?
Which ribs did you break in
the fall? Down the left side?
Yeah, bottom three. But
that was 12 years ago.
This probably cost me my
marriage, so it better be awesome.
Ferrous oxide contrast?
It gets absorbed by the spleen,
unless he doesn't have one,
in which case it's absorbed
by the liver and fries that.
You're killing him?
You think I opened him up
and didn't take out his spleen?
All organs do look kind of
the same, red and squishy.
Oh, my God.
Accessory spleens.
Okay, that is amazing.
Twelve years, eight
stories and a dumpster ago,
he broke three ribs,
damaged his spleen.
Bits of it split off, circulated
through his blood stream
until they landed and
attached somewhere else.
So, it is TTP.
I just didn't remove
all of his spleens.
Sixteen splenectomies,
pretty sure he gets a set
of steak knives with that.
I can outrun you.
Sorry about the nose. And
the eye. And the eyebrow.
Guess I deserved it.
Well, if I thought that, I
wouldn't be apologizing.
Your fist slipped?
Everybody kept bugging
me, asking if I was okay.
So you bust my nose to
keep people off your back?
Pretty much.
Making people even
more worried about you.
Maybe. But at least they're
not talking to me about it.
Fair enough.
Cheers.
Thank you.
Don't be so grateful.
You'll be delivering packages
for 70 years to pay for it.
Well, thanks for our talk.
It's been a while since I had
a stimulating conversation.
So what are you going to do?
Go back to my life.
Which one?
The one that has my wife in it.
Robotripping.
How does she feel about that?
Well, she doesn't have to
know. It's worked for 12 years.
Tell your brain I said goodbye.
Einstein's giving
himself a lobotomy,
and you're cool with that?
Ignorance is bliss.
Hold that pose.
I'll start with t-shirts and
mugs and see how it goes.
Home early.
What happened to him?
You beat up House?
Just one right hook.
Why? What happened?
You were right.
I told him we need to lay down
some ground rules, it got a little heated.
That's not what I
meant. Is he okay?
Are you going to
be fired? Arrested?
Everything's fine.
Wow.
Dr. Cuddy.
Can we at least be civil?
How's your nose?
It's okay.
Does your kid like animals?
I got tickets to that
holiday carnival.
I hear they have
a nice petting zoo.
I think I was
pretty clear before.
I don't mean with me.
Here. Take them. Enjoy.
No, thanks.
They're not fake.
I didn't steal them.
One of the nurses was selling
them for her kid's scout troop.
I know it doesn't make
things right between us,
but I just wanted to
do something nice.
I don't want them.
Okay.
I'll see you tomorrow.
They didn't split up.
She wouldn't take the tickets.
Of course. Windtalker
code for "we never split up."
House, she told
you multiple times
she wants nothing
to do with you.
I wasn't gonna be there.
She just felt guilty that I felt
guilty, so she couldn't take them.
Either that or she didn't
want to appease you.
These weren't reparations,
just a simple gesture of
remorse, and she slapped it down.
They didn't break up.
She just wanted me to
think that, so I'd back off.
Dare I ask what you're gonna do?
Nothing.
I said they'd either break
up or they'd stay together.
They didn't break up.
And you're okay with that?
It is what it is.
Good for you.
House knows I lied.
Why? What did he say?
Nothing. I could just tell.
You gonna stage another breakup?
No.
Oh.
Hi.
It seems like he's
going to leave us alone.
Mmm. Why would he do that?
I'm not completely sure.
So, we have his blessing?
I guess so.
I made you some
eggplant Parmesan.
And maybe House
isn't so bad after all.
That would be nice, wouldn't it?