Let's say you're
standing in an OR,
staring at an aneurysm
that's embedded deep
into a patient's frontal lobe.
There are three things
you'll need to remove it.
Mmm. Zola's up.
No, she's still
asleep. We're good.
No, no. She's up.
Did you hear something? No.
But you know she's up? Yes.
You'll need confidence...
You'll need an 11-blade...
And some really good instincts.
Come here, you.
No, no.
Okay, so then we coax those
initial cartilage cells to multiply...
Don't look at your cards.
So... Then we coax those
initial cartilage cells to multiply.
After two months, the,
uh, original 200,000 have...
Now I've lost my place.
Relax.
No, I can't relax, okay?
I have to do this speech at the TED
Conference in less than 48 hours.
The TED Conference.
Um, do that thing
where you picture
everyone in the audience naked.
That helps.
I'm just... I'm gonna
start from the top, okay?
Articular cartilage.
Articular cartilage regeneration
offers new hope for patients...
What are you doing?
I'm, um, helping.
Mmm.
Good morning.
Oh, I'd say so.
Gas tanker slammed into an SUV
on the I-5. Caused a huge pileup.
No telling how many traumas
are coming in. We should...
Get going.
I have it right here. - Okay...
Hey. Did a giant
tanker really flip over?
Where's Wilson?
With Grey. You've got me today.
So how big was the accident?
Do you think anyone
got impaled? I...
Wilson!
Stop sucking face
and check your pager.
I can't believe I
didn't hear my pager.
Yeah. It's hard to hear when
you have a tongue in your ear.
Dr. Wilson, right?
Um, you saw us the other night.
I'm Casey Hedges.
That's my son Parker.
Right. Is he still sick?
Well, his fever was down
when I left for my shift.
I'm a waitress.
But then my neighbor called.
She said it spiked again,
and then when I got
home, he had this rash.
You've been giving him
the meds, lots of fluids?
Yeah, but his fever's
still above 103,
and it's been like that
for over a week now.
And I mean, I know that
you told me it's a virus...
Probably adenovirus.
The fever can last at
least five days with it.
It's not that unusual.
I've been tracking the
spikes in his fever, and I...
I looked up his symptoms online
and wrote down a bunch of stuff.
Roseola, shingles, lupus.
I just...
I can't explain it,
but I know my kid.
This is not a
virus. I just feel it.
Come on.
Okay. I'll go get your chart.
Dr. Bradshaw, call recovery.
Shepherd, what are you doing?
I got your page. A tanker blew?
A tanker didn't blow.
I meant, what are
you doing with Ross?
Didn't you get the memo?
Oh, we're supposed
to read those?
Yeah, I need you to
start using other interns.
I can't have attendings
playing favorites.
These kids need a
well-rounded education.
Ross, are you feeling
poorly rounded?
No, sir. I'm very rounded.
See? He's very rounded.
Hey. I heard about the
accident. A tanker blew?
A tanker didn't blow.
Bailey, I haven't seen you
outside your genome lab for a week.
Oh, speaking of which, when
can I have my genome mapped?
I have an aunt who
died of breast cancer.
It can happen in males.
Uh, no. Yeah, it can.
It's just now I'm thinking
about your breasts.
When did you say
that tanker blew?
The tanker did not blow.
Oh. What...
Don't look so disappointed.
Cam Miller, restrained passenger
in a vehicle
T-boned on its side.
Vital signs stable. GCS is 14.
He's been disoriented.
Whoa!
Yeah, the tanker's been
leaking gas all over the road.
We did a primary
decontamination on scene,
but we had to get
him outta there.
Okay, no open flames,
no smokers, no use of cauteries.
Be safe, people.
Rachel Dawson, 42. Restrained
passenger in a car with front-end damage.
Closed head injury.
BP 110 over 70. Pulse 95.
Where's my son? Who has Ethan?
Does my husband have Ethan?
I told her they're
right behind us.
Let's get her evaluated.
Give us about five minutes.
Rachel!
Rachel, I'm here.
Paul Dawson, 45.
Restrained driver
with major intrusion into
his area of the vehicle.
Bruises to the chest.
BP 90 over 60. Pulse 120.
Where's... Where's my
son? Where's Ethan?
He's on his way. Don't worry.
Ethan Dawson, 10 years
old. Restrained in the backseat.
No obvious injuries
except for a minor wrist lac.
He was walking
around at the scene.
Ethan, my name is Dr. Hunt.
Are my mom and dad dead?
No, no. They're right inside.
You'll see them
soon. I got you. Okay?
Okay. Okay, let's go.
They said it could
be cat scratch fever
or Stevens-Johnson syndrome...
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa. Who said this?
One of those
medical sites online.
It's strep.
Casey, Parker's rapid test came
back positive for strep throat.
I have a prescription
for amoxicillin.
Oh, God. Thank God. I
just knew it wasn't a virus.
As soon as we
get you signed out,
you can take Parker
home. Thank you.
Well, I hope your
son feels better.
Dr. Zimmer to radiology.
Hey, hey.
Hey! Hey.
Where's my sweatshirt?
I want to step
outside for a smoke.
Yeah, sure, if you want to die.
Sweetie, I don't need
a lecture from you...
She means you're
covered in gasoline, sweetie.
Now sit your butt back down.
Well, if he checks out,
let's make room, okay?
We need the space.
Mm.
This little guy checks out okay.
Okay. Finish
bandaging his wrist,
and then have
somebody wait with him...
But... I thought you said
I could see my parents.
So, Mr. Dawson, there's a
little fluid around your lungs.
I'm a little concerned, so
we're gonna take you up to CT.
Widened mediastinum.
I'm betting his aorta
is shredded beef.
This is the patient's son.
Oh, sorry.
Uh, we gotta take him up to CT.
Dad.
Ethan. Hey, I'm okay.
I'm gonna be fine.
Stay with Mom. Stay
with Mom, all right?
Where is my mom?
Let's go find out, okay?
Nurses station.
Now look right there. "RD."
See? That's your mom.
Now it says that they are taking
her up to get some pictures taken.
And Dr. Murphy
here will let you know
when you can see her, okay?
Call social services.
Kepner, how are we doing?
Take a look.
From ambulance arrival,
the entire intake took
22 minutes 11 seconds.
Your new ER works.
Mm-hmm. Just like it's
supposed to. Mm-hmm.
Ohh!
What the hell was that?
The tanker must have blown. Hey.
Hey, listen, it was
just a big explosion.
And it was really far away,
and everybody's fine, okay?
Everybody is safe, all right?
All right.
Fire!
Get him on the ground!
Over here! Put it out! I guess
he went out for that smoke.
Call the burn unit. We're
gonna need a gurney.
Coming through. We
need another large-bore IV.
Right away.
I got your page. Is this...
The human fireball.
Yeah, let's get him to the burn
unit right away. Okay, let's roll.
Clear the way.
Everybody, listen up.
We're gonna be
receiving more patients.
So buckle up. This is
gonna be a long day.
Elyse Cruse, 37 weeks pregnant,
hypotensive in the field,
with abdominal bruising
and second-degree
burns on her right arm.
Page OB. WOMAN: Right away.
I'm Dr. Kepner. Can
you tell me your name?
My name's Elyse. Elyse Cruse.
Okay, Elyse... But I
don't care about me.
Please just do whatever
you can to save my baby.
Just save my little girl.
How about I save you both?
Yeah, that would be great.
Okay.
Could you call my
husband? Mm-hmm.
Okay, I don't want you to
worry. It's gonna be okay.
Hey.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
And what about my son?
We'll get an update on
your family soon, Rachel.
What's the word?
Good news is the kid's fine.
It's just a little cut that
Murphy cleaned up.
Mm-hmm.
Bad news is Yang has
the husband in surgery.
Possibly an aortic transection.
Oh.
Speaking of bad news.
Ugh. Right frontal
lobe hemorrhage.
That could be why
she's perseverating.
Oh, cool. Is that an
epidural hemorrhage?
Sorry.
I'm interrupting.
You guys were having
a moment or something.
What do you want, Brooks?
Well, Chief Hunt says I
need to learn brainy things.
So I'm with you guys today.
Abdominal
tenderness to palpation.
Damn it. She's having decels.
Her BP is dropping.
Okay, Elyse, stay with me. Okay?
Just try to stay with me.
Is my baby okay?
We're gonna roll you on
your side right now, okay?
You can't hear my baby's heart?
Try not to worry. Page OB again.
Right now.
Come on. Come on.
Where's OB? What is happening?
Kepner, she's bleeding.
What?
Cord's prolapsed.
We need to secure it.
What is happening?
Your baby's umbilical
cord has dropped,
and it's now trapped
against her body,
and that's why
she's in distress.
Ma'am, we need to
keep the cord inside
so your baby doesn't
lose any more oxygen.
To do that, I'm gonna have
to place my hand inside.
I'm really sorry, but it's
gonna hurt a lot, okay?
Did you call my husband?
Where is my husband?
I did. I called him.
Hold my hand.
Okay.
Okay? Okay.
We need to get this baby
out. All right, where's OB?
Tell them to meet us in the OR now!
- Right away.
Elyse, we're going
to surgery right now
to take care of
you and your baby.
Okay?
Matthew?
Oh, hi.
Yeah, Superman
here broke protocol
and ran into the crash to
shield a kid from the blast
with his own body.
Well, it seemed like the
right thing to do at the time.
He could've died.
Yeah, but I didn't. I'm... Ow.
I'm fine.
Just go ahead and go.
You got more important
patients than me.
Go save a life or something.
Yeah, go ahead.
I'll check him out.
Um, okay. I will be
back as soon as I can.
Just don't go crazy
and go into shock or
bleed out or something...
April, I'm fine.
I'll see you soon.
Please don't be surgical.
Okay, I'm on it.
Oh, it's surgical.
Hey, there you
are. Oh, no. Me first.
Okay, okay. What have
we got? What have we got?
Yeah, a bike messenger
caught in the blast.
My patient's in a lot of pain.
Everybody's patient's
in a lot of pain.
Yeah, these are all
gonna need surgery.
Page Dr. Garrity.
My plane leaves for...
For TED in four hours.
You're going to TED? Mm-hmm.
Lucky. My roommate
went last year.
Did tequila shots
with Bill Gates.
It's a fancy people frat party.
Oh, you'll be singing a
different tune next year
when you're there
with your genome stuff.
Ooh, map my genomes.
That sounds like fun.
It's not a spa
treatment. It's science.
Just like building
new cartilage.
As I say in my
speech... Okay, Callie.
Callie. The patients.
No, you're right.
I should keep it fresh for
the conference anyway.
Excuse me.
Uh, just looking
for a status report
for the patient's kid.
The injury extends
into the aortic arch.
So in order to maintain
head perfusion,
I have to bypass
in two circuits.
I'm just waiting on Russell
for a second opinion.
You had to call
Russell for this?
Not really.
But ever since I
became his boss,
I like to make him
think that he's still mine.
3-0 prolene.
So could I give the
kid a time frame?
Uh, give me an
hour. I'll know better.
Okay.
Dr. Shepherd, where did you get,
"It's a beautiful
day to save lives"?
Is that from a movie?
No, it's not from a movie.
Are you sure?
'Cause sometimes I think
I'm making something up,
and then I'm watching
a detergent commercial,
and I realize, that's
where I got that from.
Brooks, you know how sometimes
people downplay the difficulty of a task
by saying, "It's
not brain surgery"?
Sure.
This is brain surgery.
Right.
Sorry.
What are you doing?
He makes me nervous,
and I just want him to like me.
Clearly not the way to do it.
Okay, Ross,
now I have exposed the dura,
so why don't you come
closer and get a better look?
He loves you.
I'd been in 20 surgeries
before he ever invited
me to his side of the table.
It could take a while,
but he'll warm up to you.
Oh.
You've got some
fast hands, Brooks.
And the baby's out.
I noticed you haven't
thanked me yet
for catching your
patient's prolapsed cord.
I was on my way to the ER.
Yeah, taking your
own sweet time.
You want to cool it, man?
You're being very
unprofessional.
Okay, let's begin to
explore the abdomen.
Oh, God, Elyse. She's
losing too much blood.
More lap pads. Now!
Burn center is full.
I just closed us to new
patients. What else?
Social services came
for the little boy...
Ethan! No!
Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
Where you going?
I want to see my parents.
Sorry. He's a runner.
Honey, we need to go.
No, I don't want
to. You need sleep.
No, I'm not going anywhere!
Yes, you are. You're
coming with me. Now come.
No. Look, he's worried
about his parents.
How about we set
you up in a room,
and you can stay with him there?
That's not a permanent solution.
I know, but it's for one night.
And then we can
figure out the rest later.
How does that sound?
Yeah? Sound good?
Okay.
Come on. We need to go now.
The baby's dad just arrived.
Myers is bringing him up.
I still don't know what
she sees in that D-bag.
Right? What does
she see in that guy?
He's so handsome
and friendly,
charming, nice.
Vince, this is Dr. Karev.
He's been taking
care of your little girl.
Look at her. She...
She's perfect.
She's doing really well.
And I spoke to Dr. Kepner.
Your wife is still in surgery.
We should have an update soon.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
Your baby's pretty darn cute.
Want to hold her?
Also sensitive.
Did I mention he's sensitive?
We went home, but
then his fever got higher.
It doesn't make sense.
Ma'am, we'll be with
you as soon as we can.
We're extremely backed up.
Yeah, I understand everyone's
very sick, but so is my son.
Casey, what's wrong? What
are you doing back here?
This isn't strep.
Whatever you
prescribed him did nothing.
It takes at least 24 hours
for antibiotics to start working.
Yeah, but then he should be
getting better, and he's getting worse.
This isn't strep.
Please just calm down.
Calm down? Calm
down? My son is sick.
He's sick, and you
gave him medicine,
and it's not working.
And now you just
keep dismissing us,
just like all the
other doctors did
at Seattle Pres
and Urgent Care...
Wait. Hang on.
You've been to both of
those places, too, this week?
Yeah, and I'm not gonna let
you push me around like they did.
You either don't care about
my son or you don't believe me.
Either way, you suck,
and I want someone else.
Find me another doctor!
Keep an eye on Rachel's ICP.
Update me with any changes.
Will do. Anything else?
Yes, Brooks, think fast.
Anything else medically?
A neuro exam every two hours.
Contact me immediately
if there's any sign of
herniation or a new hemorrhage.
You got it?
Yes, sir.
Good.
Dr. Shepherd, I'm open.
That was my phone.
I'm sorry you have to
stand there for so long,
dealing with my ass.
Ah, it's fine. I'm
a plastic surgeon.
It's not that big a deal to me.
Actually, can we not
talk while you do that?
Sure. I feel for you, dude.
But I have seen way worse.
Okay. I'm gonna come back later.
April...
It's cool. I'm just gonna...
I'm gonna leave now. Yep. Now.
Like that.
That was worse.
He's cranky, he's
not sleeping well,
and then he's got
these really chapped lips,
and then today it
was this weird rash.
And how are you doing?
Are you getting enough sleep?
No, of course not. I
told you, he's up all night.
And it's just you, no husband,
no boyfriend, or partner?
It's just me.
Well, that's a lot
of pressure on you.
Are you a psychiatrist?
Casey,
just listen...
Oh, my God. You are.
You think I'm crazy.
You think I skip work
and I drag my kid to
the ER, because it's fun,
because I enjoy this?
My son is sick,
okay? He is sick.
He used to wake me
up every morning at dawn
by jumping on my bed.
Now I can barely get him up.
He does this thing
before school...
I let him run out and
get the newspaper...
It's his big-kid
chore. He loves it.
He hasn't done it
in a week and a half.
I show him cartoons,
and he doesn't care.
I try to get him to eat...
I mean, I even gave him
potato chips for breakfast once,
and... Nothing.
I know
that I am not a doctor,
but you have to believe me.
You have to. You have to.
Hey. Hey, hey, hey.
I believe you.
We're gonna take
care of your son.
Admit him.
I believe you.
Yes, I alerted security.
Of course. I looked all over.
Where's Ethan?
Hang on. I don't know.
I went to the restroom. When
I came back, he was gone.
When? I told you, he's a runner.
When did you lose him?
About a half-hour ago.
Yeah.
No, Shepherd still hates me.
Now he just makes me do tricks.
It takes more than just
good instincts with Shepherd.
You have to be
prepared, diligent...
Says his star pupil.
I'm his circus act.
Wait. Mom.
Hang on, buddy. Mom.
What are you doing?
Who are you? What...
Why don't we go outside, okay?
It's me, Mom. Ethan.
It's okay, ma'am. Ethan.
It's your son.
No, it's not. Who
is he? Who is that?
Who are you?
Help me! What's happening?
Who is this? What's
happening to me?
Help me! Help me, please!
So you're in the
semifinals, huh?
What position do you play?
Coach stuck me at left defender.
Hey, left defender is crucial.
I guess.
So...
Why doesn't she know who I am?
Ethan, your mom hurt
her head pretty bad.
And sometimes that can
make people act really weird,
even with the
people that they love.
So she's gonna remember me?
I think so.
Ethan, I...
I need you to stay
with the social worker.
The lady? Mm-hmm.
Can I stay with you?
No, no. No, I have
to... I have to work.
I have to help your
mom and dad get better,
and they're gonna
get better quicker
if they know that
you're somewhere safe.
So can you help
me out with that?
You done?
And I'm telling you...
The guys bring the
ball down the wings,
left defender can save the game.
She has a new hematoma
in the temporal lobe.
Now why would that cause
her not to recognize her son?
Uh, the hematoma
could be putting pressure
on the white matter tracts,
causing her to experience
symptoms of Capgras syndrome.
Good. And what would
your plan of action be?
Relieve the pressure with
evacuation of the hematoma.
What about watching her coags
and correcting her ICP with mannitol
and aggressive ICP drainage?
That's a good thought, Brooks,
but, in this case, I
think Ross is right.
Uh, find an OR
that's available. Okay.
Oh, Brooks.
You never miss, do you?
Star pupil.
Circus act.
His CAT scan is
completely normal.
I know this must be
so annoying for you.
I mean, I know I know nothing,
but I did all this research...
No, not at all.
Let's go through it.
Please.
What's first?
Okay, are you sure
that it's not lupus?
He doesn't fit the criteria,
and the rash is quite different.
What else?
What about, uh, enterovirus
or meningitis?
Well, I can see why
you would think that,
but, again, the rash
associated with enterovirus
is commonly distributed
over the hands and the feet.
And we ruled out meningitis
when his spinal
tap came back clear.
Okay. Um...
I read this one article
about something
called Kawasaki disease.
They said it can
cause a heart attack.
That's a good one.
It would explain the
fever and the rash.
But there would be
other symptoms...
The strawberry tongue
and peeling skin and red eyes
and no positive strep.
Dr. Grey... What
do you think this is?
I think it's strep.
Yeah, but then he
would be getting better.
I'm sorry. I know
that you're a surgeon.
You don't even normally
handle cases like this.
No, it's, uh...
I own the hospital, and I
can do whatever I want.
I want to do some more tests.
You and me, Elyse, we're a team.
Ever since Professor
Sheldon paired
us up in that
stupid poli-sci class.
I don't work without you.
So you can't leave me or us.
We're supposed to be together.
Elyse likes the name
"Rose" for the baby.
What do you think?
I think it's beautiful.
Okay, honey.
Rosie it is.
I'm gonna go down and see her.
I love you.
I'm just gonna
check on her burns.
How's she doing?
Not well.
She's acidotic, and
her creatinine's sky-high.
You know, they dated in college.
But then her dad died,
so she had to leave
school, and they lost touch
till about three years ago,
when they both randomly decided
to move from
Wisconsin to Seattle
and joined the
same bowling league.
How weird is that?
That people join
bowling leagues?
The universe kept
pulling them together,
just waiting for
them to see that
they were meant to be together,
and then...
And then a tanker explodes,
and she ends up in the hospital.
Yeah.
Your paramedic is
gonna be fine, by the way.
Mm. Ooh, Bailey.
You have to map me.
I need to know which
parent I take after.
My dad eats three salads a
day and has high cholesterol.
My mother, bunions.
If Torres gets
mapped, I get mapped.
Hey, my genome
sequencer is not a toy.
It is an expensive and
complex piece of equipment,
to be used for people
with serious conditions.
Oh, like this guy?
'Cause you should
really map his genome,
look for the idiot gene.
He managed to snap his elbow
after lighting himself on fire
when he wanted a smoke
while covered in gasoline.
Oh.
Callie, I asked for an ortho
consult, and they sent me to you.
Weren't you supposed
to leave hours ago?
I was, but then... Baked Alaska.
I'm so sorry.
Well, hey, look at it this way.
Now you have time to spice
up your speech for next year.
And I still need an ortho
consult in OR 3
when you're done.
Spice... Spice up?
No, I didn't say that.
Uh... You did, though.
No, no. I'm just
saying that these...
These talks are never about
what they're... About.
I heard one about
floating algae pods,
and it ended up reminding me
to live every day to the fullest.
Uh-huh.
It was very inspiring.
Yeah. Yeah, and yours
is just about, you know...
Cartilage, right now.
But no one sells
cartilage like you.
And it is... It's
a great speech.
You know, this invitation
was the one uncomplicated good
thing that's happened in a while,
the one thing I was
really looking forward to.
Yeah, and I'm telling
you that it's great.
No. You're telling me it's not.
Finally.
And it helps.
I feel better about not going.
I'll see you in OR 3.
So any idea when the kid's dad
is gonna get transferred
out of the CCU?
He's pretty freaked
out right now.
No, no idea.
He's stable, but his
hemoglobin is still low.
Mm. That aortic repair took
a lot longer than I thought.
Oh, I have to be back on rounds
in 29 minutes.
Oh.
Should I sleep or
should I shower?
I could sleep in the shower.
Oh, but I'm also
starving. Have you eaten?
Shoot.
Sorry, baby.
His pressure dropped out
and he went into cardiac arrest.
Hold CPR.
Pulse is V-tach.
Paddles. Charge to 200.
What happened? I
was doing my exam,
and she started bleeding
from her incisions
and her IV sites,
and then she dropped into V-fib.
We just shocked her once.
I'll take over. Charge to 150.
Push another epi. Clear.
No. No, no, no, no, no.
Come on. Give me 200. Clear!
Got him. Got him.
Clear!
Come on, Elyse!
Push 5 of epi. April.
Epi now! April, we lost her.
Okay?
I don't know why this one
is hitting me so hard.
It's not supposed
to happen this way.
It's...
It's not right.
I can't tell him. I
can't tell him. I...
And, uh, I can't make him
feel worse just 'cause I feel bad.
I'll do it.
No, no.
I'll do it. I can do it.
I just...
I need a minute.
Okay.
Hey.
I was coming to give the
mom an update on her baby...
Elyse Cruse.
Yeah, she didn't...
She didn't make it.
We were gonna go
tell the husband now.
No, I was. I was. I will.
I just... I need...
Oh.
I just have to pull
myself together.
Chest Peckwell's
name's on the file.
You want me to make him do it?
Yes. Yeah.
More ice.
Could it be Munchausen by proxy?
What? That she's
making her own kid sick?
No. She just has
a strong feeling
that it's something
more than strep.
Or she's crazy.
What's his core temp?
Still 93.
I mean, it's strep, right?
If it walks like a duck
and quacks like a duck...
Mer, the duck's
strep test positive.
What happened?
He had an MI. He coded.
Why didn't you wake me?
Why would I? He's my patient.
So what are you doing?
Uh, therapeutic
hypothermia, just 24 hours.
I'm cooling his body so
he'll avoid another attack.
But he just had a surgery.
This could increase his
risk of infection and bleeding.
Or it could save his life.
Did Russell agree to this?
You know, I don't
know. I didn't ask him.
'Cause he's my patient.
Dr. Keller, Extension 2249.
I think he's gonna
tell your teacher.
Okay, Ross.
Open up the bone flap.
Yes, sir. You got it.
Good.
Okay. A little bit more.
Thank you, sir.
Brooks, why don't you step up
and help me excise the dura?
Really?
Yeah. Switch with Ross.
Okay.
So when I cut, I want you to
coagulate the bleeders
with the bipolar.
Exactly.
God, you have
fast hands, Brooks.
I'm so sorry, Casey.
But I can't find anything
wrong with Parker
other than the strep.
So you're gonna discharge him?
I can't find a reason
to keep him here.
It's not surgical, his labs
keep coming back clean.
I know I keep saying
this, and I know it's crazy.
I mean, I can hear
myself sounding crazy...
But this feeling won't go away,
this feeling that there is
something wrong with him.
And I know you're telling me
that there's nothing wrong with him
and that I should believe
you because you're a doctor
and I'm just a waitress.
But how do I ignore this?
How do ignore my gut
telling me that there is something
seriously wrong with my son?
Hey, you seen super
douche around?
Peckwell?
Jason?
Ah, conference room.
Myers.
Oh, Grey's paging me.
I'll catch you later. Hey.
Vince Cruse's
wife didn't make it.
I figure the news might
come better from you.
I'm sorry. She's not
my patient anymore.
I passed her off to Kepner.
Okay, but his wife was your
patient when she first came in.
The guy knows
you. He trusts you.
Dude, I'm sorry, but she
is not my responsibility.
You're a douche.
No, you're a douche.
You don't have a problem
with how I do my job.
You have a problem
with who I'm dating.
You're really not coming
with me to talk to him?
What do you think?
Guess I'll be doing
your job, again.
Dr. Leon, call the blood bank.
You paged me?
Oh, we're discharging Parker?
Yes, I have it all ready to go,
but I just need you to go through
it with me all one more time.
Okay.
Latest white count? 18.
Platelet count?
500,000.
High fever.
Unresponsive to meds.
It's gotta just be a weird
presentation of strep, right?
Actually, hang on. The
labs were just updated.
Yesterday's rapid test
was a false positive.
The strep culture's negative.
Who are you calling?
No one. I'm
checking my calendar.
What day did his fever start?
Wednesday, I think.
Damn. We're already at Day 10.
What's Day 10? Did
Parker have red eyes?
Uh, he was asleep the
last time I checked on him.
Let's go.
Oh. Is everything okay?
We need to check Parker's eyes.
What... What's going
on? You're scaring me.
Page peds, page cardio,
start an IVIG right away.
We're already on Day 10.
What? What is happening?
Casey, if we're right, this
could be Kawasaki disease.
But we need to get this IV
started on Parker right away.
We're still within the window to
prevent permanent heart damage,
but we have to do it right now.
Oh, no.
No.
Casey, hey.
Hey.
You okay? Yeah.
Okay.
So this is Parker's echo.
That right there is the
fluid around his heart.
The IVIG will fix that.
He's gonna need another
echo in six months.
And... Do you remember this?
Mm.
Parker has Kawasaki disease.
You fought for your son.
You didn't give up.
You saved his life today.
You were right.
I was right?
Dr. Shepherd, I've run a
full post-op exam on Rachel.
Mm-hmm. I'm gonna monitor her
for the next four
hours, but don't worry.
I'll still be here early
tomorrow morning
to prep for
Mr. Yoshida's craniotomy.
Yeah, Ross, about
that. Hunt's right.
Everybody needs a shot at neuro,
and you need a chance
to see other specialties,
so Brooks is gonna be on my
service for the rest of the week.
Oh.
Okay.
I'll see you when
it's your turn again.
Arizona, I just want to go home.
I just want to curl
up in a ball, do...
Whoa.
What the hell? What is this?
Your TED speech. RICHARD: Sit.
What? How?
How?
I made a call. We set up a
video stream to the conference.
You're going on live.
Oh! I don't have my notes.
Oh, yes. Yes. Yes, you do.
Even though I know
you know it by heart.
I mean, I know it by
heart. Just start talking.
Okay, it's almost time. But I...
It's a terrible speech.
It's a great speech.
I'm not... Ah. Ah.
Oh, no.
Okay.
Five, four, three...
Coming to you live from
Grey Sloan Memorial Hospital
in Seattle, Dr. Calliope Torres.
Just talk. Just be who you are.
Hi.
I'm Dr. Callie Torres.
And...
I've had a pretty bad year.
I was almost killed
in a car wreck.
Then I nearly lost
my wife in an accident
that claimed the
life of my best friend
and the father of my child.
And some other stuff.
I'm an orthopedic surgeon by
trade and I work with cartilage,
so I've spent a lot
of time thinking about
what holds us together
when things fall apart.
I'm so sorry I haven't been
to visit you more today.
Are you okay?
Do you...
Do you believe that God plans
for two people to be together?
Yeah, I do.
My patient died.
Her husband is left
with their new baby.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
It Just... It doesn't...
It doesn't make any sense.
Why would he bring
these two people together,
make them fall in love,
open up to one another,
make them feel like they
were meant to be together,
and then just pull them apart?
April...
I get it.
I know today scared
you, but I'm here.
I'm... I'm fine.
I promise you, I'm
not going anywhere.
And I love you, too.
Come here.
Dr. Albright to OR 1.
I talked to Russell.
And he agrees with your
course of hypothermia,
although he may only be
agreeing because he's afraid of you.
Like you said...
You're his boss now.
Yeah, what's going on?
This guy has a
little boy, Cristina,
who is scared to death
that both of his parents...
Oh, my God. A little boy?
Why didn't you say that?
I would've rethought everything.
I would've actually
tried to save the man.
Cristina...
Do you think that I
would make a decision
that is not in the best
interest of my patient?
I just want this kid
to see his dad again.
I do, too.
I know.
It's been a hell of a day.
Yeah, let's get outta here.
Yeah. Um, I gotta wrap
up a few things first.
Okay, sure.
Okay.
There are some feelings
that refuse to go away.
They're little distractions
whispering in your ear.
Thank you for not
being a douche.
You're welcome.
Where's Wilson?
Probably with assface.
Beer, please.
You got it.
Hey.
I know what you're doing.
And apparently
you think I'm too nice
to do anything about it,
but you're wrong.
So you can try to snake
neuro out from under me,
but just so we're clear,
I'm not going down
without a fight.
I'm not...
Save it.
Some things just
get under your skin.
So she's sleeping?
She made it through
the day, just like your dad.
They both have a lot of good
doctors taking care of them.
And I can see them tomorrow?
Yeah.
But right now...
Right now we need to
get you back to your room
so you can get some sleep.
All right?
Hey, you know,
I played some left
defender myself.
So you played soccer?
Mm. I did.
Did you score any goals?
Mnh-mnh.
Look, Mommy. I
made this for you.
Aw.
Buddy.
Try as you might...
Thank you.
You can't ignore your instincts.
Hi, Dr. Bailey.
What do you need, Grey?
Genetically, I don't
know anything about Zola.
And I want to be
able to fight for my kid.
I want you to map her.
And if I'm gonna
have to fight for her,
I am gonna need to know if
I'm gonna be around to do it.
So I want you to map me, too.
I want to know if I'm
gonna get Alzheimer's.
It's like they say...
Hey.
Always follow your intuition.