This is Andrews' fault.
Agreed. The bourbon may
also bear some responsibility.
Agreed.
You said "fault."
You don't regret that we...
No, not at all.
Seriously. It was pretty great.
Yeah.
And definitely
shouldn't happen again.
- No, it shouldn't.
- No.
Make things too
complicated at work.
Let's chalk it up to
a "Andrews screwed us, so,
we screwed each other" impulse.
I gotta get going. I'm
covering the ER today.
Ooh, right before Christmas?
Gonna be a madhouse.
Yeah.
I love those J-I-N-G-L-E bells
Oh, those holiday
J-I-N-G-L-E bells
Oh, those happy
J-I-N-G-L-E B-E-double-L-S
I love those
J-I-N-G-L-E bells Oh
Jingle bells, jingle
bells Jingle all the way
Oh, what fun it
is to ride in a...
What is that noise?
Jingle Bells?
Two ambulances
coming in back-to-back.
Hey, we need you on
your game today, Murphy.
Okay.
Uh, male, mid-30s, found
unresponsive at Arrivals.
Restarted his heart on-site.
Low O2, wheezing, significant
airway resistance to the bag mask.
We need more
hands on deck, STAT.
I've been calling. Everyone's
left town for the holidays.
- Reznick's around.
- Weird you know that, but glad you do.
- Get Reznick in here.
- On it.
Take him to Bay 4.
Murphy, I need you
with me. What do we got?
This is Marianne Southam.
She collapsed in Baggage Claim.
Both patients came
from the airport?
It's that time of year.
Everyone's traveling.
Right leg is red and swollen.
She's complaining of chest
pain, shortness of breath,
and she has a low-grade fever.
- Did you just get off a long flight?
- Twenty hours, from Malaysia.
Deep vein thrombosis
formed while she was seated.
That explains the
red leg and the fever.
Part of the clot broke
off, traveled to her lung.
That explains the chest
pain. Pulmonary embolism.
We've lost his pulse again!
Take Marianne to Bay 5.
I'll talk you through managing
a pulmonary embolism.
I'm gonna light him up. Clear.
Got a rhythm.
Barely. He can't live
on 30 beats a minute.
His lungs are too
stiff to preoxygenate.
Fiber-optic blade
and a 7.5 ET tube.
Murphy, anti-coagulate her
with a 5,000-unit heparin bolus.
Set the ventilator
to assist-controlled.
- Heparin bolus infused.
- Fever's spiking at 103.5.
Could be ARDS from a viral
pneumonia. Get a chest X-ray.
We've lost him again.
O2 sat is 92. Your chest
pain should be getting better.
- It is. Thank you.
- Peak airway pressure's 50.
Switch the ventilator to
PRVC. Pushing IV epinephrine.
Now, you need to insert a central
line in case we go to thrombolysis.
I need you, Murphy.
Still V-fib. Push
300 of amiodarone.
Asystole. He's
still not responding.
That makes over 30 minutes
of brain and cardiac hypoxia.
Stop compressions.
Time of death, 10:07.
Have you had
contact with this man?
He was on my
flight from Malaysia.
They both have vesicular
rashes on their necks.
Whatever infection killed
him, she may have it, too.
This is a negative
pressure room,
designed so no air flows out.
It keeps germs from spreading.
Because whatever I
have is gonna kill me,
just like the man
from the plane?
Your symptoms are
not as severe as his.
Although yours will probably
get worse as the virus progresses.
We don't know for sure
whether you have the same thing.
We know nothing about him,
his condition or his history.
- When did you start feeling sick?
- On the plane.
I've never even been
outside the US before.
My ex-husband
hated to travel, and...
Was the man who
died sitting near you?
No, he was six or
seven rows in front of me.
Were you ever
physically close to him?
Say, waiting for the
restroom? In line to board?
No, I think he slept
almost the entire flight.
That suggests the virus
can be transmitted in the air.
Which means
everyone in the plane
and this emergency
room has been exposed.
We'll start
conditioning tomorrow.
We use chemo and
total body radiation...
To wipe out my crappy,
leukemia-producing bone marrow
so, you can replace it
with some good stuff.
Well said.
Looks like your dad's good
to go on his marrow donation.
Please don't call him that.
Bob Cravens walked out on
me and my mom when I was four.
His biological
material gave me life,
and apparently, he's gonna
save me, but he's not my dad.
Any unusual complaints or
pain we should know about?
I've been tired. And the
last day, achy, kind of stiff...
Standard leukemia woes.
Anywhere in particular?
My neck and left arm.
All right, Chris, you're
having a heart attack.
No. My chest feels fine.
We need to get you up
to radiation right away.
Call and let them know we're
coming. Get his donor in here.
How is radiation gonna
help a heart attack?
Your blockage is most
likely excess blast white cells.
The best way to clear out your
heart is to treat your leukemia.
It's what we planned,
just a day early.
It might not be airborne.
Maybe both passengers were already
infected when they got on the plane.
Marianne said she
felt fine before the flight.
Even if she did
contract it on the plane,
it could've been through a
shared water cup or napkin.
Which would make a
quarantine unnecessary.
I'll call the Public Health
Department and the CDC.
They may wanna track the passengers
and anyone they came into contact with.
- Keep me up to date.
- Okay.
Hey, I'm done.
Jill, you still on?
Get me the CDC and a
change of clothes. I'm coming in.
Thanks for getting
me called in, Tyler.
- You're welcome.
- That was sarcasm.
No, it wasn't.
If this turns into a crisis, where
else would you wanna be?
- I hear you're having some stomach pain.
- It hurts a lot.
I figured it was probably
the candy canes,
but I took some
Pepto. Didn't help at all.
How many candy
canes are we talking?
Three or four dozen.
Of the little ones.
They pass them out at
the mall where I work.
I like to munch on them.
It keeps me in character.
Sounds like you might be
overdoing it. Take off your shirt.
How'd you know
I was still in town?
Because the holidays are
"an obligatory performance
"where families buy each other
gifts and pretend everything is perfect."
Which is why you tell yours
you have to work every
year, even when you don't.
He's a good listener.
What's that scar from?
Rudolph is an ass.
It's a minor bowel resection for
diverticulitis eight months ago.
Uh, we need to do a contrast CT.
You need to come with me.
Dr. Lim, he has it, too.
There, on his neck, a
rash. It wasn't there earlier.
It hasn't fully developed,
but it could be the same thing.
It can't be. I had
on a mask, gloves...
- You keep on the mask the whole time?
- Not after...
With airborne diseases,
that's important...
It's Marianne. Her
O2 sats are crashing.
Get another dose of
IV methylprednisolone.
We need to move up the transplant.
No, it doesn't change anything.
You'll be anesthetized.
You won't feel a thing
and when you wake up,
your son will be on his
way to being healthy.
We'll see you soon.
Sorry I couldn't meet
you at the airport.
- That's a cool T-shirt.
- It probably freaks you out, right?
Like, is he gonna
gender-transition or something?
Nah. If that's your
thing, I'm cool.
- How long am I stuck here?
- It's just for the rest of this shift,
then I'm out of
here for three days.
There's a new rock-climbing
gym we can check out,
and the batting cages.
I'm good. I got a season of
Rick and Morty on my phone.
Clear!
That's six rounds of defib,
and 30 minutes of CPR.
Okay, Dr. Murphy, you can stop.
I just spoke with Dr. Andrews.
We're on soft quarantine
while he consults the board.
Call dispatch, put all
ambulances on diversion.
Do your best to
stop all walk-ins.
Say we're at capacity
and send them to County.
Stall all discharges.
Tyler stays in isolation,
and on antivirals.
Fever's likely the next
stage, so, keep a close eye.
What else are we dealing with?
I always have lunch by
2:00. It's 2:15. I need to eat.
I've got a banana in
my bag if you want it.
A banana isn't lunch. A turkey
sandwich and milk is lunch.
Dr. Murphy, patients first, then we'll
work on that sandwich. What else?
Sixty-year-old woman with angina
visiting her family for the holidays
forgot her blood pressure
meds, came in for a prescription.
Her refill just got
delayed. What else?
The crib was almost finished
when the screwdriver slipped.
And my family doctor is
closed for the holidays.
They would've sent
you here, anyway.
This type of injury can
cause permanent damage.
Makes me feel less guilty for
bringing my baby into a germ pit.
No offense.
Guessing this is your first.
My husband and I waited a long
time. I want everything to be perfect.
Which, as my husband
reminds me, is impossible.
Yet my birth plan
is five pages long.
Mmm.
All closed up.
So I can go home?
Not before we do a nerve study.
I would hate for you to
lose feeling in your fingers.
You can't leave.
I'm sorry. What?
EMT: Hospital policy.
Look, I'm not a
patient, all right?
I just came down here to get
some chips. My dad's a doctor.
- Who's your dad?
- Dr. Alex Park.
- Can you call him?
- My phone's charging upstairs.
I'll call him, so, he knows where
to come find you when he's free.
- But for now, you gotta stay put.
- Why?
Because I'm older than you.
Find the employee
contact list, call Park.
- He should know where his son is.
- Sure.
I feel so much worse than
when I was having a heart attack.
I don't doubt it. Because of
the urgency of your situation,
we used combined
leukapheresis, chemo and radiation.
You're no longer at risk for
another heart attack or stroke.
And I also no longer
have an immune system.
My donor is on his way, right?
I spoke with him. He said
he was getting in his car.
When was that?
I'll follow up.
He's still finding new
ways to let me down.
I thought you guys
were gonna do a CT.
We're doing a KUB X-ray
instead. It's almost as good.
Why would you go with "almost"?
Can you hear that?
Hear what?
- Excuse me. I'm looking for a patient.
- You'll need to speak with a nurse.
I've been waiting
to speak to a nurse.
You must hear that.
The light is buzzing.
I don't hear anything.
It's loud and very distracting.
It needs to be fixed.
You like Italian? La Nostra?
It's great. Barbecue? Ethiopian?
What are you talking about?
Where we're going on our date.
You haven't asked me on
one, and I haven't said yes.
Who turns down the request
of a man trapped in isolation?
What about sushi?
Everybody likes it.
Also, I'm pretty
good with chopsticks.
Never hurts to display
a little manual dexterity.
Tends to impress.
I will want a cocktail to
soothe my nerves, but...
Why would you be nervous?
Have you seen you?
You are smart, as
well as beautiful,
and I will need all the tools
in my toolkit to dazzle you,
so, no drink for me.
Have one after the appetizers.
I'll be impressed by then.
You have a fever.
He has a fever, and the
rash has fully materialized.
Okay.
Here we go.
Quarantine has been approved.
Yeah. Okay.
Can I have everyone's attention?
This Emergency Room and
everyone in it is now under quarantine.
We're hoping none of
you have been exposed,
but a serious respiratory virus
has infected three patients.
What? This can't happen.
We're starting everyone on
antivirals just as a precaution.
We'll be bringing
in food and water,
so, if any of you have
any dietary restrictions,
- please let us know now.
- You can't make us stay here.
That's right. I can't, especially
not if someone's seriously ill.
We are legally entitled
to keep you for as long...
They locked us in.
- Are we locked in?
- Oh, no way.
- I gotta get out.
- Sir...
Sorry.
Like it or not,
no one's leaving.
The decision to
implement the quarantine
was made after
consultation with the board.
The CDC has been
kept fully informed,
and we will be proceeding in
accordance with all protocol...
Shaun, Morgan
and Lim are in there.
And our patient is out here.
There's still no sign of the
donor. He's not answering my calls.
I asked my contact at San
Jose PD to do a home check-in.
Park.
He's down there?
How... Yeah, put him on.
It's security. Kellan's
stuck in the quarantine.
I'll pass along anything I
hear from San Jose PD.
Tyler's started coughing.
Let's up his antivirals,
start high-flow oxygen
and Zosyn to counter
any underlying infection.
Santa Pete has a sigmoid
volvulus. He needs surgery very soon.
My call ended 37 minutes ago.
I'm supposed to be
somewhere. It's important.
No, it's not.
We need a non-surgical fix to
a bowel obstruction. Anyone?
Murphy...
- Hmm?
- You got something?
Not really.
Anything at all... Please.
We... We usually...
We... We usually make a hole,
and come at an obstruction
from the side, but we can't.
We need to use
the existing holes.
An endoscope risks tearing
right through the bowel.
A saline enema doesn't
and it might untwist the bowel.
Simple, but it could work. Nice.
I'm fine.
- Do you have your inhaler?
- Of course, I do.
- What were you doing down here?
- This isn't my fault.
- If you hadn't been working...
- Kellan, I know you must be scared...
I'm fine.
- I'm keeping this hat on. For luck.
- Here we go.
I'm threading the tube into the
rectum. Now, slowly push the saline.
This is... It's not a
pleasant experience.
I'm getting some resistance to flow.
I must have reached the obstruction.
- Push harder. Hang on, Pete.
- Call me Santa...
- Keep pushing the saline.
- Okay. I'm sorry, Santa.
I feel so much better.
We've got you on a pretty
high dose of antivirals.
So, what's next?
We're debating nitric oxide.
No, I mean, if this
doesn't turn around.
What happens to me next?
ARDS, then full
respiratory failure.
Hey, I've got a new
idea for our first date.
Archery. I used to
compete when I was young.
Oh, basically, you'd
be showing off?
I can show you some tricks,
teach you a split-finger
hook, how to anchor,
and then proceed
to demolish you.
Now, that sounds
like a reason to live.
I'm here to take you to
your imaging appointment.
- Where's Shaun?
- Shaun is quarantined in the ER.
"Quarantined"? What quarantine?
Apparently, for some highly
contagious, deadly virus.
But Shaun sounds fine,
except for some buzzing light,
and his concern about lunch
and you missing your
appointment at the imaging clinic.
- So, let's go.
- Take me to the hospital.
We are going to
your appointment,
and making sure your think
melon remains tumor-free.
Take me to the hospital,
please. I'd like to help.
How? By taking your old
job back and saving the day?
Putting on an outbreak
suit and rescuing Shaun?
Some people may find
your sassy attitude appealing.
I'm not one of them.
And I am crushed.
Sir, I'm sorry, you can't...
My Wife's in there. Viola!
Look, that's her. I
need to get in there.
They're setting up a room
inside for friends and family.
Clifton, what are you doing?
Look, I'm coming
in. Let go of me!
- Calm down, or you're gonna get hurt.
- Stop.
- This is all my fault.
- No.
If I'd put the crib
together like you asked...
Forget about the crib. I need
you to take care of yourself.
Because if something
happens to me,
our son needs someone
to take care of him.
It's a boy?
I'm sorry I'm
ruining your surprise.
No. I...
Oh...
Baby, I love you so much.
I love you, too.
I love you.
Dr. Shaun Murphy.
Shaun, why are you
answering our donor's phone?
Because he's here in quarantine.
What happened to the CDC
getting a team here today?
They've confirmed that it
started in Malaysia last week.
Between the virologists already there
and the ones grounded on the East Coast
- because of the snowstorm...
- Stay on them.
What do we know about the virus?
Similar symptoms to SARS,
but much faster moving.
Bob Cravens infected?
Not so far. Currently
Tyler Durnes, the EMT,
is the only person
displaying symptoms.
I need his bone marrow.
I'd like to go in and get it.
I'll comply with all protocol.
You're not hot-zone
certified. None of us are.
My leukemia patient
has no immune system.
He'll die soon without
a marrow transplant.
Then you best find
him another donor.
Because no one, or their bone
marrow, is leaving that quarantine.
Have we heard from County
about taking our PICU transfers?
How are my O2 sats?
Holding steady.
Do you want to call anyone?
I thought about
letting my mom know
what was going on,
but she'd just worry about me
and feel bad that she's not here.
So... She knows I love her.
How's it going in here?
Dr. Reznick was just telling me about
some college lesbian experiences...
Was that just my imagination?
Actually, we were talking
about your mother. Interesting.
I don't like the drop in his O2
sats. Let's start him on nitric oxide.
I knew you liked me.
He's in this hospital?
Bob actually came
through for once.
Unfortunately, we can't wait
for him to get
out of quarantine.
But we've found an alternative
donor in the Bay Area.
How compatible are they?
They share five out of
eight of your markers.
Bob is a much better match.
I can't handle marrow rejection,
or having to repeat this nightmare.
That's a symptom of the MAC
pneumonia. The antibiotics aren't working.
You need bone marrow, or
this infection is going to kill you.
Soon. Days, not weeks.
Seven years I've
been battling leukemia.
I've been through four
full courses of chemo,
so many trips to the
hospital, I've lost count.
Just knowing my father
showed up... I'm grateful, relieved.
I'm okay if this is the
end. I'd like to sign a DNR.
Chris, the CDC will
be here tomorrow.
If they can identify the virus,
we can test Bob. If he's negative...
Whatever you can manage
before my heart stops, go for it.
Please, get me the form.
- His fever's climbing.
- Give the nebulizer time to work.
Cooling blankets, that could help.
I'll go get some from the supply closet.
- Put your mask back on.
- Why?
Because I'm infected.
You got it, too?
Are you guys any closer
to figuring this thing out?
Afraid not.
On the bright side, I think
I'm growing on Morgan.
There's gotta be a way.
You can't go in, Bob can't come
out, the marrow can't come out.
What if it doesn't?
What if the marrow never leaves?
Are you suggesting we put a man with
no immune system into the quarantine?
We expand the quarantine,
create a section just for him.
One of the doctors inside could
do the extraction and the transplant.
Then one of two things happens.
He stays in isolation until we know
he hasn't been infected, or it kills him.
There's no way Andrews
will let us expand a quarantine.
Wish me luck.
Going to 360 joules. Clear.
We can crack his chest
and do cardiac massage.
Dr. Reznick...
Have Petringa bring in the internal
paddles from the trauma bay...
Morgan...
Hey, Doogie.
You didn't hear me talking to
you? My sugar's crazy high, 650.
Hmm.
That doesn't make sense.
I gave you the proper
dosage of insulin. Ten units.
Ten units? Ten units doesn't
even make a dent with me.
You got a doctor here
knows what he's doing?
I'm Dr. Shaun Murphy. I'll
give you another 10 units.
- Waste of time. Make it 20.
- I'll give you 10.
What's wrong with you?
You sound like an idiot.
- Don't be a jerk.
- Mind your own business.
Doc. Doc, I don't feel so...
What the hell? Did
he just infect me?
Possibly. I need to
examine your abdomen.
Your obstruction has returned.
You need surgery, now.
But we're stuck in here...
And there's no operating room.
We will have to improvise.
There's no Neptune Machine.
Without suction, the surgical
field will be filled with blood.
We can use the wall
suction, set to continuous.
That'll do.
No electrocautery to
control the bleeding.
You'll have to do
this combat-style.
Tie off each artery
before you cut.
Dr. Reznick, are you ready?
Because I think we are.
I'll go get the patient.
You should lie down.
- He's out.
- Scalpel.
If we expand the quarantine,
I can do the transplant.
The only technical
breach will...
She's infected.
Melendez. Yeah.
Take down the
adhesions on the sigmoid.
How are his vitals?
Holding steady, Doctor.
That's dead bowel.
- It's perforated.
- Damn it.
- I need a doctor!
- Petringa needs help.
If I don't secure these clamps,
there'll be stool everywhere.
Murphy, go.
- He signed a DNR.
- He shouldn't have.
This is battery.
He doesn't need to die. We're
gonna get his donor's marrow.
- Andrews agreed to the plan?
- Not yet.
If he doesn't, we'll
think of something else.
He said he was
feeling light-headed.
I hear you. Please, stay back.
He's...
Is he infected? From when
Santa vomited on him?
He should go to isolation.
He's in hypoglycemic shock.
Give him D50.
- It's spreading.
- Kellan!
Kellan!
- Ma'am, I need you to step back.
- Kellan! Kellan! Kellan!
Dr. Glassman.
Hi.
We got what we needed for
images. You are okay to go.
- We'll send them to Dr. Blaize.
- Anything I should be worried about?
You're seeing Dr. Blaize
before the holiday?
As a matter of fact,
I'm seeing her now,
so, I could just show
her the hard copy.
I'm not supposed to do that.
Oh, no. I know. I've been a
neurosurgeon for 100 years.
I understand protocol.
I'm not gonna look at it. I
just wanna move things along.
Thank you.
It's back.
Suction.
I must've nicked a branch of
the inferior mesenteric artery.
- Can't see where.
- Can you feel it?
- I think so.
- Use your finger to plug the hole.
Now, what?
Dr. Lim?
Everyone, calm down.
Hey, Kellan. Kellan,
look at me! Look at me.
Breathe! Can you hear
me? Can you hear me?
- Crash cart!
- Help my son!
Silent night
Holy night
All is calm
All is bright
Round yon virgin
Mother and child
Holy infant
So tender and mild
Sleep in heavenly peace