Hello?
What?
Who is this?
Okay, tell me what happened.
Who is it? Kynesha, slow down.
Hey, it's me. What's wrong?
Did he put his hands on you?
All right.
Where are you now?
What intersection?
All right. No, no, no,
just... Just wait there.
I'll pick you up.
Yeah, I'll be there.
You're going?
She got into it with somebody
at the halfway house.
She got scared and took off.
Did she report it
to the manager?
I don't know. I guess there's
some kinda problem there too.
So where is she?
South Federal.
I thought that wasn't
a safe neighborhood.
That's all she knows, Cleo.
Peter, don't you think
that it's a little strange
that she waited until 4:00
in the morning to call us?
Yeah, but what you
do you want me to do?
Leave her out on the street?
It's 10 degrees outside.
You're never going
to get rid of her.
Hey.
Mark, go to sleep.
You feeling nauseous?
No.
Have a bad dream?
Please, Mark.
You've gotta get your rest.
So do you.
You shouldn't be walking
around. You could fall.
Good thing you're a doctor.
How long have you been up?
I never went to sleep, really.
No point worrying about it.
There's nothing you can do.
Gordon didn't say
anything else? Any...?
Any indication why this
meeting was so urgent?
Just that Patterson's
lawyers called it.
It's probably not bad.
They wanna talk.
Yeah, but what about?
You'll know soon enough.
Hurry! Open up! Open up!
Hurry up. Kynesha, what the...?
Go! MAN 1: Hey, hey!
Open up! Hey,
hey, right here. Go!
Hey!
You owe me, girl! MAN 2:
Hey, man, come back here.
I'm gonna find you
I'm gonna find you.
What the hell was that?
A bunch of fools
used to be my friends.
I told them you a doctor.
Ain't nothing on this radio?
♪ ...trash Getting all Pampers ♪
♪ Looking like some old
Washed-up exotic dancers ♪
I don't understand.
You don't like the food?
The room-service guy
has seen all my pajamas.
So we'll just get up earlier.
Or we could sleep
in, at my place.
Dr. Kovac, the paramedics
are 10 minutes out
for a possible hip
fracture. Can you take him?
Yeah. Guess you're
having breakfast alone.
John, how'd it go last night?
With what?
Weaver. Did you tell her?
Right. Uh, I think
I'm gonna wait
until after my
midyear evaluation.
When's that? Sometime today.
You're procrastinating.
You're nagging.
No, I'm being your sponsor.
It's different than
being my mother.
Don't you think? Okay.
Mr. Lambert's in Curtain
3 with fever and cough,
Mr. Mohlsick in
Exam 1 with frostbite.
Carter, you got evaluation
at 11:00 in the lounge.
Yes, ma'am. Don't be late.
So you want Mrs. Furtado?
She has vaginal bleeding.
She had it last month too. It's
called her period. What else?
Oh, Roger Pilarsky's back.
He has abdominal pain.
Oh, no. Again?
It's the cold snap.
When it dips below 20...
I know. Where is he? Exam 2.
Like a "bishop" bishop?
Yep. I think he may
have confirmed me.
Oh.
Started a line and gave
him four of morphine.
Sir, were you able to
get up after your fall?
He tried, but several
of us had to help.
I can speak for myself.
Peripheral pulses plus two.
Call him "Your
Excellency." Bishop is fine.
All right. Let's get him inside
and get him into a gown.
All right. You have a
rear window in stock?
Great. Great. All right, thanks.
That shower felt good.
Don't worry about the
window. I'll pay for it.
With what? I don't
know. Something.
You know what, Kynesha?
You need to learn how
to start respecting people.
I respect you.
I called the halfway house.
They said you started
a fight and then took off.
I hate that place.
The lady that runs it's a bitch.
That's where you live now,
so you better make it work.
Well, I'd rather live with you.
We've been over this.
You can't stay
here indefinitely.
I could if you had
your own place.
Be a lot easier.
What do you think
you're doing? Depends.
What you want me to do?
Kynesha, you better...
Where she at? At work? Hey.
It's all good.
I'm too tired now anyway.
Mr. Pilarsky, you
haven't stopped taking
your Mellaril, have you? No.
How long's your belly
been bothering you?
A few days, but it's
definitely gotten worse
since I've been here.
He's afebrile. BP's 180/70.
Blood pressure's a little high.
Are you upset, Mr. Pilarsky?
Depressed mostly.
I haven't had intimate
contact in 11 years.
It takes its toll after a while.
Well, why don't we
take a look at your belly,
find out what the problem is?
Oh, oh, for God's sake. Conni?
Mr. Pilarsky, why do
you do this to yourself?
I'm an only child, you know.
Are those ours? Yeah.
Start a line, draw
a trauma panel
and set up the SonoSite.
Never did get married.
Want a Psych consult? No.
Put my career first.
Let's clear him
surgically first.
You wanna catch a movie later?
You didn't get my
message, I take it.
No. Did something change?
The meeting was canceled.
We took a
conference call instead
and agreed on a
settlement figure.
Does that mean we accept guilt?
The hospital's
taking it in the shorts
to the tune of $1.5 million.
But our insurance will pay that.
And so will we, with
sky-high premiums.
It could've been worse.
We're not getting off
cheap. She didn't pay a dime.
There was a recall on
the curettes that you used.
I didn't have trouble
with the curette.
Nonetheless, there was a recall.
We also signed a
confidentiality agreement
keeping the details
of the suit private.
So you can't speak
to anyone about it.
But there was nothing
faulty with the equipment.
Apparently, there was.
And the manufacturer
has deeper pockets.
Well, that's wrong.
Look at it as a gift.
We pay up the nose
and you get a little ding
at the National Data Bank.
How lucky is that?
And then my parents went through
this whole charismatic phase.
But they're still pretty
Catholic. I mean, you know.
So, uh, what religion do
they practice in your country?
This is my country, Dave.
That's not what I meant.
Smooth.
Excuse me. I need...
Fill out your name
and complaint.
No, I need a laxative.
Uh, Amira, why don't you get
an emesis basin for Miss...?
Never mind.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Why don't you just take
a seat right over here?
My stomach hurts.
Thank you very much.
I just need to go to the
bathroom and I can't.
Tell me your name.
Anne. Anne, I'm Dr. Carter.
Has anything like this ever
happened to you before?
It started on the plane.
From where? Texas.
You just flew in?
Did you eat anything unusual?
Airplane food.
Well, that could do it.
Let's get you in a room
and find out what's going on.
Oh, my God. It's blood. It's...
I'm gonna need a
little help over here.
Did you land on your
side or on your back?
On my keister.
Several small children
found it amusing.
We were quite worried.
Any tenderness here?
Not so much.
Joe, you're making me nervous.
Go get yourself a cup of coffee.
Please.
Last thing I need
is an entourage.
Any physical conditions
I should know about?
Osteoarthritis.
Runs in the family.
Are you currently
on any medications?
Tylenol.
And the occasional
glass of wine.
Where are you from?
You have an accent.
Croatia.
Ah.
Any numbness in this area?
No.
Do you have a
primary care doctor
I should notify?
He's playing golf in Arizona.
Okay. Someone
will take you to X-ray.
Would you like
anything for pain?
I have a high threshold.
Croatia is a very
Catholic country.
Yes.
Are you Catholic?
No.
That's it? That's all
you're going to tell me?
She got into a fight and took
off to hang out with friends.
So this whole "I was attacked"
was blown out of proportion.
A little.
Did you take her back
to the halfway house?
Uh, not yet.
Then where did you take her?
Well, sh-she needed
to take a shower.
Uh, Cleo, it's just for the day.
That's what you said when
she stayed three weeks.
I'll handle it.
Small Mallory-Weiss tear.
No active bleeding, though.
Temperature's higher, 102.
Wait.
Foreign body obstructing
the gastric outlet.
Good call on the
ultrasound. Okay. Grasper.
Reminds me of one
of those big claw things
they have at the arcade.
What do you call 'em?
Big claw things.
What the heck is that?
Got it.
Okay, slowly extracting.
BP's rising. 160/100.
Up.
And out.
Pulse is 140.
BP's high, 240/100.
Is that a condom?
Probably cocaine.
Uh, must have leaked.
I need phentolamine
and esmolol drips.
50 grams of charcoal
and four of Ativan
in case she seizes.
She's a drug mule.
Hey, Kerry. I just heard
that Roger Pilarsky
was treated for a
self-inflicted injury.
Yeah, with a pair of our
suture scissors no less.
You sent him home?
It was superficial.
Didn't breach the peritoneum.
There should have
been a Psych consult.
He's a frequent flier. Has
a new injury every week.
Could be part of an
accelerating pattern.
Look, he's never had a
serious suicide attempt.
Your department's refused to
admit him on three occasions.
He tried to harm himself.
We're supposed to be called.
All he wanted was
food and company.
Frankly, I thought you'd...
Kerry, I...
I think that we should not let
what happened between us
interfere with patient care.
What?
We're both professionals.
Excuse me. I did what I thought
was medically appropriate.
And it had nothing
to do with the fact
you've been avoiding me?
It doesn't, and I haven't.
But if you'd like me
to call you every time
someone the least bit disturbed
comes into the
ER, you've got it.
Thank you.
Hey, where'd you really
fly in from? South America?
Belize.
Well, you're lucky you
didn't pop at 35,000 feet.
You might've died.
Maybe that would
have been better.
Hey, you mind, uh, telling
me how you got into all this?
I was robbed.
They took everything:
My money. My
passport. My clothes.
Even my shoes.
So you decided to
smuggle drugs to get back.
I met this man.
He was very nice to me.
He said he would help.
All I had to do
was stop here in the
United States for him.
But you knew what he
was asking you to do.
I just wanted to go home.
That's all.
I wanted to go home.
That whole celibacy
thing was always
the sticking point
for me, though.
Yeah, me too. But I got over it.
Heh. Yeah, well...
Hey. Dr. Kovac, did you know
that St. Peter was married?
Anyway, I should get going.
It was nice talking to you,
Bishop Stewart. Same here.
You have a lot of
degenerative changes,
but no fracture.
There will be
bruising, but the worst
should be over in a few days.
Yeah, I know the drill.
You fall a lot?
Damned arthritis
makes me wobbly,
especially when it's cold.
Ever use a walker?
Now, that would cramp
my style, don't you think?
Might save your hips.
Last time I had a flareup,
my doctor put me on this IV,
gave me some, uh...
some kind of steroid.
Solu-Medrol? That's it.
The stuff worked wonders.
You realize it's
a temporary fix.
I'll take whatever I can get.
Just so it gets me
through the hard bits.
Okay.
I'll give you the Solu-Medrol
if you promise to use a walker.
What? Are we negotiating?
Not really.
Do you want the steroids?
I'll use a cane.
Yosh? 125 milligrams of
Solu-Medrol for the bishop
and order a cane
from Central Supply.
You got it.
What was your confirmation name?
Mihael.
After the patron
saint of the sick.
How appropriate.
"On occasion, he has
questioned the decision-making
of more senior physicians
in critical-care settings."
Yeah, I have a more
detailed list if you're interested.
Probably not.
Interpersonal skills, dealing
with patients and staff,
all excellent.
In fact, it's hard to find
fault with your work.
Really?
You've made a
remarkable comeback
from a serious addiction.
And I think I speak for everyone
when I say that
we're proud of you.
Thank you.
Good. We're pretty
jammed up out there,
so unless there's anything
you wanna talk about,
sign the bottom of the form.
Is there something
you wanna talk about?
Sorry. Multi-victim trauma.
We're gonna need everybody.
Let's go.
Seven-year-old hit in the
crosswalk by a pickup doing 30.
Complains of chest pain
and shortness of breath.
Tachy at 120. BP 90/60.
Honey, can you
tell me your name?
Amy. Where's my
mom? Next ambulance.
Take a breath, Amy.
Does your tummy hurt?
No. Is my dad okay?
We'll find out as soon
as we finish with you.
Let's go. We need a
chest tube on the left.
Julie Hembree, 32 years
old. Chest and abdominal pain.
I thought there were three.
Father was DOA at the scene.
Systolic of 80 in the
field. Up to 100 after a liter.
Where's Amy? Where's
my husband? Ah!
Sorry. Looks like it
might be a rib fracture.
Okay, she needs an ultrasound.
Let's get Surgery down here.
Mandy, can you push
the cholecystectomy
to next week for me?
Sure. These are lovely.
Glad you think
so. They're for you.
From Dr. Greene?
Yes.
O.R. Hold on.
Dr. Corday, they
need you downstairs.
I'm on my way.
Should I put these
in your office?
Please.
Mr. Patterson, what
are you doing here?
I came to see you.
I've been called to the
Emergency department.
I'll ride down with you.
Okay.
Please allow me to
say that I feel terrible
about what's happened.
Which part?
Me being crippled or you
getting sued for malpractice?
My concern was for
your situation, not mine.
Yeah. Doesn't really
compare, does it?
Strange how it all comes
down to faulty equipment.
My lawyer tells me I
can't really blame you.
But I can't quite
forgive you either.
Imagine I'll always
remember your face.
I wonder whether
you'll remember mine.
Start in Trauma 1.
Weaver needs that in 2.
They'll need you right away.
I'm really sorry. Go, go.
I'm so sorry.
What is it, Conni?
Auto versus peds.
Mother and daughter.
Any critical? The kid
in Trauma 1 looks bad.
Where's Benton? I don't know.
What is it? Blunt chest,
hemopneumo on the left.
Did you scan the belly?
It seemed pretty benign.
Where's ultrasound? Next door.
Why don't you examine her first?
- Where's my mom?
Why don't we take this collar
off? You'll feel a lot better.
One percent with epi.
Sats are down to 82.
Put her up to 15 liters.
Ten blade.
How's the abdomen?
Non-tender. I can't clear her
until we have an imaging study.
Ow, that hurts.
Amy, it's okay. You
wanna intubate?
No, let's wait for
the chest tube.
Green zone on the Broselow.
Give me a curved Kelly.
I want my mom!
Slow breaths, Amy.
Slow, deep breaths.
Pressure's down to
60. She's bleeding out.
Okay. Hang two units of
O-neg on the rapid infuser.
We need to intubate. Let's
pre-medicate with atropine.
Dr. Corday, Dr. Weaver
needs you right now.
Okay. Let's keep up
with the blood loss.
Kerry, you need me?
Rebound and guarding
in the right upper quadrant.
Looks like a surgical belly.
Please, how is she? My daughter.
I'm afraid there's some
bleeding in the chest.
What does that
mean? Is she okay?
She's stable for right
now, but it is serious.
And what about my
husband? Is he here too?
Oh, God. No.
Hey, we don't know
anything for sure yet.
We've got a liver laceration.
You have some internal
bleeding from the abdominal injury.
We need to get you up
to the O.R. right away
so that we can
stop the bleeding.
Type-specific's up.
Squeeze in two units. Tell
the O.R. we're on our way.
Connie, get her
upstairs. Let's go.
Over a liter out on the left.
Get another two units of blood.
Push the etomidate.
We need to tube her.
No, wait. J-just bag her.
Bring your patient in here.
I'm red-lining her to the O.R.
We're not maintaining
pressure. What are you doing?
Her daughter
should see her first.
Please. I wanna see her.
She has a critical laceration.
How much blood do you have?
Four units. You'll be just fine.
Listen. Her
systolic's down to 80.
Okay. Get two pressure
bags for the blood.
Push the etomidate,
then the sux.
Amy, it's Mommy.
You're gonna be all right.
They're gonna take
me to surgery now.
But I'll see you
real soon, okay?
She's out. Five-and-a-half tube.
Amy? That's it.
We're going. Now!
Cricoid pressure right there.
I'm in. Bag her.
Okay, call X-ray
for a portable chest.
Good breath sounds bilaterally.
Pulse ox is up to
92. Set up a vent.
FiO2, 100 percent. Rate of 20.
Damn it! Lost her pulse.
Starting compressions.
Charge the paddles to 100.
And get another 8 units
from the blood bank.
Keep pouring it in.
Charged and ready.
Clear.
This the ex-lap?
Yes. Still a little
shocky after five liters.
Did you give FFP? Not yet.
What are you waiting
for? We were rather busy.
Will you be doing
an atrial-caval shunt?
I won't know
until I open her up.
It would help if I knew
what you were planning.
Yes. Well, when I
decide I'll tell you.
Shirley, I think
Anspaugh's in the lounge.
Can you ask him to assist?
He's ready to go
on a fem-pop in 4.
Any other Attendings around?
They're all scrubbed in.
It's just you on this one.
Give another epi.
Sats are down to 70.
Two more liters
out of the chest.
Autotransfuse and
hang another two.
She's losing it too fast.
Hold the compressions.
P.E.A. rate of 49.
Set me up for
pericardiocentesis.
Take over here.
You think she's in tamponade?
It's our last chance
for treating P.E.A.
Give me the alligator clip.
Hook it up to the V-1 lead.
JVD's four centimeters.
She's still hypovolemic.
Bradying down to 40.
Watch for any injury current.
There. Back off.
Anything in the pericardium?
Nothing. Resume compressions.
What's this?
I called for a consult.
I'm admitting her.
Why? Danger to self.
Does the pound of cocaine
she swallowed figure into this?
It wasn't a pound.
We don't have to report
drug use to the authorities.
But I'd imagine in the
case of drug smuggling
we'd make an exception.
She's not a dealer. She's a kid.
She made a stupid mistake
and she almost got killed.
Maybe, but she's not suicidal.
What's your problem, Kerry?
What? She's 18 years old.
Could you excuse us, Dr. Carter?
Her going to prison isn't
going to, uh, benefit anybody.
Excuse us.
Don't you ever
talk to me like that
in front of a resident again.
I wouldn't have to
if you didn't insist
on interfering
with my admission.
She's an ER case.
Which I was called into.
I'm admitting her.
Agonal rhythm, rate of 29.
Has she had two
doses of atropine?
Fifteen minutes ago.
What about thoracotomy?
No. She had a fatal injury.
Probably tore
her aorta. That's it.
Asystole.
Call it.
Time of death 1:47 p.m.
Paramedics just brought
in another trauma.
We need a doctor in here.
I've got it.
Let me out of here! I gotta go!
Let me out!
Kevin Poole, 42, very drunk.
Under police pursuit until
he hit a concrete column.
Needed the Jaws
of Life to get him.
Vitals are stable, but
he's a pain in the ass.
Settle down. Huh?
I'm Dr. Kovac. I'm going
to examine your injuries.
I need you to stay
calm. What injuries?
Lovely. Why were
the police chasing him?
Hit-and-run. Took out
a family at a crosswalk.
They come here or Mercy?
Here. MAN: I
gotta... I gotta go.
I gotta find my wallet.
I'm gonna put a
tube in your nose.
You want me to
numb him up first?
No. Just hold his head still.
Swallow, sir.
I can spray the
back of his throat.
Just keep swallowing.
Hey.
This is good.
What's wrong? You ain't hungry?
Hi, Kynesha.
Who is she? This
is Adele Neuman.
She's a social worker.
Nice meeting you.
I thought you called me
here so I could be with you.
Kynesha, I'm trying to find
you a permanent place to live.
I have a husband
and wife in Riverside
who are both African-American.
And they have two other
foster children your age.
I thought you said
you cared about me.
I said I care about
what happens to you.
Yeah, right.
You only doing all
this 'cause of Jesse.
You think I don't know that?
That's not true.
I know that bitch
Cleo don't like me.
Kynesha. I knew
that from jump street.
You are underage without
a way to provide for yourself.
Now, it's either foster care or
becoming a ward of the state.
Which would you prefer?
Fine. You don't
want me. I'm gone.
Kynesha. Kynesha.
Just let me take it from here.
She's got a stage-three
stellate fracture
into the deep parenchyma.
More suction,
Shirley. Canister's full.
Well, change it.
She's oozing all over the place.
How about platelets?
Already gave 'em.
You need to correct
her coagulopathy.
ET and bleeding time are
normal. It's your problem, not mine.
All right. Right.
I'm gonna try and pack
the liver and get out.
Okay, uh, gel foam, Penrose.
Come on. BP's dropping. 90/60.
Dr. Corday, you have
to control the bleeding.
The injury's too extensive.
Maybe I can get caval control.
Um... Bovie, pickups.
I can't maintain her vitals
unless you get hemostasis.
I know that. She's
lost another liter.
Two more going
up on the infuser.
Call. Call for six more.
BP's still dropping.
Heart rate up to 120.
There's too much
blood in the field.
I-I can't isolate the vena cava.
She's bleeding out.
Get Romano.
I don't know if he's available.
Get Romano. Get
Benton! Get somebody!
Come on, more laps.
How's he doing?
Blood alcohol level is
0.35, but he's stable.
You're under arrest for
vehicular manslaughter.
What? Your
Morrison's Pouch is dry.
Liver intact. Three
DUIs, revoked license
and the idiot still
gets behind the wheel.
Let me out of here, damn it.
Sir, you have to hold still.
His spleen looks good.
She said stop.
All right, what do we got?
MVA with a lot of ETOH.
And no free fluid?
Crit is 42.
Excellent. Sir,
does it hurt here?
Who the hell are you?
Okay. How about here? All right.
Some periumbilical tenderness.
Okay, let's call
Radiology, order a CT.
Do you think it's necessary?
It's hard to assess them
when they're drunk like this.
I like to be sure.
Hey, it's Abby in the ER.
Yeah, I can hold. How'd it go?
The evaluation?
It went very well.
And? What?
Forget it. I didn't
get a chance.
You interrupted with
the trauma. Forget it.
Yeah, hello. What's going on?
Sorry. Can you
hold on? With what?
With you and Carter. Nothing.
It seemed like
you were fighting.
We were.
I'd tell you, but it's a
privacy thing. His, not mine.
Hi. Yeah, Benton's on his way
up with a blunt abdominal trauma.
Better be good.
Liver fracture with
uncontrolled hemorrhage.
You called me out of a lunch
because you
can't tie off a liver?
BP's 80/40, pulse rate 120.
Ten units already in. Shirley,
set up the argon beam.
I tried to get caval
control, but I...
You try the Pringle maneuver?
You learned it in grade
school, Dr. Corday.
Ligate with 4.0 chromic while
I occlude the hepatic artery.
Get out.
Argon's ready. All right.
I'll coagulate the parenchymal
surface. Tie off the vessels.
Robert... Not now, Lizzie.
Get to work. You
need another assistant.
Make yourself useful and sew.
Robert, I'm sorry. I can't stay.
I'll send in a resident. Where
do you think you're going?
I'm sorry.
Lizzie, get your ass
over here now! Damn it.
Mark?
Hey, Luka.
Need some help?
No, no, no. I'm fine. Thank you.
So, what are you doing here?
Radiation therapy.
Every day for six weeks.
Elizabeth's giving
me a ride back,
but she's stuck in surgery.
Doctor Chen still out
on leave? Yeah. Yeah.
You coming back to work
soon? Next week, I hope.
Wow. Fast recovery, huh?
Yeah. Speed of light.
I heard you were
doing immune therapy.
As soon as the
tumor vaccine's ready.
So everything okay around here?
Okay as ever. Don't worry.
I don't. Honest. Life's
too short, you know?
I know.
So how are you, Luka?
The same.
Good to see you. You too.
Where is he? Who?
The bishop. I think
he went to Trauma 1.
What for?
To give someone
their last rites.
Are you sorry for your
sins? What happened?
He crashed during CT. Yes.
May our Lord Jesus
Christ grant you absolution,
and by his authority...
I can't hear. May our
Lord Jesus Christ...
Cross match another six.
Pressure is 60. I absolve
you of all your sins.
Put him in Trendelenburg.
Needs a central line.
Let's get an eight
French trauma kit.
Okay, prep for a subclavian.
Sats down to 75.
He's not moving any
air. Bag him. I'll intubate.
You should leave.
Okay, one of
Pavulon, 100 of sux.
I need a sterile drape in
here. Come on, let's move.
Hey. You taking off? Yeah.
I know a guy
playing in a blues club
later, if you're interested.
No, I think I'm just
gonna go home.
Maybe tomorrow.
He'll be here all week.
Hey.
I need to talk to you
about this Weaver thing.
Look, nothing really
happened. I threw them up.
Carter. I know I'm fine.
You know I'm fine.
Weaver thinks I'm fine.
So why give her
any reason not to?
I don't know.
Maybe you can take that
up with your next sponsor.
What?
I don't want to be
your sponsor anymore.
Whoa. Where's that coming from?
I care about you.
And I care about your recovery,
but I can't keep saying the
same things over and over.
Because it's hard enough
for me to do it for myself.
You serious? Yeah.
Fine. I'll get another
sponsor. Okay.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Dr. Finch, you
lose your compass?
I'm here to see Julie
Hembree. One lucky lady.
A Pringle maneuver
courtesy of me
kept her from bleeding out.
I thought Corday
did the surgery.
Long story. I'll tell you
over cocoa sometime.
She's all yours.
Mrs. Hembree?
You were one of the
doctors for my daughter?
Yes.
Is she all right?
Amy was hit in the chest
at a very high speed.
I know. I was there.
She needed help
breathing, so we intubated.
We gave her transfusions
to treat the blood loss.
But despite all that, her
heart stopped beating.
No.
We used intravenous drugs
and shocked her
heart for an hour.
But her injuries
were too severe.
No.
And she died.
I'm so sorry.
No.
Okay.
With the type of
injuries she had
and the massive blood loss...
No! I'm sorry.
No. No! Calm down. Calm down.
Just calm down.
I'm sorry.
I'm gonna have
you take prednisone
for the next four days.
Bishop, our car is here.
Thank you. I'll be right there.
What happened to Kevin Poole?
The drunk?
He died on the table.
At least he found absolution.
You don't believe that.
He ran down a
family in the street.
The mother's
upstairs in surgery.
I see.
Does that make him any
the less worthy of salvation?
He was more afraid than sorry.
Yes. But he found God
in his final moments,
and he asked for forgiveness.
So any fool can get into heaven
if he's scared enough to say
he's sorry right before he dies?
Dr. Kovac...
Everyone deserves to be
comforted in their darkest hour.
Too bad you weren't
there to comfort
the little girl he killed.
I didn't need to
be. God was there.
Was he?
You should arrange to
see your doctor this week.
And use the cane for stability.
Okay. Haleh, I am outta here.
Good night,
Dr. Weaver. Good night.
Hey, can I give you
a hand with those?
Uh, thank you.
You going home? Yeah, shortly.
Hey, do you, uh, do you
have a minute to talk?
Of course.
In there? Okay.
Look, if you're concerned
about what happened earlier,
you don't need to be.
I respect your judgment
enough... A couple weeks ago,
I took some Vicodin out of
a patient's prescription bottle
and I swallowed them.
And then I went
into the bathroom
and I stuck my
finger down my throat.
Did you successfully expel them?
Yes.
I don't know... I don't know
why I did it. I really don't.
I just found myself... Doing it.
I just thought you should know.
I appreciate you telling me.
I'll see you tomorrow, Carter.
What are you gonna do?
Give it some thought.
Meanwhile, keep
going to your meetings.
I can't believe you waited.
I thought you would
have taken a cab.
Well, I thought you
could use some company.
Are you all right?
Yeah. You should have
seen me an hour ago.
I could've danced a jig.
How did the meeting go?
Oh, we settled rather cheaply.
Um, something
to do with a recall.
Great. Shall we go
out and celebrate?
Get a bite to eat?
What? With you like this?
Or we could just, uh,
go home, take a nap.
I don't feel like
celebrating anyway.
You're off the hook.
It's okay to be happy.
I can't. It's my fault, Mark.
Elizabeth, we're
not saints, okay?
We just try to get it
right as often as we can.
I don't want to talk
about it. Elizabeth...
Mark, please.
You know what I noticed?
What?
Amy's shoes. They
were brand-new.
When she woke up this
morning, she had no idea.
It's always harder
when they're young.
Yeah. So, what am
I doing in Pedes?
You're good at it.
You know what I want tonight?
Climb into a hot bath,
get in bed and be taken care of?
I won't hold you
to the last part.
Oh, my God.
Look what she did to my house.
It's okay. I'll take care of it.
No, it is not okay.
Look at this.
I know. Come here.
I'll take care of it.
Hey. Oh, hi.
I was just about to leave,
if you want the table.
Actually, I called your office
and they said you might be here.
I was hoping that we could talk.
I don't know, Kerry. We've
already talked a lot today.
Look, I know that it's
been tense between us
and I really don't
mean it to be.
I'm sure it'll pass.
Kim, I want you to know that
I respect you as a colleague.
Today notwithstanding?
I miss you.
Well, that'll pass too.
In a few weeks we'll just be
friendly co-workers
all over again.
Yeah, I've been thinking,
and I'm not sure
that's what I want.
You have a good night.
Okay? Kim, please.
I'd like you to stay.
Look...
I know you might not
want to hear this right now.
I know it's been
rough with everything...
Between us.
I'm not easy.
I haven't been there for you.
Not the way you've
been there for me.
I've never worked at
being with someone.
I've never even wanted to.
But I want to with you.
I love you.