Previously on ER:
You don't wanna see me, fine.
But you still have to teach me.
Well, for that to be possible, my dear,
you'd have to have the ability to learn.
So in order to get to the next
level, each intern will get a mentor.
How'd your respiratory
physiology exam go?
Ugh, I think I flunked it.
You're a good mother, this is important
to you and something you should do.
One day you will wake up next to me
and wonder, "How did this happen?"
You're a cocky bastard.
Frank.
Her abdomen's
covered in abscesses.
So much for the
Tijuana tummy tuck.
Tell us you're wearing
something underneath that.
- Wanna see for yourself?
- I don't approve...
- of ER personnel wearing costumes.
- Kids seem to like it.
Yes, but what adult wants
to get a cancer diagnosis...
- from a reject from Animal House.
- I'm Julius Caesar.
We'll drain under CT
guidance to avoid surgery.
Going to Kayson's talk on
recurrent pericardial effusions?
Since when do
you go to lectures?
- I'll save you a seat.
- Don't bother.
- Hi, Dr. Brenner.
- Nice legs, Frank.
You gave me some
great tips on our last shift.
I'm glad we're working together.
Dr. Gates won't
be mentoring today.
- I won't?
- You get to do the culture list.
All positive cultures from last
week. Wounds, urine, sputum.
Make sure they're on
appropriate antibiotics.
- Call them if they have a resistant bug.
- Great, I'm on pus patrol.
- So I won't seeing patients?
- You get to do that too.
Just stick with the non-criticals.
Dr. Brenner will mentor you both.
Dr. Banfield, I've already done
a rotation, so maybe I can skip?
You're an intern. Being
mentored is part of the process.
Dr. Morris, Tracy
Martin is with you.
- Where is Dr. Martin?
- Not in yet.
Oh, I hate working on Halloween.
It's always the same thing.
Got the idiot who slices
his hand carving a pumpkin.
Your shoes end up
covered in candy-corn puke.
Let's not forget the old chestnut:
sloppy drunk dressed as Frankenstein.
Halloween is new to me. I
didn't celebrate it in Australia.
- You never been trick-or-treating?
- Nope.
No candy, no costumes,
no mischief night?
What's mischief night?
Kids soap up windows,
egg cars, tp front lawns.
You were one deprived child.
Michael Leary, 18, stab
wound in the chest. School fight.
- Is that a fork?
- Vitals are good, sats 97 on room air.
- Stupid little dude went crazy.
- Okay, Trauma One. Let's go.
I'm sorry I'm late. This costume
is almost impossible to walk in.
Dr. Martin. Care to explain?
I was told that all the interns
were supposed to dress up?
You were misinformed.
Breath sounds equal.
Let's get some access.
- Mm-hm. I'm on it.
- He snuck up on me.
- Need some help?
- His pants need to come off.
If I'd seen him... Did you
tell her to take off my pants?
Yep. LEARY: Oh, go for it.
Surgery's on the way.
Laverne.
- Nice new 'do.
- Thanks. I like to change it up.
- Okay, Dr. St. John, what's next?
- Plain films and ultrasound.
- Good idea.
- It is?
- I mean, you think it is?
- Yeah. Get the machine.
Oh, the needle's at too steep
an angle. Try 45 degrees.
Okay.
- I... I got a flash.
- Nice. Here, I'll tape it up for you.
Oh, shoot. Shoot. Sorry.
- "Intra-operative hypotension"?
- For my nurse anesthetist program.
- I have a big test tomorrow.
- School sucks, huh?
You're learning to push
drugs for an anesthesiologist?
I'll be able to
administer them myself.
Yeah, but a real anesthesiologist
will be watching over your shoulder.
Actually, no.
How do you go to
classes, work full time...
raise a kid and have a life?
Ha, ha, ha. When you put it
like that, it sounds like a lot.
- Good luck with that.
- Thank you. I'm gonna need it.
Nonsense. A year from now, Sam'll
be running her own cases in the O.R.
- You need something?
- Oh, yes.
I wanna thank you for turning
in your schedule request on time.
- My pleasure.
- Yes, but I'm a little surprised.
You opened up your work
availability considerably.
I'm just trying to
be a team player.
Good. Then maybe you can
be in charge of scheduling...
- guest speakers for grand rounds.
- Me?
Figure out someone good to
start off with. We have no money.
You'll have to use your charm.
See that? The lung's
inflating at the pleural interface.
That's impressive, doctor.
- Radiology elective.
- That was smart.
Hello, all.
Hi, I'm Dr. Wade. I'm a surgeon.
- I still can't get used to sound of that.
- Get used to it.
Okay, Daria, why
don't you do the honors.
- Okay. Fork versus chest. Waiting on CT.
- Rule out vascular involvement.
- Maybe the pectoralis major.
- Pectoralis major. Good.
- Vitals? Crits?
- Fine. Stable.
- Dinner later?
- Mazzarino's.
One gram of Ancef,
page when the CT's done.
Sam, uh, we got a kid out
here with a bloody nose.
Okay.
Uh, well, you two
are certainly in sync.
Yeah, what can I
say? It's chemical.
Ha. You missed me.
Mrs. Ferreri, you can pick
up prescriptions in the ER.
- You're not gonna believe...
- Frank. Give these to Banfield.
- Tell her they're all susceptible.
- Okay. Morris...
Also, could you, uh, get me a new
clip for, uh, my ID? This one's broken.
Fine.
Banfield got some more
positive cultures for you.
She wants you to see she
sore-throat kid in Exam Three.
All hail Caesar.
Morris, you gotta see
the guy in Curtain Three.
Frankenstein? Great,
just like I called it.
You need to see him now.
In a minute. I've just
gotta make a phone...
Okay, don't get
your toga in a bunch.
Laverne, look at this.
See any fracture?
Um, no, I don't.
Yeah, me either.
But, uh, look here.
Posterior fat pad sign.
That means there's blood
in the joint from a fracture.
Listen, I've been wanting to talk to y...
- Dr. Brenner.
It's Danny Raskin, 14. Persistent
nose bleed. His brother, Scott.
He got in a fight.
School nurse couldn't get it to
stop. Complained of nausea in the rig.
That's probably from
swallowing blood.
Fork boy's going up to CT.
You know him?
Not really. Classmate.
- Did the school call your parents?
- It's just our mom.
They tried, they couldn't
get her. It's okay, I'm here.
I'm sorry, but we need to get ahold
of her before we can treat Danny.
Okay. Scott, I'll take you to the
phone. You can try your mom again.
You don't look like
the fighting type.
I guess I'm not.
Princess Jenny, open wide.
Tilt your head back a little bit.
- No fever.
- Yeah, but white spots on the tonsils.
- Dawn, any emesis basins?
- Try the second drawer.
And swollen glands.
- Could it be strep?
- You'll need a dose of penicillin.
- We will?
- No, let's do a rapid strep test first.
She's got exudate
and lymphadenopathy.
Don't wanna give
unnecessary antibiotics.
I'll get the swab.
There's a positive blood culture
from a week ago at the front desk.
Grab it, take it to Medical
Records and hunt down a chart.
I'm with a trauma, got six
other patients. Send your intern.
Don't have one today. No point
sending a doctor on a no-brainer.
All right, Your
Highness. All done.
I need this? GATES: Nope.
Sure, no problem.
- Should have the results in 20 minutes.
- All right.
Dr. Livingstone, I presume?
What you got here?
Birds aren't allowed in the ER.
- Oh, but he...
- It's okay.
I don't think this wild animal's
gonna give us any trouble.
Left another message for Mom.
Here, if you throw up,
throw up in that, okay?
So, Danny, how'd
you get in a fight?
There's this guy at school.
He's been saying stuff about our mom.
- What kind of stuff?
I don't understand all
of it, but I know it's bad.
I told you not to listen. Huh?
Staph aureus sensitivities.
Well, they're always pointing
and laughing at me in the halls.
It's because he's a jerk, man.
They just like picking on younger kids.
Got it. Thanks.
That's a marker for inducible
clindamycin resistance.
You should check to
see if the lab did a D test.
Daria, stop being so smart.
You're gonna make me look bad.
Daria, get some 2x2s.
So, what happened at lunch?
Well, I asked him why he
was talking about my mom.
He just laughed and
called her a name.
You don't need to
know this. Just fix him.
So I got mad and I
hit him with a food tray.
He grabbed me and
his friends piled on.
I don't remember after that.
- Low-grade fever, 100.6.
- Give her 15 per kilo acetaminophen.
You, uh, tame any
wild lions today, buddy?
Um, Owen doesn't
like to talk much lately.
He's been having a hard
time since their father and I...
I see.
My ex moved out of state with his
younger pregnant wife, Veronica.
I hate Veronica.
Did that bird just talk?
Uh, the therapist thought
Trevor would be good for Owen.
- Might help him express his feelings.
- Trevor is very expressive.
- Where is she? I don't wanna miss this.
- Maybe in surgery.
She here yet? BOTH: No.
Tell her it's a perfed ulcer.
That'll get her down fast.
- Archie, where's Neela?
- Paged her again.
She's here. Quick, act natural.
Morris, you can't keep paging
me every five minutes. What is it?
Very, very sick patient
in Curtain Three.
He doesn't look that sick. He's
walking around. What's his complaint?
Uh, he's... He's turning green.
Hello. I'm, uh, Dr. Rasgotra.
How can I help you?
Mm.
- Neck hurt.
- Mm-hm. I see. And, uh, anything else?
Need brain transplant.
Sir, this is an ER...
with real patients who are
sick and who need our help.
Hey, roomie.
You bastard.
Oh, my God. Oh.
Could've told us
you were coming.
Miss the surprised look
on your faces? No chance.
- You in town long?
- Yeah, we should all go out.
I'm only here for one night for the
annual rehab medicine assembly.
So you working at
an ER down south?
I left emergency
medicine, actually.
I'm doing a residency in PM and R.
Physical medicine and rehabilitation.
- And you like it?
- Yeah, I do.
I get to work with traumatic
brain and spinal cord injuries...
um, stroke patients, amputees.
And it keeps me on my toes.
Well, make that carbon-fiber toes.
Well, it's good to see
you up and around.
Thanks.
- Ray.
- Hey.
- How you doing?
- I'm good.
Okay, people, I'm sure
you all have work to do.
Gates, Sam, there's a hand injury
in Exam 2 that needs attention.
- Ray, good to see you.
- You too.
See you around.
We'll talk later. Neela,
don't let this guy get away.
- Uh, who's that?
- Uh, new chief of the ER.
- Another one?
- Mm-hm.
- How many does that make?
- I've lost count.
- You wanna head over to Kayson's talk?
- Oh, yeah, the talk. Uh, I can't.
- I hear it's gonna be pretty good.
- Yeah, no doubt. I'm, uh, busy.
- Well, um, if you wanna, you should go.
- No, I don't. I mean, I can't.
Okay. All right. Well,
I'll, uh... I'll fill you in later.
Guess who's in charge of the
ER's new teaching conferences.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I've invited Atul Gawande
to speak at grand rounds.
He's, uh, far too busy.
You'll never get him.
A bottle of
champagne says I will.
Hi. I'm Ray Barnett.
Oh, sorry. Uh, this is Simon
Brenner, the new attending.
This is, uh, Ray,
used to work here.
Ah.
So...
So you've been lucky enough to
work with the brilliant Dr. Rasgotra.
I've had that privilege, yes.
So where are you practicing now?
Baton Rouge.
Baton Rouge. I hear it's nice.
Oh.
Neela, I will catch you
later. Ray, great to meet you.
- Right back at you.
- All right.
- If you need to go to Kayson's...
- No, I don't.
But I've got some work to
finish off. It won't take long.
All right, I'll come with you.
- So that Brenner guy?
- Mm-hm.
Kind of seems like a dick.
- I think my wife put glue in there.
- Your wife? Why would she do that?
Well, she says I love
bowling more than I love her.
And, uh, well, ha, I got
a girlfriend on the side.
Hey, I heard you might
have a good teaching case.
Oh, a sports injury, huh? Hi.
- Yeah.
- Hi. GATES: Got
tingling in the thumb.
Numbness in the fingers.
What do you make of that?
Oh, uh, median nerve
neuropraxia from hyperextension.
Nice. What about
motor and reflex deficits?
Wrist extensors...
Biceps. No.
Brachioradialis. Oh,
folks, she was so close.
- Can I give another four of morphine?
- Yeah. Morphine fine, amphetamine fat.
Morphine overdose gives
you fine, constricted pupils.
Amphetamine gives
you fat dilated pupils.
It's a mnemonic. Might
help you with your test.
A mnemonic is a saying to
remember complicated facts.
Yeah, I know what a mnemonic is.
And I also know what morphine
does without some stupid saying.
Sam, that mom
you called is here.
Ha. I gotta go.
- Uh, Mrs. Raskin?
- Oh, Sandy Raskin.
Hi, I'm Sam.
Uh, Dr. Brenner,
this is Danny's mom.
- How's my son?
- Anxious to see you.
Wow, finally.
Couldn't check my messages until
break. You know how it gets at work.
We're gonna need your
consent to pack Danny's nose.
Sure, sure, whatever he needs.
- Honey, how did this happen?
- It was nothing.
No, he's in the hospital,
Scott. That's not nothing.
I'm sorry. My aim's not so good.
It's okay. Happens all the time.
Danny. Danny, are you all right?
My head hurts.
Okay. Sam, get a blood pressure.
Did the other kid hit
him with anything?
- I don't know. I wasn't there.
- Did he fall? Hit his head?
He's hypertensive, 138 over 89.
Let's move him. Surgical
consult, 25 of mannitol.
Ms. Hoffman's Vanco trough is 6.4.
Should we keep her on a gram q. 12?
Push her levels to 15.
Change it to 1.5 q. 12...
and repeat the
trough with third dose.
So how are you
liking rehab residency?
Well, it's not always
fun, but it's rewarding.
I've gotten involved with the
academy's Injured Soldier Task Force.
We facilitate access to care
for wounded soldiers and vets.
- That doesn't sound easy.
- Yeah.
Especially when you're working with
the VA and the Defense Department.
I hope my surprise visit isn't
wrecking any of your big plans tonight.
Well, if you consider working out
and doing laundry big plans, then...
Neela, Anspaugh was gonna do a
laparotomy on that abscess patient.
- Went with your plan instead. Good job.
- Thanks, Marisol.
I'm, uh, done in about 20 minutes.
We can sit, grab some coffee.
- No, let's work out.
- Really?
Yeah, it'll be good
after traveling all day.
Find me when you're done.
Uh, wait. Wait. You
haven't got a good seal.
What? What are you smiling at?
Ha.
Nothing.
Okay.
Sorry about this. The
lab lost the first specimen.
They won't lose this one?
I'll hand it to them, stand
there while they run it.
We need this room, so go out in
the lobby and wait for the results.
How long will that
be? It's Halloween.
Candy at the desk.
The kids can stop there.
Time to put Trevor in his cage.
- Owen.
- I'll take care of this.
Take her to Waiting.
- There you are. You want some?
- Ooh. No, thanks.
I still remember what
County coffee tastes like.
You look great,
man. How are things?
I still have a few more operations
in my future, but nothing like before.
I was in for a skin graft
when I heard about Greg.
I'm sorry I couldn't
make it to the funeral.
Hey, everybody understood.
You doing okay?
I miss him, it sucks, but,
you know, what can you do?
I gotta say, the way you walk on
those prosthetics, pretty amazing.
Well, I got some custom foot modules.
Makes it easier to move and climb stairs.
You know, sometimes when I wake
up, I actually forget what happened...
and I jump out of bed
and wind up on the floor.
Ha.
- Sorry, that's not funny.
- Yeah. Yeah, actually it is, every time.
Oh, um, Dr. Morris,
have you seen Dr. Gates?
No. Do you need something?
Yeah, I just got a
question on a knee effusion.
I'm sure Dr. Brenner
can answer that.
It's okay. I'll just...
I'll wait for Tony.
- So, Neela, she's doing good, huh?
- Dude, Neela is a surgery superstar.
She's gonna be running
the department one day.
They must be working her hard.
Lots of long hours, nights, weekends.
I mean, that can't be too much fun.
Dr. Morris, the D-stick
on your ballet dancer is 34.
Okay. I gotta run.
If I don't see you before you
leave, take care of yourself.
Oh, and, uh, no, Ray. As far as I
know, Neela's not seeing anyone.
What? No, no,
no. See, I wasn't...
Owen! Owen!
I know Trevor's smart, but I doubt he
opened that door and flew down here.
Come on, let's go.
Oh.
Don't worry, I'm gonna call the front
desk and someone will come let us out.
Wild Kingdom, I don't suppose
you have a cell phone on you?
Help! Hey!
CT can take him in five minutes.
I just don't understand why Danny
would be in a fight. It's not like him.
Put him on the portable.
Maybe he didn't like
hearing all the rumors, Mom.
- What rumors? What's this about?
- My intern will go with him.
Where you going? - I'm off.
Call Dubenko as soon as Neurosurge
reads the films. This is their case now.
- Hey, um, do you guys need help in here?
- You're a little late.
Scott, what rumors?
Like you really can't think of any
reason kids are talking about you?
- Are you stupid or just drunk?
- Just calm down.
You're not helping your brother.
There's Mike. Maybe
he can explain it to you.
- What's he have to do with this?
- Go ask. You're banging him.
Okay. How does "to the
zoo and back" sound?
Sounds good, but
it's about four miles.
Well, these babies can
take it. Afraid you can't?
Okay. Last one
there buys dinner.
Better get your wallet out.
Ready?
All right. You "ready" ready?
Hey, Danny, hang in there.
- Tired.
The CT showed a subdural
hematoma over the right parietal area.
- What does that mean?
- Sats only 93.
Blood putting pressure
on the surface of his brain.
Get a non-rebreather.
It needs to be cleaned out
to prevent further damage.
Can you spare an intern?
Dr. Banfield's doing a pleural tap.
- Laverne can go. It'll be good experience.
- Are you sure?
You go. You've earned it.
Scott, tell me what
happened. Now.
Danny attacked Mike because
he was bragging all over school...
- about what an easy lay you are.
- Mike wouldn't.
What, you think he is in love with
you or something? He's using you.
Pulse ox is only 87.
He's hypoventilating,
needs a tube.
- Danny, breathe. Breathe.
- What's going on?
Daria, you're up, 15
etomidate, 75 of sux.
- Already drawn, pushing.
- MAC 2 and a 6-O.
Always check the
equipment before you start.
- How could you?
- You ready?
Yeah. MIKE: I
didn't say anything.
Watch the teeth.
- I can't see the cords.
- Here's some suction.
Your freak kid attacked me.
- Don't say that.
Mom, get out. Danny needs you.
Know what? You're nothing
but a crazy drunk whore anyway.
What do you want, man?
Stop! Stop! Stop!
Pull out and bag
him up. I'll be back.
Scott! DARIA: He needs a cord.
- Pull the blade upward.
- I am.
No, you're rocking it back.
- Dr. Brenner, I can't get it!
- Watch out. The tube.
- Wait, I thought you just said...
- Tube. Give me the tube.
You don't need a mnemonic
to save someone's airway.
Hey!
Well, we're not
getting out that way.
Don't worry. Pretty soon,
I'm gonna get you out of here.
You're gonna be with your
mom and your sister and Trevor.
The important thing is
not to be scared, okay?
Looks like you made out
pretty good there, huh?
Can I have a piece of candy?
No?
You have enough sugar in there to
put all of Chicago into a diabetic coma.
One piece?
All right. You know
what you're doing there?
It's called emotional eating.
Anybody seen the chart
on my flatulence guy?
It is not in the rack and I am not going
back into his room to look for it again.
Why is there a
bird on my charts?
That's Trevor, he belongs to
a family Dr. Gates was seeing.
- Where is Dr. Gates?
- No one's seen him in a while.
Frank!
Find Gates and get this bird...
James Mackey, multiple gunshots
to the chest and upper left arm.
- Party got out of hand.
- I need vitals.
Tachy at 120, pressure's
at a 100 with a liter.
- Four of O neg, x-ray.
- No pulse in the left wrist.
- What's with the police escort?
- They say this guy tried...
to shoot at some cops.
They shot at him first.
Five stitches.
That's not too bad.
Danny's gonna be fine.
When we're finished
here, I'll take you upstairs...
and you can wait with your mom.
He's right. She's a whore.
You shouldn't say that.
Then why does she
act like she does?
Lets us go to bed when we want.
Never yells at us to do homework.
- We can have friends over any time.
- Some kids would love that.
She lets us drink.
Better at home than some
strange place, she says.
But then, uh, she
starts drinking with us...
starts flirting with the guys.
Does Danny know what's going on?
When he was younger,
I could make stuff up.
Now he's in the same school.
I hate her.
I know she's let
you down. I get that.
But try not to hate her.
That's not gonna
get you anywhere.
Do you want some
more orange beef?
Mm. No. Any more and I won't
be able to fit through the door.
Well, then I guess you'll just
have to stay here and never leave.
Ah.
Well, don't tempt me.
Actually, it'd be nice. It gets
lonely around here sometimes.
Yeah, I know what that's like.
But you have your mom nearby.
Mm-hm.
She's great.
But a lot of the time,
she doesn't get it.
She can't understand
why I don't want her help.
Must be frustrating.
Yeah, I just think that deep down
she's a little worried that I might...
I kind of freaked her
out at one point, so...
When?
It was long time ago.
It was a bad time.
What happened?
It was at the hospital,
after the accident.
I tried to hurt myself.
I tried to kill myself.
Vicodin.
I wish I'd known. I
would've tried to help.
No.
No, it was something that I
had to go through on my own.
And I feel pretty strong
now, having overcome all that.
- Intubation tray.
- Prep for a chest tube.
- So we don't get a tension pneumo.
- Set up fiber-optic and open a crike tray.
- We can get those if we need them.
- Induction meds on board.
Let's do it.
Give the meds a minute
to work. Bag him up.
This the guy from the
Halloween party shooting?
Are you family?
- No, police officer.
- Sorry, but you can't question him now.
You gotta make
sure this kid makes it.
All right, do a jaw thrust so
you don't fill his stomach with air.
Okay, Tracy, he's
loose. Go for it.
Twenty years on the job, never
fired my weapon before tonight.
You shot him?
I didn't get a good look at him. All
I saw was a weapon pointed at me.
Then you did what you had to.
Part of his costume.
It was a toy gun.
Keep pushing. Lean into it.
- Maybe you should take over, Dr. Morris.
- Need another doc in here?
I got it. MORRIS: Way to go.
Dr. Brenner, glove up,
check the Thora-Seal.
- We were about to.
- Fair amount of blood.
- Have a thoracotomy tray ready.
- He's hemodynamically stable.
For now. You have to be prepared
for anything and everything.
- You sound like a cop.
- Our jobs aren't all that different.
- O-silk, please.
- Yeah, things can turn on you real fast.
Okay, set up for
a portable chest.
Let's step out for the x-ray.
When I was younger, I had a
traffic stop, guy's tail light was busted.
Routine, right?
My gut told me
something was wrong,
I ignored it.
As I was telling him
to get the light fixed...
he pulled out a gun, shot his
wife in the passenger seat...
and then killed himself.
- That's horrible.
- Yeah.
Took a desk job after that.
Pushing papers isn't why I became a
cop and so I go back on the street and...
Officer Flores is
here for her partner.
- Friends of the patient are in Waiting.
- Have them wait there.
- What are you doing?
- Gotta make sure he pulls through.
They sent us home. The brass finds you,
finds me talking to you, we're in trouble.
Systolic's down.
Squeeze a liter. Hang the O neg.
Call Thoracic. Take him to O.R.
Now? CATHERINE:
1200 cc's of blood.
Let the docs do their job.
Let me take you home.
- No, I'm not leaving. It's my fault.
- He's hypotensive. Wait until he arrests?
- I didn't mean to shoot him.
- Don't say anything.
He must've thought we were guests
at the party, dressed up as cops.
Maybe you guys
should step outside.
I'll come find you.
Yes, yes, he'll get his own red
cells, platelets and clotting factors.
- Decreases the risk.
- His output is slowing down.
Okay, just give us 10
minutes, we'll turn him around.
You know, at first I thought, I
don't know how to be a father.
I mean, what business
do I have, you know?
You know, I'm not saying I
didn't make mistakes with Sarah...
but things are good now between us,
you know? I've adjusted, she's adjusted.
Just like I know you will
with your new family situation.
And soon, I hope, huh?
Hey, hold that door, will you?
Come on, kid, we're out of here.
Let's go. We're free.
Come on, Owen.
Come on.
These are my favorite.
Only 100 cc's of
additional blood.
BP is 110 over
75. Heart rate's 85.
- Best so far.
- All right.
Angio is waiting
to squirt his arm.
Vascular's ready to
repair the brachial artery.
Have the blood bank
stay two units ahead.
You really should try to
control your enthusiasm.
Excuse me?
We just kicked ass in there.
Why not enjoy victory a little?
Because we need
to remain vigilant.
Patient can crash while
you do your victory dance.
Yeah. Listen, Cate.
- Anyone call you that?
- Once.
Okay. We work under a lot of stress,
so when something good does happen...
why not enjoy it,
just have some fun?
There is no room
for levity in the ER.
No offense, but if
that's your attitude...
then your day is
always gonna suck.
- Night, Frank. FRANK:
Have a good one.
Thanks.
Sam. Where you going?
- My review class.
- Thought you were gonna blow that off.
Yeah, well, going to school
isn't just a cutesy little hobby.
What are you talking
about? I support this.
I know. When it's convenient for
you, doesn't interfere with your life.
That's not true.
You have an outdated,
sexist view of what nurses do.
- We do a lot more than change bedpans.
- I know.
Wish you'd respect
what I'm trying to do...
- to learn. TRACY:
Want a tall triple decaf?
Heaven forbid you get
an intern to do scut work.
Showing off to Daria by
making me look small?
Know what? That
is never gonna fly.
Teaching the interns is part of
my job. What do you want me to do?
Nothing. Forget it.
You're nervous. Let's go
home and I'll help you study.
Okay.
All right, well, what is the anesthetic
of choice for open-heart surgery?
- Yeah, that's what I thought.
- Don't be like that.
I gotta go.
Any word on Danny?
They removed a small
blood clot from his brain.
Said he'll be in recovery soon.
- Where's Scott?
- Upstairs, waiting for his brother.
They're good kids.
Why don't you stop
screwing them up?
- What do you know about it?
- You're sleeping with a high school boy...
- Mike is 18. We're adults.
- No, he is a kid.
He sees you as nothing more than
an easy lay and he's not afraid to say it.
Mike didn't mean to say
those things. He loves me.
You know what?
He really doesn't.
- I'm not talking to you about this...
- Talk with Social Services.
And the boys too. I called them.
You have no right.
Scott has seen way
more than he should've.
He tries to protect his brother.
He's not the parent. You are.
So why don't you
start acting like it?
You have done a number on these
kids and that is gonna last a long time.
Go to hell.
Just fix your life,
lady. It's not too late.
Thank you.
You know...
I wish I could've been there for you
when you were going through all of that.
Well, we weren't really on a
talking basis for a while, so...
- Oh, I love this song.
- Cool tune.
Give me that.
Come here.
You know...
I felt responsible
for what happened.
I still do sometimes.
Neela, I was drunk and stupid.
And standing in the middle of
the road in the middle of the night.
- But the way I handled things was...
- Neela.
Let it go.
I have.
Ugh.
It's probably trick-or-treaters.
Let's ignore them. They'll go away.
So you were saying.
After the accident...
um, I had a lot of
time to look at my life.
And what I had to do to get
back on my feet again, literally.
And it's given everything
that happened before...
it's put that into perspective.
Mm. Bollocks.
- Um, let me get rid of them.
- Okay.
Sorry, kids... but
I'm all out of candy.
- You owe me $80.
- What are you doing here?
Look, I'm sorry, I
didn't realize you...
- Give me a minute, okay?
- Sure.
- Okay?
- Okay.
- You can't just show up.
- I...
There's nothing
going on between us.
- We work together and that's it.
- I know, I just...
I thought we could have a
drink and... Like a celebration.
Dr. Gawande agreed
to do grand rounds.
Good for you, but as you
can see, I've got company.
Right, right, Ray.
Okay, well... - I'll go.
- Yeah, please do.
So, I'll see you...
I'll see you at work.
I'm, uh, sorry. I
didn't invite him.
No, it's getting
late. I should go.
You don't have to.
It's been a great
day, a fun night...
but I have that conference
in the morning, so...
You can stay here instead
of driving to the hotel.
I'm in a good place now.
And you seem good, too, so...
I'm gonna go.
See you soon.
Mr. Mackey's out of surgery.
The bleeding in his chest was from
vessels that clotted off on their own.
Bullet tore through an
artery in his upper arm...
but the surgeons
got to it quickly.
- So he's gonna be okay?
- He should be fine.
No residual
paralysis or disability.
Oh, good.
Oh.
That's good to hear.
Uh...
Yeah.
You do what you can...
but you can't be
prepared for everything.
Make a mistake at some office
job, what happens? Nothing much.
Our watch...
people get hurt, people die.
Yeah, yeah.
But you can't let it
take away all the good.
Uh...
I suggest you leave
before you're seen.
If you get your partner, I'll show
you a side door that you can use.
Yeah.
Thanks.