Santa.
Mr. Claus, wake up.
Santa, you okay?
Santa...
Oh, must have dozed off.
I woke up feeling
a little dizzy.
Must be those double shifts.
Come on back.
We'll check you out.
Oh, okay.
Up you go.
Oh, my gosh, it's 10:00.
Kids will be lined
up for blocks.
I got to go.
Oh, I think you ought
to see a doctor first.
I'm already late.
At least let me check
your pressure, okay?
Are you taking any medication?
Um, I'm feeling a lot better.
Thanks, young
man. Thanks anyway.
But...
Okay, I've got skates
for Rachel... that's easy...
But I never know
what to get Jen.
Only six shopping
hours left till Christmas.
I can't believe I'm
waiting till the last minute.
I got to make up for last year.
What did you get her?
A dustbuster.
Ow.
Hey, get her a
broom. It's cheaper.
I'm running out of ideas.
Okay, go to field's.
Fill me in on the patients.
I'll cover for you.
You sure? Yeah. Just
be back in an hour.
Can I borrow your
car? Chloe has it.
Dr. Greene... Freeman,
Zimberg and Woo
are waiting to be discharged.
Sounds like an
international law firm.
Here. Thanks.
Okay, be careful going in here,
'cause Regina's
busy hallucinating.
Mr. O'Neill, he
opened up his hand
along with a can of mixed nuts.
Incoming head
trauma on the chopper.
Okay. Susan, take over for me.
Uh... sure.
Oh, Susan, there's an
electrical burn in One,
a "weak and dizzy
all over" in Two,
Uh-huh. and torn
cartilage waiting in three.
Ah, Dr. Lewis, from
your Secret Santa.
Oh, you know... uh, okay.
Suz, I'm tied up
here with an LP.
Will you Gram stain
that for me? Oh, man.
All right.
There, thanks. Uh,
Merry Christmas.
Yeah.
Hey, Dr. Green.
Haleh's fudge.
Ooh, you're spoiling me, Jerry.
Help me! Help me!
Help me! Somebody help me!
My son's dying!
I'm, I'm a doctor.
Give me your kid.
Come on, I got him, I got him.
He fell in the lake. Yeah?
Please help him. Uh-huh.
Murray! Murray!
Near drowning!
Murray!
Kid's frozen. Trauma One.
Got it, Haleh?
It's all my fault.
Murray, don't die, please.
Please don't...
Sir, you got to back up.
Get him out of here.
Get him out of here!
Sir, you got to come with me.
Sir, you got to wait back here.
I have to stay right here.
He's not breathing.
Start pulmonary suction.
Laryngoscope.
Five-and-a-half ET tube.
Yeah. Perfect.
All right.
Come on, little guy.
Tube's in.
Let's suck the water
out of him, then bag him.
Connie, I want blood studies,
a coag panel and a chest film.
What happened?
I took him ice fishing.
Murray ran ahead and fell in.
How long was he under?
How long?
I don't know, five
minutes, maybe.
I couldn't find him.
B.P.'s 30 palp, pulse is weak.
He's bradycardic,
heart rate's 32.
What's his temp? Eighty.
Let's warm him up, or
we're going to lose him.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou among women,
and blessed is the
fruit of thy womb Jesus.
Holy Mary, mother of
God, pray for us sinners
now and at the...
Oh, God, don't
take my little boy.
Please don't take my son.
Put him on heated,
humidified O-2.
I need the suction cath.
The warmed IVs are here.
How about a pleural
lavage to warm up his heart?
Yeah, yeah. That's a good idea.
Lydia, grab me two 36
French thoracostomy tubes.
Right.
We may have to do a
cardiopulmonary bypass.
All right?
All right, Carter.
You know the drill. Come on.
Keep your head down.
What do you got?
25-Year-old male.
Crashed his snowmobile
on the convoy.
No helmet. Found him comatose.
Pulse 110.
Normotensive, 140/90.
Reps 12 and agonal.
Tubed him in the field.
Neuro exam?
GCS 4, right pupil blown.
Decerebrate posturing.
Ready.
He's in asystole.
How about atropine?
Body temp's too low.
I'm not getting a pulse.
Come on, Murray.
Don't give up on me now.
Come on, pal.
Let's get the crash
cart over here.
Come on, Murray.
Hold on. Stay with us.
Stay with us.
All right. Let's go.
Carter, diagnosis.
Hematoma, right side of brain.
Same side as the blown pupil.
Uh-huh. Prognosis? Poor.
Yeah, well, with a
Glasgow score of four,
I'd say he's doing
about as good as a rock.
Let's go, people.
Let's put him in! Let's go!
All right. Hurry up.
Unstrap him. We've
got to move him.
We've got to move him quick.
All right, here we go.
Come on, people, let's move.
One, two, three, move him.
Here we go.
All right, Carter.
How do you decrease
intercranial pressure?
Burr hole decompression. Uh-huh!
Spoken like a true surgeon.
But I don't like to drill holes
in people's heads
unless I have to.
All right, hyperventilate him.
Pressure's holding. 130/90.
All right, Malik.
Rapid bolus him
with 75g's of mannitol.
Positive Babinski.
Uh-huh.
He's got fluid
draining from his ear.
All that cerebral spinal fluid.
Basilar skull fracture?
All right, Malik.
Get a head CT
and a nuclear scan.
Let's see how much
brain he's got left.
Haleh, try and track
down the next of kin.
Carter, get a blood type.
Anybody know his name?
License says Teddy Powell.
He's back!
Good boy.
Let's start a warm
peritoneal lavage.
Kid's clotting
factors look normal.
Let's keep those
heated IVs going.
I'll watch for rewarming shock.
Good.
So, Hathaway's engagement party?
Uh, I heard.
You going?
Not invited. I'm going
to be in Winnetka
with Linda's parent's
eating goose, in a tux.
Life could be worse.
You won't need me here anymore.
I am off page.
Where are you going? Shopping.
Doctor, Doctor...
thank you for helping my son.
I'm Dr. Greene.
I'm Dante Valario.
I'll never forget you.
Mr. Valario, your
son's condition is stable,
but he's not out of danger yet.
Now, we're still
warming up his body
and it's too early
to know how he'll respond.
Can I see him now?
Yeah. Yeah.
Shoot!
Regina's still agitated.
Would you take a quick peek?
Do I have a choice?
Claims a grinch
spiked her eggnog.
It's my party.
It's my party!
♪ And she'll cry
if she wants to ♪
♪ Cry if she wants to ♪
♪ You would cry, too,
if it happened to you ♪
♪ Give her 5 Haldol. ♪
The E.R. is no place
for a case like this.
I.C.U. is maxed out.
Okay, well, can't Neuro take it?
Soon as there's an opening.
Till then, it stays
in your service.
All right, all right.
He's got a big
right-sided bleed.
Midline shift.
Herniated. Mm-hmm.
No uptake activity
in the brain stem.
Can we do anything?
Carter, he's brain dead.
Let's keep his heart going
till we can locate a relative
and get permission
to recover his organs.
Okay, we already got that.
He signed the
back of his license.
He's got family. Get consent.
♪ It's my party... ♪
Mark!
Head lac in the suture room.
Oh, call Susan.
She's covering for me.
Susan's tied up, and your
name is still on the board.
Come on.
You should have seen it.
The Trib called it
"a masterpiece of
electrical ingenuity.
86,239 bulbs of
scintillating brilliance."
Huh?
Uh...
Enough wattage to
light ten city blocks.
Uh, you know, it
takes me two months
to put all the lights up.
You know, people travel
from all across this state
just to see it.
That's how famous we are.
Connie, get a C.B.C, lytes
and C.P.K. to make sure
there's no muscular damage.
My wife said I should
charge admission this year.
I said no.
We-we-we take and we take.
We should give
something back, you know.
Bring some joy to
the neighborhood.
I'm sure it's beautiful,
Mr. Kaminski.
Beautiful? No. It-It
was breathtaking.
Do you know we took first
place five years in a row
in the amateur division?
Right. You know,
that's a record.
This year was the topper.
It was an alpine Christmas.
We had everything.
We had... mountains and chalets.
We had a... a miniature ski lift
that went all the
way to the roof.
All I needed was
just a little more juice.
The power company said no.
I tried to tap into
the main power box.
Now... now look at me.
We'll give you a
topical antibiotic
and keep you on
the EKG to make sure
the power surge
didn't hurt your heart.
My heart?
What can that machine
tell about a broken heart?
How's his temp?
Up to 88.
B.P.'s steady.
Still got a long way to go.
Brain damage?
It's hard to say.
If you're going to
drown, do it in cold water.
Murray?
Hey, buddy.
Merry Christmas, Murray.
Oh, Mark, Mark...
Merry Christmas.
Aah.
Hey, you're five minutes
late. What'd you get?
I haven't even gone yet.
What happened?
Too many patients,
not enough residents.
Your offer still stand?
Oh, yeah. Just be back by lunch.
I'm starving. Okay, thanks.
Bye.
Malik, can you erase
my name off that board?
Stabbing coming in.
68-Year-old male
mugged in a parking lot.
Penetrating stab
wounds to mid-abdomen.
Mark?
Pressure crashed at 60.
Brought him up to 130
with 1,000cc's normal saline.
Blood loss?
200cc's, bleeding contained.
Give me six units of O-negative.
Notify the O.R.
Let them know they may
have a laparotomy coming up.
Are you his wife?
Yes.
Does he have any history
of medical problems?
Heart problems? Hypertension?
No, no, no, he's
in perfect health.
Okay, you have to
stay right here, ma'am.
The ventilator will keep
his blood hyperoxygenated
and his heart, kidneys
and liver perfused
until we're ready for surgery.
He may be going into D.I.C.
All right, give me ten packs
of platelets and two units
fresh frozen plasma.
I am not losing his organs to
a bunch of damn blood clots.
I've located Mr. Powell's wife.
She's on her way over. Good.
He's in V-fib.
All right, come
on, let's spark him.
I need this heart.
Come on, Carter, let's move.
One hundred.
Charging.
Good. All right.
Ready.
Clear! Clear.
He's in sinus rhythm.
Carter, call
cardiology for an echo.
I just resuscitated a dead man.
Pretty nasty cut, Patrick.
How'd you hurt yourself?
Can... can I have
some ch-chocolate milk?
Sure.
Patrick, what happened
to your helmet?
I lost it.
Okay.
Did your father bring you here?
Wh-Wh-Why did
the cat walk on sand?
Why?
To... to get sandy claws.
Jerry, is the organ
network on line?
Yeah, I linked you up
with local and regional.
All righty, let me get in.
Carter, did you
get the blood type?
Yeah, I did. It's B-negative.
Okay, here we go.
Age... 25.
Male.
Height... 5 "10".
Weight... 70 kilos.
Blood type... B.
All right, let's
see what we got.
What we got, what we got...
Okay, here we go.
Cincinnati General's got
a guy that needs a heart
and there's a woman in
Altoona dying for a liver.
Both perfect matches. Good.
It's going to be a
merry Christmas
for a few lucky people, huh?
I feel ridiculous coming
here, but Aaron insisted.
He's worried... his cousin
died of a ruptured appendix.
Ooh, that's pretty tender.
Do you think it's serious?
I wanted Aaron here
to be here with me,
but his plane's been delayed.
Look, if there's anything wrong,
I don't want to hear it alone.
I'm not too concerned,
Mrs. Skulper,
but I want to do a few more
tests just to be sure, okay?
Okay, thanks.
I got this from Neuro.
This is the best they could do.
Ah, thanks, Malik.
Look, Patrick, I have
a new helmet for you.
No, I d-don't want it.
Why? If you don't wear it,
you'll hurt your
head when you fall.
A-And I'll have to c-come back?
Do you want to
stay here for a while?
Okay.
Look, Patrick, no one
answers at your home.
Does anyone know you're here?
Hmm...
Do you see anything yet?
I don't see any gallstones.
Oh, my...
It's my appendix.
I knew it.
No, it's...
It's something worse?
Is it a tumor?
It's a baby...
About 12 weeks old
with a steady heartbeat.
A baby?
My baby?
We tried for years.
They said it was impossible.
Well, you proved them wrong.
I'll have obstetrics come
down, but everything looks fine.
Oh, look at that.
It's a miracle.
Aaron's gonna flip!
Thank you, Dr. Lewis.
Thank you.
Well, be sure to
send me a picture.
Oh, a baby!
We have been
waiting over an hour.
Kirby could have died.
He'd have to eat an
entire poinsettia plant
to be sick, Mrs. Bower.
Even then, he'd only
have a bad stomachache.
This is my
colleague, Dr. Carter.
He's going to examine him.
Please hurry.
We have company coming.
Need any help?
I think I can handle this one.
Merry Christmas.
Thanks. Merry Christmas.
Carter, you might
want to wait a minute.
I'm just having a little trouble
getting Kirby to open his mouth.
Carter, watch it.
Almost got it.
Carter! What?
Oh!
Doug!
Buddy, got to know when to jump.
Ew...
You heading home, Mr. Kaminski?
Yeah, yeah. Try and rescue
as many bulbs as I can.
The power surge probably
blew out most of them though.
Well, just remember to
change the dressing daily
and apply the
antibacterial ointment.
Okay.
Hey, these are beautiful.
Thank you, Dr. Lewis.
Just use them safely.
These are old,
antique twinklers.
I mean, they're... they're
a real collector's item.
Perfect for next year's
old-fashioned theme.
Where'd you find them?
Oh, man.
First, somebody
eats all the popcorn
off the Christmas tree, and
now the lights are missing.
Have you had any
trouble sleeping
or with your appetite?
I'm been waking up very early
and I can't seem
to get back to sleep.
Mm-hmm. How have
your spirits been?
I don't know.
Have you ever suffered
from depression, Mrs. Abernathy?
Well, the holidays are
always pretty rough for me.
And this year is worse.
How much worse?
Sometimes... I can
barely get out of bed.
I've made some
terrible mistakes with my life.
Christmas just seems
to bring them back.
He was injured this morning
in a snowmobiling accident.
He never regained consciousness.
The medical examiner
determined that your husband is...
is brain dead.
I'm... I'm sorry.
I don't understand.
Why is he hooked up to all
these machines if he's dead?
Well, because he
could help others
by donating his organs.
His face... it's so warm.
And his hands...
I've heard of people
waking up from comas.
There is this man in our
church who was in a coma
for six months, and
everybody said it was hopeless
and then one day he woke up.
I'm sorry, Mrs. Powell, but...
there is absolutely
no possibility
of your husband ever recovering.
Well, I want a second opinion.
Look, I know...
I know he looks like he's alive,
but the only reason he's
hooked up to this ventilator
is to keep his heart pumping.
I want a second opinion.
Hi. Have you seen Doug?
Sorry.
Oh. Dr. Greene, are you a skier?
Uh... no.
My company is sponsoring
an emergency physician's
conference in Aspen...
Tax deductible,
continuing medical education
credits, free lessons...
Oh, hi, sweetie.
Linda's drumming up business.
Residents don't
buy pharmaceuticals.
They just like your freebies.
You like my freebies?
That's a whole other story.
I left the tux in your locker.
Any luck finding bargains?
I haven't been
able to go out yet.
Do you have any idea where I
can get Jen in 15 minutes or less?
Well, I'm a killer shopper.
You wouldn't mind?
I've got some last-minute
shopping to do.
What's your price range?
Huh...
I get it. Strictly budget
basement. Same as Doug.
Nice tie.
Oh, Thanks. I got it from
Haleh, my Secret Santa.
Oh.
Have you opened your
Secret Santa gift yet?
Oh, no. I haven't had a chance.
♪ I will face the unknown ♪
♪ I'll build a world of my own ♪
♪ No one knows better... ♪
Miss Cavanaugh.
♪ ...than I myself ♪
♪ I'm by myself, alone. ♪
Miss Cavanaugh, can I help you?
I'd like a suite with
a view of the lake.
And would you take
my bag up, please?
He's developing neurogenic
pulmonary edema.
Lydia, give him
renal range dopamine
and 40 milligrams of lasix.
How much time do we have?
I don't know.
About an hour before
we start losing organs.
Also, increase the
vent pressure to ten.
Peter, Dr. Hicks is outside.
She'd like to speak to you.
All right.
Why are you holding Powell?
Cardiac and liver transplant
teams are waiting upstairs.
Well, I...
I ran into a little problem
with the patient's wife.
What?
His wife won't sign the consent.
You called the team before
you had his wife's consent?
His driver's license
gave us permission.
I told you to
contact the family.
It's his wife's
decision, not yours.
If she doesn't want
it, we don't do it.
You've got eight
transplant surgeons flying
into this hospital,
with patients and their families
waiting at the other end.
If we can't harvest, what are
you going to tell these people?
You may need an antidepressant.
I'm going to give you
the name of a therapist.
I think my sadness may
be connected to something
that happened a long time ago.
Mm-hmm. On Christmas?
40 Years ago...
a young man proposed
to me and I said no.
It was the biggest
mistake of my life.
Why'd you say no?
He was Jewish.
My parents didn't approve.
And last year
after my mother died,
I found his letters.
She'd kept them hidden from me.
He wanted to know why I
wouldn't answer his letters,
why I stopped loving him.
He lived in Tulsa.
So, I got his number
and I called him
and a beautiful voice
that I hadn't heard
in 40 years answered.
It was his son.
Sammy died three years ago.
Hey, Mark.
Could I borrow your pen?
Great save on that
mesenteric rupture.
Thanks.
Listen, uh, I've got a problem.
I've got a gork's wife
who won't sign a consent,
and if she doesn't
change her mind soon,
I'm going to start
losing organs.
I was hoping maybe...
you could persuade her.
Sometimes you can't.
Yeah, but I already
called the chop,
and the transplant
teams are on their way.
That wasn't very smart.
See what I can do.
He's not breathing.
Crash cart to Trauma One.
Call a code!
Fill me in.
I don't know what happened.
He complained of
dizziness this morning.
You let him go?
He left against medical advice.
All right, I'm going to
need some muscle in here!
Okay, got it. Thanks.
All right, let's move him.
One, two, three.
Taking any medication?
Under the belt.
I can't find a pulse.
Okay.
He's in arrest.
Malik, give him an amp of epi.
Atropine. One milligram IV.
Mrs. Powell, I'm Dr. Greene.
I'm the chief resident here.
Are you taking over the case?
Dr. Benton just asked
me to come speak to you.
To sign the consent.
I want you to do what you think
your husband would have wanted
and what's right for you.
I don't know what Teddy
would have wanted.
I haven't spoken to
him in five months.
But you are his wife?
We were separated last summer.
He called me yesterday.
He wanted us to spend
Christmas together.
I told him no.
I wanted to hurt him as
much as he'd hurt me.
I wanted him to
come crawling back.
beg for forgiveness.
Now all I want
to do is hold him.
I just want him to
know that I still love him.
Mark it 1922.
Do we get an I.D.?
No wallet, no driver's
license, nothing.
Carter.
Oh, God...
I killed Santa.
Any word from Neuro?
They haven't been down yet.
Hope he's the same
kid he was before.
Yeah.
Did he say anything?
Hasn't made a sound.
♪ We three kings of Orient are ♪
♪ Bearing gifts we travel far ♪
♪ Field and fountain,
moor and mountain ♪
♪ Following a yonder star ♪
♪ Star of wonder,
star of light ♪
♪ Star of royal beauty bright ♪
♪ Westward leading
still proceeding ♪
♪ Guide us to
the perfect light. ♪
His parents went
away on vacation
and left him with the neighbors.
Her family left
her with a cousin.
All of sudden, her
Alzheimer's gotten a lot worse.
Hey, Jerry, I've
paged Div twice.
Are you sure he hasn't called?
Yeah. Sorry, Dr. Lewis.
Yeah, he probably just forgot
to turn on his beeper again.
But I thought Cvetic quit.
What?
I thought he quit.
Yes, Dr. Cvetic, please.
Okay. Thank you very much.
Is everything all
right, Dr. Lewis?
What?
Is everything okay?
I don't know.
When do you get off?
Just signed out.
Would you do me a favor?
Sure. Could I have a ride?
Prom night?
Something like that.
Linda picking you up?
No, I'm meeting her there.
Cocktails at Jack's Place,
then on to Winnetka
for 200 of her parents'
close, personal friends.
Do I detect a lack
of enthusiasm?
It beats putting in chest tubes.
Mark, we got a bunch of choir
kids and a minor fender bender.
Anything serious?
Only cuts and scrapes.
Merry Christmas, guys.
Merry Christmas.
See ya.
You okay?
Thought I was.
I think about her all the time.
Do you ever tell her that?
No, no, no.
Why not?
'Cause I was afraid.
Afraid of what,
she might say no?
Afraid she might say yes.
It's too late.
She's not married yet.
You spoke to Dr. Greene.
Yes.
Mm-hmm.
We're running out of time.
So what?
Okay.
Hey.
Where's the form?
Div?
He moved out.
Hello.
They hung up.
♪ Dashing through the snow,
on a one-horse open sleigh ♪
♪ Over the fields we go... ♪
Bob...
did you take those
Christmas lights down?
No. It is not true.
Whoever says this is a liar.
I was asking a question.
So you going to be okay?
Thanks, Carter.
You're a really
good friend to me.
Good Secret Santa, too.
You're my Secret Santa.
Oh, I-I haven't
even opened it yet.
It's a music box.
Thank you.
So, uh... you're sure
you're going to be okay?
Yeah, I'm always okay.
'Cause I could come,
come in for a while.
Keep you company.
Uh...
I don't, I don't think
we should do this.
I'm sorry.
No, don't be.
Oh.
Well, this was for Div, but...
Thanks, I guess.
Well, I got to get
back to the hospital.
I got to check on
Miss Cavanaugh, so...
Merry Christmas.
Excuse me. Hi. Uh...
Hey, buddy.
We're here.
What?
We're here, the cafe.
Change your mind?
No. Here you go.
Hurry up! We're late.
Hey, no, hang on!
Hey! Hang on, hey... hey!
Hey, come on!
Linda Farrell
brought this in for you.
Oh, thanks.
Wow, is that for Jennifer?
You got good taste.
Thanks.
All my ex ever gave me
was a vacuum cleaner.
Okay.
Organs look good.
Let's proceed with the harvest.
Stop the heart first.
Insert the catheter into
the brachiocephalic artery.
Okay.
Catheter's in.
Now, cross-clamp the aorta
right above the diaphragm.
Doctor, clamp.
Okay.
Aorta cross-clamped at 2048.
Now infuse the
cardioplegia solution quickly.
Heart rate's falling.
Heart stopped.
Let's get these organs out now.
Susan.
Susan!
Where's Div?
I don't know.
Wasn't he supposed
to come home with you?
Well, his apartment's
empty and he's gone.
So, I guess not.
Aw, man, cheer up.
I've been dumped
by lots of guys.
I got over it.
You'll get over it, too.
Hey, that's my robe.
May I borrow it?
Yes, you may.
Thank you.
That music's pretty.
It was a gift.
Ooh...
Mm... you know, it
reminds me of that...
that merry-go-round
we used to ride.
That looks so cool.
Oh, I got you something.
Oh...
Oh, it's pretty.
"Susan."
Thank you.
You'll have to share
it with the baby.
We're naming it after you.
What baby?
I'm pregnant.
Oh, Chloe.
Go home, Doug!
I love you.
You love some old idea of me.
And you love me. No, I don't.
Yes, you do. No, I don't!
You haven't changed,
Doug, and the sad thing is,
you don't even know it.
All right, then I will change.
I am not asking you to change!
Carol, listen to me!
I don't want to listen to you.
I don't want you, Doug.
Leave me alone.
What the hell's he doing here?
Leaving. No, I'm not.
What's going on? You're
coming home with me.
You need to get some help.
Get out of here, okay?
Go ahead and tell him
that you don't love me.
Tell him that you don't think
about me when you're with him.
Hey, hey, hey!
Stop, stop, stop, please! God.
Stay out of my life, Doug.
Tag... Tag, please.
Come on, please.
Let's get the liver and
kidneys up to the copters.
Thanks, everyone.
That's it. Benton, nice work.
The heart's only good for
three hours, so get it on ice,
then pray the weather
clears in Cincinnati.
Vinnie, could you sew him up?
Uh, if you don't mind,
I'd like to, uh, I'd
like to sew him up.
Okay.
You want staples?
No. I'll sew him up right.
Give me a number one
silk on a swedged needle.
♪ Have yourself a
merry little Christmas ♪
♪ Make the Yuletide gay ♪
♪ From now on, our troubles... ♪
Come on, Dr. Greene.
As soon as I'm finished.
♪ ...will be miles away ♪
♪ Here we are as in olden days ♪
♪ Happy, golden... ♪
His EEG is normal.
What does that mean?
It means his brain
function wasn't affected.
♪ Gather near to us once more ♪
Murray?
Murray, it's Papa.
Can you hear me?
Daddy...
That's my guy. Come here.
♪ Hang a shining star
upon the highest bough ♪
♪ And have yourself a
merry little Christmas now... ♪
Cincinnati's
cleared for landings.
Chopper's on its way.
Hi.
Here you go.
Thanks, man.
It worked out, huh?
Yeah, it did.
Merry Christmas.
Thanks.
♪ Through the years ♪
♪ We all will be together,
if the fates allow ♪
♪ Until then, we'll have to
muddle through somehow ♪
♪ So, have yourself a
merry little Christmas now. ♪
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org