Previously on Grey's Anatomy...
Goodbye, Derek.
- Right, Meredith.
- What do we got?
Katie Bryce, 15-year-old
female, new onset seizures.
Katie belongs to the new
attending now, Dr. Shepherd.
It's a subarachnoid hemorrhage.
She's bleeding into her brain.
You earned the right to follow
her case through to the finish.
I will discover that I am not
just the other Dr. Shepherd.
I'm the wrong Dr. Shepherd.
I'm just not ready
to forgive you yet.
Looking sharp.
You got a hot date?
Uh, yeah, something like that.
When we're alone, she's
so... She's a wildcat, huh?
Richard. Pierce.
Do you really want this?
This is one of the
simpler divorces I've seen.
You just signed divorce papers,
and you don't want a drink?
What are you... What
are you, pregnant?
I think I am.
"Any day where no
one died is a good day."
Someone said that once.
Wait. It was me. I said it.
Any day you wake up...
And your body's still moving...
Is a good day.
Keys. Where are my keys?
Did you check in
your jacket pockets?
You can start over.
Found them!
You can forget
your past mistakes.
You can make a new start.
Live every day
like it's your last.
All that crap they put on
pillows and car bumpers...
Sorry.
It's all true.
Guys!
You're alive.
Respect that.
Not everybody is.
This room is full
of dead people.
I know it's easy to
forget, but come on.
Something happened to them,
a mistake, a disease,
a stupid twist of fate.
They left their bodies
here for us to learn from,
to become better.
Let's have a little respect.
Time of death, 8:12.
Keps, call the
plumber, would you?
Sure.
Did he really just call
the morgue "the plumber"?
Oh! Yeah. That's
something we say over there.
They circle the drain, then
they clog it. "Call the plumber."
Hunt's right. We hate that guy.
Hey, you got a minute?
Hi, yeah. What's up?
Um... Listen, I just got
our last joint cell phone bill,
and I'm pretty sure they
still charged your card,
so I just want to
write you a check.
It's fine. No, no, no.
You shouldn't have to...
No, seriously,
Jackson. It's fine.
If you're sure...
This one's on me.
Okay.
You have to tell him.
Why? "Why"?
So he'll come back to me?
He doesn't want to be married.
A baby wasn't gonna change
that. It shouldn't change that.
Because it's his
baby. Because he...
I know. I know.
But I am happy for
the first time in a year.
And as soon as I tell him,
everything's gonna get all complicated.
And for right now...
Obviously, obviously
I'm going to tell him.
When I'm ready.
Oh! Hi. Hi.
You're only wearing one boot.
I know. I was late. And I
couldn't find the other one.
Amelia.
Ah!
You think I'm bootless
'cause I'm drunk.
It's fine. I'm not drunk.
I just got my 60-day chip.
I am bootless because
I had sex with Owen,
and his stupid
trailer is very dark.
And I was very late
because of the sex,
which was so great.
So I just thought, "Screw it."
I may not know where my boot is,
but it's gonna be a great day.
I hate you. Don't hate.
I haven't had sex in days.
DeLuca and I almost
got caught by Webber.
By Webber?
So we had to cool
it in the hospital.
And he's never got time.
Interns never have
any freaking time.
So I never have sex.
I know where all my boots are.
Why me? I don't know.
Webber just said
he wanted you today.
You know, every year, Webber
singles out one intern to be his guy.
My first year here, it was me.
He called us the Big Dogs.
Okay, well, why me, though?
Are you complaining right now?
Because this is an honor.
You have been anointed.
Webber is on top
of his own service.
You just listen and
learn from a master.
You have got the golden ticket,
my friend.
Dr. Webber. Here's your guy.
Good morning, sir.
I'm, uh... I'm
really excited to...
You look tired.
A late night?
No, sir, I...
I have a consult with Robbins.
Great. Let's get started.
Okay. You can do
rounds on my post-ops.
I've got a stack of
intern applications
on my desk that need filing.
3316 needs her drain checked,
and 1242 could
use a rectal exam.
Okay.
Oh! Um... You know,
actually, DeLuca...
Yes, sir.
What's this?
Dry cleaning.
Address is on the card.
Edwards! Morning.
Uh, Pit's called for a consult.
I rounded on all
of your post-ops.
Four aneurysm
repairs, all doing fine.
Mr. Klein is awake
and responsive.
What's the matter with you?
Nothing. Edwards.
It's all good.
It is a great day, and you are
bringing me down, Edwards.
Spill it.
It's like we're in a rut
of clipping aneurysms
'cause that is all we do.
It would be nice to throw a
glioma in there once in a while.
You're hoping for someone
to have a brain tumor?
Just to mix it up a little.
Because you're
bored of aneurysms.
I'm not complaining. I'm just...
You are. But I'll tell you what,
if you are so bored, the next
aneurysm that walks through that door,
you will clip it yourself.
Are you serious?
Okay, we'll take
you up for a scan,
and then we'll figure
out what's going on.
Yeah, sit tight. Don't worry.
Her baby's fine.
Yeah, I'm betting it's
an appendicitis. Mmm.
Yeah.
So, how'd it go? Hmm?
You left the bar with
the girl in the jean jacket.
I would have put you with
crop top. She looked smart.
I mean, so how was
it? Did you hit it off?
Oh! Um...
It was fine.
Fine? Yeah.
Fine.
Fine?
Patient's 25, complaining
of new onset headache,
transient numbness
on the left side.
She passed out in
gymnastics practice.
Do you know what I'm thinking?
You're thinking
it's an aneurysm.
I'm thinking it's my aneurysm.
It could be a tumor.
Don't say that.
This morning, you
were praying for a tumor.
Hi. Katie.
Who are you? I asked
for Dr. Shepherd.
And here I am.
No, you're not.
Dr. Shepherd is a guy.
Ah.
Look, I was here
before, years ago.
My First year. My first day.
Subarachnoid hemorrhage.
You're Katie Bryce.
IV lost en route,
started grand mal
seizing as we descended.
All right, get her on her side.
And I didn't get stuck
with someone this clueless,
and that was, like, a nurse.
Oh, my God.
They still let you
be a doctor here?
So, let me get this straight.
I had a thing.
You guys fixed it.
Now the symptoms
are back and worse.
I mean, I'm not
having seizures yet,
but I keep going
numb, and my head...
Well...
We're not exactly
sure what we're
dealing with, Katie.
I was going to say your
prelim neuro looks good.
The symptoms are
different from last time.
For the record,
I don't want to go
through that again.
You shaved my head.
I was, like, an
ug-mo troll for weeks
until I could get
extensions going.
Did you guys screw
this up last time?
Found it.
It's so old it's not
even in the computer.
Webber had to show me
the archive room.
You still doing pageants, Katie?
What was it,
rhythmic gymnastics?
Nope. Stopped those.
Pageants got me a
full ride to UW, though.
And now I coach gymnastics.
Two of my girls are
Olympic qualifiers.
Wow. Impressive.
No offense, but are you
gonna be operating on me?
Dr. Grey is not a neurosurgeon.
Good.
I mean, she was
kind of a train wreck.
She kept getting me lost.
It was my first day.
Hey, Katie Bryce is back.
Katie who?
Katie Bryce.
Day one of my internship,
mystery seizures,
Cristina and I solved
it, Derek operated.
It was my first surgery, Bailey.
How do you not remember this?
You were an intern, Grey. You
weren't even a person to me yet.
Okay. So, what
do you think it is?
A re-bleed or...
I don't know yet.
It feels like a tumor.
Could be a re-bleed
or the clip slipped.
Well, I watched Derek place
the clip. The clip didn't slip.
Meredith, clips slip.
Yeah, I'll get her to CT.
Order an angio, too,
based on her history.
Meredith.
What?
She's my patient. She came back.
She was Derek's
patient. Now she's mine.
Oh, Katie Bryce!
When Derek had
all of the interns
chasing their tail
for the answer...
Yes!
And he was chasing
your tail? Yes.
I'm gonna stay with you on this.
Mer, I have it.
My name is on the chart. I
need to make sure that we...
I will update you.
I'm gonna go discharge
a cancer patient.
I will be back.
Counting the minutes.
Daphne.
You hitting the books?
Yeah, I have to. I
have finals on Monday.
Physics. I loved physics.
Yeah. It would have
been easier when I was 20.
Well, but you're starting over.
It's impressive.
Starting over is hard.
String theory is harder.
But I pass this, I graduate
in June with honors.
Okay. You want to tell
her how she did here?
Flying colors. All your
follow-up labs came back clear.
Dr. Grey got all the
mets off your liver.
No recurrence. So...
So, after 10 months...
Say it.
You're cancer-free. Yes!
Thank you! Thank you so much!
Of course. Oh, man.
Okay, so, now are
you going to call David?
You're a nag.
I kicked your cancer.
We had a deal.
I need another month.
One more month,
and I get my diploma.
Also, one more round of chemo,
and then they take
my headphone jack out.
And then I will.
How long's the
redness been there?
I don't know. A week.
All right, put the books down.
I need to take a look at that.
Damn it! I was
almost out of here.
Hey. Hey.
So the ring is in your drawer.
Yeah.
What are you gonna do with it?
Well, what do you
mean? It's in my drawer.
Are you gonna take it back?
Do you want me to take it back?
Well, it was...
It was probably
expensive. It was.
And, uh, it's not doing anyone
any good in your drawer.
Yeah, well, I didn't
buy it for the drawer.
Look, you didn't say yes or no.
Is this no? Is that
what you're saying?
No.
"No," like, "no"?
Or, "no," like, "not no"?
I...
I don't know.
This was great!
Hey. The scans back
on our appendix yet?
Robbins, we've been
at this for a while.
What?
I have facilitated
in the introduction
of over a dozen women for you.
Mmm-hmm. I mean, I'm
invested in this project.
So when the results
we're getting are "fine,"
we can do better than that.
Um... It was... It
was better than fine.
It was...
You don't want
to hear about this.
No, no, no, I think feedback
is crucial to our success.
That way we can
course correct if need be.
It was way better than fine.
It turns out that she's in real
estate and an insanely good kisser.
And she...
I mean, she knows her way
around the neighborhood.
Oh! Where'd you go? Everywhere.
If you know what I'm saying.
From the hills to the low
country and all around downtown.
Ah. I get... Yeah, yeah.
Oh, my... I'm sorry.
I got carried away.
No, no, I asked.
Thought that you wanted to know.
I asked. Scans are ready.
I rounded on your
post-ops, got your labs back,
filed the intern applications,
and picked up your dry cleaning.
They got the stain out
of your purple sweater.
Excellent.
Yeah, so, you were right
about the appendicitis.
All right, DeLuca, you can go
get my surgery transcriptions.
Yes, sir.
Oh.
Hey, what's wrong with you?
Me? Oh, I'm fine.
I just never got
time to eat today.
Richard.
Don't kill the interns.
DeLuca, go eat.
Quickly. Thank you.
Did you know 8% of all
repaired aneurysm patients
had a recurrence?
It's gonna be a tumor.
Statistics say aneurysm.
Her symptoms say tumor.
And if it is an aneurysm,
you said I could clip it.
You said it's a great day.
And I agree with you, it
is a great day. I feel great.
Uh, so I will clip it, right?
Hush.
Crap. It's a tumor.
No. It's an aneurysm.
That's... That's an aneurysm?
I've never seen one that big.
Yeah, I don't want to clip that.
Neither do I.
It does look infected.
It might be superficial,
but it needs to come out.
Lidocaine.
You should have come in sooner.
I have a history paper
due on Wednesday.
I'm supposed to blow
that off? Plus two jobs.
I only fight cancer
on the weekends.
So, there might be some
blood, but you can look away.
Please, you guys have poked
and prodded me forever now.
Oh, my God,
that's a lot of blood.
Let's page cardio.
It's okay. That
doesn't look okay.
I know. I know. It's scary.
Daphne, look at me.
You're okay.
That's normal? All that blood?
Let's hang FFP, platelets,
one gram of TXA,
and crossmatch her.
Where is cardio?
Riggs is coming.
Ugh. Riggs.
Yes. "Ugh. Riggs" is here.
Daphne, right? What do we got?
Daphne's portacath got
infected, and when I removed it...
It was a gusher, looks like.
All right, I'll book an OR. No.
Daphne, I've given you some
medicine to help your blood clot,
so I'm just going to apply
pressure and wait for it to work.
Well, I think we
should move her,
get a good look at the vessels.
Well, I'm hoping it
just resolves itself here
so we don't have to open
her up and make it worse.
So you're just gonna
keep holding pressure?
That's the plan. Katie Bryce.
Oh, you need to be
somewhere? I can do it.
Are you leaving?
No, no, I'm here.
It's just holding pressure.
She's my patient.
She's sort of my patient
now. It's a cardiac case.
You can wait if you like.
All right. We'll wait a
little while, and we'll see.
Blake, you need repeat
coags every 30 minutes.
And push my chole
and cover my post-ops.
And get an update on
Shepherd's patient Katie Bryce.
Dr. Shepherd. Absolutely.
Speak.
Dr. Grey was wondering if...
Yeah, tell her
she's off the hook.
It had nothing to
do with the old case.
Your original repair is fine.
Okay, great. This is new.
It was a frontal lobe aneurysm,
the biggest one
I have ever seen.
How big? Like...
This isn't charades,
Blake. I need to see it.
She just wants to
look at the scans.
Then why doesn't she
come here and look at the...
She's busy with a patient.
You know what? So am I.
Tell her I don't have time
to give her computer access.
Tell her she doesn't
need to see the scan.
Absolutely.
That's a monster.
What's her approach?
Is she going to clip it
or do a primary repair?
I don't think she's
gone that far yet.
Well, find out!
Tell her if she
wants to talk to me,
she can come down
here and talk to me
and not keep sending her mole.
Tell her, "Thank you, Meredith,
"for the overwhelming
vote of confidence,
"but I will use the
approach I deem necessary."
And if she doesn't trust me,
she can come down here
and clip this thing herself.
And also, you can tell her to...
Yeah, I don't want
to do this anymore.
What is your problem
with Shepherd?
Mind your business.
I don't think she
likes you very much.
Ooh, you picked up
on that, huh? All right.
All right.
Go tell Shepherd...
Tell her to not screw it up.
I think she gets that.
Ow, ow, ow, ow. All
right, a little more lidocaine.
Ooh, maybe sailing.
Maybe I should get a boat.
That's too much upkeep.
Well, I need something, all right?
I feel like, you know,
it's a new chapter.
Start something new. I
need something that I can...
What about golf?
Nah, I think it's too
cliched, though...
Golfing doctors.
What did you do with your ring?
Ow. Ow. A little
lighter. A little lighter.
Um... I didn't know what to do
with it, so it's just in a drawer.
Right. It goes in a drawer.
And if she didn't
say yes or no...
And April... I mean,
she's, like, fine.
It's like she's
better than fine.
You'd think that she was the one
that was pushing for the damn divorce.
Sloan always
wanted me to try golf.
I never liked golf.
Love golf.
Just don't try hockey. Ow!
Jo doesn't know what she
wants. Neither does Amelia.
One day, she wants
to stop things cold,
the next, she never
wants it to stop.
If it keeps going like
this... It's all a lot of upkeep.
If she didn't want
a ring on her finger,
why does she care
what I do with it?
Because it's just sitting in
that drawer like a loaded gun.
And every time we
have sex or a fight,
he could just pull it
out and point it at me.
Do you even want the ring?
I don't want it... Right now.
Grey and Shepherd
are gonna kill each other,
and I'm going to
die in the crossfire.
Grey needs to chill 'cause
it's not even her case.
Shepherd could cut her
some slack. It was her case.
It was supposed to be my case.
Do you think I should
tell him to take it back?
Jo, you already did. If you
wanted it, you'd be wearing it.
I mean, are you doing all right?
'Cause after Arizona
and I got divorced,
it felt like my insides
were ripped out of me.
No. I mean...
Yeah, it was awful.
It was amicable, I
guess is the word.
Civil and polite and awful.
But, um, no.
I, uh... I feel good.
I feel really good.
You got divorced really
different from how I did.
Hey, man, you got
to take this, okay?
No, no, just take
it. Just... Here.
You're exhausted. You're
not too exhausted, right?
No. No. No. Okay.
No! No!
It's Webber.
It's Webber?
Yeah, he's made me his guy now,
which apparently means
relentless pages and endless scut.
Webber has singled you out?
Yeah, anointed me, apparently.
Oh, okay. He knows about us.
No. No.
Why would he make
me his guy, though?
I don't know. Um,
he's my father.
He's your what?
Yeah, maybe he doesn't know.
You said your folks
are from Boston.
Yeah, yeah, he's
my biological father.
Maggie, he's your father?
Maybe it's just a coincidence.
Oh! I'm so screwed!
No, no, I'll ask
him. I'll find out.
No, Maggie. I told
him you were a wildcat.
What? Why? Why
would you do that?
Webber's your father?
Hi. Ah.
What do you have?
Mitral valve.
I got Cross.
What about?
No, I mean, my intern.
I got Cross today.
He's pretty good.
A little green.
Who have you got? Ah, DeLuca.
Oh, you like him?
I've only worked with
him a couple times.
Yeah, he's an intern.
You know, he shows potential.
Mmm-hmm.
You know, he's calm
in surgery. Steady.
Yeah, he's got great hands.
I beg your pardon?
In the OR. 'Cause he was an EMT.
I heard... Oh.
I think. I guess.
Um... Yeah, I think
I heard that, too.
Yeah. Yeah.
He's a great roommate.
Dependable. Quiet.
What? DeLuca.
Right.
So, yeah, have
fun with him today.
Or... Have a good...
Yeah. Bye.
Yeah. Bye. Yeah.
And these are the consent
forms. There you go.
And this is a new one?
Yes.
And this one's bigger.
It's a very thin,
fragile balloon.
Even the tiniest disturbance
walking around could pop it.
And if it pops, I die?
Why does this keep happening?
You're predisposed to aneurysms.
It's just something that...
Dr. Shepherd fixed the last one.
I know. The other Dr. Shepherd.
He knew how to fix it.
Your first aneurysm was
very difficult to diagnose,
but it was easy to solve.
This one...
It's very risky.
Are you saying you can't do it?
I'm saying that I
will do my very best.
Katie.
We have to try.
Otherwise... I know. I just...
Are you as good as your brother?
Are you better than him?
Camera scope seems jittery.
Hold the damn
thing still, DeLuca.
Sorry, sir. I'm trying.
"Great hands."
So, are you gonna be
seeing "Jean Jacket" again?
No. Not her again.
She was fun, but a little crazy.
"Hoop Earrings,"
maybe. She was funny.
Tonight is, um, oh, "Artisanal
Soap." Remember her?
You said she was ditzy.
Yeah, she was. But she
smelled like lilacs everywhere.
Robbins, how many
women are you seeing?
Mmm, not that
many. Right, DeLuca?
Hmm? Oh! I don't know.
I mean, who's counting?
How would you know?
You're never there.
Mr. Secret Lover spends every
night at his girlfriend's place.
That's not true.
I told you. He's
the best roommate.
He has a girlfriend
with her own place
and clearly a crazy sex drive.
Is that the ileum
just above the...
That's what that is.
ARIZONA: Oh, yeah.
He brought her
to our place once.
Oh, my goodness.
I thought he was
killing her in there.
She's a screamer.
All right, that's enough!
Can we focus on the base
of the appendix, please?
Hmm.
Here's her latest lab results.
Do you want me
to book an OR now?
Septicemia. Pseudomonas.
PCR positive times two.
I can go in, try to get local
control, maybe subclavian repair.
Yeah, but she's got a possible
D-dimer with SIRS brewing.
We may have to.
I'm worried she may
not withstand GA, though.
Do you want to
dumb it down a little?
Okay, Daphne, your
portacath got infected,
and it's caused sepsis.
A big infection all over, which
can cause your organs to fail.
If I take my hands off and
you're not bleeding, we're good.
And if I do bleed?
Then I have to take you into the
OR and try to stop the bleeding.
But if Dr. Grey's right,
the surgery could
make you worse.
I should have come in sooner.
Do you want to call David now?
No. I screwed up again.
Who's David? Your husband?
David is my son.
He was my son.
I made a bad choice.
I made lots of bad choices.
I chose all sorts
of things over him.
I left him.
That was a long time ago.
Six years.
He's 20 now. He's in college.
He has another mother now.
And I'm just a mess.
You're not. Not anymore.
Call him. DAPHNE: Yeah.
When I've cleaned
up my act, you know?
I want to have my diploma.
I want to show him that I can
be someone he can be proud of.
Seems to me that
you already are.
Yeah, and then I got cancer.
And that is not your fault.
Daphne, you have earned this.
I have watched you become
a completely different person.
And he deserves to know you.
Please call him.
No.
I'm not going back to
him with more problems.
Okay. Are you ready
to take a look now?
Let's just wait a little
while longer, just to be sure.
Hey, you paged? What's that?
This was Derek's?
Yeah.
But that's not why I paged.
I left a boot at your
place this morning.
Yeah, yeah, I brought it in.
It was wrong of me
to come over last night.
I should not be
starting anything new.
Not now. Okay, here we go.
No, I screw everything up.
I don't want you to be
one of those things. I...
Listen, what else
have you screwed up?
Are you kidding me?
I nuked my relationship
with Meredith.
I got kicked out of
my place. I drank.
Sixty days ago. And
you're doing great.
Yeah.
I hit 60 days for the
fourth time in my life.
Ever since, I have been
avoiding big cases like the plague.
I have just been
doing aneurysm repairs
until I know I'm ready.
And then today,
I get this woman with a
live grenade in her head
who happens to be Derek and
Meredith's surgical love child,
and I get to screw
this up now, too.
I...
I think I'm gonna
kill this girl.
Okay, you want to
know what I think?
I think if there were any
other surgeon's name
on this old chart,
you wouldn't be
thinking twice about this.
Meredith doesn't
think I can do it.
Who cares what she thinks?
Meredith is not a neurosurgeon.
And she certainly isn't you.
Why are you giving a
second to what she thinks?
You're the one who
has to do it, Amelia.
So just do it.
Daphne, are you cold?
I'm hot.
Grey, we got to move now.
Okay. Let's get ready to move.
I need some extra lap pads
and Surgicel right here by me.
Daphne, I'm gonna check
and see how we're doing, okay?
No, wait.
Daphne, call your son.
Not like this.
It's been too long.
He'll never forgive me.
Well, he might not, but
you deserve the chance.
Okay, you made a bad
choice, but you turned it around.
You've atoned.
All right, you've
tried, you know that,
so you have to forgive yourself.
Now, you deserve a
chance to show him you tried.
He's right.
Let's call.
David?
It's Daph...
It's Mom.
Okay, Katie, it's time to go.
All right. Let's move.
Wait.
Just please don't kill me.
Okay.
See you then.
He said he's coming.
He's coming to see me.
He sounded so grown-up.
Okay, let's hang some
blood and push pressors.
Daphne, I have to check
now, okay? Don't. I'm scared.
Hey, Daphne. We're here, okay?
Dr. Grey's here. She's
just gonna take a look.
Okay.
Ready, one, two, three.
Okay, okay. Okay, let's go.
Blake, we need an Ambu bag.
And let's keep the blood coming.
We got to go. Let's
get her in there.
Ready? Let's go.
David said he was coming.
Is he coming?
He's on his way. Stay with me.
All right, everybody.
It's a beautiful
night to save lives.
Let's have some fun.
I told the morgue she's coming.
Nurse's station.
You called the
morgue "the plumber."
It's habit.
It's different over there.
You work on people who...
It's part of their job
to get hurt and die.
You never have
to call the families.
Someone else does that.
It makes you...
Yeah, I'm trying
to break that habit.
Why did you come here?
What happened
with Owen's sister?
You're a friend of Owen Hunt's.
I figured he would
have told you.
He said you put her in a
helicopter, and it crashed.
All right, Meg and I were
working in a field unit.
We needed to
transport a patient.
There was only room on
the chopper for one of us.
It was gonna be an ugly
ride, unprotected airspace.
So I said I was gonna go.
Meg said it was her patient.
I told her no.
And we fought, and finally...
I mean, it was her patient.
I would have done the
same thing if it was mine.
So I couldn't tell her no.
And the helicopter...
Never got there.
No one knows what happened.
Just disappeared.
No trace.
So he thinks you should
have been on that helicopter.
I don't go asking about
your dead husband, do I?
Oh! Well...
Don't you look nice? Thank you.
Hey.
Are you... Are you
done for the night?
Yeah, I am. You know, I just...
Oh, good. Well, hey, have fun.
Thank you. Have a good night.
Yes, have fun with,
um, who is it again?
Oh! Um... Artisanal soap.
Um...
Robbins, you're an
outstanding surgeon.
Oh, thank you. And an
extraordinary woman.
Oh, Richard. I'm super gay.
Like, I'm the gayest
of gays. I'm lesbianic.
And you're a very handsome man.
That is very... Oh, cut it out.
Someone like you deserves
someone very special...
A quality person.
And I worry that if you
squander your heart
with all of these many,
many more frivolous...
Whoa, whoa. The thing
about being my wingman is
you can't also be my dad.
Richard, I owe you.
I'm too young and too fun to
spend the rest of my life alone.
And I was... I was
too scared to try,
but you helped me
remember what it was like
when I was open and confident
and fun and a little slutty.
You helped me be slutty again.
Well, I'm not sure
I'd phrase it like that.
You helped me fly.
So, good job.
Thank you.
I got to fly now.
Keep it in the drawer.
Huh?
I don't want it, but
I don't want it gone.
So the drawer is good.
Just, um, keep it in the drawer.
Here. My half of the phone bill.
Oh. No. I told you.
And I appreciate that.
But I don't want to
leave anything undone.
Okay?
Okay.
What?
Uh, you need anything?
What do you mean?
It's just... I mean, if
you need anything,
let me know, okay?
Did, um...
Did Arizona tell you...
I worked in peds.
I figured it out.
You're, like, all
happy all the time,
kind of sweaty.
How far along are you?
Nine weeks.
He doesn't know?
Not yet.
Well, you should tell him
before he figures it out, too.
DeLuca's working late.
Um...
Well, I needed
some old case files
uploaded into the
computer system.
Ah.
Well, that'll keep him
here until dawn, at least.
DeLuca's a hard worker.
Yeah, he is.
He really cares.
He's a good guy. Truly.
I like him.
Well, I suppose I could
cut him some slack.
I appreciate it.
I like that you were
looking out for me.
What?
It's just gonna be nice to
have all those charts uploaded.
Want to go get some
dinner? I would love that.
How is she?
She's great.
Am I missing my pageant?
She have deficits?
No. No. No deficits.
Neuro exam checks out.
She's just a little
loopy from the meds.
Okay. Good.
Did you fix me?
Dr. Shepherd and
Dr. Edwards did.
I fixed you last time.
Right.
I was such a bitch to you.
That was a long time ago.
You're all grown up now.
Yeah. You are, too.
I don't get lost
around here anymore.
Dr. Shepherd fixed me?
She did.
She's very good.
What happened to
guy Dr. Shepherd?
That's a long story.
You take care, okay?
Take care of that brain.
Congratulations.
We're not starting something
new. I don't accept that.
If it were new, I
wouldn't have your boot.
Now, if you want to start over,
forget all that, start fresh,
if that's easier for you,
then we can do that, too.
However you want
to do it. But let's...
Let's do it.
Just like new?
Yep. Square one.
What are you doing?
I barely know you. At least
ask me out on a date first.
We can start over. Every day.
We get second chances...
Just be prepared.
She may look a little...
I know.
I mean, I haven't
seen her in six years.
To become who we
always wanted to be.
We can leave our past behind.
You sure you're ready for this?
Or we can learn from it.
And honor it.
Hi, David.
Hi.
We can decide it's
never too late to change.
These people don't
have that chance.
They left it to you.
They let you learn from them.
So let's say thank you.
And not screw it up.