Hi. Sorry I'm late.
Grab a bite. He's not here yet.
Of course not. Why
would Ross be on time?
Neal...
He puts a kid in an
unsecured news chopper,
and the hospital's going
to give him an award.
Neal, face it.
Ross is a bona fide hero.
He's brought terrific
press to the hospital,
and the board wants
to acknowledge that.
Well, why don't
they ask him to stay?
Why do I have to do it?
Because you're the
one who fired him,
a fact the board is
none too happy about.
Is there any more cream cheese?
Sorry I'm late.
Please. Sorry to
drag you out so early.
Um, juice? Bagel?
No, I just ate.
Have a seat.
Got your tux ready for tonight?
I'm renting one.
Mine's still drying out.
It's going to be quite a gala.
We've got two aldermen coming,
so be prepared for pictures.
I've asked Mark
to be the presenter.
Demi Moore wasn't available?
You jest, but the truth is
we're all proud of you, Doug.
All of us.
Yes.
So much so, we want
to extend your fellowship
for another year.
Uh, well, who would
be my supervisor?
Him.
Hope you'll stay, Doug. We'd
hate to lose you in the ER.
Well, uh, thanks,
but being as I
thought that I was fired,
I have taken another
position at a private practice.
I know. We'd like you
to reconsider that decision.
Wouldn't we, Neal?
Yes, indeed, we would.
You going to stay?
You need to know now?
Pretty soon.
Well, can I have
four extra attending
shifts a month?
I could use the extra dough.
Possibly.
How about Saturday nights off?
Don't push your luck, pal.
You think I'm kidding.
Ah, mail, from your
newfound fans...
Mostly female,
by the handwriting.
Ah, the wages of heroism.
And we got a marriage
proposal on the fax.
Does it include a
bank statement?
Morning. I'm Dr. Carter.
You must be... Ramiro.
Uh, Wilbur. That's
my American name.
I pick it.
Interesting choice.
I understand your
face feels funny.
The right side.
Yeah? Can you
show me your teeth?
How about those?
I can't.
No?
Can you squeeze
your eyes really tight
for me like that?
What was that?
She, uh, thinks you're
too young to be a doctor.
Ah, thank you.
You speak English?
She don't, but I do.
Okay.
You have an inflammation
of the facial nerve,
also known as Bell's Palsy.
It's not serious.
No es serioso.
Uh, she still doesn't
think you're a doctor.
Well, tell her in four
months, I will be.
We want to see a real doctor.
I haven't seen the schedule.
Am I working Thanksgiving?
No.
Cool.
But I need you to
work tomorrow night.
Uh, I haven't found
a night nanny yet.
I can't keep covering
nights for you.
I did four in a row last week.
Yeah, you're right.
You've been great.
I appreciate it.
I'll figure something out.
Peter?
Yeah?
I thought Zeidenberg
was covering the ER today.
Schedule change. Why?
I'm supposed to spend the day
with the surgeon on call
to practice my suturing.
If it's a problem...
It's not a problem for me.
Is it a problem for you?
No. All right.
Knee lac in bed 5.
Hey, Hathaway.
Hey, what do you got?
Apparent suicide attempt.
Brother found her next to
an empty bottle of Tylenol.
What's her name?
Julia.
Okay.
Hey, Jerry, could you
go find Greene, please?
Vitals?
She's normal.
Hey, listen. I got the
number of that roofer for you.
Oh, great. Thanks.
I hear you bought yourself
a real money pit, Hathaway.
Yeah? Where did you hear that?
Tylenol OD? Yeah.
How much did you
take, Julia? Huh?
When did you
take it, sweetheart?
She hasn't said a word.
We need an acetaminophen
level, liver-function tests,
gastric lavage, 50
grams activated charcoal.
Coming up.
Is she going to live?
Yeah.
Haleh?
Come on, hon.
You want something to eat?
♪ Rule, Britannia ♪
♪ Britannia rules the waves ♪
Good morning.
Oh!
I see you're making
yourself at home.
I hope you don't mind.
I find having a few
knickknacks around
makes a room more cheerful.
So, you're feeling fatigued?
Uh-huh.
Aah.
A bit fatigued, I'm afraid.
I was hoping you
could give me something
to put me back on my feet.
Any fevers? Colds?
Hmm-mm, neither one.
Any headaches? Vomiting?
Oh, um, no.
A bit short of breath.
Are you on any medication?
No. No, not a drop.
Oh, listen to that
poor little lamb.
Hmm...
I want to x-ray your chest
to rule out pneumonia,
and do a blood test, okay?
Ah, tea time, is it?
Well past, I'm afraid.
Set up an albuterol nebulizer.
Let's get a pulse ox right away.
What do you got?
Asthma attack.
He can't breathe.
Respiration's 40.
Dusky nailbeds.
He's cyanotic.
Let's start a low flow O-2.
I got him here
as fast as I could,
but he got worse on the bus.
What's his name?
Alan.
All right, Alan. Here, buddy.
Now, I need you to take
a deep breath on this.
It's okay. It's all right.
This medicine is going
to help you breathe.
Okay? Here we go.
Take deep breaths.
What's the pulse ox?
87.
Is that bad?
About what I expected.
There you go. There you go.
Nice and slow. Slow,
slow deep breaths.
Mrs. Corvalan, I
spoke to a doctor,
and he agreed
with my evaluation.
This is a prescription.
Follow up in the
clinic in five days.
You're welcome.
It's not going in.
She's biting the tube.
Julia, you can't bite the tube.
We need to put
the charcoal in your belly
to clean out your
stomach... oh! Oh!
All right, that's it.
Restraints! That's it.
Settle down. Don't
make it even harder.
Tie her hands down.
Julia, if you don't stop,
I'm going to have to put
a tube down your nose,
and you're really
not going to like it.
Ow! She's pulling the tube out.
Damn it!
All right, nasogastric tube.
More charcoal? Good idea.
I know.
I'm sorry I have to do this.
Malik, come hold her head down.
I need a new cath-tip syringe.
Here you go.
We're in.
50 grams.
Do we have a washcloth?
All right. Okay.
It's okay.
The worst is over. I know.
God, I hate this.
It's okay.
Shh...
Hey, Hathaway, I
love your new scrubs.
Yeah, right.
Let me know when
her level comes back.
Okay.
She put up a fight, huh?
Yeah, she was really serious.
That's really the
exception, you know?
Most of these girls, they're
just looking for some attention.
Yeah, they have a
fight with their folks
or their boyfriend,
swallow five pills
instead of two,
and then call 911.
Yeah. I mean, come on.
If you really want
to kill yourself,
forget about pills.
Get yourself a straight razor.
You find that artery.
You slice right on up.
You'll be dead in a minute.
Pills are for people
who don't really mean it.
I really meant it.
Yeah, right.
She's kidding, right?
Mom, it's not a
money kind of favor.
I was hoping you and Dad
could look after
Susie tomorrow night.
Uh, about 8:00 a.m.
Yes, it would mean she
would have to sleep there.
Jerry, we get an
acetaminophen level
on that suicide attempt?
No, I'll call the lab.
I need to get on there
when you're done.
I'm... done.
Yeah? Thanks.
What time you
getting off tonight?
About 6:00.
Do you want to have dinner?
Oh, I got a presentation.
It's not till next week,
but I haven't even
started preparing for it...
Hey, Carter,
did you work up this
kid with facial paralysis?
I'm sorry. Am I interrupting?
No. See ya.
Bye. Uh, yes, I did.
Kid had Bell's Palsy.
Classic presentation.
Okay. No vesicles
or sores in his ears?
I don't think so.
You're not sure?
I'm pretty sure. Why?
Well, The vesicles indicate
Ramsay Hunt syndrome,
which could infect the brain.
I wasn't looking for vesicles.
If you think you missed
him, I would call his folks,
get him in here, and make sure.
Yeah. Mom, yeah.
I know how you are
when you don't get enough sleep.
Okay, okay. Bye.
So much for Ozzie and Harriet.
Any other ideas?
Uh, call in sick.
I'm kidding.
Just kidding.
Here, Julia. If
you need anything,
you just press
this button, okay?
Carol?
Level's back?
480.
Wow. She must have
swallowed two bottles.
She could be in
line for a new liver.
Start Mucomyst. 12
grams through the nose.
Let me know when
her LFTs come in.
Contact her folks?
Don't have a number,
and she won't talk.
Have you seen her brother?
Not I.
Open your mouth. There you go.
Now you're getting
the hang of it.
Pulse ox is up to 98.
You had me scared
there for a while.
Any idea how this happened?
Granny's got a collie.
Let me see this.
Okay, Mrs. Almont.
Alan's going to be fine.
Does he live with you?
No. Just visiting for the week
while his folks are out of town.
Well, if he's going to
be staying with you,
then you're going to
have to get rid of the dog.
You're the doctor
who was on the TV.
Yes. That's me.
You gonna be okay, sugar.
That's the doctor
from the TV.
Doug?
I talked to the boy's HMO.
They want him to go
to their Urgent Care.
Where?
Oak Park.
That's ridiculous.
This kid was in acute
respiratory distress.
I'm not going to send him
all the way across town.
His pulse ox is up to 98.
And I want to make
sure it stays that way.
There.
"Pulse ox 89?"
Tell his HMO that,
they'll let him stay.
What's going on?
Dr. Ross, I'm not going to
fudge with my nursing notes.
Nobody's asking you to.
When this chart
comes up for review,
there's going to
be a discrepancy.
I'm not sending him out.
Do you know why she did it?
My mom died in a
car accident last May.
Might have
something to do with it.
She and Julia were close?
Not really.
Does Julia get along
with your dad okay?
He ain't around.
Works a lot?
He just can't deal with stuff.
I don't think he likes
being in the house.
Do you have a
phone number for him?
Yeah.
Somewhere.
No, no, no, no, señor,
señor. Es muy importante, uh,
por tu wife telefono mio.
Dr. Carter, County ken-e-ral.
Oka..? Hello? Hola?
Hel...
No, no, no, no, no.
What was that all about?
Oh, I might have missed
a diagnosis. Ramsay Hunt.
You forget to check the ears?
No, no, I checked, but I
wasn't thinking Ramsay Hunt,
so I didn't really look for it.
Pretty big miss.
Bring him back and make sure.
A lady with chest pain,
history of lupus
and renal failure.
Benton said you should take it.
Don't miss anything.
Oh.
Your x-rays are back.
Shh.
Poor dear was exhausted.
Your lungs look fine.
Oh, would you?
Oh, uh, sure.
Thank you, love.
Oh, yeah.
I have another cup.
Oh, no. I'm fine. Thank you.
Do you work with children?
Yes.
I raised three right
here in Chicago.
Of course, they grew up
and made me obsolete.
Are you looking for work?
Well, yes, actually.
Work nights?
Mm-hmm.
Pour it through the
strainer, if you would, please.
Oh.
Chuny, can I not
read your writing,
or is that a "98"?
That's a "98."
So you wrote down
this asthmatic
kid's pulse ox as 98,
and five minutes later,
Doug noted it "89."
Did he crash?
He didn't crash.
Could this be a case
of numerical inversion
due to temporary dyslexia?
I don't know, I'm just a nurse.
So I'm correct in deducing
that there's an
inconsistency here?
Looks that way.
Someone made a mistake?
I didn't make a mistake.
Thank you.
Give me a sec.
Carol.
Yeah?
Look, I'm really sorry
for being a jerk
back there before.
I mean, I didn't know.
Look, it's no big deal.
Don't worry about it, really.
No, it is to me.
Can we get together later
and have dinner, go
to a movie, something?
Look, I'm busy, but
I'll call you, okay?
I don't hear anything unusual.
Temp's normal.
Mrs. Briggs, sit tight.
We'll be right back.
Let's order a CBC,
Chem-7, ABG, EKG,
chest film, abdominal series,
uh, anti-DNA, anticentromere,
antiphospholipid
antibody, cryoglobulins...
Whoa! That's going
to be $2,000 right there.
Mm-hmm. I don't
want to miss anything.
Because she's
Vucelich's patient?
She's Vucelich's patient?
Better get a cardiac
echo too. And a CT.
260? Good job, Alan.
Doug?
Let's get one more
neb treatment,
and then I'll okay
him for transfer. Okay?
Doctor? Thank you so very much.
You're very welcome.
You want to fill me in?
The kid had a bad asthma attack,
and his HMO wanted
him transferred.
So you falsified his
chart to keep him here?
That sounds about right. Yes.
It's illegal.
Well, should I put him
on a bus to Oak Park?
No. You should have come to me.
I could have called his HMO
and backed you up,
But now when they see
this, they're not going to pay.
There's no way
I can justify a lie
on a medical record.
We're just going
to have to eat it.
Good. Eat it.
You know, I can't
keep banging heads
with you every other day.
It's just too much work.
If you're going to stay
here and work for me,
this cowboy crap
has got to stop.
Stay here and work for you...
Now, there is an
attractive prospect.
Is that what this is all about?
You can't take the
fact that I'm your boss?
That's typically
narcissistic of you, Mark.
I can't take the fact
that anyone is my boss.
I need to speak to
your sister alone.
Okay.
How are you feeling?
These have to stay on?
We took some new tests.
One of them was
a pregnancy test.
It came back positive.
You knew that.
Did that have something
to do with taking the pills?
You know, sometimes
keeping things inside
makes them seem worse
than they actually are.
You don't know.
I know about wanting to die.
I took a bunch of
pills a year ago.
I loved my mom.
When she died, it's like
everything fell apart...
and Kyle was a mess.
At night, I'd hear him crying,
like when he was little...
We never meant for it to happen.
I only went in to hold him
until he stopped crying,
and now I'm pregnant.
It's okay.
Hmm-mm.
Man, if I'd had
recommendations this strong,
I could have gone to
an Ivy League school.
Recommendations?
Yeah. This patient of
mine. She's a nanny.
Her agency just faxed them over.
Her name's not Ransom, is it?
Yeah.
Ooh. I wouldn't be counting
on any long-term commitments.
Oh, no!
Oh, no.
Heads up.
I got it.
51-year-old male, vitals normal.
Involved in a Civil
War re-enactment of...
Battle of Malvern Hill.
Took on Lee,
Magruder, and Stonewall.
Two-ton cannon broke
loose, rolled over his toe.
Damn artillery sergeant.
Ought to be court-martialed.
Let me take a
look. Oh... oh, yeah.
That is pretty smushed up.
What's open?
Trauma 1.
It was musket butt to
bayonet all morning.
The damn rebels were thicker
than fleas on a dog's back.
Hi.
She told you.
Kyle, whatever your sister
told me is confidential.
I'm not free to discuss it.
She told me she told you.
We're going to do everything
we can to help you guys, okay?
Oh, man, she did tell you!
Kyle...
When my dad finds
out, he's going to kill me!
I mean kill me, man!
He carries a gun!
Kyle, I'm not going to
tell your father anything
you and your sister
don't want him to know.
I'm not waiting
around to find out,
you know what I'm saying?
Kyle!
Ay-yi-yi.
You wanted to
practice your suturing?
Here's your man.
Turned 25 years old today.
Celebrated by drinking
himself into a stupor
and walking through
a plate-glass window.
It's a two-man
job. Carter will help.
Okay, let's get
the chest films first,
and then the echocardiogram.
I'll have Carter meet
you in the suture room.
I got a heart and a spleen
waiting for me upstairs.
Can you give me
two minutes, please?
Carter? What?
What the hell are you doing?
Nothing.
She came in with a history
of lupus and renal failure
and complained of chest pains.
I'm working her up.
Carter, come.
Excuse me.
Carter, only an idiot
would order that many tests
for chest pain.
I'm trying to be thorough.
She's Dr. Vucelich's patient.
You're kidding.
No.
Oh, damn.
Dr. Benton...
Oh, God.
Tell me, did you order
these labs on my patient?
Dr. Vucelich, I apologize.
I left my student
unsupervised...
No, no, I take
full responsibility.
Dr. Benton had absolutely
nothing to do with this.
Fine. Then you're
the one I should thank.
Thank?
The test for anti-phospholipid
antibodies was positive.
Miss Briggs has a very
serious blood disease,
and we need to put her
on heparin right away
and get her upstairs.
So, tell me, what was
your thinking, son?
Actually, there was very little.
Miss Briggs has a
very complex history,
so I took a... shotgun approach.
Come on.
Don't underestimate
yourself, mister...?
Carter.
Carter. Yes. That's right.
Given the circumstances,
your approach was
valid, more than valid.
Not that I advocate
indiscriminate testing.
No need to run Chem-20s
on every runny nose
that walks in, right?
But... when someone has
a constellation of problems,
you can't hold back.
Remember that, Benton.
Good work, son.
Thank you. Thank you.
Oh, by the way, I'm
doing a fem-pop bypass.
You want to assist?
Go, Carter.
So you're familiar
with the procedure?
Fem-pop bypass?
Yeah. How many have you done?
Mrs. Ransom?
Oh...
I must have drifted off.
Oh, did you get my references?
Oh, yes. Yes.
Very, very impressive.
Oh, thank you.
Uh, you know, I was
thinking that, um...
I could drop around tonight
and make it a little less
intrusive on the little one.
Mrs. Ransom, we need to
talk about your blood tests.
Your red and white cells
and platelet count
are extremely low,
which is suggestive
of aplastic anemia,
which is very serious.
Perhaps you could,
um... give me a few pills.
You know, pep me up.
Mrs. Ransom, your condition
is most likely terminal.
You need to be
admitted to the hospital
for a bone marrow biopsy.
Oh, pish-posh.
Not another one
of those. Hmm-mm.
You've had one?
Yes, months ago.
Most unpleasant.
Have you been
getting transfusions?
Oh, from their description,
they are simply ghastly.
No, no, no. I would rather
just carry on and, uh...
you know, hope for the best.
I, uh... I could come around
about, uh, 7:00 tonight if...
that's convenient with you.
Mrs. Ransom, your
disease has reached a stage
where you can't work anymore.
You need to be
admitted to the hospital.
I think, uh...
I'm the better judge
of that, don't you?
Hmm?
Oh, man, that smarts.
You've avulsed most of the skin
off the top of your big toe.
Just saw it off and
throw it in the basket.
I need to get back to the field.
Amputation isn't necessary.
I just launched a countercharge
at Jackson's center.
Damn cannon came off the blocks.
Are you General Grant?
No. Grant wasn't
at Malvern Hill.
Major General Fitz-John Porter,
tactical genius...
Used the 5th Corps to
outflank two rebel divisions
and drive them back
across the Chickahominy.
I'm going to have
to rongeur the bone.
Let's get Mr. Richter
some lidocaine.
Oh, no, no, no. Ether.
That's all Porter had
when they cut off his leg.
Mr. Richter, we
haven't used ether
as an anesthetic
in over 40 years.
Lidocaine, two
percent digital block.
Just give me a
bullet to bite on.
We may be out.
I got it.
Psst.
Can we send out a private
to round up some bourbon?
Mr. Richter, we're fresh out
of privates as well.
I'm about to use this tool
to grind down the
bone in your toe.
I highly recommend that
you take the lidocaine.
Not as long as I'm in command.
Go to it, surgeon.
Do your stuff.
Saw your sister
Jackie last week,
near the State
of Illinois building.
She was buying a
Polish dog from a vendor.
Don't think she saw me.
She's supposed to be on a diet.
Uh-oh, busted.
She works near there.
Thought she worked at
the Botanical Gardens.
Used to.
Always wanted to work outdoors.
She's allergic to pollen.
You're kidding.
So they put her in
this little room
with no windows.
And a plastic plant.
Probably.
She told me she saw you.
Didn't tell me about
the hot dog, though.
I'm Richard Kazlaw.
I was told you have
my daughter Julia here.
Mr. Kazlaw, I'm Dr. Greene.
Julia tried to kill herself.
The good news is she's okay.
Where is she?
She's actually in with the
social worker right now,
and you can see her
when they're done.
Um, if you could just
fill out this paperwork.
Consent form,
that sort of thing.
High-speed motorcycle collision.
Victim 1 complains
of abdominal pain.
BP in the field of 80/50.
Repeat BPs came up with...
Head trauma,
non-responsive, GCS seven,
possible tib-fib fracture.
Wearing a helmet?
No. Neither of them.
Let's get a CBC,
dip a urine for blood,
get X-ray to run the spine...
Cervical, thoracic and lumbar.
Chuny, see if he's oriented.
What's your name?
Tom Spagnoli.
What's the date?
November something.
My stomach's killing me.
He's got a tire track
on his belly here.
Bowel sounds hypoactive.
Possible intra-abdominal
hemorrhage.
DPL?
No, he's got a scar.
I had an operation
when I was a kid.
Laparotomy?
Okay, we can't lavage him.
Let's call CT. Tell
them to hold a table.
Let's get a Foley in.
He opened his eyes.
All right, Jimmy,
can you hear me?
Do you know where you are?
Responds to pain. Otoscope.
Moves extremities times four.
No obvious paralysis.
Get C-ray, cross table C-spine.
He's got blood in the canals.
Ross has X-ray.
Fundi normal.
Disks are flat.
Maybe it's just skull fracture?
I'm worried about
the blood in his ears.
Call CT. Tell them
to hold a table.
Dr. Ross is holding already.
What do you got?
Tire mark across the
belly, bruising, tenderness.
He's got a lap scar,
so I can't DPL him.
I'm sending him to CT.
Rebound, guarding?
Little bit.
My kid's got blood in the canal.
He's sicker, so he'll go first.
Hold on. This kid could
have a ruptured spleen.
What's his crit?
Forty-two.
It's normal. He can wait.
Lateral C-spine is
next. Set up suction.
Ophthalmoscope.
Pupils are fine. No papilledema.
There's blood in the canal.
Otoscope.
What the hell do you
think you're doing?
This kid has a skull fracture,
not an intercranial bleed.
You're way out of line,
Doug. Go back to your patient.
My patient is going to CT.
No, he's not.
This kid is going to CT now.
Fine. Then mine's
going to the O.R.
for an exploratory lap.
Like hell he is.
You are not putting a
patient under the knife
just to try and win
a pissing contest.
You're damn right I'm not.
I'm doing it so he
doesn't bleed out
while you tie up the
CT for a skull fracture.
Go home!
What?
I'm taking over your patient
and writing you up. Go home!
Let's get a portable
ultrasound in here.
Check out the belly.
Let's go! Come on!
So that's why she
swallowed two bottle of pills.
Yeah. Awful.
He was forcing
himself on his sister?
No. The way she tells it,
it came out of grief
over losing their mother.
She went in to comfort him,
and they ended up
sleeping together.
And now she's pregnant. Ooh.
Can I help you?
Sir?
What?
The name on the consent.
Oh, God.
It appears that your
father may have overheard
two of our staff members
discussing your case.
Oh, man.
He's going to kill me.
Do you really think
that he might hurt you?
Yeah.
Someone's going to
stay with you at all times.
I'm afraid that we didn't
handle this very well,
but we're going to make
sure you guys are okay.
Tony's going to stay with you.
Lydia, Carol...
You have no idea how sorry I am.
It's stupid to talk
about it out in the open.
Really stupid.
Let's put protecting
patient confidentiality
on the agenda for
tomorrow's staff meeting.
Right. I got the
girl an ICU bed.
We should move her upstairs.
Alert security just in
case there's trouble.
Okay.
Hey, Dr. Ross, your tux came in.
Oh, great, Jerry, thanks.
Uh, wait, that's Dr. Greene's.
Okay.
Ready for your big award?
Yeah, I can't wait.
Doug, you got a sec?
No.
Hey, Dr. Ross. Phone for you.
Who is it?
Your father.
Who?
He said he was your dad.
Hello?
Uh-huh.
Fine.
No, you...
yeah, this isn't a good
time, so... yeah, I got to go.
Mm-hmm, yeah, here's fine.
Bye.
I thought he and his
father didn't speak.
As far as I know, he hasn't
seen or heard from him
since he was 12.
This is going to be
an interesting evening.
One more.
All right, last one.
Nice.
Fun.
I like the staple gun.
Hey, hey.
Hey, guys.
Carter, how was surgery?
Incredible. Watching
Carl anastomose
is truly a humbling experience,
and I got to hold
the bulldog clamp,
and I got it on tape in
case you want to see it.
Pass.
No? No.
I'll get some Xeroform
dressings for our birthday boy.
Bye. Bye.
Hmm...
very attractive.
Carter...
And smart, too.
And available.
She's married. No, she's not.
Yes, she is. No, she's not.
What are you talking about?
She told me she was divorced.
So, listen, if it's okay,
I finished my notes
on your patients.
I'd like to take off.
Is that okay?
Yeah, yeah, Carter, go.
Okay. I'll see you tomorrow.
How's it going, huh?
Yeah.
That's right.
Please tell me he's your father.
He's my father.
Thank God.
He showed me an
expired driver's license.
Dad, what are you doing here?
Oh, I was in the neighborhood.
You were?
Your mother and I had
a slight disagreement
about the responsibilities
of being a grandparent.
I'm here to apply
for the job of night nanny.
What did Mom say?
Use your imagination.
I'd have to come
to your apartment.
I mean, I will...
If you want me to.
Really? You'd do that?
I should have done
it a long time ago.
Uh, veinte, 20, veinte minutos.
Right, okay.
You taking off?
Yeah. I got to make
a run to Humbolt Park.
Yeah? What for?
I had a kid this morning
with facial paralysis
which I diagnosed
as Bell's Palsy,
but might have missed
vesicles in his ears
that suggest Ramsay Hunt,
and it's been driving
me crazy all day.
So I guess this is a no,
then, to my dinner offer?
Uh, well, would you be
paying for this dinner?
Actually, I thought I'd
be cooking this dinner.
Know your way
around Humbolt Park?
I can read a map.
Mr. Kazlaw?
I took care of your
daughter today, Mr. Kazlaw,
and I feel terrible because
you overheard something
you didn't want or
need to hear right now.
I'm so very sorry.
I don't know what to do.
There are people
here who can help you.
You should talk to some...
Take this, please.
No sign of him?
Nope.
Isn't this dandy?
Give him five more minutes.
If he doesn't show,
we'll make some
sort of an excuse.
Say he's out scouring the sewers
for lost kids and stray pets.
Are you Dr. Greene?
You're missing a really
bad chicken dinner.
Shh, I'm shooting.
Nah, now you see? You jinxed me.
Hey, Mark. You want
to hear my speech?
Ladies and gentlemen,
thank you all very much
for this tremendous honor.
I want to take this opportunity
to acknowledge
some of my colleagues.
First, David Morgenstern
for his stalwart support.
One minute he's stamping
my walking papers,
and the next, he has
his face so far up my butt
if he had a mustache,
it would tickle my throat.
Let's not forget Neal Bernstein,
Neal, proof that any
idiot who can nod his head
can rise right to the
middle of pediatric medicine,
and last, and
definitely not least,
Mark Greene...
Mark the self-righteous
shall-inherit-the-ER Greene.
Mark the I-am-behind-you-110%
but-you-are-out-of-here Greene.
Thank you, kiss my ass,
good night, God bless.
What do you think?
This how you want
to end your career?
Can you think of a better way?
What'd your father want?
You got me.
I'll tell you something, though.
I bet he'll get a kick
out of what I'm about to do.
Don't do it, Doug.
It's a big mistake.
Well, you know what
my father always said?
If you're going to
make a mistake,
make it a big one.
Still sewing.
Thanks for teaching
me the staple gun.
Well, good night.
Why didn't you tell
me you were divorced?
Separated.
We haven't had many
conversations lately,
at least not civil ones.
Peter...
Al and I had a lot of problems
that had nothing to
do with you and me.
Good night.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
I had no idea you
were this neurotic.
Coming all the way out
here to check a kid's ears?
Listen, I thought you
came out to support me,
not to ridicule me.
Yeah, but ridiculing
you is so much more fun.
This is it, 218.
Hey, your first house call.
Hi, hi... hey, Wilbur,
how's it going?
You messed up, huh?
Well, we'll soon find
out. Let's take a look.
That's one down.
Two down.
All clear?
All clear.
You done?
I'm done. Thank you,
and I'm really, really sorry
to bother you at home.
It was no surprise to me
to see Doug Ross on TV
sloshing around in
the freezing water
trying to save a kid in trouble,
because, in a way, that's
what he does every day.
I don't know any doctor who
cares more for his patients.
I'm proud to present this award
for outstanding
community service
to a great pediatrician and
a great friend, Doug Ross.
Thank you.
Uh, I'd like to take this
opportunity to single out
a few people who have
influenced my career
for better or worse...
but I guess you all
know who you are
and how I really feel about you,
so perhaps the
less said, the better.
I...
thank you for this.
Thank you.
It's scary to think
that in four months,
I'm going to be a doctor.
I'm not going to have Residents
looking over my shoulder,
checking my mistakes.
It's an awesome responsibility,
if you think about it.
Do we have to talk shop?
What?
I'm sorry.
I just hate to think
that medicine's all
we can talk about.
No, we can talk
about something else.
Good.
Great. You first.
No, you go first.
Did you do that
because you couldn't
think of anything?
Well, at least take your hands
out of your pockets
and do it right.
Not thinking about doing
anything rash, are you?
You mean like this?
Whoa, what are you, crazy?
Those awards really bounce.
Must be acrylic.
Thanks for the speech.
Thanks for not
giving your first draft.
Oh...
I'm an idiot.
You have your moments.
You know why my old
man called me today?
Because he saw me on TV.
I haven't heard that
voice in 22 years.
Son of a bitch.
The scary thing is
I'm doing a pretty
good imitation.
He never kept a job
more than two years.
Most of the time,
it was two weeks.
He had a nasty
habit of getting drunk
and punching out his boss.
Maybe it's just me,
but I take a dim view of
that particular approach.
Yeah... yeah.
So I still have a job?
If you still want it.
Damn it! Aw, damn!
Damn it!
Damn it, damn it, damn it!
What are you doing up there?
I'm destroying your roof.
Oh, that's great.
That's just what I need.
No, seriously, I saw
some of these rotting tiles,
and I figured I'd
start pulling them off,
and I sincerely think
I've ruined your roof.
Well, stop.
Oh, my God.
I know, I know.
This is horrible.
I figured I could save you
some money on roofing.
I'm sorry.
About what?
Putting a really
big hole in my roof?
The roof, the mouth...
whatever odious behavior
I'm about to commit.
All of it.
I'm sorry.
Ah, look, I shouldn't
have made you
feel stupid this morning.
Hey, I did that all on my own.
No. I blindsided you.
Well, that's true.
Look, about what you said today.
Actually... it doesn't
matter to me.
You know, I mean...
I don't think any less of you.
Most of all...
I'm really glad
that it didn't work.
Me too.