♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
I'm a worrier.
I... I know
you know that about me,
but most people don't.
Professionally,
I'm very confident.
But personally...
I spend a lot of time
worrying about
what's happening in my life
and what isn't happening,
what could've happened
but didn't.
Does it help?
I like to think
it makes me more prepared.
I don't ever
want to be blindsided,
and if I'm ready...
Well...
It's good to be prepared,
and I am...
Very prepared.
Oh, I want my husband!
We've called him,
he's on his way,
but we can't wait.
It's too early.
We're not due
for another two weeks.
Well, the baby doesn't
know that.
You almost delivered
in the car.
B.o.a. Kit.
All right, I need you
to give me one more push.
Ready? Push.
Good.
Congratulations.
You have a healthy baby boy.
♪ but I don't seem to care ♪
♪ about what they say ♪
Busy morning?
One breech, one c-section,
and one precipitous delivery,
and it's not even
9:00 A.M. yet. You?
Uh, yeah, yeah.
I got one patient
on suicide watch,
and another who's claiming he's
getting bad investment advice
from his cat.
Do you have time
for coffee?
Not really.
I-Is everything okay?
Yeah, yeah. Yeah,
Scott and I broke up.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm supposed to be sorry,
right?
Oh, I don't know. I mean,
look, Scott's a great guy,
but there was no next level,
you know?
I mean, not while I have
feelings for Pete.
Okay, did you tell Pete
about that?
I can't.
Violet.
I don't want to make him
feel pressured.
Really?
No. I'm just not sure
what I want to say yet.
Oh, tell me about it.
I'll see you later.
Okay.
Hi, Jake.
Good morning.
Hey.
Listen, I have a-a mother
who just delivered.
She's worried
about her baby.
I think it's jaundice,
but I'd appreciate a consult.
I'm slammed at the moment.
Can it wait till this afternoon?
Whatever you can spare.
Hey, hey. It was,
uh, really great
meeting Angela.
I had no idea you had
a stepdaughter.
I do.
Yeah?
Do you--do you--you get
to see her often?
Not often enough.
I miss her.
But, you know, it's--
it's cool.
She has a way of reminding me
what's important in life.
She seems like a great kid.
Yeah, she thought
you were pretty neat, too.
Hey.
We were supposed to
go running this morning.
I'm sorry. I just wasn't
feeling up to it.
What happened?
That's not like you.
I know.
Corinne?
Yeah, yeah.
But it's a good thing.
They're gonna take
way better care of her
than I ever could've.
Well, that's true
if you just believe it.
So you want to go out
and grab a drink tonight?
Uh, maybe some other time.
It'll be good for you.
It'd be good for me.
Yeah.
Still enjoying
the nightlife, huh?
Eh, that's done.
What happened?
Nothing.
Violet?
She's with Scott.
No, she's not. According to
the nurses, that's done.
How do you feel today,
Elise?
You know, the last time
I was here,
we didn't get very far,
and I was hoping today, you'd
like to share a little more.
I know it's painful,
but I truly believe that
talking about it will help.
You can't help me.
I'd like to try.
You want to know
how I feel today?
The same as every day.
I feel like I'm a monster.
I don't think
you're a monster.
I murdered
my two children.
What would you call me?
Hey.
Hey. I was just about
to page you.
I've got about another
15 minutes
before I head to the O.R.
for a c-section.
Bet I could do
an ultrasound.
Oh, uh, yeah.
I'm way behind today.
I'll be quick.
I'll even warm up
the gel for you.
Another time.
Amelia...
You really should do this.
So I can see everything
that is wrong with my baby--
the horns sticking out
of its head...
Its long corkscrew tail?
I know that you're freaked out,
but part of it
is because none of this
is real for you yet.
But as soon as you see it
on the ultrasound
and you hear the heartbeat,
it's all gonna change for you.
It's gonna be real.
I'll do it tomorrow,
okay?
All right. You've got
about another five minutes
before those baggy sweaters
aren't gonna hide that bump.
Hey. This is a good thing.
Be happy.
Hey.
Good morning.
I'm starving.
Me, too.
Uh, you want to go to
the breakfast burrito place
down at the pier or...
It's a school day.
I don't want to be late.
Oh, okay.
I-It's just, I don't want
my mom to get mad at me.
Well, she's in the hospital.
I think she'd understand.
Um, I mean, I was thinking,
I could play hooky from work,
and we could
go do something fun.
Uh, uh, that's okay.
We could go fishing.
Hey, if I
eat some cereal fast,
could you drive me
so I'm not late for math?
Yeah, of course.
Cool.
Oh, hey, mase. I need a new
picture of you for my phone.
Okay.
Mm.
Here's something
you might want to see.
He's...
Going...
Going to school?
Mm-hmm.
Good.
I could have Coop
bring him by this afternoon.
What do you think?
No.
It might be good,
for both of you.
I said no.
Don't...
Argue...
With a dying woman.
Is it true?
Mr. Wilson.
I heard some shrink
in this practice is defending
that murdering bitch in court.
Whoa. W--slow down.
What?
The prosecutors just told me
that Elise's lawyers are
getting a-a Sheldon Wallace
to testify in her defense.
You're my doctor, too.
You gave us a family,
and now you're helping
the woman who took it away?
Elise was on suicide watch.
I only asked Dr. Wallace
to talk to her.
Do you remember Josie?
She had red hair and freckles.
She was 4.
Max was 2.
Still in diapers.
They were awake.
They must have been
so scared.
My wife murdered
our children.
She should rot in jail.
And you should be
ashamed of yourself
for helping her at all.
You're the one who asked me
to talk to Elise
in the first place.
She was in jail and suicidal.
I asked you to help
with her mental state,
not to work to set her free.
What Elise did
was horrific.
It was beyond horrific.
It is possible that she had
a psychotic episode,
brought on by an undiagnosed
postpartum depression.
You might be right,
but you should've come to me
before you agreed
to help her out.
I'm not trying to justify
what she did.
I'm trying to shed light
on what happened.
Right, and the effect of that
could be a court
setting that woman free.
Okay, postpartum
is a real thing, all right?
Jake, 80% of mothers suffer
from some form of it.
Yeah, but they don't asphyxiate
their own children.
Sam, you know how brutal
mental illness can be.
This is
a kind of mental illness.
Look, guys,
this is about Elise.
Sheldon, you can help her
all you want,
just don't defend
what she did in court.
Yes, well, I'm sorry, Jake,
but she's my patient now.
Okay? You don't get
to make that call.
Hey, you okay?
Uh... I'm fine. Yeah.
How much longer
does she have?
I don't know.
Days maybe, but...
It's still, uh...
Too long.
I'm wearing down.
Well, because...
She's not just a patient.
She's in your life,
which means you can't get
any emotional distance.
And without that,
you're not a doctor anymore.
You're...
Well...
You're family.
I should be able
to do this.
There's no right way
to do it.
Just...
Be there.
Cooper's with Mason.
And I...
I...
You want to tell me
what's going on?
Curt and Elise came to me
three years ago.
They already had
a little girl--Josie.
But they had trouble
conceiving again, so...
After two rounds of I.V.F.,
they had Max.
After another year,
they, uh...
They said they were ready
for a third.
That one took a little longer,
but, um...
Every time Elise
came into the office,
curt would come with her.
They'd bring the kids.
I remember, uh...
Elise seemed a little off.
But with two kids and--and more
fertility treatments,
I-I figured,
she was overwhelmed
and affected by the hormones,
but she said
she could handle it.
My job
is to give people babies,
not judge whether
they should be parents.
So I...
I helped Elise
to get pregnant again.
There's no way anyone
could've known
what Elise was going to do.
But I was her doctor.
I mean, I could've...
I could've been
more tuned in,
could've asked more questions.
But instead, I shot her up
with fertility drugs
and probably made
the problem worse.
Jake...
You didn't cause this.
You have no idea the effect
that medication had on her.
Except I know
that I made it possible
for her to have
another baby.
Because of me, this woman
who killed her two children
is about to have another.
All right, spelling.
You obviously nailed that.
Yeah.
Math, you got 8 out of 10.
What about
the other 2 points?
Kidding.
Good job
on your history.
And a drawing...
Do you like it?
Yeah.
You and your mom?
Whenever I'm scared,
she lets me get in her bed.
Then I'm not scared anymore.
That's great.
That is a great drawing.
I was thinking maybe you could
help me find a frame for it,
and we can put it in her room
for when she comes home.
Mase...
We talked about this.
She's not--
she's...
She's not coming home.
She's dying.
That's what you said
last time in Seattle,
but then the doctors
fixed her.
Right, but, Mason...
They can't help
your mom there anymore.
Nobody can.
Somebody will.
Why are you back?
I want to be left alone.
I want to try to help
with your defense,
but to do that,
you have to talk to me.
I don't deserve your help.
Elise, you have to get
beyond the self-condemnation
and open up.
Don't you want to understand
what happened?
Curt was out--out of town
on business that week.
Max had been sick.
He wouldn't stop crying.
I took him to the doctor.
I did everything
that they told me to do,
but he just...
He wouldn't stop.
Josie was upset because...
I couldn't give her
the attention that she needed.
Neither of them would sleep.
It took them hours
to go down,
and then...
They would wake up
over and over at night.
I was exhausted.
It was like torture.
And then I realized...
That it was my fault.
I had to have
done something wrong.
My children were...
Upset and in pain...
Because I was a bad mother,
a terrible mother,
which made it even harder
to watch them suffering.
So...
I told them that we were
going to the park.
I got them dressed,
and I put the sand toys
in the back,
and I... I...
I put them in their car seats.
And I started the car.
And then I told them
that I was going to go back
and get their snacks.
Ohh.
The pain and the guilt
that you feel now
is a reaction...
To what you did.
It's a rational reaction.
But what happened to you,
what you experienced that night
was something
completely different.
I think you had
a psychotic episode,
the result of years of
untreated postpartum depression,
compounded by
a hormonal imbalance.
You're not the same woman
you were that night.
That night,
you were not rational.
You have to understand that,
and I have to help your lawyers
help the court
understand that.
I don't deserve your help.
I don't deserve anything!
No, I killed them!
I killed my babies!
I killed them! Oh!
Call 9-1-1!
So how's he seem to you?
He seems like a little boy
who doesn't want to accept
that his mother's gonna die.
We've been as honest with him
as we could be.
I know.
I thought we--
I thought he understood.
Kids Mason's age
can't process a tragedy.
They'll often resort
to magical thinking.
But he already
said good-bye to her.
He knows that Charlotte's
at the hospital with Erica.
He knows Erica's still alive.
I just don't think I should let
him keep thinking there's hope.
I think you've done
everything you can do.
But...
If I didn't know that Erica
had already refused,
I would say,
take him to the hospital.
Let him see his mom.
Let her explain.
Right.
I-I mean, I tried.
Charlotte tried.
Erica won't budge.
Well, maybe take him anyway.
You can explain to him that
he--he can't see his mom,
but at least
he'll be close to her.
Then what?
And then hope like hell
Erica changes her mind
before it's too late.
Oh. Stop. Stop.
Hush. Your mouth's
leaking like a faucet.
Who cares?
You want to be drooly, fine.
But it's freaking me out.
I can't handle it,
sister.
Okay. Okay.
Okay.
Here we go.
I'm sorry.
Don't worry about it.
I'm scared.
I am gonna be here with you
the whole time.
I am here.
You're here.
I'm here.
What happened?
I'm Dr. Montgomery,
Elise.
You had
an eclamptic seizure.
My baby--w--
is she okay?
I did an ultrasound,
and you're on a fetal monitor.
The baby's gonna be fine.
I put you on medication
to get your blood pressure
under control
and make sure you don't
have another seizure.
Just as soon
as you're stable,
we'll go ahead
and induce labor.
How soon?
Hopefully tomorrow.
Should be routine.
You'll deliver vaginally
unless there's a complication.
You'll have a few moments
with your baby,
and then she'll be
turned over to your husband.
As soon as you recover,
you'll be discharged
back to county.
The first time,
I was so happy.
Curt and I wanted a family
so much.
But they don't tell you.
It's so hard.
Wanting to be a mom
and having a baby...
They're different.
My babies deserved
something more...
Someone better than me.
I tried my best,
but I...
I wasn't good.
I wasn't...
A good mother.
And then, i--
and then I became...
What are you doing here
so late?
I was just, uh, signing off
on a patient discharge.
Well, i-I'd invite you
for a cup of coffee,
but I gotta get back
to the E.R. soon.
Oh, no, no, no, no. I just
stopped by to say hello.
So hello.
Hi.
M-Maybe we could
have lunch tomorrow.
I-I mean, unless you're
doing something with Scott.
No.
Oh, okay.
Uh, i--it's no problem.
I get it.
No, no, no.
I meant, no, I don't have plans
with Scott, because...
Scott and I broke up.
Yeah, I know.
You do?
Then why...
I was just--i was try--
I don't know. I was...
Pete.
Well, I, um...
I do have
a lot of pat--
I have patients
all day tomorrow, so...
Some other time then.
Okay.
Addison,
are you home?
Yeah, up here.
Surprise.
What happened
to your office?
I got rid of everything
so you could fill it up.
I figured we could put
the crib right over there,
the changing table
right under the window
so you get plenty of fresh air,
and these...
These are
all of my baby books--
everything from what
to name your baby to,
oh, what weird food object
your baby
is the same size as
each week.
Some of them--
some of them are highlighted.
Actually--actually,
all of them are highlighted.
That--a lot of people
don't like that.
But this is supposed to be
your nursery.
Doesn't matter.
I don't think I am
ever gonna have a baby.
But the universe works
in amazing ways,
and you...
Are.
I'm sorry. All this is...
Wonderful, Addie.
I just--
this is too fast.
And I'm not ready.
Okay.
Where's my mom?
Right upstairs.
This isn't fair, buddy.
This is just--
it's nowhere near fair.
And I wish I could keep
all the bad things
in the world away from you.
But I can't.
I'm just so sorry
about that.
Dad, if there's no cure,
how's my mom
gonna get better?
I-I read this story once
about a grandma
who got sick.
And the entire family prayed,
and she got better.
Should we be doing that?
Does praying help?
Sometimes, yeah.
Can you teach me?
Yeah, um...
Let's see.
I think you start by folding
your hands together.
You, too.
Okay.
Um...
And then you just... talk
about your life
and about what you want.
Aren't you supposed
to kneel?
Uh, uh, I don't.
Then I won't.
Okay.
Amen.
Dad.
Mm-hmm.
Did I do it right? Do you
think god heard me?
Yeah, I do.
Hey.
Hey. Another session
with the crazy cat lady?
Uh, no.
Combative schizophrenic.
Apparently, I look like
his mother,
and, uh, he hates his mother.
Took two nurses
and a security guard
to hold him while I pushed
the haloperidol.
Coffee or tea?
Tea. Um, so, uh,
Pete and I ran into
each other last night.
Mm-hmm.
I think he wanted
to kiss me.
Did you let him?
No.
Violet.
Oh, I wanted to,
believe me.
But?
Well, I just--
it seemed lazy after,
you know,
everything we've been through.
Yeah.
Maybe you're right.
Every time
Sam and I'd have a fight,
he'd show up later
all sexy,
smelling like cookies.
And what would you do?
Oof. I fell for it,
every single time.
Well, maybe
I'm overthinking this.
Mm. I don't know.
Didn't work for us.
Turns out, some problems
are too big for even...
Mind-blowing sex to solve.
Mm.
Hey.
Thank you.
You two doing okay?
I couldn't get him
to go home last night, but...
How's Erica doing?
It's almost over.
Hey, sweetie.
You want to head home
for a while,
maybe sleep
in your own bed?
I think I kinda want
to stay here.
Is that okay?
Of course.
Oh, um...
I have something
for my mom.
Uh, do you mind
giving it to her?
Sure.
I didn't get to frame it,
but, um, I was thinking,
maybe if she saw it,
she wouldn't feel so alone.
Well, that's real sweet.
Hey, uh, maybe I could
hang out with you for a while
so your dad can go
take care of some things.
Okay.
You need
to go see Erica.
Now?
Now.
Hey.
Hi.
I'm so sorry you were alone
all those years,
raising Mason.
I wish I'd known. I wish
I'd been able to help.
But this kid
that you raised?
My god, Erica,
he's amazing.
And you did that.
You.
And I am so grateful
you brought him to me.
Thank you for that.
I'm so... glad you're...
His dad.
Come on, judi.
You're almost there.
Did you page me?
Yeah. I thought
you should see this.
What's happening?
Just your
garden-variety miracle.
Ah!
It's okay.
You can do this...
Judi.
I'm just here
for moral support.
I'm having a--oh--
a boy.
And he's almost here.
Push.
Good.
There.
Ohh.
There he is.
Good.
Ohh.
He's perfect.
Can you believe I got to
do that seven times today?
He's beautiful.
And your baby
will be, too.
Shh.
I just watched Addison
deliver a baby,
which is about the thousandth
time I've seen it,
but...
But what?
But nothing. It...
It was surreal.
Yeah, I remember watching
Maya being born.
It was--
it was magical.
I can understand why--
why Addison wants it so badly.
Mm. Well, not anymore.
What do you mean?
She told me, she's given up
on having a baby.
Elise's labor
is progressing quickly.
She should give birth
relatively soon.
She'll get to spend
a little time with the baby,
and then--
the second my daughter
is born,
you bring her to me.
Are you sure
this is what you want?
Look, I'm not defending Elise.
I'm not defending myself.
This never should've happened.
But you and Elise are about
to have another baby together.
You know, everyone is so
concerned with Elise's feelings.
Well, what about mine?
What about
my right as a father
to watch my children
grow up?
Curt...
If Elise is set free
because of that shrink,
I will sue you.
I will sue all of you.
I'll ruin you.
Elise,
on the count of three,
I need you to start
really bearing down, okay?
Mm-hmm.
Okay. One, two, three.
Push.
Oh, it hurts.
I can't do it.
Elise,
you have to keep going.
No, I can't.
I can't.
I can't be a mother again.
Elise, I need you
to look at me, okay?
I know that you're scared,
but your baby needs you
right now.
You can do this for her.
I know you can.
So on my count.
One, two, three.
Push.
Good. Good, Elise.
I can see the head.
I just need
one more big push.
Good.
There she is.
Ohh.
Look at your beautiful baby...
Elise.
Elise, do you want
to look at your daughter?
She's--
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Do you want to name her?
Her father should do that.
Shh.
Elise.
You did a really good job.
God, she's so beautiful.
Hey.
She looks just Elise.
It wasn't supposed
to be like this.
We were supposed to be
a family.
How could she do this to us?
Yeah.
I don't know if you can
ever forgive Elise,
but you have to try
not to... not to hate her.
At least right now,
because right now,
she is
the mother of this...
Beautiful new daughter
of yours.
And this baby deserves
a fresh start,
just like you do.
It's okay. Shh.
How's Elise?
She's doing okay
for a woman
who just had to
give up her baby.
She couldn't even bring herself
to hold her.
Shh. Shh.
How did Elise's delivery go?
It was rough,
but she got through it.
Okay, good.
I'll check on her.
It's good that
she has you, Sheldon.
Hey, do you think--i mean,
is it possible for her
to ever get past what she did?
I don't know, but I don't
plan to give up on her.
How's Jake?
Sounds like he might need
some help moving on, too.
Thanks.
Hello.
Erica, it's Charlotte.
I brought you something.
It's a... a drawing
Mason did.
It's the two of you together.
It's really beautiful.
He wanted you to have it
in here.
Okay, you just...
You try to relax.
Erica, I'm gonna
tell you something,
and I know it's not
quite fair to you,
but... Mason needs
to see you.
He won't be able
to move on otherwise,
and I know it's not
what you want,
but it is the only thing
I can do for him,
and he has to come first now.
Our son needs to see you.
I'm gonna go get him.
You just--you hang in there.
♪ Hold my hand ♪
♪ I am afraid ♪
♪ please pray for me ♪
♪ when I am away ♪
♪ comfort ♪
Mason,
you need to come with me.
Your mama wants to see you
and we don't have much time.
Okay?
♪ Help her understand ♪
♪ no memory ♪
She's not gonna look
like your mama.
She's pale and weak.
♪ No matter how sad ♪
She's not
gonna get better, is she?
No, she's not.
But she's in here right now.
And we're gonna go see her,
okay?
♪ No violence ♪
♪ no matter how bad ♪
♪ can darken the heart ♪
He's here.
♪ Or tear it apart ♪
Charlotte, it's too much.
Come on, Mason.
♪♪♪
I love you, mommy.
I love you so much.
♪♪♪
♪ Comfort the man ♪
♪ Help him ♪
♪ understand ♪
Hey. Oh.
Is this an indicator
that you're finally
embracing motherhood?
It's a gift from Addison.
She's trying to entice me.
How much enticement
do you need?
I mean, you do realize,
at the end of this,
you're going to get
a baby, right?
The one I watched Addison
deliver today was this...
Perfect little boy.
I wonder what flavor
this one will be?
It's a boy. Definitely.
Well, how are you
so sure?
I always say it's a boy.
Half my friends
think I'm a genius.
Okay.
You don't need
any more enticement, do you?
No, I don't.
I'm in.
I'm gonna call Addison,
and she'll do an ultrasound,
and...
I'll get to see my baby.
I'm in.
Well, that's excellent.
Uh, hey, I'm done here.
Do you want to grab dinner
and celebrate?
Uh, I'd love to, but i-i
have to leave town tonight.
Sheldon...
Is everything okay?
I hope so. I just have to
go see my ex-wife.
You're a good doctor.
Actually,
you...
Are amazing.
You do everything
in your power
to give your patients
what they want.
You're an intuitive,
supportive,
baby-giving miracle worker.
Look, I appreciate what
you're trying to do, but--
I'm not done yet.
Just because you can
work miracles
doesn't mean
that you're able to read
what's inside people's hearts
and minds.
And you are not...
Responsible
for what happened
with Elise.
You're a good doctor...
And a good man.
♪♪♪
♪ hey! ♪
♪ Hey ♪
♪ do you hear,
do you hear that sound? ♪
♪ It's the sound of nonstop ♪
Right.
I'm, uh,
still your doctor.
We, uh...
We can't do this.
Actually, you're not...
My doctor anymore.
I decided I'm not gonna
have a baby.
♪♪♪
But...
♪ Shooting stars ♪
Not yet.
♪ A lost and broken heart ♪
I should go.
♪ Name your stars ♪
♪ with the touch
of a new heart ♪
♪ and it sounds like ♪
What are you doing here,
Pete?
♪ It sounds like ♪
I still love you,
Violet.
♪♪♪
I love you, too.
Wait. Wait.
What?
That's all it takes?
Just take a little break
from our marriage,
mess around
with other people,
and then we're just ready
to jump back in?
Violet--
I still don't know why
you walked out that door, Pete.
I don't think
you know either.
Why do you have to
make this so complicated?
Because our marriage
is complicated.
And it's important to me.
You, me, Lucas...
Our family...
It's everything,
and I can't
just jump back in because...
Just because we're still
in love with each other.
♪♪♪
I want this. I do.
I want this.
But I... I don't know.
For it to happen, we...
We have to do
the work first.
♪ I'm afraid
you'd name your stars ♪
You ready to do that?
♪ With the touch
of a new heart ♪
Hey.
♪ And it sounds like ♪
I've been meaning
to say thank you.
For what?
Everything you did
for Erica,
and what you're doing
for Mason.
Don't say that.
Why? I mean it.
'Cause you don't thank me
for any of that.
It's what you do.
♪♪♪
♪ now ♪
♪ oh ♪
♪ now it's the start ♪
♪ go ♪
♪ and it goes with... ♪
Whoa. Long day?
Mm.
Long, hard and...
Confusing.
Mm. Want to talk about it?
Oh, you know how sometimes,
just...
Nothing makes sense?
♪ Oh, it sounds ♪
Things haven't made sense
for me in a long time--
Corinne, Erica.
You want to know
the last thing
that made sense to me?
Hmm?
Us.
♪♪♪
We made sense.
Sam...
No, we do.
We make sense.
♪ Now is the start ♪
♪ hey! ♪
♪ Hey! ♪
Mm.
Uh...
Hello.
♪♪♪
Excuse me?
Yes, yeah, okay.
I'll be right there.
Uh...
Yeah, uh...
♪ New, a new start ♪
I have to go
to the hospital.
Okay.
♪ Now is the start ♪
♪ it sounds like ♪
♪ oh, it sounds like ♪
Mrs. Clemons, I got here
as fast as I could.
Mm-hmm. Traffic. I know.
Well, I-I just--
I hadn't heard from you
in a while,
and I just assumed--
anyway, and, uh, to get
a call so late...
This won't be the last time
a baby wakes you up
late at night.
My agency got a call
this evening.
A mother delivered a baby
she won't be able to keep,
thinks you're a good fit.
Wait.
She thinks I'm a good fit?
Wait. Me. Okay.
I'm a good fit?
Birth mother went through
the book of prospective mothers,
chose you,
wants to see you.
Uh...
Okay.
You want to comb your hair...
Or do you want a baby?
♪ The start ♪
♪ now is the start ♪
Judi?
I couldn't believe
when I saw your picture.
I figured, it's meant to be,
right?
Do you want to hold him?
♪♪♪
So how do you feel now?
♪ It sounds like ♪
Addison?