♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
I am 407 days sober.
I debated whether or not
I should say the exact number
or just rough it,
but I figured,
I've earned every day so...
My friend Charlotte
was 8 weeks pregnant
when I celebrated a year.
I use her to keep track.
If she were here,
she would probably say,
"glad somebody's getting
something useful
out of this pregnancy."
S-Sounds less awful
if you know her.
I'm doing okay
in my second year.
I got
this great new apartment.
Been there a couple of months.
I'm really trying
to make it a home.
It's been a while
since I've been on my own,
but I'm adjusting.
Ew.
It's nice to have
my own kitchen,
be able to cook
whatever I want.
And I started
working out again,
which is good,
you know...
And healthy.
Year two is a challenge,
but I'm ready.
And it's all about growth,
and I've set myself up
to grow.
I'm good.
I'm really good.
Holla.
"Holla"?
Good weekend?
Didn't leave my apartment.
Unpacked.
You've been there
three months.
I'm methodical.
You should be out there,
doing things
that make me feel old.
She did greet us
with a holla.
Thank you, Coop.
Have you met
any of your neighbors?
I'm focused on my recovery.
Well, socialization
is an important part
of your recovery.
Have you considered dating?
So I can see how quickly
I make dudes my age
sprint
in the other direction?
Aw.
Oh, come on.
We're all doctors.
We're doctors with friends
who don't scare easily.
Mm-hmm.
Would you be open to dating
someone we all vetted?
If I say no,
it'll be a thing, right?
Yes.
Oh, yeah. Yes.
Fine.
Just don't
make me regret it.
It was great, right?
Don't answer.
I already know.
Did you like your steak?
You don't already know?
So you liked it?
Almost as much
as you ordering it for me.
Was that sarcasm?
You'd tell me
if that was sarcasm, right?
Thanks.
Could we split this,
please?
Yeah.
You're really interested
in this?
You cut
into people's brains.
If that's not interesting,
then what's the hope
for the rest of us?
Something wrong?
Nah.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
She just thinks
when she says "jump,"
I should say, "how high?"
She?
My ex-wife.
You know, it was perfect,
and then all of a sudden,
it wasn't.
She doesn't think
I deserve an explanation.
But... she still tells me
she loves me when she drinks.
I'm gonna cry.
Ahh.
Uh...
Mm.
Should we split the check?
We should split the check,
yeah.
I mean, are--were you guys
also part of the team
that vetted Sarah Palin?
I'm so sorry.
I thought George
was over her.
And I thought Marshall was
a good old-fashioned Texas boy.
What are we
talking about?
Amelia's awful dates.
Oh, you're dating.
Oh, that--that's good.
Yeah, no. That's over.
Oh, come on. Bad dates are
kind of a necessary evil.
I dated a poet once.
He was a really,
really bad poet.
Turns out the odds of
finding a-a poe or a frost
are like
a million to one.
Dating Edgar Allan poe
would probably be a drag.
I mean, if I had to imagine.
I mean, finding someone
shouldn't feel like a job.
My parents met at a dance.
They both walked in,
saw each other across the room,
that was it.
Yeah, but that was
a different time.
Okay, miss "I met my guy
at the grocery."
Oh,
I went out with a guy
who said he knew
the best brunch spot in L.A.
Well, he wasn't lying.
The rub was, it was
being served by his cult.
Ohh.
I'll do you one better.
Imagine you're having
a lovely time,
and then
at the end of the night,
your date is engaged
to someone else.
Oh.
I never thanked you
for that dinner.
You're welcome.
Okay, all of this is just
making my couch
seem that much more
appealing.
Who are you gonna meet
on your couch?
Oh, I met Cooper
on my couch.
Or was I in bed?
Uh, you met Cooper
on a sex site.
I mean, it was probably
the bedroom, I would guess.
I'm not trolling the Internet
for dates.
I've seen what's out there.
Alone is better.
I guess my agent
can submit me
for bride of Frankenstein
now.
I get that she's a monster.
But I always thought
she was too good for him.
Been in anything
I may have seen?
Hmm. Ever been to
the linden boulevard church
in Albuquerque?
Can't say that I have.
I know
I'm starting out here
about ten years too late,
but this is the only thing
I've always wanted.
And I just keep
coming back to it.
After college, I had loans,
and my mom got sick.
I stayed with her
till she passed.
Six months ago,
I decided to get in the car
and just drive.
Doesn't work out,
at least I tried.
And I got to smell the ocean
every morning along the way.
Not so bad, right?
You paged me, Dr. Peterson?
She refuses
to call me James.
This is kaye,
new onset seizure.
I was at an audition--
my first real audition--
and the only thing I remember
is hearing my name.
I'm not holding my breath
for a callback.
Presented with a classic
tonic-clonic seizure.
I stabilized her with
10 milligrams of lorazepam.
Small lac secondary
to the fall.
Ordered tests
on the usual suspects.
Any previous history
of seizures?
Recent headaches,
dizziness,
visual changes,
numbness, or weakness?
Nothing.
New meds?
Drug or alcohol history?
Damn it.
Another 10 milligrams
of lorazepam.
Protect her airway.
Pulse ox is dropping.
She's not breathing.
We may need to tube her.
Wait.
Just give it a sec.
Let's get a C.T.
see what's up.
Keep me in the loop?
Dr. Shepherd.
It's Friday.
What do you kids
want for dinner?
French fries! French fries!
They want French fries,
and you don't want
to break the bank.
So why not turn that tired
sack of potatoes
into something your kids
actually want
with the e-z cut
American fry maker?
Adjust the blade settings,
and snap!
Traditional cut...
Shoestring...
Even restaurant-quality
steak fries...
Really, really good fries.
You know Billy's
on north canon?
I'm there every Friday night.
Really, really good fries.
When's the last time
you had really,
really good
homemade fries?
Really, really good fries
are hard to come by.
Really, really good fries.
I prefer steak fries,
but I guess these will do.
Just be careful
with the ketchup.
"Speed"?
Yeah. Every woman I know prefers
"speed" over "die hard."
Of course they do,
because "speed's" about Keanu
doing everything that he can
to protect Sandy.
Every girl wants that.
You have
such pretty eyes.
Abandoning
the subtle flirtation thing.
And smart...
Stop.
And challenging.
Are you always
this aggressive?
I'm a douchey E.R. doc,
remember?
Does it work?
You're here.
That does not answer my--
only you can answer
that question.
Why did you come?
I wanted to discuss kaye.
Our stable patient
whose test results
won't be complete
until the morning?
Why did you come?
What would you say
if I told you
that my TV told me to?
Does that happen often?
Mm. First time.
What time is it?
I don't know.
Well, you didn't look
at your watch.
Oh, my god.
It is almost midnight.
I gotta go.
That's why I didn't want you
to know what time it was.
Please express my gratitude
to your television.
Mm. Oh, uh, your jacket.
No. Keep it.
That way, you have to
talk to me again.
And if you don't, I'll have you
arrested for theft.
The valet probably
wants to go, so...
Okay.
When a girl lets a guy
buy her dinner,
she has certain expectations.
What are you talking about?
"Really, really good fries
are hard to come by."
You were in my head.
You went out with James?
Being alone wasn't terrible.
I-I was nesting.
I was making progress
on my apartment...
Sort of.
Now all I can think about
is mixed-message James
not kissing me.
I mean, I am not the girl
who sits around
trying to unmix messages.
I mix them.
I think I follow that.
Look, this...
This part of the relationship
happens only once.
There is no relationship.
Okay, what I'm trying
to say is,
let the attraction
percolate.
Play hard to get?
I didn't say that.
But it does work.
Yeah.
I'm not doing that.
Kaye has no trauma
or family history
of epilepsy.
Tox screen is negative.
Not drugs.
Electrolytes?
Normal.
Do you have plans
tonight?
I do.
Well, when you have time,
I'd love to take you to
my favorite Italian place.
Yeah. I'm pretty busy
until next week.
Kaye is new to L.A.?
Uh, Albuquerque, new Mexico.
Hmm. The desert.
Environmental?
Fungus. A-A fungal infection,
maybe?
Titers are high
for cocci meningitis.
Okay.
Well, now all we have to do
is find the lesions
and...
Found one.
Right here
in the cortical area.
I'll schedule a biopsy
for tomorrow.
You're gonna do
brain surgery?
Well, a biopsy will confirm
the diagnosis.
You're gonna cut into her head
when we could treat her
with antifungals
and keep a close eye on her?
My way is faster
and definitive.
It'll also take her
out of auditions
for longer
than she can afford.
All signs point to
a fungal infection,
which, if you don't mind
me saying,
was a magnificent catch.
Okay. Don't try
to suck up to me
just so that I'll do
what you want.
I wasn't. It was magnificent.
Uh-huh.
But I was hoping
getting my way
would be an unintended benefit
of stating the truth.
We can schedule
a follow-up C.T. in a month.
She stays
on the anticonvulsants,
and we schedule a follow-up
in a week.
Are you really busy tonight
or are you playing hard to get?
Well, I... Have
a lot on my plate right now.
If next week is the soonest
I can see you, okay, but...
I was really hoping to spend
some time with you before then.
How did you score a table
overlooking the kitchen?
I took care
of the chef's daughter
a few months ago.
High fever, vomiting.
My intern diagnosed the flu,
was about to send her home,
but I had a feeling.
We did a spinal tap--
bacterial meningitis.
I saved her.
Well... this is me.
Thank you for dinner.
That was really lovely.
I had a wonderful time.
Me, too.
Get home safely.
Yeah.
Okay.
But it doesn't make sense.
I'm hot.
I would kiss me.
Wouldn't you kiss me?
Absolutely.
I would, yes.
I didn't ask for this.
He pursued me.
Would not let it go.
Finally I gave in,
this is what I get.
You can't let it
upset you.
I'm not upset. I'm pissed.
Maybe he's just
not that into you.
I've always wanted
to say that.
Maybe now is not the right time,
Addison.
I got waxed.
Like "waxed" waxed.
I spent a small fortune
on new underwear and heels,
both of which are
supremely uncomfortable,
and for what?
Oh, the things we do.
Women.
I mean, why, when we could be
on our couch in sweats,
vegging out to a marathon
of "bitch snapped"?
Because you like him.
I want to do something
that justifies
the pain I'm inflicting
upon myself.
Do you think he's--
he's not gay.
Maybe he got over
a really bad break-up
and he wants to go slowly.
Mm.
Is that really a thing,
going slowly?
I mean, doesn't that
only happen in the movies?
I'm done. I'm j--I'm done.
No, you cannot quit.
And you can't put
all your eggs in one basket.
The quest to find somebody
to spend your life with
is not easy.
You need time and fortitude.
Do you hear yourself?
I-I was just looking to get
out of my apartment.
Okay. Well...
Then staying in that vein,
humor me a little longer.
Are you free tonight?
No, really.
I mean, you could stay home...
And wonder why
James isn't kissing you...
Or...
Ah.
Ortho surgeon.
Totally single.
Great conversationalist.
Mm.
Definitely not a sociopath.
Want me to see
if he's free tonight?
Well, you're already waxed.
Mm. Okay.
James.
You look beautiful.
Date?
Yeah. I, uh, actually
was on my way out.
Cool.
I can't stay but a minute.
Middle of my shift.
It's just...
The anticipation
was killing me.
Enjoy your date.
Gone?
Like--like completely gone?
There's no trace
of the lesion.
The antifungals
were effective.
So no more falling
on my face at auditions
in the literal sense?
There is no reason to suspect
that you'll have
another seizure.
I'd already called my dad
and told him that I
might have to come home.
Thank you.
Both of you.
Oh, if I leave now,
I can still make it
to my class across town.
Thanks.
Did you ever have
that much energy?
Yep.
I know I should wait
until tonight,
but now that
the patient's gone...
You can totally kiss me.
Condoms--
ribbed, glow-in-the-dark,
tingling?
Which is usually the sensation
that sends you to the doctor.
Slow down. Back it up.
I'm seeing someone.
James.
You know?
Of course you know.
Doesn't matter.
What matters is,
I went to buy condoms today,
and there are, like,
a billion choices,
and I don't want to insult him
by not buying magnums
or buying them
and making him think
that my previous boyfriends
are the Lakers.
Well, since when
are you shy about sex?
I--I'm not. I just
don't want to offend James.
Ah, that's crap.
I think this is about you
gettin' back in the saddle
after a year.
I don't know. Maybe.
You doin'
what you need to do?
I'm here talking to you.
That's not what I mean.
I am getting to meetings.
You know why I'm asking.
I know why you're asking.
When you meet someone new,
sometimes sobriety
takes a backseat.
You start cutting corners,
and then...
You slip. I get it.
Last time you had sex,
you woke up to--
a dead Ryan.
Yes... I remember.
But it's not gonna be
a thing.
You sure?
I'm sure. I'm ready.
I just need that push.
Oh.
Ahh.
Ribbed,
glow-in the dark,
tingling.
They call this one
"the soldier."
Huh.
Trial and error.
Find out what works
for you,
and have fun doing it.
Oh. Just in case.
Hey.
Wow.
Yeah?
Please.
Hey.
Wow.
Do you have a condom?
I didn't want to be
presumptuous.
I have some.
I think.
You are so gorgeous.
What's wrong?
Sorry. Uh...
Can you not touch me?
Are you--
You're here.
Yeah.
I got this thing
where I can't let a date
end in tears, so...
I was gonna
make you breakfast, but...
You only have
salsa, ice cream, and bread.
Bon appetit.
I owe you an explanation.
You don't.
I like you.
And last night,
I wanted to.
I mean,
I've got enough condoms
to supply a frat house.
I thought I was ready.
But then when you started
taking off my dress...
I haven't had sex with someone
who mattered in a long time.
And now I'm sober,
and I'm in a good place,
but in some ways
I'm still a mess.
So...
I'm giving you an out.
What do you want
on your toast,
salsa or ice cream?
What are you lookin' at?
You.
No, what are you
looking at?
I have a freckle.
What about it?
It looks like Indiana.
Can I kiss it?
Mm. You're going to anyway.
I see a few more down here
that require my attention.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
What are you thinking about?
I don't know.
Don't know or won't say?
I'm not
thinking about anything.
And that's good.
Why don't you drink?
You don't really--
I do.
Really.
I'm an alcoholic.
And I used to do oxy.
I fell in love,
I thought, with an addict.
Mm.
I don't know why I said
"I thought."
I mean...
I do.
It's because
I'm not sure anymore
if I was actually
in love with him, but...
To say that I wasn't
feels cold
because...
He's gone.
I woke up
from this amazing high
to find him dead.
And it didn't feel fair
when I found out
I was pregnant.
This baby...
Our baby
helped me stay clean.
Maybe it would've
gotten him clean
and we could've...
I don't know about
being in love with him
because that time
in my life...
The drugs...
I lived it, but...
It doesn't feel like
my life.
You loved him.
We were sober together
for, like, five minutes.
If it felt like love,
then it was.
Don't let the perspective
you have now
diminish the feelings
you had then.
That wouldn't be fair.
Have you ever
been in love?
Couple times.
Not counting Halle Berry.
What happened?
With Halle?
Mm-hmm.
I knew
I wanted to see
more than
dickson county, Tennessee.
I'd like to see it.
When you got an hour,
I'll show you.
Something just doesn't
sit right.
It doesn't bother you that
there was only one lesion?
Kaye?
Yeah.
It would bother me
if she were presenting
with more lesions
or more seizures,
but she's not.
I don't know.
Her titers were high,
but not incredibly.
Amelia, you did great
for kaye.
She's halfway to an Oscar
as we speak.
Take the victory.
Mm.
This is
a public service announcement
from the American soci--
Throws it out of bounds,
and that's gonna--
With happy dog
dog chow--
Listen,
the conservatives can say...
Not this windbag again,
please.
How do you keep up with
what's going on in the world?
I read the paper.
Mm. Smarty-pants
probably has a subscription
to the "times."
The "journal."
I prefer objectivity
in my news.
You're calling out
one of the most esteemed
news publications in the world
for a lack of objectivity?
How can it be objective
if all of its reporters
are progressives?
Who did you vote for?
In the last presidential...
It's called a secret ballot,
and it's the foundation
of our democracy.
You're a republican.
Because I wouldn't tell you
who I voted for?
Because you ended
a sentence with
"foundation of our democracy."
I'm a conservative.
Just say you're a republican.
No.
Why?
Because you really,
really want me to.
I'm in bed with a republican.
I'm pretty sure
it's not the first time.
Just think back to
the best sex you've ever had.
Not funny.
Deal breaker?
Abortion?
Pro-life.
The death penalty?
This is the sexiest
pillow talk ever.
Don't try to avoid it.
The Bible says
"an eye for an eye."
Ohh!
All right, that logic
drives me crazy!
You just said
that your for life,
but you're for
the death penalty?
I am for life--
innocent life.
Whose job is it to judge
innocence and guilt?
Does the person who took
Sarah Nelson deserve to live?
Doesn't the Bible also say
something about
turn the other cheek
and god's the only one who can
judge and stuff like that?
Wouldn't have pegged you
as someone who would
quote scripture.
I did not quote scripture.
I paraphrased.
And everybody knows
that stuff.
Ugh.
♪♪♪
♪ it would be nice ♪
♪ to get away ♪
♪ get on a train or plane ♪
♪ and never look back ♪
"You are capable
of being a great leader."
So... I'm not, I guess.
"You can't have rainbows
without the rain."
Is that insanely stupid
or incredibly profound?
It's a Dolly Parton quote.
I can't believe
you know that.
I'm not the one
being seduced
by the philosophies
of Dolly Parton.
Okay, we weren't all
bequeathed
a subscription
to the "journal" at birth.
How many other Alex p. Keatons
did your parents turn out?
Just me.
I have, uh, three sisters
and a brother who is
as close to perfect
as a human can be.
People looking for
a higher power submit to him.
When I look at you,
all I see is perfect.
♪ Da da da ♪
♪ da da da da da da ♪
♪ oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ da da da ♪
My parents are coming
into town.
Have dinner with us?
Yes.
This liberal heathen
desperately wants to meet
your parents.
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ da da da ♪
♪ I want to get away ♪
♪ da da da da da da ♪
♪ with you ♪
♪ oh, oh ♪
♪ whoa, whoa, whoa ♪
♪ I want to get away ♪
♪ da da da da da da ♪
♪ with you ♪
♪ oh, oh ♪
♪ whoa, whoa, whoa ♪
♪ I want to get away ♪
♪ da da da da da da ♪
The sun's coming up.
♪ Oh, oh, oh, ♪
♪ da da da ♪
The sun is coming up.
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ oh, oh ♪
Thank you.
Hey. Your parents
get in all right?
At the hotel now.
I just wanted to check in
with you about tonight.
5:00 because they're
on east coast time.
That chain restaurant
in the mall
because they're allergic
to new experiences.
I mean, you're sure
this is something
you're ready to do?
I... it's not like they'll
never be in L.A. again.
Look, if you've
changed your mind
and you don't want me
to meet them--
no, no, no,
it's not that. It's--
what is it?
I dreamt last night
that the ceiling
in the restaurant collapsed.
Everyone was all right,
but... I don't know.
Meeting the folks
is a big deal.
Is this you freaking out?
No.
Yeah.
Sort of.
I think it is.
I'm your girlfriend,
and I am totally excited
to meet your parents.
I wanted them
to experience L.A.
He took us
to one of those restaurants
where they don't cook
the food.
For my money,
you can't beat a restaurant
with an unlimited salad bar.
Well, I wish
they would put a limit
on these cheese biscuits.
I am not gonna fit
into my scrubs tomorrow.
That's a good one,
Amelia.
You know,
I was not expecting
to like you as much as I do.
Mom.
No, I didn't mean it
like that.
I just always envisioned
that you would
settle down
somewhere near us
and marry a local gal.
Oh, let's, uh,
let's toast to new friends.
New friends.
Hear, hear.
So, Amelia, do you have
any siblings?
Three sisters, one brother.
All doctors.
Oh. Did your mother work?
Yeah, she was a nurse
in the Navy for 25 years.
Huh.
That's probably where y'all
got the idea to be doctors.
Mm.
I teach English.
No idea where he got
an aptitude for science.
But I couldn't be prouder.
Ah, I just direct traffic
in the E.R.
Amelia's the genius
at the table.
He's being modest.
The night we met,
he caught something I missed,
saved a man's life.
Well, I'm not
the least bit surprised,
but then I might be
a teeny bit biased.
It is cool seeing the three
of you together as a family.
You guys...
Get along really well.
It's nice.
Well, that is so sweet
of you to say, hon.
You know, I think
it might have to do
with the fact
that I was able
to be at home
when he was growing up.
What kind of surgery
do you practice?
I'm a neurosurgeon.
Oh.
Amelia.
Your job sounds as hard
as... rocket science.
Is that something you could
ever do part-time?
Mom,
we talked about this.
Why would I do
the thing I love part-time?
Well, I was thinking, if you
ever want to have children...
I won't quit working.
Amelia,
you don't have to answer.
Mom, now is not the time.
I am just making
polite conversation.
It's okay.
I can answer.
She promised
not to interrogate you.
Well, it's not
an interrogation.
You see?
I just want to make sure
that you're taken care of.
Mom, not the place,
not the time,
not your business.
Let's move on.
Well, I'm gonna have
the chicken parmesan.
Ooh, that does sound good.
It's always good.
How about I get
the francaise, this one?
It has that mushrooms
and zucchini.
I like zucchini.
I'd say it went
pretty well.
You mean once I kept
my mouth shut.
Well, she promised to play nice,
but you know how mothers are.
I wasn't talking about her.
I was talking about you.
You cut me off.
I stopped her from asking you
about things
we haven't discussed yet.
It was like you didn't think
that I had ideas
about my own life.
Or you didn't trust me
to talk to your mother.
I'm sorry if that's
the way it came across.
It's just my mother
I don't trust.
You know what? I will not
be treated like a little child
who needs to be silenced,
all right?
This is not working.
What are you talking about?
Wait. Are you breaking up
with me?
You need to go.
I'm not going anywhere. We're
just having an argument here.
Go.
No.
Fine.
Amelia.
Are you awake?
I'm awake.
I might be hallucinating,
but I'm awake.
I don't want to bother you.
I've been laying here
for weeks.
Everything's a bother.
You look like
death warmed over.
Thanks, Heidi Klum.
Mm. I got a headache
that would put Godzilla
in a fetal position.
I don't know if it's noon
or a quarter to midnight
or, well, 1976.
It's 2:00 A.M.
What the hell
are you doing here?
I couldn't fall asleep
in the on-call room.
You on call?
No. I...
James and I had a fight.
He's still at my apartment,
which, in an act
of sheer freakin' brilliance,
I stormed out of.
Who storms out
of their own apartment?
Ugh. I'm so embarrassed.
I mean, I-I was just trying
to stand up for myself,
and now...
Oh, god.
I'm so humiliated.
I can't go back.
I just--i wanted...
I just need to sit
with someone.
Sit.
Hey.
Late night with James?
Mm. Something like that.
So it's going well?
Things are fine.
Why do I get the feeling
there's something
you're not telling me?
Why don't you get the feeling
that I don't want to talk?
I don't need a shrink.
I didn't need
a matchmaker either,
but that did not stop you
from shoving dates in my face
in some quest for true love
that I did not even remotely
hint at being interested in.
Just let it go.
Sorry.
Oh.
No. Uh...
I'm sorry.
I didn't get
much sleep last night.
No, you're right.
You are right.
I've been spending a lot of time
on my couch alone, too.
And the thing is...
I'm not a young woman.
I mean, I know,
I still got it, but...
I'm not young.
So sometimes I think
maybe...
I will spend
the rest of my life alone.
I have to go the hospital.
Violet, you can call me.
We can hang out in the couch
in sweats together.
I got the page.
What happened?
Another seizure.
I know. I'm taking her for
a C.T. to see what happened.
I thought you said
the lesions were gone.
They were.
We'll figure this out,
kaye. We will.
Please. I can't...
What's wrong with me?
I'll take it from here.
Glad you're okay.
I was worried.
You okay?
Do I deserve someone?
Amelia, of course.
I mean, why--
why do you--
because I don't know
if James and I can't work
or if don't want us to.
I mean, at the end of the day,
I'm a recovering addict
with a dump truck
full of baggage, right?
And the worst tragedy
that has ever struck James
is having to put down
his golden retriever.
You're not giving him
any credit.
He's an E.R. doctor, right?
He's--he's seen things.
Sure.
Other people's tragedies.
That does not
prepare someone
to live with crazy
day in and day out.
He's a republican.
Do you even vote?
That is not the point.
I don't think
you're seeing the point.
You've been so strong
this past year.
And there's no doubt
in my mind
that if you wanted to
work through this, you could.
But what you're not seeing,
and what I didn't really see
until recently is,
none of it matters.
The petty things
that we argue about
and wish we could change
about the other person, it...
You want to know
the only thing that matters?
If someone will hold your hand
when you have cancer.
Sheldon--
it's prostate,
and I'm fine.
Well... I hope
I'm gonna be fine.
But I...
I've never been happier
because I've found someone
who'll hold my hand.
And trust me,
that is...
That's all that matters.
♪ Light is darkened
in the rain ♪
♪ whispers linger and remain ♪
♪ there you are ♪
♪ wondering who to blame ♪
So...
What was that fight
really about?
♪ ...by ♪
♪ like a stranger
in the crowd ♪
All the men
I care about die.
♪ All you have
are distant memories ♪
My people live
a long time.
♪ Listen to your heart ♪
I have an uncle who's 103.
Smokes 2 packs a day.
♪ Whoa, listen to your heart,
baby ♪
♪ it'll be okay ♪
Amelia, I love you.
♪ Whoa, listen to your heart,
baby ♪
♪ it'll be okay ♪
It's her heart.
What?
Kaye.
The single lesion,
the--the lack of clusters,
the--the titers that--
that aren't that high--
it's her heart.
There's something in her heart.
She could be throwing emboli
that are causing her to seize.
♪ Get away from it all ♪
Echo confirmed
a tumor in the left atrium
of her heart.
What does that mean?
As the tumor broke apart,
you threw emboli,
and one went to your brain.
That's what caused
the lesion.
And subsequently,
the seizures.
Lifesaving catch,
Dr. Shepherd.
You're in good hands.
Dr. Bennett's gonna
get the tumor.
You're gonna be up
and running in no time.
Gonna be a hell of a story
to tell at auditions.
Save it for kimmel.
♪ Listen to your heart,
baby ♪
♪ it'll be okay ♪
Todd reiter.
Your first night,
crazy night in the E.R.
Spinal infection.
I told you to discharge,
and you didn't.
Yeah?
♪ It'll be okay ♪
Everything we know,
all the knowledge
that we have...
Pros, cons,
probable causes,
likely diagnosis,
years of schooling,
and it still comes down
to instincts,
and sometimes, all signs
point one way, but--
but sometimes you just gotta
get in your car and drive...
And forget that you know
what failing looks like.
♪ Whispers linger
and remain ♪
What are you--
I love you, too.
♪ Baby, it'll be okay ♪
♪ whoa, listen to your heart,
baby ♪
♪ it'll be okay ♪
♪ whoa, listen to your heart,
baby ♪
♪ it'll be okay ♪
♪ okay ♪
♪ ahh ♪