Murphy, single vehicle
car crash incoming.
Two victims, husband
and wife. You want in?
Yes, I would like
that very much.
Motor vehicle accident.
The other victim's behind us.
Forty-one year old female,
lacerations to her face,
contusions on her
chest and abdomen.
She was behind the wheel
when she lost consciousness.
She has three centimeters
full-thickness scalp lac
extending to her hairline.
Heart rate's normal.
Possible internal bleeding.
What are we doing, Dr. Browne?
- Fast ultrasound.
- Get on it.
Forty-five year old male.
Superficial abrasions to the neck.
Appears that he's
dislocated his hip.
The affected limb is in position
of flexion and internally rotated.
We need to relocate the hip.
Do a Captain Morgan.
How are we doing?
There is a lot of free fluid
in the recto-uterine space
and Morison's pouch
from internal bleeding.
Let's get her into OR One.
When you're done,
join us, Dr. Murphy.
Okay.
Where are they taking my wife?
She has internal bleeding, so
they are taking her to surgery.
Today is our
10-year anniversary.
Tell them not to let her die.
That woman is my everything.
She's all I have.
We use a small tool
called a laparoscope,
kind of like a metal straw.
We go in through
here, here and here.
Everything gets tucked
back inside and we're done.
It only leaves a
few small scars.
How long have
you had a stiff neck?
Uh, couple days.
Been feeling tired
or have back pain?
Little bit of both, I guess.
Going to test your reflexes.
Left patella reflex is
minimally responsive.
What's that mean?
We might have to
postpone the surgery.
We're gonna run some
tests. If everything checks out,
and we figure out why you have
pain and fatigue, we'll operate.
Come here, buddy.
Spleen and liver
are fully packed.
Where's all this blood
coming from? Suction.
- How's the hubby?
- His hip has been relocated.
He asked me to tell
you not to let her die.
She's his everything.
Duly noted. Retract the stomach.
I can't find the bleed.
Hold on. The left
fallopian tube is swollen.
And there's a large
defect in it. It's ruptured.
Our labs came back negative,
but Finn's fatigue and left leg weakness
suggests a viral or bacterial infection.
Well, he hasn't had a fever.
Other than the stiff
neck, he's been fine.
Are his vaccines up to date?
Your pediatrician
didn't send us anything.
He's never been vaccinated.
But my niece came down with
long-term intestinal problems
after getting a shot.
We did a lot of research.
Things have only
gotten scarier since.
Not really.
Weakness and fever
might mean polio.
- If you guys traveled outside the US...
- We don't travel.
And we reduce his
exposure to infectious disease
by putting him
in a public school
where he's surrounded
by vaccinated kids.
That's herd immunity.
By surrounding him
with vaccinated kids,
you're tacitly admitting
that vaccines work.
We're not saying they don't
work. It's just not worth the risk.
They save millions of lives.
You're endangering your...
I get it.
I've worked with other families
who feel the same way as you.
It comes down to
personal choice.
Dr. Park, may I consult
with you outside?
Excuse us.
They're gonna
be here for a while.
If I gain their trust, I can work to
change their views from the inside.
They're part of a movement
with social media support
and bogus research
to feed their beliefs.
You want to help?
Send them away.
"Do no harm."
I'm not sending them
home with a sick kid.
One of my best friends refused
to vaccinate her 1-year-old boy.
I told her she was crazy.
Three pediatricians
refused to take her on.
She was rejected so often
that she was finally
considering vaccinations.
And then some idiot
decided to do no harm,
that it was better that Carol's
kid had a doctor than a vaccine.
A year later, the kid
contracted whooping cough.
A month after that, she
was planning his funeral.
I'm sorry for your friend.
But we don't have a choice.
He's already a patient.
Let's test him for polio.
Your wife is gonna be fine.
She had a ruptured
fallopian tube.
Mr. Williams, unfortunately,
we couldn't save the pregnancy.
The fertilized egg
implanted outside the uterus.
Pregnancy?
It was fairly early.
She may not have told you,
may not have even known herself.
That can't be.
I had a vasectomy 10 years
ago, right before we got married.
I need to see my wife.
Mr. Williams,
that's not possible.
She's, uh... She's
sleeping. She needs to rest.
There is no way she was
pregnant. You guys made a mistake.
- No.
- We didn't make a mistake.
She's not like that.
If she gets the wrong
change for coffee,
she's driving back 20
minutes to make it right.
And the sex...
We haven't been this
active since our honeymoon.
Maybe the vasectomy failed.
I'm sorry, but a vasectomy
doesn't just fail after 10 years.
It is more likely she got pregnant
from someone who is not you.
Dr. Claire Browne is being
courted by other residency programs.
Heard it from the president
of Kaiser, San Jose.
He was surprised to hear
that she was leaving. So was I.
Just 'cause she's taking meetings
doesn't mean she's leaving.
When I was a resident, if
someone was willing to buy me food,
I would meet with
them almost anywhere.
She's approaching them. I don't
like being blindsided, Marcus.
Well, this is news to me.
But I also didn't know I had to
report human resources issues
to the vice president
of the foundation.
Why isn't she happy?
She went over Melendez's
head. Now he's freezing her out.
And I have no interest in
getting in the middle of that.
You're the president.
It's your call.
But I wonder how it would
look if Saint Bonaventure
lost two of its surgical residents
with diverse backgrounds
in less than a year.
Is it polio?
We're still waiting
on the results.
Yeah, I was talking to my colleague,
and I realized I owe you an apology.
I lied to you.
I had this good
friend I grew up with.
She had a one-year-old boy
she didn't want to vaccinate.
She couldn't find
a pediatrician.
Do you guys use alternative
medicine? Homeopathic? Herbs?
Homeopathic.
That's what Carol,
my friend, did, too.
Unfortunately, I...
I guess they didn't work. The boy
came down with whooping cough.
The coughing got worse.
And one night, the boy
just stopped breathing.
I know you know this stuff.
You know how dangerous
these diseases are.
But it's different for me.
It's different when you
see a friend go through this.
Please reconsider.
Dr. Reznick.
Do you have the test results?
Finn is negative for polio.
But given the leg weakness and
how the spine controls movement,
we'd like to do an MRI.
Thank you for your advice,
and we are sorry for your friend.
But our opinion hasn't changed.
Any fatigue? Skin problems?
No and no.
Difficulty swallowing?
No. And no dry mouth.
No soreness of the jaw.
No lymphedema. No seizures.
- Do you want to sit here and do my job?
- I could.
Radiation is going
fine. Just a little nausea.
Is that why you forgot
where you left your wallet?
Oh, stop! People forget
where they put their wallets.
People do that.
It was just a little memory
lapse. A slip, nothing more.
Have you had any other
memory slips recently?
Not that I remember.
No!
You're lying.
And you know that I know you are
lying. What do you think is gained by that?
I think I avoid you
blowing out of proportion
the fact that I forgot where I
parked my car the other day.
Once. And again,
not unique to radiation.
I want to do a
mini-mental status exam.
Not gonna happen.
Would you let your
patients treat you this way?
- Yeah.
- No.
Well, then, again,
you're not me.
Thank God. If this is memory loss,
it would impact your coordination.
Also, your ability to
juggle multiple tasks.
You would need more in-home
care, and your driving would have to...
I'm not gonna give up my car
because I might have
misplaced my remote.
And I didn't misplace my remote.
I know where it is.
It's on the coffee table
next to the National Geographic
from June of last year,
page 74, two-thirds of the way
through an article on medicine in Hawaii...
Haiti. Medicine in Haiti.
If anything changes,
don't forget to tell me.
- Ha-ha.
- Thank you.
You stole my story.
It's a good story.
Stories don't change minds.
Stories are the only
things that change minds.
We're compelled by
fear more than reason.
What these people
fear is doing something
that will hurt their child.
So they do nothing,
thinking that inoculates them.
They won't change.
Care to wager on that?
I'll take your money.
Not money, liquor.
I like me some whiskey.
Saint Elison 23-year bourbon.
Fine. You will owe me a
2002 Chateau Montpouillan.
The blue bottle, not the black.
Wow.
Never seen that before.
Our boy has two spinal cords.
It's called diastematomyelia.
It's a congenital disorder in which
part of the spinal cord is split in two.
Congenital?
So, he's had it since birth?
Why didn't anyone see it?
It's rare. And with
no obvious symptoms,
doctors generally
have no reason to look.
The problem is,
when Finn hit puberty,
the split spinal cords
rapidly stretched.
The two strands got
tethered to his spinal canal
which led to the
weakness in his leg.
As he grows, he's put
at risk for paraplegia.
Now, we can go
in and untangle it.
But any time you're
dealing with the spinal cord,
- things can get complicated.
- What are the dangers?
He could become quadriplegic.
But the fact that he's presenting
with weakness right now
makes me think that
this is progressing rapidly.
I don't think we
have a choice here.
Okay.
It's not possible.
- Did you step out on me?
- That's absurd.
You're my everything. What
could I get from anyone else?
You could get pregnant.
I didn't have an affair.
Maybe one of Todd's
swimmers got through.
I heard it happens. It
must have happened.
It's unlikely, but I
suppose not impossible.
We can test Todd's sperm count.
Uh, Dr. Park?
I had a long talk
with my husband.
We want to vaccinate Finn.
That's great, Bethany.
Your son will thank you.
We want you to do
it, as soon as possible.
Uh, unless you can't
because of the surgery.
Oh, it shouldn't be a problem.
We can start with the
first round right away.
How much is a bottle of
Saint Elison 23-year bourbon?
Five hundred a bottle.
- $500?
- $500.
Park...
Mind if I join you?
Of course.
I know you haven't been pleased
with the way things have
progressed with Dr. Melendez.
You pushed me to
be more assertive.
And I'm not going to apologize
for doing what I thought,
and still believe, was right.
Enjoy your meal.
Saint Bonaventure will soon be
a surgical center of excellence.
We'll be able to select every
unique and amazing surgery
to come through San Jose.
It could open you up to a
whole new range of experiences.
- I'd hate for you to miss out.
- I would hate to miss out, too.
But when Melendez
cut me from his service,
he cut my education in half.
He will take you back.
If I grovel.
- I have no doubt...
- You haven't spoken to him, have you?
Why come to me first?
What, you figure I'm the
path of least resistance?
I came to you first
because you're a resident.
Even though you are valued,
you're still earning your
place at this hospital.
If you care about your job,
you will speak to Melendez.
I have nothing to say.
Ow!
Yeah. But chicken
pox feels even worse.
That's it.
- I need to pee.
- Wait, you should let me help you...
Don't get up. Stay
where you are.
I need a lift team and have
them bring a backboard!
I can't feel my
leg. The left one.
- How about that?
- No.
- Can you wiggle your toes?
- I'm trying.
Page Dr. Melendez.
We need an OR now!
Hello.
Where's Todd?
He's in the cafeteria. He's
waiting for his sperm count results.
I do love him.
You look very
young for a doctor.
Oh, God, I'm sorry. I didn't...
I didn't mean to... Wait.
I was just thanking
you for saving my life.
Todd's sperm count is zero.
Do I have to tell him that
his wife kissed me on the lips?
She was thanking
me for saving her life.
I helped save her life,
too. Where's my kiss?
This isn't funny. That kiss
could be considered assault.
Oh, come on.
If the genders were reversed,
we'd be having a serious
conversation right now.
What about it, Murphy?
You wanna file a report?
Hmm...
I'll have to think about that.
Until then, tell Todd
about the test results.
You can keep the
kiss to yourself.
Dr. Park, nice
drilling off the laminae.
Dr. Reznick, carefully
open the dura in the midline
overlying the cords.
We need to separate the
cords from the midline dural sacs.
- A - $500 bottle of whiskey?
You should have checked
before we agreed to...
He's losing
his motor and sensory
evoked potentials.
Stop. We need to figure
out a way to dissect the cleft
free from the
split, and remove it
without putting pressure
on the spinal cords.
Suggestions?
We should use the laser to
cut any tethering adhesions
- before removing the septum.
- Very good.
Excuse me. I have
your test results.
Okay.
Were you gonna leave me, too?
Not that I really
care at this point...
What are you talking about?
The doctors screwed up.
We didn't.
- Then the lab must have screwed up.
- The bank?
The bank, too? It's all
just a big conspiracy?
Our medical insurance was canceled,
so I started making some calls.
We have $400 left in savings.
Checking's empty. The
retirement account's drained...
I don't know, it
must be identity theft.
- Dawn, stop lying to me...
- I lost my debit card a few months ago.
Look me in the eyes and
tell me you didn't cheat.
That you didn't take the money.
Oh, my God.
I'm so, so sorry.
How? Why?
I tried to stop, but I
just couldn't help myself.
Todd... Toddy!
Why did you marry Todd?
Because I love him.
He's the best thing
to come into my life.
He's...
I couldn't imagine
living without him.
Why did you kiss me?
I don't know.
It was a mistake.
I know why you kissed me.
I'm not excusing her actions,
but the deep brain stimulation
surgery was a bold move.
Would you have gotten to where
you are without a few bold moves?
I never broke protocol.
I looked for opportunities
and I took advantage of them.
And now you have
another opportunity,
an opportunity to show
leadership through forgiveness.
And more importantly, an
opportunity to show leadership
through not looking like an ass.
Come on, Neil. This is
like David and Goliath,
except David
forgot his slingshot,
and Goliath is beating
the crap out of her.
Unless this is resolved,
you'll make it harder for me
to make you Chief of Surgery.
Hell, it'll make it harder
for me to go to bat for you
when even bigger issues come up.
I decided not to press legal charges
against our patient for kissing me.
She has a legal defense.
Her actions were caused
by a medical condition.
Just now, she had an involuntary
muscle movement in her hand.
A spasm? That's all?
Yes. That means the kissing and cheating
were caused by a neurological problem.
Possibly a tumor.
It's also medically possible
that she's just a jerk that has a tic.
Yes, but Todd is the best
thing to come into her life.
Okay. Go test your theory.
Thank you.
Can you feel this?
- Yeah.
- Good.
Now we have to do a very
complicated scientific test.
Can you wiggle your toes?
Good job.
Finn, your temperature's
rising. How are you feeling?
I've got the chills.
Is this from the surgery?
Or is it something else?
Your heart rate's jumping, too.
- His pressure's dropping fast.
- What's... What's wrong?
Sorry, Shaun. I'm
with Lim on this one.
We are not going
to find anything.
She was happy with Todd. Todd
says they had a good sex life.
But cheating is
about more than sex.
Maybe her emotional
needs weren't being met.
Maybe she was going
through a personal crisis.
I left home with Steve
when I wasn't happy.
Why doesn't she leave?
Money, fear, shame.
There are plenty of reasons
why she'd rather stay.
She said kissing
me was a mistake.
She had no reason
to lie to me, Claire.
Shaun, I know you want to
believe there's another explanation,
but sometimes people,
even the people you
love and trust, betray you.
Look. No tumors.
The brain is clean.
It's sad.
The world is sad
and very complicated.
I wish it wasn't.
The MRI scan shows there is
nothing wrong with your brain.
You are just a liar.
Everything was good.
These last few months with
Todd... It was like our honeymoon.
Then some client flirts with me.
Now, here I am.
Shaun.
I'd like you to draw
the face of a clock.
Please.
You do have a tumor.
There's definitely something.
I think we were just
looking in the wrong place.
- Hey, Shaun.
- Hello.
Can I buy you lunch?
No, I'm not hungry,
and it's not my lunchtime,
and I have to get ready for
an important MRI. Goodbye.
Wait, wait, wait. Can I...
Can I talk to you for a second?
I had a little
incident yesterday.
I may be experiencing some
memory loss due to the radiation.
Yes, memory loss is very
common with radiation.
I can book you an MRI after
I'm finished with my patient.
No. No cognitive
tests. Not here.
There are plenty of other hospitals
in San Jose that can test you.
No hospitals,
Shaun, no hospitals.
I can administer these
tests by myself, okay?
I just... I just need your help.
Come to my apartment tonight.
We will find out if you're
losing your memory. Goodbye.
Finn has a staph
infection at the surgical site.
But we gave him oxygen and
fluids. He's stable and resting.
He will have to go back into
surgery to wash out the wound.
I want to assure you
this has nothing to do
with any side effects
due to Finn's vaccination.
- His what?
- His first round of vaccinations.
You vaccinated my son?
I asked Dr. Park to do it.
Without telling me?
I was scared.
If Finn got sick...
If he brought something
home to the baby...
We talked about
this. You promised.
Bethany?
The second MRI confirmed
the tumor is in your chest,
not in your brain,
but it produces a protein
that travels to the brain,
causing mental disorders.
Including loss of inhibitions.
The betrayal was medical, not
personal. Reason and intent matter.
You should hug her. Kiss her.
She's going to have surgery
which will be dangerous.
All that missing money, it didn't go
to hotels or... Or weekend getaways.
I've been donating it.
Animal shelters,
Feed the Children...
Every time I saw an
ad, I'd pull out my wallet.
I couldn't help it.
You couldn't say no to anything?
How many?
When we take the tumor out,
there is a very good chance her
inhibitions will return to normal.
How many affairs?
Four.
Did, um...
Did you enjoy it?
In the moment.
But the minute it was over...
Mom and Dad haven't visited
me together since yesterday.
Have they told you anything?
This has nothing to do with
you, if that's what you're thinking.
It's about the vaccination.
Dad didn't know?
So I'm not gonna get measles, but
my parents are gonna get divorced?
- I'm sure once they start talking...
- Are you gonna talk to them?
I'm sorry. This is between them.
The vax thing you wouldn't
let drop, but this doesn't matter?
My mom's pregnant and
my dad's not talking to her.
And it's your fault.
Dr. Browne, I've been
asked to speak to you.
You're an excellent doctor
and I respect your skills...
I'm sorry.
I should never have undermined
your authority the way I did.
I was wrong.
- I appreciate that.
- But I don't mean it.
You've been sent here
on an impossible mission.
Senior staff have basically
ordered you to take me back.
So if you don't take me
back, you're screwed.
If you do take me
back, you look weak.
I don't know what decision you've
made or what you were about to say,
but if I tell you I'm
sorry, it gives you cover.
So, this is me giving you cover.
I'll see you tomorrow.
We got the tumor
out. She's fine.
I'm glad you didn't leave.
I was afraid she would die.
But I don't think
I can forgive her.
I'm not sure "forgive"
is even the right word.
You've never been
attracted to other women?
Of course not.
You don't check
anyone out at the beach?
You see a girl on the
street in tight jeans?
I check them out.
I don't jump them.
I don't even want to jump them.
Your wife acted on every
single temptation she had,
every single ugly,
stupid temptation.
But she never left you.
The one thing you know
for sure, through all of that,
she was never even tempted
to walk away from you.
She never stopped loving you.
You know, I knew this couple.
They had a child.
They were happy
and building a life.
One day, the husband found out
that the wife hadn't been honest.
It broke their trust.
And instead of working it out,
they let the deception fester.
Eventually, the husband
moved out, moved away,
barely sees his kid.
I don't need any
more of your parables.
You and your stories
are the reason I'm here.
You're here because
you choose to be here.
Was that even true? That story.
No.
It's done?
Yes, the tumor
has been resected.
Would you like to kiss me?
Maybe a little.
But I'm not going to.
That's a very good sign.
Measles kill.
Broken homes don't.
Go to a bar. Let off some steam.
I'm going to the range.
- You have your own gun?
- I have three.
Can I come?
- Are you gonna talk?
- No.
You pay for your own ammo.
- Hi, Shaun.
- Hello.
No Lea?
She's out drinking with friends.
Other friends. I'm her friend.
But I didn't want to go. So
I'm watching Albert the fish.
Okay. I brought some tests.
- Where did I get my couch?
- What?
It's a memory test.
Hopkins verbal learning,
COWA, these are memory tests.
Some of the
questions are harder.
- We are going to do this right.
- Where did I get my couch?
Okay. Fine,
you got your couch from the
bus you lived in with your brother.
Who gave me my bookshelf?
The town librarian. Jennifer.
And my lamp?
Do you know?
A teacher. Shannon.
No, that's wrong. Her name was
Sheryl. What kind of teacher was she?
Sheryl, Shannon...
You never told me that.
- Yes, I did.
- I'm pretty sure you did not.
Oh.
What's my brother's name?
Oh, come on, Shaun. Really?
This is stupid. I
know your brother's...
Your brother's name is Sam.
It's Steve.
You're losing your memory.