The human brain contains
roughly 100 billion neurons.
Alone, these neurons
would only allow us to retain
about as much information
as a flash drive.
Fortunately for us, our
neurons connect and combine,
creating a web that exponentially
increases the brain's storage capacity.
It is so peaceful up here.
Oh, yeah.
It's great.
Yeah. According to the map,
- the waterfall is just around the bend.
- Okay.
In fact, this
process creates so much space
that we can store the equivalent of
three million hours of video content.
Um... No waterfall.
Did I read this wrong? I
mean, that is a waterfall, right?
Yeah, yeah. But the map also
rates this trail as moderately difficult.
I'm sorry. This was
supposed to be a fun day off.
No, I am having fun.
Mud on the boots, fresh air.
It's the great outdoors, right?
Let's go. Okay.
So, why can't we remember
everything we try to commit to memory?
"Following
resection of the ileum,
a patient is most likely to require
supplementation of which vitamin?"
B12.
Round starts in five minutes.
Coffee takes longer.
Yesterday, she yelled at me
for going to the bathroom.
Well, everyone is on edge
because the ABSITE's tomorrow.
Or because she's
not getting laid.
I'm not getting any either.
That'll be 4.85, please.
- Wow.
Oh. Uh, yes.
I swear my wallet is
in here somewhere.
Hey, let me get it.
Do you want breakfast?
I'm in an unhealthy relationship
with these almond croissants.
Uh. No, you
really don't have to.
I know. I want to.
- Here. Keep the change.
- Thank you.
What?
She bought me coffee.
Yeah. Maybe she was being nice.
Or weird.
I don't have time
for whatever this is.
Dr. Wagner to Radiology.
I've been texting.
I'm on your service today.
- I think we can downgrade Mr.
- Quint from... -Just...
I'm practicing my
speech to Altman in my head.
I am quitting general
as soon as she gets here.
Altman's off today.
No. What?
I was up all night rehearsing.
You could channel all that energy into
signing off on Mr. Quint's step-down room.
Also, Mrs. Valenti still looks distended,
so you might wanna order a CT.
Also, did you review the
nurse's notes from last night?
Did you forget how this works?
I tell you what to do.
- Now, go do all that.
- Then what are you gonna do?
I'm gonna stew thinking about how
long it took my resident to do what I asked.
Crap rolls downhill,
Schmitt. Go.
And they wonder where I get
my tone of voice.
Out of my way.
I was here until 11:00
last night doing rectals.
A heads-up would have been nice
before dumping Helm.
I didn't dump anyone.
I just needed space.
Walk faster.
- She's like a pissed off bee.
- I finished my procedure log.
Sorry it took a minute.
I was studying for the ABSITE...
Just hand it to me, Griffith.
You're supposed to
submit that to me or Schmitt,
but why start
following the rules now?
Well, congratulations.
In under two months,
you have collectively done
dozens of A-lines,
chest tubes and other
critical procedures.
And I know it is not how
you wanted to spend your time,
but you went back to basics,
worked together, and
you're ready to move forward.
Does that mean we're allowed
back in the OR?
Effective immediately.
Wait, can I please
scrub in on Dorian's...
I was on his case
from the day he got here.
Have I given the impression
that this is a democracy?
Helm.
Griffith and Adams,
you're with Dr. Bailey.
Millin, with Shepherd.
Yasuda, Ndugu. Kwan, Lincoln.
Oh, uh... And study
when you can today.
If you don't score above
the 30th percentile
on your exam tomorrow,
Joe's is hiring.
I actually loved that job,
so joke's on her.
Keep up with your notes and pages
and please don't kill anyone in the OR.
Yeah.
Go.
How we doing this morning?
My lung is still collapsed,
but I'm having
a great hair day, so...
I'll take it. Yasuda.
Emmy Chen, 16,
born with cystic fibrosis.
Admitted for a persisting
left pneumothorax.
Currently on Mucomyst
and two-liters nasal cannula.
I've had way worse.
Tomorrow, she will
undergo a VATS pleurodesis
to irritate the outside lining
of the lung and chest wall.
No way I'm consenting to that.
We've talked about this.
- You and your parents agreed.
- My body, my choice.
For the tenth time, that's
not how you use that phrase.
And your body is leaking air
from your lung into your chest.
So listen to Dr. Ndugu.
- Hi, Caroline.
- Hi.
I'm Dr. Beltran.
This is Dr. Millin.
And I'm Emmy.
And unfortunately,
peds is a full house today,
so welcome to Emmy's world.
- We're just living in it.
- Hi.
- Hi. You must be Diane. How was your trip?
- Easy.
And thank you again
so much for seeing us.
We've heard great things about
you from our support group.
Well, I hope I can
live up to the reputation.
Can I take a look?
You're better than
the first doctor we saw.
He was super judgy.
Safe space here.
We can hear you, Emmy.
That doctor judged
me for being trans.
Yep. Most doctors suck.
Thank you, Emmy.
Millin, present.
Uh, Caroline Early, 14,
presents with progressive
discomfort behind the left knee.
Diagnostic ultrasound at an
outside facility showed a lipoma,
scheduled today for an excision.
Your last scans
were a couple months ago,
so I wanna get an MRI
and just repeat ultrasound
just to make sure
nothing was overlooked, okay?
- Okay.
- We'll be back for you soon, okay?
Thanks.
Dr. Griffith, present.
Dorian Cardenas, hospital
day 55, transferred back...
Fifty-six.
Fifty-six. Transferred back to
the ICU after recurrent sepsis
and high-output enterocutaneous
fistula. Treated with IV antibiotics.
Has since recovered
from the infection.
Scheduled today for a laparotomy
and takedown of the EC fistula.
Hey, it's a good day.
You ready for surgery?
Does anyone answer "yes"
to that question?
You okay with an abdominal exam?
Whatever.
It looks like 320 ccs overnight.
Mm-hmm.
How exactly does
this surgery work?
As you know, Dorian's skin
and small bowel are connected.
So today, we are going to remove
that connection
and while we're at it, we're going
to try and reverse his ostomy.
Wait, really?
You are young.
Your nutritional markers are where
we want them, so we're gonna try.
One step closer
to a cheeseburger.
I'll believe it when I eat it.
Maybe we should
just give up on the waterfall.
Wait, I... I've
seen this tree before.
Are we... Are we
going in a circle?
Rosie!
- Rosie!
- Dad, help me, please!
Please help me. My ankle.
What happened?
My daughter fell. Please help.
Did people
come? Can they help us?
Rosie, my name's Owen.
This is my wife, Teddy.
We're both doctors. We're
gonna figure this out, okay?
All right. No service.
I'm gonna go down and call 911.
- Ow, ow, ow.
- Rosie,
can you move your
arms and your legs?
Yeah, but my ankle
really hurts though.
Okay. Try to keep your
weight off it and stay calm.
Is that a joke?
Sense of humor's still intact.
Okay. Once we get
the park rangers on the phone,
there'll be help
in less than ten minutes.
- I'm on a ledge!
- Try not to move too much, okay?
- Dad!
- I'm here, honey! I'm here!
Hold on. We're
trying to get help.
How am I gonna get out of here?
Hold on!
I'm gonna get you out!
- Dad, what are you doing?
- I'm coming, Rosie!
- Sir, wait!
- Dad, no! Dad!
No, no, no!
- Joseph, are you hurt?
- Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
I cut my leg.
It's... It's pretty bad!
- Rosie, I need you to take a look.
- Okay.
No, I don't... I don't think I can.
We're on the edge of a huge drop!
- I need you to tell me what you see.
- Oh, my God. Okay.
Oh, my God.
He's gushing blood.
When you say "gushing," do
you mean it's slow and steady?
I mean gushing!
We're gonna need to try
and stop the bleeding, okay?
Is help on the way?
- Not yet.
Until then, you're gonna need to
try and help him yourself, okay?
Now, there are three steps
to controlling bleeding:
apply pressure, pack the wound,
and applying a tourniquet.
God, I didn't even want to come
on this stupid hike!
Right now you need to listen to me.
Do you have a shirt that you can use?
You need to take that off and use it
to apply pressure in your dad's wound.
Okay.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Okay. Okay.
Hold on. Hold on. Hold on.
It's not helping!
Pack the wound with some kind of
fabric. You can use the same shirt.
You need to stuff that
completely inside the wound.
Pack it as tightly as possible.
This doesn't seem sanitary.
- You don't have any options.
- Okay.
- Rosie.
- Okay, it's in.
- Okay, good.
Now, press down as hard as you can.
We need steady and direct pressure.
Okay.
Okay. Okay.
Are you still there?
I'm still here. I'm
not going anywhere.
Come on, Teddy. Come on.
You're almost done.
Could you try not to
move around as much?
How are we not done
yet? This is torture.
Caroline,
are you a betting woman?
I don't know. Maybe.
All right. If this scan isn't done
by the time you count to a hundred,
I will give you $100.
I could buy
so much embroidery floss.
Are you into crafting?
I make friendship bracelets.
Usually during my study hall.
I can focus on tying all these tiny
knots and it's like I'm not even there.
Well, your friends are lucky that your
hobby makes them such cool accessories.
- I'm gonna start counting!
- Too late. We're done.
You can relax now.
Okay. What are we
looking at here?
Well, there's not enough
fat deposits for a lipoma.
There's a nerve running through
it. Is that a neurofibroma?
That I did not bet on.
Which of the following is an absolute
contraindication to administration of TPA?
Uncontrolled hypertension,
recent spinal surgery or the...
Yeah. I don't
wanna study right now.
Calms me down. Think I'm
nervous to be back in the OR.
Are you?
No.
Kwan, our hip replacement
got pushed a few hours,
so you can go ahead
and keep studying.
What are you doing?
I, um, am fixing a sock.
- You're taking the ABSITE tomorrow.
- Yes.
You asked me not to do op notes so
that you could have time to prepare.
And I appreciate the time.
Which you're
using to fix a sock.
Yeah, it's... Um...
- It's...
- Lucky?
Would it be weird if I said yes?
- You're Serena Williams.
- I'm not following.
She's got a thing about socks. She
won't change 'em during a tournament.
She won't even wash
'em if she's winning.
You know how many athletes have
lucky socks or shorts or beards?
You're in good company, Kwan.
You just got one problem.
You need your op notes sooner?
No.
The gauze.
It'll never hold up.
Let me see that.
So the lesion
looks benign, but...
There is always a "but."
Hey!
Unfortunately, it's not a lipoma
like your primary doctor thought.
It's most likely a neurofibroma,
which is a spontaneous growth
in the nerve tissue,
and it can damage
the nerve itself.
Which is why you're
experiencing pain.
- So, can you still remove it?
- Yes.
But we need the help
of the neurosurgeon,
which is why my friend
Dr. Shepherd is here.
Hi, Caroline.
Hi.
Is... Uh...
I'm sorry. With all due respect,
we came here from Texas
to work with Dr. Beltran.
We discussed limiting the number
of physicians for Caroline's comfort.
Yes, I know. But we need someone
extremely skilled at preserving nerve tissue
to do the actual procedure.
Dr. Shepherd and I have
collaborated on a number of patients,
so I know she's the best. If I needed
a neurosurgeon, she's who I'd choose.
Plus, she's really good
at Gem Crush.
I don't know.
This wasn't the plan.
You can say no.
Can... Can we just have a second?
Please don't take
this personally.
- No, of course.
- Yeah. We'll give you some time.
Almost through the fascia.
Okay.
Let's see what we've got.
Damn it.
Griffith, Adams.
What is that?
Are those adhesions?
- It's like one giant massive scar tissue.
- Which is known as?
Frozen abdomen. But why
didn't we see this on the scans?
Sometimes you don't see
a frozen abdomen
until they're
staring you in the face.
Okay. This is going
to be a long ride.
If the two of you feel the need
to step out
and study for your exam, no
one in here will question that.
But I need to know now.
Dorian cannot have
distraction in here.
I cannot have
Then buckle up.
Right angle.
I'm gonna need traction.
- How's it looking? Any improvement?
- Oh, God.
It's better, but he's still
bleeding through the packing.
I finally got
through. Help is on its way.
Where is the dad?
You have got to be kidding me.
Is he injured?
Well, I can't see from this angle,
but Rosie says it's a leg wound.
Lot of blood,
possible femoral injuries.
There's blood everywhere!
How does he have any left?
Maybe I should just try
to slide down there and...
And gravely injure yourself so the
EMTs have to send another team? Hell no.
He could die. He needs a...
Rosie, do you have a belt?
I'm wearing yoga pants.
Okay. That would be a "no."
- Anything with a strap?
- Yeah, I have a small fanny pack.
Does the strap come off?
- Yeah.
- Okay, that'll work.
You're gonna make a tourniquet
for your dad's leg.
You'll rap it around his leg
right above the wound,
and you're gonna tie it
as tightly as you can.
It's okay.
Okay.
I'm sorry. I'm done.
Okay. Now, can
you see any sticks?
Uh... Uh...
- Yeah. Yeah, there's one right here.
- Okay, now take the stick,
and tie it to the tourniquet
right where the knot is.
You're gonna twist that stick
and it'll tighten the strap.
- Rosie.
- Okay.
Okay, I'm twisting.
- It's getting tighter.
- Great. You're doing great.
Just keep going
until the bleeding stops.
I think...
I think it stopped.
Great work, Rosie.
Now hold that in place.
Help is on the way.
Just hang tight, okay?
Okay.
Griffith, get the Metz.
You're gonna take
down the adhesions.
I'm not sure I can see where the
adhesions end and the intestine begins.
You want me to change my mind?
Metz, please.
All right.
Nice and easy.
One layer at a time.
Never go any deeper than what
I show you with my right angle.
Okay.
- Good.
- We've barely made a dent
in this dissection.
Griffith is doing just fine.
Do you think we should continue?
Dorian's had complication
after complication.
We can't even see. If you go further,
you could cause even more damage.
He was dead on
the first day here.
Kwan held his heart
in his hands.
He's had multiple
cases of sepsis.
I've opened him bedside as he
was dying, but he's still here.
He's holding on. So,
I am too.
I see things through.
I am seeing this through.
Okay.
All right, Griffith.
They came a long way to see you.
That must be flattering.
It's enraging.
Caroline shouldn't
have to travel
to see a doctor
who treats her with respect.
You didn't wanna stay in Texas,
try to help more kids there?
You know, as much as I hate it,
I think maybe it is safer
for them to come see me here.
I mean, it's just
gotten so hostile.
Forget the awkward
stares and the microaggressions.
One family was talking about
putting a bulletproof vest on their son
just to come see me
because he's trans.
That is...
Yeah, there's no
words to describe it.
Hopefully Caroline's
mom will talk to her.
And Emmy won't.
Have you seen Emmy Chen?
She's not in her room.
- Yeah. She's kind of a wanderer.
- Well, thanks for the heads-up.
- You two wanna help me find her?
- We're about to prep a patient.
Oh, you won't be if it's
Caroline. She's also gone.
- You gotta be kidding me.
- Okay.
The elastic bandage
is the most underrated dressing.
It controls swelling, eases
pain, and it's durable and flexible.
Everything you
could want in a sock.
How's your
continuous suturing skills?
- Even distance. Decent tension.
- Great. What kind of suture?
2-0 silk. Strong and permanent.
Yeah, works for me. Let's do it.
They're moving Mr. Quint now.
So once he's settled, make sure
you check his white count again.
And track down Dr. Wilson.
Make sure she sees that we
schedule Mrs. Price's chole.
Can I scrub in on that?
Did you hear anything I said
before "chole"?
Technically I'm on
Dr. Ndugu's service.
Crap rolls downhill, Yasuda.
Yasuda, did you
see Dr. Ndugu's text?
Gotta go. Sorry.
- Emmy and Caroline are missing.
- Oh? Maybe they scrubbed in on a surgery.
All the cool kids are doing it,
except for me.
Well, at least you have
more time to study.
I have a photographic memory.
I don't need to study.
I need to cut. I deserve to cut.
Entitled much?
I finished my
procedure log weeks ago
and then I had to wait patiently
for everyone else to finish theirs.
- That was you being patient?
- Yeah.
And now that all the
bottom-feeders are finally done,
I can't scrub in
to save my life.
I... I am dying here.
Well, on behalf of all the
bottom-feeders, my sincerest condolences.
Did Ndugu check
the attendings' lounge?
What, you think
they'd let themselves in?
I put nothing past Emmy Chen.
She's been my problem
child since day one.
You sound like my mom.
I was not an easy kid.
I thought she was hazing me
my first week here.
She paged me 20 times just
to look at one TikTok video.
And it turns out
her parents work,
and they have two other kids,
so she's alone a lot.
I've spent more than a
few dinners in her room.
She's a headache,
but she's my favorite headache.
Reminds me of me at that age.
Stubborn as hell.
We probably
would have been friends.
Hmm. Probably not.
Seriously? You know you're not
supposed to eat before your procedure.
She knows. We're not idiots.
They're for later.
- And you shouldn't be out of your bed.
- It's my fault.
I just wanted to take a snack,
and we didn't have time...
- Emmy! Emmy?
- Emmy! Emmy, Emmy.
- Emmy, are you okay?
- We need oxygen and a gurney.
Give me
her head. Come on.
Stay with me.
Emmy.
Hunt?
Joseph Scott, 47 year-old male.
Status: post fall into a cave
Sustained a left leg
puncture wound from a rock.
Arterial bleeding
with significant blood loss.
Controlled with a tourniquet
and packing in the field.
No other injuries
or head traumas.
And Altman.
Right. What do we got?
Rosie Scott, 19-year-old female.
Status: post fall
into the same cave.
Isolated left ankle injury.
Awake and alert. Vitals are stable.
- How's my dad? Is he okay?
- He's tough. He's hanging on, okay?
Let's do a workup on her ankle.
Gonna get him straight up to the
OR, okay? Rosie, he's in good hands.
We'll update you
as soon as we can.
Hell of a way to
spend your day off.
All right. Kwan,
let's get her inside.
What if she hates me? It was
my idea to leave the room.
It's gonna be okay.
She's getting help.
Take a deep breath for me, okay?
Good, good. Okay.
Welcome back. Welcome back.
All right. Let's go.
We gotta get your chest tube
hooked back up to suction, okay?
What's wrong?
You're scared? It's okay.
No, no, no. Leave it on.
I'll try to name it. What is it?
The pneumothorax?
You're scared it's worse?
Okay. You're scared
you won't recover?
You will. I got you.
I'm here. So is Caroline.
We're all here. We just
want you to be safe, okay?
But I swear
I'm gonna put a tracker on you.
- That's all connected to the... -Stop talking.
- I'm thinking.
Yeah, it's not gonna work.
We'd have to take
too much of his bowel...
- Wait. But you said that...
- Yeah, I know what I said.
But the amount of bowel he has
is far less than what we thought.
Look, there's friable bowel
around the fistula.
After we resect this area and
get to healthy bowel...
he'll be worse off
than when we started.
Could we put him on medication
for short bowel syndrome?
That could help, but he still doesn't
have enough bowel to keep him off TPN.
We did all this, and now Dorian's
gonna have to get all his nutrition
from an IV bag for
the rest of his life?
- He's 23.
- Adams.
No, no. He'll end up in liver
failure by the time he's 30.
Do you think I don't know that?
Do you think I'm at
all okay with that?
In pediatric cases
of short gut syndrome,
which of the following techniques
increases residual bowel by 20%?
Dr. Griffith, the OR is not a place to
quiz yourself on your ABSITE exam.
A serial transverse
enteroplasty procedure.
A STEP procedure.
Tell me what it is, Griffith.
You cut the residual
intestine in a zigzag fashion.
And why do we do that?
To lengthen it
and help increase absorption.
But it is not the standard
of care for an adult.
Because most of the research
on it focuses on pediatric patients.
And nothing this man has
gone through has been standard.
Change of plans.
Adams, switch with Dr. Webber.
We are converting
to a STEP procedure.
Follow my lead. Do
exactly as I say.
I'm gonna need a GIA stapler
and multiple reloads.
Hi. Put a rush on these and
text me their BPs every two hours.
I thought you were meeting me
in the ICU to remove drains.
Yeah, I'm just checking on a few
postpartum moms from yesterday.
But you're in navy scrubs.
Oh, right. I forgot.
When I change my scrubs,
I just forget about all my
patients from the day before.
Also, I checked your notes.
Half the things I told you to do
you gave to the interns.
I supervised them because
I'm a supervisor. Are you?
If you need help
removing drains,
we have bigger problems
than you just being annoying.
Bailey and Webber are still in surgery,
so I'm also covering their patients,
and studying for the ABSITE.
Okay. Are you having
the same conversation with them?
You haven't quit yet.
You made this decision, like,
48 hours ago,
and you've already checked out.
Hey. Your mom said
you wanted to see us?
Yeah. I still haven't decided
on the surgery, though.
Mmm.
Well, that's okay.
Do you have questions?
Emmy's been gone a while.
Oh, yeah. She just
needed to get some tests done.
I'm making her a bracelet.
I didn't know her favorite
colors, so I chose mine.
Green and purple.
Caroline, we do wanna help you.
That thing Emmy did,
can I do that?
Where you say what
you're scared of?
Oh, sure.
Emmy and I usually take
turns though, so I'll go first.
Um...
I am scared of forgetting
my patients' parents' names.
So I write them on my hand.
I'm scared
I won't recover from surgery
in time for the spring dance.
Mmm.
I'm scared of
the hospital basement.
Actually, any basement.
I'm scared of
going under anesthesia.
I've never done it.
Yeah.
I am scared of
not living up to
my patients' expectations.
I know that
they're counting on me.
I read online that when
you're on the operating table,
you're naked.
I've never been
naked in front of anyone,
let alone an entire room
full of strangers.
I'm scared they
won't be able to...
won't understand.
I'm scared they won't see me.
Caroline.
Hey.
We see you.
You're an amazing girl,
and we are gonna make sure that
everyone in that operating room knows that.
Okay.
I'll do the surgery.
We will get you prepped.
And I will go tell Diane.
Okay. This will be
more comfortable.
I'll be back to
check on you later.
Can we talk?
Usually I'd say yes, but you've
been ignoring me all week.
Yeah, because you screwed with
my ability to become a better surgeon,
which honestly,
I rank as high as cheating.
But I am coming
to you as my boss.
I need surgery.
It's our first
day back operating,
Ndugu is not in the OR today and I
finished all my work on his service.
Study for the ABSITE
like the rest of us.
Put yourself in my shoes.
When you worked at Joe's, weren't
you dying to get back into the OR?
- No.
- How are you my boss?
Beckman could use
an extra set of hands on a TAVR.
OR 4.
- You better run.
- Thank you.
Oh, I mean it.
And... And we'll talk.
Eventually.
Thank you.
Punctured the SFA.
We could do a primary repair.
- Mmm.
- We just need to clean the edges.
You know, this is not how I
thought our day was gonna end.
You're telling me.
I had a cheese
and charcuterie plate ready
for when we got to the top.
Irrigation.
You know, when I was standing
up there I couldn't see anything,
and I thought for sure
that he'd lost his leg or worse.
Some people are
just lucky, I guess.
What's lucky is that we
were hiking the same trail.
Geralds, please.
Hey, thank you for today.
- It was great.
- Speak for yourself. I want a redo.
I don't know. Reminds me of the
old days. Me, you, out in the field.
- Lots of blood, no supplies.
- Adrenaline likes us.
I mean, but would a bed-and-breakfast
on Whidbey Island be so terrible?
- Any fracture to the lateral malleolus?
- No.
If there was?
Well, it depends if it
was stable or displaced.
Good. Displaced?
Plate and screws.
Exactly.
Why don't you take this?
Is my ankle broken?
It's a bad sprain.
You need to rest it,
use ice and compression,
and keep it elevated.
Any word on my dad?
He's still in surgery.
He... He left me and
my mom when I was six.
Got remarried,
started a new family.
We just reconnected last year.
And he invited me to go on this
hike, and I didn't wanna go.
And then he...
he told me to stay on the trail,
but I wanted to see
inside the cave, and just...
I needed some space.
So he has to be okay.
We'll let you know
as soon as we hear more.
Thank you.
Another reload, please.
Excellent solve.
I think this is
gonna work out nicely.
Deploying the staple.
He's coding.
- Wh-Why? What happened?
- No, no, no.
We're losing him. Okay. Move.
You two, out of the way now.
Okay. Starting compressions.
Push epi. Okay. Come on, Dorian.
You've come way too far
to give up on us now.
Come on.
Hey.
- How's Emmy doing?
- Hey. She's good.
Her O2 sats are up.
She's pretty much her old self.
So, on her phone,
and wondering where I am?
Something like that, yeah.
- Uh, sounds like Caroline's surgery went well?
- Yeah, thanks to Dr. Shepherd.
All right. Well, I gotta go check on a
patient, but I'll round on Emmy later.
Hey.
Still waiting for mine.
They weaned her off oxygen in
the PACU, and vitals are great.
- Well, how you feeling, Caroline?
- A little tired.
Not bad for someone
who just got a tumor removed.
So how long will
it take to recover?
Well, she will need follow-up
care, but I expect a quick recovery.
Yeah, that school
dance is gonna be fire.
No one says that anymore.
You can just say she'll
have fun, like a normal person.
Thank you.
- I'll text you pics.
- You better.
Thank you... both of you... for
taking such good care of my daughter.
- Of course.
- I think we make a pretty good team.
Hey, Rosie.
He should be awake soon.
You know, we...
we fought about that fanny pack
this morning before we left.
He said that hikers need
backpacks so they can bring supplies
and be prepared for anything.
But I was stubborn,
and I brought it anyway
because it went with my outfit.
Well, I bet he'll feel differently
about that fanny pack now.
Thank you for saving us.
Rosie, you did all the saving.
All I did was talk.
I mean, what you taught me
wasn't hard.
It's just... I just didn't know
it was what I needed to do.
But if you hadn't been there,
my dad wouldn't be here now.
Push more epi, please.
Come on, Dorian.
Adams, take over compressions.
Good. Good.
Come on.
- Come on. Come on. Come on.
- Griffith, what do you see?
Hold.
V-fib. It's a shockable rhythm.
Okay. Uh...
Paddles, please.
Check his pulse.
- Anything?
- Nothing.
No pulse.
All right. Charge to 150. Clear.
Adams, clear!
Adams, clear! Adams!
Lucas! Hey, hey.
It's okay. It's okay.
It's okay.
And clear.
Charge to 170.
Clear.
Charge to 200.
Clear!
- Bailey.
- Again. Clear.
Oh, Millin. So I have
good news and bad news.
The good news is
I found a surgery.
The bad news is now Ndugu needs
someone to pull wires on one of his patients.
So, could you just do
me a huge solid and pl...
Are you okay?
I haven't gotten
a single question right today.
- I'm going to fail.
- No, no. You're not going to fail.
Yeah, and then
I'm gonna be unemployed.
I'm gonna have to crash with my
hippie parents or my stupid brother.
You're gonna do fine.
I know all of this.
I know it
backwards and forwards,
but every time I look at the
test, my mind just goes blank.
I love my job.
I don't wanna get fired.
Sounds like you need
the Yasuda technique.
What is that?
My patented study method.
It has a 100% success rate.
By 100%, do you mean just you?
Do you want my help or not?
And what about your surgery?
I'll get on one tomorrow.
Okay. So...
Here we go.
Okay.
I saw you updated Rosie's chart.
Uh, yeah. I thought I'd try
to get some of your notes done
before I get back to studying.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
Kwan.
I've watched you work all day.
I know you're gonna ace the
ABSITE, and not because of luck.
It's because you work hard. You're
prepared. You know your stuff.
Remember that when
you're in the exam.
Thank you.
But I should still wear
the socks though, right?
Yeah.
And if you have to clean them,
hand-wash only.
Oh, yeah.
You're still here?
I'm monitoring him myself.
I sent the interns home.
ABSITE's tomorrow.
You've done a good
job with them, Bailey.
Him too.
Yeah, it doesn't feel like it.
And he's hangin' on,
but who knows... if he'll wake up...
what his functional output will be.
And the interns...
And I thought I did a good job
with them too.
I thought the repetition
and the focus
would prepare them
for anything. But this?
I mean, shot point-blank
on his way home from work.
And he's just one of the
thousands of gun violence victims
who show up in
hospitals every year.
One of thousands who have to undergo
surgery after surgery after surgery.
I don't know
how to prepare them for that.
I don't wanna have to
prepare them for that.
I'm still not prepared for that.
No one is, Bailey.
No one is.
- Hey.
How's Rosie?
She's good. You know,
shaken up, but good.
Listen. If we were
just able to teach
a 19-year-old how to stop
her father from bleeding out,
why couldn't we
teach that to everyone?
Think of how many traumas occur
every single day
and how many lives are lost because
someone with medical training just isn't there.
I mean, we could make videos, hold
classes, build websites. I don't know.
But if stopping a bleed
was taught just like CPR,
we would save so
many more lives.
I mean, what do you think?
I think it's a great idea.
- You do?
- Mm-hmm.
I mean, would you
be able to fund it?
I mean, even just the research
and development?
Um... I...
Well, I just... I'd have to
see how much I have left.
Okay.
This is gonna be great.
Come on.
That's me apologizing.
You could just say,
"I'm sorry, Levi."
Fine. I'll give it to Helm.
Okay.
I almost lost a pregnant mom
the other day.
And now I can't get
her out of my head.
And now I'm literally worrying
whether all of my patients
are still breathing
in the middle of the night.
- Jo...
- Link found me at 2 a.m. last night
logging into the hospital system
just to see
everyone's blood pressure.
So, no, I'm not checked out.
I'm just... freaked out.
You are an amazing surgeon.
You're so good both
specialties want you.
Mistakes happen. You've
told me that, like, 20 times.
Why are you still making mistakes
after the first time I told you?
You can go to OB now.
I'm good.
Oh, hey. No dinner
with Emmy tonight?
Nah, she has a new bestie.
I'm old news.
Oh, hey. Um, thanks for earlier.
You said nice things to Caroline
and her mom.
Hmm, well, I lied.
You suck at Gem Crush.
I'm never letting you
near my phone again.
- But you would let me operate on you.
- Well, I've seen your hands.
So I, uh, wanna say
a thing. Uh...
and I'm a little
afraid to say it.
So I'm just gonna blurt it
because that is what I do.
Would you want
to go out with me sometime?
Clearly I misread
the situation. Um...
You were just very complimentary
today, and you bought me a coffee, uh...
Please forget that I
said anything ever.
No, it's just, um...
I am going through a
really messy divorce.
And my wife's
still in Texas, so...
Hey.
Emmy's parents are
in the family room.
I'm happy to talk to them, or...
No. No. I'll come with you.
Okay.
Hey, you okay?
I'm fine.
I've been there. It's hard when the
person on the table is more than a patient.
I couldn't stop.
Bailey was
right there telling me,
and I still couldn't.
I guess it's been my
problem all along, right?
I don't know when to let go.
You know how I thought of
the STEP procedure today?
You're an ABSITE genius?
I thought of you.
You're fearless when you
advocate for your patients,
no matter who's in the room.
I've been afraid to take chances
when I might be wrong,
thinking that's putting
my patients at risk,
but it's riskier not
to take the chance.
And you taught me that.
I'm a braver doctor
because of you.
I'm a better
doctor because of you.
Our brains are constantly
adapting to the present moment.
Hi.
What time is it?
The test starts in five minutes.
No, that's impossible.
We literally just fell asleep.
- The test starts in five minutes!
- I know!
Oh, my...
Just run!
Our brains can override
information we no longer use
with newer, more relevant ideas.
So this is a class?
We'll also have video tutorials,
community outreach.
Well, it sounds like the kind of thing
the Fox Foundation can get behind.
We could start this at
Grey-Sloan, and if it goes well,
we could branch it out to all
of the Fox Foundation hospitals.
Have you spoken to
your chief of surgery?
I don't wanna be the cause
of any marital discord.
Yeah. Teddy likes it.
I just... I didn't wanna put her in an
uncomfortable spot asking for money.
- So...
- No, you don't. Church and state.
- Exactly.
- Okay, Dr. Hunt.
I will look into our discretionary
fund and see what I can find.
Our brains make these decisions
for us, whether we like it or not.
You will have
a total of 240 questions
divided into two
150-minute blocks.
You have a
45-minute optional break
and cannot go back to
section one after submitting.
Please enter your
authorization codes and begin.
They help us hold onto
the things that matter
and make space for
whatever the future may hold.