♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
♪ oh, oh, oh,
oh, oh ♪
♪ oh, oh, oh ♪
New York is far.
It's a plane ride away.
You want Maya
a plane ride away?
Well, she said that the Dean
of admissions called her
"perfect Columbia material."
Which makes me proud,
but do--do you want Olivia
a plane ride away?
No, no.
Olivia's not going anywhere.
Mnh-mnh.
What do you hear
from Addie?
Uh, Archer left.
She's gonna stay
a few more days
and help the captain
get ready to move out.
She holdin' up?
Sounds like it, yeah.
How about you?
Well, things have been
a little crazy
between Addison
and me lately, so...
Some time apart
might be good.
But it's good. I'm good.
You're lonely.
I have Olivia.
Yeah, I bet when you're
feeling sorry for yourself,
you keep her up later
than you're supposed to.
You do. You know you do.
I exercise
the grandfather's prerogative,
uh, from time to time.
Well, since one baby
needs her sleep
and the other one
needs some company...
Why don't we pick a night,
and I'll come back,
and we'll put her down on time,
and then I'll cook dinner?
What if we keep her up
a little later
and order in?
Deal.
Okay.
You got it?
Uh-huh.
Mm.
Hey, I can finish up if you
want to get ready for work.
We're fine.
You can't still be mad.
Oh, that's where
you're wrong.
Come on, Pete.
You know I had to rewrite
the manuscript.
The publisher asked me
to go deeper, and to do that,
I had to share all my stories
and--and the people in them.
Going deeper into your life
is fine.
But completely exposing mine
is not.
But you're a part
of my life.
My first marriage isn't.
And neither is the fact
my mother's in prison.
But you--
you overcame all that.
Which makes it my story,
not yours.
♪♪♪
Okay. Well, um...
I gave the revision to
everybody else in the practice
when they got back
from bizzy's funeral,
and no one else has had
a problem with it.
I don't care
what anyone else thinks.
I hate your book, Violet.
♪ Hey, hey ♪
♪ hey, now, now, now, now ♪
♪ ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh,
ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
We were cooking dinner
together with Jack,
that's my fiancé,
and it just--it happened.
She got quiet
and she seemed confused,
and then her voice changed.
And I asked, "Andi,
are you okay?" And then...
Gina responded.
Gina?
That's one of her others.
That's what my sister calls
her alternate personalities.
Was that the first time
that's happened?
Andi was diagnosed with
multiple personality disorder
when she was 7.
We were, uh, driving to dinner
with my parents.
It was raining.
A car barreled through
the intersection.
Our parents died.
We survived.
And it took
a lot of therapy,
but i'm--
I'm with her everyday.
I haven't seen
another personality in...
Almost ten years.
I had already
tucked Tanya in
and was getting ready
for bed myself
when I heard these noises
coming from her room.
Sometimes
she likes to stay up,
playing with her stuffed
animals, but when I went in...
It was just Ricky.
Who's Ricky?
My friend.
We go to school together.
Yeah.
They were
having sex, Dr. Bennett.
He comes over sometimes.
Apparently,
it's been going on for a while.
Don't tell your mom.
Oh.
She'd been complaining
of stomach pains.
I didn't know why,
and now...
I think she needs
a pregnancy test.
Oh, well, stomach pains
could mean anything.
It could be the flu,
it could be appendicitis.
Please.
Okay. All right.
Tanya, why don't you
lie back for me, okay?
I'm gonna check your belly.
You're not gonna check
my heart?
I know I normally do
check your heart,
but today, I'm gonna look
inside your belly
with a special machine.
This may be a little chilly.
You ready? Mm.
Yuck.
I know.
You know how closely
I watch her.
Erin, you are a great mother,
and of a teenager,
which means hormones and...
What's in my belly?
Oh, god.
Lara's been taking care of me
since our parents died.
She had just turned 18,
and suddenly,
she was looking after
a 7 year old full-time.
Which is how
she still treats me.
She's a big sister.
Yeah, but it's
almost 20 years later.
I have a job.
I pay my bills.
She can't
worry about me forever.
Losing your parents
at such an early age
is a significant trauma.
And I think she's worried
about how you're coping.
Meaning, she's worried
about my others.
She mentioned them.
But she also said
that they had gone away
for a long time.
Yeah.
It's okay, Andi.
It's not your fault.
Lara said
that you were having dinner
when one
of your others appeared.
Do you remember anything
about that?
No. I black out.
I-I don't know
what they say or do.
It's awful.
So you
can't remember anything?
Not really.
Nothing at all?
Andi?
She answered the question,
jackass.
My name is Gina.
And you need
to back the hell off!
I think shrinks are good.
I think talking is good,
and Charlotte and I
as a couple, we're...
Good.
But here you are, so I have to
assume there are some issues.
We don't have issues.
Well, no big ones.
Uh...
She won't wear
her engagement ring.
It was broken, and I had it
fixed and polished.
How did it break?
I was raped.
The attacker
broke my left hand.
They had to cut it off
at the hospital.
Well, that must have been
very difficult for you.
The ring's a reminder.
Why didn't you tell me?
I'll buy you another one.
I don't want another one.
You can't wear the one you have,
but you don't want another one?
What does that even mean?
Well, it seems we do have
something to talk about.
I mean, one minute,
she's talking calmly,
and then bam. She's yelling
obscenities at me.
Andi?
Gina. Her alter.
What was she mad at?
Me. She thought I was attacking
Lara and her fiancé.
I mean,
Gina's very protective.
And how did you know
it wasn't Andi?
The transformation
was remarkable--
the--the inflection,
the--the change in her posture.
And you're sure
she wasn't faking it?
Every woman does.
No, that's... we're talking
about a patient with multiple
personality disorder, not, uh...
Orgasms. Gotcha.
Is that even real--
the whole Sybil thing?
Gina's very convincing,
and she was not happy
that I was poking around
in Andi's head.
Well, can't blame her
for that.
Oh, says the girl who delights
in drilling holes in skulls.
Well, at least what I do
is rooted in science.
There is pet-scan data
evidencing neurological changes
in the brains of patients
with m.P.D.
One. One study, and it is
right up there with that wacko
who said that vaccinating
your kid causes autism.
I am not saying I don't believe
in dissociated behavior.
I-i-I've had patients with
borderline personality disorders
who--who act out,
who--who try to manipulate.
But it's usually
for, uh, for personal gain.
You... Okay, no.
I'm sorry. I know this is
totally uncool of me to ask,
but, um...
Have either of you
read my manuscript?
The one where you basically
call me a whore?
Yep, I read it.
That's not what i-i--no.
Y-You have a certain
sexual confidence,
which--which is great.
And I was trying to
contrast that with the fact
that I had some, uh, issues
with intimacy after the attack.
Ah.
Well, y-you understood that,
didn't you?
I haven't gotten
to that part.
I'm still enjoying the section
where you're discussing
cheating on Pete with me
and then chucking me overboard.
Not that I don't enjoy being
described as "rebound sex."
Sheldon, I never said--
I believe "sexual leftovers"
was your phrase.
I mean, honestly, Violet, if
you're gonna go down that road,
the least you could have done
is discuss
my more positive attributes.
So if you have any more books
in you, I would appreciate it
if you'd refrain
from any and all discussion
of our sexual history
as well as any failure
I might have had
in pursuing you romantically.
What he's really saying--
"filter."
Tanya can't
safely carry a baby
let alone deliver one,
can she?
Well, because of
the cardiac issues
that are secondary
to down's,
it would be
a high-risk pregnancy.
But with proper monitoring,
yes, she could do it.
Yeah.
I mean, Tanya has down's,
Ricky has
severe learning disabilities.
I just--i don't know how
they could raise a child.
Well, they'd need your help.
And if the baby has
special needs, too?
Well, i-it may not.
Yes, there's a 50% chance
that the baby could be born
with down's and could be
at greater risk for other kinds
of complications, but--
please, Dr. Bennett.
I appreciate how supportive
you're trying to be.
I-I love Tanya
more than anything.
But after I had her,
I couldn't have another child.
I wanted to keep her at home,
raise her myself,
and it was so much work.
Tanya couldn't do it,
and i'm...
I don't know
if I can do it again.
So you're prepared...
To abort the baby?
I'm not sure
I have another option.
Well, how would Tanya feel
about that?
Erin has power of attorney
for Tanya,
so it would be her decision.
Okay, well, at this point,
it's--it's a procedure.
It's not a pill.
So what would you tell Tanya?
Well, I wouldn't want
to lie to her.
But...
Why don't you take some time
to really think this over?
And, uh, in the interim,
we can do c.V.S.
Genetic screening?
If you are serious
about this abortion,
Tanya is already 11 weeks.
A couple more days,
it becomes a bigger procedure.
But if we do the c.V.S.,
you'll be able to know
whether or not the baby
has down's
or any other abnormalities
or if the baby is fine.
Well, then...
Let's--
let's do the test.
Great.
You know
what I don't understand?
Why can't people
just be happy for me?
I wrote a book.
It's a big deal.
When Sam published a book,
we threw him a damn party.
Why aren't you
looking up at me?
Oh, not you, too.
"Man-child"?
Okay. Uh, yes.
I did call you that once.
Maybe twice.
But--but that isn't
all that I said about you.
I-I-I repeatedly refer to you
as my best friend.
Man... child.
Oh, come on, Coop.
I need someone on my side.
Man-child!
You guilted Erin
into taking that test.
No, I am just trying
to make sure
that she understands
the situation
before she makes a decision
that she and Tanya might regret.
You just didn't want her
to have an abortion.
No. No, I don't want her
But you're not the one
that's gonna have to raise
that child--her grandchild.
I know what it's like
to help raise a grandchild.
What are you
hoping for here, Nai--
a healthy baby and for Erin to
decide that Tanya can keep it?
Yes.
And if that baby has down's,
then what?
I know you're not gonna advise
her to have an abortion.
The catholic in you
couldn't tolerate the sin
while the doctor would worry
it feels like eugenics.
Look, if Erin has
the responsibility
of raising two children
with down's, how good
do you think that's gonna be
for Tanya and the baby?
What's gonna happen
when Erin's gone?
The longer this goes on,
the more aware Tanya's gonna be,
and the harder
it's gonna be for Erin
to explain to her daughter
that she doesn't want
to have another baby
that's like her.
Maybe the baby
won't have down's.
won't have anything.
That's the hope you're selling
her--of having the baby
she didn't get
the first time around.
I never said that.
You didn't have to.
She does seem
to be dissociating.
I've known Andi
for five years, Dr. Wallace--
almost as long
as I've known Lara.
Not once have I seen any of
these so-called personalities.
I know this disorder can be
difficult to understand.
Disorder? Is that what we call
it when my future sister-in-law
decides to go crazy cakes
a week before we move?
Calling her crazy
is not helping the situation.
I'm sorry.
You're right.
So...
Where are you moving?
Arizona.
Jack got promoted.
I'll be managing
a new plant in Phoenix.
We're supposed to go down
this weekend
and look for houses.
No, you're gonna have to go
without me.
I'm gonna have to stay here.
We talked about this at dinner,
before your sister started--
stop it.
Look...
I'm not going without you.
I can't leave Andi.
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
Hey.
You can stop being
all moody moose now.
I'm wearing it.
I don't want you
to wear it.
Yes, you do.
No, I...
You were wearing it
when he raped you.
I was also wearing
my skin that day.
There's nothing I can do
about it.
If you don't want
to wear the ring,
you shouldn't wear it.
Why can't I get you
another one?
It's a waste of money.
It's just a ring.
It's an engagement ring.
It says you're mine.
It makes it official.
We're official because we're
committed to each other.
There are steps in people's
lives together, Charlotte--
sex, moving in,
ring, marriage.
We're on the ring.
Which I'm wearing.
"And then the woman I thought
was my friend and confidant
told a judge I shouldn't be
given custody of my own child."
Paging Addison Montgomery.
"It was hardly
an impartial opinion
"since at the time,
she was basically
living with my son's father."
Oh, man. I better hide Addison's
copy of this manuscript
before she gets back.
Anything can be made
to sound bad
when it's taken
out of context.
Like the part where Violet
says she reconsidered
all of the parenting advice
you gave her
once your 16-year-old daughter
got knocked up?
She did not drag Maya
into this.
Mm-hmm.
You know what part
I thought was a hoot?
The section where she hinted
that I don't know my fiancé
as well as she does.
That's no hint.
She dragged Maya
into this.
Don't look at me.
I didn't write the damn book.
You need
to sit her down, Pete.
And say what?
- That she needs to take us out of the book.
- Tell her own story.
Don't drag the rest of us
through the mud.
What makes you think
she's gonna listen to me?
She has to,
'cause you're the only one
who's still talking to her.
Okay, we're almost there.
This feels funny.
Hang in there, Tanya.
And...
We... are done.
- You did a great job.
- Right.
Are you okay?
I'm okay, mom. Did you get rid
of the dot we saw in my belly?
Uh, that's not
what this was, honey.
I didn't like it.
I-I-Is Tanya here?
I-I'm Ricky.
- Ricky!
- Ricky, could you give us just a minute?
Uh, Tanya's almost done.
No, come in.
A-A-Are you okay?
I'm okay.
Uh, wh-wh-wh-what--
what were you doing?
We were doing a test.
It was a test
on a baby.
You and Tanya made a baby,
and it's in her belly.
We--we--we made a baby!
We made a baby?!
I remember art therapy.
My last shrink
was a big fan.
It's just another way
of expressing yourself.
I met your sister's fiancé
yesterday.
Jack?
He's a good guy.
So you two get along?
Why wouldn't we?
He told me about
his new job in Arizona.
Are you planning
on moving there with them?
No. It's just gonna be
the two of them.
Are you okay with that?
Sure.
Does this look like Jack?
Yeah.
You'll be alone
for the first time
since your parents died.
How do you feel about that?
I think
I can manage without...
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ ooh ♪
♪ ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
Andi?
They don't care about Andi.
♪♪♪
Is this Gina?
My name is Maggie.
♪ I saw you in a dream ♪
How can Lara just walk out
on her like that?
They're sisters.
Don't you think
Lara has the right
to live her own life?
♪ ...beneath the stars ♪
You sound like Jack.
He's not nice.
I hate him.
He's taking her away.
♪ Sway, sway ♪
Well, why would he want
to do that, Andi?
I told you.
I'm Maggie.
♪ Yeah, we'd sway ♪
♪ sway ♪
Do I get to draw, too?
♪ The feelin',
think 'bout how all... ♪
If you'd like.
♪ Change ♪
♪ ooh ♪
♪ ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ and you ♪
♪ ooh ♪
I've always treated Tanya
with respect
and couldn't not tell her.
Well, no one's blaming you.
I know that--that raising
a child is a challenge,
but they have
so much love to give.
And if their abilities were
anywhere near their enthusiasm,
it would be different.
But as wonderful as they are,
would--would you trust
your grandchild with them?
I'd have to take care
of their baby and them.
Well, uh, if you'd like for me
to arrange a termination--
uh...
And tell them what,
that I'm scared their baby
will be just like them,
or that even if it isn't,
everything they've spent
their whole life hearing--
that they're special,
they can do anything
they put their minds to,
it isn't true?
I'm--I'm gonna learn
how to change a diaper.
His mom's gonna show him.
I-I can do hard things.
I got here all by myself
on a bus.
My--my mom wrote it down,
and--and I did it.
That's great, Ricky.
But you know
if you're gonna be a father,
you need to do more than just
change diapers, right?
We can write everything down.
Guys, I want to explain
something to you.
The baby that you made,
you do not
get to have it for sure.
Wh-wh-why--why--why--why don't
you want us to have a baby?
She didn't say she didn't
want you to have a baby.
You think we're dumb,
but--but we can have a baby.
It's not that simple.
You're not being nice.
None of you are being nice.
You'll let us have the baby,
right, mom?
♪ How it used to be,
sway ♪
♪ sway ♪
♪ ain't no rhyme or reason
going to tell us ♪
♪ why the good goes away ♪
I see you're wearing
the ring.
Apparently, it's a step--
post-sex, pre-wedding.
What?
You wanted to come here.
Might as well be truthful
with the lady.
Are steps important to you?
♪ And you ♪
We keep going back.
What?
Well, like, one step forward,
two steps back.
Every time
we get to a good place,
something tears us apart.
I'm sorry I was raped.
Charlotte, that's not
what I meant.
So you think the ring can
cement your relationship?
Well, when you put it
that way, it sounds, uh...
Ridiculous?
Cooper,
we've been through...
We hated each other.
Then you pushed,
the sex was life-altering,
and it started to work.
♪ ...time ♪
But I slept with Archer,
I didn't tell you
I was married before,
I was raped.
♪♪♪
And after all that,
here we are.
Cooper, we are forward.
There is no more back,
no roadblocks, no hiccups.
I have no secrets.
You have no secrets.
♪ Sway ♪
♪ sway ♪
Cooper?
♪ It's dizzyin' the feelin' ♪
What don't I know?
♪ All good things change ♪
This is the place
to talk about it.
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ ooh ♪
I...
I kissed Amelia.
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
When?
After you were raped.
♪♪♪
You will be happy to know
you're not alone.
Everybody hates my book.
Look, we're all proud of you
for writing it,
we just don't want
to be in it.
Everything I wrote is true.
And if you took all of us out,
everything that's left
would still be true,
and we could go back
to being proud of you.
But it's a better book now,
Pete. You have to see that.
And--and this is what
the publisher was looking for.
It'll sell,
and--and I want that.
N--
not because I am selfish,
but because I think this book
will really help people.
It'll help people.
What if it alienates the people
you love in the process?
I don't want to have to choose
between the two.
Well, that's where we are.
You know how everybody feels,
Violet.
What you do with that
is your call.
I screwed up.
I am so...
So, so, sorry.
Unbelievably sorry.
How can I
make this better?
You won't even look at me?
You know, in the past,
I have forgiven you
because I could see beyond
what you've done
in a moment of crazy
to who you really were,
who you are.
Don't I get
the same courtesy?
Oh, my god.
Charlotte, look at me.
Come--glare, scowl, yell.
Punch me.
Come on.
You have to fight back.
Mm.
Cooper,
you told me something.
Now I get to process.
Let me.
Hey.
Either Andi's Meryl Streep
or this thing is real.
So it's true
multiple personality disorder?
I started art therapy with her
during our last session.
When--when she shifted
from Andi to Maggie--
Maggie? I thought
it was Gina.
No, Gina's the older,
angry one.
Maggie is the emotional,
little one.
It was her this time.
Anyway, when they switched,
Maggie continued to draw,
right?
But this time
with her left hand. Look.
This is Andi on the right,
and Maggie on the left.
Her different personalities
draw with different hands
with the same ease.
You know, only 3%
of the population
is ambidextrous.
So you've made
your diagnosis.
Well, yes, and...
No.
I-I'm not--
something's not right.
I know this disorder
presents strangely, but--
well, does it really matter?
I mean, whatever the reason,
this woman
is profoundly disturbed.
And whatever
you want to call it,
you have to keep
treating her.
Well, if Andi is faking it
to stop Lara
from moving on with her life,
I-I need to know that.
Well, just... be careful.
If--if you push too hard,
she could collapse emotionally,
and then...
Then everybody loses.
I didn't mean to make this
harder on Erin.
I know.
But I did.
Yeah. Yeah.
God, I just, you know, I just
keep thinking about Olivia,
and if we had encouraged Maya
to terminate.
Well, you did.
I know I did.
But she didn't.
And I'm so grateful.
Of course, but... it's
different with Erin.
You know, she's alone
raising Tanya,
and with another baby,
down's or no down's,
it's--it's a lot.
Oh, Sam.
What are we gonna do
if Maya gets in to Columbia?
Ugh. I've been thinking
about that, too.
Oh, it's... it's not easy
to be a student and a mom.
Well, we'll figure it out.
We always do.
Yeah, well...
It's--it's not the same...
You and me.
What do you mean?
Well, I mean, it's just--
it's not just you and me
anymore, you know?
Wait. Ad-Addison isn't--
she--
Addison is my best friend.
And, uh...
Well, the fact
that you chose her...
I-I could pretend
that it doesn't hurt,
and I think I do
a pretty good job--
not all the time,
but given the circumstances.
It...
Still hurts, Sam.
And as much
as we have a history
and Maya and, uh...
I love you.
I just...
I don't trust you.
Well, not like
I used to.
Uh, uh, but I can try.
And I-I will try.
I mean, I am.
I'm trying. I'm trying.
It's just...
It's--
it's just not the same.
Okay, look, uh, I know you've
all read the manuscript.
And, um, I know that
in this latest revision,
some of you feel--
mischaracterized?
Betrayed?
Blinded by
near-murderous rage?
Um...
No, I was gonna say
that some of you feel like
I took some cheap shots.
Okay, so here's
what we're gonna do--
everybody in this room,
right now,
say the ugliest thing
you've ever thought about me.
The thing you never thought
you'd say? Say it.
Violet, do you really think
that's a good idea?
Absolutely. Let her rip.
Whatever you--
you're condescending.
Sorry.
I just really wanted
to be first,
because if you tell me
to filter again,
I am gonna bludgeon you to death
with a reflex hammer.
Okay. Okay. Good.
Looks like we've started.
You're cheap.
Never once have I seen you
reach for the check.
Well, I-I prefer "frugal,"
but--
you can't dance.
I know you think you can,
but you can't.
Well,
that's not terrible--
and you still play air guitar.
That is terrible.
Yes.
Yep.
So anything? You?
Man-child.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
Truly.
I-I probably should've
gotten your permission
before I started all this,
but I'm new at this,
and, uh, and it's hard.
And I-I tried to, uh, sketch
a full picture of each of you.
And I tried to be harder
on myself than anyone else.
But if there is anybody
in this room
who is honestly saying that
they can't get past this,
if what I wrote
is gonna cost my relationship
with even one of you,
then I'll tell the publisher
I can't do it.
So you decide.
Andi, you can see
that your sister and Jack
are worried about you.
But you don't think
they need to be.
I'm fine.
See?
We don't need to stay.
She's not fine.
You told me your sister
still baby's you.
Andi, you said that?
I told him
it was out of love.
She plays both sides
of the fence.
She tells everybody she's fine,
and then when she's with us,
she freaks out.
Why would I do that?
To keep your sister here.
Is that true?
She has always resented the time
Lara spends with me.
Jack, please.
No, no. Just let him talk.
Please.
We are building
a life together.
That could include
your sister,
but she doesn't want to share
you with me. She never has.
I've put up with it because I
love you, but it's enough.
Jack, leave her alone!
Open your eyes!
Don't yell at my sister!
Gina...
Please calm down.
Okay, enough
with the craziness--
I hate you.
I've always hated you.
That's not true, Andi.
My name is Gina.
No, it's not.
It was Maggie, not Gina,
who told me she hated Jack.
You got them reversed.
Andi...
After everything
we've been through,
why would you lie?
Because...
I love Jack.
And you're going to take him
away from me.
Hey. I got the results of
Tanya George's c.V.S. Test,
but I can't get Erin
on the phone.
Oh, well, i'm--I'm sure
she'll call you back.
Yeah, I know, but I-I feel
like I want to tell her now.
Will you drive with me
to her house?
Okay.
♪ Following steps
like water in lines ♪
Did you kiss him back?
♪ I can walk
through the streets ♪
Did you kiss Cooper back?
♪ I imagine the life ♪
♪ that I'm starting to lead ♪
It doesn't matter.
I beg to differ.
♪ ...to believe ♪
I'm still mad at you. I want to
make that clear right up front,
but I need to talk,
so time-out, okay?
You can't talk to Charlotte?
Charlotte's not talking
to me...
Because I... kissed Amelia.
You what?
And I told her about it.
I was a blow-up doll,
Charlotte.
Don't try to downplay
what happened.
I-I don't have to.
Nothing happened.
He was a scared, lost man
who felt powerless
and alone.
Look, I could've been anyone.
But it didn't matter
because I wasn't you.
That's a load of crap.
I'm a lot of things.
Dishonest
is not one of them.
Cooper was hurting
because he tried to take in
all of your pain
and because he was consumed
by his own.
Charlotte,
he is a good man...
Who almost made a mistake,
which is where you are
right now
if you turn a cry for help
into something that it wasn't.
We're in therapy. What am I
supposed to do, lie?
Well, no, not lie,
but there are times
when full disclosure
is not the best idea.
Really?
Man-child.
♪♪♪
I don't like people. It's rare
that someone comes along
I can even tolerate.
But going to meetings
with you...
That's...
It's big.
I trusted you.
You still can.
But if that is hard,
trust this--
Cooper loves you.
♪ Wanna feel,
wanna learn ♪
Only you.
That is a gift.
♪ Which way should I turn? ♪
I'm sorry.
I did get your messages.
But we had
a hectic morning, and--
Tanya's baby
doesn't have down's
or any other
genetic abnormality.
We understand this might
only be one factor
in the decisions
that you have to make,
but we just thought
you, uh, should know.
I took Tanya for an abortion
this morning.
I told her it was
a different kind of checkup,
and she was sedated anyway,
so--
how could you do that?
Naomi.
What choice do I have?
They're not capable of raising
a baby, and I can't.
I can't do it again.
I don't know how I'll explain
what happened to her baby,
but it's done now.
Mom?
I don't want to rest anymore.
Are you here to check
my belly again?
♪ What came from the heart ♪
♪ can never be wrong ♪
Well, she won't look at me.
She won't talk to me.
I mean, we were great,
and now--
Cooper, you wanted to come here
so that you could
tell Charlotte about the kiss.
You were afraid
that if you told her outside
the safety of counseling,
that the damage
would be irreparable.
Well, I should've
just told her in the office
because now we're here,
we're 42 steps back,
and, uh...
No.
We're not.
I forgive you,
Cooper.
I understand
why you did it.
And I forgive you.
You are the first man...
The only man,
to know all of me
and to love me anyway.
I know the rape
wasn't my fault.
But the lying...
And the cheating...
It came from fear.
Fear that I'd lose you.
Fear that...
I didn't deserve
a man like you.
It's no excuse, but...
It's the truth.
You made one mistake
when you had
nowhere else to go...
And everyone
was so worried about me.
I forgive you.
I told you
we were good.
From the time I can remember,
it was just me and Lara.
It never felt
like anyone else...
Really understood.
It was just the two of us
against the world.
But then she found Jack,
and he understood.
He loved her so completely.
I guess...
I wanted that, too.
I wanted him.
And as--as long
as they were here...
I'm sorry
I wasted your time.
I shouldn't have lied.
Well, people lie.
But the important thing is,
you're here now.
And if you want,
we can start over.
I'd like that.
Yes.
I thought
you and Jack left.
What you did
was so incredibly screwed up,
and I am so mad at you.
But you're my sister,
and I still love you.
So we're gonna have to
figure this out,
because I want you
in my life.
Jack and I both do.
I want that, too.
Why don't you join us?
Hmm?
♪♪♪
So?
We took a vote.
And?
Everyone thinks
you should publish it.
♪ too much ♪
Really?
Really.
♪ Patiently wait ♪
I'm gonna publish a book.
You're gonna publish a book.
♪ Watching the time
roll by ♪
You want to fool around
with a soon-to-be-famous
best-selling author?
♪ On a train
that never leaves ♪
Very much.
♪ And you try to hop on
in San Francisco ♪
♪ when do we walk
in Memphis? ♪
♪ When do we ride
the train ♪
♪ all the way
across the state of Texas? ♪
What was that for?
You're a good man,
and you love me.
I do.
And I'm in this...
Forever.
I mean, you're right.
It's not about a ring.
It's not about a wedding.
It's just about us.
Maybe you were
a little right, too.
Spring barbecue?
What?
Next step--our wedding.
I'd like a barbecue
in the spring.
We'll make it kosher
for your parents.
♪ An old train whistle ♪
♪ cries for me ♪
♪ you're too late,
once again ♪
Uh, Olivia's stirring.
If you want
an illicit cuddle or two,
you'd probably just have to
walk by her room.
Oh, I sh--we should--
we should
just let her sleep.
That's true love,
passing up
baby therapy like that.
♪ All the way ♪
Was I so wrong
about Ricky and Tanya?
I mean, maybe they could've
helped raise that baby.
Maybe, but...
Erin had to be involved,
and...
Yeah.
She wasn't ready
to make that commitment.
♪ Passed down
from the last guy ♪
Hey, i'm--I'm trying
to tell you
that it's--
it's not your fault.
Well, it's not helping.
♪♪♪
Why, because you don't
trust me?
♪ Dead-end jobs ♪
♪ so we seek another dream ♪
Could you...
♪ The only dream I see ♪
I need--
I need a hug.
♪ That never comes ♪
Well, come here.
♪ Who you are ♪
♪ and you still try to hop on ♪
♪ in San Francisco ♪
♪ when do we walk
in Memphis? ♪
♪ When do we ride
the train ♪
Okay?
Okay.
♪ Across the state
of Texas ♪
♪ hop on ♪
♪ in San Francisco ♪
♪ when do we walk
in Memphis? ♪
♪ When do we ride the train ♪
♪ all the way ♪
♪ across the state of Texas? ♪
♪ Whoo! ♪