You said that you
wanted to leave the house.
On average,
the fastest your heart
should beat per minute
is 220 minus your age.
Yeah, but what about
your feelings for me?
Why is this guy
still in Seattle?
Well, he won't leave
without her, and she
wants to wait him out.
What do you want to do?
Well, I want to deck the guy,
but I'm not as patient
as she is.
Are those Molly's scans?
Gotta be on my game.
After flying solo,
there's nowhere to go but down.
I'm assisting on
your girlfriend's surgery.
You want me to slack off?
-Carry on.
-Yeah.
But, ideally,
vigorous exercise
is between 70 and 85%
of your maximum heart rate.
Did you pack Allison's blanket?
Your mom says
it's not in the bag.
- It's in the backpack.
- Oh.
What are you gonna do with
the whole house to yourself?
Well, with any luck, sleep.
I'm jealous.
The conference agenda
is jam-packed.
Well, you should
skip something,
you know, get a massage
or do something else
for yourself.
Exceeding your maximum
heart rate can result in
- dizziness, chest pain,
or even fainting.
-Okay. Okay.
-Yeah.
-You got that?
-Yeah. Here.
Okay.
You two have fun. You know,
what happens in Vegas
stays in Vegas.
-We're going to Oakland.
-That too.
Bye.
So listen to your body
and don't push your limits.
Hey, I didn't know
you were here.
I'm helping Dr. Webber
with one of my old patients.
Is it weird, you're kind of
like my boss now?
No. I invested in
her and Meredith's
Alzheimer's research.
I'm a silent partner.
That's it.
Are you going to Boston?
Because I'll take Griffith
on my service.
He's salty because
she's been helping me prep
for an experimental procedure
all week.
I needed our best intern
for the case.
-Griffith's
someone to watch, huh?
-Yeah.
-How's Adams doing?
-Well, he's with us today.
You tell me.
-Okay.
-If your schedule changes, I--
She's still mine.
Do you know how lucky you are
you don't have to worry about
vaginal tears?
And good morning to you too.
I just sewed
a third-degree tear
encroaching on the sphincter,
and that's after the mom
labored for 24 hours
with a nine-pound baby.
You know, men have
their share of...
Yeah, that sounds awful.
Oh, Wilson, hey.
While you were in L&D,
Mrs. Badgley started bleeding.
Okay, well, I will tell Kincade
she needs to move
her myomectomy to this morning.
Oh. Already on it.
I-I figured you three
wouldn't want to be
on your feet for a long surge.
Dr. Kincade already
approved it, so we're set.
Um, did Jo Wilson just let
a guy who calls surgery
a "surge" shark her?
-He saved my babies.
-Oh. Come on.
That's all I can think about
when I see his overachieving,
stupid prodigy face,
and if you tell anyone that,
I will punch you.
Hey, not for you.
Have you exported your cases
into the spreadsheet yet?
What spreadsheet?
Uh, our case logs
for our meeting with Bailey
at the end of the year. Sorry.
It's fine.
Well,
if it's any consolation,
I'll be able to help you
-with your case logs next year.
-Thanks.
-Uh, good morning.
-Good morning.
What... What's this?
It's a thank-you for saying
you would help me get
my first solo surgery.
- I promise
I won't let you down.
All right, lesson number one:
always under-promise
and over-deliver. Yeah?
Hey, Nora.
-Hi, I just got your text.
-Sorry for bugging you.
This is...
Liz. Hi, can we make this
quick? I have a high school
reunion to pull off.
I'll do my best. Follow me.
Um, how far along are you?
Uh, 19 weeks.
It's been an easy pregnancy
until a couple days ago.
I started to have indigestion,
shortness of breath,
some pressure
in my chest.
-Um, I have
an OB appointment next week.
-Okay.
She has preexisting
mitral valve prolapse,
so I kidnapped her here.
Yeah, I have to be
at this reunion tonight.
I'm the committee chair.
Liz runs a tight ship.
She got the boosters
to repaint the gym.
Finally. There's no way that
'70s paint wasn't full of lead.
I was a senior
when you were a freshman.
-Owen Hunt.
-Megan Hunt's brother.
Megan has a brother?
Okay, I'm gonna page cardio
and OB.
While we wait, I'm gonna run
some labs and an EKG.
-Sound good?
-I'm pregnant.
- Only snacks and baths
sound good.
Thank you,
and it's good to see you again.
Yeah.
Allan Lewis, 50,
developed PTLD after
his third kidney transplant,
had eight rounds of rituximab
to reduce the tumor burden
in his retroperitoneum.
Here to debulk
the residual tumor
before resuming chemo
and to alleviate
the bowel obstruction symptoms.
Not the kidney's fault.
Don't blame the kidney.
No one's blaming anyone.
That's right. PTLD is
a real complication
caused by...
A weakened immune system
that triggers
the Epstein-Barr virus.
Of course, Allan is
in the less than 1%
of all people who get this.
Now it feels like
you're blaming me.
Okay. Shelby is Allan's sister
and the donor of
his third kidney.
I wouldn't have asked
if I weren't such a hard match.
My other two organ donors
came through UNOS.
Which donor drove you to chemo?
Oh. The one
who "inherited" Mom's
1969 Mercedes convertible.
I took care of her
all those years.
Where were you?
Working in Singapore.
She came through for me
when I needed a kidney,
but there was a time
when Shelbs and I
weren't speaking.
-They don't need to know this.
-Look, okay, it's
my medical history.
Okay, let's get some new scans
and we'll go from there,
shall we?
-Mm-hmm.
-Bye.
Cass,
I didn't know you'd be here.
Oh. Teddy, hi.
-I will catch up
with you later?
-Sure.
Friend of yours?
We sometimes plan
to attend the same conferences,
balance the snoozefest panels
with extracurricular
activities.
Oh.
Is David here?
I believe he's covering
his chief's cases
while she's at a conference.
Right.
What about Owen?
-No. Nope. Just me.
-Oh.
Altman.
-Oh, okay.
Can you help me? Please.
-Oh, yeah. Yeah. What--
-Hi.
Griffith, present.
Molly Tran, 33, experiencing
grand mal seizures.
Currently refractory
to anti-epileptic medication.
Here for placement of DBS
to suppress seizure activity.
We'll make a small hole
in your skull to implant
the device in your brain,
then place the pulse generator
under your collarbone.
It's like a pacemaker
for your brain.
And what about getting
my memory back?
Let's take it
one step at a time.
Once we place the DBS,
I will put a grid on your brain
and then stimulate
each section one by one,
but we're only doing that
because I will already be
in that part of your brain.
It's never been proven
to retrieve memories
lost to retrograde amnesia.
Will the extra stimulation
induce seizures?
It's possible,
but my hope is that
the device will prevent that.
Are you sure you want to
do this? What did
your parents say about it?
Um, they were nervous until
I sent them Dr. Shepherd's bio.
Hmm.
I want my memories.
I just didn't realize so many
people would be watching.
It's a big case.
Excuse me.
All right, so you can see
the device will be implanted
in the crown.
It's one thing
to show up at my house,
but to come to hospital--
-Hey. Back off.
-She doesn't wanna talk to you.
Look, I don't
wanna talk to her.
I need to talk to you.
Molly hasn't told you
everything you need to know.
But when I did the test run
in the auditorium,
the slides looked like they
were in a fun house mirror.
Well, they must be formatted
to the wrong size.
-Right.
-That's what Ron,
that AV guy, says,
and apparently
the only way to fix it is
to redo the whole damn thing.
Well, how long
did the first one take?
No idea. I paid Tuck to do it.
Dr. Bailey is presenting
on her program
training OB-GYN residents
from states with abortion bans.
So important.
Now more than ever.
Well, how am I supposed to
inspire other hospitals
to start programs like ours
if they can't read my slides?
Well, Cass is actually amazing
at slideshows.
Sorry, I don't know
why I said "actually."
She's just... She's amazing.
-Uh, can you work fast?
-For this cause,
it would be my honor.
-Thank you. Thank you.
-Oh, thank you.
All right, are you ready?
Yes, aligning the MRI and
CT images to create a 3-D
representation of the brain.
-Which approach
would you suggest?
-Transfrontal.
Good thought. We are gonna go
with frontal temporal.
Uh.
-Target?
-Oh, that area of gliosis
on the MRI.
All right, divide it into
three separate targets,
so I have options.
What if we trigger a seizure
and have to put her in
a barb coma?
Isn't the whole procedure
a wash?
I don't let myself
think like that.
Yeah.
You really are
the one to watch, huh?
Just been lucky.
Get on amazing cases.
Don't do that.
You're a woman surgeon.
There are enough people out
there who want to dismiss you.
Don't be one of them.
Now, our patient will be awake.
So it is crucial
that you follow my lead,
keep your voice neutral.
As far as Molly is concerned,
everything is fine.
-No problem.
-Mmm.
Your labs are normal.
Same with your EKG and echo,
and your mitral valve
looks stable.
Great. See? Told you,
just regular old pregnancy.
So, can I get back
to reunion planning now?
While your symptoms are common,
they are new for you,
and we would like to run
a few more tests.
Okay, fine.
Um, where's my phone?
Do you have someone
we should call?
Uh, nope.
Just a second-in-command
who can't alphabetize name tags
to save his life.
Come on, Bobby.
M comes before O.
Liz is having this baby
on her own.
She's my personal hero.
It wasn't always
the plan,
but I've been on
at least one date with
every age-appropriate bachelor
in the greater Seattle area,
and some not so
age-appropriate.
But none of them were the one,
and I'm not getting
any younger,
so I'm going it alone.
Liz, how long have you had
that lump on your neck?
-What lump?
-May I?
Millin, can you grab
the ultrasound? Thank you.
She's about to go to the OR.
Make it quick.
You can't let her do
the experimental part
of surgery.
I respect her decision.
Because if she gets
her memories back, it absolves
you of what you did?
You don't know
what you're talking about.
When the accident happened,
she tried everything she could
to get her memories back.
Psychotherapy, hypnotherapy,
Vietnamese herbs.
Her parents said that she spent
everything she had,
and when none of it worked,
she spiraled.
Not eating, not sleeping.
They finally talked her into
getting help.
She never told me any of this.
Okay, and why would she?
You think she wants you
to know?
Look, I love her,
and I wanna be able
to live with myself
- if anything bad
happened to her.
Coming to Seattle,
the sudden breakup,
the experimental brain surgery
just to get
her memories back. It...
It just feels like
the on-ramp to another crash.
She picked me. Get over it.
Hey.
There's pens
and extra card stock in the bag
under the welcome table.
No, under the welcome table.
Call if you need anything.
-Great.
-Thanks.
- Oh, my God.
- Hey, you okay?
Just Bobby,
our class secretary who
doesn't know how to CC people,
is now the one in charge.
It's like a designated survivor
situation.
Well, if no one
took this seriously,
there would be no reunions
and no one would reconnect
with old friends,
- and I guess life
would just go on.
Reconnecting can be...
can be pretty great.
Mm-hmm.
Uh, so far so good with Liz,
by the way.
Should I have taken Liz
somewhere else?
Why?
Well, the last time I saw you,
you didn't want to be
a part of my care team.
And now we're sharing a bench.
Well, you know...
You brought in a friend
for medical care,
so this is... this is
an above-board
bench-sharing situation.
In that case,
can you sit a little longer?
It's just hitting me
that my friend might be sick.
Sure.
There's the two native kidneys,
the two nonfunctioning
transplanted kidneys.
That's the working one
right there.
Have you ever seen
a scan of five kidneys
inside of one patient before?
-Is that the mass?
-Yeah, that's it right there.
Is it kinking the vasculature
of the working kidney?
No, it's close,
but fortunately, no.
Yeah, we should debulk enough
that the chemo has a shot
at killing the remaining cells.
Should we remove
the native kidney?
I could help with
the retroperitoneal
lymph node dissection.
Mmm. It's not necessary.
We still have good access to
the paracaval lymph nodes
but good to know
you're thinking ahead.
Book us an OR.
That was pretty bold
to ask to do
a nephrectomy
and a lymph node dissection.
You never know
if you don't ask.
-Can you do
his pre-op paperwork?
-Nope, but good try.
Poor Liz. She worked so hard
on her reunion,
and now some bumbling wannabe
gets to be there
for the big moment.
-Probably just trying to help.
-Is he?
Is he? Or is he a man who is
threatened by a woman in power
and he's stealing it
in the name of generosity?
For the record, I'm a feminist.
This morning,
my co-resident stole my surgery
so that I didn't have to
"be on my feet."
-Did you punch him?
-No, he saved my babies.
Well, he didn't save my babies.
What's his name?
Scans are up.
Oh. That's not something
you see every day.
Is it cancer?
No. Your thyroid, larynx
and lymph nodes are all fine.
It appears you have
a rare condition called
achalasia with megaesophagus,
-which is aggravated by
your pregnancy.
-Which means?
You have a fair amount of
undigested food
sitting in your esophagus.
Um, how long has it been there?
It's hard to tell
without knowing how much
you eat in one sitting.
I had fish tacos yesterday.
Ugh, stupid Bobby gave me
a strawberry smoothie
for breakfast.
It's all right. Don't worry.
We're gonna run
a scope down there
-and clean it all out, okay?
-Yeah.
Oh.
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Yeah, bit nervous, but...
Your vitals are strong.
Hey, going to OR one.
You know, the next time
I see you, I-I could have
all my memories back.
You know,
the odds of this working
are almost impossible.
I just want to make sure
you'll be okay if it doesn't.
There must be other
experimental treatments, right?
If this one doesn't work,
I mean, we'll try another one.
Dave came to the hospital.
Oh. Uh.
Well, what did he say?
He just wanted to make sure
that you'll be okay.
I am.
I will be.
-You'll be here
when I get out, right?
-Of course.
Okay.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
Okay. Don't let Shepherd
push it in there.
We've seen her go overboard,
especially with
difficult cases.
You know I can't control that.
You're on top right now.
You have more influence
than you think.
I got you.
Oh, there you are.
I was starting to get
flashbacks to that party
where you ditched me
to make out with Scott Jonas.
- We just... We got some air.
- Tell me
that lump's benign.
-As benign as chicken pot pie.
-Oh, thank God. What is it?
Chicken pot pie.
Yeah, that was
yesterday's lunch.
My throat's full of food.
What? How?
The sphincter
connecting her stomach
and her esophagus won't relax,
so food's getting stuck.
Is this gonna be
for the rest of my pregnancy?
No, we can remove the food
with a scope
and then inject Botox
into the lower sphincter.
So it looks young
and wrinkle-free?
No, so it relaxes and food
can get into your stomach.
Okay, so this is
gonna take a while.
Will you please make sure that
someone steams the tablecloths?
-I'm on it.
-A nurse will
get you prepped, okay?
-Thank you.
-Okay. I gotta go
back to work. Okay.
Brush up on
your EGDs in the skills lab.
I thought we had
Mr. Oden's CABG today.
I am doing Mr. Oden's CABG.
You were gonna brush up on
your EGDs
so you can do
Liz's esophageal disimpaction.
I'll go practice.
Can you just cut and paste?
The graphics, yes,
but not the text. Will you
read me those bullet points?
Oh, sure. Um, okay.
"All trainees come from
the more than one-third
of US counties
that are maternity care deserts
with no OB providers,
hospitals, or birth centers."
That's bleak.
Didn't you win
a Catherine Fox Award
for your program?
I did. Felt like
an accomplishment then.
Now, feels like I'm trying
to bail water with a thimble.
I get it,
but programs like yours
are a beacon of hope.
Thank you.
Now let's just make sure
your presentation is
as great as you are.
Next bullet, please. Teddy.
Oh. Yeah. Oh, sorry.
Uh, "following Dobbs"...
DBS is in place.
How are you doing, Molly?
Pretty well,
considering my head's
basically in an Erector Set.
Are you feeling
more discomfort?
I don't feel a thing,
but I can hear tools clinking
and things buzzing.
- Are we almost there?
- Yes.
Griffith,
we are ready to connect
to the stimulation panel.
-And that should stop
the seizures?
-It should.
Wow. Wait,
that's incredible. Thank you.
And are you starting
with the memory part too now?
-In a minute.
-Dr. Shepherd,
I see epileptiform waves.
All right,
adjust the frequency.
- They're improving.
- Okay.
All right, Molly,
now it is time to place
the grid for memory retrieval.
I'd nod, but, um,
I can't move my head.
Grid, please.
Here we go.
It's not that bad.
You were just moaning
like a dead animal.
Let him check you out.
Urine output's low. Hang on.
Let me take a quick look
with the ultrasound.
Are you wearing perfume?
'Cause it smells like feet.
Remember when
I gave you a kidney
and you promised to be nicer?
This is how all of our fights
end now.
Do you have a sister?
-I have four.
-Oof. I thought one was a lot.
Kidney.
I learned early on that I'm
better off not fighting back.
Oh, look at you now.
You're a surgeon.
See what happens when you
learn how to go with the flow?
To adapt?
I'm the senior VP
of human resources
at a giant tech company.
- Kidney.
- It only works when I do it.
No. My kidney. It really hurts.
Damn it, we need to move.
-What's happening?
-Am I dying?
Allan's kidney's thrombosed.
A clot's cutting off
his blood supply.
If we don't get him to surgery
right now, he could lose it.
Tell Webber and Marsh
to meet me in the OR.
Okay, breathe.
I did it.
-You... You... You did it?
-Uh-huh.
Thank you.
Uh...
You were right. She's amazing.
She's also very hungry.
Would you hand me those chips?
- Uh, you can have
whatever you want.
-Thank you.
-Uh, I'll be right back.
-Okay.
-'Kay.
Well, you saved the day.
Well, this saved me from
having to go to my boss's panel
on change management.
Where is her thumb drive?
Do you wanna skip
the afternoon lectures?
Well, we clearly have seen
Bailey's presentation.
-I'm supposed to
meet up with Phil later.
-So meet up with me instead.
You said to let you know
when I have figured it out,
and I have figured it out.
You are all set.
Oh.
Um... Would you keep it
until we get there?
My luck today, I'd drop it down
the elevator shaft.
Y... You are coming, right?
Oh, I've been having
stress dreams all week about
showing up to an empty room.
- Yeah.
- Wouldn't miss it.
- Okay. Here.
- Mm-hmm.
Okay, the renal artery is tortuous.
IR never would've worked.
Agreed. Fogarty catheter.
Will the kidney be okay?
I don't know, but it's got
a shot thanks to you.
The embolectomy is complete.
- Heparin. Thank you.
- Now what?
-  -We wait for it to pink up,
then we go after the tumor.
- Okay.
- Nothing's happening.
It's still ischemic.
Yeah, the clot
caused too much damage.
The kidney's dead.
-Let's prep for a nephrectomy.
-Yeah.
But he has to be in remission
before he can go back on
the transplant list.
-That could take months.
-It's our only option
at this point.
He got lucky three times.
Maybe it'll happen again.
So that's it?
You just tell him good luck
and send him on his way.
Well, what if we give it
more time? Try papaverine?
You know that's not gonna work.
Adams, you want to
suture ligate this vessel?
You found the clot.
You want it or not?
0 silk.
Okay, nice and easy. Good.
Oh, Mr. Oden's in the ICU.
We did his CABG off-pump.
It's actually really exciting.
You should review
the surgical tape.
Wilson, quick update.
Ms. Badgley had a massive
uterine hemorrhage mid-surge--
You did a hysterectomy?
On my patient?
Technically, Kincade's patient.
But yep.
Good luck with your, um...
-Esophageal disimpaction.
-Mm-hmm.
I'm gonna tear him
limb from limb.
Millin,
you are flying through this.
At the rate you're going,
we'll be out of here
in 15 minutes.
My parents never sent me
to summer camp.
They just dropped me off
at the arcade every day,
and I played the claw machine
for six hours straight.
You know how to work those?
-Mm-hmm.
-What have you won?
Strawberries and fish tacos.
Stimulate S-5.
- Molly, remember,
if you see anything,
no matter how faint the image,
just let me know.
Nothing yet.
All right. Let's increase
the frequency to 180 hertz.
If it gets uncomfortable,
let me know and I can stop.
Okay. Let's bump it up
to 200 Hz.
Dr. Shepherd, she's starting
to get D waves again.
Sporadic episodes.
We still have time before
a potential seizure. W-5.
Decrease the amplitude
to two millivolts.
How you doing, Molly?
Still fine.
Just... just waiting.
The waves are increasing
in frequency and amplitude.
I'm keeping my eye on it. X-5.
- I'm stopping.
- Griffith,
you will press that button
if I tell you to.
-Y-5.
-She's going to seize.
-If we have to put her
in a coma, she--
-Dr. Griffith,
I need you to trust me
or get out of my OR.
I see something.
Can you tell me what you see?
I'm outside.
I'm walking near a lake.
I see... I see mountains.
It's, it's beautiful here.
Wait, wait, it's all gone.
Because I stopped stimulating.
That was absolutely amazing.
Is it time to close?
That's not why I stopped.
Hand me the control panel.
We need to verify
that the stimulation
is provoking the memory.
Her seizure activity
is becoming more unstable.
Restarting. See anything now?
I'm still at
the same place and...
there's someone else here.
-A man.
-Do you know who it is?
No, he's too far ahead,
but he's wearing a red jacket.
I think we're here together.
Wait, did you stop again?
I did.
All right.
How about now?
I'm still here. I'm-I'm taking
something out of my pocket.
It's, uh... it's a map.
It says, "The Beehive
Basin Trail." It's Big Sky.
All right,
we are going to reduce
the frequency back to 140 hertz
and one millivolt,
terminating the stimulation
and removing the grid.
Wait, no, no. Wait,
why are you stopping please?
We can't risk
more seizure activity,
but, Molly, you did great.
-Would you like me to close?
-I've got it.
The EGD went well.
We were able to clear your esophagus
and administer the Botox
to relax your sphincter.
And once we confirm
everything's going down okay,
you'll be good to eat
whatever you want.
Just need to take it easy
for a couple of days.
-I'll take it easy
after the reunion.
-No, wait, you need to rest.
Otherwise, you'll wind up
back here in a week.
Two years of hard work,
and Bobby's about to
undo it all in two hours?
Well, why doesn't Nora go?
Make sure he doesn't
mess things up.
-Okay, you need to fire him.
-We don't pay him.
Look, we can't just let Bobby
have what he wants
because he means well.
You need to go down there
and tell him that he is out.
Well, um, the good news is
we were able to debulk
a lot of the mass.
So there is bad news... again.
Yes, so we couldn't revive
your working kidney,
so we had to remove it.
Back to dialysis.
More hours of my life wasted.
Once you're in remission,
we can put you back on
the transplant list again.
I've already had three.
I'm a hard match.
I won't find another.
You never know.
Before my first transplant,
I made a bucket list
of all the things
I wanted to do before I died,
you know,
like climb the Great Wall
or drive on the Autobahn.
Oh, see the Rockettes.
I mean, I thought
I'd be lucky to do half.
I did all of 'em.
Organ donors gave me
a second chance on life,
and then a third and a fourth.
And I'm happy with
what I did with them.
So, if this is it...
this is it.
Or you could call Gary.
We're not calling Gary.
-Wait. Gary is...
-Our brother.
Well, I'll be damned.
I'd rather live
the rest of my life in a box.
By box do you mean coffin?
It'd be better than
calling Gary!
She loved Big Sky.
We went a couple of times.
I can't believe she actually
remembered something.
All the way down to
your red jacket.
I'll check on her in a bit.
-Hey. How are you feeling?
-Hmm.
Tired.
Hey. They said I had a memory.
I just wish my brain
could hold on to them
when it's not being stimulated.
Does, uh, Dave have
a red jacket?
He has a lot of jackets.
Did you ever go
to Big Sky with him?
A couple of times. Why?
Is that what I remembered?
But that was a memory
from after the accident.
You don't need to remember
anything for us to have
a future together.
You know, it's all in my brain.
It's all in there.
We just have to find
a way to unlock it.
Hey, maybe there's
a clinical trial.
No, you... No, no, no, no,
you don't let people dig into
your brain when you're healthy.
I'm worried about you.
The worst
has already happened.
- I lost my life.
- No, you didn't.
You're here.
You should rest.
We can talk about this later.
- Okay. All right. Thank you.
- Hey.
So Liz is being discharged.
She is. But she needs to rest,
so she's sending me
to go make sure this reunion
doesn't fall apart.
Mmm.
I wish Megan wasn't chaperoning
your nephew's camping trip.
Yeah. I can go with you
if you want. I'd love to see
the new paint in the gym.
Seriously? Teddy won't mind?
We've agreed to...
We've agreed
that we could see other people.
-Oh.
-Yeah.
Okay.
So I'll go home,
and I'll change
and come pick you up.
I'll text you my address.
-Okay.
-Yeah.
So, the program
is a 16-week rotation,
but we operate
on a rolling basis.
The trainees request
start dates,
based on where it fits
within their home curriculum.
So at any given time,
we have 20 to 30 trainees
from 13 different states,
but still that's
not nearly enough
to address patient demands
across the country.
You know,
somebody recently said
that programs like this
are a beacon of hope
in a dark time.
Well, I hope that
you will join me
in lighting the way. Thank you.
-Are you okay?
-Yeah. Yeah.
-Are you sure?
-Yeah, yeah, yeah. I'm good.
I'm good. Come here.
Wait. Wait. Um...
I'm sorry, it's just dumb.
It's not you.
It's just I, um...
I feel like
I'm cheating on my husband.
Is this what it felt like
when you first opened
your marriage?
Our marriage
was suffocating us.
Being with someone else...
...felt like
finally breathing fresh air.
You really are amazing.
So I'm told.
But this... this...
is not gonna fix my marriage.
-I'm so sorry.
-Me too.
It's okay.
I checked on Liz,
and a smoothie went down and is
in her stomach safe and sound.
You handled that disimpaction
like an experienced surgeon.
You didn't need a surgeon
for that.
Any teenager in an arcade
could've figured it out.
Maybe just take the compliment.
Where are you going?
To update Liz's chart.
Oh, you thought today
was just about learning
to disimpact an esophagus?
What else would it be about?
Your first
transesophageal echocardiogram.
-Really?
-Yeah, come on up.
-So you... You want me to...
-Find the heart.
It's just like the EGD, okay?
Insert the scope, flat side
facing the floor of the mouth.
Good, slowly feed it
down the esophagus.
Good, good.
Now adjust the angle.
There. I-I might be biased,
but every time I see that,
it feels like the first time.
It's incredible.
Her EEG looks stable.
Mm-hmm.
I'm sorry for challenging you.
Kwan was in your head.
Yes.
Your star may be on the rise,
but that is not the same as
having years of experience
with hundreds of patients.
Whatever you know about
the patient's family,
their loved ones,
you keep it out of my OR or you
do not step foot inside it.
It won't happen again.
Okay. Now get started on
a write-up for grand rounds.
You're gonna present this
at grand rounds.
We are. Congratulations.
Wilson, hey, about that surge.
No. Marcus,
I am grateful to you
for saving my pregnancy,
but that does not mean that
you get to walk all over me.
-I'm sorry?
-I'm not your patient.
I'm your colleague.
Sharking my surgeries
doesn't help me.
It undermines my authority
and limits my training.
-I was just trying to help.
-Don't flatter yourself.
-I can advocate for myself.
-I'm sorry.
And it's "surgery,"
not "surge."
This some sort of OB showdown?
The three of us decided
it was time for a little talk.
Well, he earned it.
Do you want to go for a burger?
As long as I don't have to
talk about vaginal tears.
- Okay.
- Good deal.
-I love those crackers.
-Yeah. You never
let me throw them away
when we got soup
from our neighborhood deli.
What kind of soup?
You liked
their Manhattan clam chowder.
-I called your parents.
-What?
-Why?
-I was worried.
And then I found out that they
had no idea about your surgery
-or that we're back together.
-Well, I didn't want them
to freak out.
Okay, but you lied to me
about it.
I think you know
you're on a slippery slope.
This isn't like last time.
Yeah, which you also
didn't tell me about.
I found out from Dave.
Okay, look,
I am so close to remembering.
No one with retrograde amnesia
has ever gotten
their memories back.
What makes you think
you're different?
I don't know. But that day
that I saw you in the ER,
I mean, that was the first time
I felt like
a piece of my old life
was trying to resurface.
I do. I wanna remember
my grandparents
and-and family vacations
and my college graduation.
I don't feel whole.
I want to.
I need to.
Because I don't know
what will happen if I don't.
Are you only with me
because you think it might help
get your memory back?
I, um...
I don't know.
-Hey, um...
-Yeah.
...so I reviewed
Allan's post-op labs.
-Everything looks good.
-Great, thank you.
And great catch with
the thrombosis. He could have
gone septic and died.
Yeah, I don't understand why
he won't just call his brother.
He'd have a kidney tomorrow.
Yeah, sometimes people are
their own biggest obstacles.
Hey, uh, do you think
I need to repeat intern year?
You said that all internships
should be longer,
but they're not.
The rest of my class
is already moving on.
If I have to remediate,
that'll go on my record.
Competitive specialties
and fellowships
will be off the table.
My surgical skills
are as good as my classmates,
but my career
is going to suffer
because I tried
to save a patient
who was going to die anyway.
You're right,
but that's up to Catherine Fox.
Do you think
I can change her mind?
I'm not sure,
but I know someone who might.
So, if you have
any suggestions
on how I could approach her
or what to say,
I'd really appreciate it.
You want advice
on how to persuade my wife?
Yes, sir.
Couple of years ago,
I surprised her
with a trip to the Maldives.
Booked one of those bungalows
that's over the water,
a five-star restaurant,
sunset yacht cruises.
It sounds really nice.
Oh, it was paradise.
You know what she said
the best part was?
Yeah, I don't--
It was a little coffee pot
in our room
that was stocked with
Seattle roaster coffee.
Said she never found
anything better.
You understand what I'm saying?
You could've saved
a lot of money and gone to
the caf next door?
No.
I'm saying that once she makes up her mind about something,
she needs a really good reason
for her to change it.
And you don't have it.
Sorry.
When you want
something badly,
it's hard to know if or when
to throw in the towel.
A glass of the house white,
and his next drink is on me.
I'm presenting at grand rounds!
It's over. Me and Molly.
I'm so sorry. Was it Dave?
Hey. It took me longer
to get out of there
than I thought it would.
-Did someone die?
-Blue and Molly broke up.
Oh, sorry.
Did she go back to Dave?
I just did my first
transesophageal echocardiogram.
Read the room, Millin.
Blue and Molly broke up.
Don't ask about Dave.
-Who's Dave?
-Can you not talk about me
in front of me?
Nobody wants to talk about you.
Could I just get a rum and coke
and whatever he wants?
Hey, hey, what about me?
I'll buy you a drink
when you and Griffith break up.
So, never.
-Hey, can I get...
-Shh, shh, shh.
So we push the limits.
Hoping if we put in a little
more time, more effort,
maybe it'll all work out.
You're not
a margherita flatbread
with a side salad.
Um, Ben, Teddy's here.
Yeah, I'll call you later.
Uh, did you want, uh,
mini red, mini white?
The mini bourbon's mine.
Uh, mini gin and tonic.
Ah, only if you, uh, want it
served in a giant glass.
Okay.
Uh, congratulations on
your presentation.
Thanks.
Uh, I didn't see you
and Beckman after.
Oh. Yeah, we, uh...
we left and ended up--
You know, I don't need to know.
I work with both your husbands.
We ended up going to
the environmental health panel.
That's not what I expected.
Honestly...
me neither.
-Cheers.
-Ah.
Take it right out of the...
Okay. Get you some pretzels.
Uh...
Or you could
crash and burn.
Taking everything you love
down with you.
But you won't know
until you try.