- Do we have any pretzels?
- Sorry, I...
- What about the salt at the bottom?
- No, I...
- It's one of my mixtapes.
- Oh, well, I would like to hear it.
Naughty thought.
How about we don't wait
for our next kiss?
We would never see
the end of the movie.
Mm.
It's better if we stick
to the schedule.
Sure.
Didn't hear you come in last night.
So I'm guessing it
went well at Carly's.
The end of the movie
was very predictable.
Not the question I was asking,
but you still managed to answer it.
- Carly touches me when we kiss.
- You don't like her touching you?
- Oh, I do.
- Oh...
But I prefer to touch only one thing
at a time.
Have you told her you prefer
to touch only one thing at a time?
In those exact words?
- Okay. Whatever it is, I'm in.
- My first lead surgery!
- Oh! Shaun! That is awesome!
- I am going to rock it!
Oh, hell... yeah, you are! Yes! Yeah!
Oh.
- How you doing?
- I'm good.
Thank you for helping me
with the sea lions.
I'll never say no to a caper.
But I'd like to keep my mother's death
between the two of us.
I just... I can't deal
with people's platitudes.
Okay, but that suggests you're not good.
This is textbook denial, it's only
going to inhibit your grief process.
Denial is the first step,
so I'd say I'm right on track.
But thank you for your platitudes.
This is Curtis. He decided to fix
his chimney without a safety harness.
Open bilateral tib-fib fractures.
They wanted $1200 for a two-hour job
and I can still do a hurricane grind.
It's a skateboard move that
builds off a 180 ollie.
I got great balance.
Pupils are slow to react.
Unfortunately, balance is less great
after a few cocktails.
Not me.
Clean and sober six years,
three months and 24 days.
Get him on IV antibiotics
and to OR level one. And run a BAC.
I'm Dr. Shaun Murphy, your surgeon.
Esophagealcancer
is a serious condition.
However, you don't have any remote
or metastatic disease,
and responded well to chemoradiation,
so a resection of the esophagus
should render you cancer-free.
You look awfully young.
I always say, the younger they are,
the smarter they must be.
Oh, yes.
We will pull the stomach up
and attach it to the remains
of your esophagus,
keeping your GI system connected,
so you will not need
a permanent feeding tube.
My oncologist told me all this...
but I refused to believe it,
that it was all gonna be okay,
until I heard it from my surgeon.
I'm sorry, it's just...
I've been through a divorce
and a career change
and I finally bought my own cafe,
three days before I got my diagnosis.
And I thought it was a sign
I was making a mistake...
but it was just the opposite.
I wasn't done.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I have to inform you of the risks
of this procedure.
There is a seven percent chance
of heart and lung problems,
a 12 percent chance of infection,
a point-five percent chance of death,
among others.
Bring it, Dr. Murphy.
Shaun got very lucky.
Landed the world's most genial patient
for his first case.
- Nice.
- Of you.
You picked that patient for him.
I heard it was Park's chart
before you stepped in.
Shaun's weakness is
patient management.
You shouldn't coddle.
We challenge him too much,
we lose him.
Murphy?
He perseveres.
He's annoyingly resilient.
I agree that some failures
don't seem to faze him at all.
But it's his lifelong dream.
So, yes, I think we could lose him.
I'll tough-love his ass next week.
- Okay, Curtis, we're good to go.
- Curtis, are you okay?
- Should've gone with the contractor.
- His thinking was impaired,
he had a blood-alcohol level
of point zero nine.
Your test must be wrong.
You were quite inebriated
when you came in.
That's impossible.
Curtis doesn't drink.
- We'll make a note of it.
- We've gotta get him to the OR.
You play softball?
Uh, my junior year in high school,
I had an ERA of 2.95.
My wife's got an arm.
I can't believe you're my wife.
Till death do us part.
- Oh, you found Wally.
- You have a name for it?
Yeah, he's my Walther PPK 32.
He and I go way back.
Is it loaded?
I mean, is this a problem?
Because I just... I keep it
in my bedside table, in my gun safe.
- Combination 7-3-5-9.
- I'm not gonna remember that.
I don't wanna remember that.
If we're gonna live together,
we're gonna need to make some...
compromises.
You nervous?
How badly are you freaking out?
I'm not badly freaking out.
I've assisted
in six esophageal resections,
all of which were
free of complications.
So you're overdue for a blow-up.
Sorry, I'm just a bit annoyed
because I had
my hand on this case first,
and now I'm third
out of four at best.
But I'm happy for you.
Really.
I'm happy for me too.
She has extensive scar tissue.
And it's plastered her stomach
to her anterior abdominal wall.
I told her she wouldn't need
a permanent feeding tube...
but she will.
We've gotta tell a chef
she'll never eat again.
- How will she react?
- Don't know.
- Badly. But the specifics she...
- You should tell her.
- She's your patient, it's your job.
- I'm bad at patient communication.
If I make her very unhappy,
she may not want me to do the surgery.
If you're not willing to take that risk,
then hand the case to Park.
No. I don't want to hand the case
over to Dr. Park.
Park will tell Beth.
And, Shaun, it's still your surgery.
Drill.
Do you see his heart rhythm?
Rate controlled A-fib.
Wasn't on his record.
Ask his wife about it post-op.
Probably a symptom
of binge drinking, which he'll lie about
and she'll tell us she believes.
She's in denial?
You had surgery as a child.
As a baby. I don't even remember it.
There's considerable scar tissue,
more than we'd
typically expect to find,
which has affected our surgical plan.
- How?
- Dr. Murphy will field that question.
- No, Dr. Lim said...
- Proceed, Dr. Murphy.
Somebody please tell me.
We can't move your stomach up,
so you will need a feeding tube.
For the rest of your life.
The good news is that this surgery
is simpler,
so your recovery time will be shorter
by three to five days.
Hey.
Do any of you own a gun?
Is there someone you'd like
taken care of?
Ha.
- I still have my service pistol.
- I have a SIG P365.
Do any of you have
or have you ever had issues about it
with your significant others?
After our son was born,
my wife suddenly hated
having a firearm in the house.
Then one night,
I came home late to...
a PowerPoint presentation.
Ninety minutes of horrifying statistics.
Now it's in a locker at my gun range.
Lot of setup, but I like that.
I had a boyfriend who felt very weird
about me having a gun.
He wasn't big on logic,
so I took the emotional approach.
It's not for the firepower,
but the confidence it gives me
as a woman when I carry it.
I lived with a guy who had a gun.
Had to use the nuclear option.
It goes or he goes.
It worked, they both went.
Well, that's just wonderful.
I heard your news.
It's pretty exciting.
I jumped seven times.
- How's the anxiety level?
- Why do people keep asking me that?
- Everyone has doubts, Shaun.
- I'm excited.
You can be excited and nervous.
Usually they go together.
Speaking of, uh, I'm sorry if I was a bit
too assertive last night.
Lea said it must be tricky for you.
So now Lea is also privy to the intimacies
of our intimacy? Great.
Yes.
Oh, Lea said to tell you
that I prefer to touch
only one thing at a time.
Located upper esophageal sphincter.
You have a good tumor margin
resecting above or below?
- Below.
- Mm-hm.
Shaun gave the news
to his patient after all.
Shaun did what I expected.
He upset her, but the news is upsetting,
- she'll deal with it, he'll learn...
- She wants him off.
- Shaun.
- No.
- Shaun, I will find you another case.
- This...
is my case.
I prepared for this case.
I don't want another case.
Dr. Murphy.
You're learning, Shaun.
That's what you do
at a teaching hospital. I'm learning too.
Going from attending
to chief of surgery is a big deal.
Every day, every decision, every mistake,
I learn something.
So do you.
No, I don't.
I have a developmental disorder.
Come with me.
- I'm waiting for my bus.
- Well, take a later one.
I'm sure I mentioned I was chief.
Hi, Beth.
I'm sorry for what
you're going through,
and Dr. Murphy's phrasing
was unfortunate.
But there's been no deceit or negligence.
He's an excellent surgeon
who has my full confidence in the OR.
If you don't trust him,
you don't trust me.
So I would recommend
you have your surgery
at a different hospital.
I can make arrangements.
However, if you reconsider,
we can proceed as scheduled
first thing tomorrow morning.
If you don't want people to know
your mother died,
stop acting like someone
whose mother died.
I'm gonna move on
to the second stage of grief: anger.
- I'm not acting depressed.
- No, you're acting bitchy.
But you're not,
so that looks weird on you,
and people are gonna
know something's up.
So do you want me happier or sadder?
Let me know, because I'm really
looking for your approval.
Bitchy.
You really think this guy's
still on the wagon?
Just because he's a drunk
doesn't mean he's not sick.
But all you can see is an addict
married to an enabler,
so all roads lead to rum.
Come on, that was cute.
No LV wall motion abnormalities.
No valvular disease or dysfunction.
Ruling out any structural cause
for the arrhythmia.
You win. Congratulations.
- Hey.
- How was your day?
- Good, good.
Pensive. I was thinking about
your gun and why you need it.
- Oh, Aaron, I don't...
- No, no, no. I was an idiot and a guy.
I get it. You walking alone
in a garage late at night,
you walking alone on the street
late at night.
Or getting into my own car,
or even my own house.
Exactly. That's why
I got you a surprise.
- Yeah?
- Right outside the backdoor.
You have exactly 10 seconds
to punch in the code
before Seal Team Six arrives.
Seven-three-five-nine.
Every door, window,
every vent over 36 inches.
This is your security fob.
It works in all 48 contiguous states
and Canada.
You have no idea how much
extra comfort this is gonna give me.
Actually, I was hoping it would be
your primary source of comfort.
You were thinking that...
- this would mean I'd give up my gun?
- That's exactly what I was thinking.
The first rule of security systems
is redundancy.
By that logic, we should get a tank
for the garage.
It shouldn't matter why I want a gun.
Whether it's because
it makes me feel more secure,
or it was a memento of my dad's,
or just because it's fun to shoot.
All that matters is I'm a grown-up
and I'm responsible.
And I want it.
You're ruining Shaun.
Maybe you got him over the hump
of patient management,
but what about surgical management?
Taking charge of the OR,
keeping lines of communication open,
everyone cooperating.
You're throwing him into the deep end
and that's unfair,
unless you plan to scrub in
as a lifeguard.
He'll be fine.
You handpicked his surgical team?
You're ruining him.
The tests prove his arrhythmia
is associated
with excessive ethanol consumption.
But there's no permanent damage
and his rhythm will return
in the absence of
any further drinking.
We met when we were 15.
I was first clarinet, he was second.
We were at a band festival in Anaheim
when he found out his parents died
in a plane crash.
We grieved together and fell in love.
Then he started drinking.
It wasn't until I threatened to leave
that he woke up.
The day he received
his two-year recovery chip
was the day we got married.
The day he vowed to me in a church
full of our family and friends
that he would never drink again.
Our marriage is
built on his sobriety.
I believe him.
Teal...
we ran the BAC three times...
and the results were consistent.
I believe in my husband.
I have to.
His BP is dropping.
- Temp is normal.
- Check for causes of shock?
Upper GI bleed. Need stat
hematocrits and transfuse blood.
Surgery's the easy-peasy part.
You wanted this... enjoy it.
I can't.
If I get distracted,
if I get upset...
If you do, Andrews has your back.
If Dr. Andrews has to take over,
then I have failed.
I have failed and I have
endangered a patient's life,
and if I'm no good at the easy-peasy part,
then what part am I good at?
What do we do when we get all nutty?
Blow out the candles.
How many do you need?
Three.
Hey, I was looking for you.
Big day, huh?
- How are your nerves holding up?
- I'm not nervous.
Of course you're nervous.
Everybody's nervous.
It just means that you care.
Being nervous means
I feel inadequate and unprepared,
and if I am either of those things
it doesn't matter whether I care or not.
You are more than adequate
and you're very prepared.
You remind me of a young surgeon
I knew once.
The day he got his first lead,
he was thrilled,
but he was a mess trying
to remember a million things,
imagining a million things
that could go wrong.
But then he remembered
the birth process.
How moms are asked
to pick a focal point,
let everything filter through that.
So he chose
the color orange to focus on.
This is the cap that he focused on,
and he got through it
with flying colors.
Maybe it'll help.
Why do you have the
young surgeon's cap?
I was being coy.
The young surgeon was me.
That's Japanese for "hello."
Konnichiwa. I have surgery
in 42 minutes.
Which is why I'm here,
to wish you luck.
I don't need luck.
Everyone needs luck.
That was a good-luck kiss.
How can a kiss give you...
So was that.
I am feeling a bit lucky.
You know the thing
that Lea told you to tell me?
- Yes.
- That was actually great advice.
It's important we tell each other
exactly what we like and what we don't.
I also don't like pickles, sirens,
anything woolen...
I was thinking more
in the romantic area.
And right now, we are not
going to touch lips anymore...
because there's something else
I want you to touch.
Oh.
So, what do you think?
You don't have any lumps.
Win-win.
Lab and imaging tests rule out
Crohn's, gastroenteritis,
C-diff colitis and even H pylori.
Leaving bleeding ulcers
caused by alcohol abuse.
He needs to be on a proton pump
inhibitor and octreotide
to prevent further blood loss.
No.
He loves you,
that's why he hasn't been honest.
It doesn't make it right,
but it's that same love that
kept you together through everything.
And it'll get you through this too.
He's telling the truth.
We'll run more tests.
Your faith in your
husband is impressive,
but it may have just killed him.
Ten blade, please.
Located lower end
of esophageal lesion.
Linear cutting stapler.
Resecting the esophagus
from the stomach.
I'm now at the upper
end of the lesion.
Hemoclips?
- Dr. Murphy?
- No.
- What's the matter?
No. No. No.
- Shaun, what are you seeing?
- Can't do this.
- What? What can't you do?
- No!
- Don't! No.
- No, no, no.
- Dr. Murphy!
- No!
Page Dr. Lim. Keep her stable.
No. No, no. You're...
No, no.
- No. You're...
- What happened?
- No, no, no...
- He lost it, walked out mid-procedure.
- Yuri... Y... Yuri...
- Shaun?
Sayo... Yuri...
- Okay, Park, take over the surgery.
- No!
Dr. Park.
- No.
- Well, he obviously can't.
I don't think he lost it.
He was in complete charge.
- I don't think this is a meltdown.
- He said he can't do it.
He said, "Can't do it."
Maybe we can't do it.
- I think he's seeing something.
- We have a patient open on the table.
Shaun, you have to tell us
what you're seeing.
It's okay, Shaun.
Breathe.
That's it. Now, slowly...
what are you thinking?
When...
Okay. When I examined
the upper portion...
When I examined the upper portion,
there was a much larger area
of tumor-free esophagus
than anticipated.
That's correct, but not nearly enough
to reach the stomach.
But there is enough to accept
a jejunum free flap...
using a portion of the small intestine
to replace the resected esophagus.
- We don't do jejunum free flaps.
- They do in Japan.
They do in Japan.
I've been studying their technique.
"Yuri kucho saiken."
They have had great success.
It would mean
Beth wouldn't need a feeding tube.
But...
it is very complex.
It's too complex for you to lead,
so you'll lose your case.
Yes.
I haven't done a transposition graft
like that before.
Think you can walk us through it?
Yes.
I'll scrub in.
Stomach...
is perfect.
Check the duodenum.
The only way
Teal will accept the treatment
is if we give her no room for denial.
Did you really believe what you said?
That their love is enough to get them
through this?
Such BS,
the belief that love is enough.
Even worse, it's corollary
that a lack of love is the real problem.
If they had someone in their life
who had enough faith in them,
had enough love for them,
they could've pulled through.
It's wrong and it's mean.
What's that?
Flush the area.
- There's our bleed.
- But it's not coming from an ulcer...
- It's coming from a tumor.
- It's obstructing his digestive tract.
I'm paging Melendez to the OR.
Okay.
Actually, I'm gonna need
an extra shot.
Rough day?
I had to help out in the ER
with an 8-year-old boy who
was accidentally shot by his sister.
He'll survive, but with brain damage.
That's horrible.
Yes, it is.
And quite...
- coincidental.
- Like so many other coincidences.
You know how many kids are shot every
day in this country? Nineteen.
You know you're three times
more likely to be shot
if you have access to guns
than if you don't?
Here's another fact.
One in four women
are victims of violence
at the hands of
their intimate partner.
No, no, no. I'm not afraid of you.
This isn't about you.
Did something happen?
Because if it did,
I wanna know about it.
You figure something horrible
must have happened
to drive me to such an irrational,
fear-driven choice?
I'm sorry, hi.
The ends of the harvested
jejunum have been matched
for caliber size
for the attachment sites.
You should begin proximal
attachment at the neck incision,
using layer-to-layer technique
on the esophagus
and microvascular anastomosis
of the vessels.
You wanted to know
when Dr. Semler
was heading to OR number three.
Dr. Park, scrub out and join Semler.
If it's all right, I'd rather stay here.
You're needed where you're needed.
Tumor is free.
Bag it, tag it and get it to Path.
Do you smell that?
Smells like a distillery.
But we knew he couldn't have
touched a drop for at least 24 hours.
The final stitch is yours.
It's completely symbolic,
but symbols can be powerful.
Easy-peasy.
You had something called
auto-brewery syndrome.
The tumor we found
was blocking your intestinal track,
so carbs weren't being digested, they
were being trapped and fermented.
Your stomach was actually creating
its own alcohol.
You were drunk,
but not from drinking.
With the removal of the tumor,
which was benign, you're all good.
And the arrhythmia's gone too.
I never doubted you.
Her faith in you saved your life.
Thank you.
I was so pissed when
Lim kicked me out,
until I found Semler had an
appendectomy waiting for me.
Got my first lead after all.
I'm happy for you.
- Really.
- I'm happy for me too.
You earned it.
And you'll get your chance
again soon, Shaun.
So that's it? All's well that ends well?
Your surgeon walked out on his case.
That's your takeaway? That he failed?
- A chef can eat!
- Yeah.
As a diagnostician,
he did something wonderful.
But as a surgeon?
Yes, he failed.
We don't work alone, Marcus.
Every time we have a good outcome,
it's because everyone in the room
did something right.
Shaun came up with the idea.
Park got it out of him.
I approved the surgery, and you?
The only reason Shaun is working here
is because you believed in him.
Yay, team.
Are you still having a gun fight?
Oh, yeah.
Second day of my marriage
and we are at an impasse.
Tried the logical approach,
I tried the emotional approach.
No compromise.
Only thing left is the nuclear option,
which really sucks.
The thought of having a gun in my house
makes me sick.
Has Debbie let you touch her breast?
What?
Yeah.
Then you shouldn't worry
about anything else.
I was wrong...
this time.
But 99.9 percent of cases,
I would be right.
If someone acts like an addict,
lies like an addict, smells like an addict,
then they are an addict.
And just because we stumbled across
the one ridiculously fluky exception,
that isn't gonna change my attitude
moving forward.
I respect you, Claire.
Might even go as far as to say I like you.
And I know you're angry right now.
At your mother, the world...
yourself.
Eventually, that'll go away,
or at least some of it will.
But until then,
giving up on that 0.1 percent
means giving up on something else:
hope.
Hope...
killed my mother.
We need to talk,
about the 800-pound gun in the room.
I'm working on my compromise skills.
Okay.
Looks like
your first lead surgery went well.
I didn't have a first lead surgery.
Yes, it went very well.
Can I check your other breast?