Say you're in the OR,
repairing a vena cava,
when suddenly,
everything goes to hell...
I think we should practice
our statements to the judge.
I think you should stop
worrying about it and relax.
I could help you with that.
Derek, we have 36 hours
before we have to convince a
judge that we're Zola's parents.
We are Zola's parents.
But they don't know that.
And for all they know,
we hate children.
We feed cute little kittens to a
dog we keep in the backyard.
Meredith.
I'm just saying,
they don't know us.
All we have to do
is just stand up there
and speak from the heart.
That's all the
convincing they'll need.
Okay?
Okay.
So you cut this, suture that,
and soon that crappy
situation is a thing of the past.
I missed you this morning.
Is everything okay?
Yeah. I just wanted to
get a run in before work.
Oh.
Okay. I gotta get upstairs if I'm
gonna beat Shepherd to rounds,
so I'll see you later?
Too bad you can't meet all of life's
challenges with a surgical scalpel.
Yeah. All right.
I'll see you later.
I mean, you could try.
Going up? Nope.
Yeah, you are.
Avery. Today's the day.
You, me, cross-facial
nerve graft.
You pumped? I'm pumped.
All right. Get pumped.
Getting pumped.
But I'm pretty sure that'd
be considered assault.
Dr. Bailey, I've been
going over this islet cell data
and I think that... Dr. Bailey?
Are we not going to the
mouse lab today? Because I...
We've got bigger things to
worry about than mice, Grey.
Like, um, guinea pigs?
Are your feet as
quick as your wit?
Move 'em.
Ooh! Sorry, Karev. I'm gonna
need your esophageal atresia.
What...
Oh, and you have
a pyloric stenosis.
I might need that one, too.
What are you... Why?
'Cause we have a prospective
Peds fellow coming in today,
and she's being courted
by all the big guns,
USC, Johns Hopkins, CHOP,
and Hunt asked me to help to
make sure she got the red-carpet tour,
and that includes scrubbing
in on a couple of surgeries.
Wait.
You're already meeting
people for the fellowship?
It's a little early,
but when someone with
Polly Preston's resume
wants to observe in your
hospital, you make time.
Justine, these three
bubble-like spots.
Those are your aneurysms.
Just a second.
Sorry. I didn't hear
a word. Say again.
Ah! My aneurysms.
Horrible things.
What are they
doing now, growing?
Is that why the
god-awful headaches?
One has sprung a leak.
Great.
Go ahead. Say it.
Say I told you so.
He's been warning
me about this for years,
and I have been
avoiding this surgery.
Fine.
Okay.
But it's gonna have to wait
until I'm done with my book.
Dr. Grey, what are the
possible consequences
of not fixing a warning leak?
Stroke, hemorrhage, death.
Dr. Grey, what are the possible
consequences for a botched clip?
Stroke, hemorrhage, death.
So I'm dead, and my
book's not finished.
I can't do that to my readers.
I just need to find a way
to get Kate to the bridge
where she's supposed
to meet Nathan
before she's
pulled back in time.
After that, I'm all yours.
Justine...
Yeah, between your voice
and my leaky aneurysm,
I'm having a bitch of
a time focusing, so...
Could you...
Please?
When I say this is a
very important patient,
I mean, she is very
important to me.
I do not like it, but I have
a very full schedule today,
and you will have
to be my proxy.
No one touches
this patient but you.
You will run
every test I ask for.
You will report every
result back to me personally.
This woman has lost a husband
and a son in this hospital.
I will not have another
O'Malley lost under this roof.
O'Malley? George's
mother is our VIP?
Meredith Grey.
As promised.
It's been so long. Oh, you come
over here and give me a hug.
This is so freaking cool.
I bet it never occurred to
you to put this on your wish list.
How's that coming, by the way?
Why? Do you need it today?
Because I can't... I'm not done.
You do get that this is
supposed to be fun, right?
Right. I need more time.
Um, do you mind just moving
more to your left, please?
Your husband's in the gallery.
I know.
Henry's been begging
for a ride-along.
I figured, if you're
gonna observe a surgery,
this is the one you want to see.
How are we doing, Dr. Park?
Just a few more minutes,
and my guy down at UCLA
will have the heart he's been
waiting on for over a year.
Okay. Let's roll.
Got it.
Make sure that
connection is secure.
This tube connects
directly to the aorta.
That's right, and this
tube removes waste.
Got it.
Dr. Park, your
hospital's on the line.
Look at that.
She's about to
catch a flight to L.A.
and not even know
she left the body.
Damn it.
What is it?
My guy arrested. They
weren't able to resuscitate.
He's dead?
Damn it.
All dressed up,
and no place to go.
Here. Let me get it.
It says here you've had
surgery three weeks ago
at Seattle Pres for a
gallbladder removal?
I've gone back there
a couple of times,
and they always tell me I'm
fine and send me back home.
Bring me a 20-gauge
just in case, and benzoin.
And, you know,
it's freezing in here.
Have someone take a
look at that thermostat.
Yes, Doctor. I'm going
to palpate your abdomen,
and you let me know if you
feel any discomfort, okay?
The boys insisted I do my
surgery somewhere else,
after what happened here
with Harold and Georgie.
She's got some
midepigastric tenderness.
We should check
that gallbladder.
Have you been experiencing
any fevers at all, Louise?
Any pain, vomiting?
Yes, actually, I have.
Mrs. O'Malley, those
aren't good things.
I know. I'm sorry.
It's just that... Look at you.
You know how proud it makes
me to have you as my doctor?
Thank you.
Grey, let's get a
CT, CBC, lytes,
and a liver panel, and let's
get another couple of blankets.
I kept hearing Georgie's voice
saying, "Mom, get a second opinion.
"Go to Seattle Grace.
They'll take care of you."
We will, Louise. We're gonna
take very good care of you.
A doctor.
You're all grown up.
Looks like Columbia's got a good
match who's already consented.
We're contacting them
now to arrange pickup,
but it will be hours
before they arrive.
In the meantime, her
vitals need to be monitored
and lactate levels
checked hourly.
Okay, so I'll find
an intern to babysit.
Oh, I'm not leaving
her with an intern.
You're not serious. Dr. Yang,
this is a beating
heart in a box.
I'm very serious.
And you need more time to
finish your wish list anyway.
Right?
Page if you need me.
Shepherd, I can't approve this.
I'm not asking your approval.
I'm giving you a
heads-up, as a courtesy.
I have to be at a board meeting.
Don't let me hold you up.
Yikes. These are intense.
Are these patients of yours?
They will be. I went
looking for patients
who were told no by
every doctor they've seen.
So what are you gonna do?
Tell them yes.
Tell them I will do my best.
It's not just me. It's you, too.
You ready? Me?
Mmm-hmm. I...
Yes, of course.
What's this?
Uh, Justine Campbell's AMA form.
She's leaving against
medical advice so...
So you're not ready.
What? Why?
Yes. We're saying yes.
If you can't get her to say yes
to a simple surgery
that will save her life,
how do you expect
to tackle that?
Tear those up.
Get her to say yes, and I'll
let you jump on one of these.
Okay? What do you say?
Yes. Damn right.
Come on. Tell me I'm
paranoid or something.
You're paranoid. Thank you.
Although, she did throw
a softball at his girlfriend.
I know. Screw this.
You know, I can't be
around Sloan today. I...
Just take me off
Plastics, just for the day.
I gotta clear my head.
I am not gonna rearrange
the whole surgical schedule
just 'cause you're
having girl problems.
Just suck it up.
You guys ever hear
of a Polly Preston?
Chief resident at the Brigham?
She's only my number
one peer role model.
You're a freak, and I hate you.
What are you working
on today, Karev?
A fat lot of nothing now. Why?
How would you feel
about a nerve graft?
I would feel great
about a nerve graft.
Fine.
Thank you.
Ooh.
The pain's getting worse?
Does it look like
it's getting better?
I know what can
really help. What?
Clipping your aneurysm. Cute.
Look, I'm sure if you
call your publishers
and you tell them, they'll
extend the deadline.
It is not about a deadline.
It's about my readers out there,
who are waiting for
me to finish a series
that they have been
following for ten years.
You're really that popular?
You really know how to kick
a girl in the ego, don't you?
I'm sorry.
We don't get a lot of
time to read around here.
Uh, what about your family?
I mean, I'm sure that
they wouldn't want...
Do you see any family
sitting with me, Dr. Grey?
I'm a writer.
My characters are my family,
and I care about them.
And I've managed to
make a lot of other people
care about them as well.
Yes, I want to give
my readers closure.
But Kate and Nathan
and Alexander,
I owe them closure.
And I'm the only one
who can give it to them.
I'm just trying to help you.
You want to help me? Yeah.
How fast can you type?
Hot diggity.
There it is.
I ran into Altman,
and she told me what you
were up to this morning.
And I swear, I can't believe it.
It's astounding.
What are you
working on over there?
Um, Altman is offering to track
down surgeries I want to perform.
Uh, may I?
No. This is... Thanks.
Let's see what we got here.
Uh-huh.
Yang, what's wrong with you?
You're wasting an opportunity
on 300 pages of
common procedure.
She let a starving person
loose in a grocery store.
She asked what I want. I want
everything. What am I supposed to do?
Get creative.
I mean, look at that.
Okay.
It's the key. To what?
To the list.
So use it.
Use the key.
Unlock your mind.
What are you talking about?
I'm just talking about
a heart-in-a-box.
A heart-in-a-box.
Hot diggity.
It's such a treat, seeing
you again, Meredith.
I want to hear everything.
How have you been?
Catch me up.
I got married.
Oh, that's wonderful. Any kids?
No. We're working on it.
Callie.
Oh, my God!
Mama O'Malley.
Hi.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
It's so good to see you.
I know. I haven't called,
and I meant to
call so many times,
but you're here now, right now.
Why are you here? Are
you okay? Is she okay, Grey?
Yeah, we're hoping.
I'm just waiting
for CT to open up.
Okay, good. Right. Good.
Hello. Hi.
Uh, oh, right. Sorry.
This is Dr. Robbins.
Hi.
Mmm-hmm.
Louise O'Malley.
Whoo! That's us.
Good-bye, dear.
It was really nice to see you.
You okay?
Yeah, I think so. Maybe?
Hold on. Yes.
Polly? Okay, you're
here. I'm on my way.
My prospective Peds
fellow's here, so I gotta run.
Okay. I'll see you later.
All right. Dr. Torres.
Imagine my surprise
when I check out the
schedule expecting to see
Jackson Avery's name on it,
only to find he's been
replaced by Alex Karev.
We've been preparing
this nerve graft for weeks.
I know. I mean,
it's just you and me.
The Plastics Posse,
kicking surgical ass
and taking names.
The Plastics Posse?
Just something I'm trying out.
Look, Dr. Sloan, the thing is,
I gotta get this paper
in by 7:00 tonight
or I am screwed.
It's just bad timing.
Wait. You're missing a
rock-star nerve graft for a paper?
I know. It's fifth year.
You know? I can't
slack off now, right?
Oh, Dr. Torres.
Oh, I'm sorry. I panicked.
I didn't mean to introduce
you as Dr. Robbins.
But I guess I didn't
know how to say,
"Guess what, Mama O'Malley,
"I'm into girls now,
and this is my wife."
You know?
Polly.
Yes, Dr. Robbins.
I'm gonna need a minute.
Sure thing.
I'm gonna go take a look at
your nuclear protein machines.
Okay.
Peds prospect Polly?
Yep.
Oh, I'm doing so well today.
I get it. It's okay.
Wait. Really? 'Cause
you seemed kind of pissed.
Really? I thought
I was being funny.
Then you suck at jokes.
Look, coming out is
important. It's everything.
With your family
and your friends,
I'd kick your ass if you
tried to hide me from them.
But coming out to your dead
ex-husband's super-Catholic mom?
Not necessary. I
mean, not for you.
And certainly not
for me. So it's okay.
Thank you. Okay.
I'm gonna go find Polly
'cause I have no idea
where we'd keep the
nuclear protein machines.
Yeah.
Excuse me.
Sloan will not
shut up about you.
I wouldn't have
taken the surgery
if I knew I was breaking
up the Plastics Posse.
He's using that in public now?
What? You're lucky.
I wish I had an attending who
had my back like Sloan's got yours.
Excuse me. No cuts.
Sorry. I just gotta
get back to my patient.
Oh, my God. You guys
should read this. It's amazing.
Wait. Is that one of those books
about the time-traveling chick?
Yeah, every other mom in
Peds has got one in her purse.
Uh, 'cause they're awesome.
I mean, one minute, Kate is
running through 1890s Paris
with this pickpocket that
she loves but can't trust,
and the next thing she knows,
she's being pulled across time,
dodging Nazis with this
adorable American G.I.
It's like Slaughterhouse-Five,
but totally hot.
'Cause that's what
Vonnegut's missing, hotness.
Okay, I gotta go.
Come on. Let's eat
somewhere else.
It's kind of soothing, like
sitting in front of a fish tank.
It's not a fish
tank. It's a key.
What's that supposed
to mean? Ask Webber.
He came in here,
trashing my wish list,
and told me heart-in-a-box
was the key to fixing it.
I'll tell you something,
she's not talking.
Heart-in-a-box, what
should I put on my wish list?
should I put on my sandwich?
See? Nothing.
Heart-in-a-box, what's
wrong with George's mom?
Who's George?
He used to work here. He died.
Whoa. Who died?
George.
And we're talking about
that creep because?
Alex, you're an ass.
His mom's in the hospital.
Wow. O'Malley. I haven't
thought about him in...
Why would you? Alex.
Come on. Don't act like you stay up
nights writing poetry about the guy.
Remember when
you gave him syphilis?
How... What?
Remember heart-in-an-elevator?
Heart-in-an-elevator. I
should put that on my list.
George made you
look like such a chump.
George was the
heart-in-the-elevator guy?
I heard about that.
That sounded badass.
Were you there?
I just wanted to eat my
freaking lunch. That's all.
Wait. Wait. Everyone, shut up.
Heart-in-a-box,
heart-in-an-elevator?
It works. It totally works.
Webber is a genius.
Heart-in-a-box is
starting to creep me out.
Don't talk about her that way.
Kate looked at Alexander
with pity more than anything.
"Fine," she said. "Go. Go
wherever the hell you want,
"but first, you're
gonna apologize."
Why?
Why what?
Why is he
apologizing? Alexander?
Because he stole the ring that
Nathan gave her in book two.
What? Nathan gave her a ring.
Yes, he did, in book two.
Does Alexander know
that Nathan gave it to her?
No, Dr. Grey, he is a thief.
If a thief sees a ring,
he's gonna take it.
But he promised that
he was going to change.
Dr. Grey. What?
I'm doing what
you told me to do.
I told you to get her to the OR.
You're hosting a book club.
She won't go into an OR
until she finishes her book.
I'm helping her finish.
And how long will that take?
You can't rush the
creative process.
Grey, I asked you for preliminary
tests and hourly reports.
What part of that did you interpret
as, "Also, if you find the time,
"please shove a scope
down Mrs. O'Malley's throat"?
Her endoscopic ultrasound
showed a 16-milimeter
dilation of the common duct.
I also did not ask for an
endoscopic ultrasound.
See? Why can't you just do
the things that I ask you to do?
Oh, look. There.
See? She's got inflammation
and scar tissue around
the remnant cystic duct.
She's gonna need
surgery. Wonderful.
You just proved that your
former colleague's mother
had a botched surgery
at another hospital,
a hospital that she only went to
because we let her down
so shamefully in the past.
I just don't know why
you're celebrating.
I'm not celebrating...
Just go prep her for surgery.
Or is that too much to ask?
You were amazing in there.
I mean, from where
I was standing,
it looked like you pretty
much rebuilt that guy's heart.
What do you call that again?
A modified Fontan procedure.
Ah. After Dr. Fontan?
I can only assume.
I can only assume
that Dr. Fontan
never looked as hot doing his
own procedure as my wife just did.
What happens in here?
So the surgeons at Seattle
Pres left a length of cystic duct
inside of you when
they operated.
That's what's causing
your problems.
So we're gonna take that out.
Do you have any questions?
I saw a ring.
Excuse me?
On Callie's finger, when
we ran into her earlier.
Did she get remarried?
She did. A few
months ago, actually.
Oh! Oh, good.
Do you think... Is she happy?
Oh, I hope she's happy.
She seems happy.
Do you have any questions
about your surgery?
I raised a bunch of boys.
It was so nice to
finally have a daughter.
I miss her, all of you, really.
George's friends.
You were so important to him,
to me.
You're doing exactly what
George would be doing,
being in charge.
Oh. You'll be doing my
surgery, won't you, dear?
All by yourself. If
you're uncomfortable, I...
No. No, don't be silly.
George said you were the best.
I'm comfortable. I'm more
than comfortable. I'm ready.
Let's do this.
Let's cut me open.
I'm gonna need the
hand back for the surgery.
Yeah.
Avery.
We're about to get to
the hypoglossal nerve.
Why don't you come down
here and get a closer look?
I'd just get in the way. I
can see fine from here.
You're a fool, Avery.
Sitting in the gallery when
you should be grafting nerves?
You're lost.
Adrift.
You know what you need?
No, sir. I don't.
You need to see heart-in-a-box.
Yeah, I've seen it.
Maybe you looked at it.
But if you really saw it,
you'd be down in
that OR right now.
See it, Avery.
See heart-in-a-box.
Any idea what's
going on with Avery?
He seems so distant.
You want me to put
a note in his locker?
What's that? You want
me to suture in the graft?
No, I'll handle that.
What did you find?
There were retained stones
blocking her cystic duct remnant.
Oh. Okay. That's
not super serious.
She should be okay,
right? Yeah, she'll be fine.
Okay, good. Thanks. Yeah.
Oh, uh, she knows
you're married.
What? How? How did she find...
She saw your ring this morning.
She asked me, and all I
said is that you were happy.
It's not your place
to say anything.
She's going into
surgery, and she's scared,
and she's alone
and she misses you.
I know it's complicated,
but I don't think it would be
a bad thing if you were there
to hold her hand
when she woke up.
You got a second?
Wait just one second.
I'm a little worried
about Avery.
I'm this close to getting this.
We had a real
connection, you know?
Okay.
We were having such
a good time together,
and suddenly he's avoiding me.
He's cold and distant.
You're afraid you're about to
have your heart broken by him.
Kind of.
Derek, you know me.
I never gave a crap
about teaching in my life,
but lately, I like the
idea of passing it on.
And I, you know, I
want to see him do well.
Maybe I just need to back off.
Ah, Hunt. Just in time.
Mark is afraid that Avery
is gonna break up with him.
Can this just stay
between you and me?
I'd prefer that. Shepherd,
about these cases...
I know what you're gonna say.
You're worried about the
hospital's mortality rate going up.
See, that's the worst
part about being chief.
You have to say no to
everybody, and they hate you for it.
And you say no enough,
you're gonna hate yourself,
which is why I'm not gonna
watch you go through this.
I have a consult.
If you love someone,
set them free.
If they come back...
I'm gonna punch you.
Let me ask you something.
No.
I gotta say, I'm a big fan of
what happens in this room.
Every day should be bring
your husband to work day.
Listen, I've had this idea.
I felt silly even
considering it.
Like, really?
You think that's
something you're gonna do?
But now, though, I'm
thinking I really want to do it.
I want to go back to school.
Oh. Okay. I mean...
I mean, that's not silly.
Adults go back to
school all the time.
Medical school.
Wow.
I mean...
Wow. Yeah.
What time is it?
We got another surgery to get
to. Come on. Up and at them.
Kate couldn't keep it
to herself any longer.
She took him by the hand
and looked deep into
those ocean blue eyes.
"I have figured out why I
travel through time, Nathan.
"I have figured it out, and
now I know how I can stop it."
Oh, my God.
"I can choose where
to be, when to be,
"and I have chosen."
Oh, my God. Yes.
Nathan pulled her into
his arms and held on tightly.
Kate whispered
against his chest,
"I'm sorry. I am so, so sorry."
Wait. What?
She'd never know
if he heard her.
When she opened her eyes,
Nathan was gone.
She was in Paris.
It was time to
look for Alexander.
What?
She chooses Alexander?
No!
No way. It has to be Nathan.
It's not Nathan.
But he's so handsome and good.
And Alexander...
Is her soul mate.
He doesn't even have a soul.
I mean, he's a criminal.
They don't even
want the same things.
They make each other miserable.
Dr. Grey, I cannot
betray my characters.
You're the writer.
You can make them
do whatever you want.
And picking Nathan,
that is the right thing to do.
Oh!
You hate it. No, I know.
No, no. You hate it.
Oh, God.
Okay, page Shepherd. Now.
I think her aneurysm blew.
Suction.
Oh, damn. It's a big bleed.
If you had spent less
time taking dictation,
we could've avoided this.
Did she at least
finish the book?
No, but she did tell me how
it's gonna end. It's so stupid.
She's written this incredible story
with these amazing characters,
and then she just blows it.
Wow. You're 15 right now.
It's criminal, what she's doing.
And when she wakes
up, I'm gonna tell her that.
Or maybe it's none
of your business.
It's the same thing that you are
doing with these hopeless cases.
You know, you think
that you can change
the way the patient's
story is gonna end.
And if you think that,
then you're at least
obligated to try.
So I gotta try, right?
Yes.
You double-checked
her labs and scans?
Yes, of course.
I just don't want any
surprises once I'm in there.
Actually, she thought I'd
be performing her surgery.
Oh, I'm not
comfortable with that.
I can do a septoplasty.
You taught me a septoplasty.
I thought I taught
you a lot of things.
Now I'm thinking, I must not
be much of a teacher at all.
I'm going to court tomorrow,
to prove to a judge that's never
met me that I'm a good person,
a fit mother.
I want my kid back so badly,
I'm racking my brain for anything
that'll make him
see me that way.
I want to dress the part, so
I'm thinking my navy dress.
But there's a button missing,
and it shows too much cleavage.
My charcoal pants
have a hole in the ass.
I've got one shot at this.
I'm useless
and frustrated.
But I know how to do an ERCP and
I know when to double-check labs.
And I know how
to do a septoplasty.
I'm not useless here.
Fine. Do the surgery.
Off-pump coronary bypass.
No.
En bloc transplant,
heart and both lungs.
Yes.
I don't get it.
I mean, Webber talks about
this thing like it's a Magic 8 Ball.
It's a heart
in a box.
Okay, when you take an organ
out for transplant, what do you do?
Put it on ice. Yeah,
you put it on ice
and run to place it in
the recipient's body,
and then you wait and
hope for this cold, dead heart
to warm up and come
back to life, right?
But she... She?
She has never stopped beating.
She's never stopped being
warm, never stopped living.
Sure, it's pretty... It's a
frigging miracle. Okay?
You're standing
before a miracle.
And once you realize that,
she'll change your perspective.
Okay, here's what I do.
I look at an item on my list,
I look at heart-in-a-box.
And if that surgery on my list
isn't half as cool as heart-in-a-box,
then it is not worth my time.
She lets you know what's
most important to you.
That's what heart-in-a-box does.
And she's nice to talk to.
Shut up. Shut up.
What do you think about
the University of Washington?
Um, I'm not sure.
It's not like Harvard
or Stanford. It feels...
I don't know. It feels doable.
Doable?
Okay, I'm sorry, but...
Medical school isn't something
that you just decide to do.
Really? How did
it happen for you?
The Lady of the Lake appeared
with a gilded scalpel and
anointed you a med student?
Ha-ha.
I'm actually being
serious right now.
I mean, how is my decision to go to
med school any different than yours?
First of all, I was 19.
All right, great. So
I'm old. What else?
Uh, I don't know.
Have you taken your
three years of prerequisites?
How about the MCAT?
No, I have not, but I do
have a college degree.
I may have been
a baseball player,
but I think I remember
how to study.
Okay, that still doesn't account
for the four years
of actual med school.
And if you decide to
go completely crazy
and you want to try
to become a surgeon,
that's five years of
residency, a fellowship...
No, I never said I
wanted to be a surgeon.
There are plenty of other
ways to use a medical education.
Okay, fine.
Fine.
I love the way things
are right now. I really do.
And I don't want to spend ten
years married to a med student.
No. You'd just rather I followed
you around, looking cute.
Okay, you know what?
You know that that's
not what I'm saying.
I was gonna die.
My disease was going to kill me.
And then I met you.
You came into my life, and
suddenly I have insurance,
I have a wife, I have a life expectancy
beyond the next three months.
Sue me if I don't
want to waste any of it.
Henry, I... Just...
I'll see you at home.
Okay, probe passes easily
through the common duct.
One more biopsy, and I
think we're ready to close.
Dr. Bailey, is there something
wrong? Did I miss something?
This woman worked
so hard to raise her son,
and then one day, he just
threw himself in front of a bus.
I mean, yeah, yeah, he did it
to save someone else, but...
You work and work,
trying to teach your
kids to do the right thing,
and you want to
be so proud of them
when they stand up for
what they believe is right.
But watching them
destroy themselves
in order to do it,
to do what you taught them,
it's just maddening.
You. You are maddening.
He was my favorite.
George O'Malley.
He was. My favorite.
I know.
He was the good one.
So I'm going to put in a T-tube.
Wear a sweater set.
People have preconceived
notions about surgeons.
They think we're cold,
intimidating, egotistical.
A sweater set says
you're warm, motherly.
If it was me, I'd
wear a sweater set.
Thank you.
You paged?
I can't get outta here yet.
I gotta follow up
with my patient,
make sure she's in
her right frame of mind.
Yeah.
You okay?
Yeah, I missed a
surgery today that...
That's not true.
I avoided a surgery today,
one I wanted to do for weeks,
because of this thing
with you and Mark.
There is nothing
between me and Mark.
Yeah, I've been trying really,
really hard to believe that.
But there is a thing.
And it's not going
anywhere anytime soon.
And this new thing
with me and Plastics?
That's not going away either.
Something's gotta budge.
So I have to walk away
from you, for me.
So...
You're picking Mark?
I've spent way too much time
sabotaging my own career, Lex.
Yeah,
I'm picking Mark.
Can you tell me I shouldn't?
Heard a helicopter
touched down on the roof.
Let them come. You were right.
She was the key.
Now this is a fine list.
Thank you, sir.
You made a list, too?
I was inspired.
Oh, oh, I want to
put this on my list.
If one of those comes in, we'll
have to see who gets to it first.
Okay.
Hi.
We're the procurement
team from Columbia.
She's all yours.
Heart-in-a-box.
Hot diggity.
How are you feeling?
Like a woman who
just had brain surgery.
Fair enough. Can
you tell me your name?
Justine Campbell.
And what's today's date?
I never know the date.
Ask me something else.
Why can't Kate choose Nathan?
She's going to.
I just feel like you have
a moral obligation to...
Wait, really?
Yeah. For now.
I had a dream while I
was under, and I figured out
how to stretch the series
out two or three more books.
So... For now,
she'll get to see what it
feels like to be with Nathan.
So... What?
They're gonna be
together for a few books,
and then she's gonna
choose Alexander?
Yeah, probably.
What is wrong with you?
I mean, why do you
hate Nathan so much?
I don't hate Nathan.
I love him,
probably as much
as you apparently do.
He's kind and funny
and incredibly honest.
It's Kate.
She doesn't love him.
She should.
I know.
It's not fair.
But it makes for a
really, really good read.
Come here.
Do you want to work on
the book a little bit more?
Will that make you feel better?
Okay.
Callie.
Meredith said the
surgery went great.
Oh. Yeah.
I like girls.
As in, romantically.
It turns out, I like girls.
Uh, women.
And I met the most
amazing woman.
Do you remember
Dr. Robbins from this morning?
Yeah, we got married, and...
Oh, no, but before that,
we got in an accident,
a car accident,
a really bad accident,
and I almost died.
But I didn't, and Sofia,
neither did Sofia, our baby,
our perfect, beautiful baby.
And I'm screwing all this up.
Look, I...
I know this is a lot.
And I understand.
Um, and if this is too
much for you to handle,
believe me...
My own mother
practically disowned me,
so I understand.
Oh, God. I'm making you cry.
Please don't cry.
You have a baby?
I do.
Do you have any pictures?
You want to see them?
Are you kidding?
Okay.
She's beautiful.
Thank you.
That man just booked
a flight from Wichita.
You want to tell him no,
I'll give you his number.
You can tell him yourself.
I'm not worried about the
hospital's mortality rates, Derek.
I'm worried about you.
You've had a lot
of losses this year,
and I am concerned that
you're lining yourself up for more.
You're worried
about my reputation.
There is that.
I don't have a
reputation anymore.
See, I was gonna be the
guy who cured Alzheimer's.
Now I am blacklisted by the FDA,
so I don't have to worry
about that anymore.
I get to choose
what I worry about.
And I choose them. I feel
I can change their story.
I owe it to them
to at least try.
That's pretty damned
arrogant, don't you think?
I have a reputation
for arrogance.
Could I have a Cabernet?
Actually, make that
a Scotch and soda.
Okay.
You know what? Forget the soda.
Hi, it's me.
Turns out today was a bust.
She kept going on about this guy
who helped these kids in Africa.
And I was like, "Have you
seen my three articles?"
But apparently, this
guy craps puppies,
so who cares about me?
Anyway, my plane
lands at 10:00, so wait up.
I'm gonna be drunk
and I'm gonna cry.
Just warning you.
I have to catch a plane.
Keep the change. MAN: Thanks.
Avery, wait up.
Oh, right, Dr. Sloan.
You need to talk to me...
I am sorry about today...
No, I'm sorry. It was my...
No, you don't have
anything to be sorry about.
No, I think I should
apologize to you for...
No, it wasn't you. It
was me. I have been...
I just think we had some... I
don't want to screw things up.
Okay, I'm gonna talk,
then you talk, okay?
Okay.
I want to be your teacher.
I want to be your student.
I have a cranial vault
reconstruction tomorrow.
I will be there.
Good. Good.
Great.
I guess the Plastics
Posse is back in action.
Kicking surgical ass
and taking names.
All...
Just... All right.
Just do that. Yeah.
Great. Okay. All right.
Drive safe.
It's a little bit horrifying
just how quickly
everything can fall to crap.
O'Malley wasn't a creep, okay?
If he were here now, he'd
be kicking all of our asses.
He would've slapped chief
resident right out of Kepner's hand.
I just don't like
thinking about him
because then I have
to think about Izzie,
and then I get all
sad and sappy and...
I totally miss the chance
to nail hot, drunk chicks
who spent the day thinking
about how I'm awesome,
which I should be all about.
George is dead, and Izzie is
gone, and we're all different.
We're different.
Sometimes it takes a huge loss
to remind you of what
you care about the most.
Sometimes you find yourself
becoming stronger as a result,
wiser, better equipped
to deal with the next big
disaster that comes along.
That was our first real fight.
You okay?
Okay, okay, okay,
okay. It's okay.
Okay. You're gonna be okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
Sometimes... Look at me.
You're gonna be okay.
But not always.