There is a procedure
to treat epilepsy
that involves surgically
severing the connection
between the left
and right brain.
The goal is to block
signals that cause seizures.
A packet?
We're gonna
convince these people
to give us $175
million with a packet?
It's a nice packet.
Mer, Owen stopped calling.
If this doesn't work, he'll
never speak to me again.
Once we buy the hospital,
the sneaking around stops.
And once Owen
finds out what we did,
he's gonna be
the happiest of all.
Derek is completely...
The problem is,
this also cuts off the brain's
ability to communicate with itself.
Hey. Hi.
Good morning.
The left side has no idea
what the right side is up to.
The patient may experience
problems with coordination...
Memory, speech.
Okay, really?
It's been a week.
What the hell is going on?
You walk out, no warning,
and now the
hospital's falling apart.
Yesterday a bunch
of nurses walked.
We lost lab techs,
support staff.
What?
I mean, if you wanted to screw
the Pegasus deal, success,
high five.
But now people are
saying that without a buyer,
the whole place could
go belly-up in a month.
What are you trying to do?
We... Cristina.
Fine. Whatever.
It's a drastic solution
that's only considered
when all other
options have failed,
because once a
surgeon makes that cut,
there's no going back.
Shane, have you seen the
Chief? Yeah, he's right over...
I'm too young to be this tired.
At least we still have jobs.
Stop saying that.
Hospitals don't just close.
Right?
Chief, the ORs are overbooked.
Seven more nurses didn't
show up for their shift today.
Too many surgeries,
not enough staff.
Um, do me a favor.
Go back up there and
see what can be pushed.
Dr. Bailey, you
look nice. New suit?
Old suit.
Been in the back of my closet
since my last job interview,
somewhere around Y2K.
You're going on interviews?
This place is a sinking ship.
This place is not sinking.
We're having some trouble,
but we're gonna fix this.
Cahill's convinced Pegasus
to come back to the table.
She's having that
meeting right now,
and she's going
to make this sale.
Everything's gonna be fine.
Whatever you say, Cap'n.
Bailey, please.
They're reevaluating their offer
based on all of these walkouts.
We can't afford to lose
another surgeon, most of all you.
Me?
You're the heart of
this hospital, the spirit.
You set the tone that
others can aspire to.
This place can't
function without you.
Right, Brooks?
What?
Yes. Right.
Fine.
You better be right.
'Cause if this boat goes under
and I don't have a life jacket,
I'm coming looking for you,
fists swinging.
And I'm short, so
my punches land low.
Neuro Resident,
extension 2-2-1-9.
Neuro resident,
I think Dr. Webber's
having a stroke.
You need to go.
Where?
Don't care. Just go. Go now.
She's pretty. Mom.
How was breakfast?
Ah, informative.
If what Richard
tells me is true,
it's time for you
to come to Boston.
What have you done?
Okay, now just wait a second.
I've seen the kind of garbage
that goes on in a Pegasus hospital.
If your options are
either working for them
or this hospital shutting
down altogether...
Catherine,
okay, this hospital
is not shutting down.
In uncertain times,
men like Jackson and
myself have to stand tall.
We can't pack up and flee
at the first sign of trouble.
A man who does not
bend to the winds of change
is a man that you
can be proud of.
That's poetic.
I'm just sayin', let's slow down
and see how this all shakes out.
I don't think...
Mom, I agree with Dr. Webber,
with Richard.
I can't say that
I like this at all.
You can push it a day.
It's a tumor surgery
on a little kid.
Right, but is he
"dying today" sick
or "can't play soccer
but still hanging on" sick?
I'll see myself out.
Dr. Glass, call the
operating room.
You take Bobby Brinn in
for his pre-op scans yet?
Oh, no, not yet.
What about Julie Chang's labs?
Just about to do that.
Are you pissed at me? What?
I blew you off last night,
and you're pissed at me.
I'm pissed because I have
85 million things to worry about
since Robbins walked out.
You hanging out with your
boyfriend isn't one of 'em.
I shoulda gone to Hopkins
when I had the chance.
I'll get those labs.
Okay, so this time, I'll do
the peds and trauma stuff first.
And then I will
go into the neuro.
Okay, can somebody
else do the closing?
I was awful last
time we practiced.
No, you were fine.
We really want to
end on my flop sweats?
Derek, you do the closing.
I'm sorry. It should be
just a few more minutes.
Can I get you any
water or coffee?
No, no, I'm fine. I'm fine.
Coffee.
And a bagel or something.
I'm starving.
This meeting was supposed
to start half an hour ago.
Okay, he's a billionaire.
One of his minutes
is worth 40 of ours.
I can't believe we got this
meeting in the first place.
Yeah, nice job, Stan.
I really believe Julian
Crest is our guy.
He made all his money in
late-stage Internet mobile.
Medical tech is the one area
he doesn't have a foothold.
Your focus on applied
research, it's right up his alley.
Yeah, well, someone
should buy him a watch.
Who are you calling?
Heather Brooks.
Mousy.
Wait. What are you doing?
What happened to
not talking to anyone?
I left patients behind. She's
keeping an eye on them.
I haven't said anything to her.
I'm giving her advice.
Oh.
We're all set if
you'll follow me.
Oh. ARIZONA: Oh, okay.
Leave it.
Mmm!
I am not the heart
of the hospital.
I'm a chump who didn't quit
when she had the chance.
Now I'm stuck
cleaning up the mess.
Brooks, you gonna
answer that phone?
Sorry.
Oh, it's my mom.
She's going through
a rough patch.
Less about your mom.
Right. Okay. Uh, Melissa
Keyser, 28 years old.
She's a former
patient of Dr. Grey's.
She's been on dialysis but
has exhausted all viable veins
and is now septic.
Which means she's done. Ha!
Dr. Grey left me a hopeless
patient. Of course she did.
May as well have left me
a pillow to smother her with.
Are you the doctor?
My mom won't wake up.
Dr. Granville to recovery.
You're lurking. You blame me?
I did it. They're in.
The deal closes at
8:00 a.m. tomorrow.
Seattle Grace-Mercy
West will officially
be a Pegasus Horizons hospital.
I can't... That's... Really?
I told you I was good at this.
There are just a
few things to iron out,
so I'll find you
when we're done.
Okay, well, I have...
I have a surgery,
but I could come in right...
No, go, go. Be a
doctor. I'll find you.
Okay. Hey, Alana?
Thank you.
You are investing
in an institution,
a reputation, a legacy.
But Seattle Grace-Mercy West
Hospital is worth more than its past.
Our plan is to build
on that reputation,
to make Seattle Grace a
place where medical innovation
is developed and delivered
to the patients who need it.
That is our plan.
That is the future
of Seattle Grace.
And we invite you
to be a part of it.
Neat.
We'll, uh... We'll let you know.
I thought you were
taking us to Julian Crest,
not his day care center.
You don't just walk in and
talk to a guy like Julian Crest.
There are hoops to jump through.
Those junior execs like us,
they pass us up to his
business development guys.
We impress them, then
we see the man himself.
Oh. Will they do this
before or after their naptime?
You were golden in there.
There's no way you don't
make it to the next level.
I'm telling you, any second now
this phone is gonna ring.
Really, any second now.
Yes, I understand.
What are they saying?
Yes, yes, yes. I understand.
Understand? What
do you understand?
Thank you. Thank you
very much for your time.
You guys, you were kind of rude.
Well, what did
they freaking say?
I'm sorry. You got the meeting.
Oh! Yes.
Brooks.
Brooks, what's the story?
I'm sorry, but I'm on
Bailey's service today,
and she is not your biggest fan.
Okay.
Melissa Keyser's
in septic shock.
Her last systolic
was in the 70s,
but Bailey's not ready
to throw in the towel yet.
Which is why I've
been trying to reach you.
So I found this article on
surgeons crafting artificial arteries
for patients with
exhausted vessels.
Brooks, what are you doing
in here with the lights off?
Gotta go, Mom.
Bye. Uh...
Dr. Bailey, here is the work-up.
Ooh.
Maybe we really do need to
look into that smothering pillow.
You know...
I actually think
I read an article
about artificial arteries for
patients with exhausted vessels.
Really? Tell me more.
I don't remember more.
Well, then find me that article.
Angry Avery returns.
What? Your face.
You get all mad and your
eyebrows do that thing. It's cute.
It's my mom.
She's been on me for
years to come back to Boston
and take a leadership role in
the Harper Avery Foundation.
And now she is
ringing that bell again,
that loud, very loud bell.
You're leaving?
No. I work here.
Did you prep Mrs.
Preston for the rhinoplasty?
That's been pushed.
Leah says Dr. Hunt's canceling
all non-emergent surgeries.
I actually thought that's
what Angry Avery...
That's the fifth time this week.
I never thought I'd say this,
but maybe my mom has a point.
Okay, Bobby. So here's the plan.
What I'm gonna do is I'm
gonna make a small incision
right about here.
Then I'm gonna take Phil and
I'm gonna stuff him in a bag.
And I'm gonna chop him
into a tiny million little pieces.
And then I'm gonna
yank him right outta there.
And adios, Phil.
Hear that, Phil?
You're going down.
Phil's his tumor. Mmm.
He was six when we
found out about the mass.
Bobby heard "man,"
which, you know, kind of
made it easier to talk about.
There's this evil little
man inside of him.
Dr. Karev,
can I keep Phil's head?
When I'm done grinding up Phil,
there's not gonna
be a head left to keep.
That's so gross.
Just admit it, Dr. Hunt.
My gut's a mess
because you screwed up.
Adhesions are unfortunately
a normal complication of this...
How can four surgeries
in two years be normal?
You're supposed to be in
there clearing out my scar tissue.
Instead you keep making more.
Sorry I'm late.
I had to do lots.
And now you're gonna let Tardy
Marty dig around in me, too?
Why do I keep coming
back to this chop shop?
Because today we're
trying something new,
something we only do
with high-risk patients.
Which you certainly seem to be.
Pick up on that, did you?
Andy, this is going to work.
What happens if I get up
and walk outta here right now?
The blockages caused by
your scar tissue will stay blocked,
and then you die.
Well...
You could've led with that.
Something I can
do for you, Avery?
I don't know. Is there?
What?
I think you know something.
I know many things.
The kind of things to get a man
talking about winds of change
and standing firm,
even though it
feels like the ground
is about to crumble
out from under me?
A week ago, I came
across Torres, Yang,
Robbins, Shepherd, and Grey
all having some kind of powwow.
When I asked them
what they were up to,
they slammed the door in my face
like I was Diane Keaton at
the end of The Godfather.
Hour later, they resigned.
That sound at all
suspicious to you?
Sir, something tells
me you used to watch
a lot of Unsolved Mysteries.
I solved three of 'em.
This would restore
Seattle Grace-Mercy West
as the region's leader in adult
and pediatric trauma medicine.
Dr. Shepherd?
Yeah, we'll lead the
way in neuroscience,
a dedicated research institute
for the advances
of brain mapping,
with applications to the
treatment of Alzheimer's
and Parkinson's disease...
May I stop you for a second?
We would love to see a
little bit more on the financials.
Income statements, profit
projections, cash flow.
Your allocation of revenue,
perspective payment for
MS-DRGs versus capitation income?
Um...
We've got all that.
Yep. Right here.
Got it.
Marketing, customer
retention plans...
Is there a trend study here?
Yep.
One second.
I'm just running
it by Mr. Crest.
Oh.
Mr. Crest apologizes,
but he's leaving this
evening for Dubai.
Oh. Okay.
Dubai.
Wow.
But he can make 15
minutes for you this afternoon.
Great. Thank you.
All right. Great.
Alana.
I didn't expect it to
happen this quickly,
but I also didn't expect
it to happen this way.
I know.
The board just needs to review
their counteroffer and accept.
I called an emergency
meeting in an hour.
I would like you to be
there when I tell them.
Have you told Dr. Hunt yet?
That Pegasus is buying
his hospital for parts,
liquidating its assets,
laying off its staff?
I just haven't figured out how.
It isn't pretty, but
we needed a deal.
And it's a deal.
Brooks? What's going on?
Is it Bailey?
It's my fault. It's my fault.
Everybody's
gonna lose their jobs
'cause I had a stupid
idea. Oh, no, no, don't.
Nobody is gonna lose their jobs.
Everybody is. Brooks
heard it straight from Cahill.
The hospital is liquidating.
The deal is closing
tomorrow morning.
Does Owen know?
She didn't say.
All right, so Crest is our last
meeting, and it's our only chance.
In two hours.
Oh, no pressure or anything.
Ugh.
Okay.
Well, if we only get 15 minutes,
then we need to make
the most of them, so...
Right.
Right, right. We can't
just sit on our thumbs
and let 'em read
Stan's boring crap.
No offense.
None taken. It's
interesting to me.
We need to know all
of this boring crap, too.
All right, so we need
to be able to answer
every single
question he could ask.
Okay, well, let's divide it up.
Stan, give us all the
boring crap you have.
That doesn't make any sense.
It's true. Cahill said...
Brooks.
Okay. You... You
just can't say anything
to anyone else.
Something like this, it's...
People panic. It's too...
It's too big.
I don't understand.
This morning, you called
this place a sinking ship.
No, that's different.
I never thought it
would actually sink.
You keep your mouth
shut, you hear me?
They are stripping us for parts
like a busted ass truck.
What, and we're just
supposed to believe that
because you got a
kicky little haircut?
And also because it's true.
Ugh. I'm gonna be sick.
And I have a surgery.
I'm gonna be sick
in my final surgery.
This is not how I
wanted to go out.
Jackson might be
going to Boston.
I mean, I don't know.
Maybe I... Stop right there.
I know this is really
bad, but don't be that girl.
What girl?
That girl who follows her
boyfriend across country
like a puppy dog.
I am not that girl.
They were just awarded
millions of dollars.
I'd quit my job, too.
No, you wouldn't,
and neither would they.
They're not that kind of people.
Oh, that's bull. They're
exactly that kind of people.
They're only out for themselves.
They're probably pooling
their money together
for some private
practice or something.
I don't buy it.
You want to start a restaurant,
you don't use your own money.
And they have no reason
to keep that a secret.
I shoulda gone to
freakin' Hopkins.
Yeah, that was a bad move.
What do you think's
going on over there?
You guys, we
cannot say anything.
News like this will
just make people panic.
Yeah, no kidding. I'm panicking.
Exactly, so don't say anything.
Don't say anything about what?
Marcia Lowe,
return to admitting.
Patient Marcia Lowe,
You heard.
Your intern.
Damn that girl. I...
Could just grab
her by the hair...
What's that?
Oh, I'm...
Giving a patient
an artificial artery
so that she can
stay on dialysis.
Keep her alive long enough
to get the kidney
she's been waiting on.
Sounds like fun.
Want to scrub in?
Might be our last chance.
One more for the road.
I thought I'd be chief
of surgery someday.
You shouldn't spread
that kind of rumor.
It's not a rumor.
I heard it from Brooks.
She heard it from...
That is a textbook rumor.
And it's not true. Just
ask Hunt. He'll tell you.
He'd never confirm
something like that to an intern.
You ask him.
It's not my rumor.
Hey. We ready to roll?
As an academic medical center,
we are currently at 411 beds.
But once we're restored
to a level I trauma center,
that number will raise to 500.
Right, increasing
revenue streams
for both acute
and long-term care.
Pause.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
This is in Chinese.
Literally in Chinese.
Tell Simon I need these in
English before I go back in there.
And have Alyse cancel
my tee time at Canterwood.
Right away. Sorry. Go.
Yeah, we're all very...
Did Sandy take my
luggage already?
I need my charger thingy.
So we're passionate about patient
care and medical advancement.
We want to be the premier
hospital in the US for both.
Your bags are at Sea-Tac
already. Should we bring them back?
No, that's silly.
Mr. Crest, here it is.
Not you. You're
great. Keep going.
All right, we would comprise
the managing board,
and with you being the
primary shareholder, you could...
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
wait. Stop. Go back.
I thought you were
looking for an outright buyer.
You want to run this?
We do.
But we all trained
and worked there.
Yeah, we know the
place better than anyone.
We've invested ourselves...
Yes. Invested
yourselves. I love that.
Sir.
You have totally done that.
The Shepherd method of
viral glioblastoma treatment...
Dr. Grey, your name
was on that, too, right?
It was.
You wrote the book on
scaffold-free cartilage fabrication.
First in your class at Smith,
Berkeley, and Stanford.
And Tim Kenner at Hopkins
won't shut up about you.
Oh.
Oh, well, um, clearly,
you've done your homework.
Yeah, I did.
What I found is, there's
not a manager in the bunch.
No administrative
leadership experience.
You gotta have someone
who can keep the lights on.
Dr. Shepherd was
the chief of surgery.
Yeah, for about ten minutes.
Then you stepped down,
own volition, no reason given.
What my gut tells
me is, you didn't like it.
Surgeons like surgery.
I know when I find
something I don't like doing,
I don't do it well.
They're ready for you.
Sorry. I have three meetings
before I get on a plane.
Thank you all so much
for coming to me with this.
I respect your passion.
I share it.
But I'm not feeling this.
Get someone on your team
with some real
administrative experience,
and we can talk.
Hmm.
This is what I've been saying.
We have the experience.
Well, he doesn't
think so. So we're...
Don't. Don't do that.
Don't do that, okay?
There's still something we
can do. What can we do?
He wants experience.
Let's get Richard.
What about the
guy who's chief now?
Well, we can't tell Owen.
What the hell difference
does it make now?
We need him.
All right, so if we get
Richard and Owen, then what?
Do we get another meeting?
Crest is leaving
for Dubai tonight.
Well, then we do
it before he leaves.
Uh, okay. Well, we can't
all march into the hospital.
Well, I'll go. I'll
go get Richard.
Okay.
Brooks, if that's your mother
on the line, so help me...
Dr. Webber, Dr. Grey is
in the waiting area for you.
It's urgent.
Meredith Grey?
Um, Brooks, come over here
and assist Dr. Bailey, please.
Wait. You're not actually going.
I'm sorry, Bailey. Hurry.
What else?
What else can Meredith Grey
possibly take from me today?
She gave us this fix.
What's that?
She doesn't even
work here anymore,
and she's still out there
trying to help her patients.
Uh, what the hell are you
doing sharing patient details
with someone who
doesn't even work here?
She cares.
Oh, she cares?
Now don't you tell
me about caring.
I'm the heart of
this damn hospital!
All right, these adhesion
barriers we're placing
should keep the tissue
separate while it heals.
You said "should,"
but you told Andy that
they would for sure.
Right, with a guy like Andy, you
tell him the best version of the story.
So what happens
if it doesn't work?
Ross.
Well, if it doesn't work, then
we come back in six months
and we try again.
But we won't be
here in six months.
Ross heard a stupid rumor
that the hospital
is shutting down,
and now he's apparently
having a breakdown.
All right, everyone, I
shouldn't be telling you this.
It is still in the works,
but Pegasus is
buying this hospital.
And nobody is going anywhere.
You're lying. APRIL:
He wouldn't lie...
Yes, he would. He just
told us that he would.
Only this isn't telling the
best version of the story.
It's a flat-out lie.
What are you talking about?
Don't pretend like
you don't know.
Pegasus is buying the
hospital so they can liquidate it.
We're all losing our jobs.
Would you just
tell him it's not true?
It is not. Who said that?
Cahill.
It's okay. Uh, I got this.
He lied then he walked away.
He didn't lie, Ross.
He didn't know.
Have fun in the bag, jerk face.
Morcellator, please.
That's gnarly.
Yeah, Bobby would love this.
We could record the live feed.
He could rewatch the carnage.
Share it with his friends.
Nah. He'd be expecting
arms and eyeballs and crap.
Finding out the truth would
break his freaky little heart...
About Santa Claus
and how people get
sick and let you down,
and everything just falls apart.
Till then he can believe
whatever the hell he wants.
Yeah, you're right.
I mean, I'm a grown-up
and I was still a
little disappointed
we didn't find arms
and eyes in there.
All right, here we go.
Oh, sick.
Well, that's a very
interesting offer, sir.
But I wouldn't be
comfortable with...
Really?
That's a... Really?
I was able to do
some rearranging
and get Avery's rhinoplasty
back on the board.
He's on the phone with the
Boston chief of plastic surgery.
Jo was right. You're that girl.
I know.
We're all about
to lose our jobs,
and all I can think
about is the fact
that I'm gonna have to
stop sleeping with him.
I'm so gross.
Come on. The sex
can't be that good.
Look at him.
Really? I'm gonna
go talk to him.
Every step you take
is a giant leap
backward for womankind.
There goes the right to vote.
Roe V. Wade.
Cut it out.
Besides, you're just as bad.
You were hung up
on Karev for weeks.
Yeah, but you don't want
to be like me. You hate me.
Thanks.
And I don't hate you.
Yeah, you do.
Dr. Chan to the isolation unit.
What are you doing
here? I have to talk to you.
Oh, now you want to talk?
You're about a week
late. I need to find Cahill.
You have to listen.
Owen, is it true, they're
selling the hospital for scrap?
This is the deal you made?
This is the deal you made,
you, Shepherd, and all of you,
when you walked out on
me, when you lied to me!
We're trying to
buy the hospital.
So we've been looking
for an outside investor,
trying to get the money
together, but we've hit a wall.
I'm good for $3 million.
No, Richard. We don't want...
No, I just have to move
some things around.
It'll be everything
I have, but I am in.
No, we don't need your money.
We need your experience.
We need you.
I mean, we'll take your money,
too, if it comes down to it, but...
How much do you need?
$175 million.
That's pretty good.
It's not really funny, is it?
No.
So we only walked out to
stall the sale to Pegasus.
And it's not over.
We have an investor.
We just need you and
Webber to get him on board,
now, before the
Pegasus deal closes.
You couldn't tell me this?
Why couldn't you
just tell me this?
I could've fought for you.
I could've fought with you.
I'm sorry.
I wanted to tell
you. I wanted to.
But they said you
signed nondisclosures,
and if anyone found out you
were involved in a competing bid,
they could sue you,
or if they were pissed
enough, jail you.
Please trust me. I...
I was trying to protect you.
You don't need to protect me.
Wait, wait, wait. Where
are you going? The board.
If they think we can save this
place, it could buy you some time.
You can't take that chance.
Cristina, you need
to trust me, too.
Boston then?
No. Not Boston.
My mom wouldn't want
to win that way anyway.
But it's probably time to start
thinking about someplace else.
What about you?
Where are you headed?
I don't know yet.
Well, you never know.
We could end up
somewhere near each other.
That wouldn't be the
worst thing in the world.
Yeah. Sure.
Suction, please.
Hey, buddy.
They got him.
They kicked Phil's
butt straight to the curb.
I wish you coulda
seen the look on his face
when I pulled his eyeballs
right out of his stupid head.
Oh, dude. It was so nasty.
There were brains
and hair everywhere.
Don't forget the intestines.
How could I?
They got all tangled up
in my tools like spaghetti.
We had to take a break
just to get rid of all the goo.
What else?
Excuse me.
Hey.
You okay?
You faking?
Joke's on you.
There aren't gonna be
that many more surgeries
for you to con out of me.
You're gonna be fine.
There are other programs.
Not like this one.
Not with a teacher like you...
Who shows me
cool tumor-in-a-bag surgeries
and thinks it's fun to talk to
little kids about guts and stuff.
You know, I, uh...
I barely saw you this week,
and it sucked.
I'll find another job. Whatever.
I... But I don't want to
never see you again.
Hey.
- I'm fine. I'm okay.
- I'm good.
Thank god Stephanie
wasn't here to see this.
Section 15,
allocation of equipment,
basically states that
all of Seattle Grace-Mercy
West medical devices,
radiology equipment, etcetera,
will be distributed between
Pegasus' existing facilities
at their discretion... Dr. Hunt.
You can't take this deal.
Dr. Hunt, can we step outside?
Dr. Hunt, I'm sorry.
It isn't what you want.
It isn't what any of us want,
but it is the deal we have.
No, it isn't. I have
another buyer.
I'm sorry. I told you.
He's not available.
Rita, I'm right here.
Hey, guys.
This is the leadership you
asked for, Richard Webber.
Pleasure. Pleasure.
Richard was Seattle Grace's
chief of surgery for 12 years.
Um, can we have a
moment to talk to you?
I have to be on a plane in
20. Can you guys ride with me?
That's fine, yeah. Mmm-hmm.
I only have room for two of you.
Not fair.
So what do we do now?
We go pick them up.
It is a solid capital investor
with a team of surgeon
consultants led by Richard Webber,
Derek Shepherd,
Dr. Torres, Robbins...
A group of
disgruntled employees.
Grey, Yang, and myself.
Well, where are they, then?
They can formally present
their offer to you tomorrow
if you hold off on
this sale to Pegasus.
No, you can't do that.
You can't make Pegasus wait...
You all have a choice here.
You can either be
responsible for consigning
this world-class hospital
to the scrap heap...
There's no choice. Or...
It's not a deal.
Or you can partner
with the doctors
who made this place what it was
and see what it can be.
The Pegasus deal went away once.
If it goes away again,
you have nothing,
no severance packages,
no paying off creditors.
You can't make
payroll next week.
Nothing.
All we need is one day.
One day.
Do you see them?
There.
Do they look happy?
I can't tell.
Sad?
I got them to wait.
The board is gonna
wait for one more day.
You can make your pitch.
I did it.
We didn't.
Crest met with
Richard, liked him,
liked all of us,
then he said no.
Said he just wasn't feeling it.
So it's over.
It's over.
Dr. Kepner?
Andy's awake.
He's got some questions, and
I couldn't track down Dr. Hunt.
Okay. I will be right there.
I just needed some air.
Can I ask you something?
You want to know how
something like this could happen?
I don't know.
I guess I have to believe
that everything
happens for a reason.
It's all part of some plan,
and you're supposed
to learn something.
You lose a patient because
you forget to check their airway,
you don't make
that mistake again.
You fail your boards
'cause you're too busy
sleeping with your best friend,
maybe you stop doing that.
The hospital you
call home shuts down
just when you're
finally starting to feel
like you've got
your life together...
Actually, I was gonna ask
for a letter of recommendation.
Oh.
But I could probably
ask someone else.
That might be best.
Go on home, Brooks.
I'll take it from here.
If it's all the same,
Dr. Bailey, I'd prefer to stay.
Suit yourself.
What's wrong with your face?
You're right.
You are the heart
of the hospital.
I was, Brooks.
Was.
We're not buying a house. Hmm.
Well, we're not
buying a hospital.
We could buy a house.
Or build one.
We don't even know where
we're gonna be in six months.
So we build it in
Chicago or Miami
or New York.
We have each other,
and we have a
beautiful baby so...
We can go wherever we want.
Probably want to sell
Mark's place, right?
Probably.
We don't have to
move yet, do we?
No.
Not yet.
Vermouth?
That'll have to do.
Oh, and now you're
stealing my freakin' booze.
It's just vermouth. Shut up.
You don't get to
make stupid little jokes.
We had a good
thing going, all of us.
And now people
are losing their jobs,
and it's your fault.
We were trying to
buy the stupid hospital.
We were trying to help,
and we screwed up.
I'm sorry.
Oh, well...
40-year-old Scotch.
A patient gave it to me.
Now you're gonna sit down
and you're gonna
freakin' talk to me.
Oh, Derek, it's over.
Enough. You have to stop.
Yeah, I know. Ross asked me to
write a letter of recommendation.
And I'm gonna do them
for each of the interns.
Did you do one
for Heather Brooks?
Who? Mousy.
Oh, no. Not yet.
I will.
They were trying to buy
the hospital themselves.
They... They just
needed more money.
They couldn't get it in time.
Well, what are you gonna do now?
Well, I heard
Boston's awfully nice.
That thought has crossed
my mind a time or two.
I just didn't want to be pushy.
That hardly sounds like you.
I poured so much of my
life into Seattle Grace.
Always seemed like
a foregone conclusion
that I'd end my career
there, and I just...
I'm not ready to retire yet.
I never thought it would
be gone before I was.
How much money did they need?
What are you guys... Oh.
Folks!
You're right on time.
Come on.
Mom, come on. What is happening?
Have a seat. I'm
about to tell you.
There's a reason surgeons
are willing to roll the dice
on a risky, go-for-broke,
point-of-no-return surgery
with potentially
devastating consequences.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Dr. Webber's brought
to my attention the fact
that all of you have been
looking for an investor
to partner with
you in purchasing
Seattle Grace-Mercy
West Hospital.
It is my pleasure to tell you
that the Harper Avery
Foundation would like very much
to take you up on that offer.
What?
We have only one
condition. Only one.
Since the foundation will be
putting up the majority of the funds,
we would like a
representative of our choosing
to sit on your
board of directors.
Well, yeah...
My dears, we only have a
couple of hours to make this bid.
Do you want to
do this thing or not?
Yes. Of course. Okay, yes.
Sometimes...
Yeah. Yes.
It works.
Wow.
Wait, you woke up
me at the crack of dawn
to tell me you're coming to Seattle
to be my boss? That doesn't...
Oh, no, no, sweetheart.
You misunderstood.
The foundation is electing
you as our representative.
We're the majority shareholder.
That means you are in charge.
Wait. What?
Now give your
mama a kiss, Jackson.
She just bought you a hospital.
Hmm.