- You've reached
Dr. Helen Sharpe
at NHS Hampstead.
Please leave a message,
and I'll ring you back,
no ifs, ands, or buts.
- Voice mail
never sounded so good.
Your diction is perfect.
So long, embolic stroke.
Dr. Helen Sharpe is back.
And I can't wait
to be back with you.
Uh, I'm on my way
to meet the asset,
and I think we're gonna send
Veronica packing for good.
- You're fired.
- Yeah.
I'm gonna call you back.
Hi, there, Veronica. Sorry.
You were saying something.
- You know, I want you
and your two-bit accomplices
out of here now.
- Totally get that.
Thing is,
in your haste to acquire UMI,
you kind of forgot to read
the employee contracts that me
and my two-bit accomplices
signed.
It's funny--
I got a copy right here.
Article 17 states that,
"Employees shall be safeguarded
from termination
due to sale or merger."
So I think
that's pretty clear.
It's funny--it's kind of like
we planned it or something.
I'll see you
at the company picnic?
Is the asset secure?
- Patient room three.
- Great.
Sergeant Todd,
you sly son of a gun.
♪
- You said 0900.
It's 0930.
- Well, I'm usually
way later than that.
Sorry, won't happen again.
- So why all the subterfuge?
- Well, I know that you
and I don't see eye to eye
on most, if not all, aspects
of daily life.
- Only because
you're a socialist.
- And you are
a raging capitalist
who--who has graciously come
to hear me out,
so I'll get right to it.
Um, what do you think
about Veronica Fuentes?
She is the
leader of this organization,
and she has my support.
- Yeah, but maybe...
maybe you...
- Will that be all?
Yeah. That'll be all.
Dismissed.
Sorry. Sorry to have
wasted your time.
- Dr. Fuentes is everything
I hate in a leader.
She doesn't care
about you or me
or anyone in this hospital.
She's only
in the war for profit.
♪
- So...
- If you are asking me
if I would support
a regime change,
the answer is yes.
- Todd.
Yes!
Sorry. Socialists like to hug.
Um, okay, I think this is
the smoking gun
that is gonna finally
bring Veronica down.
These are financial records
for Urgent Medicine, Inc.,
that Veronica just acquired.
♪
- My people at the DOJ will be
very interested in this.
- Well, I was hoping
they might be.
♪
- The instructions
were no jewelry, Mum.
- So what?
Why you insist
on constantly meddling
in my personal affairs
is beyond my comprehension,
especially since,
as you so often remind me,
I'm the worst mother.
- My stroke was a wake-up call.
In spite of how healthy
we may think we are,
we must check
in with our bodies,
and regular colonoscopy--
- It's like you
want me to be ill,
because doctor-patient
is the only relationship
you understand.
- It's just
a routine colonoscopy, Mum...
and I'll be with you
every step of the way.
My face will be the first thing
you see when you wake up.
- Brilliant.
♪
- All right, then, Serwa.
Will you count backwards
from ten for me, please?
- Ten, nine, eight...
sev...
♪
- Floyd?
What are you doing
in Dad's car?
- Driving it.
- Because...?
- I need your help
with something, Cort.
- Does Mama know
you have that thing?
- No. She doesn't
know anything yet.
I'm gonna be a father.
- Like, to a baby?
- Yes, to a baby, but it...
it's complicated.
I'm--I'm gonna be involved
but there's--
there's two more parents.
The child has two other
parents,
and that means my level
of contact might not be--
- Wait, wait, wait, wait.
You haven't told Mama
any of this, have you?
- Mm-mm, no, no.
I wanted to come to you first.
See if you had a line on Dad.
- Who left our
mother swimming in debt
with three children
to raise alone?
No.
I don't have a line
on that son of a bitch,
and I don't want one.
- Look,
if you don't know anything,
then I got to talk to Mama.
- No! No.
You tell her
about your child out of wedlock
and wanting to start
something with your father,
you'll send her
to an early grave.
Don't you say a word to her.
♪
- Dr. Frome?
- Hey!
- Everything okay?
- Yeah, yeah, fine.
Just, um,
got a lot on my mind today.
Um, have you seen Trevor?
Mr. Vaughan?
- No. Would you like me
to page him?
- No. No, no. That's okay.
Thank you.
♪
- Hey, boss.
I was hoping to get some filing
under the belt
before you got in.
- Oh, yeah, okay.
Well, um,
I-I'll leave you to it.
- Is everything all right?
- Hmm?
- You're not still sketched out
about the other night, are you?
- Uh, Trevor, I, uh...
- Hey, nothing happened, Ig.
It's only weird
because someone doped us.
It's not our fault.
- So no harm, no foul,
all right?
- Yeah. No harm, no foul.
- Great. All right, then...
have a good one.
- Okay.
- You deserve it.
♪
- This your card?
- No.
- Oh, right. This is my card.
Yours was
the seven of diamonds, right?
- Right.
- Ah, yeah.
It's on the ceiling.
- What?
How did you do that?
- Magic.
Now check your pocket.
- My brother Jace--
master of "cardistry."
- The nerdy fruit
of a lonely childhood.
Oh.
- Pick a card, Doc.
- Uh, no, thanks.
- Not a magic fan?
- I prefer
to operate illusion-free.
Uh, to that end,
Isla, your labs are in.
And that pain you're feeling
in your stomach
isn't from an ulcer.
It's cirrhosis.
- My liver?
But I don't drink.
Neither of us do.
Our mom was an alcoholic.
- Yeah,
this isn't about drinking.
The type
of cirrhosis you have is
Alpha 1 Antitrypsin Deficiency.
It's a genetic disorder.
- Is it treatable?
- It is, but I'm afraid
you will have to have
a liver transplant.
Now, we can put you
on the UNOS list,
but your best bet
would be your brother.
If you're a match,
you could save her life.
- Uh, yeah, uh...
that's not gonna work.
- What?
He's joking.
- I'm not.
W-we have to find another way.
♪
- This is our son!
He's getting worse!
- His school called us.
He was confused, dizzy.
- Hey, can you tell me
your name?
- Darby.
- Heart rate's low.
- Finger stick
blood sugar--12.
- Okay, let's get him
to a room,
and let's push
an amp of D50, now.
- Uh, is he diabetic?
On insulin?
- No.
- Uh, any other meds
we should know about?
- Just human growth hormone.
He gets a shot from the school
nurse every day at lunch.
- He can't see!
My son--he can't see.
He's diabetic!
- Look at me.
- Hey, buddy. You're okay.
We're gonna take
good care of you, okay?
- Hey, Kayden,
is it getting worse?
Finger stick of 600.
- He must have missed
his insulin.
- No, Mom,
I told you I got my shot.
- Let me guess--
from the school nurse?
- Yes.
- Do You know
a kid named Darby?
- He's in Kayden's grade at
PS 441--how did you know that?
- Uh, let's get him in a room,
and let's start an IV
and 10 units of insulin Sub Q.
- The school nurse
mixed up their medications.
- Where are you going?
- To PS 441.
- Excuse me, I'm looking
for the school nurse.
- Do you have an appointment?
- No, no,
I don't have a student here.
I'm, uh, Dr. Max Goodwin
from New Amsterdam Hospital.
And, uh,
we just admitted two boys
who we believe were given the
wrong meds by the school nurse.
- Oh, my God.
Are you talking
about Kayden and Darby?
- Yeah.
It--it was a mistake.
People kept calling me
out to the desk, and I--
I must have confused--
Are they gonna be okay?
- Wait--
You're the nurse?
♪
- I'm the secretary.
Because of budget cuts,
we haven't had a licensed nurse
here for almost three years,
so I've been subbing.
- Do you have
any medical training?
- No.
But someone had to do it.
- Did you report it
to the superintendent?
He's the one who authorized it.
- Thank you
for taking the time, Dr. Frome.
- Yeah, it's my pleasure.
So Oncology forwarded me
your records, and, um...
Well, first, let me just say
that I have helped
many patients who've received
the same diagnosis as you.
And, uh, yeah,
it's a challenging time,
but navigating
through our own mortality
is always challenging.
- I'm not dying.
- Oh. I'm sorry.
I thought, uh...
I thought the cancer was, uh...
- Spontaneous recovery.
- Yeah.
- After three years,
I'm now officially...
Cancer-free.
- That's--I mean, that's--
that's incredible news.
- Congratulations.
- Uh-huh.
- Oh.
You know,
I would be willing to wager
that most people who got
that kind of news
would be overwhelmed with joy.
But that's not quite
what I'm getting here, so...
- When Dr. Schmidt first
told me I was in the clear
and I wasn't going to die,
I felt enormous relief.
I couldn't wait
to tell my family.
They had been with me
through the whole thing,
taking care of me every day.
- Support like that
can be invaluable.
- Yes. But when I told them
that I wasn't going to die,
I found out
how they really felt.
- Which was?
They actually wanted me dead.
- Oh.
♪
- How we doing over here?
- Daddy can come later.
- Okay.
- And I can go get your trains
at home.
Do you want me to stay here?
- Your friend's gonna be okay.
- He is?
- Mm-hmm.
- That sucks.
- I'm sorry.
Uh, what?
- Kayden's not my friend.
He's a bully.
- Right. He's mean to you?
- Oh, yeah.
He talks down to me,
tries to make me look stupid
in front of the other kids.
- That's awful.
- You watch.
He'll probably just try
and blame me
for what happened
with the nurse.
- How exactly--
- Dr. Bloom?
- Uh, not now.
- I was just wondering--
- You're interrupting, Casey.
Didn't I order labs, like,
an hour ago?
- Yeah, but--
- So where are they?
Thank you.
I'm sorry about that.
Um, so how exactly
does Kayden bully you?
- Like that.
- All right, I put your sister
on the UNOS list, but...
it's a long wait.
I don't know that
we'll get her a liver in time.
- I can't help her.
- Well, we won't know
until we test you.
It's not about
whether I'm a match, doctor.
My liver's shot.
♪
I'm an alcoholic.
I have been
since I was 13 years old.
- But Isla said--
- She doesn't know.
She's never known.
Because of the hell
our mother put us through,
we made a pact that we
would stay sober together.
But I never could.
- Wait, so you've been drinking
since you were 13
and your sister doesn't know?
- I'm drunk right now.
Can you tell?
No, because my tolerance
is off the chart.
I've been fooling
everyone my entire life.
My best trick.
♪
- Well, uh...
I want to test you anyway.
You may have a portion of your
liver that's still good.
- If Isla finds out
that I've been lying to her
after all these years,
I will lose her forever.
- Brother, you're gonna
lose her right now
if you don't step up, Jace.
Look, just let me test you...
please.
She's crashing.
- ALS cart flying in.
- Right behind you.
♪
- Welcome back, Mum.
- Wait. It's happened?
It's over?
- Yes. it's all done. See?
Easy peas.
- Dr. Sharpe?
Can I talk
with you for a moment?
- You will talk with me,
please.
- Serwa...
I'm afraid we found
multiple polyps in your colon
that are malignant
and have metastasized.
- Meaning?
- If we had seen you earlier,
I might be able to offer you
a different prognosis,
but I'm afraid at this stage...
your cancer is terminal.
♪
- Nice serve.
Are you Superintendent Davis?
You a parent?
- I am. Yeah.
But, fortunately,
my daughter's only three,
so she doesn't attend any
of your schools.
I'm also a doctor treating
two boys from PS 441
who ended up in the hospital
because your non-nurse
mixed up their meds.
- I, uh...
I didn't know about this.
- I'm not surprised,
but I am curious why--
why you would authorize
a secretary
with no medical training
to hand out drugs to children.
- How are the boys?
- In the hospital...
but stable.
Look, it's not just PS 441,
Dr. Goodwin.
Even if I could come up
with the money,
there are over 400
other schools in our district.
- That don't have nurses?
- They used to--
back in the day
when you and I went to school.
We've had over
a billion dollars
cut out of our budget
over the past decade.
- So w-what happens
when a kid gets sick?
- We treat them
as best as we can,
and then we send them home,
often to an empty apartment.
It's a disaster.
I mean,
is your budget on the rise?
You have any nurses
you can spare?
Didn't think so.
Look, I took an oath
to make public schools better
for our children.
I kept as many teachers
as I could,
but something had to go.
So now I come down here
every lunch break,
and I imagine that each ball
is a bureaucrat
who's taken something
important away from our kids.
- You want to hit one?
- Okay, Mr. Fontenot, thank you
very much for coming in.
I appreciate it.
I, um--I had an interesting
session with your wife,
um, but I realized
after speaking with Pauline
that I really needed
to meet the entire family.
- Oh?
- Yeah.
You know, y-your wife
had a miraculous recovery.
How has that made
everyone feel?
- Oh, blessed.
- Relieved.
- I just couldn't stop
hugging her.
- I was beyond grateful.
- Huh, okay.
So, um, since Pauline found
out that she was cancer-free,
has anyone noticed
that she was a tad depressed?
- No. No.
- Not really.
- Huh?
- Okay.
I used to love
watching the Spurs.
They're my team, right?
After Pauline
got her diagnosis,
she'd always insist
we watch something else.
I mean, how could I argue?
She had cancer.
- But when I offer
to make her dinner,
she always asks for fish.
And most of us hate fish!
- Could you believe it?
She actually asked us
to go skydiving.
And I'm terrified of heights.
But I couldn't say no
to her
because it's all
on her "bucket list."
- After a while,
we all wanted cancer.
- Um...
- Huh.
Yeah.
Uh, your tests indicate
a severely damaged liver.
85% scarred and cirrhotic.
So...I can't be a donor.
- I'm afraid not.
Our only option now
is to wait for one.
- 85% unusable.
That means 15% is good.
Can't you use some of that?
- Technically,
but that would leave you
with a minimally
functioning organ.
I mean, the slightest toxin
could kill you.
I mean, you could never have
a drink again...
you know, and given
your history,
I don't think
that's a realistic path.
♪
- I can stop drinking.
- Jace...
- I will.
I have to for her...
because if she goes...
I'll be right behind her.
♪
- So blood sugar's leveled off
in both boys.
- Yeah, I saw the labs.
- So...
Am I a bully?
- 100 %.
Why?
'Cause I don't want to be.
Well, you may not want brown
eyes either, but, you know...
- I mean, look, I know
I can be strong-willed, but...
Me, I mean, a bully? Really?
Uh, Lauren, just listen to me,
all right?
- Dr. Bloom, room seven.
- It's Darby.
What's happening to him?
- Run IV,
normal saline wide open.
Start a second IV.
- On it.
- Type and cross
a unit of red packed cells.
- O-2 sats dropping.
- I think he's choking
on his own blood.
- Help him, please.
- Come on, Darby, come on.
Stay with me.
- Mum, Mum, we are going
to deal with this.
I'm gonna call people.
There are loads of trials,
new medicines.
I can get you in
to see the best of the best.
And together we will--
- Enough!
That is enough.
- Mum, please.
Please let me help you.
Mum, where are you going?
- Home.
♪
- Mum...
- Just watch.
♪
- So this is home.
- As close as
I can get for now.
♪
When I was a little girl,
this dance, the kpanlogo,
was something
only Ga-Adangbe did.
- In Accra?
- Young people cutting up--
my grandmother would sniff.
In her mind, dancing
was only for praising God.
But it brought me to life.
We'd have to sneak
so she wouldn't catch us.
When we moved to London,
I thought I'd become
a professional.
- You wanted to be a dancer?
Why am I only just
hearing about this now?
- I grew up.
Things change.
- What changed?
- I met your father.
♪
- Come on, Mum.
Wote.
♪
- Darby's gonna be okay.
- What happened?
- The bleeding was caused
by an ulcer in his stomach.
We managed to stop the bleed,
so he's gonna be fine, but...
- But we can't let
this happen again.
Ah, look, we appreciate
you all coming down.
After meeting
with your superintendent,
I think I have a better idea
of how this happened.
We've been dealing with
a shortage in nurses ourselves,
and to combat
that problem,
we've had to bring out a number
of student nurses
and volunteers.
- Can you send us one?
- Well, we're hoping
to send you a whole bunch.
- From where?
- From this room.
- I'm sure many of you
are volunteering at the school
in other ways.
Uh, PTA, fundraising...
- Yeah,
but no one here's a nurse.
- You don't have to be.
All you need is
some basic medical training.
And, look, for those who
are willing, we can offer it.
Here at New Amsterdam,
you can become CNA's--
certified nursing assistants.
- But many of us have jobs,
more than one.
How could we--
- Chipping in
just an hour a day,
one day a week,
we can make this work.
And we know it's not an ideal
situation, but it's a Band-Aid.
And Band-Aids serve a purpose.
They help keep things
together, so...
So who's in?
♪
- You said
that during your illness,
your family was always there
to support you, right?
Always by your side?
- They were, yes.
- Well, that's pretty easy
to get used to, isn't it?
People doing what you want
whenever you want it--
that's powerful stuff.
But now that you're healthy,
it is important
to give those same people the
space to attend to their needs.
- Pauline, why are you crying?
- Because you're agreeing
with them.
T-this is why they
don't want me around anymore.
- Okay.
Okay.
Let me ask you this.
Before the cancer,
what would happen
if you didn't want to watch
the Spurs game
with your husband?
- We'd watch anyway.
- And if you wanted fish
and everybody else
wanted steak?
- I'd eat steak.
- Did you ever push back
on this?
- I'd go along.
- Your generation
was taught that it was rude
to ask for what they wanted.
When you got cancer
and you finally did ask for it,
they gave it to you.
That had to feel
pretty darn good, right?
- More than good.
It made me feel alive
for the very first time.
- Well, that's ironic,
isn't it?
- Huh.
- Considering you were dying.
Pauline, you know, you spent
your entire life
bending over backwards
to support
the ones that you love,
and then you
got sick with cancer,
and those people
worked overtime
trying to do the same for you
to support you.
- I can't go
back to the way it was.
- No, nor should you.
But you need to figure out how
to take turns
supporting each other now.
Balance.
And when that works,
do you know what we call it?
Family.
♪
Whoo!
Now, that was fun.
Oh, I've sweated
straight through my knickers!
Helen.
You're not the only one.
- Right.
So this is who you really are,
you little sneaker.
All these years...
- I once read that the
best gift you can give a child
is to let them know you.
- Yes.
Yes, Mum.
- I didn't do that.
- No.
No, you most certainly did not.
So I say
we bring extra knickers,
and we make this
a regular once-a-week thing.
- This was lovely today, Helen.
- Yes.
- But this must remain mine.
Why must you
always shut me out?
Honestly, it's...
it's so confounding.
I mean, my marks
at school were always...
"good but not perfect."
Whenever I needed a hug,
you would chide
that I was too needy.
And you're always
going on and on
about how much
you had to sacrifice
so I could get
my fancy degrees, but now...
now you won't even let me
use them to help you.
I...
I can't keep begging you
to love me, Mum.
- Child, you don't have to.
You have my love, always.
- Please...
- It's true.
It may not be how you want,
but it's there...
in a gaze or a smile
when you're not looking.
♪
I marvel at what
you have become, Helen.
♪
You are magnificent.
You are my greatest joy...
♪
And deepest pain.
Welcome back, Mum.
- Did it happen?
Is it over?
- Yes, it's all done.
Everything went famously.
- So, uh, as expected, you are
in blindingly good health.
Clean as a whistle.
- Oh, Mum.
What a relief.
L-let's get you some water.
- Healthy lobe
ready for transplant.
- I'll get this
to Dr. Flores' OR.
- Should do Isla quite well.
And enough liver left over
to sustain
a hopefully sober Jace.
Let's go ahead
and close him up.
Give me a 3-0 vicryl
on a needle driver.
- Dr. Reynolds,
this doesn't look right.
- Oh, no. What's left
of his liver...
is dying.
Hepatic artery's hardened.
Must be a blood clot that's
choking off the blood supply.
Give me one milligram of TPA.
♪
Just give it a minute.
- It's getting darker.
- It's gone.
With no viable liver,
he won't clear anesthesia.
He'll never wake up.
♪
Close him up.
Let's get him ready
for post op...
so his sister can say goodbye.
- Hey, Max.
So I just got word
that the DOJ is sending a bunch
of FINCEN agents in order
to seize our financial records.
- That's odd--maybe it has
something to do
with your new acquisition.
- Okay, you do not want to go
down this road.
- You choose profit
over people,
never care or compassion
or any of the principles
that this hospital
was founded on.
And if you had,
then maybe you would have done
your due diligence.
- Of what?
- Your new asset.
UMI--it's a vast
money-laundering operation,
and you bought it
with public funds.
So now you have exposed
this hospital
to some serious
criminal negligence.
- No.
You were running UMI,
so this is all on you.
I was just
a concerned employee
who blew the whistle.
Excuse me.
- Max, look...
just call off the feds,
and I'll make you
co-medical director.
No, thanks.
- Okay, then choose somebody
that you trust and--
- Nope.
- Max, I'll resign.
♪
You call off this raid,
and I will walk
out of this building,
and you will never, ever hear
a word from me again.
- That's not enough.
- What do you want from me?
- What I want is for you
to never run
another public hospital again.
- Max.
They're here.
♪
- You sure I can't eat
real food?
- Yeah, I'd take it easy
for a couple of days.
No solids, only fluids.
You're a tough kid, Darby.
Don't let anyone tell you
any different, okay?
- Thank you, Dr. Bloom.
- And, uh, some of us
got to talking...
- We saw
how short-staffed you are,
and you still went
the extra mile for our son.
- So we figured
if you can do it, so can we.
- You got your volunteers.
♪
- Wow.
Dr. Reynolds?
- Are you sure
your name isn't Lazarus?
- What? Why?
How's Isla?
- Oh, no, she's doing fine.
But you, my friend,
you shouldn't be here.
- Um, what's the trick?
- I was certain
you weren't gonna wake up.
Then your vitals
started improving,
and so I just took this
and waved it over you,
and, look, look at that.
You see that there?
That's an ectopic liver.
That is a second liver
outside your old one.
That's a rare genetic anomaly.
That is hard to spot
and one hell of a lucky break.
- It's also why you managed
to drink so much over the years
and not really feel
the effects.
♪
- Does Isla know
about my drinking?
- No. Not yet.
- So, technically,
with this second liver,
I shouldn't have to tell her.
- Oh, man.
♪
Look, secrets aren't good
for any family, Jace.
♪
You believe in magic?
- I believe I can get you
to believe in it.
Illusions don't come
from magic.
They come from hours
and hours of work.
- That's right.
Right, so...
magic is just putting
in the time
to create a miraculous result.
And I would imagine that
getting sober's a lot
like that, too.
And, hey,
since you've already proven
that you can put in the time...
I'd lean into the truth
and see what kind of magic
that can bring.
♪
- The good news is,
you will not have to have
another one of those
for ten years.
We do, however, need to get you
scheduled in for a mammogram.
- The NHS has an array
of perfectly adequate doctors
my GP can refer me to.
- But, Mum--
- Helen...
I know you love me.
You don't have to keep trying
to prove it.
Walk with me.
- Where?
- There's this place
I'd like to show you.
Wote.
- ♪ Speechless
♪ I wonder if you feel...
- Hey. I'm out, Ig.
Have a good night.
- Uh, yeah, Trevor, hang on.
Would you mind?
Can we--can we talk a second?
Uh-oh.
Of course.
What's up?
Um...
You were--you were
very gracious this morning.
Um, but I--
I have to be real with you.
I have been seeing a therapist,
and I've been trying to repair
damage done to my marriage.
I've let the attention that
you give me get into my head,
and it has started to affect...
my relationship with my family.
- Oh, man, I'm--I'm sorry.
- Yeah.
I have a lot of work
to do on myself.
And I don't think...
♪
I can't work with you anymore.
And so I'm going to call HR--
- You're gonna call HR?
Why are you gonna call HR?
- Uh, nothing, I'm just
gonna tell them the truth.
I'm gonna tell them that
I hired a very qualified nurse
who I have chemistry with
and who's attention
I have clearly been enjoying
in an inappropriate way
and that it's not healthy
for anybody.
Hasn't my work been any good?
- Your work
has been fine, Trevor.
♪
It's not why
you hired me, is it?
♪
- No, no.
Everybody thinks
you are such a nice guy,
but you're not, are you?
♪
I quit.
- Hey.
♪
Hey. What's up?
- I'm really sorry
for bullying you.
- What?
Oh, no, no, no--
- I mean, I had no idea.
- No, Lauren, I--
- No, listen to me, okay?
I...
I had a real problem
with this when I was a kid.
I mean, I was not nice.
I had a lot of anger
towards my mother,
and I took it out
on the other kids.
Then as I got older,
I just--
I thought I'd moved past it,
you know?
- You have.
- Well, clearly, I haven't.
I mean, you said so yourself.
Lauren, uh,
I was messing with you.
- You were?
- Yeah!
Yeah, you're not a bully.
You're bossy, super impatient,
moody, temperamental.
I can go on and on,
but the point is,
is that bullies go out
of their way to hurt people.
They prey on the vulnerable.
You lift people up--
Brunstetter, Leyla, Walsh...
me.
- You were joking?
- Hey. Hey, come on, now--
- Well, it wasn't funny, okay?
- Listen, you set me up. I--
- Get out of here, okay?
Get out of here...
- Okay.
- Before I actually get mad
and start yelling!
- It was a little funny.
A little funny--
un poquititofunny.
- Mm-hmm.
- Un poco,a little bit.
- Nope.
- A little funny. You laughed.
You're laughing now.
See you later, boss!
Oh, God.
Hey.
Sorry, I know you're sleeping
I just wanted to tell you
that, uh, it's...
it's over.
I'm coming home.
And I can't wait to wrap
my arms around you.
Uh, I'm gonna call you back,
but I love you.
Todd!
Are the, uh, agents still here?
- No.
They left.
- Oh, well, I just wanted
to thank them and you for--
- Actually,
they wanted me to thank you...
for alerting
them to this issue.
- What?
- They're concluding
the investigation.
It seems they are going
to monitor
the situation going forward.
- But they're shutting down
UMI, right?
I mean, they're making arrests?
This is fraud.
Our shareholders--
- Someone called them off.
Uh...
You--you read
the documents, right?
I mean, am I...crazy?
This is criminal.
- Do you know who owns
the other franchises of UMI?
Right.
And you never will
because UMI is too big.
It's in all 50 states.
It's owned by politicians,
corporations,
even doctors.
Everyone is making a profit,
and it seems everyone is
willing to look the other way
to keep the profits flowing.
- So what are we supposed
to do now?
♪
- Well, you can start
by getting out of my office.
♪