Hey, Bert.
What are you doing?
These two people
went through
a terrible divorce,
they haven't talked
to each other for a year.
I just want them to
be happy. That's it.
Sharon?
Bert?
Toddler in Treatment Six.
Parents just got here.
If there are natural
options without side effects,
we try those first.
Perhaps a more
immediate treatment...
You mean antibiotics? No.
On the outside, he may look
normal, but on the inside,
pneumonia is notorious
for its slow progression.
You scare people
with diagnoses
and then you sell them
on treatments they don't need.
This is
the second time this month
that parents have lost faith
in your judgment.
No more. We're going home.
He needs these
antibiotics. Now!
No!
Hey!
Security!
Are you out of your mind?
It's okay, buddy.
Everything's gonna
be all right.
Open this door!
Well? Where are we?
In a better position
than we were four hours
ago, but barely.
Lucky for you, Kalmick
did some quick maneuvering
and wrangled up
a court order
to treat Lucas.
Well, that's a relief.
Still, there's no excuse
for your extremely
reckless behavior.
I made every effort to keep
Dr. Manning on a short leash.
I understand my actions
appear rash...
You locked that boy
in a room!
I didn't have a choice.
Kidnapped him
from his guardians.
They were risking his life!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Why don't we all just bring it
down a few notches, okay?
Dr. Manning, you understand
administering antibiotics
against the parents' wishes
and before securing
a court order
left this hospital open
for a major lawsuit.
Lucas' parents gave me
no other options.
Okay? They were unwilling
to accept the diagnosis
and wanted to leave
the hospital.
Well, she's right about that.
I want that boy discharged
as soon as possible.
Not so fast.
If you are in any way
compromised,
you need to recuse yourself
from this case immediately.
I assure you,
my medical judgment is sound.
I hope for Lucas' sake, and
your own, that that's true.
Hey, I heard what happened.
I don't need another
lecture right now.
I wasn't gonna lecture you.
I was gonna offer to talk...
I don't need to be supervised,
and I don't need your help.
Hey. Just cleared
two more shelves for you.
Can you just give me the guest
room closet? His and hers.
All yours, have at it.
And after we're married,
you know we're getting
a bigger place, right?
With a lot of closets.
Ah, yes, ma'am.
Good news. I got out of
pulling a double tomorrow.
Dinner and a movie?
I can't. Training a new nurse.
How about Saturday?
I got that Navy
recruiting event.
I do have a lunch break
from 1:00 to 1:30.
What are we gonna do
with half an hour?
Oh... I have some ideas.
See...
Time to hit
the pavement! Hurry up!
The gentle sounds
of Noah in the morning.
Coming! Bye.
Bye. Have fun.
What happened to
all that noise you
were talking? Keep up!
Hey, did you
hear that?
Yeah.
It's coming from the alley.
Come on! Get up!
I changed my mind!
I'm going to follow him!
Hey! Get off of her!
Hey!
Punk bitch.
Get off her!
Come on, come on. Let's go!
Call 9-1-1.
Okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
I'm calling.
No police!
Please! I'm illegal.
Okay. Okay, all right.
Hey. We work at the hospital.
We'll keep you safe. Okay?
No!
End the call, April.
What if they come back?
Just do it. Hey, hey.
What's your name?
Jacinta...
Jacinta, just stay put
and let me check you out,
okay? I'm a doctor.
Deep head lac.
Use this.
All right, look. We really
need to get you to the
emergency room, all right?
No!
I'm fine.
Jacinta?
Hey, hey, hey.
Jacinta, Jacinta!
Come on, man.
Come on, come on.
Stay with us. Jacinta.
Jacinta. Stay with me.
Come on, come on.
The bleeding's stopped.
IV bag is out,
I'll grab another.
Okay.
Where am I?
Jacinta, I'm Dr. Sexton.
My sister and I,
we found you after you'd been
attacked this morning.
You're at the hospital.
The hospital?
Yeah.
No. No. I can't be here.
It's okay.
We didn't call the police.
But you shouldn't
move right now.
You suffered a small
pneumothorax.
A collapsed lung.
I don't feel anything.
We gave you some
morphine for the pain.
Your lung should
re-expand on its own,
but you really need to
stay in bed for a while.
Meantime, you want to tell us
what happened this morning?
It's okay. I know it's hard.
Take your time.
You wanna start with
where you were heading?
To a friend's house.
Should we notify your friend?
No.
I don't want them
to see me like this.
Okay.
Hold that elevator.
Morning.
Sharon, again,
I swear on my life,
I had not a clue that CeCe
was gonna invite Bert
to dinner last night.
I found out literally a minute
before you walked in the door.
Yeah, so...
Literally, a minute.
So you said.
And now, you know,
he's asked me out for a drink.
Well, are you gonna go?
Of course not.
All right, somehow,
CeCe got it into her head
that, you know, you guys
need to get back together.
That it'd make you happy.
Is that what she thinks?
Listen. I am not defending
her actions or saying
I agree, I just...
I just hope you
understand that her heart
is in the right place.
Look, Daniel, uh,
I think it's wonderful
that you and CeCe found
your way back to one other,
I really do, but that's not
gonna happen with me and Bert.
I get it.
Good.
Then tell her, no more
surprise reunions.
You got it.
Dr. Charles, good morning.
Mmm. At least somebody's
happy to see me.
Huh?
What's up?
Doris told me
there's a patient
in Treatment Three
that's asking for you.
A Titus Witherdale.
Oh.
Not exactly
a name that you
hear every day.
No, it isn't. Grew up
down the street from me.
Shoot me his chart, will you?
Done.
He used to play soccer
with my little brother.
Titus... Witherdale.
I go by Claire now.
I'm sorry.
It's fine. Um, it's still
Titus on the insurance.
I haven't finished the process
of legally changing my name.
Good to see you, Dan.
Well, it is really good
to see you, too, Claire.
Ah, so, how you been?
I retired a little
over a year ago.
Ah. Congratulations.
Yeah. It was time to focus
on other areas of my life.
I hope I didn't pull you
away from anything?
It's just, I find doctors
can be a bit intrusive.
And I remember you as being
so sweet and respectful.
Oh. That's nice of you to say.
Um, so, what brings you
in here today? You sound
a little short of breath.
Yeah, it's been on and off
the last few weeks.
And, uh, I've had some pain
on the left side of my chest.
It's probably nothing, but...
Why don't I just...
I'll take a little listen?
Um, full disclosure,
I'm actually a psychiatrist,
but on a good day,
I still know my way
around a stethoscope.
So, why don't you put this on
and I'll be back in a few.
Oh, jeez.
You all right?
I...
It just it really hurts.
Okay. Okay. Lie back,
lie back. Legs up. Legs up.
Oh, jeez.
Here we go.
Oh, God.
Dr. Choi! I need you!
Phillip? What are
you doing here?
Well, I know I shouldn't
stop by unannounced,
but I just wanted to
bring you breakfast
'cause I know you were
working late last night.
And brought you
your favorite, chilaquiles.
Thank you.
And what is that for?
Our six-month anniversary.
Phillip, I'm so sorry.
I just... My head is all over
the place right now.
It's okay. That's all right.
You don't need to apologize.
We're still on
for dinner tonight?
Honestly, I don't know
how today's gonna pan out.
I mean, my patient
isn't even discharged yet,
and I have so much work.
It's okay.
You don't need to say
another word. I get it.
Just keep me posted, okay?
Sure.
Okay, well,
I'll leave you to it.
Bye.
Here we go, incoming.
Will, Crockett, you're going
to Baghdad. Level one MVC.
Copy.
David Bridges. Twenty-year-old
male. Car rolled. Ejected out
the side window.
Wild guess. No seat belt?
Correct.
GCS, three. HR, 125. BP, 100
over 72. Sats, 100 percent.
Tried to clean
him up for you guys,
but some of that glass
is in there pretty deep.
Appreciate the effort.
David, can you hear me, bud?
All right.
Transfer on my count.
One, two, three.
Thanks, guys.
Yep.
Bilateral
breath sounds.
Hey, David, can you hear me,
bud? Can you open
your eyes for me?
Fluid in his belly.
All right, let's find
the source of the bleed.
Chest and pelvis X-ray.
While this pressure's
still holding, let's
send him over to CT.
Get a panscan. Get a type
and cross, CBC, CMP, coags,
and a urine tox.
Hold on a second.
He's got a "No Blood"
card in his wallet.
He's a Jehovah's Witness.
Doris, let me see that.
Okay, card's almost
a decade old.
It was signed by his parents
when he was still a minor.
All right, well let's
get them down here
and ask 'em about it then.
Meantime, let's see what
the scans show, hope things
don't go from bad to worse.
Dr. Manning?
Yeah?
Lucas' latest labs.
How's he looking?
His temp just spiked again
to 102.2. Higher than before.
His sputum gram stain
came back negative.
It's not pneumonia.
I can double-check
with the lab.
No. No, that's okay. Just...
Okay. If it's not pneumonia,
but... Let me think.
What am I missing?
Draw a lactic acid and, um,
repeat blood cultures.
Keep his fluids at 100 and add
vancomycin to his antibiotics.
You think he's septic?
We're operating under that
assumption. For now.
Should I call Dr. Lanik?
No.
That is not necessary.
Hey. Check this out.
Looked Jacinta up.
She was admitted here in '07
with a case of food poisoning.
I thought she was
terrified of hospitals.
Yeah. And get this, she listed
a social security number.
Was it real?
Yeah.
Turns out she was
born in Indiana.
I don't get it. Why would
someone lie about
being undocumented?
Unless they really needed
to avoid the police.
I'm still waiting on your
second set of cardiac labs,
but it looks like you've had
a small heart attack.
Oh, my God.
All those
late nights at the office
and greasy takeout.
Didn't do myself
any favors, I guess.
Well, but you're
retired now, right?
So, plenty of time to
focus on turning it around.
Yeah.
We're gonna send you
up to the cath lab
so Cardiology can take
a closer look at the
vessels in your heart.
Oh, sorry, I must have
the wrong room. I thought
the nurse said that...
Excuse me, miss...
Oh, my God.
Melinda?
Wait.
Titus?
What's my ex-wife doing here?
You didn't have
an emergency contact
listed on your intake form.
I just used the most recent
contact in your records.
I'll be right back, okay?
Right back.
Excuse me. Melinda?
Melinda,
it's Melinda, isn't it?
Melinda, hi. I'm Dr. Charles.
I'm one of the doctors who's
looking after Claire today.
Claire?
That's his...
I mean, her name?
Yeah. Listen. Do you have
a few minutes, maybe
for a cup of coffee?
Okay.
Hey.
You all right?
Yeah, thanks. All good.
You're talking to the queen
of "got it all together."
Can't put one over on me.
Maggie.
I have been a terrible friend.
I am so sorry.
I should have known something
was going on. I feel awful.
Stop it.
You've got nothing
to apologize for.
I did my best to keep
my cancer under wraps,
and you had a lot going on.
I promise to fill you
in on everything.
Okay.
Now, spill it.
I was wrong about
Lucas' diagnosis.
I have been combing through
case reports and trying to
make sense of his symptoms,
and I'm just at a loss.
What if it is just
a sinus infection?
What if when I locked
Lucas in that room,
a small part of me
was doing it to just...
I don't know...
Prove Will wrong?
Absolutely not.
No matter what
you've got going on,
you would never jeopardize
a patient to prove a point.
Trust your instincts.
I've never seen them
steer you wrong.
Thanks, Mags.
Come on.
Hey, Monique. Will you
set up a punch biopsy?
I wanna sample the rash
on Lucas' arm. See if that
gives us any direction.
You got it.
Thanks.
Oh, baby.
Mr. and Mrs. Bridges, your
son suffered significant
laceration to the spleen.
Now, we already took him
to interventional radiology
to embolize it,
but he's still
actively bleeding.
I bought him that car
when he started pioneering.
I kept telling him
to get those tires checked.
Pioneering?
Spreading the ministry.
David has a real gift
for connecting with people.
What can you do for our son?
Well, we need
consent to operate,
which will require
giving David blood.
No. As Witnesses, we can't
accept any blood products.
Mr. and Mrs. Bridges, I wanna
make sure you understand
the severity of
David's condition.
Without this surgery,
it's unlikely he will survive.
We'll pray.
Listen, I'm a man
of faith myself.
But if you're praying
for a miracle...
We don't pray for miracles.
We pray that Jehovah will
sustain and comfort David.
Baby.
You went through my stuff?
I didn't. I was
just itemizing...
Just stay outta my business!
Jacinta, we just
wanna help you.
That's all we're trying to do.
I gotta go.
If they find me here...
If who finds you?
Is someone after you?
Listen, if you're in
some kind of trouble...
I promise you we won't judge.
And anything you say
stays confidential.
They...
They were jumping me in.
It's how you become legit.
Jumping you in?
Like a gang initiation?
You let them do this to you?
I knew you wouldn't get it!
Okay, look, I'm sorry.
You're right.
We do not know the first
thing about your life,
what you've been through.
But we really want to.
If you just...
If you just trust us.
I always felt Titus was
keeping something from me.
I tried so hard to
get him to let me in,
but eventually, I just
couldn't take it anymore.
Constantly being shut out.
Why didn't he trust me enough
to share this with me?
A lot of times, when we
hide who we really are,
it's because
we fear rejection.
We're scared of losing the
people that we love the most.
I'm not saying
it would have been easy.
I think I would have
tried to understand.
Well, maybe you have
that opportunity now.
No. It's too late.
Thanks for the coffee,
Dr. Charles.
You take good care of her.
You update that for me?
So, what? That's it?
We're just gonna
let David die?
Not up to us.
You heard his parents.
We just gotta hope
he turns around on his own.
What about using pressors
to get through the operation?
Hemoglobin's too low.
He needs blood and surgery.
I do one without the other,
I'm not a surgeon,
I'm an executioner.
How can you accept this?
Those folks obviously
love their boy.
So, way I see it, if they're
willing to take this chance...
No. You mean if they're
willing to risk his life.
For the Bridges,
the consequences
of receiving blood
are worse than death.
May not like it,
but we do have to respect it.
You may need a little
refresher in medical ethics.
Lucas, honey?
Desatted down to 89.
Call respiratory
for a breathing treatment.
Oh, my God. Honey.
You said it was pneumonia!
Why is it getting worse?
The tests don't
support pneumonia.
I knew it!
What?
Yeah, but your son
is still very ill.
What is wrong with him?
Well, coughing up blood could
be a bleeding disorder...
You expect us to
believe a word you say?
He's worse because you're
pumping him full of
antibiotics he doesn't need!
Get that IV out of my son!
Is everything okay in here?
We're leaving.
Come on,
let's go, Janet.
It's my understanding
Dr. Manning has a court order
to treat this child.
I don't give a damn
about any court order.
I am taking my son.
No, you can't!
Sir?
Get your hands off me!
Earl, please remove
Mr. and Mrs. Harper
from the room.
I'm sorry, but if you
take Lucas home,
you are putting him in serious
danger. I need to scope him.
Don't you lay
another finger on him.
Hurry. You won't
have much time.
Monique, transfer him to the
PICU and prepare the scope.
Dr. Manning, are you sure...
Do it! Now!
It's okay, sweetie.
When I aged
out of foster care,
I had nowhere to go.
Was living out of my car,
but I had to sell it.
You didn't have any
family you could call?
Just my cousin,
Angel. That's who
I'm crashing with now.
He's part of the gang?
He brought me in.
Yeah, they're my family now.
What if you found
somewhere else to stay?
You can't just quit.
They'll kill you before
they let you out.
Excuse me? Miss Nieves,
you have some visitors.
Angel.
Hey, cuz, how you doin'?
I'm fine. I didn't
even wanna come here.
Get dressed. We're bouncing.
Hey, I'm Dr. Sexton.
Jacinta actually needs to stay
and rest for a while.
Oh, I promise you, Doc,
I'll take good care
of her at home.
She's like a little
sister to me.
Did you ever get
Miss Nieves' labs back yet?
No. The lab's been pretty
backed up, but I can call
and see if they'll rush it.
Sorry, but we have to go.
You can call her
when you get the results...
It's really better
that she waits.
We just need to rule out
anything serious.
Hey, man, you want her
healthy, don't you?
Fine. We'll stick around.
Okay, I will show you
to the waiting room.
Damn it, man!
You should've just
left me how I was.
You shoulda let them finish
what they started.
They were beating you.
That's better than what
they're gonna do to me now.
What are you talking about?
If they don't get
to jump you in,
they sex you in.
Did you push the Versed?
Yes. We're ready to go.
All right, let's take
a look at his lungs.
Natalie, wait!
Lucas' parents
had their lawyer
look into the court order.
They just found out that
you started treating him
prior to having it.
The police are on their way.
Then this is my last chance.
I have to figure out
what's wrong with Lucas.
Okay.
Almost there.
Oh, my God.
There is massive amounts
of bloody inflammation
in his airways.
This is no sinus infection.
It never was.
Dr. Halstead?
David Bridges' tox screen.
Hey, cath lab just
sent Claire's results.
What are we looking at?
Significant coronary
artery disease.
Cardiology placed
several stents.
And there's something else.
Claire's been taking
feminizing hormone therapy
for a little over a year.
And coronary artery
disease is a possible
contraindication.
And cardiology is advising
that she go off the hormones.
Does she know yet?
Not yet.
I'd like to be there
when you tell her.
Of course.
Hey, look at this.
I don't think
David's a practicing
Jehovah's Witness.
Because there's booze in his
system? That's a big reach.
His blood alcohol level's
three times the legal limit.
And he tested
positive for marijuana.
So, he isn't winning Witness
of the Year. Doesn't mean
he left the faith.
And his tattoo? You know
what it is? A symbol
for the Holy Trinity.
Witnesses don't believe
in the Trinity doctrine.
Someone's been studying up.
What if he converted
and didn't tell his parents?
Speculation, at best.
A tattoo is not
an advanced directive.
Look, fact is, David was
in the ED less than a year
ago with strep throat,
and put his parents down
as his emergency contact.
That was strep throat.
I doubt he imagined
they'd be choosing
whether he lives or dies.
Yeah, nobody ever does.
But if it were me
lying in that bed,
I'd want my family
making that call, not you.
Take this down
to the lab. Quickly.
You got it.
Stop right there,
Dr. Manning.
Lucas! You scoped him?
We told her not to!
Dr. Manning, I'm sorry,
but you need to come with us.
Hold on.
What are the charges?
Unlawful restraint, as well as
medical assault and battery.
Please, Mr. and Mrs. Harper,
Lucas has clots
and inflammation
in his lungs and airways.
This is not a sinus infection.
It is far more serious.
We want our son
discharged now.
Let's go, Dr. Manning.
No, please, if you wanna help
your son, okay,
just wait for the labs
to come back.
Do not take him
out of the hospital. Please.
I'll page Peter Kalmick
and have him meet
her at the station.
Absolutely not.
Excuse me?
The hospital's not
gonna protect her.
She got herself
into this mess. She can
get herself out of it.
Get out of my face!
Hey, I'm not asking you.
I ain't goin' nowhere.
You can either come
with us voluntarily
or you go in cuffs.
I told you not
to call the cops.
I was not gonna
let you put that girl
or yourself at risk.
The cops can protect her
better than we can. Noah...
Where'd Jacinta go?
Didn't you discharge her?
Wait, why do I have to
go off the hormones?
I thought you said they
were not responsible
for my heart disease.
They're not.
But because of
your severe atherosclerosis,
we want to
mitigate any factors
that increase your risk
of developing a clot.
What if I'm willing
to take the risk?
That's your choice
to make, Claire.
But the next heart attack
will probably kill you.
Claire?
I'm sorry I didn't tell you.
I'm sorry, too.
I'm sorry I left you.
It's okay.
Mrs. Harper...
There's nothing more to say.
We've been put through enough.
I understand why
you'd feel that way,
but are you 100 percent sure
you wanna sign those papers?
We have always tried
to do right by our son.
We would never, ever
do anything to hurt him.
I know you wouldn't.
And I'm sorry you felt
that your devotion to your
son was in question.
You know, it isn't fair,
the medical community's
dismissal of holistic
treatments.
And it's created a lot of
mistrust on both sides.
Which is deeply unfortunate,
because it isn't an
either/or situation.
There's a place for both.
I just don't know
what to believe anymore.
All I want is for
my son to be okay.
Yes, I know.
And right now, your son
needs more than you
can give him at home.
Now, I'm not gonna
defend the way Dr. Manning
handled this, I can't.
But regardless
of your differences,
I'm asking you to trust
that you have the same goals.
Everything that Dr. Manning
did was to save your son.
Did you find Jacinta?
No.
Noah, I'm sorry...
I told you I had it covered.
You didn't give
me any details.
See?
That's the problem,
right there.
You still see me as some
knucklehead kid that you
have to micromanage.
You were making
a huge mistake.
Then it was my
mistake to make.
Just back off
and let me breathe.
So, wait you're saying
no one has seen him at his
Kingdom Hall in months?
Has anyone tried
to contact him?
Well, what...
Dr. Halstead!
I'm sorry, Mr. Baker,
I gotta go.
Excuse me.
BP is down 72 over 47.
Heart rate is 148.
Twenty-five grams of albumin
and start him on Neo.
Page Dr. Marcel.
If we don't operate on David
within the next few minutes,
he will die.
We already told you,
it goes against
our son's wishes.
I don't believe
you know your son's wishes.
What are you talking about?
David stopped pioneering.
I just spoke
with the Overseer
at his congregation.
David hasn't turned in
a service report in months.
And when he crashed,
he was drunk and high.
No, no. I don't understand
any of this. There
must be some mistake.
What about this?
Why would he put
this heresy on his body?
Because he no longer
shares your beliefs.
It's not right
he should die for them.
Okay.
What'd you do?
The Bridges have
abandoned their son.
We now have the authority
to make all decisions
on David's care.
Do the surgery
and transfuse him.
Open the Hybrid OR.
Let's move.
Let's go.
Maggie.
Nat.
They said the charges
were dropped?
Yeah. Goodwin.
She worked her magic.
And what about Lucas?
Is he okay? Did the
lab results come back?
Along with the rash biopsy,
Lucas has an autoimmune
disorder, granulomatosis
with polyangiitis.
GPA?
Yeah.
Wow.
I have never seen
an actual case before.
Untreated, it would have
attacked all of his organs.
So, the parents came around?
Yeah. Lucas has already
started plasmapheresis.
You saved his life, Nat.
But, wait, I can still live
without my spleen?
Absolutely.
You're gonna be just fine.
Can I see my mom and dad?
Are they here yet?
David, I'm sorry to tell you,
they were here, but they left.
I don't understand.
Why would they leave?
When they found out
you were no longer
a Jehovah's Witness...
What?
What are you talking about?
Well, we knew you'd need blood
during the surgery.
Blood?
You gave me blood?
Oh, I can't. I can't.
No! No, no, no, no. No!
Okay, David.
Take it easy, buddy, okay?
Take it easy.
I'm sorry, David.
You had alcohol and marijuana
in your system,
and the tattoo
on your chest...
That was a mistake!
I was gonna get that removed!
I was lost for a while,
but I was finding my way back.
I was gonna repent.
What have you done to me?
Hey.
Any interest in
a quick cocktail?
Ugh. Not tonight, thanks.
It was a rough day.
Oh.
Okay. Well, uh,
another time then.
Hey, Daniel?
How about you?
How was your day?
My day?
Um, well, you know,
since you're asking,
I think that I'm...
I might've just witnessed
something kind of remarkable.
Yeah?
Yeah. Two people who had
hurt each other greatly,
I think, becoming a source of
real comfort to each other.
Food for thought, eh?
Night, Sharon.
Okay. Guest room's
right over here.
Bathroom is down
the hall to the right.
And the futon's kind of old,
but it's comfy.
Oh, and if you get cold,
there's an extra blanket
in the bottom drawer.
This is just for
a couple of days.
So you can rest and heal.
Then we'll find a way
to get you out of town.
Dr. Sexton...
It's Noah.
Noah. Thank you.
Thank you so much.
He's doing well.
Good.
I promised Phillip
I'd meet him for dinner.
Hey, you told me
to trust my instincts.
And you should.
Okay. Then that's
what I have to do.
Sharon. You came.
Well, I wasn't sure
I was going to.
Please.
You still take
your whisky neat?
Better make it a double.
Yeah.
Excuse me, miss?
Whiskey, double?
Whiskey double.
Oh, good. I hate
to drink alone.
No, thanks.
We're off duty.
It'll be all right.
Oh.
Well, come on, you can say it.
Oh, I don't like to kick a man
when he's down.
Especially when it looks like
he's beaten me to it.
Besides, you did
save that boy's life.
Yeah, but he thinks
it's cost him
his eternal life.
I was convinced David
was no longer a Witness.
I couldn't accept the choice
his parents were making.
Yeah, you weren't
altogether wrong.
You heard the kid, you know,
he was questioning his faith.
I did the same thing
to Natalie.
What's that?
I wanted to believe,
because of her TBI,
that she didn't remember
she still loved me.
The truth is,
she chose Phillip.
Right, that night in my car,
she was coming to tell me
she was engaged,
show me her ring.
I didn't wanna accept it.
I don't know
what she was gonna say to you,
but I do know she wasn't gonna
show you any ring.
What are you talking about?
Hey! Do you need
a second to change?
We can always go
back to your place.
I think the reservations
will be held for, like,
15 minutes or something.
No. I'm not going to dinner.
Oh!
Is everything okay
with your patient?
Yeah. My patient's fine.
It's about us.
What about us?
On the surface,
everything seems perfect,
but in my gut, it just
doesn't feel right.
I'm sorry, Phillip, but I have
to trust my instincts.
I can't marry you.
Natalie, can...
Please just leave it
at that. I'm sorry.
Natalie!
He's been lying to you.
What?
He slipped the ring
on your finger
when you were unconscious.
I don't...
Wait, I don't understand.
What does he mean?
You never said
you'd marry him.
He made you think that.
Is that true?
No. Of course not.
Natalie, look at him,
he's jealous.
He's looking at you right now
and lying to you.
You know what? It doesn't
matter. Because it's over.
Hey! Natalie.
Hey, you stay away from her.
From the moment
I met him...
Just stop.
Look, I'm sorry. I just...
I should've done something.
No!
Said something.
Here you are again
trying to save me!
I can take care of myself.
I don't need your help.
I don't want your help.
Please.
Just get out of my life.