Will!
Owen! Hi!
Oh, you're getting so big.
Might be time for you
to start playing football.
No, Mom wants me
to protect my brain.
Smart lady, your mom.
Where is she?
Um, Natalie's in the café.
She's just getting us
some coffee really quick,
so I'm watching Owen.
I'm Phillip Davis.
Yeah, Will Halstead.
We haven't officially met.
Natalie and I,
we work together.
She's told me about you.
Good things, I hope.
Of course.
How's your daughter?
She's doing her best.
We're here for
a surgery counsel,
and I suggested Dr. Rhodes.
Yeah, he's one of the best.
You're in good hands.
Phillip is gonna teach me
how to ride a horse.
He is?
Yeah, I own
a ranch in, uh...
In Texas.
Ain't that
right, partner?
Yee-haw.
Yee-haw!
Oh, hey, Will.
Did you guys meet?
Yeah, just now.
Thank you.
All right, come on, Owen,
let's get you to daycare,
buddy.
Come on.
See you later,
little man.
No, I want to
play with you.
Some other time, bud.
There you go.
Yeah.
Let's go.
Will, it was great
meeting you.
Yeah, you too.
I'll see you at work.
See you.
Are you ready to go?
All right, bud.
This is Gaia.
She won't let us
treat her.
No visible injuries,
but she's been screaming
in pain the whole ride over
and wouldn't tell us why.
Gaia, I'm Dr. Choi.
Oh, yeah. She's
combative, too.
Is she under arrest?
We'll see.
We raided a flophouse
after neighbors complained
of a smell.
Drug den?
Looks like it.
All right,
let's transfer her
on my count.
One, two, three.
Any idea what she's on?
Not a clue, but it's lethal.
We've got 10 dead bodies,
only two survivors.
Gaia and another
woman, Meadow.
She's in the ambo
behind us.
I'll go get her.
Gaia, I can see
you're in pain,
but I can't help you
if you don't help me.
Dr. Choi?
What kind of drug does that?
Gaia, what did you take?
This is Burgess.
Meadow, keep looking
at me, all right?
Keep breathing.
It burns!
I'm on fire!
All right,
let's transfer her
on my count.
Ready? One, two, three.
All right, let's get
a urine and blood toxin,
a CBC, CMP,
a chest X-ray,
and an EKG.
No! I don't
want your help!
Oh. Get her.
Meadow?
She's not putting
any weight on her legs.
Leave me alone.
Meadow, you do that again,
I'm gonna need to put you
in restraints.
Don't touch me!
Meadow.
No! I said don't touch me!
Gaia, this would go
so much easier for you
if you just talked to me.
Just tell me
what drug you took,
and we can forget about all
my other questions for now.
Would you let us take
a little urine sample
so we can figure it out
for ourselves?
Okay. No IV, no monitor,
no blood, no urine.
Look, you're clearly
very uncomfortable.
At least let me give you
something for the pain.
Gaia has pronounced
hyperesthesia.
Excruciating pain
from the lightest touch.
Even a slight breeze
against her skin.
So does Meadow.
But she also has
lower extremity paresis.
And still no idea what drug
we're dealing with?
Whatever it is, it's going
after the nervous system,
and it'll be days before
the county sends us
the autopsies
on the other victims.
You get anywhere?
They won't say anything.
And no guarantee of
doctor-patient confidentiality
would put them at ease?
They turned down morphine.
I'm guessing they could
care less about HIPAA.
So what do we do now?
They're cognizant,
responsive.
They have the right
to refuse care.
Hopefully these young women
will change their minds
and accept treatment.
Seriously? Wait and see
is the best we can do?
Our hands are tied.
Well, keep me posted.
Now, I know that
I have given you
a ton of information,
so if you get home,
you feel overwhelmed,
and you realize
you have some questions,
just give me a call.
Okay. I'm nervous.
Sophie's gonna do
just fine.
Okay.
Damn, I am saying...
Get on that... Get me some...
Hey, hey. What's going on?
I can't breathe.
Okay.
What are you doing
all the way up here?
Why didn't you go
to the ED?
Your lungs sound junky.
How are your legs?
Uh, swollen.
All right.
Yeah.
We're gonna admit you
to the CICU.
Let's get stat labs,
chest X-ray, EKG, and echo.
Mmm-hmm.
Come on. Here we go.
Yeah, I feel like
I did before my surgery.
I thought Dr. Bekker
fixed my ASD.
Yeah, so did I.
I met Natalie's boyfriend,
Phillip, this morning.
He told Owen he owns
a cattle ranch.
Okay.
You ever seen
his hands?
They're smooth.
Like, manicured.
No calluses.
So people with pretty hands
can't own livestock?
Come on. No way a guy
with hands like that
owns a ranch.
Or he just wears gloves
when he works,
like we do,
all day long.
I don't buy it.
I think he's lying and using
Owen to get close to Natalie.
I think you overthink things.
Hey.
It was nice to see Owen.
Been awhile.
Yeah, he was
excited to see you.
Phillip seems like
a nice guy.
He is. Thanks.
I mean, he must be nice
if you're bringing him
around Owen.
Excuse me?
You've been dating,
what, six weeks now?
It took you a heck
of a lot longer to let me
get close to Owen
and we'd been
working together
for years by then.
You know, I don't need
to defend my parenting
choices to you.
Honestly, though, how well
do you really know him?
Okay, Dr. Halstead,
you have a patient in Six.
Hi. I'm Dr. Halstead.
Vasiley Qipaqli?
Butchered it, didn't I?
You got close.
Just call him Vee.
It's easier.
Uh, I'm his cousin,
Brandon Wycoff.
Nice to meet you.
So, Vee, what happened?
He's visiting me
from Moldova.
He knows, like,
10 words of English.
Yeah, that's okay.
We can get a translator.
Well, good luck.
Most people there
speak Russian or Romanian.
He's from the South.
He speaks Gagauz.
It's just better
if I do the talking.
Long story short,
he fell in the shower.
All right.
Look at the back
of your head.
Ah.
Minor head laceration.
Doesn't even need a stitch.
Yeah, hey...
Anything hurt?
Pain?
Oh. I okay.
Okay, good.
Yeah.
I want to get an X-ray.
But I think the arm
is just bruised.
There's nothing internal?
I'm not seeing
anything concerning.
Oh, thank God.
If he's a no-go,
I'm screwed.
Sorry?
Oh.
That came out wrong.
Um...
Fistula for dialysis.
End-stage renal disease?
Yeah.
My only hope
is a new kidney.
Luckily, he's donating me
one of his.
I love you, cuz.
Meadow,
these are the same lesions
we found on Gaia.
You're getting worse.
Please just let us help you.
No.
Dr. Choi, come quick!
Gaia.
She's not breathing.
No pulse. Ventilator.
I'll take a quick look.
Asystole. She's gone.
Time of death, 11:10.
I only left her
for a few minutes.
I didn't hear her, I swear.
It's not your fault.
She wouldn't let us
put on the monitors.
She killed herself?
Suicide? Why?
All I can come up with is,
the pain must've been
too much to bear.
I'm gonna
have to imagine.
Meadow's going through
the same thing.
I'm sorry, Ethan.
Yeah.
Dr. Manning?
We ordered a postmortem
tox screen for Gaia.
Hopefully it'll show us
what drug we're dealing with.
Yeah, but I'm not so sure
we're dealing with
a drug anymore.
Look at all this hair.
Is that from when Ethan
pulled off the bag?
Yeah, but there's
too much of it.
I can't think of
a recreational drug
that would account
for this amount of hair loss.
Heavy metal toxin
or poison?
That run-down house
where they found them?
Any number of contaminants
could be in there.
All right, I'll have the labs
expand Gaia's blood tests,
search for
heavy metals and toxins
as well as other drugs.
But, you know,
it still doesn't add up.
If neither Gaia or Meadow
were taking an illegal drug,
why were they so adamant
about refusing treatment?
Patient's middle name?
Is that really necessary?
I never put mine
on anything.
Okay. Date of birth.
I don't know, I...
I'm 30.
He's a year
younger than me,
maybe two.
Is everything okay?
Yes.
The intake form
has a few blank boxes.
More than a few.
Look, the paperwork
is irrelevant.
I'm covering the costs.
Billing is still
going to want information.
Cash is king. I'm sure
they'll make an exception.
Are we done?
Thanks, Leah.
Kind of shooting
the messenger,
don't you think?
I'll buy her something
from the gift shop.
Vee's X-ray?
No fracture.
Great.
We can go.
You all right?
I'm exhausted.
Kidney failure
will do that to you.
I bet.
Transplant is next week
at East Mercy.
I'm supposed to be resting,
keeping my stress level low.
I brought you to Chicago
to cure me, not make it worse.
I'm sorry.
Let's go.
Hold on. Let me take
a look at you first.
I really am okay.
I have my own nephrologist.
He'll make a house call.
End-stage renal disease,
I suspect they'll just
send you to an ED for labs.
Yeah, you're probably right.
That's been the drill.
All right, but I want
my doctor in the loop.
I'll have my assistant
reach out to the hospital
and set everything up.
Works for me.
I'll send someone in
to get you registered.
We're gonna stay.
Hey.
I heard about
your patient.
You all right?
Yeah.
Emily and Bernie are here.
Bernie's not feeling well.
You are up, but I'll
get another doctor
if you need
a few more minutes.
I got it.
Okay. Treatment three.
Be nice.
It's okay, Bernie,
we'll find something else.
I know, baby.
You're so good to me.
I love you.
Hey, guys.
Hey.
What's going on?
Emily just found
a really good apartment,
but it was a little pricey.
Bernie, honey, I think he's
talking about your stomach.
Oh, right, yeah, I'm, uh...
I'm a little bloated.
Yeah, he's got
a fever, too.
Belly's really distended.
How long has it been this way?
Couple of days.
All right, well,
we'll get some labs
and a CT abdomen,
then go from there.
So you guys are
getting an apartment.
Trying to.
That's good.
So everything's settled
with your wife?
Ethan.
Okay, then.
I'll go put in
the order for your tests.
Hey there, Vincent.
I'm looking
right at it.
Even my father still has
a left-to-right shunt
through a patent
atrial septal defect.
And I'm telling you
it wasn't there
after I placed
the intracardiac patch.
Negative bubble test.
His post-op echo was good.
I fixed the problem.
Clearly, you didn't.
You're incredible.
You've made it clear you think
I'm a horrible person.
Now I'm a lousy
surgeon as well?
No, you're
an excellent surgeon,
which is why
this is so glaring.
I take it that's your
passive-aggressive way
of saying I was careless?
Or worse?
However it happened,
my father still needs
a repeat repair of his ASD
and I am going to advise him
to have Dr. Latham perform it.
At first, I thought
your attacks on me
were just you
blowing off steam
after we broke up.
But now I really think
you're losing your mind.
Gaia's body
tested positive
for a highly toxic substance
called thallium.
There may have been
traces of it in the house
where you all were staying.
The good news is,
there is an antidote.
Prussian blue.
It stops the thallium
from being absorbed
into your body.
Meadow, do you understand
what Dr. Manning
is saying to you?
Yes.
Are you willing
to take the medicine?
If you don't take
the Prussian blue soon,
you will die from this.
Will you leave me alone
if I take the pills?
Promise.
Okay.
I'll take them.
Here you go.
We finally got
through to her.
Yeah, but why?
I mean why now
all of a sudden?
I'll take the win.
Would you do me a favor?
Keep a very close eye on her?
Sure.
Thank you.
Hey, let me ask you.
What's going on with
Emily and Bernie and this
hunt for an apartment?
They're looking.
Yeah, I heard her place
fell through, too expensive.
I just hope Bernie
isn't dragging his feet.
Well, Emily
hasn't complained.
Maybe, but she's still
sleeping at your place
with the baby.
I don't mind.
And Bernie's what?
Sleeping across town
on his wife's couch?
Doesn't seem to
faze him a bit.
Ethan, if you're thinking
of getting involved, don't.
It's not gonna help.
You're Bernie's doctor.
Focus on that, okay?
Dr. Halstead, this is
Dr. Richard Haley.
Mr. Wycoff's nephrologist.
Nice to meet you.
So you'll handle
the red tape?
Absolutely.
A VIP room
is being prepared
for Mr. Wycoff
as well as our
conference room
for you to consult
with our transplant team.
I'm sorry.
What's happening?
Well, I didn't like
Brandon's labs.
His phos is up
and he's anemic.
I'm moving up
his kidney transplant
to today.
I want him to get two units
of O-neg, stat.
Whoa! Not so fast.
Mr. Wycoff's my patient.
I'll handle those orders.
Dr. Halstead. I appreciate you
getting the ball rolling,
but Dr. Haley
is gonna take over.
Ms. Garrett,
I am not comfortable
with this.
Brandon doesn't seem to know
anything about his cousin.
He's avoiding a paper trail
by paying cash,
and now some doctor
we met two minutes ago
is rushing him off to surgery?
What about repeat labs?
Pre-op scans?
HLA confirmation?
It will all happen.
Only now, it's going
to take place here
instead of East Mercy.
An easy and profitable win
just fell into our laps,
Dr. Halstead.
Be grateful.
We're moving Mr. Wycoff
to the Ambassador Suite.
It time?
Not yet. Soon.
Vee? Vee.
Do you understand
what's happening?
Brandon, need.
I have give.
You have to or want to?
Dr. Manning,
Dr. Charles.
Monique, get me suction.
Mmm-hmm.
I don't understand.
The Prussian blue
should be making her
better.
It's only
making her worse.
It's 'cause she didn't
take the pills.
Where are they?
Dr. Charles.
Meadow, where...
Monique.
Meadow, without these
pills, you will die.
We're supposed to die.
The oceans are warming.
Ice caps are melting.
We're killing the planet
and no one cares.
Except for us.
The Angels of the Earth.
"We, the Angels
of the Earth,
"will not be so blind
to ignore that
human greed, negligence,
"and abuse are
destroying the planet.
"We will serve the Earth
by removing ourselves
from it."
My God.
They're a cult that believes
the Earth is destined
for destruction
and the only solution
is to kill themselves.
At least they're not
making it all up
out of thin air.
Each one of their claims
is linked to a legitimate
scientific study.
Yeah, I know, but their
whole manifesto is still
one big suicide note.
Well, at least you can put her
on a psych hold, and we can
force treatment.
No, no, no, we can't.
Look, a psych hold
just means we can
keep her here
so she doesn't
harm herself more.
It still doesn't mean we can
make her take Prussian blue
or undo the things
she's done to herself
unless she wants us to.
So what can we do?
Well, it's a long shot,
but I could petition a court
to deem her
mentally incompetent
because of the brainwashing
she's received
at the hands
of this cult.
If not, Meadow controls
her own fate.
I just got word
your patient's
gonna be admitted
and moved upstairs
to meet with transplant.
Mags.
I need you
to stall the transfer.
I'm waiting on calls
from translators.
Gwen Garrett called me
personally on this one.
I can buy you
maybe half an hour.
That's not
gonna do it.
Damn it!
Okay, let's get a head CT.
Will!
Due diligence.
I'm just making sure
there's not a delayed
subdural hematoma that might
endanger Vee in surgery.
This case smells that funky?
It smells illegal.
Okay, I'll order you the CT.
You got an hour now.
But if I were you,
I'd find a Plan B.
Yeah, I need Ms. Goodwin.
Dr. Latham, how'd it go
with my father?
No problems.
Good.
So, what was it?
Was the intracardiac patch
not sewn in properly
or did the sutures
come loose?
Neither,
the patch itself
was faulty.
The patch?
So there was no error
on Dr. Bekker's part?
Absolutely not.
Her sutures were
placed perfectly,
as always.
So, Bernie, I've got
your CT results.
You have a complete
small bowel obstruction.
Likely caused by adhesions
related to your pancreatic
pseudocyst surgery.
Wow. Uh...
I've got an OR
prepped for you now.
What about
recovery time?
A few days in the hospital,
then another week or two
of bed rest.
Honey, we'll have to put
a hold on our job
and apartment search.
Of course,
your health comes first.
And I'll call Ashley
and let her know I'm gonna
be there a bit longer.
It's all gonna work out.
How, Bernie?
How is everything
gonna work out?
Without a job?
Without a place to live?
Can't you see
how hard this is on Emily?
Not to mention her baby?
For reasons, I may
never understand,
Emily loves you
with all of her heart.
So start showing her
you feel the same way.
Get it together.
Mr. Kim? I'm Dr. Wilde.
We're here to take you
to pre-op holding.
Let's go.
The black market?
You think Mr. Wycoff is buying
your patient's kidney?
Wouldn't be the first.
World Health Organization
estimates that 7,000 kidneys
are illegally harvested
annually.
I have other reports
from human rights groups,
economic equality firms.
All right.
"Buyers of trafficked organs
are high-income individuals
"from developed countries.
"The typical seller
is male, around 29,
"and from some of the
world's poorest areas."
I mean, this is
Brandon and Vee.
Yes, they fit the profile,
and I'm well aware
of the magnitude
of illegal organ transplants.
But this is Brandon's file
from East Mercy.
Transplant list status
as well as Vee's donor papers.
Our lawyers have been
all over these documents.
Nothing appears
out of place.
And what about
the nephrologist,
Dr. Haley?
Privileges at hospitals
across the city,
including ours.
So Brandon's
covered his bases.
That doesn't mean
money hasn't changed hands.
Ms. Goodwin,
I'm telling you,
there's something
going on here.
This is the mission statement
of the Angels of the Earth.
I've read it
three times now.
Are you beginning
to understand, then?
I'm trying to.
As a scientist, I agree.
But I'm having a hard time
believing that the planet
is doomed to become
uninhabitable.
Or how poisoning
yourself with thallium
will change that.
Would you have heard
of the Angels of the Earth
otherwise
if I wasn't here?
So you're a martyr?
In 1963, a monk
set himself on fire
in protest of the
Vietnamese government's
discriminatory laws
against Buddhism.
The government
was overthrown.
Is that your hope?
That the government
is overthrown?
No.
My hope is that people
wake up and take action
instead of continuing
to cook our planet
by burning fossil fuels.
So then you believe
the planet can be saved.
You're twisting my words.
I'm not.
Mmm-hmm.
Your logic is flawed.
You want people to change,
but you also think
that change will be
meaningless.
So what is the point
of martyring yourself
if it's unclear
what you stand for?
I'm not taking your pills.
Meadow, your hair
is falling out.
You're running out of time.
Good.
I am not gonna let you die.
Monique, John?
Put her in the
soft restraints,
then prepare for an NG tube.
I'm giving her
the Prussian blue.
No!
Maybe I should
call Dr. Charles.
I'm a licensed physician,
and I am deeming
the patient nondecisional.
Put her in the restraints.
Now.
No! No, you can't do that!
I'm sorry.
You can't!
No, please!
You can't do this! No!
Stop.
I have to ask you.
Is Brandon paying
for your kidney?
Money. All right?
Is Brandon paying you money
for your kidney?
No, no money.
It's okay.
Just tell me the truth
so I can help.
Help? Yes.
Me.
Brandon.
Uh-huh.
Brandon sick.
I help family.
Dr. Halstead?
Is there a problem?
No, just checking
on Vee.
Making sure he's okay.
Me too.
Oh.
You gotta be kidding me.
Look at us.
My mom took me to Moldova
when I was eight.
She wanted me to
experience the homeland.
And village
after village,
I was so bored.
But then on the
last day, I met Vee.
And we couldn't
speak to each other,
but we both knew
how to play soccer.
Football.
Football,
football.
Football.
Thank you for what
you're doing for me.
You're saving my life.
I wish he knew
what I was saying.
I think he does.
I'll leave you guys alone.
I have gifted millions
to this hospital.
I expect first-class care.
Connor, get in here.
You should hear this.
A budget
bloated with waste,
and what is
Ms. Garrett's solution,
is to save money on
intracardiac patches.
Again, Mr. Rhodes,
I sincerely apologize.
I will personally look into
how these patches ended up
in the OR
and I will make sure
that it never happens again.
Full report
next board meeting.
Of course.
And, Gwen, if memory serves,
your contract extension
is also an agenda item
at that meeting.
I believe it is.
Perfect. See you there.
It's okay. Shh, shh.
Hey, uh, just got an update.
Bernie's surgery went well.
He'll be out soon.
That seat's taken.
And that seat's taken too.
Okay, I get it.
You're mad at me.
Why'd you yell
at Bernie like that?
I was sticking up for you.
You were kicking him
when he's down.
Everything I said,
Bernie needed to hear,
and you were never
gonna say it.
Yes, I want an apartment.
I want him to get a job.
But tough love
won't get us there.
And coddling does?
Ms. Choi?
Mr. Kim's being moved
to the ICU for recovery.
Whenever you're ready,
you can go down and see him.
Thanks, Lizzie.
You don't get it.
Bernie's delicate.
He's warm, affectionate,
and he needs
encouragement
and support.
And if you can't
get behind that,
then get out of our lives.
Dr. Charles? I need you.
What the hell
were you thinking?
You could lose
your license for this.
For doing what's right?
For breaking the law!
I don't want her
to die either, Natalie,
but the woman has rights!
What are you going to do?
Well, now that
you've boxed me in,
there's only one thing
that I can do.
If you take out that tube,
the only thing
you will be doing
is pushing Meadow
one step closer to death.
Get out of my way.
Okay, this is gonna be
uncomfortable.
Sorry about that.
I apologize for Dr. Manning.
It's hard for her
to understand
why you're doing this.
I thought you'd want
to know that, um,
because of your
friend's deaths,
everybody is talking about
Angels of the Earth right now.
I mean, the Internet's
going crazy.
We knew it would.
So thallium, huh?
Clever.
A chemical compound
not found in nature.
A poison that deteriorates
the body in much the same way
that climate change
affects the Earth.
It's poetic.
You're smart.
You know, you've gotten
pretty much everything
you wanted.
And all that's left now
is to wait?
I think you've
suffered enough, Meadow.
And I'd like to help
ease that transition
and give you
a couple of sleeping pills
if you'll let me.
Suffering is the point.
Look, Gaia put a bag
over her head.
There is no one
on the Internet
calling her out
for taking a shortcut.
Trust me.
It's just a thought.
Okay.
I'll take the sleeping pills.
Good.
Give Meadow
five of eszopiclone.
It's okay.
Meadow has agreed
to take eszopiclone.
Once she's out, she will
no longer have the ability
to advocate for herself.
And a strong legal case
could be made
that we then have the right
to act under implied consent
as surrogate decision-makers
on her behalf.
So you can re-place
the NG tube and administer
Prussian blue.
Ava, hold up.
Leave me alone, Connor.
Look, I am sorry
for jumping to
conclusions earlier.
I should have
considered
the possibility
that the patch failed before
placing all the blame on you.
And?
And what?
Seriously, Connor?
Accusing me of botching
your father's surgery
is the only conclusion
you're sorry for?
What about your claim
that I slept with him?
That I manipulated
the oversight committee?
That I let you
cut my hand in surgery?
And God knows what else.
No apology for
any of that madness.
I'll be honest.
When we broke up,
I was devastated.
And I'm still
getting over it.
But at no point
have I cast you
as a monster.
So why do you insist
on making me one?
Why do you want
to hurt me so badly?
You're such a good baby.
Yes, you are.
Hey, Bernie.
Bernie, look...
I was out of line earlier.
I appreciate you
saying that, Ethan.
Now on, if you
need anything...
I want you to know
you can come to me,
no questions asked.
Em, do you mind if I,
uh, have a moment alone
with Ethan?
Okay. We'll be
right outside.
Let's go outside.
You were right, Ethan.
I better step it up,
and I'm going to.
I promise.
I'm glad to hear that.
There is, uh, one thing
you can help me out with.
Name it.
Lately, I've been
having trouble
sustaining an erection.
What?
It's called
erectile dysfunction,
and there's medication
that can possibly help.
I'm reluctant to write you
a prescription.
You should really talk
to a urologist.
Thank you. Thanks for
everything, Ethan.
Dr. Charles...
I know you're upset with me.
But I just wanted to thank you
for what you did today.
We prevented a suicide.
Have we, though?
I mean, two doses
of Prussian blue
won't be enough
to neutralize the thallium.
She's gonna need
dozens more.
When Meadow wakes up
tomorrow morning,
the battle to get her
to take them,
it starts all over,
and I'm just worried
that we haven't really
prevented a suicide
as much as
we've postponed one.
Natalie, um...
This is the second time
in as many months
that you've, um,
well, you've misstepped,
and I'm just wondering,
is everything okay?
Yeah.
Okay.
Well, um, I will
see you tomorrow.
Hey, Phillip.
Oh, hey.
Waiting on Natalie?
Yeah, she's picking
Owen up from daycare.
Look, man, if I seemed
weird earlier, I'm sorry.
What do you mean?
I was just thrown
when you mentioned
your ranch to Owen.
I'm so sorry,
when I mentioned my...
Your ranch.
Oh! Yeah. That.
Well, look,
the kid loves horses.
I was just playing.
So you don't own a ranch.
No. No.
Oh.
But I figured that...
Owen got a pretty big kick
out of it, right?
Yeah, I guess.
I'll see you around.
Yeah, take care.