Previously on ER:
So you quit your job and
get married in the same week?
I'm a new guy now.
Maybe some of that love
will rub off on all of us here...
and help us find someone
as special as you two have.
I got them the honeymoon
suite at the Ritz for a few nights...
but they say they can't
use it on account of Joe.
Oh, it's go time.
You're a real prick,
you know that?
- Gates.
- Stop it, Tony.
You know I don't love you.
So that's it?
- We're done?
- Yeah.
Because Ray
couldn't get over you?
Have you seen my other
sock? I just bought these.
Nobody wears socks in Hawaii.
Oh, I can't believe
it's almost 9:00.
I can't believe
Joe's still asleep.
Couldn't find anyone
to cover your shift?
No, that's the problem
with surprise weddings.
It's hard to plan.
I'll stop by later.
I have to tie up some
loose ends with Anspaugh.
You've gotta be kidding me.
What?
Married five days and I'm already
getting mail addressed to Mrs. Luka Kovac.
Nice.
You know, being married isn't
gonna change the fact that I don't cook.
Or sew.
Or keep track of your socks.
Okay, that's fine in Chicago.
But on our honeymoon...
you're gonna be serving
me martinis wearing only this.
You got me a bikini.
I'm a liberated modern husband.
And I like to shop.
Abby and Luka are crazy.
Who turns down three free nights
in the honeymoon suite at the Ritz?
Hope?
Wow.
Oh, my... Ohhh.
You know, when I was 8, I found
this book in my parents' bedroom:
Sex and the Christian Marriage.
And the very first page, it said,
"Orgasms bring a couple closer to God."
So that night at the dinner table, I
asked my parents what an orgasm was.
What did they say?
An orgasm is a very
special kind of prayer.
Which is fine and
actually kind of sweet.
But, like, later that week, I had my
first sleepover at a friend's house.
So her mom asked me
what my bedtime routine is.
And I said, "Bath,
toothbrushing, orgasm, sleep."
You did not.
I did. I was never invited back.
Heh. Champagne?
It's 8 in the morning.
I have no sense
of time in this place.
Arch, you gotta be
at work in like an hour.
- Shh. Dirty word.
- What is?
- Work.
- Oh.
Well, I don't have
to be in till 4...
so you go ahead, and then
I'll check us out of the room.
No, no, no.
No, no, we're
staying another night.
Another three nights.
What? That's crazy.
This room must be, like,
a thousand dollars a night.
They comped us.
Why would they do that?
I guess we're spending so much on
room service, we made it worth their while.
Now, mimosa?
- Mimosa.
- Oh.
Hey.
Damn it.
Hey, hey, Bettina.
Hey, hold on.
All right, all right,
look, look. Heh.
I got it now.
I figured you out.
Figured me out?
You've had it with guys who try to be
cool. You're ready for someone real.
- Got someone you wanna set me up with?
- Help me out, okay? I've seen the light.
You're just saying what I
need to hear to go out with you.
No, it's not like that.
Really. Really.
Greg, I like you.
But I have been dating
guys like you for years.
You will do whatever it takes to get the
girl, but in the end, it's about the chase.
Bettina, I'm not
like that anymore.
I've changed.
This is it? They closed
the ER for a paint job?
It's only been a few days.
Can't expect a drastic
change overnight.
My point exactly,
Dr. Pratt. See you later.
- I've got Radiology rounds in the ICU.
- Wait.
Pratt, I got a hypotensive
patient here, 87/45.
- What's her baseline? Whoa!
- Dr. Pratt.
She runs low, always has.
Why is it that you
know that and I don't?
She's febrile too, 103.
Okay, any vomiting?
Any coughing?
Just a little belly pain.
I could see my doctor
when I get home.
- Where's home?
- Boston.
We're here for her
physics conference.
I'm gonna cut his eyes
out and send them in a box.
Need some help here.
Sam, liter of saline, monitored
bed. I'll be in as soon as I can.
- Can't he just give me an antibiotic?
- We've been in triage nearly three hours.
Sorry. This is how it goes
here. Let me see if there's a bed.
- I'll be right back.
- Okay.
Oh, Sam.
Meet my parents, Barb and
Len. They're from Long Island.
Oh, hi, nice to meet you.
Hey, Weston, you're up.
This guy needs a chest tube.
- I'll find you guys later.
- Okay, bye.
You must be very proud
of Larry. Have a good tour.
You're even prettier
than he said you were.
We're so happy he
finally found a girlfriend.
Let me out of here.
- Where did they move the ortho stuff?
- I'm sorry for springing my parents...
I am not your
girlfriend. You know that.
Oh, come on.
Sam...
We made out.
At a wedding.
That's what drunk single
people do at weddings.
Doesn't mean we're an item.
Well, I'm not the type to
take sex casually, Sam.
We did not have sex.
- It depends on how you define sex.
- Larry, we did not have sex.
- What, outercourse doesn't count?
- Oh, my God.
What?
- Ace or splint?
- Ace is cool.
Where are all the improvements
you guys did while you were closed?
What? You didn't see
the new admit desk?
Or how about our electrical
outlets? They are a new shade of red.
- All right, how did you hurt your ankle?
- Running all over the hospital...
- with Dr. Moretti.
- Who?
Dr. Moretti, he's
head of the ICU.
- I'm doing a month up there with him.
- Wiggle your toes.
I'm wearing the pager for
the Rapid Response Team.
- The what?
- Moretti's latest invention.
When nurses get a bad feeling
about the patients, they call us, we run.
- Oh, like a code team.
- More like a pre-code team.
Why don't you have the docs
look at your ankle just to be sure?
- As long as it's not Ray.
- Yeah, you got it.
Okay, Morris, you finally
close the deal with Hope or not?
Hey, all I can say is this is the first
time I left our hotel room in three days.
- Ha.
- Mostly, we're just praying.
- A lot of special prayers. Huh?
- Heh-heh.
What about you and
our favorite radiologist?
Come on, you gotta
respect a woman's privacy.
You sly dog.
- Anybody see Ray around?
- No, he's late.
He's probably still hung-over.
He was in pretty bad shape.
And, Sam, whoo, baby.
- Wild night, huh?
- Please shut up.
Katey Alvaro's in Curtain
2. She twisted her ankle.
- Doesn't look broken, but take a look.
- I'm on it.
Larry. Hmm.
I'm gonna kill him.
Hey, anybody see our
physicist in Curtain 3?
Yeah, I gotta slow down an
SVT, but she's next for sure.
Excuse me, we're
still waiting for a doctor.
I'm sorry, we're really busy.
How you feeling?
Run-down.
I've been working my ass off for six
months prepping for this conference.
Six months?
Try 20 years.
You've been working on quantum
processing your entire career.
Quantum processing?
Theory in physics
which says that an atom...
can exist in two
places at the same time.
And I showed that it can
work in a larger matrix.
I have no idea what you just
said, but it sounds impressive.
Yeah, pretty much blew
the lid off the entire field.
I think what you've
got is probably viral.
But I'm gonna send some
blood tests to be safe.
Sam, we're gonna do
dinner at 8 at Osteria Angelo.
Great. Have a good time.
I don't mean to sound like an
uptight mainlander, but I just...
I find it hard to believe that you
can't rent a car with a car seat in it.
Okay. Right, we'll
bring our own.
Yes, mahalo for nothing.
Sophia Van Brummelen, 35,
fell down 15-foot flight of stairs.
Can you tell me your name?
- I'm gonna be sick.
- Roll her on her side.
Please be okay. Let her be okay.
- Abby, need some help here.
- Hello?
What happened?
- She fell down the stairs...
- I wanna hear it from her.
She slipped and fell.
Her head was
bouncing on the stairs.
When she got to the bottom, she
wasn't moving and wasn't talking.
Any medications or allergies?
- No, she's healthy.
- Mice.
Okay, we're gonna
take care of you.
Access? GATES:
18-gauge in the antecube.
- She's seizing.
- Ativan, 2 mgs.
Get Trauma down here.
I need a second line and
50 of mannitol right away.
I've got a dilated stomach with
exaggerated incisura. Call Ultrasound.
- Why?
- Caterpillar sign.
Could be pyloric stenosis.
Pratt, I need an antibiotics
order for our physicist in 3.
Micro called. She's got
gram-positive cocci on the stain.
Probably contaminated. She
looks too good to be septic.
She's still febrile and tachy.
How'd you know how she
looks? You haven't seen her.
Got an obstructed newborn, a
perfed ulcer on his sixth unit of blood...
and my aphasic boxer
dropped his pressure in CT.
Give her 2 grams of ceftriaxone,
and I'll see her as soon as I can, okay?
Guess what. I'm house-sitting
for Luby while they're away.
- Luby?
- Luka and Abby.
You know, like Brangelina,
Bennifer, TomKat?
I hear it's a nice place.
- Abby says it's okay if you sleep over.
- What? Are you for real?
I didn't think it would be right to
have sex in their bed without asking.
Load him with a
gram of Dilantin.
- What's that?
- Medicine to keep her from seizing again.
You wanna be here? Step back.
- More suction.
- Cranked all the way up.
- Nothing's coming out.
- Come on, Gates.
- Can't see crap.
- Sats are down to 86.
- Is that bad?
- Abby, switch with Gates.
I haven't even tried yet.
- Exactly.
- I'm being blamed for equipment failure?
- Don't make this about you, please.
What are you doing?
The tube will allow
us to breathe for her.
Is he mad about the propofol?
Yeah, that or the
thing at the wedding.
- What happened at the wedding?
- Nothing.
Yeah, it's the propofol. He
wants me to kiss the ring.
Well, why don't
you just apologize?
- I have nothing to apologize for.
- Chest tube. Call Respiratory...
Post-op morbidity and mortality
are up 7 percent this year.
- Really? Why?
- I'm gonna find out.
I'm conducting an
internal audit into Post-Op.
I want every med, every
hiccup, meticulously recorded.
Nurses are gonna hate you.
No, they'll hate you. You're
in charge of the investigation.
It's the ER. Trauma call.
Not you, Dusty. I want
you in the PACU unit.
You're not doing consults
till the audit's over.
Aw, boo.
- Hey.
Hey.
Surgery's here, what do you got?
A 35-year-old, fell
down a flight of stairs.
Head trauma, intubated,
FAST negative, labs pending.
Came in altered.
Five-centimeter scalp lac.
- Access? GATES:
Eighteen-gauge times two.
First crit 37,
second one cooking.
- Okay.
- Want me to bag for you?
- No, I got it.
- Bolus is done.
Better run D5
half at 75 an hour.
Don't want a fluid overload
till we know what's going on.
It was a nice wedding.
Thanks.
Sorry I got so crazy.
I think because I knew I was
leaving, I let it all hang out.
I mean, you hardly even know me.
And then I had to go and be like that.
Don't worry about it.
Dr. Morris, your
TPA patient is seizing.
- I'm busy here, find Pratt.
- Don't worry about it. I got it, go.
Mae Lee, call CT. Tell
them we're coming up.
Is there a Megan Strand here?
That's me.
Neighbors heard screaming
in your house this morning.
We were having an argument.
Where the hell
is my ceftriaxone?
No, it's Pratt.
P-R-A-T-T.
Hell, no, I'm not new. Are you?
Just send the stuff down.
I ordered the antibiotics
over an hour ago.
Learned helplessness
is pervasive in the ER.
Can't have a homeschooled
pharmacy tech wag the dog.
You rang?
What's going on? Who are you?
I'm Dr. Kevin Moretti. I'm
the clinical director of the ICU.
We were called because
your wife is deteriorating.
- Talk to me.
- Fever at 103.
Stain showed
gram-positive cocci.
- We thought it was a contaminant.
- Which is stupid.
Katey, set up for a subclavian.
Prime the line and get a CVP monitor.
Draw lactate now, you.
And give me six units of packed
blood cells standing by in the blood bank.
- Who is the Attending on this case?
- Me.
Really? You dropped
the ball, didn't you?
- Excuse me?
- She's septic.
It's obvious. You
should've anticipated this.
She's young, she's
healthy, she had no reason...
She doesn't need a reason. Heh.
A reason. Breathe, please.
Katey, do you see any signs
of impending shock here?
Tachycardia out of proportion with
the fever, widening pulse pressures.
See that? Even a medical student
could see it coming from a mile away.
Must be some
new Attending thing.
We'll take care of your wife.
- I can manage my patients, thank you.
- Really?
Why did one of your nurses
activate my team? Excuse me.
I knew you were getting
slammed. She needed attention.
The Rapid Response Team
doesn't even cover the ER.
If you can't handle cases
like this, maybe we should.
Give me 1 percent
lido. Let's go.
Explain this again, I don't
understand. My wife is healthy.
- Calm down.
- It's okay.
Bacteria could've seeded the bloodstream
through lungs, a cut, intestines.
- Second liter's in.
- Mm-hm.
Goal-directed resuscitation
for septic shock...
is so easy yet so
difficult for you ED types.
She's in shock?
- Systolic's only 82.
- That would be a yes.
The key is to preserve
effective tissue perfusion...
while avoiding excess
myocardial oxygen consumption.
Translation: get oxygen to the
body without stressing the heart.
We need CVP monitoring and continuous
central venous sats to keep track of that.
See that? He's learning already.
That requires ICU-level
monitoring. We're too busy here.
- We can't do that.
- Really? You can't?
You can and you will.
- Watch.
- We don't have the nursing capacity.
Patients come in. We stabilize
them, then send them up.
That's how it works.
Yeah, you forgot about that eight
hours that they sit around in triage.
Wait another five to get a bed.
It's not great, okay,
but it's the reality.
Reality is nothing more
than a persistent illusion.
Einstein said that.
I'm a physicist.
- Memorized everything he ever wrote.
- See that?
Even more reason not to sit around and
let your organs rot away like rancid meat.
Nobody's organs are rotting.
Free air under the diaphragm.
Probably perfed diverticulum.
What's that mean?
That means an infection in your
intestines has eroded through the wall.
We need to clean,
repair the hole.
Lucien, don't you get tired
of ER docs waiting around...
for the surgeons to come
down and save the day?
Give them a break. You know what it's
like. I'm gonna call O.R. to bring her up.
True, I know that we're just monkeys
on a minor planet on an average star...
but let's not pretend that
sepsis is beyond our reach.
If you're trying to quote
Hawking, you mangled it.
I think I'm in love. - Allison.
- What are you doing here, Blake?
- Hey, she called me.
- Hey, whoa, guys.
- You don't get to do this.
- Hey, whoa, come on.
- She wants me here, okay?
Come on. Whoa!
Stay away from my wife!
- Where are you taking her?
- CT scan.
- Can I go too?
- No, you stay here.
Dr. Gates will be with
her the whole time.
Is everything okay?
No, my girlfriend's in a coma.
It's all my fault. So no,
everything is not okay.
All your fault? How's that?
I left my rollerblades
at the top of the stairs.
It's polished concrete.
It's very slippery.
We were fighting
and she tripped.
Did you explain to the cops?
- I'm sure they'll sort it out.
- Yeah.
No, it's been a bad year.
How so?
We moved to Chicago
five months ago for my job.
Ever since, we've
been fighting constantly.
These huge dish-breaking fights.
And we never used to do that.
It's like the city's
changed her.
Well, transitions are hard.
We've been together
ever since college.
Been through a lot.
You know, us coming out to
her family and her brother dying.
You think you can make
it through that stuff...
you think you can
make it through anything.
Who knew after 15 years
that everything would turn?
So much?
It's scary.
Yeah.
Quantum information
processing, teleportation.
We've been chasing the same
questions since grad school.
Sorry if he feels
threatened by it...
but there are conversations she
can only have with me, vice versa.
But it's only work, right?
Yeah, we're both
married. Happily married.
Can't say that the idea's never crossed my
mind, but Allison and I just really click.
I don't know anybody else, male or
female, who challenges me like she does.
They have this thing.
They're together in the lab all
day, and then she gets home...
and everything's, "Blake
said this, Blake did that."
Something about it
has always felt weird.
He's her work husband.
Yeah, people spend more time
at work than they do at home.
You share experiences,
develop a verbal shorthand.
Of course some
intimacy develops.
The two men in my life,
they don't get each other.
Really? Never would've noticed.
- The O.R. is ready.
- Okay.
Two planets revolving around the
same sun. Collision is inevitable, right?
They try to stay out
of each other's orbits...
to keep the solar
system in order...
but, oh, it's a
useless exercise.
- Disorder rules.
- Oh, yeah.
The universe always
reverts to equilibrium.
I'll see you upstairs, okay?
- Wait.
Honey, I'm sorry. I
went a little crazy.
James.
I want you to do
something for me.
- Am I gonna have a scar?
- The edges came together nicely.
It'll be small.
I have to head back to ICU,
but I wanted to suggest...
that you write this case
up for M and M next week.
What's M and M?
It's a conference where we present
our mistakes and learn from them.
- You made a mistake with Allison?
- No.
Will you please
excuse us for a minute?
What are you trying to do?
Trying to wake you up.
Why talk like that in front of a
patient? How does that help anyone?
- Where did you go to medical school?
- Here.
- And your Residency?
Mm-hm. Your internship?
Why are you asking?
You know it was here.
Because I think that you have
been lulled into complacency...
by too many years in this place.
You got a problem with
the ER, you talk to Kovac.
No, it's too late for Kovac.
He's the old guard.
I think you could really
turn things around here.
You're really
starting to bore me.
How about you go up and harass your
own department and stay out of mine?
It's always nice to
talk to you, Dr. Pratt.
Will someone make
this jerk disappear?
Who? PRATT: The guy is toxic.
What guy?
Oh, hey, excuse me.
Excuse me. Can you hold up?
- You finish interviewing Megan Strand?
- Yeah.
We're waiting to see if we can
get a statement from Sophia.
That might be a while.
But listen, I was talking to Megan
and her affect seems totally appropriate.
The injury matches
her story, and I'm just...
- I'm not getting that abuse vibe.
- Thanks, doc.
Write that in the record.
Helpful if it goes to court.
- Right. Thanks.
- It's how much?
No promotional rate?
What about
frequent-flier programs?
AAA?
Three more nights at the
honeymoon suite. Charge the card.
Don't get snarky, I'm fragile.
Oh. I thought things were
going well with you and Hope.
Yeah, they are. Really well.
Staircase girl has a head bleed.
Frontal parenchymal bleed?
Yeah, less common than sub or
epidural, but consistent with a fall.
Okay, I'll call
Neurosurge, thanks.
Hey, Neela. Hey.
Have you heard
anything from Ray yet?
No, I thought he'd be here.
Yeah, well, maybe when the ER
closed, maybe schedules got confusing.
- Yeah.
- I'll try paging him again.
Hey, I hear you're taking
the gastroschisis kid.
I'm about to write
the admission orders.
Operating on adhesions
create new adhesions?
Possibly, but we don't have a
choice if he's acutely obstructed.
All right, I'll keep
him NPO. Thanks.
Hey, I got a snake breeder
with a fang in her leg.
Nice seeing you, Tony.
Thanks for the consult.
Hey. What?
What'd I do?
- This is easy for you, isn't it?
- What?
"Did you see my
gastroschisis kid?"
- Like nothing happened.
- You're not...
- How can you be so casual?
- You're the one who broke up.
Meg, Sarah, everything
just rolls right off of you.
Why don't you tell me how
upset you want me to be?
On a scale of one
to 10. A seven?
When you feel
needy, crank it to eight.
Down to five when you
wanna get work done?
Now you're being an ass.
You think this doesn't upset
me, it does. This is painful.
But you want what you want.
We'll figure out how we'll
work without the drama.
But now I realize
something. You like this.
- You want drama.
- Not true.
It is true, no matter how I
act, you're gonna be upset.
You know why?
Because that's the only way you can
maintain this stupid narcissistic game.
Wow. I hope that
never happens to us.
They managed to
repair her intestine...
but her blood pressure
dropped very low.
It'll be a while before
we know anything.
Six hours ago, she was giving a
talk in front of hundreds of people.
How did she end up here?
Well, sometimes
things just happen.
There's really no way
to make sense of it.
She's not in pain?
I'll make sure she
has a morphine order.
How is she doing?
Still needs dopa to keep her systolic
above 85. I think she's third-spacing.
She had a touch of DIC,
lost 2 liters in the O.R.
Hey, why didn't you scrub in?
- I wasn't sure that you'd want me to.
- Why wouldn't I?
Oh, men are impossible.
- Listen, Neela, about the...
- Do you think I'm a narcissist?
Well, to a certain
extent, all surgeons are.
Yeah, it's good for the job.
Hey, guys, Mae
Lee's off to the airport.
I just wanted to thank you
guys for an amazing experience.
- Goodbye, Mae Lee.
- Yeah, strong work this month, Mae Lee.
It's the ER. One final
consult before you go?
Call me if you're
ever in San Francisco.
Little freak tried to
kiss me at the wedding.
What's she doing
here? Get her to the ICU.
Runs of V-tach. She's
not ready to move.
Come on. It's a
hundred feet of corridor.
Better for her to code
in the ICU instead.
Well, for her or for us?
I'm serious, Neela.
We got five full O.R.'s.
We need to make room. Let's go.
She loves tulips.
Yellow.
No, no, no. White.
White, two dozen white tulips...
Hey, newlyweds.
To be delivered to
Room 1258 at the Ritz.
How's it feel, guys?
You know Morris is staying
in our honeymoon suite?
- What?
- Yep, with Hope.
They won't leave.
Did you wake up
feeling different?
- Not really.
- Yeah.
- Just a little.
- Not that much.
Wedding was awesome. Hope that thing
I did didn't make you lose your deposit.
- What thing?
- What? Hey, everyone.
In the ER, for the first time,
Mr. and Mrs. Luka Kovac.
Yeah, oh, sorry, Abby.
Dr. and Mrs. Luka Kovac.
Doctor and doctor, sorry.
Chief, aren't you supposed
to be in Bora Bora?
Hawaii, and I just attended my
last department-head meeting.
So I'm officially no
longer your chief.
- You're kidding.
- Wow.
It's like your wedding happened
and now everything's changed.
You're married, I'm with Hope,
you're not the chief anymore...
there's new ramps
in the bathroom.
It's a brave new world.
Gates is still a pain in the ass.
- There's something you can count on.
- You done? Had enough?
Tony, there's a lawyer
who needs to talk to you.
Thanks, Dawn.
Hide, Gates. I'll tell
him you went home sick.
I'm going. See you at home.
Okay.
Being married does
feel a little different.
Yeah, it does.
Aw.
Look at that.
Lucien. DUBENKO: Hey, Luka.
Abby, I saw the Cheetos bezoar.
Send him home on
MiraLAX, follow up with GI.
- Okay, done.
- Nice wedding, by the way.
I offered to replace the bidet.
What bidet?
Abby, your head injury
in Trauma 2 lost her pulse.
Clear.
Still V-fib. Going again.
And clear.
They paged me. What's going on?
Her heart went into
dangerous rhythm.
Oh, my God. MARQUEZ: Epi's in.
All right, back up. Back up.
- Clear.
- Resuming CPR.
- No, no, baby. Don't do this.
- Lidocaine's ready.
Is Neurosurge involved?
There's nothing to evacuate.
Bleed's parenchymal.
You can't leave
me now, you hear?
Go ahead, give the lido.
The things that we said,
the way we were, it's not us.
Right?
- You're my rock, always calm.
- Another epi, charge to 360.
When you said Chicago
changed her, what did you mean?
That she's been
testy and paranoid.
- Oh, my God. Please don't.
- Okay, clear.
- Watch out.
- Please clear.
- We have a pulse.
- She's back.
Oh, God. Thank you.
What do you think of this film?
Frontal lobe bleed, no shift.
You think it could be
a preexisting AVM...
exacerbated by the head trauma?
A frontal lobe mass would explain the
personality and the behavioral changes.
You're a romantic, Abby.
- What?
- You don't wanna believe...
that after years of partnership,
they started hating each other.
Call Radiology. If you're
right, she needs angio.
The girl's lived with you for 10 years.
Closest thing she's had to a father.
- So that's gotta count for something.
- It does.
Given the situation, you have
equal standing to seek custody.
Equal as her grandparents? Even
though I'm not a blood relative?
Yep, especially if Sarah
wants to stay with you.
Oh. I just thought, because I wasn't
related... This is good. All right, good.
Good, what else? What's next?
The first thing
is talk to Sarah.
- Make sure she wants to stay.
- I know she does.
Twelve-year-olds can be fickle.
I have two adolescents at home.
- Talk to her.
- Then what?
Then call the grandparents
and let them know.
- So that's it?
- That's it.
Okay.
Injecting the cyanoacrylate.
Amazing pick-up, Abby.
What made you think of AVM?
Her girlfriend kept going on...
about how she'd
become a different person.
Lots of couples go through that.
They don't all have arteriovenous
malformations in their brain.
Well, it was just
a hunch, I guess.
And congrats on the wedding.
Strange to be a husband
and wife working together?
Well, it's definitely strange to
have people refer to us that way.
Get used to it. Contrast.
- Are you married?
- Oh, no.
Only people I ever
meet are doctors.
And doctors make crummy
husbands. No offense.
I used to think it would be cool to
end up with a composer or an artist...
someone that would bring something totally
different to the dinner table, but...
You know, it's really nice to go home
to somebody who understands all this.
I can see that.
Look, no more antegrade
opacification of contrast.
- So the embolization worked?
- Yep.
Great. PRATT: Very nice.
What are you doing here?
I just came to check on the patient.
- Wait a minute.
I thought that Morris was
the Attending, so you...
Okay. Thanks, Bettina.
I'm gonna give
Megan the good news.
I was on a break, so I thought
I'd bring you some coffee.
Oh, don't drink coffee.
Well, that's good to know.
Hey, listen, Bettina, I just wanna
hang out with you for a while.
No plans, no games, just me.
And the patient
here on the table.
You can stay, but
don't touch anything.
Hospital day 12 for this
72-year-old with a GI bleed.
Vitals stable
overnight, pressure is...
Who's the first person to
measure blood pressure? Anybody?
It was a clergyman in
the year 17-blah-blah-blah.
And he took a glass tube and he stuck
it into the carotid artery of a horse.
And he was very surprised to see the
blood rise up into the air about 9 feet.
Why he did this
exactly, I have no idea.
I mean, it's impractical
for human beings.
I'm sure the horse
didn't appreciate it.
Sorry about that. Go
ahead, finish, Katey.
- Go ahead.
- Okay.
Next, we have a 64-year-old presented...
- Hi, we need a room.
This is Allison
Mackenzie, bowel perf.
Lost a lot of blood, didn't
tolerate the trip down the hall well.
Tachy's on two pressors.
CVP is only a six.
- Run of V-tach.
- Can I ask you a question?
Why didn't you stabilize the patient in
Post-Op instead of bringing us this mess?
- She got four units of blood and...
- Look, I'm not an idiot.
I knew about the
audit Dubenko's doing.
He doesn't want this
patient. It'll mess up his data.
That's not what's happening.
Rather have her code and
die in the ICU than on his watch.
- Die?
- Yeah, well, we'll try to avoid that.
- Tell Lucien this can't happen again.
- This wasn't his idea.
- Yeah, right.
- I thought she was ready to move.
V-tach.
No pulse.
Starting compression.
Oh, no, this can't be happening.
Charge to 200.
JAMES: No, please.
- Nice job, Neela.
- Just stay focused on the patient.
Clear. JAMES: Please help her.
Someone on the phone
says they gotta talk to you.
- I'm in the middle of a code.
- No, go. Just go.
And there's a guy outside begging
to come in to see this patient.
He's not family.
He can't be here.
- You might wanna rethink that.
- What?
She is doing everything she can not
to die. She could use all the support.
- Epi's in.
- Okay, going again.
Clear.
Well, her heart is beating
in a normal rhythm...
but her blood pressure
is still dangerously low.
Is there something you can do?
We've maxed out on the
medications. They're not helping.
The part of her brain that
controls blood pressure...
isn't functioning properly.
What? Why not?
Because she received
45 minutes of CPR.
Her brain was deprived
of oxygen during that time.
And when that happens, we often
see some degree of neurologic injury.
She walked in here today
with a stomachache...
and now you're telling
me her brain is damaged?
Look, I don't wanna take away all
hope, but I wanna be realistic here.
If she survives, there most
likely will be neurologic deficits.
When will we know?
Well, there's no way to predict.
It's a waiting game
now, I'm afraid.
Sorry.
I see.
You can go.
Please go.
Before she went into surgery,
she asked me to give this to you.
James.
I've resented it for so long,
this thing you two have.
Even now, I've gotta
share her with you.
What did he give him?
I don't know.
Data.
Some kind of
treasured lab secret.
Well, how do you know?
Well, you work in
the ICU long enough...
you start to recognize these
scenes are frighteningly familiar.
They kiss their spouse, the
kids, they say goodbye to friends.
A certain percentage
have a deep, dark secret...
like an illegitimate child or
a secret debt or something.
But occasionally, you
see something like this.
Practicalities.
Information that
must be passed on.
A computer password or
combo to a safe or something.
Wow, you're pretty jaded.
Many long, torturous cases.
You know, the human psyche
was not designed to deal with this.
Cave dwellers had to deal
with a lot more actual death.
But they were not subjected to the slow
and mechanized torture that is the ICU.
Well, why do you do it, then?
To save the salvageable.
And to give the rest
a dignified death.
Just a little low on
dignity these days.
Well, I'd have a hard
time working here.
Surgeons just like to get
in, do their job and get out.
Yeah, well, that's your job.
But we are left to
deal with the dregs.
And it's not pretty.
I just want us all to do better.
I'm sick of seeing people die.
She had an arteriovenous
malformation in the part of her brain...
that's responsible for
mood and personality.
That explains why she
seemed different to you.
And it's fixed now?
Yes, the radiologist was able to clot
off the vein using a special kind of glue.
- And she'll go back the way she was?
- That's the hope, yeah.
Did you hear that, baby?
It's all gonna be okay.
She's waking up, so we're gonna
take out her breathing tube now.
NIFs are good, and she's
following commands perfectly.
I'll need you to cough
on the count of three.
Ready? One, two, three.
Megan.
I'm sorry.
I am so, so sorry.
I was upset. I just...
I didn't mean to push you.
Okay?
Okay.
Chocolate-covered
strawberries, Room 1258.
The room has been
checked out now.
- No. No, I haven't checked out.
- That's what I'm telling you.
- There must be some mistake.
- There's not a mistake.
- I checked out of the hotel.
- What? No.
Why? I paid for
three more nights.
I know you did, which is crazy.
I got them to refund your card.
I don't want a
refund. Let's call them.
Archie, stop.
No, look.
The flowers, the spa treatments,
it's all lovely, but I don't need it.
- Time to get back to real life.
- I don't want real life.
I like fake life.
Where we wake up and take bubble
baths and eat bonbons for breakfast.
I don't want our crazy
wedding fling to end.
Uh... Who said
anything about it ending?
I wasn't sure...
Dr. Morris, I have not
done this with anyone...
in a long, long time.
And it's not because I
haven't had the opportunity.
I decided to sleep with you
because it means something.
This isn't a fling.
At least, not for me.
She snapped, she had a lapse.
It's not like she's a chronic abuser.
We don't know that. Even
if we did, it doesn't matter.
Guys, did Ray ever show up?
No. NEELA: Or did he call?
It's not like Megan
was trying to throw her.
Give me a break. She pushed her.
If this didn't happen, Sophia's
AVM wouldn't have been diagnosed.
- Excuse me, is Dr. Pratt still in?
- Nurses' station.
One incident doesn't
make it abuse.
She responded to anger with
violence. That's the definition.
- Dr. Pratt.
- Oh, boy.
- I thought I was done with you already.
- Millicent Lawford.
MI in the ER waiting room.
Sat there seven hours
without being triaged.
Gertie Minton. Renal failure.
Twelve hours to be seen and
then arrested from hyperkalemia.
Derek Shank.
In the ER three days
without DVT prophylaxis.
Died.
Died of a PE before
he made it to the floor.
- We can do better for these people.
- I get your point, okay?
But the problems are systemic.
Too many people, not enough resources.
How do you suppose we address that?
Well, first, I think we start by not
believing that this is the best we can do.
Because it's not.
Right.
These are for you.
Ray?
So I could totally tell that
Melissa was copying off my paper.
But if I tell on her,
then I'm a snitch.
And if I don't, then I'm,
like, an accomplice, right?
Right.
And I know, I know.
She's just cheating herself.
But it still seems like
she wouldn't do that.
Yeah, and we learned in chemistry
today how to freebase cocaine.
Really?
Tony, you're totally
not listening to me.
Sarah, when your grandparents
wanted you to move in with them...
I thought that maybe
it was the best thing.
I don't wanna go to
a new school, Tony.
I don't wanna go
and live with them.
Well, I was scared, and I...
I just didn't think I had
what it takes to do this.
But then when we took
the test, I realized that...
I wished it'd gone the other way,
that I wanted to be your daddy.
I wanted that too.
So...
I work a lot and I'm messy.
I may embarrass you at
father-daughter dances.
But I really love you,
Sarah. You're my family.
And it turns out that...
If you wanna stay
with me, you can.
If you... I mean,
if you still want to.
- Hi.
- Hey.
- I missed you guys.
- We missed you too.
- Oh.
- How was the shift?
Oh, who cares?
It's done.
No work for two weeks.
The honeymoon starts now.
Mm. Does that mean you're
ready to change into the bikini?
Maybe after Joe goes to bed.
Joe, go to bed, now. Heh.
I got him.
Sweetie.
Hello?
Hey, Donald, it's Kevin.
Yeah.
Look, I'm glad I
caught you. Ahem.
Do you remember the thing that
we discussed earlier about the ER?
Yeah, well, I can't believe I'm saying
this, but I think I've changed my mind.
I have changed my mind.
I'll do it. Okay, bye.
- Have a good one.
- Oh, good night.
Oh, good night. Good night.
Stay out of the ICU.
That guy's a dick.