What are you starting with?
Laminectomy.
Are you doing it open
or endoscopically?
You know what?
I'm not gonna do this.
What?
You're the one who left neuro.
I know.
Yeah, well, I'm not
gonna do this whole thing
where you're sad about
every case that I have.
I'm not sad.
I'm trying to start
a conversation.
Okay, well...
Make conversation
about something else.
I gotta go.
There are distinct differences
between male and female brains.
Female brains have a
larger hippocampus...
Which usually makes them
better at retention and memory.
Okay, I get that you like
to put your dirty clothes
in my laundry because,
frankly, if you didn't,
you'd never have
any clean clothes.
Fine. I will wash
your dirty underpants.
But you know what? I
am not okay with washing
your skank of the
week's dirty underpants.
Male brains have a
bigger parietal cortex,
which helps when
fending off an attack.
Actually, those are...
Lexie's. Thank you.
Oh.
She... Oh, yeah.
Okay. Never mind.
Not Lexie's. Nope.
Lauren, third floor, Radiology.
Oh.
Nice.
Male brains confront challenges
differently than female brains.
It's three days.
We're gonna be fine.
Bye, Mommies.
Have fun at the
conference, Mommies.
Bye-bye, baby boo.
Go.
Just one more kiss.
Go. Come on.
I'm gonna miss you so much.
Bye. Bye.
See ya.
Bye.
Women are hardwired to
communicate with language...
It's just you and
me, kid. High five.
Detail...
High five.
Dap. Blow it up.
Empathy.
Men...
Not so much.
It doesn't mean that we're
any less capable of emotion.
We can talk about our feelings.
It's just that...
Most of the time...
We'd really rather not.
Great. I come here to eat
breakfast, and it smells like feet.
What's another
word for "crappy"?
Sucky.
Suckity. Stankin'.
Shut up.
You could go with
assy, also, or ass-like.
You're ass-like.
No, that toe jam on
your feet is ass-like.
Honestly...
You ever bathe? No.
I've got that damn
Africa paper and boards.
Man, fifth year blows.
Oh. Hey.
Chief. Sorry.
You don't have
to apologize to me.
You're at the top of
the resident food chain.
The world is your oyster.
Now, if you want
to waste your time
bitching about it,
that's your business.
Hey, have you heard
anything about anything big
coming in today, like a car
accident or a building collapse?
Chief, are you
trolling for cases?
Dude, don't you have a
laminectomy with Shepherd today?
Yeah, but that's a snoozefest.
No, don't you have it now?
Right now.
Oh, damn it.
Shepherd is gonna
have my ass. Damn it!
Wait. Wait. Just tell him
you had an appointment
with Mayfield in
22 and it ran long.
He'll understand.
Yeah. Okay. Thanks, Chief.
Not the chief. Not the chief.
You started? I'm supposed to
be lead surgeon on this case.
You forfeited the
right to take lead
by showing up 20 minutes late.
Dr. Warren, when
you were a fifth year,
were you late to surgery?
Are you kidding?
He's a professional.
And respectful of my OR staff.
Of your attendings.
Definitely my attending.
Dr. Grey was never late.
No. She was many things,
but late was not one of them.
See, Karev here is
just trying to sock away
as much non-peds
hours as possible.
Oh. Slummin' it in neuro, huh?
I'm sorry. I had an appointment
with Mayfield in 22.
It went a little long.
We didn't... DEREK:
Oh, well, in that case...
We didn't realize...
Why don't you come
in and finish up, then?
Thanks.
Can I get a Kerrison Rongeur?
Sloan.
Um...
Look, I'm putting the word out.
My case load's been
kind of light these days,
so if you hear of any
red meat on the floor...
Look at him,
acting like he runs the place.
Well, he does.
He's hanging on by
his teeth. It's undignified.
What are you guys looking at?
Hunt's not cut out for the job.
What, did something happen?
Nothing happened.
You can see it in his demeanor.
He's got fear in his eyes.
He's a decorated
military officer.
What do you think got to
him, call schedule, lunch order?
I'm just sayin', when he belly
flops, I'm here for the hospital.
You're a good man.
Gentlemen, anything
I can do for you?
Just watching the magic.
Actually, I'm glad I ran into
you. I'm gonna need your OR.
We just a call about a big
accident at the convention center.
So I'm gonna have
to bump your brow lift.
Did you say big accident?
Watch him.
How big is big
exactly? Hard to tell.
All I know is, the
paramedics suggested
that we clear as many
beds in the ER as possible.
Did they now? Okay,
what else did they say?
Well, to prep the blood bank,
that we're gonna
need a lot of blood.
Blood? Blood? Did
they say anything else?
Not much. It was hard to talk.
There was a lot of
commotion in the background,
you know, some
screaming... Screaming?
Yeah, screaming.
You know, I don't think I have
ever triaged in a tie before.
Well, just tuck it
in your belt. Okay.
I don't know who
Mayfield in 22 is,
but that's the first time Shepherd's
been off my back all week.
Webber knows things.
The guy is a freakin' genius.
Who's a genius?
Nobody. Um, you look nice today.
Have you heard what's coming in?
Human stampede at
a comic convention.
Dr. Hunt.
Which means crush
injuries. Lots of them.
I have admin on the phone.
They say it's important.
Okay, I've got an
abdominal crush injury.
I'm available.
Oh, I have it, sir. It's
okay, Grey. I'm don't mind.
I have it. It's too
routine for you, sir.
All right, looks like some
lower extremity fractures.
I'll take that for you, Chief.
Got another one coming in.
Ooh! Dibs on footprint face.
I got an unconscious
sexy zombie nurse.
I'll take it.
Oh, no. No, no.
This one is mine!
This is my sexy zombie nurse!
You hear that? Okay.
Bend your knee for me.
Good. Now your ankle.
15 collector's edition replicas
of the Doctor Who TARDIS
in original packaging,
signed by Russell T. Davies,
free to the first 15
people through the door,
and I was there,
right in the middle of it.
Your other knee. I'm never
in the middle of anything.
Ankle.
I have battle wounds.
All right. I'm gonna get
you some painkillers,
and then we'll get
you up to x-rays.
Oh, God. Okay.
Um...
Am I gonna walk again?
No.
I'm just messing
with you. You're fine.
Just got a few
broken toes, if that.
Just toes? Yeah.
Do I at least get
a cast for that?
Primary survey looks good.
Well, this laceration
looks deep.
Let's set up a suture
kit and 4-0 vicryl.
Right away, Doctor.
This is, um...
Why isn't this bleeding?
What is...
It's fake.
The damn thing is fake.
Ah. Never mind. Moving on
to the laceration on her clavicle.
You gotta be kidding me.
Look, is there any
real blood here at all?
Huh?
It was crazy.
500 people trying to fit
through this one little door.
Hell, that kid in the Borg
costume tripped me on purpose.
They just kept
coming and coming,
like they didn't even realize they
were running over a human being.
All right, guys, we
got neck tenderness,
so we want to
be careful on this.
One, two, three.
The worst part was
when Keith's head
got caught on this one
guy's costume and...
And it ripped off his ear?
That's bad, isn't it?
How did nobody mention
that your ear is ripped off?
Well, we looked around
on the floor for a while,
but it's probably, like, stuck
to some Stormtrooper's boot.
Well, at least we
got what we came for.
We got a TARDIS.
Well...
I got a TARDIS.
You broke seven
toes, but really five,
'cause pinkie toes barely count.
So we're just gonna tape
'em up and get you outta here.
Tape? I survive a human
stampede, and all I get is tape?
I'll throw in some crutches.
You don't look like
you've got great balance.
What are you
supposed to be anyway?
I'm a hobbit.
We're a gentle folk
from a farming
community called the Shire.
It's in the northwest
corner of Middle-earth.
We live a simple life,
but we crave adventure.
And when we find it,
some become heroes.
The Dothraki princess.
Yeah. I stopped caring
about 10 minutes ago.
No. That... That doctor
over there looks just like
the Dothraki princess from the
legendary Song of Ice and Fire series.
Not her hair, but her skin
and her eyes, and...
Oh, oh, God. Oh,
God. Here she comes.
Her?
You have nerd chub for Kepner?
Kepner.
Karev, trauma room, now.
Give me my TARDIS!
It's not yours! I fought for it!
I lost an ear for it!
Karev. Please.
No, he's stealing
my TARDIS! Let's go.
Just stop him. Mr. Hitchens,
your ear has lost all
of its soft tissue, but...
We'll be able to construct
an entirely new ear.
We'll take cartilage from
your ribs and match it
to the exact size and
shape of your existing ear.
It's a long process,
but when we're finished,
that ear will look good.
Anything you want to add, Avery?
No. You covered it.
Mr. Hitchens,
what are you feeling right now?
Hurt, betrayed.
Anything in your legs?
No. Nothing.
All right. He needs an
MRI right away, okay?
You paged. What's going on?
Dr. Warren's resident punctured the
dura of your patient from this morning
during what should have
been a routine epidural.
Okay, first of all,
there's no such thing
as anything routine after
a patient's had surgery.
And you have no right
to yell at my resident.
There was spinal
fluid all over her bed.
How is the patient?
Just checked on her.
She's stable and pain free.
Your resident was
sloppy and rushed.
You have no idea how
difficult epidurals can be.
Because I'm a nurse?
Watch your tone with me.
Or what? What are you gonna do?
Okay, okay, done. Break it up.
Walk away. We're done.
Walk away. Walk away.
I get why you're mad at the guy,
but if you're gonna
have a fight about Bailey,
do it on your own time.
Fight about Bailey?
Wait. No.
No, Bailey... Bailey's with him?
I should go.
Like they went to
dinner once or twice or...
You really don't want
to know. Shepherd.
Like don't go into
the conference room
on eight or nine
without knocking.
Oh, come on. You asked.
Does she talk about him?
Yeah, she said his hands
have a kind of tenderness,
uh, some kind of
magic. You're an ass.
Don't yell at my
nurses, even the men.
Sure. Just drop a
bomb and walk away.
Walk away!
Okay, what's next? Sign these.
And these.
And this needs to be
in by this afternoon.
Well, I will look at that
right now. Thank you.
Sure.
All right.
Coming through!
Code blue in 32-12.
Code blue, 32-12.
Hey, Avery, check this out.
Damn.
C-6 is totally shattered.
I know.
I used to eat my
lunch here, too.
Yeah.
Helps break up the day
and gets you outta the office
and let's you feel like
you're still in the action.
Yeah.
Is there something
you might need me for?
Oh, oh, no, no.
I'm just cutting through
on my way to the skills lab.
Um...
Actually, um...
You gonna eat those grapes?
How are the scans?
He's got a burst fracture of C-6
so we need to do
discectomies above and below.
I thought I'd put in a
fibular graft and a plate.
Sounds like a good plan.
You think since I'm
operating in two places,
that this could count
as two neurosurgeries?
Because you need to log
more non-peds surgeries?
Yeah. That's your question?
Young man's spine is pulverized.
You blink once, he
may never walk again.
You don't want to talk
to me about the surgery?
You want to ask to see if
you can get two gold stars
instead of one? No, I...
Just get outta here.
You're off my service.
Go.
Shepherd just
kicked me off neuro
'cause I don't piss myself
every time I look at a spine.
The guy is a douche.
His wife was his resident,
and now he's got you.
Tough act to follow.
Sorry, Chief. I'm not the chief.
We're practicing
microsurgery techniques.
Not for snacking.
You know, you two
need to find a way
to start feeling the joy again.
I mean, there's
gonna come a time
when you're gonna be wishing
you were a fifth year again
just to get back in the OR
and get your hands dirty.
You'll operate
on a grape just so
you'll keep from getting rusty.
You're in the OR all the time.
To supervise, sure.
They'll bring me in on a
really complicated part.
But I never open, I never close.
Is this a technique I could
use on an ear reconstruction?
Yeah, now you see there?
Avery's starting
to feel the joy.
Pull up a grape.
Yes. Please.
Sloan won't let him
touch an instrument.
He barely lets him
finish a sentence.
At least he lets me in the OR.
Can I get you a grape?
Thanks, but Robbins says
she's kicking me to the curb
if I don't publish.
I gotta do my damn Africa paper.
Ugh!
He's not feeling the joy.
Nope.
Now you see this,
how I'm doing it here?
Wow. That bad, huh?
I'm completely
buried in paperwork.
I'm chained to this damned desk.
Finish your drink.
Let's get outta here.
And go where?
Just finish your drink.
I don't understand. Your
contractor doesn't care
that you're building
this deck yourself?
Well, I wouldn't say that,
but he does work for me.
If I didn't have this,
I'd kill my resident.
Karev?
Ah, he's just not interested.
The vertebral column
was wide open,
perfect view of the cord... It's
beautiful. He just could care less.
He's just punching a time clock.
He's not Meredith.
No, he's not.
You know, when
you quit as Chief,
I thought you were
out of your mind.
Now not so much?
Is it me or is everyone
in the hospital
just waiting for me
to fall on my face?
Oh, no. We all got money on it.
I got you down for $100 that
you make it at least six months,
so buck up.
I've been walking on
eggshells at home for weeks.
I used to come to work
to let off steam, and now...
That's become a nightmare, too.
And then Dada used
5-0 monocryl inside
the big man's nose,
and poof!
Like magic, there
was no scar at all.
We're fine, just like
we were 20 minutes ago
and 20 minutes before that.
Are you gonna keep
this up all three days?
Because it got old hours ago.
Oh, God.
Mark? Mark?
Are you there?
Guess who just rolled
over for the first time.
Karev!
Hunt told me I
could take his chair.
Sofia rolled off
the sofa last night,
and she hasn't cried
since. Something's wrong.
Yeah, I'm not a
pediatrician. Sorry.
If I tell anyone in peds,
they'll call Arizona.
Yeah, I got a paper to write.
You drop what
you're doing right now
by the time I count to
three, or I will end you.
One, two...
All right, the residents'
lounge needs a new couch.
Make sure that gets there.
And let's see if
the nurses' station
on the third floor
could use this desk.
Okay. Thank you.
I know. I know what
you're thinking, and no,
as much as you might want
me to, I am not resigning.
I'm just getting
rid of a few things
that I don't feel I
need to be Chief.
And you can say what you want
about how I'm gonna need my office
or need my desk.
I say you're wrong. I say my
office can be wherever I am. Okay?
The procedure went well,
but your spine
is still very fragile.
Good news. We found the ear.
I found it.
I went back to the
convention center,
stayed there all night, looking
through dumpsters and trash.
But guess where it was.
The lost and found, hooked
on to some crazy helmet.
Where's my TARDIS?
Okay.
How about a, "Thank you,
Greg, for finding my ear
"in the trash"?
I don't care about my ear.
I care about the TARDIS.
We care about the ear, Keith.
Keith, try not to move, okay?
Fine.
Can you at least...
Keep it in the living
room so I can look at it?
Actually...
Oh, my God. You
sold it, didn't you?
You sold it? No!
I'll stabilize his neck.
All right, move
your fingers for me.
Your toes.
Is he okay? Move your toes.
Is he okay? I don't know.
His lower extremities
just went limp.
Keith, try and move
your feet for me, please.
Now wiggle your toes.
She's usually a lot
more alert than this.
I sat up with her all night,
checking to make sure
she was still breathing.
Maybe the reason she's not alert
is because you
kept her up all night.
What's that?
Right there. See that?
Yeah. It's a perfectly
healthy brain
of a perfectly healthy baby
who didn't need a CT scan.
The baby's fine. I'm going now.
Yeah, there's the tiger.
Ooh! There's the tiger.
The guy threw a
beer bottle at me.
Who throws bottles
at people's heads?
Carter? Why are you back?
The nurse says you
think I missed something.
Get off me!
You stupid kids with
your idiot convention!
Every year, you
line up on my lawn,
block my driveway.
It's my property, got it?
Sir! Sir! I'm gonna
have you arrested!
You threw a bottle at me!
Sir, get back in the
gurney right now!
I need you back in
the gurney. Thank you.
Bed six, please.
You're here to see Kepner again.
No. I'm here for
an exam. I feel sick.
Look, why don't I give her
your number, you get outta here,
you give her a call,
get your geek on?
Oh, no. I could never...
No, trust me. You two have
more in common than you think.
Couldn't you just admit
me as a patient for the day?
It's not gonna happen.
But what if my foot
was hurting, or my leg?
I'm not giving up a bed for a
stalker with fake symptoms.
Forget it. I have chest pains,
which means you have to admit me
and keep me for
observation, right?
Keith reinjured his spine,
creating an epidural bleed
that needs to be addressed
as soon as possible.
- So does the ear.
- His ear is cosmetic.
The bleed could
leave him paralyzed.
The ear's been detached
for over 20 hours.
If we don't reattach it
soon, it won't be viable at all.
Are you going in through the
front of the neck to get to the spine?
Yes.
So the patient will be
on his back already.
Mmm-hmm.
Why don't we insert the
ear into the abdomen?
Keep it viable with
the blood supply there,
let you operate on the spine.
Take it out
tomorrow, reattach it.
Good idea. Really good idea.
Shep, you need me?
Oh, yes.
So I just swung by your
office, and you weren't there.
Neither was any
of your furniture.
My office is where I am.
You're really taking this "not
being chained behind your desk"
thing seriously.
You find a new resident yet?
I might have a candidate.
By the way, my
contractor called.
The lumber for the deck is in.
I'm there. I get the power saw.
Ow!
Yeah, that's what
real pain feels like.
You think she's okay
over there with that guy?
She's fine.
Get off of me!
Sir, if you do not calm down,
we will have to
restrain you. Are you...
I'm leaving.
Are you sure she's okay?
Now! Ah!
Call security!
Sir. Sir. What the hell?
I have to protect my house!
Oh, God. He's hulking out.
Security!
Give me 5 of haloperidol IM.
I have to protect my house!
Can we get some help?
Hey. Hey. Get off me!
Get outta my way!
I said no!
Somebody, they need
some help over there.
Get off of me! ALEX:
You've gotta hold him still!
I'm trying!
We are a gentle folk
who crave adventure.
When we find it, we become...
Heroes.
I can't be here!
Someone stop him!
Excuse me, sir.
You need to calm down
right now and stop...
Screw you!
- Where is he?
- Around the corner.
Book OR two for a possible
concussion and a broken jaw.
We have a patient
with a broken jaw?
We're about to. I'm on it.
Hey.
Is it true, did you punch a guy?
Shep, I need a neuro consult.
Why, because you punched a guy?
What's this I hear about
you punching a guy?
All right, yes, I
punched a patient
who was endangering
the safety of my nurses,
my residents,
and other patients.
You know you're the
Chief not the sheriff, right?
The scan is clear.
Thank you, all of you, really.
All right.
Yeah, somebody paged me?
This is Carter.
He just got into a fight
with a guy twice his size.
There's a lot of blood
in the peritoneal cavity
and a splenic laceration.
Well, this could
take a while to fix.
Well, you said you wanted
to get your hands dirty, so...
Yeah. Okay, now where
do you think you're going?
Oh, I don't need trauma hours.
I need neuro hours
and to finish my paper.
No, you're not going anywhere.
Boki, you still have
my playlist on rotation?
Well, crank it up.
I had a meeting in the
conference room on nine.
Great deal of
difficulty concentrating.
You asked.
Yeah, but you knew I
didn't really want to know
and you told me anyway,
because you enjoy my pain.
Well, next time, you won't ask.
You have a reputation
for being a nice person.
I think it's a load of crap.
You know what?
I'm building a deck.
Why don't you come by
tonight, take it out on the deck?
That work for
you, hitting things?
Doesn't hurt.
You know, before you
insert that ear, Avery,
why don't you move
over and let me show you
that trick for creating a
subcutaneous pocket?
You showed me
that last week, twice.
And now I'm gonna
show you again.
Where's your resident, anyway?
Don't tell me he's late for
an epidural decompression.
Avery.
Ever decompress a
spinal hematoma before?
I've seen one on a video, yeah.
Great. Do this one.
What? MARK: What?
I'm right here if you need me.
Start with the Leksell,
work your way down
through the bone to the dura.
Okay. Okay?
Hard for you to see
what I'm doing, Avery,
from all the way over there.
Well, I figured you could spare
him, since his hands are free.
Excellent control with
the epidural vein, Avery.
I'm surprised you
never considered neuro.
I was hoping you'd consider
letting me create the
pocket myself next time.
Shepherd let you
touch a vertebra,
now you're ready to
rebuild a face by yourself?
No.
I just want a chance to try
to practice your surgical trick
on something other than fruit.
You're not ready. That's
why you're working on fruit.
When you're done maiming
fruit, we'll talk about it.
Everything okay?
This may be out of line,
but is there any
way I can come over
to your place and
hammer something?
I like your initiative, Avery.
So the wiseass
from legal tells me
I need to apologize to the drunk
who tore up my ER.
She wasn't ready for a
relationship, and now she's in one.
Right. So where is
the accountability?
That's what I want
to know. What the...
You guys always get
worked up like this?
You should give it a try.
No. I'm good.
Just hammering.
Okay.
Thanks for this, by the
way. I know Sloan's my boss,
and he's your friend. I
wouldn't want to overstep.
Not that I ever get a
chance to overstep with him.
Since he has me
on training wheels,
which is fine most
days, except...
When I get home, and it
turns out that my girlfriend,
who is a fourth year, has
done more surgery than me.
Then she asks me
how my day went,
and the answer is,
"Great, sweetheart.
"I just spent the last nine
hours standing around
"watching your ex operate."
Yeah.
I know you feel you have
somewhere better to be right now,
but you don't.
I just want to
finish my paper, sir.
It all falls away...
The research, the
tests, the papers.
We do it to get to this.
Uh-huh.
Adele does that.
What?
She "uh-huhs" me.
Every night when I
fill her in on my day,
she nods and gives
me a lot of "uh-huhs."
But I can tell that
she's uncomfortable
because half the time, she
can't remember where I work.
And it makes her nervous when
I say I'm cutting people open.
Sometimes you
can't see the joyful
part of your life
until it's over.
This is it, Karev.
It's right now.
You're in it.
He's bottoming out.
Grab the hilum and hold
pressure so I can get a better look.
Okay, I'm on it.
All right.
Trying to ligate
the artery and...
Damn it! It's retracting.
Come on, Carter.
Come on!
Let's see if that'll hold.
Ready.
Vitals stabilized.
Feeling the joy yet?
I'm feeling it, sir.
Okay.
Hey. I'm heading up to the lab.
Webber's gonna show
me his signature stitch.
You want to come? Crap.
I'm supposed to help Bailey
and April with a skills lab
for the first years right now.
Grow a pair, bitch boy.
Hey, come on, Avery. Let's go.
Actually, I forgot, I
have an appointment.
So...
An appointment? What
appointment? Hmm?
Uh, with Mayfield, in 22.
Oh. Okay.
That... Sure. Yeah, that's
fine. Right, Dr. Bailey?
Some things, Avery, I
just don't need to know.
Avery. Deck tonight?
Uh, wouldn't miss it.
We still on for the
AVM Tomorrow?
Yes. Absolutely.
Good. Yes.
I finished. Nineteen pages.
Oh, well done.
Hey, hand it over.
Oh, no. It's not
ready for anyone to...
Hey, dude, give that back.
You're gonna fight the Chief?
You're not the Chief.
Once you're the President,
you're always Mr. President.
Now Shepherd wants me on his
surgery, which is great, obviously,
but I'm supposed to be in surgery
with Sloan at the same time.
How am I supposed to choose?
Who do you want
to work with more?
I dig plastics,
but I'd like to actually
be able to operate.
Well, you're choosing between
two world-class surgeons.
This is not a problem. It
is a privilege. Embrace it.
Yeah, feel the joy.
Look at you.
Hey, how'd you get out of
your skills lab with Bailey?
Oh. Mayfield excuse.
You used the Mayfield
excuse on Bailey?
Yes, sir.
I know, right?
Right?
You... With Bailey?
You want a grape?
What happened?
Well, you must have run
the CT wrong or something,
because it's been over 27 hours,
and she still hasn't cried yet.
Something's wrong.
You want to know why
your kid isn't crying?
Because she likes you.
You're a good dad. She's happy.
You want to see her cry?
There. Now she's crying.
It's okay.
They look happy.
Yeah, they do.
Guess I'll be seeing
you at the deck tonight.
The guy was twice my
size. What was I thinking?
I'm an idiot.
Or a hobbit. What?
That's what you said, right?
When hobbits find adventure,
they become heroes.
You stepped up.
All right, so you got
flattened by a giant.
It's still cool.
And I'm not the only
one who thinks so.
All right. Remember...
All you have to do is
say hi. Let her do the rest.
Wait. Wait. Hang on.
Hey.
Thank you for what you did,
standing up to that guy the
other day. That was so brave.
I was a hobbit.
Oh.
Okay. I'm not really
familiar with hobbits,
but anyway, that...
Okay. Thank you. Bye.
Whatever happened
to just saying hi?
Not familiar with hobbits?
They're only the central figures
in one of the most famous
pieces of literature in history,
not to mention the subject
of one of the highest-grossing
film franchises ever,
but, okay, not familiar
with hobbits. Sure.
Hi.
Hey.
You get that ear prepped yet?
I may
have to scrub out
of your rhinoplasty
just a little early
tomorrow, if that's okay.
You're in my light.
Uh, last night,
Shepherd asked me
to scrub in on his AVM surgery,
which is a big
opportunity for me,
because he's gonna... He's
gonna let me take the lead, so...
Last night?
Yeah.
You were with Shepherd
last night? Where?
Oh, just...
What? Hmm? At his deck.
At his deck?
Yeah.
You're right.
Taking the lead on a
surgery is a big opportunity
you should not pass up.
That's why...
I'd like you to
take the lead now.
Sew this guy's ear
back on by yourself.
Thank you.
Don't screw it up.
Hello. I'm Dr. Hunt.
I am the surgeon who
repaired your broken jaw.
I am also the guy who broke it.
It's wired shut right now, so
I'll do the talking.
Now they want me
to come down here
and apologize to you,
and I want to make
something quite clear.
I feel good about what I did.
Now, I reviewed
the security tape,
and I easily prevented
half a dozen people
being injured by you.
You assaulted a
girl with a beer bottle.
You attacked hospital staff.
You put a man on the critical list.
You were violent and abusive
in front of dozens of witnesses,
and I will stand up
in any court of law
and say just that.
I do not apologize for
things I feel good about,
and I feel good about this.
So...
If you want to sue,
you sue.
And good luck
with your recovery.
Take a look.
Dr. Jason Mayfield,
ED specialist?
Room 22. Mayfield in 22.
You told Bailey you
had erectile dysfunction.
You told Shepherd.
Oh, hey, Karev. There you are.
Just read your paper.
Excellent first draft.
Oh, uh, and...
Don't hang out by Mayfield.
People get the wrong idea.
Yeah.
This looks fantastic, Keith.
You should have
very minimal scarring.
Oh! Go away. GREG: No.
Sorry? I've got a bad ear.
Pretty sure I didn't hear that right.
Okay, yeah, I sold the TARDIS.
But as your friend, I'm
gonna be honest with you.
It was the right thing to do.
Our place is crammed
with all that stuff you collect.
You spend all your
money on it. You're broke.
And do you have
any idea how many
medical bills you're
about to have?
That TARDIS was worth cash.
Real, actual cash
that you don't have.
So, yeah, I am sorry that I
sold your precious TARDIS.
I am.
But I did it for you.
Who'd you sell it to, anyway?
The guy with the comic
store. The one in San Diego.
Morris? Ugh! I hate that guy.
How much did you get for it?
$7,500.
Well, he ripped you off.
What's wrong with you?
The chief beat the
crap out of my paper.
I basically have
to start all over.
I can't believe this.
I am back where I
started three days ago.
No paper, no neuro
cases. I mean, it sucks.
Grab your coat.
This is a bad idea.
Shepherd hates me.
I hate the woods.
You know there
are bears out here?
I hope you don't mind.
I brought Karev.
Fifth year is really
kicking my ass.
I mean, it's no
excuse, all right?
But I didn't mean to be
disrespectful or whatever.
Also, I lied about
Mayfield, just to be clear.
Derek.
You're trying to steal my guy.
He's my guy. Avery,
go get in the car.
What? No. Mark...
You've been moving
in on him all week.
You weren't even
interested in him
till you saw how
much he meant to me.
I don't take the time to
teach anyone if I can help it.
Mark... But I'm taking
the time with Avery
because he's a quick learner
and he can do a z-plasty
better than I could at his level.
I can?
Hey, hey, don't do that.
Don't just yell at
me, then walk away.
I'm not. It's just, Sofia
likes it if I'm moving.
Oh.
You guys talk.
I'll take the baby.
Okay, careful. We
had a scare this week.
Okay. All right.
Now...
Thank you.
Avery, go get in the car!
How are you tonight?
You good? You want
to come and sit with me?
Here we go.
We're just gonna sit right here
and have a look at
the little tree up there.
Friends don't steal
from each other.
It's not stealing if he asks
to scrub in on my surgery.
- Don't be a jackass.
- All right, look.
I appreciate this, I do,
but if I have to choose,
I choose plastics.
I mean, I really appreciate
being able to take the
lead on your neurosurgeries,
but I feel like... You
using my boy here
to get more surgery?
Nobody uses my boy.
Why are we the only
ones with hammers?
I'm getting a beer.
Be a man.
People say it all the time.
You want to play with the truck?
You can touch the truck.
But what does that even mean?
Honey.
Dinner's ready.
Is it about strength?
We're gonna sing a song
and look at the tree.
Are you tired?
You're tired. Right?
Is it about sacrifice?
What do you think
they're talking about?
My guess?
Which one of 'em gets
to take you to prom.
Is it about winning?
Maybe it's simpler than that.
You're not getting laid.
That's why you have this
sudden interest in education.
When Richard asked you
who should be the next Chief,
did my name come up?
You just had a baby.
You don't want to be Chief.
And he didn't ask me.
What if he'd asked?
You just had a baby.
You know, a few weeks ago,
I knew exactly how the
next 10 years would play out.
Work, family...
And then...
I lost the trial, baby...
Blacklisted by the
FDA and Meredith...
Some days, I miss her so much,
I don't know if I'm gonna make it.
You have to know
when not to man up.
Did you tell Hunt any of this?
I did not. Just checking.
I think Sofia needs a change.
Here.
I'll tell you what
else you don't know,
is how to build a deck.
This thing isn't level.
I gotta call my contractor.
Sometimes it takes a real man
to set his ego aside,
admit defeat,
and simply...
Start all over again.