The Patuxent River
Naval Air Station near DC
was commissioned in 1943
by John McCain's grandfather.
I'm thinking of
going hang-gliding.
Pax River's, like,
completely flat.
I think that's why they
tested the V-22 Osprey there.
I like naval stuff.
I like their oranges and lint.
What looks like kidney disease
but isn't? And where's Chase?
Root canal and Berger's. The
first one was regarding Chase,
root canal, if done correctly,
doesn't look like kidney disease.
Got a case for you.
Smells funny.
Patient had an idiopathic
anaphylactic reaction,
stumped two ER docs and an
immunologist from Johns Hopkins.
Patient went from asymptomatic
to fried kidneys in less than a year,
stumped three internists and a
department chair from Harvard.
Fourteen-year-old
girl, intermittent attacks.
Four-year-old boy,
consistently at death's door.
This patient died
five years ago.
Didn't say which side
of the door he was on.
The fact that he's dead
makes it more interesting.
Four-year-olds do
not die of Berger's.
I thought it was relevant.
Death is a consequence,
not a symptom,
and if it's not a
symptom, it's not relevant.
Shouldn't we be trying to
maximize what we can save here?
The 14-year-old, your
freedom, our asses...
Right. Save your asses.
She was in a car accident
when she was two.
She only had minor
injuries but her father died.
That was 12 years ago.
You think that's pertinent?
No, I think it's sad.
She got sick in the middle
of her 14th birthday party.
Which is sad and pertinent.
Maybe she was opening a
present that triggered the reaction.
Where's House? Pissing
contest with Foreman.
Last thing she ate
was strawberry cake
but allergy tests for
everything were negative.
You like your dentist? I'm
still going to my pediatric one.
What's your dentist's name?
Williams.
But what if it's not
an allergic reaction?
Hereditary
angioedema or systemic
mastocytosis could
mimic anaphylaxis.
You're not sure of his name?
You just saw him this morning.
The assistant's name is
Angie, her home number is...
Normal complement
studies, no skin lesions.
You had a manicure. This is
fresh. You weren't at the dentist.
Why would you lie about that?
To avoid having
this conversation.
Elevated BP. What
about pheochromocytoma?
Or an anaphylactoid reaction, which
could be triggered by certain opioids.
You've had your hair cut
three times since I've met you.
You can't be embarrassed
about a manicure.
There's got to be
a deeper reason.
Did House give you homework?
She's not on any meds.
Haven't you heard?
Everybody lies.
And the tox screen was clean.
Feel free to jump
in at any time.
We'll check
catecholamines for pheo
and run an expanded
opioid panel.
You see what the
patient says about
drug use when her
mother's out of the room.
No. Never.
Nobody's here to bust you, Iris,
we just need to know
if... No. I already told you.
I just take vitamin C sometimes.
What exactly were you doing
when you had your reaction?
Opening a birthday
present. The Magic 8-Ball.
The joke gift, not
the cocaine. Is that it?
Certain drugs could
explain her reaction.
What kind of drugs?
What kind did you have in mind?
Iris has always
been a moody girl,
and now that she's a
teenager, it's gotten worse.
So for the past few months, I've
been giving something to relax her.
Diazepam. I tell
her it's vitamin C.
Being normal is
very important to Iris.
She couldn't handle the
thought of being on meds.
Anti-anxiety medications
would explain it.
If we keep her off, she'll
be moody but healthy.
Or it's something else.
Need to DDx a patient with you.
I thought you had
a team for that.
According to
Foreman, they're only
for DDxing people
who are still alive.
You have a dead patient?
Bigotry is born when
we add modifiers.
I don't see creed, color, pulse.
Foreman will find out you're
taking this case and he'll bust you.
But you know
that, which means...
You want to go back to jail
because it's the one place
you're unable to indulge
your self-destructive habits.
Yeah. It's much more
likely that I'm taking this case
because I miss showering
with Cro-Magnons,
than I actually happen
to find it interesting.
Four-year-old kid.
His kidneys died, they
transfused, his lungs died, he died.
Have you seen
Bride of the Monster?
I just got the Ed Wood box set.
What if the chicken was the egg?
What if the lung
involvement came first?
I don't really care
about the movie,
I just don't want
to indulge your...
Lupus.
Because this is a
bad idea, House.
If the kid had a rash or
some circulation issue...
Damn!
Sorry. Just realized I'm late
for my anger management class.
Traffic, for sure.
- Taxes.
- Definitely taxes.
Spoiled grandchildren.
Platitudes.
Any others?
And I lose my temper
when someone suggests
that a handful of
pop-psych catchphrases
can control our most
seminal, intractable
and natural reaction
to a dead child.
Am I right, Emory?
I don't think Emory
wants to share right now.
They blew it, didn't they?
They missed your son's rash.
A faint one, on his cheek.
He didn't have a rash.
I think we should talk
about Lena's grandchildren.
They're alive.
Was he sensitive
to sunlight? No.
Greg. Cold fingers and toes?
No!
Wegener's granulomatosis.
I need to examine your son.
You're a bit late
for that, you ass.
With you and
your wife's consent,
we could get an
exhumation order.
Find out what killed him.
Ex-wife and you'll
never get her consent.
She's moved on,
new hub, new kid.
She wants nothing to
do with Drew's death.
Or me.
You're angry
because your kid died.
More than that, because
you don't have an answer.
People need answers.
He's in a crypt at
St. Jude's Cemetery.
You feeling any pain
or cramp in here?
A bit.
But not just there. Um...
Here.
Breast tenderness. Have you
been having regular periods, Iris?
Not really.
What is it?
I think we should
run a pregnancy test.
Iris isn't sexually active. She
doesn't even have a boyfriend.
Pregnancy would explain
all of her symptoms,
can even cause some
unpredictable allergic reactions.
How can I be pregnant if
I've never even had sex?
We just need to
draw a bit of blood.
What's the matter?
My arms.
I can't feel my arms.
At this rate, I'm gonna need
to pick out a plot for myself.
Thanks to your generous
donation, you have all morning.
More like 13 minutes.
Before we proceed any
further, Doctor, I'd like to inquire
as to exactly what procedure you
intend to perform on the remains.
You ever heard of the North American
Man Dead Boy Love Association?
I consider these
grounds to be a holy place
and I would ask you to
observe them with due decorum.
So you're taking bribes to plunder
graves and I need to show respect.
I think they got the
cause of death wrong
and if I find a hole in the cartilage
of his nose, right about here,
then it means I'm right.
Please be respectful.
I have prepared the
sarcophagus for you.
Thank you, Igor.
It's Milton.
You owe me a new pair of pants.
She is pregnant. Test
came back positive.
So she lost the use of her
arms and her innocence.
A vengeful god or...
Cerebral tumor.
Vasculitis.
MS.
I gather from the silence
that Chase isn't there.
No, I'm here. Where are you?
"Nowhere," he said cryptically.
I assume you concur
with the diagnosis.
Absolutely.
Even though there
are three diagnoses.
And MS and vasculitis usually
get better with pregnancy.
Yeah. I was saying I
agreed with the other one.
He's had his eyebrows waxed.
I met a woman who likes
her men well-groomed.
All over?
I assume from the silence
that Chase has had a Brazilian.
Cool. Interesting.
Ouch.
The question is, is this
really about a woman,
or is it about something
more profound?
Another question is, could the
paraesthesia be caused by an STD?
HIV-related
mononeuritis multiplex.
I gather from the silence that
either you all agree with Chase
or you're just staring at
his emasculated brow.
In either case, test for HIV and
do an MRI to rule out tumors.
And check Chase
for testosterone.
Bloodwork was negative for
HIV. All the money's on tumor.
How was the Brazilian?
It was fine. Hurt a bit.
What about House's
theory? Why'd you really do it?
Because I'm vain and shallow.
And you weren't before?
The girl I was seeing wasn't.
There's nothing profound here.
No tumor either.
It's not her brain.
Everything looks good.
What's the matter? My arms.
Still nothing? No.
Now they're sore.
The paraesthesia's gone.
Could the bruising be
caused by physical trauma?
You think she fell
out of bed repeatedly?
A blood disorder,
maybe thrombocytopenia?
A vitamin K deficiency or scurvy
could explain bleeding problems
and pregnancy
could exacerbate it.
Boys, do a home search,
girls, do the lab tests.
I'm pretty sure
that's not sexist.
Where've you been?
Picking up dry cleaning, filling
up the tank, violating the dead.
If you don't believe me,
call the monitoring company.
I did.
Unfortunately,
the Patuxent River
Naval Air Station
was GPS testing
and disrupted the signal
at the exact same 45
minutes you weren't here.
If I'd known I had 45
minutes of freedom,
I would have gone hang-gliding.
I admire the creativity.
But what happens when
the stunt doesn't work?
You think you're gonna
have to pay off a bet?
You think I'm gonna
triple your clinic hours?
I'm gonna call your PO and
you're gonna go back to jail.
There are Mees
lines on his fingernails,
so now I'm thinking
heavy metal poisoning.
You're an addict.
And I'm an idiot
for thinking that your
addictions were limited
to pills, anti-social
behavior and sarcasm.
Sorry. Vicodin repeating on me.
You're also addicted to puzzles.
You show all the
classic behaviors,
lying, neglecting
responsibilities,
and you can't stop no matter
how devastating the consequences.
Working on a medical case is not
a parole violation,
it's my job description.
Your job description is doing
what Foreman tells you to do.
Never mind Bride of the Monster,
you need to watch Norma Rae.
Before we get
started, I just want to
thank you all for
agreeing to relocate.
I had an appointment
in this part of town
and I obviously didn't
want to miss this meeting.
But thank you. I'm buying.
Not literally.
Hey, Emory, shall
we powder our noses?
Hey, did you know your ex-wife
still lives right behind this place?
She finishes work at 4:00,
picks up her new kid at 4:15.
Gives us about 20 minutes.
I made some calls.
It's amazing what people will
tell you if you ask rudely enough.
Was that table here?
Some kinds of pressure-treated
wood can contain arsenic.
We shouldn't be here.
We don't have a choice.
This is the only way I'm
gonna get your answer.
Does your ex leave a
spare key anywhere?
How did he look?
Peaceful.
Vitamin K deficiency's a bust.
Fridge has more spinach and
broccoli than a farmers' market.
The Brazilian, you
said it hurt a bit.
You've had one? More
than one. And you haven't.
They hurt all your bits.
That's my dark
secret. What's yours?
I had the nails and
eyebrows done but that's it.
I just needed to
create a distraction.
I met a TV producer at a dinner,
she asked me to appear
on their medical segment.
I screen tested it
yesterday and shot it today.
You're a TV doctor?
It's a one-off. When did it air?
Two hours ago,
otherwise I'd still be lying.
This is what she was opening
when she had her attack.
Will anyone believe
Chase is an actual doctor?
"Don't count on it."
She does have a boyfriend.
Love letters.
Porn? CHASE: The nasty kind.
Torture, rape, animals.
Sweet kid.
This is all that's left.
One box in the
bottom of a closet.
He used to wear those
stupid things all the time.
I used to have to
pretend I was scared.
Made in the People's
Republic of Lead Paint.
Back door.
Let's get out of here first. Need
to catch the end of our class.
I met him at school.
He was the only
boy that liked me.
It's a little more than like.
We haven't had sex.
Oh, come on, Iris,
you're pregnant.
So I'm just lying
about everything?
Well, you lied
about the boyfriend,
you obviously lied about
sex and this garbage.
They're his. He can't
keep them at his place.
Well, I'm glad we could
be so accommodating.
What else don't I know?
Honey.
What is it?
He came here last night,
and he told me I should leave.
But I didn't want
to and he got mad.
He hit you? Physical trauma.
Explains the negatives
for the blood disorders.
We should call the police.
I won't tell them anything.
That's ridiculous, he beat you.
What is it?
It's getting hard to see.
What the hell is
happening to me?
Rubbing alcohol, vinegar...
Not sure what this is.
Aren't there actual
medical tests?
Dead patients usually get
a lower standard of care.
Pink means lead, orange means
mercury and rust means arsenic.
What's brown mean?
Scotch.
He used to call him Deezer.
He couldn't say "zebra."
Made up his own words for
everything. We called them Drewisms.
How does your ex-wife do it?
How come she's not
angry and miserable?
She treated it like
it never happened.
She never even cried.
Not even at his funeral.
I was a mess and
she just sat there like
a statue.
We have a problem.
Does it limp?
Why do you care if he
works on two cases?
Because next it'll be
three cases, then four,
then animal cases and ghost
cases, then animal-ghost cases.
Assuming, of course, we
are talking about House.
You're just setting
yourself up to fail.
He has a lot more to lose
than I do. And he knows that.
He's rational.
No, he's not.
He's the most rational man
I've ever met. Annoyingly so.
He's not gonna put himself
back in jail over a dead kid.
He's an addict.
And he will put himself
back in jail over a puzzle.
He'll back down.
Halfway through the perimetry
exam, her tunnel vision went away.
She could see perfectly. - TIA.
The word "transient" is
right there in the name.
Ah. Here we go.
Shazza, after giving
the pics an eye or two,
I can confirm that Lauren's
surgeries cost her some big bikkies.
Not only was there a gut
tuck, nose tuck, and arse tuck,
but her new fake norks
stick out like nuts on a mutt.
The original script wasn't...
Anyone notice Brad's
cossie fitting a little bit
snugger? He's enlightening us.
That's 'cause he's
retooled the ol' todger.
Let's just hope no one
cut the wrong wire, eh?
So you just wanted
to look pretty on TV?
Question is, why
did he want that?
Clinic time.
What do you want us to do?
MRA for TIA.
ROFL.
Thought you only
had clinic on Tuesdays.
Oh, you're right.
Hi. I'm here for the free
flu shot. I got a call saying...
And I'm here to find out why
you didn't care about your first kid.
Losing a child, you just
breezed right through it.
What do you know
about my first kid?
Couldn't even squeeze out
a single tear at the funeral.
Where are you getting this?
Couldn't wait to squeeze out
a brand new replacement kid.
Damn it.
You had no right to say that.
I know. I deserved the slap.
But I was hoping that
you weren't capable of it.
Apathetic hyperthyroidism.
Could have kidney involvement, could
be genetic, definitely causes apathy.
I was hoping that
your lack of emotion
was a symptom of something you
could've passed on to your first son.
You know Emory.
We belong to the same club.
He wants to
relive this, I don't.
So I heard.
Emory was a wonderful man.
Never afraid to
show his emotions.
Which is great most of the
time but when Drew died,
it overwhelmed him.
I vowed I wouldn't
let that happen to me.
That's why you left him?
I left because of his eyes.
He had Drew's eyes.
Who used to babysit Drew?
My father, but...
His place or yours?
There are two types of people.
Those who can move
on and those who can't.
My father keeps up a good
front but he's just like Emory.
You need to leave him alone.
So he has two types
of people inside of him.
MRI was normal.
Yeah...
I found out where
your boyfriend lives.
When I paid him
a visit, he took off,
ran in front of a car.
You're lying.
He's down in the ER right now.
Shut up, you lying sack of crap!
Iris.
How do you know I'm lying?
How do you know that
your boyfriend is okay?
'Cause I'm right here, you dick.
Iris has dissociative
identity disorder
also known as multiple
personality disorder.
Are you saying I'm crazy?
It's the mind's response
to a severe trauma.
The person experiences something
that's too difficult to accept,
so they create alternate personalities
that don't have to accept it.
Some think it's quite
a natural reaction.
Iris hasn't had any
severe traumas.
The car accident.
I was two.
I don't remember anything.
These personalities that I'm
supposed to have, where are they?
They only come out when
you're afraid or anxious.
That's why House used
the hurt-boyfriend story.
But if there's no boyfriend,
where did the bruises come from?
The pregnancy?
When you say your
boyfriend hit you,
it means you
actually hit yourself.
And the pregnancy doesn't
take a boyfriend, just a boy.
You may not be aware of
half the things you've done.
How could this be happening to my
own daughter without me knowing it?
Diazepam was masking it. Taking
her off made it more apparent.
But I... I wasn't on...
Diazepam? What is that?
That's what those
vitamin pills were.
Iris, I'm so sorry.
I just thought you were moody.
I didn't want you to think
you needed medication.
Oh, my God, I can't
believe how stupid I've been.
We need you to help
us with something.
Different alters can have
different apparent symptoms,
allergies, paraesthesia, vision
loss, changes in blood pressure.
Do you think I'm making this up?
Your symptoms are real,
but some are physiological
and others are psychological.
So there's something
wrong with her
in addition to the
multiple personalities?
Yes, but we won't know
what until we access her alters
and compare their symptoms.
How do you do that?
Hypnosis.
Foreman's not gonna back down.
He's not an idiot. Yes, he is.
Just like you. If you keep being
stubborn, he will keep being stubborn.
Eventually you will
screw something up,
which will be bad
news for both of you
but only one of
you will be in prison.
It just isn't worth it, House.
Okay.
Uh... Yes, sir. Yes,
I know I told you
that I had a
chiropractor's appointment,
but I got a flat.
I know, right?
So, don't send out the Marines.
I should be back on the
road in a few minutes.
Okay, bye.
Dr. James Wilson,
county coroner.
I'd like to ask you about
your grandson, Drew Lemaine.
What did he do when he was here?
Where did he play?
What did he eat?
We watched a lot of
TV. And ate biscuits.
Did you give him
sidewalk chalk? No.
Fingerpaints? No.
A sandbox?
Like I said, we
watched a lot of TV.
You expecting someone?
What?
Dr. Wilson, my ass.
I told you to leave him
alone, you son of a bitch!
Temper trigger!
Who am I talking to now?
Nobody.
You must be somebody.
I'm too little.
Nobody sees me.
Nobody knows I'm here.
BP just went to 140 over 90.
What is it?
My arms.
You can't feel them?
It's okay, we can fix that.
Do you hurt anywhere else?
Not right now.
But you used to hurt?
When I eat strawberries.
And when I remember...
You remember being hurt?
I remember everything.
Baby...
It's going to be okay.
Iris, why didn't
you ever tell me?
It was my fault Daddy died.
Oh, no.
Yes, it was. I was crying
and he couldn't drive.
It was my fault Daddy died.
Oh, no. No, no, honey.
You were just a baby.
It wasn't your fault. No...
It was my fault.
I'm sorry, Mommy.
Poor baby.
I'm so sorry.
It wasn't a miscarriage.
Tests show she's still pregnant.
Okay, cross out everything
that doesn't appear in every alter.
When she opened
the Magic 8-Ball,
it triggered a switch to a
personality with a strawberry allergy.
Pregnancy, vaginal
bleeding and elevated BP.
Could be a preeclampsia.
Worst case, could be
an ectopic pregnancy.
We need to ultrasound.
Not seeing an embryo
in the fallopian tube.
Not seeing an embryo anywhere.
Which idiot did
the pregnancy test?
I did one of them. Chase
did another, Taub did a third.
Three tests, three positives.
What happened to your eye?
I grabbed Park's ass.
Exoplanets.
I think he said
exoplanets. Wait for it.
We can't actually see them,
but we infer their existence
because of the effect they
have on the star they orbit.
Pregnancy test only infers
an embryo's existence
because of elevated hCG levels.
Which could also be
caused by choriocarcinoma,
which affects the
placenta, mimics pregnancy,
and causes elevated
BP and vaginal bleeding.
Occult choriocarcinoma,
which is why
we didn't see it
on the ultrasound.
Tell all the alters
that they have cancer.
Mom or dad?
Mom, dad and mom's dad.
The good news is it made
me realize that you were right.
I can't drop it.
But now that I accept that,
I feel much less conflicted.
I've ruled out Wegener's,
Berger's, heavy-metal poisoning...
Two trains are about to collide
and I'm trying to
talk them out of it.
I still think I'm
missing something.
No, no. You don't
want to listen to me,
then I don't want
to listen to you.
That is so fifth grade.
I agree. And you know why?
Because I'm just as bad as you.
I knew this would
fall on deaf ears
but I just kept
talking and talking.
You're right.
You don't even
know what I just said.
That is ridiculous.
You said, "Blah, blah, blah,
deaf ears, blah, blah, blah."
Absolutely
essential information.
Ray! Ray!
Leave him alone! What
are you doing to him?
It's okay.
Mickey.
You? You brought him?
I asked him to meet me
here for a family reunion.
Ray!
Let's just get out
of here, okay?
I know what killed your son.
You don't get it, do you? I
don't care what killed him!
It's called Alport syndrome.
It's a genetic condition
characterized by kidney failure,
bronchial myomas,
Mees lines and deafness.
Idiot, Drew wasn't deaf.
Son of a bitch! Get
away from them!
House. House!
It's a genetic condition.
Shut up! Genetic.
Your father has the
gene and so do you.
It was Grandpa's slight deafness
that gave the game away.
You're apparently asymptomatic,
but you still passed the
gene on to your children.
Plural.
You're lying.
He has high frequency hearing
impairment and so did Drew.
That's why Drew
made up his own words,
'cause he couldn't
hear properly.
It's okay. Now that
we know what it is,
he'll need treatment
but he'll live.
You know, there are platitudes
that can help you with that.
I miss him, too.
She's responding well.
Cuddy threatened
him with clinic duty.
I thought threatening him
with jail would be different.
Not an irrational thought.
I'm still sending him back.
He saved two lives.
Which means it's too
late for me to back down.
It's no longer my choice.
It's just me telling him he
can get away with anything.
I have to send him to prison.
Your job is to keep
this machine running.
It's your choice to make House
a useful tool or a monkey wrench.
Cuddy's way didn't fail.
Because she didn't try to
control House, she managed him.
And she knew better than
anybody what a tool he could be.
What would Cuddy have done?
Ten clinic hours.
Cuddy's not here anymore.
You've got 30.