♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
I keep sneaking into the lab,
checking on the embryo.
Checking for what?
I don't know. I guess...
Just standing watch?
That sounds ridiculous,
right?
It doesn't sound ridiculous.
It sounds maternal.
♪ ooh ♪
♪ you're pissing me off ♪
♪ ooh, but your hair is
so luxurious ♪
Hey.
Hey, uh, where do you think
you're going?
I gotta go into
work and write up some consults.
Hey, have you seen my cell?
I can't find it.
Uh...
Uh, you were sitting
on Amelia's deck...
Oh, yeah.
Where you had it last night.
Yeah, I'll swing by
and get it before I go in.
And don't forget...
Mm.
We have Violet's thing
this morning.
Mm-hmm. Okay.
Mm.
♪ Well, your looks had me
putty in your hand now ♪
Okay, I can't do this.
I can't do this.
Mm. Come on.
Come on. Come on.
No. No, no, no.
I got some condoms.
I promise I'll stay far away
from your injection site.
We can--
that's...
Very chivalrous of you,
but, um, I can't,
because, uh, I can't have sex
for two days before I get...
Impregnated.
Well, technically,
it's implanted, but yes.
And that's tomorrow?
Yeah.
Okay. All right.
I understand.
Okay.
♪ Yeah ♪
Mm.
♪ Everybody tells me ♪
♪ ooh ♪
♪ I need to let go ♪
♪ I know ♪
♪ but your cocoa butter skin
now ♪
Hello.
Hi.
I could get used to this view.
Mm.
I'm Addison.
And you?
Ryan, uh, Amelia's friend.
How do you do?
Morning, Addie.
Good morning. Ahem.
I see you met Ryan.
Yes.
So no surgeries
this morning?
♪ Please, baby ♪
Surgeries?
I thought we were
going back to bed.
Yeah, I'll--
I'll be there in a sec.
♪ Yeah, you can walk
your cold heart, baby ♪
♪ right out of my life ♪
♪ so long ♪
Taking the day off.
Really?
Well, look at him.
If I canceled work every time
I met a hot guy...
I'll call you later, okay?
♪ Keep on walkin' now ♪
♪ so long,
you did me wrong ♪
♪ leave me alone ♪
Mm.
"Welcome back iolet"?
There was no sign,
no "do not touch"
or "these are for the party."
The sign is on the cupcakes,
Sheldon.
Hey. Sam has rounds.
Where's everyone else?
Oh, Pete's covering a shift
in the E.R.
What about Amelia?
I called her this morning.
I never heard back.
Well, she's at home.
Sick?
No, she's, uh, shacked up
with this very handsome guy.
What guy?
His name is Ryan.
So she's playing hooky
with this Ryan guy,
and--and you're
just letting her?
I'm not her mother, Sheldon.
I'm sure
she'll be back tomorrow.
I'm not so sure.
What do you mean?
Well, she quit.
What?
We had a disagreement about
punctuality and her lack of it,
and she elected to resign
from the hospital.
Violet. Violet. Violet.
Surprise!
Thanks, you guys.
Oh!
We missed you around here.
I know your patients
will be thrilled.
Oh, not as thrilled
as I am. Mm.
Hi.
I gotta go to the E.R.
welcome home.
Thank you.
"Welcome back olet"?
What?
We already yelled "surprise."
Set the vent on fio2 of 100,
rate of 26.
What happened?
Shannon iverson.
She's one of my patients.
Motor vehicle accident.
Severe blunt head trauma.
Absent corneal reflex.
She's carrying
a 16-week-old fetus.
Mom have any brain activity?
None. And she's not breathing
without the ventilator.
Okay, fetal heart rate
looks strong.
Looks like she's still carrying
a healthy baby boy.
Hey. Thanks for calling.
Is this Shannon?
You know her?
She's an organ donor, Jake.
Yeah,
my patient needs her heart.
I worked with Shannon
and her husband for four years,
multiple rounds of I.V.F.
This baby is their miracle.
A 16-week-old miracle
who's not yet viable.
My patient has cardiomyopathy--
status 1A, desperately needs
a new heart.
So you do a risky transplant
on your patient.
If she's lucky,
she gets what, ten years?
This baby
can have a full life.
If it even survives.
The mother's brain-dead.
Can the baby make it?
It's a long shot.
But it is possible?
It's possible, yes,
but it doesn't justify
turning the mother
into a human Incubator.
So what, you'd rather just
pull the plug on this woman?
Would I rather? No.
But the reality is, she probably
won't survive long enough
to bring the baby to viability,
and even if she does,
the placental blood flow
and fetal oxygenation
might be compromised,
both of which are critically
important to the fetus.
She signed the donor card
so she could save
a lot of people with her organs.
And I know this woman wants
this baby more than anything.
Well, she's not gonna
be around to raise it.
But her husband can.
Well, where is he?
They're taking
some time apart.
Actually,
it's been about a year.
The stress
of the fertility treatments
was really hard on them,
so Doug took off, and Shannon's
been trying on her own.
Okay. So the husband's
not in the picture,
and she's--she's brain-dead.
Why are you fighting this?
The point is moot.
Without a family member to make
an affirmative decision,
the hospital has to rely on
the intent of the donor card.
In 24 hours,
we'll do a repeat e.E.G.,
certify brain death,
and Shannon becomes a donor.
What if I find Doug?
You better do it fast.
Hey.
Is everything all right?
Well, I drove Mason
to school this morning,
only we get there,
and no school.
There was no school?
Well, there's a school.
Open it is not.
She talks like Yoda
when she's stressed.
Someone,
who shall rename nameless,
forgot to mention
it's teacher planning day.
So hang out
with Mason today I must.
I will pick him up
around 6:30.
At my place.
But it'll just be you
hanging out with him, right?
No Charlotte?
Right. Right.
Okay.
You ever built a fort
made out of tongue depressors?
No.
Mm-hmm.
I brought you the "o."
Thanks. I'm still digesting
the "v" and the "I."
Uh...
How's it feel, being back?
Oh, it's a relief.
I really missed being here.
And I had enough
of being at home.
Do you want
to talk about that?
No. I-I just want
to get back to work.
Okay.
So, uh,
one of the requirements
for, uh,
reinstating my license
is to have a period
of practice supervision.
Well, i'd--I'd be honored.
I mean,
if--if you're asking me.
I am.
You know, I've supervised
a few therapists before.
Just so you understand,
it's more of a formality.
Just dotting the i's,
crossing the t's.
Actually, it's, uh,
a little bit more than that.
You know, it can be a valuable
experience for therapists
who want to
shake the rust off,
provided both parties
take it seriously, of course.
Of course.
It's gonna be fun.
Should we have the, uh, carnitas
or the al pastor?
Both. Then you can
have me again.
Hey, Amelia.
Hi. Uh...
What are you doing here?
We're getting tacos.
Uh, this is Mason. Mason,
this is Dr. Shepherd.
Nice to meet you.
Hey.
Mason's my son.
How you doing, man?
We just washed our hands.
Whatever.
You doing okay?
Why wouldn't I be?
No, I just heard
that you quit your job
and you're hanging out
with some guy.
His name is Ryan
and he's great.
And did Ryan
quit his job, too?
Okay, don't start
getting all judgmental.
You knocked up some random chick
in a bar parking lot.
Hey.
Really, Amelia?
Sorry.
Enjoy your tacos.
Yeah.
She doesn't really
seem like a doctor.
Yeah, I know.
Sam, you, uh, you paged me?
Yeah, just wanted you
to meet the schaeffers.
Dr. Reilly, this is Mike.
He's a med student.
Studies way more
than I ever did.
And here we have j.J.
He's gonna be a nurse.
Shut up.
And this...
I'm Lee Ann.
It's nice to meet you,
Dr. Reilly.
Same here.
Are you
on the transplant team, too?
Do--do you think
we'll get the heart today?
I can't wait
to go back
to taking care of my kids again.
Instead of the other way around.
Listen, great meeting you guys.
Um, if you'll excuse me,
I have to have a word
with Dr. Bennett
outside for a minute.
What the hell was that?
Well, I just thought it was
important for you to meet them.
Or maybe you just thought
you could guilt me
into changing my mind.
Jake, if Lee Ann
doesn't get that heart
in the next day or two, it's not
just her life that's destroyed.
Those kids--they need her.
You know, I'm not
a first-year intern, Sam.
I'm your colleague
and your friend.
And that?
That was not cool.
Gentlemen, meet my son Mason.
Pleased to meet you.
Clearly, he has his mother's
manners. Hey, I'm Pete.
I'm Sheldon.
Why are you all smiling at me?
Well, you're such a...
Mini Cooper.
Yeah, I know.
New hire?
Hi. I'm Mason.
Cooper's my dad.
Hello. I'm Addison.
We went for tacos.
You want one?
Uh, yes,
that would be lovely.
Thank you.
Oh, yeah, and we bumped into
Amelia and... Ryan.
What's he like?
Handsome but shiftless.
Mason.
I don't even know what it means.
You said it in the car.
Well, I shouldn't have.
So Amelia's skipping work,
she's hanging out with this guy.
You think she's, um...
Eating tacos again?
Eating tacos?
You know, she has a history.
With tacos--
she doesn't digest them well.
Oh, right, right.
Yeah, uh, well,
um, I don't know,
but I suspect that she is...
Drinking soda again.
Soda or margaritas?
Because I think
we can say "margaritas."
Okay, well, fine.
She's drinking margaritas.
Are you sure?
Have you seen it?
Well, she looked
pretty hungover this morning.
But you didn't see
any taco usage?
Margaritas are bad enough,
but if it's tacos,
she could be in big trouble.
I think tacos are good.
But, mm, that doctor kinda
looked like a druggie to me.
So your boyfriend
just blindsided me.
What are you talking about?
Paged me
to his patient's room
so I could meet the woman
who needs a heart,
listen to her two boys
thank me for helping her.
Okay,
that doesn't sound like Sam.
Yeah, it surprised me, too.
Well, maybe you misunderstood
his intentions?
Oh, I doubt that.
Look, he wants Shannon's heart.
He's gonna do anything he can
to get it. Addison.
I'm sorry. I don't have time
to talk about this right now.
I've got something to do.
Two years
I worked on that case.
Two years of nights
and weekends
and "sorry, I can't make it
to dinner" excuses
to my family...
Then that bastard
screws me out of the trial
because suddenly
it seemed winnable.
How'd that make you feel?
Pissed.
I was frustrated.
Well, it must have been
very painful
to have something you worked
so hard on get taken away.
And he took credit
for all of my work.
You know, I had that
happen to me once.
It was, uh, a paper
that I'd written,
and my supervisor...
W-When I find myself
in a situation
where my professional space is
not being respected,
it's important for me
to re--
deep-breathing exercises
are an effective way
of handling unexpected stress.
Let's try one now, shall we?
Deep breath.
Ready?
Bring it.
Oh, my god.
Amelia.
Hey, you're back.
You wanna join?
No.
Your loss.
We need to talk. Now.
I'll just...
Go get some more limes.
You don't want to talk.
You want to lecture,
and honestly,
I'm not in the mood.
It's a beautiful day,
most of which I have spent
having mind-blowing sex
with a guy who looks like
he walked off
a Calvin klein billboard.
I think you're in trouble,
Amelia.
Well, if this is trouble,
you should try it.
I'm worried about you
and I love you,
and we are family, and family
looks out for each other.
We stopped being family
when you started sleeping
with my brother's best friend
while you were still married.
I'm not the enemy.
I'm just trying to help you.
Well, consider yourself
off the hook.
Ryan, we're leaving.
Okay, what's happening?
She dropped her sats.
Couldn't ventilate her.
All right, delayed breath sounds
on the right side.
I'm gonna put in a chest tube.
No offense, Dr. Reilly,
but when was the last time
you did that?
It's been a while.
We're just delaying
the inevitable here.
I spoke to her husband.
He's flying in from London.
What we need to do is keep her
alive until he gets here.
Tube's ready.
Wait. Wait. Wait.
This is insane.
Sam.
What's insane is you ambushing
me with Lee Ann and her family.
Just wanted you to see
what the other side of this
looks like.
What about
Shannon's husband's side, hmm?
What about his?
Okay.
This woman is gone, Jake.
My patient is at the top
of the u.N.O.S. List,
waiting for her heart,
and you're just worried about
her husband's feelings.
All it's gonna do
is cost my patient her life.
Her husband doesn't have
that right, and neither do you.
So what kind of doctor
are you?
I'm a neurosurgeon.
Seriously?
I could cut into your brain
right now for kicks.
In this hotel room? Wow.
What about you?
What's your story?
Me? Okay.
I'm overprivileged,
overfunded,
undermotivated.
Kind of the opposite
of a doctor.
You're saying, you're
unemployed but you got bank.
I'm saying,
I'm the family disappointment,
but yeah, you could put it
that way, too.
I was the family disappointment
once upon a time.
Actually...
I think this week,
I probably am again.
I like you, Amelia.
I don't want to drag you down.
Into your unemployed,
overprivileged misery?
I'm a pillhead.
It's kind of all I do,
and I know I'm probably
gonna have to
do something about it
someday soon,
but the truth is, I haven't
got that much left to lose.
You're a doctor.
You've worked really hard
for that.
And you're smart
and beautiful.
And I like you enough
to tell you
that you should probably go
to work or something, you know?
Because if you lose your job,
who's gonna write us refills?
Four pages of notes
on one session?
Really, Sheldon?
Feedback is an essential part
of re-immersion
into your practice.
Don't you think you're taking
this a little too seriously?
Maybe you're not taking it
seriously enough.
What does that mean?
Personal anecdotes,
talking about your own life--
patients can do that
with their friends,
but you're a therapist.
It is effective.
It establishes rapport,
trust.
Self-disclosure should only
be used as a last resort.
I cannot believe you are
judging my methodology.
Well, that's what I get
for even thinking
of asking you to monitor me.
No, that's what you get
for thinking I'd be an easy "a."
There is a process
to reinstatement, Violet.
I'm following it.
A little too aggressively.
Hey, you came to me. I'm not
gonna sugarcoat my opinion.
Fine. I'm not
gonna sugarcoat mine.
Because we're friends, I'm going
to leave that out of my report!
Ugh! I cannot be this bad
at this. Are you cheating?
Since when do we own that?
Match point.
Since, uh, today, on the way home from work.
I thought you had
a staff meeting at the hospital.
Canceled.
Game, set, match.
Charlotte, Mason.
Mason, Charlotte.
I saw your picture
in Cooper's office.
You're his wife, right?
I am indeed.
Prettier in person.
Well, you got your daddy's gift
for smooth talk.
That's for sure.
You wanna play?
Cooper kinda sucks.
Hey!
You're on.
Oh, nice.
Sorry I'm late.
I got held up at work.
But I really appreciate
your...
Mom.
It's been such a cool day.
Get your backpack.
But, mom--
get your backpack
and just wait for me outside.
I ask one thing--keep your wife
away from my child.
I didn't know--
it's not his fault.
I came home early.
I wasn't talking to you.
The last time I checked,
you were in my house.
Not anymore.
Okay, let's not do this, okay?
Come--
thanks for making me
the bad guy.
Can I say good-bye to Mason?
No.
She ever gonna let me
off the hook?
Oh, give her some time.
Let her get to know you.
Does she seem like a woman
who wants to get to know me?
♪♪♪
Didn't you have
another bottle?
It's gone.
What about your stash?
Concierge. She'll make
a drugstore run.
I forgot to pack
my prescription pads.
Oh, well. The party's over.
It's not over
until I say it's over.
You're hot when you're bossy.
Okay, hold that thought.
I'll be right back.
♪ asleep in my arms ♪
You're the woman of my dreams,
Dr. Shepherd!
Your fertility doctor
is out of his mind.
And the other side
weighs in.
She has no brain function,
she can't breath on her own.
Yes, it's a tragedy,
but Jake--he won't accept it.
Well, you know,
he's attached to Shannon
the way you're attached
to Lee Ann.
You both are just trying to be
the best doctors you can.
Whatever. Let's just--
let's just go to bed.
You know, I, um...
I'm gonna sleep
down here tonight.
What? Don't tell me you're--
are you mad at me?
Because--
no. No, no, no. Not at all.
I just--i have that,
you know, feeling I get
where I can't wait for you
to walk through the door,
and then now you're angry
and for some reason,
I find that ridiculously sexy,
and I just don't trust myself.
Trust yourself to do what?
To go upstairs
but not have sex with you.
Oh, I won't complain.
But Jake will.
Well, you know, there are
other things we could do
and still follow
doctor's orders.
Really?
Yeah.
Like what?
What do you have in mind?
Well, I could...
♪ Oh, lover ♪
♪ lover ♪
Police.
Put your hands in the air.
I'm a doctor. I work here.
Hands in the air. Now.
When are you coming to bed?
When I finish writing notes
on my patient charts from today.
Since when do you do that?
Since Sheldon is
reviewing them tomorrow.
He's reviewing
your charts now?
He's driving me insane.
He's using
this patient monitoring
to pick apart everything I do.
I'm sure
that's not what he means.
He's probably just--
oh, good. Yeah. No,
that's good. Take his side.
Did you tell him to back off?
I would like
to tell him that.
I would like to tell him
a lot of things.
And all I want to do is
be there for my patients
and do good work, both of which
I thought I was doing
when I wrote my book.
Every day since my suspension,
I've thought about what I did
and how it affected everybody,
and I've...
Punished myself more than
the medical board ever could.
And now it is so close
to being over,
but I still can't get
my life back.
We had a life,
you know,
before?
And I just...
I just want it back.
I'm Dr. King.
I'm on call for the practice.
The silent alarm went off.
I forgot to turn it off. You
know that happens all the time.
I told them who I am,
but they won't listen.
She didn't have any I.D.,
so we need you to confirm
whether she actually
works here.
This is Dr. Shepherd.
Just like I said.
I'm sorry for the trouble.
I can take it from here.
Sorry
for the misunderstanding.
What'd you steal?
Spare me the drama,
Charlotte.
When I left the other day,
I grabbed my purse,
forgot my wallet.
What the hell are you doing?
Cut the crap and give me
your prescription pad.
I know that's
what you came here for.
It's mine.
I didn't do anything wrong.
How many prescriptions
were you gonna write tonight?
Screw you, Charlotte.
You're not going anywhere.
What's your plan?
You gonna call the cops?
'Cause I'm pretty sure
they were just here,
and you told them you'd
handle it, so handle it.
You don't see what's happening.
You can't.
Please.
Let me help you.
Get out of my way.
Stay out of my life.
It's worse than
I thought it was--
maybe, uh, maybe a lot worse.
She could wind up dead,
Charlotte.
I just--i was trying
to protect her.
If Amelia gets arrested, they're
gonna take away her license.
You could've called someone.
You should've called me.
Okay, she said
she made a mistake.
The question is,
what do we do now?
I don't think there's
anything we can do.
Until Amelia wants our help--
she isn't in any position
to ask for it, Violet.
It doesn't mean
she doesn't need it.
So Amelia has had this problem
before?
She struggled for a long time.
Oh, come on. Let's just call it
what it is. She's an addict.
Right now she is in a bad place,
and she doesn't seem to care.
So make her care.
Suspend her until she gets
serious about this.
I'm willing to do
whatever it takes,
but first she needs to show up.
Or we go out and find her.
Do you have any idea how?
I have some friends
in the police department
I can talk to, off the record.
The problem is Amelia
doesn't want to be found.
We just have to hope
she comes to her senses
before something terrible
happens.
Yes, if you do hear from her,
Juliette, could you call me?
Yes.
Okay. Thank you.
I can't just sit around here
while Amelia's just--
god knows where--do...
Do you know I called
the morgue?
She might be more than
just missing, Pete.
She--she could be dead.
O-Okay, don't get ahead
of yourself, Sheldon.
Okay, I'm just gonna--I'm just
gonna keep making calls.
Okay, yeah, of course. Okay.
But can I-I actually came here
to talk to you about Violet.
She was up all night
working on her charting,
which, as you know,
is not her thing.
Yes, well,
even though it should be.
Well, I have a hard time
believing
it's gonna make her
a better therapist,
but she is doing everything
she can to please you, so--
Amelia's dropped off
the face of the earth, Pete.
Violet staying up
a little late
to fulfill what is, after all,
her professional responsibility,
doesn't seem all that important
in comparison.
It's important to me.
I'm surprised
to hear you say that,
given your attitude of late.
She's my wife, Sheldon, and we
are working through... a lot.
I'm allowed
to be critical of her,
just the way she's allowed
to be critical of me.
It's a fair fight.
It might be a stupid fight,
but it's a fair one.
But you--you are just using
this position of authority
to push her around, and Violet
deserves better than that.
Did Violet ask you
to come here?
No.
Defending Violet
is a big step for you.
It's nice work.
Hey.
I spit on a kid once.
I'm sorry. What?
This little 6 year old spit on
Mason on the playground.
He was only 3,
and she was a real...
She was a bully, and I spit
right back at her.
You spit on a 6 year old?
One of the worst things
I've ever done.
And still, I don't regret it.
I was protecting my son.
I was standing up for my son.
I think maybe that's
what your wife was thinking
when she handed me that check
and asked me to leave town.
I think she thought she was
standing up for you.
It's messed up.
But, um...
She doesn't seem like
a monster.
She's not.
Okay.
Can I say hi to Mason?
Yeah.
Uh, excuse me. I got a call
about my wife, Shannon iverson.
I'm Dr. Bennett.
What happened?
I mean, I know about
the accident, but...
Shannon's being kept alive
on a ventilator,
and she...
I'm afraid there's not a lot of
hope for a meaningful recovery.
And the baby?
She's carrying a fetus
that's about 16 weeks old,
which means that he can't
survive outside the womb.
And to keep him alive--
it's a boy?
Yes.
I'm sorry.
So, uh...
What happens next?
Well, Shannon signed
an organ donor card.
And we have a woman here
who's a match.
She desperately needs a heart.
Doug.
Now I under--
she didn't tell me
she kept going with the I.V.F.
Well, she--she knew
how hard it was on you,
and I think she was
going to tell you
when she was certain
it would work.
And it did. Dr. Bennett
told me about the baby.
I also told him that the chances
of survival are--are remote.
I'm not sure "remote"
is accurate.
If we can get Shannon
to 25 or 26 weeks,
then, uh...
Dr. Bennett told me that Shannon
was gonna donate her heart.
Doug, have you had a chance
to go in and--and see Shannon?
Uh, no. Not yet.
There's a neonatologist
and a neurosurgeon in there
who can answer
some of your questions,
and then we can--
we can talk again, all right?
Where does it end with you?
I just told him that his wife
was a match for Lee Ann.
You took advantage
of the situation.
You would've done
the same thing.
I'm advocating for my patient.
The only difference between
your patient and mine is
that your patient's already dead
and mine doesn't have to be.
You know that
we can hear you in there.
Good. Maybe at least you'll get
both sides of the story.
Look, I'm not trying
to manipulate the man, okay?
Lee Ann is
running out of time.
And that baby needs more time.
You understand that, right?
Okay, both of you
need to understand
that you are not going
to manipulate me either, okay?
Because I'm not gonna choose
between you.
It doesn't matter what the two
of you want or what I want.
It should've been about
what Shannon wanted.
Now it's about Doug and what he
wants. That is all that matters.
Hey, look who's awake.
Mm-hmm.
Who are you guys?
What are you doing here?
We're here to thank the lady
with the 'scrips.
What are you doing, inviting
total strangers in here?
They're not strangers.
They're my friends.
Well,
I don't want to them here.
You heard her.
- The party's over.
- Are you serious?
No.
The party just started, man.
The party's over. Get out.
Oh, man.
That was manly.
I know how to clear a room.
I'm sorry.
Sorry. I'm just--
you're coming down.
What are you doing?
Taking the edge off.
You ever smoked it?
No.
Trust me.
This will make you happier
than you ever imagined.
After your hopes have been...
Crushed so many times...
Something inside you dies.
At least it did with me.
I couldn't hang on to the dream
of being a parent anymore.
But Shannon--
she never let it go.
Maybe we should keep her alive.
Having this baby was her dream.
It was.
But the question now is,
is it your dream?
How does it work?
With her and with the baby?
Well, if we're...
If we're fortunate,
we can keep Shannon alive
until the baby gets to term,
but that's unlikely.
What's more likely is
that the baby will be born
prematurely,
maybe traumatically so,
which puts him at serious risk
for chronic lung problems,
developmental issues,
blindness.
I'm telling you this
because I want you to understand
what you'd be agreeing to.
There's a chance the baby
would be fine, but...
There's a greater chance
that he and you...
Would have
some serious challenges.
And knowing all of this,
if having this baby
is still your dream...
Then I will stop any doctor
coming through that door
who wants to pull the plug.
But if you don't want this...
Shannon would have been
an amazing mum.
She can still do
something amazing.
Either way...
It's up to you.
So I finished all these files,
and y--
you okay?
I've called everyone
and everywhere I can think of,
but there's no Amelia.
I left her so many messages
that her mailbox is full.
I'm sorry.
J--I'm just--
i'm--I'm sorry.
I may have been a bit hard
on you about your casework.
And you know how worried I am
about Amelia.
And...
The truth is, I was annoyed
about how you micromanaged
my overseeing of your patients
while you were on suspension,
and it's possible that I was
using the peer review process
to--to be petty and vengeful,
which, if true,
would be wrong.
And you just came to this
realization all by yourself?
As a fellow therapist,
I think you can appreciate
that sometimes
our most important insights
about ourselves can come
from someone else.
Anyway, I sent in my report
to the medical board.
Oh, yeah?
And what did you say?
That you're
an excellent therapist
and you deserve
to be back at work.
Let her go.
Okay.
Are you okay?
Fine.
Why am I not convinced?
I'm just getting
everything in order.
All right,
before you do this,
let's talk about what happened
with Shannon.
We don't have to.
It's not like I think
you're gonna miss.
It's just--
it would be nice...
I just want some good juju
in here.
All right.
Shannon's lungs went to
a young dad who got cancer
even though he never smoked.
Her liver's being partitioned
between a woman here
and a soldier in Fresno.
I get it. It...
That's all good news,
but, uh...
It still isn't easy.
I know.
It used to be easier,
for me, anyway, you know,
it was save the mom.
You just... save the mom.
And now
when I think about babies,
it's not clear
or easy anymore.
And I don't know
if that's better or worse.
It's just the way it is.
What we do--it's...
It's personal.
It can't be anything else.
So long
as it doesn't carry over.
Look, Sam fought.
I fought.
At the end of the day,
Doug had
all of the information.
It was...
It was his call to make.
So yes...
It won't carry over.
Okay.
Look, don't worry.
There's good juju flowing.
Hey.
Hi.
Sheldon apologized.
Well, that's good.
He doesn't usually do that.
Or at least
it takes him longer.
Thank you.
Hey, do you wanna...
Um...
I think "American bake off"
is on.
You don't like
"American bake off."
No, but you do.
♪ I'm tired ♪
♪ of good times ♪
♪ they move much too fast ♪
♪ to be there is beautiful ♪
♪ but the colors don't last ♪
♪ I'm tired of good times ♪
♪ I've shined all my shoes ♪
Hey, Charlotte.
Hi, Mason.
Hey, you guys.
Come in. Come in.
I'll take that.
You made good time, huh?
Yeah.
Um, he's gonna try
to get out of flossing,
so make sure he does it.
Okay.
And, uh, I packed Jersey sheets.
That's all he'll sleep on.
And don't give him chocolate.
He's allergic.
Tennis, anyone?
♪ I've shut up the shutters ♪
Thank you.
Take care of him.
Are you kidding me?
♪ I've had it with moonlight ♪
Have fun with your dad
and, uh, Charlotte.
♪ ...for dawn ♪
♪ when I turn off the radio ♪
I got winner,
which means, Coop,
you'll be ordering pizza.
♪ Ba, da, da, da, da-da-da ♪
♪ Ba, da, da, da, da, da ♪
♪ ba, da, da, da, da, da, da ♪
♪ ba, da, da, da, da, da ♪
♪ back here in my bedroom ♪
♪ I've turned off the lights ♪
This egg--
this little
tiny fertilized egg--
if all thousand things
go right,
it becomes a person,
a whole person,
not just a baby--
a toddler, a teenager, a whole
person with this whole life.
It's a lot
of responsibility.
Yes. It's--it's not
just responsibility.
It's thrilling
and--and terrifying.
♪ Da, da, da ♪
♪ ba, da, da, da, da, da ♪
You know, I imagine
this baby kicking inside of me
and then riding a bike,
going to prom.
♪ ...the light ♪
♪ I've shut up the shutters ♪
♪ I'm saying ♪
Heartbreak, weddings, births--
I imagine
all of these moments
in this person's life,
all this possibility.
♪ I never wanted to stray ♪
♪ I know where the keys are ♪
And I hope...
I hope we get to have them.
So...
♪ But I don't think I'll stay ♪
I'm keeping watch.
♪ Oh ♪
♪ oh ♪