I got you a donut.
Apparently.
What are you doing today?
My least favorite
thing in the world.
Looking for an apartment?
Yeah, I'll be out
of here in 48 hours,
for both of our sakes.
What about your old apartment?
Kenny got arrested, so I
don't think he needs it anymore.
I don't think being neighbors
is such a great idea.
We had a fight.
I bought you a donut.
A really big fight about
some really big issues
that aren't gonna go away
because you got me a donut.
Remember that
Usher-themed party I had?
I remember searching the
entire house for a Tylenol.
Is it too late to
apologize for that?
No. Never.
I miss you, Daddy.
Who are you talking to?
I'm talking to...
To the chair?
If you can't fall
asleep on your own,
you can have the
Ambien you asked for.
You sleep, I go away.
I don't need an Ambien.
Okay.
I'll be keeping an eye
on you, Dr. Glassman.
Trying to hop a fence, Mac?
I wanna go home.
We will, sweetie, as
soon as we fix you up.
Mac has Fragile X syndrome.
A genetic disorder characterized
by intellectual disability,
behavioral issues,
and hyperactivity.
The good news is that the
picket hasn't compromised
any vital organs,
major nerves or arteries.
The bad news is that it
splintered inside his shoulder.
All right, let's get this
stick out of you, Mac.
- Will it hurt?
- Not a bit.
You're gonna sleep
through the whole thing.
Third time's a
charm, right, Shaun?
Her name's Bill,
short for Sybil.
She likes things
nice and simple.
Possible internal bleeding,
heel bone calcaneus fractures,
tibial pilon fractures,
and cervical fractures.
Her name's Kitty Kwon.
Kitty, you know where you are?
Unfortunately, yeah.
I was 150 feet from the summit.
Would've been the
first female free solo.
Free solo?
Climbing without ropes.
Let's tidy up these bleeders,
irrigate the wound and close him up.
How do you find a new friend?
Lea is very mad at me.
Well, whatever you
did to her, apologize.
I did. I said, "I'm sorry."
It may take even more than that.
Make a statement. Go big.
An apology's an apology.
If she doesn't accept
it, just walk away.
And there we have the entire
spectrum of male response,
dazzle them or dump them.
Just be nice to her, Dr. Murphy.
I don't like you
looking like this.
I want you in a suit with
one of my famous ties.
I had more ties than birthdays.
How did that happen?
You know what's funny?
What?
I only have great
memories of you.
What about all those other
memories? Why can't I remember them?
Good memories are
like a beautiful song.
You don't want them to ever end.
I don't think that's all
we should talk about.
You're looking awfully sleepy.
Our clock is ticking. We
need to get to the good stuff.
You know, Dad, the
real reason I'm here...
The surgery went very well.
We got every bit of picket,
Mac is recovering well.
- Thank you.
- He can go home today.
This is all good news, Nicole.
I know, I know, I
was, I was just...
I was hoping to have
one night without him.
Katherine.
Mom, Dad.
Thank God you're alive.
Thank you.
Unfortunately, there's still a
serious issue we have to deal with.
Kitty has cervical fractures.
She broke her neck.
Luckily, we can repair
it by fusing her spine.
Your range of motion
will be restricted,
but when everything else heals,
you should be walking
within three months.
Will I be able to climb again?
Not at that level, and
certainly not free solo.
They should've just left
me on that mountain to die.
Then I think you'll
prefer the second option,
the odontoid screw procedure.
It doesn't involve
vertebral fusion,
and could maintain
your full range of motion.
Seriously? Sign me up.
The spinal-fusion surgery
is generally preferred,
because it has
higher healing rates
and more favorable
long-term results.
But the screw procedure
is less invasive,
so there's reduced collateral
injury and no permanent damage.
Would she be able to climb
again? Free solo? Everything?
Eventually, yes.
Can I say yes now? Yes.
No.
If you give her this
operation, you'll be killing her.
You can get help.
Do you mean IEPs, speech
therapy or behavior mod?
Have you considered a
residential facility, a group home?
Give him away? To strangers?
To professionals
who can help him.
He was abandoned by his
father. I'm all that he has left.
God, he was such
a beautiful baby.
And he was perfectly
normal, walking, talking.
But just after he turned two,
we noticed a change.
He started to lose his words.
He was going backwards.
When we got the test results,
everything we'd hoped for
our perfect little boy was gone.
By the time he was nine, he
was too much for my husband.
And that was before his growth spurt,
and before his mood swings became...
I don't wanna
give him up. I just...
I just wanted a break
for one lousy night.
Nobody blames
you for that, Nicole.
And you don't have to
send your son anywhere.
I'm sure that'd be
devastating for a kid like Mac.
I don't go to church, I swear,
and I have sex with strange men.
Your room's on the left.
Yes, it would.
Then he'd get used to it.
It started with a broken
arm and a concussion.
Next time it was
a shattered femur
and a ruptured spleen.
Then a broken pelvis.
Then a skull fracture that put
her into a coma for three days.
She needs this crazy fix.
I'm not an adrenaline
junkie, okay?
When I climb,
adrenaline is the enemy.
I need to be calm, relaxed
and focused, or this happens.
You've always wanted me to
believe I can do anything I want.
Each time that I summit,
every roadblock in
my life melts away.
It's what I live for.
We just want you to keep living.
And I will, Dad.
But I can think of worse things
than dying doing what I love.
Mr. and Mrs. Kwon, I
understand how you're feeling,
but your daughter's 18.
It's her decision.
Thank you, Dr. Reznick.
I'd like to proceed
with your surgery.
Remember you telling
me when you grew up,
you wanted to be a nurse?
A male nurse?
- You're deflecting.
- Yes, I am, I'm deflecting.
I am deflecting.
- What is the point, Maddie?
- Then let's get to this, Daddy.
What do you say?
Who are you talking to?
Shaun, what are you doing?
You don't sneak
up on me like that.
You may be
experiencing delirium,
with possible auditory
and/or visual hallucinations.
- I'm fine.
- It may be a symptom
- of severe post-operative...
- Shaun, I'm fine.
I'm just, I'm really...
I'm just really tired.
I'm...
- I'm remembering.
- Lying to your little buddy.
I thought you two were
Gilligan's Island tight.
I'm just remembering.
Okay.
Lea said I was a total
jerk and a jackass,
even though all I did
was tell her the truth.
And then I did everything right,
but she still got mad at me, again.
I thought this was Maddie time?
I asked for advice and
Dr. Park told me to go big,
and Dr. Melendez
told me to walk away,
and JL, the anesthesiologist,
she told me to be nice,
but I don't know which...
Shaun, Shaun, Shaun, I just...
I'm not in the best wisdom
mode at the moment, okay?
I'll tell Dr. Dulay you may
be experiencing psychosis.
I'm not psychotic. There's
no need to bother her.
It won't bother
her, it's her job.
- Shaun, stop!
- He won't listen to you, Daddy.
- He never does...
- Maddie, please! Will you please?
I'm having a vision.
Just a vision.
Maybe it's the
drugs, I don't know.
You're talking to Maddie.
Shaun, can you
keep this between us?
Please, just for a little while.
Okay.
We both know he can't
keep a secret worth a damn.
- Better get to it.
- I don't wanna get to it.
I wanna talk
about the rest of it.
I wanna talk about the
Usher parties and the ties.
Why can't we talk
about your track meets?
Because we're past that, Daddy.
We need to talk about
why you're talking to a ghost.
Why I'm not sitting here for
real, holding my father's hand.
Good dreams,
please, good dreams.
You want good dreams?
Go ahead, take your pill.
This has gotta happen,
Daddy. You know it.
What if they're right?
What if we are, in effect,
killing their daughter
by giving her the
surgery she wants?
These are not issues
doctors should think about.
That's what we tell ourselves
because it makes it easier
for us to just do our job,
and not worry about whether
we're helping or hurting.
For all we know, on her next
climb, she may meet her soulmate.
If, on the other hand,
you're not God, and
like the rest of us,
you have no idea
what will happen to her,
then you should back off,
focus on the medical issues.
Because as long as
Kitty is a competent adult,
it's all moot.
This is the two-bedroom.
The one-bedroom
went about an hour ago.
Oh, no. I wanted the one.
Sorry. This has a
much bigger living room,
and a much better view.
And a much bigger price.
Oh, I didn't know
it had a fireplace.
Damn it, Willow, I just
fell in love with this place.
Which is just cruel,
since I definitely can't...
You fall in love very quickly.
Shaun.
I found a cheaper apartment
with comparable amenities.
- I wrote down the address.
- What are you doing here?
You said you hated apartment-hunting,
so I decided to help you.
That's being nice. And
don't forget about the donut.
That isn't being
nice. It's being creepy.
Did you follow me here?
No. I saw the rental address
highlighted on your
tablet this morning.
That is creepy, too.
I didn't ask for
your help, Shaun.
I do not need your help,
and I don't want your help.
Katherine, if you won't
- reconsider this surgery...
- I won't.
Then we have to
consider other options.
The decision is yours, unless
we have you declared
mentally incompetent.
You're saying that
I might be crazy?
You were in Vienna
for my sweet 16?
I was the keynote speaker.
And that birthday card
signed by your secretary?
What's the point, Maddie?
All the committees and
councils and boards.
Evenings, weekends, holidays...
I was working my ass off.
That's an excuse.
You were avoiding me.
- I - was avoiding you?
When I was home, you
paid no attention to me,
or anything I had to say.
Heard you've been
experiencing some delirium.
Possibly hallucinations.
Shaun?
I kept our secret
for 30 minutes.
He betrayed you.
He's not a friend.
It could just be ICU psychosis
brought on by lack of sleep.
But as you know, or would
know, if you weren't psychotic,
it could be a lot worse.
It could be an indicator
of surgical complications,
like infection or
cerebral ischemia.
I'm not psychotic,
I'm just tired.
Oh, my God.
Either take the pill, or
I'm gonna knock you out.
All right. Nighty-night.
How sweet.
You're willing to risk
your life to finish our story.
- This is ridiculous.
- Why do you say that, Kitty?
This is about two overbearing
parents who just can't let go.
She wants to kill herself.
I fell off that
mountain, I didn't jump.
You said you'd be happy to
die as long as you were climbing.
Mom, what I meant is
people take risks all the time,
risks that reduce
their lifespan,
every time they get into a
car, or they smoke a cigarette.
We're all doing the same thing,
just calculating our chances
and hoping we defy the odds.
What about when you
took the sleeping pills?
It was four years ago, after
I'd been dumped on Twitter.
And I called my parents
as soon as I had done it.
It was hardly a suicide attempt.
You spent the night in the
ER. They said you nearly died.
I'm such an idiot.
I thought the window was open.
That's what I get for
keeping them so clean.
Possible nerve, vessel,
and ligament injury.
And she's lost a lot of blood.
Let's get her into an OR, now.
Mom, no!
I'll stay with him.
It's gonna be okay,
sweetie. Ask Deezer.
Mom, where are you going?
No.
Two milligrams lorazepam.
And some ice.
Kitty believes the surgery
her parents want will
make her an invalid.
That's not true. She won't
be able to be a top athlete,
but the impairment
will be minor.
She'll be able to enjoy
an active and safe lifestyle.
That minor impairment could be
as much as a 50%
restriction of head rotation,
and a reduction in
flexion extension.
That's worst-case scenario.
It's a permanent disability.
All kids make bad choices.
Kitty's may be worse than most,
but are we really gonna
hobble an adult woman?
"Adult"? She's 18.
Fits the definition.
And two months ago, she
was 17 and a helpless child?
I mean, she's obviously just as
immature and unreasonable as ever.
This is about your
mother, isn't it?
If you could've controlled her,
you would've prevented a lot
of pain to herself and others.
Thank you.
I think I have enough
to make my decision.
I'm sorry
that I hit you.
When you get scared,
do you think about
something that helps you?
Deezer.
Do you think about something?
School change their dress code?
I'm not going to school.
Mr. Decker's still substituting.
I know Ken.
Dated him in high school.
He's a real horse's ass.
Tough titmouse. Get dressed.
Tough titmouse.
I see a vibrant,
engaged young woman,
but I also see a reckless
disregard for your life.
And it's not clear to me if
that's a pathological state,
or simply a product of youth.
But either way,
I have to err on the side of
the preservation of that life.
No.
I'm sorry, Kitty.
Oh, my God.
Nothing I ever did was enough.
When I was home, you were
out, or you were high, or both.
You don't remember that, do you?
You've always found
lots of time for Shaun.
Oh, stop. Shaun has special
needs, he had no one else...
I had needs. I was lost and
confused. I needed my father...
Now? Now you tell me?
Now, when it mattered, when
it might've made a difference,
you turned me away every time,
screaming, "You don't know me."
- You don't!
- I know.
I know.
I have no idea who you are!
I have no idea what you
wanted, what you wanted from me!
- I wanted you to be there!
- I was there!
- Not enough, obviously. Otherwise...
- Otherwise?
Otherwise?
You were such
a happy little girl.
- My God.
- We were best friends.
I don't get it.
What happened?
What made you so unhappy?
You did.
My only sin was growing up.
When I couldn't be your
pinafore princess anymore,
- you wanted nothing to do with me.
- That's not true.
I loved you, and
I still love you.
I hate you.
And I died hating you.
Think I'm gonna
let you off that easy?
The night,
let's talk about that.
Tequila, stat.
I went big.
Baby, when I met you
there was peace unknown
I set out to get
you with the fine...
Karaoke?
Hershey meant
everything to me, Shaun.
I took the biggest chance
of my life going back there.
And then it just went away.
But I knew I could come back
here to get the support of my friend,
who was so different,
because he was so
open and nice and honest.
But you gave me nothing.
You never even asked me once
what happened in Hershey.
You just... You
just didn't care.
It went very well.
You should get most of the
sensation back in your hand,
but we do need to monitor your
motor strength and perfusion.
Okay.
We know Mac caused your injury.
No, I told you, I
cut it on a window.
No, Mac has never hurt anyone.
What were you doing to him?
Trying to help him.
You need to find
a place for Mac.
That is not our call.
You're overwhelmed, Nicole.
There's no shame in admitting
you need help, to get Mac help.
He'll hate me.
You gotta move out,
soon as they find
someone who'll take you.
Okay, stop.
Not everything is about you.
Doctors say I'm dying,
and there's nothing
they can do about it.
Tough titmouse.
He won't hate you.
He'll just be very scared.
You have been given
an enormous challenge
that a lot of people
couldn't handle.
But I know you'll find the
strength to keep going.
I will.
Thank you.
Five years from now...
I want you to tell my
parents something.
Tell them I never
wanna see them again.
Dr. Melendez, I knew a
kid who had a lot of issues.
Got into a lot of trouble,
fights, mainly with his dad.
And when I met his dad, I
understood. He was a real piece of work.
So I stepped up, found
the kid a place to live,
got him a pretty decent job.
But he was already too broken.
He needed a lot more than a
friendly cop. He needed a doctor.
The next guy he got
into a fight with had a gun.
Nicole trusts you,
and that's why you have to
give her permission to let go.
How are we supposed to give advice
without dragging our baggage into it?
Maybe our baggage
informs our advice.
Gives us perspective,
maybe even wisdom.
Maybe you're confusing
baggage with experience.
What's the difference?
If I knew, I
wouldn't be up here.
Mom was out of town...
I can't take any
more of this. I can't...
You caught me high
for the umpteenth time.
Maddie, why are you doing this?
The night I broke
another promise,
you decided to
quit the bargaining
and the threats and take action.
So you dragged me
outside and locked the door.
I prayed you would
come and find me.
Why didn't you come and find me?
I thought that you
would go to Jessica's.
I thought you'd go to Aunt
Becky's. If I had any idea...
If you thought I'd die that night,
you would have let me back in?
Good to know.
How could you do that?
Why would anyone
do that? I don't get it!
How dare you do that?
Maddie, look at me.
I died that day. Maddie,
I died that day, too.
I don't get it! I don't
get it! I don't get it!
- Is there a problem?
- No.
I just wanted to talk to you
before we started the surgery.
Kitty doesn't want you
here when she wakes up.
She'll change her mind.
With time, she will
change her mind.
I have somebody in my
life who's self-destructive.
And there have been times
when I could have
forced her into treatment,
and I'm sure it would've
helped, for a while.
But I think I have
been pushing you
because I sometimes think
I made the wrong choice.
But she would've hated
me, and I would've lost her.
You're trying to
save your daughter,
but I think you're
gonna lose her. Forever.
If we do this, she
will grow and learn.
And when she walks down the
aisle with her loving husband...
And when she holds her baby
in her arms for the first time,
we may not be there,
but those are the
gifts we're giving her.
And it's enough.
It will have to be enough.
Maddie, please.
Maddie, look at me.
Maddie, don't do this.
Maddie!
Two milligrams Haldol.
No, don't.
I can't have her
leave me like this.
Maddie... Please
don't leave like this.
I should've held onto you.
Until you'd talk to me.
I should've held on.
Your mother wanted
to send you to rehab,
and I said no! I said no!
I can fix it!
She's my little girl.
She'll listen to me.
I wanted to be the hero.
I wanted to earn you back.
I wanted you to love me again,
like you did once upon a time.
It was stupid.
I don't know what to say,
except I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
I know you loved me, Daddy.
I loved you, too.
If you send Mac away,
there will be people who
think you let him down,
question your love for him.
They'll say you gave
up on him as a parent
and took the easy way out.
They may even hate you for it.
But those people,
they don't understand.
I didn't.
Giving him up will
be the hardest thing
that you will ever have to do.
But maybe you need to do it
because of your love for him.
The surgery went well.
As long as you
stick to the program,
you'll be walking within
8-12 weeks, or less.
Great.
You know, your parents did
this because they love you, Kitty.
So much.
I know.
No!
I'm sorry I hurt
you, I didn't mean to!
No...
No! Shut up! Stop it!
You gather up all your crap?
Yes, I checked three times.
Good, 'cause anything
you leave, I'm chucking.
I'm scared.
Tough titmouse.
I'm not a hallucination.
You've been asleep for 13 hours.
Was seeing Maddie therapeutic?
She said she loved me.
Hmm.
That's very good.
Or maybe it was just
me telling myself that.
You always tell the truth.
Thank you, Shaun.
Hey, kid.
Neil.
Hey.
I almost did my puzzle.
I can see that.
That's a great job, Gabi.
Mom and Dad gave it
to me for my birthday.
Yeah, I remember.
Are Mom and Dad
coming for me today?
Oh, mama.
No, no, they can't.
Gabi, we love you,
but you have way more
fun here than at their place.
I think I see a
piece of the cow.
Thank you for letting me crash.
Yes.
You rented an apartment?
No. I'm gonna get an Airbnb.
All right.
What happened in Hershey?
Do you care?
I tried to be nice.
And I tried to go big.
And I don't want to walk away.
And everyone likes donuts.
And I don't know
how to answer that.
Just be honest.
I don't care what
happened in Hershey,
but I care that you care.
You wanna try that song again?
Yes!
Okay.
Tender love is blind
It requires a dedication
All this love we
feel needs no...
I went bigger.
We ride it together, ah-ha
I rented that apartment
you liked for us to share.
Oh, islands in the
stream That is what we are
No one in between
How can we be wrong?