And why don't you check
the drawer next to the pantry?
I'm sorry, Robin,
then I don't know
where they are.
I'll tell you what,
I'll get another set made
on my way home.
Look, babe,
I really have to go.
Yeah, sure, that's fine.
Okay, I love you, too.
Bye-bye.
My apologies.
Everything okay?
Yeah, Robin just couldn't
find her keys.
Rough morning? Perhaps I
should take over the pre-op?
That will not be necessary.
Shall we?
Please.
Just a heads-up,
the board is gonna push you
for more growth.
The bottom line
has them concerned.
When hasn't it?
Can set my watch
over their money worries.
I'll be fine.
It's different this time.
C-Suite feels
we can better recognize
how medicine and business
are one and the same.
Ah, let me guess,
scale back on outreach,
combine responsibilities,
outsource?
So basically,
sacrifice patient care?
I won't do that, Peter.
Well, Sharon,
you have to do something,
because the ED
is hemorrhaging cash,
and if the bleeding
doesn't stop,
it's not going to be good
for anybody.
Mmm.
Need I remind you
Randall Memorial
closed their ED?
Dr. Halstead, Doris,
you're with me.
Copy that.
Barry?
Alex Mayer, 23.
Slash and stab.
Large diagonal lacerations
of the abdomen.
He's a little tachy.
GCS 15.
Get it out!
You're going Baghdad.
The weapon still in?
I don't know.
Wasn't even a call.
We were a few blocks away,
I saw him on the street,
bleeding,
loaded him in the ambo
and rolled.
I can feel it inside me!
Whoa, whoa!
Alex, keep your hands down.
I got you, Dr. Halstead.
Let's transfer.
On my count.
One, two, three!
Two of Versed
to calm him down.
Thank you, boys.
How's that Versed coming?
On it, Doctor.
Gaping diagonal incision
of the right upper quad.
Evidence of evisceration?
No, I can see the base.
Abdomen's still intact.
Just a flesh wound.
It's really clean, though.
Wash it out
and stitch it up.
Irrigation.
Sir, you're a lucky man.
Whoever knifed you
didn't do any serious damage.
Look at this.
Betadine's smeared
all over the abdomen.
The skin was prepped
before the cut.
I'm telling you,
that incision is precise.
Back-alley surgery
gone wrong?
Alex, what happened?
I was desperate.
Dr. Halstead, his hand,
under the blood.
More Betadine.
So he doused his own hands.
Alex, did you cut
into yourself?
I had to!
I had to get it out!
Get what out?
The person living inside me!
Oh, I'm sorry.
Are you all right?
I was just trying
to say "hi."
Um, it's Edith Lake.
Your insulin patient?
The woman
who slashed my tires?
Oh, the woman you think
slashed your tires.
Who else?
I saw her yesterday,
across the street
from my apartment.
You really think it was her?
Looked like her.
Next.
Dr. Latham,
this is Ray Preston, 53.
Fell short of breath
while jogging.
I was only two miles in.
I'm always good
for at least five before
I start to get tired.
Ray lives in Galena.
It's about three
and a half hours
west of Chicago.
His cardiologist
performed an EKG,
stress test,
and cardiac cath.
Told me to skip
the community hospital
and come straight here.
Dr. Rhodes,
I know we're getting
pretty close
to show time here,
but are you
absolutely sure
I need this surgery?
I'm positive.
But I'm not in any pain.
I know, that's the danger.
Severe three-vessel disease,
complicated by...
Heavy calcification
and extremely poor targets.
CABG is still doable,
but it will be more
challenging than normal.
Indeed.
You're a lucky man,
Mr. Preston.
Keeping fit bought you
the time
to notice something was wrong.
Yeah.
Well, Dr. Rhodes said
people with arteries
as damaged as mine
usually just drop dead.
He's absolutely right.
Not to worry, Ray.
We'll take great care of you.
To streamline costs,
Dr. Stohl and I
are implementing a system
to track supplies
to know exactly
what we've used.
Everything will be barcoded
and logged into Pyxis.
It will operate
by finger scan,
like we do for medications.
That's easy enough
for minor treatments,
but what about emergencies?
Not a lot of time to stop down
and scan your prints
during a trauma.
A tech will take note
of what was used in the moment
and then scan
after the fact.
"In the moment."
They'll follow us
into the trauma bay?
Between nurses and equipment,
we're already tight on space.
Another body...
We'll find the room
because we have to.
Not to worry, Miss Goodwin.
All right, uh,
let's get back to work.
Thank you for your time.
Doctors, one more thing
before you go,
while I have you here,
charting.
When I was in Attending,
it was pen, paper,
and long-form.
Today, it's... It's tablets
and shorthand.
I get it.
Tech saves time,
but details get lost
in translation,
so please be explicit
in procedure notes.
Okay? Document everything.
If you do it,
write it down.
Okay?
I clean up nice, don't I?
I haven't noticed.
I saw that.
Why don't you believe me?
I'm not crazy.
Something lives inside of me,
right here.
I hear you.
I understand.
Then get it out!
I feel it all the time!
Alex...
We're gonna help you,
I promise.
Sedative?
No, no, no.
Wait, wait, wait.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I'm telling you the truth.
I can feel it inside of me.
Please.
Please...
What'd you give him?
Five of Versed.
Hmm.
Two probably
would have sufficed.
He put hands on you.
I was being cautious.
So what are you thinking?
Schizophrenia.
Yeah, that was
my initial thought,
but now I'm not so sure.
Seriously?
His, uh, paranoia
that there's something
living inside him,
and his attempt
to remove it
is literally a textbook
definition
of a somatic
delusional disorder.
I'm stuck on the level
of premeditation.
You know, sterilization
with Betadine,
the clean incision,
doing it near a hospital...
All that kind of forethought,
it's just not consistent
with schizophrenic psychosis.
So he's a germophobe
with a steady hand.
It doesn't mean
he's not schizophrenic.
Mmm, could be true, too.
So, um,
start him on anti-psychotics
and reassess
when his mind's clear?
I'm just not there yet.
My gut tells me it's chemical.
You know, like maybe
a methamphetamine overdose.
Before we go any further,
let's run a tox screen,
see if he's just... high.
What's with you?
You look half-dead.
Yeah, these 90-hour weeks
are killing a brother.
Law says you can't do
more than 80.
When Dr. Stohl
asks you to volunteer,
you don't say "no."
Game is rigged.
All part of being
a big-shot doc.
Big shot, right.
Big shot, living off of
ramen and cheeseburgers.
What?
Yeah, that's all
I got time for.
You are getting
a steady paycheck now.
Sign up
for one of those
meal delivery services.
You're gonna need the fuel.
That's not a bad idea.
Hey, um...
Do you mind
setting it up for me?
What? You...
You always know what I like.
Sure.
Thank you.
Thank you, thank you.
I'ma try to get some Zs
before the troll hawks me
for more rounds.
Don't give me that look.
Mmm-hmm. Okay.
Thank you, Helen.
Bye.
Good news,
Helen's gonna
watch Owen tonight.
Watch as in all night?
Mmm-hmm.
Yes.
Just one thing I ask.
Anything.
That you shave.
You don't like
the sandpaper feel, huh?
Mmm-mmm.
You ask a lot.
Mmm.
But okay.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Proximal anastomosis
is complete.
That looks good.
Let's move on to the base.
Do you have
a suitable landing spot?
Yeah.
Lighter calcification
in this area.
Potts, please.
I'd go more distal.
Vessel's bigger.
You'll get a cleaner target.
This area of vessel
is perfect.
If you say so.
8-0 Prolene.
The artery could probably
handle the 7-0.
I prefer the 8-0.
Just thought
the larger stitch
might be easier for you
to work with.
I don't understand
the debate.
The difference between
vessel location,
and now suture choice,
is negligible.
Good point, Dr. Latham.
Dr. Rhodes,
you're lead surgeon.
I'm only assisting.
I defer to your preference.
Thank you, Doctor.
Now, how about
from here on out,
we keep the background noise
to a minimum?
Myra Adams, 20.
Passed out in her bathroom
washing her face.
Struck her head as she fell.
Chamber two.
GCS 6. BP 128 over 60,
heart rate 102.
Her brother Eric's
a step behind.
Total wreck.
Hey, uh, what's...
What's wrong with her?
She's tensing up.
Decorticate posturing.
Can you hear me?
Excuse us.
Can you tell me your name?
Responds to pain.
All right, we're gonna
transfer on my count.
One, two, three.
Uh, she was complaining
about her stomach last night.
I told her it was, like,
uh, something that she ate.
It's okay.
Please give the doctor
some room to examine her.
Okay.
Clear breath
sounds bilaterally.
CBC, CMP, coags, and u-tox.
Nat, belly's soft.
All right, nasal airway
and a head CT.
And while we're there,
let's scan her C spine
and belly, okay?
We're on it.
All right, let's move her.
Look, I should have
brought her in last night.
Uh, why... Why is this
happening to her?
Look, we're gonna do
everything we can
to help your sister, okay?
She's lucky you found her
when you did.
I gotta, uh,
call my parents.
Sure.
This level of posturing...
Has to be some sort
of brain injury.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Uh, we're looking for
our daughter, Myra Adams.
Our son called.
Is she all right?
Come with me, please.
Dr. Manning, Dr. Choi.
These are Myra's parents.
What happened?
We talked to her two days ago.
She was fine.
Myra? Myra, honey!
Oh, please,
I'd like to see her.
Yes, of course, please.
Honey.
What's going on?
I don't know.
You poor baby.
Myra?
Honey? We're here.
What's wrong with her?
We don't know yet.
She collapsed in the bathroom
and hasn't regained
consciousness.
We don't think
it's a brain injury.
Myra's CT scans were clear.
Last month, her friends
brought her in to the ED.
Could that have something
to do with this?
Honey, that doctor said
she was just dehydrated.
She, uh, got an IV.
She was, uh...
She was fine.
We checked her chart.
Back then, Myra's tox screen
and blood work
was normal, except
she was slightly anemic.
Same as now.
She vegetarian?
Vegan.
As long as I can remember.
Never liked meat.
Well, that would
explain the anemia.
Is there anything else
you can tell us?
Uh, she, um...
What?
No, it's just, uh,
it was finals week,
so she wasn't
really, like, eating,
or sleeping much
at all.
She always worked so hard.
I tell her all the time,
she needs to rest.
How do you know all that?
I've been staying with her.
Since when?
Myra?
She's tachycardic
and tachypneic.
That means
her heart is racing
and she's having
trouble breathing.
We need to intubate her.
Please let the doctors
help her, okay?
My baby, no, oh, God.
Please, okay?
Let's get an EEG and LP,
an antibiotics and antiviral,
just in case.
Gram of Ceftriaxone,
500 milligrams Acyclovir.
Why is it happening? Why?
And lift.
I still would've
landed the grafts
more distal,
but your way worked, too.
I'll take that
as a "nice job."
Didn't know my approval
meant so much to you.
Always on, aren't you?
"Always on."
What does that mean?
Nothing.
It's just, um...
Steel sharpening steel.
Hmm, can't say
I'm any more enlightened.
BP's falling.
We're in to the 80s.
Anterior lateral
ST elevations.
Damn it.
Cardiac ischemia.
One of your grafts
must have went down.
All right, get him back
on the table.
I'll go back in
to fix the graft.
No, we've already
broken down the room.
By the time we re-prep,
we'll have lost too much time.
IR's a better option.
What about
the hybrid room?
I have it booked for
a stenotic dialysis arm graft.
I'll bump it and cath Ray.
If I can't fix the issue
noninvasively,
room's already prepped
for us to reopen him up.
Dr. Rhodes?
It's a good idea.
Okay, let's go.
Myra's lumbar puncture
was negative.
There's no infection.
However, her EEG
was positive for seizures.
We've put her on Ativan,
but unfortunately,
they haven't subsided.
Myra's always been
so healthy.
I just don't understand.
But the Ativan,
it'll work, right?
Well, we're gonna do an MRI
to get a closer look
at her brain,
see if there's something
that the CT didn't pick up.
Oh, my God.
What... What's happening?
She's posturing again.
I'm afraid whatever's going on
in her brain is getting worse.
Her pupils are sluggish.
Bolus another five milligrams
of Ativan on top of the drip
and get her
up to MRI, quickly.
Hey, can I...
Can I go with her?
Sure.
No, no.
Eric, you stay with us.
I'm gonna order an echo,
check for heart vegetations.
You're thinking sepsis,
but her white blood cell count
was totally normal.
Everything was normal
the last time
she was here, too,
but she's back,
even worse than before.
Ethan, these two ED visits
could be totally unrelated.
No, I think they missed
something last time.
Missed what?
I don't know.
Don't beat
yourself up, Connor.
Grafts fail,
often in patients
with far less calcification
than Ray.
Doesn't make any sense.
I checked every graft
before I closed.
They were solid.
They still are.
Good flow through all
repaired vessels.
One, two, three.
The problem is here.
Clot of the left anterior
descending artery.
Likely a bad reaction
to the protamine
administered
during anesthesia.
Recommendations
on how to proceed?
Treat noninvasively
with heparin.
Thin the blood, let his heart
clear the clot out
on its own.
Too conservative.
Clot's already stopped up
the vessel.
The LAD is the widow-maker.
If it's down much longer,
Ray's not coming back.
We've got to suck it out.
I agree with Dr. Bekker.
Thrombo-aspiration,
though the riskier procedure,
ensures complete removal
of the blockage.
Excuse me, Dr. Rhodes.
Alex's tox screen's
negative for methamphetamine.
Negative for all drugs,
in fact, he's clean.
Yeah, I saw the report.
So now can we start him
on a course
of anti-psychotics?
I'm just still not convinced
it's schizophrenia.
How? He's presented with
more than enough evidence
of a thought disorder
to warrant the diagnosis.
Yeah, but even so,
before today,
I mean,
his medical record's clean.
History doesn't track
with schizophrenia.
Or meth addiction.
He doesn't fit the profile
of a user, either.
Just 'cause he's clean today,
doesn't mean he's free
of the drug.
So that's what the fan
is for?
White noise, Dr. Charles?
Really?
Yes, really.
White noise
has been proven to trigger
auditory hallucinations
in meth users.
How long have you
been waiting
for something to happen?
Hmm, seven or eight minutes.
How long does it
usually take?
Two or three.
Probably not meth.
Go ahead,
start anti-psychotics.
Two of Haldol.
Dr. Charles...
Oh, my God.
Alex. Get his hand,
get his hand!
I needed it gone.
Just see... Wait!
Help!
We need some help in here!
What happened?
He used a pen
to pop the stitches
and chisel through
his abdominal wall.
Clearly.
All right, no time to repack.
Got to scoop and move.
Saline.
Okay, call OR. Tell them
we're coming immediately.
Let's go!
Okay, go, go, go!
Hmm, sweet potato
or quinoa?
Noah's menu.
Why don't you feed yourself
before the next wave of orders
come down?
You've been ripping
and running all day.
Exactly why I need
to get this done now.
Dr. Manning?
Yes.
We think we know
what might have caused this.
Eric.
Myra got sick
while he was
staying with her.
We never wanted him
around our daughter.
He's a bad influence.
He never applied himself.
He's the opposite of Myra.
No job, hangs out with
a bunch of deadbeats.
We kicked him out because
he was stealing from us.
He takes drugs.
I'm sorry.
I'm... I'm not following.
He probably slipped
her something.
A drug of some sort.
There's no evidence of that.
Well, are you sure?
Because if you knew
what it was...
I understand that this is
a very difficult time,
but the best thing
we can do right now
is wait for the MRI
to come back.
And I promise,
as soon as we hear anything,
you will be the first
to know.
Okay?
All right.
They're blaming Eric
for this?
How is this his fault?
They're desperate,
looking for answers,
and we don't know
the whole story.
Family dynamics
can be complicated.
Doesn't matter.
It's family.
It's blood.
Time like this,
they should be
banding together,
not ostracizing
one of their own.
I'd expect you to say that.
This again? Really?
Here we go.
You've got a soft spot
for family,
sometimes at your own expense.
Planning meals for Noah
when you're slammed at work,
for example.
Helping my brother
when he's exhausted,
that's a bad thing
in your eyes?
The day I turned 18,
it was sink-or-swim.
Noah's a grown man, April.
You're not doing him
any favors
by constantly picking up
his slack.
Some point,
we've all got to learn
to go it alone.
I'd expect you to say that.
All right,
think we're there.
Vacuuming.
Got it.
Ah, blood flow's good.
BP's holding.
Nice job.
Thanks.
Look, I know I have
a tendency to step on toes,
not personal.
I just want to...
Win?
What happened?
Artery ruptured.
Blood is pouring
into his chest.
Blood flow was blocked,
and now it's out of control.
All right, help me
stent the leak
before he arrests.
Where's the rupture?
Distal LAD.
Are you kidding?
That's not even
where the clot was.
It's an entirely different
section of vessel.
Murphy's Law.
How's he doing?
A few more feet to go,
but no perforations
to the bowel.
I was just standing there.
Meanwhile,
he was ripping himself open
with a pen? Wait.
The extra Versed.
It completely
tranqed him out.
But if I hadn't
given it to him, who knows?
I mean, Alex was intent
on harming himself.
He could have attacked
one of us.
What the hell?
There's something embedded
deep in his left gutter,
next to the colon.
What is it?
I have no idea.
Did you see this?
Myra's MRI.
Global edema in the brain.
Two hours ago,
there was no sign of swelling.
Echo was clean, too.
It's not sepsis.
Or encephalitis, meningitis,
HSV, CMV.
We need to brainstorm zebras.
Paraneoplastic syndrome?
Usually presents with a fever,
but there could be
cancer cells
in her spinal fluid.
Or another autoimmune,
lupus,
sarcoid,
some kind of tumor.
What about
FilmArray PCR tests?
I'll draw paraneoplastic
and autoimmune panels.
Have the lab
put a rush on 'em.
I'll talk to hem-onc,
get bone and PET scans.
Okay.
Myra's mom says
she's been busting her ass
for this fellowship
in New Zealand.
She got it.
She's just
starting her life.
We keep testing
till we find out
what's wrong.
Yeah.
Dr. Halstead,
I've been reviewing
your write-up
of our self-surgery patient,
Alex.
Not bad, but I think
some small additions
to the chart are in order.
Additions?
Perhaps "elaborations"
is the better word.
Regarding the initial intake,
you noted,
"Wound lavaged and closed."
I was there.
It was a little more
than that.
I think we should say,
"We lavaged and irrigated
with chlorhexidine
"and two liters
of normal saline." Okay?
"Six-inch lacerations
repaired in two layers
"with 60 interrupted
"2-0 nylon sutures."
You don't think that's
overdoing it a little bit?
Absolutely not.
This is exactly what we did.
So you'll adjust?
Yes?
Yes.
Residence charts, too.
Good man.
The art of charting.
The one thing
I didn't learn
in residency.
I'll look them over.
Thanks.
I don't understand.
What are you...
What are you saying?
We did what's called
a nuclear blood
flow study
and it showed no circulation
to her brain.
Well, there must be
some other test you can run.
They've all been negative.
Something else you can do.
I'm sorry.
There isn't.
We've done everything we can,
but unfortunately,
your daughter is brain-dead.
No.
Okay.
Our little girl.
I'm so sorry...
No, no,
no, no, no.
She's gonna wake up.
She's gonna be fine.
Myra? Myra...
My baby.
Myra.
She's gone, sweetie.
Your little girl's gone.
We'll give you
some time with her.
No. Our baby.
Oh, baby.
Excuse me.
Mr. Adams.
Our daughter was always
doing things for other people.
She told us if anything
ever happened to her,
she, uh,
wanted to donate her organs.
Of course.
We'll get that started.
We want her life
to have meant something.
We understand.
Thank you.
Of course.
You're high.
Look at you!
Your sister's dead
and you're high!
Wait, Myra's, uh, de...
She's dead?
Ah...
This is your fault,
isn't it?
You did this.
See?
I told you he is no good.
He is a drug addict.
What did you give her?
Nothing.
We told you.
Myra's tox screen
was negative.
You worthless piece of...
Oh.
Whoa.
Get out.
Get out!
He's moving
in the wrong direction.
He'll turn around.
Your optimism
is enchanting.
Reality, though,
between the clot,
then the bleed,
his heart is dying.
We should push
for a transplant.
We're only
a few hours post-op.
We are miles away
from that discussion.
Normally, yes,
but a hit-and-run
just died in surgery.
His heart is an HLA match.
You already tested
for compatibility?
Ray's not even on the list.
Anything that could go wrong
with Ray has.
We fix one thing,
something else breaks.
A heart has fallen
into our laps.
Let's use it
and steal a win.
Is that our priority?
You want his death
on your record?
Dr. Bekker, you may have
elbowed your way
onto Ray's case,
but he's still my patient.
Transplant's not an option.
Then you're just
wasting time,
because the balloon pump
he's on won't hold.
He'll max out on pressors
but he'll still need
to go on VA-ECMO.
Then it gets invasive,
a procedure
for a temporary LVAD.
When that's not enough,
a bigger procedure
for a permanent one.
You're going to put Ray
through months of
physical and emotional strain,
only to get back
to exactly where
we are right now.
Ray's arteries were bad,
not his heart.
Now that the vessels
are repaired,
it will compensate
for the clot and the bleed.
It'll heal.
No, it won't.
And when I'm right,
I'll make sure the blame
is on you, not me.
Wow.
I guess there was something
living inside Alex.
I'm still not exactly sure
what I'm looking at.
Is it a tumor?
Possibly.
Or it could be
a fetus in fetu,
a twin that he absorbed
in utero.
Either way,
it's not a result
of schizophrenia or meth.
How about that?
That's gotta be so rare.
To say the least.
It's very cool.
Hmm.
But how did he know,
not only that there was
something inside him,
but exactly where it was?
Beats me.
And after all the advances
we've made,
splicing the genome,
reprogramming viruses,
mapping the brain...
In this case, you know,
just completely trumped
by human instinct.
Everything I've learned
about human nature,
I still can't
see things coming.
He scared you?
There's risk in our work.
I guess I realized
a long time ago,
you... You choose to see
the threat
or the opportunity.
Hey, Eric.
Hey, uh, listen,
the last thing that I need
right now is a lecture.
Hey, I'm here for me
as much as I am for you.
What happened back there,
sometimes
when people are grieving,
they lash out.
Yeah, no, that's...
That's how my folks
always are.
Man, they think I'm, uh...
I'm worthless.
I don't know.
Maybe I am,
but they think
I want to be like this,
and I really don't.
Uh, you know, Myra,
she was the only one
who ever, like...
Like, really,
like, saw me.
You know?
Yeah.
And now it's...
What do you want, Eric?
I want to get clean.
You know, I wanna, like,
wake up
and just feel clear.
Okay.
We'll set you up
with a social worker,
get you in a program.
Wha... Seriously?
Yeah.
You'll get the support
you need,
but it's up to you
to come through.
Why are you
doing this for me?
I guess I'm seeing that
there's a difference
between a crutch
and a helping hand.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Let's get you something
to eat first, huh?
Help you come down.
No, no,
I had a burger earlier.
Uh, it made me, like,
feel really sick.
It's why I...
I had to get high.
You know, not to...
Not to feel it.
Maybe food poisoning?
Uh, no, I just...
I just felt crappy,
like I always do.
Always,
or just after eating?
Hey.
Oh, you again.
Yeah, last guy
only had a hangnail.
Brought him in anyway.
Okay.
Crew's meeting
at Molly's tonight.
Come and hang?
This sudden flirting...
What is it?
Have you seen you?
You're still a catch.
I always have been.
You should've thought
about that before you cheated.
I'm not
the same guy anymore.
Hmm.
Barry up to something?
I'm not sure.
Yeah, right.
This round two?
Too much baggage.
Mmm-hmm.
Make him work for it.
Mmm.
Can I help you
with something?
No, I'm just giving
today's charts a once-over.
Ugh, well,
you better settle in.
Some of them
are a few chapters long.
Stohl's five-minute
knee aspiration
reads like War and Peace.
Hey, Nat,
I was speaking with Eric.
The drugs,
he's self-medicating.
Since he was a kid,
he's gotten sick
after eating protein.
Myra was a vegan,
avoided protein.
You're thinking that's
what made her sick, too?
Last month, when Myra
was feeling confused,
she was fasting
while studying.
Ketosis.
Her body was starving,
so it started digesting
muscle as fuel,
which released protein
into her blood.
Okay, well, that explains
what made her sick last month,
but what about today?
The fellowship.
She probably
wasn't eating again.
I think this is OTC,
a metabolic disorder fits.
You were right.
The visits were connected.
Yeah.
Wait.
Did they transplant
the liver yet?
It's still up in the OR.
They can't use it.
If Myra had OTC,
she couldn't
break down nitrogen.
So it built up in her body
as ammonia
and finally
put her in a coma.
And if the liver
gets transplanted...
Same thing will happen
to the recipient.
Is the transplant finished?
No, the last surgery
ran late.
They moved the transplant
to OR 3.
Come on.
Okay...
Stop!
What the hell?
Liver might not be good.
The biopsy was clean.
It's a genetic defect.
It wouldn't show up
on the biopsy.
I got my patient
wide open, Choi.
You transplant that liver,
he could be dead
within hours.
We need time to test
the donor's blood,
see if she had OTC.
I'll pack and hold,
but the donor's liver's
only got four hours
till it's shot,
so move it.
A metabolic disorder
caused her death?
The precise term is
"ornithine transcarbamylase
deficiency,"
or OTC.
You see, Myra's liver
was missing a vital enzyme
that helps
break down protein.
Something as simple
as eating a burger
could cause toxic levels
of ammonia
to build up in her blood
and attack her nervous system.
But Myra was a vegan.
Which is how she was able
to avoid symptoms
for so long,
but when she pushed herself,
and didn't eat...
Finals, the fellowship...
Her body started
breaking down muscle,
which released protein
into her blood.
So, you mean,
she'd be alive right now
if she'd just...
eaten?
If this disease
is genetic,
that means one of us
gave it to her.
Yes, um, it is passed
through the X chromosome,
from mother to child, but...
OTC sufferers exhibit
totally normal liver function.
That's why
all of Myra's tests
came back clean.
We were only able
to diagnose her
once Eric explained
his lethargy and sickness
after eating.
We believe he has
the defect as well,
and he's been self-medicating
with drugs.
Wha...
Oh...
Eric...
Is this true?
I'm so sorry.
Oh, son...
Forgive us?
Will you forgive us?
We're so sorry.
Oh, Eric.
So, how's our patient?
Heading for ECMO?
Actually, no.
Uh, BP's risen
and is holding,
vitals have stabilized
as well,
so I'm going
to remove the balloon pump
and give his heart back
its full load.
What do you want,
an "I was wrong"?
I'm not holding my breath.
Ah, I see our patient
is making a turn
for the better.
For a moment,
there was concern
the damage was irreparable.
A transplant option
presented itself,
but upon discussing
the visual assessment
of the heart during surgery,
the decision was made
to give it more time
to come back on its own.
It was a risk,
but it appears
we made the right choice.
Indeed.
Nice work, Doctors.
Thank you.
You and Dr. Bekker,
your successes
suggest a good pairing,
but your...
exchanges often convey
the opposite.
What's peculiar is Dr. Bekker
seems to enjoy this...
discordance.
Do you?
Maybe I do.
You okay?
We turned this hospital
upside-down chasing zebras,
but a simple ammonia test
would've given us everything
we needed to know.
There's no way
you could've known.
Silver lining,
the liver transplant
was stopped
before it was too late,
and thanks to you,
Eric's getting the help
he needs.
I may coddle my family,
but seems
I'm not the only one
with a soft spot.
Yes, yes, yes.
Wonderful, Dr. Halstead.
Above and beyond.
Excellent medicine,
and no red ink
for the ED.
It's been a good day.
We're gonna
turn this place around.
He more happy
about the work,
or the bill?
So I guess the rumors
are true.
This morning's board meeting
was basically an edict
to shake the old money tree?
Ah, nothing that hasn't
come down the pipe before.
I'm handling it.
And these itemized charts
that Stohl's championing?
I mean,
detail equals charges, right?
Basically a menu
for Billing
to pad the invoices?
Well, I've looked
at every chart coming out
of the ED today.
Each one has been accurate
to the services provided.
Well, I should hope
he's not committing fraud.
I mean, the fact that
you even had to check...
Look, Sharon.
You set the tone,
so if you're okay with it,
well, then, it must...
The numbers are clear.
If I don't improve
the bottom line,
the board
will start slashing.
Do you want to see
the ED closed,
or contracted out?
Because that's what'll happen.
No, of course not,
but I also don't wanna see
the bottom line
dictating patient care.
Well, let me
tell you something.
Psych is the biggest
money-loser in the ED.
You, Daniel,
are a major part
of our problem,
so don't get on the soapbox
with me.
You seen Natalie?
She's in the doctor's lounge.
Oh, she told me that you had
a hot date planned tonight.
Mmm-hmm.
And I'm even
gonna shave.
No. The things
we do for love.
Hey.
Day like today... Mmm.
Tell me about it.
You make
a really nice pillow.
Your hot date?
Nice.
Hi.
Dirty Martini.
Extra olives.
You remember
the important things.
Wasn't sure you'd show.
Well, don't get
ahead of yourself.
You say that you've changed.
We'll see.
Thank you.
April,
I'll be there
in 10 minutes.
Okay.