Sometimes, you
can't go it alone.
You need someone on your side.
In medicine, we have surgical
assists, second opinions...
I'm sure Amelia's
up. Let's just wait.
No. If my kids can get up
and get dressed on time,
then so can she.
Okay.
We stack our deck.
We can't just leave her.
Yes, we can.
She's made me
late too many times.
She knows better than
to be late for carpool.
Don't look.
We're dealing with
life and death here.
What? Go to the
car. Go to the car.
Hey!
Oh!
Uh... Oh, uh...
You don't want to get
caught with your pants down.
We fell asleep.
Someone was awake.
Yeah.
Major Hunt reporting for duty.
Can we not talk about it?
I don't know why
you're embarrassed.
We should be congratulating you.
Now I know what Cristina saw.
I think we all learned
something today.
I'm gonna grab a
different ride home.
Don't worry. I'm
sure after this morning
Owen will want you guys to
spend the night at his place.
No, I'm not gonna see
him tonight or any night.
That... That was the last time.
We cannot be in a relationship.
I've got too much stuff.
Owen's got too much stuff.
Yeah, we all saw his stuff.
Yeah. Yeah.
Wait. Shut up.
Nice one.
I'm saying, you better
stay out of my OR.
And if my department
heads are smart,
they'll say the same thing.
Shower's free.
So, you just gonna
sabotage me, huh,
turn the whole
hospital against me.
You don't think maybe
you're sabotaging yourself?
You lose nothing by letting
me work as an anesthesiologist.
I'm still falling behind,
getting talked about.
It's humiliating, which
should make you very happy.
There ain't nothing of
this makes me happy.
This is about you
learning from what you did.
No, no, no.
This is about you
disagreeing with what I did
and being embarrassed
that you were wearing my ring
when I did it.
So I will see you at work. Oh!
I have to get
Meredith on my side.
People will follow her lead.
Grey is going to take your side.
She might side with Arizona.
They were in a
plane crash together.
You'll be fine.
You're just saying
that 'cause you like me.
Today's the day I
lose all my friends.
You won't. I might.
I won't. I won't do it.
And why is it my job to
ask my friends to testify?
Isn't that the subpoena's job?
Oh, I imagine you'd want to know
who'll be a sympathetic witness.
So, I have to ask
people to choose sides?
Just ask your friends
to help you out.
That's all. Uh, look... Try it.
Okay, um, well, I'm...
Okay, I'm gonna see
April, so that's in the bag.
And then there's
Jackson, who's an Avery.
So, I mean, if I get
them, then I'm good, right?
Thanks.
I tell my children,
when you're finished with
your toys, put them away.
Uh, good morning.
And my kids don't
need to see your penis,
so the same goes for you.
Meredith, please.
There was a time I
would ask, but I've learned.
What have we got?
Leo Paulson, 76,
fell down a flight of stairs.
Initially complaining
of back pain.
Is he gonna be all right?
Mr. Paulson was coming
back from his morning walk,
and he tripped coming
up the steps in the lobby.
I was almost able to catch
him, but I... I just missed.
And you are? Uh,
Vincent. I'm, uh...
I'm Mr. Paulson's doorman.
Okay, well, let's
get him inside.
Kyle, good to see you again.
Hey, nice to see you, too.
Edwards, I thought
you were off today.
Well, yeah, I was,
but... But I ruined it.
She made me come
in. Probably the best call.
Thanks, babe.
Oh, okay.
Well, let's, uh,
get to it. DeLuca.
Kyle Diaz, post-op DBS implant
from about a month
and a half ago.
He's developed another tremor...
This time, in his left hand.
- Okay.
We did DBS to treat
your right-hand tremor.
I'm worried he's
developed a new lesion
on the other side of his brain.
Okay, Kyle, let's get
you changed into a gown.
We'll do a full work-up.
DeLuca, let's do an
MRI, evoked potentials.
Edwards, a word.
I didn't realize you
two were a thing.
Oh, we're not. Not
a... Not a thing thing.
It's new.
Anyway, uh, I was thinking
we start with the MRI first,
and then, if no acute
intervention is indicated,
we can maybe just
adjust his meds. We can't.
Yeah, we can. I looked it up.
You are dating a patient.
You cannot treat him.
I told you we
barely have even...
Edwards, it is not a big deal.
You can keep him company.
You're kicking me off his case?
I am, yeah.
So, I'm supposed to do what,
just sit around and
hold his hand all day?
That is up to you.
It is your day off.
Take it.
Multiple stab wounds,
chest and abdomen.
Chest tubes placed
in trauma bay.
Hemopericardium on ultrasound.
A mess, then. A mess.
All right, let's clean it up.
Dr. Warren.
Chief.
I thought Dr. Knox
was... Dr. Knox is out sick.
Warren, what the hell?
I was an anesthesiologist
in a former life.
Hmm. Right on.
It's good to have you back, man.
I think.
10 blade. 10 blade.
Is something wrong?
Not on my end.
Dr. Bailey?
I didn't say a word.
Suction.
All right, here we go.
Um, now that I have
both of you together,
can I ask you,
um... I need a favor.
Sure. Yeah.
So, you know that Callie and I
are going to court.
Yeah?
Blake.
Do you need something?
Yes. Uh... You.
I'm on your service today.
Um... Uh, really?
Maybe I should talk to
somebody about switching that?
Yeah, I think that we should...
You know what? Just
wait a second, okay?
What were you
saying about the favor?
Uh, nothing, nothing. Let's...
Let's take a look at this baby.
Okay. Okay.
First things first...
No obvious deformities.
The length of the femur is
appropriate for gestational age,
and that is a perfect
and beautiful thing.
So, that means...
No OI.
No signs of
osteogenesis imperfecta.
That is great news.
It is. Ah, there we go.
We've got a strong
beating heart.
Look at that.
It's beautiful.
Eight, nine, ten fingers.
All right, let's
count those toes.
Yeah, we got one,
two, three, four...
What just happened?
Huh? What?
What did you just see?
Uh...
You stopped talking.
Your mouth smiles, but
your eyes keep thinking.
It's that thing that
you do when...
April, I'm pretty sure
she's just smiling.
No, it's that thing you do
when you have bad news
and you don't want to say it.
What? What did you see?
It might be
nothing. It might be?
Okay, so, it's not OI.
No, it's not OI. It's...
It's the baby's brain.
Obvious contusion and
step-off in the lower thoracic.
Easy. Dr. Grey, if it helps,
uh, these are his medications
and what paperwork I could find.
Oh, thank you.
This is very helpful.
Good. Thank you.
Leo.
Oh, Mrs. Paulson,
you got my message.
Vincent, thank God you
were there. How is he?
He is stable for now, and
I will keep you updated,
but I have to ask both of
you to step outside, please.
Oh, uh...
Of course. Of course.
Wilson, would you
chart these for me?
Great service. OWEN: Yeah.
Your MRI results did
show an abnormality here,
in the internal capsule.
Whoa, can you,
uh, go back a slide?
I need to take a look
at the basal ganglia.
DeLuca, you're fine.
Wait. I need surgery again?
I thought you said
they could just probably
change out my meds.
I know.
Why wouldn't meds
work in this case?
Uh, you see, the meds help
prevent the formation of new lesions.
Once you have the tremor,
you need a repeat DBS
implantation performed. Otherwise...
Look, it's the same
surgery that you had before,
just on the other
side of your brain.
What she said.
We can do the surgery today.
Whoa.
Why the rush?
Why wait?
Well, Kyle's got three
more dates left on his tour.
He's worried he'll miss
them because of the surgery.
Kyle, the tremor will
only continue to get worse
if we don't treat it right away.
You can sit out one show
and play the other two.
I highly recommend surgery,
but, obviously, it is up to you.
Yeah, let's do it.
Kyle?
What she said.
Hey.
Spinal fracture? Hey.
T-10. Are you available?
Yeah. No, that's not too bad.
Yeah, I can do a spinal
fusion with a bone graft.
Meredith, can I
ask you something?
Sure.
Okay, um...
Are these Leo's scans? Yeah.
Yeah, we're just
discussing the, uh, surgical...
You know this morning...
I saw Owen's junk.
It was untucked. Meredith.
No. Where? In the living room.
He was hanging out with Amelia.
Can we not, please? It's fine.
You should just take
it upstairs next time.
There won't be a next time.
If I know Amelia, it won't
happen again until it does.
I can't listen to you two.
I'll go update Leo.
Yeah.
Hey, did you want
to ask me something?
Uh...
Nothing. Just never mind.
Okay. Yeah.
Closing the septal defect.
Teflon pledgets.
Second unit's going in.
We took little Tuck
to the amusement
park a few months ago.
Oh, the new one over on, um...
Yeah, I need more suction here.
Poor thing.
He didn't meet the height
requirement on one of the rides.
Know what he did?
He tried to scam
the ticket taker.
He didn't scam anybody.
Little scammer.
Wanted to stuff his
shoes with his socks...
Here, retract.
Make himself taller.
Because he was really passionate
about that new roller coaster.
Too bad. He was too short.
3-0 Prolene.
Less than one inch.
One inch is all he needs
to go flying out of his seat,
to smash onto the
pavement like a cantaloupe.
Suction.
Rules are in place for a reason.
Sometimes rules
can be excessive.
Necessary.
Overkill.
Must have been
tough on little Tuck.
Oh, Tuck had a fit. Wonder
where he learned that.
Really? Really?
Are we really trying to
make this comparison?
If the sneaker fits. Suture.
The ventricles in the baby's
brain are slightly dilated.
It's hard to tell.
It's really hard to tell.
Well, so, that means...
What does that mean?
It could be a positional
glitch in the ultrasound,
so let's... Or it
could be an infection,
CMV or varicella.
Unlikely, but, yes.
You know what? Let's just...
What... What else?
What else could it be?
Uh, neural-tube defects or
a chromosomal abnormality.
This is not happening.
I don't believe this.
Hey, listen, I'm not
sure if this is happening,
so let's just play it safe.
And let's do a full work-up,
and we're gonna get a bigger
picture and we'll be able to say.
How did you miss this?
You said... You said
that everything was fine.
Weeks ago, you
did an ultrasound,
you looked at it, and you
said, "That is a healthy baby."
I know, and... You
said we were fine.
So, did you not look closely
enough? What... What...
Hey, let's be calm.
You said we were fine.
And now you're... Let's
just... Can we calm down?
Calm? Okay, you know what?
I held my baby, and I
watched him die last time.
Forgive me if I'm not calm.
Of course.
Look, um... I just...
I just... I meant...
Can you just leave right
now? I'm sorry. Just...
Can you leave now, please?
Can I do anything?
Check your post-ops? No.
Should I just find
another service?
No, no. I don't have time.
I don't have time to
find someone else.
All right, um, you know
what you can do is,
April Kepner. You can run
a complete blood serology,
Karyotyping, IgG, IgM levels.
I want to check for everything.
See if anything was missed?
I want to know if this
baby has a hangnail.
Can you do that?
I can.
Nice. Your bilirubin is down.
You're ready to go, champ.
Hey, I need your help.
Good morning.
As a friend... And a doctor,
and a peds doctor,
but more as a friend.
Uh, whichever. What?
Um, well...
It's, uh... It's a
big... It's a big ask.
And, uh... I wouldn't
ask, but I need someone
who knows me and my kid...
Someone who people trust
with kids, and you're the...
Well, you've known me
for the long... Callie, just...
No, wait, hold on. I...
Okay, I also know
that you have a
relationship with Arizona
and you're very...
Are you asking me to
take the stand for you
for your custody thing?
Oh, God, yeah. Thank you.
'Cause it's a no.
I like you both. I'm
not picking sides.
Kyle, we've scheduled you
for surgery this afternoon.
Dr. DeLuca is just
gonna draw some blood.
Okay, and then?
Moving forward?
Steph said something
about a... A trial?
The monoclonal antibody trial.
I did a little research
while we were waiting,
and they are experimenting
with MS. regression.
Huh.
Maybe, something to look into.
I think it would be a
very good fit for Kyle.
Down the line.
Right now, we need to focus
on getting you ready for surgery,
so I will see you soon.
DeLuca.
Right, um, I'm gonna
need your right arm.
I got it.
You scared me to death.
I know.
And Angelica?
Is she here?
She's getting a cup of coffee.
I'd like to stay if
you don't mind.
Please. Stay.
Excuse me? Mr. Paulson.
I was just coming to
talk you through pre-op.
How are you feeling, sir?
I'm here. I'm here.
I had to call the
kids and the grands.
Everyone was so worried.
Hold the door! Can
you hold the door?
Are my labs back yet?
Hey. Um, no, not yet.
I put a rush on them, but I really
think they're gonna be normal.
Yeah, but they'll
be inconclusive.
Yeah, but, you know,
I... Then, I'll just...
I'll do a repeat ultrasound
in two weeks to see...
Two weeks? I can't
wait two weeks.
We might be able
to do something.
I know that you're
worried, but I really...
Look, what about a fetal MRI
to get a better look
at the baby's brain?
To get a clear image,
I'd have to put you
and the baby under
general anesthesia,
and I don't want to do
that unless I have to.
Neither do you.
Look, you need to trust me.
I know that I've tested
your trust before,
but you need to trust me.
I trusted you to catch this.
So, here's some more info on
the monoclonal antibody trial.
Edwards, maybe you
didn't hear me this morning
when I said you
are off this case.
I am not asking to operate.
I just figured I could sit
with him like last time.
Last time, you were
in there as his doctor,
not as his girlfriend.
I'm not his...
He is scared, and I
can keep him calm.
I can handle it.
DeLuca, shut it.
Uh, DeLuca, would you
take this up to the OR, please?
Sure.
Look, I get it. Yeah?
You have feelings for this
guy, and I am not judging.
Well, kind of
sounds like you are.
I can be impartial. I'm...
Oh, Edwards, you have been
the family member from hell today.
This is why we don't
doctor the people we love.
You are pitching treatments.
You are second-guessing me.
I cannot help that I
have knowledge that...
And I am not gonna risk
you doing that in my OR
when I am inside his brain.
Fine. I'll sit in
the gallery. It's...
No family in the gallery.
We slept together
a couple of times!
Good enough. Here is
what is gonna happen.
You are gonna hand
me your access badge.
You will walk
Kyle to the red line
and go sit in the waiting
room until he is out of surgery
like any other loved one
because today you
are not a surgeon.
Are we clear?
You're kidding, right?
Badge.
Now.
Get a chance to look at her?
I know what you think you saw.
Mr. Paulson...
Nothing happened.
I have never cheated on my wife.
Vincent and I, we're not...
I have been married 51 years.
I have three kids,
seven grandchildren,
and another one on the way,
and my wife is happy.
She loves me.
But my feelings for Vincent...
I would destroy my
wife. And I won't do that.
So, please...
I didn't see a thing.
You know, I saw the doorman
waiting at the waiting room.
That is dedication.
Wow.
Leo must be one
hell of a good tipper.
They're in love.
What, Leo and the doorman?
Avitene.
I caught them.
That's awesome.
Like, caught them caught them?
Just holding hands, very PG.
Nothing like what
I saw this morning.
They're in love. That's sweet.
It's sad.
They have love
right in front of them.
That doorman is just gonna
keep opening that door,
letting love out and
letting it back in again
and then letting it
walk right by him.
Hmm.
15 blade.
You know, that is sad.
Hmm.
And when Dr. Warren accuses me
of trying to sabotage
his surgical career,
would you say that's
a fair assessment?
No. You haven't tried to
sabotage anything. Irrigation.
Of course she's
gonna agree with you.
You're the Chief.
And a fair one. My
doctors can speak freely.
But not your husband.
I'm ready to close.
You got something
to say, say it.
I have been. For weeks!
And doing whatever
you want to do, too,
with no care that your presence
in the OR is stressing
out my surgeons.
Isn't that right, Dr. Riggs?
Um, well, I don't really
have a dog in the race.
You hear that, Dr. Warren?
Unnecessary levels of stress.
And Dr. Riggs operated with
bombs dropping on his head.
Okay, okay, see,
here's the problem...
- Multifocal PVCs.
- Air embolism.
Must have sucked
air in the septal wound.
Get your hands out! Out now!
Riggs, he's gonna
need a needle aspiration
through the ventricle
before he throws an air
embolus and strokes out.
Already on it.
No air on the
TEE. You got it all.
Oh, uh, I was about to make a
point about your questions, Chief.
You see, these two, no offense,
but they're gonna
say whatever you want,
'cause Pierce works for you,
and Riggs works for Pierce.
So you can ask them all you want
and you can compare
me to a child all you want,
but the fact is you
are never gonna know
what they really think,
because unlike me,
they're beholden to you.
Now, I'm good back here
if you all care to continue.
You are so arrogant.
Huh? Callie asked you?
Yeah, and I said no.
And you're saying no to me?
Alex, we're friends.
Callie's my friend, too.
No, I know. Come on.
Dr. Robbins?
Blake, what do you want?
I just got the labs.
You are everywhere.
She is everywhere.
It's like she's
a spy for Callie.
Listen... What?
Did you hear enough?
Do you want us just to
go over anything for you
so that you can report
back that I'm incompetent
and that I miss things as
a doctor and as a mother?
I mean, what else? What
else? You know what?
Hey, do they know
about the fake leg?
'Cause I'm definitely not
the best runner in a crisis.
So why don't you go back
and report that to them
and just back off of me!
Just back off!
So, I'm gonna have
to look at the pretty boy
instead of you this time?
You know I'm right here, right?
Relax. He called you pretty.
Kyle, this is your stop.
Hey.
Yeah.
Come here.
You have something
over here. Come here.
I'll see you after, okay?
See you after.
Husband?
I'm sorry?
Are you waiting
for your husband?
Or... Sorry, I didn't
mean to presume.
Family member?
Uh, my, uh...
Boyfriend. I guess. Mmm.
I don't know what he is.
Ah, yes, well...
I certainly understand that.
I shouldn't even
be sitting here.
I shouldn't, either. Um...
Uh...
I'm gonna get myself some tea.
It helps to calm me.
Uh, may I bring you a cup?
Oh, no.
Well...
Yes. Thank you.
All right. Good.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Thank you.
It's just... Oh...
I just want to lie down.
I should, because I'm
gonna lose this case.
I am putting up a losing fight
that's just gonna...
It's just gonna hurt Sofia.
And it's gonna end up with me
losing my little girl anyway
because that woman
is watching me
be a terrible doctor
and a terrible mother,
which, maybe, I am.
Today, I feel like both.
If you want your daughter,
you're gonna have to fight
like you've never fought.
And you have to
stand up for yourself
and believe you deserve it.
You want to lie down?
You don't get to.
And I'll see you inside.
How many times
have you done that?
Uh, once...
Counting today.
Bailey was right.
You are arrogant.
I'm sorry? The
patient was dying.
I wouldn't be pulling
any cowboy moves
in front of the Chief right now.
Look, I was doing my job.
Miranda has to
accept that I can work
and be in an OR and
learn at the same time.
If Bailey really didn't
want you working here,
you would be long gone.
She could shut you out,
freeze you out, kick you out.
She is the Chief of Surgery.
She has all the power.
But she didn't.
You did something wrong.
You got punished for it.
You didn't like it, so
you went around it.
The only reason you
were able to do that
is 'cause she's your wife.
Yeah, uh, page me if
the post-op scan shows
any evidence of air embolus.
Right.
Chief?
I know you're my boss
and my boss's boss,
but speaking freely...
Well, you're not Warren's
boss, not right now.
And you don't have to
like that he's working here,
but it's what he needs to do.
I mean, we were
residents, right?
The good ones,
the ones who love it.
And we learned where
we could, when we could,
and as much as we could.
And I think Warren
is just doing that.
I'm not sure you can stop it.
And, um...
I'm not sure you should.
Good night.
April, you really want an MRI?
You want me to put you and your
baby under general anesthesia?
I want to know.
Come with me.
Okay, Stephanie,
Kyle is out of surgery.
It is "Dr. Edwards."
Yeah, you know what?
The loved ones, we like
to use the first-name basis.
You shut up. I taught you that.
Okay, well, the surgery
went as planned.
I know. Or Dr. Shepherd
would be here.
We always send the B team
when the surgery goes well.
Can I see your tablet, please?
Mmm, can't. It's HIPAA
rules and Shepherd's orders.
I'll let you know
when you can see him.
I'm glad everything
went well with your, uh...
Whatever he is.
Thanks.
I, uh... I hope it
goes well with yours.
Thank you.
Hold here, Wilson. Right here.
Is that enough exposure?
No, I need more retraction,
please, right there... That.
I'm not gonna be a doorman.
Good.
Yeah, I mean, that
would be a step down.
No, no, I'm...
I'm choosing the life I want.
That's why I'm
moving to New York.
And the life that I want has
Penny and Sofia in it and...
Um, I need your help.
My custody trial is starting
soon, and I'm wondering if...
We'll testify in court for you?
You know what?
Just think about it.
Absolutely, Callie.
Yes, of course.
No, 'cause I know that you
and Arizona are friends, too,
and so I'm just...
Callie, absolutely.
Dr. Torres?
Yeah.
Oh, God.
What?
Oh.
No wonder why the spine snapped.
Thank you.
There's nothing you can do?
Your cancer is inoperable.
It's metastasized to
your bones and your liver.
How long until...
Six months, maybe a year.
Would you like me
to call your wife?
Is Vincent still here?
He hasn't left.
The first time I saw Vincent
my heart jumped out of my chest.
I thought I was
having a heart attack.
It was butterflies.
And when I came to know
he felt the same way...
I smiled for weeks.
I love my wife.
But...
This is... This was different.
We've spent
15 years doing this.
Talking at his desk...
Passing by each other.
15 years.
You have one more.
You're awake.
Are you all right?
I'm...
Yes.
We got to talk.
Vincent.
He refused to leave
until he knew you
were out of surgery.
Wasn't that nice?
It was my pleasure.
You've always
been too good to me.
Thank you for everything.
But you can go now.
We've kept you long enough.
I don't know
what we would do
without you, dear.
Okay, so, here,
the baby's brain
ventricular diameter is 10.1,
but here is a much
clearer picture.
So, it's nothing? It's
definitively nothing.
A false positive on the
ultrasound, a glitch, just like I said.
Thank you, God.
Oh, thank you.
God.
Thank you so much
for doing the MRI.
I know that you
weren't crazy about it,
but I... I needed this.
And I know I was... I
went a little crazy today,
and I just... I
got really scared.
I needed to know. Um...
This is a list
of the very, very, very
best OBs that I know.
What? What do you mean?
Because I can't be your doctor.
Wait, listen...
Listen, I'm... I'm sorry.
I just needed to know for sure.
If I'm gonna be your doctor,
then I can't be your friend.
And... No, come on.
And I want to be your friend.
I'm sorry.
Oh.
You just getting started?
Something like that. Ugh.
I had the saddest day.
Two old men, impossible
love... The worst.
I just want to go home
and crawl into bed.
Then go.
Wow.
Are you okay?
I, uh...
I broke up with Kyle.
Oh, Steph.
What happened?
Shepherd, uh, cut into
his brain today without me.
Yeah, she made me
sit in the waiting room,
and all I could
think about was...
I was him when I was a kid,
in and out of hospitals
for years and...
And I just can't sit
in the waiting room.
I can't handle it.
I need to be on the
other side of the red line.
I need to be helping
people and fixing people,
and I can't do that
if I'm with him, so...
So you chose surgery.
No, I chose me.
You want to go for a drink?
No. No.
I... I want to go to work.
I thought today
was gonna be bad.
I mean, epically bad.
But? I got Mer and Hunt.
See? I told you Mer
was gonna side with you.
I think we have
a real shot at this.
I feel better than I did
this morning. How are you?
I spent the day with
Dr. Robbins. I was on her service.
Oh, God.
How was it? Was it terrible?
Was she terrible to you?
Not at all.
She was great.
Huh.
Hey! Wait for me!
Are you coming?
We figured you'd be
staying at Owen's place.
No, I told you, there is no me
and Owen. We're not a thing.
Oh, 'cause it seemed like you
were when we saw his thing.
Oh, my God!
Are we not doing that anymore?
You are a thing.
It's happening all the
time, and it should,
but not on my couch.
I second that.
And you have happiness,
and you keep throwing it away.
Stop the drama. Just
get on with it already.
She makes a really good point.
Don't you start. You do it, too.
You fell for an
intern and freaked out
because it was
against the rules.
Who cares about that?
No one!
Get it together, sisters.
Amelia, come on.
Let's go.
We can't just leave her.
Yes, we can.
The thing about being on
a team is it's a commitment.
You have to bring it.
You have to help with
the win no matter what.
You may not always
like your teammates...
You're still sleeping
on the couch.
I know.
You have to learn
to share the ball.
You have to be all in,
one side or the other.
Hey. Oh! Ha!
Whoa, sorry.
What are you doing?
I went for a walk.
Oh, gee, okay.
Are you all right?
Yeah, I think so.
Okay. Yes. Here it goes. Okay.
You and I are not
the kind of people
who say, "I love you."
Well... At least,
I'm not anymore
because, uh, I know better.
It's a lie.
You don't just meet
your perfect match
and then everything
is beautiful and perfect,
and that's not how life works.
And if anyone understands
that, it is you and me.
I'm having trouble
understanding you right now.
Oh, stick with me. Okay.
I create these obstacles
out of dead people,
and drugs
that I may or may not
do, and sisters-in-law.
And I do... I know
that I make this tough.
It feels like work.
'Cause it's gonna be work.
If you and I move
forward together...
It is harder to...
It's harder
to love somebody than
to walk away from them.
And this is... This would be...
This... Oh, geez.
This is messy and scary and...
God, Owen, it just... It
scares the life out of me.
I'm scared, too.
But if you play hard...
If you and I decide
to be together,
I mean, really together,
I will wind up
screwing all of this up.
Me, too. That is how I feel.
I screw everything
up all the time.
Oh, well.
Give it your all,
really commit...
Amelia...
victory is that much sweeter.
Let's screw some things up.