Today is not Saturday. Why
did you make me pancakes?
They are fresh-start pancakes,
like the first day of
school every year,
when you get to wear
a brand-new outfit.
Well, not everyone
wore a new outfit.
But the rule in
this house is that
when you start a new life
event, you get pancakes.
I don't want a fresh start.
I want to stay in surgery.
I know, and I am really proud
of you for handling it all so...
Doctors, please give
me one more minute.
We have an associate
pastor at the church,
but Clarence likes
to write the sermons.
Sorry.
Please. Although
this is important, too.
The surgery
consists of two steps.
First, we fuse the
spine to stabilize it,
and then we remove the tumor.
Now, because the cancer has
spread to your lymph nodes,
you'll still have to
follow up with chemo.
Clarence, are you in pain?
Quite a bit,
actually. But I'm fine.
Well, since what's
causing your pain
is the tumor pushing
against your spine,
spinal fusion will ease
pressure on your nerves
and should eliminate your pain.
Please, I... I need this pain.
Can't you just do the second
part and remove the tumor?
If we don't fuse the spine,
it'll make removing the
tumor a lot more difficult.
More difficult, but
it can be done?
It can, but I
recommend against it.
Especially since
there's no reason not to.
I did something unforgivable.
This pain is my punishment.
Can I ask what you
did that was so bad?
I killed someone.
My sister and I were coming
home from climbing Mount Whitney.
We're doing the State 50 Climbs.
The numbness started
during the climb?
First my hands,
and then my feet.
- Do you have a headache?
- Yeah.
High altitude causes headaches.
Dehydration compounds it.
From now on, just climb
slower and drink more.
Tell them about the other thing.
Before leaving for the mountain,
I had this weird
sensation, like dread.
I couldn't shake it.
Well, when people describe
a sense of impending doom,
it's usually anxiety.
No, it was like a premonition.
That I was going to die.
I'm sure it was...
Dr. Park will run a brain scan,
and we'll do some lab work.
Shaun.
Hello, Dr. Lever.
"Carly" is fine.
Welcome to pathology.
It is going to be great
working with you.
What do you think?
I know it's a lot to take in.
It's kind of like your first
time at Disneyland, right?
I've never been to Disneyland.
Let me give you a tour.
Cytopathology, forensics,
genomics, microbiology.
We get to identify organisms,
interpret cell morphology,
sequence genes.
Is that a D300e pathogen
antibacterial bioprinter?
It's new.
You're working on
antibiotic resistance
in emerging microorganisms?
It's "we" now,
Shaun. Yes, we are.
Do you wanna play with it?
Very much.
Go ahead. It's kind
of your job now.
We're the detectives,
surgeons are just the beat cops.
Our best bet is to try to
separate the tumor from his cord,
and then resect it.
Okay, this is insane.
You know how he killed a person?
He was counseling a
parishioner who committed suicide.
That must've been traumatic.
Traumatic, yes. Murder, no.
Hey, I know it's stupid,
but he has autonomy.
I didn't say "stupid."
I said "insane."
You wanna override his
wishes because he's religious?
Something like 90% of
Americans believe in God.
I'm one of them. Are
we all mentally impaired?
Should you ignore us all if
you don't like our choices?
Only those getting divine
messages from their tumors.
He's not crazy.
Okay, you're right,
he is just stupid.
But don't we have a
duty to educate him?
You're gonna talk
him out of his religion?
No.
You told him the surgery
was more dangerous this way.
I don't think he appreciated
how much more dangerous.
Good idea.
He thinks he'll go to hell if
he dies before he's forgiven.
Make sure he knows it
can happen on the table.
An MRI for anxiety?
It does fly in the face of reducing
unnecessary medical tests.
When I was a resident, I had
a patient come through the ER.
Female, 35 years old.
Slight cough, slightly
hypothyroid, normal vitals.
I labeled her a whiner because
she kept insisting, "I'm gonna die."
I sent her home.
And she died?
No.
She kept coming back,
over and over again.
We do this test, we prove
there's nothing wrong with her,
we send her home reassured.
Damn.
The MRI showed a
high-grade meningioma,
an advanced tumor that grows in
the tissue layers that cover the brain.
Its features are consistent
with it being malignant.
These tumors tend to be aggressive
and impossible to fully resect.
Um, so, what can you do?
Palliative care, symptom
control with medications.
You're risking spinal
damage, paralysis, death.
If that's what God
chooses, then that is His will.
If you have cancer because
He wants you to have cancer,
why are you here,
getting treatment?
I'm here because I
believe in science.
I am who I am because
I believe in God.
So, do you think all people
who are sick are being punished?
I mean, we have an 8-year-old
down the hall with bone cancer.
You wanna go tell
her God hates her?
I'm sure that girl is not
suffering as a punishment.
She's suffering so others may
have a chance to show her mercy,
to show her compassion,
so she can inspire.
I don't know His plan, but I know
it's not as simple as you would...
No. No, it's not simple.
Except for your pain.
His name was Michael.
His wife found his body.
You had no idea.
I knew he was depressed.
But you thought he
was getting better.
I didn't take his call
because I was having a drink.
It'd been a long day
dealing with the renovations,
and I was having a damn drink.
Hey, Shaun. Hey, Carly.
I started Sadie Barnes
on anti-seizure medication.
Need you to run a
peak phenytoin level.
The couriers must be happy
that the surgeons are doing
their own specimen deliveries.
How you doing down here?
Carly says pathologists
are the detectives,
surgeons are just the beat cops.
Shaun, are you happy here?
When did you give the
patient her loading dose?
One hour ago.
Shaun, if you're
happy, that's great.
But if you're not, you have
to tell Han how you feel.
You need to show him you care
and that you believe in yourself.
Do you need this done stat?
No, she's asymptomatic.
It's just for seizure prevention.
Good.
Carly says that in pathology, you
can take a break whenever you want.
I want to take a break
now. I'm going for a walk.
He shouldn't be in pathology.
He's a good surgical resident.
You're right.
Then you'll move him back?
No. You're wrong
about that part.
He should be in pathology, but
he was a good surgical resident.
Then why...
Because he'll never
be a good surgeon.
How do you think
he'll do in three years
when no one's looking
over his shoulder?
When he's looking over
someone else's shoulder?
Supervising new residents,
leading grand rounds,
advocating for
vulnerable patients...
Do you see him doing any
of that without a safety net?
We can help him get there.
Just because he
wants to be a surgeon,
just because you want
him to be a surgeon,
doesn't mean he gets to
have that dream come true.
Has it occurred to you that maybe
we know Shaun better than you do?
Has it occurred to you that
that might be your problem,
that your view of him might be
distorted because you like him?
Has it occurred to you that
maybe he's better off in pathology?
That maybe he'll even like it?
Do you care?
I thought you might.
We need better ventral exposure.
Drill off more of the
pedicle and vertebral body.
Ligate the exiting nerve root.
We'll take it with the
tumor for a wider margin.
I can't see it.
Tumor's causing the spinal
cord to be bowed up to us.
We need more exposure to
get around and in front of it.
The vertebrae is too
fragmented and displaced.
We can't get a complete
resection without stabilization.
He's tanking.
Probably spinal shock
from the tension on the cord.
We need to abort.
All right, on three.
One, two, three.
You fixed me.
Nope. Nope.
What happened to my pain?
Stop.
We didn't fix you.
There was a complication.
We injected anesthetic.
It'll wear off.
We had to stop the surgery
before we could remove the tumor.
You went into shock.
We lost your heart
rate and blood pressure.
We warned it would be a
trickier surgery without the fusion.
Nothing has changed.
The anesthetic will wear off, the
pain will come back, but worse.
When can you try again?
"Try again"? We failed.
There is no reason to
think we will succeed...
But you know what the
issues are. You learned.
Why haven't you?
Do you think God
wants you to die?
Please.
Try again.
Cyanide poisoning.
The cause of death
on the Atlin case.
You know how I found
it? I smelled it. Almonds.
Dr. Park's patient, I
flagged her eosinophil count.
It doesn't match up
with the diagnosis
of advanced meningioma
listed on the requisition.
Great. Nice work.
I'm going to talk
to Dr. Lim about it.
Whoa, there, Shaun. Hold
up. You don't need to do that.
The attendings are on
the lookout for the flags,
they'll run with it.
I want to run with it.
You've been on the receiving
end, you know how it works.
How it works is I see
something abnormal,
and then I discuss it with the
team, and we plan how we'll fix it.
We run with it.
Shaun, once a test is done,
we move on to the next one.
I'd like to take a walk.
Are you going to walk to Dr. Lim
and discuss this case, Shaun?
That's not what we do here.
We investigate, report,
and then we move on.
Are you gonna be able
to do that? Move on?
I don't know, but
I will try very hard.
Next time.
Dr. Browne. Is this
about a patient?
No.
Come in.
I've heard a lot about you.
I'm aware you stood
up to a supervisor,
is that what's happening now?
I put together a list of cases
which Dr. Murphy
contributed to, uniquely.
You're a loyal friend.
I've specified the ideas he had,
ideas that no one else
around here could have...
Do you think I hate him?
No.
But I think you might be biased
against him because of his condition.
So, he doesn't have communication
issues, I'm wrong about that?
No, but he...
If he had the flu, I would tell him
to stay home until he got better.
He has autism.
I could tell him to stay
home until he gets better.
Instead, I found a place for
him to help us to save lives.
And you should know, I have
rather mixed feelings about loyalty.
All righty. There you go.
Hello.
Aaron. It's good to see you.
Yeah. Feeling is mutual.
Can I have one of those?
The chocolate chip muffin?
Yes, please.
Special occasion?
- Yes.
- Yeah?
As of today, I'm no longer
injecting toxins into my body,
except, of course,
with chocolate chips.
You're done with chemo? Wow,
that's amazing. Congratulations.
Thank you.
I was thinking of
going out tonight
and celebrating what may be
very good news, if you're free?
My treat?
I'm sorry, Aaron. I have
another commitment.
Tomorrow then?
Yeah, this week is really crazy.
You know what?
I'm not doing chemo
every night next week,
so I am free every
single night. So...
Aaron, I'm seeing someone.
I'm sorry.
Nothing to be sorry about.
It was good to see you.
Keep an extra-close eye on
blood pressure and heart rate.
I have extra fluid, vasopressors
and inotropes ready.
Why no God?
You follow in the tradition
that you're handed.
My family wasn't religious.
We never went to church.
I was there every Sunday,
8:00 a.m. for Catholic mass.
My parents eventually got tired of
all the rules and turned Lutheran.
They found that dull
and went back Catholic.
That's my tradition.
Well, what do you think
it'll be like when you die?
Probably like it was
before I was born,
a whole lot of nothing.
We're there.
Where we were when
everything went wrong last time.
We need to remove
the tumor without putting
any pressure on his cord at all,
or he'll be back in spinal shock.
And we need more tumor
release from the vertebral body.
Extend your osteotomies
proximal and distal.
Good.
I think I've got a free plane.
Retract it from the
cord a little more.
I got it.
Now, when you remove it,
careful not to morselize it.
Can you hold that up?
Dr. Reznick, give
me a measurement.
Max length is 4.5.
Get a pre-op scan up.
That says the tumor's
eight centimeters.
How does a tumor shrink
from eight centimeters to 4.5
without radiation in two weeks?
It doesn't.
Why the page, Shaun?
And why are you in radiology?
We rely on flags.
You have to count on the
ordering physician seeing it
while you move on
to something else.
Okay. And?
I don't agree with
Sadie Barnes' diagnosis,
and I think her tumor
should be biopsied.
- Shaun...
- Dr. Han wanted me away from patients.
Patients are not allowed
in the viewing room,
so I'm not doing anything wrong.
Two radiologists said
it was a malignant
meningioma in the insular region
and encasing the MCA vessels.
That's exactly where it is.
And her clinical picture matches
perfectly, arm and leg numbness.
The tumor attachment to
the dura is slightly anomalous,
and the insular region
is slightly atypical, too.
What differential diagnosis
are you proposing?
I need to speak to the patient.
Should I ask Dr. Han for permission?
Shaun,
I will bring your concern about
the scan to the head of radiology.
But approaching
Dr. Han, don't do that.
I already talked to him
about your reassignment.
I don't know if it'll make
any difference, but...
If I were Claire,
would you let me approach Dr. Han
about something that concerned me?
Yes. I probably would.
Hmm.
Is that because Claire doesn't make
mistakes when she's communicating?
Yes.
Then, do you think Dr. Han
made the right decision
by sending me to pathology?
No.
The lymph nodes
have shrunk, too.
This is the PET scan
from two weeks ago,
enlarged and cancerous.
Today... They've all regressed.
Spontaneous regression
has been reported
in melanomas,
renal cell carcinomas,
neuroblastomas and some
types of blood cancers.
In a sarcoma
that's metastasized?
No, but if it happened
in those others, why not?
Because none of them make sense.
When I read about
disappearing cancer,
I always think some
doctor missed something,
forgot something,
screwed up something.
The theory is that the
body somehow triggers
an immune response
against the cancer.
Something somehow lights a fuse.
The theory says the
fuse is lit by an infection.
His lab work proves
he hasn't had one.
At this point, the most
credible explanation is...
Are you going to
use the "M" word?
You seriously can't say it?
Only when referencing
the 1980 US hockey team.
Keep testing.
Anything you can think of,
molecular markers, T cells, PD-L1.
We'll need permission
from the patient,
which raises another issue.
What are we gonna
do next, medically?
He was supposed to
start chemo next week.
No, it'll wipe out
his immune system,
which may be what's
actually killing his cancer.
If we don't know what's
making him better,
we don't know what
to stop, what to start.
So, we do nothing?
Just trust God to fix him?
We trust whatever is currently
fixing him to keep fixing him.
If he took a Tylenol
yesterday at 8:00,
he takes a Tylenol
today at 8:00.
Monitor him, closely,
scans constantly.
Hello, Dr. Glassman.
Hi. Thank you for coming.
He has been doing
this for two hours.
Shaun? What are you up to?
Alphabetizing our canned goods
and checking all the expiration dates.
Well, somebody's gotta do it.
Is something wrong?
No.
- Okay.
- Okay,
I think Dr. Lim's patient's
diagnosis is wrong,
but I can't prove it
without information,
and I'm not allowed
to talk to patients.
Shaun.
I want to run with things.
I want to fix people.
Can you help me become
a surgical resident again?
No. I can't, Shaun.
I'm not president...
Yes.
I'm not the president of the
hospital anymore, Shaun.
And even if I
was, it's irrelevant.
You have to stand
up for yourself.
And you know what?
If you can't, then the new head
of surgery, the chief, he's right.
Now, I can go tell him he's
wrong, won't do any good,
or you can go show him.
I'm doing research
concerning Sadie Barnes.
She's asleep.
Perfect, I'm not allowed
to speak with her.
I'm looking for
her sister, Jess.
I haven't seen her, sorry.
What are you doing?
Can you explain why, instead of
remaining in pathology as directed,
you were in a patient's room
going through her purse?
I didn't speak to
her. She was asleep.
Dr. Murphy,
any reticence I had about removing
you from surgery just vanished.
You shouldn't be in
contact with patients,
or their families, or
anything they own.
Do you understand, or am I
gonna be forced to fire you?
Sadie's social media says that
she finances her climbing travel
by working as a
freelance food critic.
She reviewed a
Japanese restaurant
that used to have a restaurant
grading-system score of A,
but then it dropped to a C,
which corresponds to very
bad food-safety practices.
Bad sushi can lead to
worms, but it usually doesn't
because stomach acid almost
always kills fish parasites,
but not if someone is
taking an acid blocker,
which 60 million Americans are.
I saw a bottle in her purse.
Sadie could have sparganosis
with an encapsulated worm
that is mimicking a meningioma.
That's a good idea.
Excellent. I'll
tell the patient.
I will tell the patient.
I'll tell her we're doing a biopsy
to confirm the initial diagnosis.
But we're...
It will tell us if the initial
diagnosis is correct.
Your theory is a real long shot.
It would be irresponsible
to get her hopes up.
The surgery went well.
We were able to extract the
entire tumor without complication.
Thank you.
When can we start chemo?
There are a few follow-up
tests we wanna run first.
And we wanna
retake your history,
make sure we have a proper list of
all medications you've been taking.
You wanna take his
history after the surgery?
What's going on? What
are not you telling us?
What went wrong?
Nothing.
The fact is, the surgery
went better than we'd hoped.
Your cancer seems to
be going away on its own.
We'll run our tests.
We're confident that there
is a medical explanation.
Oh, Clarence.
Hi.
Hi, Aaron.
What I...
What I told you earlier, that
I'm seeing someone... I'm not.
I mean, I had one date,
but it wasn't, you know...
Okay.
We're just... We're
not a good match.
That's what I
wanted to tell you.
That's not true, you know.
You know that's not true.
You like me a lot, and I
like you even more than that.
So, what is this?
You know, I'd really
rather not get into it.
You came to my house.
To tell you what I told
you, which I just told you.
Okay. You came
here to be honest,
and you're only gonna
be honest halfway?
- You're not timid.
- No.
Okay, then what?
Last time I was here,
we were headed upstairs.
Yes, we were.
You fell.
Yes, I did.
I tried to help you, and
you pushed me away.
I was embarrassed.
You were sick. You needed help.
And I'm not sick anymore, maybe.
And I wanna go and
celebrate with you,
specifically with you.
'Cause we have fun.
You make me laugh,
you make me feel good.
I like being with you.
That sounds horrible.
But bad things are
gonna happen, Aaron.
It can't just be about
having fun together.
One of us is gonna get sick,
one of us is gonna
need to be taken care of.
Wait, wait, wait. I just wanna go
out and have a nice dinner with you,
not to run away to Reno,
find a priest in an Elvis suit.
What are we gonna do, Aaron?
Just drive to a hill with a
view and neck till prom?
And then I'm gonna come
home and hope you call?
You know, I just
came to apologize.
I'm sorry.
And I'm really glad...
I'm glad you're
finished with chemo.
And...
You're gonna... You're
gonna beat this thing.
Your immunoglobulins are normal.
Everything is normal.
We can't find a
scientific explanation.
Our prayers. It's a miracle.
Miracle or not, it seems
we're on the same page now.
There is no reason not
to do the spinal fusion
to eliminate your pain.
Do more tests.
Clarence.
There are no more tests.
There must be. There
must be an explanation.
Redo your tests. Find new tests.
"Let all bitterness
and wrath and anger
"and clamor and slander
be put away from you."
Ephesians 4:31.
I didn't take you
for a believer.
I'm not anymore.
I'm not sure you are, either.
God speaks directly to Noah,
Moses, Job and Solomon.
And now, apparently, he has singled
out Pastor Clarence of San Jose
to join the ranks
of the prophets.
I'm sorry, but unless
there is a burning bush,
it is narcissistic to think that God
has made you his personal project.
God speaks to every one of us.
You just have to listen.
You are not listening.
People get cancer all the time.
Often that results in pain.
Those things are not unique.
What is unique is having an
aggressive metastatic cancer
start to disappear without
any rational explanation.
The issue isn't God.
You have to forgive yourself.
What I did...
Cannot be undone,
but your pain can.
Clarence.
Your pain...
Your pain does no one any good.
Okay.
Osteotome and mallet.
You lied when you said you never
went to church. What happened?
I didn't wanna have this
conversation is what happened.
I'm not judging.
My brother took a
year off school to travel
and came back a non-believer.
So, ask him.
Was it freeing, or
did you feel empty?
Hand me the first
polyaxial pedicle screw.
It was like losing a loved one.
Moment of truth.
Follow me.
Our initial diagnosis was wrong.
You don't have a meningioma,
you have a worm in your brain.
And while that sounds fairly
gross, it is completely curable.
So, the sense of
doom, it was wrong?
It saved your life.
As did Dr. Murphy.
This is the pathologist who noticed
an abnormality in one of your tests.
That led us to this discovery.
Can I give you a
hug, too, Dr. Murphy?
No.
You and your sister
will be free to conquer
whichever of the remaining
50 peaks you choose
as soon as my team
surgically removes the worm.
- Thank you.
- Of course.
There are not a lot of doctors
who would've made the leap
that you made today, Shaun.
Good work.
Yes, it was excellent work.
Most people would
say, "Thank you,"
but technically, that's
not an incorrect response.
Hmm.
Have a good evening.
You've earned it.
I don't want to go on walks.
I don't want to move on from
cases after the tests are done.
I do not want to
be a pathologist.
Dr. Han, you need to make
me a surgical resident again.
I appreciate you
telling me that.
I was wondering whether you
had it in you to advocate for yourself.
But the truth is, Shaun,
what you did today,
it proved I'm right.
Your skills are tremendous.
Your weaknesses,
equally significant.
You could be a
great pathologist.
Just think of all the
Sadies out there,
waiting for you to save them.
Dr. Browne. Dr. Reznick.
The surgery went well.
Your spine is stable.
I'm scared.
There may still be some
residual pain as you heal, but...
No, I...
I keep wondering,
what if I disobeyed God?
You have to have faith.
But you lost yours.
I didn't have a miracle to
help me through the dark times.
Hmm, hmm
Oh, oh-oh-oh-oh
In the muddy water we're falling
In the muddy
water we're crawling
Hold me down
Hold me now
Sold me out
In the muddy
waters we're falling