.
Any chance you'd want
to be my advisor?
Yeah, I'd like that.
We need to be deliberate
and tactical
in our approach to medicine.
We can't just do
a three-minute evaluation.
Gotta spend more time
with the patients.
Maybe psychiatry
just doesn't belong here.
I'm Jessa Rinaldi.
We at Vasic want
to make the Vas-COM
the new standard of care.
Doctor cooper said that
you could be a real asset.
I am definitely interested.
So is anything
jumping out?
No.
Each of these patients,
I think Dr. Cooper's choice
to use the Vas-COM
was appropriate.
Yeah, I did too.
But that's good.
It's a relief, actually.
Mm, there he is.
And the rep, Jessa Rinaldi?
Do you think she's
in on it with him?
As far as device reps go,
she's as green as they come.
Hasn't even graduated
from the backpack
to the roller board.
You should know,
she and Dr. Cooper asked me
to pitch the Vas-COM
at Grand Rounds.
We're having
a practice round today.
Well, that's good.
Show them you're onboard.
Just don't agree
to actually go through
with Grand Rounds.
Yeah, I won't.
Oh, I gotta go.
Hey, break a leg.
Thanks.
Oh! Hi, Dr. Halstead.
Good morning.
I didn't even see you
sitting here.
Hiding in plain sight,
I guess.
I am so excited for today.
If everything goes well,
you can start pitching
the Vas-COM for real.
Maybe! One step at a time.
Can't wait to get you
in front of
those department heads.
Go team!
Well, here, take my table.
I, uh, gotta get to my shift.
Looking forward to later.
♪
Morning, Dr. Scott.
Morning, Maggie.
So I was wondering--
No thanks, not interested.
You don't even know
what I was gonna
talk to you about.
You got a friend
you think I'd like.
No, uh, a cousin.
Mm.
You're sharp.
Once a cop, always a cop, huh?
Yeah, I made you
as soon as you started
walking my way.
Right.
You know, the cop thing,
it doesn't mean that
you can't have some fun.
Right.
Hey, Pam. Yeah, what's up?
Whoa, whoa, slow down.
Uh-huh, yeah. I'm on my way.
Hey, Maggie, I gotta jet.
What's going on?
Family I look after,
there's an issue
with the son, Roland.
He's in trouble.
Want me to call the
paramedics?
The police?
No, don't call anybody.
Wha--
Mom! Mom, where are you?
I'm right here, baby.
Get back! You're too close.
I--I can't--
I'm right here, baby.
No! Get away from me!
Leave me alone.
Dylan, thank God.
Hey, Roland. It's D.
Roland?
It's all right. I'm here.
You all right?
Dylan. Dylan.
Yeah, man, it's me.
You hear me?
Huh? Roland?
Hey, sir, step back.
Step back.
Hey, this man
is in the midst
of a psycho--
Sir, he said step back.
Let us do our jobs.
Get away from me!
Show me your hands!
Hey...
Look, I'm a doctor, all right?
Look, you see my badge?
This man is experiencing
a psychiatric episode.
Please, just let me
work with him.
♪
Hey, Roland.
I'm stepping back, okay?
I don't see you.
Where are you?
Hey, I'm right here.
I'm right here.
Just focus on my voice.
All right?
D--don't hurt me.
I would never hurt you.
I'm your friend.
Hey, Roland?
I just need you
to breathe deep for me, okay?
Uh-huh.
Come on, don't stop.
Come on.
D.
There you are.
I'm here.
I'm right here.
Please, help me.
I got you.
♪
Breathe, Roland. Come on.
Come here, come here.
Come here.
It's all right.
Help me.
Help me!
I got you. I got you.
You all right? You're safe.
Hey, morning, Dr. Taylor.
Hi, Dr. Marcel.
I've got three patients
in process.
Oh.
First, a 26-year-old female.
Ankle injury,
said she wore heels on the "L"
instead of sneakers
and changing at the office.
X-ray's negative.
It's just a sprain.
Other two are a father
and his teenage daughter.
Single vehicle crash.
Driving lesson gone wrong.
Exams were unremarkable,
cleared their c-spines.
Both were amnestic to the event
so I'm getting CT Heads.
Wow, well done.
My only confusion--
I'm 30 minutes early
for our shift,
and you're already
tripled up on patients?
I like getting here
a little early.
Uh-huh.
Or a lot early.
I have a lot of energy
it needs to go somewhere.
Okay, look, Vanessa,
I'm all for the gung-ho spirit,
but it's important
to pace yourself.
These days, residents
getting rest is a good thing
And required.
That's what they say,
not what they mean.
All right, then.
What's this?
Your prescription.
Every now and then,
take a break.
Did you catch that?
Vanessa and Crockett?
Yup.
First-year resident falling
for their mentor?
That's not good.
Doesn't usually end well
for the resident.
Nope.
Ambo's coming in.
We're in Treatment 4.
On it.
Vanessa, got time
for another case?
Definitely.
Ashley Bardsley, 48,
in line at Starbucks
when she had a seizure.
Witnesses said
she fell pretty hard,
hit her head.
Gross deformity
of the left arm.
She was groggy when we arrived,
but protecting her airway.
BP 120 over 80, heart rate 72,
sats 100% on oxygen.
Couldn't get an IV.
Okay, let's transfer
on three.
One, two, three.
Thank you, Courtney.
Yep.
Hey.
Good breath sounds. Ashley?
Can you hear me?
Ashley. Still out of it.
Post-ictal phase
is a wildcard.
Fuzziness could last a while.
Get a good IV, CBC, BMP,
chest X-ray, and a head CT.
You got it.
What about the arm?
Life over limb.
We'll deal with it
after the CT.
Mr. Channing,
I'm Dr. Halstead.
Oh, call me Pete.
I'm not going to be
Mr. Channing
until at least 35.
You got it.
Tell me, what's going on?
I've been puking up a storm.
How fun.
Vitals are normal.
Temp's elevated, 101.1.
Not for nothing, Pete,
but you smell like a keg.
Yeah, sorry.
Back on campus
after a year and a half online.
Been making up for lost time
on the party front.
Aha.
That hurt?
Everything kind of hurts.
I thought it was just
another bad hangover,
but the elixir that
usually knocks them out, isn't.
May I?
That coconut water?
With some electrolyte powder
and ice.
I've been drinking it nonstop
all morning,
but I'm not feeling any better.
Okay, all right, well,
let's run some labs,
and we'll go from there, okay?
CBC, BMP, amylase, lipase,
and a chest X-ray.
I'll be back in a bit.
Saw you in the café
this morning
with that device rep.
Was gonna say hi,
but I didn't want
to be a third wheel.
Jut business, Dean.
Hey, my mistake.
Must be one hell of a device.
It's all right, come on.
It's okay.
Maggie, what's open?
Treatment 3.
Okay.
You need a psych tech?
On standby. Dr. Charles?
On his way down.
All right.
♪
Hey, you need anything?
Water? Something to eat?
No. No, thank you.
Hey, you call
for a psych tech?
Yeah, just stay close.
Restraints?
No.
It's okay. It's all right.
Hey, Dr. Charles.
Roland is 22--he was diagnosed
with schizophrenia,
like, three months ago.
These are his meds.
Fluphenazine.
First generation antipsychotic.
30 milligrams a day?
Heavy dose.
His mom, Pam Baxter,
says he never misses a dose,
yet today he still had a break.
How you doing?
Nothing I haven't
dealt with before, man.
Ms. Baxter?
How are you doing?
I'm Dr. Charles.
It's great to meet you.
You'll help my son?
That's why I'm here.
Uh, you mind if I say hello
to him?
Roland, how you doing?
I'm Dr. Charles.
It's all right. It's okay.
Pam, let me show you
to the waiting room, okay?
Cardiac output and index.
Pulse pressure
and stroke volumes.
Central venous pressure,
mean arterial pressure,
and calculated values
like oxygen delivery.
The Vas-COM is the all-in-one
cardiac monitoring device.
It almost makes us unnecessary.
Almost.
I love that.
Dr. Cooper.
So with Covid cases,
it can be useful
to quantify pulmonary edema.
Is that something the Vas-COM
is capable of?
Lung water volume?
Absolutely.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to interrupt.
Uh, I just--I left
my water bottle there
from the budget meeting.
Gotta stay hydrated, right?
Sorry, just forget
I'm not here.
Uh, actually,
speaking of water,
what were you saying
about lung water volume or...
Right. Yes.
It can be calculated
in seconds.
The reason:
the Vas-COM's sophisticated
neural network AI.
This, in combination with
a thermistor at the tip
of the central venous line
and the waveform analysis
from the arterial side
ensures the device delivers
consistent and accurate
measurements.
And it's minimally invasive.
Well, not when it comes
to your wallet.
I mean, those catheters
are pretty pricey, right?
Oh, I'm sorry, I didn't mean
to say that out loud.
No, I mean,
it's a fair point.
What do you think,
Dr. Halstead?
Well, yes and no.
I mean, the Vas-COM is
more expensive
than other devices,
but it's certainly
not overpriced considering
the multitude of functions
it's capable of.
Oh, yeah, I mean, it is
a Swiss army knife,
there's no doubt about that.
Dr. Archer,
that's not a bad thing.
Uh, no, but it's
not necessary, either.
At the end of the day,
the Vas-COM just seems
like a high-tech repackaging
of all the hemodynamic devices
already out there.
I mean, why complicate things
when info from central venous
pressure's been working
perfectly well for decades?
At least, that's, you know,
that's how I see it, so.
Well, I disagree.
I'd liken the CVP
you're describing
to a flip phone.
The Vas-COM though,
is the smart phone
we all want in our pockets.
Yeah, well, not all of us.
Some of us just want
to make a phone call, right?
And this has been
working excellent
for me, still does.
Anyway, I'm old school.
All right, I got my water,
and I'll leave you to it.
♪
X-rays on Ashley's arm.
Distal radius fracture.
I paged Ortho--
they're gonna come down
and cast it.
Is that her CT?
Take a look.
Oh, man. Lesions.
Four.
Yeah.
And this area here
is a resection cavity.
Surrounding tissue shows
evidence of radiation necrosis.
So there was a tumor
that was removed.
It must have been cancerous
given the dead tissue.
Anaplastic astrocytoma.
I was able to pull up
Ashley's medical records
dating back to 2000.
That's when everything
started going digital.
Diagnosis was made
sometime before that.
Yes, since 2000,
there have been
three recurrences.
Appears biopsies
on those lesions, though,
were all negative.
So all benign,
but only three recurrences?
I'm counting four here
on her CT.
Yeah, there's a new lesion.
The cancer may be back.
.
So I'm thinking an
adverse reaction to his meds
definitely had a lot to do
with his episode this morning.
Yeah, I was leaning
that way too.
I noticed some
spastic muscle contractions
when I brought him in.
Yeah, he's also
having a hard time
controlling his tongue
inside his mouth.
Both of those things, you know,
symptoms of overmedication.
I just think his dose
is too high.
He's coming down now, though.
Oh, yeah.
Gave him some Ativan and some
Benadryl so he can rest.
I'm gonna reassess in a bit.
You know, I've known the family
since I was a rookie cop.
Roland's always been
a bright kid
but shy, sensitive.
Doesn't help that
his neighborhood's a war zone.
Yeah.
I'm sorry that you had to
go it alone out there,
but, look, thank God
you were there, right?
So a good job.
I'll check back.
Hey, Mr. Kumar.
I'm Dr. Marcel.
I'm the E.D. surgeon
on call today.
Oh, man, I've been upgraded?
That's--that's not a good sign.
Well, the resident you saw
when you came in
asked me to consult because
of your chest X-ray results.
It's protocol,
not necessarily an omen.
All right, the X-ray.
Lay it on me.
So it showed
a widened mediastinum,
partition between your lungs.
So given your symptoms,
fatigue, back pain,
trouble swallowing,
hypertension.
The widened mediastinum
could by symptomatic
of a lot of things,
or it could be nothing.
Nothing. Let's--
Yeah, let's go with that.
Right.
Well, you know,
I'm gonna send you
for a CT
of your chest and abdomen.
Get a better look
at what's doing,
and then we'll go
from there, okay?
I'd be on my bike by now.
I'm sorry?
I had to pull out
of a Half-Ironman triathlon.
Oh.
1.2 mile saltwater swim,
56 mile bike ride.
Now it tires me out
just watching the race online.
Well, I'm sorry
to hear that, man.
Yeah, well, listen,
hang in there.
Tech'll be by soon,
get you that scan, okay?
Okay.
All right.
It started with migraines
when I was in the 11th grade,
and they found the tumor
a year later.
The day after I graduated
from high school,
they took it out,
and I felt much better.
No speech issues,
no more balance problems.
I was healed, or so I thought.
Turns out the tumor
was cancerous.
Anaplastic astrocytoma
has been my life since 1991.
The previous recurrences
were benign.
It's possible that
this one is too.
But we can't be sure without--
A biopsy.
Digging out a little more
of my brain.
No, thank you.
Do you not want to know
what it is?
The original chemo
and radiation,
they were brutal.
And the biopsies?
Each one has left me
a little worse for wear.
My eyesight's bad,
my hearing's going,
my hormones are out of whack,
my bones are brittle.
I just don't want
to risk anymore damage.
So, okay, you can treat my arm.
But after that,
I want to go home.
♪
Okay.
Ortho will be by soon.
I feel so bad for her.
She's been through hell,
there's no question.
But her diagnosis,
Anaplastic astrocytoma,
it doesn't add up.
What do you mean?
A.A. is fatal.
Life expectancy post-diagnosis
is a few years at best.
Ashley has survived 30.
You don't think she has it.
I don't know what's going on.
But whatever's happening,
it started in 1991
with that original tumor.
30 years.
I mean, any chance
a tissue sample still exists?
Oh, no, I doubt it.
But maybe the pathology report
still does.
Pre-dates 2000,
so it won't be
in her electronic file,
but it has to be
on paper somewhere.
Yep.
Let's start looking.
Okay.
Roland's sleeping now.
When he wakes up,
Dr. Charles will come
do another exam.
We were on the bus
when the break happened.
To visit Harold Washington.
Hmm. City College?
Since the diagnosis,
Roland hasn't left
the apartment.
But yesterday,
he said he wanted
to try again at school.
I was so hopeful it was...
The beginning of something
for him.
But the bus was crowded.
And there was traffic.
If you hadn't come,
it was almost my family today.
Roland is a sweet boy. Kind.
He is.
I wish we weren't
the only ones who knew that.
Labs are back on Pete,
your belly patient.
White count's 21,000.
That's high.
Let me see the chest X-ray?
Motion artifact. Tough to read.
He vomited just before
the image was taken.
He had a hard time
staying still.
All right.
Oh, Doc, thank God
you're back.
My stomach is killing me.
Yeah, your labs show
you're fighting
more than just a hangover.
Let me take another look.
Ahh!
That hurts
way worse than before.
Okay, Trini, grab Mike.
Sorry, I gotta keep checking.
Oh, this is bad isn't it?
Oh, God, okay,
no more crap food.
Just give me salads
and vegetables.
No, no, full vegan from now on.
I promise.
Let's get another X-ray
before you make
any huge life decisions.
Upright chest, 90 degrees.
And Pete, I know you're
in a lot of pain,
but you gotta stay
really still, okay?
Clear.
Yep, free air
under the right diaphragm.
Trini, find me Dr. Archer.
What's going on?
So you need surgery.
Your stomach pain is
from a tear in your GI tract.
Air is leaking into your belly.
Leaking?
How does that happen?
Well, around here,
typically I see it
from penetrative trauma, uh,
bullets, stab wounds...
Guns and knives?
But I'm keg stands
and peer pong.
I think I'm gonna puke again.
I need my drink.
Sorry, man, no liquids
before surgery.
Hey, your elixir.
I saw you eating ice.
Is that always
part of the process?
Yeah, chewing on a cold cube
is just satisfying.
Well, I think one
might have caused the tear.
Yeah, it's likely
been getting bigger
with each cube
you've swallowed since.
Seriously? An ice cube?
It's looking that way.
What's up?
Hey, so this is the surgeon.
I'm gonna fill him in,
then he's gonna take over,
okay?
Pneumoperitoneum.
I suspect the tear's
somewhere near
the gastro-esophageal junction.
Yeah, there's no blood.
Ah, wasn't shot or stabbed.
I think an ice cube
went down the wrong way.
Get out, really?
All right, cool.
All right, I'll take it
from here.
You know, Dean,
kid's a nervous wreck.
Not in the greatest shape,
either.
Post-surgery, I think
cardiac monitoring
would be appropriate.
Uh, let me guess, uh,
use the Vas-COM?
I know you like
your old-school CVP,
but I do think the Vas-COM
might be better suited
for this patient.
Well, I'll consider it.
Thank you.
Okay, I've considered it.
No. I'll stick with my device.
.
Archer's a real
ball buster, huh?
Yeah, he enjoys it, too.
But still, part of me hoped
he would at least
consider the Vas-COM.
You mind if I offer you
a little advice?
Please.
Look, you nailed
highlighting
the Vas-COM's positives.
You nailed it.
But you whiffed on pointing out
the CVP's negatives.
That monitor has to be
leveled and calibrated
before each use.
Right.
But what if
that's not done appropriately?
All the numbers are off.
None of that data
can be trusted.
A bad calibration
in the moment.
That's happened before?
Not to me.
Because I use a Vas-COM.
Anyway, food for thought.
You know, as we move
toward Grand Rounds.
See? Right there.
CT shows the wall
of the aorta has thickened.
I think it's an aortic tumor.
No way.
Thoracoabdominal
aortic aneurysm.
I don't know, the walls
are abnormally shaped.
Aneurysms are symmetrical.
It isn't a classic
presentation,
I'll give you that,
but aortic tumors
are super rare,
aortic aneurysms are not.
Okay, look, I get it,
Dr. Bickman.
Common things are common,
but that doesn't rule out
a curveball.
No, but your point is moot
'cause that's a fast ball.
Thoracoabdominal
aortic aneurysm.
I'm not comfortable
with that diagnosis.
It's an IR case now,
Dr. Marcel.
Send him up to the cath lab.
I'll put in a stent,
and he'll be good as new.
How's it going?
I've only come across
four cases in which
patients outlived a diagnosis
of anaplastic astrocytoma,
and two of them were determined
to be misdiagnoses.
So odds are Ashley likely
isn't another medical miracle.
No. But can we prove it?
Maggie and I have been
trying to dig up
her original files
and path reports.
Slow go.
Sweet. She's got something.
Your research, good stuff.
Hey, Dr. Hammer.
How many cases you working?
Just one.
That's an improvement.
You had any food?
I'll take that as a no.
I'll grab something later,
but this is just
more important than lunch.
Yeah, I disagree.
You can't help your patients
if you run out of gas.
Dolmeh, koufteh ghelgheli.
Made them last night.
Take five. Recharge.
Roland. How you feeling?
I'm Dr. Charles.
We met earlier.
I remember. Kind of.
I'm sorry about
my behavior earlier, sir.
You have absolutely nothing
to apologize for.
You mind if I come in?
We can chat a bit?
Sure.
Last time the doctor
just stayed in the doorway,
wrote me a prescription.
So, um, I understand
that you and Dr. Scott
go way back.
Long as I can remember.
We not as tight
as we used to be, though.
No?
I mean, he doesn't
send the calls
to voicemail or nothing,
it's just...
He's a doc now, so, you know,
he's not around
as much anymore.
I miss him.
I can understand that.
I would too.
Yeah.
I wish I was more like D.
Guy's not afraid of nothing.
Shadow doesn't even mess
with him.
Shadow?
It's outside.
Waits for me
to leave the apartment.
Always feels like
it's gonna attack me.
So do you ever see
the shadow inside
when you're at home?
No.
Except when I don't sleep.
What does the shadow
look like?
I mean, is it a person?
Does it have a specific shape?
I don't know.
It's just a thing.
A blur.
I see it,
but when I turn around,
it's someplace else.
Shadow ever speak to you?
I mean, does it have a voice?
No. It don't make any noises.
It's just always there.
Watching.
You know what,
I really appreciate
you sharing all this stuff
with me.
Really, I do.
I'm just going to
get back with Dr. Scott,
and then come check in
on you in a bit, okay?
That's it?
That's all the questions?
For now, yeah.
Last time,
the doctor had a checklist.
I'd answer yes or no.
Guess we do things a little
bit differently around here.
I'll see you in a bit.
♪
How'd it go?
He talk about the shadow?
He did. He did.
You know, there's no doubt
in my mind
that it's very real to him,
but it could be related
to irregular sleep cycles.
Hmm.
Also, you know,
he only sees the shadow, right?
It doesn't talk to him,
and with schizophrenia,
you'd think there'd be an
auditory hallucination as well.
Also, there's this
extreme level of agoraphobia,
and I don't know,
it's just not tracking.
So you don't think
it's schizophrenia.
You know,
I'm not ruling it out,
but I honestly have my doubts.
Let's go ahead and order
the labs and imaging.
Hopefully it will point us
one way or the other.
Yeah.
This one.
♪
Oh, hey, Dr. Halstead.
Hey, hi, Trish.
What's new?
Same old, same old.
But who knows
what tomorrow may bring.
Powerball's up to 68 million.
Nice.
Might need to get myself
a few tickets.
Oh, were you in here
waiting for me?
Did you need anything?
No, no, I was just
checking on the patient, Pete.
But I guess he's, uh--
This is what I like to see.
Hero's welcome.
Hold your applause, please.
Okay, so, I placed a line
during surgery.
Connect him to the CVP,
grab a baseline.
I am going to change my scrubs
and, uh, please page me
when he wakes up, all right?
So as you suspected,
esophageal tear at the GEJ.
That's a hell of an ice cube.
Guess he needs
a new hangover cure.
Yeah, I got one. Drink less.
College senior, Dean.
Not sure moderation
is realistic.
Yeah, well, you know,
what do I know, right?
Dr. Archer, there's an issue
with the CVP.
Vitals are normal,
but a CVP of 38 is--
Yeah, way too high.
Way high, I see that.
I see that.
Yes. Yes.
I can't zero it out.
Here, let me try.
Maybe I can recalibrate--
No, no,
just hold on a second.
Let me just check something,
let me just check something.
Ah. Look at this.
Cable's got a kink in it.
See that?
Can I have a new one, please?
Yeah.
Yeah, must have snagged
on the bed railings
on the trip from the O.R.
Oh, yeah.
CVP of 11. And problem solved.
That was a close shave, yeah?
Yeah. Glad it worked out.
Yeah.
See you back in the E.D.
All right.
♪
Help me!
Please. Help me, please.
Hey, Mr. Kumar, I'm here.
What's going on?
My back. My back is on fire.
Okay.
Radiologist said
that the stent
would ease the pain,
but it's worse, it's worse.
And my legs are numb.
They're numb.
Okay.
I can't move them.
Okay, we're gonna
figure this out.
No way this is an aneurysm.
I need an MRI.
Ow!
.
Damn it. I knew it.
Tumor in the inner layer
of the aorta.
It's occluding several
perforating vessels
to the spine.
It's not getting enough blood.
Explains why
his legs went numb.
Looks like blood's leaking
into the wall of the aorta.
If it keeps compressing
the vessels--
His legs will go
from numb to paralyzed.
That tumor's gotta come out.
Roland doesn't
have schizophrenia?
I don't believe he does.
After talking with him,
looking at his test results,
getting more medical history
from Dr. Scott,
it's my belief that
the more appropriate diagnosis
would be bipolar disorder.
But the other psychiatrist--
Was wrong.
But he was so sure.
Said he'd seen it before.
Psychiatry is far
from an exact science.
And unfortunately,
research does show
that African Americans,
particularly males,
are misdiagnosed
with schizophrenia
far more than whites.
We're perceived as dangerous,
and so we get a diagnosis
to match that perception.
This why the dosage
on Roland's meds
was so high also?
Because he was assumed
to be a threat?
It's very likely.
And that high dose
also probably contributed
to exacerbating the condition
that I think
that he actually has.
Today could have been
avoided.
I'm so sorry.
Is there a way
to make things right?
We do a complete
reassessment, okay?
New meds. The right doses.
Therapy.
I know of an outpatient clinic
that I think that Roland
would really respond to.
Okay?
I'm gonna leave you two
for a minute.
Thank you.
Of course.
What do you think?
I think he sees
the same thing in Roland
that we see.
What do you say?
Follow Dr. Charles' advice?
An anomaly?
I don't understand.
According to
your medical records,
we have reason to question
whether your original tumor
was in fact
anaplastic astrocytoma.
We came across
a pathology report
that suggests it might be
pilocytic astrocytoma.
Well, what's the difference?
Anaplastic is malignant.
Pilocytic is benign.
So I might not have cancer?
We don't know.
There's no tissue left
from that original tumor
to examine.
In order to make
an updated diagnosis,
we'd need to test a new sample.
Biopsy the latest recurrence.
In 1991,
technology only allowed us
to analyze the tumor's tissue.
Today, we're able to dissect
its molecular structure.
Identification will be exact.
Even so,
I might still have cancer.
More and more
I'm suspecting that
that is not the case.
Why?
Because you're alive.
People with
anaplastic astrocytoma
simply don't live
as long as you have.
Okay.
Okay, do the biopsy.
♪
Dr. Marcel, I presume.
Yeah.
Dr. Simms,
cardiothoracic surgery.
Pleasure.
Radiology filled me in
on the patient.
Aortic tumor.
Mm-hmm.
Nice call.
From the get go and
despite the cath lab, I hear.
Yeah, it wasn't
a straight line, but, uh,
we're back on track now.
I appreciate the head start,
but I'll take it from here.
Uh, I assumed
I would perform the surgery.
I understand,
but this is
a cardiovascular procedure.
Not a trauma.
Little out of your lane.
I'm aware of what it is,
and I have the skills.
Maybe, but you don't have
the credentials.
You're a general surgeon,
not a specialist.
I just want to make
something very clear,
Mr. Kumar is my patient.
Dr. Marcel.
Do you really want
to waste time
fighting an argument
you're not going to win?
You're free to watch
from the observation room.
♪
.
Wow. What a view.
You can almost see
the entire city.
And yet, it's the best spot
in the hospital to be alone.
Rehearsal didn't go well
this morning.
Okay...
So I flirted
with the subtle suggestion
from Dr. Cooper to sabotage
Dr. Archer's CVP monitor.
Sabotage?
Yeah.
So that the Vas-COM
could save the day.
And I came this close
to doing it.
But you didn't.
But I'm afraid I could've.
Look, in the past,
every time you've acted
injudiciously,
you've always kept
your patient's best interest
at heart,
and I know you always will.
Thanks.
And Dr. Halstead...
If this ever gets to be
too much for you,
tell me, and I'll put
a stop to the whole thing.
♪
Benign?
So all this time,
I never had cancer?
No.
There are two pathologists
listed in your medical records.
The first who examined
your tumor
thought that it was benign.
But he was a young attending.
Inexperienced.
Wanted a second opinion.
So he sent a sample
to a renowned cancer center,
and the pathologist there
diagnosed
anaplastic astrocytoma.
30 years.
Every headache, every seizure.
Just feeling off,
I thought it was the end.
Three decades of facing death
every single day,
and my family and my friends,
they suffer too.
Ashley.
I'm so sorry
for what you've been through.
But at least
you are no longer living
on borrowed time.
Your future can be anything
that you want it to be.
Heard your door
is always open.
Literally, right? Come on in.
Am I sensing
that it might be time
for a little drink?
Oh, pour it up.
Have a seat.
Thanks.
Oh, man.
Had I not beaten the cops
to the scene today,
Roland could be
in the system now, or worse.
Seems like happy endings are
hard to come by these days.
Seems that way, huh?
Situation like today,
there's nobody else to call
for help but the police.
But they're not equipped
to handle mental illness,
you know.
I mean, don't get me wrong,
there are a few bad cops,
but the rest, most, are just
doing the best they can
with the tools
they've been given.
It's a tough job.
Huh.
And in need of some updates.
So, uh,
so what are you thinking?
CPD is developing
a crisis intervention program.
A unit trained specifically
for de-escalation.
Sounds like a solid first
step in police reform to me.
Agreed.
I mean, it's what I did
today on the street.
Which proves that it works.
Was hoping you'd say that.
So the thing is,
the program, it's on the table,
but it's stuck there.
Lots of training
needed for police,
but not enough
training resources.
I don't know
the time commitment,
and I can only imagine
that the bureaucracy
will be infuriating--
I'm in.
That was easy.
Oh, excuse me.
Just grabbing a snack.
Taking five, I hope?
More like a 30-second
breather.
But, since I've been caught,
I guess I have
four and a half minutes to go.
You okay?
Yeah.
No.
My aortic patient.
His procedure was a success,
I just--
I wasn't able to see it
all the way through.
Got benched
by the powers that be.
It's frustrating, you know?
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
Sorry. I, um--
I didn't mean to, uh--
you know what,
that was inappropriate.
I don't know what
I was thinking.
It's okay. We're good.
Don't worry.
Okay. Cool.
I have to go, uh, check
on some test results, so, uh.
Uh, Dr. Hammer, Maggie,
I just--I need a minute.
Sure.
That's gonna sting for a bit.
She'll be okay.
♪
Heavy day.
Yep.
And not just the case.
I, um--
I made a fool of myself
for Dr. Marcel.
The doctors' lounge?
I'm so embarrassed.
I'm crushing on my advisor?
Seriously, I'm a cliché.
Kind of. Welcome to the club.
For real? You?
Yeah.
My Crockett was
Dr. Andrew Jacobson.
Well, I'm sure
you handled it
better than I did.
If only.
Would have spared me
a lot of heartache.
Instead I married him.
Oh, I didn't even know
that you were married.
I'm not, no.
Didn't work out.
That's our cue.
Get back to it?
Let's go.
♪