Psychologists believe that
every aspect of our lives,
all our thought processes
and behavior patterns,
are the direct result of our
relationship to our parents.
You're looking all thoughtful.
I'm just thinking
how pretty you are.
And also how pretty
our children would be.
Children?
- Like, multiple?
- Child.
Let's just start with
one and see how it goes.
You wanna start?
I'm just saying you're pretty.
That's all I'm saying.
That every relationship
that we have
is really just another version
of that first relationship.
Have you talked to Dr. Wyatt?
- Cristina...
- When's the last time...?
It's just us trying over
and over again to get right.
- Alex?
- Mer?
OK, so Izzie's not here
and Cristina's not
answering her phone
and I have a thing, so I
need you to be a girl for me.
What'd he do? You
want me to kick his ass?
He wants me to have a baby.
- So you do want me
to kick his ass?
- Alex.
- Do you want to have a baby?
- A baby doesn't want me.
I had the worst
mother in the world.
I'd be the worst
Izzie wants a divorce.
She sent the papers.
- The official papers.
- You want me to kick her ass?
Hey, Alex... Hey.
- He's being a girl for me.
- Dude, it's true.
Right. There's a guy downstairs
who says he's your brother.
Do you want me to
send him to the bathroom,
since this seems to be where
you receive your visitors?
- Um, tell him to wait.
- Right.
- You have a brother?
- Yeah.
- Do you want me
to go get rid of him?
- Crap!
What's he doing here?
Alex is the oldest, then
me, and then Amber.
Amber's graduating
from St. Saviour's in May.
She's... She's smart like Alex.
She could go to
college if she wanted to,
but she's, like, "What's
the point?" you know?
I don't know what to tell her.
Alex is the doctor
in the family.
- I move people for a living.
- Hey. What are you doing here?
- Oh, man! You got old!
- Dude! What are you doing here?
I had to drive to Portland on a job,
and since I was in the neighborhood...
Portland's not in
the neighborhood.
It's three hours. I do
three hours in my sleep.
Alex, he's your brother.
He's allowed to come say hi.
You're gonna be
late for pre-rounds.
OK. Well, it was very nice to
meet you. I'm Lexie, by the way.
I'm overdue for a visit.
It's been seven years.
- No, it has not.
- Since you've been home.
- Seven years.
- You haven't been home
in seven years?
Derek. I have this.
Mm-hmm.
- Derek. Nice meeting you.
- Aaron.
- Take care. I'll see you.
- Meredith, by the way.
- Hello.
- Nice to meet you.
Has it been seven years?
Amber was ten last
time we saw you.
What's going on?
What do you want?
I do miss you, OK? And
I did want to say hi, but...
since you're a doctor,
I thought I'd ask.
Should I be worried about this?
- Thank you. Cappuccino.
- Cappuccino.
So? How'd the
date go with Teddy?
I don't know if
I'd call it a date.
Doesn't going on a date imply
actually going somewhere?
Shut up. You had sex?
- Hey, guys!
- Hey!
Oh! Pound cake.
I love pound cake.
Rich, buttery pound cake.
- Mmm.
- Yum, pound cake.
- Mmm. Mm-hmm.
- Hmm.
- Pound cake?
- Oh, I'm good. Thanks.
So, what exactly
constitutes a pound cake?
- It's a yellow cake.
- There you go.
- Kinda heavy.
- Come on.
Code for something dirty, right?
Like you eat her pound cake,
- she eats your pound cake.
- No.
Oh, please, tell me it's
dirty. Because otherwise,
that was the most boring
conversation I've ever been a part of.
We are talking about pound cake
because I want a
kid and she doesn't.
We're not talking about that.
How long are you two not
gonna have that conversation?
- A year? Two years? Five?
- Wow.
So... you and Teddy
ate pound cake together?
- You're changing the subject.
- You like how I did that?
- So how was it?
- Mind-blowing.
- Yeah?
- I pounded her cake.
She pounded mine.
Excellent pound-caking.
- Pound-caking is not a thing.
- Whatever. I blew her mind.
- Life-changing?
- Life-changing,
earth-shattering.
The point is, he's a
legend for a reason.
He has skills that I never
even knew existed. It was like
- there was a party going on.
- A party in your panties.
Oh...
Morning.
- Good morning.
- Hi.
- Bye.
See you.
He's always so grumpy.
He's going through something.
And Cristina doesn't get it.
She can't, which isn't her
fault. But I do get it, and...
and I can't be there
for him, and that's...
That's really hard.
But you're seeing Mark.
But I'm seeing Mark.
So then a couple days ago,
we're at the grocery
store, Gary and I.
The next thing I know, I'm flat on
my back in the frozen food section.
- She fainted.
- And I have never fainted.
I've never even
seen anybody faint.
- I don't believe in fainting.
- Did you hit your head?
I would've if this one
hadn't caught me.
Mrs. Clark is anemic
and guaiac positive,
so there's internal bleeding,
which looks like
it's coming from...
A friable tumor near
the ampulla of Vater.
Yes, thank you
for that, Dr. Kepner.
Dr. Swender told us the biopsy
showed the cancer was back,
but she said you might
be able to take it out.
There's a chance I won't be able
to go in as deeply as I need to.
But I'll promise to
do everything I can.
- Anything you could do...
- We appreciate it, Dr. Webber.
Thank you.
- I honestly don't
think I need surgery.
- You do.
- It doesn't hurt that bad.
- You have an umbilical hernia.
You need surgery. Shut
up and fill out the paperwork.
Surgery'll make it hurt worse.
Remember when Dad
had his gallbladder out?
- Stop talking and write!
- Write what?
I don't have insurance.
What am I supposed to write?
- Ask Bailey to do it pro bono.
- I can't ask her to do that.
- Alex, he's your brother.
- Evil spawn has a brother?
Aaron, Cristina Yang.
Nice to meet you,
Dr. Yang. I'm Aaron Karev.
Oh, my God, you're
so nice. He's so...
Why can't you be nice like
your brother, angel spawn?
- Why can't you?
- Fair enough.
- Mer, what's up? You called?
- Ten times.
Owen's still in his dark
place and he's still not talking.
So I turned off my cell in
case he'd say something.
Which he didn't. I hate
men. They're stupid.
Derek asked me to have a
baby with him this morning.
Really stupid.
Oh, great. The Pit, with
Owen and his dark place.
- What have we got?
- A cop with multiple GSWs.
- How many cops did you say?
- Just one.
Officer Gina Thompson, 34,
GSWs to the hip and chest.
Vitals 100 over 70,
pulse 118, respirations 28.
That's quite a police
escort, Officer Thompson.
- I told those guys I was fine.
- I wonder why they
didn't believe you.
- I've been in worse shape.
- Seriously?
Oh, yeah. You should
see the other guys.
You took down three
guys by yourself?
Hey, a girl's gotta do
what a girl's gotta do.
Am I right, ladies?
- Coming through.
- Let's go.
- How many
bullet wounds?
- Four. I'm wondering...
- No exit wound for right leg.
- Busted the femur.
- I have to debride.
- The trajectory...
- Seems to have gone upwards.
- - Breath sounds are...
Three chest wounds
can't be transthoracic...
Oh, God, Gina. Baby.
- Baby, look at you.
- I'm OK.
They're taking good care of
me. This is my husband, Jimmy.
This is Lieutenant Moore.
What'd you find
out at the scene?
You were told to
wait for backup.
I was first on the scene.
I heard a shot. I went in.
You disobeyed a direct order,
you endangered your own life
- and everybody in the building.
- I took down three men
by myself.
- And got yourself
suspended for it.
- What?!
It's going to the review
board this afternoon.
You'll be lucky to have a
job by the end of the day.
- I gotta get out of here.
- I need you...
- I gotta go defend myself!
- She's bleeding into her chest.
- Throw in a chest tube now!
- Get them out of here now!
- No, I gotta go! Please!
- Gina, just lie back.
- Go. You must go.
- All you
have to do is breathe.
Dr. Webber, did you consider
doing a Whipple on Mrs. Clark?
I did. But since the
cancer came back,
I think I can do
a local resection
and get the entire
visible tumor.
- Dr. Kepner, are we boring you?
- No, sir.
I just... I wasn't
expecting Chief Shepherd
to be up in the gallery
during a general surgery.
I guess that's the chief's job,
right? Evaluating, observing.
Dr. Kepner, you're in my OR,
and the only one observing
and evaluating
you right now is me.
Yes, sir. I'm sorry, sir.
- Go get it, guys.
- Put the orange in the red.
How's that? Orange and the red.
- And it's...
- Dr. Bailey, you got a second?
I do. I have a second.
Which is why I'm
spending it with my child.
Here, look. Say bye-bye,
Dr. Karev. Yeah, bye-bye.
- Say goodbye.
- Dr. Bailey,
my little brother is here
with what looks like
an umbilical hernia.
I didn't know Dr. Karev
had a little brother.
Did you know Dr. Karev
had a little brother?
He has no money, he
doesn't have insurance. So...
Mommy sees where this is going.
He'd have to have you
perform the surgery pro bono.
Did you hear that funny word?
Pro bono.
Mommy's got a mountain
of surgeries to schedule.
Does she have time
to do free surgeries?
And I'll schedule your
surgeries for the next...
week if you want.
Think Mommy should fix up
Dr. Karev's brother, make him feel better?
- Two weeks. A month.
- All right!
I will meet Dr. Karev's
brother in half an hour.
- Say bye-bye,
Dr. Karev. Bye-bye.
- Come on.
I would have done it anyway,
but he just kept talking, didn't he?
You're so good.
Dr. Sandoval to OR
three. Dr. Sandoval...
- Mr. Clark?
- How is she?
She did great in there.
She was a total trooper.
The surgery went great.
We got the tumor, all of it,
- with good margins.
- Oh, thank God! Oh.
Dr. Grey, thank you.
Thank you so much.
My wife keeps telling me...
I need to be more
manly about all this.
After all, she's the
one with the cancer.
- She's afraid I won't make it.
- I think you're
doing just fine.
- You both are. You like to see her?
- Can I?
She should be
waking up any minute.
How is it your
brother is a surgeon,
and you waited months
to take care of this?
I don't know. Karevs are tough.
I guess five years in foster
care will do that to you.
- Foster care?
- You're all foster children?
Well, me and Amber were in
and out, but Alex, he had, like...
17 different foster
homes in five years.
- So Alex was a foster child?
- - Yeah, because my mom was...
It was before they had all
the meds they have today,
and she was... I guess she was
doing her best, but my dad, he...
wasn't a good guy and he was...
You know... whatever.
And so Alex, he got
shipped around a lot.
And he was a pretty rough
kid if you didn't know him.
So people didn't like to keep
him. And he ended up in juvie.
Juvenile detention?
Yeah, 'cause my mom, she'd...
Sometimes, she'd
forget to buy food, so...
He was good, though.
People wouldn't even know
he was stealing anything if it
hadn't been for the video cameras.
How old was he?
- Mmm... Eleven, maybe 12.
- Hey, what do we do with 2807?
- Dude, are you
talking crap in here?
- No.
- Dude, I work here.
- So go to work.
- Check the chest tube
in 2807. Go.
- Shut it, Aaron.
- So what happened after juvie?
- Dr. Bailey,
I don't think Alex...
Mind your business.
Aaron? After juvie?
They couldn't just expect me to
just sit there with a 10-71 in progress.
I had good, solid information
the perps were threatening...
- Your doctors are here.
- We need to take you
to surgery.
Kenny, did you get that? 10-71.
Baby, he got that. You gotta go.
Wait! This is important.
They're gonna need a statement.
Baby, that's what's important?
Trying to save your job?
- Jimmy...
- - Listen, every year you promise me
that once you make detective,
we're gonna buy a house,
have a kid and
settle down. But...
Baby, it's been seven years,
and every time you
get close to a promotion,
- you go do something stupid.
- Baby...
These people are
trying to save your life,
and you want them to wait?
I'm not gonna stand
here and watch you die.
I want a life with you,
baby. I want a long...
happy, boring life.
- Tell me everything you did.
- I was trying to wean her off
the ventilator,
but then I realized
she wasn't breathing on her own,
so I put her back on her
previous vent settings.
- Dr. Webber,
what's happening to her?
- She may have stroked out.
Get a CT and get the
scans to Shepherd.
Also, run an EEG. We
need to find out right away
if there's any brain activity.
If there's not, then we need...
She looks great. Oh, thank God!
Dr. Grey told me
you got the tumor.
Thank you so much,
Dr. Webber. Can I wake her?
Sweetheart?
You still sleeping?
The doctors said
you did great in there.
Honey?
You awake?
Alison? Alison?
The patient's had a massive
hemorrhage. Look. See here?
The left temporal lobe.
- Hemorrhages... looks like a...
- Wow. That bleed is huge.
- What?
- You look even prettier
in your scrubs.
What are you gonna do
about your giant stroke?
Nothing.
- Nothing?
- Yeah.
Mrs. Clark has a left temporal
lobe hemorrhage that's extended
into the ventricular system.
There's nothing we can do.
Want to get a cup of coffee?
Only if you keep telling
me how pretty I am.
We got three bowel injuries
here. You got anything, Avery?
- Found what did the damage.
- You see the bullet?
Lodged near the liver.
Teddy, I'm looking
at a Devastator.
- What? What does that mean?
- It means be careful.
They're sharp like shrapnel
and explode on impact.
Can you imagine
going to work every day
knowing you're gonna end
up on the wrong side of a gun?
I know. She is awesome.
Now her husband
wants her to give it all up.
He's all, "Start poppin' out
babies or I'm leaving you."
Why does it have to
be one or the other?
You don't want to have kids if
you're facing mortar fire every day.
- It screws with your head.
- Is that why you don't
have them? Iraq?
First, it was residency.
And then it was Iraq.
And now it's... I don't know.
- Waiting for the right guy?
- You want to have kids?
- Wait, you don't?
- Have you met me? No.
OK, we're done here.
- I think I feel it.
- Feel what?
The bullet. It's right
next to the heart.
There's still some
bleeding. I got it.
No, no, don't...
Oh, God!
- Damn it, Cristina!
- What happened?
You essentially fired a bullet
into that patient's
chest, is what you did.
- That's my intestine?
- Yeah. And that
part right there
is supposed to be on the inside
of the membrane, not the outside.
Dude, that is sick.
Can I get a copy of one of these?
I want to hang it on my fridge.
Are we doing consults
at the desk nowadays?
'Cause I kind of need
to use the computer.
Oh, uh, This is Alex's brother.
Aaron, this is Arizona Robbins.
Nice to meet you. How come I
didn't meet you at the wedding?
- Actually, Dr. Robbins...
- That's right,
no one's family came.
- Last minute switcheroo
and all that.
- What wedding?
- Alex and Izzie's.
- No one's.
Alex got married?
I'm just gonna go use the
computer over there. Bye!
He got married and
he didn't even call us?
No, it sounds weird, but it was
totally a spur-of-the-moment thing.
- You know,
because of the cancer.
- Alex has cancer?
- Lexie...
- No, Izzie has cancer.
- Who's Izzie?
- Alex's wife.
But she's not really
his wife anymore.
It's... I wouldn't
worry about it.
- They got divorced?
- No, but they...
She left, and then,
you know, she came
back, but he didn't think
- it was the right thing...
- Lexie.
- Stop talking.
- OK.
- You guys all right up there?
- There's shrapnel everywhere.
I was going for the bleeder. I
didn't touch the bullet. I don't know...
When your commanding officer
tells you to stand down, stand down!
I'm not in the Army,
and you're not my
commanding officer.
Dr. Altman and I
are your attendings.
And you are our subordinate,
and do exactly as we say,
even if you do not agree.
You know why? Because
we know more than you do.
For example, we know that Devastator
bullets have chemicals in them,
and they do not
detonate on impact.
Sometimes, the
heat from that Bovie
is enough to make them explode.
Do you understand?
Dr. Yang, do you understand?
For whatever it's worth, I would've done
the same thing Yang did. Anybody would.
- If it's a bleeder...
- The damage is done.
There's no point in arguing
about it. Let's just fix it.
Yang, I need your hands
right now. Right here.
- OK, you see this? Hold it.
- Yes. Mm-hmm.
- Hey.
- Dude.
How could you not have
told me you got married?
- You told him?
- No. It wasn't me.
- Some of it was...
- It was Arizona Robbins,
- and it was an accident.
- She figured your own brother
would already know
you married somebody...
This is why I didn't wanna tell
you. You'd make a big deal...
It is a big deal! You get married
on the spur of the moment,
- you walk out on your wife...
- I did not walk out!
She walked out on
me. She walked out!
You have any idea what Mom's
gonna do when she finds out?
- She's gonna go off her meds.
- She's not. You're
not gonna tell her.
You're gonna get free
surgery, get back in your truck
and you're gonna
get the hell out of here!
Fine. You know what? I
don't need your free surgery.
- I'll see you.
- Aaron, stop.
- You're not going anywhere.
- I don't need your crap!
You walk out on us,
you walk out on your wife.
Like father, like son.
- Take it back! Take it back!
- Get off me, man!
Alex!
- Alex!
No, no! This is not
happening! Alex!
- Get off me!
- Karev!
- What the hell is your problem?
- You are!
You hitting people now, too?
You really did turn into Dad!
Walk away. Alex, walk
away. Just walk away.
- OK...
- Give him some space.
- OK, don't follow him.
- OK.
I need a gurney. Run, honey!
She could wake up, right?
I mean, people wake up
from comas all the time.
I'm sorry. Your wife's
coma is irreversible.
Dr. Grey, would you
explain it, please?
Mrs. Clark's scans showed a
massive hemorrhage in her brain,
and the EEG showed
minimal brain activity.
But that means there's
hope, right? Because...
At least there's activity.
And... and her
heart's still beating.
Only because the mechanical
ventilator is breathing for her.
When we turn the machine off,
the heart won't get
the oxygen it needs
- and it will stop.
- Why would you turn it off?
People can live for
years on these machines.
Mr. Clark, the advanced
directive your wife signed
specifically requested
no mechanical ventilation.
She filled that form
out three years ago
when the cancer
was first diagnosed.
The doctor told her she
had six months to live,
and she held on for
another three years.
She'll come back from
this, too. You'll see.
- You can't unplug her.
- - Legally, we don't have a choice, sir.
But... she's my wife.
- It's my choice.
- It's your wife's choice.
And she made it three years ago.
You said the surgery went fine.
- That's what you said.
- It did.
- But...
- No.
You're not a doctor, you're
a child! And you're useless!
I'm done talking with you!
I'm done talking
with all of you.
Who's in charge here?
He protected me my
whole life, you know?
He kicked my dad's ass so hard,
the son of a bitch
never came back.
I thought he did that for me,
but maybe he likes
throwing punches.
Aaron, I like you. I do.
But you can't talk about
my friend that way, OK?
I need you to count
backwards from ten for me, OK?
OK. Ten.
Nine. Eight...
That's it.
A junkie dad, a crackpot mom,
and somehow Karev
still became a doctor.
I'm not easily impressed,
but I'm impressed.
- Prep him, we'll go scrub.
- Yes, doctor.
Dr. Grey, we're meeting
Gary Clark in Shepherd's office.
- Five minutes.
- Yeah.
I told a patient's
husband that she was fine.
That her surgery went perfectly.
And then next thing we
know, she has a stroke
and we're supposed
to just unplug her.
I know that I am
supposed to toughen up.
I know that I am supposed
to not care, but how...
How do you not care?
It's the hardest
part of the job.
The very hardest part.
How did you do it?
How did you learn?
I'm still learning.
Why is her BP still low? Is
she still bleeding up there?
- We've got it under control.
- We've had LR and blood hanging
since we got here, but we can't
catch up. Is her liver bleeding?
- No, I think we got it.
- Dr. Torres is right.
Still bleeding in
the retroperitoneum.
We need a retractor in here.
That's a lot of blood. Get
in there with the suction.
- See where it's coming from?
- I can't see past the clots.
- The suction's clotting.
- Let's use our hands! Scoop!
Did you check the uterine
artery? That could be the source.
Down to 64 over 32. We gotta stop
this thing or we're gonna lose her.
If we hadn't been
distracted by artillery,
- we might have found this...
- Hunt, not now.
That was, um... That
was our fault in there.
We were speaking in shorthand.
We forget sometimes
that you guys are civilians
- and you don't know
about ballistics.
- It's not just that. It was...
It's not the first time.
He's been...
It's been...
He has been through so much.
It's not like he talks about it.
He can't.
I can't talk about
it either most days.
But Owen had it worse than me.
Has it worse.
He's triggered. Right
now, he's triggered.
And his triggers
might never go away.
They'll get better over time,
if you give him time,
which you should,
because he is in love with you.
He just needs time.
He needs therapy. I keep
telling him to go to Dr. Wyatt...
No, don't do that. He
won't go if you tell him to.
He's... He's very...
He's a guy that way. A man.
Don't ever tell him
what to do. Just...
Just tell him how you feel.
When's the best
time to have kids?
The best time to
have kids... is never.
- What? You asked.
- Well, yeah, but...
They cry all the time.
Nonstop. They never sleep.
They're terrible
conversationalists.
They take everything you've got.
All your time, all your focus,
all your patience,
all your sleep.
Everything, till you
got nothing left for you.
Wow.
But this morning...
Little Tuck woke me up
by putting his nose
up against mine.
His cold, little nose.
And he goes, "Wake up!"
And he got the "K"
sound in "wake."
Wake up. See, up until today,
he'd say "D" instead of "K."
"Wade up."
Girl, him nailing
that "K" sound?
It's the pride I felt.
The irrational, unbridled joy.
Yeah. It's at least as
good as any Whipple.
Look, if you're waiting for
the perfect time to have kids,
you're never going to have kids.
Hey.
Aaron's surgery went well.
His hernia defect
was fairly large,
but Bailey was able to
use mesh to bridge it.
So...
He'll be waking up in a few
minutes if you want to stop by.
Mr. Clark, I'm deeply
sorry for your... for your loss.
No, don't speak about
my wife as if she's dead.
She's still here.
She could wake up.
She's not gonna
wake up, Mr. Clark.
Not with the brain
damage she's suffered.
- You don't know that.
- Mr. Clark, if we don't obey
your wife's directive, if
we ignore her wishes...
She signed that
form three years ago.
Her health will deteriorate.
She'll lose body mass.
She'll have no immune system.
She'll require
around-the-clock care,
and that can become
very expensive very quickly.
I don't care about that.
It'll be no life
for either of you.
And that's why your wife
signed the advanced directive.
She didn't want to have
to live her life this way.
And she didn't want
you to live this way.
Don't you speak for my wife.
Don't you dare
speak for my wife.
I'm sorry, Mr. Clark, but the ethics
committee has reviewed your case.
We are bound by law
to obey her wishes.
If you unplug my wife...
you'll be killing her.
I'm sorry.
You should take all the time
you need to call your family,
to say goodbye.
There's no one to call.
We didn't have any family.
It's just us.
We didn't have any kids.
It's just me.
He's my sister's husband.
- Excuse me?
- Don't play stupid.
I'm not playing
stupid! I am stupid!
I'm stupid and I'm humiliated.
And I'm sorry. I just...
I've never felt anything...
I've never felt
like this before.
So if you just please
forget what you saw,
because I promise you
will never see it again,
and we can just go
back to being doctors.
Please.
This day sucks. I hate this day.
Oh, God.
You don't have to
be here. You can go.
I'm just making sure you don't
croak, and then I'm outta here.
You saved my ass every
day when we were kids.
You... You were a better parent
than Mom and Dad put together.
And every day, I
feel bad for Amber,
that she has just
me instead of you.
What happened to you, man?
I send you money every
month. I send Mom her meds.
You want that to stop?
I am this close to
being a real surgeon.
I can't...
I can't be in that and do this.
I can't.
Amber's a good kid.
She turned out
OK. You'd like her.
You turned out OK, too, Aaron.
I'm sorry your wife left you.
Or... got cancer or whatever.
Thanks.
We repaired the damage
to your liver and intestine,
cleaned out your fractured
hip and fixed your lung.
There was a bullet and
some shrapnel near your heart.
- Oh, my God.
- But Dr. Altman was able
- to repair all the damage.
- Thank you.
Thank you all so much. Honestly,
I don't even know what to say.
There was, um...
There were complications, Gina.
There was a lot of
bleeding in the abdomen.
The uterine artery was involved.
We were able to
stop the bleed, but...
in order to do
that, we had to...
remove your uterus.
What?
We had to perform a
hysterectomy. I'm sorry.
She can't...? We
can't have kids?
I'm so sorry.
We can never have kids?
- Oh, God.
- It's OK.
- It's all right, baby.
It's OK. It's OK.
- How long has he been there?
- - About three hours.
It's time.
See it through.
- Mr. Clark?
- Please.
I'm sorry.
I keep telling myself there's
a chance she'll wake up.
Once you turn
off the respirator...
there is a chance...
even... even if it's just
a less than one percent chance,
that she'll start
breathing again.
Right?
Miracles do happen.
That's what... That's
what she always says.
Please.
Please, darling, wake up.
- Please.
- I am so sorry.
Please. Please.
Please. Please wake up.
Please wake up.
Hi.
Were you checking up on
me in that surgery today?
I wasn't checking up
on you. I was observing.
You know, that's the closest
I get to an OR these days?
I'm gonna choose
to believe you on that.
Hm.
They were married 32 years.
There was nothing
you could've done.
I'm going home to my wife.
You should do the same thing.
Looking good, Gina. You're gonna
be back on the beat in no time.
That's what they call
it, right? The beat?
Yes, they do. And no, she won't.
Jimmy and I talked
about it. I'm quitting.
- What?
- Why?
Well, 'cause Jimmy's right.
I mean, it's a job, you know?
And I love it. But I
love my husband, too.
And we're gonna adopt ten
Haitian orphans or something.
- Eight.
- - Well, congratulations.
- Thank you.
- Gina.
I want you to know I did the
best I could with the review board.
- Josh, it's OK.
- They want you back on the job.
Are you kidding me?
Welcome back, Officer Thompson.
- Oh, my God!
- Look out now! Watch out!
Oh, my God!
- Oh, my God!
- You're killing it, Gina!
Thank you so much.
- Where's Aaron?
- He went back to Iowa.
You let him drive after surgery?
I'm not his dad.
He's got my number.
You know, you're nothing
like your father, right?
You're nothing like your mother.
You're good. You'd be
good. You'd be a good mom.
It's the most important
job in the world.
You probably should
need a license to do it,
but then most of us wouldn't
even pass the written exam.
You ever wonder if
moisturizer really works?
I mean, what's in this stuff?
I'm a doctor and I haven't
even heard of half of it.
Dimethicone? No idea.
Distearyldi... Hmm.
I can't even
pronounce that, so...
I want to have a baby.
And I can't talk about lotion
or pound cake or anything else
because you don't want
to have a baby and I do.
So...
we're gonna talk about it.
Yeah.
We are gonna talk about it.
Some people are naturals.
They were born to do it.
Some have other gifts.
- Oh, you're making dinner.
- It's just pasta.
Smells good. Are
you baking bread?
So...
You said you don't
want to have kids.
What?
- Your sausages are burning.
- They're fine.
- No, they're burning.
- Listen. They're fine. They're...
Damn it!
I'm sorry.
Are you scared of me?
I don't want to be.
I have to go back to Dr. Wyatt.
It's OK. It's OK. It's OK.
But the good news is,
biology dictates you
don't have to do it alone.
- Hey.
I don't want you to be alone.
If anything should
happen to me...
I don't want it to just be you.
Well, we would
make pretty babies.
- So you're thinking about it.
- Oh, I'm thinking about it.
You can waste your
whole life wondering,
but the only way to find out
what kind of parent you'd be
is to finally stop
talking about it...
But we're not making
babies right now.
We're practicing. It's
very important to practice.
And just do it.
You taste good.
You have no idea
how good you taste.
Mark, I... Oh...
I'm really, really
enjoying myself with you.
I am. But I need to, um...
I need to be honest
about something.
No, you don't, if you're
honestly enjoying yourself.
I... I am. I am.
Then right now, that's as
honest as you have to be.
- OK.
- Now, turn over.
I wanna try a little milk
chocolate on your belly button.
Ignore it. They'll go away.
I'll get rid of them.
Sloan.
The baby's coming! The
baby's coming right now!
The baby's coming!
Oh, the baby's coming!