The waiting can kill you.
You make a decision, and
then the world has to turn.
The consequences unfold.
Out of your hands.
There's only one
thing that seems clear
in those quiet
moments while you wait.
Whatever you chose was wrong.
You think he put
you in his will? No.
Next of kin. Maybe
you get the house.
I have a house.
Well, you can give me his
house. I mean, I could use a house.
He's not my father.
I've been telling
him this for years.
He just feels guilty because he
busted up my parents' marriage.
That's not my problem.
It is now.
Yeah, I mean, sticking
me with his end of life care,
doesn't ask, doesn't give
me an out, that's real love.
Well, it sounds
like family to me.
Maybe he is your father.
Banged your mom enough. Alex.
Did they know each other
before you were born?
They met when I was three.
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
That's what they told you.
I gotta get back to the ER.
Ow. Oh, no, no. Let me get it.
This is Yang.
And how about Brooks?
Hey.
I know. I'm fine.
Hey, look. I need to run
to my nec fasc surgery.
He's in cardiogenic shock. No.
Bailey feels like there's
likely some internal necrosis.
So she took him up to the OR.
With this kind of
cardiac compromise?
Yeah, and she...
Uh-uh. She... Mom. Mom?
Look...
I need Hunt in here.
I can try to... Now!
Ready? Go. Two, three...
Bowels are completely clean.
Should we recheck the pelvis?
I have, four times.
What the hell do
you think you're doing,
cutting open a man
in cardiogenic shock
with nothing on his CT?
There's dead tissue
somewhere inside him.
I'd like to find it
before it kills him.
He can't handle this stress until
his cardiac status is stabilized!
Get him off that table!
Lap pad, please.
Dr. Hunt! Dr. Avery, I'm
gonna have to ask you
to keep it down while
we're doing our work.
Huh, there's a surprise for you.
Pressure's dropping. Is
his dopamine maxed out?
Yeah, it's at 20.
Close the patient!
Come on. Where are you?
Dr. Hunt! Brooks is crashing.
Bailey, he's having
runs of V-tach.
Close him up!
Closing.
Can you get by
without me? Just go.
Hey, how's it going with Brooks?
Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
You gotta drink the juice, man.
You give us half your blood
and head back to the pile,
you're gonna pass out.
Heather didn't make it.
Come on.
I'm gonna give the interns
the rest of the night off.
Can you give me a hand if
there's anything they drop?
Of course.
I'm so sorry about Heather.
Yeah.
Dr. Hunt, Lydia's desatting,
decreased breath sounds on the left.
Sharpie lady.
Oh. Should I throw
in a chest tube?
Dr. Yang is gonna
take over that case.
Why? I can handle a chest tube.
Oh, my God.
I got a woman with
necrotizing fasciitis,
and the interns
aren't operating.
So can you... Of course.
Well, she's
already on the table,
and the anesthesiologists
are lining her up.
Be ready in 10. Okay. Hey.
It's just terrible.
Jackson.
Oh, hey. I'm sorry.
And what about Richard?
Still critical,
but his pressure stabilized
once Bailey closed.
So Bailey closed
because his vitals tanked,
or because Catherine Avery
was in the gallery screaming?
Oh, Derek.
You heard about Brooks?
I can't believe it.
Can we have a conversation?
Not now.
I know you're mad.
And telling everyone, I
guess I deserved that.
But if we could just...
I said not now.
Hey, it's right behind me!
Are you headed back out?
Be careful, okay?
It was Avery, right?
He's the guy that you...
I get it. He's a
good-looking guy.
Practically runs the
hospital. Matthew...
And I proposed to you
in front of 100 people.
I didn't really give you the
opportunity to say no. So...
Did you want to say no?
Callie?
We got the clot out but there
was just so much swelling.
Couldn't get it to stop.
Did you tell the family?
Yeah, I had someone call
her mom when we found her
to tell her that
she was injured.
She's coming down from
someplace in Oregon.
I just didn't want to tell her
when she was still on the road.
Okay, so you need to go to
the day care and pick up Zola
because she's gonna
think we had a baby
and forgot about her.
I'll call the babysitter
and tell her to meet you
at the house in an hour.
And you should tell
the interns to hang out
and wait till Heather's
mom arrives.
Give me the baby.
Okay.
I know.
That is a lot of blood.
Should I book an OR?
No, not yet.
We'll monitor her for
the next couple of hours
and then decide.
My house.
Ma'am, you've lost
quite a lot of blood.
You should rest.
I wouldn't worry about
the house right now.
Oh.
You can't scream at my doctors
when there is an
open body on the table.
I can't believe
you let her talk you
into a boondoggle like that.
Dr. Avery, if you
have any issues with...
Does he know why
you cut open a man
in severe cardiac distress
just so you could poke around
and see what's going on?
We looked at all of
the options. Tell him.
You tell him you feel guilty
because the last thing
Richard Webber heard from you
is that he's a drunk
who ruined your life.
After all he's done for you.
We talk on the phone
for an hour every night.
It came up.
You feel bad, go find a priest.
But do not try to fix
it with a Hail Mary
that very well may kill the man!
I want access to
his charts right now.
I'll be back in about an hour.
Heather's mother won't
probably be here yet,
but if she is,
uh, someone stay
with her until I get back.
We don't tell her, do we?
No, I will.
Just think of some
good Heather stories.
Once she knows,
she's gonna want to know
that she died among friends.
Who's gonna wait?
I can't. I can't. She'll
see it in my face.
What the hell is his problem?
It's not like they were friends.
I am not waiting with
her alone. I'm not either.
Okay. Nobody goes. We all wait.
Now go find Shane and tell
him we're doing this together.
What are you, my
mother? You find him.
Yes, yes, yes.
Hey. Hey, can you
watch her for a minute?
Yeah. I need to get my laptop.
Come here.
What's going on?
My wife's an S-L-U-T.
Sofia and I are spending
the night at a hotel.
And then what?
I don't know. Okay,
I'll be right back.
We're gonna let
her stay at a hotel?
So is this the woman whose
fiance is also a firefighter,
but they couldn't
find him for a while?
Yep. Forceps.
Wow, this wound is really deep.
To get good margins,
we're gonna have to...
I got it.
You are one sleepy girl.
I'm gonna get you
to bed right now.
Um, I was gonna go to a hotel.
But Mer said I should come here.
Well, I guess I should have
read those five text messages.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. Sofia's
asleep in Zola's bed.
And I can move her.
She probably won't wake up.
Yeah, okay.
Catherine may be
right. I mean, it's possible
I'm too close to
this to see it clearly.
Am I supposed to
be seeing this clearly?
Well, Yang was advocating for
a more conservative approach.
I guess that's what we go with.
Catherine's reviewing his
charts, labs, I don't know.
If she wants to
make the decisions,
then maybe she should.
Here you go. Thanks.
Hey, how is she doing?
Oh, I put in the chest tube.
One of her broken
ribs sliced into her lung.
So, I mean, she
put out a lot of blood.
We're watching her. Okay.
How are you?
Fabulous.
Yeah.
What? Nothing.
What? I just...
I wish I had known
it was gonna be
the last time you
and I were together.
I would have done
things a little differently.
Well, was the last time bad?
No, the last time was Wednesday,
when we knocked that
plate off the counter,
and I spent half the night pulling
shards of glass out of your foot.
That was not the last time.
Yeah. Mm-hmm. It was?
Not our best work.
Well, that's awful.
After the kind of run we had...
It's just a shame.
Shameful.
Everyone I love either
cheats on me or dies.
Callie...
Or cheats on me and dies.
George did both.
Arizona's not gonna die.
Yeah, that doesn't
make me feel any better.
Ugh.
I'm sorry. I'm
drinking all your wine.
You should be
drinking all your wine
after what you went through
tonight with Heather and...
And Richard, oh, my God!
Why is everything so horrible?
Please, it's okay. Go ahead.
It's all yours.
Yeah?
Yeah. Please.
Okay.
I'll open another bottle.
Just page her!
I can't page someone 911
without the name of
the patient... Andrea.
When Dr. Torres calls in,
she'll expect to know who...
No, there's no
patient. Just page her.
We can't page 911
without a patient emergency.
Look at me. Does it look
like this is not an emergency?
Hey, hey! What's going
on? What's going on?
I need you to page Callie 911.
Why?
Because she took off with my
baby, and I don't know where.
And when I call her,
she doesn't pick up.
All right, did she
maybe... No, just do it!
So we were able to remove
all of the necrotic tissue,
but the labs suggest that your
organs are beginning to fail.
Well, is there anything
that you can do?
Well, we're giving you
some powerful antibiotics.
And we're hoping that
that stops the process.
But... But I might not make it.
We are going to do
everything that we possibly can.
Bri...
We want to get married now.
Right now. No matter what
happens, we want to be married.
We need a chaplain.
Hey, Bailey.
Arizona is in the lobby
screaming at nurses.
Why?
'Cause she has no idea
where Callie is. Or the baby.
Oh, well, you need to tell
her they're at my house.
Ha! Callie's not a
battered woman.
We're not harboring her until
she gets a restraining order.
She just wants some space.
But you don't think Arizona's
called her, like, 300 times?
If Callie wanted her to
know where she was,
she'd have told her.
You think it's okay that Arizona
doesn't know where her baby is?
She's Sofia's mom, too.
They're both our friends.
We shouldn't take sides.
It's not taking sides to tell
Arizona where her kid is.
Oh, you think that's how
it's gonna go? Mm-mmm.
What happened to your hair?
She wasn't funny-funny,
but she was weird-funny.
We're not saying
that to her mom.
Hmm.
Remember when she swallowed
that marble? We could talk about that.
Her mom knows she
swallowed a marble, idiot.
You know what? When you have
a better idea, you let me know.
You were her roommate.
How do you not have a
single nice story about her?
She took my white
sweater and returned it pink.
She left the apartment
without waking me up
when we both had rounds,
which she knew about and said,
"I didn't want to bother
you. You looked so peaceful."
She'd drink all the milk
and return the empty
carton back in the fridge.
Then why are you all
red-eyed and puffy?
We weren't soul mates. It
doesn't mean I wanted her dead.
What's going on with the baby?
Oh, nothing. He's fine.
They have him in
the nursery. Oh. Oh.
I thought something
happened. No, no.
I paged you because I
wanted to let you know
that Callie and Sofia are
going to stay at my place tonight.
I think she just needs some
space. She needs to cool off.
And I know you're not gonna
go run over there or anything,
but I just thought
you would like to know
that she and the
baby are... Arizona.
Arizona?
Is "I told you so"
inappropriate? Shut it.
Come on. What about Hassan?
He's out at the pile, too?
You realize they can't
all be out at the damn pile.
No, I don't care
what religion they are.
Just give me somebody,
anybody that can officiate this.
Yeah, as a member of
the board, I'm gonna say
you want to stay
away from phrases like,
"Even a Catholic."
Yeah.
All right, uh,
just call me back.
How is Richard?
Hanging by a thread.
Thank you very much.
You're gonna scream
at me, too, now?
I heard you already had
a go at Hunt and Bailey.
I just wanna know what in God's
name was going on through your head...
Stop!
You are terrified. I get that.
You love him.
And you are as scared
as you have ever been.
Marching through this hospital
telling everybody
they are incompetent
is not gonna fix that situation.
We are all doing our best.
And we are gonna
take good care of him.
take good care of you.
Okay?
Oh.
As soon as he's stable...
Yeah. As soon as
the storm passes,
I'm going to move
him to another hospital.
Visitor Carol Erdman
return to the admit desk.
I'm gonna do a
thoracotomy on Lydia.
Just waiting for
an OR to open up.
Okay.
So thanks for before.
"Thanks"?
Are you gonna send a
card on pretty stationery?
I'm just glad
that we've given each
other a better last memory.
Uh-huh.
What?
I don't know.
If we'd really
thought it through,
then for the last
time we'd have...
What?
Is he in there? I
can't see anything.
Keep your voices
down. She's sleeping.
No, she's not.
Oh, sorry, um, we were
just looking for Dr. Shepherd.
He's not here. He'll be back.
He went to take Zola home.
What do you need?
He asked us to come up
with something nice to say
about Heather to her
mom for after she knows.
We're having trouble coming up
with something that's appropriate.
We were thinking if we
looked at some of the cases
she worked on with Dr. Shepherd,
we could talk about those.
Her mother is not gonna give
a crap about her glioblastoma.
She wants to hear
about how you loved her
and how she was
like your family.
Nothing? Doesn't
have to be deep.
When my friend George
died, I told his mother a story
about how he stole
us all Jell-O cups.
And then he dropped
them all over the floor
and made a huge mess.
And then he tried to clean it
up with those blue bed pads,
which only made it
worse because, of course,
those blue bed pads
aren't absorbent at all.
It's not a sonnet,
but it made her smile.
And then she
went back to crying.
Okay.
Asleep? What do you think?
My mother's planning on moving
Richard to another hospital.
What? I know.
I know you weren't
sure about how to handle
Richard's medical decisions,
but I'm just telling you,
you turn the reins over to her,
that's exactly what
she's gonna do with it.
Okay. Get me a wheelchair.
You just had a
splenectomy and a child.
I'm not putting
you in a wheelchair.
Jackson, just get
me a wheelchair.
There are no chaplains
anywhere in the building.
Everyone is out dealing
with storm victims.
We have storm
victims right here.
What... Chaplains are
supposed to stay here!
Anybody seen my patient Brian?
Firefighter, busted ribs.
Yeah, he's getting married.
Not without a
chaplain, he's not.
Well, I can go online
and get certified
by that place on the Internet,
but me and weddings, today,
I don't think that
I'm the best choice.
The damn firefighters
keep taking off, injured.
If you see any of them, tell
them to stay in their damn beds.
Kepner. What?
Get me a wheelchair.
Uh... April!
I don't think we can be friends.
Really?
Mm-mmm.
This will keep happening.
Yeah. I really wanted to
be able to work with you.
Yeah, of course.
But if we, you know,
talk on the phone
or grab lunch...
Just because I'm the
one who said it was time,
doesn't mean
this is easy for me.
I know.
This is not easy for me.
Hey, hey.
What do you really believe is
the best course of treatment?
It's not that simple.
Yes, it is.
You always taught us,
when you know, you know.
I think there is
something in there,
and no matter how
much it stresses his heart,
I think letting it
get worse is worse.
Hi. This is Dr. Grey.
I need to book an OR for
an exploratory laparotomy.
Surgeon is Bailey.
Patient is Webber.
Oh, they're opening
him up again.
Yup. Don't say
anything. I'm not.
She thought it was a
stupid idea the first time
and even more
stupid the second time.
You're the one who has to decide
what Richard would want.
Wouldn't want to be you.
Thanks. But to be clear,
when you're making
these decisions for me,
give my heart at least
24 hours to recover
before you cut me stem to stern.
You just couldn't
hold it in, could you?
Wait, she's your
health care proxy?
I get to make the
decisions for everyone.
Not Owen?
No.
Who's yours?
Oh, I never filled
out the forms.
I had the papers back
when it was gonna be Izzie.
Ooh. That was a bad plan.
That was all a bad plan.
Why do you think I
never turned them in?
Well, Mer could be yours, too.
You think I make the
wrong decisions all the time.
I don't know why
you're selling me to him.
Will you stop being so insecure?
Just because I disagree with you
doesn't mean I don't
respect what you think.
I can hold more than one
point of view in my mind.
I am mature.
I don't believe you.
Hmm.
You can be mine.
Health care proxy? Really?
I mean, Mer's got
enough to take care of.
You want extraordinary measures
or should I just unplug you?
Use your judgment.
Hmm... Uh-oh.
Sharpie lady's ready.
Mom!
You knew they were
taking him back into the OR?
Right, now you can't march
in there and shut 'em down.
The hell I can't. Hey!
He didn't choose you
to make his decisions.
He chose Meredith.
How's the ER?
Ugh, quiet for a while.
But we got a couple of
ambulances on their way in,
people they pulled
out of the pile.
Can I come? No, no. You're
supposed to be working.
I don't need the night off.
We're supposed to be sitting
around telling Heather stories.
Turns out we're not a very
tight group. You think you're not.
But when it all hits the fan,
you'll be glad you have 'em.
Someone just died.
Shouldn't this be the time?
Oh, come on.
You're not gonna go cry
to them when we break up
and you have to move your trash
bag full of crap out of my house?
Okay, one,
I never leave more than a change
of underwear and a toothbrush
in anyone else's
house. That's smart.
And two, I will have
dumped your sorry ass,
so I'm not gonna be crying.
I'm just gonna feel bad
that I made it so you
can never love again.
Oh, yeah. It's gonna
be ugly. Mmm-hmm.
But see, I've got Mer and
Cristina. I can cry to them.
When the next guy after
me breaks your heart...
I'm gonna want my bitches.
Voila.
This, it'll help.
Hmm.
Brian and Sasha,
your commitment to
each other is an inspiration.
Your love, your
devotion, it's unwavering.
You aren't swayed by anything
that life puts in your path.
When people talk about marriage,
this is exactly what they
ought to have in mind.
I can't believe I
yelled at a woman
who clawed dying
victims out of the mud
and triaged them with
her bleeding little hands.
Super tacky.
I think I'm the worst
person I've ever met.
Shut up.
Mmm.
It speaks.
It wants more booze. All right.
All right, we all have to focus.
Heather.
She was a fine, upstanding
citizen with limitless potential.
You say that to my
mom when I'm dead,
and she's gonna
know you're lying.
My mom will believe it. You
can say it when I'm dead.
Write it down 'cause
I'm gonna forget.
That I was a nice person?
How is it that we spend
this much time together
and we don't really know
anything about each other?
So tell us something
we don't know.
About me? Mm-hmm. Don't be shy.
What?
I can't.
You guys are gonna hate
me more than you already do.
No, we won't. Circle of trust.
My mom knew Mark Sloan.
The one who died?
They, like, dated a hundred
years ago or something.
And he kind of helped
me get into the program.
What?
Oh, I knew it.
I knew you didn't make
it in here on your own.
You are such an evil cow.
Whatever. At least I got
in here on my own merit.
What happened to the circle
of trust? I was a street kid.
Foster homes, lived in my car.
You were not. Hand to God.
Really? Do you know
how to pickpocket?
No. I wasn't Oliver Twist.
Could you teach me
how to shoplift? No!
It'll help me in the OR.
Calm hands under pressure.
You couldn't
handle it. You could.
Thank you. Mmm.
I went through college on
a cheerleading scholarship.
What? JO: No!
Yes.
That is my child!
Okay, so I can screw
some whore on shore leave,
but this is over the line?
Hey, I could have
called the police on you.
Okay, and now she's your baby.
I had to talk you into even
considering having a child.
And I had to talk
you into marriage.
Yeah, because I knew
it would be a mistake.
And you know what? It was.
You cannot take a
baby and just disappear...
Oh, look at the stars
and the sky light.
Yeah? Yeah, should we go...
Let's go to the swing.
Should we go to the swing?
Okay. Go to the swing.
Go to the swing.
Let's go to the swing.
We are excited, united,
and here to win the fight.
We're here to meet
you, defeat you,
we dominate tonight! Ow!
Tigers.
Tigers. Mmm.
Tigers. JO: Whoo!
Oh. Tigers.
Tigers.
Excuse me,
somebody said you might be able
to help me find my daughter,
Heather Brooks.
We have run this
bowel four times now,
and there is nothing there.
I don't know how much
longer we can keep at this.
Come on. I know you're in there.
Owen.
Oh, my God. The pancreas.
Look at that.
That's all necrotic
tissue hiding underneath.
Get her some forceps, please.
And a 15-blade.
Here you go, Doctor.
Hey, somebody call
Meredith Grey up in maternity.
On it. Tell her, "When
you know, you know"!
It was a beautiful wedding.
What you said... Can we not?
Why are you
snapping at me all day?
I'm not snapping. Yeah, you are.
I'm sorry I asked the question.
It obviously made you
really uncomfortable,
and I guess that's my answer.
There's no need to
beat a dead horse.
That's what it's supposed
to look like, you know.
I mean, they can't even
imagine not being together.
Do you see the
difference between that
and "I think I'll
marry this guy,
"or maybe I'll marry that guy,
who I banged in a bathroom
"because I flipped
out over my boards,
"but when he was into
me, I couldn't handle it.
"But suddenly, when he almost
dies, I can't live without him."
That is so unfair!
It's what happened!
You didn't want me when I
was okay, when I wanted you.
No, you just want me now
because you are in
something that is real. And that,
that scares the crap out of you.
Marry this guy because you
want to make a life with him,
or don't, and move on.
But none of this
has to do with me.
No, this is entirely about you.
I'm very sorry about how
I spoke to you yesterday.
With the storm and
everything, and we're all just...
Your house...
It didn't make it, did it?
I'm sorry.
You saved a lot of
people triaging like you did.
Were you a doctor or something?
No, I've just lived on the side
of the mountain for a long time.
It's not our first storm.
An ex-marine showed me
how to do it our first mudslide.
Oh, I can't believe I have
to build that house again.
Ugh. Maybe you should
find someplace else.
No.
We're a few houses on
the side of a mountain,
and we take care of each other.
I'm sure you'd find new friends.
No one else would have me.
She was really good.
Fast hands.
One time,
we'd all been working all
night, and we were starving,
and she went to where they
make the food trays for the patients,
and she stole Jell-O
cups for all of us.
And they fell
all over the floor.
She tried to use one of
those blue hospital pads
to clean it up, but it
just made it worse.
Got everywhere.
Jo told Heather that
she swiped an apple
from a grocery store
when she was a kid.
And Heather asked her
to teach her how to shoplift.
She thought it would
improve her surgical technique.
You must have been close.
April, I really don't have
time for this. Please just...
Please.
I want to accept your proposal.
In private, without anybody
pressuring me to say yes.
And I want to do
it in front of God.
Actually, no, you know what? No.
I'm not accepting your
proposal, I am proposing to you.
I want to be your wife.
I think you need to
think some stuff out.
I did.
Okay. Yes, it was Jackson.
And, yes, I have
feelings for him.
He's always gonna
be a part of my life.
And that gets
confusing sometimes,
especially when he's pulling
babies out of burning buses, but...
I'm not good at this.
This is all new to me.
Okay, I was never the girl
that got picked at the dance.
I'm not good at it.
And I'm indecisive
because I see eight
sides of everything.
And that's what you're
picking when you pick me.
And you may not want that.
I thought maybe nobody
would ever want that.
April... But I want you.
I want to marry you.
So will you marry me?
Sofia is downstairs
in the day care.
I'm sorry I called
you a baby-snatcher.
I was upset, and I shouldn't
have spoken to you like that.
You were just
trying to cool off,
and that was the
right thing to do...
Sofia and I will be staying
at Mer's again tonight.
That'll be two nights with me.
You can take her the
following two nights.
And we'll switch off like that until
we can figure out a real schedule.
Well, how long is this
gonna be going on?
I don't know.
Dr. Ben Warren,
this is your wife.
Sorry, I keep
missing you. It's...
It's been...
Um...
Something happened with Richard,
a health situation.
I got involved in that.
Uh, he's still unconscious.
I don't know how
he's going to...
But he's alive.
Hey.
Heather's uncle just arrived.
He's with her mom, and
her brother's on his way.
Thank you for staying with her.
Go home. Get some rest.
You need to tell your guys to stop going
out to the damn pile if they're injured.
I keep patching up
the same damn guys.
I could tell 'em, but it's not
gonna make any difference.
They can't just sit around.
It makes them nuts.
All right, try harder!
Where's the rig?
You okay? You sure?
Okay. Out back.
Hey, sir?
Can I ride out
there with you guys?
Sure.
What are you doing?
Shane!
Shane, you're not
a firefighter! Shane!
Stupid.
Damn it.
What are you doing?
We're his people. We have to go.
Uh, actually, no, we
don't. We're not trained...
Sharpie lady helped.
Sharpie lady almost got
herself killed. We have to go.
I don't know what the deal
is with him and Heather.
I don't know if it's their
weird competition thing.
Or maybe they were having
secret sex in the bathrooms.
I don't care. Whatever it is,
Shane hasn't said a
single word since she died,
and we're what he has.
We're what we have.
Maybe we get through
this program normal.
Or maybe we end up
cranky, work-obsessed people
who live on the
side of a mountain
and have no family or children,
and we only have each other
because no one else can stand us.
What is she talking... Get up!
Hey. Everything okay?
Yeah, uh, Meredith just wants
me to hang out at her house.
Zola needs some attention.
And Derek is pretty wiped out.
Callie and Sofia
are there, so...
Is there anything I can
do? I mean, I could, uh...
Good night.
Yeah.
Zola is asleep.
All right, little miss.
In five minutes, it's your turn.
To be clear, I am
happy to do the dishes,
but there is no universe
in which I generate dinner.
All right, we'll figure it out.
Mac and cheese.
Oh, no, we had that last night.
Well, and it was good.
Right? It was good.
Oh, thank you.
HI. Um, I'm sorry
to bother everybody.
No, it's okay.
Can I see her for just a minute?
You saw her this afternoon.
You can get her tomorrow night.
I know. Um, but...
You can see her
when it's your night.
I could, uh, just take her on the front porch
for a minute, and I'm not gonna take her.
Do you have any idea how
confusing this is for her?
Yeah, I realize that.
Well, you know what? She's
supposed to be in bed right now.
How am I supposed to get her to
sleep with you coming and going?
Five minutes. Are
you kidding me?
She shows up here with this act,
and you're just
gonna take her side?
It's an act. Callie, look at me.
I'm your friend.
Five minutes.
Come here, Sofia. Come
here, baby. Okay. Yeah.
We just want to
survive the storm.
I missed you so much.
We pray, "Please, God,
"just get me to the other side."
We never imagine what
it'll be like when we get there.
I love you so much.
And I miss you every second.
'Cause you're my girl.
What if when the storm
passes, nothing's left?
I always said I could
handle anything.
I was wrong.
I was wrong about
a lot of things.
I think there's no harm
in getting another opinion.
Was I or was I not correct?
Why does that make
you feel so threatened?
I'm another opinion,
and I have to tip my hat.
Dr. Bailey called it.
Nobody said it wasn't good
to deal with the pancreas,
but he is still
clearly unstable.
He hasn't regained
consciousness...
None of that is unusual.
I would like to bring in another
person, somebody that could tell us...
I will make the decision.
You've said what you think,
and then you said it again.
And I will take that
under advisement.
Dr. Grey...
He picked you
to be his girlfriend.
And we're all very
happy about that.
But he picked me
to be his family.
And you walked away from that
responsibility the second that...
No one said I
would be good at it.
And he knew that. But
he picked me anyway.
I'm the family. Meredith.
Please, don't get involved.
But I was right about one thing.
Hi.
I was right about this.