- Previously on The Resident...
- You want Conrad to go down.
Whistleblowers like Hawkins
cost hospitals millions.
It's him or you.
If it were easy, everyone
would be a doctor
because this is the
best job in the world,
despite everything,
because of everything.
Cardiac issues can escalate
quickly for pregnant women.
Worsening heart failure
could kill both you and the baby.
So, guys, hey.
These are the doctors
that are gonna be
helping Dr. Cain save Mom.
There is only a slim hope
this will buy you more time.
I will do anything
to stay with my kids
- as long as I can.
- When is she gonna wake up?
Dawn has endured
17 hours of surgery.
Her body is
struggling to recover.
She hasn't regained
consciousness and as yet,
isn't able to
breathe on her own.
- What?
- Mina, I think it's happening.
What do you mean it's happening?
- The baby.
- It's five weeks early.
- How far apart are
your contractions?
- Hang on a sec.
20 minutes maybe.
I think some are coming sooner.
I think they're
getting stronger.
Use the app. It's
important to log each one.
- Did your water break?
- N-No.
- Where are you?
- I'm at Peachtree and 4th.
It's a big sale. First come,
first serve. I need a crib.
- I'm in line.
- Sit down immediately.
- Yes, Doctor.
- Okay, I'm on my way.
I'm taking you to Chastain.
Okay. Okay.
- Hey, what's up?
- Adaku is in labor,
and in line at a box
store, if you can believe it.
- I'm gonna get her right now.
- She's five weeks early.
Yeah. So to be safe,
I'm taking her to the ER.
Well, of course. With her
heart condition, she needs
- to be monitored.
- Obviously, I will not
make lunch today.
- What was that?
- Um,
I, uh, almost hit
a car. All good.
- Okay. I'm coming to meet
you both at the ER.
- Uh, no.
It's your day off. Enjoy your...
- yoga.
- On a scale from one to ten,
your stress level
sounds like a 12. Emotional
support is required,
and that happens
to be my superpower,
so I will see you
at the hospital.
Now turn off your
phone and slow down.
I will. I promise.
And we're done here.
Dr. Voss, the hip is all yours.
He's bradying down.
Coleman, push two grams of
mannitol and open up the drain.
His brain is swelling again.
What's your issue, Dr. Voss?
He had advanced
dementia even before he fell.
Uh, he's 89.
Yes, I've had the pleasure
of reading his chart.
Your point?
His ICP's increasing.
He's gonna herniate.
There's no way this
is gonna end well.
Given his physical
and mental status
before surgery and
this complication,
he'll have zero quality of
life, if you could even call it life.
Are you suggesting
we let him die?
He'll be a body in
a bed. A vegetable.
It's the compassionate
choice at this point.
I'm gonna say this
once and never again.
Nobody...
and I mean nobody...
Dies in my OR!
Coleman, proceed.
Pushing two grams of
mannitol and opening the drain.
So, the son is
expecting an update.
Why don't you go out
there and talk to him,
tell him the surgery went well.
Tell him his father is
stable and in the ICU.
Remember to smile.
It shows you take pleasure
when delivering good news.
Understood?
♪ ♪
Last day as an intern
for Dr. Devon Pravesh.
Yeah!
- My, how time flies.
- Seriously?
- Thank you.
- That felt like
the longest year in history.
12 more hours,
you'll be free of me.
I will never escape you
since you're going
to be chief resident.
Oh, yeah.
- Good point.
- As a second-year resident
with interns of your own, you'll
need to up your wardrobe game.
I could definitely
see him in a bow tie.
Oh, yeah, I've already
got three picked out for him.
- What? No. No.
- Nic leans towards plaid,
but I think he's more
- of a polka dot kind of guy.
- Oh... Uh...
Batman, Robin, you're
needed in Bay Two.
Hello. I'm Dr. Hawkins,
this is my intern Dr. Pravesh.
Hi.
Now, can you tell
us what happened?
Uh, I, um, I think Tyler
took a bunch of these...
I'm not sure how many...
And a few sleeping pills.
Okay. Sleeping pills.
I... it-it's not what you think.
H-He's been having
trouble sleeping
and lots of pain
from sports injuries.
I think he took too much
acetaminophen by mistake.
Okay. Thank you.
We will let you know as
soon as we have an update,
- okay?
- Nurse Hundley?
Would you mind taking
Tyler's mom outside
- where she can wait, please?
- Sure.
- Excuse me.
- Come on.
Vitals are stable.
Pulse 80s, BP 120/70.
- Satting 100% on room air.
- Tyler.
Tyler, can you hear me?
- Where's my mom at?
- She's here. We got you.
I'll order a set of labs with an
acetaminophen and aspirin level.
- Don't forget...
- Coags.
- I know.
- We'll add a liter of saline.
Labs could be hours and we
have a high index of suspicion.
- Let's start him on NAC.
- Hmm. Hey.
I think it, he says it.
It's like I taught him
everything he knows.
Hey. I was also involved.
- Eh.
- Okay, guys.
Chill out.
Katie and I cooked
dinner yesterday.
Tim cleaned. Well...
He sort of cleaned.
We always have to
wash his dishes twice.
I miss you.
I bet your mother loves
hearing about your day.
Do you really
think so, Dr. Cain?
She never squeezes my
hand or makes any sign
that she even knows I'm here.
Well, I have some good news.
Your mother is
ready to leave the ICU
and go to a great
rehab facility.
Rehab? She, she
doesn't even move.
Hmm? Give her some
time. Don't count her out.
Your mother is a fighter.
She survived the
Mother of All Surgeries.
She's being transferred today.
Just let her settle
into her new home
and then you can go visit her.
And, Malia, don't give
up before the miracle.
Okay?
Where are you
taking this patient?
Long-term acute care facility.
- On whose orders?
- Dr. Cain,
at the family's request.
Adaku?
So, this is your
baby's birthday.
So excited. Scared and excited.
Where is her OB?
I texted her to meet
us half an hour ago.
Dr. Lin has a patient
but will be here soon.
Put her in Trauma Bay 11.
How is that good enough?
I'm going to call the
OB chief and complain.
Dr. Lin is the OB chief, Mina.
That's why you chose
her. Remember?
Breathe.
I'm not having a contraction.
He means me.
- Mina, darling. One minute.
- What? Do you have pain?
- Is your heart racing?
- I'm fine.
Soon we will meet my baby,
the child I've wanted my whole life.
And you'll be her godmother.
You are my dearest friend.
I've known you half my life.
It's time for us to
be happy. Together.
Okay.
♪ ♪
Got a new one for the vent farm.
- From Chastain. Dr. Cain's patient.
- Another?
We won't have a
room ready for her
- until later today.
- Got to put her somewhere.
She can't go back to the
hospital. Doctor's orders.
Okay. Stash her there with
the others who are waiting.
How you doing, Tyler?
Uh, I'm-I'm better. Thanks.
Do you want to tell
us what happened?
Sophomore year, I
was tackling a fullback.
He was a big guy and
I... dislocated my elbow.
Painful.
Yeah, and... junior year, I
lost sight of the quarterback.
- Got blindsided.
- Did you get this bruise
playing football?
Uh, that one, I don't know.
I'm not sure.
When's your next game?
For me?
Never, 'cause I got cut.
And then Tilly, my girlfriend,
she broke up with
me the next day, so...
Did that happen today?
Tilly was yesterday and...
team was the day before.
Um...
Then, this morning...
uh, my parents told me
that they're calling it quits.
Filing for divorce.
That is a lot to deal with, man.
I-I did something
really stupid, um...
I...
I tried to kill myself.
Yeah.
- Tyler?
- Yeah.
Listen, have you been thinking
about taking pills for a while?
No, man, no.
It was...
gosh, it was a
spur-of-the-moment thing.
I was just...
I was, I was angry and I...
I'm not like that,
like, I'm-I'm not...
I, uh...
Where am I...?
- Hey, Tyler, look at me.
- Oh...
- Huh?
- Open your eyes.
- Okay, okay.
- Bruising, confusion,
- scleral icterus.
- No, guys.
I'm good, I'm okay.
I'm okay...
Whoa, whoa.
Okay, okay.
I'm okay, I'm okay, I'm good.
And what time did
the contractions start?
Her first contraction was
at 6:42, second at 7:15,
- third at 7:33.
- It sounds like early labor,
which isn't great, considering
she's five weeks early.
We can deal with that, and
we'll give her steroids to help
- the baby's lungs mature.
- Her heart rate has raised
from 100 to 125
in the past hour.
She has a history of
dilated cardiomyopathy.
She cannot handle a
sustained tachycardia.
Believe it or not, she
can be a ton of fun.
You should see her when
she has a few drinks in her.
Mina, I'm sure Dr. Lin
is very well versed
in her patient's medical needs.
An excess of caution is
appropriate in this case.
So, normally, if your
contractions stopped,
we would watch you, we might
even consider sending you home.
But with your cardiac
history, I think the safest choice
is to get you comfortable
in labor and delivery,
and we will monitor
you and the baby.
And you'll be back to
check on her shortly.
Thank you, Dr. Lin.
You're welcome.
I'm getting Dr. Austin.
A full cardiac exam should
put everyone's mind
at ease, especially...
All right, good news.
Tyler's brain CT is negative.
No bleeding and no signs
of cerebral edema...
What about the labs?
Not good news.
Let me guess.
Fulminant hepatic failure
from all the
acetaminophen he took?
He needs a liver
transplant or he'll die.
I wish I could say I
haven't seen this before,
but I've seen it too many times.
Acetaminophen overdose
is the leading cause
of liver failure in the U.S.
He's young, otherwise
in good health.
That should put him at
the top of the transplant list.
He could get an organ quickly.
If we tell the transplant board
that Tyler attempted suicide,
he will be ruled ineligible.
He won't be at the top
of the transplant list.
He won't be on the list at all.
That is a rule here at Chastain.
As long as we get
him counseling,
I say...
what suicide attempt?
Wait, did I hear that right?
Is that Dr. Pravesh
or is that an imposter?
Look, I'm the same man
that I've always been,
but I see more shades
of gray than I used to.
Sometimes, to do right,
you can't follow the rules.
I think the short answer
is, I'm not an intern anymore.
I'll transfer him to the ICU.
And I'll contact
the transplant team.
Well, you're definitely still
pregnant, but I'm guessing
you already knew that.
Shallow breaths, use
your abdomen like this.
What do you see?
Heart's beating a little fast.
But you're pumping for
two, so that's totally normal.
What is it?
All good.
Listen, I've got some
instructions for your ladies
in waiting on how to
best take care for you.
- So, they'll be right back.
- Okay.
One of her heart
valves is failing.
It's leaking severely.
Mitral regurg.
It's causing fluid to back up
into her lungs.
We have to, uh, get
her in surgery right away.
I'm gonna book
an OR and scrub in.
Whoa, wait, take
your foot off the gas.
The regurg isn't emergent.
The valve needs to be replaced.
With the continued stress
of pregnancy, she could
- decompensate rapidly.
- Or it could last
another week or another
month. There's no way to predict.
Do not play Russian
roulette with Adaku's life.
No delay, we need to get
her to surgery right now.
No... I'm gonna close
my eyes and pretend
the last 15 seconds of this
conversation never happened.
And when I open them,
history will be erased,
and I will know that you
still have unlimited faith
in my ability to deliver
the best care possible
to your friend.
We obviously
trust your judgment.
What I think Mina's
trying to say is,
we need to save Mom and baby.
No, that is not
what I want to say.
The mother is
priority number one.
There is no choice
to be made, Mina.
We save both baby and the mama.
Adaku is a high-risk pregnancy.
We need to get
our ducks in a row
- before surgery, Mina.
- Thank you, Nic.
Now, that means we have to
line up the best anesthesiologist,
the best neonatologist,
have an on-call perfusionist,
and put blood on hold.
It's gonna take a few
hours, and once everything is
in place, Dr. Lin
will deliver the baby
and we will repair the valve.
And there is every
reason to believe
it's going to be fine.
If her condition
changes, page me.
Look, if you are frightened,
you are gonna transfer
that anxiety onto Adaku.
The only thing we can do
now is show rock-solid support.
And to restate the obvious,
Mina, I'm here for you.
Okay?
So, your patient, Dawn Long,
you moved her to an LTACH?
Family didn't want to let
her go, so in deference
to their wishes, I
admitted her to a facility
where she can be
safe and comfortable.
Yeah, just wondering
about the timing.
Meaning?
Well, if you keep her
alive past the 90-day mark,
then her outcome won't
be tracked anymore
and you can claim
your patient survived
the Mother of All Surgeries.
As can the hospital.
Better outcomes
mean more patients
and better Medicare
reimbursements.
Yeah, agreed,
except neither of those
are appropriate reasons
for a medical decision.
So, tell me, what's
the harm in allowing
a family to live with hope
for just a little while longer?
In a facility owned
by Red Rock costing
thousands of dollars a day.
Exactly... you're
making my case for me.
Tyler's an excellent
candidate for a liver transplant.
The patient is
otherwise healthy,
no underlying
medical conditions?
None, and he's a teenager
with his whole life ahead of him.
According to your
notes, he presented
with an overdose of painkillers.
Yeah, acetaminophen.
He's a football player.
Tried to self-treat
his back pain.
Took too many.
Ah, this was a...
a-a therapeutic misadventure.
You know, people don't
realize how easy it is
to take too much
over-the-counter pain medicine.
You talk to our ER
staff, they'll tell you.
- They see it all the time.
- You understand that
patients with suicidal
ideations are disqualified
from receiving
transplants at our hospital?
- Mm-hmm.
- We've had a few
recent bad outcomes.
And any more could put
our program in jeopardy.
Of course.
Was Tyler's overdose
a suicide attempt?
Absolutely not.
We'll get Tyler listed.
Notify UNOS.
With his numbers,
he's first priority.
Great.
Thank you.
Torturing yourself?
Facing our new reality.
The Barrett Cain
Center for Neurosurgery.
He's a pot of gold at the
end of Red Rock's rainbow.
I'm the chief of surgery,
and I still can't control him.
You remember Dawn Long?
The lovely woman with seven kids
who had the Mother
of All Surgeries?
He had her transferred
today to an LTACH for rehab.
You're joking.
He was gaming the
system to boost his own stats
at the expense of his patients.
That's what I'm here
to talk to you about.
You know how I've
been trying to play nice
with Cain in his
sandbox to find out
- what he's up to?
- Yes.
I've seen multiple surgeries
with residents in charge,
overtreatment, up-coding.
This morning he
operated on a patient
who shouldn't have had
surgery in the first place,
then condemned him to life
on a vent in a vegetative state
just so he wouldn't
have a death in his OR.
I'm not surprised.
We have to do something.
No, we don't have
to do anything.
You have to stay
out of the line of fire.
Chastain needs good doctors
like you now more than ever.
And your contract is
coming up for renewal.
If he thinks that
you're against him,
you're gone.
What about you?
My contract is virtually
unbreakable, so...
I guess what happens
next is up to me.
Chest feels heavy.
She became acutely short of
breath and her 02 sat dropped.
Harsh holosystolic murmur.
We need to take
another look at that valve.
Coming up.
A chord must have ruptured.
It's wide-open
mitral regurgitation.
That valve is blown.
What? What does that mean?
It's time to have this baby.
Page Dr. Lin!
- Mina, what's happening?
- We're gonna proceed
immediately with the C-section
with Dr. Lin, and then you're
gonna go into surgery
right after with Dr. Austin.
It's my heart? Listen to me.
Take the baby first. Save my,
- save my...
- Adaku?
Save my baby.
Adaku?
I still have a pulse,
but she's hypoxic...
We need to bag her.
- Acute pulmonary edema.
- Get a code team in here now!
She's in V tach!
V fib. We lost her pulse.
Starting compressions!
We got no time
to waste... Let's go.
Where's Dr. Lin?!
- OR Three is ready for us.
- Good.
We need to get this baby
out as soon as possible.
No, no. Adaku's
coding. We save her first,
- then think about the baby.
- Negative.
We do that, then the baby dies.
Adaku made her wishes clear.
She said save the baby first.
- Austin, I swear,
if you don't save Adaku...
- Mina! Listen to me.
We get her on bypass
as Lin delivers the baby.
Then we deal with the valve.
That's the only way
we save them both.
Trust me.
- How long do you need?
- About a minute.
Ten blade.
Adaku won't make it.
Yes, she will.
We just have to
buy her more time.
All right, baby's out.
Baby's not breathing.
Now I'll prep her for bypass.
You handle the cardiac massage.
Let's get some blood in here.
How we doing over there, Nic?
Baby's still not breathing.
Okay, let's bag her.
- Heart rate's still in the 50s.
- She's been hypoxic too long.
Okay, I'm starting compressions.
Giving 0.5 milliliters
epinephrine.
Okay.
Thank God.
Welcome to the
world, little one.
Let's get her to
the NICU, please.
She's ready for bypass.
How we doing?
I'm starting to repair
the heart valve.
Mina.
Let's go to the NICU.
I can finish the
surgery, Mina. Go.
We saved the baby,
but Adaku still might die.
You should have
operated her hours ago.
- We shouldn't have waited.
- Mina,
that's not helping.
He made the right call.
Adaku and the baby
are both still alive.
- That is the best possible...
- I'm staying.
- No more mistakes on my watch.
- There were no mistakes!
That baby is going to have
her mother, and I'm going
to make sure of it.
- Looks good.
- What?
It's perfect.
Let's start weaning
her off bypass.
She's undergone
two major surgeries at once.
Her heart was already
weak to begin with.
It may never restart.
Even if it does restart,
she may never wake up.
Please clear.
Sinus rhythm.
Look at that.
That's a win for now.
I'm going to give you a
pass on how you behaved
because I know
how upset you are.
But I certainly won't forget.
It's all you.
Conrad.
Dr. Moore, how we doing?
Your organ is perfect.
The timing is
practically a miracle.
Hey.
- We have a liver.
- Incredible.
Tyler is still down here.
They had no beds in the ICU.
All right, we'll send him
up to the OR now. Let's go.
Take good care of her.
How is she?
Uh... alive.
We fixed the valve.
Her heart's beating,
but beyond that?
I don't know if I'm gonna
be okay if she's not.
You want to see the baby?
♪ ♪
Hey. How's it going?
So far so good.
Three more hours
and you're official.
That first day you told
me, "Go be a doctor
or go be something else."
Yeah, I remember.
And you said this is
the best job in the world,
despite everything.
Because of everything.
That day I watched
a young girl die.
And today I watch good
doctors save a young man's life.
And right now all
I am thinking is...
what a privilege it
is to be a part of it.
Dr. Cain still in surgery?
Uh, I don't know.
He was in OR Two.
Where is Dr. Cain?
Uh, he left 15 minutes ago.
Who are you?
I'm his resident.
- Uh...
- What's going on?
- Page Dr. Cain.
- What is going on? Talk to me.
I lost control of the bypass,
can't stop the bleeding.
He's losing
perfusion to his brain.
Page any attending.
I need help now.
Hang on, I'm coming in!
- What's happening?
- I can't finish the patch. The artery's shredding.
Take a deep breath.
I'm not kidding.
Take a deep breath. Do what
I say and this will be all right.
There's blood everywhere.
I've only done
this in-in a sim lab.
First we need to
see the field. Suction.
Now I'm gonna help you get
proximal and distal control.
- All right.
- Grab the vessel clamps
and put them
- where my fingers are.
- All right.
- Do you see that?
- Yeah, right there.
Okay, good. Now what?
Um, reinforce the patch.
Uh-huh. Do it.
Bajwa here. Dr. Cain
left the hospital.
He did what?
It's gonna have to
wait. I got an urgent text.
Yeah, don't worry,
it's been handled.
- By whom?
- Yeah... by me and Dr. Bajwa,
who happened to be on deck.
I've been a surgeon a long time.
I've seen attendings
come in drunk,
I've seen 'em fall asleep
from sheer exhaustion.
I've seen incompetence
and heroics and everything
in between, but this
defies description.
Your patient nearly died, you
left him wide open on the table.
You want an attaboy
for saving one life?
I save dozens every day,
hundreds by the week.
- Get over it.
- Do you save them
or manage not to kill them?
Wheeling a patient with
a blown brain into the ICU
and hooking them up to a vent
is not a life-saving procedure.
- It's abusive.
- Oh.
Look who's talking.
One glass of ten-year-old
bourbon and your residents
cannot wait to share the
tales of the mighty HODAD.
Hands of Death and Destruction.
That is what they
call you, isn't it?
Patients dead after a
routine appendectomy,
catching fire in the OR?
Yeah, I've made
mistakes, but I was there.
With my staff in the
OR, not off joyriding
while my patients
were left incapacitated.
I have saved the lives
of kings and princesses
from every corner of this world.
They worship me.
They want to name
their children after me.
They will never forget who I am.
- But it seems that you have.
- No.
You're the one who's
forgotten who I am:
chief of surgery and your boss.
You will answer to the board.
Yeah? What do you think?
Wow. Nic let you out
of the house like that?
What are you doing?
I've gotten a free sandwich
here ever since I started.
- These guys love me.
- Is that right?
Let me guess, fried egg.
Yeah. How'd you know that?
They like you,
but they don't
like you that much.
Have you been buying
my lunch this whole time?
Yeah. Something my resident
did for me. It's a tradition.
You just pay it forward,
do the same for your intern.
It's a way to say thank you
for all the hard
work they put in.
Last one. Better enjoy it.
Listen.
I want you to know that...
I do know.
Hey, I want to
show you something.
- You mean...
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Wow.
- Congratulations.
- Aah!
I haven't... asked her yet.
I just have to find
the right moment.
- She needs to say yes.
- Oh, she will.
You guys are inevitable.
No, I know how I feel about Nic.
That's never changed.
It never will change.
She's everything.
- Hi.
Oh, no, no.
Come on.
How's Mina?
Rumpled and grumpy.
She slept in a chair by
Adaku's side last night.
And Adaku?
Critical.
She's intubated and sedated.
It's gonna be a long road ahead.
She'll be in the
hospital for a while.
The baby, on the other hand,
might be able to
go home in a week.
With Mina.
Wow, that's a scary thought.
Ho...
I'm sorry... for earlier.
The things I said.
But I was not wrong.
If we had taken her
to surgery first thing...
Mina, stop.
Taking care of her was my job.
Look, I get it.
It's been a rough 24
hours for everybody.
And you have another
challenge ahead of you now.
She's just so small.
The surgery went perfectly.
We're hopeful
for a full recovery.
That's wonderful.
How you feeling?
I've been better,
but I can't complain.
Still here, right?
I know I have you
to thank for that.
Well, the person we
have to thank is the donor.
He gave you a
very precious gift.
Look, I promise I
learned my lesson.
I'm not gonna make
that mistake again, okay?
I'd like to be sure of that.
I want you to start by
being honest with your mom.
- I can't do that.
- No, no, no, no.
It's okay. It's important.
She needs to know.
And this is why... I want
you to get counseling.
You need to talk to
someone about why you tried
to take your own life to make
sure it doesn't happen again.
Are you sure the transplant
surgeon heard you?
Positive.
- What did he say?
- Nothing.
He walked away
without speaking to me.
Okay, this is bad.
Well, maybe, maybe not.
We don't know if
he'll tell anyone.
The surgery's done,
the outcome is good.
They can't turn back the clock.
This shouldn't even be an issue.
There are no
guidelines from UNOS
telling transplant centers
whether to give organs to
someone who attempted suicide.
Transplant protocol varies
from hospital to hospital.
If Tyler had gone
to Atlanta General,
they would have approved
the transplant surgery
with virtually no
questions asked, but...
Chastain doesn't work that way.
So what do we do now?
Behave as if nothing happened.
Where's the board? I
requested a meeting.
Your request was denied.
Well, you can't do that.
It's in the hospital charter.
The chief of surgery
may request...
You've been stripped
of that title, Dr. Bell.
What'd you say?
Dr. Cain is Chastain's
new chief of surgery.
All future requests
will go through him.
♪ ♪
Randolph, I heard.
Are you all right?
Tending to my first love.
Putting my affections
where they stand a chance
of being returned.
Will you leave Chastain?
I won't give 'em
the satisfaction.
And if they fire me, they will
owe me a substantial sum.
But they will fire me.
You know how the pressure
drops before a storm,
and you're not aware of
it in any conscious way,
but you know
something is changing?
I finalized your
paperwork last night.
You have a five-year
contract, ironclad.
I don't know what to say.
Just be what you
are, a great surgeon.
All right, everybody, can I
have your attention, please?
Let's welcome our
new chief resident,
Dr. Conrad Hawkins.
Speech!
Oh, yeah.
If Devon wants a speech,
he's gonna get a speech.
Keys to the palace.
Got your own office, a
call room with a shower.
- Ooh.
- She's all yours.
Thank you, thank you.
We'll see if you're all
still clapping for me when
I'm busting your asses
first thing in the morning.
- Did you meet your interns yet?
- No.
I don't know anything about 'em.
- Nice coat, Hawkins.
- Thank you.
Not that it matters much.
I was never chief resident.
Look at me now.
So, I hear
your office has a
brand-new 72-inch flat-screen
and an Xbox.
You got time for Call of Duty?
- Oh, yeah, let's make it happen.
- All right.
- Just the man I was looking for!
- Aah!
I can use the new shower, right?
Anytime, anytime.
Hey, how about me?
Ah, not a chance.
What, the free fried
egg sandwiches
- weren't enough for you?
- Mm...
This is impressive.
I've never had my
name on a door.
Let me try.
Maybe they haven't
programmed it yet.
Dr. Hawkins.
Uh, I'll-I'll take
that. Thank you.
You lied to the, the
transplant board.
We don't give organs to
patients who are suicidal.
Wait, Tyler's not suicidal.
It was a stupid mistake.
Am I talking to you?
You're fired.
Ah, that rule's arbitrary
and you know it.
You don't care
about Tyler Warzel,
you care that I'm
a whistleblower.
That's what this is about.
Huh? I blew the whistle
on a bad drug, and you're
afraid for your bottom line.
You're afraid of me.
And you should be.
Security will escort you out.
Give me your pager.
Thank you.
- What's going on?
- They're firing Conrad.
- You can't do this.
- Whoa, whoa.
- Get your hands off me.
- Hey, hey, hey, hey!
It's okay, it's okay.
Then I'll quit, too.
No, you'll stay here.
I'll see you tonight.
♪ ♪
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH