Hi. Name?
Dr. Carter.
Somebody should
have called ahead.
Okay. All the
information is confidential,
and you can have
a seat over there.
Thank you. Mm-hm.
Ninety days? This is a
three-month program?
Yeah, I guess so.
Can you send me some clothes?
Or do they issue
prison garb here?
You okay?
This pen doesn't work.
Do you have a pen?
He's diaphoretic, cramping.
We'll take care of it.
When? Soon.
He's got tremors.
He needs something.
You should go now.
What?
It's important that
he checks himself in.
Right. Mm-hm.
Here.
You, uh... You good from here?
Yeah, I guess so.
Carter, you can do this.
Hey, you got any Compazine?
I'll give you something after
group if you're still nauseous.
Group?
Yeah. Group therapy.
When is that? Now.
In the middle of the night?
The entire group meets
whenever a new patient arrives.
Ready?
No, I need to lie down.
You'll make it.
Group therapy is not
what I need right now.
If you want to be in the
program, you do the program.
Otherwise, you can leave.
And when you want a fix,
you can score down
on 10th and Piedmont.
Which is six blocks
down, one block over.
Those guys are
out there all night.
John Carter?
Yes.
Security!
I put the needle down!
I said no needles!
I told you to put
him in restraints.
I did.
Lily, get extra
security down here.
On their way. Give him Haldol!
The toilet's clogged. Unclog it.
No plunger. Maintenance
closet's locked.
Hey, Malucci, what is
Mr. Hunter still doing out here?
Transpo's backed up.
Their guys are out
to support the janitors.
Then you take him down yourself.
Can't we give them their raise?
Yeah, I'll recommend you
for the negotiating committee.
What about the
maintenance closet?
Use some initiative.
Pick the lock.
Take a fire ax
to it. I don't care.
Okay.
Oh, my God.
Can somebody please put
Mr. Spencer in an Exam Room?
Excuse me. What?
We've been waiting
here for a while.
Shouldn't we be doing something?
Any plumbing experience?
What happened?
You know what, Mark, just
don't start with me, okay?
What?
Custodial staff is on strike.
So they had to
destroy the admit desk?
This is a remodel.
Open floor plan.
It's supposed to be safer.
I've already scratched
myself on a nail twice.
Make sure you
update your tetanus.
Where are my fans?
Working on it.
What's the deal?
I don't know.
The construction workers
won't cross the picket line.
You mean those three
guys I saw with signs?
Mark, how was your vacation?
It was good.
You go anywhere?
Wisconsin Dells. Camping.
I just drove back this morning.
Where's the board
supposed to go?
Don't ask.
They weren't supposed
to take out this wall.
And we're not
supposed to talk about it.
Cleo, you got that covered?
Yeah.
I hate needles!
Hi, Dr. Greene. Hey.
Is it me, or do
those med students
look like 12-year-olds?
How long they been waiting?
Three hours.
Two and a half.
I'll take 'em.
Be my guest. But make
sure you see some patients.
Malik? What?
Malik.
Strong, steady heartbeat.
The amount of
amniotic fluid is normal.
Everything looks fine.
I've got a good angle here
if you wanna know the sex.
Sure.
You are having a boy.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Your, um, blood-sugar
level is normal.
But you're a little anemic.
You taking any iron? Yes.
You arrange with Kerry
to take some time off
after the baby's born?
Oh, um, no, not yet.
You still have time.
Actually, I haven't
told anyone yet.
I think you may want to.
I don't see how you can
keep this a secret much longer.
Yeah.
So, what are you
supposed to talk about
in an exit interview anyway?
That you don't
have all the answers.
No argument there.
You scared?
I don't remember the
last time I wasn't scared.
Good.
What, that's it?
"Be afraid. Be very afraid"?
We're like the Army, okay?
We break you down, make
you face your addiction,
then we build you up.
You start to function.
Feel healthy, confident.
Don't worry. Pride's
what got me into this.
Yeah. And deep down,
you feel like this is something
that just happened
to you, right?
No, I took responsibility.
I take responsibility.
But I'm gonna get my life back.
It's not gonna beat me.
Yeah, that's what I thought.
First three times.
But I hope you do.
Day or night.
If you ever need to talk.
Are we done?
You're just getting started.
Is this where I'm
supposed to say thank you?
Some people do.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Someone's still on
vacation time I see.
Sorry. That's all right.
Peter was just helping me
hang this straight. How's that?
Great. Yeah.
Did you finish the interview?
We're just getting there.
Okay, so where were we
before we left off last time?
You were just about
to give me the job.
Developing a sense
of humor, Peter?
That's progress.
You get points for that.
Uh, why don't we discuss
faculty responsibilities?
Peter, as an Attending,
you'd be responsible
for supervising
Resident research.
I look forward to that.
Liar.
I like working with Residents.
You mean you like abusing them.
You don't have the
best track record
in the research department.
That can change.
Uh-huh. Where else
have you applied?
What?
Where else did you apply?
You can't ask me that.
Oh, no. Someone call
the interview police.
Has anyone offered you anything?
You're not supposed
to ask me that either.
Come on, it's a simple question.
I've looked elsewhere
as a backup.
But I'd like to stay
here as an Attending.
Okay. Was that so difficult?
Elizabeth, what are you doing?
Uh, my hands itch
for some reason.
Cut it out. It's distracting.
Linear vesicles. Probably
a phytodermatitis.
Are you allergic to any plants?
I don't think so.
You have a garden?
I went camping.
Tell me you know what
poison ivy looks like.
Poison ivy? Is
that in Wisconsin?
Oh, boy. Sorry,
Peter, I gotta run.
We'll have to finish this later.
When?
My office will reschedule.
Good luck with that, Lizzie.
He's never gonna
give me this job.
Of course, he will.
He's just being Robert.
Don't scratch. Put some
hydrocortisone TID on it.
If it gets worse, get
a shot of steroids.
It won't spread, will it?
Well, that depends on
what you touched last
before you washed your hands.
Oh, dear.
These are your
orientation packets.
You guys have a seat over
there and read them over, okay?
Then we'll give you the tour.
We'll go over charts,
order sheets and
discharge instructions.
Any questions?
Remember, you're students.
The only stupid question
is the one you don't ask.
Dr. Greene? Well,
I have a question.
What?
Something wrong with
the Australian boys?
Who? You're
scratching down under.
Oh, yeah. Doesn't make
a good first impression.
Pickman, what do you got?
Mike Palmieri,
17. Wide receiver.
Got hi-lowed in
midair. Brief LOC.
Complains of neck
and chest pains.
Can he move extremities?
Yeah, but because of
the numbness in the hands
we left the helmet on.
Give the med students the tour.
I gave it last rotation.
Well, then you're
getting good at it.
Okay, Mike, I'm Dr. Greene.
Can you squeeze both my hands?
My neck's not broken, is it?
Now we're gonna check you out.
Mike, does your chest hurt?
A little.
The safety speared
me with his helmet
on the way down.
He's tachy at 120. BP's 110/68.
Good breath sounds bilaterally.
It's illegal. Second
play of the game.
Let's get him on a pulse ox.
They were looking
to take me out.
Who's that? The other team?
They're our rivals.
It's their homecoming.
You want to push any drugs?
Sure. One amp of epi
and a mg of atropine.
Does she have a pulse?
Oh, she's dead. I know.
Like, blue dead.
Pulse ox, 65.
That's because she's dead.
Her husband drove her in.
Oh, right.
Luka, you okay in here?
Yeah, I've got it.
Still asystole.
As long as we're faking it,
can one of the med
students practice CPR?
No. Go outside and tell him
we are doing everything we can
but his wife is very sick.
She can't get any sicker.
Malucci, please. Go on.
Go on. Give the poor man
some time to prepare himself.
No problem, chief.
I can act with the best of 'em.
Watch this.
Still flat line. Want
to do a fluid bolus?
No, that's okay.
Abby? Abby!
Yeah?
The registrar didn't put
your name on my roster.
You sure you're
back on ER rotation?
That's what my schedule says.
Okay. They must be backed
up because of the strike.
Checking out? Yeah.
Dr. Benton called
to confirm your flight
and said he'd pick
you up at the gate.
Thanks.
Goodbye, Margaret.
Good luck, Dr. Carter.
Where did he go?
He was in the hallway
with Malucci a minute ago.
Here's her medication.
I forgot it in the car.
She's on Elavil, and
codeine for arthritis.
Have a seat, Mr. Bristo.
You don't need these?
Mr. Bristo, your
wife has suffered
a massive heart attack.
We exhausted all medical
resources available to us.
But the damage to her heart
was beyond our
capabilities to save her.
She died, Mr. Bristo. I'm sorry.
You see? I should have
called the ambulance sooner.
I should have gotten
her here quicker.
There's nothing you
could have done differently
that would have saved her.
It was just her time.
Would you like to see her?
Okay.
How was I supposed to know?
Excuse us. Sorry.
Haven't you ever heard of
"leaves of three, let it be"?
What?
"Leaves of three, let it
be." As in don't touch.
Sorry. We don't have
poison ivy in England.
"Leaves of three"
or any other kind.
Oh, man. Let me see.
No, no. Mark, don't be shy.
You've done enough damage.
Well, do you have it?
Yes, I have it.
Who picks poison ivy?
I was making a
wildflower bouquet.
C-spine's back on
the football player.
Thanks.
When you went skinny-dipping
in the lake, I got bored.
You remember what
happened after you got out?
Yeah. It's a big price to pay.
Mark.
I have to worry about
where you've been?
It's not that horrible.
Yeah, you've only
got it on your hands.
Mike, x-ray is normal.
His mom's here, out in Chairs.
Okay. Why don't you get
off the helmet and pads
and I'll be right back?
Does that mean I can go?
Not yet.
So do you want the
cream or the shot?
Probably both.
Fine. I'll get them.
Mrs. Palmieri?
Yes?
Hi. I'm Dr. Mark
Greene. Good news.
Mike's neck x-ray
came back normal.
No fractures or swelling.
Why were his hands numb?
He was hyperventilating.
That can cause
a little numbness.
But no nerve damage?
No. No broken bones,
no spinal-cord
injury, no paralysis.
Thank you. Thank
you. Can I see him?
Sure. Here you go.
What's your name again?
Priya Shailendra.
Do you remember
where Trauma 1 is?
I think so.
Could you take Mrs. Palmieri?
Certainly.
This way, please.
Malucci?
Hey, Dr. Greene.
How's that jock itch?
I told you to supervise
the med students.
You told me to give
them the tour. I did.
Show them the charting system.
I'm juggling eight
patients here.
Have them help you.
Hold this.
Hey, Cleo. You're up
with the med students.
Says who? Dr. Greene.
Then Dr. Greene can ask me.
It's not infected, Mr. Fletcher,
but I'm gonna have
to débride it again.
No. Leave it alone.
Well, I would if you
changed the dressing
four times a day
like I told you.
I'm not a damn nurse.
How'd it go?
It didn't. Romano postponed.
Again? What's wrong with him?
He's a maniacal sadist.
What did you call me?
Not you, Mr. Fletcher.
Is this machine working?
I feel like I'm drowning.
It takes longer when
you're fluid-overloaded.
Happens when you're
three days late for dialysis.
I told you my son
didn't have time
to drive me to the clinic.
What's wrong with this picture?
Those med students.
Not a black face in the bunch.
That doesn't concern you?
I see five. Not exactly a
representative sample.
Glad you take such
an active interest.
You're gonna have to hold
your foot still, Mr. Fletcher.
She your wife?
Hm? No. No, no, no, no.
She talk like she your wife.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
Brought you a chair, Mr. Bristo.
Someone will be by
to take her downstairs
but it could take a while.
Do you have a funeral
home you'd like to use?
I could call them.
We have two plots.
But Florence took care
of it. I forget the name.
Okay, well, if you remember...
Can I stay with her?
As long as you like.
It was very decent of you
to work on his wife like that.
Part of the job.
Well, no. I mean,
he's really shaken.
It could be a lot worse if he
thought he was responsible.
He does.
He's alive, she's not.
Wonder how long
they were married.
I don't know. Forever, probably.
How long have you?
What?
Been married.
I'm not.
I thought someone told
me you were married.
I was. But my... My divorce
became final last month.
Sorry.
Don't be. I'm not.
Lockhart, is that
your name or his?
It's his. But I'm keeping it
because it's the only
good thing I got out of it.
Why? What was your name before?
Wyczenski.
Right. Lockhart is better.
Have you seen Dr. Greene?
Suture Room, I think.
Oh, Dr. Weaver's
looking for you.
Me?
Yeah.
Dr. Greene... Sorry. Sorry.
That's okay, Haleh.
Just getting a shot.
I didn't say anything.
What's up?
Mike Palmieri is
having trouble breathing.
Complained of chest pains
when we removed the pads.
All right. I'll be right there.
You done?
All done.
Keep laughing, flower girl.
You're welcome.
Thanks a lot.
Mike, how's your breathing?
A little sore.
Okay. Tell me if this hurts.
BP's stable.
115/70. Satting at 98.
There.
Okay. Any belly pain?
No.
Are you sure?
A little. Okay.
Haleh, book a CT.
And let's sit him up.
Where's your mom, Mike?
She went to check
on the score for me.
If we're losing, I
need to get back.
We need to take another
picture of your chest and belly
just to make sure
everything's okay.
How long does that take?
Relax, Mike.
You're gonna be
with us for a while.
Mrs. Palmieri?
What happened?
Nothing serious. Mike
might have a broken rib.
And I need a CAT
scan just to make sure
that it didn't nick his liver.
His liver? What...?
What does that mean?
Well, it all depends.
But it's really a
remote possibility.
I just wanna make sure.
I knew something like
this was gonna happen.
I hate that he plays
football. I hate it.
But it keeps his grades up.
He's not a great student
but he has to keep good
grades to play so I let him play.
I'm sure everything
is gonna be just fine.
I'll check back with
you after the scan.
Chen?
Chen! Yes.
You okay? Yeah. Great.
Can you find Dr. Corday
and have her meet me in CT?
Uh-huh. No problem.
BP, 136/88. Pulse, 125.
They nailed me after the
play. Refs didn't even call it.
Draw up some Demerol.
Open tibial fracture.
Titrate 100, slow IV push.
55. That's the number
of the guy who hit Mike.
It was a clean hit.
GSW on the way.
Crashing in the rig.
Frank. What's open?
Stiff in Trauma 2. Other
than that we're booked.
Clear it. Take this guy.
Got it.
You led with your helmet.
You're not supposed to.
Ma'am, wait in Chairs.
It was an accident.
It was a cheap shot.
What do you call breaking
my leg on purpose?
Payback!
Thank you.
Sir? Sir?
Oh, thank you.
Can I get a gin
and tonic, please?
Anything for you, sir?
No, thank you.
From Atlanta or Chicago?
Chicago.
Atlanta on business?
No.
Vacation?
I was just visiting a friend.
So, what do you do for a living?
I'm a teacher.
High school English.
Wow. And you fly first class?
They must pay teachers
pretty well in Chicago.
Excuse me.
Mr. Bristo?
They needed the room.
Oh, okay. Well, don't worry.
We'll find her another room.
Are they coming to get her?
Yeah. Soon. They're coming soon.
Lost the pulse!
Starting compressions.
What's on the monitor?
P.E.A.
Amp of epi.
Squeeze in the blood.
Malucci has an assaulted
cheerleader coming.
Bat to the face.
Okay. Get Mark.
He's in CT. Got a pulse.
Increase dopamine.
Get him up to the O.R.
You finished in the Trauma Room?
Yeah. Abby, I'm glad I saw you.
I need to talk to you.
Somebody find Kovac, please?!
This man's wife died.
We told him he could wait
until Transpo picks her up.
We'll lean on them.
I checked with the
medical-school registrar and...
Out of the way!
They retracted your clerkship...
What?!
Is that from the
football game too?
Yeah, someone jumped
her in the bathroom.
Dr. Weaver?
Something about
delinquent tuition.
My ex-husband was supposed
to pay that. I apologize.
No need to apologize.
I'll get it paid by tomorrow.
You don't understand.
You need to go home.
You're not covered to work.
I'll work it out
with the registrar...
Once a clerkship
is pulled, it's pulled.
Nothing I can do. You have
to wait till the next quarter.
In three months?
Sorry. Dean's decision.
We got a blown pupil!
Turn in your lab coat to Frank.
Heart rate's dropping.
Okay. Prep for an intubation.
Hang the mannitol. 40 of
Lasix. She needs a Foley.
Give me some gloves,
somebody! Move!
Pressure's sky-high. 180/120.
Bolus her with 100 of
lidocaine, 75 of sux...
What's this for?
Sorry. Sorry.
Abby, what's wrong? Abby?
Abby?
You got cleaned up.
Looks good. Thank you.
I'd choose the
fish if I were you.
The steak looks, uh, ugh.
I'm not hungry.
Excuse me, Dr. Carter.
Were you smoking
in the lavatory?
Yes.
Then you're in
violation of federal law,
punishable by a $2000
fine and imprisonment.
Do I need to have the
marshals at the gate?
No. It won't happen again.
Do you have the butt with you?
All right then.
Doctor, huh?
Mrs. Palmieri?
What is it?
Apparently, the blow
to Michael's chest
caused a little
internal bleeding.
Some of it in the sac
surrounding his heart.
Oh, God. That sounds serious.
It can be, but right now
there's only a small amount.
But we need to operate
to drain the blood
before it restricts function.
Open-heart surgery?
No. We go through
the upper abdomen,
very small incision.
It's a really simple
procedure. I just need you to...
Now?
I just need you to
sign the consent.
You're gonna do the surgery now?
Right now Mike's blood pressure
is stable, which is a good sign.
But more blood could accumulate.
We need to do the
operation immediately
to avoid an emergency
procedure down here.
You just need the
one signature, right?
I... I couldn't find his
father if I wanted to.
One is enough. All right.
What's the emergency? I'm here.
I didn't call you.
Robert.
If you're gonna leave
messages with my assistant,
don't also page me.
It gets annoyingly redundant.
Sorry to inconvenience
you, Robert,
but we have a real
crisis down here.
Yeah? And?
And it's become a health hazard.
If somebody calls the
county, we'll be fined.
But someone's not going
to call the county, is she?
Look, Robert, housekeeping
won't clean any sheets or towels.
I need the nurses here.
It's not their job
anyway to be doing...
What do you want me
to say? Troubleshoot.
It's called being a manager.
You need to end
this strike, Robert.
Find me the half-million
a year it'll take
to meet their demands, I will.
Peter, keeping banker's hours?
I've been on since 5.
Well, you got a sec?
I gotta go pick up somebody...
Let's finish this. What?
The interview. Walk with me.
What about Elizabeth?
I let her sit in to make
her feel important.
It's my decision.
Let's talk turkey.
I know you've got
the surgical skills.
I don't question that.
I do, however,
question your loyalty.
My loyalty lies
with my patients.
As it should. But don't
take this the wrong way
you have a real propensity
for being a pain in the ass.
I'm not gonna jump
you, you homophobe.
Damn janitors!
You should try paying them.
You see? That's
exactly my point.
Instead of trying to
understand my problems
you immediately
champion the opposition.
The janitors?
Whoever. Peter, look.
If I'm gonna give
you a faculty position,
I've gotta be sure you're
gonna be part of the team.
My team.
Of course. Of course what?
Of course I'll be
a part of the team.
Then I can expect
your full commitment?
No whining, no complaining
no excuses about your
kid or your cat or whatever?
I don't have a cat.
Splendid. You're hired.
Congratulations.
You are a free man,
delivered from the shackles of
your residency and fellowship.
Dry your hands first.
Yeah, right.
Oh, well. Wasn't me.
You selfish son of a bitch.
Well, hello, Abby.
Is this fun for you?
Or is it like an addiction?
Do you wake up thinking:
"How am I gonna
screw Abby today?"
Okay. What's the problem?
I lost three months of
school I can't make up
three months that put me exactly
one year behind on my residency.
This is about your tuition.
Yes, it's about my tuition.
Calm down. I was gonna call you.
The IRS disallowed our
'97 home-office deduction.
I don't want one
more lame excuse...
Call the IRS. They were
gonna hit us with a huge penalty.
This was important to me.
And you knew it,
so you ruined it.
Can you be more dramatic?
I put you through med school.
You were gonna put me...
You did not put me
through med school.
My student loans put
me through med school.
I only fed, clothed,
sheltered you.
Loans I'm still paying,
along with a house,
your condo and two cars.
And the apartment for the whore.
I assume you're
cheating on the whore.
All right, just stop it.
You stop it.
Haven't you done enough already?
I didn't make you unhappy,
depressed and miserable.
You did that all by yourself.
Screw you, Richard.
Right. Screw me.
That's right. Screw you.
Screw me. Screw you!
You're the one who wanted more.
You're a manipulative,
cheating, spineless...
You decided to change your life.
Spiteful ass!
Are you done? No.
You're in violation of
our divorce agreement.
I am hiring a lawyer and I
am getting my tuition money.
Hell, Abby, do me a favor.
Why don't you take it all?
Take the debt with it.
Shut up, jag-off.
Hey, Nat.
Hey, Dr. Benton.
Still plugging away?
You know it.
What are you doing?
Go around the other
way, would you?
Yeah. Nat, I'm late, man.
The news is here.
All right, brother. Good luck.
Thanks.
Chen?
I'm on break.
Right.
You all right?
Yeah. Yeah.
Good, you're still here.
We got a mass "cas" coming in.
Riot at a high
school football game.
I was just leaving...
Not anymore.
Blunt abdominal trauma.
BP's low at 90 palp.
Give two liters of saline.
What happened? Bleachers fell.
Give two units O-neg.
Draw pre-op labs.
Ultrasound? You bet.
Also, page me if
anything changes.
All right, go.
Drop an NG, check his
urine, shoot a chest and pelvis.
Sorry.
The game was too ugly.
Refs called it before the end.
And everybody just
started swinging.
You okay, Cleo? Yeah.
Doc. They need you.
Damn kids jumped a
teacher in the parking lot.
Head trauma, maybe
a collapsed lung.
Short of breath. BP
110/70. Pulse 120.
Mitch, do you have
any pain in your chest?
It hurts.
Titrate another six of morphine.
Page Ortho and Vascular.
Elizabeth, what
are you doing here?
I thought you'd be operating.
Mitch? What happened?
They're backed up.
Rooms are empty but filthy
because of this work stoppage.
Really? You doing okay?
They gotta operate. But who won?
Where are we going?
Nobody.
Try an exam room.
Get an EKG, chest x-ray,
and find me when
the femur film's up.
How long before
you get into O.R.?
The nurses are cleaning
but there's a leaking
triple-A going first.
We're gonna keep him down here
and do a pericardiocentesis.
All this so Housekeeping
doesn't get an extra dollar an hour.
I don't need the
operation anymore?
You just have to
wait a little longer.
Hang in there, Mike.
You chucked my guy with
your helmet. Don't whine.
Hold still. You
did it on purpose.
You want some more?
Hold still or I'll put
you in restraints.
What did they hit you with?
The pavement.
Frank. Frank, what's open?
Nothing. Nothing's open.
I can't believe this. I
mean, it's just a game.
Is the nurse taking me up?
We're gonna have to drain
some of the blood down here.
You said he was going
straight to Surgery.
But it can take a while to prep
and drape and anesthetize him.
His cardiac echo shows
the effusion's grown...
Crush injury at 70 palp,
despite a fluid bolus.
Respiratory status?
Intubated for
agonal respirations.
Two units of O-neg
on the rapid infuser.
Set up a supraumbilical
peritoneal lavage.
I'm never gonna leave.
Pulse 140. Satted at 92.
Hey, med student,
what's your name?
Ryan. Ryan Bradford.
Ryan, get over here. I
need your help. Move!
That's not so bad.
This is the little needle to
numb you for the big needle.
Oh.
But you're a tough
guy. You can take it.
BP's 90.
I can't believe all
this started over me.
You're a popular guy.
He looks so pale.
Mrs. Palmieri, perhaps
you should wait outside
during the actual procedure.
I can't stay?
I'm okay, Mom.
Just a little tired.
Haleh?
This way, ma'am.
I love you.
I love you too, Mom.
Alligator clip.
He's in tamponade, Mark.
I know. Mike, how
are you feeling?
Pulse ox down to 78.
Mike?
Mike? Mike, open your eyes.
8-0 ET tube. I'll intubate.
He's still breathing.
Not for long.
Just keep an eye
on the injury current.
Just get that needle in.
Dr. Carter? Are you Dr. Carter?
Yeah.
I'm Ryan Bradford.
I'm a third-year.
The ER got slammed
and Dr. Benton
asked me to come
down, pick you up.
Oh, great.
Need a hand with that?
No, no. I got it.
Okay. Right this way.
Where you going?
Pre-op. He needs an ex-lap.
There's no room.
He's stable. He
can wait upstairs.
What's his BP? BP's 140/60.
All right. Grab the
head injury in 3.
All right. Malik. You got this?
Yeah, I got it. Go on.
Hey, sir?
Sir, are you all right? Sir?
Malik. I need a gurney now.
Oh, my God. Malik.
You. Come here. What'd I do?
Help me move this
man. Now. Come on.
Sats are up to 92.
You want me to try?
No. He has weird anatomy.
I have to go more anterior.
I should be there.
Run of five. Pull back.
Pressure's dropping down to 70.
Give him another
liter of saline.
Look at the monitor.
Profound ST elevation.
Damn it. He's having an MI.
More PVCs.
A hundred of lidocaine.
You must have transected
the coronary artery.
No, no, no, no, no.
It's a known complication.
You went in blind.
Prep the chest.
He should be upstairs right now.
Mark.
Thoracotomy tray.
What happened?
He swallowed a whole pharmacy.
I found empty bottles of
Elavil, codeine and lorazepam.
Did you give him Narcan?
Yeah. Two mgs times two.
Sats are dropping.
Resps eight and shallow.
Add an amp of bicarb.
Chem-7, CBC and a tox screen.
Yeah, I'm in. Who's Florence?
What?
Well, the pills say "Florence."
His wife. She
died this afternoon.
Pericardium's tight
as a drum. Metz.
Okay. Start internal
compressions.
Need suction in here.
We've got a crowd.
Someone close the blinds.
Can you see anything?
Sponge stick.
Right there.
Laceration of the L.A.D.
Can you repair it?
Not without bypass.
You got to do something.
I am not losing him.
Right. Open some
sterile IV tubing.
The blinds, now.
I don't know how you
guys do it every day.
It's pretty intense.
You sure get to do a lot.
You know, you
just jump right in.
I was interested in surgery.
But I don't know.
Maybe the ER's my thing.
I guess if today's
any indication,
there's never a
dull moment, huh?
Yeah, right.
Tubing's in. There.
Hold compressions.
He's in V-fib.
Charge internal paddles to 15.
Charging.
Clear.
Still in V-fib.
Charge to 30.
Haleh.
Clear.
Another amp of epi.
Charge again.
50 of lidocaine.
Start a drip at two per minute.
Clear!
Still in Torsade.
Three-sixty. Magnesium on board?
That's four grams.
Isuprel's pouring in.
Clear.
Asystole.
It's the tricyclics. We'll
never get a rhythm back.
Maybe we could
try overdrive pacing.
No. He's been down too long.
That's it. Time of death, 19:54.
Take him downstairs.
Make sure he's
put beside his wife.
You guys done?
I've got stab
wounds to the thigh.
Yeah, we are done.
Come on, Mike. Come on.
How many units of blood?
Six so far.
The heart's filling well.
He's not hypovolemic.
When was the last epi?
Three minutes.
He's had two of atropine?
Both amps are in.
Someone should prep the mother.
Dopamine's wide open?
For the last five minutes.
Son of a bitch. Mark.
Let's keep going.
You want me to talk to her?
No. I should do it.
Chen.
Can you come take
over chest compressions?
Okay. Let's go again
with the paddles.
Charge to 30.
Clear.
Hey, man, what's going on?
Is he dying?
What's happening
to him? Hey, come on.
He's our friend.
Someone said you
had to shock him.
Is that true?
We've had some complications.
What kind of complications?
The needle poked
a hole in the artery
that supplies the blood
and oxygen to Mike's heart
which caused him
to have a heart attack.
We opened up his
chest to repair the artery.
But his heart has been
deprived of oxygen for too long
and it wasn't beating.
Oh, my God.
We're giving him
intravenous drugs
and shocking his heart.
There's been no response.
What does that mean?
What does that mean?!
We might not get him back.
What? He could die.
But you said that this
was a simple procedure,
that he would be fine.
That he would sail through this.
I know. I know, Mrs. Palmieri.
This is an exceedingly
rare complication.
I don't care. I don't care.
You fix him.
You fix my son!
We'll try. No.
But...
You promised me.
I have to go back.
Is he gonna be all right?
We're working on him.
You gotta give us room.
Everybody back
up. Back up, guys.
Let the doctor through.
Still in V-fib.
Sats are dropping.
Carotid pulse with compressions.
Clear.
Anything? No.
Again. How long
are we going to go?
Until I say stop.
Clear.
We're out of epi.
Chen, I want you
to go get some epi.
Sure.
Crash cart Curtain 3.
Clear.
Excuse me.
The doctor told Mike's
mom he was gonna die.
Hey.
Malucci!
You okay?
Stop it. Let it go!
Let it go! Stop it!
Break it up.
Break it up. Get off.
Security. We've got
a problem down here!
What is going on out there?
I don't know. They
just started fighting.
Clear.
Chen, are you okay? Yeah.
Are you okay?
Mark. Mark. What?
A rhythm. We've got a rhythm.
What's that?
I don't know.
I better get back.
You coming in?
No. I'm gonna go home.
Hey, well, it was
good to meet you.
Thank you.