I said the lap-chole at 11,
the gastric bypass at 3:30.
Yeah.
Have you seen my earring? Nope.
Well, look, why don't
you try to get hold of him
and then call me back?
Yeah.
You're already dressed?
My schedule's all
jumbled up. I need to get in.
Besides, Romano's got
me buried in paperwork.
Oh, there they are.
Oh, come on.
You're going to cover
me in shaving cream.
Hi. Did you get him?
Uh, y-yes, um, hello.
Yes. Uh...
Oh, he's... He is. He's
right here, actually.
It's your father.
Oh. I'm sorry.
Hi, Dad.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, calm down. What?
Wh...? Wh...? What happened?
Wa...? Was anyone hurt?
Is everything all right?
Oh, well, that's good.
Yeah, um... So
this was last night?
Mm-hm.
You need me to stay?
I'll catch you later. Okay.
So, Dad? D-dad, okay, fine.
Look, i-it's just a fender.
Okay, a fender
and a cypress tree.
Oh, you know what?
Um, just cornflakes and a
small orange juice, please.
That's it?
Yeah, there's just
no room left for food.
I'm eating like a horse.
Well, twins. They're
squishing my stomach.
I just have one
squishing more than that.
Meg, I can't read
this. What's this say?
Two over medium.
Large coffee to
go, please. Sure.
Hey, morning, Carol.
Hi.
What?
I think you have shaving cream
on your earlobe.
Oh.
Thank you.
How is Mark?
Clean-shaven.
That's twice in one
morning. Oh, I'm sorry.
Just clean it up.
And get this guy another order.
How are you managing
without coffee?
Oh, you know, it's not so bad.
It's actually the, uh, growing
out of my maternity wear
that's starting to worry me.
Not to worry.
You'll drop a couple
of those pounds breast-feeding.
See you later. Thanks. Bye.
Here. Oh, thank you.
Not easy maneuvering, is it? No.
Do you know what
you're having? No.
Nothing on the ultrasound?
I... I haven't had one.
Oh, you really should.
It's important for the baby.
Who's your OB?
I gotta pick up an order.
You do have an OB?
My boss is gonna
yell at me again, heh.
Can I borrow your
pencil and your pad?
I'm a nurse at County. Mm-hm.
I'm gonna write down my name.
You should come
by after your shift.
We'll examine you
and check out the baby.
I... I don't know. I... I don't
have insurance or anything.
It's okay. Where I
work, you don't need it.
Morning.
Hey, the celebrity herself.
Beg your pardon?
Dr. Corday, right?
Yeah, what are
you talking about?
"Prescription for Danger:
Are You Safe at County General?"
Good picture.
Oh, my God.
Stop it! Stop it! Get
that thing away from me!
Leave me alone! Let go!
Robin, calm down.
This isn't so bad, is it?
I hate you! Robin!
Yosh?
Do you like koala
bears, Robin? Why?
Because I have a special
bear that wants to meet you.
It's Mr. Koala Bear.
- I hate bears!
- Robin, stop it.
Maybe you could you
hold her, Mrs. Bourke?
If you're good,
I'll take you to
the toy store. No!
When did she start vomiting?
This morning, right
after she drank her juice.
Mommy, make them stop!
We had Chinese takeout,
my husband has an
upset... I hate you!
Any diarrhea?
A little.
Childhood illnesses?
Uh, just a few colds.
And prescription medicines,
keep those out of reach?
Yes, our home is
childproof. Okay, okay, okay.
She probably has food poisoning.
I'll give her
Compazine... Let go.
For the nausea.
Robin. I'm sorry.
And observe her for a
couple of hours, okay?
Honey, did you hear that?
We're gonna stay here so
they can take care of you.
I hate it here!
Oh, wait... Okay.
You were looking
for me? Yo, Dr. Pete.
I definitely was.
I've got one seriously
hot appy here for you.
Hot appy? Ready to
be sliced and diced.
Well, then why don't
you call for a consult?
I told you. Thought
you'd want him.
He can't do general surgery.
I don't do general surgery.
Told you. Thank you, Conni.
You're welcome, Dr. Dave.
You know what,
I don't blame you.
Hernias, appys, gallbladders...
It's boring. Am I right?
I think you're like me, man.
You like the guts, the
glory, the bright lights.
We're cut from the same cloth.
Know what "skating
on thin ice" means?
Okay, this is me backin' off.
That's good. Stay up
there as long as you can.
You're doing great.
Kerry, hi. Morning, Gabe.
How much longer?
Uh, the expulsion of flatus
marches to its own
drummer, Mr. Rineberry.
And the more I fart,
the better I'll feel?
Yeah, well,
to put it somewhat
indelicately, yeah.
I... I'll be back.
Stay with her.
Keep your eye on him, okay?
I was just gonna
grab a cup of coffee.
Great, I'll join you.
So you're starting off your day
with a splenic
flexure syndrome, eh?
Guy didn't want to
stand on his head
until I reminded him gas rises.
That seems like you're
settling in well, huh?
Oh, yeah, everybody's
been terrific. Great.
Mark Greene is still
pissing on trees a little...
Do you want me to
say something to him?
Dr. Lawrence? Yeah, Lily? Yeah?
Uh, it's Lucy. Lucy Knight.
Lucy. Sorry. That's okay.
Did you wanna
order the, uh, Oxacillin
for the cellulitis in Four?
Cellulitis in Four. Yeah,
he should have some.
You just didn't sign for it. Oh.
Easily fixed.
Here you go. Thanks.
Sure.
Is it just me, or are
medical students younger
than they used to be?
It's definitely the students.
I... I haven't felt this old
since your class
graduated from med school.
My class? Yeah.
I remember your mom came up to
me and she was thanking me for...
You know, for inspiring you
to go into emergency medicine.
And the whole time she's
talking to me, all I can think is:
"My God, we're
practically the same age."
Oh, no, she had a year
or two on you anyway.
How is she? How is she
doing? She passed away
a couple of years ago.
Oh, I'm sorry.
That's rough. Yeah.
Yeah, it is.
How is your family doing?
Oh, all my ex-wives
are alive and living well.
And your son was going
into medicine too, wasn't he?
No, that was my dream,
not his, as he would say.
Of course, he doesn't say
much of anything to me anymore.
Families, huh? Go figure.
- Get away!
Get away from me!
Sorry. Excuse us.
Think I'll have
more cream. Sure.
I certainly never
meant to convey
any deficiency at County.
I could hardly anticipate
a shootout. Mm-hm.
And not everything in
the account was negative.
I particularly enjoyed the
description of Dr. Carter
clamping off his first aortic
rupture in an 8-year-old.
Yeah, which, as the account
clearly states, was successful.
Do you remember, Lizzie,
the point of this article?
To toot County's horn.
Actually, it was
to toot my horn.
Which is why you understand
that I am disturbed at, uh...
Not only at getting heat
on this from upstairs,
but at, uh, finding my picture
in a sidebar next
to the obituaries.
I'd gladly give
up the front page.
Lizzie, when I appointed
you Associate Chief,
it was for two reasons:
One, to serve. Two, to
protect my needs, my interests.
But I have sensed
some reluctance.
To what?
Corralling Benton, for one.
We've settled that. Oh, have we?
So I haven't made a
mistake in appointing you?
No, Robert, you haven't
made a mistake. Good.
Oh, by the way, there's
been some slop-over
from the Anspaugh
administration.
It seems Donald is still
scheduling his own surgeries.
Speak to him about
that, would you?
You can't be serious.
It's interfering
with my schedule.
I am completely serious.
Dr. Corday. Carter.
Is Elaine Nichols'
path report back yet?
You'll need to speak
to her about that.
Right, of course.
I will when she comes
in to have her sutures out,
which generally is about
a week after surgery?
Generally. And in Elaine's case,
that could be sometime
today. This morning even.
Carter. Or perhaps
this afternoon?
Carter. Yes?
There's some chance it'll be
this afternoon,
say, around 3:00.
Thank you. By the
way, loved the article.
Tommy Stevens. Attempted
suicide by hanging.
Yeah, that makes one
nasty rope burn, huh?
What?
Finish up, Dumar. Vital signs.
BP 80 palp. Pulse
thready. Shallow resp.
I didn't want to intubate
in case he broke his neck.
Okay, everybody, nice
and easy. On my count:
One, two, three.
He's gettin' dusky.
We need to tube him.
Be a tricky intubation.
Tricky's my middle name.
And potentially
dangerous. Like I said,
Danger is my middle name.
Pulse ox down to 84.
Okay, let's get in there.
I'm gonna give you
inline stabilization.
Whatever you do, do
not extend the neck.
I'm as gentle as a kitten, sir.
BP's still 80.
All right, run
another liter of saline.
Too much edema. I
can't see the cords.
We need to crike him.
Whoa, hold on. Let's bag him.
Get his sats up. We need
a fiberoptic laryngoscope.
I'll get it.
Fiberoptics. That is cool.
You ever done one?
I've certainly seen them.
So that's a no, huh?
But, you, Dr. Greene,
could change all that.
I'll give you one
shot. Then it's mine.
Yes.
Yeah, it doesn't look too bad.
Not very deep.
Probably just need
a couple of stitches.
Did the paramedics bring you in?
Would you get us some
more four-by-fours?
We're running a
little low here, okay?
So your parents weren't with
you when this happened, huh?
No.
This is liable to sting
a little, Becky, okay?
How'd it happen?
He wasn't outside.
Who...? Who wasn't
ou...? Outside?
Tommy. M-my boyfriend.
Did he do this? Did he cut you?
I didn't even know
they had a basement.
I saw a light bulb
hanging down there.
And there he
was, right next to it.
Tommy was in the basement?
He tied the rope around a pipe.
So I ran back up to the
kitchen and got a knife.
And you used the
knife to cut the rope?
He just fell down.
I couldn't hold him or anything.
That's when the knife slipped.
And you cut yourself.
Is he gonna be okay?
Did the paramedics bring him?
They wouldn't let
me come with him.
I came in a different ambulance.
If you wait here, I'll go check
and see what I can find out.
Okay.
Tell me when
you're at the cords.
We are about to make contact.
I'm there.
Okay, advance into the trachea
and slide down the tube.
Yup, the eagle has
landed. Let's bag him.
Okay. Let's get X-ray down here.
I need a portable
chest and a C-spine.
Good breath sounds
on both sides. Nice work.
Thanks, boss.
Pulse ox up to 91.
This the suicide? Tommy? Yup.
How's he doin'? Great.
Neck is swollen up like a blimp.
Couldn't even see the cords.
Dr. Greene here let
me do a fiberoptic.
I passed that baby through
like I was threadin' a needle.
How's he doing?
He's pinking up.
But with the prolonged
oxygen deprivation,
I'm not sure about
his neuro status.
Come on, he was
too blue for too long.
We might be lookin'
at veggie burger.
Dr. Greene.
Oh, God.
Tommy! GREENE: Haleh.
Come on. Tommy, Tommy.
Let's get you outside.
Tommy! Is he all right?
Help her out.
What does he mean?
Is he gonna be all right?
You a resident? Yeah.
Well, you still need to learn
that every patient in here
is somebody's boyfriend,
girlfriend, father, mother, son.
They don't exist simply
for you to learn new
and interesting
procedures. I didn't see her.
Well, next time open your eyes
before you open your mouth.
Jeez, what's with the new guy?
Oh, which new guy
would that be, Malucci?
Dr. Lawrence or you?
He never said anything
about killing himself.
It's not your fault, Becky.
Be thankful you found
him. He's got a good chance.
I almost didn't go back inside.
I was gonna be late for school.
But I don't know. I just did.
Were his parents there?
No. At work.
His dad. His mom
lives in Florida.
You know where? Where...?
Where his father works?
Some kind of construction.
I don't really know him.
He's not around much.
Are you sick? You
don't look good.
She's just a little tired.
Who do you belong to?
Here, I'll make you
better. Say "ah."
Thank you, but this
patient has a doctor.
No, let go of me!
Okay, whoa, hold it.
Hold it. Robin!
Wait a sec... One
s... One second.
I want my mommy! Your... Wait.
Your mommy is right
over here. No! Let me go!
I'm so sorry, Dr. Lawrence.
No, that's quite all right.
I have that effect on women.
My mommy. No... Okay.
May I have my
stethoscope back, please?
When?
Twenty minutes ago.
He started triggering
the vent on his own.
Tommy, my name's Dr. Greene.
You're in the hospital.
Your girlfriend found
you and cut you down.
And the paramedics
brought you in.
What's his PO-2?
Ninety-eight percent
on an FIO-2 of 21.
Tommy, we have this tube down
your throat to help you breathe.
But we can take
it out now, okay?
You extubating him?
Yeah, he's got
good tidal volume.
You gave us a
scare there, Tommy.
I got it.
Thanks.
So, Tommy, what I want you to do
is take a deep breath
and then blow out
as hard as you can when
I pull out the tube, okay?
All right, take a deep breath.
All the way in.
Good, good, good.
And blow.
Good job.
Okay, it's gonna
be a little tender.
Don't try and speak right away.
Where's Becky?
Becky's here. She's fine.
She's worried
about you, of course.
Told me your mom's in Florida,
so I guess we'll call your dad.
You know his number at work?
I could talk to him
for you, if you want.
Pager number?
Here. Look, why don't
you write it, okay? Here.
Okay, okay. All right.
When you're ready.
Dr. Lawrence, you have a second?
Yeah, sure.
Tommy, I'll be right back.
What are you doin'?
Getting his father here.
Yeah, we're working on it.
Chicago P.D.'s working on it.
Don't pimp the kid. He
just attempted suicide.
Calling a psych consult?
Yes. Good.
Do you think I should
find out the sex?
Well, everyone's different.
Some people like to
know, some people don't.
What are you having?
I don't know.
Oh, come on. You know.
You're a nurse. So?
Seems like you'd
know. That's all.
Well, I figure there are few
really true surprises in life.
This is for your scrapbook.
Thanks.
Everything okay?
Fine. Little small for 32 weeks.
We'll put you on
some prenatal vitamins.
It's not too late for that?
Meg, are you smoking?
No.
I mean...
not a lot.
You know, it's really
bad for the baby.
It can cause prematurity,
low birth weight.
I know. I know.
I know. I'm just...
I'm really stressed. You
know, I lost that stupid job.
At Doc Magoo's?
I didn't move fast enough.
Excuse me, you know,
I'm seven months pregnant.
Well, you know, I could
call a social worker,
see if they could
get you some aid.
How about here? Do
they need people here?
Maybe the cafeteria?
I don't know. I... I
could check, I guess.
That would be great. Thanks.
If you promise to stop smoking.
Deal.
Well, Dad, just have
the insurance guy
call me here. Hey, Mark.
Mark, we got a double
trauma coming in.
Can you take it? Romano has
called this emergency meeting
for spin control... Look,
Dad, if you want to
handle it... Where's Benton?
He took up some MVA.
Okay, page Corday then.
You can't catch me! Hey!
You can't catch me!
No running. You can't catch me!
Hey, no running! Stop!
You can't catch me!
And that stuff is expensive!
I don't care! My daddy's rich!
I'm gonna call Security.
Brat.
Dad, I'm gonna call you back.
What's up?
Oh, my dad, he got
his insurance canceled.
Don't ask. So can you take it?
Because all the
department heads have to go
to this public
relations meeting.
This newspaper
thing is a disaster.
I don't know what
Elizabeth was doing.
- What newspaper thing?
- Right here.
Anybody seen Lawrence?
I got the neighbor
of the suicide kid.
He's got the dad's number.
Calling Lawrence?
That's what he said.
Yeah, I'll take it.
Hello, Dr. Greene here.
Thirty-one-year-old male
in parachute accident.
Bilateral tib-fib fractures.
Alert and oriented. Good vitals.
Your chute didn't open?
My lines got tangled.
Barely had time to
open the auxiliary.
Four dead at the scene.
What...? What about Larry?
Head... Head trauma.
What do you mean, head trauma?
Fifty-one-year-old male,
blunt head and chest trauma.
Intubated for
agonal respirations.
Blown pupil. Dropped
his BP to 90 over 60.
Flip you for it. What?
Well, the other guy
just has leg fractures.
Gee, Dave, that's too bad.
Come on, call it.
It's your lucky day.
Set up O-neg on
the rapid infuser.
I look at you, I think,
"Rocky, you can't lose."
I'm not callin' it, Dave.
Pulse ox has dropped. At 90.
But you're the man.
It's you're world.
Come on, call it. Heads.
Ouch, tails. Sorry, buddy.
Stay away from
the blackjack tables.
Get me a portable
C-spine, chest and pelvis.
Send off a trauma panel.
Type and cross for four.
Okay, on my count.
One. Two. Three.
Talk to me, Carter.
We got a fall from height.
Hypotensive severe head injury.
Regular rate and rhythm.
Tracheal shift to the left.
Survey says: chest tube.
Ten-blade. Thirty-two
French. Let's go.
Dave's your man. I got
a couple leg fractures
waitin' on me.
Pressure's down to
80. He's non-responsive.
Okay, pupils fixed and dilated.
GCS, five.
Brave son of bitch
for an old guy, huh?
He's 51.
He was probably trying a canopy.
It's a thing of beauty
when it's done right, actually.
I'm in. Thora-Seal.
You need me, Mark?
Uh, I think we're okay.
We just gotta get him to CT.
Horizontal mattress,
Dave. Yeah, I know.
Where's Peter?
He took up a hernia.
A hernia? Don't worry,
Evel Knievel's in good hands.
Excuse me.
How 'bout I throw
in a subclavian?
I don't think so.
Pressure's good.
We've got good
access. Hm. Art line?
How about a thoracotomy
while you're at it?
Really? Dave!
Oh.
Chest is clear. He's
gonna need a tetanus
and 3 grams of Unasyn.
Apply traction with dorsiflexion
to disengage the talus.
Like this? Yeah, perfect. Good.
Now I apply anterior
pressure to the posterior calf.
I felt a pop. Okay,
good. That's good.
You guys okay in
here? Got it and covered.
Pedal pulse is stronger.
Good. Nurse, call X-ray.
We'll get a post-reduction film.
You got it.
Ever do the wick
catheter technique?
Read about it. Today
you're gonna try it.
Cool, can I help?
Yeah, yeah, get a
pressure monitor.
Dave, I need you to
take this guy to CT.
Well, can't you get
a nurse to do that?
The guy's critical. I need
a doctor to stay with him.
But I was gonna help these guys.
We got it covered, Dave.
Listen, I want a neuro
check every five minutes.
And tell me if his
pressure drops.
All right.
You won him fair
and square, Dave.
Oh, and, Gabe? Yeah.
My patient, the kid?
The neighbor called, and
I got the dad's number.
Okay? Thanks. Oh, good.
I'll go get the transducer.
Urine dip is four-plus,
positive for blood.
Get a cystogram.
And let's get X-ray in here
for a post-reduction film.
I heard you the first time.
Right, okay, um...
Where was I? Uh,
wick catheter technique.
Oh, right, yeah.
All right, grab two
pieces of aught Dexon...
All right.
I've opened the peritoneal sac.
Can you see the fascial ring?
Almost.
Well, I'm glad our
schedules synced up, Peter.
It's been a long time
since we operated together.
Yeah.
All right, there
are no adhesions
to the anterior wall.
Oh, there's another defect.
We'd better do a
Gore-Tex repair.
Okay. Metz.
Hey, Elizabeth.
Interesting article in
the paper this morning.
Excuse me, Donald.
Peter, would you
please step out?
Heh. I'm in the middle
of operating here.
I'm sure Dr. Anspaugh
can handle it.
Please step out.
What is going on?
Peter's a trauma fellow.
He should be down
in the ER, not up here
covering elective hernias.
Right, but this patient
needed surgery.
And I was called down to
cover your multi-victim trauma.
I was down there all
morning. As you should be.
Now for the third
time, Please, step out.
Dr. Anspaugh, would
you, uh, take over, please?
Hey, I saw you touch that.
Barely.
Can't you make up your mind?
Nothing looks good.
How 'bout a grilled
cheese sandwich?
Looks less than a
day old. Mark, please.
Here, this. It's on me.
I'm not gonna eat that.
You've gotta eat something.
I have a mother. Thank you.
She calls every Sunday
for weekly weigh-ins.
Well, that's nothing.
My dad called four
times this morning,
obsessing about
this cypress tree
that he crashed into last night.
Is he okay?
Well, his pride's
a little wounded.
Front fender's
extremely wounded.
And apparently, the
neighbor's 100-year-old
cypress tree is
circling the drain.
Here, how about some Jell-O? No.
Come on, everybody
has room for Jell-O. No.
Got your employee discount card?
Oh, yeah.
And, um, I need to
speak to the manager.
Is someone around?
Viola Simpson.
Actin' like she be the
big boss, right over there.
Great. Thank... I saw
you eatin' that carrot.
Gotta pay for it.
Okay.
She's kept down the juice
and she doesn't have
any abdominal pain.
So she'll be fine at home.
Just give her some
fluids and come back
for vomiting or fever.
Thank you, Dr. Finch.
And you too, Yosh.
Oh, you're welcome.
She's been a completely
fascinating patient.
Muffin, muffin,
we're going home.
You wanna thank the
nice doctor and nurse? No!
Okay. All right. Hold my hand.
I don't wanna hold your
hand! Thanks again.
Wait! Robin! No, no,
no! Don't go outside!
Okay, Mr. Raybush. Here
we are. Back, safe and sound.
How was the CT?
Ugh, like someone scrambled
his brain with an eggbeater.
Is it a subdural?
Wanna take a look?
No. Mostly diffuse
swelling, microhemorrhages.
Nothing we could fix. Have
you seen Dr. Lawrence?
I think he's in the lounge.
All right, hyperventilate him.
Call Neurosurgery.
Get an ICP monitor.
Then I'll check and
see what else is in.
Track down his family.
He's wearing a ring.
He must have a wife.
Well, shouldn't a nurse do that?
Only if you fail.
Elaine?
John.
How are you feeling?
Lighter.
Sorry. That's a stupid joke.
May I sit down?
Yeah.
I tried calling you.
Dr. Corday said
the tests are clear.
My cancer hasn't spread.
That's... That's great news.
Yeah, that's what
everybody says.
But you don't feel that way?
I don't know what I feel.
Well, I think that's...
probably normal.
I think most people
probably... John.
Sorry.
I'll spare you the platitudes.
You waiting for Dr. Corday?
Yeah, I'm, uh... early, heh.
Well, maybe we
can get together later.
Go for a walk,
get a drink or talk.
Talk?
About anything other
than your surgery
and my miserable
life as an ER resident.
And what would that leave?
Sports.
Or music, or art, or Y2K thing.
Oh, yeah. The Y2K thing.
Yeah, I'm grasping
at straws here.
Yeah, I... see that.
But I'm not giving up.
Well... I guess I'm...
probably free at 7.
Mrs. Raybush, the
parachute accident
was extremely
serious, and he's...
H-he's in a coma.
I think you need to get
here as soon as you can.
You're in Dallas.
Dallas. Right, um, of
course. Three-hour flight.
Uh, I need to be
honest with you.
There's a good chance he won't
be able to hold out that long.
I'm very sorry.
Excuse me?
You wanna dictate a message
and have it read to him?
Um, I don't think I... Do it.
Of course I can do
that, Mrs. Raybush.
Yeah, I have a pen.
Doc Greene, it's your dad.
All right.
Hey, Dad. What is it?
Okay, go ahead.
He wants a replacement cypress.
Well, that seems reasonable.
How much?
Well, I know it's a
100-year-old tree, but...
And decided to kill himself.
Conni, who's that
talking to Dr. Lawrence?
It's the father of that
kid, Tommy Stevens.
Listen, Dad, I gotta go.
Don't worry, we'll
work somethin' out.
Hold on here. No,
I'll call you later.
Yeah, I will. Bye.
I'm working two jobs
just to keep our
heads above water.
Well, that's a hell
of a lousy excuse.
I took extra projects.
We need money.
What...? What, more
than you need your son?
No. Hi, I'm Dr. Greene.
Can I be of some help?
Yeah, get this
guy out of my face.
He hasn't even
let me see my son.
Tommy is in a very fragile
state right now, Mr. Stevens.
I'm not sure that it's
good for him to see you.
What the hell?!
I...! I am his father!
What...? What, you mean,
like, for an hour a day?
Okay, Dr. Lawrence, just
a minute. Just a minute.
Mr. Stevens, yes, as a father,
you do have a right
to see your son.
Haleh, can you take Mr. Stevens
down to Curtain Area 3?
This way, sir.
What was that all about?
Shows up and expects to waltz...
He is the father. Yeah.
Somebody oughta
give this guy a talking-to!
Not your job. The
hell it isn't, man.
You don't know the details.
Yeah, I know enough!
And, uh, what did you
say her name was?
Viola Simpson. She
said she was glad
you had food experience.
And was she glad to
hear I was pregnant?
Well, glad's an overstatement,
but she didn't seem to care.
Your appointment's at 5:30.
Oh, that gives
me plenty of time.
I can pick up the rest
of my stuff at Magoo's
and still get home
and... And change.
Thanks, Mrs. Hathaway.
Oh, it's Carol. And
you're welcome.
Let me know how it goes. Okay.
Hey, and stay
off the cigarettes.
Scout's honor.
No. Not a retraction really,
just simply the other
side of the story.
Yeah. Well, think about it.
Elizabeth, you wanted to talk?
Please.
Yes, thank you.
Um, if it's not a bad time.
No, not if you don't
mind my scrubbing.
Not at all.
Has this mirror
always been there?
I believe it is a recent
Rocket addition.
Whatever for?
One can only imagine.
God, I hate these caps.
I look like a Yorkshire pudding.
Elizabeth?
Yes...
Um, I did need to
talk to you, Donald.
I'm sorry to even
have to mention it.
Don't apologize.
Someone has to
do the devil's work.
Well, I'm relieved
you see it that way.
And it is not easy
managing colleagues.
Yeah, I'm beginning
to realize that.
When I was doing my rotten job,
much of which you've
recently taken on,
I always tried to get
to the core of the issue.
Right.
Ask yourself this:
Do you believe Peter
Benton is a good surgeon?
Peter Benton? Mm-hm.
Yes, of course, he's
an excellent surgeon.
Ah, even better.
Now ask yourself this:
Should County have
excellent surgeons
working on its staff?
Absolutely.
Then don't you think
we should all want Peter
to practice surgery
whenever he can?
Yes.
I... I do, actually.
Um, I don't agree
with Dr. Romano.
Now, one thing to keep in
mind in your new position:
If you don't agree
with the dirty work,
don't do it.
Hey, Malooch. I've got a
gnarly split kneecap in Exam 2.
Ah, you're teasin' me.
No, it's a disgusting
mess. Your kind of case.
I'm sorry, but I got a
little readin' to catch up on.
Sure you do.
What happened?
He coded.
Dr. Benton called it.
Wait, you called it?
Wh...? BENTON: Yeah.
That's usually what I
do when a patient dies.
Oh, man.
What the hell am I
supposed to do with this?
This a 4-year-old?
Back from this morning.
- I remember.
- I - couldn't wake her up.
Finch said she'd be okay.
Found her in V-fib,
unresponsive to
defibrillation times three.
- Epi and lidocaine.
- Get Cleo.
She's been down
at least 30 minutes.
Do something!
We will, Mrs. Bourke,
everything we can. Here we go.
On my count. One,
two, three. Gently.
What happened?
Cardiac arrest at home.
Any problems this morning?
Thought it was gastroenteritis.
Hold compressions.
- Check rhythm.
- Still in V-fib.
Paddles. Charge to 30.
Is she gonna be all right?
Clear! WOMAN: Clear.
Oh, my God!
Procainamide, 17 per kilo.
Could she have
ingested anything?
Just the Chinese food. I
already told Dr. Finch that.
What about drugs,
antidepressants, insecticides?
No.
Gasoline, cleaning
fluids, bleach...
Cleo, are you running this?
Yes. Charge to 50.
Think, Mrs. Bourke.
We need to know.
Uh, iron tablets,
detergents...? No.
Uh, we keep vitamins
on the kitchen table.
Vitamins with iron? Yes.
It's iron poisoning. Clear!
- Clear. MRS.
- Oh, God!
She's asystole.
Pupils are fixed and dilated.
High-dose epi!
Conni, move her out.
No, no, no. I want to stay.
- Come on.
I want to stay.
Oh, my God.
I want to stay!
No, I want to... Please.
It's all right. It's all right.
Dr. Finch, you want atropine?
Do you want atropine, Dr. Finch?
No.
We got a case number
from the coroner's office.
Why don't you see if
you can you track down
the family pediatrician?
The nurses can do that.
I wanna do it. Ahem.
I'm sorry.
You know there'll
be an M and M, and...
there could be
medical legal issues.
Do you mind if I
look over your notes?
Chart's on the counter.
Now, what was your
discharge impression?
Food poisoning.
Or a mild case
of gastroenteritis.
Okay, did you ask
about household poisons?
Mom said the house
was childproofed.
Prescription meds?
Out of reach.
Did you ask about iron?
No.
I'm not sure I
would have either.
Okay, the chart looks good.
Everything you did was
within standard of care.
Risk Management
won't have a problem.
Is that it?
Cleo, you saw the child
in the second phase
of the overdose.
But she looked and
felt completely normal.
You did exactly what any
one of us would have done.
I should have asked.
Iron is on the differential.
So are 200 other
things. I should've asked.
You did everything you could.
No, I didn't. She's dead.
Malucci, did you
call Public Health
about that bat bite? Huh?
The guy in Exam 3, he's
gonna need a rabies series.
He died on me.
Yeah, the parachute guy.
Suffered massive head injuries.
Didn't stand much of a chance.
I wrote down everything his
wife wanted to tell him on this box.
But he died before I had
a chance to read it to him.
You took the message
more for her than for him.
Yeah, I guess.
It just feels weird
throwing it away now. Mmm.
She said some
really nice things.
Private things.
I've got a bad nosebleed.
Can someone take him?
If we had any beds.
Hey, why is that
rhinitis still in Four?
I don't know. Ask Dr. Lawrence.
Here, let me. I think
I know where he is.
I used to work all the time.
Hell, I even volunteered
for the shift at Christmas.
Didn't mean I
didn't love my kids.
Dads are like that.
How you feelin', Tommy?
Okay.
His blood gas is
back. Good PO-2.
Good. Thanks.
Tommy's father had to leave.
Back to work.
There was a problem at the site.
Were you able to
talk to Dr. DeRaad?
The shrink?
I know it's hard talking to
somebody you don't know.
But they're here to... You
know, they're here to listen.
I'm not crazy.
I didn't say that.
I just... I know
you think it's stupid.
But I love her.
I mean, I really love her.
Who? Your girlfriend?
And she loved me. And
then suddenly she didn't.
How can somebody love you
that much and then just stop?
When did she
tell you about this?
I didn't believe her
until this morning.
Lizzie. You talk to Anspaugh?
Yes. And how'd he take it?
He didn't. I didn't
discuss it with him.
What, you didn't get
around to it or what?
I hope when you
offered me this position,
you did it because,
my surgical skills aside,
you trust my judgment.
Naturally. Now, if
I'm here to protect
your interest, then
I have to tell you
it's in your best interest to
keep Donald Anspaugh happy.
Not only is he a great
asset to the surgical staff
and to you, but he's also
on special consideration.
Now, if this interferes
with your tennis
lessons in anyway,
then I'm sorry... I
don't play tennis.
Well, whatever. The point is, if
you want to push Donald out...
You'll have to
do it by yourself.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Who
said anything about pushing him out?
Well, I assume this
is just the first step.
Lizzie, when you "assume,"
you make an "ass"
of "u" and "me."
What? Whatever.
Look, I... I just
wanted Fridays off.
I thought you
could talk to Donald,
but if you're
uncomfortable, I understand.
Oh.
Okay?
Yeah, that's all right. Mm-hm?
You're feeding it wrong.
What?
Try folding it longways.
And then flip up the
corners, and fold it flat.
Or you can just tell me
to mind my own business.
Go ahead.
No, I'm kidding.
I use quarters myself.
What do you want?
Uh, Coke.
Caffeine, the ER
doc's best friend.
Tommy went up to Medicine.
DeRaad put him on a hold.
You don't have to fill me in.
I jumped to
conclusions about Dad.
I wan... I wanted to help.
Wanna sit down?
Yeah, sure. Thanks.
Well, kid's in trouble.
You know, you go
to the parents first.
Dad was still an ass
for going back to work.
Yeah.
You have a family?
A daughter.
Are you divorced?
Get to see her a lot?
She lives in St. Louis.
You know, when I was...
When I was about your age...
my son was brought into the ER.
He'd... He'd, uh...
He'd fallen out of a tree.
They patched him up,
you know, good as new.
And it wasn't
till later I realized
he had jumped out of the tree.
He wanted to come see me.
- But that was then...
- Dr. Lawrence?
A Mr. Henderson is
on his way to the O.R.
I just need you
to cosign his chart.
I can do that.
Thanks for the Coke.
You bet.
Did you check a second crit?
Thirty-eight, um, and
the EKG was normal.
I reviewed the
films with Radiology.
And you were right.
Comminuted tib-fib.
Nondisplaced calcaneal fracture.
And the cystogram was normal.
Cystogram? Why'd
you get a cystogram?
You ordered it when the
urine tested positive for blood.
He had microscopic hematuria.
I ordered an IVP.
No, you said cystogram.
I wouldn't order a cystogram
for 30 red cells. You did.
Lucy, I've been
treating trauma patients
for 30 years.
I think I know what I ordered.
Get an IVP before he goes up.
He's already on his way.
Then catch him and
get him into Radiology.
He's not going to
surgery without an IVP.
Sutured the scalp lac
in One. I'm outta here.
Did you sign out your patients?
Yep. Oh, hold on. Forgot this.
Hey, Dad. It's Mark.
No, nothin'. I was just
callin' to see how you're doin'.
I'm sure it's a mistake.
See you, Mark.
You takin' off?
Yeah, I gotta go
home, soak my feet,
and the rest of my body.
- Carol?
Meg, how did it go?
I screwed up. What happened?
I missed the interview.
I... I thought you said
6:30, but it was 5:30.
And I... I blew it.
Well, it's not true.
I... I couldn't go
through with it.
Why not?
No one wants to hire
a pregnant woman.
And I can't blame them.
I mean, why should
I waste their time?
It's not like I'm not gonna
quit in a month, anyway.
Meg, stop.
We're gonna go there together
and work something out, okay?
Okay. WEAVER: Coming through!
Ben Sessa. Six years old.
Two-day history of fever...
Carter, I need your
help! I'm off in 15 minutes.
I got it. Thank you.
Pulse 140. BP 60.
What is it? MAN:
Couldn't get an IV.
Cleo, you don't
have... What is it?
Altered with fever.
Could be sepsis,
maybe meningitis.
On my count:
One, two, three, lift.
CBC, blood cultures, chem panel.
Okay, let's get
a line in this kid.
He's dry as a bone.
Let's get a fluid bolus.
No response to painful stimuli.
He's got no veins.
I can't get a draw.
Call Surgery for a cutdown.
I'll try a central line.
That's gonna be tough. His
veins are completely collapsed.
Prep the ankle.
If I don't get it,
Surgery can do the cutdown.
Systolic's down
to 50. Pulse 145.
Okay, do it.
Cutdown tray now.
Spike two liters of saline,
one at the ankle
and one at the head.
Pulse ox 92.
Got it. Here's your blood.
Get a crit. Get an Accu-Chek.
Stand by with
saline. I want a bolus
of 20 per kilo, about 400 cc's.
Run in a gram of
ceftriaxone and cath a urine.
I'm in. Let's go.
Dr. Weaver, I have
Robin Bourke's
pediatrician on Line 2.
Cleo, you got this?
Yeah, I got this.
Send up a UA and
culture after that.
I'll do an LP.
Carter, do you have a second?
Not really.
Did you hear Dr. Lawrence
order that cystogram
for Mr. Henderson? No.
Did he have gross hematuria?
No, just microscopic.
Then you don't need one.
That's what I thought.
He told me to order it.
You must have heard
wrong. No, he said cystogram.
Dr. Lawrence wouldn't
order a cystogram
for microscopic
hematuria. Right.
It seemed strange to me,
but I figured he knew
what he was doing.
He does know what he's doing.
You ordered the wrong
test. See you tomorrow.
"I love you, Larry.
The girls love you.
"You have been the best
husband, the best father,
"the love of our lives,
the light of our lives,
"our true north.
"You could never leave us...
"because you'll be
with us and in us.
We'll love you always."
So, what did you tell him?
That I spoke to the adjuster,
and they agreed to
accept the late payment.
Except they cancel
his policy. Ahem, right.
So who pays for
the cypress tree?
You're lookin' at him.
The dutiful son.
Yeah, well, duty
comes at a price.
You're gonna have
to buy me dinner.
Whatever you want.
Oh, good. 'Cause I'm hungry.
What have you got there?
What have you
got? Mark! What is it?
Quit grabbing! Quit grabbing.
I'm gonna grab.
All right, I got it
framed for your office.
You've just lost dinner, mister.
What?
Hey, Dr. Lawrence.
Oh, please, it's Gabe.
You off? Almost.
Uh, we're getting a bite
to eat. Care to join us?
No, thanks, I still have some...
You know, some dictations and...
Well, we're just going across
the street to Doc Magoo's
if you change your
mind. Right. Thanks.
Have a good night.
Yeah, you too. Good night.
It's not everybody
who gets to be
on the front page
of the newspaper.