I respect LeBron James.
I admire LeBron James.
But compare him
to Michael Jordan?
Come on!
You only think that
because you're
a Chicago chauvinist.
Oh, no.
No, I'm completely objective.
Stats, clutch playing,
it's Jordan all the way.
Will, you are
a very good doctor,
but very limited on your
understanding of basketball.
Give me a kiss.
Dr. Manning,
radiology called.
Yes.
Your scans are up
on the computer.
Okay.
I got it.
Thank you.
Morning, Connor.
Good morning, Will.
Hey, how's Robin?
She's much better, thanks.
Yeah, she's shopping
like a fiend.
She left me about a foot
of space in the closet,
and three hangers.
Uh-oh.
Excuse me.
Maggie.
Yeah?
Do me a favor. Call CT,
tell them I had to leave.
I'll be back as
soon as I can.
You got it.
Hey, Darren.
Sorry about this, Dr. Rhodes.
No, I appreciate the text.
Where is she?
This way.
Okay.
One of my guys caught her
trying to walk out with this.
Had no idea who she was.
We would have called PD
if your dad hadn't been here.
Appreciate that.
Did you really
have to lock her in?
Standard procedure,
Dr. Rhodes.
Robin.
I don't know what's
the matter with me.
Shh, come here, come here.
It's gonna
be all right, honey.
It's gonna be all right.
I hear Mama hollering
from the bathroom
and I run in and
find her on the floor.
That's when I called 911.
Told her a bus
would suit me just fine,
instead of wasting all
that money on a ambulance.
Well, I'm glad you did
decide to come in,
Ms. Buckley.
Luckily, it's only
your wrist that's broken,
but your X-ray shows what
we call a Colles' fracture.
So we need to reduce it,
re-align your bones,
and then we can
put you in a splint.
If you say so.
Okay. April, draw up
10 milligrams of lidocaine
for a hematoma block.
So, let me guess. Virginia?
North Carolina.
Mmm.
We've been here 20 years.
Guess the Tar Heel never goes.
You all right?
Yeah, it's nothing.
Okay, now this
is gonna hurt.
So I'm gonna have you take
some deep breaths for me,
okay?
All right, you ready?
Mmm-hmm.
Okay, take a deep breath.
Good job.
Now I'm gonna have you
take one more really big
deep breath for me, okay?
Ready? One, two, three.
Ah!
All right,
the hard part's over.
Great job.
Thank you.
Mmm-hmm.
Orthopedics will be down later
to set you up
with a cast, okay?
Thank you.
Sorry. Thank you.
How's Noah doing?
He's gonna have a black eye
for a couple days,
but he'll be okay.
He'll be in later today.
Glad to hear it.
Honey, this is
the encephalitis.
This isn't you.
You don't know how it feels.
It is humiliating.
Things like this,
they're gonna pass.
You know that.
You're already better
than you were a month ago.
Am I though?
Really?
God, I've got to
pull myself together.
Dad.
Thank you for
not calling the cops.
Connor, this friend of yours,
she's a kleptomaniac.
No, she isn't.
She's recovering from
an illness that makes her
do things
she wouldn't otherwise do.
Well, still, you have to
admit she's unstable.
You don't know her.
You don't know
anything about her.
So what she did
was sane, reasonable?
After what happened to Mom,
I would say that
you are the last person
that should be discussing
anybody's mental health.
You're making this
about your mother?
Yes, I am.
She's been gone
for 20 years.
Time to move on,
don't you think?
Yeah,
it took you what, a week?
Okay, listen to me.
If she's not unstable,
she's a criminal.
Either way,
fatherly advice,
get rid of her.
Good morning.
Morning.
Hey, so you and April?
Yeah.
How long has that
been going on?
About six months.
You managed to keep it quiet
for six months in this place?
It wasn't easy.
On several occasions, we came
close to blowing our cover.
Hmm.
Sharon?
Yeah?
I'm a charge nurse,
and I'm hanging IV bags.
I know, Maggie.
You're short-staffed.
For a month. When are we
gonna hire more nurses?
We can't afford it.
It's not in the budget.
Sharon, we are required to
have one nurse for two beds.
That's 12 nurses per shift.
Four shifts, that's 48 nurses.
Right now, I only have 42.
Well, even it out
with overtime.
Time and a half?
How is that supposed
to save us money?
It doesn't,
but overtime
comes out of
a different account.
We still look good.
Work with me.
Dr. Halstead, incoming.
Arlo Littman, 20 years old.
Delusional and combative.
Says he's radioactive.
You can't let anyone
touch me, make them stay away!
Negative on
radiation poisoning.
He hasn't vomited
or been nauseated.
Too agitated to get vitals,
restrained in the field.
He on something?
Roommate says no,
he doesn't do drugs.
No one touch me!
Karen, page Psych.
All right, let's get him
on the bed.
Arlo, I'm Dr. Halstead,
I'm gonna help you.
I'm death, don't touch me.
Yeah, let's get him
on the bed.
Uh-huh.
One, two, three.
Get away from me, no!
Restraints.
Courtney, get his left leg.
Yup.
You'll die, you will all die!
All right.
Let's move him up
a little bit.
Spontaneous movement in all
four limbs, anyone disagree?
Pupils equal,
round and reactive.
Don't touch me,
save yourselves.
Hey!
Okay, easy, buddy.
Try and relax.
Yeah, I didn't sedate him,
didn't want to over-snow him.
Thought you'd want
to hear his spiel.
Five diazepam,
five olanzapine.
Got it.
Hey, I'm Dr. Charles,
I'm here to help you.
I'm death.
Let's get him on
the monitors.
U-tox, blood alcohol,
CBC and CMP.
You want the restraints off?
Eh.
Let's leave them on for now.
See what his state of mind
is when he wakes up.
All right, he's all yours.
Thanks, Will.
Yup.
Initial thoughts?
Schizophrenia usually
manifests at his age.
Mmm-hmm. Doris, could you give
us a second, please?
Sure.
You okay?
Yes.
All right, just making sure
you're comfortable
treating the patient.
Yeah, absolutely.
I'll be here if you need me.
Hey, you.
I got to get back to work.
Uh, there's leftovers
in the fridge, if you want.
Turkey, asparagus...
I'm not hungry.
Robin, you should eat.
You'd feel better.
You take good care of me.
I guess you do that
for all your patients.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
hey, hey, hey, hey.
You are not my patient.
I love you.
Do you?
Because I wouldn't love me.
I'd get rid of me.
Listen, my dad
is a son of a bitch.
He likes to destroy things.
And you,
you like to fix things.
People with blocked arteries
or leaky valves.
Unhinged girlfriends
who like to shoplift.
Meaning?
Wanting to save someone,
needing to save someone,
it's not the same
as loving.
Robin, your illness,
it gives you
a distorted view of things.
Right.
Unhinged.
No.
It is a matter
of brain chemistry.
And obviously, right now it's
not being addressed properly.
So I am going to
make sure that it is.
You're my knight
in shining armor.
I'll be home
as soon as I can.
And this one, too.
Yep.
Dr. Halstead, you're back on.
You're going
to treatment four.
Hey, Monique?
Jessie Rowe, mid-twenties.
Shortness of breath,
abdominal pain.
I'm her husband.
Okay. I'm Dr. Halstead.
Any idea
what might be causing this?
Something you ate?
Did you fall?
No.
Might be the IVF therapy.
We've been
trying to get pregnant,
Jessie's had
three rounds.
Embryo transfer two weeks ago.
Okay, let's see
what's going on.
I'm hearing a slight crackle.
I got it.
Pam, we need an X-ray in here.
Yes, Maggie.
How long
you been feeling this way?
Been bloated a couple days.
Shortness of breath
just this morning.
Heart rate 86, BP 124/73.
O2 sat's at 93%.
That's a little low.
Put her on a nasal cannula.
Jessie, I'm gonna ultrasound
your belly.
Thank you.
Your ovaries
are somewhat enlarged,
but that can happen after IVF.
Can you tell?
Am I pregnant?
Uh, too early
for that to show.
We need a chest.
Yes, Doctor.
Wait. What if she
is pregnant?
The lead apron
will protect her.
Stand back, everybody.
I'm seeing some congestion
in the lungs,
but not enough to concern me.
This could all just be
in response to the IVF,
but we're gonna make sure.
Hopefully you'll
feel better soon.
And we'll all cross
our fingers
the embryo transfer took.
Mr. Janichek, I'm Dr. Choi.
I understand you cut yourself.
Yeah, and maybe someone
can finally tell me why.
I see this isn't
the first time.
It's been happening
a lot lately.
I drop things, I fall down.
It's not like me.
Basic vitals are all normal.
You know, I don't care.
Something's wrong with me,
and no one can
figure out what.
Well, let's take a look, huh?
Put your index finger
and thumb together
to make a circle.
Try not to let me break it.
Good. Relax.
Can you feel this?
This, this, this, this?
Your tendons and nerves
are intact.
A gram of ancef,
draw up lidocaine,
and give me the suture kit.
Yep.
That's it?
You're just gonna sew me up?
Well, I don't see anything
else that needs treating.
You're just like
all the other docs.
You don't care.
You don't listen.
You just want
to get me out of here.
I am listening to you,
Mr. Janichek.
I feel crummy.
Crummy?
Yeah, pretty much
all the time.
Doris, let's get
a CBC and CMP.
Yes, Dr. Choi.
Now can I sew you up?
Hi.
A nurse is gonna come by
to start
your discharge paperwork.
Nance, look up the bus
schedule, will you, hon?
Yeah. Ah!
Honey?
Nancy, are you okay?
Let me check your abdomen,
if you don't mind.
How long have you
had this pain?
Uh, I don't know.
A few days?
Is there anything
in particular
that makes it hurt worse?
Eating, twisting, lying down?
Hurts just the same.
Ah. Oof.
Yeah, seems like
appendicitis to me.
I had my appendix out
when I was 14.
Any other surgeries?
C-section, any kids?
No, I always wanted them,
but it never panned out.
Well, it might be a hernia,
but I'd like
to get you into a bed
and examine you
more thoroughly.
Run some tests.
It's probably
just a bellyache.
Listen to the doctor, hon.
You'll be all right?
Of course.
Well, go on.
Come on.
Thank you. Right this way.
Reese.
When was the last time Robin
had a full work-up?
Just before
she was released from rehab.
That was almost
two months ago.
How about a little
follow-up with your patient?
She is not asymptomatic,
but that's to be expected.
Recovery does not happen
overnight, it's a process...
So you reviewed
her medication?
Yes.
With her neurologist?
And her internist,
and her pharmacist.
I've been monitoring Robin
very carefully.
Maybe somebody else should.
Someone with more experience.
Maybe a little more
familiarity
with her condition.
All right, if Robin
wants to change physicians,
that is her right.
But that should be
her request, not yours.
I'm bringing her in tomorrow.
She's gonna get
a full neuro work up,
plus labs, plus scans.
Understand?
Jessie, I have news for you.
Some of which will
make you very happy.
So we ran a test
to check on your hCG level...
That's pregnancy hormone...
And it indicates that indeed,
you are pregnant.
That's great!
Honey, we did it.
But?
The other tests show that
you're hemoconcentrated.
And that's a thickening
of the blood.
It's a symptom of
a condition called OHSS,
Ovarian Hyper
Stimulation Syndrome.
Now, this can occur when
the hCG
from the IVF treatments
and your pregnancy interacts
adversely with your estrogen.
So because she got pregnant,
she got sick?
Yes.
Is it serious?
The concern is that
you're more likely to clot.
And possibly throw a clot.
So we'll monitor
you carefully,
but I think we can
resolve the OHSS.
We'll continue to hydrate you,
and start you
on a blood thinner.
So everything's
gonna be fine.
Well, you're still
a little short of breath,
so I'd like to send you
for a CT scan
just to play it safe.
Okay.
All right.
Hey, Barry, you're going to
treatment three.
Doctor Choi?
You guys... You guys are...
Hey, I'm okay.
Thirty-three-year-old male,
found in the park.
Alcohol on the breath,
the GCS is 13.
He's a little groggy,
but improving.
Minor head laceration.
I got it, Barry. Thanks.
You got it.
Mags, how about a nurse?
I have no nurses,
I'll be in in a sec.
This patient.
Indigent, no insurance?
Afraid so.
The hospital's gonna
have to eat up the cost.
What are you gonna do?
We'll give him the best care
humanly possible,
no expense spared, but you
know, it would sure be nice
to balance patients like him
with a few that
have insurance.
So maybe we can
hire a few nurses.
Maggie...
Next time you're in
the Gold Coast
picking up an MI
with a fat wallet,
how about bringing them here?
Just as close
as anyplace else.
Nancy Buckley's results?
Yeah, it's not a hernia.
It's what I thought,
her CT shows appendicitis.
But her charts said
her appendix was removed
when she was a teenager.
That's not
the only thing that's off.
Tubal ligation clips.
She had her tubes tied.
Why wouldn't she put that
in her history?
Maybe she didn't want
her mom to know.
Might be a touchy
subject for them.
You know what, Nancy said
she always wanted kids.
This doesn't feel right.
Well either way,
she's going to need surgery.
Yeah, on an organ
she thinks she doesn't have.
Ms. Buckley, your scan clearly
shows an inflamed appendix.
We need to get you
up to surgery
right away before it ruptures.
Well, how can it be inflamed?
I had it out when I was a kid,
you saw the scar.
Yeah, I understand that
this is very confusing,
but that scar is actually
from a different procedure.
No, I ain't had
no other surgeries.
Ask my mama, she'll tell you.
Dr. Manning.
BP is 75/20 and dropping.
Ms. Buckley? Nancy?
BP's still dropping.
Heart rate spiking to 145.
Her appendix is ruptured,
we need to get her to surgery.
Get her IV wide open,
and call up to the OR
and tell them
we're on our way.
Let's go!
What's wrong with my Nancy?
I'm afraid we had to
send your daughter up
for an emergency appendectomy.
Appendectomy?
Yes, her appendix burst.
Oh.
Ms. Buckley.
Your daughter believes that
she had her appendix out
when she was 14 years old.
Why would she think that?
That's what the doc
said back then.
Well, she does have a scar,
but it's not from
an appendectomy.
Well, uh...
I don't know what to say.
Her appendix is not the only
thing we saw on her scan.
She was a minor.
You would have
had to give consent.
Back home,
in Blue Ridge country,
I was young and poor
when I had her.
Nancy was a wild teenager,
always getting into trouble.
Finally, this judge who
practically ran the county,
he told me if I wanted
to keep Nancy out of jail,
I had to make a choice.
So you agreed
to have her tubes tied?
The way she was going,
she'd have been pregnant
by the time she was 15,
dropped out of school,
come to nothing.
That was my life.
I wasn't about to see
my daughter turn out the same.
Ms. Buckley,
don't you think your daughter
deserves to know the truth?
Well, I thought about it.
What good would it do?
What's done is done.
She always wanted
to have kids.
Knowing what
her mama did to her
would only
bring her more misery.
Please don't tell her.
Hi, Arlo, I'm Dr. Reese.
I'm here to help you.
Please, don't touch me.
You'll be contaminated.
Uh, contaminated with what?
Radium.
How were you exposed
to radium?
My professor,
he works for the CIA.
He put it in my food.
I see. I see.
Do you mind if I take a seat?
Just don't touch me.
All right.
Be careful.
Arlo, I, uh... I appreciate
your concern for me,
but I understand
the risk that I'm taking.
Uh, I just want to help you,
if you will let me.
My arms hurt.
I'm sorry.
Uh, we can remove
the restraints
if you can stay calm.
Can you do that?
Just don't touch me.
We will only touch
the restraints.
I said be careful!
Okay.
Thank you.
Then make room
in the schedule, okay?
She's getting that
scan tomorrow.
Connor.
You okay?
Yeah, uh...
Robin's not having a good day.
Sorry to hear that.
Look, I need a consult,
but I'll ask someone else.
No, I'm good.
Jessie,
this is Dr. Rhodes.
He's a cardiothoracic surgeon.
What did you find?
So the scans showed us this.
What you're looking at is
a partially obstructing
saddle pulmonary embolism.
It's a blood clot.
Now, because of the
location of the clot,
surgical intervention
may become necessary.
But not yet.
The clot is small,
so I'm hoping that if
we up the dose
of the anticoagulants,
switch to a heparin drip...
Mmm-hmm.
That may take care of it.
Okay.
We'll bring you
back down to the ED
and keep a close eye
on you.
Thanks.
You got it.
Mr. Janichek,
I have your test results,
and everything is normal.
You're mildly anemic,
hemoglobin's at 9.5,
but that'll resolve
if you just eat more red meat.
Nothing else?
You look like
a healthy man to me.
Well, what about my symptoms?
The clumsiness, feeling lousy?
I don't see a medical reason
for any of that.
Have you been getting
enough sleep?
Oh, forget it.
I've been through this
dog and pony show before.
I understand it's frustrating
not to get
a definitive diagnosis.
Just let me get out of here,
that's all you want anyway.
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
I don't want to
send you home
feeling that way.
I can call for
a neuro consult if you want.
Yes, anything.
Okay.
Come in.
Sharon?
Hey.
I've been thinking about
how we can hire
more nurses for the ED.
Maggie,
I've already told you...
I know, I know.
No money.
But if the ED
had more patients,
hopefully with insurance, that
would mean more money, right?
Yeah.
So who brings us patients?
The paramedics. And if they
liked coming to Med,
if they were motivated to come
to Med, that's what they'd do.
They'd bring us more patients.
And how do you propose
to motivate
the paramedics, Maggie?
That's really pretty simple.
Hey. What's going on?
Sorry, um...
Did you know that up until
1973 in North Carolina,
women could get sterilized
without their knowledge
or consent?
My patient had
her daughter's tubes tied
when she was 14.
Fourteen.
All because a judge thought
it would be good for her.
Man.
The daughter always
wanted to have kids,
and never knew
why she couldn't.
She never went to a doctor?
No, too poor.
Can you believe
they could do that?
Deprive a woman of her ability
to have children,
something so fundamental.
This woman
who was sterilized...
How do you break
news like that?
I'm asking myself
the same thing.
Mr. Janichek's not exhibiting
any neurologic deficits.
And what about
his clumsiness?
Awfully vague complaint,
hardly warranted a consult.
It's just
the patient's desperate.
He insists there's something
wrong with him.
Since when
do we listen to patients?
Maybe some sort of
heavy metal poisoning,
lead or mercury...
Dr. Choi,
if you want to waste the time
and money ordering
those tests,
you be my guest,
but I'm done here.
I just got a call
from Robin.
She was arrested
for shoplifting?
No, she wasn't arrested.
She got caught trying
to leave the store,
but I took care of it.
Well, apparently it's been
going on for a while, though.
I realize that now,
but I had no idea.
Have there been any signs?
Like, at home, or...
Dr. Charles, a woman has new
clothes and that's suspicious?
She's not a prisoner,
I can't keep her locked up.
She's got a life of her own.
I have a patient to see.
Connor, I appreciate that
you're doing the best you can,
but given the
all-consuming nature of...
Dr. Charles,
Robin and I are fine.
I'm gonna see her
through this.
Will?
Heart rate's 140,
BP's down to 90/70.
Keith.
I'm right here, honey.
O2 sat's down to 85.
Heparin's not working.
She's continuing to embolize.
She's in respiratory failure.
Why? What's happening?
The clot in her lung
has progressed.
It's cutting off blood flow
and straining her heart.
BP's down to 60/30.
Sat's at 75.
Okay, we need to intubate.
20 of etomidate, 100 of sux.
Maybe you want
to wait outside?
No, I'm not leaving her.
All right, tell the OR
we're on the way up
and to prep the hybrid room.
Yes, Doctor.
Your wife needs surgery now.
We need to remove the clot
from her pulmonary artery,
otherwise it could kill her.
Just save her, please!
I'm in.
All right, let's go.
We're in a good position.
Let's start the extraction.
Pressure's a little soft,
80/50.
I've been working on that.
Gas looks fine, but I've given
a half liter of crystalloid
to minimum effect.
Starting Neo now.
You let in the anesthetic?
Already done.
She's still dropping.
The catheter must be
obstructing the outflow tract.
Her heart's failing,
we need to open her chest.
Bring in the bypass machine.
Marty, start a second pressor
to buy me some time.
I put in the catheter,
did I make a mistake?
Nope, it's not your fault,
it happens sometimes.
Scalpel and sternal saw.
Let's move.
Sternal saw.
I'm just out of control.
It's okay.
It's okay, it's okay.
I don't know what to do.
And I feel like
I will never get past this.
What, your illness?
Of course you will.
You just... You've had
a setback.
That's all it is.
No, Dad. It's more than that.
It's about
what I have become to Connor.
And to everyone, it's like
I'm someone to be pitied.
Or taken care of.
And I am drowning.
No, no, honey.
Come here, sweetie.
It's okay, I'm here.
I'm gonna help you, okay?
No, Dad.
Don't you see that
I don't want to be helped?
I am tired of being a disease.
I want to be a person again.
Okay.
Okay, so, um,
so how you want to do that?
Mr. Rowe.
So we tried to remove the clot
from your wife's lung
with a minimally
invasive procedure.
Unfortunately, her heart
couldn't tolerate it,
so we did have
to open her chest.
Now, the important thing is,
we were able to remove
the clot successfully.
Her pulmonary artery pressures
have already come down,
and I have
every reason to believe
that she's gonna make
a quick and full recovery.
And the baby?
No indication that
the pregnancy was affected.
Thank you, Dr. Rhodes.
I don't know what else to say.
Keith.
I'm right here, honey.
You're gonna be fine.
It's all good.
Great.
Thanks, Connor.
Nice people.
Yeah, they've really
been put through it today.
Kinda makes you realize
how small your
own problems are, huh?
And that sometimes,
things work out.
Who's got three?
Where's Monique? Monique?
I need you to turn over three
and get it cleaned up.
Here are the files, here.
Yes, ma'am.
Oh!
Ladies and gentleman,
by unanimous decision,
and still retaining his title
as welterweight champion
of the world,
Noah "The Doctor" Sexton!
Welcome back.
Are you sure
you should be at work?
You don't look very good.
Thanks.
You look good.
She's doing well.
They're weaning her sedation
and should extubate soon.
Good.
Now here comes the hard part.
You mean
you're gonna tell her?
It's her body, April.
It's her life.
She has every right to know.
These two women
only have each other.
We drop this on Nancy, she may
never forgive her mother.
I understand, but we are
legally bound to tell her.
We're gonna
destroy this family
over something they
can't do anything about?
That is for Nancy to decide.
She has been denied a choice
her entire life.
We cannot change her past,
but at least we can give her
a say in her future.
Seventy-five inches?
Sixty wasn't big enough?
You know how it is.
It's never big enough.
Accounting is gonna
raise hell.
Well, we've got to spend
money to make money, right?
Eh, well, let's hope so.
Mmm-hmm.
This for the doctor's lounge?
This way.
Nope.
I'm sorry,
it's for the pizza room.
What's a pizza room?
Motivational tool.
Has he been agitated?
No.
Any need to put him
back in restraints?
No.
Good, let's transfer him up
to the psych ward.
Do you want to examine him
before we do?
Uh, no, no.
I'll check on him upstairs.
Okay.
Hey.
Sarah.
I got this patient in six...
Ataxia, clumsiness,
general malaise.
I can't find anything,
and Abrams cleared him.
Do you want a psych consult?
The guy's convinced
he's sick,
and wasn't happy when
his labs came back normal.
Adamant we keep testing.
Maybe factitious disorder,
likes being in the hospital,
doted on, needs people
to believe he's sick.
Want to take a run at him?
Otherwise, I got
no reason to keep him.
Sure.
Thanks.
Mr. Janichek? I'm Dr. Reese.
I'd like to ask you
a few questions.
What kind of doctor are you?
I am a psychiatrist.
A shrink?
You think I'm crazy?
No, we just can't find
a, uh, physical reason
for the symptoms
you're describing.
Which means you think
I'm crazy or I'm making it up.
No, we just want to explore
all the possibilities.
I don't believe you people.
I'm a sick man.
I come here looking for help,
and no one believes me.
How many doctors
do I have to go to?
Mr. Janichek,
please back away.
What do I have to do, huh?
Why won't you help me?
Mr. Janichek!
Sarah, what happened?
My eyes!
She sprayed me!
Oh, my God.
Get me some water.
Ah, my eyes!
Sarah, you should go.
Go!
Mr. Janichek, just try to
breathe normally, okay?
Dr. Charles isn't answering.
Where are we on this,
Dr. Choi?
We flushed
Mr. Janichek's eyes.
There's no sign
of external injury.
His vitals are stable.
He's lucid.
And extremely pissed off.
A doctor attacking a patient,
really?
Go on, Dr. Choi.
Mr. Janichek
hit the gurney when he fell,
so we're ordering
an abdominal CT
to make sure there's no
internal injuries.
Did he hit his head?
Are you ordering a head scan?
There's no head injury.
No indication of concussion.
Dr. Choi,
this is CYA time.
It's bad enough he sues us
for the pepper spray.
If we miss something...
Order a pan scan.
Yes, ma'am.
Thank you, Dr. Choi.
Dr. Stohl, Peter.
Can you give me any
explanation for your behavior?
I'm sorry.
Dr. Reese, you're suspended
until further notice.
I need your pass.
Go home.
So this is what?
A ploy to woo the paramedics?
Pretty much, yeah.
It'll work.
Mmm, pepperoni and sausage.
Mmm-hmm.
Nice.
Mmm!
Sterilized?
When?
But how?
When you were 14.
When they said they were
taking out your appendix,
they were actually
doing a procedure
called tubal ligation.
Your tubes were tied.
They did this
without asking me?
Did Mama know?
You'll have to ask her that.
Oh, my God.
I'll give you two some time.
How could she ever
forgive her mom?
I lost my baby,
but I can still have another.
If that were
taken away from me,
I don't know
that I could forgive.
I don't know.
People can
sometimes surprise you.
Robin?
Thanks, Dad.
It's gonna be
very hard on Connor.
He cares about you a lot.
I know.
But I have to do this.
I have to get away.
Gonna miss you.
I'm gonna
miss you, too, Dad.
Make sure you remember to say
hi to your mom for me, okay?
Goodbye, honey.
Bye, Dad.
Come in.
Mr. Janichek's scans were
negative for concussion
or any other acute injury.
All right,
dodged that bullet.
But we did notice
something else
unrelated to his
being sprayed.
An enlarged spleen?
Yes.
This our fault?
No.
I ordered an enzyme activity
level test to follow up.
It showed Mr. Janichek
is suffering
from a genetic disorder
called Gaucher's disease.
An enzyme deficiency
which presents
with a vague
constellation of symptoms,
malaise, anemia,
low platelets.
Please tell me
there's a treatment.
Because we cannot
assault a man
and then inform him he has
an incurable disease.
His spleen
is dangerously enlarged,
so it has to be removed,
but the deficiency itself
is easily treatable
with regular
enzyme replacement infusions.
All right.
You'll inform the patient.
Yes, ma'am.
Thank you.
I should say
that Mr. Janichek
will find this
to be good news.
A genetic disease?
He's been suffering
a long time,
unable to find a diagnosis.
In fact, I was ready
to send him home.
We never would have ordered
that pan scan
if Dr. Reese
hadn't done what she did.
She might have saved his life.
Hey.
I got home,
and I found this from Robin.
Did you know that
she was planning on leaving?
Connor, she just made
the decision today.
She doesn't feel like
she can get well here.
And nobody thought to
involve me in this discussion?
Well, she didn't
want to tell you
because she knew
you'd try and change her mind.
You're damn right I would!
Where is she?
It's really up to Robin
to reveal that, I think.
No, you have no right
to keep this from me.
She asked me not to tell you.
Look, Connor,
she promised me she'd call you
as soon as she is
feeling better.
Oh, man, I bet you love this,
don't you?
What?
You didn't want me
to be with her
in the first place.
You didn't think
I was good for her.
In fact, I bet this was
all your idea.
Connor, whatever reservations
I had about your relationship
are long past, okay?
I promise you,
this was all Robin's decision.
Fine. I don't care
if you don't want
to tell me where she is,
because I'm gonna find her,
and I'm gonna
bring her back.
Hey, Dr. Charles.
Thanks, Noah.
What have I done?