Morning.
Are we alone?
I'm alone. Are you?
Thought I heard a woman's voice
during the night.
You eavesdropping?
Ah, just, you know,
kind of hard to miss.
Didn't sound like Hulda.
You want a bagel?
Fresh?
Baked this morning
by elfin hands.
Works all day,
entertains all night,
and he gets up at
sunrise, goes to the bakery.
What's your secret?
I'm a virtuous man.
Good morning, Jer.
And a delightful morning to you.
Fresh buttered popcorn?
Oh, I'm watching
my triglycerides.
Turfed the
slip-and-fall to Ortho.
Well done. Popcorn?
Oh, yum.
Hello! Isn't it a wonderful day?
Good morning, ER!
Are the nitrous
tanks leaking again?
Better. It's Weaver's day off.
And if that's not
cause for celebration,
I don't know what is.
Perfect.
May I have this dance?
Oh, mm.
You guys are bad.
Turn it up.
♪ Oh, happy day ♪
♪ Oh, happy... ♪
Hi. Just getting on?
Yeah. You?
No. No.
I spent all night in the O.R.
A woman with a bowel
obstruction crashed.
Big mess.
And I floated my first
Swan-Ganz catheter.
Wow. You've done a
lot of procedures lately.
Yeah, cut-downs, chest tubes,
opened a coley,
closed an appi...
Benton's bum
finger's the best thing
that ever happened to me.
I even got to staple a stomach,
and Benton just
had to stand there
and watch. Okay?
The look on his
face was classic.
Just...
Carter. I have a new
procedure for you.
Foreign body extraction.
What, uh... kind
of foreign body?
Flashlight. Claims he fell on it
while changing a fuse... naked.
Adoption proceedings can't begin
until 90 days after abandonment,
so assuming we proceed,
the Hallorans would
petition for custody
in early January.
However, they would
like to take Susie
sooner than later.
How much sooner?
End of the week.
They feel the change
would be less traumatic now
than in a month or two.
Right.
I mentioned your wish
to continue to be
part of Susie's life
as her aunt,
and they are willing
to think about it.
Right.
Yes?
Mr. and Mrs. Halloran are here.
I'll come out.
They're nice people,
but there's no reason
to feel that you have to comply
with their timetable
and conditions.
You need to feel comfortable
with the arrangement...
I know.
And you should take
all the time you need.
I don't think time will
make it any easier.
Ready?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, what are their first names?
Kevin and Lisa.
Lisa, Kevin.
Yeah.
Thank you. Oh, we're so excited.
I'd like you to
meet Susan Lewis.
Hello.
Nice to meet you, Susan.
This is Susie.
She's so beautiful.
Thank you.
Do you want to hold her?
Oh. Yes.
Oh.
Oh... You are so precious.
So precious.
Not my shift. Not my shift.
Why are all these
old charts still here?
Dr. Weaver usually
weeds them out.
You can sure tell
when she's not here.
Yeah.
Where's Susan?
She took a personal day.
Huh?
Let there be no doubt,
flu season has arrived.
I have half the board.
One more. Chia-Chia Loew.
Oh, yeah, let me see him.
The little boy with AIDS?
Yeah. He spiked a fever.
He can't even sit
up. I put him in 3.
Kid in 2's done.
You get the French
fry out of his nose?
Yeah. I had to listen to his
mother talking 20 minutes.
I'll be glad when
this splint is off
and I'm back in surgery.
Hey, look at the bright side.
You've been given
a chance to perfect
your cozy bedside
manner. Here's another.
Great.
All yesterday,
he is in bed, throwing up.
He stopped talking.
Mm-hmm. The first
thing we need to do
is get his fever down
and stop the vomiting.
Yes.
In order to know
the right kind of
medicine to give him,
we're going to have to
do a lumbar puncture.
That's where we
take some of the fluid
from around the spine
and we test it to
see what's wrong.
That's what we're
going to do, okay?
Yes, uh... you make him well?
Well, we can't cure the AIDS,
you knew that,
but we'll do what we can
to make him feel better.
Thank you.
It's a piercing sort of pain,
like a spike through the temple.
Mm-hmm.
How long have you
been having migraines?
All my life. You ever get them?
No.
You?
Count your blessings.
I'm going to ask the doctor
about giving you some Imitrex.
Oh, I had that once.
Gave me chest pain.
Okay. In that case, Toradol?
Can't.
Gives me hives,
but they gave me something
here that worked wonders.
Began with a "D."
What was it?
Demerol?
That's it.
Okay.
We'll be right back.
She's sweet.
She's a junkie.
What?
It's a snow job.
She's faking migraines
to get a quick fix.
How can you tell?
If you hang around
as long as I have,
you can smell them.
Have you ever
seen the turkey file?
Hey, Dr. Benton. It still works.
Just kidding.
Different flashlight.
Thought that splint
was supposed to stay on
till tomorrow.
You got that circled
on your calendar?
You know, I handled
a lot of dislocations
when I did my Ortho rotation.
Not interested.
You're risking
permanent joint laxity,
osteoarthritis...
Goodbye, Carter. Tendinitis...
Dr. B., got a lady
here beat up bad.
Can you hear me, hon?
What happened?
Anonymous call.
Found her on the
floor of her house.
Multiple contusions,
bruises to the face and chest,
conscious but unresponsive.
Okay, let's lift her
on my count, people.
Nice and easy. Here we go.
One, two, three.
Do we have a name?
I.D. says Vickie Mazovick.
Vickie, squeeze my hand.
No blood in the canal.
Negative Babinski.
What's wrong with her?
Maybe psychotic.
Vickie, talk to me.
Tell me who did this to you.
All right, can you feel this?
Responds to pain.
Leave me alone!
Damn.
Maybe should have
kept the splint on, huh?
Extensive bruising to the ribs.
Get X-ray. Carter,
how's her chest?
Good bilateral breath sounds.
She's crying.
It's a good sign, I guess.
It's okay, sweetie.
It's okay.
Damn!
What was her last name again?
Krupke.
Krupke, Krupke. Aha.
Krupke, Lottie.
Also known as Kamen, Laura,
also known as Kimball, Myrna.
Addicted to narcotics,
alcoholic, bipolar.
God, this is sad.
No, what's sad is
when they con you
out of five or six doses
before you catch on.
Then you really
feel like a chump.
Nurse Hathaway?
Uh, Carol.
E. Ray Bozman. I'm
your nurse trainee.
Oh, yes, right. Come on in.
Grab a lab coat
under the counter.
I'll be with you in a second.
Mark? I've got to do an LP
on a 4-year-old.
I could use a hand.
Harper, you ever seen an LP?
No, but I'd like to.
I don't really want to babysit
a med student right now.
Well, it's either Harper
or the guy wearing
Morgenstern's lab coat.
Harper, let's do it.
Yeah, they seemed like
nice people, didn't they?
Yeah?
Smart, funny, not so
perfect. They're obnoxious,
and they have a little boy.
Yeah, huh? You could
have a big brother.
Someone to look out
for you, teach you stuff.
Oh, Susie...
This is so hard.
I just don't think I'd be
a good enough mother.
We have ways of screwing
kids up in my family.
I just want you to be happy.
I love you. You know that?
I do.
Oh, God.
Orbit's okay. No fracture.
She's got a cracked rib.
Two cracked ribs,
two healed fractures.
Old shoulder
fracture, humerus...
Hey, you put your
splint back on.
Wise choice.
She said anything yet?
No.
Uh, actually, she did to me.
She told me she
wanted to go home.
Not a good idea. She's
been here three times before.
First time, she said
it was her husband,
but wouldn't press charges.
How about the
second and third time?
Said she fell down the stairs.
All right, call the
social worker.
Give Mrs. Mazovick
some Vicodin for the pain
and tell her to follow
up with her doctor.
You're not going to talk to her?
Not my job.
All right, kiddo.
Let's get started.
Okay, here we
go. Let's get going.
Hi, Chia-Chia.
Hold onto the
back of his thighs.
With your other hand,
you hold him on
the back of his neck.
Lean over.
Mm-hmm. Hold on tight.
No. No.
Now, buddy, your mom tells me
you like to play with
the neighbor's dog.
Mama. It's okay.
No, no, no.
You have to hold him tight.
Okay.
Shh. Shh.
Shh, shh, shh.
That's just to numb it. The
next one won't be so bad.
Now, when I was a kid...
I had a dog named Louis.
No, no, no.
Louis the dog.
You're doing great.
There we go.
Doing great.
He stopped moving.
Yeah.
He's surrendered.
Just a little more.
Not much longer.
Jerry, if anybody calls for me,
I'll be up in the
O.R. with Dr. Hicks.
Okay.
Is it lighter in here?
Did they repaint?
The Weaver has lifted.
Ah. Cake?
Uh, sure.
Subtle.
What's going on?
Uh, birthday party.
Oh, yeah? Whose birthday?
Bob's.
Bob's not working today.
Well, it's still her birthday.
Well, in that case,
how about a piece?
Sorry. It's all gone.
Hey there.
Man, was that no fun.
What?
LP on a little kid.
Always rough.
I'm on my way to resect a bowel.
Want to get some
lunch after that?
Sorry. I got to ride
herd on this kid.
How about dinner?
Possibly. Possibly?
Possibly.
Carter... Mm-hmm?
You and Harper,
something extracurricular
happening there?
Mmm...
Dr. Greene.
Loretta, how have you been?
Oh, lousy. I threw my back out.
How?
At work.
Jerry, can you start a chart?
Lydia? Come on. Coming.
So this is like a mid-life
career shift for you?
Yeah. I tend to shift a lot.
I've been a UPS delivery man,
a short-order cook,
a rodeo clown,
and then, in the mid '80s,
I got into the
human-potential movement.
Doing what?
Lectures,
inspirational speeches.
I'm a nurturer.
I like helping
people, so nursing
seemed like the
next logical step
in my life progression.
Okay, Mr. Keller.
You can take a seat right here.
There you go.
Great.
All right, I want you
to shave his head,
clean and irrigate the wound.
I'm going to start a chart
and get a doctor to stitch him.
Okey-dokey.
Dr. Ross. I went to pick up
Chia-Chia's lab results.
Mm-hmm.
They did a cell count,
differential, protein, glucose,
Gram's stain, and culture,
but they ran out of fluid
before they did
the India Ink stain.
I don't believe it.
Is that the test for the
cryptococcal meningitis?
Yes, yes.
Okay, tell me if this hurts.
Keep your leg straight.
It's okay.
I don't see any sign
of a slipped disc.
Just a muscle strain.
You need to stay off your feet.
No problem.
I mean bed rest, Loretta.
Emphasis on "rest."
Gotcha. Ooh.
It still hurts like
hell, though.
Can we give her something?
Yeah, I'll write
her a prescription
for Feldene.
Ooh, that ought to do the trick.
Dr. Greene?
Dr. Lewis is here to see you.
Loretta, take care.
It figures this
would happen today.
I was supposed to
have a job interview.
Really?
Yeah, answering phones
for a place that makes
clothes and stuff.
The social worker
put me up to it.
Sounds like a good job.
I never get these
things, though.
They take one look at
me, they know the score.
I wonder how.
We have a closet
full of clothes here.
You could see if
there's anything
right for an interview.
What do you got clothes for?
Whoever needs them.
Where do you get them from?
Dead people, mostly.
Oh, you've gotta be kidding me.
No, there's some nice stuff.
We get some pretty
rich dead people.
Okay. We need to do
another lumbar puncture
on Chia-Chia. Another?
Mei-Sun, I'm sorry, and if
there were any other way,
I would do it.
It's just going to
be a small amount.
Not as much as before.
Okay?
I'm sorry.
I met with a lawyer today
about putting Susie
up for adoption.
Really? Is it definite?
Before I make my final decision,
I need to know
what my options are
here at work.
If I keep her, there's no way
I could continue to do
my residency full-time.
Could I do it part-time?
Uh, I'll look into it. Have
you heard from Chloe?
No.
Look, it's been nuts
around here lately.
You want to get some coffee?
No, Mark, I don't.
I need to know if a
part-time schedule's doable.
I've only heard of
that in Pediatrics.
So it's not?
I don't know.
I'll talk to Morgenstern
and see if we can
work something out.
I appreciate it.
You beeped me out
of a bowel resection
to sew up a drunk?
Benton said you
liked doing procedures.
Ha. Very funny.
Whoa.
Oh, my God.
Almost done.
E. Ray...
why did you shave
his entire head
for a four-centimeter lac?
Mr. Keller and I
have been talking
about how to effect
positive change in one's life
and how changing the physical
can be a symbolic first step
in transforming the inner self.
You Benton?
Mm-hmm.
McGillis. Social Services.
I'm confused about
your chart notes
on Vickie Mazovick, the
woman who got beat up.
Mm-hmm.
You didn't note
whether she had injuries
to her hands and arms.
She didn't.
Could you note that, please?
It could be significant.
If I thought it was significant,
I would have written it down.
It suggests she
didn't defend herself,
which suggests she's given up,
which means statistically
she's reached a stage
where she's in
danger of being killed.
You didn't note what she said
when you asked
her what happened.
I didn't ask her what happened.
Did you suspect abuse?
Of course I did.
I saw the chart.
Then you're supposed to ask.
So, what did she tell you?
Nothing.
So what makes you think
she's going to tell me anything?
It's worth a try,
don't you think?
Oh, this would look good on you.
Maybe not.
It doesn't really quite fit.
What do you
mean? It looks great.
Do you think so?
Oh, yeah, but it,
uh... needs something.
You see some stuff
working here, I bet.
Oh, like you don't?
My clients don't die on me...
except for that one guy.
That's it.
Do you think so?
Mm.
Doing another LP?
Yeah, lab forgot
to do an India Ink,
so I'm gonna tap
out a couple CCs
and do the test myself.
How's he holding up?
Not well.
This is going to be quick.
It's only going to
take a few minutes.
Hi, Chia-Chia.
How's it going?
Yeah, get him over on his side.
Mrs. Mazovick? I'm Dr. Benton.
I need to ask you
a few questions
about how you got hurt.
I fell.
Mrs. Mazovick, there are
people that can help you.
I don't want any help.
Okay. Uh...
I'm still going to
have to report it
to the police.
Won't do any good.
Put three drops in there
and then a drop of ink.
Then you slide it
under the microscope.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
You did really well in there.
Better the second
time than the first.
Does it get easier?
No. Catch that light.
I thought Pediatrics
was the happy specialty.
Most of the time.
Okay. Here you go.
What do you see?
Hmm. Yeast cells.
Some larger
capsules around them.
Cryptococcus.
He has cryptococcal meningitis?
Yeah. He's getting near the end.
I need somebody
to call the police
to report a suspected
case of domestic abuse.
You got it.
Carter, where you going?
Oh, Dr. Morgenstern is
doing a hemicolectomy.
He asked me to
make the incision.
Hmm. Uh-uh. Not today.
Guy in 6 cut his finger.
Uh-oh.
Please! Please! I need help!
Get a gurney! You're
going to need help.
I've got it, Carter.
What if you have
to do a cutdown?
I've got it! Where are you hurt?
It's not me. It's my
husband. He's in the car.
What happened?
He was on his motorcycle
outside our apartment,
and a truck hit
him and took off.
All right, let's get him
out. Let's get him out.
Come on.
Oh, man, that's a lot of blood.
Is he dead?
No, he's still breathing.
I tried to get him
here as fast as I could.
I ran red lights.
You did the right thing.
He's hypovolemic.
He's gonna need
at least six units.
Wait a minute! Where's his arm?
It's in the back seat!
Oh, my God.
It is the same thing
he had before?
Yes, he's, um...
He's had a relapse.
He's very sick.
Now, the best way
to treat him now
Is to give him
a high concentration of
medication intrathecally.
Which means?
It means that we're going to do
the same procedure
as the spinal tap,
but in reverse.
Again?
It's the only way to
get a high enough dose
of the medication.
One more time.
No, it has to be a full course.
That means two times a day
for 10 days.
We'll admit him
into the hospital.
We'll put a
catheter in his back.
That way, he won't have to
have the puncture each time.
It will stop the
vomiting and the fever?
If he responds to
the medication, yes.
Once his body
has fought off the meningitis,
it'll be able to work harder
against the AIDS.
If you think this is the
best thing for Chia-Chia.
I do, yes.
I work at Daly Plaza,
and my wife works at
the Merchandise Mart,
so we got together
for a picnic lunch
by the fountain
at, uh, lunch hour.
Sounds nice.
It was, until I decided
to cut the French bread
with my Swiss Army knife.
I knew I should
have gotten soft crust.
How long have you had
that mole on your arm?
Oh, a while.
Actually looks a little bigger
than the last
time I looked at it.
If you want,
I can excise it
and run tests on it,
just to be safe.
What does that involve?
Give you an anaesthetic,
surgically remove it.
Won't take long.
All right.
Yeah? Great.
I'll just run it past
the Attending,
and I will be right back.
Yes!
Hang three units O-neg.
Put it on the infuser.
He's still bleeding.
Inflate the BP cuff to 150.
What's going on, Peter?
Hit-and-run amputation.
He's hypovolemic.
Where's the arm?
Wrapped and on ice.
Get a vascular
surgeon down here.
Someone call the
Reimplantation Team.
Don't get a pulse.
He's bradying down.
Tube him.
Not with this finger.
ET tray.
Epi?
Atropine.
One milligram, IV push.
Number eight.
I got a pulse.
BP's 50 palp.
Well, that's something.
Okay, hang another
two units O-neg.
Pack. We'll move him
as soon as he's tubed.
All right. Let's move him.
Cookie, the door.
Who is it?
It's me, Mom.
Oh, do you have the baby?
Yeah.
Just a second.
Smile.
Mom...
you bought a video camera.
Well, if you're going
to be a grandma,
you may as well do it right.
Thing cost a fortune.
No wonder there's
a trade deficit.
Mom, would you do that later?
Don't be such a grouch.
Turn around. Smile for Grandma.
Well, I need to sit down.
Sit. Give me the little termite.
Come on. Come on.
Okay. Yeah. There you go.
Look up, up, up.
Uh...
I need to talk to you guys.
Look. Hi!
Mom?
Oh, she's so cute. Mom?
A-booga-booga-booga.
Look at that.
Dad. Oh, honey.
I'm listening.
I met with a lawyer
today about...
giving Susie up for adoption.
But she's not even your baby.
Mom, Chloe is never coming back.
Would you turn that thing off?
I don't know how you
could even consider that.
You really don't want to
give her away, do you?
No, of course I don't.
It kills me to
even think about it.
Then don't.
How am I supposed
to raise her alone
and finish my residency?
People do these things
all the time, don't they?
Dad, I work 12-hour
shifts, five days a week.
And I am not going to put
her in day care for that long.
Well, there must be
something you can do.
Well, could you guys keep
her three days a week?
Maybe we could do
it. Three days a week?
Oh, sure. We all
know what that means.
I'll be doing all the
work, running around...
Wait a minute. I'm here.
You haven't left this
house in six years.
You hardly ever even
leave that damn chair.
I'm retired. You make me
sound like some kind of a nut.
It's not normal.
Well, at least I
don't drink all day.
Two vodka gimlets for
breakfast? That is a lie.
Whose Path report is this?
Finger lac in 6.
I saw a growth on his arm,
convinced him
to let me test it...
Melanoma.
Bingo, and I found an
axillary lymph node on exam.
It needs to be excised.
I already spoke with Peirrera
over in Surgical Oncology,
and he agreed to
let me do the biopsy.
Peter, cop's in
with Mrs. Mazovick,
in case you want to talk to him.
Right.
I just picked up an
interesting case, I think.
Yeah? Yeah.
I excised a mole on
a 36-year-old male.
Turns out it's melanoma,
and I get to biopsy
the lymph node.
A 36-year-old has cancer,
and you get to do the biopsy.
Well, congratulations.
Well,
I hope you have an easier time
convincing Mrs. Mazovick
to make a statement
than I did.
And who are you?
I'm Dr. Benton.
I was in charge of
her case, Officer...
Mazovick.
Come on, babe. Let's go.
What goes through your head
when you're beating her?
Hmm?
What a big man you are?
Michael, please.
Please.
Your husband just
went up to the O.R.
They're trying to
reattach his arm.
They can do that?
Well, they can try.
With complete amputation,
the success rate's small.
But we only have insurance left
for three days.
I wouldn't worry
about that right now.
They'll cover it.
But Jason lost his
job three months ago,
benefits, too,
and I'm a waitress, no benefits.
Is there somebody
I can call for you?
Oh, no, no, thanks.
I keep having this weird thought
that Jason's dead
and you're just not telling me.
He isn't, is he?
No. He's in the O.R.
You're just feeling the stress.
Carrie,
would you like to
come and lie down
in the lounge?
No.
No, thank you.
How are you doing, Mr. Forchet?
I'm starting to worry
a little bit, actually.
Is something wrong?
Dr. Carter, they said
you might need some help
with a lymph node biopsy?
Ah...
A biopsy?
Do I have cancer?
Mr. Forchet, your
mole was identified
as a malignant melanoma.
Oh, my God.
No, no. The good
news is that we caught it,
which means we can
start treatment immediately.
What's the worst-case scenario?
There's really no
way to gauge that
until we stage the
cancer and see if it's...
uh, spread...
which is why we're
going to do the biopsy.
I can't believe this.
I mean, I came in here
for a cut on my finger,
and...
I need to call my wife.
I, uh...
How am I going to tell her?
What am I going to say?
It's okay.
I can't believe
this is happening.
I know. I know. That's it.
Just let it out and
work through it.
So in your opinion,
the injuries resulted
from some kind of battery?
Yep, no question.
Are you willing to testify
if we need you?
Well, I guess.
You think that's
going to happen?
It's up to her, you know?
She won't make a statement.
There's no other witnesses.
Not much I can do to help her.
And the fact that he's a cop,
does that make a difference?
No, not to me.
You seen these?
First time she came in,
missing two teeth, broken jaw.
Second time, bruises
across her back and buttocks,
third time, broken arm,
and these? These are from today.
She used to work
Dispatch at the 14th.
You know her?
Used to.
Doug? Hey.
I signed for that amphotericin B
you ordered for Chia-Chia.
I got it. Thank you.
What's the plan?
The plan is to do
everything I can
to buy that kid and his mother
some more time together.
He didn't respond to the
amphotericin the last time.
This time I'm gonna
give it to him intrathecally.
That's a pretty rough procedure,
especially on a four-year-old.
What are you saying, Mark?
I'm just wondering
if the treatment's too extreme
for the best prognosis
you can hope to get.
Not in my opinion.
Okay. Okay.
Yeah, hey.
Hey, can you see?
Can you see?
Do you remember the
nice lady from this morning?
Do you want to go on the slide?
Let's go on the slide.
What do you think?
You designed that yourself?
Yeah. You can swim in it,
or you can wrap a
scarf around your waist
and wear it out on the town.
Who does she mean by "you"?
I'm meeting with
investors next week
about designing a whole line.
I'm going to call it Randi-Wear.
Catchy.
Oh, well, you want to invest,
now is the time.
On that note,
I will bid you all
a fond good eve.
It's been a wonderful
Weaver-less day.
Nighty-night.
Is he single?
Yeah.
Carrie, your husband's
out of surgery.
They were able
to reattach his arm.
You...
You said the chances of
that happening were small.
Well, we're not out
of the woods yet.
We still have to wait
and see if the tissue
can survive the trauma.
Do you have any Valium
in there or something?
Well, I can't give you
anything without a prescription,
but I can start
a chart for you...
No, that's okay. No.
I'm gonna... try
a cigarette first.
You can't...
smoke in here.
Oh, yeah.
Carrie?
This is good news.
Yeah. It's great.
Excuse me. Mrs. Loew?
Uh, yes?
I'm Dr. Greene.
I'm the Attending
Physician here in the E.R.
I'd like to talk to
you about Chia-Chia.
Uh...
something is wrong
with Chia-Chia?
No, no, no.
I was talking with Dr. Ross
about the treatment
you agreed to.
I wanted to make sure
that you understood
everything that was involved.
Yes.
The side effects of the
medicine can be very painful...
worse, sometimes, than the
symptoms of the meningitis.
Worse?
Yes.
I want to be sure that you know
that if you don't want
to go through that,
we can give you medicine
to make him comfortable.
You can take him home.
But, uh... he will be sick.
Mrs. Loew, the fact that the
medicine failed once before
means that there's
a strong possibility
that it may fail again.
Even if we could
cure the meningitis,
your son's AIDS
is very advanced.
With or without
treatment, realistically,
we're really only looking
at a matter of days.
I'm sorry.
You need to decide
how you and your son
want to spend those days.
But, uh, Dr. Ross...
But...
he...
he said...
You went over his aftercare?
I did.
Mr. Lubow needs
his boil drained.
And we got a fresh
trauma pulling in.
Carter, you take him.
Lydia, did you take
the syringe in Room 2?
No. Why?
I just lost five
milligrams of morphine.
What do we have?
This cop is beat up pretty bad.
He's missing teeth.
Look like his jaw's broke.
Busted ribs.
What's his name?
Mazovick.
How did it happen?
He was in pursuit of a
suspect and took a bad fall.
All right, let's get
his clothes off.
Let's get an oral
surgeon down here
and wire his teeth.
We got a mandible
fracture. Call X-ray.
Crepitus on the right.
Absent breath sound.
Collapsed lung?
Chest-tube tray coming up.
All right, prep and drape him.
See you around, Doc.
Number 10 blade?
Yeah.
"Christopher Robin had
wheezles and sneezles.
"They bundled him into his bed.
"They gave him what
goes with a cold in the nose
and some more for
the cold in his head."
A.A. Milne?
Now We Are Six.
Eeyore was my favorite.
Tigger.
So it's time to get started?
Yeah, would you just
slide that tray
over here for me?
Hey.
We were just getting started.
I want to take him home.
Now?
Yes.
We... we discussed this.
Now, this is a
painful procedure,
but it's the best shot we have
of buying him more time.
I don't want him
to have more pain.
I want him home with me.
Okay.
Do you think I make
a bad decision?
No, I think you're
making the right decision.
Thank you.
Hmm.
I'm gonna get the medication
to make sure he's
comfortable at home.
Carol, you got to come see this.
It won't stop coming out.
It won't stop...
Well, found my missing morphine.
I have to get this clean.
It's Jason's favorite.
There was so much... blood.
I guess we'd better
find her a bed.
Yeah, and some Narcan.
He said it'd be easy, but
the ax wasn't sharp enough.
What did she say?
Something about an ax.
We only had three
days left on the policy.
Oh, my God.
What?
Her boyfriend's arm.
They chopped it off?
Chop, chop.
Oh, Lordy.
Five bucks says she's in there.
"Carlisle, Denner, Dougherty..."
"Diehl, Carrie."
Oh, man.
She's been in here
half a dozen times.
Drug seeking, narcotics OD.
I missed it.
And husband.
Honey, you were burned.
Five bucks.
Mark, you went behind my back.
You lost perspective.
You had no right
to go to my patient
and to tell her
what you thought she should do.
I have an obligation
to make sure
patients have the
information they need
to make decisions
about treatment.
That's my job.
I'll tell you, why don't
you just spare me
your Attending Oath of Office?
We're talking about
a 4-year-old here.
A 4-year-old
with end-stage AIDS,
who you wanted to put
through a torturous procedure
the last few days of his life.
You don't know that.
Nobody knows that.
Oh, no, of course not.
There's always the
possibility of a miracle, Doug.
I thought we were
practicing medicine here.
I'll tell you something,
if it was your kid,
if it was your kid, you
would bet on a miracle.
Lydia, I got it!
The job? Yes!
Oh, Loretta, that's great.
You are looking at a
real live receptionist.
Oh, I knew you could do
it. I am so happy for you.
I beat out five other girls.
Of course, I had to
do the guy, but hey,
I got the job!
You okay?
Oh, I'm a mess.
Yeah, me too.
You were a big help
today. Thank you.
I was going to thank you.
For what?
For giving you a front-row seat
to the...
the limitations of
modern medicine?
For what it's worth,
I think you were right
to keep trying today.
All my medical school
professors told me
that County was full of
burnouts that didn't care.
Well, they got the
burnout part right.
What do you do
after a day like today?
I tend to drink, but I'm
not the best role model.
I wouldn't mind a drink.
♪ Blackbird singing
In the dead of night ♪
♪ Take these broken
wings And learn to fly ♪
Hello.
Stopped by your apartment.
Am I interrupting?
No. Pull up a swing.
I talked to Morgenstern.
He said he'd
present your request
to the Residency Committee.
Sounds like he
wasn't too thrilled.
You ever seen
Morgenstern thrilled?
No.
He agreed to consider
it. That's something.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
I'm keeping her.
That's terrific.
I'm so glad.
You need any
tips on parenting...
You're the last person I'd call.
Thank you.
Oh, would you hold her?
Sure. Come here.
Ah. Yes! Hello.
What's your Aunt
Susie doing, huh?
Look at her. Hello.
Look at her go.
Hello.
She's silly, isn't she?
Ah!
Your Aunt Susie's loopy.
Can you believe she's a doctor?
Can you? No.