I would've
done the dishes.
You cooked, it's only fair
that I clean.
It takes you longer
to get ready.
Is that what this is
really about?
You just being considerate?
What do you mean?
Don't think I don't notice.
What?
Navy OCD.
Every single time I wash
a dish, you come behind me
to wash it again.
I do that?
Yes, you do.
No, I don't.
I don't do that.
Ethan.
Em, what's going on?
Uh, I got evicted.
What happened this time?
I didn't pay the rent.
Hmm.
It was an act of protest.
The landlord wouldn't fix
the sink.
That's not right.
Can I crash at your place?
Please?
No.
Just for a couple days.
No!
Ethan.
This is your sister.
What is she supposed to do?
Sleep on the street?
There's no one else
you can stay with?
No.
The place is clean.
I expect to find it that way
when we get home.
You will.
That means no friends.
No parties.
I promise.
Ah, thank you, thank you.
Thank you, thank you,
thank you.
You happy?
Please!
My daughter needs help!
Can you help us?
Please.
I don't know what's wrong
with her.
I'm not gonna hurt you, okay?
Take it easy.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Dr. Charles.
Dr. Haywood.
Are you all right?
No, I'm not all right.
I'm having ectopic heartbeats.
They just doubled my Lasix.
What do I need to do for you
to put me on that
transplant list?
Look, as we discussed,
I can't put anyone
on the list.
I just make a recommendation.
Have you thought about...
Yeah, yeah, I get it.
I get it.
I know what you want me to do.
Bob.
Sarah.
I reconnected with you only
to take advantage of you,
and that did not work out.
I'm no longer asking you
to take care of me
or support me.
I no longer want to be a part
of your life.
We're done.
It's not personal.
It's just the way I'm wired.
Understand?
Good.
There.
Honesty. Self-sufficiency.
Fiscal responsibility.
I think I checked
all the boxes.
I need a psych consult.
Twenty-eight-year-old female,
father found her tied to a bed
at his ex-wife's house.
Some lacerations,
pressure sores.
She's extremely dehydrated.
Dr. Reese, if you need
to take a moment...
No, no.
No, I'm fine.
I'm Dr. Charles.
Can you tell me what happened
to your daughter?
It's my crazy ex-wife.
She's been unbalanced before,
but...
Where's my daughter?
Ma'am, you can't...
Katherine!
You were keeping her
prisoner.
Are you insane?
You had no right
to kidnap her.
My daughter needs to be
discharged immediately.
I'm afraid we can't do that.
It's nothing you can
help her with.
I need to get her home now.
You're torturing her!
No, I am not the one
who's harming her.
Who is?
Who is harming her?
The demon
we've been trying
to exorcise.
The mom-wrath! Mom-wrath!
You see?
My daughter is possessed!
She's possessed!
So Ms. Campbell, when did
your daughter
start having these symptoms?
About nine months ago.
And was she experiencing any
emotional stress at the time?
I'm sorry, why are you
speaking to her
as if she's a rational person?
Mr. Ferris, please.
No.
She had just made partner
at her firm,
was seeing a nice guy.
Then out of nowhere, she began
acting strangely.
She couldn't leave the house,
couldn't work.
She couldn't take care
of herself,
and so I brought her home.
There are a couple of tests
that I'd like to run.
There's no point.
I have taken her to countless
doctors, psychiatrists.
They have run all the tests.
No one can figure out
what is wrong with her.
So exorcism is the answer.
It was starting to work.
She was starting to come back.
Look, I am not
a religious person.
But I have exhausted
every other option.
Katherine wets the bed.
She speaks in tongues,
shouts at empty rooms.
There is no such thing
as demonic possession!
I am not interested
in your opinion.
I want her discharged
immediately.
I think it's safe to say
that your daughter
is a potential threat
to herself,
and it would be my advice
to commit her,
at least temporarily until we
can figure out
what's going on.
I have power of attorney over
my daughter's medical care,
and if you put her on
a psychiatric hold,
I will have my lawyer
down here.
Ms. Campbell, your daughter
is severely dehydrated
and malnourished.
At least let us hang
some IV fluids
until we stabilize her.
As soon as she's rehydrated,
I am taking her home.
Dr. Reese, can you please
take Mr. Ferris
to the consultation room?
Thank you.
I love my daughter.
I am sure that you have her
best interest at heart.
Thank you.
We are going to take care
of Katherine as quickly
as we possibly can.
In the meantime,
why don't you try
and get yourself comfortable
in the waiting room.
Thank you.
What are you thinking?
Um, well, the mom seems
kind of rational.
Last possession case
I read about,
the underlying issue
was actually neurological.
I think maybe we could sneak
her in for a quick MRI,
see if we can cross it
off the list?
Yeah, I'll let radiology know
she's coming.
Okay.
Foreign.
I was gonna grab a cup
of coffee.
You free?
Oh, thanks, but I actually
just had
my third cup of the day.
Think I've had
enough caffeine.
Probably.
Excuse me.
Uh, Dr. Frisch is on her way,
but can someone take a look at
my daughter?
Her fever seems worse.
Sure.
I'll see you later.
Hi, I'm Dr. Manning.
It's Lily.
I called Dr. Frisch because
she was short of breath.
The girls are her patients.
Lily's fingers are cold.
You know,
when one girl's
sick,
it might be best not to keep
her in such close contact
with her sister.
We don't really have
a choice.
Which one's Lily?
Lily's on the left.
Hey, Maggs.
Hey.
Your hearing's today?
Yeah. This afternoon.
Ms. Goodwin wanted me to come
early to prep.
I'm sure it'll all work out.
Yeah, I don't know.
If they decide to report me
to IDPH,
I could lose my
nursing license.
Don't go there yet.
Yeah.
Thanks.
Um, Mr. Blalock?
Why are you roaming around?
I saw you.
I just wanted to say hello.
Hello.
Let's get you situated.
You look funny out of scrubs.
Aren't you working today?
No.
Monique?
Maggie.
Are you back?
Working on it.
There you go.
Mr. Blalock has emphysema
and comes in regularly
to be treated with Atrovent
and Solu-Medrol.
Until his treatment,
he's weak
and a fall risk.
He should have
a yellow bracelet.
Sure. Okay.
You stay in bed till after
your treatment, Mr. Blalock.
Where you going?
Hopefully I'll see you later.
Okay.
Sharon.
Yeah?
I was just on my way up
to see you.
Head on up and make yourself
comfortable.
I'll catch up with you soon.
All right. Hey.
Todd.
Marcy.
Ms. Goodwin, hi.
Dr. Rhodes. Dr. Frisch.
I see you have met
the Cronin twins.
Yep.
They're scheduled for
separation surgery
in ten weeks.
The hospital has assembled
a team
from 12 different departments.
Dr. Frisch is their
pediatric cardiologist.
How are they doing?
I detected scattered rhonchi
in both of Lily's lungs.
Intercostal and
thoracoabdominal retractions.
I'm thinking pneumonia,
but I was about to order
a babygram and a CBC.
Thank you, Dr. Manning.
We'll handle it from here.
Sure.
Let's get 'em up
to the PICU.
I want a transthoracic echo
and an EKG.
And blood and sputum
cultures.
All right, you two.
Let's get going.
Mr. Tucker.
I'm Dr. Halstead.
Hello.
Hi.
Tell me how you're feeling.
Call me Malcolm.
I'm fine.
He gave us quite a scare.
I just need my antibiotics.
Says you've got acute
abdominal pain
and shortness of breath.
Just the belly pain.
The shortness of breath
came on only 'cause I knew
I was dropping at least
a grand on that
ambulance ride.
Dad, can you please stop
complaining
about the ambulance?
So you're not short
of breath?
Maybe a little.
It's probably from the drive.
We just drove in from
Cincinnati to visit our boy.
He just started at
Northwestern this fall.
Congratulations.
Thanks.
Good school.
A scholarship would've
been nice.
Malcolm.
Sorry.
Genius that I am,
I left my antibiotics,
the Flagyl,
at home.
Why are you taking Flagyl?
Diverticulitis.
Look, we're supposed to have
a tour of the campus
in a few hours, so could you
just refill my antibiotics
and we can get out of here.
Well, shortness of breath
isn't usually
a symptom of diverticulitis,
so I need to see what's going
on with that.
I want to run a few tests.
Whoa. What's that gonna cost?
Dad.
Stop being a pain.
You have insurance.
I just want to make sure
we're not dealing with
something else.
Okay.
But just the bare minimum.
This echo shows
significant dilation
of both the right
and left ventricles.
If we look here, at Twin A...
For the record,
Twin A is Lily.
The aortic stenosis
has significantly diminished
forward flow
and has compromised ejection
fraction to 19%.
You're saying, essentially,
that she's in heart failure.
She will die within
the next few hours
without intervention, yes.
And if she does,
she takes Dot with her.
We need to consider moving up
the separation surgery.
We're not prepared.
We haven't rehearsed
the procedure.
And even if we had,
it's not an option.
The surgery is scheduled for
when it is
so the twins can grow.
Well, I'm not taking the word
of a couple fellows.
Page Dr. Latham.
He's gonna tell you
the same thing.
The twins aren't robust enough
yet to survive the surgery.
Go.
The surgery involves
separating the twins'
chest wall and reconstructing
their shared atrium.
However, we still don't have
a clear enough image
of their liver's venous system
to determine
if it can be split.
In addition, Lily is now
immunocompromised.
If you had to estimate
the odds of success...
At this point?
That both survive?
Zero.
Lily is not strong enough.
But if we concentrated
all of our efforts on Dot,
would we be able to save her?
Yes, I believe so.
Hold on a second.
Are we actually discussing
terminating Lily's life?
We are discussing the best
course of action.
Well, if as Dr. Krasny said,
the problem is Lily's
underlying condition,
we should be addressing that.
You mean take them to
the cath lab?
Exactly.
We widen Lily's aortic valve,
increase her blood flow.
Too risky.
We still don't have
a real grasp
of the twins'
vascular anatomy...
The routing,
how open the lumen is.
We're just guessing
until we open them up.
I completely agree we need
a better roadmap.
That's why we should first
perform a transesophageal
echo.
You want to put the twins
under general anesthesia...
Waste one of the few hours
we might have left...
So you can get
a better roadmap
for a procedure too risky
to even try?
Dr. Latham, care to wrangle
your fellow?
Having to surrender
a child is tragic.
I'd be remiss if we didn't
exhaust every opportunity
to try to save her.
I second Dr. Rhodes'
recommendation.
All right.
Let's get the echo.
Dr. Rhodes, Dr. Bekker,
a moment.
If we are successful in saving
both the twins,
and the separation surgery can
go as scheduled,
I have decided to name
Dr. Rhodes as my second.
Dr. Bekker, I'd still like you
to be prepared as backup.
Of course.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
So I've written down
a few notes
explaining the situation.
It may not be necessary.
Peter?
So what if I told you
that when you cric'd
Jill Fisher,
you weren't acting as a nurse
but as a licensed paramedic?
I don't get it.
As a nurse you're not
permitted to cric a patient.
You haven't been trained
to do so.
But as a medic?
You received state-approved
training
on how to perform
a cricothyrotomy.
So you were not acting
out of scope.
You were acting
as a licensed paramedic.
Your license is still valid,
I hope.
Yes, I have it at home.
Good. Go get it.
Bring it to the hearing.
Okay, now, there is
a wild card.
Because if the Fishers were
to file suit, this would
all be moot,
and the hospital would have
no choice but to sanction you.
But there's been no
legal action taken,
so keep your fingers crossed.
I will. Thank you.
Thank you both so much.
It's very often
emotional distress
that triggers this kind of
dissociative state.
What kind of
emotional distress?
We were hoping
you could tell us.
To be honest,
we had just begun
to reestablish
a relationship.
I hadn't seen Kat much after
I split with her mother
twenty-two years ago.
Hmm. Why not?
Well, it was a pretty ugly
divorce.
I mean, you've seen how
unstable my ex-wife is.
After we split, she poisoned
my relationship with Kat.
And...
That's really
my biggest regret,
is that I let Samantha push me
out of my daughter's life.
Once I reconnected with Kat,
I swore to her that I would
never let that happen again.
And when was that,
you two reconnecting?
About a year ago,
I reached out to her.
And what prompted that?
I had a heart attack.
And it nearly killed me.
And I swore that I needed to
make up for lost time,
so I would fly in
once in a while.
We went to dinner.
And then she moves back in
with my ex-wife
and then stops returning
my calls and then
I get worried.
And so I fly out here to see
what's going on and...
And now it's all this.
What if Katherine's suffering
from severe separation
anxiety?
From her father?
She lost him once
in the divorce.
He has a heart attack.
She almost loses him again.
Well, according to his
version of events,
I guess that's certainly
possible.
Yeah, I don't know where it
leaves us, though.
It's not like we can get
someone in Katherine's state
to open up.
So Malcolm,
your labs are back,
and I don't think you were
correctly diagnosed.
How is that possible?
I think your
previous physician
was thrown by
the abdominal pain.
But I don't believe we're
looking at diverticulitis.
Then what are we looking at?
I'm not sure yet.
I need to get a CT
of your chest and abdomen.
No way.
Just discharge me, I'll figure
this out when I get home.
Wait, Dad.
This could be serious.
I'm gonna have to agree
with your son.
Just get me my pills,
all right?
Just get me the hell...
Dad?
Malcolm!
Oh, God.
Lean back, Mr. Tucker.
Just breathe.
His oxygen saturation
is dropping.
Up his O2 to five liters.
What's happening?
There's fluid in his lungs.
Set me up for a chest tube.
Give him two of Versed.
Got it.
Hang in there.
Oh! What is that?
Lymphatic fluid.
It was putting pressure
on his lung.
He must have ruptured
his thoracic duct.
Ruptured? How?
I don't know.
Has he been in a car accident
recently?
No, nothing like that.
Well, the duct could have
been damaged due to
an inflammatory disease
or a tumor... Let's go.
Maybe heart failure.
You're saying he either has
cancer or heart failure?
Mrs. Tucker, these are all
just possibilities.
We need to run more tests.
Just help my dad!
Her IV bag is almost empty.
Clock's ticking. We're gonna
have to discharge her.
Okay.
We got to buy
a little more time.
April, hang another bag
of saline.
Ease her off sedation.
I want her as lucid
as possible
when I talk to her.
You're gonna try
talk therapy?
I thought she was
too volatile for that.
Well, I wasn't planning on
necessarily getting
a whole lot of help from
Katherine.
You're gonna talk to
the demon?
What choice do we have?
If she's locked in
a dissociative state
because of some
repressed trauma,
I mean, maybe, you know,
the demon
can give us a clue that might
help us unlock her.
Did I just hear them say
they're going to talk to
a demon?
Speaking of which, I wonder
what my sister's doing.
Think she's burned
my apartment
down yet?
I actually called her
to check in.
And?
She wanted to know where
the laundry detergent is,
even asked if we had anything
we wanted her to throw
in the load.
Really? Emily?
Oh, ye of little faith.
Where do you think
you're going, John?
Just getting some
fresh air.
Uh-huh.
Give me the cigarette.
Oh, come on.
The pack.
I'm down to five a day.
Give me a break.
Seriously, John?
You're being treated
for emphysema.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
They said that you got
suspended.
So when are you gonna get
unsuspended?
I doubt that I am.
What?
My paramedic license.
It was supposed
to get me my job back.
Problem is, it expired
two weeks ago
and I didn't know about it.
And they're going
to can you
for that?
This here is your calling.
They all gotta know that
by now.
You better get back
to the ED.
It ain't fair a little piece
of paper, two weeks past due,
gonna say whether you
get to be a nurse.
No, that ain't right.
Hello, Barry.
Maggie?
This is a surprise.
Yeah.
I heard about the suspension.
Sorry for the tough break.
You have a minute?
Sure.
What's on your mind?
You have a friend at the EMS
division of public health,
don't you?
I do.
Well, maybe he could
help me out?
My license... I missed the
renewal deadline by two weeks.
I need it to be current.
What are you saying?
What do you think I'm saying?
You want him to fudge
the date for you?
Two weeks.
I'm not gonna lose my career
for two weeks.
Well, isn't this something?
You weren't so keen on
bending the truth
when I was the one doing it.
Okay, forget it.
I knew this was a bad idea.
Hold on.
You need this when?
My hearing's in two hours.
I'll make the call.
Hey, um...
Hey.
I was just wondering if you
had a moment
to help me with a diagnosis.
Yeah, what's up?
Great.
I got a patient with a muddy
constellation of symptoms,
and I just can't nail down
the cause.
Okay.
A middle-aged guy, diagnosed
with diverticulitis,
you know, but inconsistencies
in his labs
and a sudden chylothorax
tells me it's not.
I agree.
No evidence of trauma.
So I'm thinking
either lymphoma
or sarcoidosis.
And sarcoidosis is almost
impossible to diagnose,
which is why it should always
be kept on the differential.
That is what they taught us
in med school.
Right.
Oh. Excuse me. Sorry.
Anyway, uh, because
he's coughing up blood,
I'm leaning toward sarcoid.
Um, then order an MRI
and a biopsy to confirm.
Yep, already did.
Well, great, it sounds like
you've got it
all under control.
Well, I just wasn't sure
if I was missing something.
Doesn't sound like
you're missing anything.
Look, I've got to get back
upstairs to my patients.
Okay?
Okay. Thanks.
Yeah.
There doesn't appear to be
much calcification
on the valve.
I think I can get a wire in.
Still too risky.
The odds just aren't
in our favor.
As I said earlier.
Taking them to the cath lab
is our only chance
to save both babies.
Or lose both.
There are umpteen things that
could prove fatal.
If the balloon ruptures,
or the catheter perforates
the heart,
both babies would die
instantly.
Believe me, Dr. Rhodes,
I share your disappointment.
It's not the outcome
any of us were hoping for.
But the math doesn't work.
I recommend separating Dot
from Lily immediately.
Let's save the one child.
How about we let
the parents
decide?
It's a tough decision we're
asking them to make.
I don't want to confuse them
with too many alternatives.
It is our duty to explain
both options.
There's only one option!
Separate them now
so Dot can live.
The CT team is unanimously
behind this recommendation.
Finally, consensus.
Now shall we?
They're being realistic.
Odds are near impossible
to save them both.
This is one time we shouldn't
be playing the odds.
My baby's going to die?
I'm very sorry, but at least
we can save one of your girls.
No.
There's got to be
something else
that you can try.
Dr. Latham?
Connor?
Oh, my baby.
My baby.
It'll take us a little time
to get prepped.
Be with your girls until then.
Her sedation's worn off.
She should be awake.
Good luck.
Hi. I'm Dr. Charles.
This is Dr. Reese.
Could you...
Could you tell me
your name?
You're in a hospital.
You're safe.
Jub. Jub. Mom-wrath.
Is that your name?
Mom-wrath!
Shun-it! Shun-it!
Shun-it! Shun-it! Shun-it!
Take it easy.
Take...
Little help!
Little help, please!
Jub! Jub! Jub! Jub!
Push two of Versed.
Got it.
Jub! Jub! Jub! Jub!
Mom. Mom. Mom. Mom.
It's just gibberish.
The manxome...
the mom-wrath...
Mom-wrath...
I'm not so sure about that.
Dr. Rhodes. It's time.
My baby.
Joshua, hold on.
Todd, Marcy.
Can I speak to you for
a second?
Dr. Rhodes.
Where are the twins?
The Cronins have changed
their mind.
They want us to perform
the valvuloplasty.
What?
We had a plan going forward
that we all agreed upon.
It's what the parents want.
You went around our backs.
Yeah, because you never gave
them all their options.
You had no right to push your
agenda with the parents.
You told the Cronins what
this procedure entails.
Yes, I did.
And they understand
the risks, all the risks?
Yes.
Dr. Latham, I walked them
through it all.
I'll talk to them.
Maybe I can walk it back.
No, it's too late.
We need to proceed with
alacrity and confidence.
Dr. Bekker, prep the hybrid
suite and notify the team.
Yes, sir.
Sharon?
I'm not late, am I?
It took me longer than
I thought to find this.
You're not late, Maggie.
There's not going to be
a hearing.
What?
Well, the family's
not gonna sue.
The way they see it, you saved
their daughter's life.
They actually advocated
on your behalf.
You got your job back.
You didn't need
that after all.
Oh.
That's great.
Yeah.
Sometimes the good guys win.
I'll see you at work
tomorrow.
Yeah.
Sarcoidosis?
That's right, an inflammatory
disease in your lungs.
The biopsy confirmed it.
The good news is the MRI shows
it hasn't affected your
central nervous system.
MRI? Biopsy?
While there's no cure per se,
most people respond well
to medication.
I am hopeful we caught it
early enough
so it can still be managed.
We thought we were gonna lose
you there for a second, Dad.
Why don't you and your mom
give me a moment with
the doctor?
Thank you, Dr. Halstead.
My pleasure.
What's this all gonna
cost me?
How about you just
concentrate
on trying to get back on
your feet?
No. Give me an estimate.
The biopsy, the MRI.
All these tubes.
What's it all come out to?
100 grand?
Two hundred?
Three?
I really don't know.
What is wrong with you?
How can you call
for all these tests
when you have no idea
how much they cost?
Your wife said you have
insurance.
She doesn't know I switched
to a cheaper plan
so we could afford
our son's tuition.
This is all out of network
for me.
Insurance won't cover
any of it.
I am sorry.
But everything I did
was to save your life.
Well, you shouldn't have.
At least they could've
collected my life insurance.
Now what?
I gotta pull my son
outta school.
We're ruined.
You should've let me die.
So believe it or not,
there is, in fact,
the case to be made that
your daughter is possessed.
What?
Not by a malevolent demon,
but, well, by her
six-year-old self.
Six-year-old self?
What do you mean?
We suspect that this could be
the result of a trauma
she experienced when she was
a little girl.
I don't understand.
It's called
dissociative repression.
Disagreeable memories
or personality fragments
are "split off" and then
pushed down into
the subconscious.
Yeah, and in your
daughter's case,
this fragment has resurfaced
and perhaps hijacked
her entire persona.
How could you possibly know
that's what's going on?
Well, aside from the bed
wetting and the tantrums,
the biggest clue
is her language.
It took me a while to realize
this is not all
gibberish.
It's, well,
it's Lewis Carroll.
There's a poem called
"Jabberwocky"
from
Through The Looking-Glass.
Do either of you remember
reading this to her
when she was a child?
I didn't.
Uh...
No, I don't think so.
No?
Wait.
You did.
When she was little,
I remember.
Mr. Ferris, would you mind
just reading
a little bit of this?
Oh, this is ridiculous...
Psychobabble.
Look, my daughter's very ill.
She's not a child,
she's a demented adult.
Just humor me, please.
No, no.
We need to get her to a real
expert and not this quack.
Just read the damn book,
Jerome.
No!
I'm not going to do it!
It's ridiculous.
In that case, uh,
will you allow me?
""Twas brillig,
and the slithy toves
"Did gyre and gimble
in the wabe
"All mimsy were the borogoves,
"And the mome raths outgrabe."
No, no.
No.
Stop it,
you're upsetting her.
No, no, no, no.
""Beware the Jabberwock,
my son!
"The jaws that bite,
the claws that catch!""
Don't! No!
No, please.
Stop this!
No! No!
Please, please, please, don't!
Oh, my God.
I remember.
She'd be crying.
She'd say it was the monster
from the book,
and I thought it was all
in her head, but...
It was you.
Now, see what you've done.
I told you that
she's unstable.
I always suspected you, but
I didn't want to believe it.
I couldn't believe it.
I...
You're insane.
You touched her?
Oh.
You did things to her?
I heard enough of this.
I'm not listening to this
anymore.
Oh, my poor baby!
Oh, my God!
Dr. Reese?
How could you do that?
A child.
A little girl!
Leave me alone.
You destroyed her.
You know that?
Dr. Reese, enough!
You're the demon!
You!
Dr. Reese!
You let this go. You hear me?
He might be a monster,
he's not the one who hurt you.
He's not the one you want
to be yelling at.
Passing the wire
into the aortic valve.
All right, I'm in.
Balloon.
Marty.
Got to run a VTAC.
You tickled the ventricle.
Damn it.
Pull the wire back.
Carefully.
Back in sinus rhythm.
Okay.
Moving back in.
Lidocaine.
Give me the balloon.
Here.
Balloon is aligned.
Dilating the aortic valve now.
Marty, talk to me.
Good contractions and
a better flow
across the valve.
Looks like it worked.
Both girls are stabilized.
There she is.
Let's celebrate.
What's the matter?
I didn't need this.
So?
Take the win and be happy.
But I betrayed myself...
What I believe is right.
Maggie, you did what it took
to survive, that's all.
That's not the finest
motivation.
Now I have to live with it!
Let me buy you dinner.
Come on.
No.
Maggie.
You helped me out.
Let me buy you dinner.
I'm sorry.
Look, you haven't had
the easiest road.
Well, certainly not as bad
as hers.
How do we even begin to treat
someone like her?
Well, same way we treat any
victim of childhood trauma.
Try and get those repressed
feelings up to the surface
so we can address 'em.
So my patient, we were right.
It was sarcoidosis.
But here's the thing...
Will, I'm sorry,
but I'm running late,
and I need to get home
to Owen.
Have a good night.
Sure. You, too.
Natalie.
You avoiding me?
Will, I told you last week...
I need a break, okay?
Good work, and I know
the board is very happy.
The twins do seem to be
responding well
to the valvuloplasty.
Perhaps I overestimated
the risks.
Dr. Latham, I want this
diva benched
for the separation surgery.
Dr. Bekker can be your second.
With all due respect,
Dr. Frisch,
CT is my department.
I'll decide who'll be
my second.
Thank you for that.
To perform an operation with
as many moving parts as this,
you need confidence
that the people
that you are working with
are pulling in the same
direction.
I fear, Dr. Rhodes, that you
are not a team player...
That you are, in fact, a diva.
I'm replacing you with
Dr. Bekker.
That is your decision
to make.
It's my turn to offer
congratulations.
I don't smell smoke,
that's a good sign.
Oh, Ethan, give her a chance.
Hey. Come on in.
Hi.
You had chicken
in the freezer,
so I made dinner.
Kind of a cacciatore.
It smells so good.
Aren't you gonna join us?
I don't want to intrude.
This is your space.
You're not intruding.
Em...
Thank you.
Yeah, least I could do.
I'm gonna go wash up.
Hey.
Set another place.
Okay.
Emily, can I talk to you
a sec?
Oh, God.
I was gonna throw those
down the toilet,
but I got afraid
they'd clog it
up and I forgot.
Did you have people
over here?
No, just a couple friends.
Emily, this is his apartment.
I know, I know.
I promise
it'll never happen again.
Please don't tell Ethan.
I promise.
Everything okay?
Yeah.
Let's eat.
Is it over and Natalie just
doesn't have the heart
to tell me?
What the hell is a break
anyway?
Yeah, I might be
the wrong guy to ask.
The last time a girlfriend
asked for a break,
she moved to Minneapolis.
So...
All right.
I got early rounds tomorrow.
Mmm-mmm.
No, no, I got this.
You sure?
Yeah.
All right, well,
thank you.
Need a lift?
Nah.
I'm gonna stay a little
longer and lick my wounds.
All right.
I'll see you soon, bud.
You saving this for someone?
It's all yours.
Halstead, right?
Maia Frisch.
I'll have a gin martini
and another round for
my friend here.
You'll join me for one, right?