- Previously on The Resident...
- I am not interested
in being in your line
of giants. I am the first
of my own line. An ancestor.
Not your descendant.
His seizures are
getting harder to control.
- So what do I do now?
- The VNS
is the best option
available to your son.
It was my responsibility
to look after my sisters.
One night I decided
to take a quick nap,
and when I woke up, the
whole house was on fire.
Dr. Mina Okafor,
will you marry me?
I know this is a
scary diagnosis.
Triple-negative breast
cancer is aggressive
and difficult to treat.
It's also more common
in Nigerian women,
and far more often, it's fatal.
Particularly in
those who, like you,
carry the BRCA gene mutation.
But, Adaku, in this
case, we found it early.
After what happened to my
mother and my grandmother,
I knew this might happen to me.
But...
A cure is possible with
aggressive treatment.
At minimum, you'll need a
lumpectomy, chemo and radiation.
But given your family history,
I strongly recommend
a double mastectomy.
Mm. I don't want to do that.
It's the only safe option.
- I won't be maimed.
- We have
great reconstructive
surgery these days.
I'll do surgery to remove
the tumor, chemo,
radiation, whatever
you recommend,
but you're not
taking my breasts.
I'll let you talk it
over with Mina.
You will get through this.
We will get through this.
I'm 28. I might die even younger
than my mother
and my grandmother.
They lived in Nigeria,
had limited access
to health care.
You are an American
and will benefit from
American medicine.
You have a real
chance of beating this
if you are aggressive.
I don't want to talk about that.
- But, Adaku...
- It's my decision, Mina.
I'm going to get you
the best breast
cancer surgeon I know.
A fellow Nigerian
who is experienced
with this form of
aggressive cancer.
Do you mean who
I think you mean?
Thank you.
Of course.
It's okay.
♪ ♪
Come on. Was there a ring?
Did he get on one knee?
Were there witnesses?
Yes, a ring. Yes, one knee.
Smattering of applause
from sentimental onlookers.
But you're not wearing a ring.
I haven't made my decision yet.
You love Micah.
You love Conrad.
- You're not getting married.
- True.
He asked me to move in
with him, and I freaked out.
Hmm. More later.
I have to meet my
friend Adaku's surgeon.
She's arriving any
minute from Nigeria.
All right, see you.
What are you doing here?
Dr. Josephine Okeke
is coming to Chastain.
Who told you that?
Well, Dr. Bell organized
a welcoming committee,
so I jumped at the chance
to meet such a
legendary surgeon.
I mean, come on, this woman
single-handedly transformed
the health care
landscape in rural Nigeria.
Dr. Okafor, how do you
say, "Welcome to Chastain"
- in Yoruba?
- Dr. Okeke is Ibo.
It's a different language.
And don't do that.
You'll only humiliate yourself.
Thank you.
You know her?
Mina asked her here
to operate on a friend,
- a young breast cancer patient.
- She's here because of you?
Oh, well then you
have to join us for lunch.
I got us a table at
The Providence Grill.
I think that's her.
That is definitely her.
Dr. Okeke, Randolph Bell.
Oh. Lovely to
meet you, Dr. Bell.
CEO here at Chastain.
- I'm so happy to have the ch...
- One moment.
Embrace me!
Lovely to see you, Mina, dear.
Aw...
Hello...
Mother.
What happened to your hair?
Oh...
Good morning.
I'm Dr. Pravesh.
Milo Trainor, right?
- How are you feeling?
- Not good, lot to pain.
- Let me take a look.
- Okay.
When did it start?
Yesterday, while I was working.
But it didn't get bad
until this morning.
- What line of work are you in?
- Ethics.
- I'm an ethicist.
- An ethicist?
Sounds like you found a job that
pays worse than my residency.
Well, technically,
I'm unemployed
while I finish my dissertation
on moral relativism.
Looks like you've been
on top of your health.
Only one surgery,
appendectomy five years ago.
Any vomiting?
- Earlier this morning.
- Uh, lift up your shirt for me.
- Yeah.
- Hundley?
Mild hydro in the right kidney.
I'm thinking you
have kidney stones,
- my philosophizing friend.
- Is that bad?
Not typically. Just painful.
We'll get you on IV
fluids and medication
for the pain and nausea,
and let's hope we can get
these stones to pass soon, okay?
Josephine Okeke is your mother?
Yes, and please
keep that to yourself.
I've got to get her
in and out of here
as fast as humanly possible.
Why? The woman is world-famous.
You call her in to
operate on your friend,
and you don't want anybody
to know you're related?
Your flight was good?
Oh, it was fine, until
Dr. Michaels from the CDC
bribed the flight attendant
to switch seats so he could be
right next to me.
Oh, he wouldn't stop talking.
He wanted to know all about the
hospital I'm building in Gombe...
200 beds...
The biggest in Eastern Nigeria.
Well, I hope you
get a chance to tour
our state-of-the-art cancer
wing while you're here.
Wherever the great Dr. Randolph
Bell leads, I will follow.
Please.
So, the great truth-teller lied.
You said you were an ancestor.
But, Mina, you are a
descendent of medical royalty.
My mother is my
mother, and yet she is not.
Excuse me.
So, this is Henry,
only eight years old,
and Henry's epilepsy
interrupted his schoolwork,
his baseball games,
his time with friends.
He suffered from
violent seizures daily,
until we implanted the
QuoVadis vagus nerve stimulator.
And now, Henry's seizures
are nearly nonexistent.
He's back to school,
he's playing baseball,
he's with his friends.
And what was once a
pipe dream is now a reality.
- A cure for epilepsy?
- Can you imagine?
I mean, the potential of this
QuoVadis device is unlimited.
All right, hold still
for just a second.
So, how's baseball going?
I got a triple last week.
Oh, nice.
So tell me, what's going on?
Nothing.
Mom's being the worst.
- The worst, huh?
- She thinks I'm having
seizures again,
- but I'm not.
- Hey, how'd you get that bruise?
- Slide into third?
- I fell.
At school.
Okay, bud. Let us talk
to your mom for a minute.
Be right back.
What's going on?
I thought the VNS would
get rid of his seizures.
The best-case scenario
was always a reduction
in the number and severity.
So far, no VNS
device is a cure-all.
And considering
how things started
for Henry, it's
worked really well.
I'll bring in Henry's
pediatric neurologist,
Dr. Eckart, and
we'll run some tests.
Uh, this sounds like it
might take a bit to figure out.
I-I've got to go to
work. I'll check in later.
- Go. Thank you.
- Yeah.
We just started dating.
Henry's condition
is a lot to take in.
Look, Zoey... I'm sorry,
but we have to ask.
There's a... there's a
nasty bruise on Henry's arm.
There's no way that
Doug would ever...
No. Absolutely not.
Okay. Well, let's see how
things go with the EEG.
We'll figure this out.
So this is where you
chose to do your residency?
I was just at Oxford,
and it's like suites
at the Hotel Cardova in Positano
in comparison to this dump.
Thank you for coming
on short notice, Mother.
Oh.
After four years
of cutting me dead,
I'm still shocked you called me.
I want the best for
Adaku. That is you.
Well, I'm touched you admit it.
I never denied it.
A decent-sized mass.
- Any sign of distant spread?
- No.
But Adaku has multifocal
DCIS in the other breast
and the BRCA1 gene mutation.
This took her mother at 39
and her grandmother at 38.
Did you set up a
gyn-onc consult?
Yes, but one step at a time.
We have to deal
with the breasts first.
Considering all the factors,
she will need a
double mastectomy.
I agree, and so
does her oncologist,
but so far, she's refusing.
Well, have you
talked to her about it?
Of course.
Ah, that's the problem.
Let me guess... You
gave her every statistic,
but without diplomacy,
tact and compassion.
Patients need warmth, Mina.
But it's all right.
I'm here.
BP 88/45.
- Heart rate, 120.
- How's the pain?
Worse. Lots worse.
You said kidney stones.
What did his UA show?
Only a few RBCs
but otherwise clean.
Okay, okay.
Abdominal pain is new.
He only had flank pain before.
He's septic. Five dollars
says it's an appendicitis.
Pay up. He had an
appendectomy five years ago.
- He needs a CT, now.
- He's already critical.
I'll give them a call, get
him to the front of the line.
VNS is functional.
And...
Henry's EEG looks good.
No seizures since
he's been here.
Oh, thank God.
But how do you
explain the falls?
I trip, that's all.
They weren't seizures, I swear.
Let's keep him here for
the day for observation,
just to be safe.
Everything okay?
My boss.
Big presentation today.
Promised I'd be there.
I am pretty sure he'll fire
me if I miss another day,
but I can't leave Henry.
The hospital can provide a
sitter until you come back.
Yeah, and Conrad and I can
check on him as much as possible.
I'll be fine, Mom.
Go, Zoey.
We got this.
Okay.
What the...?
Hope you haven't
spent that fiver,
because that would be
an appendix right there.
That's impossible.
Dr. Kays did an appendectomy
on Milo five years ago.
Well, someone screwed up.
Because that's an
inflamed appendix.
We need to get
him to surgery now
- before it ruptures.
- Good idea.
Thank you so much
for coming to see me.
Oh, I was so happy to
get my daughter's call.
It's the first time she's
ever asked for my help,
which means you
must be very special.
Now, as you know,
Mina is, um, a
woman of few words.
And I'm sure
you love her for it,
but I am just the opposite.
I love to have a good chat.
And unlike most surgeons,
I talk to my patients.
I want to know
what is uppermost in your mind.
I'm terrified.
Of course you are.
It's only natural.
I watched this happen to my mom.
I saw how she suffered
and I saw how she died.
A tragedy, for her and for you.
Every daughter needs her mother,
and you were robbed of
her love and her support.
A crushing loss.
Daughters need their
mother, don't they, Mina?
I want to have a child soon.
And I want to nurse my baby.
And then, if necessary, I'll
have the double mastectomy.
And I wish your mother were here
to see this baby
of yours, don't you?
Yes.
I miss her so much.
The last time I saw her
was right after her surgery.
And the scars were awful
and she died a week later.
The doctor maimed
her and it did no good.
Because it was too late, Adaku.
But I'm younger. I have time.
And what good would
it do your future baby
for you to leave her early
the way your mom left you?
Hmm?
You saw a part of your
mother's womanhood destroyed
and still she lost her life.
But that doesn't
have to be your story.
Adaku.
We have to act immediately,
and you have to
trust me to give you
the best chance to live,
for you and your future family.
Hmm?
Schedule the surgery, Mina.
I have a lot to teach
you if you'd ever listen.
- I listened, and...
- You're welcome.
Hey, buddy.
Taking a break
from all those tests?
Dr. Eckart said I
could for a little while.
- I'm sick of being
in the hospital.
- I know.
I can sit with Henry
for a little while.
Thanks.
Purple, that's my favorite.
- Mine too.
- Yeah?
Well, you look like
you're feeling a bit better.
How are things at home, Henry?
Are you and Conrad
gonna get married?
Uh...
That's a good question.
- I don't know.
- Don't you love him?
Yeah. Yeah, I do. Very much.
- But...
- I thought maybe...
he'd marry my mom.
But... now she has Doug.
I wish Conrad was my dad.
Buddy, that's another
bruise since this morning.
How did you get that?
I don't know.
It's okay. Don't worry.
We'll figure it out.
I heard there was an issue
with our VNS poster
child, Henry Barnett.
Has he been admitted?
Yeah. Uh...
he was brought in
with a possible seizure,
a minor seizure.
We are getting ready
to take our stock public.
- I'm well aware.
- The VNS is being
featured at the Innovation
Summit tomorrow.
If any issue comes
up, I want it handled.
Quietly.
Obviously, our first concern
is the child's welfare.
B-But we will be as
discrete as possible.
You paged me?
My patient is still hypotensive.
Are you sure that you got out
all the infection
during surgery?
Yeah, well, he perforated,
so it took me an extra
20 minutes to lavage
his abdominal
cavity, all because
you caught this so late.
A ruptured appendix, Pravesh.
It's kindergarten stuff, the
janitor could've caught it.
- Yeah, but his record said...
- Do not
give me your excuses.
The patient could've died.
In Nigeria, it is not uncommon
that the first time a
woman is seen in a clinic,
she already has
stage IV breast cancer.
I have seen tumors
the size of tangerines.
And the reason they come so late
is because of social
pressures? Lack of education?
Oh, no, no. No access to
health care or screenings.
Not until I started my clinic.
I mean, it was a battle
from the beginning,
but change is never easy.
You push, you nudge
and if necessary, you fight.
You're such an inspiration.
We need more doctors
like you here at Chastain.
Oh, no, my dear.
I have no interest.
I'll stay in Nigeria, my home.
We have too few doctors there
and that is why it's such a
shame that Mina came here.
Well, we're awfully
glad that she did.
Indeed we are.
Dr. Okafor, have you
ever thought about
going back to Nigeria to help
your mother with her work?
- No.
- You see...
having a successful
parent is difficult for children.
They have to chart
their own course.
That is not the issue.
I believe I know what
Mina is referring to.
You see, my daughter
was a med student in Lagos
and she was a good student.
She showed promise.
And then something happened
that caused her
to leave her family,
her home, her country,
and never come back.
It was a family matter
seldom spoken about
that caused us all
the greatest pain.
So... the clinics in Gombe...
- How many...
- I take it you have not
discussed this with
your colleagues.
Mother.
This lunch is about you, not me.
I think you'll be kind
enough to respect my privacy.
Excuse me.
This has been lovely
but I have to get back.
- No, Mina.
- No.
Thank you so much, Dr. Bell.
Few things are as rewarding
as spending time
with colleagues.
My pleasure, Dr. Okeke.
Oh, please call me Josephine.
Thank you again.
I thought you had to get back.
Obviously, we need
to talk in private.
- How dare you.
- How dare I?
You walk out of a luncheon
to honor me and embarrass me
in front of your colleagues,
but you embarrassed
yourself more
because they respect me.
You are worthy of
respect, as a doctor.
Oh, but I'm not worthy
of respect as a mother?
Oh, I know what's
behind this attitude.
I know it all too well.
You blame me.
You blame me for the fire.
I blame myself, and our
problems long predate that tragedy.
Oh, I know.
I work too long.
I work too late.
I should've been home.
I am a bad mother.
That is why your sisters
died. That is what you think.
Do not presume to know my mind.
We can find common
ground in the OR.
There is no reason to bring
our personal lives and the past
- into my workplace.
- Oh, please.
If there is any chance of this
coming up again,
our relationship,
both professional
and personal, is over.
Is that clear?
Your sisters adored me.
They adored me. We
were inseparable, but you...
you never liked me.
Never.
He's still hypotensive.
IVC looks good.
Increase his norepinephrine.
Let's hope he responds.
I need his full history to
figure out what's going on,
and I don't trust that chart.
Should we call his
emergency contact?
See what his... brother
- could tell us?
- Please.
Brent Trainor.
There's the number.
Hello?
We called the
patient's cell phone?
Or he has his brother's phone.
Who does that?
Wait, you said his
name was Brent, right?
Yeah.
Hold on, here.
Mina and I have never
been in the OR together.
Strange, isn't it?
Residents beg to scrub
in with me on a daily basis.
Well, then this must
be a great moment
for both of you then, right?
I am praying for the
best outcome for Adaku,
our patient.
We'll be using electrocautery.
Set up the Bovie, please.
I prefer to use radio
frequency instruments
for maximum precision.
Cautery is what I used
for a crowned princess.
Good enough for royalty,
good enough for your friend.
Bovie.
You have incredible
hand dexterity, Dr. Okeke.
The field is
practically bloodless.
Well, I've been working on
my technique for decades.
It minimizes
post-op complication
and reduces patient
recovery time.
Here we go. What do you got?
No! No!
- Let's play again.
- Yeah.
All right.
I can tell you're
scared of something,
but I don't know exactly what.
Will you help me understand?
I'm fine.
I think you might've had another
episode since you've been here.
If that's it,
you don't have to
be afraid to tell me.
I'm on your side no matter what.
Don't tell my mom, okay?
She wants what's best for you.
She's on your side,
too, you know that.
Yeah.
It's not that.
My dad left when I
got sick the first time.
- Mm-hmm.
- My mom really likes Doug,
but if I get sick again,
I think he'll
probably leave, too.
She's lonely. She needs him.
Doug and your
mom... they're new.
Still figuring things out.
It's not your
fault your dad left.
You know that?
I miss him.
But I also know he misses
you and he loves you, too.
Sometimes people just
have a hard time showing it.
Especially dads.
So...
you're falling down,
okay? What happens next?
I don't know.
It just happens all of a sudden,
then I wake up on the floor.
Mm-hmm.
It's not like my other seizures.
Okay, when did it start?
- Last week.
- How many times?
Four, maybe.
Yes!
Finally get a win over you.
Come on. Come on, come on,
come on, come on, come on, come on.
No!
Hmm.
How is Dr. Okeke doing?
Fine surgeon. Truly gifted.
Problematic human.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
- I found her utterly charming.
- That's because
she flattered you.
Common technique
amongst charming people.
I hate charming people.
Their main goal is to
make you like them.
They're narcissists, and
once you see through them,
the charm disappears,
they cut you and then they
move on to the next conquest.
That was a mouthful.
Is this about what
happened at lunch?
- Partly.
- Retract.
Suction.
Not like that!
Good God, what have
they taught you in America?
What is it? What?
- You'll need the scalpel to...
- When I ask!
I did not expect that.
So I called Milo's
emergency contact
and I finally got his
medical information.
He has rheumatoid arthritis.
That doesn't explain
any of the complications.
Well, we inadvertently
stopped his steroids,
which left his body without
the stress response it needed
to fight the infection.
Why wasn't rheumatoid arthritis
noted in his medical records?
Well, let's ask Milo.
Okay.
Milo Trainor?
- Dr. Devon Pravesh.
- Nice to meet you.
Thank you so much
for coming down.
We're so glad that we found you.
Dr. Feldman,
this is our patient's
identical twin
brother, the real Milo.
We've been looking at his
records all day because Brent
told us that he was him.
Brent?
Hey, Brent. You okay?
You stole my insurance
card, man. Not cool.
I always wanted a twin.
Oof, two Irvings?
Terrifying idea.
My mom would be happy.
I'm sorry. Brent has so much
student debt and
no health insurance.
I'm sure it seemed like
a good idea at the time.
You almost died, my
philosophical friend.
Rule number one if
you want to stay alive:
don't lie to your doctor.
Hey, girl.
Hey.
The surgery went well.
The reconstructive
surgeon and then
Dr. Osder will be in tomorrow
to talk about next steps.
Oh...
I feel like less of a woman.
You're a warrior, Adaku.
And from now on,
you have the scars of a warrior.
Thank you.
And thank you for
bringing your mother here.
She was wonderful.
She did an excellent job.
I can attest to that.
Her skills will make
your recovery far easier
and the outcome better.
You're awake.
Oh, Mina,
why didn't you page me?
I am so grateful that you
came all this way to help me.
Shh. Shh, shh, shh, shh.
Oh... don't mention it.
It was my pleasure,
and you did great.
You realize what Brent
did is insurance fraud.
If you don't report it, you
could lose your license.
- What'll happen to Brent?
- Worst case,
the insurance company
presses charges.
He pays the fines
and a whopper of a bill.
I don't think
he'll get jail time.
But he'll be ruined. In
debt for years to come.
- Yep.
- Dr. Pravesh.
You said there was a billing
error with, uh, Milo Trainor?
You called me up
here from billing.
It's your lucky day. I'm here.
Nadine, do you ever
believe sometimes,
especially when
someone is starting out,
they shouldn't be saddled
with enormous debt?
Hmm. Above my pay grade.
But everyone deserves
a break sometimes, right?
- Can we agree to that?
- If I believed that,
I'd be sipping a caramel latte
outside on a bench right now.
Well, then, here
is five dollars.
Go get yourself
that caramel latte.
Well, what about
the billing error?
It turns out it
was a false alarm.
A glitch in the
medical record system.
I can fix it myself.
Sorry you came all the way here.
Enjoy that coffee.
We are so grateful
for your visit.
I wish I had more
time to get to know you.
I-I also... I want you to
know how much we admire
and treasure your daughter.
She inherited all your skill.
She's a rising star who
will one day outshine us all.
Speak for yourself, Dr. Bell.
Hiding out?
From whom?
Everybody.
I told you I was adopted, right?
I never met my birth parents.
And if I did,
it probably wouldn't be pretty.
Every time I see her...
I think it's gonna be different.
My dad died years ago, so...
when I lost my sisters...
I lost the only
family I had left.
My mother...
is not my mother.
Not really.
So you came here, you built
your own family at Chastain.
Look, we will always
appreciate you.
Always.
- You have an update for me?
- The good news is I haven't
been able to detect
- any seizure activity.
- So the VNS is working.
-It seems so. The
bad news is -Good.
We still don't know
what's causing
these reported drop attacks.
Even though the tests haven't
revealed any abnormal activity,
I'd still like to keep
him here overnight.
- We need answers.
- Well, if he's not
having seizures,
there's no medical reason
to keep him in the hospital.
- Thank you.
- Dr. Bell, just a second...
No, I share your concerns, so
stay in touch with the mother,
and we'll bring him
back if we need to.
- Dr. Bell...
- Just set a follow-up
appointment for later,
but discharge him.
Call me if anything comes up,
even if it's the
middle of the night.
- Even if it seems like nothing.
- I will, I promise.
Look at him.
He's so happy to be going home.
Conrad, you keep
helping us over and over,
and I think maybe
I've been overreacting
to every little thing.
But you always
take me seriously.
What happened?
Excuse me.
Henry? Henry?
Lost his pulse.
Call the code team, I'm
starting compressions.
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God, baby.
Baby.
Baby...
He's back. He's back.
- What happened?
- Don't worry. I'm gonna take care of you.
Hold on, buddy. I'm gonna
put you on the gurney.
What happened? There was a code?
His heart stopped.
But it started again.
I'm not sure what's going on.
Okay, here we go.
- Get him in.
- Let's hang some fluids.
Cardiac arrest...
It makes no sense.
This one is gonna help us
keep track of your breathing.
And these guys are
gonna monitor your heart.
Ah. You all right?
- Yeah.
- All right.
Two more, ready?
Smoke over fire.
One, two, three.
- Good?
- Uh, yeah.
All right.
I heard. What's going on?
His heart stopped.
Is it the seizures?
We don't think so.
We're still learning things.
I paged cardio and neuro.
- Okay.
- It's okay.
Okay, he's safe now.
- Henry!
- Zoey, Zoey... Okay.
Just stay back with us.
- Henry! Zoey...
- He's down again.
He's going directly
into asystole.
His heart stopped.
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
Ow.
What in God's name is happening?
It's the VNS.
That controls his seizures.
It has nothing to do with this.
His heart is stopping.
The vagus nerve
also slows heart rate.
The VNS must be
overstimulating it.
The VNS is set to
send impulses every...
Three minutes.
Every three minutes, it
sends a 30-second pulse.
The VNS is stopping his
heart every time it fires.
So his heart is
gonna stop again?
Yes, if we don't
turn off the VNS.
We can't stop it without the
programming wand or the magnet.
- Do you have it, Zoey?
- Uh, not here.
I-It's at home.
There's a wand in
the ER. Go, now.
Keep up with the compressions,
and Ambu when
he goes down again.
Devon. The programming
wand for the VNS... where is it?
Supply cabinet.
- It's not here.
- Damn it.
Eckart has one.
He left for the day. Call
him and get him back here.
It would be in his
office across the street.
Tell him I'll meet him there!
Hey!
Mom...
I don't want to die.
No. No, you're not
gonna die, baby.
No, it's gonna be okay.
Just like the last time.
We've got ten seconds.
- Prepare the Ambu bag.
- You're doing great,
my brave, brave boy.
We have you.
He's down again.
Starting compressions.
Save him, please.
You have to save him!
- I'm here.
- Eckart is six minutes out.
Too long.
Please, God. Please. Please.
We should switch.
- I got it.
- We may be at this a while.
Why isn't Conrad back?
I'm sure he'll be
back any second.
Not Henry, no.
Keep going.
Come on.
Hurry.
I got it, I got it.
Baby...
At least we did it.
You saw what just happened.
Yeah, a QuoVadis
device failed in this child.
It stopped his heart.
- It nearly killed him.
- I was there.
Chastain cannot continue
to be in business
with this company.
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH