We give children
stickers and lollipops
after they visit the doctor.
Bear attack,
Longfellow State Park.
I got him.
His wife arm's shredded.
Scott?
Scott!
We congratulate them
for putting on a brave face.
Scott!
♪ Just like a tambourine
won't ever stop ♪
Needles in their arm,
strangers inspecting their body
for signs of illness.
"Here's some candy, kid.
Try to smile."
♪ When we got that magic
pumping through our veins ♪
♪ Ooh, la, la, la ♪
We do it to adults, too.
Are you Helm?
Is this the...
This is the nose. Can you take that
to Dr. Avery? - Mm-hmm.
It's considered impolite
to discuss
your cancer diagnosis
at a dinner party.
♪ So roll with it, roll with it,
roll with it ♪
You're supposed to smile,
make small talk,
suck on the invisible lollipop.
♪ Ooh, la, la ♪
♪ New wave, new wave,
new wave ♪
Because for some reason,
someone decided a long time ago
that naming pain is impolite...
♪ Hey, nothing's gonna stop us ♪
..that hiding it and hiding
from it makes more sense.
- ♪ New wave, new wave ♪
- ♪ Ooh, la, la, la ♪
♪ Ooh, la, la ♪
- ♪ New wave, new wave ♪
- It doesn't.
It's a lie,
a lie that both comforts
and destroys us.
♪ This is the new wave ♪
Matty?
Can you get me
a soda?
- Okay.
- Okay, okay.
Alright.
Okay.
I know you said
no medicine, but...
I will speak
with Dr. Riley.
Do you mind calling pathology
- to get the lab results?
- No problem.
Hey, c-can we give her something
for the nausea, please?
We are not
suppressing her symptoms...
We're studying them.
Okay,
but she's suffering.
Suffering is better
than dying.
We need the diagnosis,
DeLuca.
Stay the course.
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 16  Episode 14
Episode Title: "A Diagnosis"
Sync & corrections by srjanapala
Thought the baby
might be hungry...
even if you aren't.
You sure we can't, um,
send a doctor to check in on you?
An OB?
An orthopedic surgeon?
No.
But thank you.
Amelia.
Maggie.
Pretty recently,
you were going through something.
And you hid
in your room,
and you rejected
both food and company.
And we wanted to bury you
in love all day, every day,
but you locked the door
and...
And we grudgingly respected
your desire for privacy.
I appreciated that.
I needed it.
Fine.
Eat the toast...
and I'll spare you
the comfort.
Still haven't found
the perfect apartment?
I've given up
on perfect.
Now I'm just hoping for
four walls and a floor.
Unless you've reconsidered
letting me just stay with you.
I thought
we were past that.
Right. We are. So I'm looking
at something tonight.
- You want to come?
- Tonight?
Uh, I can't, sorry.
You can't
because you think I'm needy
- and you're secretly over me or...
- No.
Um, my... my parents
are in town, actually.
Oh.
Finally
get to meet 'em.
Uh, no,
you do not want that.
They're super critical and have
impossibly high standards.
But good luck
on that apartment.
Schmitt.
Plan on doing any work today,
or are you just gonna
stand and stare?
Morning, Joey.
Ready to do some PT?
Again?
Every eight hours.
Okay.
Let's check
your range of motion.
Okay.
Abduction's to 45 degrees,
same as last two days.
I'm not really
feeling this.
Could we just
try again tomorrow?
Joey, if you don't do
your PT every day,
you might never
regain your mobility.
Okay,
that's enough for today.
We'll be back
to check on you later, Joey.
That's it?
He's obviously
feeling discouraged.
So you're just gonna
let him off the hook?
No, we need to find a way
to make it feel less daunting.
Hey.
Anything from Amelia?
No.
- Alex?
- No.
There was a bear attack
last night, did you hear?
Avery was out camping,
and this bear just...
Just came out of nowhere
and ripped this guy's nose off
and severed his wife's
brachial artery.
- Whoa.
- Yeah.
But that's not
what this is, right?
What what is?
Amelia? Alex?
- I'm not following.
- Do we have bears, Link,
and not know it?
Are we just
sleeping soundly
and they're gonna jump out of
nowhere and rip our noses off?
Alex is going through something
with his family
that he will tell you about
when he's ready
because he's a good guy
and he loves you.
And you just
got married.
Right. Right.
And Amelia
just does this sometimes.
What?
Wait.
Well, she and Owen were once
fighting over having kids,
and then
she just ghosted him
and camped out
at my friend Stephanie's house.
Drove her crazy,
but she couldn't say anything
because Amelia was
her boss, so...
Oh.
Uh, in all fairness, there was
a brain tumor back then
that has since
been removed.
Think the brain tumor's back?
We can hope.
Well, what am I supposed to do?
Just wait it out?
Avoid Owen and Teddy?
Lock up your food,
zip up your tent?
Too dark?
Never.
Dr. Brandy to the blood bank.
- Good morning, Dr. Webber!
These doctors
need your help.
They need more training...
Your training.
- Um... you'll excuse us.
- W...
Is, uh, this you
worrying about me
because my marriage
fell apart?
Richard Webber.
You have a gift
for spotting emerging talent
and guiding them
to excellence,
and, yes, your marriage
fell apart, and...
of course I'm worried
about you, Richard.
I'm fine.
But thank you.
Okay.
But if you need to come by
- for dinner this week...
- Alright, let's go!
Scott Burke,
admitted last night
for multiple
chest lacerations,
left hemothorax,
and deep soft-tissue injuries
to the face
from a bear attack.
Don't sugarcoat it.
Damn animal
took off my nose.
- And we put it into your arm.
- Alright, Scott.
Ready to
take a look?
Thing of beauty.
Oh.
So, it's just gonna
sit there?
For how long?
Well, we need your facial wounds
to heal first
before we can
reattach it.
Got really good
blood flow
coming in
from your radial artery here.
And that'll keep it viable
until we're ready to reattach.
And...
my wife, Rachel?
Can I see her?
Okay, can you squeeze
my fingers?
Okay, she still has weakness
in median nerve distribution.
Okay, Rachel.
We repaired the artery
last night,
but today we need to do a
washout to prevent infection, okay?
We, uh...
We had j-just woken up,
and Scott was gonna make
some coffee.
And out of nowhere,
there was a-a-a bear.
A h-huge bear.
And S-Scott
jumped in front of me,
tried to protect me.
He jumped in front of
a bear for me.
- Yeah.
- And the good news is
we found his nose
and we were able
to salvage it, okay?
Do you want us
to take you to see him?
Rach?
Oh, my God.
You scared the hell out of me.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
I love you.
I love you so much,
baby.
Oh, God.
Nurse Karen.
Do you have any idea where
the video-game cart might be?
I have a patient
who doesn't want to do his PT,
and I think
it might help.
- Let me look.
- Thank you.
Did you have any idea
you'd be in the arcade business
when you took up peds?
I'd be a lot more popular
with my kids if I was.
All they want to do
is play video games.
I think I might just see
the top of their heads
until they're
25.
What are you guys working on?
We are organizing
a pro bono surgery day
for people
who can't afford insurance.
Ah. Good.
Uh, there's a-a game room
on the fourth floor.
What, like a whole room
just for PT?
Well, it's not
- exactly just a room for that...
- Uh, hey, hey, do you remember,
uh, a Fred... uh, sorry,
Frank... Fred Mercer?
You did a lap appy on him
two years ago.
You remember that?
Kind of in the middle
of a conversation here, bud.
Speaking Italian...
- You speak Italian?
- Fourth floor, you said?
- Yeah, it's, um...
It's in between the blue
and the green room.
- Okay. Thank you.
- Yeah.
And, uh, count me in for that
pro bono surgery day, okay?
- Yes!
- Hey,
- a Fred Mercer, okay? Stay with me.
- Put him down. Yes.
I was going through some of the
transcripts from a lecture that you gave.
You said he had
post-op rashes
and electrolyte
abnormalities.
Now, I need to know if his
appendix had a carcinoid tumor
because he already shares two
symptoms with Suzanne Britland,
so I'm thinking maybe she's got
a carcinoid tumor
and, you know,
we just can't see it.
Okay.
You've been going through
transcripts of my old lectures?
Well, yeah, I'm going through
transcripts from everyone's lectures.
When's the last time
you slept, Andrew?
What's that have to do
with anything?
You can't help Suzanne
if you're exhausted.
You took Suzanne off the meds
three days ago.
- Mm-hmm.
- Have you taken a break?
Look, c-can you just...
answer the question, please?
I think the rash
was, um,
propofol-infusion syndrome.
- Propofol infus...
- Okay.
You could try to run
a CgA.
Thank you.
It didn't need to be that hard.
DeLuca, the pericardial biopsy
came back negative
for carcinomatosis.
Okay.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Is there any progress?
Everything I rule out
is progress.
Are you working
in shifts?
Because he seems
pretty fried.
By the time I brought
someone else up to speed,
Suzanne could be dead,
and DeLuca, he's a machine.
He isn't a machine.
He's a resident.
And he seems like
he could use a break.
He's obsessing.
I'm relying on that,
and Suzanne's life
may depend on it.
Hi, there.
I called in sick.
What?
I thought we had a deal.
I'm backing out
of our deal.
See,
I appreciated the space
because I grew up
an only child
and I am better
at solving problems on my own,
but you grew up
in a wolf pack,
and wolves
only retreat from the pack
when they are
going off alone to die.
So, I'm backing out
of our deal.
Well, the only way
I've ever seen you
get yourself out of
a really deep spiral
is to spiral out loud
until you land on something
that is healthier than whatever
is happening inside your head.
For an only child,
you are an excellent sister.
Hi!
Your, uh,
husband wants to see you.
I-I sh...
I should go, right?
I mean, I-I go?
He jumped in front of
a bear for me.
Babe.
You have to tell him
sooner or later.
Oh, God.
Helm.
I-I love him,
o-okay?
He's... He's my husband,
and I-I love him,
but I'm not in...
In love with him anymore.
I'm... I'm in love
with Brian and...
We went
to high school together.
Uh...
We reconnected online,
and, well,
one thing led to another.
I was gonna tell Scott
on the... on the camp...
Camping trip.
I th... I thought
the nature would be c...
be comforting for...
for him, and then...
And then he jumped
in front of a bear for you.
W-What...
What do I do?
I mean, what...
What do I say?
Neither one of you needs
any more stress right now,
so we'll just...
We'll let him know
that we're prepping you
for surgery.
Helm,
prep her for surgery,
and bite your tongue.
We will clean the wound
to help her heal,
but she should be fine.
But can I see her
before you take her?
I'll sit in a wheelchair,
I-I-I'll be careful,
what... what...
Whatever you want.
I mean, I don't...
I don't see why not.
No, I'm... I'm sorry.
The operating rooms
are on a strict schedule today,
um, but we can update you again
when we're done.
You'll tell her
I-I love her?
His wife is in love
with someone else.
Got it.
O-kay.
His wife is in love
with someone else.
I just lied to him
while he has a nose in his arm
because he saved her
from a bear.
Alright, well,
sometimes patient care
is... is complicated.
Hey,
little bunnies.
- It's Mom.
- Oh, stop.
It's doing something.
Alright, well,
we've, uh...
We've ruled out
a lot of bad things,
which is a-a good sign,
but I do need
to draw some more blood
for a few more tests.
Does she have
any left?
Hadley.
Come on.
I barely have enough energy
for this.
Sorry.
Okay, um,
I got it.
- Let's do it again.
- Okay.
Okay.
Hey, little bunnies.
It's me.
I'm just checking
to make sure
that you're eating
all your carrots and...
No, wait. It's doing something
to your mouth.
Huh?
What?
Oh, my God.
Her mouth is bleeding!
What? What?
Open your mouth
for me, Suzanne.
No, no, no,
no, no, no, no.
What's happening?
I-I'm not sure.
Oh!
Platelet count went from 250 to
5. All of her cell counts are down.
Well, what does it mean?
I just said I don't know, okay?!
I just...
I-I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
I... C-Can someone page
Dr. Riley, please?
We need to prep for
a bone-marrow biopsy right now.
- Can I have her chart?
- Yeah.
Oh.
D-Dr. Grey?
- Hi.
I know you're worried
about him, right?
Yes,
for a long time now.
Yeah.
He's exhausted.
Riley is working him...
Meredith,
I came to Seattle
because Andrew is now
the same age as our father was
- when his symptoms started.
- Ohh.
It... It runs
in the family.
I mean, he's been...
he's been fine.
It's just his patient's
circling the drain,
he can't figure it out,
and we've all
been there.
It's not just
this patient, though.
There have been warning signs...
High highs, low lows.
Do you remember
when Sam left
and he couldn't get off
your sofa?
A-And then he went
and threw himself on the fire
in Dr. Webber's
operating room.
He was very low,
and he was suddenly
the opposite.
Well, he does feel things
very deeply.
Failing to understand
or properly consider
the consequences of your actions
is a sign of mania.
He aggressively pursued
a relationship with his boss,
he claimed credit
for your crime,
and then he went...
to jail,
prepared to lose
his medical career.
I mean, we're all a little manic
when we're in love.
Yes, but you don't all have
his family history.
He's not sleeping,
he's not eating.
Okay, so how do you tell
a healthy obsession from mania?
He's a resident,
and you're
chief of general surgery.
Would you even think
to ask that question
if you didn't love him?
Bailey,
do you have a second?
You okay?
I'm perimenopausal, Grey.
You know
what that means.
I go to bed freezing,
and then I wake up in the middle
of the night broiling.
I'm in an all-night battle
with my blanket.
I'm happy, then I'm sad,
I'm laughing,
and then I want to
throw this fan at the wall.
Am I okay?
I mean, what, women are
51% of the population,
and every single
one of them
have or will experience
this joy
at some time
in their lives,
so in that sense,
I guess I'm just fine.
Talk.
I'm worried about
our chief resident.
You waiting for me
to put this fan down?
'Cause that's not
gonna happen, Grey.
Sit down.
Tell me more.
Okay, so, you're familiar
with this case.
You're holding it
sideways.
Don't come for me.
The tips of the Maryland
should be pointing down,
right, Dr. Webber?
Uh, what's that?
The tip should be
pointing down...
The Maryland dissectors?
Uh, yeah, yeah.
Is this a mind game?
Maybe he doesn't like
know-it-alls.
Do you get this involved
with every patient?
Most patients
aren't this difficult.
Yeah.
Just the fun ones.
So, are you still
dating your boss?
I observe people closely
because I have to
as a doctor and as a person,
and the way people
who have slept together argue
is very different
than people who have not.
Their bodies have a completely
different language.
We're still dating,
I think.
Hmm.
That would explain her concern.
Concern? What, did she
say something to you?
Just wants to make sure
I don't work you to death.
It was nice.
You see, Joey?
It couldn't be easier.
It's exactly like
your PT exercises, so go on.
- Give it a try.
- No, thanks.
- Just try it.
- No.
Joey, you could lose
your ability to use your arm.
I can't play
video games!
I'm here
with video games
and people
taking care of me.
I sleep in a warm bed,
and I have no idea
if my little sister
and brothers are okay
or if they're safe
or if they're scared.
Uh, you guys
are all worried about my arm,
but I'm shaking.
Look, I'm so scared for them,
I'm shaking.
Why doesn't anyone care
about that?
Why doesn't anyone
try to fix that?
Okay,
more irrigation.
What if you,
uh
Found out
Amelia's baby was yours?
What?
Why would you
say that?
It's...
It's a hypothetical.
That's not something
I want to consider.
Why not?
Would it change things
for you and Teddy?
Karev,
why are you asking me this?
Alex went home to Iowa,
and I've barely
heard from him,
and my worst-case-scenario meter
is off the charts right now
because this patient
is cheating on her husband
right under his nose,
which is in his arm.
And you think
Alex is...
She reconnected with an ex
from high school,
and then one thing
led to another.
So what if he just
ran into some old girlfriend
from high school
and one thing
led to another?
Okay. Ready to pack.
Jo, it took me
a long, long time
to get to this place in my life
with me and Teddy,
you know,
just like you and Karev.
I'm not gonna screw that up
for anything.
And neither is
your husband.
Chief, i-if this can wait,
please, I got to...
Dr. DeLuca, all surgeons
occasionally have patients
that get under
their skin.
- What, uh...
- But...
Hmm.
No, no, no.
What did she tell you?
That I'm making mistakes?
Because I'm not.
Uh, Meredith Grey
will be taking over
Suzanne Britland's care.
Every test, every treatment
will be approved by her.
She's my patient.
She's the hospital's
patient.
And you need
to get some rest.
So what's your plan,
then? Do you even have one?
I have instructed
Dr. Grey
to put Suzanne Britland
back on her medication
while she continues to
seek a diagnosis. - No, no.
So your plan
is to kill her, then.
Dr. DeLuca,
do I need to remind you
to whom
you are speaking?
Just because
this hasn't worked yet
does not mean
that it won't, okay?
We are on the verge
of something.
I-I know it.
I can feel it. Please.
Meredith Grey is
the chief of general surgery.
You should be grateful
she's taken an interest
in your case.
Get some sleep.
Dr. Bailey, please.
DeLuca, walk away now
before you say something
you'll regret.
Dr. Bailey.
I've been working
with Joey Phillips.
Oh, let me guess.
He doesn't want to do PT.
How'd you know?
'Cause he doesn't want to do
much of anything.
Yeah, well, the poor kid
was living on the street
before they brought him
in here.
I'd like to try
to find a way to help him.
You don't think
I want to help him?
I mean, all I think about is,
you know,
what happens when he's ready
to be discharged?
Then what?
Do we put him back
on the street?
And th... Okay,
and then let's say
he manages to find
a place to live,
finish high school,
go to college.
Well, who visits him
on parents' weekend?
Where does he go
for Thanksgiving?
Who shows up
at his graduation
with embarrassing signs
and a foghorn?
Um...
I actually wasn't thinking
that far ahead.
I was thinking more like
how can I help him today.
Sure, uh, oka...
Oh.
H-He'd like to talk
to his brothers and sister.
Do you know
anyone we can call?
So, he's healthy.
- And that feels like a miracle.
- Mm.
And, uh, he's already
the size of a cabbage,
uh, which means that I am
further along than I thought.
So, um, the baby
might be Owen's,
not Link's.
Might be, or is?
Might be.
Um, I don't know.
There wasn't
a ton of time
between the breakup
and the hookup.
Link and I
are really good together,
um, like,
almost painfully good.
You know, it felt like
that thing that we'd both earned
in this life.
It was accidental
and it was perfect, and...
And now it's not.
Because he wants to know
the baby's biology?
Because he's, um,
not sure that he wants
to be with me
if the baby isn't his.
And that makes me
not so sure
that I want
to be with him
if the baby is his.
You and Owen have
a complicated relationship.
Mm-hmm.
- Yeah. Um,
- Yeah.
That's what he said.
But I want him
to love me enough
that that doesn't matter.
I love you more than
my biological sisters.
Biology doesn't matter.
Love matters.
Okay.
And, still,
if I were Link,
I would be terrified.
I would terrified
that the baby is Owen's
and that, if it is,
that connection might reignite
whatever embers still exist
between you and Owen.
If I were Link,
I would want to know, too.
And it wouldn't have
anything to do
with how much
I love you.
Okay, but can you stop
pretending that you're Link?
Can you pretend
that you're me for a minute?
Okay.
Okay, okay.
Okay,
if I'm you...
..imagine that the hormones
coursing through my body
would be overwhelming.
They might overwhelm
rationality,
and I just might
want to be held...
..and, um,
loved no matter what...
..and reassured that
I'm not going to be alone.
Hey,
I love you.
I got you.
You're not
gonna be alone.
I love you.
Oh.
Hey, how you doing?
Uh, great.
Yeah. You?
Uh, Teddy's still got
the flu,
so I'm in single-dad mode,
but I can't complain.
Everything okay?
Not freaking out?
Trying not to.
Amelia's... what, she's...
She's halfway there, right?
Yeah,
something like that.
I noticed
she missed a couple days.
Everything okay?
There's no complications or...
Uh, hings are
definitely complicated,
but, uh...
But the baby's healthy.
Good, good.
That's good.
Yeah,
when Teddy was pregnant,
I remember feeling useless
most of the time.
Definitely feel useless.
Yeah.
How can you not?
I mean,
women go through something
that we can't
ever comprehend.
Best we can do is just listen,
sympathize,
and just keep trying to help...
..even if
you're not sure how.
I'm the one who got
kicked off the case, not you.
You can stay,
so stay.
Please. Consult.
Consult?
Your chief of surgery gave an
order that undoes everything.
I was...
We were making progress.
But now we've really made that
poor woman suffer for nothing.
Just e-mail me
the autopsy report,
and maybe we'll know
what happens then.
- Are you even listening to me?
- I-It's Suzanne's bone-marrow results.
Th-They're showing something
called hemophagocytosis?
Have you heard
of that?
That's MAS,
macrophage activation syndrome.
Her white cells are eating
her other blood cells.
Okay, okay. It's a complication
I've seen of Still's disease.
I've never seen it before
in person.
- MAS or Still's?
- Either.
It's extremely rare.
Okay, so... so this is it?
We... We figured it out?
Yeah!
But we don't have much time
- before her organs shut down.
- Yeah. Right.
Okay, let's go,
let's go. Come on.
She'll need
a few weeks' downtime
and some
physical therapy,
but she should make
a full recovery.
I used to judge people who,
uh...
people like me,
home-wreckers.
I never in a million years
thought that I would...
thought that I could.
What happened?
Why did you?
Life came in and taught me
not to judge others.
Life came in and turned me
upside down and shook me.
I'm so in love with her
that I don't care who gets hurt.
I just don't want it
to be me.
Now, look,
I know how that sounds,
but I'm not
a terrible person.
I-I take care
of my parents.
I-I mentor my students.
I plant trees
on the weekends,
and I... and I buy groceries
for homeless people.
I'm not
a terrible person.
I'm just a person
who's terribly in love.
V-fib. Paddles.
What the hell happened?
He was talking,
and he coded
right in front of us.
Uh, chest tube put out
about 400 ccs of blood.
He's bleeding into his chest. Alright,
I got it.
Move, Helm. Thank you.
Okay, charge to 120.
And... clear.
Still V-fib.
Alright, push another epi.
Charge to 200.
Okay, and clear.
Come on, Scott!
Come on!
- I'm gonna open his chest.
- Where? Here?
Yeah. Here.
Here, let's go.
Alright. Come on.
Betadine.
Hey. Um...
Brian, could you
give us a minute?
I need to talk to Rachel,
and I think
it would be better I...
What is it? Is it...
Is it Scott?
Is it... Does he know?
Did he see Brian?
No.
No, he didn't see Brian.
I'm sorry.
Scott, he...
He had major bleeding
inside his chest.
We tried to resuscitate him,
but we couldn't.
He died.
W-W-W-What?
Sweetie, I'm...
Don't... Don't...
Don't touch me.
Rachel, I...
Please.
Please, please.
Please, you need to leave.
Please.
♪ Fragile ♪
♪ The things we hide ♪
♪ 'Cause when they're broken ♪
You've reached Alex Karev.
Leave a message.
Hey, Alex.
I...
I need you to call me.
I need to hear
your voice.
I need to know
what's going on,
whatever it is.
♪ I wanna break down ♪
Whatever it is, I need to know.
I want to know.
Because...
Because I would jump in front
of a bear for you, Alex.
♪ Oh, I know I can see it ♪
Please call me.
♪ Oh, how long has the light
been gone? ♪
Hey, Joey.
We thought maybe you could
use a little company.
I just want to be alone.
You sure about that?
- You guys are here?!
- Careful of your arm.
I can't believe it!
Well, Dr. Bailey made a few
calls, pulled a few strings.
♪ Till I can see it ♪
Are you guys okay?
How are your new
foster parents?
I have a pretty nice lady
who makes pancakes.
Ours is actually okay.
I know you told us
not to get help,
but I was scared,
and I'm sorry.
No. Hey, it's okay.
You did the right thing.
I'm just glad
you're all okay.
I have my own room
with a purple bed.
Oh, yeah?
Now, they can't
stay all night,
but they can
stick around for pizza.
- Yes!
- Ooh.
And video games, 'cause
that PT is nonnegotiable.
♪ I can feel it,
I'm ready to begin ♪
Hmm.
Dr. Evans to the psych ward.
- Dr. Evans to the psych ward.
- Perez?
What, aren't you supposed to
be with Dr. Webber?
Oh, he said we could
leave early.
Good night, Chief Bailey.
You're an icon.
It's not even 5:00!
Hey, Suzanne.
Dr. DeLuca.
What are you doing?
Suzanne,
you have Still's disease.
It's rare, really rare.
Fewer than one in a million
people have it.
Dr. DeLuca,
what are you doing?
I don't have time, Dr. Grey. I don't
have time to ask your permission
to treat a patient
that I've been monitoring
around the clock.
DeLuca, let's step away
from the IV, please.
What did he just do?
What did you give her?!
Suzanne, there's no cure
for Still's disease,
but it can be managed,
and I just gave you
high-dose steroids,
and if I'm right, you should
start feeling better
almost immediately, okay?
Dr. DeLuca,
out in the hallway, please?
Wait, what
if you're wrong?
- He's not.
- I'm not.
Andrew, we couldn't have had a
conversation before you did that?
Andrew!
Well, if you're wrong,
the steroids could kill her.
I'm not wrong.
You were wrong to take
our case away from us.
He is my resident.
I am his supervisor.
You're also
his girlfriend.
It's muddy.
She'll need supervision.
..make you sleepy.
You look like
a new person.
I feel like one.
God, I feel alive again.
So, um, was it
the appendectomy
that gave her
the Still's disease?
Oh, no, we suspect
she had it before.
The flu-like symptoms
and the fatigue,
that's all a part of it.
Oh. And I thought
I was just tired
from chasing my kids around.
Your innate immune system
was in overdrive,
and the high-dose steroids
are bringing that
back to normal,
but you can't stay
on those forever.
So, then what's next?
We're going to set you up
with a rheumatologist.
People with Still's disease
can live very full lives.
We just need to get you
on the right medication.
Can you set me up
with my kids?
Yes. Now that your counts are
up, that's next on the list.
I don't know how you all
figured this out, but thank you.
Of course.
Let me go work on that for you.
Excuse me.
You should get in there and
let them thank you. I'm good.
Why don't you go in there
and take the credit?
You took the case over,
right? It's your patient.
Andrew, that was
an amazing diagnosis.
You saved her life.
Yeah, no thanks to you.
Andrew, but if you
had been wrong,
those steroids
could have wiped out
her entire bone marrow.
If you had been wrong,
your decision to go rogue
could've cost you
your entire career.
Okay, i-if I had asked
your permission
to administer the steroids,
would you have granted it?
I would have asked
a few questions.
Yes, and she could've
died when you did.
Okay, listen, Andrew,
you saved her life.
No one is trying to
take that away from you.
All I'm saying is you
could've taken a moment
to just tell me
what you were giving her.
Because at that time,
you were not
in the right state of mind
to be making life-or-death
decisions.
Right decisions.
Life-saving decisions, Mer.
Andrew, you're not sleeping,
you're not eating...
What? You are not
acting like yourself.
You are unbelievable!
You're such a hypocrite!
All... All... All the rules
apply to everybody else
except for you, is that it?!
Speaking Italian...
Hey.
Okay, Hayes, it's fine.
We're fine.
I saved her life!
I did that, okay?!
Against all odds, it was a
one-in-a-million diagnosis!
I did the job
that needed to be done!
Andrew,
listen to yourself!
You sound like
your father.
Just please, can you just
go home and get some sleep?
You just need to
go get some sleep.
I don't need this,
and I don't need you.
So we're done.
I'm done.
You should write him up, Grey.
That's not okay.
Yeah, thanks.
I told you I don't need
you checking up on me.
And I don't need
my residents leaving early
because they've
"done enough for the day."
I don't have it in me,
Bailey.
I mean, that set...
they aren't
Grey-Sloan caliber.
They shouldn't be here.
I mean, at Pac-North,
trying to teach them
felt... like a challenge.
But this...
This feels
like punishment.
Feels like Catherine won
and she's rubbing my nose
in it all day every day.
I know this isn't
an easy time.
But I want to help.
Tell me how to help you.
I'm just tired.
Just bone tired.
Well, that sounds
like depression.
I appreciate the concern.
I'll be okay.
♪ Stay with me ♪
I did it!
I got Joey to do PT
because I am
an excellent doctor.
♪ ...with you ♪
And I want to meet
your family.
It doesn't have to
be a whole dinner.
I can just meet
for dessert, or coffee...
Please don't make this
a thing.
You met
my neurotic mom.
You met my Uncle Saul
as he was gasping
for his last breath.
- You met my Aunt Gertie...
- Levi, I told you, they're critical.
Newsflash...
I know how to take criticism.
I've been doing it
my whole life.
If they think I'm not good enough,
I can deal with that.
No, they're critical of me
all the time,
no matter what I do, which
is why I haven't told them.
♪ When we're not at all? ♪
About me?
♪ But even giants need someone ♪
That I'm gay.
♪ To land on when they fall ♪
I haven't told them.
Um...
You... You called me
a baby gay.
You said that you wanted
no part in my shame spiral,
- you said...
- I-I-I know ...I know what I said. I...
♪ The shadows that we cast
could've made us feel ♪
I have to go
to dinner now.
A survey showed the
typical adult says "I'm fine"
14 times a week...
♪ And we're giants ♪
But less than 1 in 5
of them means it.
Our default is to put on
a brave face.
Have you heard
from her at all?
I'm really worried.
Yeah, I'm... I'm...
I have heard from her.
She's okay, Link.
She's okay.
She just doesn't
want to talk to me.
She just doesn't want to tell me
what the test said.
She doesn't know
what they are.
She didn't pick up
the test results.
And I'm not going to.
She was here.
Sorry I lied.
But sometimes it's braver
to admit something's wrong.
I'm growing a whole
human in my body,
and I want to raise him with
someone who is gonna love him
and me no matter what
a blood test says.
And it turns out
that's my sisters.
And I'm gonna be pushier
next time you're sad,
because you were raised
an only child,
but you are not one
anymore.
You are everything that
I never knew I needed.
- Amelia...
- Amelia.
Go home, Link.
We're over.
♪ When time is up
and the sun it dies ♪
♪ Do the rivers flood ♪
I really think it's mostly
just the hormones.
Does she plan on telling Owen
that the baby might be his?
Doesn't seem like it.
Okay.
Um, I...
♪ I will love you ♪
♪ When I'm oh so old
and I lose my mind ♪
♪ I'll still look at you like
it's the first time ♪
Because pretending
everything's fine
eventually catches up to you.
I shouldn't have left you
alone in the woods.
I shouldn't have
walked away.
I should not
have done that.
And I've owed you
an apology
that I've just been
too proud to give.
So I do apologize,
Maggie.
♪ Make it through the day ♪
Plus, you were right.
There were bears.
♪ You gimme the reason, oh ♪
Thank you.
You're welcome.
♪ To let on my ways ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ I will love you ♪
♪ When time is up
and the sun it dies ♪
♪ Till the rivers flood
and the ocean dries ♪
And when it does...
♪ Hand in hand under the falling sky ♪
...you better hope you can repair the damage