There's a blown water
heater at a residential location.
Southeast corner
of Gaze and Throup.
Copy that. Unit 47 will
respond in about five.
All right, everyone
wears rubber boots.
Find Carol that extra pair.
Hey, I thought the idea was
that you guys respond to
emergencies, not cause them.
Hang on, hang on.
We gotta pay you nurses back.
Every time an MICN rides
along, we get double the calls.
Come on, Riley,
you're gonna jinx us.
Shep!
This is unit 47 en route.
Copy, 47.
Uh-huh.
Ross? This is Ross.
Doesn't sound like...
No, Doug Ross. Ray's
away on business.
Let me... let me, uh,
let me give you somebody
who can answer that.
Here.
Hello. Hello? Is anybody there?
This is Karen Hines.
Oh, hi, Andy.
Uh, yeah. How, how
are the marlin running?
Oh, no kidding?
I... I thought you had fished
out every key south of Largo.
So, Andy, Ray
isn't there with you?
Oh, well, I guess he must
have gotten distracted
in the Caymans.
That's nice.
Yeah, yeah, you just tell
him he's got to call Chicago
when he gets in.
Yeah. Yeah, we miss him up here.
You know...
You are a good liar.
I wasn't lying.
I wasn't. I do miss Ray.
He's a kick.
He's a dying breed.
Oh, man, this is
really perverse.
Oh, hey, it's not like your
dad and I are going steady,
so let's just minimize
this Oedipus stuff.
You want to call in sick,
rent a Jackie Chan movie?
No, it doesn't work that way.
You could meet
me for a late lunch
around 4:00 is
what you could do.
I hate hospitals.
How do you feel about diners?
There's one across the street.
You could meet me there.
Uh-huh. A real diner?
Meatloaf, ketchup on the table.
You've seduced women
before, haven't you?
She's down here somewhere!
It just blew up!
Becky girl?
Your water heater was here
and your daughter's
bed was there?
Oh, my God.
Please, sir. Please.
You have to step away.
You shouldn't be down
here with bare feet. Please.
It's still standing water.
I told you we needed a new one.
We couldn't afford it.
But we can afford a
case of bourbon a week.
Would you just shut up!
Riley, go get backup,
all right? I got it.
It was making noises all week.
Why don't you just shut up!
All right, listen,
just take it easy!
What color pajamas
is she wearing?
Pink. Look for the color.
All right, when
was the explosion?
10 minutes...
Backup's on the way!
I found a foot!
All right. Yeah, here.
All right, take it easy.
Not too close. Not
too close. Easy.
Find her head!
Gently.
All right, let's go.
Gently. All right.
Let's roll her. Get the board.
Right.
One, two, three.
Oh, God.
Weak pulse. Breath sounds?
Oh, my God, she's not breathing!
Riley, get an ET tube.
Are you with us, Riley?
Yeah, yeah! Come on, come on.
Shoot!
For crying out loud!
I got another one! Come on!
Here, here! She's got it.
Oh, thank God!
Good breath sounds bilaterally.
Okay, darling, you're
going to be just fine.
Let's wrap her up.
Let's get her up.
One, two, three.
Easy, easy. Okay.
Give me the oxygen mask.
Sweetie...
Okay, sweetie, this is going
to help you breathe, okay?
Let's get outta here.
Are you taking
her to the hospital?
County.
Is she gonna be okay?
We're going to make
sure at the hospital.
Uh... I'm coming too.
I'll get dressed.
Gotta find your own transport.
The ambulance is full.
We can make room.
Forget it.
I'm not letting these
idiots into my rig.
It's the girl's mother.
Yeah, you heard her.
They knew the
heater was a hazard,
and they got a
kid living near it.
They're too drunk to notice.
Okay...
Stupid people shouldn't breed.
Morning.
Oh, morning.
How's it going? Going.
Man, did you
see all that traffic
this morning?
I took the El today as usual.
I didn't think you
were working today.
Oh, yeah, well, I got called in.
It's just as well.
How did it go last night?
I was thinking about you.
Uh, yeah, thanks. I
got your message.
I'll fill you in later.
Susan...
Glad you could fill in
on such short notice.
No problem.
You'll be able to go home by 4.
I can do a full 12.
Okay, let's get a CBC,
Chem-7, a heel stick...
Heel stick, a glucose.
I said that already? Twice.
Lip lac in 3.
Looks like stitches.
Oh. I'll get it.
Sure you can handle another?
Yup.
Mark, were you looking for me?
Morgenstern wants
to see us upstairs.
Did he say why?
Something wrong?
No, but it's May the 2nd,
so it could be the announcement.
Announcement?
Resident of the Year...
Not that I'm expecting it.
Emergency medicine
always gets overlooked.
Oh, yeah. Resident of the year.
Did I remember to
put your name in?
I did.
Doesn't he make the
announcement in June?
First of May.
So do you think you're
gonna need me today?
The reason I'm asking
is, if you don't need me,
and there's nothing
on the schedule,
Simon got me in
to assist on a breast
reconstruction at 10,
which is a procedure
that I haven't done yet.
Somebody page me?
Dr. Ross, Trauma 1.
Hey, I hear you're doing
a OB rotation at Parkland?
I fly to Dallas on Friday.
I want to talk to you
before you leave, all right?
I'm here.
Where's Ross?
Went out to meet the paramedics.
Got a little girl in bad shape.
Dr. Benton...
since a lot of surgeons
have mentioned
that an elective in
plastics can't hurt...
Oh, plastics. The
beautiful people's specialty.
I thought I'd check it out.
Well, go on. Go. Go.
You sure? Yeah.
Thank you. Thank you!
I got your page.
Yeah. On this
lovely May morning,
we have a 6-year-old girl
exhumed from two feet of rubble.
Respiratory arrest.
Resuscitated on the scene.
BP 90/60.
Thanks for calling me early.
Just protecting myself.
If we're going to
be working together,
I'll make sure that
you're on board
from the very beginning.
He must have been
wearing a big ring.
Yeah. This could
take a few stitches.
Will there be a scar?
Well, there could be
at the vermilion border
where the lip meets the skin.
Do you want me to
call a plastic surgeon?
Not that I'll be
staring in the mirror,
but my boyfriend says
I have a pretty face.
You do.
Somebody's mighty
low to be mugging you.
Honey, three times in two years.
They think the blind
are an easy target.
Well, I think you
set this one straight.
That self-defense course
was worth every penny.
The cane worked like a charm.
Radared in on his balls.
Bam! Bull's-eye!
He let go of your purse, did he?
Wouldn't you?
What's that, Ms. Crandle?
Tip of his pinkie.
You bit his finger off?
Well, if the police
don't need it
for evidence, I want
it for a souvenir.
I want mommy!
Shh, she'll be here
in a minute, sweetie.
C-spine is clear.
Let's get that collar off.
No pneumo.
All right. DPL's negative.
Crit's normal. No
internal bleeding.
Becky...
you're one lucky little girl.
Good work in the field, 47.
Lucky Carol was with us.
It was very scary,
but you are a brave little girl.
Where's my mommy?
She'll be here any minute.
All right, hold on.
We've got a bulge in the groin.
Where? There.
Reducible hernia?
Incarcerated.
Probably caused by increased
intra-abdominal pressure.
From the trauma?
Mm-hm. Let's get
her up to Surgery.
Becky, tell you what,
you're gonna be fine.
Dr. Benton, here, is gonna
fix you right up, okay?
And as soon as your
mommy and daddy get here,
I'm going to bring
them up to see you.
Gosh, no. Sorry to disappoint.
Don't they announce
that in June?
No. First of May.
Doesn't matter.
It was a long shot.
No. I called the two of you up
to start a conversation
about next year's
Chief Resident.
Good idea.
Hope you don't mind me
including Kerry in
this conversation.
Not at all.
She's one of the strongest
Chiefs we've had in years.
You did a fine job
for us also, Mark.
I thought Kerry and you
could make this
a mutual decision.
Susan Lewis would
be my first choice.
Before we discuss
specific candidates,
we ought to brainstorm
about what qualities
we'd see in an ideal chief.
Makes sense.
An ER chief needs
to be focused in crisis.
Exactly.
A leader in the ER
needs to cut to the chase,
assume the worst.
Right. Don't you think
Susan Lewis has that quality?
I think Kerry's right.
Let's not try to
solve this today.
Let's just start
the ball rolling.
Carter, glad I caught you.
Yes, I was just about to assist
on my first breast
reconstruction.
Well, I'm afraid you aren't.
Why?
Did you call the
registrar's office
requesting a review
of your transcript?
I wanted to verify
that I'm graduating with honors.
They discovered when
they pulled your records
that you're deficient in
ambulatory medicine.
What?
You can't graduate
without seeing
the required number
of Pedes patients.
What?
Luckily...
Doug Ross is
willing to take you on
for the next four weeks.
I was hoping for an
elective in plastics.
Good news is,
if you start this morning,
you have the time to
complete this remedial work
and graduate with
the rest of your class.
Dr. Ross is expecting you.
Yeah, and I want that
consult down here stat.
Susan, did you just say "stat"?
Yeah, and I mean it.
Oh, look who's here!
Isn't she precious?
She looks just like her mommy.
Will she let me hold her?
Oh, I hope so.
My arm's about to fall off.
Hello! Hello!
So tiny!
Hello, baby. Hello.
Nice outfit.
I think so.
Hey, it's Randiwear, right?
Aw...
Susan, code.
What do you got?
A woman passed
out in a crosswalk.
GCS 10 in the field.
She's coming around.
Okay. Trauma 1.
Ma'am? Ma'am? Do
you know where you are?
Uh-huh. All right.
Let's move her
on a count of three.
One...
two...
three.
Get a glucose.
Look she's
hypertensive. 170/120.
Titrate a Nipride drip
to a diastolic of 100.
Ma'am, do you have a
history of high blood pressure?
Oh, no! Not again.
Okay, okay, okay, try and relax.
Her name is Joanne Bairos.
Joanne, we're going to try
and lower your blood pressure.
Has this happened before?
I don't wanna lose
this baby! Not again.
You're pregnant? Yeah.
How far along?
Um, 20... No, no. 21 weeks.
Okay, cancel the Nipride.
Give her 10 of Hydralazine.
Call OB.
You lost an earlier baby?
Last year in the sixth month.
Oh, God, I can't live
through this again.
Okay, hook her up to the
fetal monitor and an EKG.
Did you have
preeclampsia before?
Do you remember?
They said it was
high blood pressure.
It made my placenta tear,
and if they didn't take
the baby out, I'd die.
I see.
My baby was too little.
She couldn't live.
BP is rising. 180/130.
Add Propranolol.
Who's on call for OB? Dr. Croix.
But it's not the baby's fault.
Your hypertension is probably
related to the pregnancy.
No, no, but I've
been dizzy sometimes
in between the pregnancies.
You have?
Yes.
What's the fetal heart rate?
145. Good variability.
Please, don't let them take her.
Susan, shouldn't we
be moving her up?
No. I'm going to do
an ultrasound first.
Her BP's 190/140.
The fetus isn't in distress.
I want an ultrasound first.
What are you doing?
Trying to save your baby.
I don't know. I'll check it out.
Yeah, I heard
you. I'll check it out.
Told you they were mad.
Haleh, is that ultrasound
for the hypertensive patient
OB's screaming at me about?
Who the hell ordered that?
I'll take care of it.
Bring me up to speed.
Hypertensive woman
in her 21st week.
Fetal heart tones normal.
She responded to Hydralazine
and Propranolol.
What's the BP?
130/100.
She's stable for transfer.
Any contractions?
Some cramping,
nothing on the monitor.
It's preeclampsia.
Get her up to OB.
It's Susan's patient, Kerry.
Patient lost a
22-week fetus last year
to preeclampsia.
For goodness sake...
Complains of dizzy spells
and possible hypertension
between pregnancies.
Any protein in the urine?
Susan, if we've
learned anything...
Yes, yes, there.
Right there... mass in
the right adrenal gland.
Call the O.R. to
schedule a room.
You're right. Looks
like Conn's syndrome.
What does that mean?
You have a tumor
in your adrenal gland
producing a hormone,
which is making your
blood pressure rise.
It's very serious.
You'll probably need
surgery to remove the mass.
But the baby?
It should be okay.
Cancel OB, we're
going straight to Surgery.
Good call, Susan.
I think all of us would
have missed that one.
They could have done
the ultrasound up in OB.
Yeah, they aborted
her last time.
Let Surgery know
we're on the way.
Well, I think we've earned
ourselves a doughnut.
Anyone else want a Dinkle's?
They've got some inside.
Help yourself.
Could you bring me back one?
Yeah, you bet.
He's trying.
Now I'm supposed to eat
doughnuts with the guy?
It's not his fault
Raul died, Shep.
It's not your fault, either.
I know. I know
whose fault it is.
It's the fine,
upstanding, drugged-out
meth-burning citizens
we're here to serve.
That's who Raul died for.
Oh, you're kidding.
Yeah, that's what I heard...
Resident of the Year.
I guess it isn't a
personality contest, huh?
Do we have to go to the party?
There's gonna be cake.
Anyone seen Dr. Ross?
Check the lounge.
Ted, you're an attorney...
Never say "trust me."
So divorce wasn't slow
and complicated enough
with two parties
and two lawyers.
Now we have to get
a mediator involved.
I don't believe in divorce.
I always suspected you
were an old-fashioned girl.
Don't believe in
marriage, either.
Oh! Dr. Benton,
your highness, sir.
Dr. Bradley was looking for you.
When?
Just now. He said it
was regarding your letter
to the ethics committee.
Thanks.
I'm gonna need some help.
Loretta? Loretta, I got you.
I got you. I got you.
Clear Curtain Area 2, okay?
I got you.
All right.
So I don't pretend to be happy
about the situation,
but I'm gonna do
my best for you...
and I'm available at any hour.
She's not falling for the
guy with amnesia, is she?
Nah, she's faking.
Ever since she got possessed,
it's completely
changed her personality.
So do you need me
for anything right now?
Well, we'll see what comes in.
You're a fourth year,
so you're not going to
need a lot of hand-holding.
You're gonna get me out
on time, which works for me,
so just show up, hang
out, and you'll get an A.
Something tells me that it
will change our lives forever.
Whatever happened
to his brain tumor?
Oh, it was cured when
he was struck by lightning.
Oh.
It was not.
Watch out. He's gonna drug her.
You ready?
I promise you.
You will not be disappointed.
BP's 70/50.
Okay, let's get that EKG.
Does your father have a
history of heart problems?
Not before a few weeks ago.
He was having trouble
breathing breathing at night,
so he went to the clinic.
They said my heart wasn't
pumping hard enough.
Did they give you
any medications?
Oh, yeah, they did.
Here they are.
Danny, honey, no! I'm so sorry.
I'm really sorry.
What do we got?
Mr. Dellanova's complaining
of nausea and blurred vision.
Why don't you show
them to the waiting room?
When did he get this medicine?
Oh, on the 18th.
How's that EKG, Kerry?
Sinus brady with
second-degree AV block?
How'd you guess?
Yeah, he took way
too many tablets.
He should have
twice as many left.
Malik, get a dig
level. What is it?
Your father
overdosed on digoxin.
Is that serious?
Yeah, it can be, but
we've caught it in time.
Stand by with Digibind
or do you want a lavage?
It's all yours.
Dr. Bradley, you
were looking for me,
Dr. Benton.
Ah, yes. I'm sorry
it took so long
to respond to your letter.
Well, I, uh, I know
you're a busy man.
I gather you are too. Your
letter was dated April 23,
but you left
Dr. Vucelich's study
in early February?
That's true.
So it took you almost
three months to report
on what you yourself called
"an alarming disregard for
research study protocol?"
Well, I was hesitant
to make accusations
against Dr. Vucelich... I
mean, a man of his stature.
I believe that
caution is warranted.
Let me return your
letter to you now.
Uh... these claims are accurate.
Oh, I have no doubt
since they are reported
in the addendum
to Dr. Vucelich's study.
He's owning up to it?
Apparently, it was
always intended
to be part of the
published article.
When did Dr. Vucelich
add this addendum,
before or after
I sent the letter?
I wouldn't be able
to answer that.
Feeling better?
Some.
What happened?
You were dehydrated.
Oh. I couldn't keep
anything down.
Did your oncologist
prescribe Compazine?
No.
Did you tell him
about your symptoms?
I tried, but he's pretty busy.
I called about the burns,
and he never got back to me.
Radiation burns?
I thought it was something
that was supposed to happen,
but another woman
in the waiting room
says I shouldn't
be getting burned.
What's your
oncologist's name again?
Dr. Lyle Howard.
Look, my kids
are at a neighbor's.
Yeah.
Can they spend the night?
You're being
admitted. I'll stop back.
Mark, Susan just had
an interesting case,
but I can't convince her
to present it to the students.
There's not much to present.
Sure there is.
You all met my new
student, John Carter?
You're doing a Pedes rotation?
Never too late.
You're mighty chipper today.
Yes, I am. Thank you.
So, Mark, I was
trying to explain
that Susan needs
to think like a teacher,
explain how she
arrived at her diagnosis.
I don't know,
it just occurred to me
he took too many pills.
Oh, it's freezing in here.
I'm trying to impress on Susan
the importance of recognizing
a good opportunity
to augment her teaching files.
How did the patient present...
Oh, damn it!
Where are you?
Susan? Susan, what do you think?
I've got patients waiting.
I gotta get back to work.
Ah...
All right. Okay, buddy.
You're not feeling
so great, huh?
What's his temperature?
103.
Okay, Carter,
this is a good
place for you to start.
Why don't you come get me
and present your findings.
No problem.
I'm going to listen
to your chest.
Okay, take a deep breath for me.
Oh, Dr. Ross, someone
named Karen called for you.
Any message?
Confirming lunch.
Oh, Karen's her name, huh?
Where'd you meet her?
We have a mutual acquaintance.
Did you ever get a
hold of that oncologist
Uh... Howard?
Secretary said he would
be tied up all afternoon.
Where is he?
Uh...
Upstairs...
number 701.
Mark...
do you have a second?
This is, uh, Jennifer, my, uh...
Soon-to-be ex-wife.
Hi. Randi.
You have a great
soon-to-be ex-husband.
Excuse me.
Where's Jerry?
Huh?
Oh, he... he's off today.
Is something wrong?
No. I was just in
town to see my lawyer.
You know, I don't know,
about an hour into the meeting,
I realized I'd spent $250.
It just seems so ridiculous.
I just... We've been making
decisions together for 15 years.
I just thought we
could get together and...
cut to the chase.
My shift ends at 8.
Great. I'll swing by then.
Yeah.
1033.
Great. Now what?
Has anyone called
for paramedics?
Hello?
My brother, he's shot.
This way.
Stay close.
Whore!
One more word out of you,
and your pal can
fricking bleed to death
right where he is.
We're sorry. Please.
She's a nurse, and she works
every day saving your asses!
I'm okay, Shep.
I wish you would've
stayed in the rig.
I've spotted our customer.
Stand back, stand back.
He's barely breathing.
Time to practice again, Riley.
I've got it.
Weak pulse.
I'm gonna start an IV.
My God, how many
times was he shot?
Is he dying? Don't let him die.
Step back! Just let me work!
Riley, go get the board.
We're gonna need the board.
Got it.
All right, IV's in, wide open.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm good, I'm good.
Back off!
Come on!
Take a deep breath.
You're doing fine.
Help him, man! Come on!
You gotta step back.
Help him!
Come on, man,
help him! Help him!
Stay off!
Hey! Take it easy, man.
Easy!
Hey, what happened?
Guy wouldn't back off.
He's out cold.
Good. Maybe now I can work.
So that's your diagnosis.
That the kid has the flu?
Viral syndrome.
I prescribed fever control
measures and fluids.
He's got a rash, conjunctivitis,
swollen glands.
How long's he had the fever?
His mom said about a week.
Fever of unknown origin
for seven days.
Did I miss something?
What color's his tongue?
Pink.
Not strawberry?
Uh, maybe. I'm not sure.
Did you notice his chapped lips?
Yeah.
All right, give him an aspirin
and order an echocardiogram.
Aspirin?
I thought you never
gave aspirin to a child.
Unless, of course,
he's diagnosed with Kawasaki's.
Kawasaki's. Um...
Kawasaki's is a cluster of
unremarkable symptoms
that can lead to
coronary aneurysm.
Fever, chapped lips,
and the strawberry
tongue are the tip-offs.
Admit the boy to the Pedes unit.
Right away.
Susan?
Susan, I thought you
went home at 4:00.
What, and miss the big party?
Yeah, yeah, I just heard.
Certainly my choice
for Resident of the Year.
So you're not
avoiding going home?
Well, there's that, too.
Look, do you want
to get a bite to eat
later on or something?
Damn, I just made plans.
I can cancel... No, no.
I... I'm fine.
Tomorrow?
Yeah, sure... well, we'll see.
Mr. Dellanova, you're
doing much better.
We're going to admit
you to CICU for follow-up.
Okay, I need your
John Hancock on this.
All these lines?
Just the one marked "Patient."
Uh...
Your father said
the overdose was an accident?
Oh, yes.
The dosage was right
there on the bottle.
My mom died a few months ago.
He misses her.
I've had to take
over doing his bills,
but that's just because
he hates paperwork.
He always has.
He's not the suicidal type.
And does he need
glasses for reading?
He's more of a TV-watcher.
Ma'am, if you'll come with me,
we'll get him admitted.
Pop, I'll be right back, okay?
Bye, sweetheart. All right.
Mr. Dellanova, do
you know my name?
I know I owe my life to you.
No, my name. I'm wearing it.
Can you read this?
Um... uh... doctor something.
I can't make out
the... the second part.
I'm Dr. Lewis...
and you need to tell your
daughter that you can't read.
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
I thought the clinic said
something about twice a day.
Then I thought
maybe it was two
pills each time.
Medications can be
tricky for a lot of reasons.
I never wanted my kids to know.
I wanted them to...
to do school... right.
And you raised a good daughter,
and now you should
let her help you.
You want your kids not
to be ashamed of you.
You have children, right?
Uh, no. No, I don't.
Excuse me, it's been a bad day.
Yeah, stack it in the lounge
and put the cake in there too...
What's this?
Sparkling cider.
For some announcement thing.
Dr. Greene told
me to put it in there.
Don't tell him I saw it.
All right, Carter,
I'm going across the
street to grab lunch,
and I'm late,
so you page me if you need me,
and, Carter, if
you're wondering,
you do still need me.
I know. I will. Uh-huh.
Got a twofer.
Adolescent male
sprang a few leaks
when one of his homeboys
disapproved of his method
of tying twisties
on the baggies.
Guy on gurney two
fell down and went boom.
All right, I'm with Shep.
Carter, you take two!
Haleh, get Benton
for me, please.
I'll join you in a
minute, Mr. Carter!
Okay.
All right, start
pumping the fluids.
Four units O-negative
on the rapid infuser.
BP's 40 palp.
Kid's Swiss cheese.
He's draining like a sieve.
I'll start a central line.
Get a CBC, Chem-20,
and chest films.
How old do you
think this kid is?
My guess is 14,
but look at the scars.
He's been around.
V-fib!
Let's shock him.
No, hang on. Move back.
Mmm.
Excuse me.
Just a second.
Ross called me?
Trauma 1.
He's not responding.
Thoracotomy tray.
Finally, Peter. I'll
check on Mr. Carter.
Number 10 blade, please.
Whoa, what is that,
an entrance wound
or an exit wound?
At this point, who can tell?
You want me to crack him?
No, I got it. There you go.
Rib spreader.
I'll break it for you.
Thanks.
Oh, what a mess.
Bullet must have
nicked the aorta.
Need some suction here, please.
Aorta's cross-clamped.
He's in fib!
Internal paddles!
Need another
three units, please.
Hang on. Give me 20.
Charging. Clear!
Again, 30.
We've got a rhythm. Let's go!
Shooting!
Clear.
Okay, did you get an AP, a
lateral, and an open-mouth?
Once he clears his C-spine,
let's send him for a panorex.
No signs of
respiratory distress.
One million units Pen G.
I feel a step deformity.
What did he hit
his jaw on again?
One of those stone coffee
tables, pretty sharp edge.
Yeah, he fell right
over backwards onto it.
Well, he really
didn't fall, did he?
He was pushed.
Yeah, well, I shoved him.
I was trying to tube his pal.
You threw him across the room.
I wish I'd have
thrown him. I felt like it.
Well, however he fell,
he needs a head CT.
Let's call Maxillofacial
to wire the jaw?
Well done, Mr. Carter.
Are you looking for someone?
Um...
Coming through!
Sorry.
Hey. Hi.
Hi.
Sorry I'm late. I got held up.
I think I'll wait outside.
Okay, I'll be there in a minute.
Oh, take your time.
Yeah.
Hey, Riley. What?
Don't ever pull that crap again.
What are you talking
about? What crap...
You know what I mean!
Is it too late for our lunch?
I kind of lost my appetite.
Yeah, I guess you didn't
see anything in there
that'd change your
opinion about hospitals.
Or doctors.
Hey, Doug...
you haven't by any chance
heard from your dad today,
have you?
No, I haven't. Why?
I can't reach him
in the Caymans.
Oh, that's all
right, He'll turn up.
He always does.
Although sometimes,
it takes years.
Oh, you think that's funny.
Yeah. He's got some
of my hard-earned
money with him.
A lot of money?
Enough.
Hey...
There's really only one thing
to do after a day like today.
And what's that?
What time do you get off?
Boy, did I pick the
wrong specialty.
Yeah, what's that?
Emergency medicine.
Damn radiation oncologists
work a few hours a day,
and then they lock their doors
at 10 to 5:00.
Those radiation oncologists
sound pretty smart.
You're Dr. Howard, aren't you?
You're Mark Greene?
I saw your name
on the call sheet.
I didn't have time
to get back to you.
I was calling about
a patient of yours,
Loretta Sweet.
She's down in the ER.
She's hypovolemic with cystitis.
Yeah, that happens.
ER sounds like the
right place for her.
She seemed unprepared
for the side effects.
If she complains
at her next visit,
I'll prescribe Compazine.
She tried to bring
up a few things.
I think she feels a
little overwhelmed
and confused.
Don't they all?
Maybe that should
tell you something
about your success
at keeping your
patients informed.
I give my patients
plenty of information.
She also has radiation burns.
This a relative of yours?
Friend of the family.
Catch me during office hours,
I'll review her chart.
Trauma 2! Didn't
you get the page?
What page?
Hicks, she's frantic.
She says a multiple trauma in 2.
I didn't get a page.
She paged you half an hour ago.
Surprise!
For he's A jolly good fellow
For he's a jolly Good fellow
For he's a jolly good fellow
Which nobody can deny
Resident of the year.
Congratulations.
Congratulations, Peter.
All right, Dr. B!
So it's a prestige thing.
I mean, they'll never
give it to an ER Resident.
Susan... there's a patient here
that you're going
to want to see.
You were off an hour
ago. You want me to get it?
No, I'm fine.
I won't deny it.
When Susan's on
her game, she's good.
I agree. Focused and decisive.
She was today.
I just wish she was
like that all the time.
She's not very adept
at keeping her personal problems
out of her work.
Night, all. See you.
Uh, Peter, congratulations.
You deserve it.
I hate to run, but I
got an appointment.
Good work, Peter.
I'm proud of you.
So give my best to Karen.
So, Peter, I have
an intussusception
in half an hour.
Care to join me?
Sure.
I think I'll cash in on my
15 minutes' worth of fame.
You've worked
hard enough for it.
So did you nominate me?
No, I believe that
was Carl Vucelich.
So in case you thought
I hadn't noticed, I had.
I'm gonna miss you.
Good. You should.
I want a big piece.
There you are.
It's too big.
You want some?
What is it?
Oh, man, I'm so pissed.
What?
Over Riley.
Punk.
He put in a freaking
incident report
against me.
What?
Yeah. He said I used
excessive force with that guy,
that banger with the busted jaw.
He made it sound like
I went off or something.
Guy's supposed to be my partner.
Why would he say that?
He's green. You
know, he was amped.
We were all amped.
I mean, you saw it. I
barely shoved that guy.
Come on. It's been a long day.
So we'll say, every Wednesday,
every other weekend,
and we'll rotate
summers and holidays.
That should work.
And we'll include
the stipulation
that we both have to stay in
the Chicago-Milwaukee area
until Rachel graduates
from high school.
Can you even imagine?
No.
Well, that was easy.
So should we split
up the stock portfolios?
Ha! Sure.
I'll split a piece
of pie with you.
You're on.
Slice of, uh, rhubarb?
All right.
Two forks.
Coming up.
Why don't you wait over there?
Okay.
So, Mr. Johnson,
I hear you had
a little accident.
Yeah, I cut my finger.
I was making a sandwich.
The kitchen can be
a dangerous place.
It won't stop bleeding.
Ah, cut the tip
of your pinkie off.
We'll need to irrigate that.
Are you right-handed,
Mr. Johnson?
Yeah.
Then how did you
manage to cut the tip
of your right pinkie off?
Yeah, wouldn't you
have to cut your left hand?
I don't know.
Hmm...
and what about
your, uh, other injury?
Uh, fell back on my chair
and landed on the leg.
All right, you wanna lie back
so I can look at that?
Oh, yeah. That's one
mean testicular contusion.
We'll need to do an
ultrasound of his pelvis.
Immobilize his legs.
You're going to
need to lie very still.
So did you bring the
tip of your finger in?
We can graft it back on.
Uh, no, I couldn't find it.
Lost in the kitchen, huh?
Well, it doesn't matter.
We can probably
make this one fit.
Hey!
Let me up! Let me up!
That was fun.
Made my day.
I can't believe
we just did that.
Me neither.
Oh, God.
What am I going to tell Craig?
You've handled that one before.
Is that what this was? Revenge?
Parting shot?
No.
No, no, no, no.
Uh...
it was just a bad idea.
Yes, it was.
Girl, I'm talking, 'bout you
I'm talking 'bout you, now
I don't care what you do
This okay? Right here okay?
Um, well, I don't
think we should sit
until we dance.
No, no. No, no, no.
What? Are you getting shy on me?
Shy? What? Are you kidding me?
I was gonna complain,
because it's not
big enough out here.
Not big enough for you.
Well...
I'm talking 'bout
you You, you
I'm talking 'bout you
Girl, I'm talking 'bout you
I'm talking 'bout you, now
I don't care what you do
I'm talking 'bout you.
And... dip!
Oh, God.
That was a good one.
If you're gonna
Walk on my loving...
Well, am I right or am I right?
This a good way to end the day?
What day?
If you're gonna
walk On my lovin'
Well, the least you can
do Is take off your shoes
Yeah, come here.
Oh, yeah, you're so big.
You're such a big girl.
Aren't you, sweetie?
Yeah...
Yeah.
Oh...
Yeah. Yeah,
you're going to
go on a big, big,
big, big trip.
We're not gonna push too hard.
She usually does
okay in the car.
I love you, Suz.
Hurry and come visit.
Can you put her in the seat?
Oh, no, sweet pea, don't cry.
Here we go, sweetie.
Watch her head.
Yeah, there you go.
Oh, no, sweet pea, don't cry.
It's okay.
Yeah, it's okay.
Yeah.
Oh, my.
Where's Mr. B?
Who?
That ratty pink and blue bear.
I put him by the door!
She cannot ride without him!
Did you pack it? I don't know.
I know I left it by the door.
Where is B?
Yeah, yeah, it's
okay. It's okay.
Yeah. We'll find him.
Here, here, here.
Will this work?
No, it has to be the bear!
She can't sleep, either!
Damn it! Okay,
I'll go look upstairs.
Oh...
Okay.
Okay. Yeah. I'm still looking.
It's okay, Susie.
Damn it, Mr. B, where are you?
Susie needs you.
Hey, Susie! It's okay!
We found it!
Yeah. Yeah...
Everything's going
to be okay now.
There you go. Yeah.
Look, we found it, sweetie.
No, no. You do it.
Come on.
Shh. Here's Mr. B. See?
Come on. Come on.
Yeah.