Who picked this dump?
You suggested it.
I suggested you look into it.
Sorry, the online reviews...
Were obviously written by some
geek in their own marketing department.
Next time, call
someone you know.
Stop relying on a computer
to do your job for you.
Brightsize Apparel,
eight sexual harassment
suits in two years.
Who asked for the
meeting? They did.
Patty Michener, President
of Women's Majority.
And, wow, do you guys need me.
Nine men?
No one thought it might be a good
idea to put a suit on one of the gals
from the steno pool to make
it look like you give a damn?
We've made it a priority to
promote more women, but...
Well, from now on, you
have me standing beside you.
Which is good, because your
problem is a national problem.
With all due respect,
Miss Michener,
I'd hardly call a few isolated
incidents a national problem.
Six out of 10 victims never
even report harassment,
this is bigger than
just eight women.
That still only means 20.
Not enough for you?
How many asses does your
corporate policy allow you to grab?
Tell you what
you're going to do,
you're gonna settle with
anyone you haven't settled with,
you're going to fire any man
who's even been accused.
Somebody, help me!
Please, help me! I
can't get them off!
Please help me! Help me, please!
Somebody help me! Get them off!
You gonna call an ambulance or
you just gonna sit there and stare?
Help me, please!
Wilson's back. You gonna...
Been gone two months,
he can wait till I finish slaying a
guy in a skullcap and a pair of tights.
On a video game you stole
from the pediatric ward?
On advice of counsel, I assert
my privilege pursuant to the Fifth.
When was the last
time you talked to him?
Uh, I think it was after...
When did his girlfriend die?
He wanted time alone.
I considered being a
horrendous pain in the ass,
but I didn't want to
tread on your turf.
We got a case.
I got to remember
to close the blinds.
Just got a call from
Patty Michener,
from Women's Majority,
the women's rights...
We know who she is. I dated her.
Well, not really dated her,
more metaphorically
raped her by having a penis.
You did, too. Her
assistant flipped out,
ripped off her clothes in front
of a roomful of businessmen.
Either she cracked
under the whip,
or she started to realize
that her evolutionary purpose
is to arouse men,
not to castrate them.
Send her to psychiatric...
Anemia, bradycardia,
and abdominal pain aren't
psychiatric symptoms.
Then it's the latter, send
her to my apartment.
I'll give it to Segal.
House actually wants a
case, and you're saying no?
House has more
important things to do.
Sorry, can't help you.
You need a specialist to
remove those kinds of warts.
Preferably one with
experience spelunking.
Hallucinations,
possible memory loss,
tests show anemia,
slow heart rate,
and a stubborn refusal
to shave her pits.
Have you seen Wilson?
No, but I have seen the
patient's frequent flyer balance.
Eastern Europe, Asia, third-world
countries, sometimes more than one a day.
No fever means it's
not a tropical disease.
If it's not where she went,
maybe it's the work hours.
Could be amphetamine abuse.
She's probably popping
them like breath mints.
You haven't been by his office?
Is Wilson hallucinating ants
crawling all over him, too?
Tox screen's cleaner than
the windows she won't do.
Her job keeps her
constantly on the road,
probably living off of airline
peanuts and diet soda.
Severe B12 deficiency
could cause all her symptoms.
Why is everyone
leaping to conclude
a strong career woman's been
made sick by her strong career?
It's not B12. It's an
insulinoma in her pancreas,
it's making her hypoglycemic.
Great, now everyone knows.
You knew the patient had cancer?
Is that what she said?
I thought she said,
"I'm suddenly and irrationally
defending the patient's strong career,
"even though in reality
she's just a glorified grunt
"because I'm trying to convince
myself that it's okay not to have a life,
"" cause I don't have a life,
because I was tested for Huntington's
"and my lifespan's
been cut in half."
Been waiting two
months for her to say that.
Hallucinations,
anemia, bradycardia...
Hyper segmented polys
says that Taub's right.
Pump her full of B12,
see how a strong career woman's
been made sick by her strong career.
Are you okay?
It could be years before
you see any symptoms.
Why wouldn't you tell us?
I don't have Huntington's.
Are you lying to us? Because
it's none of our business.
If it's none of your business, I
shouldn't have to answer questions.
And I wouldn't have to, except
House doesn't want to answer
questions about Wilson.
He's deflecting his
own problems onto me.
Are you deflecting now?
Time for the B12
cocktail and my life lesson.
No, Patty'll do the hearing, she just
needs to be the lead-off witness so she...
Okay. I'll lock it down today.
Need you back in bed.
My boss has a big Beijing trip,
I've been planning it for months.
I was just tired
and dehydrated...
Yeah, whenever I
lose some shut-eye,
I pound my legs clawing
at imaginary ant colonies.
You have a severe
B12 deficiency.
Get back in bed.
I'm sure your boss can do
without you for a few days.
It's not about
her, it's about me.
I want to be there,
I want to matter.
Yeah, I mean, without you, who knows
how much starch they'd put in her shirts?
I'm sorry, I'm sure your
boss depends on you for...
I need to get up. No,
you need to stay in bed.
Please, where's the bed pan?
Oh, my God, I'm sorry, I just...
I just had a bowel movement.
It's okay, B12 deficiency
can cause sudden...
That's not a bowel movement.
My patient is still fighting in the
feminist trenches, but the war is over.
Yesterday's sluts are
today's empowered women,
today's sluts are celebrities.
If that isn't progress...
I'm leaving.
What, you're gonna
take another two months?
Boy, you're really milking this
bereavement thing, aren't you?
I mean, good for you.
Take all the time you need.
I'm resigning.
Maybe moving out of New
Jersey, I don't know yet.
Okay, that's an
understandable reaction.
It's not a reaction,
it's a decision.
I'm writing Cuddy my
resignation right now.
I'm just back for the week to wrap up
my clinical and administrative duties.
You of all people should
know, this is bereavement 101.
You think that a
change in venue...
Well, that spares me
decades of psychoanalysis.
I'm not saying
you're not in pain.
You're saying
my pain's a cliché.
I'm saying that pain fades.
Did yours?
Physical pain is different.
I'd rather have
my leg chopped off.
You don't know that
'cause you haven't felt...
Neither have you.
Sorry, patient's
got a rectal bleed.
I'm busy. We need you to...
Actually, as you
can see, I'm not busy.
It was just a euphemism
for "get the hell out of here."
This is your grief talking,
and, yeah, it is a bit textbook.
So before you give away all your
possessions to the Salvation Army...
My girlfriend's dead.
I'm glad you've read
that book before, I haven't.
I'm late to meet Dr. Olan to brief
him on the cases I'm handing over.
Bye.
It doesn't bother you
that House wouldn't take
just two seconds to
talk about the patient?
Wilson's dealing with a lot.
And our patient may be dying.
She was bleeding out her
rear, we're looking up her rear.
You think we needed House's
expertise to set us on this course?
Her heart rate's slow, bleed
should have made it faster.
And it can wait till after we
know where it came from.
And after he's done
dealing with personal issues.
Yeah? That the way
it works around here?
We get cut slack while we
deal with personal issues?
You're not the boss.
Boss gets to make the
rules, boss gets to ignore...
She's bleeding from nowhere.
You did an endoscopy?
And a colonoscopy.
CT scan? Ordered.
But it shouldn't show
anything the endoscopy didn't.
We can't do a CT scan.
Why not?
We don't need a CT
scan, we don't need House.
Stop grinning and talk.
One of the routine
pre-procedure tests was positive.
Which one? The
one that if it's positive
would explain a
hormone imbalance
that could screw with
heart rate and blood flow.
Guess she does have
a life beyond her career.
I'm pregnant?
You want to call the
father? Let him know?
Soon as you do some
DNA testing, let me know.
Must be hard to have a real
relationship when you're...
Are you making excuses for me?
I'm just saying it's
understandable.
You only have to understand
something if it needs an explanation.
I have needs, I met my
needs, end of explanation.
How recently were you needy?
It's been two or
three months at least.
What? What is it?
Nothing.
Tell me. It's actually, nothing.
The ultrasound shows
no trace of a baby at all.
Positive pregnancy
test, no pregnancy.
B12 deficit rectified, but her
heart's slowing even more.
And a bleed should
speed her heart rate.
House, this is the
kind of case you love,
contradictions piling
up left and right.
Two false positive
pregnancy tests,
bradycardia, lower GI bleed. Go.
Choriocarcinoma, would've
triggered pregnancy hormones.
Also would've shown
on the sonogram.
Immunoglobulin A deficiency.
No urinary bleed.
If she's had beta-HCG injections,
they can cross-react with...
Keep going.
You're being an idiot.
You're gonna blow up your
career, then six months from now,
when you've moved on
from Amber to burnt sienna,
you're gonna be stuck on a mobile
oncology truck in Pewaukee, Wisconsin.
I'd need a flow chart to
explain all the ways in which
that was ridiculously
insensitive.
You can't hide from misery.
This isn't your business.
My skull was cracked
open trying to save her.
Then we all need a little tea and
sympathy. I'm through discussing it.
We have a patient.
Who's obviously not going
anywhere with a bloody rectum.
Great to have you
back. Actually, I'm...
Actually, he's about to thrust a
tanto into the belly of his career.
I'm leaving the hospital.
I'm sorry. This is obviously
a terrible time, but...
Why are you leaving?
I just need a change of scenery.
Buy a plant.
Rectal bleeding, two
positive pregnancy tests.
There's nothing we can do...
You could ask House to be a
grownup and respect my decision.
I respect things
that deserve respect.
This decision, on the other
hand, is a dog wearing a cape.
Hallucinations, heart
rate won't respond...
The patient tested
positive for pregnancy
because the patient is pregnant.
Hey, who are you?
This is Dr. House.
He's too brilliant for
introductions. False positive.
You're too busy to be running a
day care center in your abdomen.
False positive.
Not to mention, you should
wait till at least 30 to punish
that pleasure portal with a
seven-pound tissue expander.
I'm 37. And I thought
I wasn't pregnant.
Thirty-seven? Impressive.
Too bad you're not
passing on those genes.
Does that look false to you?
You were looking
in the wrong room.
It's more common when
the egg lands in the oven,
sometimes it winds up
in the fallopian tubes,
in rare cases, it plummets
through the plumbing entirely.
It's using her intestine
as a blood supply.
Caused the rectal bleed, and
now Junior Miss Steinem's junior
must be pressing on her vagus
nerve, slowing her heart to a crawl.
Yank the fetus. If she survives
the surgery, she'll be fine.
What if she wants
to keep the baby?
She doesn't.
We can't take two
seconds to discuss this?
I mean, fetuses have
been transplanted before,
whole uteruses, too.
Just terminating the fetus
when it's glued to her intestines
is high-risk surgery,
saving it is a fantasy.
That was at least three seconds.
She's a 37-year old
woman who deserves...
People get what they get,
it has nothing to do
with what they deserve.
And this has nothing
to do with her genitalia
and everything to
do with your genetics.
You told me to get tested.
I didn't know it was gonna color
your every medical opinion,
every personal opinion.
You didn't think a
death sentence would...
People die. You,
Amber, everyone.
Don't act like you
just figured that out.
I gave you a diagnosis, you don't
like it, there are exits on every floor.
I'm sorry to be so
definitive about this.
I know you're still absorbing the
news, but we have no choice but to...
Remove the fetus, absolutely.
I have no boyfriend, no husband,
I'm on the road with
Patty all the time.
Where do I sign?
Oh!
Feel any tenderness back here?
No, not at all.
So you're treating
professional sports injuries now?
No, I'm not...
Familiar with the
concept of sarcasm.
Don't sweat it, it's new.
Have you spoken to Wilson?
We'll get you an
EKG. I'll be right back.
You want me to sleep
with him to get him to stay?
I put the bisexual chick on
that, but if you'd like to sit in,
so to speak. I spoke to him.
What did you tell him?
I didn't tell him
anything. I listened.
So you could feel good
about doing nothing.
Tell him... I am
not your errand girl,
the best thing
about leaving you.
The two of you
used to be together?
She dumped me when
I lost the last 85 pounds.
Said there was
less of me to love.
Grief means different
things to different people,
case in point, means
very little to you.
Grief is Newark.
Okay, it's there, you can't avoid
it, but the idea is to hold your nose,
hope the traffic's not too bad
and get on to Manhattan as quickly
as possible, not to buy property.
You think that's
facing up to things?
I'm not the one who's quitting.
'Cause you haven't
lost anything.
But you have.
He'll listen to you.
What did you do when
your husband died?
I got a new job, and I moved.
See how crappy that worked out.
Separating the placenta from
the wall of the large intestine.
Sponge. Suction,
we got some bleeding.
BP's dropping, 90 systolic.
And bleeding like hell, clamp.
BP's still dropping.
Amp of calcium chloride, fast.
Still dropping. Shut up.
Squeeze her spleen,
we need to force some
platelets out so her blood clots.
She's in weak shape,
spleen's friable,
it could rupture.
She's stabilizing,
oozing's drying up.
And I hate Visitor's Day.
Removing the fetus.
Bye.
You have to stop Wilson from
committing career malpractice.
Talk to him.
Already talked to him
twice, he threw me out.
Mocking him and
insulting him, let's see, yes,
technically, those are
categories of conversation.
Block his references
to other hospitals,
tell him he can't hand
off his cases until...
Talk to him.
Deal with his grief, talk to him
about what he's going through.
That's a brilliant idea.
I'll take him out for a beer,
that'll make up for the fact
that Amber's in a pine box,
that there's randomness
and chaos in the universe.
Tell him you're sorry.
I didn't kill her.
You were drunk and...
Yeah, if her daddy hadn't been drunk,
she might never have been born. So...
You called her up in
the middle of the night,
she was on the
bus because of you.
I didn't ask her to come
out, I wasn't driving the bus,
I wasn't driving the
garbage truck that hit the bus,
and I did not prescribe her
the flu meds that killed her.
Yes, I know,
that's all true, but...
You really don't feel
any sense of guilt?
You want to keep him, he
needs to know he's not alone.
Just tell him
you feel like crap.
It'd be meaningless.
Well, then find some
meaning. And do something.
She's got a
neurological problem.
Surgical complication?
Don't think so, she
keeps on blinking.
Her heart's not
recovering either.
So the pregnancy
was a coincidence?
Pulse's down to 39, she's
maxed out on atropine.
We're installing
a pacing wire to...
Avoid that. We need
some help in here!
Page House.
Already paged
him. Page him again.
It's for you.
If I told you that I was sorry,
would it change anything?
I wouldn't believe you.
If you believed me.
It's hard to imagine
such a world.
I'm going home
until you agree to
stay at this hospital.
You can't be... That's
blackmail. And to do your job?
Why not hold a gun
to your own head?
Your conscience bleeds
more freely than my head.
Text. Patient's in
cardiac arrest. Ouchy.
You'd jeopardize a
patient because of my...
If it keeps you here.
Your friendship matters
more to me than this patient.
I've gotta do what's right for me.
You gotta do what's right for you.
Yeah. But it comes
easier for me.
Where is he? Where is he?
Status?
Her heart's stabilized,
we have a pacing wire in her, but
the bradycardia's not getting any better.
House was bluffing.
I called him three
times, he's not picking up.
What do you want us to do?
Same thing you'd
do if he was here.
If he was here, we'd be
asking him what to do.
What are the usual
suspects? There aren't any.
She had a vitamin
deficiency and we corrected it,
an ectopic pregnancy,
we removed it.
But her heart
problem won't go away,
and now something's
wrong with her brain.
I have complete
confidence in you guys.
Who wants to go service
House so this patient can live?
We can do this without him.
Maybe something
happened during the surgery,
caused her to... Surgery was
on her bowel, not her brain.
Anxiety, stroke, Tourette's,
could all cause eye-blinking.
And cause her heart to
beat faster, it's slowing down.
MS. If a lesion took out the
sympathetic innervation of her heart,
it'd explain the
bradycardia and the blinking.
But not the vitamin deficiency
or the ectopic pregnancy.
House would want
a unifying theory.
House is gone. And
so are those symptoms.
MS explains everything
that's wrong with her right now.
Start her on interferon for MS.
Mind if I come in?
Not at all. You mind if I leave?
I told you not to take that case
specifically so you could deal with Wilson.
And the two ended up dovetailing
rather nicely, don't you think?
This is how you show your friendship?
By bludgeoning him with guilt?
Because he's my friend, I
know what works on him.
Well, I can't let you
walk away from a patient.
Then fire me.
You're willing to risk your career
but you're not willing to say sorry?
I told him I'm sorry,
he didn't believe it.
Well, make him believe
it. I don't believe it.
You don't want to believe it.
Because if you tell Wilson
how you actually feel about him,
about what happened to Amber,
about your part in what happened,
and he walks out the door anyway,
if you make yourself
vulnerable for once
in your nerve-deadening,
emotionally-obliterating...
You're doing the same thing
he is, you're running away.
Only he's not killing
anyone in the process.
Where's Dr. House?
He's not feeling well.
Was MS his idea?
We work as a team.
You know how it is,
collaborative, sometimes it's hard
to tell where an idea comes from.
But you're not really a
team. You work for him.
And you work for Patty.
I'm sure a lot of her
ideas are actually...
She would be fine without me.
I'd be nothing without her.
Maybe if you just had the chance.
I'm sure you've learned a lot.
Not everybody's created equal.
Does Dr. House think I have MS?
Yes.
Did you just shiver?
You're running a slight fever.
Is that bad?
It means we were
wrong about the MS.
You had my cable disconnected.
Well, that's quite a leap.
Just because I happen to have a
31-person maintenance department,
each of whom you've
personally abused at some point...
Why?
'Cause you think I'm okay
with letting someone die,
but I'm gonna fold if I can't
watch celebrity bowling?
That is not an
unreasonable theory,
especially with only 10
minutes till your favorite soap.
Gee, is this the remote
from the doctors' lounge?
This is your 911? Goodbye.
Stop.
I'm withholding your salary history
from every hospital in the Tri-State Area.
You go, girl.
And I'm permanently setting every TV
in this building to the Pottery Channel
unless you both sit down.
Welcome to couples counseling.
It's not the
surgery. Timing fits.
The location doesn't, unless
her brain's in her bowels.
If bacteria entered
her bloodstream,
it could have caused
an infection in her brain.
The surgery went fine.
You were there, you saw...
Peptostreptococcus could
explain the blinking and...
No. You want to watch a grainy
video and have an epiphany.
Shut up, you're making
me miss House's mocking.
I know you told us it
was none of our business,
but if House thinks that your Huntington's
is affecting you, maybe it really...
It's not, because
I don't have...
You're desperate to
do this without him.
You're not trying to cure
her, you're trying to prove...
Stop the tape.
Zoom in.
On the anastomosis,
that little bump.
It's a hematoma, a
harmless pocket of blood,
which is why Chase
ignored it during the surgery.
Could be a ganglioma, which is
why Chase shouldn't have ignored it.
If it's an abnormal
growth of nerves,
it could be causing all
the patient's symptoms.
We have to open her
up again, get a piece of it.
So what do you want to tell us?
Nothing.
Nothing I say is gonna change
anything. You guys need to talk.
Actually, you should read
the latest psych literature,
repression's
gaining a lot of fans.
What you don't
face can't crush you.
Talk to each other.
How you doing? Good?
Fine. Thanks.
Sit.
See, the two of you are
friends, look how you both...
Think you're an idiot.
We both also eat with forks,
that doesn't really prove...
Talk to him. Tell him how
you feel about what he's doing.
I told him he's an idiot.
Tell him what you
think about him leaving.
- I think he's an idiot.
- You're an idiot.
He's in pain, and your response
is just to emotionally blackmail him.
You told me what your
position is on that one.
You're against it, right?
She hasn't told you in front of me.
She needs to prove she's on my side.
Go to hell.
So much for that theory.
I'm sorry you lost Amber.
I cannot imagine what it
is you're going through,
but it will not get better
by you walking away from
everyone that cares about you.
Do you think Amber would
want you to walk away?
Nobody at this hospital
even liked Amber.
Same time next week?
You want me to do a second
major surgery on a patient
we almost lost during
a first major surgery
to see if she needs
a third major surgery?
We need a piece
of the ganglioma.
Then you're talking
about another patient,
yours doesn't have a ganglioma.
And if there is one
and you missed it?
Then you're talking about another
surgeon, I didn't miss anything.
But we're not talking
about another videotape,
this one showed a bump,
we need to biopsy it.
A bump? Oh, yeah, my
grandfather died of a bump.
She can't survive a second round of
general anesthesia, let alone a third.
You'd do this for House.
Yeah.
Then what do you suggest?
Because the patient's got a
high fever, a low heart rate,
and a dim chance of survival
if we stand here like idiots.
Then I suggest you don't
stand there like idiots.
How do you get coal out of a mountain
when it's someone else's mountain?
If we don't have House, doesn't
mean we can't think like House.
But it does mean we
don't have to talk like him.
You don't dig down.
You go in from the side.
We insert a lighted
scope through the rectum,
move the intestine till
we find the ganglioma,
then push it to the surface.
Where we see the light, we cut.
We'll make as small
an incision as we can,
but unfortunately
it'll be very painful.
After your surgery experience,
we can't give you anesthesia...
Can I talk to Dr. House?
No.
We can do this, we
know what we're doing.
I don't mean to be insulting,
but my former boss didn't insist on
me coming here because of you or...
Your former boss?
I've been replaced.
I'm sorry. I mean,
you must be... I'm fine.
She has a big Beijing trip,
ton of work to do, she can't
just wait for me to get better.
We've been well trained,
we'll take good care of you.
How can you let her
treat you like a footstool?
The world needs flunkies.
Don't say that,
you're better than that.
I have no problem
with it. Why do you?
Because life is short.
I mean, yours could've
ended in that surgery.
You'd have never lived for
yourself. What kind of feminist...
We can have
anything. No, we can't.
We can aspire to anything. But we
don't get it just because we want it.
I would rather spend
my life close to the birds
than waste it
wishing I had wings.
You're through the sigmoid,
into the descending colon.
Switching on the light.
Advance toward the anastomosis.
That's it.
Push the wall of the
intestine toward the skin.
There, I see it.
Don't look down.
Scalpel.
So your last day is Friday?
I'm gonna miss you.
You shouldn't go.
Did House ask you to talk to me?
Or are you trying to save the patient,
because there'll
always be another...
House asked me.
And you're doing it? I
told him to go to hell.
Thanks.
But I think he's right.
You think you're making a rational
choice. You think the worst is over,
and then six months later,
you look back and you realize
you didn't know
what you were doing.
Are you saying the
pain doesn't go away?
It gets easier.
Not in two months.
Not in two years.
But, no, it never
really goes away.
Being here, in this building...
I was just in the lounge, I
kept staring at Amber's locker.
I saw a guy wearing
a scarf this morning.
The color reminded
me of his eyes.
We lived 500 miles from here.
I have to do something.
Then do it.
But don't think it's the right
choice, because there isn't one.
It's not a ganglioma, the
problem wasn't the surgery.
Abnormally deposited
proteins. It's amyloidosis.
It would explain the blinking
and the low heart rate.
The only way to treat amyloidosis
is to treat whatever's causing it.
It's not as if a lot of things cause
amyloid, rheumatoid arthritis.
Familial Mediterranean fever.
Lymphoma.
Well, we can't all be right.
But you can all be wrong.
Patient's joints don't hurt,
abdominal pain went
away when the fetus did,
and no palpable lymph nodes.
Got anything
constructive to say?
Sorry. Sorry.
She has lots and lots
of palpable lymph nodes,
joint and abdominal pain,
she'll be better by dinner time.
If we don't find the
cause of the amyloidosis,
we never get her off that wire,
she never walks out of this hospital.
But, hey, who needs House? So
glad we lost those training wheels.
You want me to make the call?
There seems to be
some disagreement.
And this isn't just a pretext
to pressure me into staying?
Does it look like a pretext?
No.
She really is dying, isn't she?
Inflammation, enlarged nuclei, some
mitotic activity. It could be lymphoma.
There are no
palpable lymph nodes.
Makes it less likely,
but doesn't rule it out.
I'm an oncologist, I see cancer.
Show it to an immunologist,
they'll see autoimmune.
I already showed it
to an immunologist.
We'll start her on chemo.
You should leave.
House doesn't want
to lose his sidekick.
Cuddy doesn't want to
lose her check on House.
No one's talking
about what you want.
It's not that I want to.
Want to, need to.
If there's any chance
that being away from here
will make your life even
a little bit easier, do it.
That's what everyone
else here would do.
Don't expect anything
to change too fast.
Lymphoma was your idea?
Why?
I feel better.
Sometimes just knowing
you're being treated helps.
You've given me 18
different treatments, this
is the first one that
made me feel better.
I don't think it's
psychological.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have
gotten angry at you.
Your choices are your choices.
You're not like me.
Maybe you have wings.
I have Huntington's Chorea.
Dozen years or so, my nervous
system, my cognitive skills,
even my emotional
balance, they'll all start to fray.
I won't be able to fly, I
won't be able to walk,
I won't be able to breathe.
And you want to make
sure your life matters?
I don't want to just be tightening
bolts and following instructions.
I want something to be
different because of me.
I am.
Not just 'cause
you saved my life.
I'm applying for a job at a foundation.
Running the finance division.
I mean, I don't know
if I'm gonna get it,
but if I don't, there
are other foundations.
It's almost 4:00. Soap time.
Nurses' remote, works
in the doctors' lounge.
Why do you think
Wilson's leaving?
How many times do I
have to use the word "idiot"?
And that's a good
enough answer for you?
Whenever anyone does
anything out of the norm,
you have to tell them what screwed-up
process is really at work in their head.
That's why I locked
the two of you in a room,
so you would say something
stupid and insensitive
and maybe with
a little bit of truth.
But you didn't.
So I can only assume that you
don't want to know the reason.
You're afraid to know.
You're not listening
to me, are you?
Try it sometime, you'll see why.
You look 37.
I am 37.
You looked 27 last week.
Unless I blacked out
for 10 years, your skin...
She has got lymphoma,
chemo's probably...
Stop the chemo.
She's getting better.
Bradycardia's
improving, we didn't...
She have bruising?
She was pounding her
legs during the hallucinations.
It's not lymphoma.
Hey, don't... No, no, no.
My bad. Thought
"no" meant "yes".
Those aren't bruises,
they're mycobacterial lesions.
She has diffuse
lepromatous leprosy,
must've caught it on one of
her overseas estrogen tours.
Chemo wipes out some of the
bacteria, she feels a little better,
wipes out most of her immune
system, she gets a whole lot worse.
Leprosy? Like where
my limbs fall off?
Actually, this is the flattering one.
It's also known as "pretty leprosy".
Doesn't disfigure, makes your
skin look younger, smoother.
Don't let the girls hear,
they'll all want to lick your face.
Unless you're that
kind of feminist.
Blast her with antibiotics
and prednisone, she'll be fine.
Damn, it's after 4:00. I'm late.
Damn. What?
She's happy you're
gonna be fine,
but she'd be happier if you were
gonna be fine five minutes ago.
Test confirmed
Dr. House's diagnosis.
Thank God.
When you got pregnant,
the physical stress triggered
e-nodosum leprosum,
a common
complication of leprosy.
Inflamed the nerves to your heart,
made it hard to absorb vitamins,
scarred your fallopian
tubes. It explains everything.
Better prescribe me
some skin cream, too, huh?
You might want it for
those job interviews.
I'm going back on the road with
Patty. My replacement flamed out.
She says I can manage some projects
on my own, carve out more of a role.
Do you really think
she can change?
I don't know.
The truth is I'm not sure I...
You can change.
No.
I'm not sure I
want her to change.
If she's reasonable, if
she's just another employer,
then I'm just another employee.
In a weird way, I matter.
I like you better
now that you're dying.
I was wrong.
You took a shot.
She's going back to work
for that idiot. It's pathetic.
You thought something
would change?
She almost died because
of that job. Yeah, I thought...
Almost dying changes nothing.
Dying changes everything.
I'm sorry. I know I
didn't try to kill her,
I know I didn't want her hurt,
I know it was a freak accident,
but I feel like crap, and
she's dead because of me.
I don't blame you.
I wanted to. I tried to.
I must've reviewed Amber's case
file a hundred times to find a way...
But it wasn't your fault.
Then we're okay?
I mean, I know you're
not, but maybe I can help.
We're not okay.
Amber was never the
reason I was leaving.
I didn't want to
tell you because...
Because I was trying, like
I always do, to protect you,
which is the problem.
You spread misery because
you can't feel anything else.
You manipulate people because you
can't handle any kind of real relationship.
And I've enabled it for
years, the games, the binges,
the middle-of-the-night
phone calls.
I should have been
the one on the bus, not...
You should have
been alone on the bus.
If I've learned anything from Amber,
it's that I have to take care of myself.
We're not friends
anymore, House.
I'm not sure we ever were.