I followed Gordon Ramsay's recipe
for the perfect scrambled eggs.
Thank you. This looks amazing.
Except I cut the tomatoes in half.
The recipe says to sauté them whole,
but I once had a patient
who almost choked to death on a...
Oh, my God.
These are perfect.
I'm glad you like your breakfast.
I read that if I made you feel loved
and cared for,
it could help us work out
your insecurity...
over my friendship with Lea.
Aw, Shaun...
you don't have to do
any more research.
I am fine with you and Lea
being friends.
But you can keep making me eggs
any time you want.
You're late.
I made Carly a special breakfast
this morning,
and then she wanted to have sex...
so we did.
That's great, Shaun.
Next time feel free just to say
you missed the bus.
Women don't like it
when you kiss and tell.
- Even though they do it all the time.
- Not at work.
Apparently you've never been
in the nurses' break room.
- What were you doing there?
- Delivering doughnuts.
Best lesson I learned as a cop,
"better to feed down than kiss up."
Oh, it's my fault
we haven't started our rounds.
I missed the bus.
It's all right.
I'm glad you're all here...
because I want to apologize.
Dr. Lim told me she received
a complaint about me playing favorites.
She obviously
didn't reveal any names,
but I want to assure you all
that I don't have any favorites,
and if I did anything
to give that impression...
it's my mistake.
It won't happen again.
We're a team,
and we need to be
able to communicate...
and trust each other
in order to be our best.
So in the future,
if you have any concerns,
you can come to me directly.
Absolutely.
She got blindsided.
Thank God a woman had pepper spray,
or the dog would've killed her.
- Brave.
- Loosen the tourniquet.
Oh. Okay.
We need an OR, stat.
- Page Dr. Melendez.
- Right away, doctor.
Start empiric antibiotics. I'm gonna guess
this dog wasn't big on flossing.
Ha-ha. On it.
Wasn't that funny.
Doughnuts,
best 10 bucks you'll ever spend.
Cory's upper trachea
never fully developed in the womb,
his upper airway is totally blocked,
and he has no larynx at all.
The trach tube he needs to breathe
continues to cause reoccurring
infections and pneumonias.
He says, "It tickles
when you touch his neck."
Sorry, not much I can do about that,
but I'll make it quick.
Why are you signing?
He's mute, but he's not deaf.
It helps us stay mindful
of what he's going through.
What did he say?
He says, "When we get mad,
we don't sign, we yell."
"And when we play soccer together."
So keep your room clean,
and pass your dad the ball,
then they won't have to yell.
His lungs are clear,
and I don't see any sign of infection.
Thank God.
The better news is he's a good candidate
for the surgery we discussed.
Yes, it seems a bit experimental.
It's shown great results.
If we can excise the scar tissue,
open up the airway,
he still won't be able to talk,
but he'll be able to breathe normally.
It's a complicated procedure,
but given the severity
of the infections he's been dealing with,
I think it's definitely
the best option.
He'll do anything to get rid of
the tube sticking out of his neck.
And you two?
Okay, now you're yelling.
We hear you.
What do you think?
Let's do it.
Fran?
Fran, I'm Dr. Melendez.
This is Doctors Park and Browne.
You were attacked by a dog,
almost bled to death. Do you remember?
Yes.
We repaired
a severed artery in your arm.
So...
am I okay now?
The surgery went well.
Dr. Park?
We stopped the bleeding,
which caused you to go into shock,
but we still need to go back in.
Stabilize the shattered bone,
repair nerve damage,
and do skin and tissue grafts.
But after that?
I'm a firefighter,
I need my full strength.
With plenty of physical therapy,
we should be able to get you
pretty close.
It must be hard
for him to communicate.
My friend's daughter
took a signing class at summer camp.
Picked it up pretty fast.
Non-verbal communication
is definitely more confusing.
That's why Carly and I
always talk out our problems.
Sorry to break it to you, Murphy,
but it doesn't matter
how explicitly Carly speaks.
She's saying a lot more silently,
and it's often the opposite
of what she said out loud.
Why would Carly lie?
It's not lying.
It's communicating indirectly.
Everyone does it,
but women way more than men.
- Most of the time we don't realize it.
- That sounds sexist.
You gonna report me to HR,
or listen and learn?
Has she ever told you she didn't want
to have sex because
she had a headache?
No.
I thought you didn't want
to hear about my sex life.
Fine.
But if you ever get
the feeling she's upset,
and she insists nothing's wrong...
something's wrong.
The humerus isn't broken, it's...
pulverized.
Who do you think complained to Lim?
No idea.
And we're gonna need
internal fixation,
with locked intramedullary nailing
to stabilize the fractured pieces.
It must be Morgan.
- She's always looking for an advantage.
- Let's focus on the patient.
You can start your whistleblower
investigation as soon as we're done.
How does she expect us to trust her,
if whenever something
doesn't go her way,
- she goes to the boss, and...
- It wasn't Morgan. It was me.
Why?
You're the least competitive
of all of us.
That's not true,
and I didn't do it to help me,
I did it to help you.
If people see
you're getting special treatment,
even if it's not your fault,
they'll resent you.
I'm not getting special treatment...
and I don't need your protection.
Fine, my mistake.
So you can yell at me,
or we can get back to work.
Just what the doctor ordered.
- What?
- You.
I need a double dose of Shaunie,
stat.
Glassy is driving me crazy.
I mean, what is it with old people
and technology?
- Mm.
- Don't worry, I just need to vent,
and I'll scram if Carly comes.
It's okay.
I think Carly's not insecure
about you anymore.
Really? That's awesome.
I added the "I think"
because Morgan thinks women
sometimes say
the opposite of what they think,
but I don't think Carly would hide
what she thinks.
What do you think?
Look, nobody always says
what they think.
So Morgan's right?
- Except for the sexist part?
- No.
I think Carly is very in tune
to how you communicate.
If she was unhappy,
I'm sure she wouldn't hide it.
Yes, I agree.
Lunch is over.
We have a surgery to do.
Hey, Morgan, love your boots.
- Thanks, love your sweater.
- Thanks.
Nice work.
Look at that.
On the bone, teeth marks.
Must've been a huge dog.
During no-knock searches,
I was more afraid of dogs than guns.
Gangsters have horrible aim,
but their dogs never miss a target.
- Which was our crotches.
- Damn.
- How many times they get ahold of you?
- Never,
- another benefit of martial arts training.
- You kicked the dogs?
Like I needed a 60-yard field goal
to win the Super Bowl.
That's awful.
- It's self-defense.
- Totally.
I need 9-0 nylon micro sutures.
Next step is to suture
in the interposition graft.
Dr. Park's doing great.
Might as well continue.
- I wouldn't mind getting my hands dirty.
- Let's see how Park does with this first.
Make sure your stay sutures
are at six and 12 o'clock.
- You are very efficient.
- And you're very clever.
Intro-ing your insult
with a compliment.
Your "helping me out" appears
to have conveniently helped you out.
I was expecting worse.
Melendez is bending over backwards
to avoid anything that might convey
the slightest bit of appreciation
for my work.
Because it couldn't possibly be
I was doing a better job.
Right, you're probably
buying him doughnuts too.
I did what I thought needed to be done,
and you're accomplishing nothing
by continuing to badger me about it.
- Thanks, Dad.
- You're welcome, child.
The boy's
obstructed cricotracheal segment
looks bigger than
what we saw on imaging.
I chose to be aggressive
with resection.
Murphy,
flex the neck to mobilize the ends,
and reduce tension on the anastomosis.
You sure we're gonna be able
to cinch it closed?
Not "we," You. Step on up.
4-0 vicryl sutures
on a needle driver.
Place lateral traction sutures
at the proximal and distal airway.
- You all right?
- Yeah, it's just I...
I hit my finger with a hammer.
I was trying to hang a painting.
Murphy, take over.
- It's all right, I can...
- Move.
You're a surgeon, not a hockey player,
we don't play through injuries.
Next time, hire a handyman.
Those fingers are your livelihood.
Got it.
I know Carly says
she's not jealous anymore,
but based on what I saw at lunch,
maybe she should be.
I think Murphy's old enough
to handle his own girlfriend trouble.
I don't have any girlfriend trouble.
Eating off the plate
is the oldest trick in the book.
Lea was hungry.
It looked more like she was claiming
territory than satisfying hunger.
Might as well have peed on your leg.
You, shut up,
and you, keep a smaller gap
between sutures.
We're gonna need a solid anchor
to get the anastomosis airtight.
That's better, good job.
- Good work today.
- Thanks.
- See you tomorrow at the track.
- I, uh...
I wanted to talk to you about that.
We can't do this anymore.
It's...
It's just a run at a public track.
We're not meeting at a hotel.
I just shouldn't be socializing
with residents outside of work.
- Any of you.
- Neil...
I've been going through a tough time.
Our friendship... having someone
I can talk to, it helps.
I'm not abandoning you.
I'll be there to support you at work.
You've got your therapist,
you're gonna be fine.
This is exactly why women have such
a hard time finding mentors.
No one questions when guys hang out,
but any time a woman wants to build
a totally appropriate relationship
with a male colleague,
the stupid rumors start.
I agree...
but the rumors have started.
I'm gonna plug the trach tube,
and I want you to try to take a breath.
Nice and easy.
He says it hurts, but it's
the best feeling he's ever had.
What's wrong?
You don't like it?
It's delicious.
I hear delicious,
but I see disappointed.
It's not...
the chicken, it's my patient.
We fixed his airway,
and he can breathe
without the trach now.
- That's fantastic.
- But he still can't talk.
He can talk.
He just does it with his hands.
Mm. But only with people
who can also sign,
and they have to be looking at him,
and...
Could you do
a cadaveric larynx transplant?
- No.
- I've heard that's worked
- for some throat cancer patients.
- No. Dr. Lim ruled that out years ago.
The risk of tissue rejection
is too great in a child his age.
- Well, could you wait till he's older?
- No!
If he doesn't learn to speak soon,
he'll never be able to.
Okay.
I need to do some reading.
Come on, Shaun,
at least eat something first.
No, I'm hungry,
but I will do the reading first.
You're in early.
What's the haps?
Are you serious?
I didn't even know Michelle Obama
was in SEAL Team Six.
You noticed how Glassy grinds
his teeth listening to someone talk?
- It's like a cow chewing on her...
- You never used to do that.
Do what?
Eat food off my plate.
I used to work full-time at a place
with private chefs.
Now I work part-time in a place
with hard-boiled eggs
in a vending machine.
She said it's like you're peeing
on my leg.
Expand on that.
Morgan thinks your body language says
you're trying to assert
your dominance over Carly.
Morgan is one twisted beyotch.
Is she right?
No.
Not even close.
I promise you my voice
and body language
are communicating the same thing,
which is pure,
non-threatening, platonic friendship.
Shaun?
He also snores.
- Really loud.
- Glassman?
Oh. I have to go.
Okay.
Hmm. Incision sites look good,
and skin and tissue grafts appear
to be taking hold nicely.
We were able to reattach
your bicep muscle and tendon.
That's good to hear.
Can you lift your arm?
No, I can't.
Because it hurts too much?
It doesn't hurt at all.
I figured that was
because of the meds.
You feel that?
No.
Vocal cords aren't the only way
a person can create sounds
with their mouth.
You want the kid to learn to
burp his way through his conversation?
Mm. I don't think it would be possible
to sustain enough air output to...
- It was a joke, Murphy.
- Oh.
Snoring is a better model anyway.
Soft palate tissue vibrates,
making the sound when people snore,
but it's not stiff enough
to replace the vocal cords,
but we could use
his own costal cartilage
to act as vocal cords.
The larynx is a complicated piece
of anatomy.
Basically, a tiny musical instrument.
We can remove two of his ribs
to create
the anterior
and posterior larynx frame,
and then stretch
the cartilage across it.
And then cut open a trachea we worked
so hard to close?
We could destroy
everything we just fixed.
Yes.
I think it's worth the risk.
Because you're thinking
the kid's like you.
That he needs to speak out loud
to be understood.
She's right.
The larynx is like
a musical instrument...
but if Bo Diddley can make a guitar
out of a cigar box,
I'm pretty sure I can make a larynx
from bone and cartilage.
Oh.
Absolutely not.
He's finally healthy.
There's no need to take any more risks.
You're right,
there are definitely risks,
but I wouldn't present the option
if we couldn't manage them.
Couldn't we wait
until he's a few years older?
I assume the stronger he is,
the safer it is.
Most verbal language development
happens within the first eight years.
Cory's already 10.
If we wait any longer, he may not be able
to learn to speak even with a larynx.
He can communicate without speaking.
- You're making a big mistake.
- Murphy...
He'll always be... limited.
It'll be difficult to make friends,
to interact with strangers.
Murphy, that's enough.
They're aware of their options,
and they've made their decision.
The suture repair looks fine,
which makes me think
the nerve got compressed
between the bone and the dog's teeth.
It's too wide to repair with a graft.
What if we built a nerve conduit
out of silicone and polyglycolide?
We could guide the severed nerve ends
to grow toward each other.
Create a pathway for them
to connect and heal.
I'm not sure the nerves can grow
across that distance.
It's definitely worth a try.
We can't just
experiment on her like a lab rat.
We can't just sit back
and do nothing.
I'm not saying do nothing,
we just can't experiment on her blindly.
Maybe we could use donor tissue
to bridge the gap.
That means putting the patient
on a transplant list.
Who knows how long
before she gets a viable donation?
Firehouse won't hold her position
until she heals. She'd lose her job.
First you want to treat her like a guinea
pig, now you're concerned about her life?
- You just want to be right.
- And you don't?
Are you going to step in
at any point?
I think Park's idea has
the best chance of success.
Get her prepped.
Do you really think his idea is better,
or do you not wanna look
like you're biased?
I'm not happy
about this situation either,
but you're overreacting.
Get it under control,
or you're watching from the gallery.
Hi.
Hey.
Do you have a problem with me
staying friends with Shaun?
I know you've told him
you're fine with it, but are you?
Yes.
Really?
I mean, I'm totally glad you are.
It's great.
I'm not sure I would be
if I were in your shoes.
If it was any other guy,
I probably wouldn't be.
But Shaun, he always tells the truth.
So when he told me
he's not interested in you, I believe him.
Okay.
You told the residents
not to come to me?
No, that's not at all what I said.
You didn't tell them,
"Next time you have a problem,
come to me directly"?
I was encouraging open communication
and trust on my team.
What I have is ambitious residents
struggling to figure out how to be
cooperative as well as competitive.
You're not helping them figure it out
by suggesting they resist taking
complaints up the chain of command.
I'm sorry you've had
to waste your time dealing with this,
- but there really isn't...
- Neil, I am not wasting my time.
You do have an issue...
and you've got to stop pretending
you don't.
The incision is healing nicely.
We should be able
to discharge you today.
Are you happy to be going home?
Have any questions for us?
Are you sure?
Because you don't seem happy
to go home.
What is he saying?
He said Dr. Murphy was right.
He does have a hard time
talking to kids at school,
and making friends.
He doesn't want people to ignore him
or act like he's stupid anymore.
Honey, I'm so sorry.
Okay.
♪ May the good Lord shine
a light on you ♪
♪ Make every song your favorite tune ♪
♪ May the good Lord shine
a light on you ♪
♪ Whoa, like the evening sun ♪
That's two segments
from the seventh rib.
Let's close his chest.
♪ Angels beating all their wings in time ♪
♪ With smiles on their faces
And a gleam right in their eye ♪
♪ Whoa, I thought I heard them
Sighing for you ♪
♪ Come on up, come on up ♪
♪ Come on up, now ♪
♪ May the good Lord shine
a light on you ♪
♪ Shine a light on you ♪
♪ Make every song you sing
Your favorite tune ♪
♪ May the good Lord shine
a light on you ♪
♪ Shine a light on you ♪
♪ Whoa, like the evening sun ♪♪
Reznick, secure the posterior surface
while I place PDS 4-0 sutures.
Murphy, be ready to suture the graft
into the anterior section.
Morgan realized
our patient wasn't happy,
even though he said he was.
If she hadn't been there,
we wouldn't be doing this surgery.
It wouldn't have mattered
what I realized,
if you hadn't been obsessed
about a new surgery to help the patient.
- Blood pressure's plummeting.
- Field is filling with blood.
Can't see the source.
Murphy, expose the external carotid
and find the superior thyroid.
- BP's still dropping.
- Heart rate is up.
Place a temporary clamp on it, Reznick.
It's not working, this is venous.
Ten blade.
I see what happened.
Left and right jugular veins
are connected by a venous arc
we injured during retraction.
Dr. Murphy, just double ligate
with 2-0 silk ties on both ends.
Silk ties.
He's stabilizing.
Good job. Both of you.
Congratulations.
It's not every day you get
to build a kid a brand-new larynx.
It was very exciting.
♪ Was I on your mind? ♪
Those two are
getting pregnant tonight.
Yeah.
They should get a room...
so they can make out in private.
Oh my God, it's Lea.
She's not getting pregnant.
She definitely uses protection.
Every time one of her boyfriends
would come over,
- she would...
- That's okay. I don't need the details.
Would you ever be comfortable
making out in public like that?
I don't know.
As a board-certified pathologist,
I think we need
to conduct an experiment.
Okay.
♪ You were in my dream last night ♪
♪ Creeping in again ♪
♪ When I least expected ♪
Shaunie!
I can't believe you're here!
♪ Is this what 22 feels like? ♪
♪ Do you feel...? ♪♪
Ten blade.
Transverse incision approach
to the brachial plexus.
Adson forceps.
I can assist with ligating
the traversing external jugular branches.
I could divide the omohyoid muscle.
It's all right, best for me to handle this.
Retracting to the side.
♪ Sister, won't you listen? ♪
♪ I don't wanna love the one who lies ♪
♪ And I can hear him whisper ♪
♪ 'Bout the things you did
In days gone by ♪♪
I'm sorry,
I think we killed the mood.
No!
Mm...
- You did manage to wound it pretty bad.
- Mm-hm.
It's bleeding out.
Yes.
It's a joke, Shaun.
- What Carly did was...
- I get it.
I get it.
She anthropomorphized
the word "mood"
to make it seem like you hurt it,
and it's now hemorrhaging.
It's very clever.
♪ Boom badoom boom
Boom badoom boom bass ♪
♪ He got that super bass ♪
♪ Boom badoom boom
Boom badoom boom bass ♪
♪ He got that super bass ♪
♪ This one's for the boys in the Polos
Entrepreneur fellas and the moguls ♪
♪ He could ball with the crew
He could solo ♪
♪ But I think I like him better
When he dolo ♪
♪ And I think I like him better
With the fitted cap on ♪
♪ He ain't even gotta try
To put the mack on ♪
♪ He just gotta give me that look
When he give me that look ♪
♪ Then the panties comin' off, off
Excuse me, you're a hell of a guy ♪
Your... I...
♪ I mean, sigh, sickenin' eyes ♪
♪ I can tell you're in touch
With your feminine side ♪
♪ Oh, yes, I did, yes, I did ♪
♪ Please someone who the heck I is
I am Nicki Minaj ♪
♪ I mack dudes up, back coupes up
And chuck the deuce up ♪
Oh!
♪ Away! ♪
♪ Beating like a drum
And it's coming your way ♪♪
♪ Boom badoom boom
Boom badoom boom bass ♪
♪ He got that super bass ♪
♪ Boom badoom boom
Boom badoom boom bass ♪
♪ Yeah, that's that super bass ♪
♪ Boom badoom boom
Boom badoom boom bass ♪
♪ He got that super bass ♪
♪ Boom badoom boom
Boom badoom boom bass ♪
♪ Yeah, that's that super bass ♪
♪ Boom badoom boom
Boom badoom boom bass ♪
♪ He got that super bass ♪
♪ Boom badoom boom
Boom badoom boom bass ♪
♪ Yeah, that's that super bass ♪♪
It was fun last night.
I'm glad you and Lea are friends.
Yeah.
What was your favorite song?
Mine was "Whip It."
I have to go.
I have an early morning.
Okay, I will see you at work.
You're at 60 meters per second.
Normal electrical signal velocity
of the nerve is 50 to 65.
- That's good.
- Very. The surgery worked.
Your strength might go down a bit,
but you should get function back.
How can I thank you?
Seriously.
Well, it's Dr. Melendez you should thank.
- He did the surgery.
- We didn't really do anything.
Well, you obviously did something.
Well, okay, you're welcome.
Get some rest.
How are you feeling?
Any pain or discomfort?
Good.
If you're feeling up to it,
we'd like you to make a sound.
Now, start down here...
and just push the air up.
Be gentle.
We don't need you breaking
wine glasses just yet.
That's the most beautiful voice
I've ever heard.
It's just a primitive sound,
with speech therapy
he'll be able to fully speak.
Cory says, "thank you, Dr. Murphy,
for pushing for the surgery."
This is the best day of his life.
You are very welcome.
This is not you, and it's not right.
We can be friends
and have it not be weird.
It's already weird.
I'm not gonna stay.
You don't have to run away
because I'm here.
- I'm not running. I'm being professional.
- You're overcompensating.
Trying to play it safe...
and it's hurting things,
it got Park and I in an argument.
That's not how I want to be mentored.
That's not who you are.
At least, not who I thought you were.
Enjoy your dinner.
I'm confused.
One day you're filing a complaint,
the next you're incredibly supportive
to your fellow resident.
I told you, I just felt like
Dr. Melendez's treatment of Browne
was starting to cause dissension
on the team.
I have no doubt that's part truth.
I'm guessing the other part was...
pre-emptive.
You thought it would inoculate you.
We'd never fire someone
who filed a complaint
against their attending.
Which is why I'm so confused.
Why would you feel your job
could be in jeopardy?
I don't.
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- Okay.
Just so you're clear...
I won't hesitate to let you
or anyone go if I feel it's deserved.
No matter whether they've filed
a complaint or not.
Of course.
I understand.
Good.
Have a good night.
Two menus.
I'm going to make you
a surprise dinner tonight.
It's a special
grilled cheese sandwich.
It uses four kinds of cheeses,
gruyere, parmesan, yellow...
I don't think
we should be together anymore.
Hmm?
I can't be your girlfriend anymore.
Did...
Did I do something wrong?
No, Shaun, it's not...
Last night at karaoke...
when you and Lea
were singing together...
there was something between you two.
You love her, not me.
Oh. No.
No.
I don't.
It's obvious.
You're wrong.
You say that...
and maybe you even believe it.
But...
I saw what I saw, Shaun,
and I am telling you...
it doesn't matter what you say.
It's true.
And I think she loves you too.
♪ This one goes out ♪
You should tell her how you feel.
♪ A simple prop ♪
♪ To occupy my time ♪
♪ This one goes out to the one I love ♪
♪ Fire ♪
♪ Fire ♪♪