- Previously on The Resident...
- And you're free to go.
- What?
- You made bail.
Let's get you your clothes
and get you out of here.
- Well, have I convinced you?
- No, I did my homework.
Your new VNS device
is top-rated. Cheers.
You're telling me
that Bell thinks these
hands killed Bradley Jenkins.
- You want my advice?
- Always.
Learn humility. You
make a mistake, own it.
- It'll make you a better doctor.
- I'm benching myself
from surgery
- until further notice.
- How are things at the clinic
with Alec?
- He seems to really care
about what we're doing.
- Mm.
♪ ♪
Can I open my eyes yet?
Watch your step.
Conrad, where are we?
What's that smell?
Is that banana bread?
Okay.
Open them.
It's coffee cake, the candle.
Jane called me yesterday.
Owner's a friend.
No open house yet, but
Dr. Hawkins caught my son's IBD
last summer, so I owe him.
What do you think?
It's beautiful.
No more overnight bags.
Our own place.
Wait, is this for us?
Yes, of course it's for us.
I mean, look at this yard.
We get a hot tub,
- raise chickens.
- Chickens?
What?
Yeah. Why not?
And it's walking
distance from Chastain
and two blocks
from Trini Taqueria.
And I love all that. Um...
But I mean, how are
we gonna afford this?
The rent's basically
what we pay for
two places now, so...
Look, take your time.
Look around. Just let
me know by tonight.
Hey, what's your name?
- Jenessa.
- Okay, what brought you in...
Cough, cold, chest pain?
Do I get in faster
if I say all of them?
Nausea and vomiting. Got it.
- Nurse Myrick is on her way.
- Good.
- We need backup.
- As a patient.
It's like half
Atlanta has the flu,
and the other
half thinks they do.
Smiles, what are you here for?
I woke up this
morning with the chills,
but I've never been
happier in my life.
He's in love. Don't
get him started.
Her name is Sue.
Oh, she has this
adorable cockapoo.
- Hmm.
- But yeah, so we went out
for the first time last night,
and I've never felt
this way before.
It's... I mean, this girl...
Gentlemen, how much more
do I got to hear about this chick?
I came in with an eye problem,
now I wish it was my ears.
Whoa...
I am so sorry.
It's fine. Kid's got a good arm.
Hello, key lime pie.
From admin, to boost morale.
Oh, yeah. We need it.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
No, get your own.
Get your own!
No communal food
during flu season.
You're a monster, Pravesh.
- Hi.
Listen up, people.
For some of you,
Christmas has come again.
- My 30-year-old hernia
goes to my man Dr. Tolman.
- Thank you, Raptor.
I dig your tension-free
mesh repair method.
Dr. Richter,
my cholecystectomy
this morning is yours.
Go with God.
These are your patients.
Were.
Until Bradley's death
opened my eyes
to my crippling ego.
I have a penance to serve.
So I am guest lecturing
today at Billings University.
I figure I'd leave the cutting
to more humble hands.
Dr. Nolan. My splenectomy...
- Are you up to the task?
- You know it, man.
- Mina will assist.
- Oh...
up top.
You know he's just having
me babysit you, right?
- Thank you, Jessica.
- Mm-hmm.
Could somebody please
give me the surgical schedule
for... for the CEO?
Thank you.
Have fun.
Never been a fan of pineapple.
You?
I want to know who Gordon
Page did business with
- before Chastain.
- Uh-huh.
Find out everything
you can about
"the man who may save medicine."
But Chastain's already in
business with him, aren't we?
Currently, yes.
So... mind if I ask why
I'm doing research?
Just... think of this
as an opportunity
for you to keep this job.
Got it. Oh, also, my
mom called again.
She needs to talk with you.
Um, I'll...
- Yeah, I'll call her. Later.
- Thought you'd like to see this.
Oh.
No, no, no.
Yeah.
Don't worry, Dr. B. I got you.
Thank you, Grayson.
You can go.
Oh, actually,
I heard it's bad this year.
Do you want me to swipe
you an extra flu shot?
That's... No.
That's not the way
shots work, so no.
Oh.
What am I looking at?
Two more elective
surgeries have cancelled.
This-this flu
season is killing us.
How bad is it down there?
- What you about, man, huh? What you about?
- What's up, little man?
- What's up, little...
- What's up, man? What's your problem?
- Man, are you kidding?
- I've been here
for six hours, man.
- Oh, hell no.
- Come on,
- you want to come at me?
- What you got?!
- Come on, bro. Let's go!
- Hold it.
Come here. Hey!
Get over here.
Ear muffs, on.
Asses in seats,
hands in pockets.
Should we do something?
- Look, we're all sick.
- I think she's got it covered.
And tired.
But we're just... we're...
We got... Oh, man...
Oh...
Doc, do you want to help her?
Hey. Hey!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Deep breaths. Deep breaths.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hey, take it easy. All right.
Okay. All right. Let's see.
♪ ♪
How long have you
been running a fever?
No clue. I run hot. So I...
Heard a badass broke
up a fight in the ER.
Nic. I was wondering if I
was gonna get to see you.
- Of course I'd come see you.
- You didn't think
I'd page her?
- Come on.
- Good boy.
I heard a rumor you
were her favorite guard
during her stint in prison.
Yeah, and she was one
of my favorite inmates, too.
Mm. Sorry to say, I have
no plans on going back there.
How's your girlfriend?
Oh, in Tampa. We broke up.
- Oh.
- No, we'll stay friends.
No, scratch that. No, we won't.
So how are you lovebirds?
Yeah. Good.
So, you have any idea
what's wrong with me?
Well, your blood work
shows very low platelets.
- That doesn't sound good.
- Mm, you'll need a transfusion,
but it's nothing to panic about.
Yeah, she's right.
Let us run a few tests.
We'll figure this out.
Where will I find Dr. Shaw?
Dr. Bell. What a surprise.
Please tell me you didn't
come all the way down here
- to cut our funding.
- Oh, no.
I can do that via e-mail.
Then to what do
I owe this honor?
Well, I understand you have
an expertise in infectious disease
and flu season has
our ER short-staffed.
You don't want paranoid
patients scaring off profitable ones.
But I don't have
privileges at Chastain.
Check again. I had you instated.
Well, then I'd be happy
to help thin the crowd.
Glad to hear it.
In exchange for a few
ultrasound machines.
Oh, sorry. They're
all spoken for.
Ah, too bad. So am I.
One ultrasound.
- Three.
- Two.
Done.
An open splenectomy
is faster. Ten blade.
For the surgery, yes,
but not the recovery.
And a minimally invasive
approach has less complications.
Chastain has more
than adequate facilities
to help Mr. Fleming
with his recovery.
And the hospital bills the
insurance ten times more...
No wonder Bell likes you.
Allow me to make this
a teachable moment.
Please don't.
We're a perfect match.
Is it weird if, when we're
married, I take her name?
It was one date, Sam.
Now get this, we're
both closer to our moms,
love Thai fusion and trap music.
So does most of Atlanta.
She just went
hiking in Yosemite.
I did the same hike last year.
Match made in heaven.
- So how's your breathing?
- Fine.
Well, my heart's
racing a little bit,
- but that's probably...
- Aw, don't say
it's 'cause of Sue.
Oh, come on man, you never
felt that connection with someone?
Oh, you totally have. Who
is she? What happened?
Don't tell me she got away. Oh.
I can't let that
happen with Sue.
She leaves for Spain
tonight. I got to see her
- before she goes. Am I good?
- You're dehydrated.
I'm gonna keep
you for IV fluids.
Sit tight.
I'm about to make an
announcement, so just
sit tight, okay, you guys?
Please, please, please
- keep thinking.
- Hey, what's going on?
- Uh, right side.
- Ask him.
You guys are
together... That's perfect.
Um... okay, listen up.
Okay, people, it's 1918,
okay? No microwaves,
Babe Ruth is pitching,
and life expectancy
drops 12 years.
Anyone know why?
Was it World War I?
Wrong. War only
killed nine million,
but the Spanish flu killed
over 50 million people.
Do I have your attention yet?
All right? I've divided
you into thirds.
Left side got their flu
shots, right side didn't.
Middle group, you guys
can't seem to remember.
Middle group, do better.
Right side, stay.
Left side, good news: you're
going home with a care bag.
Chances are you'll catch
something worse waiting here.
All right?
Move for me,
let's do it. All right.
Gonna get you all better,
- promise.
- Thank you.
It's like Moses
parting the Red Sea.
When the next wave
comes, get creative.
I don't really want
to raise chickens.
Definitely seemed like
you wanted to
raise some chickens.
Look, I don't have my heart
set on that place anyway.
We could check out some others.
Uh...
I think I just...
need a minute.
I get it. It's...
a big decision.
You called for an
extra set of eyes?
Hey, yes. Thank you for coming.
We were hoping that an
infectious disease doctor
could tell us not
to worry as much
as we are.
Our patient Meg has
petechiae, her fever's rising.
Hasn't responded to treatment.
- Leukocyte inclusions
in the cytoplasm of neutrophils.
- Right.
And Dohle bodies
and toxic granulations.
And she's around a
high-risk population in the jail.
I mean, are we crazy,
or could this be a
new, rampant flu?
I'm hoping you're crazy,
but you might be right,
which means we have
to assume the worst.
It's possible Meg
has a type of flu
that we don't even
have a name for yet.
She could be highly contagious.
Look out!
♪ Hey, hey, hey... ♪
We need to take
precautions until we know
what we're dealing with.
♪ Hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ Hey, hey, hey... ♪
Stop whatever it
is from spreading.
What we need to do
is stop one patient
from becoming 1,000.
♪ Hey, hey, hey ♪
Get your head up, get back, Meg.
Deep breath for me. Deep breath.
It's okay, we're
gonna take care of you.
Deep breath.
Breathe in for me.
Can I panic now?
You call the CEO
before you initiate
quarantine at his hospital.
I know how you like to operate,
Dr. Hawkins, but it's a rule.
There's a good chance
we contained this.
You contained one
patient. I have to stay
ahead of the curve to contain
fear among hundreds of patients
- and an entire staff.
- You guys realize
you're saying the
same thing, right?
We all want to solve
this as soon as possible.
What are the facts right now?
At this point, we
only have theories,
the leading one being
a possible epidemic
- strain of flu.
- I've got something.
It may not be infectious.
Meg's taking levothyroxine
for low thyroid function.
So we could have
held off on the tent
- and all the speculation
it generates.
- No, because
there's a better
chance this is infectious.
Meg also said that some of the
inmates at the prison were sick.
They could've had visitors
who traveled internationally.
- I mean, she doesn't know.
- Jails are a nest for disease.
This could be where
her symptoms started.
Levothyroxine or jail.
An etiological fork in the road.
I'm not gonna gamble,
so go down both avenues.
Okay, I'll get her started on
broad-spectrum antibiotics
and send a thyroid panel
off to the lab, but
my gut instinct...
- It came from the jail.
- Right.
So I'll head there, try to find
whoever or whatever
made Meg sick.
I'll go with Alec.
Are you sure you
want to go back there?
I know the lay of the land.
Well, handle this discreetly.
Rumors of an outbreak are
just gonna fuel the chaos.
We have to thin the ER
again before a riot breaks out.
Dr. Shaw said to get creative.
Ooh. M... Mm, I got nothing.
Okay, listen up.
If your temperature checked
in over 100 go to the left.
If you're over 65 or have a
chronic medical condition,
make your way to the right.
- Uh, who are these people
and why are they in VIP?
- Flu patients.
ER's overflowing,
but you've got space.
Orders came from you-know-who
from you-know-where.
We'll be out in 90 minutes flat.
Thinking outside the
box might lead to Bell
putting our medical
careers in a pine box.
Never thought I'd
be back here so soon.
As a nurse?
Inmate. Cell block 6.
Relax. I was framed for
breaking and entering.
Liquor store?
Oncology clinic.
Well, either way,
- I'm impressed.
- Mm. I'm sure you've fought
some incredible battles
practicing medicine
- all over the world.
- Uh, here and there.
But I never stayed in
one place long enough
to stir up Nic Nevin's
kind of trouble.
What about now?
Is the clinic just a pit stop
or you planning on
sticking around for a while?
We'll see where
tomorrow takes me.
Today I'm just trying
to find patient zero.
This could take a while.
Conrad got Meg's test results.
It's not a thyroid storm.
As predicted.
Now we try to find an
atypical infection in the crowd.
Mm-hmm.
Hello, ladies, up here. Hi.
Uh, this is Nurse Nevin.
I'm Dr. Shaw.
Uh, it's a life-or-death
situation today,
so I really need
your cooperation.
If you check the following three
boxes, please raise your hand.
We want triple threats only.
Rash... anywhere
from the ankles up.
Swelling in the
pits, neck, or groin.
Sky-high fever.
Me, over here.
Betsy, faking it
to the infirmary... Not
gonna happen today,
unless you're actually sick.
- She was my cellmate.
- Wow.
The unhealthy trinity.
They've gotten
something from Meg,
given it to Meg, or
none of the above.
Well, we've isolated one.
Now we interrogate three.
The rash started around
the time I got cleanup duty.
When was that?
- Few months ago.
- Is it just on your arms?
- Yeah.
- Latex allergy.
Mild fever.
Have you had this
your whole life?
- Maybe.
- It's a birthmark.
Okay.
- Flu shot?
- Don't offer 'em.
- Any direct contact with Meg?
- Just about every day.
These marks on your
hand... Can I see them?
Yeah, but it ain't a rash.
Are those bites?
I feed a family of
pigeons on the yard.
One of them's
got a bad attitude.
Did Meg feed them, too?
So I feed a few pigeons
and now I'm gonna
die of what... bird flu?
You may not have the flu
at all. We think it might be
cryptococcosis.
It's a fungal infection
you can get from
pigeon droppings.
Listen, Handsome Head,
I been shivved twice,
several concussions,
mononucleosis, shingles.
I-If it's bad, tell me.
I want to know exactly
what's making you sick
before I answer that.
Do you want to call
someone... Friends, family?
Just...
tell them where you are?
I'd like to call
my ex-girlfriend,
but I really blew that one.
Looks like I'm not so good
at this relationship thing.
Not so sure I am either.
You better tighten it up.
Nic's a catch. She's a gem.
Don't let that one go.
Doing my best.
You hang tight.
Be back to do the
scope on your lungs.
I got the answers you want.
- You ready for this?
- Just spit it out.
The last hospital
QuoVadis was involved with
was Jacksonville General.
Gordon worked with
them extensively...
Define "extensively".
It was the hospital
where he ran trials
for another device of some kind.
Which device?
Who was the CEO?
- Uh, okay, you lost me.
- Oh, for crying out loud.
I'll do it myself.
The charge nurse needs
me to speak to a patient,
so you get one more
chance to get this right.
I need to talk to the CEO
Gordon did business with.
It's not just about the where,
it's also about the whom.
- Totally makes sense.
- Do...
- Really?
- Yeah, I get it.
- I will-I will do that.
- Okay.
Okay. Good talk.
Hey. You paged?
I did.
I saw something that
made me nervous.
I want to see if it
makes you nervous.
In here.
Hey, Sam.
Mm, Dr. Pravesh, you're back.
- Good to see you, man.
- How we feeling, Sam?
Well, pretty lousy, actually.
When'd you get that rash?
Uh, I don't know.
Definitely nervous.
We need help
with a patient move.
Hundley, we need to limit
exposure to other patients
- and all hospital staff.
- Masks. I'm on it.
Angelique.
Masks, people.
Keep it moving, folks.
- Here you go, sweetheart. Put that on.
- Why do we need masks?
- Does he have Ebola?
- It's just procedure.
Hundley, get a mask on.
Mask, please.
Sam, I'm gonna put
this mask on you, okay?
Ready?
- Yep.
- Let's go.
What's going on? Where...
where are you moving me?
Isolation.
So I thought you said
you had this under control.
Now there are two more
patients with worsening symptoms.
Spiking fevers, hemorrhaging.
And people are afraid
- they're caught in an outbreak.
- Nobody thinks that.
Trending hashtag...
"the outbreak hospital"...
Says otherwise.
This is not an outbreak.
I did a bronchoscopy to
check for cryptococcus.
We have confirmed
it is not fungal.
So you know what it's
not, but you still have
no idea what it is.
Marburg, Lassa.
All viral hemorrhagic
fevers are still on the table.
That's why we have
PAPR suits just in case.
And we've already
contacted the CDC.
Whatever it is, we are
prepared to handle it.
Emory will handle it. The
only thing you need to prepare
- is your transfer summary.
- Hold on.
- You are not transferring
these patients.
- I am.
Because a two-patient
problem risks being
a Chastain nightmare.
If these infections
keep getting worse,
a helicopter ride could
be a death sentence.
Emory is a top-tier
infectious disease hospital.
The federal government literally
pays them to take
charge of this scenario.
Emory is tasked with
taking care of patients
other hospitals are
incapable of managing.
But we are all over this thing.
I beg to differ.
Gonna take me a couple
hours to arrange the chopper
and the transfers.
That's how long you have.
If you can diagnose
and treat before it lands,
then... great.
Job well done.
If you see blood, it's your own.
The room is cold,
the scalpel is sharp.
I can assure you and
your weak stomach
he will not bleed.
I'm sorry. He,
uh, s-still looks...
Looks alive.
He's not.
The first time you
step into the OR
your patient will look dead,
but he won't be.
It's a tricky thing to
wrap your head around.
In the OR
you must only
follow your instinct.
Everything else,
you check at the door.
Watch.
This damn valve is too big.
No, I think you're
holding it upside down.
Which is, I believe, what Julian
was trying to tell you.
Uh, what's in the box?
Seven QuoVadis heart valves.
And why are they here?
I want you to put them
through the pulse duplicator.
And why are you here?
I'm helping someone get
back to where they belong
and you have reached the ceiling
on your consecutive questions,
so run the tests.
Okay, pump it harder.
And this time,
mimic the flow of
blood of an agile patient.
A-A little more.
We are gonna be
in so much trouble.
The valves aren't strong
enough for a younger,
active patient.
Like Bradley.
He can't breathe.
What should I do?
I'll be right in.
What's going on?
Sam's oxygen sats are dropping.
I'm on it.
Meg, don't get out of bed.
Hey, good to go.
He's not protecting his
airway. I need to intubate.
She's seizing!
Meg, hold on.
I can't get an airway.
She's gonna aspirate.
Nic, what are you doing?
It's not safe without the suit.
There's no time for a suit.
She was gonna aspirate
into her lungs and die.
You would have
done the same thing.
- I told you I had it.
- I heard what you said.
I made the call.
Let's just get back to work.
Nic...
you've been exposed.
I know.
I'll stay in isolation.
Masks on. Doors closed.
Nothing to see but
definitely something to catch
if you don't cover your
faces and clear the way.
Milosh. Golden Girls is on now.
Golden Girls?
Yeah. Get back in your room.
Nice assist.
Nice block.
No brain bleed.
So her seizure was
caused by the infection.
Lymph nodes
are filled with fluid.
Immunoglobulins just came back.
Abnormally low.
Compromised immune
system explains
the rapid progression
of the symptoms.
Not much time
before we lose her.
I'll identify the infection
once I get a fluid sample
from a needle aspiration.
Two needle aspirations: Meg
and Sam.
Feel fine.
Keeping the suit on just
in case I'm not infected.
Was my concern that obvious?
Hopefully we have
a diagnosis soon.
We can get you both out of here.
Well, apart from the potential
of having a
life-threatening infection,
living in isolation
hasn't been so bad.
Conrad, things got
crazy around here today,
otherwise I would have
found you to talk to.
Eh, don't worry.
House is off the table.
- I let it go.
- You did what?
Eh, it just didn't feel right.
But we can keep looking.
If you even want to.
Alec needs that sample ASAP,
so we better get
that transfer ready.
Where are my disciples?
Sharing a six-foot
sub, paid for by me.
You bought them a man sandwich?
Yes.
All to get you alone so I
could admit to your face
that you are a god.
I'm listening eagerly,
but I'm very hungry.
Did you order me anything?
Oh, God. You are arrogant
and your ego could fill this room,
but you're gonna shut your
ass up and listen, August.
I ran seven QuoVadis valves
through a pulse simulator.
I think I proved that
Bradley's death was caused
by a device error,
not an operator error.
Desperation is not a
good look on you, Mina.
Manipulation is even worse.
Are you calling me a liar?
I'm saying when I was
a young, spongey pup,
I would have done anything to
get my mentor Abe Benedict back
- if he were circling
down the drain.
- Oh, that's not what I'm doing.
The same Abe Benedict who
vouched for QuoVadis valves.
Who showed me that my
ego was what most likely
caused Bradley his death.
So, no, Mina, it's not
that I don't trust you.
I just trust him a
hell of a lot more.
Well, he's wrong,
and you're stubborn.
If the point of this
whole penance
is to get yourself to listen,
then I suggest
you start listening.
Bradley...
was not your fault.
Yersinia pestis.
Black Death itself.
It's not just any plague.
Multi-drug resistant.
It's the most unusual
presentation I've ever heard of.
And this strain is resistant
to every antibiotic
but colistin.
We need to get the patients
the right treatment immediately.
We need to get
Nic on prophylaxis.
Stat.
And Sam's bacterial load
is much higher than Meg's.
He's had this for longer.
So Sam infected Meg.
We need to find out
where Sam's been.
Whoever got him
infected is out there
spreading it all over Atlanta.
Sam's intubated, but I
know who can help us.
Black Plague.
That's quite a
zebra. Ever seen it?
Ten cases a year
in the United States,
mostly on the West Coast.
Sam brought it here, but
someone gave it to him.
What did he tell you in the ER?
You mean what didn't he tell me.
Okay, replay it all.
We need to know where
he went, who he saw.
Okay.
He picked flowers
in Piedmont Park.
Um, he basically spent
the entire day primping
for a first date with
his future wife, Sue.
Wait.
She hikes.
- She just hiked.
- Hiked where?
Yosemite.
Yosemite is a hotbed
for plague carried by fleas.
She could be our patient zero.
What did dispatch say?
Busted down Sue's front door.
Found her minimally responsive,
thready pulse.
Get her isolated. Let's go.
Okay, ready?
One, two, three.
- Buboes.
- We need more access. Septic shock.
All right, I'll put in the
central line. Give me the kit.
Fluids and antibiotics.
Remember, this is a
multi-drug resistant strain.
Already talked to the pharmacy.
Colistin being
mixed as we speak.
Let's just hope
we're not too late.
Is Sue okay? Tell me she's okay.
It was close, but
she's gonna make it.
- You all are.
- Yes.
Dr. Pravesh, awesome
work from you and...
the doctors and everyone. Wow.
Sue gave me the plague.
And I know-I
know it's nuts, but...
I find it kind of romantic.
Imagine what happens to this kid
had Sue bought the farm?
Make fun all you want, Meg.
I'm fine with it. You know why?
And maybe it's corny.
It was love at first
sight with me and Sue.
Please tell me you didn't
steal those two ultrasounds.
Didn't have to. A little
bartering with Master Bell.
I scratched him, he
scratched me. Everyone wins.
- Mostly the patients.
- Well, yeah.
They are all that matters,
so whatever it takes.
Hey, Nic, is everything okay?
Yeah. Yeah, no,
I'm good. I just...
I wanted to come and say
thank you for your help today.
I learned a few things.
Yeah, me, too. Now
you deserve some rest.
Why don't you go home and have
a couple cold ones with Conrad?
Enjoy yourself.
Yeah.
Yeah, I need to do that.
Have a good night, Alec.
What are we doing here?
Ah, well, there's our table.
People are at that table.
Dr. Benedict. My man and mentor.
This is Dr. Mina Okafor,
the yin to my yang.
Oh, nice to meet you. You both
- just happen to be here?
- Or we knew you'd
happen to be here.
It's Tuesday night foie
gras, baby, all right?
Oh, what can I do for
you, then, Dr. Austin?
Well, actually, Doc,
you've done enough.
You've been a great
mentor these last six years.
Oh, you sound like
somebody who's gonna quit.
Does it?: Oh, no.
On the contrary.
Yeah, I'm here because I
wanted you to explain to me
and my partner exactly
why you vouch for QuoVadis.
I told you, the
penicillin on the...
Dollars for Docs.
Ever heard of
that? Probably not.
It's a ProPublica
site on the interwebs
that releases details
on corporate payouts.
So, we're here, specifically,
to find out more
about that 1.5-mil ticket
that Mr. Gordon Page
deposited into your bank account.
Honey, will you
give us a minute?
I'd prefer to have this
conversation in my office...
I'm not going anywhere.
See, when Dr. Okafor
believes in something...
Or in this case, someone...
She will swim through a
lake of fire and brimstone
to reach her objective.
Whereas you...
you led me to believe
that my arrogance
killed my patient.
When, in fact, it was a company
that makes defective
valves and owns you.
Disappointing.
Anything you'd like to add?
Not at the moment.
See you around, Abe.
You want the good,
the bad or the ugly?
In that order.
Good: I found the CEO
and head of neurosurgery
at Jacksonville
General, Dr. Ryan Kehoe.
Also went to Cabo
with Gordon Page.
Uh, pioneered his
new back device,
opinion leader for QuoVadis.
Sounding familiar?
Bad: that scotch is from my mom.
She and my dad crossed paths
at my Aunt Denise's wedding,
and the DJ's choice of mid-'70s
soft rock reignited their spark
in a sloppy way that
makes me cringe.
- But they had...
- What's the ugly?
You can't meet with
Dr. Kehoe because he's dead.
Ten months ago, at the height
of his partnership with QuoVadis,
he jumped off the
Dames Point Bridge.
- Look, you didn't...
- Are you...?
Look, Conrad, I
like what we have.
Where we are.
I don't want things to change.
Not right now, anyway.
I just... I spend so
much of my time
trying to figure it out
what to tell patients,
trying to alleviate their fears
before and after the diagnosis,
to protect them, but sometimes
a hard truth is just the
best thing for everyone.
So...
how about you and I stop
dancing around the issue
and we just get real
honest with each other?
What do you want me to say?
Well, that we find ourselves
in different places? Once again.
Yes, but that doesn't
mean that I don't want
to move in with you
or get married, all of it,
just not this second.
- Isn't that okay?
- And I respect that.
If it's the truth.
Okay, Conrad, you seem to have
all the answers to what's wrong,
and probably a way to fix it.
Go ahead.
It's already fixed.
Look at me.
Willing to sit down, talk things
through. That's progress, right?
And that's thanks to you.
But that's the
problem right there.
There's nothing
left for you to fix.
- That's not fair.
- Well...
it's not about being fair.
Nic, it's about being honest.
I was a project for you,
and now it's finished.
That's my fear.
That's my diagnosis.
Is it true?
All right, I shouldn't
have come here today.
Well, tell me I'm
wrong, tell me I'm right.
Either way, just open up
like you asked me to do.
And I will, when I'm ready,
when I figure some things out.
Would it help if I went back
to the old version of me?
I'm not sure I like either
version of you right now.
At least now
you're being honest.
Good night, Conrad.
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH