Previously on ER:
You got one week, Mike, one.
I want you to know, I really appreciate
it. You won't even know I'm there.
- There's just a lot of stuff going on.
- Gates?
But I wanna sort it out.
I'm trying to sort it out.
I just need a bit of time.
I work on gay patients all the
time. I work with gay doctors.
Greg, you're more like
Dad than you realize.
No.
- It's not coming out like I mean.
- I sure hope someday you prove me wrong.
- Are you my dad or not?
- There's a simple test we can take.
It's called a paternity
test and if you want...
we can take it tonight.
- I'm in pain, I've been here three hours.
- I'm sorry, we're very busy.
- You haven't done crap.
- I'll try to...
- You said that an hour ago, bitch.
- I'm doing the best I can.
So why don't you
just settle down?
- No, you settle down.
- Oh!
Okay. So, what went wrong?
- She didn't stay calm.
- Her tone was threatening.
She needed to keep her distance.
You okay?
All right, good.
So let's review the key points
of managing assaultive behavior.
I made coffee.
Thanks.
Is this your history project?
- No, I'm paying the bills.
- Huh?
- You've been late three months in a row.
- Sarah...
I don't want them
turning off electricity.
- Is that my checkbook?
- I make them out, you still have to sign.
Sweetie, I know
you're trying to help...
- Morning.
- Hey.
- Nice outfit.
- Job interview.
- What kind of job?
- Executive assistant.
That's a fancy name
for answering the phone.
Maybe he can help with the rent.
We have $90 to get
us through the week.
Look, if this thing comes through,
I'll be out of your hair in no time.
- Yeah, right.
- Hey.
All right, shredded
wheat or cornflakes?
- So how you been?
- I've been all right.
Hey, how about those Cubs, huh?
Catch that game
last night? Some win.
No.
All right. Uh...
Okay, so you invite me to
breakfast to talk about baseball.
No, it's something else.
I wanna fix things.
- Neck.
- Ha!
Knee. LITCHMAN: Good.
- Nuts.
- Good, good.
Now, remember the goal
is to defuse violent behavior.
This training is
just a last resort.
- Next.
- Come on, Sam, go, go. Woo-hoo!
Kick his ass, Sam. - Let's go.
You ready? Hm-hm-hm.
Nose.
Come on, you can
do better than that.
Nuts.
- Show me some strength.
- I just don't wanna hurt you.
I've got enough
padding on to stop a tank.
Come on. ALL: Neck.
I'm worried about you, Sam.
Bad guys will rip a little
lady like you to shreds.
- Oh, really? You think?
- Yeah, I know.
Knee.
Aah! ALL: Whoa!
Look, I've been
thinking about it a lot.
I let you down. I know that.
It doesn't matter
what you wanna do...
or how you wanna
live, I'm still your brother.
See, when I pushed
you away, I messed up.
But I can do better.
I think we both can.
Look, it's just like
when you moved in.
You know, you could've
been a little bit more honest.
You could've told me what
was really going on with you.
I didn't know how to tell you.
What, are you on some
12-step program or something?
No, man, it's just...
I spent too many years
pushing people away.
I don't wanna do that anymore.
That mean you gonna
be talking to Dad?
Let me work my way up to it.
I'll give you that.
- It's been five days.
- So?
So? Fever without
source freaks me out.
- It's a virus.
- Yeah.
Or it could be a serious
infection that we're missing.
Look, he's playing well,
he's eating. Joe's not sick.
Well, I'm gonna check
this just to make sure.
- Abby.
- What?
What? I got a little urine
sample this morning, so?
Dr. Kovac.
- Bad CHF, Trauma 2.
- Okay.
- Class over already?
- It ended a little early.
You're being silly.
If this were someone else's
baby, you'd tell them not to worry.
All right, you're right.
He probably just caught my cold.
Hey, Timmy. You're back.
- And better than ever.
- Can you send this for a UA?
- Which patient?
- John Doe.
All right. I got it.
Officer Litchman needs a room.
Curtain 2, and hold for a chart.
Nice move. We were
supposed to be off till noon.
- Sorry.
- Whoa.
Dislocated patella.
How did that happen?
He was teaching the
Assaultive Behavior class.
Nurse here got a little
carried away. Kicks like a mule.
- You said to bring it on.
- I wasn't expecting Bruce Lee.
- So how long is this gonna take?
- Normally? All day.
But I'll try to get you
out in less than an hour.
Yeah, right.
I'll bet you a doughnut I can.
Heh. Man, you sure know
how to get a cop excited.
- Crackles to the apex.
- Forty of Lasix.
It feels like I'm drowning.
Ever have fluid in your
lungs? A heart attack?
High blood pressure
and high cholesterol.
Can someone call my dad?
"Rutley and Son Heating
and Air Conditioning."
- Your dad still works?
- No, he lives with me.
I moved my office home
so I can look after him.
BP's 195/120.
- Okay, nitro drip at 40 mics.
- What meds you on?
Nothing, nothing
for your pressure?
- Cholesterol?
- Ran out.
- How long ago?
- Long time.
Please call my dad.
He's expecting me.
Twelve-lead's here.
What about your doctor?
Who's your doctor?
His name's on my insurance
card. I'll see him tomorrow.
You're in congestive heart failure.
You need to be admitted to the ICU.
I'm fine. It's my dad
I'm worried about.
I was really bummed out
about the way we left things.
Hey, man, I'm glad you
came down to meet me.
You know, if you ever need
anything, I'm here for you.
Actually, I could use a favor.
I'm applying for a job and it'd help if
you could write a letter or something.
- All right, what kind of work?
- An EMT with the fire department.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Money's good, flexible
hours. Perfect for a student.
- An EMT, huh?
- What's wrong with that?
They're not the most
open-minded individuals...
if you know what I mean.
Yeah.
I mean, it's definitely a "don't
ask, don't tell" type of situation.
I mean, if you're gonna fit in,
you gotta just be one of the boys.
I know how to handle it.
And if it works out, who knows?
Maybe I'll think about med school.
- Don't do it, man.
- Really? I see what you do.
It's good work.
Really? So you're thinking
about Emergency Medicine, huh?
Oh, hell, no. Plastic Surgery.
If I'm gonna put in all that
work, I need to make some coin.
No. The swabs were
sent in three weeks ago.
Anthony Gates, Sarah
Riley. Yes, I can hold.
- Hey, trauma coming in?
- Crohn's fistula.
- Paternity results never came back.
- How's Sarah holding up?
She's all right. She
doesn't wanna talk about it.
- Must be on her mind.
- She's moving on.
Today, she finds my
checkbook. Pays all my bills.
Oh, really? Maybe
she can become a CPA.
When I was 12, I stood in line all
day for the Return of the Jedi premiere.
That's all I want her to do.
- Be a Star Wars nerd?
- No, be a kid.
No. They didn't
come in the mail.
I didn't get them in the mail. Can
you just tell me over the phone?
- Gates.
- Fine, send them again.
- You okay? We'll catch up later?
- Yeah.
- ICU said one hour.
- We're going to the cath lab.
- Is he stable enough?
- Well, we'll stay with him.
If they can open up an artery,
maybe it will reverse his heart failure.
- My dad?
- Oh, yeah.
We called him. He's on his way.
I got 50,000 in mutual
funds at First National.
Okay.
- See if his BUN and creatinine are back.
- Got it.
Hey, Gates. GATES: Hmm?
Who do you know at the CFD in
the Paramedic Training Program?
Everyone.
- Any of them actually like you?
- I'm popular everywhere I go.
Need to check postreduction
film before he leaves.
- Going to the roach coach.
- She owes me coffee.
What? You owe me a doughnut.
So let's say I had a friend
who wanted to be an EMT.
Oh, very tough. Very
competitive, a lot of applicants.
- It's my brother.
- Your brother?
Family? Why didn't you say so?
- I'll be his hook.
- His what?
In City Fire, you need someone
on the inside to help you move up.
I'll help your brother
out. No worries.
From now on, I'm his rabbi.
- What makes you think I'm buying?
- Least you can do.
- After you destroyed my knee.
- Oh. It's not even broken.
The kneecap just
slipped out of place.
- So where did you learn moves like that?
- In high school.
That's a hell of a PE class.
Yeah. A little Muay
Thai, some Krav. Whoa!
Yeah, I had to learn
to protect myself.
From mean football players
who wanted a date to the prom?
Ha-ha. No. The metal-heads who
wanted a quickie behind the Dairy Queen.
Ha-ha. Damn. You know,
you're full of surprises.
Sam.
Move, move, move.
- How's your guy?
- Good vitals.
- What about the driver?
- Ask Bardelli.
- Neck pain?
- Ahem. Nope.
- Do not move.
- I'm okay. Aah!
God, I put my knee out again.
Easy, fella.
Is he altered?
- Kind of hard to tell.
- Let's get him on a board.
- Hey, Sam, open up a trauma room.
- Got it.
Came out of nowhere.
You think he's drunk?
- Don't know. PRATT:
One, two, three.
Sir, what's your name?
Do you speak English?
- Gotta assume he's altered.
- Pupils equal and reactive.
Hey, guys?
Let's start with a trauma
panel and C-spine.
Can you unlock the door?
- I'll tape his head down.
- Just unlock the damn door.
- Whoa. What's the matter?
- Something's moving in there.
- Two more victims.
- Oh, man.
Looks like we've got an adult male
and a little boy, both unconscious.
Excuse me. How much longer?
Well, your son's
still up in the cath lab.
So it will be a while?
It's hard to say.
- Should I wait right here?
- Let's get a cup of coffee, Mr. Rutley.
- We can try 1.25 of IV enalapril.
- Okay.
Is that you, Danny?
Yeah, I'm Dr. Kovac.
- Hi.
- Wayne Rutley, what is all this?
During the cath, the fluid
in his lungs got worse.
So we had to put a
tube down his throat.
- Are you having any pain?
- Sir, he can't talk with the tube in.
- Are you a relative?
- A home health aide.
- Is this a heart attack?
- It's a cardiomyopathy.
- A what?
- His heart is squeezing very weakly.
He's young. He's
got a good heart.
He's had untreated high
blood pressure for a long time.
Well, he's always working.
He never gets to a doctor.
Has he been short
of breath lately?
I just met him today.
Danny calls an agency when
he goes out to bid on a job.
He thinks I need a babysitter.
His eyesight's not so good
and he has memory problems.
Were they aluminum ducts?
I told you. You need
galvanized sheet metal.
Tight wheezing. He's
barely moving air.
Trauma 1, let's
get Gates on this.
Head lac, good vitals. - Okay.
Little guy's concussed. GCS 14.
Okay, good. Exam
2, both of them.
- Might take longer this time.
- Some of the others look pretty bad.
Hey. Next time we
go out, I'm driving.
Does anybody know
what language this is?
- Sounds like Farsi, maybe?
- Kid needs a line.
- Grab a Buretrol from Trauma.
- Ahem.
Take slow, deep breaths, okay?
Give the medicine a chance to work.
Hey, Bards. Captain
Mahoney still with 43s?
- Had pancakes with him this morning.
- Have him check his e-mail.
- You picking up shifts?
- No, it's about an EMT applicant.
Captain Mahoney's on the EMT
selection committee. Key player.
Hey, Pratt. What am I missing?
Tight asthma. He might
be biting plastic soon.
- Everyone else is stable.
- Dr. Kovac.
V-fib. Paddles are charged.
What happened?
Clear.
Normal sinus.
- Got a pulse.
- Thank God.
- Is your son married?
- He never met the right girl.
- And your wife?
- She passed in '82.
You're doing better, Danny.
Open your eyes.
Ninety over sixty-five.
Up the dopamine.
Hang in there, pal.
Hang in there.
- More cricoid.
- Sats are dropping, pull out.
- Cords are way anterior.
- He's getting harder to bag.
Ah.
- Sam.
- Kid's starting to open his eyes.
Okay, good. Look, I
need an ET view now.
All right. Be right there.
- Head CT's clear on flower guy.
- Oh, good news.
- You need a Farsi translator?
- Oh, yeah.
He's got a head injury,
so he might be disoriented.
He doesn't speak Farsi. I
think that's Armenian, sorry.
Any Armenian nurses up there?
Hey, that's him.
- Hey, how do you know this guy?
- He saved us.
And where's my brother?
Oh! Hey. Hey, hey, hey.
- Julio, it's me, Tomás.
- Step back.
- Move it to the right.
- Is that better?
- No.
- He has asthma.
- We figured that part out.
- They're brothers.
- Ahem. So how'd this happen?
- We were going to the drugstore.
He couldn't walk.
Then he couldn't talk.
The guy with the flowers threw us
in the back and drove to the hospital.
So Yakov over there
is the Good Samaritan.
Damn it, bag him up.
- He dropped his spray if you need it.
- Okay.
Come on, there's a
better place to wait.
- I wanna stay with my brother.
- We'll be back in a few minutes.
- You wanna try fiber optic?
- Nope, I want Sam.
- Got a guy who's not breathing.
- I can wait.
I'll be there soon.
Got everything.
- Pulse ox, 89.
- Sats are good enough to tube, huh?
No, I want a cushion.
Let's get him up to 95.
All right, we'll wait.
There's a little, tiny camera
at the end of this tube.
- You're all set.
- Slow down, Lily.
He's got a long
expiratory phase.
Hey, I can get a copy of last
year's EMT exam for your brother.
- Good.
- We're up to 92.
Grab an end-tidal
detector, will you?
We'll find out who's
doing the interview.
Find out his hobbies, his favorite
sports teams, stuff like that.
- Okay. GATES: All
right. We're up to 95.
All right, cool.
Is it okay if I do this?
I'll give you one shot.
- All right.
- You need a laryngoscope?
- Yeah.
- No.
Watch the screen and
pass it through the cords.
- All right, I knew that.
- All right, come on, let's go.
All right.
Taste buds.
Tonsils.
Epiglottis and
the promised land.
- Straight shot through the cords.
- All right, bingo.
Stopping short of the
carina, and bag him.
- Nice.
- Looks like Kovac could use a hand.
Oh, yeah. Not so good.
All right, thanks for letting me do this.
This was a good thing for me to learn.
V-fib. KOVAC: Take
over compressions?
No problem.
Another amp of epi, charge to 360.
- Good.
Shock him. It worked before.
Clear.
Still in fib.
- We're not making much progress here.
- What's that supposed to mean?
His heart is too weak. It's not
responding to our medicine.
- But you're not giving up?
- No, no, we're not giving up.
I just need you to understand
that it's not looking good.
You're saying he could die?
- It's a possibility, sir.
- Oh, he's my son.
He's my little boy.
Don't leave me, Danny.
- Call the social worker.
- Don't leave me.
Don't leave me.
- I'm in pain, I've been here for hours.
- Sorry.
You haven't done crap for me.
- Ho-ho-ho. Don't start that again.
- Look where it got me last time.
All the docs are busy. I
need an order for IV sedation.
- Can't you pop it in?
- Without painkillers?
I've been shot
before. I can handle it.
I think a doctor should do it.
Come on, Sam. Don't be a wimp.
Just pop this back
in place so we...
Aah! Aah.
Hey.
Hey, tough guy. Wake up.
Asystole.
Resuming compressions.
Mr. Rutley, it's
been 45 minutes.
- Should a cardiologist see him?
- They'd do the same thing.
It's too late.
No.
- No, no. KOVAC: Look,
we're gonna stop now.
I'm sorry.
Danny.
Oh, my God.
What am I gonna do?
Sir, there's a social worker
here that will help you.
How could this happen?
I'll do the coroner's paperwork.
I'll make sure
he's taken care of.
- Tidal volume, 700. AC of 10.
- Okay.
How's the x-ray look? Good?
Well, he might have
a small pneumo.
- Call Radiology for a wet read.
- Okay.
- How long's he gonna sleep?
- Um, might be a while.
After he wakes up,
we can go home?
You know what? He's gonna
have to be here for a couple days.
Can I stay with him?
- Yeah, but you have to go home at night.
- By myself?
No, we're calling your parents.
No. It's just us.
Ever since Mom died,
Julio's my guardian.
You don't have
any aunts or uncles?
Okay, we'll figure it out. And
you can hang out here for now.
- All right?
- Good.
I'm staying with you, J.
I'm gonna stay right here.
Hey, tough guy. Wake up.
- You need a doctor?
- No, he just vagalled.
- I'll check his vitals.
- Abby, urine's clean on John Doe.
Great.
No leuks, no
nitrates. Thank you.
Hey, Timmy? Repeat
knee on Litchman.
Okay, wait. How does a 10-day
cruise turn into two months?
- Heh-heh-heh. Gracie will fill you in.
- Yeah, she's not talking.
Okay.
After we docked in Singapore, I
showed her some of my old haunts.
Climbed the temples of Penang,
cycled the Quang Ninh coast.
Elephant-trekked
through the Ratanakiri.
- Elephants?
- Yeah.
We got hung up at the
Cambodian border...
and we'd still be there if Gracie
hadn't tapped into her 401K.
Well, that's too
much information.
Hey, Miranda. How's he doing?
One-oh-two? Well, did
you give him a Tyleno...?
Okay.
Well, call me
after his nap. Bye.
No relatives, no
long-term-care insurance.
Guy worked all day, took care
of his dad, but didn't plan for this.
Take-home lesson? Don't assume
that you're gonna outlive your dad.
Abby, Pratt says you need
Social Work for your asthma kid.
Thanks.
Gates, don't get too busy. There's a
guy out in the lobby looking for you.
- Hey, I thought we could grab lunch.
- I got five minutes.
How did the interview go?
- Not so great.
- You didn't get the job, right?
- No.
- What happened?
- Well... What?
I don't know anything about
Word. And what the hell's Excel?
So it wasn't a good fit.
Since when do you need a
computer to do a day's work, right?
What about Chuck Mooney's
construction company?
He sold it.
What about, what's his name?
Your friend, Billy Prior's restaurant?
Turned it into a yoga studio.
- Something will come up, hopefully.
- Yeah.
Actually, you could help me out
tonight. I don't want Sarah cooking.
Why don't you go to the grocery
store, get some groceries?
- And cook dinner tonight.
- No, no, I can't take your money.
You used to love to
cook at the firehouse.
- Yeah.
- You love cooking.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I could do a chicken pot pie.
- Maybe a London Broil.
- Yeah, yeah.
- The boys always liked my London Broil.
- Surprise me, surprise me.
Patients are in the hall, Abby.
Water pipe burst.
Okay.
Rose Nichols?
That's me.
Ahem. Hello.
I'm Dr. Lockhart.
- Let's see, fever and a cough.
- For almost a week.
- Okay, how are you feeling?
- I'm a little under the weather.
Yeah.
Well, there's a lot of
colds going around.
And sometimes it takes a couple
of weeks, but kids usually get over it.
Eighty-one?
Could mean we're not
getting a proper signal.
Let me see.
- Uh-oh.
- What?
Sounds like pneumonia. And
her oxygen level is really low.
So I think we're gonna
have to admit you.
Everyone said she was fine,
but I knew it was more than a cold.
Okay, he's clear for discharge.
- How are the boys?
- Oh, they're doing well.
- What?
- He's asking you for a date.
Oh. Well, repeat the head
CT. I think he's still altered.
I didn't know you were here.
- Yeah, just got here.
- There's lots of trauma today.
- I heard.
Hey, the guys from my old band
are playing this Saturday night at Exit.
I might be on call.
- So we're still waiting?
- It's only been a week.
Okay. I'm gonna go clear
some of these beds, all right?
- Okay.
- See you.
Sarah?
- Have you seen Tony?
- Well, I can look around.
- No, I'll wait.
- Okay.
Or maybe you can help me.
Sure.
It's kind of personal.
Okay. Come on.
I need a vaccine.
- Which one?
- HPV.
- It prevents cervical cancer.
- Right.
But the school nurse gives it and
you need your parents' permission...
or your grandparents'
permission.
They wouldn't understand.
- Does Tony know about this?
- Not yet.
- Are you gonna tell him?
- No.
It's private.
It's okay. I mean,
you can tell him.
If you want to.
Why didn't you go
to your pediatrician?
He only takes
care of little kids.
Besides, I think I need
a new doctor anyway.
Do you know a good GYN?
So you can't place him?
Best I can hope for is a
crappy nursing home...
that'll accept $100
a day from Medicaid.
Not sick enough for a nursing
home. He needs assisted living.
Medicaid nor Medicare will
cover that, he can't afford it.
- The son's assets?
- They'll be tied up in probate for a year.
I've tried three board-and-cares.
They want cash, today.
Greedy bastards. But
we got a bigger problem.
I'm not sure he's competent to
consent to nursing-home placement.
Didn't seem that altered.
His Alzheimer's gets
worse as the day goes on.
Sundowning.
We need someone with durable
power for his health-care decisions.
The son had it. Lot of
good that does us now.
We're scrambling to get an
emergency State Guardian.
Hey, any luck finding a
foster home for Tomás?
Piece of cake compared to this.
- Dr. Pratt?
You called for a wet read?
Yes, I did. A possible
pneumo. Excuse me, please.
Haven't seen you in a few weeks.
I was doing an invasive
fellowship in Dallas.
- For six months.
- Really?
- Well, I sent you a few e-mails.
- Never got any of them.
- You must've changed your address.
- I've had the same address for years.
So you think there's
some pathology here?
Palpitations. Like your
heart's skipping a beat?
- More like it races. Every now and then.
- Ray, can I get you to look at a knee?
- Yeah, excuse me.
- It's happening.
- I'll get the crash cart.
- My chest is gonna explode.
- Got a pulse, a hundred of lido.
- Anything surgical?
Stable V-tach.
- Responding to lidocaine.
- Ahh. That's better.
I guess you won't be needing me.
Milligram a minute.
Titrate up, p.r.n. ectopy.
- Hey.
- I left a consult on your asthma guy.
- Thanks.
- Did you know Sarah's here?
- Huh?
- She's asking for the HPV vaccine.
- You're kidding me.
- Does that mean...?
- No, we didn't get that far.
She wants the world to
know how grown up she is.
I wouldn't worry about it. It's
just a phase that girls go through.
- Gates.
- Coming.
Good luck.
Thanks for your help. I'll hold.
We got a Guardian assigned and
two nursing homes to choose from.
- Great, thank you.
- Thanks.
Think he'll be able
to decide which one?
Well, let's hope so.
Hello, Mr. Rutley.
Hello. When am I leaving?
Well, that's what we're
here to talk to you about.
Well, what's
there to talk about?
We found a couple of places
that can take you tonight.
- Well, what kind of places?
- Convalescent homes.
Oh. I have a home.
Well, you're gonna need help
now, getting around, meals.
I have help. I have meals.
We eat dinner at 7.
Someone ought to call Danny,
tell him I'm gonna be late.
Wayne, you know about Danny.
Remember?
Sure. He went out to
bid on a job this morning.
He ought to be home by now.
Wayne, you know, Danny
was in this hospital today.
What, Danny?
No. Danny's not sick.
He had a heart problem.
I...
Nobody told me
anything about that.
His heart stopped beating.
We worked on him
for over an hour.
Where is he?
Uh...
He's better now?
He died, Wayne.
Danny's dead.
No. No.
No, I don't believe
it. It's not possible.
Where is he? I wanna
see him, where is he?
- He's in the morgue, Mr. Rutley.
- What?
Take me there.
Take me to my son.
Please?
Please, I wanna see
him, I need to see him.
I wanna say goodbye.
The CDC recommends starting
the HPV vaccine when you're 11.
All right, we need
to talk about this.
Okay, let's talk.
- HPV is a sexually transmitted...
- I'm not having sex, okay?
But when I do, I
wanna be responsible.
Even if I said
yes, your grand...
Okay, do you realize
how stupid this is, though?
I'm old enough to go and
get birth control on my own.
But you won't let me go and get
a vaccine that could save my life.
- Sarah, you're 12 years old.
- Yeah, I know.
- What's the rush?
- I'm not rushing.
But I can't help it if I'm
growing up now, can I?
Need you to fill out transfer
papers for Mr. Rutley.
I'll be there in a second.
Can we continue
this at home? Please?
- So I can't get it now?
- Not today.
That's so unfair.
All right. We got you
five days off work.
I have a self-defense seminar
tomorrow. Wanna fill in?
Oh, crap. V-tach again.
- It's the third time.
- I need Ray.
I'm on lidocaine and amiodarone.
Shouldn't I be in the ICU?
Hey.
- Have you been faking this whole time?
- No, I had an itch.
What's going on, Sam?
- What are you doing?
- Is it his heart?
No, it's his finger.
Ah.
- Uh-oh. V-tach again.
- Sam?
- It's a shockable rhythm.
- Shockable?
No.
- Clear.
- No. Aah!
- Crazy bitch.
- Yeah, you're the crazy one.
- Sam, have you lost your mind?
- Come on, it was only 10 joules.
Really?
Oh! Huh.
Yeah, I guess that's not so bad.
It's called a
negative Mach band.
Looks like something's there,
but it's not. It doesn't even exist.
Wow.
It's a retinal phenomenon. The
eye is fooled at a light-dark junction.
Always something new to learn.
I'm glad you're back,
thanks for the help.
Hey, hey, hey.
How about we grab some
dinner sometime after work?
Maybe. Call me.
Danny?
Pick up the phone, son. If you
can hear me, pick up the phone.
Are you...?
- Is this one yours?
- Yeah, yeah.
I don't like leaving
messages on the machine.
Let's get you back to your room.
I need to call my son.
He doesn't know I'm here.
Please.
Guys.
Guys, hey, hey,
hey. Knock it off.
I am sorry. I am upset.
My brother. He totaled my van.
Yes, but aren't you
happy that he's okay?
Without van, my
business is dead.
- All because he drives like madman.
- Sir, he saved someone's life.
Yeah.
What are you talking about?
He was speeding because he
had a sick patient in the back.
I am sorry. I didn't understand.
- Hey, Pratt?
- Yeah?
- I need you to sign the discharge.
- All right.
- Got any questions, man?
- Yeah, can I go out on crutches?
- Ha.
- Hospital policy. Wheelchair is safer.
- Oh, all right, I'll make an exception.
- All right.
Ah. Hey, Joe.
Hey, how are you
feeling? I miss you. Hello.
His temp's down, but
he didn't want the bottle.
- Oh, my God, look how big he's getting.
- Yeah.
- Hey, you need me to stay?
- No, thanks, have a good night.
Shh, shh.
- Hey, Sam, is Exam 2 open?
- Yeah.
Look, this is where
Mommy works. Look.
- Greg, I need a favor.
- Okay.
You taking me home?
You're going to a nursing home.
Heh. No. Those
places are for old folks.
- That's where you're gonna live.
- No, I told you, I live with my son.
- Mr. Rutley.
- Hmm?
I spoke to your son.
Hmm. Is he picking me up?
He wants you at the new place.
He does? Is he gonna be there?
I'm sure he'll find a way.
- So we can have dinner together.
- If that's what you want.
Well, I guess it's okay.
Tell him I won't start
eating till he gets there.
Hey, Luka. I'll
be right with you.
Well, all right, officer.
You are on your own.
Thanks, Sam. You've been great.
Ha-ha. Your day might have
been better if you never met me.
I'm not so sure about that.
- I hope I see you around.
- Yeah.
- You need a pen?
- Uh...
Yeah. Now, see...
"Rutley and Son. Since 1959."
Thank you.
When we started, it was just me.
Oh. Now, Danny's got
four guys working for him.
He's a good kid. Hmm.
I'm a lucky guy.
Take care, Mr. Rutley.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Are you still in touch
with your father?
Not since I was 3. You?
He's in Croatia. I haven't
been there in a long time.
- Hey, what's for dinner?
- Spaghetti.
There's more in the pot.
- I'll go shopping after dinner, okay?
- Oh, I don't think so.
- We have to eat.
- Come on, Sarah.
- I know what you're doing.
- What?
- Cooking, shopping, paying bills, clean...
- Somebody has to.
I want you to be a kid. Please,
just enjoy being a kid, okay?
Right, I forgot.
I'm supposed to text my friends
and hang out at the mall, right?
- What's wrong with that?
- I like taking care of the house.
- Just let me do it.
- When you become older...
you'll have plenty of
responsibility. Trust me.
Hey, smells pretty good in here.
What is that...?
Where are the groceries, Mike?
Oh, shoot.
I knew I forgot something.
All right. Sarah, go
do your homework.
- I'm not finished yet.
- Now.
- I gave you a hundred dollars.
- I know.
- How much you got left?
- I don't know.
Give me your wallet.
- Tony...
- Give me your wallet.
Six bucks? Six bucks.
Well, it was Lou Sanders' birthday
and so I bought a couple rounds.
- No otitis, no pharyngitis, no nothing.
- You sure?
Yeah, I'm sure. This is the
healthiest kid I've seen in a long time.
- Really?
- Really.
Really.
Okay.
Well, you know, the babysitter
was in the neighborhood.
And she was worried, so I
thought I'd get a second opinion.
I see.
Thank you.
- There's Daddy. Say hi.
- Hey.
- What's he doing here?
- Um...
It's a warm night, I thought we
could all take a walk to the pier.
Nice. I'm gonna go grab my coat.
I guess his urine
tested negative?
Pratt doesn't think
he needs a CBC?
No.
I know you think
I'm acting crazy.
No, I think you're acting like
a mother. A slightly crazy one.
- Did you dispo the Alzheimer's dad?
- Yeah.
Poor guy.
- So sad.
- No, he's lucky.
What?
He doesn't have to remember
losing a son every day.
Hey.
Hi.
Yeah.
You gonna keep a job if
everything sends you to the bar?
- I don't need that kind of job.
- You need something.
I am a firefighter. I rush
into burning buildings.
I axe my way through
roofs that are collapsing.
I save people's lives.
And now some snotty kid...
is trying to tell me how to make
coffee? How to answer his phone?
Send me back to the copy room
because I made a smudge on his page?
It's not right.
For 35 years, every time I
thought it was gonna be different...
I could always count
on you to screw up.
- I had a bad day.
- Yeah, yeah, it's always something.
- What are you gonna do?
- I don't know.
You don't know. Well...
You can't live here.
I'm family. I'm your father.
That what you think?
Oh, screw you, you
little bastard. Screw you.
I worked my ass off for
you and for your mother.
I admit I may not be the best at
home stuff, but I supported my family.
I paid for your braces, for your books,
and for your mother's fancy clothes...
and I never got a moment's
thanks from either one of you.
Well, you may not like me...
but you owe me, you
ungrateful little prick.
Sarah?
What?
Take those off.
So we didn't get a chance
to finish. Do you wanna talk?
Here.
- When did this come?
- Two weeks ago.
I was kind of hoping
that you were my dad.
But maybe there's still a
way I can live with you?
We'll see.
We'll see what we can do.