What brings you in here?
I'm running out of places to go.
At times like this,
it's important to
have community.
You're about to
throw your life away,
your medical license.
It's like I'm reverting back
to this old version of me,
and I can't stop it.
I'm sorry. I... I
didn't mean to do that.
I'm...
- It's okay. It's okay.
Um, I should probably go.
I can't be the one
to save you, Mitch.
I love you.
It's not enough.
♪ You and I are
holy fire, so ♪
♪ Oh, my God
♪ Let me extinguish the
habit, the sequence ♪
♪ The loss in my mind
♪ Now I believe in the
♪ Right by the
entrance, you broke ♪
♪ Finally, reality's
taking its hold ♪
♪ You're not who you were,
but you can't let it ♪
Hello?
Can anyone hear me?
Help!
Keep talking so I can find you.
Over here!
Can you hear me?
Where?
Over here!
Why can't I see you?
We're down here, in the hole.
Oh, no.
Hello?
Oh, thank God.
I can see you.
Thank you for finding us.
Thank you.
What's your name?
Sadie. Sadie Smith.
Hi, Sadie. I'm Mitch.
Uh, I'm a doctor, and...
A doctor?
Well, that's lucky
on an unlucky night.
I'm scared, Mommy.
I know, baby.
But I'm right here.
How long you been down there?
Uh, less than an hour, I think.
I pulled over 'cause
Emelia had to pee.
I was looking for a spot.
She fell in first?
And me right after.
How far below you is Emelia?
Sounds like 2 or 3 feet.
She's really, really scared.
She says her arm hurts.
Okay, which one?
I don't know.
Emelia doesn't know her
right from her left yet.
What about you?
Your leg's twisted
up pretty bad.
How much pain are you in
on a scale of 1 to 10?
A 7 or 8.
But it's better than before.
It's starting to
feel a little numb.
Okay, we gotta get
you out of there.
I'm gonna call 911.
Mommy?
Everything's okay, sweetheart.
There's a man here to help us.
Uh, I'm not getting any
reception here, so I'm...
I'm gonna try walking
back toward the road.
No, no, no, no, no.
Please don't leave us.
Sadie?
Sadie, listen to me.
I'm just going a
few feet that way.
I will not leave you, okay?
I won't.
You have my word.
Do you trust me?
Yes.
What's happening, Mommy?
You see the nice man, Emelia?
He's gonna call more
people to come help us.
And we're gonna trust him, okay?
Yes, we trust the nice man.
I will be right back.
Emelia?
Mommy, I can't reach you.
It's gonna be okay, baby.
Help is on the way.
Dr. Ripley?
I'm Chief Annabelle
Jennings, Firehouse 128.
I'm Dr. Mitch Ripley,
Gaffney Chicago Med.
Nice to meet you.
Here.
I already paired it for you.
I know you've already
formed a rapport with Sadie,
so I think it best to keep
you as our point person.
Yeah.
Hopefully I can
keep her spirits up.
So what's the rescue plan?
Come with me.
Keep up the rope bag, raise
the aerial 30 degrees.
Lieutenant, this is
Dr. Mitch Ripley.
Mouch.
Good to see you, Ripley.
You two know each other?
We do, Chief.
Dr. Ripley and I
have got history...
very recent history.
How's Trudy? How's her
recovery been going?
It came and went.
She had no patience for it,
wanted to get right back to
kicking ass and taking names.
Good.
Hey, I didn't know you left 51.
No, I didn't.
I passed the lieutenant's exam,
so I'm picking up
shifts for experience
till a spot opens
up at home base.
Dr. Ripley agreed to
be our point person
with Sadie and Emelia.
What kind of injuries
are we looking at?
Well, Sadie's got a broken leg.
Emelia says her arm hurts.
I'm guessing it's fractured.
What's the plan to
get them out of there?
Well, our best bet is
building an H rescue system.
We dig a vertical rescue
hole parallel to the well.
Then we dig a horizontal
rescue tunnel to connect them.
The well's been out of
service for 50 years.
Its walls are made out
of old powdered cement
that doesn't age well.
A brick hammer will
easily break through.
I'm guessing you
would break through
about chest level with Sadie?
- Mm-hmm.
Once we see what
we're dealing with
in terms of injuries,
we'll figure out
how and when to
bring the victims up.
You mean patients.
They're victims until we
get them up to the surface.
Dr. Ripley?
Sadie's asking for you.
Sadie?
What's going on down there?
Emelia won't stop crying.
She's terrified.
Okay, Sadie...
Please get us out now.
I need you to relax.
How? We can't move down here.
We can barely breathe.
I know.
I know this is
stressful and scary,
but you have to focus on one
thing and one thing only...
keeping Emelia calm.
And that means you staying calm
because she takes her
cues from you, okay?
Can you do that for me?
Yeah.
Yeah, I can do that.
Okay.
You have kids?
No.
Then maybe keep the
parenting advice
to yourself.
Fair enough.
Excuse me. Hi. Sorry.
I'm looking for Dr. Frost.
Yeah, you have to sign
in at the front desk
in the waiting room.
Oh, no. I'm not
a patient. I'm...
- Wait. Ainsley?
- Jonathan.
Hi. Hi.
Oh, my God. What's it been?
Like, 15 years?
Uh, 17, I think, if
you can believe it.
Crazy, right?
Maggie, this is Ainsley Towne.
I'm an old friend of
his from his TV days.
Wait.
You played his mom
in "Nick of Time."
Yes, I did.
What are you doing in Chicago?
Oh, work, obviously.
I'm downtown, shooting a movie
for the Hearts of Fire Network.
Oh, another holiday movie?
No. Oh, gosh, no.
You can only make
so many sequels
to "Heartbreak in a Pear Tree."
I love that movie.
When you taught that puppy
how to ice skate, and...
I was bawling.
Thank you.
Um, no, actually, this
is a dramatic role,
something I think I can
kind of sink my teeth into.
Oh, please, do... do tell.
Well, I play a nurse who's
trapped in an elevator
with her soul mate who
has a heart attack,
and I have to save his life.
- Yeah.
- You have to shadow me.
I'll give you a crash
course in nursing.
No, I don't wanna
be any trouble.
I just came here to
say hi to Jonathan.
- Oh.
- No, no.
I'll make some time.
Are you okay with that?
Absolutely.
I mean, Maggie is the best,
so you'll have a great time.
Jonathan will give
you my number.
Text me, and we'll make a plan.
Thank you. I look
forward to it.
Thanks, Maggie.
What?
It's great to see you.
Same.
You... you look amazing.
Thank you.
How about a catch-up
dinner at Gibson's?
- Yes, yeah.
- Yeah?
Let's... let's steak it up.
My shift ends at 5:00, so...
Okay, then I'll
circle back then.
Yeah. Okay, great.
As you can see behind me,
these brave men and women
have been working tirelessly
for 12 hours.
I am at the rescue tunnel,
switching on the helmet
light and camera now.
Stand by.
On the move.
We got a clear visual?
We do.
If we did our math
right, Sadie should be
on the other side of that
wall, and Emelia just below.
Copy that.
Okay.
Here goes nothing.
They're coming.
Too much noise.
You're okay, honey.
Help is here.
All right.
I'm gonna go easy now
so I don't bury the
poor kid in rubble.
She's got enough to deal with.
I can see you.
I busted through.
Copy that.
You look like an angel.
Oh, that's a lot
of pressure, Sadie.
You just call me Randall.
Thanks for dropping in, Randall.
I'm so glad to see you.
Oh, are you kidding?
I wouldn't miss this party.
Mommy?
Oh, hey.
Hello, kiddo.
What's your name?
Emelia with an E.
Well, it is nice to meet
you, Emelia with an E.
I'm here to help you and your
mom get back up to the surface.
How's that sound?
- Good.
All right.
Kid's alert, not critical.
How's your leg?
I can't feel it anymore.
My heart's beating really fast,
and I'm just
really, really cold.
Okay.
Let's take a look at it.
Yeah, okay.
She's pretty shocky.
I'll put on a tourniquet
and get her in a girth wrap
so she doesn't slide
down any further.
Copy that.
Looks like, as Sadie fell,
her right calf got
impaled on a metal shard,
which stopped her with enough
force to snap the femur.
But the silver lining...
it also prevented her
from falling any further.
Mouch, does she have
any pulsatile bleeding?
Uh... nah.
Just a slow ooze
from the raw surface.
Well, a tourniquet will help
with the muscular bleed,
but she's clearly
already lost circulation.
She's gonna lose the leg.
It won't be easy to extract
her from the metal rod
to bring her up.
The leg needs to
be amputated first.
You wanna go down there
and do it yourself.
It's her best chance.
The leg's already
mostly torn off.
I'd just be finishing the job
so we can get her up safely.
You're not trained
to be down there.
And Mouch isn't
trained to amputate.
Sending you down is a liability.
We're running out of time.
So what do you wanna do?
I'll vouch for him, Chief.
Ripley can seem over his skis,
but he knows exactly
what he's doing.
Okay.
Let's hope you're covered
by the Good Samaritan Act.
Thanks, Mouch.
10 feet. Keep him coming.
Lower.
Easy. We got it.
Oh.
Yes.
Nicely done.
You claustrophobic, Ripley?
Well, not that I know of.
Well, trust me.
You'll find out pretty fast.
It's a... it's a tight squeeze.
- Good?
- Yeah.
Okay.
Well, you're not ugly, are you?
I wish I were more presentable.
Mangled leg's not a good look.
Don't sell yourself short.
You wear it well.
Hey, sweetie.
How you doing?
Let's take a look at you first.
Oh, don't worry about me.
Get my baby out.
But your condition
is more serious.
Emelia first.
Okay.
Hey, Emelia.
Can I take a look at your arm?
Okay.
Ow!
Oh.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry that hurt.
You got a broken arm there.
But don't worry.
We'll fix that right up
on the surface, okay?
- Okay.
- Good.
Do your legs hurt or your tummy?
Okay.
So she's okay?
She is remarkably unharmed,
considering how far she fell.
Kids bounce, adults crack.
I keep thinking
about how she missed
getting caught by one of
these metal bars as she fell.
It could have killed her.
What if it had?
But it didn't.
And you know what else?
It's lucky that it snagged
you, because if you'd landed
on Emelia, you might
have crushed her.
Life is a game of inches.
Now, let's get
Emelia out of here.
So you haven't spoken
to Mitch since?
We haven't seen
each other since.
He's suspended and
might not come back.
Sounds like a train wreck.
Yeah.
But as you know,
I've been one myself.
I mean, I ended things
because I was afraid of...
going back there again.
I totally get that.
You've gotta put your own
oxygen mask on first, right?
Yeah.
I should let you
get back to work.
No, no.
You... you wanted to talk.
No, no, it can wait.
Is something wrong?
No.
Nothing's wrong at all.
Oh!
You're pregnant!
Oh, my God!
Oh.
You're the first
person I've told.
I was too scared
to tell anyone else
until I graduated
from my IVF doctor.
But I am past 10 weeks, so...
Oh, my gosh.
Lizzie, I...
I know. Me too.
But this is all because of you.
And I'm so, so grateful.
Mommy, I wanna get out of here.
Emelia, I need you to calm down.
I don't want you to
hurt yourself worse.
No. Mommy comes too.
Sweet girl, you need
to go with Mitch first.
I'll join you soon.
No.
I'm not leaving
without you, Mommy!
Hey, Emelia, I
understand you're scared,
but we need to get you out first
so that I can help your mom.
And I can't do
that with you here.
Hey.
What do we do when we're scared?
Sing the "Winnie the Pooh" song.
That's right.
Can we sing it together?
Yes.
♪ Deep in the
Hundred Acre Wood ♪
♪ Where Christopher
Robin plays ♪
♪ You'll find the
enchanted neighborhood ♪
♪ Of Christopher's
childhood days ♪
♪ A donkey named Eeyore
Start the pulley.
♪ Is his friend
Ow!
Just keep singing.
It's almost over.
♪ With Kanga
and little Roo
♪ There's Rabbit, and
Piglet, and there's Owl ♪
♪ But most of all
Stop pulley.
♪ Winnie the Pooh
Okay, Emelia, I'm just
gonna turn you around, okay?
Oh, wait.
I love you so much, Emelia.
I love you too, Mommy.
Okay.
♪ Winnie the Pooh
♪ Chubby little cubby,
all stuffed with fluff ♪
♪ Winnie the Pooh,
he's Winnie the Pooh ♪
♪ Willy, nilly,
silly old bear ♪
♪ Winnie the Pooh
♪ He's Winnie the Pooh
♪ Willy, nilly,
silly old bear ♪
An anxious calm
hangs over the crowd
as word spreads that
one of the victims
is about to be brought
to the surface.
Which one? Unknown.
Their condition? Unknown.
A mother and daughter
on the razor's edge
between tragedy and
a second chance.
This is Matt Rodriguez,
reporting for "NBC
News Chicago."
Bring them up.
Emelia just made
it to the surface.
Oh, thank you so much.
Sadie, we need to talk.
I know.
I feel it too.
And this was one
hell of a meet cute,
but I'm just not sure I'm ready
for a relationship right now.
And you should know
I also have a kid.
I, uh, totally hear you.
But it's the other thing.
You need to cut off my leg.
I'm afraid there's
no other option.
Will it hurt?
No. I'll sedate
you with ketamine.
You won't feel a thing.
When you wake up, you'll
be back with Emelia.
That little girl
is my whole world.
I was lost in my
life for a long time.
I never quite knew
what I was living for.
I felt so alone.
I know the feeling.
But then I met my little girl.
And I just knew that no
matter what happened,
I would always find a way
forward because I had to.
She is very lucky to have you.
But, I mean, you're okay too.
Well, I'm not sure
you'll feel that way
when I tell you about your car.
What about my car?
I may have crashed into it.
That might be how I found you.
A small price to pay.
Are you ready?
Yeah.
Okay.
Now, you'll just feel
a little pinch, okay?
That's not feeling bad.
Hey, Mouch.
What's Emelia's status?
On her way to Med as we speak.
Other than the broken
arm, she's one lucky kid.
You good?
Yeah.
Just about to start
cutting through.
I wish I had a scalpel,
but I'll make do.
We promise to update you
on further developments
just as soon as
we have them here.
- You heard about this?
- Yeah.
Kid's on her way here now.
Ainsley... she's
great, by the way.
Yeah, she is great.
And I owe her a lot.
How so?
When you are a teen
superstar on a hit TV show,
there tends to be
a lot of people
who want things from you...
people who don't always have
your best interests in mind.
Sometimes you're
shocked to find that
it's, you know, the
ones closest to you.
But I was afraid at
the time to say no.
I didn't wanna interrupt
the gravy train for anyone.
But Ainsley... I mean,
she always had my back.
Wasn't that your
parents' job, though?
Oh, my parents liked gravy too.
It's the kid from the well.
All right, let's do it.
Just give me the word, Ripley.
This may be a bumpy ride.
You want me to sing you
the "Winnie the Pooh" song?
I mean, I'm not saying no.
You don't wanna hear
me sing. Trust me.
Look, Mitch, I, um...
I will see you up top, Sadie.
Yeah.
Bring her up, Annabelle.
Roger that.
Here we go.
All right, Ripley, get
your ass out of there.
On my way.
Hold!
What happened?
I'm stuck.
Okay.
Okay, I got you.
She's all clear!
Roger that.
Here we go.
Ripley!
Get out of there now!
Mitch!
What's going on?
Listen, I've got
some alarming news.
You've heard about the
mother and daughter trapped
in the abandoned water well.
I just got a call from
Lieutenant McHolland.
- Mouch?
- Yes.
And he informed me
that it was Dr. Ripley
who discovered the
mother and daughter
and called CFD.
But the tunnel that
Dr. Ripley was in...
collapsed.
Sharon, what... what...
is he alive?
Radio contact was lost.
So Dr. Ripley's condition
is currently unknown.
But CFD is attempting
to reestablish contact
while they work to dig him out.
- I'm going out there.
- Yeah, I'll join you.
Listen.
I can't spare either of you.
He needs to see a friendly face
when they dig him out of there.
Where's Hannah?
She needs to know.
Are you there, Ripley?
Please respond.
Ripley, if you can
hear me, just hang on.
We need some time to
stabilize this tunnel.
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm here.
Oh, man, it is good
to hear your voice.
Did Sadie get out?
Yeah, she's safe and sound
and on her way to Med.
Good.
That's good.
Yeah, you did good, brother.
What's your situation in there?
Uh...
Well, I'm in an air pocket.
Both ends of the
tunnel are caved in.
And yeah, I'm thinking I might
be a little claustrophobic.
Are you injured?
Just some mild pain
in my right ankle.
Can you move the ankle
around, see if it's broken?
Well, I'm buried up
to my chest, so...
I can't feel my legs,
but I don't think it is.
I'm gonna try and
dig myself out.
No.
Ripley, do not.
Leave that to us.
Do not overexert yourself.
You have limited air.
You need to breathe slowly
and save your strength.
We need some time
to dig you out.
More time than I have?
Not if you keep
your wits about you.
Oh, come on.
You don't even like me.
But I dislike you much less now.
Thanks for that.
Conserve your air, brother.
Yeah.
Will do, Mouch.
- Hey.
- How'd it go in there?
Perfectly.
What?
What is it?
It's Ripley.
Hey, how's your breathing?
Oh, not... not great.
All right.
You just need to hang on a
little longer, all right?
It doesn't really matter.
Mitchell, can you hear me?
Dr. Charles, is that you?
First of all, all this
attention-seeking behavior
got a little out of hand, okay?
But look, we really do need you
to slow your breathing down.
You're just consuming too
much oxygen too quickly.
Well, I appreciate that, but...
whatever happens,
I'm okay with it.
Uh, agree to disagree.
This is probably what I deserve.
Huh.
How so?
I let people down.
I always have.
You just... you just
saved two people's lives.
That's not enough.
Okay.
New plan.
I talk, you listen. Deal?
Sure.
Why not?
I know that, um, way back when,
when we, you know, met at
that juvenile facility,
you thought that
I gave up on you.
And that kills me, right?
I mean, I'd do almost anything
to turn back the
clock on that one.
But the thing about
you, Mitch... and I...
I think about this
all the time...
you never gave up on yourself.
I mean, with the hand
that you got dealt?
It's like... you survived juvie.
You make it to medical
school all by yourself,
no help from anyone.
And then you survive
that insane gauntlet?
I mean, it's nuts.
Look, I know that you're...
you're going through
a rough patch right now.
I mean, Sully?
I know how much he meant to you.
But me?
When I'm in a bad
spot, I don't know,
I start to see the world in
a different way, you know?
I start to make assumptions,
maybe about the way
the world sees me.
It's weird.
I become unkind to myself.
But you know what
started to happen
ever since you showed up
and I'm having a bad day?
I just...
I just look across the room,
and I see you doing your thing.
And all that, it
just, um, evaporates.
So just real selfishly here,
pal, I gotta ask you
to bear down, okay?
Because, um, I need that.
I need you because that...
that, it makes my life better.
And, um, trust me.
I am not the only one.
Okay?
Well, I...
You what? Sorry, buddy.
I didn't catch that.
Mitch?
Mitch, can you speak a
little louder, buddy?
I can't... God damn it.
Mitch, talk to me.
Mitch!
These men and women have
been working tirelessly
in a race against time,
as we just received word
the rescue tunnel has collapsed.
- Jonathan?
- Ainsley. Hey.
I have to cancel dinner tonight.
Oh, yeah, no, please,
don't even worry about it.
Maggie told me
about your friend.
I'm really sorry.
Is there anything I can do?
No.
No, I'm good.
I know you.
Hmm?
You're not good.
I just wish that there was
something that I could do.
I know. I know.
There's nothing you
can do but wait.
I'm so sorry.
No, it's fine.
Don't... don't apologize.
I just really miss you.
Yeah, no, me too.
I, um... I really do think
I should get back to work.
How you holding up?
I don't feel great.
Cold, but happy to
be above ground.
I don't blame you.
Let's give 100 of fentanyl
and two units emergency
release blood.
Where's my daughter?
Where's Emelia?
Sadie, Emelia is here.
She's doing great.
Can I see her, please?
I'll feel better if
I can see my baby.
Mommy!
Oh.
Emelia wanted to show
you that she was okay.
Oh, am I glad to see you, baby.
She's a resilient little girl.
Always has been.
I wonder where she got that.
What about Dr. Ripley?
Did he make it?
He's alive.
They're still working
on getting him out.
We'll see.
He saved us.
I didn't get to say thank you.
Mitch, are you there, buddy?
I just... I need
to hear from you.
Anything. A grunt.
Anything?
Five minutes was his
last communication.
Damn it.
Mouch says they're close,
but there's just
too much rubble.
Buddy, listen.
We need help finding you, okay?
We are very close,
but you need to make some noise.
Hit some rocks together.
Yell.
Anything.
Well, well, well, look at you.
Aren't you a sorry sight?
Sully.
I'm serious.
You look pathetic.
It's kind of bumming me out.
Screw you.
Oh, screw me?
The dead guy?
That's low.
Just let me go, man.
Guess what?
You don't get to die.
Lynne and Nate need you.
You owe me that.
And you know why?
Because I deserted you
when I got out of juvie.
Wrong.
You're still torturing
yourself about that?
Well, stop wasting your time.
You had to save yourself.
I was circling the drain and
pulling you right down with me.
I'm not gonna lie, I was pissed.
Didn't even wanna hear
your name for a few years.
But you know what
happened when I heard
that you were in med school?
I couldn't stop smiling.
I owe you because I let you die.
Wrong again.
You lifted me up.
You were there
for me at the end.
Full stop.
And I love you for it.
No, you owe me because
despite all that...
we're brothers.
And that doesn't change
because I'm gone.
I miss you.
Why wouldn't you?
But I get it.
You wanna be angry.
That's your thing...
stewing and brewing.
So why don't you
channel all that anger
into something positive for once
instead of just giving
up like a little bitch?
Fight!
No.
I'm telling you to fight.
We hear you, Ripley!
Keep it up!
Come on!
You can do better than that!
Fight!
No!
I hear him.
He's right here.
Okay.
Get in there.
I got you, Ripley.
Good for you, Rip.
He lost consciousness?
Yeah, just as I was
pulling him out.
- Mitch!
- I can't hear him breathing.
He's in hypoxic shock arrest.
Bag him and start compressions.
Mitch, buddy, you
gotta stay with me.
We're almost there,
pal. We're almost there.
Excuse me. Excuse
me, Dr. Charles.
Come on.
No. No!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Let them work. Let them work.
Mitch? Hey.
Come on.
Hey.
Can you hear me?
I love you too.