Early 60s,
found prone on the sidewalk,
appears to have chest pain,
maybe broken ribs,
- possible heart attack.
- Did you fall?
She's very disoriented.
Hasn't said a thing.
Coley?
No, I'm Dr. Shaun Murphy.
Will you help me, Coley?
I have to, it's my job.
She has stridor. Checking her pulse.
- Radial pulse is normal.
- But much weaker in her leg.
She has a descending
thoracic aneurysm.
Page Dr. Melendez to the OR.
I just woke up
on the front campus lawn,
covered in blood,
with a skateboard next to me.
But I can't skateboard.
- Obviously.
- Were you drinking, Aiden?
- Or smoking something?
- No, to both.
There are college students
who abstain.
You were incredibly lucky.
Half an inch in any direction
and you would've bled out.
Aortic wall's tearing.
Can't expect pristine in a 60-year-old
homeless woman. Drop to a 5-0 suture.
Not great, but better.
Let's see if it holds.
Remove proximal clamp.
- No leakage.
- Let's finish the repair.
Carly broke up with me.
I'm sorry, Shaun.
I thought you two were doing great.
We were. Then I guess we weren't.
Cross-clamping.
- You must really be hurting.
- No, I'm fine.
We've all been through it.
And it helps
when you own that you're in pain.
There's nothing for me to own.
She's having epistaxis.
Carotid aneurysm rupture. Two French
Foley catheters. Give protamine stat.
Sixty-eight over 44. Holding
pressure on both carotids at the neck.
Inflate.
Forty-one over 28.
She's still bleeding internally.
Give four units of PRBCs
and start TXA.
Loading 700 milligrams TXA.
No distal perfusion.
We have to clamp her carotids.
Ten blades.
Suction, clamps, let's go.
- I can't see a thing.
- Her blood volume's on the floor.
Time of death, 10:22 a.m.
Jane shouldn't have died.
Not then, not like that.
Her carotid blew out,
what am I missing?
Patients die, Dr. Murphy.
Something else we have to own.
Your next patient's waiting in the ER.
- How are you feeling, Aiden?
- Awesome,
- considering whatever you did to me.
- Surgery went well.
Hey, I'm alive, doped up, talking
to two very attractive doctors.
I guess this is what happens
when you mix weed
with my skateboarding.
You said you didn't do drugs
or skateboard.
- When did I say that?
- When we met you in the ER.
I've never seen you guys
before in my life.
Trust me, I'd remember.
I'd like to order an autopsy on Jane.
We went over this.
There was nothing suspicious
about her death.
Oh. I was asking the chief of surgery.
I know the case, and I agree
with Dr. Melendez.
I'm not authorizing an autopsy.
Jane's vascular walls...
It's hard to lose a patient,
almost as hard as losing a girlfriend.
I'm okay and I don't know
why no one believes me.
- Isn't it okay to be okay?
- Not when something bad happens.
We should feel hurt.
If you won't approve the autopsy,
I'll get it from Jane's family.
Good luck with that.
According to the files,
Jane's last name was Doe.
You're saying I'm having
some kind of blackouts?
Which could be caused
by head trauma, or drug use.
I'm definitely aware of telling you
I don't take drugs.
I live like a monk.
Sleep, class, study, repeat, that's it.
You've also told us
the exact opposite.
I need to find Jane's family
to get their permission
to perform an autopsy.
Dr. Lim wished me luck,
but Jane has no ID, no purse, no phone.
We know absolutely nothing about her.
Mm. This should be interesting to you.
You used to be a detective.
And now I'm a doctor and so are you,
and we both have a new case.
A boring case.
He has gallstones.
So you and Melendez
sneaking around again?
I hear he is back
to being a good mentor.
Apparently, my complaint
changed nothing.
You?
- Park said he did it.
- Park was lying
because he wanted
to get you to focus on work.
Good motive, bad judge of character.
And you don't like Melendez
has gone back to good mentor.
I don't like that he likes you.
I don't like that, because he likes you,
Shaun, Park and I
are second-class residents.
For someone as cynical as you are,
you're shockingly naive.
I'll tell you what you did.
You threw a bomb because
you felt slighted.
You made Melendez doubt himself,
doubt his judgment,
you made him resent you,
Park, Shaun and me.
I like to think it's that easy
to change status quo,
but I am pretty naive.
I am with Dr. B on this.
Sorry. Office politics.
Thought you were asleep.
Watching brain waves
can't be thrilling.
Not when they're as normal as yours.
Except these delta waves.
They mean you're still asleep.
Not planning on doing
any cutting, I hope.
Jane had a knee replacement
using an LCS system,
which means
it's at least 30 years old.
She also had an abnormal number
of cavities, crowns and implants.
These are clues, right?
I don't think this is about
you losing a patient.
I think you're distracting yourself.
You don't wanna let Jane go
because you don't wanna let Carly go.
Hmm.
What?
You're a doctor now,
you won't find it interesting.
Hmm.
A hummingbird.
Am I right?
The police keep a database
of all distinguishing marks.
Jane Doe, homeless, there's no way
she was never in the system.
How's Mr. Ginley?
A gallbladder case
you should be working on.
We confirmed the presence of gallstones
and have scheduled a cholecystectomy.
It's a very simple case
and requires no work.
With that attitude, you could
send another patient to the morgue.
Focus on the living.
He's right. We need to bail on this.
Hey, Shaun...
You and Carly shared a lot of firsts.
That must make it harder to move on.
- I had a lot of firsts with Lea too.
- Yeah, you did, and you moved on.
Didn't you?
How do you move on?
Hmm.
Hey, Kenny. I need a name.
We need to keep this on the DL.
We're going undercover?
Causes of sleepwalking
run the gamut from the serious,
like MS, encephalitis
and brain tumors,
to the mundane,
like alcohol and drug use,
poor sleep hygiene and stress.
Problem is, to rule some of those out,
we need a full patient history,
but Asleep Aiden and Awake Aiden
each have their own story.
Interview them both.
Take a medical history from a patient
when they're asleep?
I've never heard
of a lying sleepwalker.
I gotta go.
Hey.
Stress?
I have to maintain a 4.2 GPA.
Well, what do you think?
You have to care about something
to be stressed, don't you?
And since I'm getting
a 4.2 without trying.
Maybe a glass of wine.
I just microdose, you know,
whenever I'm not macrodosing.
Do you nap, exercise before bedtime?
I never nap, work out five days
a week, never too close to bedtime,
which is midnight,
12:30 at the latest.
I'm surrounded by 5000 women.
Yes, right before bedtime.
That explains the headaches
I've been waking up with.
I never thought they were hangovers.
He's a Cro-Magnon.
He's not me.
He can't be.
"Maribel Ventane."
"Sharing the spirit.
Marco, Maribel
and their 5-year-old son, Jules,
open their doors to host
the fourth annual fundraiser,
'Friends in Need.'"
"Maribel Ventane, 33,
was one jump away
from a first-place ribbon,"
blah, blah, blah.
"Suffered
severe orthopedic injuries."
"After two years in family court,
Maribel Ventane, 36,
and ex-husband, Marco Ventane, 43..."
blah, blah, blah,
"Mr. Ventane was given full custody
of their 11-year-old son, Jules."
"Marco Ventane, 63,
passed away in his home.
He is survived by his son,
Jules Ventane, 32."
I've found him.
- Are you Jules Ventane?
- Yes.
I'm Dr. Shaun Murphy
and I recently treated
your mother, Maribel.
She died. I would like your permission
to do an autopsy.
We're very sorry for your loss.
She came in with
a ruptured aortic aneurysm
and there wasn't much we could do.
But we would like to be absolutely
certain about her cause of death.
I don't care how she died.
Remember we talked about moving on?
This is the time to do that.
Where do we stand with the Aidens?
Between the two alters, they engage
in just about every single behavior.
So we go back to Dr. Lim's list.
Maybe we should be looking
at paraneoplastic syndromes.
You may wanna consider
psychiatric issues.
Could be having psychotic
or dissociative episodes.
I have personal experience
with people with psychiatric issues.
If he had psychosis,
I'd have picked up on it.
- How about thyrotoxicosis?
- No irritability, agitation.
Paraneoplastic syndromes
trigger a loss of coordination,
- which could have caused...
- Actually, personal experiences
make us less effective
in spotting symptoms.
I always make an effort
to be as objective as possible.
You're not this time.
The vast majority of cases
of paraneoplastic
syndromes present with antibodies.
His labs show a normal serum panel.
Vast majority of all diseases don't present
with competing entities day and night.
- I'm just giving an idea.
- No, you're undermining mine.
Fine. Your idea's brilliant.
Go waste your time on it.
Thank you both.
Get an MRI to rule out tumors
and MS, an LP for encephalitis,
and a CSF panel to check
for paraneoplastic syndromes.
And a psych consult.
No.
Hi.
- I'm Dr. Lim, and you are?
- Trinity.
Where are your parents?
- My mother's in the maternity ward.
- She's having a baby?
- Already did, a girl.
- Wonderful.
So why the wandering?
My mom sent me to the cafeteria
to get a snack, but I got lost.
Three times?
Hey, Lucy. We're looking for, uh...
Trinity!
Please call Security.
- Stop the car.
- No.
- Yeah, I need to...
- Shaun! Shaun!
- I need your permission.
- No, Shaun!
- Let it go!
- It can't be over!
- You have to let Carly go!
- No!
- Shaun, you have to let Carly go!
- You have to let Carly go!
- It's not about Carly!
- Well, it's not about this either.
- Shaun, he's calling the police!
- No! Open the door!
- You'll get arrested!
Shaun, he's calling the police!
Come here! Shaun.
Oh, my God. Shaun, are you okay?
It was bad. I missed my surgery.
Don't worry about that.
Park's there. Everything there is fine.
- Will I have to go back to jail?
- No. No.
It's a good thing you were
with an ex-cop.
The guy's not gonna press charges,
but you're not allowed to be
near him, ever again.
Here. Let's get out of here, huh?
Park says that you're upset
about Carly.
Everyone keeps telling me that,
but I am not upset about Carly
and they need to stop.
Okay, so this isn't about Carly.
I wish Carly didn't break up with me,
but she did,
and now, I have to do what she said.
What do you mean, do what she said?
- She doesn't get to dictate to you...
- She told me to tell Lea I love her.
Oh.
And you're afraid of what might happen
if you told Lea the truth?
If I tell her I love her...
and she tells me she doesn't...
then I can't be her boyfriend.
And even worse, I...
I don't think
I can be her friend either.
And what if Lea were to say...
"You know what, Shaun, I love you too"?
Hmm.
Pretty disturbing having this
weird personality creeping out of me.
Does he represent something
I'm suppressing
and need to express, or...
something I need to bury forever?
If it's any consolation,
I kind of like him.
I think he's just
trying to enjoy himself.
Except he's sabotaging
all the hard work of his waking self.
It's not sabotage,
it's just a part of who he is.
Some parts of who we are suck.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have ratted on you
and Melendez. I screwed things up.
But this guy needs a drink
every now and again.
- You see that?
- Yeah.
You have an arachnoid cyst
compressing your hypothalamus, Aiden.
We basically just need to drain it.
Will it kill me if you don't?
- He knows the risks.
- He knows it won't kill him,
which is enough for Jekyll
to decide to keep Hyde alive.
What if we ask Hyde?
I'm pretty sure consent needs to be
informed, voluntary and conscious.
It also doesn't matter,
Asleep Aiden's a hedonist.
He's not gonna make a decision
against his interest
- just to help his alter.
- Maybe he cares more than you think.
Okay.
Dr. Lim?
Thank you. Trinity, have a seat.
There's no one in our maternity ward
with a daughter named Trinity.
So I'm gonna need some information,
and it will be much more efficient
if it's the truth.
- First and last name.
- Trinity...
Mm-hm. Last name?
Okay. Will you at least tell me
what you're doing in this hospital?
I just wanted to meet you again.
Someone left a baby girl
at the ER about eight years ago...
on Trinity Sunday.
You were so tiny.
So sick and so helpless.
It killed me not to take you home.
But look at you now, so strong
and healthy, and fast.
We need to call your mother
and let her know where you are,
that you're okay.
Do you know her number?
Yes, but...
But?
Can you adopt me?
Shaunie.
You poor thing.
I'm so sorry about you and Carly.
I want to tell you how I feel.
I know you're hurting.
Carly made a huge mistake.
You're a wonderful man, Shaun.
Maybe the most wonderful man
I've ever met.
- Lea?
- Yeah, Shaun?
I found that in my mother's drawer.
Does she know you're here?
She's been in Campbell Memorial
for the last two days.
She thinks I've been in school,
and at a friend's.
As long as I'm home by 6,
no one knows the difference.
Mm. Well, it's past that.
I'm sure she's worried.
She has a new daughter.
It's hard to share your mom, isn't it?
If she loves your sister
with all her heart,
that doesn't feel like
it'll leave much room for you.
Do you love your mom
with all your heart?
How about your dad,
you love him with all your heart too?
But that doesn't seem possible, does it?
Hearts are amazing things.
I've held one in my hands many times.
You'd never know it
by looking at them, but...
somehow they have
all the room we need.
Doctor B. Please tell me you're single.
You have a cyst in your brain.
If you leave it as is,
it could expose you to considerable
neurological complications,
potential visual loss,
endocrine abnormalities, depression.
But if we drain and treat the cyst,
there should be no complications.
Including sleepwalking.
The professor
already rejected treatment.
So you're asking the frat boy
to fall on his sword for him?
I think the frat boy
is more than just a frat boy.
We're all complicated,
we're all sometimes superficial,
selfish jerks.
But we're also capable of sacrifice.
I think you live in him
the same way he lives in you.
And that won't change,
no matter what decision you make.
Shaun.
Maribel died.
I think she had
polycystic kidney disease,
which is associated
with dilation of the arteries,
which results
in weakened vascular walls,
which in turn contributes
to the formation of aneurysms.
I need to do an autopsy.
- Dr. Melendez...
- Didn't approve.
Dr. Lim didn't approve.
The family said no.
- So, what can I...
- You're the head of Pathology.
Shaun, I'm not going to...
I can't do what you told me
I should do...
until I solve this distraction.
No sign of polycystic kidney disease.
I know this breakup has been
hard on you.
It's been hard on me too.
But I know what I saw
between you and Lea.
I did see something, didn't I?
I love you, Carly.
But you were right, I love Lea more.
Okay.
So... you know
you have to tell her, right?
I'm scared.
I know.
But look at how far you've come with me.
How scared you were.
How brave you were.
I have to go.
Thank you, Carly.
If you're watching this,
it means I'm dead. Heh.
And you're waking up from a surgery
you think you didn't consent to,
but I hereby proffer
my full and informed consent
to said surgical procedure,
signed, "Aiden Michael Porter."
The second.
Uh, just one... One more thing.
My advice...
is to try to chillax a little.
Neither of us is perfect, but...
we're okay.
We are gonna be...
okay.
And... that girl who sits in front of you
in Advanced Calculus,
her name is Staci, with an I,
and she likes you
way more than she likes me.
Peace out, Professor.
- You're kidding me, right?
- I know why your mother died.
And I said I didn't care.
When I examined her liver,
I found three aneurysms
in her hepatic artery,
which is very unusual
and made me realize she has
Vascular Ehlers-Danlos syndrome.
It's a very rare disease that often
goes undiagnosed and can be fatal...
Are you gonna make me call
the police again?
It's hereditary. No, I don't want
to get arrested again,
but do you have
an excess of cavities?
You might have inherited
Vascular Ehlers-Danlos syndrome
from your mother,
and your life could be in danger.
But its symptoms can be treated.
Okay, goodbye.
So that's all I got from my mother...
a potentially deadly disease?
Did your mother ever call you Coley?
Yeah.
Short for colibri.
The French word for hummingbird.
She said I would
flit around the house...
always going from
one thing to another.
She had a hummingbird
tattooed on her body.
And "Coley" was the last word she said.
She loved you.
Maybe...
she was just afraid to tell you.
Morgan buy the fight?
Isn't it weird how hard we have
to work to hide a platonic friendship?
Very, but it's worth it.
Hi, Mom.
Shaun?
What's up, Shaunie?
Shaun...
please, talk to me.
I love you, Lea.
I want to be your boyfriend.
I love you too.
But...
you know me.
I am selfish and I am so, so needy.
I'm... I mean, listen to me right now,
I can't even put
a complete sentence together.
I'm a... I'm a total mess.
How...
How am I supposed to, you know...
just lay all of that on you?
Why do you think
I can't handle your selfishness,
neediness and messiness?
I think I can.
It's just...
I'm a challenge for anyone, and you're...
you.
And I just know
it would be too hard for you.
You need things a certain way,
you work in a certain way, and...
Because I have autism?
You...
don't want to be my girlfriend
because I have autism?
Oh...