Meredith: A med
school professor
once told me the hardest
decision in surgery
is knowing when to
abandon a repair
and just remove the whole organ.
Female news anchor:
Firefighters are scrambling
to contain this wildfire,
the state's largest
in recent history.
Mandatory evacuation
orders have been issued
for residents in Fall City
and the surrounding areas.
Eastbound lanes are
closed on I-90...
Meredith: If a
spleen is shattered,
we'll take it out to protect
the rest of the body.
Same with the section
of colon or small bowel.
The human body can survive
a fair amount of loss.
People live without an appendix,
a kidney, tonsils, and more.
Hey. Slow down.
Where's the fire?
Fall City, spreading fast.
What? I meant that as
a figure of speech.
Well, we got paged.
All hands on deck.
♪ I could spare my covers
when it's cold for you ♪
Last night was fun.
It was. Yeah.
By the way, um, my
parents are in town.
I'd love for you to meet them.
Kidding, and worth it.
♪ I could spare a tire ♪
The body finds ways
to compensate for
what it's missing.
But it will eventually
reach a breaking point.
Okay. All the
windows are closed.
Still smells like a campfire.
It's the hospital.
They're asking for all
available staff to come in.
Guess they forgot to remove
me from the text alerts.
Do you still have your work
laptop, your phone, your badge?
Yeah, you want to
bring it back for me?
When you talked to
Catherine, did she tell you
you were no longer chief
or no longer a surgeon?
I don't know. I
kinda blacked out.
Okay, Seattle Pres
is evacuating.
No, no. Get dressed.
We need all the help we can get.
Your body can only
give up so much
before it no longer
works at all.
No, it's closed.
Don't they know we're
working through a wildfire?
I think that's the point.
There's an entire
cafeteria inside.
Well, Jason gives me
day-old pastries for free.
Oh, nice suit. Coming from
your career's funeral?
I had a video interview
with Chicago's program director.
How did it go?
Uh, they offered me the spot.
Oh. Congratulations,
Skywalker.
Hey, you owe me 20 bucks.
I bet that you'd be gone
by the end of the year.
I'll give you 20
bucks to be gone now.
Did you accept it?
I said I'd think about it.
Dorian. What are
you doing here?
They needed my room,
too many patients from the fire.
Oh, I'm so sorry about that.
No worries.
A bed opened at the
skilled nursing facility.
Oh. I'm being discharged.
That's great.
I'm hoping I won't
be here much longer.
Well, you've obviously
never been discharged
from a hospital before,
especially during a wildfire.
Bailey: And you've obviously
never worked at one in a wildfire.
I paged you 26 minutes ago.
If you're not dressed
in the next 4...
- Bye, Dorian.
- Oh!
See you!
I'll make sure and say goodbye.
Okay.
Let's push these
two laminectomies
and reschedule Ms.
Feuer's knee replacement.
So... move the whole ortho
schedule to next week.
Hey. Hey, I, uh,
I need some help.
Didn't you just finish
an overnight shift?
Well, tell that
to the wildfires.
Can I steal him?
Oh, I'm on ortho. Sure.
There are a hundred
other residents,
and you know how I
feel about birth.
And I know how you
feel about peds.
There are NICU transfers
coming in from Seattle Pres,
and Beltran needs extra help.
Bye. Thank you, thank you!
Woman over PA: Charge
Nurse, call the...
I just hope we
don't run into her.
Teddy. Teddy: Hey.
I'm so sorry. Oh, it was
my decision to fund you.
I'm just... I'm sorry that
your research is in jeopardy.
Well, we don't know it is.
Why wouldn't Catherine
just call you directly?
Oh, she knows once
I heard about Teddy,
I would jump right on a plane.
It's a pretty good power move.
Also a good power move.
I would think that Catherine
would have security
tackling us by now.
If I have access
to this building,
then that means there's
room to negotiate.
With what leverage?
Our research.
No matter what she thinks of us,
she will not stand in the way
of scientific progress.
Okay. So what are
you suggesting?
We present yesterday's findings.
The work speaks for itself.
She cannot deny that
with a power move.
When you have all the power,
I think it's just called a move.
Well, we have moves, too.
Taryn: Every resident came
in except Bradley and Kaneko.
They were evacuating
their apartments,
but they'll be
back when they can.
Oh, they're excused.
Uh...
Well, spit it out, Griffith.
I think Adams is gonna leave.
Oh, uh. Dr. Fox hasn't
decided that yet.
He got offered a
second-year spot in Chicago.
Woman over PA: Any
available orderlies...
Good for him. You
don't want him to stay?
It's not up to me or you.
Owen: Alright.
Listen up, everyone.
As of this morning,
Grey-Sloan is the only
level 1 trauma center
operating in the Seattle region.
Now, these fires are not
easy to extinguish...
and this wind is not letting up.
This could go on for
some time, maybe days.
If any of you need
help, ask for it.
Okay? Let's get to work.
Oh, Link, we have a helicopter
coming in with an
injured firefighter
with an open fracture.
A firefighter?
Oh, it's, uh, it's Theo
Ruiz, and Ben's with him.
Uh, Theo's family.
I'm coming, too.
Winston: I'm so
sorry, Garrett.
The operating rooms
are being held
for wildfire victims
and trauma patients.
But we're working on
getting your Triple-A repair
rescheduled as soon as possible.
Yeah. I get it.
I was at Woodstock '99,
so I know what
disaster looks like.
How high do you
think the AQI is?
Richard: Well, we can get you a
KN95 mask for your drive home.
Oh, I'm not worried about me.
It's that vinyl is
sensitive to, uh, changes
in temperature and
moisture and air quality.
Garrett manages Both Sides Now.
I love listening
to records there...
and occasionally buying one.
Cool.
Well, I'll stop by on my way
home and check on things.
I just hope traffic's
not too bad.
Apologies, I'm being paged.
But I will call you later
once we have you
back on the schedule.
Alright, cool. Alright.
Uh, your... your shop...
You got any Coltrane?
John or Alice? I got both.
Garrett, you feeling pain?
Some cramping in my
stomach and back,
but it's not that bad.
You have an abdominal
aortic aneurysm.
Change back into your gown.
Let's get some scans
just to be safe.
Hm. Alright.
Alright, Ben, what do we got?
Theo Ruiz, 37-year-old male,
crushed by a large tree branch.
Abdominal crush injury,
unstable pelvis,
femoral fracture with
tourniquet placed in the field.
BP dropped and we
intubated him en route.
Systolics now holding around
110 after 3 liters of NS.
Let's get him inside.
How is it out there?
We'll be lucky if this is the
worst that we bring in today.
Where's Beltran?
Can I give you some advice?
How is that answering
my question?
Beltran is a kick-ass surgeon.
She doesn't have time to
play 20 questions with you.
You need to chill
out around her.
You think I ask
too many questions?
I am showing interest.
You are sucking up to
get the peds fellowship.
Every candidate
has an advantage.
I think mine are my
pre-existing relationships
here at Grey-Sloan.
Schmitt, we've got seven
transfer patients on the way up.
Can you help with intake?
Yeah. Oh, one had a
biliary atresia repair.
I was just reading about
the Kasai procedure.
Have you ever done one of
those? Yes, I've done three.
Amazing. What
were the outcomes?
Did anyone get a transplant?
Schmitt, it's the NICU.
You can keep your voice down.
Um, if you were to...
Okay, hand your
tag to that nurse,
and they'll set you up.
Ann: Over here. E-Excuse me.
My son and his husband,
they were camping,
and I-I can't reach
either of them.
Can... Can you...
Can you tell me
if they're patients here?
Yeah. They'll help
you at the desk.
No, they don't know anything.
Their names aren't
in the system,
and... and they're too busy
to check on all the John Does.
Look, I know they're grown men
and cell reception
isn't great out there,
but I-I'm a mom, and I worry.
What are their names?
Thank you. Nathan
Bates and Andrew Smith.
Uh, also, all those people
are looking for people, too.
Man: Okay, ma'am.
Receptionist: I'm
doing the best I can.
Link: I can feel a
left femoral pulse.
Bailey: Okay, let's get
some more O-neg on standby.
Theo's lost a lot of blood.
We had to use a chainsaw to
get that tree off of him.
What? He didn't see
it coming? He did.
He pushed Montgomery
out of the way.
My badge was deactivated.
I was definitely fired.
I'm sorry. Wait, what?!
It's a long story.
Oh, damn it. That
does not look good.
Taryn: He's got
vascular compromise.
You've got to save his leg.
His job's his life.
Okay, there's free
fluid in his abdomen.
He... He needs an ex-lap.
Okay.
As... As long as his
BP continues to hold,
we can scan him.
Bailey, you said it yourself,
Theo is family.
You both need to step outside.
We will update you, okay?
Hey. The hospital
emergency coordinator
wants to talk to
you. What? Now?
I-It's about our
pre-evacuation plan.
I'll be a few minutes. Okay.
Alright, look, I'll take Ruiz.
He needs surgery and
you're short surgeons.
Catherine can't blame me
for saving a firefighter.
Owen: Thank you. Alright,
bring me up to speed.
Link: 37-year-old male,
crushed by a large tree branch,
blood pressure holding.
♪ What goes up
must come down ♪
♪ Spinning Wheel
got to go 'round ♪
Mika: Stay still,
please, Garrett.
You know, Maxine
loves that song.
Well, how's she doing?
She worried about the fires?
Uh, more like annoyed
that they might mean
her hot yoga retreat
is postponed.
Ah, I'm just in time.
Richard: Okay.
What do you see?
His aneurysm ruptured.
Fortunately, it's
still contained.
Let's book an OR and prep
him for an open repair.
You and Dr. Ndugu don't want
to go in endovascularly?
Well, Dr. Ndugu had to
run to an emergent CABG.
I'm flying solo.
As for Garrett, he's young,
surgically speaking.
An open surgery
has better outcomes
for someone with his history.
But we studied the
endovascular procedure.
Well, if you two aren't
confident retracting,
I'm sure someone
else can handle it.
Well, I'm confident.
I retract in my sleep.
Okay, well, then, page
me when he's ready.
And study up.
The one who's most prepared
will get to do
more than retract.
Woman over PA:
Dr. Spence to Pediatrics.
Dr. Kendal Spence
to Pediatrics.
How about you see patients
instead of updating
your socials?
How about you make
yourself useful
and post the link
I sent everyone?
Fall City Wildfire
People Locator.
Yeah, it's a shared database
put together on my phone.
There's over 100 people.
Yeah, might be more
if you post the link.
I'll post.
You have bed 3.
Woman over PA:
Dr. Wagner to Radiology.
Molly Tran?
I'm Dr. Adams.
How are you doing?
Um, I have a small sprain
and what's probably
just smoke inhalation.
You have asthma and you
were wheezing in the car.
We should make sure
you aren't having
a major bronchospasm.
Okay. Mind if I listen?
Yeah.
Woman over PA: Chief Ortho
Resident, call in patient services.
Take a deep breath.
Are you doctors?
I'm in pharmacy school.
He reads too much WebMD.
How long have you had asthma?
Um, hang on...
Diagnosed at 17.
I was in a car accident
a few years ago.
Spent a month in a coma,
and when I woke up,
I couldn't remember my parents,
my cat, or medicine.
Well, now I'm back
in pharmacy school
and learning it all again.
As if it wasn't hard
enough the first time.
Yeah, thank God I
kept my flashcards.
Alright, I'm going
to run some labs,
uh, order a chest X-ray,
and nebulizer treatment.
I'll be right back.
And while we don't yet
understand the causality,
there is a clear correlation.
So you found a
correlation between things
I asked you not to study.
Well, we haven't
actually spoken about it.
Things you said to my face
you would stop researching.
We are this close to
being able to prove
that Alzheimer's
could be preventable.
You have to admit
that's a game-changer.
I don't have to admit anything.
You went behind my
back using my money,
two of my best and formerly
most trusted surgeons.
Give me one good reason
I shouldn't just end
your career right now.
I'll give you 6.7
million reasons.
That's the amount of Americans
living with Alzheimer's today.
And there's another
half a million
that will be diagnosed
by year's end.
And for every man that suffers,
two women suffer.
Think about what this could
mean for their children,
for their grandchildren
if we could diagnose them
before symptoms start,
or if we could tell them
that they're predisposed
to this disease.
I am sorry that I
went behind your back.
I honestly never did intend
to use Fox Foundation funds.
But we're here now.
Don't you want to be on the
forefront of fighting this?
You're right. This
changes everything.
Fox Foundation should
be leading the way.
Would $5 million help?
Yes. Yes.
Yeah, I mean, we could
expand the sample size.
We could do a 5-year
longitudinal study.
Great. Okay.
So...
I would like for you
to deliver your notes,
your data, all your models,
all of your work
to Tom Koracick.
Um, Koracick?
Yes, you know Tom.
Brilliant neurosurgeon,
insufferable know-it-all,
and tireless Lothario...
He'll be taking over.
Wait, I don't understand.
You said yourself.
Fox resources funded
all the research.
That means it all belongs
to the Fox Foundation.
So hand it over by end of day,
and the two of you
get to keep your jobs.
Same thing for Altman.
But this project
is no longer yours.
Link: His vein has
completely collapsed.
We've lost IV access
on his left side.
We can't lose Ruiz.
He might not work at 19 anymore,
but he's still one of us.
You should be in there.
Altman and Lincoln
are perfectly capable.
I need you in there.
I need to know it's your
hands trying to fix him.
Teddy: Did his repeat
H&H come back yet?
Please.
IO's placed.
Link: Alright, we need
to get him to CT ASAP.
Okay, then I'll
meet you in the OR.
You sure that's a good idea?
You'll need all the best
hands you have in there,
and mine are pretty damn good.
Alright. Let's
get ready to move.
Link: Let's get another
unit of crash blood.
Teddy: Have you put in
the trauma CT order set?
Robert: More traction
on your side, Millin.
Mm-hmm.
Okay. There, that's better.
Now, hypothetically,
If I clamp the aorta, and
there's still bleeding
from the posterior wall,
where's it coming from?
The... The lumbar arteries.
Correct. What do we do then?
You oversew it. You st...
Yasuda's right.
Alright.
The posterior parachute is done.
And shall I ask a tie-breaker
to see who gets to
suture the anterior wall?
Yes. Well, cou...
Could we both do some of it?
Well, I guess that'll work.
Okay, Millin, you take
the needle driver.
Yasuda, you follow her
with the anastomosis.
You need to keep it tight, okay?
And then you'll switch. Okay.
Yeah. Thank you.
Now, take healthy bites, Millin,
on both the aorta
and the Dacron graft
or the suture won't hold.
Am I following you okay? Yeah.
Um, thank you for asking.
Oh, I'm mostly bringing it up
so that you do a good
job when it's my turn.
Alright.
Ah.
How does that look?
Uh, still not enough artery.
You know, just go
with it, though, okay?
We poke too many needle holes,
and we'll have to deal
with suture line bleeding.
That's better. Okay.
I'm going to tie
it down for you.
We ready to continue?
Game on. You got it.
Get ready to
reload your needle.
We are already over capacity.
I have patients stuck in ORs
'cause the PACUs are full.
I don't have time to
this bureaucratic bull...
Hello?
Damn it.
We're running out
of IV pain meds.
How long till we
get more? No idea.
There's just too much red tape.
We're going to have
to start rationing.
How do you decide who gets
it and who has to suffer?
Well, if you can think of a
way, then, please, let me know.
What's the CT show?
BP started bottoming out
so we're heading
straight to surgery.
Okay.
Dr. Altman, where do
you think you're going?
To the OR.
Catherine, he's a firefighter.
Unless Grey has turned
in all of her research,
you still don't work
at this hospital.
Okay. If you need to
go on some power trip,
I can't stop you,
but I have too many
patients, not enough doctors.
So if this man dies
because your ego
won't let one of our
best doctors do her job,
then his blood will
be on your hands.
Let's go.
Lucas: How close
were you to the fire?
I saw flames on a hill,
which means too close.
You know, I'm using this to
get out of camping next time.
Who wants to spend
their vacation
sleeping on the ground?
Yeah, I went all
the time as a kid.
Hm. I wonder if I did.
I should ask my mom that.
It must be frustrating
not remembering your past.
It was at first, yeah.
I got pretty depressed
trying and failing at
getting back to my old life.
I mean, eventually, I just...
decided to stop stressing
and start fresh.
I reapplied to pharmacy school,
moved to California,
made some new
friends, got a dog,
met Dave.
Sounds like it worked out.
Yeah, it feels like it was
supposed to happen this way.
Alright.
I'll go check on
your chest X-ray.
Thank you.
Woman over PA:
Dr. Trosclair to Cardiology.
Dr. Beth Trosclair
to Cardiology.
Hey, I, uh, I just
said goodbye to Ruiz.
Well, he's in good hands.
Yeah, I know. I know.
I... I just wish
I could do more.
Um, you could stay.
Be here when he wakes up.
Dispatch already called.
I gotta get back.
Listen, um...
I promised Pru that we would do
root beer floats
tonight, but, um...
It might need to be tomorrow.
You be careful out
there, Ben Warren,
and... and you
keep me updated.
I will.
I love you, Miranda Bailey.
Always have.
Always will.
Okay. I'll meet
you in trauma 2.
Okay, show me.
Okay, the clinic.
Alright, triage tags.
We're using the
clinic for overflow.
So anything with a green
tag you take there, okay?
Need help? Neuro
check in trauma 2.
Yeah, sure.
- Have you ever had to make...
- Coming through.
A life-changing decision,
but couldn't talk it
through with anyone
due to its confidential nature?
I know about the secret
research. Thank God.
Catherine is holding it hostage.
Yeah, Teddy told me. Koracick.
Did she say what she
thought we should do?
She said it was up to you,
but she wouldn't mind
having a job, though.
I need to work, too,
but we're really getting
somewhere with the research.
What would you do?
Why are you laughing?
I don't remember one time
you took my advice
when we were married.
Well, I'm asking now. Come on.
I know you, okay?
Somewhere deep in your
gut and in your heart,
you already know the answer.
Trust yourself.
Thank you.
But, seriously,
what would you do?
I just wouldn't
give it to Koracick,
but that's just 'cause
I hate that guy.
OR 2 isn't cleared yet.
Then find us another one.
They're all full... between
multiple burn escharotomies,
maxed out PACU,
everything's backed up.
Alright, well tell
them the chief
has a severely
injured firefighter
whose BP is all
over the place...
Okay, don't tell them
chief, but tell them...
Oh, that needs to not happen.
JVD.
Muffled heart sounds.
No pulse, let's move.
Damn it. He's in PEA
from a cardiac tamponade.
Starting chest compressions.
Alright, he needs a thoracotomy.
How much longer
till this is clear?
They said five minutes.
He'll be dead in two.
Alright, do you have
a scalpel on you? Yes.
Go, go, go, good.
Alright. Stop compressions.
We're in a hallway.
Do you want him to die in it?
Stop compressions.
After I get in there,
I'll release the pressure
from around the heart.
What... What the
hell are you doing?!
Oh, my God, Altman!
What happened?
Jules: He said
his stomach hurt.
He became hypertensive and
then dropped his pressure.
We're trying to keep
systolics over 100
and we started a transfusion.
Alright, his anastomosis
might be leaking.
Dr. Webber said
we did a good job.
Webber let you do
it? He supervised us.
He was there the whole
time. Every step of the way.
Alright, we got to get
him back to the OR now.
Page Webber.
Neither one of you
come anywhere near it.
Alright. Let's go. Let's go.
Griffith, I need you and
Link to pull his chest open
so that I can see the heart.
One on either side.
Dr. Bailey? Altman.
We don't have a rib spreader.
It is the only way. Okay.
Ready? Pull. Alright.
Is that enough?
Oh, my God. More.
More. Pull. Altman...
Okay, there, there.
Pericardium is full of blood.
I need to release the
pressure from the heart.
Okay, come on. Come
on, there we go.
Is it beating?
There we go. Weakly.
Alright. BP's coming up a bit.
Come on, Theo. We
got you. Come on.
We need the damn OR!
Schmitt, can you make room?
Do the babies not know
that there's a natural
disaster happening right now?
Schmitt, how's Paloma Deshmukh?
Oh, her bilirubin's
a little high.
Do you think it could
progress to kernicterus?
How high?
Indirect bili is 15.
No, no, she's okay for now,
but just let's
keep an eye on her.
You know, I read an article
about the prevalence
of kernicterus in
South Asian children.
I don't know if you've
heard of that one.
I'm oddly fascinated
by jaundice.
Maybe 'cause my mom said
that I have jaundice...
I get it. You love kids.
You have a genuine,
maybe excessive interest in peds
and you did do a really good job
on that rectal biopsy today,
okay?
Pending your ABSITE score,
I will vouch for you to the
fellowship committee, okay?
Thank you.
Page me when you're
done charting.
Okay.
Congratulations. Thanks.
Your competitive advantage
is annoying people
into recommendations.
That felt unnecessary.
Well...
No. Ohh.
No, no, no.
Ah.
You made a dig, and the
power almost went out.
How bad would you feel
for all of these babies
if it hadn't have come back on?
Jo? Oh, my God. Hey, Jo?
Jo.
Hey, I need some help!
I just finished a...
I lost him.
By the time I opened him,
his entire blood supply
was in his abdomen.
I'm sorry.
Millin and Yasuda said
they did the anastomosis.
That's a lot of
responsibility for interns.
Repairing a ruptured aorta?
I barely let my
third years do that.
They were ready to step up.
Clearly, they weren't.
His posterior wall was a mess.
Posterior wall?
Yes. They need more practice
before I let them near another
one of my patients again.
Bailey: Have more
lap pads ready.
Link: Where is all this
bleeding coming from?
Teddy: Let's go
quadrant by quadrant.
Taryn: His company supervisor
is asking for an update.
Let's hold off.
I want to be able to
give them positive news.
And we are not there yet.
We can use an
extra set of hands.
Scrubbing in. Griffith,
check my phone.
You want me to break scrub?
No, I want you to
look at my phone
and see if I have any missed
calls or texts from Ben.
Nurse.
It's a new TED Health Podcast.
The SMA's avulsed
from the aorta...
he is bleeding out.
Link: Alright, if we don't
repair the blood flow
to his leg soon, I'll
have to amputate.
We are not amputating.
More suction.
All due respect, It's
usually the trauma surgeon
who reminds me life
comes before limb.
What about now, Griffith?
Dangerously close to
the point of no return.
Teddy: This man
live for his job.
If we can save both,
I'm taking that chance.
Griffith? John Doe
trauma, ETA 5 minutes.
Alright, we need to get
distal and proximal control.
About to die.
Our best bet is a saphenous
vein graft to reconstruct...
Ben: I love you,
Miranda Bailey.
Always have.
Teddy: Bailey,
what do you think?
Always will. Bailey?
Bailey.
I think, um...
I...
I think I-I shouldn't be here.
Helm.
Can you...?
Alright, Helm, get in here.
Put your hand right here.
More irrigation.
Thank you, Bokhee.
More suction.
Yep.
Hey.
Hm. Here.
And your test results
came back normal.
I feel a lot better.
Thanks for asking.
I see why you get high marks
on your bedside manner.
I thought we were friends.
You live in my loft
practically rent-free.
Your check bounced twice.
Is that your way of saying
we're landlord-tenant?
What's your deal?
Why didn't you tell
me you were pregnant?
I'm what?
Oh.
I guess that's why.
Congratulations.
You look like your
mother sitting up here.
Before she got sick,
did she...
tell you about her last surgery?
No.
She was probably
in denial about it.
I'm sure there was no post-op
cake or retirement party.
Sounds like Ellis.
If I had to guess, I'd say
it was probably a Whipple
or definitely something
to do with the pancreas.
Oh, she loved the pancreas.
She said that was the one organ
that was more
stubborn than she was.
Sounds like Ellis.
You know, I've been
thinking about her
so much lately with my research.
And I've been wondering how
much of stubborn Ellis was Ellis
and how much of it was
Alzheimer's festering
before we ever even
knew she had it.
Hm.
You know...
I think my time might be up.
Hey, well, I know
I've said it before.
I know I've taken breaks
from the OR in the past,
but this time it
feels different.
It feels like...
I need to think about
putting the scalpel down.
But I've been a
surgeon a long time.
I'm afraid if I stop,
I won't know who I am.
I get that more than you know.
Well, I talked to Catherine.
Sounds like you've got some
tough decisions to make.
I don't really have a choice.
Well, you may not
like the options,
but you always have a choice.
♪ Tend to me for tonight ♪
♪ I am a fool ♪
♪ Rest your head on my chest ♪
♪ But you left the room ♪
♪ I'm the one with the grace ♪
♪ To let you move ♪
Dr. Bailey.
Uh, Griffith, you
should be in the OR.
He's stabilized.
At this point, we're
more concerned about you.
Anything I can do?
Can you make it rain?
♪ Tend to me for tonight ♪
My husband's a firefighter.
He runs toward the
danger every day,
but today... Whole
nother level.
It's a nightmare.
I keep reminding myself
that he knows what he's doing.
And I try not to think
about his impulsive nature
or his penchant for heroics.
We have an agreement.
I can text him as
many times as I want.
And he always, always responds.
But today, he...
♪ You're not stopping now ♪
I mean, it's... it's...
it's been a couple of hours.
I heard the cell service
isn't good in that area.
♪ Finally on something else ♪
[ Sighs ]
Ben Warren?
Benjamin Warren. Why?
Safe.
Updated 2 minutes ago
by the Seattle Fire Department.
What... What... What is this?
Is... Is this real?
It's a database to help
people find their people.
Dorian's mom used to
work for the city.
She sent the link to a
bunch of her contacts
to help track first responders.
He's okay.
Mm.
Oh.
Thank God. I...
Thank you.
Thank... Thank you.
It's... It's...
Oh, did you send
your files to Tom?
They're online.
Good, as long as his assistant
knows where to upload
or download... I never
know which one it is.
They're on the NIH website.
You posted your research?
That belongs to the foundation.
You have no right.
I sent in an abstract that I
wrote on my personal computer.
That means nothing.
You have a contract
with us, dear.
No, I've already resigned.
Resigned to who?
Richard.
Oh.
This is too important to me,
and I don't want to
play the politics
or the games with
you, Catherine.
It isn't fair to the
patients or their families.
You have no idea
what you've done.
Actually, I do.
Goodbye, Catherine.
You are just like your mother.
Great. That means I'll win.
Woman over PA: Dr. Call
to the Cath Lab.
Dr. Katie Call
Are you okay? Hey.
I heard you fainted.
I'm...
I'm just tired.
The air quality
isn't helping either.
Okay. You want to
sit for a minute?
We could be here all night.
Let me bring you some food.
I'm good. I'm okay.
You sure? Yeah.
Yeah. I'll see you later.
♪ Monsters... ♪
The world is literally
burning down.
Do we have to work on
the schedule tonight?
These residents put in
their vacation requests
like two weeks ago.
What resident has
time for vacation?
Me.
I got eight weeks from Webber.
I've got to buy my
tickets for Paris.
Ohh.
ABSITE scores are in.
♪ ...what's in your head ♪
55th percentile. Nice.
What'd you get?
62nd. That's great.
Anything above 50 is gold,
especially for a
fifth-year resident.
Not if you want a
peds fellowship.
I need to rethink
my entire life.
Want to rethink it
with me in Paris?
♪ ...is empty ♪
♪ Come and find me now ♪
Can I get you a chair?
Not if you want me to
ever stand up again.
Well, I heard the fire's
at 30% containment.
Is that good?
I don't know anymore.
If this day ever ends, you
want to grab dinner at Joe's?
Everything smells
like ash to me.
A drink?
I don't know if that's
what I need either.
♪ ...and that's all ♪
My place?
Sounds good.
Um, Ndugu, can we talk?
I'll catch up with you later.
I need to tell you about
Garrett's anastomosis.
Millin and Yasuda
were not at fault.
We finished the
anterior wall and...
Oh, excuse me. Excuse
me. My girlfriend...
She can't breathe, and
I can't find her doctor.
Can you please help?
Look, I don't know
what happened.
We were just talking
a second ago.
You're asthmatic, right?
I'll give you some albuterol.
Okay. Hang on, honey.
Okay. Take a deep breath.
Good, good.
Take another one.
You feel better?
Do I know you?
It just...
It really feels like I know you.
No.
Here.
Adams, she's all set.
Make sure to get her another
inhaler before she goes.
Uh, can you monitor her for me?
Dorian's transport's here,
and I'd like goodbye.
Yeah, I don't think
that's a good idea.
You do know her, don't you?
What... you two hook
up or something?
She was my fiancée.
Hey, Bailey's low-key
taking a head count.
We might want to
get back upstairs.
Sorry.
I... I'm so sorry that I
ratted us out to Ndugu.
I know he's kind of your mentor.
No, he died.
Garrett died.
What?
Yasuda: Oh, my God. Yeah.
We... We sewed his aorta.
Jules: Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah, yeah, this isn't working.
This isn't working.
Okay. Come and sit
down. Hold still.
Okay. Here, alright?
Anything?
Not really.
Okay, what about now? Better?
Today did not go at all
how I thought it would.
Yep. Same.
Mm. Hey.
Come with me.
Is it Bailey? No, not her.
ABSITE scores came in.
Yes!
73rd percentile.
Same.
78th percentile.
Hey.
Griffith. How'd you do?
75th.
We all aced it.
Yeah.
Why does this feel...
weird?
That's why I was
looking for you.
Hey! We're gonna
miss you here.
Yeah, see if they'll stop for
a cheeseburger on your way.
Hey, doctor's orders.
I already did. Fries, too.
Pace yourself.
I will.
Thank you...
for everything.
A-And thank you for, uh,
making the database today.
You helped a lot of people.
That was all Adams.
I just helped get it out there.
Take care of yourself, man.
Your ABSITE score came in.
It was the highest
in your class.
I gotta go change for
my meeting with Dr. Fox.
So, how'd it go with Ruiz?
Oh, I had to reconstruct his
SMA, and he's stable now.
Link was able to save his leg.
Thank you for
standing up for me.
That might have been
my last surgery.
Or not. You did
save a firefighter.
Yeah. Is that enough to
change Catherine's mind?
Hm. Oh!
I just blew up my life.
Meredith and I published.
Definitely not enough.
So, how are you feeling?
Mm.
Strangely calm for
being unemployed.
Okay.
Meredith: Much
like with surgery,
life is full of
calculated risks. Okay.
We often make sacrifices in
hopes of better outcomes.
Not every gamble pays
off the way we hoped.
So we ask ourselves,
what are we willing to
give up? Coming through.
♪ My love ♪
♪ I hope you forgive my mood ♪
♪ Nothing to do with you ♪
♪ I've been hiding in... ♪
What can we leave behind?
♪ ...my head ♪
♪ It's pulling
me out the room ♪
What are you doing here?
♪ Call it the winter blues ♪
Came to see how your day went.
♪ Happens now and then ♪
So, did you, uh, did
you save your research
or burn everything down?
What if I said both?
Well... that
wouldn't surprise me.
It's one of your best qualities.
♪ 'Cause my love for you
will still be the same ♪
My ability to sabotage my life?
No.
Fight for what you believe in.
You'll put everything on the
line when you want something.
♪ Life goes on and
people come and go ♪
Mm. It does make it hard
to know where you stand
when you're sidelined.
I told you I wanted
a life with you.
No, you described your life,
and you asked if I was in.
You know, I've... I had a
life, too, before we met.
It was great. It was
simple. I loved it.
And then I met you...
and I've followed you
across the country twice.
Every time you've asked, I've
given you space and time.
I agreed to run a
residency program
with interns you hired.
Am I in?
I've been in.
I've been in, and I
can't seem to get out.
If you said you were moving,
I'd probably follow you again...
as inexplicable as that is.
But here's the thing.
I'd rather not follow you.
I'd rather do it with you.
Side by side, partners.
Long after you've
forgotten who I am,
or I don't know, maybe I'll
have forgotten you first.
Well, then we'd get to
meet over and over again.
I mean...
wouldn't be the worst way
to spend an afternoon.
♪ It brings me back again ♪
♪ Life goes on and
people come and go ♪
♪ I was scared that
you would disappear ♪
What do we need to live?
So that thing you
said about moving...
Oh, boy, here we
go. Let me guess.
Chicago, San
Francisco, Orlando...
God, please, don't say Orlando.
I was thinking Chestnut Hill.
What? You want to
go see that house?
Well, we probably should
because I put an offer
on it this morning.
Are you serious? Yes.
And if you hate it,
we can back out.
But, I don't know, just
going to take a tour
didn't seem like grand
enough a gesture.
What makes life worth living?
♪ Your love don't fear ♪
What are we willing
to put on the line
when a life is at stake?
Remind me what you were thinking
when you attempted
the thoracotomy
on Mr. Sutton.
I thought he was going to die.
You got that right.
Alright.
Regarding the GME
recommendation that you...
Excuse... Hello.
I'm having a meeting.
We know.
♪ Seasons change ♪
We want to urge you to reject
the GME Council's
recommendation for Dr. Adams.
And why would I do that?
Well, Adams completed
Bailey's procedure logs,
as did we all,
and we think that should
count for something.
Oh, we're human.
We can't avoid mistakes.
What's important is
learning not to repeat them.
Look, we all push each
other to be better,
and it wouldn't be
the same without him.
Simone: You know
as well as we do
how demanding intern year is,
but we're working
through it together.
We don't want to
leave anyone behind...
or lose anyone.
If Adams goes...
What?
You all go?
Is that really a threat
you want to make right now?
♪ I'm the only one
your love don't fear ♪
I could have all of you
replaced by tomorrow.
What about me?
♪ Your love don't fear ♪
Can you replace me?
♪ I'm the only one
your love don't fear ♪
How much are we ready to lose...
if things don't break our way?
♪ Your love don't fear ♪
Captions by VITAC...