In 1949, Edward Murphy
conducted a rocket-sled experiment
to see how much pressure a
human being could withstand.
Good morning.
I've organized the
monthly rotation schedule,
I got up to speed on all the
upcoming general elective surgeries,
and I have some ideas about
which residents are ready
for the next phase of
Dr. Minnick's training.
Um, I could run
that by you, or...
Murphy's experiment
failed. Spectacularly.
Or not.
Over and over.
Whatever you like. Sorry.
What would Dr. Grey usually do?
Uh, Dr. Grey wouldn't
talk to me about any of it.
She would just do it. Go. Do it.
Oh, okay, sure. Yeah.
Needless to say, he didn't
start off on the right foot.
Kepner. You don't
have to check in with me.
I trust you. You do you.
It's your department now.
That's why it's
called Murphy's law.
Because if anything
can go wrong, it will.
You may have thought you were
done talking about this, but I wasn't.
Richard, it was
three in the morning.
I have surgery, I needed
sleep. You need sleep. Come on.
You told Bailey to replace me.
No, baby. No. I told
Bailey there was a problem.
- You told her
there was a problem?
- Yes.
You see a problem in our
marriage, will I hear about it?
Or will some consultant come
and kick me out of our bedroom?
Stop. You know
me better than that.
No, Catherine. Right
now, I don't. I really don't.
Okay. Take OR Four,
and make sure you do
the post-op debriefing
with a resident, right away.
Is Dr. Grey out
sick or something?
Dr. Grey is suspended. I am
the interim department chief.
Until further notice.
- You are?
- Yes.
Yes.
Okay.
Oh, Dr. Kepner.
Dr. Bailey told me
you're filling in for
Dr. Grey as chief of general.
- I am.
- Well, congrats!
Well, I didn't... I mean,
it was a necessary...
- I need your help.
- Mm-hmm.
I'm beginning phase two of
my teaching program today.
- Right. Phase two.
- And I need someone
to supervise Ben Warren
through a colectomy.
Dr. Hawkins was gonna do it,
but he's sick. Can you
assign someone else?
Okay. Yeah. Let's see
who has a colectomy.
Oh...
Is there a problem?
No.
No, not at all. All good.
I do have a surgeon
available with one, and
I will just assign it to him.
- Great. Thanks.
- Sure, yeah.
Do you know where Dr. Webber is?
Did April say anything?
Like why she jumped ship?
I haven't seen her. She
was home late and out early.
Oh, she's slinking then.
She knows what she did. She's
slinking. Traitor. No offense.
Look, I can't believe that she
would have done this either.
I can't believe
Bailey asked her.
- How's Grey holding up?
- She's bored.
She's worried Kepner's
gonna kill all of her patients.
Kepner's a solid surgeon.
You have to give her that,
no matter how anyone
feels about her taking the job.
Yeah, of course, she's a great
surgeon. Guys, we're losing ground here.
Okay? We lost Grey,
we're now losing April.
And we don't have the
residents. They love Minnick.
And she's about to start
phase two of her program.
- Phase two?
- A resident gets
to be the primary
surgeon on their own case.
One procedure, pre-op
to post-op, start to finish.
- Under supervision, right?
- Yeah,
but the resident does it all.
The attending is there to assist.
The resident?
- Start to finish, baby!
- Ugh, would you quit bragging
already?
- Yes!
- I don't get it. Why you two?
'Cause Minnick recognizes
I'm the best resident. Obviously.
- I don't know why you got one.
- Special treatment.
- From his chief-wife.
- It's not special treatment.
And don't call her that.
Minnick told me she
drew names from a hat.
- Yeah, see?
- Whatever, Mr. Bailey.
She's really gonna let you do
a whole surgery with no help?
No hand holding,
no training wheels,
no safety belts,
no gutter bumpers.
- Phase two, baby.
- Shut up, baby.
Yeah, what happened to you? Last night,
you were like, "Let's start a revolution!"
Well, this morning, I would
say that we're winning.
Now, gosh, if you'll
excuse me, children,
Mama's gotta go do surgery.
Dr. Sern, two-four-seven-six.
- Good morning.
- Kepner.
April. How's your new job going?
So busy, as I'm sure you know.
Dr. Webber, can I
talk to you for a sec?
Sure.
Maybe could we go somewhere
a little more private, or...
Kepner, I'm pretty busy.
What do you have to say?
Um, it's about your
partial colectomy today.
It's now Ben Warren's.
- I beg your pardon?
- Start to finish.
I'd like Dr. Warren to
scrub in as primary surgeon.
- You'd like?
- And you can assist
and help only when requested,
but it will be Dr. Warren's OR.
Why don't you let
Bailey take this one?
Because I have
assigned it to you.
Well, I suggest
you un-assign it.
I would really rather
not, Dr. Webber...
sir.
Please... just... please?
Sure thing... Chief.
- There you are.
- Yes. And I'm ready.
I have Mrs. Mallenbaum's
labs, I booked an OR.
Edwards, unbook it. Mrs.
Mallenbaum had a complication.
What? Did she have breakfast?
No. She died.
Oh.
Oh, God. That's...
- That's awful.
- It's okay to be disappointed.
You were excited.
I was excited too.
So should I go down to the
pit or something instead, or...
You know what? Yes. If you're
gonna do a true start-to-finish,
we should both go down to the ER
and see if we can start one on intake.
- We're trolling.
Can you check Mr. Lewis's
drains for me, please?
Yes, doctor.
All right, I've been thinking.
All right, we are in a
corner. Okay? It's time.
One of us needs to talk
to my mother about this.
And I know what you're gonna
say, right? I don't care how...
- Jackson, she knows.
- She...
She knew before anyone.
- She's not with us.
- No, she...
This was my mother's idea? I
thought, I thought this was Bailey's.
So did I. But no,
- Bailey decided I need to...
- You should stop talking
right now.
- What?
- Dr. Webber.
Oh, need something, Warren?
Well, um... Well you, sir.
I have my start-to-finish
surgery today,
and you were assigned to...
Assist you. Yeah. Right.
- We'll talk later.
- Mm-hmm.
- Warren.
- Jackson.
Boring. Boring. Weird and
gross. Exceptionally boring.
None of these are surgical.
Can I get a portable
ultrasound to Bed Two, please?
- Of course.
- Dr. Murphy.
Talk to me about Bed Two.
It's a nine-year-old boy with
right upper quadrant pain.
I'm betting it's
acute cholecystitis.
But I've gotta get the
ultrasound to confirm.
Mm-hmm.
- That won't be necessary.
- Am I missing something?
Wait. No, no, no!
Dr. Edwards is taking over
this case now, from start to finish.
Thank you for
finding it for her.
No! I started it, I get to
finish it! I love gallstones!
- Yes!
- You'll get your turn,
Dr. Murphy.
And when that happens,
Dr. Edwards will be there to support you.
Physical therapy to Five West.
Wait, honey, tell me
again. Where's Dr. Grey?
Good morning, Ms.
Gagliano, I am Doctor...
Not Dr. Grey.
She's not Dr. Grey.
Where's Dr. Grey?
Dr. Grey is unavailable to
perform your surgery, Lynne,
so, Dr. Kepner will be
performing it with Dr. Pierce.
She's gonna take out my cancer?
Ms. Gagliano, I've successfully
operated on several esophageal cancer...
Listen, Dr. Not-Grey. I
don't care what you've done.
Dr. Grey found my cancer.
She told me about it. She held
my hand while I bawled about it,
she told me how she
was gonna take it out.
I've been going to the same
hairstylist for 23 years. Why?
Because she knows
how I like my roots done.
Dr. Grey knows my roots.
Let's cancel the surgery.
I'll wait for Dr. Grey.
Lynne, that kind of
loyalty is really appreciated.
Thank you.
Loyalty is so
rare in this world.
But we're not sure when
Dr. Grey will be back.
And with the risk of
your cancer spreading,
we can't wait.
But I'll be there. Your
roots are safe with me.
When did the pain start?
When we were in our car
on the way to the seaport,
Matty kept complaining
about his stomach.
It's been off and on
for the last few days,
but it kept getting worse, so we just
turned around and came back here.
I mean, it's probably
just a stomach bug, right?
We're going on a cruise.
- Ooh, that's fun.
- It's called an Explorer Cruise.
All inclusive,
three ports of call.
And they have rock-climbing
walls, and even movie nights.
And they teach you
to surf right on deck!
See... He's more excited
than Matty is about this trip.
- It's like I have two children.
- Matty, can you
raise your arms for me?
Also, if we get to the car within
the hour, we can still make it.
Dana... Maybe we're
just overreacting.
- Dana!
- I'm being optimistic.
Matty's been looking
forward to this for a year.
Hillary, Dana, I'm afraid
Matty has gallstones
and a very inflamed gallbladder.
Gallstones? But he's nine.
It's very rare in someone
Matty's age, but it can happen.
Oh, gosh.
Oh, sweetie.
- But will we still
be able to go?
- It's okay, son, don't worry.
Will we be able to go?
Not today, buddy.
You need surgery.
Oh, my God. That was so hard.
Hey, they can
reschedule a vacation.
You can't get caught up
in their story. Not your job.
No, it was so hard
to keep from smiling.
Especially when I said,
"You're gonna need surgery!"
I'm just happy that you're here.
I'm trying not to
hug you, right now.
Okay, make it quick.
- Thank you.
- All right.
Now, talk me through
your surgical plan.
Well, after trocar insertion...
Your very own start-to-finish
partial colectomy, huh? Pretty spiffy.
Yeah. Yeah.
Should be pretty cool.
What's the matter?
Oh, are you nervous?
No, it's not
nerves. It's just...
I wish I had a different
attending, that's all.
If people don't like what Minnick's
doing, they don't really try...
Well, who's the
attending? I'll talk to him.
Dr. Webber.
Yeah. Yeah. So
this should be fun.
Oh, and no, no,
you won't talk to him.
I have enough problems being
your first lady. Just stay out.
My first what?
Dr. Pierce, do you think
I might have a chance
to dissect the
thoracic esophagus?
No, Wilson.
I don't see why
not, Dr. Pierce, if...
Because we already have one
surgeon we didn't plan for, is why not.
Okay, I get it, you are
unhappy about Dr. Grey,
but I am not the one
who suspended her.
I'm unhappy about
the fact that Dr. Grey
and I worked hard to plan this
surgery, and you are skipping steps.
You just ligated a branch that
we might need for the anastomosis.
And now the esophagus is ready
to be excised, which was quicker.
V-fib! She's in cardiac arrest!
- Ready?
- Grab the paddles!
One, two, three.
Paddles! Charge to one-twenty.
Clear.
So, what now? Can
we still excise the tumor?
No. We can't.
She's too unstable.
We have to close her up,
do a cardiac work-up.
Observe her in ICU.
Sorry, Lynne. You're
gonna have to keep waiting.
Why are you looking at me? I
didn't give her a heart attack.
Dr. Bailey. Need something?
Warren is doing his start-to-finish
surgery, I thought I'd observe.
Really? Observe Warren or me?
You asked her to come in here?
You don't trust me
to follow the protocol?
No, sir, I didn't even know
that she was gonna come.
Uh, he didn't say that.
And I didn't say that.
You said that.
- I think we're good.
- I think I'd like to watch.
- I had a heart attack?
- Yes,
but we were able to
intervene very quickly.
But you didn't get
the damn cancer out?
No, we weren't able to remove
the tumor. After your heart attack...
I knew something was gonna go wrong
the minute Dr. Not-Grey showed up.
Dr. Grey wouldn't have
been able to do anything...
You know, why don't we...
why don't we give you a few
minutes of peace and quiet?
That poor woman's body
is still riddled with cancer.
We did just save her life. You'd
think she'd see that as a plus.
Shut up! Just shut your face!
- Maggie!
- I thought you were with us.
I thought you were with Richard.
And then you go and do this.
- I took a job! It was an opportunity!
- It's aiding the enemy!
I'm not saying I agree
with what Bailey did!
But you are saying that it's
not a deal-breaker. Not for you.
Not if it gets you
what you want. Traitor.
I'm doing my job!
This is my job, Maggie!
Someone here has
to act like an adult!
And now I am dividing
the white line of Toldt.
Beautiful dissection,
Dr. Warren.
Thank you, sir.
Dr. Webber, more suction.
Are you gonna be one of those
surgeons who plays music in this OR?
Yeah, I might be.
Well, choose your playlist
carefully. I once had this resident
who made it all
the way to close,
and then all of a sudden,
this music comes on.
It was the most ridiculous
song I've ever heard,
it was complete gibberish.
Stay away from the ureter.
Yep. More traction, please.
I was that resident.
And "MMMBop" was
very popular at the time.
That was you,
huh? It was catchy.
Dr. Warren, did you know
that my first solo surgery
was also with Dr. Webber?
Indeed. But somewhere
between then and now,
Dr. Bailey forgot that
I know how to teach.
No, what I'm saying is,
the chief gives an order,
you follow the order,
you try to make it work.
- Spoken like a true soldier.
- Spoken like a former chief.
- Right, on both counts.
- So you're neutral,
is what you're saying.
You're Switzerland.
I'm saying Bailey's the chief.
But that doesn't mean
that I'm against Webber.
Yeah, I get that. I really do.
But what are you supposed
to do when you're completely
against the order that
you've been given?
Well, that's called a coup.
Frowned upon, but
sometimes very necessary.
Oh, so that's what
we're talking about here?
Throwing Minnick out?
Or throwing Bailey out?
No, it's just we want Webber in.
That's all. I mean, I guess
that means Minnick has to go.
So what?
I don't know what we're gonna
do here, but we gotta do something.
So, Hunt, you with us? Or are you
too busy being Switzerland over there?
How's Kepner doing?
What do you mean
how's Kepner doing?
- She's a turncoat.
- But she's also a friend.
Yes, she's a friend.
She's a poor, misguided,
very confused friend.
It's like when you find out
that your friend voted wrong.
- Can you vote wrong?
- Yeah!
- Absolutely.
- Yeah.
I'm sorry, but she
was leading the charge
and then Bailey
dangles a little carrot
and suddenly it's,
"See ya, Webber!"
I'm sure there's
more to it than that.
Well, it's not right,
what Bailey did.
You can't just throw anybody
in as chief of general surgery.
Keps is good, but Grey
put in the time for that job.
She deserves it. All right.
I'm gonna get back to work.
You know, Switzerland doesn't
engage in international conflicts.
It serves in peacekeeping missions,
and protects Switzerland itself.
Keeping the peace. And protecting
ourselves. That's what we're doing.
So we're all Switzerland,
then, aren't we?
Doesn't feel like it.
- What the hell?
- Is that the OR schedule?
Yeah, but why is a
resident listed as a lead
surgeon on a lap
chole on a peds case?
Damn it, Minnick.
I didn't want you out of the
way. Why would you say that?
- Anastomosis looks...
- Yes. Good. Good.
Yeah. We can
pull out the trocar.
- Let me see, okay, you fired me.
- I didn't fire you.
- Then you fired Grey.
- I suspended Grey.
Does the umbilical port get closed
with a deep or superficial closure?
- Both.
You know, pretty soon, you're
gonna find yourself out of teachers.
It's tough to be a leader
when there's no one to lead.
I am not afraid to be unpopular
for the good of the hospital.
That's not you. I know that
Catherine put you up to this.
- I know it was her idea!
- Fascia's closed.
- I love my wife.
- "Great, Dr. Warren, keep going."
Three-oh nylon and Steri-strips.
I can stand up just fine.
And that's exactly what I did.
Who gave you permission to let a
resident operate on a nine-year-old?
We're implementing
phase two of my program.
No, you're not implementing
phases on a kid.
Look, he's really
big for his age.
It's a lap chole. It's
a simple procedure
that Dr. Edwards is
perfectly capable...
You're not a peds surgeon. You
are a sports medicine ortho surgeon.
I am scrubbing in.
I was trained in general
surgery, just like you.
And I teach for a living.
I taught five lap
choles last month,
but if it will make you
feel more comfortable,
then please, join us,
Dr. Robbins. I'd love to have you.
- Good.
- But only to observe.
I'm gonna go get Matty prepped.
No.
No?
No. You go give the
parents a pre-game.
You are the lead surgeon.
Which means I prep your patient.
- Seriously?
- Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Look at that. See? When you
let yourself have a little fun...
Don't do that. Just... don't.
- Don't do what?
- That.
It was cute in the beginning,
but it's not anymore.
You'd rather sacrifice your
students than swallow your pride
and admit that someone found
a better way to teach them.
- Instead of...
- scissors.
You want to devote your time
to bringing this hospital down,
and me along with it,
hey, I can't stop you.
And I am done. Steri-strip
and dress the wound.
- Yes, well done.
- Good job, Warren.
- Really?
- Well, don't you think so?
No, I do. It's just...
This was my first time
as primary on a surgery.
It should have at least been fun.
But you two were so busy arguing
about how to teach
or not teach students,
that you forgot that
you had one in here.
I'm sorry, no
disrespect. It's just...
This was my first.
And I'm never gonna
get another one.
I need to go dictate the post-op
report. Thank you, everyone.
It's a really simple surgery.
I just make a tiny, little hole,
and in that hole, I insert my
camera and all my instruments.
- Okay.
- And you just end up
with an itty-bitty
scar right there.
Okay?
- Okay.
- All right.
I think it's time
to take you up.
I will come and talk to
you when we're done.
I said I think it's time to take him
up, which means take him to the OR,
um, and mark the incision spot.
I prefer an
infraumbilical incision.
You can give him
point five milligrams...
- Edwards. Rein it in.
- Yeah. Okay.
Her vitals look good.
How're you feeling,
Lynne? Any pain?
Lots. Thanks to you.
Okay, can we just
be nice for a minute?
Wilson, check the
repeat enzymes, please.
You know who was nice? Dr. Grey.
What? Dr. Grey is nice.
Yeah, no, I just... nothing.
I'm nicer...
than Dr. Grey. I mean,
ask anyone in this hospital.
There are comparisons that you can
make between myself and Dr. Grey,
but in a contest of
niceness, I take that win.
I win by a lot. I am the nicest.
Yeah, well, Dr. Grey
would've gotten my...
can...
Lynne? Lynne, what's
going on? Are you okay?
- Hard to breathe!
- She's tachycardic. Pressure's down.
- I need an EKG
and a portable x-ray.
- Is it another MI?
Dr. Pierce, there's
gastric fluid in her lungs.
The esophageal stump
must've perfed into her chest.
- My staples didn't hold.
- Lynne, there's been
a complication.
We have to take you
back to the OR right away.
You screwed up. I was dying
of cancer, and now I'm dying...
- You're trying to kill me.
- Let's move.
Okay, you can be in
here on one condition.
I can be in here however I want.
- This isn't about me,
it's about Edwards.
- She needs to feel confident.
And she won't if you're
standing over her shoulder.
You are welcome to observe,
but if you don't think you can
keep your hands to yourself,
- you have to leave.
- Fine.
In the peritoneum.
Optical trocar and
camera, please?
There's a lot of resistance. I'm...
I'm not sure how hard to push.
Right. You won't
know until you do it.
Keep going. You're good.
- It's all about the feel.
- Mm-hmm.
Together.
You're in.
That was the hard part.
The rest is a piece of cake.
- What now?
- Insufflation.
I knew you were moving too fast.
She was having a heart attack.
I stapled as quickly as I could.
I know.
So, what? Dr. Grey can
staple better than I can now?
- Lynne is prepped and ready.
- Thank you, Wilson.
- Dr. Pierce, you can go.
- What?
This is my revision. I
don't need you. You can go.
She's my patient.
No, actually, she's Dr. Grey's
patient. And I'm Dr. Grey now.
I'm in charge, whether
you like it or not
and until you get on board with
that, you are not welcome in my OR.
So you can stop
scrubbing. And you can go.
You're gonna need
an extra set of hands.
Wilson has hands.
- That was badass.
- Shut up.
Dissecting the gallbladder now.
- Just remember
to stay away from...
- From the CBD, got it.
Dr. Robbins, please.
Almost there. There's the duct.
He's tachycardic. His
pressure's trending down.
Edwards, can you see if there's
bleeding coming from the liver bed?
- Do you know how to do...
- Dr. Edwards knows what to do.
Checking the liver.
No bleeding. The
field looks clear.
Well, the blood's coming from
somewhere. So check the hepatic artery.
I don't see any... I
don't see any bleeding.
- Turn the camera.
- What?
Turn the camera. And check out
the rest of his abdomen. Just do it.
Oh, God!
All right. His pelvis
is filled with blood.
All right, pull the trocars!
He's been bleeding
out this whole time.
I don't understand. Why
would I have not seen that?
His pressure's bottomed out!
Hang two units! I
need platelets and FFP!
Move! Move! Back up!
Scalpel. All right, lap pads.
Bovie.
- Suction.
- Come on, Edwards.
- I don't understand.
More lap pads! Okay.
Edwards, suction.
All right. His
mesentery is bleeding.
Can you localize the bleeder?
Help me get some
proximal control of the SMA.
Suction!
There's an injury to the
superior mesenteric artery.
Must have nicked
it with the trocar.
All right. Lost his pressure!
Clamp! Clamp! Come on, come on!
He's bleeding out faster
than we can put it in!
Come on, you guys.
Come on. Clamp.
What did I do?
Did I... did I skip
a step? Did I...
Should I have done
something differently?
I mean, did I...
did I kill that boy?
Hey. Hey! Where are you going?
Neither of us is up
for cooking tonight.
So let's pick something up.
Or I could just make
reservations at our place.
No, I'm not hungry.
Come on. Can't we be civil?
I was always a fine surgeon.
But I am an excellent teacher.
And today, I was
a complete failure.
I know you thought this
program had problems,
but it sure as hell
has them now.
- Richard...
- Bailey was my favorite student.
I brought her in as an intern. I
saw her all the way through to chief.
She was my "start-to-finish."
And you turned her against me.
Come here, my little bug.
Oh, I thought you were... I
thought I was taking her home.
Hi.
I just wanted to
kiss her good night.
'Cause I'm gonna be here late
prepping for a department meeting.
- Got it.
- And then I've also got
my tumor debulking
to prep for, so...
You're really enjoying
this, aren't you?
Yeah. Yeah, I am.
You don't remember that you
and I started this for Webber?
I still support Webber.
So then you should
have told Bailey no.
And ignore my
responsibility to this hospital
because of a political
pissing match?
Yesterday, it was a noble
cause. What are you talking about?
Oh, but now, all of a sudden,
you've got your shiny new title, right?
- What? What does that mean?
- You realize how this looks,
don't you?
You realize what everybody's
saying? That you're an opportunist,
that you're an
overly ambitious...
And you told them that
they're wrong. Right?
Because you know me,
and you know better. Right?
I'm surprised by
you, that's what I am.
Look, Bailey gave you a
choice, that's what that was.
It was a choice.
You chose wrong.
It's not too late.
You can still resign.
You can still tell her
that you made a mistake.
Yeah, but I didn't
make a mistake.
I have a duty to this hospital, and
my chief asked me to step up, so I...
Did she? Or was
that my mom again,
telling Bailey that
she should pick you?
Why would you say that?
'Cause it's probably true.
It's not even your fault.
- It's her. It's what she does.
- No. No, it's you.
Because you refuse to believe
that I got this because I earned it.
- Because I'm good.
- That's... That's not...
What the hell is wrong with you?
She asked you a question.
She needed an answer.
- I know. What kind
of teacher are you?
I mean, you don't just teach
them what to do with their hands,
you teach them
what to do with this,
how to live through this. I
mean, you take it on yourself.
- I know.
- You don't!
You are the attending.
This is your loss!
Okay? You take the hit,
because if you put it
on her, she might quit.
She might think that
she can't survive it.
So you show her that she can.
You tell her, "When
this happened to me..."
It hasn't.
- What?
- It's never happened to me.
I never had a child die.
Never?
Not a kid. Not in residency,
not as a fellow, and
now I work on athletes.
And old people.
Old, broken hips. Torn
ligaments. Never a little boy.
I took that boy
from his parents.
And now I have to tell them.
And I don't know how.
How do you do it?
How do you stop
feeling like this?
You don't.
You... you just learn how to...
You learn how to feel
this way a little faster.
You let it hurt, and then you...
You put it behind you so that
you can face forward to the...
the next kid who needs you.
I remember my first...
like it was yesterday. So...
take your time.
And then we'll go.
Dr. Not-Grey. You're still here.
I am still here. And so are you.
- Dr. Wilson?
- The repair went very well.
- You fixed the thing you broke?
- I fixed the thing I broke.
And that nasty esophageal tumor is
in the medical waste, where it belongs.
You got the damn cancer?
We got the damn cancer.
You got it?
Well, Dr. Wilson and I did.
Full excision, good margins.
We still need to run some tests,
but it appears as though
you are cancer free.
What's your name again?
Hemostasis was established
and the patient was sent to
post-op without complications.
Dr. Webber? May I... may
I run something by you?
By me? I thought you were
working with Dr. Minnick.
Routine lap-chole,
nine-year-old patient,
the patient became
tachycardic and hypotensive.
Uh, I couldn't...
I couldn't locate
the bleeder initially,
then we discovered that his
pelvis was filled with blood.
Dr. Robbins
converted to an ex lap
and she found an injury to
the superior mesenteric artery.
Dr. Robbins tried a
repair, but the bleeding...
Edwards, what happened?
He died.
Okay.
- He was my patient and he died.
- Okay.
He was a little boy.
You know what? Here,
I want you to sit down.
No, I can't sit down.
A tear in a vessel with a
trocar insertion, it happens.
- Mm-hmm.
- It's not common,
but it happens.
And it's usually an easy fix.
But you can't fix
what you can't see.
I mean, you had no reason to
suspect bleeding, until you did.
By then, you were
racing the clock,
and the clock will
more often win.
Against all of us.
- I know you feel responsible...
- I mean, I am responsible.
You couldn't have known
you tore that vessel.
Dr. Robbins didn't catch
it. Dr. Minnick didn't catch it.
Anybody's hands could
have been on that trocar,
they wouldn't have caught it.
You lost. It's not
your fault, you lost.
Every good surgeon does.
It might be your worst,
but it won't be your last.
What was his name?
Matty.
What... what do I do next?
Okay, so if you think you're
gonna lose it, then I'll jump in.
I think I'll be fine. I just...
I guess I'm off the hook.
No. No!
I have a tip for you.
The work that's on the
page and not on the patient?
Take it home.
At least be comfortable.
Be in your pajamas.
- I'd just as soon stay here.
- Why is that?
Because my roommate
is a narrow-minded,
short-sighted, judgmental
and insulting piece of...
work.
Woo, and I am sorry, I should
not have said that to you.
He's mad you took the job.
Did you...
- Did you put me up for this?
- No.
It was all Bailey. I
thought it was smart.
April, Jackson can never
understand what you did.
He's not like you and me.
- Like you and me?
- He was raised with money.
Connections. A name.
You and I had to work for it.
I don't know. I mean,
Jackson has worked...
Jackson's always worked
hard. He worked hard in school.
He works hard now.
He's earned his
success. It's just...
He's never had
to worry, like us.
He's always known, if he
leaps, there's always a safety net.
The tough choices for
you and me are tougher.
I just, I felt like what
was asked of me
was bigger than me,
bigger than Richard.
It is. You saw that.
Put that away. Come on.
Let's go get some
dinner and celebrate this.
I don't exactly have a party
waiting for me at home either.
- I'd better not.
- Honey. You are the boss.
- Okay.
- All right.
Are we going to talk about
what happened today?
Can we not? Look,
I need a break.
I'm in the middle of
everything at the hospital, and...
You are in the
middle of everything?
Yes, me, Miranda.
I'm a resident,
so I want to side with them
because Minnick is great for us,
but the attendings
are my friends.
Now they stop talking when I'm
around because I'm married to you.
Yeah, I'm in it.
Well, if you're so in it,
whose side are you on?
I would like to know.
I just want to go to bed
and turn my brain
off until I fall asleep,
and stay out of it.
Once things start going wrong,
it's hard to break the cycle.
Murphy's law is not physics.
It's just a thing a guy said
to try and make
sense of a crappy day.
Just because things go wrong,
it doesn't mean they're
out of our control.
Pop the hood!
- You don't have to...
- Pop your hood.
Can you not? This is bad enough!
I pulled out your horn wire, so
you are gonna need to get that fixed.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
I mean... thank you.
It's on us to fix things.
You know, you could have
friends here, if you wanted to.
It's on us to take everything
that can go wrong...
and make it go right.
It's on us to try, anyway.