Dr. Legaspi?
No.
I'm Detective Graham.
This is Detective
Watkins. Chicago P.D.
We have this listed as,
uh, Dr. Legaspi's address.
Is everything all right?
Does Dr. Legaspi live here?
Yes, she does. She's inside.
Who are you?
I'm Dr. Weaver.
You live here too?
No. I-I don't. I'm just...
You know, I don't want to
be rude, but I'm... I'm freezing.
Oh, I'm sorry. By all means.
We just need to
speak to Dr. Legaspi.
Luka.
I think one of the kids
from the coffee shop
broke into the apartment.
I got breakfast.
I don't believe in breakfast.
It's the most important
meal of the day.
That's never been
medically proven.
Why are you up?
It's morning.
I got coffee, bagels
and a real-estate paper.
I'm thinking I should
get a new place.
What, did the hotel fire
you for getting up too early?
No. Well, somebody should.
Hey!
Look. There is an
entire warehouse in here
for the price of some condos.
That is very nice.
Especially in the summer
when all you smell is dead flesh.
That's the
slaughterhouse district.
It's still a good deal.
You know, first
you live in a boat,
then a hotel, and
now a meat plant.
What's next? Tree house?
Eh... Uh, you're really not
a morning person, are you?
Hey!
Hey, boy.
Hey. Good morning.
Nice toga.
Yeah. I seem to
have lost my clothes.
Oh. Your pants are on the couch.
And Norman had your socks,
so I put them in your shoes.
You named your dog "Norman"?
Well, that was his name
when I got him from the shelter.
He likes you. You think?
Yeah. Otherwise,
he would've bit you.
You want some
eggs? Oh, yeah. Sure.
Sorry.
My roommate. Think
we kept her up last night.
She seemed a little angry.
More jealous than anything.
You want some tea?
Uh, do you have any coffee?
No, sorry. I don't drink coffee.
That's okay.
Mm. Mm.
I don't usually do this.
Bring somebody home.
Trust me. I don't...
I don't either.
I really had a lot
of fun last night.
Me too.
Maybe we could do it
again some other time?
What about, um...?
Uh, well. You'll just
have to be a little quieter.
Ha-ha. Me?
Yeah. I think you yelled "stat."
I did not.
Are you working today?
Uh, I got a lecture
in the morning,
but I'll be in around 1.
Wanna have lunch?
Okay.
These are good eggs.
Oh. Thank you.
I was called down to
assess for suicidal ideation.
It was my job to determine
if the patient needed
to be admitted.
For a psych hold?
Yes.
And it was your professional
opinion that she did?
Dr. Legaspi?
Yes.
She was, um...
confused about
her sexual identity.
She was clinically
depressed and had spent
a considerable amount of time
planning to hurt herself.
You're awfully
quiet this morning.
Was just thinking. About?
Oh, nothing important.
I hope you're not worrying
about this silly
competency evaluation.
Silly evaluation will determine
whether or not I
keep my license.
They're merely a formality.
NASA astronauts
take fewer tests.
If I don't score
above average...
Mark, stop.
You're a brilliant doctor
regardless of
whether you put a...
A round peg in a square hole.
Where did you hear I put a
round peg in a square hole?
Hey, hey, hey, easy.
You don't want to shake up
that kid more than he has to be.
Listen, our baby's fine.
I've taken every
necessary precaution.
I've been extremely careful.
I haven't had a contraction
in two weeks, you know.
You still need to take it easy.
I'm medicated, I'm monitored.
I'm more than able
to go back to work.
So stop being such
a nervous Nellie.
Okay, one: Don't
ever call me Nellie.
And two: If you overdo it,
you can go into preterm...
Yes, yes, yes. I am a
doctor too, you know.
Well, this doctor's
orders are to slow down.
I remember giving you similar
orders after your surgery,
and I don't think you
listened to me either.
Meet me for lunch.
If you're not in labor.
Is that decaf?
Some guy swallowed a
couple dozen on a bet.
Now he's got tummy trouble.
No doubt. Any suggestions?
Yeah. Why don't you
get some colored rocks,
maybe one of those
deep-sea divers with bubbles.
Carter, you want a pet?
No, thanks.
How about some
coffee? What's this?
Some guy dropped it
off a few minutes ago.
You want me to read the card?
Hm. No, thank you.
Too late. It's from Rena.
Aah. Oh. Who's Rena?
Child-life specialist. Helped
me with an unruly kid last week.
Really? Hm.
So, what does she
look like, Carter?
Uh, you know, I don't know.
She's blond. Like, that tall.
Kind of cute in her
own way. Right?
Don't ask me. I
didn't get a gift basket.
Now, if she helped you, Carter,
why are you getting
all the goodies?
Because I gave her a good
assessment on her internship.
Actually, the card says...
Thank you very much, Amira.
"Thanks for a great evening.
You can bring your
own coffee next time..."
Must've been one hell
of an assessment, Carter.
We're gonna move you to
your own room. Okay, Mary?
What if Jesus comes
for me, and I'm not here?
I'll have one of the
nurses send him upstairs.
Will you? Yeah.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Hey.
Got a minute?
So Bloody Mary's back, eh?
Well, she's harmless.
Tried to page you.
You know, well, it's
been pretty crazy upstairs.
Not just because
of the patients.
So what was with the police?
Oh, you should have
stuck around. It was a party.
I had to be on
at 7:30. So did I.
I didn't abandon you on purpose.
I didn't say you did.
Okay. What did they say?
They were following
up on Shannon Wallace,
the attempted suicide who
caused that train derailment.
They probably wanna talk to you.
Why?
The patient has accused
me of sexual harassment.
What? Yeah.
She told the police that
I came on to her,
and I touched her.
Why would she say such a thing?
Well, she caused over 30 deaths.
She's probably trying to divert
the heat off of herself.
Yeah, but why... Why
would she accuse you of that?
How would she even
know you were...? Gay?
Yeah, I-I told her.
You what?
I was trying to help
her. Oh, no. Kim.
Kim, what were you thinking?
I don't know, Kerry.
That she needed help?
Yes, so you disclose
your personal life
to an unstable patient
who you don't even know?
I ca... I-I...
Mr. Hollis is crashing.
Okay.
I'll see you later. Yeah.
Elizabeth, I thought
you were on bed rest.
Hardly.
Is this another one
of my patients, Peter?
What?
Well, you seem to
have taken on several
additional responsibilities
during my absence.
Well, I didn't have
really much choice.
Oh. So you had to organize
the educational conferences
for the next two months
and do my interview?
Well, I thought you were on
medical leave for preterm labor.
Romano told me to
keep this place running.
Well... I was on medical leave.
But now I'm back.
And I am ready to resume
all of my responsibilities
as associate chief of surgery.
And if anyone has
a problem with that...
they can come and see me.
Think Greene developed
that brain tumor
after she got pregnant?
Ahem. Can I help you?
Oh. A glass of
water would be nice.
My throat's a little dry.
Has anybody seen you?
Why, no.
I didn't want to bother anybody.
That's why we're here.
But you need to check
in with the receptionist
at the Admit desk.
And then you can
speak with a nurse.
I'm afraid there's nothing
they can do for me.
I'm dying.
Who's your doctor?
I don't have one. Never did.
Then how do you
know you're dying?
Oh. It's in the cards, dear.
Ah, you read tarot cards? Mm-hm.
Cards, palms, tea leaves.
Give me your hand.
Ah.
Come on. Ha-ha.
I won't hurt you.
Oh, my.
You do have a bit of a
black cloud hanging over you,
don't you, dear?
See, there... There's
a crack in your lifeline.
It's probably dry skin.
Listen, while I'm here,
why don't you let
me check you over.
Well, you can if you want to.
The cards have already told me.
I will be dead by sundown.
Bolus a liter of saline
and call Animal Control.
How's our old friend
Super Larry doing?
He's got a fever of 100.8,
but no source of infection.
You might wanna check
for an aspiration pneumonia.
Had one last year.
Hey, wake up, Super Larry.
You know, get a head CT.
He's got abrasions.
He might have fallen.
Well, you would too if
you slept on a sidewalk.
Hey, Dr. Weaver. This
is, uh, Detective Graham.
You ran off before I got
a chance to talk to you
this morning. Why do
you want to talk to me?
You saw a patient by the
name of Shannon Wallace
that Dr. Legaspi
also treated...? Yeah.
I called for the
psych consultation.
But you didn't stay with her?
No, we had a
mass-casualty situation.
She only had minor injuries.
So you effectively left
Dr. Legaspi alone
with the patient?
I suppose.
Are you aware that the
patient said Dr. Legaspi
sexually assaulted her?
Yes. And it's ridiculous.
The young woman had
psychological problems.
She tried to kill herself.
Nonetheless, we have to
follow up the accusations.
What exactly is your
relationship with Dr. Legaspi?
We're colleagues.
Do you live together?
No.
But you were at her
house early this morning...
Well, to be honest, I
really don't have time
for this right now.
I'm sorry.
County is hard-core
blood and guts.
But I guarantee...
you'll rack up more
surgical hours here
than anywhere in the country.
I must admit I'm
intrigued, Dr. Romano.
I'll be in touch.
I look forward to that.
Is she another one
of my replacements?
Lizzie, my, how you've grown.
How you feeling?
I was doing wonderfully
until I got in to work.
What work? I thought
you're on bed rest.
See, I wish people
would stop saying that.
I took a little time off
to recoup some energy,
but now I'm fine.
Oh, that would explain
the, uh, baby monitor
I see strapped to your belly.
Or are you just glad to see me?
I spent 48 hours
in the hospital.
Yes, I've been doing
home monitoring.
But I can assure
you, I'm ready, willing
and more than able
to return to work.
Mm-hm. For how long? A week?
Look, I appointed
you associate chief
so that I'd have a
lieutenant on the front lines
that I could count on.
Now, you want to be barefoot
and pregnant in the kitchen,
you have my blessing.
Go forth and multiply.
But this is why surgery's
an old boy's club.
Have you any idea
of the hospital's policy
on sexual harassment
and discrimination?
We still have one
of those? Yes, we do.
And I'd be so happy
to reacquaint you
on the section of
maternity leave.
Well, I'd rather do a
bowel resection. Thank you.
Do you know I read somewhere
about a pregnant woman
who killed her husband
and got off on a
temporary-insanity defense
because of her
hormone imbalance.
Okay, you want to work. Fine.
We're presenting three
cases for M and M tomorrow.
Pull the charts from
Medical Records,
track down the
x-rays in Radiology,
and get the slides
from Pathology.
No. No. I want back in Surgery.
Uh-uh-uh. First things first.
Then you can set up the,
uh, projection microscope
and make 35-millimeter slides
of the gross
pathology specimens.
Anything else? Yeah.
Make sure there's coffee
and doughnuts for 100.
Uh, especially ones
with little sprinkles on top.
Give them back.
Give them back! Shh.
Mr. Perkins, keep it
down... Give them back!
Sh, sh, sh.
This bitch stole my teeth.
You call me that one more time,
I'm gonna put that
Foley bag in you.
Okay, here. You might want to,
uh, wash these off bef...
fore you put them back in.
Abby. Can you help me with this?
Sure.
So how long has she been sick?
A few days. I-I thought
it was just a cold.
Any fever?
I don't think so.
Any problems with birth?
History of lung disease?
No, no. She's been
a really healthy baby.
Dr. Kovac, could I speak
with you for a minute?
Yeah. Get a quick set of vitals
and put her on a pulse ox.
So have you figured out
what's causing
Super Larry's fever?
No, no. Not yet.
I'm still waiting on the
lab for his blood work.
Maybe something will turn up.
Okay.
Luka, wait.
Uh... you're probably wondering
what that police detective
was all about today.
Not really.
There were some charges
filed against Dr. Legaspi.
Oh. I... I'd like to
keep the rumors
to a minimum... for
Dr. Legaspi's sake.
I understand. I only bring it up
because this place
seems to feed on gossip.
And in light of an inves...
Dr. Weaver?
Dr. Romano's looking
for you. Thank you.
He said he wants to see
you at his office immediately.
Thanks. He also said if you
didn't come up the moment
you heard this message, he
was going to fire both of us.
Temp is 100.2, pulse is
120, with a pulse ox of 94.
That's not too bad. No wheezing.
I appreciated some retractions.
A little.
We'll get a chest
film just to make sure.
In the meantime, put some saline
in her nose for a few minutes
and, uh, use the bulb syringe.
See if that helps.
Is she gonna be okay?
Well, she doesn't have a fever,
and her lungs are pretty
clear, which is good.
Yeah, but she still
seems to have trouble
catching her breath.
Well, babies tend to
breathe through their nose,
so they have some difficulty
when they're stuffed up.
But I'm sure she'll be fine
once I help her with that.
He knows that I'm here, right?
Yes.
And he is aware that I am
working in the ER today?
I would imagine so.
Well, he made this sound
like it was some
kind of emergency.
I'm sure he won't
be much longer.
Okay. He can page
me when he's ready.
Dr. Legaspi.
Kerry.
What are you waiting
for, Dr. Weaver?
A written invitation?
Is that it?
Is it fixed? Can I go?
No. We have to put a splint
on you and check another x-ray.
Just try and relax, okay?
Malik... Ow.
Why don't you finish this splint
and order up a Chem-7,
cholesterol and a tox screen.
You got a skin infection
on your forehead.
And it could move into an
infection around your brain.
How's it going, Dave? Uh... Oh.
The Weasel is suffering
from a self-inflicted wound.
Weasel? That's my ring name.
Yeah. Todd's a
basement wrestler.
I had an uncle who
was a closet ballerina.
So is your friend
there a wrestler too?
James is awesome.
Calls himself Mr. Midnight.
How'd you manage to do this?
He sliced himself
with a razor blade.
It's called blading.
Fans love it.
Yeah, I bet.
You got this, Dave?
Yeah. I'm just
trying to convince
Superfly here that,
slicing open his scalp,
not such a good idea.
Update his tetanus
if he needs it.
Uh-huh. See?
There's another risk.
Tetanus. Huh? Then, of course,
there's nerve damage, otitis.
You could put your
eye out, you know?
A-and don't forget
about scarring.
Scarring's... That's
not a good one.
Chicks don't dig scarring.
They don't dig that
Frankenstein look,
if you know what I'm
saying? Right, Dr. Greene?
What's that?
Never mind.
At least give me a heads-up.
This is the first I've
heard of these allegations.
But you must have
had some indication
that she was a lesbian.
What has that got
to do with anything?
It seems to me that's the crux
of the problem, don't you think?
No. The problem seems
to be a false accusation
from a patient with
psychological problems.
She could have just as easily
made a similar indictment
against one of the male doctors.
Yeah, but she didn't, did she?
Have you had any
other complaints
against Legaspi in
the ER? Of course not.
And, uh, she's never displayed
any unacceptable sexual behavior
that you've witnessed?
Well...?
What do you think?
I'm getting a sneaking suspicion
that you're holding out on me.
Oh, please, Robert.
I think you're
trying to protect her.
Of course I'm trying to
protect her. You should be too.
She is a damn good doctor.
I'm calling for an emergency
disciplinary hearing today
with you and Anspaugh. Why?
You know these
charges are a joke.
No one's laughing, Kerry.
This is a witch hunt. No,
this is damage control.
Okay. Are we finished?
For now.
Can I give you
some friendly advice?
No!
Well, we spent an
hour hooking up two of
my grandfather's polo
ponies to this old pushcart.
Were you insane?
We were, like, 9. We
didn't know any better.
It was so cool.
It was just like
Spartacus, you know?
Right up until the part when
my grandmother sees us.
Oh, no. She screams.
The horses spook.
My cousin, as usual, bails.
The horses go one
way, I go the other,
and I'm left holding
onto the reins.
Um...
Actually, uh, I'm still
working on it. Thanks.
Thank you.
Yeah. So, um...
How was your... How
was the seminar today?
It was a lecture on
developmental psychology.
Freud, Piaget, Kohlberg.
It was boring.
Blast from the past, huh?
It's like being back in college.
Well, I am in college.
No, I meant as an undergraduate.
I am.
Mm.
Excuse me. I thought you
said you were a Pedes intern.
No, I'm doing a
child-life internship
in the Pedes Department.
I need 480 hours
of clinical
experience to certify.
And I figured if I start now,
I'll be done by the
time I graduate.
Graduate.
How old are you?
Twenty. Well, in September.
You're 19?
Yeah. Are you okay?
Oh, my God.
Hi.
Is she doing better?
Well, she's still not
getting as much air
into her lungs as we'd like.
It might just be her cold.
But we're gonna get a
chest x-ray just in case.
Can I go with her?
Of course.
Are you all right?
Yeah.
She just hasn't let
me get much sleep
in the last couple days.
Why don't you get a cup
of coffee while we wait.
Okay.
Hey. Hey.
You got a minute?
Sure.
What's up?
I just had...
Um. I just had
lunch with Rena...
and I think there's a problem.
What? She, uh, chews
with her mouth open?
She's young.
So? You're not exactly
an old man yourself.
You could use someone
to loosen you up a little bit.
She's really young.
What is she, like...
23 or something?
Twenty-two?
Is she 20?
In September. She's a teenager.
Carter. I know.
You didn't ask?
Women don't like
to tell you their age.
Well, she's not a
woman. She's a girl.
She's a woman. Believe me.
Did you sleep with her?
Oh, my God. You did.
I didn't know.
You couldn't tell?
Did you break up with her?
Not yet. What are
you waiting for?
Are you gonna call your lawyer?
Well, she's very
mature for her age.
She's cool. She's...
She's fun. She's...
She's Britney
Spear" little sister.
Thank you.
Excuse me?
Yeah?
Did they bring May to Radiology?
No. Not yet.
Then where is she?
Oh.
They must have picked her up
when I was in the hall
talking to Dr. Carter.
Darryl. Hey, Darryl.
Did you take the
little girl in Exam 4?
Not yet.
You didn't take her?
No. She's my next pickup, okay?
I-If he doesn't have
her, then who does?
She might've been
moved to another room.
Hey, hold that elevator.
Hoo. Is that May Jeffries?
Who?
Uh, May Jeffries.
She's a 4 month
old in Exam 4. Sorry.
Please tell me what's happening.
Okay. Just a second.
Haleh, did you move a
4-month-old baby out of Exam 4?
No.
I can't find her.
Where is she?
I need Security.
Where's Secur...?
What did they do...?
I need someone to
lock down the ER, now.
Dr. Greene?
Uh, Just a second.
Can you call...?
Dr. Greene, I'm
missing a patient, a baby.
I think someone
took her from Exam 4.
Oh, my God. What?
I-I was waiting for
transport to Radiology.
I just stepped outside
to talk to Carter...
Where's my baby?!
Alert Security.
Sorry. May! May!
Grab nurses. We'll do
a room-by-room search.
Hey!
Please... Look... Look out!
Uh...
Hold it! Hold it!
Wait.
What's your problem?
Sorry.
You didn't see
anyone enter the room?
Did you? What?
See anybody? A doctor,
a nurse, an orderly?
No. No.
I feel like I should
be helping them look.
Look. We've... We've
got that covered, okay?
We're searching the hospital.
How long were
you out of the room?
Like a minute. Maybe two.
You know, maybe
the person that took her
is distraught over recently
losing their own baby.
I could check the
hospital records.
We'll tell you if that's
something we want to pursue.
Did you see anyone
unusual in the vicinity?
Someone you didn't
recognize? This is an ER.
It's filled with strangers. I've
told you everything I know.
I feel like I'm
wasting my time here.
I-I-I should be doing something.
Just a few more questions.
It's okay, dear.
Sometimes God
calls little babies
home to be his angels.
Is there someone you would
like me to call to be with you?
Your husband, maybe?
I'm divorced.
What is his name?
Ed.
Ed Jeffries. But he
lives in Boston now.
Okay. The police would like
to ask you some questions.
Do you feel up to that?
Okay. I will be back when
they're done, and we'll talk.
Okay.
Hey. Hey.
How's she doing?
Better than I would be.
Um... how was your
meeting with Romano?
Homophobic. Misogynistic.
Ha. The usual.
Degrading.
What did you tell him?
The truth.
That Shannon Wallace
was a young woman
experiencing a severe
sexual-identity crisis.
She needed to know that
being gay is not an affliction.
Yeah. And what did
you tell him about us?
Oh.
Oh, I see.
Uh. Don't worry, Kerry.
Your secret's safe with me.
No, that's not what I meant.
No? No, what did
you mean? No, no.
You think that I am the only one
who has problems with this.
Th-th-th-that it's
universally accepted.
But that is not true. So, what?
So we're supposed to
skulk about in the shadows
because some narrow-minded
individuals disapprove...?
No. No. I just think that
you are fooling yourself if y...
How many openly gay women
do you know in hospital
administrative positions?
Kerry... None. It
doesn't happen.
What does that have
to do with anything?
I'm trying to explain to you
why this is difficult for me.
Guess what, Kerry,
this isn't about you.
This is about a
confused and frightened
young woman who
would rather kill herself
than deal with the
stigma of being gay.
Maybe it is about you.
Abby? What are you doing?
Nothing.
I, um... I heard about
a baby that got scooped up...
with the laundry
in another hospital.
I know it's stupid. I
just... I don't know.
Can you give me a hand
with a squirmer? Sure.
Sit still, Jason.
I just need to
look into your ears.
Do you think it's his adenoids?
His brother had to have
them taken out with his tonsils.
Abby, can you hold
him still, please?
Uh, Haleh, can you help Carter?
Sorry.
Excuse me.
Did you find her? Not yet.
Okay, I was thinking,
she's sick, right?
So whoever took her might...
Might take her to a pharmacy
to get some Infant Tylenol.
And they'll need
diapers and formula.
Right. Thanks. And
it also seems to me
that she's not in the
hospital anymore.
So shouldn't you guys
be setting up a roadblock
or checking the neighborhood?
We're doing everything we can.
Shouldn't we have
heard something by now?
I mean, the chances of
finding her get worse every...
Every passing second, right?
Abby? Abby?
Did you get the labs
back on the jaundice guy?
Who?
Jagadeeshan. No.
Oh, could you try and find them?
No. Sorry.
These are the most
recent photos I have.
Can I have them?
Look, uh...
I promise to return them.
May I, please?
Thank you.
Mrs. Jeffries, I know
I can't say anything
to change the situation.
I just wanted to tell
you how sorry I am.
She's my only baby.
I know.
I'm sure she's gonna be fine.
Why would somebody take my baby?
Mr. Kinney can go home.
There's no known cure
for being a pain in the ass.
Hm-hm.
Any news on the baby?
Uh, nothing yet.
Dr. Greene, labs are
back on that wrestler.
Anything show up?
I don't know. What
were you looking for?
Nothing on the tox screen.
Cholesterol level's a
little high for a teenager.
Too much fast food.
I think he's on steroids.
He's got acute acne,
hirsutism, aggression.
What teenage boy doesn't?
What's the turnaround
time on a steroids test?
Five days?
At least.
Hey, look, if you think
he's using, just ask him.
He might cop to it.
I thought you forgot about me.
Look, man, I need
to go home, all right?
I ordered some tests.
What kind of tests?
The kind that show that
you're using steroids.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
I think you do.
What you might not know
is that you're putting
yourself at risk
for kidney failure,
stroke, impotence...
You're crazy.
Where are you going? Home.
Sit back down, James.
Screw you, man! I'm leaving!
No, you gotta stay here
until your parents
come and get you.
You called my parents?
Todd left. Somebody's
got to get you home.
Man, forget this! Come on.
Leave me alone!
Yah!
Hey, Dr. Greene.
I'm okay. I'm okay.
Just go get him.
Don't let him leave.
Hey. Hey, man,
what are you doing?
Leaving. Why? What
are you afraid of?
I'm not afraid of anything.
I've had enough of this place.
We weren't finished
working you up.
I mean, we're only here to help.
Then let me go.
What's the big rush?
All right, look. Look. Just...
Just take it easy, all right?
Stay out of my way, man!
Look, I don't want to hurt you!
Look, look, look. Just relax,
all right? Come back inside.
I mean it, man. You
can't keep me here!
My old man will be pissed
if you don't let me leave!
Your father would want
us to take care of you.
No, that doc's gonna
tell him I use steroids!
Look. My old man will
kill me if he finds out!
He doesn't have
to find out. All right?
But he said he
was gonna tell him!
Look, James, you
need to just settle down
and come inside, okay?
Look... you don't
know my father.
He'll kill me if he finds out.
You're right. I don't
know your father.
But I know the type.
Trust me, okay?
Okay? We'll work something out.
Right, Dr. Greene?
Sure. Come on.
You have my word on it.
Deal? Come on.
Hey, who's got
the guy in Exam 2?
Carter.
He's been restrained
in there for hours.
I hope so.
Did you see all
those bite marks?
Those are self-inflicted.
That guy practically
ate himself alive.
Get somebody from
Psych. Let's get rid of him.
We've been waiting. Psych's
been slower than usual
answering their consults.
I hear they got a
shakeup going on up there.
Dr. Legaspi's being fired.
Let's keep gossip
to a minimum, Haleh.
That's not gossip.
The gossip is she's
a lesbian. Legaspi?
That's what I heard.
Really? Oh, uh-huh.
Follow my finger.
What happened?
He got whacked in
the head by a patient.
Show me your teeth. I'm fine.
You should get a head CT.
I-I'm sorry about that,
man. I got a little worked up.
That's what steroid
rage will do to you.
Cleo, could you, uh,
find James a bed, please?
Sure. Come on.
Mark, you should get a head CT.
He didn't mean
it. He's just scared.
Scared he's gonna get busted.
Scared he's gonna get
the crap beat up of him.
The kid's petrified
of his old man.
I got a feeling he's
an abuse case.
Abuse? The kid's a tank.
The steroids, the aggression,
the tough-guy routine.
It's a... It's a defense
mechanism, trust me.
I don't think you
should tell his parents.
Too late. They're
on their way. Wha...?
I said we'd work something
out. I gave him my word.
Well, you shouldn't
have. He's not your patient.
Tumor!
What was that?
The old Dr. Greene
would have helped this kid.
I am.
Maybe there's something to
this competency stuff, huh?
Keep it up, Malucci. You'll
be looking for a new job.
Her name's May.
And she's really...
got a pretty bad cold,
so... if you could
just please return her.
She's just a baby.
It doesn't matter
why you took her.
It's just that sh-sh... She
really needs medication.
If you could just
bring her back.
Have somebody bring her in.
And drop her off at
the police department.
Call an ambulance.
You should have your coat on.
I'm okay.
Why don't you come back inside?
Come on. You can
help me cast the twins
who rode their wagon
down the basement steps.
You should get someone else.
I want you.
Um... Uh...
Could you just leave
me alone, please?
I can't do that.
I lost that woman's baby.
No, you didn't. Yes, I did.
No, you didn't.
Real nice. Can't
take notes in class.
Dad, it's not that bad.
How we doing in here?
You a nurse?
Doctor.
You Greene? Malucci.
They told me I was supposed
to wait here for Dr. Greene.
I was assisting Dr. Greene.
Yeah, fine, whatever.
So is he gonna be okay or what?
Well, he dislocated his
hand, but it'll heal. Hm.
What about his head?
He didn't injure his head.
Oh, no?
Jumping around in a
costume like an idiot.
Seems like a sign of brain
damage, if you ask me.
Yeah. Can I speak
with you outside, please?
Yeah.
Get yourself together.
We're leaving right after this.
What are you doing?
What?
Your son, you
know, hurt himself.
He... He needs a
little compassion.
And... And you come in
here and you humiliate him.
You don't know him.
He needs discipline.
He's always doing
stupid stuff like this.
Ever wonder why?
Maybe there's a reason
he behaves this way.
Yeah. It's called being crazy.
And a cure for it's a
good kick in the ass.
Around here we
call that abuse, man.
Oh, get out of here. Hold on.
Where are you going?
Go work on your golf game, doc.
Golf?
What the hell is going on?
Son of a bitch, I'm
gonna sue your ass!
Oh. Kiss it while you're at
it. Malucci, get out of here.
The guy abuses his
son. Malucci, out now!
Let's go!
Why don't you let
me take a look at that?
Get away from me.
Ah-ah.
Are you sure you've
done this before?
Yes.
Ow!
I'm sorry.
I'm having a... A little
trouble finding the vein.
Can I get another
nurse over here, please?!
Shh!
Let me just take a little break.
Yeah.
Ow.
Is there anything I can get you?
Just my baby.
Maybe you should go home.
I'm sure someone will
call you if we hear anything.
I don't think I can
leave without her.
Okay.
Oh, not you again.
This is County.
County, this is
Rescue 62 en route
with what appears to be a
3-to 4-month-old infant girl
found abandoned
on the El platform.
What's her status?
Pulse 120. Resps 60.
Got a weak cry and
is cold to the touch.
Uh, is there any sign of trauma?
No. Is she alert?
Hard to tell. She's a baby.
Is she making eye
contact? Not really.
What's your ETA? Less than five.
Did you talk to Rena? What?
Your, um...
That child-life
specialist... Oh.
No, not yet. But I'm...
You know, where are they?
It's been, like,
almost 10 minutes.
I think I hear an ambulance.
Oh, God. I hope it's her.
I'm sure it is.
It's gotta be, right? Yeah.
I mean, how many kids
can they find in one day?
Open up! Okay!
Okay. Pulse ox is down to 89.
Abby, is that her?
It's her.
I need a core temperature,
put the monitors on
and get me a 24-gauge angiocath.
Where'd they find her?
May? Is she okay?
El station. Everything's
gonna be fine.
Whoever stole her
panicked and dumped her.
Let the doctors work.
No, I want to stay here.
Come on. May!
Okay Abby, I got it from here.
I've got to start an IV.
I think you should step out.
Let me do this, Luka, please.
Hypothermic. Core temp, 93.
Okay. Put her on
heated humidified O-2,
get a warm blanket,
some warming lamps...
and a set of heated D5,
and a half at 30 cc's per hour.
Anything else?
No. That's good.
Okay. You're okay, May.
Shh.
You're safe now.
You're gonna be okay. Sh-sh-sh.
Oh, yeah.
Let me get this here.
You're gonna be okay.
This is pathetic.
Not a single
trauma in the bunch.
Oh. Hello.
That's mine. What are you doing?
Go home, Dave.
I'm on till 8:00.
No, you're not.
As a matter of fact,
you're not on for
the rest of the week.
Wait, wait. Says who?
Says me.
Does Weaver know
about this? She will.
Is this because I
defended myself?
Mark!
Goodbye, Dave.
I just heard that
you were attacked.
Why didn't you call me?
No big deal. I just
ran into an elbow.
Well, did you get a CT?
Ahem. No. I'm fine. Really.
I'm just glad I didn't opt
for the surgical Velcro
when they put my
skull back together.
How are you doing?
Well, Romano's
trying to replace me.
Um, he wouldn't
let me do surgery.
So I spent the day
doing wedding stuff.
I'm not wearing a kilt.
You'd look really handsome.
Dr. Romano's
looking for you again.
Oh, wonderful. Hey, um, Mark.
This, uh, came for you today.
I-I'm gonna be in
Romano's office.
These are my competency results.
You wait until the
end of the shift?
I... I'm sorry. I forgot.
I've be... I've been busy.
You forgot? How
could you forget?
You wanna open them?
No.
Oh, Mark.
I passed.
Don't look so surprised.
Stop it!
Well, you had your
doubts, didn't you?
You had your moments.
Dr. Greene,
Dr. Corday, good night.
Good night, Carter.
Hey, where you
going, Georgia? Home.
I guess you're not dying
today after all then, huh?
John!
Hey. Hey.
What are you doing down here?
Looking for you. I'm off.
You almost finished?
I got like two hours
of charts to finish here.
Can you do it over
garlic noodles?
I don't think so.
Come on. I'll get some
takeout, a bottle of wine,
you can do your charts.
Uh, ah... I don't drink.
And... it's illegal for
you to purchase alcohol.
The age thing again.
I like you a lot, Rena.
You wish I was older.
I guess I should
enjoy this while it lasts.
Uh, I'm sorry. I
didn't mean to...
No. Please. Hm. Forget it.
I'm young. We heal fast.
I'll see you around. Yeah.
Are Dr. Romano and
Dr. Anspaugh still here?
Uh, they're waiting for
you in the conference room.
Dr. Weaver. Better
late than never.
Let's cut to the
chase, shall we?
So that we can all get out
of here and go home. Okay.
Dr. Legaspi recently,
for whatever reasons, had
what I hope was a
momentary lapse in judgment.
I take offense to that.
Really? Well, I take offense
to you having come out
to your patient, which
was grossly inappropriate...
Dr. Legaspi is a valuable asset
to the Psychiatry Department
as well as this
hospital as a whole.
I think that her
instincts were correct
and her intentions
very honorable...
considering the situation.
Honorable, perhaps.
Stupid, definitely.
Oh, come on, Robert.
Patients with
psychological problems
falsely accuse their
doctors of all sorts of things.
I had a guy today blame
me for hypnotizing him
in order to drink his blood.
Well, we'll have to look
into that another day, Donald.
But the fact is, to the
best of my knowledge,
you are not actually a vampire.
Dr. Legaspi, however,
is a lesbian. Am I right?
I've never hidden that fact
from this administration
or my colleagues.
Or from your patients,
for that matter,
wherein lies the problem.
There's a difference
between being gay and
being a child molester.
Okay. My recommendation
is administrative leave
pending the criminal hearing.
I think that's premature.
No. It's preemptive.
If we get really lucky,
there won't be any charges
and you can come
right back to work
having learned a lesson,
albeit the hard way.
Do you have anything
to add, Dr. Weaver...
considering you are one of them?
Them?
A female physician dealing with
female patients. No.
Yes. I think that Dr. Legaspi...
is a wonderful doctor.
And I... don't think that
she did any of the things
that she's accused of doing.
Well, that's well-spoken.
Kerry, that's very convincing.
Please remind me never to
ask you to testify on my behalf.
Okay. Meeting is adjourned.
I have dinner plans.
Pay no attention to him.
This, too, will pass.
I'm sorry.
I'm s... Kim.
Kim, please don't.
Kim... Please.
Uh, please...
Please stop. I'm so...
I'm so sorry.
Let's just get out of
here and talk about this.
There's really
nothing to talk about.
What did you expect me to say?
I am so sorry, Kim.
Me too.
Go back to your life, Kerry...
Don't... No, don't.
You can't do this.
We have something good.
What? What do we have?
A relationship that
you're ashamed to
acknowledge in public?
I know, you're right. I
wish I could be like you.
I wish I could be as confident
and secure with this as you are.
But I am not you.
I have been on the
outside my whole life
fighting for acceptance
and respect.
And now you're asking
me to do it all over again?
I'm not asking you for anything.
Don't, please. I just...
I... I need more time.
I can't... I can't
do this right now.
Please, Kim. Kim.
I missed you.
Hi.
She's smiling.
All her tests came back normal.
She wasn't hurt.
She's gonna be fine.
But I would like to keep
her overnight for observation.
Is that necessary? You just
said she's gonna be okay.
Just a precaution. I
pulled some strings.
And got her a private room,
and I'm having them
set up a bed for you.
Oh, okay. Thanks.
Is there anything else you need?
No, she's all I need.