Previously on Grey's Anatomy...
Your tumor is smart.
But so am I. I can beat it.
Any one of these approaches
would likely kill the patient?
I refuse to spend the
last few months of my life
feeling like a pile of crap.
I am going to give you
more than a few months.
Are you nervous?
Nobody thinks that this can
work. No one understands it.
You get at my tumor,
you get at my knowledge,
I get at my life.
Each card represents a fetus that
I'm gonna teach Robbins how to fix.
I'm not ready to
take this over yet.
Where's Dr. Herman? She
stepped out. What do you need?
It's Glenda Castillo.
I need you to scan me.
- Let's go.
I need Herman right now.
Arizona. It's time.
Amelia?
I'll get the OR prepped.
You'll inform the patient?
In 1888, William Williams Keen
became one of the first surgeons
to successfully
remove a brain tumor.
A big win. It's true.
You can look it up.
What's harder to find, however,
are stories of all the
times old Double-Billy K
tried to pull a tumor
out of a brain and lost.
The losses must have happened.
A surgeon must always
be prepared to lose.
And in neurosurgery,
with the big tumors,
we lose those battles
as often as we succeed.
The key, though, win
or lose, is to never fail.
And the only way
to fail is not to fight.
So, you fight until you
can't fight anymore.
Word's getting around.
You're gonna
have a full gallery.
Everybody wants to see the show.
You feeling good, confident?
You're not worried, are
you? Are you worried?
This is where you
leave me, Dr. Hunt.
Oh.
You okay? Do you
need anything? I'm fine.
I'm great. I just...
Prep alone. So...
I will see you
on the other side.
Okay.
Okay. Okay.
We are doing this, okay?
We're doing this.
If she's awake, she'll
tell you for the 15th time
to save her child's
life, not hers.
Listen to her, let
her say her piece,
then you do what
needs to be done.
I don't think that I can
do... No, I know I can't.
You can. You will.
ARIZONA: Nicole.
Let's get you inside now, okay?
Okay, I have everything set up.
You will have all of your films,
your favorite scrub nurse...
What is happening?
I'm being a superhero.
Okay.
There's a scientific study
that shows that if you stand
like this in superhero pose
for just five minutes
before a job interview,
or a big presentation
or a really hard task,
you will not only
feel more confident,
you will perform
measurably better.
Seriously?
Seriously.
You feel it?
We're superheroes.
We are superheroes.
Hold up your head and enter
the arena and face the enemy.
Fight until you
can't fight anymore.
Never let go. Never give up.
Here's the plan. We're
gonna embolize the tumor
to see if we can reverse the
effects on mom's circulation.
And if not, then I'm afraid...
Where's Herman?
Never run.
Never surrender.
Glenda's platelet
count is critically low,
so, we need to give
her six packs of platelets
to avoid liver capsule bleeding.
And then we'll perform the
fetoscopy to reverse the cascade...
You keep saying
"we," but I only see you.
Where the hell is
Herman? She's not coming.
What do you mean,
"She's not coming"?
Fight the good fight.
Start the clock, please.
You fight...
Ten blade.
Even when it seems inevitable
that you're about
to go down swinging.
Mmm-mmm.
So, this is a regular thing.
You all come up here and
you watch surgeries. Why?
Not just surgeries.
The big surgeries, the whale
surgeries, the rare ones, the crazy ones.
I mean, you're on
the edge of your seat.
The patient could die.
This is life or death.
The adrenaline, the rush...
Okay, so you watch,
like, the worst day
of a person's life like a movie.
No, not like a movie.
That's insulting. This
is not entertainment.
Huh.
"Movie."
Oh, okay. This is where
the good part starts.
Excuse me. Ah, thanks
for saving my seat.
Well, I almost got
my arm torn off,
but, uh, your
timing is excellent.
Ah, the dye's coming
in. It's kick-off time.
Let's go ahead
and inject the dye.
Lights, please.
What does the dye do?
Oh, the dye makes
the whole tumor glow
so that we can see
where the tumor ends
and where the brain begins.
Nice to see you face-to-face.
Now, you have to go.
Bipolars, please.
This is my favorite part.
Yeah, I thought only the
tumor was supposed to glow.
That is the tumor.
Oh, we are not in
Kansas anymore.
The baby's anemic.
Let's transfuse him.
40 milliliters of
irradiated PRBC.
Robbins, we need
to get in and out.
Glenda's pressure
is through the roof.
If we don't stop this
bleeding, the baby will die.
And the idea is to save both of
them, and I think that I can do it.
Do you think, or you know?
I know I can.
Robbins, I respect you
and consider you a friend,
so, it is with kindness
when I tell you
that you're only half a
fetal surgeon, not even.
You're half a fellow. You
brought this patient to me.
No, I brought this
patient to your boss.
I have spent the past
four and a half months
getting everything
that Dr. Herman knows
pounded into my brain.
Do you hear yourself?
"Four and a half months"?
You want her hands,
you have them right here.
22-gauge needle.
Here you go.
Hey, hey, Chief, any chance
you could lose me tonight?
What? No.
Oh, I just thought that
it's kind of quiet down here,
and now, Dr. Herman's
surgery is happening.
Every other resident is
watching that surgery.
I'm sorry you pulled
the short straw,
but I need someone down here.
Oh, so, wait. I'm gonna be the
only resident who's down here?
Just you. I'm counting on you to
hold down the fort. Can I do that?
Yes. Absolutely. I'm
your girl. Thank you.
Hunt, you pushed
my meniscus tonight.
What, uh... What
gives? I needed the OR.
Shepherd has taken Dr. Herman
up for her brain surgery.
Wait, Dr. Herman's going in now?
I thought she had another month.
Okay. Right here.
It's invaded the
chiasmatic cistern a little.
Dr. Shepherd is examining
the margins of the tumor.
Who's subbing in
for you? I'm sorry?
We're gonna be here
for another 14 hours,
probably more.
Definitely more.
You know the protocol.
Over 12 hours, have another
resident sub in to replace you.
So, you can recharge,
rest, and return.
Who's subbing in for you?
Hey, I have been
planning this for months.
There's kind of no
substitute for me.
Well, then there's no
substitute for me, either.
If you're here, I am
here. We're superheroes.
I mean, I'd do the thing
with the hands on the hips,
but I can't break scrub.
Okay.
Retract here, please, Edwards.
It's not working. I can't
embolize all the vessels.
I handpicked you. And
you are letting me down.
I need to open her
up. Oh, absolutely not.
We'd have to increase
Glenda's anesthesia, and...
He's got persistent decels.
I'm not just questioning your
abilities. Now, I'm questioning mine.
All right, I could open her up,
exteriorize the uterus and
then resect the entire tumor.
The prolonged anesthesia could be
catastrophic to both mom and baby.
If you're gonna open her up, then
you should go ahead and deliver.
No. It's not an option.
This is mirror syndrome,
Robbins. You know that.
The sicker the baby gets,
the sicker Glenda gets.
We deliver, Glenda
will get better.
I said it's not an option.
He's not far enough
along. He won't survive.
Page Alex Karev.
Okay. Wait, stop.
What are you doing?
We're delivering this baby.
It's not gonna be easy,
but Karev may be able to
keep him alive once he's out.
No. Put that phone down.
Bailey, I can do this.
Arizona, your mentor is on an OR
table right now with her skull open
and you think you
have something to prove.
I'm not gonna let you
do that with this patient.
You want to open her up? Do
it, but we are delivering this child.
Page Dr. Karev. Okay.
Dr. Shepherd is now cutting the
tumor away from the gyrus rectus.
Gyrus rectus?
The area responsible
for our sense of smell.
Shh.
I thought Arizona would be here.
She's in surgery.
Wait, fetal surgery?
By herself? Shh.
Oh, relax. It's not the
ballet, or whatever.
Though...
Though it is a kind of a dance.
There's grace, a rhythm,
an elegance.
Oh, okay. I got shushed,
but the purple prose is fine.
Shh.
Okay.
She is gonna pull
it off, though, right?
Yes. Yeah, she will.
Dr. Shepherd is now
clearing the tumor away
from the midbrain structures,
the fornix, the thalamus.
It shouldn't be
taking this long.
We're behind. Already.
Uh, using extreme care not to
violate the anterior commissure.
Dr. Shepherd calls
this the dream box.
Dr. Grey, I'm sorry,
but "dream box"?
Where we create
dreams and memories
and discern shapes and colors.
Read a book, for God's sake.
Webber, you okay?
I'm fine.
Her shoulders are tense.
Something's bothering her.
Maybe you'll get lucky
and you'll snip out the part
that makes her kind of bitchy.
Why would you say that?
It was... It was a joke.
Well, you're right.
I screw this up,
Nicole Herman will
no longer be bitchy.
She'll no longer be able to
laugh, either, or be a surgeon.
She will no longer
be Nicole Herman.
She won't be anything anymore,
and you want to make jokes about that?
No, I'm... You're right.
Damn it. Damn it. What is it?
I can't get around the fornix
without hitting the hypothalamus.
Can you move
laterally to avoid it?
There's not enough
carotid to mobilize.
I'm trapped.
Her sats are dropping.
She's hypoxic.
Robbins, it's not
going to get better.
Okay, okay. There we go.
Oh, crap. It's stuck.
The tumor's too big.
Hey, sorry. I would have been here
sooner. But I was already at home.
You should have stayed at home.
What? MIRANDA:
Nothing. She's pouting.
I can't get it from this
angle. If I force it, it ruptures.
I need, I need to
widen the incision.
You have to widen it anyway.
Karev's here. We're delivering.
We're not delivering.
He's not viable.
I can do this. It'll
be just like last time.
What do you mean last time?
We did one of these before.
Herman wasn't available.
So, we decided to deliver
and remove the mass after.
I knew it. I knew it.
That was entirely different.
Sounds the same to me.
You're trying to prove
that you're Herman.
I thought you had something.
I thought you were special.
Just do the "C," Robbins.
I'll keep him alive.
I thought you would be
better and in less time.
But today? Today,
you embarrassed me.
Excising the tumor.
Gonna need lots of kellies.
Robbins, listen to
me. Do the right thing.
Deliver this child.
I don't have time
for you to catch up...
I've given you
every last second...
I don't have time
for three strikes.
Something like this
happens again, you're out.
If Herman were here,
she'd tell you the same...
Stop it right now!
You're right, Dr. Bailey.
I am not Dr. Herman.
I am Dr. Robbins, and I
am the fetal surgeon here.
And I have chosen
to do this procedure,
and there was a point at which
you could no longer be on board,
but that point is long gone.
I am in the middle
of a woman's uterus.
And any slip I might make could
result in catastrophic blood loss.
And, and if I slip, it will be because
you were screaming in my ear
and not because I don't
know what I'm doing.
You either need to get
on board and shut up,
or you need to get the hell out.
I mean, she sounds
like Dr. Herman.
She hasn't moved a
muscle in 15 minutes.
- What do you think it is?
- I don't know.
But her game face is slipping.
Yeah, maybe I should... April.
I'm-I'm not working. I'm-I'm
just... I'm not ready to work yet.
No, no, no, it's fine. I'm
just... I'm glad to see you.
I'm just gonna sit.
Dr. Herman was with
me on my worst day.
I just wanted to
be with her for hers.
How's this going?
Uh, she's trying to
dissect around the fornix.
But she still has
a long way to go.
So, why are they not operating?
Dr. Shepherd.
If I go any further posteriorly,
I violate the hypothalamus.
If I take a lateral
approach, I hit the carotids.
If I go inferiorly and I
wreck her optic apparatus...
You could... I am lost here.
I am lost in the forest.
There is no clear path.
Just pick a path,
and you will be fine.
I am trying to find a way to
keep her whole, Edwards.
I can't move without
letting a piece of her go.
Dr. Shepherd.
Dr. Webber. What do you need?
I thought I could help,
maybe be a sounding board.
We could work through
whatever it is you're stuck on.
Kill the intercom, please.
Dr. Webber, step
over here, please.
Edwards, would you
mind taking a step back?
You can be a big help.
I need you to call my brother.
Tell him he needs
to get on a plane.
He's in D.C.,
so, if he goes now, he could be
here in, what, six hours, seven?
I'm not sure that's
the best idea.
I am in over my head.
I made a mistake.
I took on an impossible task,
and my hubris
is going to kill her.
Please. Get him on the phone.
Get him on a plane.
Get him here.
Now.
This is taking way too long.
Uh, Mom needs increased
ventilatory support.
Robbins, come on.
The baby's right there.
I've got this. Let me have
him. Ligating the last artery.
We've lost the fetal pulse.
Is the cord compressed?
No. He's in cardiac arrest.
Put your hands
under him just like this.
Good. Now apply
pressure on the wound.
Harder. He won't break, okay?
Just hold him there
and keep his chest up.
Good, good,
good. Just like that.
All right, push five micrograms
of epi while I start compressions.
Oh, dear Lord.
Careful.
You know what you're doing.
Please just call him.
I'm not even halfway through.
If I can't get past this step...
You have it in your head
that he's better than you.
But it isn't true.
I've seen him standing
exactly where you are now,
staring at an impossible
spinal tumor, terrified,
unsure where to go next.
I know that tumor.
He's got it hanging
on their bedroom wall.
A drawing, not the actual tumor.
He found a way. Yes.
Which is why I need him here.
Shepherd,
I can tell you right now what
would happen if I called your brother.
He would hop on a plane, and
seven or eight hours from now,
if she hadn't already herniated,
Derek would come in here
and he would take this surgery,
your surgery, away from you.
Then he would kill her.
Because this is your plan.
He wouldn't know where
you've already been
or where you need to go next.
You are on your own
here. No one can help you.
And you do not need them to.
He's not here. You are.
Now, what's next?
Robbins, he's not coming back.
Karev, shut your damn mouth.
It's okay. It's okay.
Come on, baby. Oh, come on.
You can let go now, Bailey.
It's time to put him back in.
Uh, uh...
He's not even... I
held him in my hands.
He's not even born, and
I held him in my hands.
I know that feeling.
It's privilege,
great privilege.
Navigation probe.
Edwards, you're on.
Intercom, please.
Dr. Shepherd is identifying
the lamina terminalis so that she
can go around the commissure,
laterally dissecting away
from the perforated arteries.
Bipolars.
Can you avoid
splitting the fornix?
I sure as hell hope so.
So far, so good.
Keep going. Find your way out.
How you feeling, Edwards?
Good. I'm good.
You sure? I can try and find
someone if you need a break.
Nope. You're not gonna
find a better assist than me.
I earned this spot.
If Dr. Shepherd
is here, I am here.
This is the point of no return.
Once we start
this, we don't stop
until the last of
this tumor is gone.
Are you ready?
Are you? Smartass.
Here we go.
Glenda's not out of the woods,
but her numbers were
definitely improving.
I'm gonna head up to the
ICU and keep an eye on her.
You did good, Robbins.
I wasn't trying to
pick a fight in there.
It's just, from where
I was standing...
Six months ago, I would
have picked the same fight.
For what it's worth,
Herman picked the right
person to pass the torch to.
She's not passing anything.
She hasn't gone anywhere.
I think...
I cleared the optic nerve.
There. That wasn't so hard.
No comments from
the peanut gallery.
Okay. We are going
radioactive, folks.
Let's get this room turned over.
All non-essential
personnel, hit the street.
Non-essential means
you, Dr. Webber.
I appreciate you coming
down here. You have no idea.
I'm happy to stay.
Edwards and I have it
from here. Right, Edwards?
Edwards?
Whoa! Oh.
I'll get the O2. Hold her head.
Or maybe you could scrub in.
All she has to do now is
place her radioactive seeds.
They'll kill whatever
tumor cells are left behind
and keep them from coming back.
I'm happy to help. I'm
just saying, "Why me?"
She needs an assist who she
doesn't have to worry about.
And if I remember correctly,
you were this close
to specializing in neuro.
Well, I haven't been that
resident in a very long time.
Have her back.
She just needs to feel
you're there. She'll do the rest.
Damn it! Damn it!
I just got here.
I haven't had a chance
to screw anything up yet.
I need to be able to place
these seeds precisely
if I'm gonna prevent
the tumor from recurring.
I had a pre-op map to
help identify my landmarks.
But with a tumor this big,
everything will move after you resect,
like a mudslide
or an earthquake.
Yeah.
I didn't count on this
much intracranial shift.
I'm gonna have to use the
ultrasound to map out the shift
and then morph it back
into the pre-op plan.
Okay, so you're pretty
much eyeballing it.
Yeah, pretty much.
Sounds like a plan. Let's do it.
How long have they been at it?
Six minutes.
They've only placed three seeds.
Even with the
gloves and the vests,
they can only be exposed
to that level of radiation
for, what, another 20 minutes?
She needs to move faster.
I need to move faster.
These gloves are so thick,
I can't feel what I'm doing.
You're doing
fine. It's not a race.
Except that it is.
Amelia, what are you doing?
Shepherd, what are you doing?
It's so much easier like this.
You're exposing
yourself to direct radiation.
You need to put that
glove back on right now.
Amelia. It's fine.
I got it. I got it.
Robbins, you're not gonna hear
this from me too often, so savor it.
You did very,
very well in there.
Oh, I'm so touched, I could cry.
Ugh, I am exhausted.
You'd think a tumor would give
you extra energy or something.
Mmm, I wouldn't.
Mmm, maybe not.
Here.
We're getting down to it,
Robbins. The final stretch.
After those dozen
cards, that's it, we're done.
You'll have completed
a yearlong fellowship
in less than six months,
and I'll have kicked the bucket.
Don't.
I knew I picked the right
horse when I picked you.
Yeah, please don't
call me a horse.
It really is an accomplishment.
Not just to do it, but to become
as good as you have become.
It's a real exercise
in perseverance.
Really something to be proud of.
Thank you.
I'm not talking about
you. I'm talking about me.
You were a complete
disaster when we started.
But I persevered, and
after all of my hard work,
you are actually
becoming a fetal surgeon.
I deserve a medal.
Arizona?
Hey.
You okay?
Yeah.
I heard you flew solo tonight.
I did.
How did it go?
Great.
That's... Congratulations.
Thank you.
I looked for you in
Shepherd's gallery.
She's still at it if
you want to head up.
I can't go up there.
Okay.
I want to, but I can't
watch. I just can't.
Over the past four months,
that woman beat
the hell out of me,
trying to shove every
piece of knowledge
and experience into
my head, and she did.
It's there, all of it.
She's in my head.
But I'm...
I'm not ready for my head to be
the only place that she exists.
Grey, stop her.
She needs to put that
glove back on right now.
She's almost done.
She has a 20-minute
window. It's only been 15.
Without the glove, she's
cutting her exposure time in half.
She's over her limit. Shepherd!
Hunt, if I don't place these
seeds, the tumor recurs,
and everything I have done
for her counts for nothing.
You're gonna make yourself sick.
Amelia, he's right. The
tumor could recur anyway.
But it won't be because of me.
Shepherd, put on the glove!
Amelia.
Done. I'm done.
Get this gear out of here,
bring back the troops.
It's time to close.
That was... Really dumb?
No, badass.
Hey.
Um, I've got a post-op abdominal-wall
reconstruction in the ICU.
Do you mind if I run up and check
on him before we head home?
Yeah, sure. I'll
just... I'll hang here.
I'll be fine. Go.
Okay.
Hey, you've been out for hours.
God.
Wait, what?
Congratulations, Dr. Edwards.
You were in surgery 13 straight hours.
Doesn't really happen anymore
with hospital regulations.
Your class doesn't get a chance
to build up that
kind of stamina.
I missed it? It's over?
Oh, no, no. It's not over.
They-they're still closing.
No. Uh...
Now, you... You lay back.
Let me get you some water.
Pickups.
Juice.
Thank you.
How are you doing?
Just need to get the dura
closed with a watertight seal.
This is the easy part.
Which anyone else can do,
so why not let
someone else take this?
Dr. Shepherd, I'm
here. I'm-I-I'm back.
I'm good to go. Just please
tell me it's not too late.
No, Edwards. You're just in
time. You can finish closing.
Really?
You started this with
me. You should finish it.
Don't let Edwards
screw up the stitch, okay?
I don't want Herman
seeing a big ugly scar
every time she
looks in the mirror.
Not a problem.
Hey, Glenda. You
just about ready to go?
Oh, my God. So ready.
And no offense, but I am so
done looking at this boring room.
Well, enjoy the fresh
air while you can.
I will see you in a month
for your post-op checkup.
In the meantime, rest.
Take it easy, eat well.
Thank you so much.
Well, don't hug me.
Dr. Robbins saved both
your life and your son's.
Um, I don't know if you guys
can tell me, but how's Dr. Herman?
Dr. Shepherd is identifying
the lamina terminalis
so that she can go
around the commissure.
Stop. Go home.
I need to figure this out.
No, you need to take a break.
There's no swelling, no edema.
I don't know why
she's not awake.
It could be any
number of reasons.
Don't tell me what it could be.
Don't you think I know every
possible thing it could be?
I'm sorry.
I just need...
I know.
You need it to be over.
I need her to wake up.
Is that...
What?
I don't know. It's
probably nothing. It's tiny.
What?
Is that a small lacunar
infarct right there?
Did she have a stroke?
Good work, Edwards.
She's gonna wake up.
She might.
But if she doesn't,
I'm gonna have to
make some decisions.
And you did this for Mark.
I did.
But you're not
gonna have to, okay?
I can't do this by myself.
I can't make that call.
And I know what she wants.
But I don't think that
I can make that call.
Hey.
Hey, you are not
by yourself, okay?
You're not alone,
do you hear me?
It's okay.
Oh.
Nicole.
Mmm, Mommy?
Is that you, Mommy?
God, I'm fine.
I'm fine.
Do you know where you are?
The same place I always am.
What's your name?
Uh, that hasn't changed, either.
Squeeze my finger.
Good. And here.
Good. Gross motor
functions intact.
Follow the light, okay?
How are you feeling? Shh...
It's all right. It's
okay. I'm okay.
You got it all, didn't you?
Edwards, did she get all of it?
Yeah. She got all of it.
Hey, no crying in
here. Crybabies out.
Dr. Hunt. Dr. Webber.
Gentlemen, looking good.
So are you.
So far, so good.
Oh, we're glad to hear it.
Dr. Shepherd did an amazing job.
Yeah, yeah. I brought the tumor.
That made her look pretty good.
Give us a second, would you?
Robbins and I have some work.
Yeah. Why don't we step
outside, give them a moment?
I will be back soon. We
will need a full work-up.
Yes, ma'am.
Good to have you back.
Tell me about Glenda Castillo.
Um...
Glenda is recovering well,
and, uh, she's still pregnant.
The baby's doing well, too.
I knew I picked the right horse.
Please stop calling me a horse.
I knew it. I knew you
would not let me down.
I had no doubt.
Can you see anything?
Anything at all?
No. Nothing.
Completely blind.
You better not be crying.
I'm not.
Are you all right?
I don't know. It'll
take a while to sink in.
I don't think you're gonna want
to be around me when it does.
That will be ugly.
I will be. If you
want me to, I'll...
You're missing the point.
You're so thick, Robbins.
You're always just
to the left of the point.
The point is I'm going
to get to figure it out.
Something is going
to happen next.
The point is I'm alive.
And I wouldn't be if you hadn't
been such a pain in my ass.
I picked the right horse.
Why do we even try when
the barriers are so high
and the odds are so low?
Why don't we just
pack it in and go home?
It'd be so, so much easier.
It's because, in the end,
there's no glory in easy.
We were so close.
We were more
than close, Edwards.
Dr. Herman lost her
sight to her tumor.
We took revenge on
the tumor by killing it,
by tearing it out
and decimating it
and decreasing its odds
of killing Nicole by 100%,
by sending death
running like a crying bitch,
by telling death
to screw himself.
That is the battle.
And it is the only
battle worth fighting.
You should be on
a high right now.
And you should be chasing
that high for the rest of your life.
You defeated death.
Mere mortals cannot
do that. Only we can.
No one remembers easy.
Only superheroes.
They remember the
blood and the bones
and the long,
agonizing fight to the top.
Only freaking superheroes.
And that is how you become...
legendary.