17-year-old male.
Multiple G.S.W.
to the chest and abdomen.
Pulse 140 and thready.
B.P.'s 80 palp.
Stop squirming around!
This fool look familiar to you?
Uh-huh, somebody shot
him a couple of months ago.
Oh, man, it hurts!
I hope so. Two
times in six months...
You got yourself a real low
learning curve going here, boy.
Unit 68's on the way.
Drunk dove off the balcony
of the Westside Motor Lodge
looking for the pool.
Did he find it?
Nope.
Ouch.
Hey, hey.
Dr. Carter, I presume.
Carter, what's up?
So surgical interns are supposed
to meet down here someplace?
Yes, yes. Your lemmings
are all over here.
Hey, Jerry, that lead
poisoning come in?
Yeah. Trauma two.
Hey, are you going to make
to the Fourth of July
picnic this afternoon?
My bat and glove are in my car.
I parked the guy with T.B.
hocking up red
snappers in the fish tank.
Hey, Dr. Lewis.
Carter, your first day?
Hey, Carter, if you
can't cut it in surgery
there's always family medicine.
Or Gerontology.
Or Psychiatry.
Don't forget: they
can't throw you out.
Nope, they can make
your life so miserable
you're going to beg
them to let you quit.
Susan, we need you down here.
Don't worry, It's only a year.
You'll make it.
Well, I guess I better
go join the group.
Right. Good luck then.
Yeah. Hey, try
not to kill anyone.
Surgical interns?
John, Dale Edson, Harvard Med.
We met last year.
Yeah, yeah. How you been?
Great. Great, Just spent the
last six weeks down at Hopkins
on a thoracic elective.
The resident was a nazi,
but they let me scrub in
on 20 valve replacements.
Wow.
This is Julie Dixon, Duke.
Hi. Hello.
This is Leung Joo Hua,
U.C. San Francisco. Hi.
And Dennis Gant, ol' Miss.
L.S.U., actually.
They let us wear scrubs?
Yeah, yeah. It's pretty
informal around here so...
Oh, great. John
went to school here.
He can show us the ins and outs.
All I want to know at 6:00 a.m.
is where the hell is the coffee?
Blue team surgical
interns, good morning.
My name is Dr. Melvoin.
Today is the last
day of my internship
and the first day of yours,
which means, in this great
game of medical education
tag... you're it.
House staff guidelines.
This lists the
conferences and clinics
that all interns are
required to attend.
Miss one, and your evaluation
will be degraded.
Vascular conference:
Monday, 4:00 to 5:00.
Pathology: Monday, 5:00 to 7:00.
Radiology: Tuesday at 5:00.
M&Ms: Wednesday, 7:00 a.m.
Intern reports: Monday,
Thursday, Friday
at 7:00 a.m.
Vascular Journal
Club, Tuesday at 7:00.
Chairman's Conference:
Friday, 7:00 a.m.
Doesn't the chairman's conference
conflict with the intern report?
Yep. You're on five days a week
5:00 a.m. till you
finish up after 7:00 p.m.
You're on call every third
weekend and every third night.
Which means, every
three days, you will be here
from 5:00 a.m. the first day,
till at least 7:00
p.m. the next.
When do we get to sleep?
You don't. You are wedges.
The wedge is the most
primitive tool known to man.
That is you.
You think you know
what you're doing.
Believe me, you don't.
Breakfast with your senior
surgical resident, Dr. Benton
will begin in 15 minutes.
Dr. Benton is an
intern's worst nightmare.
He's smarter than you.
He never eats, he never sleeps,
and he reads every medical
journal, no matter how obscure.
He is the antichrist,
Beelzebub, Lucifer,
a devourer of wedges.
You will go to sleep at night
wishing plague and pestilence
on his unborn children,
and you will wake up
every morning praying
for his approval.
You won't get it.
Welcome to hell,
ladies and gentlemen.
Benton... he can't
be that bad, can he?
Peter.
Hey.
Hi.
I left a message last night.
You never called me back.
I was in surgery.
I, um...
I tested positive.
Did you get your results back?
No. I, uh...
some time today.
I'm going to have to talk
to Mark Greene about it.
Yeah.
I thought you'd want to know.
I'm sorry.
There you go.
Now you're getting
the hang of it.
All right, remind me
again why we're doing this.
'Cause it's fun.
Oh, it's fun, right. I forgot.
All right, 10-1.
Here we go.
Hey, how was
that date last night?
Awful.
Oh!
You're supposed
to use your hands.
Ha, ha, ha.
Okay...
Hey, did you call Alicia?
The aerobics instructor?
Yeah.
What the hell are we
supposed to talk about?
She's an aerobics instructor.
Don't you want to talk
to someone before sex?
Uh, not really, no.
Shared experiences?
Common interests?
Are you suggesting
you and I date?
No, I just...
I'm looking for a
little more than that
in a relationship.
A relationship?
You're 32 years old.
Have some fun.
Dixon, Charcot's triad?
Um... hypercoagulability...
stasis...
pain, fever, jaundice.
Gant...
the ducts of Luschka?
Um, aberrant
ducts that drain bile
but do not communicate
with the gallbladder lumen.
An intern who wasn't
asleep during med school.
Thank you.
Edson, this morning's patient
is jaundiced but
no cholangiolitis.
Now, should we
perform the surgery open
or laparoscopically?
Open. There may
be multiple stones.
I'm going in laparoscopically.
You get an E.R.C.P.?
Hmm.
Okay, Edson, you scrub in.
Don't you want to
ask me something?
Dixon, Leung, you
guys cover the ward.
Gant, you're runner-up.
Take the S.I.C.U.
The surgical I.C.U.?
Don't worry, the nurses
won't let you kill anybody.
Any questions?
Dr. Benton?
Oh. Carter.
Help with the wards
and cover the E.R.
The E.R.?
Lastly, we need to discuss
the on-call rotation
for the night shift.
Dr. Benton, I was
kind of hoping...
Good, Carter. Thank
you for volunteering.
You can take the first
shift starting tonight.
I'll set up the other schedules
and post them in the
on-call room okay?
Tonight?
Surgical ward, four minutes.
Better start looking.
Ah, it's just a rumor.
They're closing us down.
They can't close down county.
Where would the patients go?
It was in the Trib.
The mayor's setting
up a commission.
What was in the Trib?
They've got to squeeze
a couple of hundred
million out of the budget
so they're shutting us down.
I read that article.
They said closing county was one
of the options under consideration.
They said that?
We're all getting fired?
Nobody's getting fired.
Man, I just took a
second out on my house.
So what's the union say?
We got a contract.
They've been talking about
closing us down for years
but we're still here.
Hey, uh, are all you
guys going to the picnic?
Yeah, I'm going to stop
by on my way to work.
Me, too. I'll see you all later.
It was in the Tribune?
Sun Times too.
Oh, God.
Hey, Carter, what are
you doing down here?
Oh, Benton dumped
me back in the E.R.
It's my first day as a surgeon
and he ships me off to
do trauma assessments.
Well, sounds to me
like he trusts you.
Somebody beep for
a surgical consult?
L.O.L. In two.
82 Years old, rule out
small bowel obstruction.
Benton on his way?
No, I'm the surgical consult.
He'll be fine.
God help the poor patients.
Mark, I'm concerned
about the lack
of direct communication
between attendings.
I noticed last year as Chief.
Biweekly meetings would give us
a chance to get
on the same page...
Improve patient care.
Tuesdays and Thursdays
during lunch might work.
That will be a little rough
on the night shift guys,
having to be dragged down here
in the middle of the afternoon.
I also think we need to adhere
to Jcaho Guidelines all the time
not just when we're
expecting the committee.
The nurses will hate that.
The rules were
created for a reason.
Take the board, for example.
Patient confidentiality
is breached every day.
Here, look at this entry.
"Al Johnson
Penile Discharge."
How would you feel if
that were you up there?
Not only are we risking lawsuits
but we could lose
our accreditation.
Unit 79's bringing in an
86-year-old male, altered L.O.C.
I've created a diagnostic
code for the board.
It's a list of a few hundred
easy-to-remember
two-letter combinations
of our most common
patient complaints.
And we can use the patient's
social security numbers
to protect
their anonymity.
"B.E." Uh...
Barium Enema?
Blunt Extremity Trauma.
Some guy with a nasty bruise
is going to get a
radioactive colon cleansing.
Mark, can I talk to you later?
Yeah, sure. This afternoon?
And there's a conference
on Saturday at Northwestern...
"Modern Architecture for
Emergency Medicine Management."
I definitely think we should go.
Saturday? I got to
be with my daughter.
Why don't you go
and fill me in later?
Sure. I'll tape it.
She's got to be kidding.
What brings you in today, ma'am?
I'm sick.
What's wrong?
My stomach hurts.
Didn't you tell him?
When did this pain start?
I don't know.
Early this morning maybe?
I said I don't know.
What is he, an idiot?
How old are you? Old enough.
I want you to tell
me if this hurts.
The abdomen
is apparently tender.
I gathered that.
Let's go ahead
and order a C.B.C.,
chem seven and
an abdominal series.
They're done.
I'm going to check
your tests, Mrs. Lukasi,
but I'm afraid that you're
going to require surgery.
You don't want to examine
her a little bit more, doctor?
She's had previous
abdominal surgery.
She probably has adhesions.
You sure he's a doctor?
You might consider,
uh, doing a rectal.
Never let the sun set on the
small bowel obstruction, Nurse Rey.
Dr. Carter, may I see
you for a moment, please?
Excuse us, ma'am.
What the hell is taking so long?
I come down here, for an
API and all of a sudden I see
you have four
patients on the board.
Didn't you check it?
I got beeped to
examine a patient.
Always check the board first.
How could you possibly tell
that this patient was emergent?
Small bowel obstruction.
She's going to need surgery.
I'd like to scrub in on
this one, Dr. Benton.
Carter, all surgical
abdomens require a rectal.
Even first-years know that.
She's impacted.
Look, go check on
the rest of your patients
and come back here
and disimpact this one.
Isn't that a nurse's job?
Not today, it isn't.
88-Year-old male, altered
L.O.C., hypotensive.
B.P. 60 palp, sinus tach at 128.
Resps shallow at 30.
Skin's warm and dry.
Poor cap refill.
Couldn't get an I.V.
O2 four liters, nasal canula.
All right, let's go. Trauma one.
What's the matter
with the board?
What are all these
letters and numbers?
Patient confidentiality system.
How am I supposed to figure out
who's surgical
and who's medical?
I don't have time for this crap.
Whose stupid idea is this?
Mine. First day on the
surgical service, Dr. Carter?
Nice to have you with us.
Need a surgeon in
one. Is Benton in?
It's you, right? Let's go.
There's always a
first time, doctor.
Might as well get it over with.
Oh, God.
Somebody call for a surgeon?
Drop a central line.
I'll intubate
after you get it in.
Pulse ox is 85.
Trendelenburg, please, nurse.
Central line kit.
One percent Lidocaine with Epi.
Thank you, nurse.
Intubation tray.
Angle toward the sternal notch.
I know.
Foley's in.
Come on.
How you doing over there,
Dr. Carter?
Almost.
I can't find it.
Prep for a right
subclavian approach.
Please.
Try not to hit the lung.
All right, what do we got?
88-Year-old male
needs a central line.
I couldn't get the
internal jugular
so I tried for a
subclavian approach.
Set me up. I think I might
have nicked his lung.
Oh, Damn! Decreased
breath sounds on the right side.
He's getting dusky.
I need to intubate.
His veins must have collapsed.
I'm in. Stethoscope.
Get respiratory down
here to set up the vent.
Congratulations, Dr. Carter.
Your patient now
needs a chest tube.
Chest tube tray. 28 French.
Ten blade.
All right, let's go, hook me up.
Hold still for the driver.
Vaseline gauze will be next.
Four by fours, how's
his pressure? 90 systolic.
Two liters, wide open.
Temps 103.
1.5 grams, Q.A.
I'd check him for pseudomonas.
Ceftazidime, two grams
Q-8 plus gent.
All right, people.
Somebody call up radiology,
get a stat for the chest...
Listen to this:
"Pearl white beaches
"set against an azure
blue tropical sky.
"Cool breezes that make
your semidetached bungalow
your own little
piece of paradise."
Where's that?
Micronesia.
Who cares?
It's a long, long
ways from here.
Ooh! "Dive with Lenny
and Francis and the boys
"at Fish 'n' Fins,
Palau's oldest
and most experienced
charter operators."
Is that a shark?
Ooh, five or six of
them. Cool, huh?
Oh, look! Hawaii.
Have you ever been to Hawaii?
Hawaii, South Pacific.
Don't all these places require
that you get on a plane
and fly over water,
like, at great heights?
Oh, I don't care. They
all look so beautiful.
I'll just self-medicate
and sleep through
the whole thing.
I can't understand a
damn thing up here.
What the hell is O.T.,
Occupational Therapy?
I mean, half the patients
on the board need it.
"Other." It's what you put
when you don't know
what's wrong with them.
Yeah, or you're too busy to look
at the abbreviations in the book.
Give it time, people.
Rome wasn't built in a day.
And what is this P.U.?
I can't find it in
the book anywhere.
Pleuritic chest pain.
E.H.?
Behavioral problems and psych.
How's he do that?
I reviewed the notes at lunch.
Hey, Dr. Benton,
some outside lab called
with test results for you.
How long ago?
I don't know. A couple of hours.
Why the hell didn't you tell me?
Hello.
Hi. You have an appointment?
No, I thought this
was a walk-in day.
Oh, normally, but
with the holiday
things are pretty jammed up.
You here for testing?
No.
You are HIV-Positive?
Yes.
When did you find out?
Yesterday.
I'll come back later all right?
Wait, you're already here.
Why don't you fill out a form,
and I'll make sure you
get in to see somebody,
okay?
Top form is general information,
next few pages
are for insurance.
Thanks.
You work here?
In the E.R.
HIV-Positive?
You, uh...
haven't told anyone
you work with, have you?
Not really.
You shouldn't be here.
You need to go someplace
else for treatment;
somewhere where
they don't know you.
Look, I was a surgical tech
over at Southside.
Believe me, don't tell anyone
you're HIV-Positive,
especially not anyone
in management.
They can't fire me.
Not legally, no.
But, uh... when I came
up positive four years ago
I told the chief of surgery.
First, they sent
me to Gerontology.
Wouldn't let me do
anything but take B.P.'s.
When that didn't
work, they stuck me
down in Pathology
working nights.
After six months of that
I-I finally quit.
I'd been there for eight years.
There's a real good clinic
up in Highland Park.
It's a long drive,
but it would be a lot safer.
I'm sorry if I'm scaring you.
Matthew.
I'm Matt Hyams.
What's your name?
Maybe I should
give you an alias.
Jeanie Boulet.
Get out of here, Jeanie.
Don't ever come back.
Uh... yeah. This is
Dr. Benton over at county.
Uh-huh. Um... you have
the results of an AIDS test
for a patient of mine.
Yeah, I-I-I know it's late.
Look, I don't want the patient
to have to agonize
over this thing
over the weekend, okay?
Uh, I-I'd really appreciate it.
The patient's name is Benjamin.
Peter Benjamin.
Yeah, thanks. Thanks.
Yeah. Yeah, I'm still here.
Okay. Uh...
Thank you.
Yeah, uh...
Dr. Benton, I'm all caught up
and my night shift doesn't start
for another half hour,
so should I get
something to eat?
Take ten minutes,
then find Melvoin
for the hand-off.
Ten minutes.
That's more than
you'll usually get.
Are you going to
be with me tonight?
No.
Karubian's the resident on-call.
You okay, Dr. Benton?
Yeah.
I'm fine, Carter.
You going to the picnic?
What, are you kidding?
Last year, six at
bats, 15 R.B.I.S.
I love to play the pedes unit.
We're playing
paramedics this year.
The firemen? Really?
Who set that up?
It was either that
or the Orthopods.
Looked rough either way.
Ortho's got two ex-all Americans
and one retired minor
league shortstop.
If y'all are going to the picnic
pick up some more
chicken and ribs.
Carol, Darcy
called. Her kid's sick.
She can't work tonight.
Oh. Anybody want
to pull a double?
On the Fourth of July?
Oh, come on, guys. Please.
Somebody?
Guys, I'm playing right field.
Ooh. It's tough being boss, huh?
You could always quit again.
I can cover for a few hours
if you come back by 10:00.
Thank you, Lily.
Where's everybody going?
Barbecue and softball
game over at Grant Park.
Everybody's going?
I'm coming back.
Bring me back some barbecue.
Anything else, Doctor?
Yeah. Chicken, no dark meat.
Beans if they're not too sweet
and coleslaw, lots of coleslaw.
Carter is getting
a little uppity.
Really.
He may need a little
midnight potty training.
I'd be delighted.
Carter.
Last day, huh?
My vacation begins
in 14 minutes and 24 seconds.
I set my watch.
Fourth of July.
You're in for a treat tonight.
Knife and Gun club
should really get going later.
Where are we going?
Surgical wards.
Why?
You're covering them tonight.
I thought I was
covering the E.R.
Well, that, too,
and the S.I.C.U.
O.R. Prep, if the
resident needs you,
trauma team, pre-op
and all the surgical admits.
Hey...
Hey!
Look what the cat dragged in.
You've got a good
turnout here. Damn.
Yeah, you know this
neighborhood, Peter.
Mention free food and
beer, and they come running.
I'm glad you came.
What do you mean? I
said I was going to come.
I figured you were lying,
like always.
What are you
so happy about?
I'm just happy.
I can't be happy?
Now, you knew she was coming
didn't you?
That's why you showed up.
Jackie, how many
times I got to tell you
we're just friends, all right?
Okay, okay, all right.
Can I get you
something to drink?
Uh, yeah. Some, uh, some juice.
Give me that one.
I know what I'm doing.
Hey, man, what's up,
doc? You come to save me?
This crazy woman thinks
she knows how to grill.
Get out of here.
Bald-headed men don't
know how to barbecue.
She's just mad
because I'm big, black,
bald, beautiful,
barbecue-cooking man.
I'm going to go in and get
some chicken and links, okay?
I'll be right back.
All right, Walter.
I want my place back!
How you doing?
Pass me that plate over there.
You look good.
You don't come around
the restaurant no more.
You know, I, um...
I gave up meat.
You know, I heard
that about you.
I did.
All those long hours
you been working, I bet.
Yeah. It keeps me
pretty busy, you know?
That's a shame.
No time for old friends.
Well, you know, I, uh...
I get an hour here and there.
Well, it only takes
an hour, Peter.
Or don't you remember?
Oh, man.
Jeanie. Hi.
Hi.
How are you feeling?
I'm fine.
How's your husband?
He's doing all right.
Good. That's great.
Yeah.
Uh, did...
Uh, did you ever get that test?
Yes.
It was negative.
Oh, that's great.
Mm-hmm.
I won't keep you any longer.
I'm glad the news was good.
Let's go, Jer. Put a lock
on the ball.
Safe!
Who told Jerry to pitch?
17-3. Let's go.
Okay, why don't we just forfeit
so we can go get
back to drinking?
Jerry, come on!
17-3. We're still in it.
Come on, let's go!
17-3. We're still in this.
Jerry, come on!
Oh, we're in it.
I got it! I got it! I got it!
I got it! I got it!
All right, that's a
momentum swing.
This is our inning. Let's go!
Hi.
Hey.
You playing?
I don't know.
I just got off of work.
It seems like my guys
are doing okay without me.
Uh, your guys are
kicking our butts.
You left your boom
box at my house.
I got a new one.
Hey, my old one still have
my Best of Conway
Twitty tape in it?
If it did, I would
have burned it.
What happened to my beer?
Vicki Pastroni, this
is Carol Hathaway.
She's the head
nurse down at county.
Nice to meet you.
Oh.
Looks like Greene's going to try
to make a game of this one.
Maybe I better go warm up.
Hey.
You all right?
Yeah.
Fireworks!
Wow!
Whoa! Oh, I love fireworks!
Ah. Me too.
God, they're beautiful.
If we're all here
who's at work?
I don't know.
I don't care.
Tachycardiac at 180.
Get that o-neg
on a rapid infuser.
Step up here, Dr. Carter!
He's arrested.
Thoracotomy tray.
Make the incision deep and fast.
Spreader.
Vascular clamp.
Dr. Carter?
I'm up. I'm up.
What?
Mrs. Nupica's temp's up to 100.
Can we give her Tylenol?
How long have I been asleep?
About ten minutes. The Tylenol?
Yeah. Great.
Two?
Two. Right.
Dr. Carter?
Mm-hmm?
Can we give
Mr. Sifkin a little toast?
He's asking for
something to eat.
Sifkin?
Leg lac.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, right.
Toast okay?
Toast, oatmeal,
prime rib, whatever.
Thank you, Doctor.
Toast?
God.
Dr. Carter?
Mm-hmm?
Do you want a stool culture
on Mrs. Haney?
She's got diarrhea.
Haney. That's
Weaver's patient, right?
Yes.
What does she say?
She's upstairs getting coffee.
What would you normally do?
Not bother.
Let's not bother then, okay?
Thank you, doctor.
Haleh, is it always like this
when somebody's
trying to get a little sleep?
I wouldn't know, Doctor.
Nurses aren't allowed
to sleep on shift.
Should I beep him again?
Only if he doesn't come out.
Ah, bingo!
Cops are bringing in a drunk.
Fell through a
plate glass window.
Yeah, well, find a bed.
This guy's growing roots.
Resident's sleeping.
Claims he doesn't
have space upstairs
because he doesn't
want to work anybody up.
Good morning, Dr. Carter.
Get any sleep?
Somebody beep me?
E-ray?
No. Maybe another floor.
Really? 6195.
6195. That's the E.R., Isn't it?
Yes, but I didn't page you.
Must have been
some kind of mistake.
They can make your life easy
or they can make it miserable.
Whatever you did, I suggest
you apologize immediately.
I didn't do anything.
Apologize anyway.
Police are bringing in a drunk.
Went through a
plate glass window.
What? What?
Busting windows with his fist.
Trying to bust a display
window at the Gap,
but couldn't do it,
so he runs straight at it
from across the street.
Boom! Went right through.
We found him in
women's underwear.
I'm okay. I'm okay.
Hey!
Someone want to help me out?
No! No!
Hold on. Hold on. Wait.
He's not on yet.
I got him. I got him.
All right, clean it up.
Check his Tetanus, and
prepare him for suturing...
Lots of suturing.
That should take
the rest of the night.
Dr. Carter, Connie, I need you.
Malik, let me know
when he's ready.
Elderly man, found down.
Vomiting blood.
B.P. 100/70.
Pulse is thready at 145.
Two I.V.'s in the field.
He's kind of yellow.
Don't we know this guy?
Jim... he's a regular,
alcoholic, cirrhosis, seizures.
Oh, yeah, he's drunk.
Okay, let's move him.
Gently now.
One... two... three.
He's got a big scalp lac.
We found him in the gutter.
He may have hit his
head when he fell.
Whoo! What's that smell?
Code brown in the
shorts. Lots of blood, too.
C.B.C., type and
cross, four units.
Coag panel.
Dr. Carter, help us
with an N.G., please.
Hang a banana bag, wide open.
I'm ready for you, Dr. Carter.
Hold still, sir.
What's the surgical
plan, Dr. Carter?
Transfuse and take him
to the GI lab for endoscopy.
Cauterize the bleeding sites.
Sounds right to me.
Dr. Carter, did you hear me?
Damn it, Malik, I said
I'll be there as soon
as I can all right?
God!
Sure.
Take your time.
Multiple burn
victims on their way.
Set up one
and alert plastics.
I'll be right there.
Don't look at us.
We're working here.
Tube's in.
What's 1019?
Surgical I.C.U.
Yes. This is John Carter.
You just paged me?
How many days since the surgery?
All right, I'll be right up.
Post-op, day two.
Triple-A repair.
Guy's desatting.
Don't be gone long, doctor.
We're getting buried down here.
Can I help you?
I'm Dr. Carter.
66-year-old male.
Abdominal aneurysm
repair two days ago.
Dropped his crit.
I don't know if he's leaking
or if he's hemodiluted.
What do you think?
Well, I hope he's
not bleeding out.
What should we do,
transfuse or diurese?
That's why I called you.
What's his crit?
30. It was 33 an hour ago.
The senior resident,
he's asleep?
Mm-hmm.
What time does
he usually get up?
Some time after 5:00.
That's two hours.
Two hours.
Do you want to wait and
see how low his crit goes?
If I don't transfuse
and he's bleeding out,
he's going to go into shock,
and if I diurese and I'm wrong,
then he's going to
go into renal failure,
right?
It's the E.R. 911.
Where's Dr. Karubian sleeping?
Dr. Karubian?
This better be important
or you'll be draining
rectal abscesses
for the rest of your
surgical residency.
Post-op, day two.
Aneurysm repair.
Crit's 30. Sat's down to 90.
Is he on oxygen?
Nasal cannula. Yes, sir.
Try a mask.
Check his crit
again in half an hour.
Yes, sir. Thank
you. Thank you, sir.
It's Carter, right?
Yes. Right, sir. Yeah.
All right. Shut up,
Carter, and close the door.
15 liters oxygen by mask
and call me in half an hour.
What's going on?
Third-degree burns.
Kid was playing with
fireworks in his apartment.
Sofa caught on fire.
Pulse ox is 65 on 100% O2.
Dr. Carter, nice
of you to join us.
Where the hell you been?
I was up in the S.I.C.U.
Acute pulmonary edema.
Six E.T. tube, Versed.
Guy next door's in trouble.
Go. Go.
When I page you 911
I want you out of breath
when you show up down here.
What's going on?
He's taching at 200.
What?! No palpable BP.
Looks like S.V.T.
That's cardiovert, right?
How much?
I'd start at 50.
Hit the synch switch.
All right, everybody, off.
100. Off!
Okay. Okay.
Okay, sinus?
B.P. 70 palp. Dopamine?
Do you want dopamine?
I don't know, I don't know!
Somebody call a doctor.
You are the doctor.
Yeah. Yeah, uh...
right, right. Dopamine.
Titrate to a...
systolic of 100.
I can do this. I can do this.
He's not breathing,
so we have to intubate.
7.5 now.
I.V.'s blown.
That's okay. In a minute.
In a minute. I got it.
All right, let me get in there.
Hey.
Need any help in here?
Little early, aren't you?
Yeah, well I couldn't
get any sleep.
Figured you could use a hand.
Yeah, get a third line started.
I.V.'s blown.
Okay, bag him.
What's wrong with this guy?
Known alcoholic, G.I. bleed
history of cirrhosis.
Possible subdural hematoma.
I had to cardiovert.
You're kidding.
No. Zapped him twice,
got him back, then
he goes apneic on me
and I had to tube him.
On your first night?
I haven't even told you
about the guy who
desatted up in the S.I.C.U.
Benton's breakfast starts
in a couple of minutes.
Last ones.
Breakfast... right.
After this year,
I'll associate
omelets and oatmeal
with a deep sense of
personal inadequacy.
How many sutures
have we put in this guy?
I've lost count. Hundreds.
At least.
How you holding up?
Okay.
I'm really tired.
I can look on the
bright side, though.
I'm off in only 13 hours.
Whew.
I'm on tonight.
Thanks for coming in to help.
It's no problem.
Well, that's it.
We're done.
Well, then, guess it's time
for our early
morning humiliation.
Benton's breakfast it is.
Just in time too.
I was starting to feel
too good about myself.
Hi.
Hey.
Did you get your test back?
Uh...
Yeah.
It was negative.
That's good. That's good.
Yeah.
I'm glad.
Have you told anyone yet?
About my test? No.
About me.
No.
Good. I don't want you to.
Uh... I've decided not
to tell anyone about it.
Is that what Greene
told you to do?
No. It's a personal decision
and I'd appreciate
it if you'd honor it.
Jeanie...
Are you asking
me to lie for you?
I'm not asking you to lie.
I'm asking you to
keep your mouth shut.
But I don't know
if I can do that.
Fine. Thanks for
all your support.
Hey, hey, hey. Jeanie,
come here, come here.
Come here.
So, what?
Do you plan to
keep on practicing?
I don't know what the hell I'm
doing, Peter. I just don't want
my personal life spread
all over the hospital.
Is that asking too much?
I don't know, Jeanie.
Right.
Look, Jeanie, I'm...
We really need to
formalize chart review.
Why would we want to do that?
Quality assurance.
The residents can't
improve their diagnostic skills
without monitoring and feedback.
Our residents' diagnostic skills
are pretty terrific the
way they are, Kerry.
They don't need
more supervision.
They need more vacation.
Good morning, everybody.
Mark, it was just a suggestion.
We can discuss it in depth
at the Tuesday
Attendings meeting.
What Tuesday Attendings meeting?
Memo in your box.
Mark, what's up with this board?
Is it going to stay
like this forever?
No, it's not.
Come on, Jerry.
Let's put the patients'
last names back up here,
and let's list their
complaints in English, please.
Yes, I promise I'll
give him the message.
I will.
Okay, bye.
Bye now. Bye-bye.
Ross in yet?
That girl called again.
What girl?
Every five minutes.
She's driving me crazy.
You crazy, Randy?
We can't have that.
Gretchen... she's
called 50 times.
It's not even 7:00 a.m.
Thank you.
Call her back. I'm
not your secretary.
I've got a lot of work to do.
Another stewardess? No.
Cocktail waitress?
Hat-check girl?
You all think you
know me so well.
Yes, that's because we do.
Gretchen's a mergers
and acquisitions specialist
at First National.
She went to Smith and Yale law.
She's a Rhodes scholar.
Smith. Wow.
Most of the women you
date can't even spell Smith.
I'm shocked.
Yeah, well, I'm
full of surprises.
Hey, when do we get to
meet this renaissance woman?
Uh...
a Rhodes scholar?
Carter have a nice
night? Oh, yeah.
Boy will fetch, heel,
roll over and play dead
if you ask him to.
Doughnuts. Lydia, donut?
I bought them for the nurses.
Chocolate. Why,
thank you, doctor.
Carter, come.
I need you.
Doughnut, Dr. Benton?
Dr. Karubian told me that
you woke him last night
asking him how to
work an oxygen mask.
It was a little bit more
complicated than that.
Carter, where's your tie?
Long story.
Uh-uh. No time for that.
Five flights?
I hope you had
plenty of rest last night.
Doug.
Gretchen, what
are you doing here?
Hey, I've been
calling you all morning.
Well, I've been busy.
They're doing inventory
at the store today
so I was hoping we
could have lunch.
Today, I can't. I'm sorry.
Um, uh...
but, uh... listen.
I've got to get back
to my patients, okay?
So, why don't you
come over later?
I don't want to come over later.
I want to meet your friends
go to dinner, go see a movie.
Okay, Gretchen, listen to
me. All that is going to happen
but right now, I've
got to get back to work.
When, Doug? When will it happen?
Tonight, we're going to go to
dinner, 7:00. I'll pick you up, all right?
Yeah?
Yeah. You pick the place, okay?
Okay.
Okay. But I now have
to go to work, okay?
Okay.
Okay, all right. I'll see you.
7:00?
Yep, 7:00.
Gretchen?
No. She's just somebody
that I haven't seen
in a... in a long time.
Jerry, don't you have
some work to do?
Hi. This is Gretchen.
At the tone, leave your name,
number and message. Thanks.
Gretchen, hi. It's Doug.
Listen, you just left here.
Uh, I'm sorry.
I just realized I can't have
dinner with you tonight.
Uh, I'm swamped,
and I just forgot.
Uh, I'm sorry.
Uh... I'll talk to you in
a couple of days, okay?
Bye-bye.
Carter.
Uh, someone left some sparklers
in the trauma room.
You want them?
I heard you caught
another central line.
Any trouble?
No. I hit it the first time.
Yeah. That's the way it is.
You know, sometimes,
you can't find them.
Other times, they
are right there.
I haven't seen one of
these since I was a kid.
That's...
It's me, it's me, it's me.
You're a very popular guy.
It's the E.R.
I'll go check it out.
Get some more fresh air.
Thanks.
Carter, how much
longer are you on?
Two hours.
You're going to make it.