Previously on
"The Resident"...
My father,
he died alone
because his public hospital
in a poor brown neighborhood
didn't have enough resources
to save him.
There's something
I have to tell you.
I'm pregnant.
Oh, my God, you're gonna be
the best mother ever.
Listen, I'm sorry you got
the cold shoulder all day.
All will be forgiven if
you answer one question.
Who's replacing Logan Kim
as CEO?
Chastain isn't getting
a new CEO.
I don't understand.
Someone has to be in charge.
Who's gonna run
the hospital?
Ben Mullins
has a clotting disorder
that is threatening
his heart, lungs
and now his brain.
This is your fault.
This is on you.
No, it's on the patient,
who was advised
- of the risks.
- Mm-hmm, deny it all you want.
But you will be
held responsible for this.
His prognosis is good.
Dr. Cain said the same thing.
We are indebted to him.
Mrs. Mullins, there's something
you should know.
♪ Don't know
what I'm running from... ♪
What's up?
I have bad news.
The guy
who got COVID
in your OR
is suing you.
Well, that's too bad...
It's my word against his.
No, not this time.
One of your colleagues
at Chastain
is testifying against you.
Find out who it is.
I'll see
what I can do.
Just don't talk to anyone
at the hospital about this.
There's an accident.
Help!
Help! Please open the door.
Oh, my God.
It'll be okay.
Get out of the road!
Get out...
*The Resident*
Season 04  Episode 03
Episode Title: "The Accidental Patient"
Aired on: January 26, 2021
Mr. Yorn?
Dr. Bell.
Thank you.
Dr. Bell, come on in.
Check this out.
EKO composite barrel.
Feel this thing.
- Wow.
- Yeah.
It's for my son.
That's him right here.
He's got a hell of a swing.
Little man's living
his best life.
- You got any rug rats?
- Uh, no.
Yeah, you don't know
what you're missing.
So, listen, uh,
I caught your show.
Um, not for me.
Numbers are pretty good though.
Well, I'll get right to it.
I spoke to Dr. Voss
and I know that you're...
I haven't hired a new CEO
for Chastain.
You're here because you want
the job back.
No...
No, not at all, but I do
want to see the chair
filled with someone
who can put Chastain
back on its feet
and overcome the losses
we suffered during COVID,
so I'm offering to help you
in that search.
I'm sorry you came
all this way for nothing.
Excuse me?
We have no need
for a new CEO.
Not now.
Not ever.
You're selling the hospital?
Yeah, Red Rock
doesn't throw good money
after bad.
Hey...
maybe someone else
will.
Mina?
We need to talk.
You didn't seem to want to talk
when we woke up this morning.
All right, listen.
We are both passionate
and opinionated people.
Inside and outside
of the operating room.
- So we need ground rules.
- Exactly.
Inside these walls,
we keep it
strictly professional
at all times.
Agreed, no physical contact
of any kind.
Well, we can table that part
of the discussion for later.
But for now, in general,
it's understood
that we will not always agree.
Like your choice of OR music?
A bypass should never be
performed to the blues.
Or your choice
of furosemide drip over boluses.
It's the only way
to diurese.
Why you choose
interrupted suture
for skin closure is beyond me.
Or how you told Mrs. Mullins
that Cain lied to her.
Mina.
I'm giving Barrett a chance
to see if he can redeem himself.
I'm not gonna
hold my breath for that.
I'm not asking you to.
But I am asking you
to remember
that I am still your attending.
Well, there's just one more
ground rule.
This lounge...
It is the Residents' lounge.
Just because you are
dating a resident
does not mean
you have access.
Oh, really?
So it's like that, huh?
Yeah, it's like that.
I never really liked
the coffee in here anyway.
Hey.
Paged to the ER?
Yeah.
Me, too.
You okay?
Yeah, just...
in my head.
Those home pregnancy tests
are 99% accurate.
I know, I just, I don't,
I don't feel any different.
I'm not tired, I'm not nauseous.
You want to do a blood test
so we're not guessing?
I want to know for sure.
Today.
Without anyone else finding out.
What's going on?
Incoming multi-vehicle accident.
A dozen cars,
two dead on scene.
Let's get ready.
25-year-old male
with blunt abdominal trauma.
BP 92/62, pulse 110.
Laceration of the left forearm,
bleeding controlled.
- What's he have?
- Two liters normal saline.
- Let's get him in Bay Three.
- This is so intense.
67-year-old male
with burns on his face,
arms, chest and legs.
BP 100/60,
- pulse 120.
- My car caught on fire.
- I tried to get out, but...
- Easy, easy. Don't talk.
We're gonna take care of you.
That man saved my life.
It's Cain.
- Go, I got this.
- Dr. Cain.
48-year-old male.
Ambulance versus pedestrian,
with right shoulder pain.
BP 110/80.
Heart rate 120.
I hear you're a hero,
saved one of the victims.
No good deed goes
unpunished.
Just came out of nowhere.
All right.
- On your count.
- All right, we're good... one, two, three.
Aah!
Get the ultrasound.
Yeah, we know the protocol.
Clear breath sounds bilaterally.
My airways are fine.
See any free fluid?
Negative.
Pupils are equal,
round and reactive to light.
Touch your fingers together.
Now grab my fingers.
Squeeze, squeeze, squeeze.
Grip strength five out of five
and symmetric bilaterally.
Does this
feel the same as this?
Again.
This. This.
Cain?
Get me to CT.
Talk to me.
Not each other.
I'm the patient.
I'm right here.
Dr. Cain,
put down the tablet.
You shouldn't move.
It could exacerbate
your injuries.
Scapulothoracic dissociation.
My arm must've been yanked
with significant force,
ripping the scapula
from my thoracic cage.
Tearing the nerves
in my brachial plexus.
Can't close my hand.
Can't touch my fingers together.
He's gonna need surgery
if he ever wants to operate again.
That is a complex procedure,
even for the best
orthopedic surgeon.
Page Dr. Voss.
Hey.
Well, that was certainly
a hot mess.
- You heard about Cain?
- Yeah.
How is he?
In imaging.
He may be seriously injured.
Well, nobody deserves that.
Listen.
I saw Yorn.
And?
Did he say
why he hasn't hired a CEO?
They're selling the hospital.
God.
Uh, is there a buyer?
I mean, Red Rock's been
a disaster.
I-I don't know,
but any big corporation's gonna
put profits over patients.
You think we're better off
with the devil we know?
I need to show Yorn
that Chastain is worth
a hell of a lot more
than he thinks it is.
You have a rather unsettling
sparkle in your eye.
I'm guessing you have a plan.
Oh, Randolph.
I don't like this.
Look, we need
to show Red Rock that we can
remedy our anemic bottom line
or it's over.
And filming a segment
highlighting Chastain's value
to the community is
the quickest and best way
to get rich people
to write checks
and sick people
to flock to us.
Surgeries have complications.
Things can go wrong.
Worse than they have already?
It's Cain.
Don't do anything crazy.
And let's keep Red Rock's plans
to ourselves.
The last thing we need to do
is panic the staff.
Mm.
Really?
Come on.
- Ready?
- Mm, no.
Too bad.
Mm, maybe I should've
married a nurse.
Here.
I won't quit my day job.
We'll know soon.
Now all we do is wait.
Hey, Doc, how long do I
have to be like this?
Mr. McCloud,
your condition is critical.
We need to discuss it.
I know I look like a burrito,
but it can't be that bad.
I can't even feel any pain.
The fire destroyed
your pain receptors.
And we're gonna give you fluids
to make you feel comfortable.
- But that's all we can offer you.
- Wait a minute.
What are you telling me?
You might not survive this.
Is there someone we can call
to be with you?
I saw that your daughter was on
your emergency contact list.
No. No.
I don't want Ariana
to remember me like this.
You shouldn't be alone.
And I'm sure that your daughter
- wants to see you.
- My daughter and I... she...
we don't talk much.
There have been problems.
When I was growing up,
my father was always
driving his cab.
Nights, weekends,
birthdays, you name it.
Then there was this one day
that I asked to ride along.
We drove all night.
He let me sit up front, he even
taught me how to spot a fake 20.
And then we just
started talking.
He spoke to me about India,
what it was like
immigrating to Queens.
Starting a family.
We never talked like that again.
When he died,
I didn't even get to say goodbye.
What I would do
for just one more day,
one more ride,
one more talk with my dad.
My point is that maybe your
daughter would feel the same.
You don't know our story.
It's our story.
It's not yours.
Just be my doctor,
and try and get me through this.
Okay.
C-spine is cleared.
I know what you're thinking.
That this is karma,
the accident.
The sooner we operate,
the better chance you have
to restore your hand function.
That's what
I'm thinking.
I assume you'll be accessing
my brachial plexus
- from my neck?
- Yes.
Once I have, we'll decide
on the best approach
to reattach your scapula
to your thoracic cage
and perform a nerve repair.
I want my surgical residents
to observe you in the OR.
You don't trust me.
Fine.
There are other
orthopedic surgeons here.
No, no, I want you.
You're the best.
But I nearly killed
your son-in-law.
Yes, you did.
And now I'm gonna try
and save your surgical career.
His neck veins are
distended.
Heart sounds are faint.
That combined
with your low blood pressure
and tachycardia...
Beck's triad.
Which means I have bigger
problems than just my hands.
I have to tell you something,
otherwise I'm going to explode,
but you can't get mushy,
and have to agree this
conversation never happened.
Okay.
I'm seeing someone.
He works here.
Well, it's about damn time.
Who else knows?
Just you and AJ's cats.
Oh, my God,
I have so many questions.
- When did it start?
- First kiss, your wedding.
First hookup,
shortly after that.
First fight, here.
Now you're caught up.
Wow, you're terrible at this.
I don't know
what else to tell you.
He and I are totally
on the same page.
Most of the time.
But that's another story.
- Now we have ground rules.
- Mm.
- I know all about the ground rules.
- Exactly.
I had to tell someone, and
obviously that someone was you.
I'm so happy for you.
Thank you.
Wait. Where are you going?
Man or woman
is fine. They just...
they need a face
for camera, okay?
I'm not looking
for a supermodel, just
- someone to share the frame with you.
- I get it, I get it, a face
- for camera.
- And a nice, safe surgery.
Okay? Nothing too messy.
Or... or sad.
- A quick fix with a "ring the Bell" ending.
- Nice and safe...
does not make
for impactful television.
- We have to take a risk here, Terry.
- Okay. Okay.
A small risk.
On a charismatic patient.
Bingo.
You look familiar.
Are you one of those...
dancing doctors on TikTok?
Mr. Mackey.
I'm Dr. Bell, general surgeon
here at Chastain.
I'll be operating
with Dr. Okafor today.
- Where's Dr. Nolan?
- There was a schedule change.
Let me get to the big question
right at the top.
Will I have a scar?
- A small one.
- A lot of my followers online are ladies, and,
well, let's just say they don't
follow me for my pithy captions.
They come for this.
And a handful of gents, too,
if I'm being honest.
So I got to keep it
looking prime time.
Well, Emmett,
I'm not just a doctor
here at Chastain.
I also... host a TV show.
And I would like to do
a feature on you.
We'd interview you
and then film the surgery.
With your permission, of course.
I love it. Have at it.
Exploit me.
CT, pick up line 2292.
CT, pick up extension 2292.
Why are there cameras here?
I don't want to be filmed.
They can't film you
without your consent.
Um, your chart said that
you have rheumatoid arthritis.
Are you on any medications?
Not anymore.
Nothing ever worked.
Hmm.
Sorry.
Where you from?
The Midwest.
Oh, my God.
No. I'm on television.
Take out my IV.
No, we're still waiting
on your lab results.
Hey, don't do that.
Hey!
We need some help over here!
Yep, just as expected.
The fluid around your heart
is preventing it
from pumping properly.
You know I'm a doctor,
too, right?
Your pericardial effusion is
growing and causing tamponade.
Why didn't you
catch this earlier?
When I did your initial
FAST exam in the ER,
it wasn't there,
which means
two hours ago,
you couldn't even see it.
- So now you drain it.
- Yes.
But you might have
a cardiac or aortic injury
- that needs repair.
- My hands are
the painfully obvious
priority here.
Heart before hands,
I'm afraid.
How long until I can operate?
Just enough time
for me to perform
a pericardiocentesis
and drain.
Then he's all yours.
Okay.
This is Eva.
She tried to run
when she saw herself on TV.
Any explanation?
She's still in Bay One refusing
to answer any questions.
I mean, she understands
that she needs to stay, but...
she's still visibly shaken.
Head CT's negative.
But the labs show
she's in renal failure.
Spiking a fever.
I'll send for a new set of labs,
but we're
definitely missing something.
I'll try
her emergency contact,
see if they can help us
figure out what's going on here.
Any news
on that other blood test?
The important one to us?
Still waiting.
Hi. This is Dr. Hawkins
at Chastain Park Memorial.
I'm calling about Eva Wolman.
We just admitted her.
That's correct.
Okay. I understand.
Thank you.
The number Eva listed belongs
to an FBI agent.
He's on his way.
He says we need to secure
her area.
No visitors.
Direct medical personnel.
I'm guessing she's in some sort
of witness protection program.
Okay, well, then we should get
her a guard and a private room.
I'll call security.
If someone wanted to hurt Eva,
now they know where to find her.
All right, fluid has drained
from your heart.
Confirm with echo.
Hmm.
Ham and cheese crepe.
I was in the cafeteria,
dining on that savory galette
when they told me
Chastain's next recruit
was the Barrett Cain.
The food wasn't inspiring,
but the name was.
Why?
Come on, man.
Another surgical god
under the same roof?
And a brother at that.
I had hoped for...
a colleague,
a comrade.
But, brother,
you have managed to alienate
every single doctor
in this hospital.
And even still,
I have my instincts.
That hope I felt
is still very much alive.
We know traumatic events
like this
can have a profound impact
on one's constitution.
You know? So maybe you come out
on the other side of this,
surgical gifts intact...
with a different outlook
on life.
Are you testifying against me
in the Mullins lawsuit?
You're too proud
not to tell me if it was you.
So who is it?
I will tell them
to prep the OR.
♪
So, how soon
can we transfer her?
We don't know.
What do you mean you don't know?
We're trying to figure out
what's wrong with her.
Eva wasn't severely injured
in the crash
and yet her organs are failing.
We need to figure out
what's going on with her.
We pulled this
from your cameras.
This guy approached
the front desk
looking for her room number.
When they asked his name,
he disappeared.
Let's notify Chastain...
Tell them to report
but not engage him.
Should assume he's dangerous.
How much danger is she in?
She testified
against some powerful people.
That's all I can say.
So figure out
what's wrong with her,
'cause she's not safe here.
Emmett's crits
are drifting down.
He may have a bleed
from his spleen or liver.
Surgery is risky,
with the potential
for complications.
- Agreed.
- So filming it is unethical.
The patient consented.
Just because he said yes
doesn't make it right.
I think we should attempt
this laparoscopically.
We need to be focused
on what happens in the OR.
Our minds should be fully on
Emmett,
- not on cameras, which could...
- My mind is
exactly where
it needs to be.
You don't understand...
No, I understand. They took
your face off the building,
so you had to find
some other place to put it.
I'm a surgeon first.
- Mm.
- Not today.
Good news.
Your labs are improving.
Available RN to Surgical.
That looks painful.
Must have been
from the accident.
I've always bruised easily.
No, no, it's okay. It's okay,
it's okay. I just wanna see her.
It's all right.
I won't let him hurt you.
He's not here
to hurt me.
I'm the one who hurt him.
I think it would be good
for them to talk to each other,
under supervision.
Eva's very happy
to see him.
Says they've known each other
their entire lives.
That doesn't mean
he's not a threat.
Until we complete a full
background check on this guy,
we keep them separate.
- Understood?
- Okay, yeah. Fair enough.
- I'll talk to her.
- Mm.
I was moonlighting
at this little dive bar down on
Park Street, and, uh...
one day, she walked in.
She looked at me, and...
we basically had our first date
right then and there.
Only a few months in,
we were already talking
about marriage.
I wanted a summer wedding.
Eva hates the cold.
So much that I-I had to get rid
of my Bobcats season tickets.
That's how much she hates it.
He stopped going
to hockey games.
That's how much he loved me.
And then, one day,
she was gone.
No calls.
Nothing.
She wouldn't return my messages.
My friends all said
that I had moved too fast and...
I spooked her,
that she ghosted me.
But that didn't make any sense,
'cause we were good together.
My sister lives in Atlanta.
So when she texted me
and said that she saw Eva on TV,
I just got on
the next flight here.
Even if she never wanted
to see me again,
I needed to know why.
I couldn't tell him why.
I blew the whistle
at the firm where I worked.
Insider trading.
My words sent guys
to prison.
FBI said I had to go
into witness protection,
and I didn't want
to bring Darren into that.
I've been where you are.
I was a whistleblower.
Yeah.
And I was afraid
that doing the right thing
would hurt someone I love.
So, I know the pain
that comes with that.
I didn't want to hurt him.
I still don't.
But I still think about him.
You could tell him that.
Might give you closure.
Closure.
Yeah.
That could be good
for both of us.
- Could you...
- Eva. Eva.
Eva. Squeeze my fingers.
Squeeze my fingers.
Call a code stroke!
What?
What is it?
I'm sorry. It's an emergency.
I have to go.
Wide... we want
to feel the whole room.
Get all the toys,
everything that's...
Soon as they land,
tight on Bell.
Get a few shots of the surgery,
but I don't want to see
too much mess.
You, I don't want...
Hope it's more fun being on your
show than it is watching it.
You've seen it?
Once.
While folding laundry.
You oversimplify science.
You referred to a minor study
as "evidence."
And now you're bringing
your entourage into the OR.
Also,
you wear too much makeup.
His pressure's plummeting,
- heart rate's rising.
- He must be bleeding out.
We got to move.
♪
Hey.
You okay?
Yeah. I lost a patient.
It was expected,
but still...
Is the family here?
I'll notify them for you.
There's no one.
He died alone.
Sorry.
Losing someone's never easy.
I tried to get him to...
call his daughter, talk to her
one last time, but...
I'll get someone
to cover for you.
No.
I'm okay.
I just need a minute.
When do we expect Dr. Voss?
She's late.
She must be wrapping up
her last surgery.
Cain's already under.
He always lets us start
without him.
He used to say,
"How else will we learn?
"Closed eyes mean cut away.
No need to wait
for the attending."
I need the practice.
10-blade to me.
Oh, crap. He's awake!
Up his sedation!
Dr. Cain!
Dr. Cain, please...
10-blade to me.
Uh, Dr. Bell?
A little camera right, please.
Perfect.
Spleen is dry.
We should have done an ex-lap.
The source of the bleed must be
coming from the liver lac.
Is it coming
from the arteries or the vein?
I still... I can't see a thing.
He's gonna bottom out soon.
Let's try the Pringle maneuver.
Transition
team to OR Four. Transition team...
How is she?
I wish we had better news.
Eva had a mild stroke.
Are you saying she could die?
We're monitoring her.
I finally find her after
all this time, and now this?
We're doing everything we can,
Darren.
But we need your help.
I don't understand.
We don't know Eva,
but you do.
Is there anything
about her medical history
that you could tell us?
Something that could help us
figure this out.
Anything out of the ordinary?
I-I-I'm sorry.
Nothing's coming to mind, no.
You know,
when you love someone,
we... dismiss certain things.
- Certain quirks become normal.
- Yeah.
What about those types
of things?
Yeah, yeah. She used to, uh,
try to hide her stress.
Um, especially during midterms
or finals.
Not many people could tell,
but I knew.
She used to talk in her sleep.
Sometimes it was creepy,
but...
most of the time,
it was pretty hilarious.
And she would eat, uh,
odd foods
at weird times.
And she would break out
in this, um,
purple rash
every once in a while.
But I'm only remembering that
'cause she was so self-conscious
- of it.
- Did this rash look like a bruise?
U-Uh, yeah. Sort of.
And would it come at
a certain time of year?
Now that you mention it, yeah.
In the winter.
Purpuric lesions.
Renal failure. Fever.
Combine that with her diagnosis
of rheumatoid arthritis...
Eva, you have a condition
called cryoglobulinemia.
It's rare and can be mistaken
for rheumatoid arthritis.
And it's why your meds
never helped.
And why you always hated
the cold.
Cryoglobulins
are proteins in your blood.
They clump together
during the cold,
get trapped
in your blood vessels,
like a... like a traffic jam.
And why am I so sick
now?
It was cold outside
during the accident
- and you weren't kept warm.
- And the nurse
turned the temperature down
in your room
because of your fever.
And this rash is...
It's actually called "purpura."
And it's due
to the cryoglobulins clumping
in the vessels in your skin.
And they're doing
the same thing in your brain,
which is why you had
a mild stroke.
But now we can treat you.
We're just gonna get this blood
to the lab, confirm it.
We'll be right back.
Who told you
to start without me?
We always start
without Dr. Cain, so...
Well, this is my OR.
And in my OR,
residents
never cut unsupervised.
You should have waited.
Step aside.
O2 sats and BP are falling.
- What the hell did you do?
- We just started
the dissection.
It was going perfectly.
Well, this situation
says otherwise.
You went too deep and punctured
Cain's pleural cavity.
We need thoracic.
Page Dr. Austin.
I still don't have
source control.
Activate
massive transfusion protocol.
- Get the cameras out of here.
- Just keep rolling.
- Don't stop shooting.
- We got this.
Converting to open.
Hold down on the liver.
What next?
Partial hepatectomy.
Resecting a part of his liver
could cause more bleeding.
He's already lost
half his volume.
He can't afford to lose more.
It's a risk we have to take,
and we've got to be perfect.
Retractors.
Stapler. Blue load.
There it is.
- Hepatic vein bleeding.
- Right angle to me.
One more staple.
Blue load.
Ligating the vein.
Bleeding stopped.
Call down to the blood bank
for more blood products.
More suction.
All right, Kit, lay it on me.
Tension pneumothorax.
We decompressed it,
but now he needs a chest tube
and a vessel repair.
Which one of you neophytes
punctured Cain's lung?
I need a chest tube. Scalpel.
- How's the view?
- Better.
I found the bleeder.
All right, normally, this is
the part of the story
where he stabilizes.
Then why the hell hasn't he?
What is this, Bikram ICU?
It's hot in here,
- even for me.
- Well,
we have to keep you warm
so this machine
can remove the abnormal protein
from your blood.
You're gonna make a full
recovery. And now that you have
a proper diagnosis,
you're gonna feel
better than ever.
Thank you.
- Hi.
- Hey.
So, on a scale from one to ten,
how, um, upset/angry are you?
At the moment,
I'm just glad you're okay.
I owe you
a long explanation and...
I really missed you.
I guess I thought about you
a little bit, too.
Eva...
I got a job that I hate
and a special-needs bulldog
that I love.
Would it be crazy
if we came with you this time?
Darren, this...
isn't a decision
you make in a moment.
Trust me.
I've lived it.
You have to be sure.
I would love
for us to be together again,
but I understand
if you can't do this.
Don't try to talk me out of it.
I'm sure.
That's Mr. McCloud's daughter.
He called her before he died,
but she came too late
to see him.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
Hi, I'm Dr. Pravesh.
I treated your father.
I'm...
I'm sorry.
If it helps,
he wasn't in any pain.
I wanted to see him.
It had been too long.
I thought there was time.
At least he called me.
We got to talk for a bit.
I got to apologize.
I'm s...
I'm so glad he reached you.
And I'm so grateful to you.
He said
you convinced him to call.
We always think there's
so much more time, and then...
something happens
out of the blue.
I'm so sorry for your loss.
I'll send one of our counselors
to come talk to you.
Thank you.
Well, as you've seen,
medicine is unpredictable.
No matter how much
you prepare,
the human body
is full of surprises.
How you feeling?
Warm. Tingly.
Like I could hug you.
Well,
that could be the pain meds.
What's your handle?
For Twitter.
- Insta.
- I...
So I can follow you.
I don't do that.
Give me your phone.
Well, I guess
I'll be doing that.
Every day,
patients walk through the doors
of Chastain
with different needs,
and our staff is ready.
Our doctors and nurses
work tirelessly.
They care deeply.
Sacrifice willingly.
This hospital is a cornerstone
of this community
and a center
for medical innovation,
and...
that's why I'm so proud
to call
Chastain Park Memorial home.
And cut! Fantastic.
We got it, Dr. Bell.
- All right?
- Yeah.
Hey, thanks, Randolph.
You were right.
This was a smart play.
Thanks.
Bet you're glad
the circus is leaving town.
I was wrong.
You didn't bring
the cameras here for you.
You're trying to help Chastain.
How bad is it?
Bad.
You're not the only one
who loves this place.
So, what can we do?
What happened in there?
Cardiac tamponade.
I thought he had
a pericardial drain in place.
Yeah, he did.
And it clotted.
By the time I cracked his chest
and got him on bypass,
15 minutes went by.
Even with cardiac massage,
there's no way to know
if his brain
was adequately perfused
for those 15 minutes.
But we do know we don't want
survival for survival's sake.
We want our patients to be more
than just a body in a bed.
No matter who it is.
- And his hands?
- We'll have to wait
to do his brachial plexus repair
when he's stabilized.
Yeah. That's if he wakes up.
I got to go.
Keep me posted.
Can we agree that if one of us
goes into witness protection,
we both do?
Yep, definitely.
With our chickens.
We got to raise them right.
Now that we're clear on that...
Are the results in?
Just a click away.
I may have already ordered
a case of nonalcoholic
sparkling cider for you.
And a few other things.
Like what?
Prenatal vitamins.
Pregnancy pillows.
What?
- Support bands.
- Wow.
- Oils for your stomach.
A heat wrap for your back. - Conrad.
And a foot massager. I know,
I jumped the gun
just a little bit, but...
I may have bought
some oils, too.
- Huh.
- And some leggings. Lots of leggings.
Oh.
I think we're ready.
Let's do it.
It's official.
Aw.
♪
Now, that is the only face
I want to see
after the day I had.
Our rule was no physical contact
inside the hospital.
Yeah, I don't think we ever
locked that one down completely.
Besides, you know rules
are always subject to revision.
- Mm-mm.
- No?
Moot, as we're not...
- inside.
- Mm-hmm.
You okay?
Yeah.
But there's something
about Chastain you should know.
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
Sync corrections by srjanapala