Previously on ER:
Ready for crash innovation?
I'm in love with you.
I don't know why
I'm being so crazy?
I couldn't tell you.
Because we've become friends.
Started out with 14, now they're
down to five. But you're still standing.
But nothing will make them
focus on you like getting an offer.
Headhunters? Why?
You're leaving us?
I have to move out.
You're gonna save her. You're
gonna save her right here.
Right now or no one's leaving.
But I don't know
what else to tell you.
It's up to you.
I got nothing.
No, I'm sleeping fine,
work's good, I'm good.
Surprised, you
know, that I'm okay.
Didn't think I would
be. I mean, who would?
But I am.
Hostage situations
are very traumatizing.
Especially when
there's a fatality involved.
Yeah. No doubt, no doubt.
- Are we done?
- If you wanna be.
- Okay, then, yeah, yeah.
- I'm here anytime, Dr. Morris.
Feel free to drop by or call
and set up an appointment.
Whatever.
I don't wanna go
to school today.
Well, I don't wanna have
surgery today, but look at me.
Come here, give
Mommy a kiss. Come here.
All right, babe. Be back in an hour.
- Mm-hm.
- Bye, Mom.
- Bye.
Be good today. CHRIS: I will.
You all right?
Yeah, yeah. Fourth
time's the charm, right?
Yep. I think I heard
that somewhere too.
So you've been at County
since you were a nurse, right?
- Well, you must like it here.
- Yeah.
Amazing people. It's hard to
imagine being anyplace else.
- Well, it feels like home?
- Yeah, sad but true.
Yeah, I did some time
in a county hospital.
In the trenches, the adrenaline.
It's great and frustrating.
Constantly fighting the system or
trapped in some bureaucratic quagmire.
- Am I right?
- Yeah. You're pretty right.
Here, no bureaucracy,
no broken system.
Just the best care we can
provide every patient we treat.
I mean, County's a dinosaur.
We'd love to have you
come here in the 21st century.
That sound like something
you might be interested in?
Yes, definitely.
- Usual wound dressing?
- Excellent work, Nurse Taggart.
So when do you
get your next break?
Again? Wow.
- I'll come meet you in a half an hour?
- Okay.
Hey, Frank, can you get
me a V/Q scan for Exam 2?
Do I not look busy to you?
Figured out how to beat
the computer at solitaire?
If you have to know, I'm adjusting
the patient through-put database.
Always ask your nurse
for preemptive orders.
You won't have to
wait for an attending.
- Thank you, Chuny.
- You're welcome.
Do you have the PowerPoint CD
and the notes for the conference?
- Check and check. RANDALL:
Go away from me, woman!
Put the gown on!
Hey! DAWN: Mr. Randall.
- You owe me 5 bucks!
- Mr. Randall!
- You're presenting at the conference?
- Yeah, hemostatic resuscitation.
- Sounds boring.
- Did I do this right?
Hey, I'd like to introduce a
new fourth year, Kaya Montoya.
Hi. SAM: Hi, I'm Sam.
- Hi.
- Hi, I'm Chuny.
Kaya comes to us from the
University of New Mexico.
Be gentle. It's her first day.
- You're a Lobo, huh?
- Sure am.
I'm a big fan. Spent a
lot of time there as a kid.
- Used to go to football games.
- My dad has season tickets.
Hi.
What time did you leave? I must
have fallen asleep. Red wine...
Dr. Montoya, care to assist
me on a corneal foreign body?
- Mr. Randall.
- "No" means "no"!
No. Ugh!
What? You couldn't
wait a half hour?
BP, 175/100.
I know my pressure's
high. I ran out of my pills.
Yeah, for the third time. The ER
is not the place to go for med refills.
- Bless you.
- Oh, God bless you.
My doctor died five years ago and
I haven't found another one I like.
- I can refer you to the county clinic.
- Oh, six months' wait.
Don't know if you
noticed, sweet cakes...
but time ain't
exactly on my side.
Oh, it's okay, Purdy. Come
on, come on. It's okay, it's okay.
Hey, you are not supposed
to have that in here.
Oh, she's just a baby.
You know what? I'm gonna give you
a two-week supply of meds, no refills.
Get a regular doctor.
Abby, got a couple rigs coming
in. Brenner told me to get you.
You qualify for Medicare.
We'll find somebody.
Won't find anyone I like.
Can you make sure Social
Work gets down here?
Bless you.
Who has 27 cats?
That's disgusting. I hate
cats. Did I mention that?
- So, what's up, girl? How are you doing?
- I'm fine. This will go away.
No, I mean with you.
Something's on your mind. I can tell.
No, not more than usual, really.
- Is it Luka?
- No.
Well, yeah. But
it's not just that.
- I got a job offer.
- What? Where?
- Payton Medical Center.
- Ooh. Fancy.
Don't you go and
get all stuck up on us.
It is nice.
- Bet the pay is nice too.
- Pay's good, the hours are good.
They use a portion of their profits
to provide free care to the uninsured.
- It's all good.
- Wow, look at you, girl.
I remember back when
we were nurses together.
And now, you're about to
go off and be an attending.
- I'm happy for you. I'm proud too.
- Thanks, Chuny.
Glad you could join us.
- Got here soon as I could.
- Of course.
Says her name's Lois. She
was staggering, she passed out.
- Is she drunk?
- Nothing on the breath. No head trauma.
One-fifty over 90.
Normal time's at 62.
You been partying,
Lois? We got this one.
- What do you got?
- Manny Bonilla, male truck driver.
Swerved to avoid the lady.
You're gonna want four units of O-neg,
a surgery consult, auto versus pole...
abdominal and pelvic
trauma. All right. On my count.
One, two, three.
- Hi, I'm Dr. Morris.
- I'm Manny.
Uh, trauma panel,
C-spine, chest and pelvis.
- UA and 12 lead?
- Yeah.
I can't believe this.
One second, I'm driving
along, minding my business...
and there she is, right
in the middle of the street.
- I got the HemoCue.
- Scleral icterus. Bradying to 55.
- Slow heart rate. That why she fainted?
- No, her BP's fine.
CBC, chem panel,
type and hold, coags.
Go through her stuff,
see if there's any family.
Kaya, do you
appreciate the jaundice?
- HemoCue, 11.2. BRENNER:
How do we put it all together?
- Maybe she...
- I didn't ask you, Laverne.
Put the patient in a gown.
- Is it a head bleed?
- No, no sign of trauma.
But we do have asterixis.
Jaundice means liver.
What lab's gonna help us?
No.
- ALT?
- It's ammonia.
That's right. So
she may have...?
Encephalopathy
from liver failure?
Very good. Forty-five
cc's of oral lactulose.
- You're quite the teacher.
- You should try it.
Oh, I teach. I'm
just very selective.
- Distal aorta's closed. Clamp.
- EBL, 250 cc's. Pressure is good.
- It's not pretty.
- How did this happen?
Just one of those things.
- O.R. 2.
- Send this for cultures.
- ICU's got a postop heart...
bleeding through the chest tube.
- Be right there.
You'll what? DUBENKO:
Yup. The hard stuff's done.
Keep the heparin at 18
cc's per kilo per hour...
and check coags
P4. You'll be fine.
- Okay, hip's back in.
- Pressure's up to 130/82.
All right, have Surgery meet
him at the CT to review the scan.
I need to go up to
Psych for my debriefing.
Total waste of time. I don't know
why they're making it mandatory.
I don't mind. That man
could have killed us all.
You know these people
out here are crazy.
Your liver is pretty
damaged, Lois.
Have you had a fever?
No, just weak and achy for a
few weeks. Thought it was the flu.
Okay, everybody goes
right to hep A and B.
You should consider
other infectious etiologies...
Mm-hm. Like CMV, HSV,
paramyxovirus, hemorrhagic fever.
I'll send serologies. Are you
on any prescription medication?
What kinds were
you thinking about?
Certain antibiotics.
Antivirals, antidepressants,
oral hypoglycemics...
seizure meds, and NSAIDs.
I gave grand rounds on
fulminant hepatic failure last year.
Grand rounds?
- I guess I don't have to teach you.
- I guess you don't.
How long am I gonna
be? I work tonight.
You're probably gonna have to
stay in the hospital for a little while.
We went ahead and
contacted your family.
- You what?
- We found your wallet.
Our clerk was able to get in touch
with your mom, and she's on her way.
- Oh, my God.
- Don't worry, we'll figure this out.
You had no right to go through
my things. I don't want anyone here.
Well, you're pretty sick, and...
I'm fine on my own. I
don't need any help.
Everybody needs
some help sometimes.
Nothing to be ashamed of.
Saline at the splenic flexure.
She's got some abscesses.
Fourth liter's up.
Crap. I think the bowel's
perfed. Page Dubenko.
You nick it removing the graft?
- Injury's old and ratty.
Maybe we missed
it. Page Lucien yet?
Yeah. What do you
wanna do? GIA stapler?
Lesion's less than 30 percent.
Better off with débridement
and primary closure.
Okay, 15 blade pickups
and 3-0 vicryl. Let's go.
I'm keeping my hand in the
midline. Now elicit a fluid wipe.
Laverne, would you mind calling
the lab for our results, please?
After that, I'll show you how
to check for urine bilinogen.
So, Lois, you said you first
got sick a few weeks ago?
You live with somebody?
Alone. I left home
a long time ago.
Abby? I've got the mother here.
Hi, I'm Dr. Lockhart. Lois
passed out on the crosswalk.
We think she's having
problems with her liver.
Lois? Who is Lois?
Where is my son?
- I'm sorry?
- I'm Edith Landry.
They said you had my son, Loni.
I'm right here, Mom.
- Let's get Pete's Village.
- No, no, let's get some beef.
- You guys like sweet peppers or hot?
- Both.
Me too. And dip twice.
Shut up. You're
making me hungry.
I haven't had
normal food in days.
You got a little fever.
I've had a fever for weeks.
- I'm not worried.
- Good. We'll check back in a bit, okay?
Thank you.
Why's she still spiking?
It's to be expected when you've
manipulated infected tissue.
Fever, shifting vital signs.
All part of the healing process.
Should have done a
resection and anastomosis.
- Primary repair was the right thing.
- Maybe my sutures were too loose.
Stop it.
I've watched you do primary repair
of a bowel perf a hundred times.
- But I just can't be positive...
- Neela, you stepped up.
You made the right calls.
I told you I didn't
want anyone here.
She's upset.
You know, sometimes...
the people closest are the ones that
have the hardest time with the truth.
I'll be right back.
Don't worry. Look, we'll talk
about it when I get home, okay?
Okay. Bye.
That was my husband.
I lied to him.
He doesn't know
that Loni is here.
We're not sure yet, but
I think her liver is failing.
- Her?
- I know. It's a lot, I know.
When you people called
me, you said my son was here.
There was a driver's license
in the personal belongings bag.
Our clerk used it to
contact you. We had no idea.
Loni always had a
flair for the dramatic.
We woke up one
morning six years ago...
and he was just gone.
My strange, sweet little boy...
just gone.
He never had many friends,
you know. Kept to himself.
His father, they
never saw eye to eye.
Um...
I have to go check on
some of Loni's tests.
But you can go in there
if you like. I'm sure...
your child could
use the company.
- What are you doing?
- I don't see anything.
- Surveillance footage.
- Right there.
Charlie's crew caught some couple
knocking boots all over the hospital.
I've seen more
steam in a shower.
You don't see the
gyrating? Look.
- Is that a leg?
- We gotta get the picture enhanced...
bring up the sound levels.
- You've got cameras wired for sound?
- Some.
- God.
- What a tease.
Hey, Morris, you need
to sign off on my CHFer.
- What are you guys looking at?
- Surveillance footage.
Of what?
People getting busy
all over the hospital.
- What?
- No idea who they are, huh?
Uh-uh.
Well, hang onto the DVD, look
again, see if you recognize anyone.
Will do.
That look like sex to you?
- Yeah.
- I mean, no.
- Well, not good sex, anyway.
Hey, Morris, I gotta go to
Psych to do my debriefing.
- Did you do yours yet?
- Yeah, it was lame.
Hey, Gates, come here a sec.
What?
It's surveillance footage
of people having sex...
in different rooms
in the hospital.
I know it's been a long, but
that does not look like sex to me.
Frank, I've been waiting forever
on LFTs. Can you check on that?
- Yeah. Sure.
- Hey, do you have a minute?
Yeah. Come on, walk with me.
- What's going on with the attending job?
- You still haven't heard anything yet?
- I got another job offer.
- What? Where?
Payton Medical Center.
They want an answer today.
- Can't you get them to wait?
- They've been waiting for two weeks.
- Get them to wait one more day.
- You told me to get out there, so I did.
I need a plan or
end up in Lubbock.
Abby, got Lois' labs back. They put
them in the system under the wrong name.
Bilirubin's, 8. AST, 10,000.
Look, I'll get an
answer as soon as I can.
Mrs. Landry, I
got the test results.
That's him.
- Abby, just got the coags. ProTime's 96.
- Okay, hang an FFP.
- What's happening?
- We give plasma because her liver...
is not making proteins to clot
blood. I need to talk to her about this.
I think you should come.
Last HemoCue was 11.
Okay, stay ahead.
Four pack cells.
Hi, Mom.
It's just me.
Don't worry, your
father's not coming.
It's been so long. You
didn't call or even write.
I didn't know what to say.
We didn't know where you were.
If you were even alive.
Six years.
I'm sorry. Please,
don't hate me.
Honey, honey, I
could never hate you.
Lois. Lois?
Your test results show
that you're in liver failure.
Do you take hormones?
Estrogen injections,
twice a week.
Where do you get them?
- From a friend of a friend.
- A doctor?
It's this guy who brings them
back from Mexico. They're...
They're way cheaper. I'm
just trying to save money.
That's okay. Is there a
way we can get a sample?
Do you have any at home?
I have a vial in my
purse. I had it with me.
It's right here.
I'm sorry. I know
they're in here.
There.
- Can you get that to Toxicology?
- Yeah.
- You think it's the estrogen.
- We'll find out.
Have you had the
reassignment surgery yet?
No. That's what
I'm saving up for.
Hey, Abby, can you
wait till next Wednesday?
They only do gas
chromatography once a week.
- Since when?
- Since budget cuts.
I love County.
What do you mean
you didn't get it?
- Do I have to get it myself?
- No, I'll get it.
- It's right there on the desk.
- I see it.
Aren't you the cutest thing. Oh!
You going soft on me, Frank?
- Well, look at the face.
- Not doing it for me.
- Let me see, let me see.
- Please.
- Oh, that's so...
What's the matter with you?
- I'll get it.
No, I'll get it. - I'll get it.
No, I've got it. Scram.
You've done enough.
Dr. Gates, broken-arm
kid is ready to go.
- All right.
- Oh, my God, look how cute.
Her name is Purdy.
- Mrs. Gaines, what are you doing here?
- Stretching my legs.
Well, you left me
back there for forever.
I wrote the discharge at 10 a.m. What
does it take to send someone home?
- What? You forget where you work?
- Would you mind?
- Right this way, ma'am.
- Thank you, miss.
Messenger from Payton
picked up your toxicology sample.
Abby, Lois is vomiting blood.
- Suction's on high.
- Push the pack cells.
What's happening?
- She had FFP?
- Two units.
Call GI. We're gonna heat
coagulate with an endoscope.
All right, hold on. Let's use
recombinant factor VIII-A.
It's a brand new drug.
It can normalize the PT in
20 minutes if the FFP fails.
Okay, grand rounds, your show.
Sensitivities on Sheryl Hawkins.
Cultures came back
positive for Acinetobacter.
Resistant to vanco, imipenem
Nasalide, everything...
- What are you doing?
- Calling ID
- There must be another
drug - No, Neela, there's not
She is septic If we can't
treat this, we lose her
I understand that
- Why are you not upset?
- Who says I'm not?
- I don't need to indulge it -
What do you suggest I do?
Take a deep breath, gather
yourself, and go back in there
and find out how
aggressive she wants us to be
Hey there How are you feeling?
The same
Eyes and nose look good
How's PCA working
out? You in any pain?
No Should that have changed?
Not necessarily
You already did your
rounds Why are you back?
I've been here a month
You never just check in
Well, there's a first
time for everything
Neela
I'm a mother of four
Do you really think I don't know
when someone's not telling the truth?
Where's your family?
Getting lunch
We should get them back
- Angi output has slowed down -
Looks like your factor VIII-A worked
Repeat CBC and coags
Abby, this is Mr. Landry
And a Dr. Jensen called
Said he'd try your cell
Mike MIKE: Edith I
told you not to come
You said, "Hospital"
I thought you got hurt
- Look, I'm fine ABBY:
Keep her NPO, D5
What's going? If you're
okay, what are you doing?
Mr. Landry, I'm Dr. Lockhart
And maybe you two might wanna
talk about this outside, okay?
Chuny, show them the family room?
- Sure thing
- Wanna follow me this way, please?
- Check your KUB film and do plasma
This case got more
interesting, didn't it?
You got this?
Absolutely
Hi Dr. Jensen, hi
Listen, I really appreciate
you running that for me
Our lab is It's a mess, you know
Yeah, about that I need
to ask you for a favor
Yeah, I...
I was hoping that you would give
me one more day to make a decision
Yeah, I know, I know I...
Right now?
No, you're right,
you're right Yeah
I accept
Yeah
I'll take the job
Sats only 77 on 100 percent
Lungs are wet Send a blood gas
and get her on a non-rebreather
Translation, please
The infection is causing
fluid to collect in your lungs
So, what now?
Without a breathing tube,
your oxygen will continue to drop
and you'll eventually
fall into a comatose state
Get the tube
Okay, then
Give me the tube
But you don't think
it's a good idea?
You won't be able to talk
You got a point there Yeah
Sheryl
if we put this tube in,
we may never get it out
So I shouldn't even
try to get better?
It's not a matter of trying
The antibiotics aren't working
Maybe my immune system
can fight the infection on its own
It would take a miracle
I believe in those
I need to be sure you
understand exactly what I'm saying
If I don't try, what
does that say?
That's what I teach my kids
Put the bed... I want the bed up
I want you to be in my blog
Can't say no Can't say no
Course I... Okay
Hi Hi, everyone
This is the beautiful
and talented Dr. Neela Rasgotra
She's the one always
avoiding the camera
She saved my life
- Don't you say that - What
the hell am I supposed to say?
Excuse me
We got the toxicology
results back It's not great news
Okay
The estrogen you've been
injecting contains tetrachloroethane
It's an organic solvent
extremely toxic to the liver
How can we fix it?
Well, the medicine I
gave is only a temporary fix
It's okay to look at me, Dad
Lois
I don't think your liver can
recover from the damage
We've already seen bleeding
complications, encephalopathy
If it's very serious, it can
cause seizures, a coma or death
So, what do we do?
Your best hope is
for a liver transplant
- Transplant?
- How do we do that?
There's some kind of list, right?
- Yes
But that could take a long time
There's something called LDLT
If a family member or a friend
is a tissue match, they can
donate a portion of their liver
Siblings have the highest
odds of being a match
- We don't have any other children -
The odds are also good for a parent
- We're not doing
that Let's go - Mike
Damn it, Edith, no We're leaving
Mr. Landry, please
- Please, what?
You're her only parents
You already lost her once
- How many times I gotta say no?
- You're gonna let her die?
- I'll do it - Edith
I'll do it Test me
- Frank?
- Hm?
If you're not too busy, could
you help me with something?
I need somebody big and strong
to help me put a box
on a shelf in Sutures
- Okay, Sam -
Chivalry's not dead
Oh, I have to forward the phones
For the back pain, I have
an MVA waiting on LS films
Got a guy in Exam
2 who is pain-free
Troponin is negative
Last but not least
first-trimester bleed, ultrasound
and quant-beta HCG pending
Hey, so I heard you
made the short list for chief
- When's your final interview?
- Next week
- You ready? You got your game face?
- Oh, yeah, I'm good
- Where you going, anyway?
- It's personal, Morris
Ooh Okay International
man of mystery
All right, it's Bettina She
needs a few things and can't wait
- Postop things - Cupcakes
worked, didn't they?
It's cool Don't give me credit
My advice worked I know you
know And I know you know I know
- Hey, Pratt Did you talk to Anspaugh?
- No I haven't had a chance Why?
- Because I took the
other job - What? Why?
They wouldn't give me another
day And it's a really good job
All right, look, I gotta go, but
when I get back, we're gonna fix this
Okay, everyone,
let's get started
The five-year war in Iraq hasn't
yielded weapons of mass destruction
but it has given us some
advances in trauma resuscitation
Hemostatic
resuscitation is about
replacing coagulation
factors and platelets early
So soldiers who received
plasma on a one-to-one ratio
with PRBC transfusion,
have lower mortality
Lights, please
You're such a tiger.
Is it coming?
- Louder.
- You're a tiger.
- What?
- Yes.
That's my kind of presentation
- That's how tigers play.
- That's right.
Oh, mama.
- Hey - Hey Got everything
Drainable pouches, no-stink
prep wipes, Stomahesive powder
You romantic fool
So you need anything?
I gotta get back
- More water?
- Sure
Oh, with ice, please
Sure, no problem
- Is there anything else I can get you?
- Kiss, please
So I was thinking, I should
stay here for a few days
Why?
Look, we both know that you
shouldn't be alone right now
I can sleep here on the couch
and tend to your every need
And not because I'm supposed
to, but because I want to
- Get it?
- Got it
Good
Come here
I missed you, Mommy
I missed you too
Mrs. Landry, we got
your lab results back
- And they show you are a
tissue match - Oh, thank God
How soon can we start?
- We can't
The tests also show
that you have cirrhosis
I used to be a drinker but I thought
I was okay I haven't been sick
You are okay now, but it's
too risky for you to donate
- Mr. Landry...?
- Don't say it
Mike MARQUEZ: V-tach, no pulse
She's still ours
ABBY: Charging 300
That is not my kid
Clear - I don't know who that is
No change - Mike Don't
you walk out of here
She's still ours, Mike
Pulse is V-tach ABBY: All right
Continue compressions
Intubation kit, 80 ET tube and suction
Chuny, what was her last creatinine?
- Two-point-nine
All right, push
an amp of calcium
- On the outer...
- Just push it
Can I have a crash cart?
Were you thinking hypokalemia?
- Hypo what?
- Too much potassium -
You said it was her heart
She's had six units of
blood A huge potassium load
If she's in hepatorenal
syndrome?
Kidneys can't clear
Her heart will stop
Oh, God ABBY: Calcium's in
All right, hold compressions
- Got a pulse - Nice work, Abby
Amp of D50, amp of
bicarb, 10 units of insulin
- Pressure, 100/60
- Oh, thank God
- Oh, thank you -
Great work, guys
All right, send out a
chem panel and call Renal
- He's okay, right?
- Lois is in critical condition
She's gonna keep arresting
or die until she gets a new liver
Hey, what's up, man?
What are you doing out here?
Oh, it's slow Just
taking a breather
So how'd that trauma
conference go?
Oh, probably the best one ever
- Really?
- Oh, yeah
How's Bettina?
She's a little sore,
but she'll be all right
You did the right
thing going back to her
Well, actually, it's weird You
know, I've never felt like this before
I used to think that falling in love
was like getting sick or something
So we try to avoid it, right?
I know what you mean
You know, I was thinking about
the thing that happened to you
- You know, the
hostage thing - Oh, yeah?
Yeah, well, you know
how things like that go
You keep thinking about them,
even when you don't want to
So if you wanna talk,
man, it's cool with me
What is there to talk about?
I don't know It's just sometimes
it helps I know I've had to do it
So if you want, you could talk to
me or somebody more qualified
There's no shame in that
You know, I already did their
mandatory little psych debrief
I don't need it I'm good
All right Cool I'll
see you inside
Oh, that's right, tiger Yes, yes
- No way - We kid
you not It was great
- I didn't know you had it in you
- Yeah, now you do, you all do
Sorry, still doesn't
look like sex to me
Oh, my favorite part
was the linen cart
All right You know what?
There You got us
Gates is my boyfriend
Are you happy now? Show's
over! Now go back to work
Yeah, what she said
Cover for me, will you? I
gotta go see Uncle Donny
Sure I've been covering
all day Why stop now?
Dr. Brenner, we're
ready to present
The dutiful young fourth years
- I'm all ears Present away -
Fifty-six-year old woman with a history...
Let's start with the chief
complaint that brought her in
Chief complaint is "headache,
backache, nausea, dizziness..."
That's four complaints
Go back and find out
what the biggest problem is
Kaya, take a look
at the nosebleed in 2
- We're gonna pack
it together - Okay
Dr. Brenner
Yes?
Why are you
treating me like this?
Look at me
Well, what the hell
was last night, huh?
Boring
To be honest, dull,
mundane, mechanical
Thank God I had two
bottles of Bordeaux in me
I thought you'd be a better
student in bed than you are here
but I guess the Bordeaux
helped with that as well
You don't wanna see me? Fine
But you still have to teach me
For that to be possible, you'd
actually have to have the ability to learn
- I could get you
fired for this - Really?
And risk sullying that
spotless reputation
to become the student that sleeps
with attendings and then rats them out?
That would be
something, wouldn't it?
You can fill out all the
admit papers up in the ICU
Nurse Marquez
will show you there
I think she's saying thank you
Hey, Mr. Landry, can I
talk to you for a second?
The people you love, they
can't always help who they are
And they do stuff we don't understand
But you have to try and get past that
Especially when they need you
Okay
Okay There is a clinical trial
It's called a bioartificial liver...
Okay Okay I'll donate if I can
How do I get tested?
We could do it here
Come here my love. Come here.
You got no moves, Dad.
He's got moves.
Shake it, baby. CLETUS: Yeah.
- Those are moves. Those are moves.
- Oh, yeah.
Look at Mom move.
Family seems
to be taking it well
Should have been in
attending this morning
- Would have been the
same - You don't know
Been operating with
you three years I do know
- The patient in the ICU would have
died - What? So instead it's Sheryl?
You're emotional
because you got close
That's okay But it's
clouding your judgment
If wanting her to get the
best treatment is clouded
then, yes, you're right
You could have approached
the perf differently
- I can't be sure I got all
the abscesses - Stop, okay?
I know what it's like to be close
But you're not a little intern anymore
I expect you to handle bad
outcomes like a professional
What does that mean? I
should stop giving a damn?
No, it means, no matter
how much we care
sometimes the people
we try to save die
Are you trying to
rationalize this?
Because we both know you
should never have left that room
That's enough
Please, there are more patients
than there are doctors in this place
and I can't be everywhere
None of this should be
news to you This is the job
Oh, Abby Exam 2 lady
finished her Dilantin load
Okay, she can be dispo'd
- Thank you Take care - You too
Laverne, you know
how to bury the knot?
Okay, just start at the base
of the wound, sub-Q Good
And now go sub-Q
to the other side
There you go
It gives you better
approximation cosmesis
- Thank you, Dr. Lockhart - Sure
Hey, Abby, wait up
- So I talked with Anspaugh - I
told you, I already took the other job
Yeah, I know, I know
Just hear me out, okay?
- Hi I'm not interrupting, am I?
- No, not at all
I was hoping
maybe you had a
little time next week
to talk
- Where have you two been?
- Nowhere
- Exam 3 - Dr. Gates,
GYN has a bed
but they can't take
your PID for two hours
All right, everybody, listen up
I have a wonderful
announcement to make
It is with great pleasure to
introduce Dr. Abby Lockhart
our newest attending physician
- Cider?
- What happened? You staying?
Yeah Wild horses
- A glutton for punishment, huh?
- I guess so
- A party? No one told me -
No Abby's the new attending
Oh, that's great Way
to go - Thanks Frank
Just cool your jets, everyone
Hey, Luka I
thought I'd catch you
I know I'm gonna see
you when you pick up Joe
but I just wanted to tell you
that I got the job at County
Thought you'd wanna know
Glasses up, people
Here's to Dr. Abby Lockhart