When my mother left my father,
she didn't tell him she was
leaving and taking me with her
until we'd landed on the
other side of the country.
In those days, it was
called family troubles.
Today, it'd be
called kidnapping.
Could you page
Dr. Shepherd one more time?
I paged him two minutes ago.
It's really very important that
I speak with him right away.
He's a brain surgeon.
Everyone looking for him
thinks it's really
very important.
I'll let you know
when he calls back.
Sir, you know how I said I
wanted to do a Gunther today?
I sent you an e-mail with my new
screening criteria for my clinical trial.
Did you get a
chance to look at it?
Not yet. Torres has a
patient from the sinkhole,
she would be perfect for...
You know, I'm inserting an
islet cell device this afternoon.
I'd like you to be there,
see how it works, okay?
Oh, no. You're gonna
do a hundred of 'em.
Can I see the next one?
Today's just not a good day.
I'd like it to happen today.
No, sir. The fifth years
are at each other's throats.
And it's affecting the work.
I almost pulled a spleen out
of a man with a hole in his lung.
I need you in this surgery. I can't
have you supervise a Gunther.
Torres can supervise.
It's her patient.
Who doesn't love a Gunther?
Fine. Do a Gunther.
But be in my OR by 4:00.
4:00. Okay. Come on. Go.
Cristina.
What are you doing?
Oh, Bailey paged 911.
Well, what happened
to the chest tube?
An intern's doing it,
'cause it's intern's work,
which I love.
I'm loving the
back-to-the-basics thing.
It's so valuable,
but, 911, so...
Hey. Oh, and you have to go.
So no worries. We'll talk later.
I had such a good attitude
today, and now it's gone.
Dr. Webber called.
He's gonna put the thing in.
Now?
Uh, 4:00.
They just call... Why
would he do that?
I don't know, but
I'm not complaining.
I just want the
damn thing over with.
So I'll call you
when I'm in a room.
Okay.
Bye.
You see that? I wish I
did. I can't see anything.
Hold the nerve root retractor.
It's yours again, Dr. Shepherd.
Why is my pager going
off every 30 seconds?
Gloria's checking on it.
His SSEPs are coming back up.
There's still a lot
of epidural bleeding.
Dr. Shepherd, when
you have a second.
Does it look like
I have a second?
What the hell is the problem?
They said it's something
about your baby.
She was pinned under her car,
her leg was amputated
in a pit of dirt,
her abdomen is pulp, and
her pelvis is probably crushed.
You will work together
to assess her injuries
and repair them.
In the OR?
No, at the Jiffy
Lube. Yes, in the OR.
Now, Dr. Torres will
supervise your work.
If you're killing
her, she will step in.
Otherwise, you're on your own.
Don't screw this up
like you screwed everything
else up you've touched lately.
Ladies and gentlemen,
step away from the patient.
Is she... Is she here? - She is,
and as soon as...
I want to see her.
Hey, hang on. We need
to check you out first.
Does she know about her
leg? She's unconscious.
All right? I'll go and see
how she's doing, okay?
Hey, lie down.
I will see how she is doing.
I'm gonna get someone
to take you to CT.
And then I will come
back with a full report.
Okay? Okay.
All right.
It's an open-book
pelvic fracture.
And a comminuted femur fracture.
Has anyone fully
examined the stump?
Pneumopericardium and
an enlarged cardiac shadow.
She needs a chest tube and a CT.
Free fluid. She needs the OR.
An embolization and angio would
help stabilize the pelvic bleeding.
An angio's just
gonna waste time.
We could pack her in the OR.
Call the OR, tell them to prep
for an emergent laparotomy.
Excuse me.
Oh, no, no.
What do you mean,
no? That's my patient.
We're doing a Gunther.
What the hell's a Gunther?
It's, uh, like a
team-building exercise.
See, the hospital does
it when the residents
aren't working well
together. It seems to help.
If the patient doesn't die.
One time, the patient died,
and then it didn't help at all.
So, what, they
prep her and then...
No, no, no. No attendings.
Just the bunnies.
In the OR?
Yes, the OR. Why does no
one seem to get that part?
No, no. Not this patient.
I just pulled her out
of a hole in the ground
that almost ate her alive,
and her husband
had to cut off her leg.
Dr. Torres will be there
every step of the way.
Bailey... They can handle this.
I said no.
The Chief said yes. I'm sorry.
Oh, yeah? Who died
and made you God?
Okay, look, I think
what we need to do is
we just need to take a moment...
April, you're chief resident,
not chief of surgery.
Did somebody call the OR?
No, because she needs a CT
to assess her cardiac injuries.
What did I say about...
No one gives a crap
what you have to say.
Still want to take
her to Radiology?
Maybe wait in line for a little
while till the machine's free?
Is somebody gonna call the OR?
They're still
finding their groove.
Mmm.
You've reached
Dr. Meredith Grey. I can't...
Let's check the liver first.
It's the most likely source.
What? No.
Hey, Yang. Where's
Meredith? I don't know.
She's in cardiogenic shock.
That's our main concern.
Yang... They fired her.
Maybe she's putting
anthrax in Karev's locker.
BP's tanking. We
need to up her fluids.
No. Her pericardium is
filled with air and blood.
Do you listen to
anyone else, ever?
All the time. Just not you.
Or me, apparently.
She's not answering
her phone or her pager.
I haven't seen her. I was in
the pit. She's not in the pit.
I was in the elevator.
She's not in the elevator.
Page Dr. Grey.
I just did, sir.
She didn't answer.
Page her again.
Chief, Henry just told
me that you called him in
to insert the device today.
Yeah. I had an opening.
Well, but he hasn't
had his pre-op labs
and he hasn't had...
Well, we can rush
the labs. It'll be fine.
Well, but he could
come in in a week.
I mean, it just seems a
little weird to race him...
Look, it is a simple procedure.
It'll be over in an hour.
Don't worry about it.
Dr. Bailey.
I wanted to keep an
eye on the Gunther.
An intern just pulled me...
I need you now.
You need to spend
some time with the mice.
This is why I left my Gunther?
Once you put a couple
of devices in mice,
putting one in a
human's a breeze.
All that space.
Sir,
I have a full schedule
that I already had to take apart
so I could watch you put this
thing in a person this afternoon.
Henry, Altman's husband.
I would like to keep
an eye on the Gunther...
Put on a mask, Dr. Bailey.
Even with mice, you
need a sterile field.
This is mouse T.
He's skinny. So
it won't be easy.
Get yourself some gloves.
Danny, you have a little
bit of blood in your brain,
so I'm gonna have one of my
colleagues take a look at your films.
Is it bad?
It's probably nothing,
but I just don't want
to take any chances.
Did Susannah wake up?
They're starting
her surgery now.
And she does have
some internal bleeding
that they need to repair.
Well, when will... When
will you tell her about her leg,
after the surgery?
We'll just see how
it goes, all right?
But will she be able to feel it?
I mean, what if she
sees it... Danny...
Her leg is not the big
problem right now, okay?
She just needs to get
through the surgery.
But she has an incredible
team working on her.
Really, they're unbelievable.
Give me a 10-blade, please.
Don't give her a 10-blade. The
woman just had her leg hacked off.
She doesn't need
her chest cracked open
for something we're
not even sure she has.
Yeah, well, I'm sure,
and if her heart craps out,
she's not gonna give a
rat's ass about her leg.
Look, we know
that she is bleeding
from her pelvis and her abdomen,
which gives her plenty of
reason to be hypotensive.
Let's just do an x-lap and
see what we're dealing with.
No! Karev, start the incision.
Why him? Just because you're
pissed that I'm chief resident
doesn't mean that you
can pretend I'm not here.
Nobody cares that
you're chief resident.
Can everyone just shut up,
please? We are wasting time arguing.
The only logical conclusion
is take care of the heart first.
Hey, is the ER still a zoo?
No, they got everyone who
survived out of the hole a while ago.
- It's quieted down.
- I'm right.
The changes were
subtle on the x-ray...
She got the
crossword down there?
Sudoku. You ever try it?
Bores the crap out of me. Amen.
You're outvoted, Yang.
Who do you think the Gunther is?
What do you mean?
Is this your first one?
Hmm. The name Gunther comes
from the doctor, not the patient.
One of the residents always
kind of emerges as a leader
when they do this.
And the first time, it was this
little quiet guy named Gunther,
and everyone thought he was
gonna flame out of the program,
but it turns out, he's
the alpha dog. Great.
We know it won't be Avery.
He doesn't have any balls.
Well, Karev's got the balls,
but everyone hates him.
So I don't really see
them following his lead.
Bound to be Yang.
I don't know. Kepner's kind
of a dark horse these days.
You'll realize that
the heart is a very...
You feel good
about that position?
Huh?
You willing to back that up?
What, like, 50 bucks?
Bring it.
How are they doing?
Still trying to agree
where to start.
I just had to put an
islet-cell device in a mouse.
Do you know how small
a mouse's omentum is?
I'm gonna go with really small.
Up the dopamine to 15.
Happy now? She's bottoming out.
Well, if we'd get in
there and pack the pelvis,
that alone will help
the blood pressure...
Well, yeah, I hope so, 'cause
her systolic's down to 68.
Because her heart
is exploding. Okay...
Is this where I step in?
Stabilize the internal bleeding
and then we can get a
TEE while we're in there...
Yang! What are you doing?
Opening her chest.
What does it look like?
Rib spreader.
Oh, my God.
We'll have these lab
results back in a few minutes,
then you'll get
a happy cocktail,
and they'll take
you up to the OR.
I mean, his glucose levels
aren't spiking or anything?
No. I mean, nothing that would
make you want to push this up?
Nothing. We got an opening...
Opening, right. Okay.
Are you nervous?
No.
She's nervous. It's kinda cute.
All right.
I'm gonna go.
I love you so much.
And you have made me so happy.
I mean, like...
Like really,
really happy for the first
time in my life, I think.
Are you saying goodbye?
No. No. No.
'Cause you keep telling me,
this is a simple procedure.
It is. It is.
It, it'll, um...
It'll, it'll, it'll be fine.
Yeah, but that sounded like,
"And if I never see you
again, remember I love you."
It did.
I should go.
I think it's a good idea.
It's a rim subdural.
It'll probably reabsorb.
I'm not that concerned.
You should keep an eye on it.
Good.
Everything all right?
Uh, Meredith
disappeared with Zola.
What do you mean,
she disappeared?
She had a rough day.
She probably just
went out for a walk.
Derek, there are a hundred
possible explanations.
Don't assume the worst.
You know why I do that?
Because lately,
the level of insanity
in my wife's behavior
defies imagination.
I know, but sometimes,
even with Cristina,
sometimes, they surprise us.
Got some bleeding In
the upper right quadrant.
Give me more
suction and lap pads.
Do you see any bile or
pancreatic secretions?
None here. ALEX: Negative.
Hey, I'm watching
Henry's surgery today.
Why?
'Cause the Chief
loves an audience.
Not because he's worried
that something's wrong
and he wants you there to help?
I don't think so.
Have his ACCU-CHEKs been bad?
No, but he wasn't
supposed to be in surgery
for another two weeks...
And then this morning,
he calls Henry up
and has him race
into the hospital...
He's getting batty
in his old age.
Oh, well, that's great, 'cause he's
cutting open my husband today.
I'll be standing there,
contemplating my mortality.
If the batty acts
up, I'll lend a hand.
Something is not right.
You can detach the
omentum from the anterior...
You know what you sound like?
A wife.
Cardiac rupture, like I said.
A lot of bleeding down here.
Jackson, help her
hold pressure there.
Lap pads down in there, please.
Looks like Yang's the Gunther.
Yep. No surprise.
What does that mean?
It means she took
over while everyone else
is standing around
looking like idiots
doing whatever she says.
I mean, look at Avery. Useless.
I gotta go. Kepner.
What was I thinking?
Oh, no. No, no. This is the
opposite of what she should be doing.
I'm trying to teach
her some humility,
and she's running the
OR on a massive trauma.
What can you do?
Some people are
racehorses. She's a racehorse.
V-fib.
I need the paddles.
Charge to 20.
Clear.
No change.
I need one of intracardiac epi.
Someone take over
massaging the heart.
I got it.
Ow! Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Alex?
Look at me.
Alex, look at me. Alex?
Oh, my God, Alex! What the...
Alex!
Racehorse?
My bad.
What the hell just happened?
Epi. Give me another epi.
Here you go, Doctor.
I can't find a pulse.
Why the hell doesn't he have
a pulse? I need a crash cart.
An epi doesn't stop a
healthy person's heart.
What did you do? I don't know.
Her heart's back. I'm gonna
deal with the pericardium.
Forget about the pelvis for now.
She's bleeding through the
packing in the right upper quadrant.
Should I repack it?
Try a Pringle
maneuver. Graft, please.
Hey, get me and Dr. Altman
gowned and gloved,
and I need
something to stand on.
Dr. Bailey, it's under control.
We got a lot of hands in
here, and two more surgeons
are only gonna confuse matters.
I'm gonna ask you
to step back, please.
Can I get another pledgeted
3-0 prolene? Suction.
V-fib. Charging to 200.
Clear.
Alex?
Alex? Alex, can
you hear me? Alex?
You crazy bitch.
You almost killed me.
Oh.
I called home. I
scoured the hospital.
I even had an intern
call every ER in the city
to make sure she
wasn't run over by a bus.
There's no simple explanation.
Why don't you let me
handle talking to Nicky's dad?
I don't mind. I'm fine.
How is he?
There were three
fractures in Nicky's spine.
We repaired the damage.
Looks like,
neurologically, he's intact.
This is the "wait and see" part.
Can I see him?
He's in recovery right now.
They're not gonna
let you see him.
I can't believe that
this is happening.
We were just walking
down the street,
talking about why
people don't have gills.
I was holding his
hand, and he just...
Slipped away.
How do you go through the
day when one minute to the next,
your child could just...
Excuse me.
I'm sorry.
He's...
Let's go find Nicky.
I thought you said they
weren't gonna let me see him.
Well, we're gonna
figure something out.
You need to see your son.
Don't touch me.
I'm not touching you.
Don't touch my gurney!
All right, get this
artery. See right there?
Yeah. Good.
Now do a tie on the hemostat.
Who'd have thunk it?
Avery's the Gunther.
What the hell happened?
Yang almost killed Karev,
and Avery's the Gunther.
Avery? Get outta here.
Hand to God.
Avery...
Good job, son.
Thank you.
I'm right here if
you need anything.
Oh, damn it.
My guy won.
We're gonna be great together.
Sorry.
A little hiccup in the Gunther.
Well, take your time.
You know, I've seen you
open an abdomen before.
Whereas Dr. Grey...
I don't want an
observer. I want an assist.
Oh, okay. Is something wrong?
No, this is a teaching hospital.
And you're not too old to learn.
Yeah, but it'd be good
experience for Grey to see...
Dr. Bailey, if wanted a
resident's help, I'd ask for it.
Here you go, Doctor. Thank you.
Whenever you're ready.
All right, then get back
to me with her post-op crit.
And make sure you're aggressive
with the dressings on her leg.
I'm still worried about
an infection. Okay.
Hey.
You know why she just
did what he said, right?
Because he's the Gunther.
How did it go?
We'll have to go back
for definitive repairs,
but we stopped the
major hemorrhaging,
got the leg all
cleaned out. Good.
Nice work today,
Avery. Thank you.
I just hope she pulls through.
How's Alex?
He should be fine.
Apparently, he had an
underlying arrhythmia,
so the epi...
I was moving too fast
and I made a mistake.
You think?
Boy, you got a mean streak.
I mean, you look
like a nice girl, but,
scratch the surface...
Don't mess with the nice ones.
I think I stole a baby.
Okay, first of all, you
didn't steal the baby.
She's your baby.
What you did is,
you took her for a nap.
In a very odd location and
you failed to answer your phone.
But, you know,
many people find all the
technology in our lives to be intrusive.
So you're not the first person
who didn't answer her phone...
Or her pager.
Well, and, you know,
all we have to do
is find a reason why you
were AWOL for an hour.
Four,
hours.
Janet was gonna take
the baby, so I took off.
Okay. Okay.
You know, people make mistakes.
I mean, I almost killed
Alex in the OR today.
So we'll just figure it out.
How?
I don't know. No.
How'd you almost kill Alex?
With a CC of epi.
Whatever. You
know, he'll be fine.
Just...
Just stay here. I'll fix this.
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna fix it.
Hand me a 10-blade, please.
Have to be careful not to cut
too deep into the omentum.
Uh, Dr. Webber.
Yes.
Hi. Teddy Altman here.
Yeah, nice to see you.
I thought that Dr. Bailey
was just observing.
Yeah, well, she's here, so
she's gonna make herself useful.
Dr. Webber, I'm a surgeon.
That's the word on the street.
You have an
attending assisting you
in a simple subcutaneous
device insertion.
You rushed Henry into
surgery with an hour's notice.
What... What are you not
telling me? Dr. Altman...
Is there something that he
didn't tell me about his checkups?
I mean, is his HbA1c too high?
Here we go. Look, I am a doctor
and I know when something is
wrong, and something is wrong.
Dr. Altman, I'm fond of you, so
I'm gonna count to 30 in my head
before I call security.
Richard, I'm just asking you...
Get out of my OR right now.
I don't need to be here.
They just want to observe me
and make sure I
don't pass out again.
Mmm.
Not a bad idea.
How'd the kid do?
He has a few spinal fractures,
but it looks like he's
out of the woods.
You need to make
up with your friends.
Whatever.
One of them almost
killed you today.
It was an accident.
Nobody has your back.
Nobody is looking out for you.
That's when accidents
happen, okay?
This isn't a personal problem.
This is a professional one.
It makes you a bad hire.
Also, it means that I
have to worry about you,
because no one else is.
And I don't want
to worry about you.
I'd much rather be kicking
your ass on my Peds ward.
Cristina.
Do you want to sit
and talk for a minute?
I do. I...
I really very much do,
but I have to go do
something right now,
and it can't wait.
Please,
please believe that
I want to talk to you
and I'm not blowing you off
because I'm a terrible person
or because I don't
care about you.
None of that is true.
She okay?
No change.
I just...
I don't want to mess this up
like I messed up everything else.
What? You were great in the OR.
I wasn't the Gunther. I
was a super-duper assistant.
Are they gonna fire
me as chief resident?
No.
It was your first day.
They'll just make
you do it again.
It's time to place the device.
What do you want me to do?
Place the device.
Sir, is there anything
you want to tell me?
Don't screw it up.
A surgeon doing the early stages
of human trials on his
experimental procedure
never hands over the
reins to someone else, ever!
Unless something is wrong.
Altman said this was weird,
I just thought she was
being a wife. Bailey...
Are you drinking again?
Ooh! That would explain a lot.
Yes, it would.
God, I wish it were that simple.
Pick up those
forceps, Dr. Bailey.
Now watch the superficial
arteries. That's where it gets dicey.
Let's get more
retraction, Dr. Grey.
Right. Okay. Don't,
don't, don't rush it. All right.
You see those
blood vessels? Yep.
Implant the device as
close to those as possible.
Without their oxygen supply,
the islet cells would die off.
Good.
And eventually, the vessels
will just take over
the oxygen delivery
to the device completely.
Look at that.
It's interesting, right?
It's actually kind of beautiful.
Nice work, Dr. Bailey.
Close him up.
Did... Did... Did he just...
He just left?
Get up.
No. I'm under 24-hour observation
because you almost killed me!
I revealed an arrhythmia
you didn't know you have.
I probably saved your life.
I'll run an EKG on
you later. Just get up.
You're supposed to have my back.
I made a mistake.
All right? I was drunk,
I was pissed off...
Oh, for the love of...
No, I screwed up! You
screw up all the time.
I don't have anybody.
You guys are all I have.
You have to forgive me! Fine!
Whatever. Forgiven.
Just... Get up out
of the damn bed.
Oh, sorry. I was paged here.
That was us.
We paged your wife, too.
Do you know where she is?
Well, that is the
question of the hour.
I have no idea where she is.
Well, we'll fill her in later.
Shut the door, please.
Dr. Webber just informed
me that he tampered with
the drugs and placebos
in your clinical trial.
Excuse me?
No, it was Meredith.
Dr. Grey apparently
was covering for him.
She knew and she
was trying to protect him.
You have my apologies.
I destroyed your trial.
She wasn't covering for you.
What the hell are you doing?
I'm protecting your wife.
What are you doing?
This is wrong,
and you know that.
What are you
trying to do to her?
She was trying to save Adele.
She was trying to save me.
At what point are you gonna
stop punishing her for that?
And there's no pain
in your abdomen?
Nope.
Really? Or are you
just being stoic for me?
I'm a man in a gown. I can't
pretend to be brave and strong.
You can.
I kinda lost it today.
Dr. Webber kicked
me out of the OR.
Really?
Okay, um, so...
You know how we both
figured that since I was a doctor,
that I would be really calm while
you were having your surgery?
Mmm-hmm.
That may not be the case.
You're just a mess, like
any ordinary wife would be?
Yeah, it's pathetic.
I think it's adorable.
I have a chronic
tumor condition.
I'm a frequent flyer in the OR.
I'm gonna be a
basket case every time.
So sad.
If you're headed in there,
you may want to wait.
They're acting like he just
came back from the wars.
What?
Something happened
with the chief.
Where have you been?
We've been trying
to reach you for hours.
I'm sorry.
Where's Zola?
Hey. Susannah just
got out of surgery,
and it went as well
as it could have.
We're not gonna know
much for a little while.
Look right here.
We had such an
awful fight right before.
I brought up her
mother in an argument,
and that is one
of the red buttons.
I swore I would never
do that. Why did I do that?
She'll forgive you.
You saved her life.
Maybe for a while,
and then she'll get better
and she'll remember
why she got out of the car.
Maybe she won't. You know?
Maybe you both just
decide to forget, move on.
Pretend it never happened.
Does that work?
It can't hurt to try.
You married?
I'm sorry. It's not my
business. I didn't mean to pry.
Oh, that's all right. Yes.
Yes, I'm married.
What did you do?
I want you to shut the door
and then I want you to sit down.
You're throwing your
whole career away
for that damn girl?
This is not the
end of my career.
The FDA will never come
anywhere near you again.
That is the end of
your islet cell trial,
not to mention any other thing you
might be cooking up with the FDA...
Sit down!
You...
Open it.
What...
And read the first page.
"The Artificial
Pancreas: A Cure for..."
How about, "The
Artificial Pancreas:
"A Huge Missed Opportunity
That You Blew Because You..."
Read the next line.
"Principal
Investigator: Miranda..."
It's yours now.
I have no pending
trials with the FDA.
Ever since her surgery,
Zola's had weekly blood tests,
and, the results I got today
were a little weird, so I
wanted to take a look at her.
Yeah, and, you
know, with babies,
I mean, when a doctor
calls... I got worried,
so I just rushed her right in,
and I must have left my
phone in the day-care center.
And your pager.
My pager I had to turn
in because they fired me.
What's wrong with her?
Her white count was elevated.
14.5. I wanted to make sure
there wasn't a post-op infection
or a CSF leak or something.
On my exam, she looks fine.
No signs of spinal shock.
I re-ran her CBC, and
her white count was eight.
Totally normal.
Must have just been
a stress reactant,
or a fluke in the labs,
'cause, well, she's fine.
It's true.
CSF leaks are a problem
with spina bifida babies.
That's great you caught that.
I'm sorry. I didn't
mean for any of this...
I didn't mean for
any of this to happen.
I know. I know.
I still don't understand
what you possibly
could've been thinking.
They fired me.
Janet basically told me they
were gonna take Zola away.
I mean, possibly send
her back to Malawi.
You and me.
I just needed some time.
I just needed to hold
her and look at her
and just think about
how everything,
everything got so screwed up.
You should take Zola.
Janet has a problem
with me, not with you.
And we need to
do whatever we can
to make sure they
don't take her away,
and if that means that you
have custody of her and I don't,
well, then that's
what we need to do.
You're not fired.
Richard's gonna
take the fall for you.
What?
He can't do that. I'm
not gonna let him do that.
Yes, you will.
If you want to keep this baby,
you will let him protect you.
Dan?
Oh, my God. Sweetheart.
Danny, I was scared.
Oh, I know.
I didn't know where you were.
I'm right here.
You were asleep, and they
didn't want me to wake you up.
I fell down.
You sure did.
You stayed, though.
I'm not going anywhere.
Don't go anywhere.
I'm right here.
Oh, I love you so much.
Ow!
You're a big baby.
Okay.
All right, the top row all got
the device on the first round.
Dr. Webber tweaked the protocol
pretty substantially after that,
which means the second
set, that's these guys here,
they all tend to
do a lot better.
I've been off the project
for the last couple of weeks,
but I'm pretty sure I
remember the drill.
I can walk you through it.
It had to be mice.
All right. Let's
take it from the top.
How's it looking? Can't tell.
They can't just take the
baby away, can they?
I don't know.
Meredith says
you didn't do it yet.
I didn't change my mind.
I know.
I know. You don't
change your mind.
You'd cut off my leg
for me, wouldn't you?
Well, I wouldn't botch
it like that guy did.
I'd leave you a good stump
so you could get a prosthesis.
When's the appointment?
Now.
Okay.
Let's go.
I... Oh, God.
They're not gonna find a
better family than two doctors.
It's gonna be fine.
Anybody want to
go check on Sofia?
Why?
'Cause when somebody's talking
about taking someone's baby away,
you wanna see your baby.
Oh, you guys. She's fine.
I'm right behind you.
Maybe we should leave, too.
I mean, I'm sure
they don't want us
just sitting here
staring at them.
I don't know.
They're trying to keep a
family together. That's not easy.
You know, it can't hurt to stick
around, make sure they're okay.
You see, this is why
you're the Gunther.
I have terrible
leadership instincts.
That doesn't make
me a better leader.
A better person
maybe, but... Oh...
We are in a bit of
a bind right now.
A lot of questions came up
today about your relationship,
about your employment...
Well, she got her job back.
That was a misunderstanding.
She disappeared.
Well, that was a
miscommunication.
And the part about you two
living in separate houses,
that's miscommunication, too?
Look, I get it.
It's not easy bringing a
child into a relationship.
You're allowed to have
some bumps in the road.
But this afternoon, when it
looked like you two had split up,
your wife got fired,
she lied to me about it
and left with the baby.
I set off some alarms.
Now I'm trying to dial them all
back, but it's not that easy to do.
Once the system
is set in motion,
there's a certain protocol
that has to be followed.
Once the agency believes that
there are questions
about Meredith...
Janet, Meredith is the best
mother a child could have.
She loves Zola. She loves me.
And if there is a
flaw with her, it's...
She loves people so much
that she'll do anything for them.
Derek, please.
I hear you.
But no matter what I say,
social services still has to
reevaluate the placement.
And while that happens,
Zola can't be in your home.
I'll give you a minute
to say goodbye.
We should... We
should let her sleep.
She's ours. Nobody's
taking her away.
And
she'll wake up in half
an hour, and then we'll
take her home for dinner.
Nah. We should wake her up.
Yeah.
Hi, little baby.
Daddy's here.
Hi.
Hi, sweet girl.
Little goose.
Adele. Honey.
Yeah, I'm on my way home.
No, I'm not working late.
I told you, I'm having
dinner with you.
Yeah, well,
this time I mean it.
Okay.
I'm gonna give you an
injection to numb the cervix.
If you'd like some IV diazepam,
it won't knock you out,
but it'll calm you down.
Okay.
I want to ask you one more time.
Are you absolutely sure
this is what you want to do?
Then let's get started.
Sorry, but it's time to go.
Derek.
Here you go.
Okay. Hey.
Janet is a very nice lady.
We like her a lot.
Yeah.
She's gonna find you a very nice
family to go stay with for a while.
And then you're gonna
come right back to us,
and everything's gonna be fine.
Okay?
Okay.
She likes her bottle room
temperature, not too warm.
And she cannot sleep
without that giraffe.
It's in the front pocket
of the diaper bag.
And there's extra
pacifiers in there.
You're gonna need them
when you put her in the car.
You think that true
love is the only thing
that can crush your heart.
The thing that will take
your life and light it up.
Or destroy it.
Then,
you become a mother.