We're doctors.
We're trained to care
for human beings.
And we're pretty sure
we know what to look for.
No, it doesn't make any sense!
Everybody wants a kid! You
wear roller skates for shoes!
- I don't get it!
- You know what? I don't know!
Maybe there's something
wrong with me. It's not natural.
It's not womanly. Maybe I'm
cold and heartless and dead inside.
- No, I'm not saying that!
- Well, but a little bit,
you are.
- No.
- Cuts...
- OK.
- infection...
genetic mutation...
You know what? Just...
Just humor me for
one minute, OK?
Close your eyes.
Now, picture a baby.
A warm...
smushy little... baby.
Wrapping its chubby little
arms around your neck.
Now, breathe in that...
that intoxicating baby smell.
Doesn't it just melt you?
No. You know what melts me?
Spain. The beach.
You in a bikini.
Me holding a sangria. Oh.
Wait. What's that I hear?
Oh... The baby's crying.
We can't go to Spain.
Sangria? That's
why I don't get a kid?
- I can make a friggin' sangria.
- Just a minute!
- What?
- Yang, you got a suture kit?
- Yeah.
- Where's Robbins?
- In there.
- Robbins!
- What's going on?
- Two! I need two suture kits!
- Why is he screaming?
- Baby! Now!
Why are you...?
Oh, God! He's serious!
Holy mother of...
- Get my bag.
- Give me a clamp.
- All right, another clamp.
- Clamp.
- Scissors.
- How is he? Is he OK? Is he good?
He's great. You did great.
All right.
- Any sounds?
- Not yet.
Come on, baby boy. Come on.
Come on.
OK! That's my boy.
OK, that's what I'm talking about.
That's what I'm talking about.
Here you go, Grandpa.
Hey. So is it true you helped Teddy
and Mark deliver Little Sloan's baby?
- Yeah, not now.
- What's wrong with you?
Tom Evans, in with your husband.
That's Tom Evans.
- He seems a lot younger than...
- Try and be cool.
- Good morning.
- Hey, hey, hey!
- He's in with Shepherd.
- Who?
Tom Evans.
- Tom Evans is here?
- You didn't know?
He's doing his bloodless CABG
on a beating heart, today in our OR.
- Shepherd didn't tell you?
- No, no...
- Bless you.
- Excuse me. No, he didn't.
An Evans bypass.
Clear your schedule. Scrub in.
No, I can't. I gotta go.
And here she is. Your
cruise director, Dr. Yang.
Dr. Evans, hi. Hi.
Hi, I'm Cristina
Yang. I'm a huge fan.
She's a groupie, but forgive her
because she's one of the finest
- cardio residents you'll meet.
- Quite a recommendation.
- You scrubbing in
with me today?
- Yes.
It's an honor and a privilege.
Here are the patient charts
and the most recent labs.
If there's anything
else you need, ask.
I'll be around all
day following you.
- If that's OK with you. Uh...
- She is a groupie. I like her.
This is my wife,
Dr. Meredith Grey.
- Pleasure to meet you.
- Likewise. I hear great things.
I hear them from your husband,
so grain of salt.
- Dr. Yang.
- Yes?
- All yours.
- Yes, of course.
The patient is
right this way, sir.
- Think she's
gonna drool on him?
- I think she is.
OK. I gotta go.
I'll see you soon.
Is that Thomas
Evans from Baylor?
Yes, but don't get too excited.
- He's only here for one case.
- Are you sure?
I overheard Chief Shepherd
discussing the fact that Dr. Altman
doesn't have a permanent contract,
so it would be a really genius move
- on the chief's
part to go in...
- Here we go again.
- What?
- Shut up.
She thinks your
husband walks on water.
I don't. I don't. I, um...
No, I'm... I mean...
It's a professional thing.
It's, um... It's a mentor thing.
He's just my mentor.
'Cause he's married... to you.
And you guys are so great.
And, um... Together.
Together, as a married couple.
- You... You... You're so great.
- Wow.
I, um... I do... I do think
that your husband is brilliant,
but I'm sure that you think that, too.
- OK, then.
- Thank you.
You can see it, right?
The resemblance?
It's a newborn. It
resembles other newborns.
OK. All right, fine. But you
want incontrovertible proof?
Here we go.
- Look at that.
- Oh.
It's impressive,
I'll give you that.
I mean, a lot of that swelling
is from the birth. It will go down.
He's a Sloan.
- Right.
- He's a Sloan.
What is it?
- Trauma choppers.
- Nice.
Hey, could you hand me my...?
Oh... Well, OK. Good morning.
- Good morning.
- Yes, it is.
I have a trauma chopper 15
minutes out and a small window of time
- where I can practice medicine.
- Right. Plus,
Thomas Evans is here.
- He is. He's doing a coronary...
- Is he interviewing for my job?
I've been waiting to hear about
a permanent contract from you.
- I haven't,
Thomas Evans is here.
- You have a temporary contract.
- You said you
were looking elsewhere.
- Yeah, I was, but I stopped.
- I didn't know that.
- I'm sorry. I should have told you.
I'd be happy to consider you
for the permanent position.
- Consider me? For my job?
- I had to run a search.
I can't get caught
without a head of cardio.
OK. Well, I... I'd
like to be considered.
I'll throw you in the mix.
Hey. The baby's sleeping.
Um...
Thank you for...
- everything.
- I'm happy to help.
- Dad?
- Hey.
Everything's fine.
The baby's doing great.
- Hey, can you grab my bag?
- Yeah.
What is all this?
You...
- Did you buy all this for the baby?
- - Yeah.
I figured he was gonna need
stuff. And I was already in the store.
I know it's lame, all the girl
stuff was way better, but...
- Boys like Army crap, right?
- Oh! No, that's
a choking hazard.
Well, he's a little
young for that.
And that.
Whatever. It doesn't
really matter anyway.
He's gonna be getting
a lot nicer stuff soon.
Here.
This is the number for the
people that are gonna adopt him.
Trish and Keith.
Can you call them?
- Mark...
- Yeah.
- Do you want me
to handle that call?
- No, no. I'll take care of it.
It was a fishing boat accident.
Two patients, one with a head lac
and abdominal pain. The other, something
about a fish hook stuck somewhere.
Why would they send a
chopper for a guy with a fish hook?
I'm pretty sure they said
fish hook, Chief Shepherd.
OK.
"I'm pretty sure they said
fish hook, Chief Shepherd.
If I'm wrong, you can spank me.
Chief Shepherd, I do hope I'm wrong."
What do we got?
We got the son, head laceration,
crush injuries. The dad's right behind.
- Let's go!
- OK.
Fifty-year-old male,
penetrating trauma to the chest,
hypotensive in the field. Got
him two liters of LR en route.
Oh! Big hook!
Big hook!
Mrs. Smitte, when is the last
time you took a flight of stairs
instead of an elevator?
God, it's... it's been years.
This time next week,
you're gonna do it.
Your grandkids,
you have grandkids?
- Two.
- They're not
gonna know what hit 'em.
They won't be able
to keep up with you.
- You mean it?
- I mean it.
He means it.
Excuse me. Sorry.
- Come in here...
- No.
Why?
- Hold steady. Grey, get in there.
- What do we have? Oh, my God.
Here we go.
Boat accident.
Something fell on him.
- And the hook?
- Looks like he fell on it.
- Pressure's at 68, systolic.
- Tracheal deviation,
absent breath sounds.
Get me a 14-gauge needle.
- Right behind you.
- Dad? What are
you doing to him?
- Grey, get him out of here!
- I'm trying. Doug, please.
Oh, God! What the hell is that?
Dad, I don't know what happened. I
had the rope in my hand one minute...
- Doug, Doug, come on.
- No, I did this.
- I'm sorry. Dad, I'm so sorry.
- It's OK. It's not your fault.
Of course it's his fault!
I was thrown on top of the shark
hook because he let go of the rope.
Who the hell's fault is it?
Let's leave the hook in
until we get him up to the OR.
I'm feeling depressed
skull fracture.
- Order a head CT.
- Right away, chief.
That was the first thing he
taught me when I joined the crew.
I don't know how...
We didn't play ball
when I was little.
We tied knots. I know
how to tie that knot.
Doug, you made a
mistake. It was an accident.
What if it wasn't?
I thought about it sometimes.
Hitting him, or hurting him.
He pisses me off
sometimes. He's harsh and...
- You did this on purpose?
- No.
Not on purpose. I just...
- I don't feel so good.
- OK, try to relax.
Deep breaths. Deep breaths.
OK, Grey, order a head
CT and get a CT angio.
- I saw some fluid
around his spleen.
- I'll do it.
I think there's some...
Um... I'll just deal
with the vomit.
So the nurse says
I'm being discharged.
I have to leave tomorrow? I
just had the baby, like, today.
It's a good thing. It
means you're doing great.
No complications.
Right, little man?
Where am I supposed to go?
My mom kicked me out and those
friends I was staying with in Portland
were like, "You gotta pay rent, or
you gotta leave." And I can't pay rent.
I don't have a job.
I don't have anything.
You can stay with me.
- Really?
- Sure.
Until you figure things out.
You're gonna be OK.
Sloans are tough.
You hear that? We're tough.
Maybe we should... keep him.
You think you could?
Maybe.
- You wanna hold him?
- No.
- I don't think I know how to...
- Do you wanna hold him?
He's pretty great.
- Look who it is.
- Hi, baby.
Look at that.
You're a natural.
It's up to you.
If you think we can do this.
Raise him.
Together. If you think we can.
Hey, guys. He really needs to
go to the nursery to be monitored
- and get his newborn check-up.
- I'm monitoring
and I did the exams.
He's all good.
Mark, when you get a minute,
I'd love to have a quick word.
- Caught a big one?
- That's funny.
He's got a small hematoma.
Can I ask you something?
Why did you hire Altman?
- What'd you see in her?
- Well, what do you see in her?
I think she's good. She works
hard. I feel bad even looking.
I'd feel worse, though, having
a stronger candidate pass us by.
It's not the
feel-good job, is it?
- Can't you give me
a little insight?
- No.
See, that'd be
doing the job for you.
I'm not gonna give you the fish.
You got a big hook in there.
Learn to fish yourself.
What kind of life is that?
Living five months
at a time on a boat,
working 20 hours
in terrible conditions?
In 2007, the CDC marked crab fishing
the most dangerous job in the U.S.
with an annual fatality rate 28
times higher than any other job.
What?
Dude, it's like working
with Forrest Gump.
The kid's 15. He
should be doing algebra
and going to school dances.
- How much you bet he did it?
- What?
- Hooked his old man on purpose.
- I'd say 70 percent
it was an accident,
thirty percent attempted murder.
What? Karev's right.
Too much nature
makes people crazy.
OK, there is the tear.
Grey? You wanna embolize it?
Really? I've never
done it before.
- But I've read that if you...
- You want this kid
to bleed to death
or what?
Don't analyze everything.
Just... do it.
Tell me you called the parents.
Sloan's having second thoughts.
Sloan picked those parents.
She asked you to call them.
She was pretty clear.
Now, she's not clear. By law,
she's got 48 hours before the
court terminates her parental right.
- Sloan changed her mind?
- - Maybe.
- That's great!
- No, it's not.
She can't change her mind?
People change their minds.
This baby needs parents,
not an 18-year-old child
- and a father
she met five minutes ago.
- Shut up!
- Mark...
- No.
You don't get to tell
me what to do here.
I appreciate your
help, but you don't...
My mom is dead.
My dad's never gonna
get off the couch again.
I don't have any
brothers or sisters.
This is my grandson.
My grandson!
I'm not gonna turn him
over to some strangers
when I might have a
chance at a family. So just...
give me a minute here!
- How's he doing?
- His temp's high.
I can't figure out why.
Is his dad in surgery yet?
Yeah, they're prepping him now.
Doug, would you like to see your
dad before he goes into surgery?
- He's probably calmed down.
- He hates me.
He's always hated me.
Now, I practically killed him.
He doesn't want to see me.
Once when I was little,
I was really mad at my mom.
And I had heard that
saccharine can kill you,
and so, I swear to God, I almost
put ten packets of Sweet 'N Low
into her coffee all at the
same time. I was this close.
While she was thinking of
sweetening her mom's coffee,
I tried to run my old man
over with a car. It's normal.
No, that's... That's not normal.
Those hooks were
meant to catch sharks.
He's never letting me
near him or the boat again.
I don't even know
where I'm supposed to go.
Ow! My head is, like, pounding.
Hey. We should get blood
cultures and a repeat CBC.
We need to find out
why he's burning up.
You do that, Sweet 'N Low. I'm
gonna go watch them pull out a hook.
The baby smiled at Mark.
He looked up and smiled
at him like he knew him.
That poor baby's
parents just sitting...
- Stop calling
them the baby's...
- That baby's parents.
The mature, capable,
financially secure,
emotionally stable,
loving parents,
who were deemed fit by Sloan
and the State of Washington,
are sitting there
by the telephone,
staring at the sky-blue nursery
walls that they just painted.
Those are the parents,
not Mr. Midlife Crisis
and his teenage kid
who bought her infant son a bag of
lollipops and Juicy Couture onesies.
So she has a lot to learn.
No, she doesn't.
She made the one sound parenting
decision she needs to make.
She found a lovely
couple to raise her baby.
She did that months ago when she
wasn't flooded with postpartum hormones
or overwhelmed by
heartfelt pleas from her dad.
She had time to think clearly
about what was right for her
and what was right for the baby.
She made a decision,
a good decision.
And it would be great if we
could all try and respect that.
OK.
Crap. Sloan.
- Is he OK?
- I don't know. He won't stop crying.
- What happened?
- I don't know.
I was holding him and
Mark went to go get a bottle
and he started crying.
He's not stopping.
- I think something's wrong.
- What happened?
Sloan got worried.
The baby's fine.
He's just hungry, is all.
No, I... I don't
know how to do this.
We're right here
if you need help.
No, he's crying. I don't
think he wants me to do it.
Here.
- Oh, God! I don't feel so good.
- You've been up all night.
You're exhausted and
dehydrated. Drink that.
Thought I'd check to
see how far along we are.
Almost ready to extract
the hook. Suction.
After they get him off the hook,
we'll evacuate the hematoma
- and plate the skull fragments?
- - I thought we'd throw him back.
Catch and release.
Thank you, Dr. Kepner.
Well, Walter's lucky. It looks like
he doesn't have to lose any lung.
Yeah, no thanks to his kid.
Well, it was an
accident. It happens.
The kid shouldn't have
been there in the first place.
Well, he's the guy's son.
Family business. There's
something to be said for loyalty.
Put a person in a job like that
because they have
the skills to handle it,
not because they're
your friend. Or your kid.
Are you intentionally equating
me with the idiot son that dropped
the crab cage on his dad, or is
that just a happy coincidence?
All right. Ready to extract
the hook from the man.
All right, nobody
move but Dr. Hunt.
On my count.
One...
two...
Snagged an artery.
- I'm sorry.
- God bless you.
He's stabilized
and ready for you.
I'm sorry.
Look, if this doesn't go your
way, please don't take it personally.
You're an incredible
surgeon. I see that.
It's that Evans has
published dozens of times.
- He's won awards.
- She won a Bronze Star
for service to her country.
Does that not count?
And the anastomosis is done.
- Fine suture hook?
- You're not
using the side clamp?
No. It's a special technique.
I get a very clean, very
nice anastomosis this way.
Much less trauma to the
surrounding structures.
You just parachuted
that vein graft down.
Is that to avoid memory in
the suture or tangles later on?
Excellent observation, Yang. Have
you already applied for your fellowships?
- Oh, I'm only in third year.
- Oh. Right, I forgot.
It feels like I'm
working with a fellow.
Thank you.
Oh. Would you like me
to cut the last suture?
That's OK. I already got it.
Wow!
It looks like you've
barely operated at all.
- It's so perfect.
- That is the goal, Dr. Yang.
That is the goal.
Excellent.
Hook guy is stable
for now. How's the kid?
Crappy. Nothing we can do
now until we finish with the angio.
- Lexie's baby-sitting.
- Hey!
Have you, uh, seen Evans?
It was amazing. Who saw?
Dude, you're like a
kid with trading cards.
- Except with heart surgeons.
- Yeah. I gotta have 'em all.
I thought Teddy was
the love of your life.
She is. She is, but...
Evans, brilliant.
I mean brilliant.
So is she, but...
I love them both.
I'm a cardio-thoracic whore.
Saying it makes me feel so good.
Speaking of whores,
has anyone seen the love-struck
intern fawning over my husband?
- April's not an intern.
- Bat your eyes like that,
- you're an intern.
- Don't worry. That's not Derek's thing.
- Anymore.
- I was the love-struck intern.
- It is his thing.
- He's grown out of it.
Out of what, chicks who shave
their legs and laugh at his jokes?
- Sure, he's grown out of it.
- I shave my legs.
Sometimes.
You could always call
him Chief Shepherd.
- Ew!
- I don't make the rules.
I'm telling you, it's a thing.
- Powerful guys
like adoring girls.
- Oh, my...
Whatever. Do what you want.
Oh! That baby's delicious.
Yeah. I was thinking I
could take paternity leave.
At least for a couple of weeks.
It'd help Sloan get
the hang of things.
I don't know if a couple
of weeks is enough.
She's a good kid.
She's got good instincts.
Well, her instincts lead her to
put the baby up for adoption.
I don't know.
She's unformed,
she's a baby herself.
I don't know.
Yeah.
I don't know either.
Arizona wants to go to Spain.
She's picking a suntan over
a family, which I don't get.
Didn't she have, like, a
happy, idyllic childhood?
Totally! She talks to her
parents every day. Every day!
Part of which could
be the brother thing.
- What brother thing?
- He died.
Her brother died.
And I'm an idiot.
You have a cold. It could
have happened to any of us.
Yeah, but it didn't.
It was me.
On the day that Shepherd is
interviewing Evans for my job
and I'm the new girl here
who no one really knows,
and even Yang is
in love with Evans
and I... Ah!
And I have a freaking cold!
- I'm sorry!
- It's OK.
You're gonna be OK.
What happened?
He became lethargic and
febrile. Coughed up blood.
His X-ray shows there's a large
hemothorax where we took the hook out.
We'll have to go back in. The
repairs must not have held.
Should get a CT to confirm before
cutting into a patient that's unstable.
There's no time for that. He could
go into multi-system organ failure.
Shepherd, you have to trust
that I know what I'm doing.
I'll call up the OR. Let
them know you're coming.
Yes this is Chief Shepherd,
we're gonna need a cardiac room.
- You paged me?
- What's up?
Doug has fever and rigors and he's
starting to get a productive cough.
So deal with it. Hook guy's tanking.
He coughed up blood or something.
They're taking him
back to surgery.
Wait, he coughed up blood?
What did it look
like, currant jelly?
Did he have leukocytosis with a
left shift? His P.A.CO2 was 28, right?
I don't know, Encyclopedia
Brown. I didn't memorize the chart.
Let him go, Grey, he has
a surgery he wants to see.
Thank you, Dr. Bailey.
Dr. Bailey, both patients
have productive coughs
and signs and
symptoms of sepsis.
I am probably wrong, but
if I'm not, this is infectious.
You're probably not
wrong. You're probably right.
Why do you want to hand
your big save over to Karev,
who's gonna march around the
hospital acting like he put it together?
- I didn't...
- You are handing your power
over to a boy because
he's giving you sex.
- I'm not...
- I'm Dr. Bailey. I know everything.
And you have a superpower.
That memory of
yours is a superpower.
And on top of it,
you're a good doctor.
And yet you're letting Alex
Karev treat you like a scut monkey.
I don't care how good the
sex is, if that's what it costs,
- you're paying too much.
- I'm not!
- Scut monkey all day.
- Doctor?
Thank you.
- I was right.
- I know.
Now, what are you
going to do about it?
Karev, what's the
status on your patient?
Temperature spiked.
The dude's doing fine.
- We're running new labs.
- Dr. Altman, stop!
Dr. Grey, you always shout at
people right before they start operating?
Doug has Klebsiella pneumonia,
and I'm guessing Walter does too.
We need to start imipenem
stat or things could get ugly fast.
- Klebsiella?
- Highly contagious in close quarters.
Like living on a crab
boat for months at a time.
I think that hemothorax is a
mixture of blood and an empyema.
- Thanks for the heads-up.
- You were busy.
- Maybe we should
open and check...
- No, I, um...
- I think I was wrong here.
- Get him out of the OR,
into the ICU now!
- This day has to end.
- Tell me about it.
I was supposed to watch
Tom Evans work.
Meanwhile, I got stuck in an OR all
day watching Teddy Altman decompose
- in front of my eyes.
- I don't understand.
- What's Tom Evans doing here?
- Taking a look around.
Why? You don't need
Evans. You got Teddy.
- I don't need Teddy
if I've got Evans.
- What?
No, you can't. Me and...
Me and Teddy, we...
See, this is my point exactly.
I can't staff this hospital
based on the fact
that she's Hunt's friend
and your flavor of the month.
I'm just sick of worrying about
this. This job's exhausting.
I'm sorry. That's what you're
complaining about? Screw you.
I'm losing everything today.
Everything!
Go ahead.
How am I supposed to call a couple of
strangers and tell them to take my kid?
Sloan's your kid, Mark.
You're not losing her.
They're not taking her.
Hey. Did you see me in the OR?
- You're an idiot.
- What?
You really think that Evans is gonna
take you under his award-winning wing?
He won't. He doesn't need you.
He doesn't care about students.
He's a rock star, not a teacher.
He is a rock star. Teddy,
he's totally a rock star.
Did you see him in there?
He was like an octopus!
Doing a million things, cutting,
retracting, suctioning all at once.
You think I need you to hold
my instruments when I operate?
You think that helps
me save the patient?
I do it so that you
can learn, Cristina.
I'd be a lot faster in
the OR without you.
Did you notice you never
even touched that patient?
Your gloves were totally clean at
the end of surgery. You learn a lot?
Teddy, it was one surgery.
He's here for my job,
Cristina. Do you not get that?
If Evans is in, I'm out. So, you know,
good luck with your new attending.
I get it.
You watch parents go through
horrible, unimaginable pain.
Every day.
And you went through
horrible, unimaginable pain
when you lost your brother.
And your parents never got over it.
But if we had a baby...
our baby's not gonna be
one of those kids in your NICU.
Our baby won't be your brother.
I mean, knock on wood.
Do you know how
happy our baby would be?
I'm gonna say this once.
And then I'm not
gonna say it again.
I'm not broken.
I'm not some psychodrama.
My lack of interest in having
a child is not some pathology
that you can pat yourself on
the back for having diagnosed.
I like my life the way that it
is. I don't want it to change.
I thought I liked
it with you in it.
I hope I'm not wrong.
Wait.
- I called your mother.
- What?
Why?! She kicked me out!
She's on her way.
She misses you.
- She's worried about you.
- Right.
- I'm worried about you, too.
- If this is the part
where you tell me
that you talked to her
and she convinced you
that me keeping my baby was a bad
idea because I'm young and irresponsible...
That's not what the
conversation was about.
OK, well, so you thought it over
and you decided that you
don't have time for a kid?
That's fine. I get it. You
have a life. You're busy.
But you know what? I can
handle this kid on my own.
No, you can't.
Having a kid is hard. And you
are young and irresponsible.
And keeping him is
probably a bad idea.
But if that is your decision,
if that's what you want,
then I'm in. I'm all in.
I'm not too busy for my family.
But...
don't keep the baby for me.
You'll always have me.
And I'll always want you.
And that's true no
matter what you decide.
You're my kid.
And I'm so happy I
get to know you, Sloan.
I'm so happy about that.
Hey. What are you
doing right now?
- Uh, I'm...
- Can we walk and talk?
- Where are we going?
- You need to talk
to Derek Shepherd
about Teddy, and why replacing her
with Evans would be a huge mistake.
Remember, be
persuasive and strong.
- Use a lot of words.
- Cristina, I'm not 12.
- I'm not saying you're 12.
- Dr. Yang.
- Good work today.
- Thank you, Dr. Evans.
This is important.
- Shepherd.
- Hunt.
Before you say anything, I
want you to know that I think, uh...
she's a fine surgeon.
- Evans is interested?
- Yeah, I think so.
Evans is good, he's really good.
Patients would come here
from all over. That would be...
That would be
good for this hospital.
- I'm glad you feel that way.
- Yeah.
And Teddy has a
lot of connections.
Mainly on the East
Coast, so she'd be fine.
If that's what you decide.
She'd be fine.
Thank you.
Walter, I need you
to squeeze my hands.
All right, let's do a
little push against them.
Not bad, all things considered.
You like being captain?
Do I like it?
No.
Me neither.
You know what it beats, though?
It beats not being captain.
Come here, son.
You OK?
This was my fault.
I'm sorry.
Thanks, Dad.
Just remember.
The Sloans, we bloom early.
So when you start to grow
hair on your face, don't be shy.
Live it up.
All the other guys
will be jealous.
It's OK to rub
it in a little bit.
But not a lot.
You don't wanna be
considered too full of yourself.
No one likes a vain
guy in the locker room.
Mark.
Oh, my God!
Is that him?
Hey there.
Hi there, little guy.
Oh!
He's so beautiful!
This is...
And this.
Thank you.
- He has your dad's chin.
- What?
That's crazy.
Come in.
Chief Shepherd, are you busy?
- You just called
me Chief Shepherd?
- I did.
Go with it.
What are you doing
with the shades?
Shh...
- No one can know.
- No one can know what?
About our secret
love, Chief Shepherd.
- Secret love?
- By the way, chief,
I picked up your
dry-cleaning for you.
And I...
- Ooh!
- Had your car washed.
And I dusted off your desk.
With my bottom.
Is there anything else I can
do for you, Chief Shepherd?
Let me see if I can come
up with a list of things.
Oh, Chief Shepherd!
Give me a beer.
You screwed me today.
That was my patient.
You made me look like a
moron. Get your own beer.
You...
You can't be an ass to me all day
and expect me to give you respect.
and then expect me to give you sex.
And you can stop with the patronizing
nicknames. I am a nice person,
who couldn't even bring myself to
attempt matricide by Sweet 'N Low.
That makes me
charming to anybody else.
I am a nice person.
And I am nice to you.
So, whatever your damage is,
you better start to
be frickin' nice to me,
or I am not spreading my legs for you
anymore, no matter how much I want to.
Now give me a damn beer!
As doctors, we have an
arsenal of weapons at the ready.
My cousin's baby
punched her in the face.
Literally.
She got a black eye
from a one-year-old.
Who needs that, right?
I don't need that.
They scream,
they're grimy, they...
smell like poop, the
house smells like poop.
Don't.
Antibiotics to kill infections,
narcotics to fight pain.
Tell me you're staying.
Please.
I'm staying.
OK.
Scalpels and retractors to
remove tumors and cancers.
- Derek!
- - To eradicate the threat.
I heard you gave
Teddy a contract.
- Yes, I did.
- I'm glad.
It was the right move.
Loyalty, it's a powerful thing.
It makes for a great chief.
I offered it to Evans.
He passed.
But just the physical threat.
For every other kind...
you're on your own.