♪♪
Our bodies play host
to trillions of bacteria
and other microbes.
They live on our skin,
in our guts, up our noses.
Alright, the kids are
cleaning their rooms.
What's next?
Uh, appetizers, salad?
Anything.
I should've taken
this whole day off.
Microbes are found in almost
every part of the body.
It doesn't need to
be perfect.
It's just dinner.
It's a dinner party
to welcome Nick.
You know what?
I don't remember getting
a welcome dinner party.
You arrived
during a pandemic.
Plus, Nick is very important
to Meredith,
and I want to
get to know him.
Mm-hmm.
You want to grill him.
That's what you wanna do.
Hospital?
Hotel.
Wendell's room service
is on the way.
How's he doing?
Apparently
living it up.
On my dime.
At least we got
our couch back.
So when's he supposed to hear
about that job in Boston?
Well, he says
any day now.
Oh, do you want me
to slice these?
No, Amelia's
gonna make guacamole.
Where is Amelia?
Microbes help us
produce vitamins
and stimulate
our immune system.
♪♪
Wow.
That was...
Better than forcing me
to go sight-seeing?
Ah. I don't know.
The view from the Space Needle
is pretty spectacular.
Hmm. More
spectacular than this?
You can see Mount Rainier...
...Puget Sound,
Meredith's house...
♪ Turn it out,
give 'em what they came for ♪
We're late.
We g... we gotta go.
Maggie is gonna freak out.
We gotta go.
Hey. Hey.
♪ Just tell me
the place and time ♪
You sure?
They break down food and
perform many other functions
that we need to survive.
Nope.
♪ Make it look like
I never try ♪
♪ Now shake it, shake it,
watch me move ♪
Hey.
I thought you
had a transplant.
No, I'm all done.
Ms. Olick is in the ICU.
I'm gonna
drop by my place
and then I'm gonna head to yours.
Okay.
I just have one more patient
and then I'll see you there.
Okay.
- What?
- No, it's nice.
Just living in the same city.
I like it. It's nice.
Well, hopefully you feel
the same way after tonight.
If you're
trying to scare me off,
it's gonna take a lot more than
your sisters and your kids.
Promise me you won't get home
and decide to skip the party.
And miss the awkward
small talk?
Never.
See ya.
You're still here?
Don't tell me
the party is canceled.Wow.
I got all the senior residents
working, a babysitter.
I got my party shoes
in the car.
Do not ruin this
for me.
Bailey, the party is
not canceled.
I will see you there.
Good.
Look at my face.
I need fun.
Me too.
Ay, yi, yi, yi.
ABG looks good.
Patient's less acidotic.
You want me to run
another one in an hour?
No, no.
You should go home.
I don't want your hours
to become a problem
for the Medical
Accreditation Council, hm?
Mm.
Why aren't you
in party clothes?
You have chemo.
Yes, I have chemo.
You have a party.
A dinner party.
Look, I promised
if you did this trial
that I would stand by your side
for every step.
Baby, you went with me
to my first infusion.
I'll be fine
by myself.
I'm not breaking
my promise.
♪♪
We're here!
Everyone, this is Kai.
Hi!
Nice to meet you.
I'm Maggie.
I'm Amelia's sister.
- This is Winston, my husband.
- Hey.
- Ooh!
Sorry!
And this is
Zola, Bailey, and Ellis.
- Hi!
Sorry we're late.
It was my fault.
Oh.
Hi. Nice to meet you.
Uh, put... put us to work.
Uh, how can we help?
Did you bring the ice?
Ah.
- Alright, I'll go pick that up.
- Thank you.
Yeah.
What else can we help with?
- Oh.
- Hey, that's mine.
No, it's not.
Yes, it is.
It's not.
Can you keep them from
breaking each other?
Hey, guys!
Why don't we take
this party outside?
Yes!
Yeah!
You play soccer?
I was hoping
that you do.
Come on.
Hey.
Aww.
Is that how we
greet our guests?
I thought it was Mama.
Aww.
I'm sorry.
- Come in. Come on in.
- Okay. Yep.
Um, Meredith isn't here yet, obviously.
Okay. Yeah.
And you are on time
to the minute.
Yeah, it's
a transplant surgeon thing.
If I'm late,
organs die, so...
Yeah.
Here you go.
Oh, thank you so much.
Welcome.
Yeah, well, I wanted to bring
flowers, but Meredith said
that only stresses out the host,
because then they're
forced to find a vase
and put water in it, so...
Listen,
wine is always welcome.
Okay. Good.
So, uhh, Winston is
out getting ice,
and I'm a little behind on the food.
Oh, okay.
So, uh, make yourself at home,
and I...
Yeah, okay.
Oh.
- Hey!
It's customary to be
at least 15 minutes late!
We could wait outside, or...
No, no, no.
Come in, come in.
Hey!
Hi.
Uh...
should I open these?
I'll take the two of them.
Oh, of course.
No! No, he can't.
No, no, no.
It's alright. It's alright.
Um, who's not on call?
Me.
- Alright. Mm-hmm.
- Come on in.
Well, good night, Dr. Grey.
Have fun at your party.
It's just a dinner.
Well, it's not work.
Fair point.
Plus, it gives the residents
a chance to step up and help.
I remember
having that attitude.
Alice Tom. 72.
Massive facial trauma
and complaining of right arm
and abdominal pain
after an assault
at a bus stop.
Oh, my God.
Tachy in the 120s,
BP 140 over 90.
She received 4 of morphine
en route.
Okay, let's get her inside.
What happened?
Bus driver said the attacker
was using racial slurs
and yelling at her to
go back to where she's from.
Oh, my God.
Okay.
We've got you, Alice.
Oh, UCSF's starting trials
on a new treatment.
Maybe we should
look into it, huh?
Maybe.
Does your oncologist come
to all your appointments?
This is my husband.
He's not my oncologist,
but he is a doctor.
One who cares very much
about your health.
Mm.
Hm.
Chondrosarcoma.
Synovial sarcoma.
Hmm, that's tough.
We like to say
it's persistent.
You.You like to say
He's being exceedingly
optimistic.
For me.
How much longer?
I'm 35 weeks and...
Not that she's counting.
No, of course
I'm counting.
You have to be able
to meet him.
Oh, nanotechnology's
come a long way.
Maybe we should
look into that.
Maybe.
Mm.
So, have you two
picked out a name yet?
Please tell me everything.
I need a distraction.
Sorry.
I know it hurts.
Push another
2 of morphine.
She has a comminuted mid-shaft
humerus fracture
with a wound over
the fracture site.
♪♪
It was a hate crime,
wasn't it?
It appears that way.
We can get another
ortho surgeon...
No, no, no, no. I'm here.
I'm... I'll do it.
I'd like
a maxillofacial scan.
I am seeing some fluid
in the upper left quadrant.
Let's order a CT to rule out
any other injuries.
I'll call CT.
Okay, I'll clean out
this fracture wound
as soon as you're done
with your evaluation.
Let's get her started
on antibiotics
and just page me
as soon as you're done.
Please.
Okay.
♪♪
Right. Okay.
Oh, may I?
No, you are
the guest of honor.
...who has impressive
knife skills.
Please. I got it.
What? Oh. Hey!
I can help.
Oh, uh...
It's a salad.
Right.
So, uh, how long
you been at the clinic?
Um, about 16 years.
I did my residency
in D.C. before that.
You didn't
like the East Coast?
No, I got a fellowship
back home,
and, well, to be honest,
my uh, sister couldn't stay
sober long enough
to remember she had a toddler.
So, two birds, one stone, I guess.
That's probably
the wrong analogy,
but you get the picture.
Yeah.
You got kids?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Toddlers.
Hey, I got ice.
Nick, hey.
Hey.
Welcome.
Backyard cooler.
Alright.
Hey, where does Mer
keep the games?
Games?
It's a dinner party.
Well, I mean...
is dinner ready?
Hi. How are you?
What's wrong?
Oh, geopolitics
are a mess,
global warming's
getting worse...
You meant him.
Yeah.
I think he wants
Amelia.
- Oh, it's okay, buddy.
- Here we go!
Hey.
Ahh.
It's okay.
Hey, it's okay.
- Hello.
- Hi.
Food's in the kitchen,
drinks are out back.
Come on. Come with me.
Go, I got him.
♪♪
Why didn't you say that?
Hold on. What does that mean?
Well, good evening,
Chief Bailey.
Can I take your coat?
How about a drink?
Oh, Bailey!
Want to play Boggle?
I very much do not.
Come on,
it's so much fun.
You made me the ambassador
of fun, remember?
Yeah, I never
understood that.
Uh, Grey couldn't bother
to make it to her own party?
Or set out a few crackers?
Chief.
Marsh.
Yeah, Meredith is running
a bit late, but, uh...
can I get you a drink,
glass of wine?
Bourbon. Neat.
And generous.
Okay, I approve.
This way.
Mm.
No, no. I'm not playing
Boggle with you.
I've been texting you
for like 10 minutes.
What the hell
are you doing here?
Having dinner?
My lenders are after me.
I couldn't stay
at the hotel.
Wendell.
Maggie, you look so nice!
H-Here you go.
Do you happen to have
room for one more?
♪♪
I am so sorry.
I never thought he would
just show up here.
Did you tell him
we were having a party?
No, I told him
I was going to a party.
That guy's
a walking sales pitch.
I wonder what
he's selling them now.
Maggie, please.
I will... I'll ask him to go.
No, no, I'm not
asking for that.
No, I-I-I want to.
I just... I need
a minute to figure out
how he doesn't make
a big scene about this.
Hey.
Um, are you okay?
Fine. Yeah.
I'm not just talking about
tonight, Winston.
I am worried about you.
About us.
I know.
Sorry,
the t-timer's still going.
Yeah.
You into music?
Do I like music?
Yeah, I like music.
Uh, unless you're asking me
to join your garage band.
Then... Then, no.
No, I-I don't.
Got it.
What's your opinion
on contact sports?
Uh, hard pass for kids,
and I'm... I'm more of
a running/cycling guy.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
Mountain bike?
Not a lot of mountains
in Minnesota.
Ah, right.
This back burner's been
finicky for over a year.
When Meredith was
in the hospital with COVID,
it was me, Amelia,
and four kids living here.
So...I grilled a lot.
Right.
So you and Amelia are...
are Scout's parents?
Yep.
♪♪
You're probably
friends with Kai.
Friends?
I-I mean, not really.
But, impressed, yes.
Their... Their work
has brought in
some pretty amazing grants
to the clinic.
There's a reason they work
with David Hamilton.
♪♪
So you're saying
my ex traded up.
It's hard to say.
I haven't known you
that long.
♪♪
I'm gonna need
more beer.
♪♪
I know.
Hey, we should, uh,
have a playdate soon.
Yeah.
Your kids
play with Scout?
Yeah, Amelia.
I'd say that she's
their favorite aunt,
but my sister
would be mad, so...
Aunt?
Unofficial.
Mm, yeah, she was there
the day I got Leo.
And she drove Teddy
to the hospital
when we had
Allison, so...
That's right.
Aunt, okay.
Okay. He's overtired.
Or overstimulated.
I'm gonna... I'm gonna
try and put him down.
Ellis wants more sparkling
cider, and my drawing app froze.
Oh, here. Let me
try to restart it.
Would you mind?
Oh, s-sure.
Yeah.
Bailey.
Mmm.
Maggie couldn't have
made this spinach dip.
She's a Boston girl.
She knows better than to
put garlic salt instead of...
Look, how bad is it?
Well, you know, Nana Ante
only used sea salt,
so the situation's
fairly dire,
but we won't be
too loud about it.
The lenders, Wendell.
When you say that
they're after you,
does that mean
physically, or...
Oh, hey, man.
Can you tell Maggie
the veggies have
another five minutes?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah. Hi.
Wendell Ndugu.
Hi.
I'm Winston's brother.
Ah. Nick Marsh.
Everyone here related,
or...?
Uh, Wendell's
just visiting.
Got it.
Well, for now.
Seattle's not so bad.
Might be nice to
be around family.
Sure.
Come on,
you love Boston.
You love Boston.
No one loves Boston.
That's a fact. It's true.
It's very true.
That can't be good.
No,
I think it's just small talk.
What if Nick is
a con man like Wendell?
Because con men
only talk to each other?
Because the only person
who has charmed me
as much as your brother
is Nick Marsh.
What about me?
I haven't. Yeah, we're...
we're ahead of the curve.
Okay.
And these...
There's
the husband, right there.
Perfect.
Thank you so much.
Mr. Tom. Excuse me.
Hey. Hi,
I'm Meredith Grey.
Uh-huh.And this is Dr. Schmitt.
We are part of the medical team
working on your wife.
How is she?
Will she be okay?
Uh, she has a... she suffered
a pretty serious attack, sir.
She's in surgery
right now.
She has a broken arm
and some facial fractures,
which our plastics and
orthopedic teams are working on.
Okay.
She also suffered an injury
to her spleen,
which at this point,
opening up her abdomen
could do
more harm than good.
And the blood flow
to her organs is stable.
Oftentimes,
these things heal themselves.
We have a family dinner
every week.
She went to the store
to buy chocolate syrup
so the grandkids could have
sundaes for dessert.
I said I'd drive her,
but she was an engineer
for the city's
Transportation Department
for 30 years
before she retired.
She insisted on taking the bus.
♪♪
When will I be able
to see her?
♪♪
Very soon.
And... And I will let you know
as soon as
she's out of surgery, okay?
Can we get you anything?
Coffee or... or more water?
Uh, no, no, no.
I'm fine, thank you.
But is there a way I can
tell Alice that I'm here?
That we're all here?
I want her to know
that she's not alone.
Of course.
I would be happy
to tell her that.
And again, I'm... I'm very sorry
that this has happened.
Yeah.
♪♪
- Ooh!
- Kris?
Ooh, that was weird.
I'm sure it's nothing.
Oh, honestly,
I hate puzzles.
Why do we do them?
You hate doing puzzles.
You love
having finished them.
Mm, but at
what cost, babe?
At what cost?
Sweetheart, you know,
I was thinking...
we should create
a wellness room at home.
You know, with a yoga mat,
a meditation stool.
Lord.
Yeah,
I did that, too.
It's now a very
calming storage room
for our golf clubs
and our luggage.
Aah!
What?
Contractions?
Should be
too early for that.
Maybe he's just kicking
because he hates puzzles, too.
Maybe we should call
Dr. Wilson.
W-Wilson's your OB, huh?
Yeah,
she's checked in on us
a few times
since we've been here.
Page her, baby.
Yeah, I am... Okay.
What if... Ah!
What if...
No, no, it's too
early for that.
- What if it's not?
- Nurse. Nurse.
Ahh!
Take some deep breaths.
♪♪
♪ Who's gonna cut the rope?
When I was a kid, I used to
stare at my face in the mirror
and wonder if I could use
my mom's makeup
to make me look
more "American,"
which, of course, I understood
to mean more white.
You wanted to be like
all the other kids.
And my teachers and people I saw
in movies and on TV.
I wanted to feel normal.
Like I belonged.
♪ Carry on
Do you even think we'll ever
stop being seen as foreign?
Well, being wrongly blamed
for COVID did not help.
But also,
the Watsonville Riots.
The Japanese American
internment.
Vincent Chin.
A long history
of being outsiders.
How ironic.
We are Americans.
♪ How do I drain
all of this bad blood? ♪
Your face is American.
♪♪
♪ I do the best I can
Have her vitals
been stable?
Uh, yeah,
she's okay for now.
Okay.
Do you mind if I...
♪ Balancing on the edge
Alice,
your husband is here,
and your whole family
is here.
We're going to
take care of you.
You're not alone.
You are not alone, Alice.
I'll check back in a bit.
♪ Carry on
I'm so sorry.
♪♪
♪ What do you say
when your chance is gone? ♪
♪ Fair enough
I heard, and I didn't
want to go home.
♪ How do I drain
all of this bad blood? ♪
No one called for help.
No one intervened
or even took a video.
♪♪
It's so awful.
And I just...
I wish I could help.
♪♪
Okay.
Okay, Kristen.
So, your contractions are
irregular and not too strong,
so it appears to be
just Braxton Hicks.
Doctors always say
"just" Braxton Hicks
as though they
don't actually hurt.
I know. I'm sorry.
Doctors are the worst.
Excuse me?
Stop hovering.
Mind your business.
Come over here.
Thank you. We really
appreciate you taking a look.
Of course.
I do want to take you to OB
triage, do a cervical exam,
and to monitor you
just for a bit in case.
And we can see how the baby's
doing with the contractions.
No, no.
I-I can't leave Simon.
You'll just be upstairs,
and we can page if any...
Please.
I don't want to be alone.
- Hey.
- Richard, take her up.
You've been cooped up here
all night long.
Simon will keep me company,
and you and Kristen
can go somewhere
where there are no puzzles.
Please, babe.
I don't want
you hurting, too.
Okay.
Come with me.
I'll be fine.
I promise.
Okay.
This way.Promise.
Dr. Williams to Radiology.
Dr. Sandra Williams
to Radiology.
So, uh, Nick, what's
your favorite place
to do a transplant?
Oh, um, well,
I put a pig's kidney on
a man's groin the other day.
That was pretty fun.
Uh, no.
Probably San Diego.
It doesn't matter when you get
off work, you can always find...
Tacos.
...tacos.
Yes.
Uh, I did a rotation
there in med school.
UC San Diego?
G.I. Department.
Under Ned Powell.
Ooh, Ned Powell.
Incredible surgeon.
Terrible at cards.
Uh, what about,
uh, board games?
The people in this house
are fiercely competitive.
Depends.
Alright.
What about Scrabble?
Sure.
I mean, you know, that game
isn't so much about
the vocabulary
as the math.
Yeah, long, brainy words
made up of one-point
A's, T's, and R's
aren't nearly as good
as words like "X-ray."
Yes, with the "X" on
a triple letter score.
Correct.
Ever try
cryptic crosswords?
No.
How 'bout Boggle?
Uh...
You know, I always wanted one
of these when I was a kid.
I liked
the Y-shaped pieces...
the idea that you could veer
off the main course
but still be on track
intrigued me.
Huh.
You know, I-I just
thought trains were cool.
I'm supposed to remind you there
are hiding people out there
waiting for you
to seek them.
Oh, yes. Okay.
Scout?
Oh, he's upstairs with Amelia.
Okay, good.
Coming!
And after ten years of
studying...
You having
your own party up here?
Yeah.
He's almost settled.
Oh. You want me
to take him?
Hm.
I could be the closer.
I'm pretty boring.
I got him.
I really don't mind.
And you have a date.
Hmm.
It's okay.
But thank you.
Mm.
"...patients with inoperable
plexiform neurofibromas
showed durable
tumor shrinkage... "
Are you reading
a medical journal?
I can be boring, too.
"How does this nomogram
correlate with survival..."
Hey.
Who was on the phone?
No one.
Uh,
is dinner ready?
Uh... Wendell.
Hey, uh, I-I don't
think you should stay.
Alright, um, I'll pack up
some food for you,
but then you should
go back to the hotel.
Alright?
Look.
The people that I owe...
they're not good people.
They know you're here
in Seattle?
Yes.
Wendell.
But that's why I need to
disappear for a while.
Look, I just wanted
to spend one more night
with my big brother.
Hm.
And ask for some cash.
Look, I'll pay you back
in a month...
You've gotta be
kidding me.
No, i-it's not a lot.
J-Just enough...
These people know where you are
and you came here?
You came to
this house?
Nobody's following me,
if that's what you mean.
Do you know that
for sure?
No, but...
There are children here,
Wendell!
Winston, calm down.
You're putting
my family at risk.
No, I'm your family.
♪♪
Leave tonight.
Leave Seattle.
Tonight.
♪♪
Should we...
Eat.
Hey, uh, here.
Oh, thanks.
I'm sure Amelia
will be back soon.
I'm sorry you got
stuck on kid duty.
Oh, not a problem.
I'm used to it.
Oh, you got kids?
Uh, niblings.
Nieces and nephews.
Oh.
So do you...
you want kids?
Oh, uh...
Uh, no. No.
My career is my baby.
Oh.
Why, are you trying to unload
one of yours on me?
No, it's just... you kind
of sound like Amelia,
before she had Scout.
I finally sold
the last one last week.
Poor guy dropped
his first ring in the Sound
while he was proposing.
Mm.
I gave him a good deal.
Why'd you buy so many?
I-I used to ask myself
that a lot.
None of the answers
made sense,
so I just tried
to move past it.
How'd that work out?
Um...
I burned my relationship
with Amelia to the ground.
I trashed
my friendship with Jo.
So...not great.
Is it 'cause
you slept together?
I don't regret Scout,
if that's what you mean.
Not Amelia.
Jo.
She told you?
Well, we were drinking.
You say things
when you're drinking.
Did she mention
anything about feelings?
'Cause, apparently,
there were some feelings.
There are
no longer feelings?
Now there's Todd.
Oh.
I-I hardly
see her anymore.
I miss my friend.
But, you know,
I want her to be happy.
And she deserves
the best.
Do you have
feelings for her?
Sometimes.
Maybe, a little.
I'm...
Should I tell her?
That you maybe have
occasional small feelings?
No.
Okay, good.
The food was delicious.
But this seems like way
more plates than people.
Well, three of those are
the other Bailey's.
He doesn't like
his food to touch.
You have cooked and cleaned,
as my guest.
I... My mother would be
mortified in her grave.
Well, my mom's
probably proud.
Sorry about earlier.
Winston's brother is,
uh, complicated.
Well, complicated people
can be hard to love.
Erica, my younger sister,
she has an uncanny ability
to break my heart
and enrage me all at once.
She's been doing it
for two decades now,
and I-I fall for it
every time.
You see her much?
No. No, I-I don't.
I really don't.
But even when I do, it doesn't
matter if she's sober or not.
She still lies to my face
without an ounce of remorse.
She's a master manipulator.
Despite all of it, despite
all she's taken from me,
I-I still struggle to say no
when she asks me for something.
Honestly, sometimes
it's the easiest way
just to avoid
another heartbreak.
♪♪
Here.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
For your hand?
♪♪
Yeah.
Any of those clinical trials
have success?
The ones I've read
are still ongoing.
Before Simon's diagnosis,
I always thought
that cancer was this thing
that you either beat or didn't.
Like it was a stupid puzzle
and we just needed to find
all the pieces.
But I didn't realize that there
was a third, awful option
where you don't die,
but you don't get rid of it.
You just live with it...
waiting for it to get worse
and praying that it doesn't.
Yeah,
I know the feeling.
For a long time,
I was in denial.
I was sure that Simon
would be the exception.
That we would find a way to
beat the thing that's, uh...
♪♪
Yeah.
I think I became obsessed
with us conceiving
because it would mean
that he couldn't die.
There's no way,
right?
God wouldn't kill a man
before his child was born.
♪♪
I was
so happy when we got pregnant.
So happy that
we'd finally be a family.
♪♪
And then I'd realized that
we'd always been a family.
Me and him.
♪♪
And by not letting him
accept and grieve the fact
that he might not
survive...
♪♪
...I'd left him alone
in it.
♪♪
And no one
wants to be alone.
♪♪
What's happening?
She's hypotensive.
Her crits are dropping,
and her belly's distended.
And I'm seeing way more
free fluid than before.
Yeah, her spleen has
probably ruptured.
We need to get her
to the OR... stat.
Let's call the OR and tell them
we're bringing her down.
She's in V-fib. Let's get
the crash cart in here, now!
Come on, come on,
let's go.
Take out
the cut down tray.
We're opening her up
in here?
Yes, we're
opening her up in here.
We're not going to let
her die, Schmitt.
She's not dying.
Charge paddles to 120.
Clear.
Charge again.
♪♪
♪ My fire is starved of oxygen
♪ A flicker in
the howling wind ♪
♪♪
♪ Beware,
the night is closing in ♪
♪♪
♪ And if I fall asleep...
♪ ...the shadows win
♪♪
♪ Oh, to sing
and make my mother proud ♪
♪♪
♪ Mm, to sing
and make my mother proud ♪
♪♪
♪ In the dark,
I learned to love again ♪
♪♪
♪ A sacred place
it's always been ♪
♪♪
♪ Where souls depart
and life begins ♪
♪ The dark led me
to light again ♪
♪♪
♪ Yeah, the dark led me
to light again ♪
♪♪
She is okay.
Oh.
♪♪
Thank you.
We... We could never
thank you enough.
♪ Yeah, the dark led me
to light again ♪
We still have to monitor her
for the next few days, as well.
Of course.
Popo's okay!
Yay!
♪♪
Mm.
Catherine, honey...
I want you
to live forever.
And if I could do that with
a surgery, you know I would.
Richard, I can't listen to
another study right now.
No, no... Just...
Baby, I can't do it.
What, um...
What I'm gonna say is,
uh...
if you're putting yourself
through this for me, then don't.
If you want to stop,
I'm going to support you.
I don't want to stop
my treatments, baby, no.
It's just...
Sometimes I feel like
I just need time to think.
Like I need to just be able
to live in the moment
without judgment or worrying
about what's next,
even when I'm doing
this chemo.
And you are so serious
all the time,
sometimes that
makes me feel...
makes me feel worse.
Because
a-any one of us
could drop dead tomorrow
from a million different things.
I have cancer,
and that sucks.
But I still
want to live.
I still want to laugh.
♪♪
I-I can come up with a good joke
if you give me a minute.
That's... mmm.
That's what I need.
Oh.
Hey.
Sorry.
Is Scout okay?
Yeah.
Sometimes he just needs
some soothing reassurance.
Takes after his mom.
Your family and friends
seem like good people.
They are.
You'll see,
once you get to know them.
And I promise Scout
is not always this fussy.
He became real
to me tonight,
because I got to see what an
amazing parent you are to him.
And to
Meredith's kids.
You are so much more
than just an aunt.
Mm.
I don't want kids,
though.
I have things I want
to do with my life...
professionally
and personally.
If I had kids, all of that
would have to come second.
I don't want to
do that.
Well, y-you've
told me that before...
I am not going to
change my mind, Amelia.
Ever.
♪♪
W-What...
What does that mean?
♪♪
I thought this
was going really well.
Yeah, I did, too.
And I don't know.
♪♪
I just know
I don't want to lead you on.
♪♪
Because I was once
led on by someone
who did not want
what I did.
♪♪
Oh, I needed that.
I had fun.
You know, despite
what you all think,
I know fun.
I will never doubt it again.
Hi.
Hey.
Mm. Mmm.
Mmm.
Hey, are we...
Mm-hmm.
Really?
Okay.
Alright. Okay.
Come here.
It's good.
Mm.
Come on, now.Oh!
You people are parents.
Come here. Mmm.
Wendell left
about 45 minutes ago.
Yeah, I'm sorry
I walked out.
I just...
I needed a minute.
And I'm sorry that
he showed up here
when he's
in so much trouble.
If I had known that he
had people...
Winston, I'm not worried about
Wendell or his lenders.
I gave him the money
to pay them back.
I really wish you hadn't
done that, Maggie.
I know, I know, I know.
I should have asked you first.
It's not your place
to pay him...
You're right.
$10,000 is a lot of money,
but I had the savings
and he's
my family now, too, so...
Maggie. Maggie.
I gave him
the money, too.
♪♪
Microbes may sound
like uninvited guests...
♪♪
...but most live harmoniously
in and on our bodies.
♪♪
Oh.
Hi.
♪♪
I didn't realize...
I'll go.
Stay.
Nice out here.
It's quiet.
It is.
♪ I don't mind a heavy heart
You know,
I read somewhere
you can see the Northern Lights
from Seattle.
Is that true?
Sometimes.
Very faintly.
♪ 'Cause it's a little bit hard,
a little bit so much ♪
You know everyone was
vetting you tonight.
Yeah, I mean, I figured
when Maggie was asking me
if I support public television
and the U.S. Postal Service.
It kinda
clued me in a little bit.
♪ I'll hold you tight...
I don't blame them.
♪ ...when you're feeling
lonely ♪
Everybody
loves Meredith.
Yeah.
We're gonna
miss her a lot.
I know.
♪ No matter what,
I'll stick around ♪
Do you have
any questions for me?
♪ Please know I'll be
your one and only ♪
Meredith left
once before.
After my brother died.
She just disappeared
for a year.
She was
hundreds of miles away,
and I have never
felt closer to her.
♪ But you find it somewhere
I knew...
she left because
she was drowning...
in grief and pain
here...
same way that I was.
♪ How it changes color
when you get there ♪
♪♪
♪ Cause it's
a little bit hard... ♪
I think you
make her happy.
And she deserves
to be happy.
Others would have
been broken
by a fraction
of what she's survived.
♪♪
I want her life
to be full
of love and joy.
♪ Know you can cry...
My only ask of you...
♪ ...when times get ugly
♪ I'll never go
and let you down ♪
...is just
to want that, too.
♪ No matter what,
I'll stick around ♪
♪ Please know I'll be
♪ Your one and only
We need a diverse set
of microbes working together
to stay healthy.
Hey.
Oh.
You're still here.
Yeah,
I'm still here.
I'm sorry I'm so late.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
It's okay.
They're an essential part
of our systems.
What's all this?
Well, I figured
you had a tough case.
Probably didn't
have a chance to eat,
and I thought you might
need some company.
♪ I'll hold you tight
♪ When you're feeling lonely
♪ Know you can cry...
♪ ...when times get ugly
I love you.
♪ I'll never go
and let you down ♪
I love you, too.
♪ No matter what,
I'll stick around ♪
♪ Please know I'll be
It turns out, they're
right where they belong.
♪ Your one and only
♪♪