They say you
fight fire with fire.
We do it in
medicine all the time.
Owen won't say what it's about,
and nobody knows this
Riggs, except Kepner.
Maybe Kepner knows.
We cut you to
repair your injury.
Is that snow?
We hurt you to heal you.
Are we still good?
Yeah, we're good, I told you.
I'm just making
sure. We're good.
Good with what?
Nothing. Don't worry about it.
Guys, it's like 60 degrees
out. That can't be snow.
We stoke the flames.
They just keep
circling each other.
I keep thinking one of them's
gonna pull out a switchblade.
Oh, it's about a chick.
When two guys hate each
other, it's usually about a chick.
Is that snow? Really?
Where? Yeah, you're right.
That looks like
snow out there. Huh.
But playing with fire
is a dangerous game.
Well, you know they're
saying it's about you.
What?
You and Riggs. A
torrid affair in Jordan.
That's... Oh, no!
That is not at...
Don't worry, I shut that down.
God! Thank you. Geez!
No, I think it goes
back further than that,
because I worked with Riggs,
and he never even
mentioned knowing Hunt.
Oh, my gosh. Hunt and Riggs!
What if they had
the torrid affair?
Come on. No.
Just think about it.
Wartime, no rules,
men in uniform... Kissing.
Huh.
Oh, no way. What?
I didn't say it. Arizona did.
I heard that Riggs lost
a patient on the table
and tried to blame it on Hunt.
Yeah, the gossip mill is getting a
little out of hand, don't you think?
Oh, no, it's not gossip.
It's, um...
What do you call
it? Scuttlebutt.
No.
Callie, um...
You and Arizona,
before you guys split,
you did the
counseling thing, right?
Oh, God. Yeah. Yeah.
I heard that you were
looking more for a lawyer.
You heard that, huh?
Scuttlebutt.
Sure.
You're on my
service today. I am.
You're good with that, right?
I mean, you and I...
You don't have any problem
working under me, right?
Well, I think we've
established that.
No, but see, this...
This is exactly what
I'm talking about.
Outside of that door,
we are professionals.
There can be none of this.
Yes, ma'am.
Hey.
For the road.
Is it snowing?
Is it what I think it is?
Uh-huh. Just got the
call. It's all coming here.
Okay, how many we looking at?
Over 40. Where's
the protocol for this?
Bailey... Gotta be
some guidelines.
Look, it's your first
crisis. You'll be fine.
I know! As soon
as I can find the...
Bailey, there's nothing
you need in those binders.
Okay, you just have to
take things as they come.
But you won't see them
until they're right here.
You know what to do. If you're
in control, they're in control.
Oh, and, uh, stand on the
stairs when you talk to them.
Makes them feel watched over.
Is that why you do that?
Four crews of firefighters
were trapped battling
wildfires east of town.
We have at least
40 injuries en route,
I said we would
take all of them.
Forty? We're gonna
hit capacity and...
We will take all of them.
We're looking at second,
third, and fourth-degree burns,
smoke inhalation
and some traumas.
All non-critical... Patients...
Um...
Are being transferred to
Seattle Pres and Tacoma.
This entire hospital is now
a burn-treatment center.
If you are a little rusty...
Did you stay here
again last night? Yeah.
You sleep at all?
I'm fine.
Plastics will be
available for consult,
but they will be in high demand,
and cannot be everywhere.
If you need them...
It's definitely because
of a chick. Shush.
Residents, stay with
your assigned attendings
unless needed in the
burn unit, or in the pit.
Uh, everyone who is on
call has been called in.
This is an
all-hands-on-deck situation.
You with Grey again?
I'm always with Grey,
which is the problem for Callie,
so I'm a nun, basically.
Worship at the altar of Our
Lady of General Surgery.
That's a good choice. Mmm.
You know, I tried
dating an attending.
It just... It doesn't work.
Prioritize according
to... Wilson does it.
Yeah, well, Wilson got lucky.
Triage in the ER.
Send the critical patients
to the burn unit or the OR.
Dr. Avery is your point
person on this, okay?
Uh...
Let's see, then that's...
That's it, people.
Okay, get to work.
I'll jump on triage and
the most acute injuries.
April. You take any
compromised airways.
Stop running away from me,
eventually we have to
find time and talk about this.
It's been three days
already. Now is not that time.
We have time,
before it gets crazy.
It's already crazy. My ER's
about to be jam-packed.
I don't have time,
neither do you.
We would if you'd stop talking about
how much damn time we don't have.
Let's get 'em loaded.
Okay, got it. Status?
Choppers are
stacking up, let's move!
Come on, let's go! Move!
No, no, no! That's
gotta go over there.
People, if you are not on
your specialty, you are on burn.
Consider yourselves
burns and plastics
specialists for the day.
We treat, debride, admit,
if you have any questions
at all, you come find me.
Take him to trauma
two. This way, over there.
Patient has partial
thickness burns
on his chest and abdomen,
and severe smoke inhalation.
Let's get to the part with
the metal in his chest.
He lost his footing in the
smoke, he fell into the ravine,
and a steel spike
broke his fall.
We need a heart ultrasound.
Let's page cardio, get Pierce.
Okay. No problem. I'm here.
I can wait for Pierce.
I said I got it.
Okay. He has blood
in the pericardium,
but I can't tell if it's
penetrated the ventricle.
Blake, get Pierce. Okay.
Most likely the only
reason he isn't bleeding out
is because the metal
is blocking the hole.
That's an interesting theory.
Only one way to find out.
Blake, let's pull out the spike.
Oh, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa!
We're gonna take
it out in the OR,
where we can
control the bleeding.
There might not be any bleeding,
so let's don't fill up an OR
until we know that we have to.
And risk him bleeding out
before we ever get up there? No.
No one is touching this
thing until we get Pierce.
There. Now she
can get a proper look.
Who the hell do you think
you are? If I say wait, we wait.
You are out of control!
And I will not stand for it.
Hey, Kepner, how are we?
Stretched. I need somebody to
take a look at the guy in bed four!
Um, I will do it. I
will see bed four.
They're coming in! I need
more morphine over here.
Tyler, how's Tyler?
His hand's pretty bad. He
might lose some fingers.
You tell him he'll live.
I'm Dr. Bailey.
How we doing here?
I'm fine, I've been
burned so many times,
my wife says I smell like bacon.
You need to put
that mask back on.
You need to check
on these other guys.
They're in worse shape than me.
We will take care
of all of you, okay?
So just let me have a look.
Mmm-hmm.
Okay.
How bad is it?
He's bleeding right
there. In the pericardium.
It's not much. It'll
likely resolve on its own.
Or it won't and
it'll be too late.
Admit him, monitor him closely,
and tell me if his
pressure drops.
Book an OR. Absolutely.
I'll book an OR.
She's my God.
Hey! Hold on. Do
you have time now?
Not really, I'm on my way
to surgery with a maniac.
Yeah, so let's do it now
before we both get too busy.
All right, well, let's
make it quick, because...
Alex, could you...
Wilson, go away!
Just give us a minute,
okay? We're busy.
Thanks a lot.
She'll be fine.
We were taking a break
at base camp, and...
Casey, I'm gonna need
you to stop talking, okay?
There's severe lung damage here.
Book an OR. Yeah.
Casey, we're gonna take
you into surgery right away.
OR's backed up.
They're saying it's an hour.
Tell them that's
not good enough.
No. Take these other guys first.
I'll decide who goes
where, all right?
Hey, I did my best
to get those guys out.
You got to make
sure they're okay.
Can you do that?
Yeah.
Let's get him to the burn
unit while we wait for the OR.
Excuse me. Coming through.
Chief, the burn unit is full
and I need beds down here.
We can't take any more,
we're already at capacity.
I have patients with extensive burns
that are on gurneys in the hallway.
Well, we need to start
diverting to other hospitals.
No, no. We're not doing that.
Well, I need to know
what we are doing, please.
Do I need to
notify Seattle Pres?
Chief!
I said we're not turning
firefighters away.
Come with me.
Okay!
You folks, take your food to go.
All of these tables
go. Put away this food.
We triage here.
I need gurneys, in lines
of three, all the way back.
Minor and first-degree burns
are going to the pit, guys.
Criticals can go to
any available ICU bed.
We need burn supplies, surgical
trays, gowns, gloves at every station.
This enough room?
This will work.
I know you have to
do your doctor thing,
but maybe you can keep
the full moon under wraps.
That's the part that I
kind of need to see.
Oh, you can see
whatever you want.
It's the guys in my squad.
I'll never hear the end of it.
I'll be discreet. No free shows.
No guy has seen that
since a middle school
wardrobe malfunction.
Hopefully you're an expert, a...
What, a butt doctor?
That can't be right. You
can fix my butt, right?
Yes. The burn is
confined to one cheek,
and luckily, I have a
good one to compare it to.
Wow. Thank you very much.
No. No, no, no. I didn't mean...
No. I'll take it.
Yeah, it's... It'll do the job.
Hang in there, Turner.
God.
Here I am, complaining
about my butt burn.
Don't do that. Don't feel
guilty for not getting hurt.
I mean, I work a
job where in order to
make a house payment,
put food on the table,
there have to be fires.
And big fires mean
overtime, hazard pay.
You work like hell
to put them out, but...
A dirty, little part of you is
thinking, "Burn, baby, burn."
And you hate yourself. It sucks.
I make my living
off of sick babies.
You get it.
All right, you feel that?
Comin' through. Dr. Hunt?
Give him morphine. Owen?
Mmm-hmm.
Your mom's boyfriend,
he's a firefighter, right?
Yeah. Why?
Because she's here, your mom.
Nurse's station.
How can I help you?
Cross, take over.
Mom? Owen!
John was working the fire.
They said they brought him here.
Have you seen him? Uh...
Hang on, hang on.
He is in surgery.
Oh, dear God. Dr. Grey and...
Kepner, page Pierce
to OR three. Okay.
Mom, stay right here, okay?
There, I was right, there's
blood in the pericardium.
I could've relieved it
with a needle downstairs.
You did not need to open him up.
Well I did, because we're
not in a tent in a war zone.
Meredith...
Hunt, is there a problem?
Grey, the patient on your
table is my mother's boyfriend.
How's it look?
It's not good. I didn't ask you!
Dr. Grey cracked his chest
when she shouldn't have...
Shut your mouth, step away
from the table, and scrub out.
Hey, what's going on here? I
need you to scrub in for Riggs.
What? Why?
Hunt, I got a guy in the burn
unit missing part of his chest wall,
I don't have time...
Owen, I have this.
Dr. Pierce, we're fine here.
Riggs, step back.
Okay, Hunt, I don't
work for you, okay?
I work for Pierce. If she
says leave, then I'll leave.
Hunt, is there a reason
that I should be removing
Riggs from this surgery?
Are you okay?
Yeah, no, my mom's boyfriend.
The firefighter. Yeah.
He's here. Yeah,
Meredith is working on
him right now with Riggs.
And that's a problem.
Owen, talk to me.
Why is this guy...
I just don't want
him near my family.
Proximal humerus fracture.
All he needs is a
sling for a few weeks.
Yeah, but I've got a full thickness
burn on his hand and forearm.
Will a graft even take?
You've got bone exposure.
Give me a minute
to think about it.
I'd recommend it.
Yeah, the graft? Counseling.
It gave us a sense of where
we were, which was nowhere.
But still...
Second-degree
burns on the chest.
Do you even want to
work it out with Kepner?
Can we not do this
right now? Sure.
Okay.
But one thing our therapist
said, that turned out to be true,
do not have sex while
you're sorting things out,
it's messy, it's
confusing. No sex.
You guys had sex. Yeah.
We did, too. It's messy.
It's really messy.
I think you can both
get what you need.
Yeah, I don't know. I mean,
I feel like it's so complicated.
No, no, no, no, no. I'm
talking about his hand.
Right.
We do a living graft with
an abdominal pedicle flap.
We literally sew his
hand into his abdomen.
He'll have a graft and a sling.
That's good. Yeah.
I found the one! Oh, good.
Now you can help me
find an arterial line kit.
Not "the" one, a one,
maybe, but at least an option.
I found an option!
She's funny and cute,
and she actively
contributes to public safety.
She's one of the firefighters?
Yes. And she's great.
And I think that
she thinks I'm great,
but I need you to find out.
Sure, why don't you
write her a little note,
you know, the ones with
the boxes that you can check,
and I'll pass it along.
Mmm.
Mmm. Don't you think
that sounds a little childish?
Yes, it does!
I'm not gonna wingman
a patient for you!
I set the Mayfield,
let's just drain the clot and
bring him back to the burn unit.
Maybe it was, like, a
classified mission gone bad.
What?
Hunt and Riggs.
Maybe that's why
he won't talk about it,
maybe it was like
a secret mission,
and one of them
double-crossed the other.
I don't want to talk about it.
Well, everyone
is talking about it.
I don't want to gossip about it.
Dr. Hunt's a sleepwalker
and a sleeptalker, actually.
Enough!
It's not gossip. It happened.
I found him in an on-call room
totally asleep, standing there.
He was all, "Help,
help!" It was freaky!
What did he say, exactly?
"Do something," I think he said?
I don't know. I was a little...
I was scared.
Wait. Cross...
They'll probably take a big
piece of skin from your back
called a latissimus flap.
Now, it's gonna
leave a pretty big scar.
Scars are okay.
They show where you've been.
My leg is the Kelso fire of '08,
and my shoulder's the
Yakima Valley of '13.
And... Oh... That...
That's, uh, my oven.
Birthday cake for
my wife, Ruth's, 50th.
Casey, Casey, we
have to intubate you now.
No. I can breathe.
Ruth's on her way.
I... I want to
talk to her first.
Sir, we really need to give
your lungs a rest, okay?
No. I don't need it.
Hey... I don't want it.
I think we can give
Casey a few more minutes
till his wife gets here.
But you put that mask on. Deal.
He's being ridiculous.
We have to tube him, right?
His left lung is
partially collapsed,
the other one is damaged
from smoke inhalation.
It's causing his heart to fail.
Yeah, and he's starting to
have arrhythmias from rhabdo.
Oh. I gotta go. Yeah, go.
We need to clear an OR.
Uh, no, Casey's right,
we need to be treating
the more urgent cases first.
I'm sorry, but
what's more urgent
than a guy with a
hole burned in his side?
A case that will
survive surgery.
So what? We're just supposed
to tell him he's gonna die?
We don't have to
tell him. He knows.
Make him as comfortable as you
can, and tell me when his wife gets here.
We are never eating
in that cafeteria again.
I'm a little busy right now.
Do you need something?
I needed a break. I
thought I'd take a minute.
You know when I had a minute?
This morning, when you and
Meredith were whispering in the hallway.
I'm sorry about that.
And she yelled "Get
away" in my face
like I was a stray dog.
Come on.
It's not funny. That's
not what she meant.
God, you always defend her,
even when she's being
a complete bitch to me.
Look, don't do that. Don't call
her that. And why wouldn't you?
Everyone here
just follows her lead.
If you're out with Grey,
you're out, and I'm out.
You're not out. You're fine.
She spent a year acting
like I didn't even exist.
So what is it? What? You think
she just sees you as my girlfriend?
She doesn't even see me as that.
She would show up in our bedroom
and kick me out whenever she wanted to.
That hasn't happened
in a long time.
Yeah, because I hauled
you out of that house.
Oh, I'm...
I'm sorry, you "hauled"
me out of there?
I had to, she had an
all-access pass to you.
And you know what the
worst part is? Is that you let her.
Here I thought we decided
to move in there together.
Because she's always
your priority! That is not true!
She has been through
a lot! Her husband died!
So what, that gives her a
license to treat me like crap?
No! No!
It means she has the license
to take her crap out on me!
It means I'm gonna be there
for her when she needs me,
'cause she's the only
one I can count on!
She's the only
one? Just, I meant...
Look, she stood by me for years
when everybody else left, no matter what.
I didn't mean... No, I get it.
You're taking her side again,
'cause she is your priority.
You don't get to tell me
what my priorities are!
I have to focus on my patient.
Look, Jo... Just go.
Last stitch repairs the
rupture in the heart wall.
3-0 prolene and pledget hold.
Blake, can you snip, please?
And Hunt said this guy
was dating his mom?
Hmm? Suction.
Blake, you heard that, right?
Suction here.
Hmm?
He's fibrillating. Paddles.
Got it.
Charge to 10.
Clear.
Charge to 10 again.
No, 25, okay? Let's don't
screw around. Twenty-five.
25. Clear.
This never would've
happened if you hadn't...
It absolutely would have,
we just wouldn't be
here to catch it. Clear!
All right, give me one
milligram of adrenaline.
Okay, come on, come on. Damn it!
Okay, where's the adrenaline?
Oh!
All right.
Well, the fire is 80% contained.
Okay.
My crew. No losses today, Casey.
No. Many injuries,
but no losses.
You prepare...
The best you can.
You can't control everything.
You can't control
the wind, you know?
You did everything you could.
Now.
What can I do for you?
Uh, just waiting for Ruth.
Okay.
This will heal nicely,
probably in about six weeks.
So, um...
Maybe we could
see each other again?
Like a follow-up appointment?
Oh, um...
No, I don't mean... I mean yes,
you can always make an
appointment with the admissions nurse.
But I did... Okay.
Can you just sit tight?
Well don't sit tight,
just... Be. Just be.
Heh!
I just tried to segue
from a wound closure
to a first date invite.
Now that's just clumsy.
Over her exposed
butt. And that's creepy.
I need your help.
Can you just go put
the good word in?
You don't need me. You're
a smart, confident woman.
Stretch your wings, Robbins.
Stretch them out. Feel the air.
Stretch them out. Feel
the air. Feel the air.
My wife needs to come home.
I mean, I knew it
was a good idea,
but looking at it up close,
it's pretty spectacular.
Yeah, yeah. It's a
miracle of the modern age.
So, what kind of sex was it?
Make-up sex or break-up sex?
It was, you know, I
have no idea, actually.
Bovie? Well, what did April say?
Nothing. She didn't say
anything, she's not talking to me.
She spent the last few
months hunting me down,
and now she just
keeps walking away.
Let's be done
talking about this now.
Agreed. Well, okay,
'cause, you know,
break-up sex is, um...
Well, it feels sad-happy.
It's an emotional potpourri.
All the feelings,
all the history,
all of it, it's all
just right there,
'cause it's... You know, you just know,
you just know that it's the last time,
and it's like taking
in all the air you can
before you go underwater.
It's like, "Do me or die."
Break-up sex is the best.
Yeah, but then you're broken up.
Huh. You know
what? You're right.
Make-up sex is better,
because make-up sex
is like coming up for air
when you thought there
wouldn't be any more air.
So it's like all is forgiven,
and you can throw off your
troubles and your clothes,
and you're like out of the dark
and into the light, full speed ahead.
Oh, God, it's the best.
So which was it?
I'm not answering that.
Jackson. I don't
know, all right?
Because maybe I thought it was one
thing and she thought it was the other.
What? Ooh. See? Messy.
But you know what's
not messy? This.
I mean, this... This is elegant
genius. Mmm. Mmm-hmm.
I'll tell you one thing.
He is gonna be pretty
surprised when he wakes up.
I was just looking
for extra Betadine.
Which is right there.
So, obviously,
lamest excuse ever.
You can't just
ignore me forever.
You don't have to like me, or be
my friend, or even be polite to me,
but at least
acknowledge that I exist.
Acknowledge that I'm a person
standing in front of you, saying words.
Forget it.
You got lucky. It wasn't luck.
He would have died
if I hadn't taken him in.
John's surgery went well, his
doctors expect a full recovery.
He's not awake yet,
but you can see him.
Nathan?
We don't think Riggs
and Owen's mom...
You don't think
that's the thing? No.
But do you think Owen's
mom is Riggs' mom?
Because that has
happened to me before.
Keep me updated
on how he's doing.
So Riggs knows your mother.
Owen, I want to help
you. Just talk to me.
Amelia, I'm not like you. I don't
need to talk everything to death.
Listen to what I'm saying. I do
not want your help, not with this.
Casey is conscious, but he
might not be able to speak.
He can hear you, though.
But he's not hurting?
No, no, we've made
him comfortable, that's...
That's all we can do.
Ruth,
his injuries are quite severe.
You may want to
prepare yourself.
I've been preparing
myself for 30 years.
I'm just gonna sit with
him, if that's all right.
Of course.
Mrs. Hunt, it's none
of my business,
and I'm not asking,
but Owen is my friend,
and I am worried about him.
How worried do I need to be?
Close the door, dear.
Hey, old man. Mmm.
They say the fire's almost out.
So this is it.
This is the one, huh?
Ah.
Doug and Susan
are on their way, so...
So don't worry,
I won't be alone.
They said that they love you,
and I told them
you love them, too.
I love you.
You did good, Casey.
You did good.
You talked to Owen's mother?
Yeah.
What was that about?
Did you find anything out?
Meredith!
Look, it's not my
thing. It's Owen's thing,
and he asked me not
to talk about it, so...
He's talking to you?
Yeah, he did,
enough so that I can...
Why are you shutting
me out of this?
Because this does
not concern you.
But it concerns
you? No, it doesn't.
I made a promise
that I would help him
keep his head above water.
Promised who? To Cristina.
So I am watching him,
and I am letting him be,
and I am not sticking my nose...
What does Cristina
have to do with this?
You're in some sort
of three-way trust circle
with Owen and his ex-girlfriend?
Ex-wife. God, Meredith,
you are the most loyal
person I have ever met
to everyone except me.
You're loyal to some woman
halfway across the world...
Yes, I am. When I am right here.
Cristina left you. I'm
here. I'm your sister.
You are not my sister.
Cristina is my sister.
You are Derek's sister,
and Derek is gone.
Dr. Grey, I changed
the mediastinal drains...
Get out!
Is this why you hate me?
'Cause I remind you of him?
Does it help you to hate me?
Asking you not to
push me. Am I like her?
Something you cling to
to keep the memory alive?
You are such a child.
You wrap her around you
like some sick widow shawl.
The widow Grey. She's
okay. She's moving on.
She'll never love again,
but she's holding it together.
That is crap. You've given up.
You are crawling into
your little hole and dying.
You are hollow.
And Derek would be sick
about it if he could see it.
He would be disgusted.
I want you out of
my house. Done!
Thanks.
Hey.
Are you all right?
You can't touch me at work.
Not in front of people, like
we're together or something.
Like we're together?
Right. Well, maybe we should
just stop while we're ahead.
No. I'm just saying...
I know you want to
keep things professional,
but my feelings...
My feelings for you are
not professional. Not at all.
So I'm calling this.
Where are you going?
To see my patient. Well,
I just did, and he's fine.
Well, if it's all the same
to you... No, it's not.
He's stable. Grey has him.
You can just walk away,
walk very far away, in fact.
Owen, listen.
I've already seen Ma.
Okay? We talked. She...
Let me make this more clear.
Stay the hell away
from my family.
It's my family, too.
No, it's not. It's not
your family. It is mine.
So, just use the crutches
until it doesn't hurt to walk.
It's not the walking
I'm worried about.
It's the sitting.
Well, when your
sitting improves, um...
I wonder if you'd like
to get a cup of coffee.
Charlotte!
Alice. Honey, I
told you I was fine.
I know, but then you
didn't pick up your phone,
and I thought...
You're okay, right?
You're okay? Yeah, yeah.
I'm okay, I promise.
This is Dr. Robbins.
She patched up my butt.
Thank you.
Thank you. She has
a really good butt.
Yeah, she... Um, you're welcome.
You flew?
I crashed.
Hey. Thank you. Okay. Thank you.
Hey. You want help?
No, I don't need help.
I know you don't need it.
You debrided, irrigated,
and cleaned all these burns?
Yeah. Despite what some people
think, I know what the hell I'm doing.
I know you...
I'm not saying you're
not a good doctor. I'm...
I'm sorry for everything.
We started out together, and
you just blew right past me.
I started to think that...
Jo, if they don't see what a good
surgeon you are, it's not your fault.
It's theirs.
I'm sorry, too.
I miss you.
Me too.
You did well today, Doctor.
Forty-four patients, 19
critical, you lost only one.
Then why do I only feel the one?
That's the job.
"That's the job."
Uh, it appears my doctors
are punching each other.
There's always
a fire to put out.
Same place?
I've been dreaming about
those jalapeno poppers.
April! April, come on!
Stop, damn it! Come on.
Jackson, I've had a long day.
Yeah, we should
probably talk about that.
What is there to talk
about? We had sex. That's it.
That's not it, and we
should talk about that.
Fine.
Fine. Talk about it.
We had sex.
And that was...
Confusing. Amazing.
Oh, man. It was...
Sure, it was also
amazing, but this is why I...
See? No! Stop, stop! I'm not
confused about the situation.
I know exactly what it was.
Because it was, it was amazing.
It felt good!
For the first time in
forever, it felt like us!
And then, then I saw it.
I saw it on your face, Jackson.
This was it.
This was goodbye.
And then I thought,
"Well, if we're over,
this is the way to go out."
At least this is what
I want to remember.
The amazing.
I wanna end where we
began, in a bed, in love,
and I just wanna keep
us there for a minute.
And anything you say
right now is gonna ruin it,
so please just don't!
Don't you see?
This is what you do.
You just decide how
things are gonna go.
I am not the one
deciding in this situation!
Of course you're the
one deciding! What?
April, you're always deciding!
You decide to go to Jordan.
You decide to leave,
you decide to stay.
You decide you need me,
then you decide you don't.
You decide we can talk,
you decide we cannot.
What? I don't want to talk because
I know what you're gonna say!
You're gonna say
you love me but...
You don't know what I'm
going to say! I'm pretty sure I do.
It doesn't matter! You
don't! Fine, then go ahead.
Say it.
Oh, my God, Jackson!
God, please, just say it!
I have feelings, too.
Unprofessional
ones. A lot of them.
I like you.
I just...
I just can't like you at
work. It's difficult for me.
Okay.
So can I like you and...
Not like you at work?
Can you do that?
Lock the door.
I need to talk to you.
No, no, no, no, no. Listen.
This isn't working. I need
someone in my corner,
and the more I look at it,
the only person I have is me.
Jo... And I don't want
to make you choose
between me and your
friends, your friend,
but I can't keep feeling like
everyone's second choice,
especially not yours.
So, I'm gonna go stay
with Steph for a while.
Jo, stop.
Oh, my God. Alex.
Yeah?
You suck at proposing!
What, you don't
like it? No, it's not...
It's when you do it!
Either I'm falling apart,
or you're falling apart,
and then you just do
this crazy, sweeping thing.
What, do you think I
got this at the 7-Eleven?
Mer has been holding
on to this for a month
so you wouldn't see it in my
freaking underwear drawer.
All day, she's been
trying to pass it off to me
without you seeing it.
You think this will
make everything okay,
but you don't listen.
I am listening.
You're saying you need
someone in your corner.
I'm right here, Jo.
I'm in your corner.
I've been thinking about tonight
every day since I
left that jewelry store.
I would have asked you sooner,
but this was the first
day on the schedule
that I thought you'd
even be home.
Tonight was the
night, is the night.
I've been listening,
and I'm listening now.
I love you.
Yes or no?
When we strike that match,
we like to think we
can control the burn.
Hell of a day, huh?
Can I have a
whiskey, please? Neat.
Sure. Coming right up.
And can I get you one?
We like to think we
have any control at all.
No.
A vodka tonic.
Vodka tonic.
Yeah, right away.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Cheers.
But fire is wildly
difficult to contain.
And just when you think
you've extinguished the blaze...
All right, we'll load it up.
Bailey's looking for you.
Okay.
You have to pull it together.
You're getting yourself
in trouble. I know.
It reignites.
It sucks in air,
and it burns hotter
and brighter than ever.
You never told me
you had a sister.