Previously on
The Good Doctor...
I've been thinking, and I
need a break from our coffees.
If you don't value
what the nurses do,
how much can you care about me?
- This is my patient.
- And I'm your boss.
You can either do this with me,
or I'll find someone who will.
If you don't trust me, fire me.
And if you do, then
stay out of my way.
Are you trying to
pick your embryo?
I'm leaning towards a girl. I
have a playbook to work from.
I didn't OD because
of you. Or us.
Jordan, if I let myself
get close to you,
I will fall for you.
I can't risk that.
You deserve somebody who's
ready to fully commit,
somebody who makes you happy.
Your brain cancer
may have returned.
The crib needs to be assembled.
Go. I got this.
There are two screws missing.
Dr. Glassman doesn't
have brain cancer,
but there is something
wrong with his brain.
Lea forgot to add
the blueberries,
but we can still
put them on top.
Sorry.
Not a problem.
Underneath, on top, on the side.
I can eat them here.
I can eat them there.
I can eat them anywhere.
Not Dr. Seuss fans.
We need to discuss
something very important.
After we eat.
Don't worry, I'm
fine, the baby's fine.
Shaun just wanted to have
a bit of a discussion...
You forgot two screws
when you built the crib.
- Okay.
- Okay, Shaun, slow down.
Let's all at least
take a seat first.
We're gonna have a
discussion about a crib?
Your CSF DNA test showed your
brain cancer has not returned,
but there is clearly something
impacting your
neurological function.
Shaun, the crib has
like 100 different parts
and instructions
without any words.
Just pictures with arrows going
in every possible direction.
Okay. Thankfully, I was there
to correct your mistake,
but that won't always
be possible in the O.R.
The O.R.?
Yes.
- I would like to do more tests.
- That's not gonna happen.
- And... And Dr. Lim should be notified.
That's absolutely
not gonna happen!
If your executive
function has deteriorated
- even a small percentage...
- Shaun, just one second.
Just stop for a second.
Two screws?
There's nothing
wrong with my brain.
There's nothing wrong
with any part of my body,
for that matter, not
that that concerns you.
You go to Lim, and you're
gonna look ridiculous.
- Doctor...
- That's the end of the discussion!
And breakfast.
He's right.
It's okay. You
were just trying...
I can't go to Dr. Lim
without conclusive
medical evidence.
Or maybe he was right.
It is just a crib,
and he was in a rush.
Everyone forgets things.
I-I forgot the blueberries.
Instead of tests,
I can gather data through
direct observation.
What does that mean?
Are you gonna spy on him?
Please put my pancakes
in the fridge.
I will eat them for dinner.
Good morning.
Mind if I join you?
Sure.
How are things in surgical?
- Great.
- Great, as in, actually great?
Or great, as in, "I'm
saying the right thing
because he's the president
of the hospital"?
Both.
Well, any feedback you have,
you can always come to me.
Sorry to interrupt. I
have a clinic patient
who needs a surgical consult.
It's a former patient
of yours, Eddie Richter.
Eddie?
I haven't seen him in years.
He came in with GI
pain and acid reflux.
Ultrasound reveals a small
mass on his duodenum.
He'll need surgery to remove it.
I think I can fit
that in. Join me.
Dr. Lim scheduled us
with Dr. Park today.
Doctors Park and
Lim will understand.
This is a unique case.
A small duodenal mass?
I don't know.
Eddie!
Long time no see.
I wish it were
longer. No offense.
I wasn't planning on
seeing a surgeon today.
Yeah, yeah, fair
enough. I've brought along with me
Doctors Allen and
Wolke to assist.
- Hi.
- Nice to meet you.
Judging by the astonishment
they are both desperately
trying to hide,
you did not tell them
about my condition.
I did not. Very few
residents get to see
Epidermodysplasia Verruciformis
outside of a textbook,
and I figured this would be an
important learning opportunity.
They definitely failed
the bedside manner part.
I'm sorry.
Eh, heartthrobs like me and
Brad Pitt are used to it.
Resync By M_I_S
www.opensubtitles.org
Any deep pain or
tenderness here?
A little.
How's business?
Oh, fantastic. Thank the Lord.
Eddie is an amazing carpenter.
He built Isabel and I
this stunning mahogany
live edge dining table.
I have no idea what that is,
but it sounds delightful.
Yeah. Not much
good for guitar,
but I can still
wield a power tool.
You'll need to use a
carotid pulse monitor
and upper thigh for BP.
Got it.
How painful are the growths?
I mean, that depends. They're
basically just huge warts,
so face, not much.
Hands, a little.
Feet, a lot.
I'm blessed.
The Lord knows
that a pretty face
can only get a
handyman in trouble.
Dr. Reznick gave us a really
good view with her ultrasound,
but I'd like an MRI and a biopsy
to better assess the lesion.
Ah, might as well get
my money's worth, huh?
It's good seeing you, Eddie.
The team doc's playing it safe.
It was a damn curveball.
Well, even a damn
double-A curveball
comes in at, what, 80, 85?
It can still do some
damage, helmet or no.
Two weeks isn't a long time
to be in concussion protocol.
Okay, well, I-I didn't
have a concussion.
I mean, I barely even
had a headache, so...
Can I help you, Dr. Murphy?
I came to observe.
Please continue.
Your ImPACT scores are a
bit worse than baseline.
Okay, that's one test.
I mean, I-I passed
all the others,
but the doc still
won't clear me.
It's not a bad idea to
play it safe, though.
It is your brain
we're talking about.
I mean, you're an outfielder, so
you don't need one just now...
but you
are gonna retire someday.
Look, if I don't get
back on the field ASAP,
I won't have a career
to retire from.
I wouldn't have come to the best
brain doctor in town otherwise.
Alright. We'll take a look.
Do a neuro and get me an MRI.
An MRI? For a concussion?
Well, he's got some
dilation of his left pupil.
Probably not significant,
but if we're gonna
override the team doctor,
we better be sure, hmm?
- On it.
- The MRI is a good idea.
I did not notice
the dilated pupil.
Well, thank you.
Not a problem since
it's not your case.
But it is an interesting case,
even if I did not know
that when I came here.
Since I've cleared my schedule,
I would like to
continue observing.
You cleared your schedule of
people with actual ailments?
Mmm.
Okay, fine. Observe
all you want.
I will.
Both you and the case.
Oh, there's no bleeding
or hematoma in your groin,
which means you're
doing fantastic.
Her color looks better.
Everything looks better.
I just got off the phone
with Eden's social worker.
She's having trouble
finding foster parents
who are willing to take a
newborn with Turner Syndrome.
Well, it's not that difficult.
Her long-term symptoms might
not even be that severe.
Still, Eden will always
need special care.
It'll take a minute for the
lidocaine to take effect.
You may feel some discomfort
when the scope goes
down your throat.
Got it.
I assume you've discussed
surgical removal
of your EV growths
with Dr. Andrews?
Yeah. No, he wanted to try,
but obviously, there's
the risk of nerve damage,
plus they would just grow back.
This is how I was meant to be.
Lord works in mysterious ways.
But surgeons don't.
The risk of nerve damage
is actually quite small,
and I'd imagine easier to
live with than the pain
and lack of mobility and...
Repulsiveness?
No, no. I-I was...
It's alright.
I know how I look.
I see the frightened
kids, people laughing,
staring.
I just try my best to
keep my eyes and arms open
to all of God's gifts.
Cannot imagine taking an
80-mile-an-hour baseball to the dome.
Some guys in the
majors throw over 100.
Phew.
I don't see any edema or
evidence of a hematoma.
Neither do I.
The anisocoria's
probably harmless.
Twenty percent of people actually
have one pupil larger than the other.
You play any sports?
I played football and
baseball in high school. Why?
I have a friend who runs a
sports program for at-risk teens.
I've been helping coaching
some indoor football,
I mean soccer.
She's always looking for help
from positive role models.
Yeah, I've... I've never
coached kids before.
Mainly just making sure they have
fun and stay off the streets.
And my friend's super cool.
She's cute, too.
Well, helping kids sounds great,
but I'm trying to get
a year in recovery
before I start dating.
Damn, my bad.
Oh, it's no big
deal. I just...
No, I mean the...
The anisocoria.
Definitely not harmless.
Or a concussion.
You have multiple
cerebral aneurysms,
which puts you in danger
of a brain hemorrhage.
So, what now?
Well, we're gonna map the
precise vessels involved,
take some pictures of
the inside of your brain.
It's called a...
Cerebral angiogram.
We'll feed a catheter
into your brain
through an artery in your wrist.
You'll be sedated.
It's harmless.
As soon as we get the results,
we'll map out a surgical plan.
B-Brain surgery?
Hey. Best brain
doc in town, right?
It just
keeps getting worse.
The tumor has significantly
damaged the bile duct.
Eddie's gonna need
a surgical resection
or possibly a major
GI reconstruction.
The poor guy.
As if one rare and devastating
disease wasn't enough.
Well, the surgery is manageable.
I've known Eddie for years.
He's always been the embodiment
of, "What doesn't kill
you makes you stronger."
Who needs strength
when you're cradled in
the Lord's loving arms?
Given his situation,
don't you think his,
"I'm just thankful for all God's
gifts" attitude's just a bit crazy?
I find the strength he draws
from his faith very inspiring.
Except that his faith
has inspired him
to not do the only thing
that would actually help him.
Get an octreoscan to confirm
that his liver, pancreas,
and lymph nodes aren't involved.
On it.
- You should probably go and...
- Referee?
Assist.
The radiolabeled tracer
will light up any areas
infiltrated by the tumor.
Will I get spidey strength, too?
Can I get you flat on
your back for the scan?
That won't be too
painful, will it?
No. Sure, I'll be alright.
Is there any family
you'd like to contact?
No, it's just
me. I live alone.
If you don't mind my asking,
E.V. is genetically inherited.
I'd assume at least one of
your parents suffered from it?
Yeah, they both did.
Did they both also decide
against surgical treatment?
Well, my parents were
circus performers,
made a living off
their appearance,
so I doubt they
wanted any treatment.
Can't say that for sure, though.
They gave me up, uh,
right after I was born.
I'm sure they were trying to
protect you from the life they had.
Heh. No, from
what I found out,
they thought a family
act would be too sad
and ruin the gig, so they
didn't want me around.
That's horrible.
Not at all.
I grew up in foster homes.
I had one mom who
was a minister,
introduced me to the
power of the Lord.
And then, when I was older, I
had a dad who was a carpenter.
Taught me everything I know.
I've always been blessed.
Advancing the catheter to
assess posterior circulation.
Dr. Murphy, do
you mind if I ask,
qhy are you observing us?
I don't mind.
Why are you observing us?
I am not observing you.
I observing this case
because it is interesting.
Also, because it
is Dr. Glassman's,
and he may display
additional symptoms
that will help me diagnose
his deteriorating
executive function.
So you're worried
because he forgot
- a couple of stitches on a routine close?
- Stop.
The third aneurysm is low
lying at the basilar trunk.
That will be very
difficult to clip.
And dangerous.
Definitely a very
interesting case.
♪♪ Hush, little baby
Don't say a word ♪♪
♪♪ Mama's gonna buy
you A mockingbird ♪♪
You sure you should
be doing that?
Changing bandages or singing?
Both.
She's gonna be leaving soon.
I'll be fine.
No, I'm
not overreacting.
He is covered in these tree-like
growths but refuses surgery.
But everyone acts as
if he's so inspiring.
It's a pretty brave choice.
No, it's a stupid choice.
Living in isolation
and unnecessary pain,
all because of his belief
in the Magical Mystery
Tour that is religion.
Well, given your family history,
I see why this patient is a
little triggering for you.
Okay, I'm not triggered.
This has nothing to
do with my family.
Religion is the
opiate of the masses.
You know, Marx got a lot
wrong, but not that one.
Why don't we talk
about something else?
I mean, look at terrorism,
the countless wars,
the KKK, al-Qaeda,
bombed abortion clinics,
the assault on women's
rights, not to mention
the rampant persecution
of the LGBTQIA community.
I mean, you either have to
have your head in the sand
or be a complete
moron not to see that.
Mmm.
This is done. Will
you grab the salad?
Sorry. I was looking
for a place to meditate.
It's okay.
I came here to decompress
before I head home.
Jordan.
The other night at karaoke,
I shouldn't have tried to
give you relationship advice.
I mean, you don't
need me for that...
or anything else, really.
You're everything.
Thanks.
Sorry, I gotta go.
He started vomiting blood
and then lost consciousness.
Get two units PRBC,
stay two ahead,
- and place an NG tube.
- On it.
Eddie, can you hear me? Eddie?
The tumor's caused a
severe duodenal ulcer
and major hemorrhaging
in his upper GI tract.
Yeah. We can't excise it
if we can't stop the bleed.
We could do it in two steps,
endoscopy to stop the bleed
and a partial duodenectomy
to remove the tumor.
But it'd be safer to debulk
the tumor after the scope
and follow up with
aggressive chemotherapy.
Chemo would increase the
pace of the E.V. growths.
Which he doesn't
seem bothered by.
Doesn't mean we
should make it worse.
Well, it's better than
bleeding out in the OR.
He's not going to bleed out.
We can solve both the GI bleed
and totally excise the tumor
with a pancreaticoduodenectomy.
A Whipple while the
patient is hemorrhaging?
That's even more risky than
combining the scope and...
I'm aware of that, but
unlike your department chief,
I'm not interested
in whether residents
approve of my decisions.
Get him prepped.
We'll
approach all three aneurysms
from a left-sided craniotomy.
Even though the ICA aneurysm
is on the right side?
Yes.
We'll go after
the basilar first,
as that is the most challenging.
What about the ipsilateral PCOM?
It's pressing the third
nerve and may rupture soon.
If you'd let me finish,
step two will be the PCOM,
and after that,
we'll cut across the infield
and go after the ICA.
Have you considered...
Shaun, will you stop?
Will you just please stop?
I'm fine. I know
what I'm doing.
My memory is intact.
Does anyone have an
actual objection to the surgical plan?
- No.
- Nope.
Thank you. It is extensive
and could put Ricky at
risk for future seizures.
And your outburst could indicate
a lack of impulse control,
which is a symptom of
executive dysfunction.
I am exhibiting extraordinary
impulse control as we speak.
As to the risks, I have
clipped over 2,000 aneurysms.
Tomorrow morning, I'm
going to clip three more.
Put Ricky on the schedule.
Go home. Get some sleep.
It's not milk and cookies,
but it'll have to do for now.
Oh, sorry. I was gonna
take care of that.
Why? Did Park tell you to?
Dr. Park? No. I just
got off my break,
- and I was going to...
- Great news.
I just got off the phone
with her social worker.
She found a foster family.
Lucky girl. You've got a home.
I know you were hoping
for a pancake dinner,
but I was thinking maybe we
could go to Barone's instead.
I'm really craving a meatball.
Yes, Dr. Glassman is not
only highly experienced.
He has above average
intelligence.
I don't know. He
is an A's fan.
I have not noticed any symptoms
significant enough
to alert Dr. Lim,
but even with a decline
in executive function,
he might not show
serious deficits.
I think we should definitely
discuss it further,
over sauteed artichokes.
I am not hungry, but I will
come and keep you company
while I continue to work.
If Glassy can still
do brain surgery
and you haven't seen
any serious deficits...
There is definitely something
wrong with his brain.
He's getting older. It
happens to everyone.
This is not just aging.
I know Dr. Glassman.
Do you think Glassman is
a danger to his patients?
No.
Not yet.
Then let's go to Barone's
and eat some meatballs
and chicken wings that I will
enjoy for a few glorious hours
until the indigestion kicks in.
You are right.
Meatball, stat.
That's the last
anastomosis. Remove the clamp.
Looks like the
sutures are holding.
I can't believe we did
a Whipple in under six hours.
That's gotta be a record.
More importantly, no more
tumor, no more bleeding ulcer.
Went even better than I'd hoped.
Gotta give
the good Lord his due.
Eddie is truly blessed.
We need a few more 4-0
prolenes on a Castro
and two surgical drains.
Hey. You got your
gear for tonight?
Yep.
Dug out the old football cleats.
Awesome.
Samira's really looking
forward to meeting you.
Don't worry. I
respect your recovery.
- I'm not trying to set you up.
- Thank you.
Jordan also told
me she'd kill me
if I did anything to
tempt you off your path.
You and Dr. Allen
were talking about me?
Yeah. She was just making sure I
knew what you were dealing with.
She's definitely
looking out for you.
My head. It's gonna explode.
He has a thunderclap
headache and double vision.
His left eyelid's droopy, looks
like complete third nerve palsy.
Left pupil
non-reactive to light.
The PCOM aneurysm
must have ruptured.
We need to get him
to the OR, stat.
Page Dr. Glassman.
Scalpel.
Intracranial
pressure is dropping.
We've bought him some
temporary relief.
Can we see the CT scans,
the new ones, please?
Given the
subarachnoid hemorrhage,
the risk of the previous
surgical plan has increased.
I can still clip the
two smaller aneurysms,
then ligate and bypass
the ruptured one.
We should consider
coil embolization
of the ruptured aneurysm.
We treat that now and then
come back for the other two
once Ricky has recovered.
Then he has to come in every
six months for an angiogram,
weakening his muscles,
damaging his coordination,
effectively ending
his pro career.
That's your recommendation?
The treatment
is a much safer option.
He's 19.
He has lots of life to
consider after baseball.
I'm confident
in what I promised.
I'm confident that
I can deliver it.
Your experience mitigates
the increased risks
of the craniotomy, but it
does not eliminate them.
The patient should decide.
Fine.
Let's wake him up and
present both plans.
The surgery went better
than we could have hoped.
We removed the tumor,
and your liver and
pancreas are working great.
So when do I get to go home?
Well, we need to keep an eye
on you for a couple days.
I took the liberty of
getting you a few things
to help pass the time.
Thank you.
I'm so grateful to you all.
I've spent so much time on my own,
I can forget how wonderful it is
to have other people
there who care about you.
Hey. Sorry. I got a
little aggro last night.
My family was big on
dinner debate time.
Okay.
That's all you have to say?
I have a blood draw to do, so...
It was just a
philosophical discussion.
It's not like we got
into a fight, right?
No, we didn't.
- It was awful.
- Terrible.
Somebody's in a good mood.
Indeed I am.
It's the Eddie effect.
Our patient radiates positivity.
It's oddly contagious.
It's got me wondering
why I'm always so focused
on choosing the right
path instead of...
just being open to God's gifts.
Sorry.
My gift is using my
stomach as a speedbag.
I don't know what's worse...
that I might not
walk out of here,
or walking out knowing that
I'll never play ball again.
Yes. That is the question
you need to answer.
Don't get stuck on
worst-case scenarios.
I worked real hard to
get here, you know?
And I... And I got
people counting on me...
Hey, hey, hey.
Shut out the noise.
Other people are
gonna have opinions,
whether you swing 3-0,
whether you don't
take the extra base.
Whatever decision you make,
that's gonna be
the right decision.
You know, uh, there's
a... There's a saying
back in the DR...
"You can't walk
off the island."
You gotta take big swings.
Let's fix all the aneurysms now.
Good call.
You'll need to keep the
wound site clean and dry.
And be sure to monitor her
caloric intake closely.
Babies with Turner Syndrome
have difficulty swallowing
and tongue dysfunction.
Turner Syndrome?
Will she need
additional surgeries?
Yes, but not for a few years.
With things like this, it's best
to take it one step at a time.
We were hoping to
foster to adopt.
And these long-term
medical issues...
they're significant.
When it comes to medicine,
Google is not your friend.
Patrick, Annie, I know
it all sounds scary,
and you have every
right to be nervous.
But you can do this.
Eden needs you.
Wouldn't it be best for Eden
if you found someone
more qualified?
I'll let Social Services know.
What's the score?
How am I doing? My
executive function.
What's the score?
It is not a score, it is data,
and I am not ready to
draw my conclusions.
Well, you're wasting your time.
You should focus on people
who actually need you.
I'm fine.
I am focused on you...
because for most of my life,
you've watched out for me.
No one asked you to do it.
You chose to.
Sometimes when I
didn't want you to.
I'm very glad you did.
So no matter what anyone,
including you, says,
I am going to watch out for you.
What are you talking
about? It's fantastic.
These are incredible, seriously.
I didn't mean to interrupt.
No, Dalisay was just showing
me her watercolor landscapes.
She's a wonderful painter.
Really?
I had no idea.
There's increased output
in his J.P. drains.
That's not surprising,
considering your EV.
Send a sample to the
lab and add meropenem
to his antibiotic
regimen, just to be safe.
Your recovery looks
to be on track.
And we've made
significant advances
in plastic surgery techniques
since your last consult.
Yeah, I don't doubt it.
But we both know it
would still be painful,
and they'd just
grow back anyway.
There's one thing I've learned
from the home reno business,
"If it ain't broke,
don't fix it."
A proverb for the ages.
I wanted to say goodbye.
The foster parents backed out.
She's scrambling to
find someone else.
I don't have another
family lined up.
Can you give me more time?
N-No.
Eden needs a home, and I know
the perfect person to foster her.
Me.
One
down, two to go.
It's been five
hours. Do you need a break?
Not when I have a
30-year-old Macallan
waiting for me at
the finish line.
Fenestrated aneurysm clip.
We've got
an intra-op rupture.
Bleed is massive.
Suction. Both of you, suction.
Let's keep this field clear.
Should we try balloon occlusion?
- Or a flow diverting stent?
- No.
We should adjust the clips
to get better proximal
and distal control
and pivot
to a Muslin wrapping.
Push
6 mg bolus adenosine.
We're gonna stop the heart.
Push it, please. Push it.
Aneurysm clips.
Oh. That is very innovative.
Inducing a brief cardiac arrest
reduces blood flow
to the aneurysm.
Gives us time to
apply the clips.
Okay. Let us proceed with the
parent vessel reconstruction.
One more time,
fenestrated aneurysm clip.
Thank you.
That was exciting.
He's in Vfib,
not responding to chest
compressions or epi...
We need to shock
him. Charge to 200,
and push another
milligram of epi.
He must
have thrown a clot.
Clear!
Time of death, 7:34.
His underlying illness
weakened his immune system
and made his blood more
susceptible to clots.
There's nothing we
could have done.
Do you know what
hospital you're in?
St. Bonaventure.
And why are you here?
Aneurysms, which you
were supposed to fix.
Which we did. And
we did quite well.
In fact, if you
stick to your rehab,
you might be back on
the field by mid-season.
Thank you, Dr. Glassman.
You got a surgery that can
help me hit a curveball?
Try
hitting a knuckleball.
You don't know what it is
until, pfft, it's too late.
That's old school.
I haven't even
seen one in a game.
Oh, I used to throw a
knuckleball, actually,
back in the day.
I tried
to be a pitcher.
But I didn't have a fastball...
And then you
have no idea where it's gonna go
'cause it had just a...
Just a slight amount of spin.
You heard?
Thank you for checking on me.
Andrews was right.
There's nothing more
we could have done.
I'm really sorry
about your patient,
but I actually came to tell you
that I'm meeting up with
some friends tonight.
I'm gonna go back
to my place after.
Okay.
But what's wrong?
Nothing.
I've been meaning to see these
folks for a while, and...
we're meeting near my
place. No big deal.
Well, it's starting
to feel like one.
Clearly, you're mad.
Please tell me what I did.
Sometimes having a
conversation with you
feels like combat.
Well, I was
just stating my opinion.
No, you were obliterating all
other opinions, including mine.
And calling me a complete
moron in the process.
I have never said
that you were a moron.
- I said...
- Ash, I didn't grow up discussing religion
or quoting Marx at
the dinner table.
That doesn't mean I
don't value your opinion.
It doesn't seem like it
when you take a sledgehammer
to my every argument.
I can give you 100
examples of times when...
This is not another
argument for you to win.
I have to get to dinner.
I'm so sorry.
If you want some company
or someone to talk to...
It's alright. I'll be okay.
I know.
But...
if you change your mind,
I've got your back.
Like you've had mine.
Thank you.
You...
really see me.
I think maybe you and I
could be gifts to each other.
And we should be open to that.
I have no idea what it looks
like for us to move forward.
We'll figure it out.
Dalisay.
Dr. Andrews.
Your landscapes you
showed Eddie before he...
I think you shared them with him
because he was so open-hearted.
See, my whole
life, I've believed
that success only came
from constant striving,
constant dissatisfaction
with where I was
or what I'd accomplished.
Contentment was a
sign of complacency.
That's no way to
go through life.
I know.
And I know I didn't
show you enough respect,
and I didn't make enough effort
to see things from
your point of view.
But I want to change.
I want to value the
people I care about
and who might care about me.
And if I haven't screwed up
too badly, then maybe one day,
I'll be worthy enough
to see those landscapes.
How about dinner?
You pick me up at
7:30, Saturday.
We can try that Filipino place.
Why would you say that?
- You know...
- Oh, man.
Hey, what else do you
say in that situation?
I think I agree with the guy.
I mean, I think
he's... I think...
You were right.
I have a tendency to go
scorched earth in a debate
because I just want to win.
I lose sight of what's
important because I'm...
I-I'm a moron.
But today, I realized
I shouldn't take anything
or anyone for granted.
You showed me what it
truly means to belong,
to not be an island.
And I just feel so blessed
to be in your life.
Uh, and you should order
the salmon carpaccio.
It's delightful here.
It's like butter.
Is your boyfriend
really that passionate,
or is he a little insane?
Both.
Hi.
I thought I'd stop by, see how
you and Eden are settling in.
We're fine, so far.
I think.
I'm fairly sure I have
everything Eden needs,
though peds might find
a few things missing
from their inventory this month.
I don't see one of these.
Oh.
Oh, Eden will love it.
Thank you.
Toys.
Onesies. I need to
get a stroller...
Hey, you'll handle it.
It's the perfect practice run
for when your own comes along.
I'm going off my IVF meds.
I'm not doing another cycle.
Eden,
she's what I've
been waiting for.
She's my daughter.
♪♪ Send ♪♪
♪♪ Your dreams ♪♪
♪♪ Where nobody hides ♪♪
This is a
knuckleball, and it fooled me.
I thought it was Dr. Glassman's
cancer returning,
but it is damage to
Dr. Glassman's brain
as a result of a mini-stroke.
If that were the case, the
area would have smooth edges.
Mmm, usually, yes.
But rare presentations
can show abnormalities
like these rough edges,
particularly when the patient
has had radiation treatment.
It explains why his
memory has been impacted,
especially during
periods of intense focus
involving many sequential steps.
It is permanent.
♪♪ No time ♪♪
He shouldn't be doing
surgery anymore.
♪♪ Disappear ♪♪
♪♪ With the night ♪♪