They've installed cameras.
They're all over the CCU.
Next they'll be in the
ORs, the hallways,
the on-call rooms.
We're being spied on, Mer.
Who knows what evil lurks
behind that electronic eye?
Morning, Dr. Yang.
Big Brother knows my name.
Big Brother can
see your name tag.
Excuse me.
The cameras are not
here to spy on you.
They are here to supplement you.
On the other side of the
camera is a remote physician,
an extra set of eyes to
help reduce mistakes,
improve patient care, and
maximize physician hours...
We've all heard
the buzz words...
"Streamline, optimize,
integrate, adapt."
Every day someone comes
up with a new strategy or tool
or technology to
increase our efficiency.
The idea is to make
our lives easier.
But the question is, does it?
And of course, ultimately
reduce costly litigation.
So does that answer
your questions?
With disturbing clarity.
All right. Let's move on then.
As you can see, this OR
has been arranged
with maximum efficiency,
specifically for OR turnover.
Now, what are the main
causes for bottleneck?
The layout of OR supplies,
equipment, and instruments.
So what we have done here...
What did we miss?
ORs are sloppy.
There are doctors
in the ceilings.
What? What do... What
does that even mean?
We'd know if you'd just
put her stupid tights on her.
I was talking her into it, okay?
She was getting on board.
She's two. At a certain point,
she doesn't have to get on board.
She has to be in day
care. So you pick her up
and you yank her tights on her.
That's what you do.
And then she cries.
Yeah, because you wasted
all that time cajoling her,
so now I have to be the bad cop.
If you just made it
clear in the first place
that she has no choice.
Because when
every second counts,
you need the most
efficient approach.
Mm. What she said.
It's about new hospital
procedures, and we weren't invited.
Thank God. It looks boring.
Don't you guys get
what's going on?
Yeah, they're closing the
ER. And streamlining the place.
It sucks, but...
They're gonna fire us.
Why bother teaching
us the new protocols
if we're gonna be gone
anyway? You're crazy.
It's not that bad.
Is it? Look at this.
Nurses are stockpiling.
The end is coming.
Your average time between
surgeries is 37 minutes.
With these new OR procedures,
I'd like to see that cut in half.
Thank you, everyone.
Closing the ER should
cut down on time.
We won't have any patients.
How's Hunt feel about that?
He says he's not gonna
do anything about it
until it actually happens.
It's happening.
And he can't be a trauma
surgeon without an ER.
Is he gonna leave town? 'Cause
if you go with him, I'm screwed.
I'm kind of depending
on your rent check.
Way to make this all about you.
The ER is not going to
close. Derek has a plan.
Where is Derek?
He spent the night with Kepner.
It's gonna work, right?
Of course. See, 'cause
if derm cuts a fellow,
and then cardio skips
the TED conference,
plastic/ortho
shares lab facilities,
we'll get a little bit
here, a little bit there,
and we'll have enough
saved to keep the ER alive.
They're gonna be mad
about the TED conference.
They're gonna be
pissed about everything,
but that's okay. It's gonna
work. Do we have a reply yet?
Uh, no, not yet.
That was the subject line?
What, is that bad?
Well, would you open an e-mail
that said "proposed budget cuts"?
Oh, no. Did I just
kill our proposal?
No. We're just gonna
have to pitch it in person.
Go door to door,
which is better anyway.
It's hard to say no
to someone's face.
Oh!
No offense, sir. You have an
unusually appealing face, but...
I have to brush
my teeth. Mm-hmm.
I know. You do, too. Oh.
Standardizing an
OR is one thing,
but that's not going to
make much difference
if we don't standardize
what happens in the OR.
To that end, I have brought
in Dr. Darrell Nesbaum
to show us how it can be done.
Everything will be scanned...
When did you become
such a kiss-ass?
The last five hospitals
whose efficiency she improved
ended up cutting
their staff by 30%.
I'll learn to rope cattle if
it means keeping my job.
Well, I'm safe because they
can't fire the pregnant lady.
Can they?
Uh, Dr. Nesbaum, you
can take it from here.
Of course.
Good morning, everybody.
Now, I have just one
question before we begin.
Are you ready to
rock some hernias?
Whoo!
That's what I'm talkin' about.
Has she moved yet?
What do you think?
Is her mom here? 'Cause
she's nicer when her mom's here.
No, she had to leave for work.
You sure the kid didn't eat her?
You guys, stop.
She's angry. She's 13 and she
had a double hip replacement.
You'd be angry, too.
She's mean. Like a badger.
She's three days
post-op now. Okay?
If she doesn't move her
hips, we're looking at clots,
contractures, poor recovery.
We just have to make
her do it for her own good.
Oh. Look who I'm talking to.
Can't even put a
toddler in tights. Huh?
Oh. Oh.
Well, then you just... You
show me how a bad cop does it.
Karev, get in there.
Why me?
We're attendings. You're
a fellow. It's an order.
That's how a bad cop does it.
Dr. Hunt, I sent contractors
to measure the ER space.
Yeah, and I told
them to get lost.
I know. That's
why we're talking.
The ER is open for one more day.
Uh, Dr. Hunt,
the ER is closing.
I know you don't want it to, but
you're gonna need to let that go.
While we are treating patients,
I don't want your
workmen in the way.
We are on a tight schedule
with the renovation.
I was hoping that
you would cooperate.
Yeah, well, you're
gonna need to let that go.
Well...
I'd just like to hear
you name one thing
that you can put in there
that's more useful than an ER.
It's still under review, but...
In the army, the guys at
the front get the most saves.
Why? Because the closer
you are to the moment of injury,
the better chance
you have to help.
That is what an ER is.
Where are we going?
Roof. Medevac's coming.
I shouldn't. I
should hop off now...
Emergency medicine
is the front line.
We're the first
responder. We're closest.
It's the most important
thing that a hospital does.
It's arguably... So
name me one thing
that you would replace
it with that matters more.
You've made your point.
Now, if you don't mind,
I have a big day, and I...
40-year-old male
logger versus chain saw.
Deep neck laceration affecting
most of the major blood vessels
and extending into the chest.
He's hypotensive
and tachycardic.
And his nose is
pretty much sliced off.
How's his airway?
Intact. It was never stridorous.
Did not appear to
involve the trachea.
Oh! Oh!
I got it. I got it.
It's the carotid.
I have it. I got it.
I was closest.
Okay, everything appears stable.
Let's redress the
nose. Page plastics.
- Right away.
- Gown me.
Work around Dr. Cahill and
see who else is available.
I'll check. Keep
holding pressure.
As soon as I find
another surgeon,
I'll take over and I'll
get you out of there.
No, I got it.
Having one person
control the carotid
limits his chance
of stroking out.
All right. Gown her, too.
Right away.
Start with Russell. You
want to do the opener or me?
Well, the numbers
are so compelling.
I think I'd start with how much
his department's cuts
will save the hospital.
And then I would...
I'll do the opener.
Sorry. I get a little
excited about statistics.
Not everybody shares
that passion. Not everybody.
Okay, so you do the talking,
and I'll hold up the chart
when you give me the signal?
Perfect. Damn it. Hunt
needs me in the OR.
You're gonna have
to start without me.
No. People don't like me.
Talk from your heart,
not about the charts
or the numbers.
You can do this.
Uh...
And there you have it.
A technique I have
developed through years
of highly focused research.
I eat, sleep, and
breathe hernias, folks.
After today, something
tells me you will, too.
Gross. Dr. Nesbaum.
Over the years, I've
developed my own technique
for a hernia repair.
So if it's all the same
to you, I'll stick to that.
I'm sure it's lovely,
but the point here
is to standardize the way
Seattle Grace-Mercy
West approaches the hernia
so every OR can be
prepped the same way.
It's quick, clean, efficient.
I suppose.
Listen to old man Webber.
"My ways are the best ways.
"Ooh, it's drafty in here.
"Somebody bring me a blanket."
Now what do you say to a
little friendly competition? Hmm?
The first surgeon who can
perform 20 hernia repairs
using my exact
tension-free mesh technique
will win bragging rights,
the respect of their peers,
and... Aha!
This sweet baby.
Oh.
I've seen those in the gift
shop. They're not cheap.
I knew it. They're
making us fight to survive.
First prize is a fleece.
Second prize is a
one-way ticket to the curb.
Shall we begin?
Tributes. May the odds
be ever in your favor.
Take 'em off.
What?
Well, we gotta get you up
and moving. Today's the day.
Maybe tomorrow's the day.
Look, if you don't get up, your
hips aren't gonna heal right.
I don't care.
I know it's hard.
But you're only 13.
You talk like your
whole life is over.
Like you even know
what my life was.
I know that you
were into gymnastics.
I wasn't "into gymnastics,"
stupid. It was my career.
Ever since I was four years old,
it's all I've ever wanted to do.
My mom worked double
shifts so I could be in the gym
five hours a day.
More on the weekends.
And I knew that if I
worked really hard,
someday she wouldn't
have to anymore.
I ranked number one at the
Future Stars Nationals last year.
I was going to the Rio
Olympics. I was next.
When my hips started to hurt,
I thought that I pulled a
muscle, so I trained through it.
I'm not next anymore. I'm
nothing. I'm number zero.
Hey. No, you're not.
Maybe this part might be over,
but you got time to
do all sorts of things.
They said that if the
surgery was successful,
I might be able to ride a bike,
'cause that's as good as having
your face on a
slurpee cup, right?
You might understand if
you've ever been
great at something.
Been best at something.
So, yeah, my life is over at 13.
I get to ride a bike
and go to school
and wait to die.
Cardio tech to the ER.
Dr. Yang, about the IV heparin
you ordered for room three.
Is there a problem?
No. It's just Dr. Richardson
insists I give sub-q enoxaparin.
Who the hell is Dr. Richardson?
Yeah. Ignore it.
I tried.
He keeps insisting, and it's
really upsetting the patient.
Open the pod bay doors, HAL.
It's Bob Richardson.
Dr. Richardson.
I have a little problem, Bob.
I'm here to help.
You're supposed to be
our eyes in the sky, correct?
Yes.
Then how about you just do that?
I'm sorry?
Don't question my
medical decisions.
If I order my intern
to give IV heparin,
I want IV heparin.
I guess you haven't
read the results
from the SYNERGY trial,
which showed enoxaparin
reduced the need for monitoring.
Oh!
Got a lot of time to read, Bob,
hanging out in your underwear,
watching your wall of monitors?
'Cause that same trial found
that there was more bleeding...
Dr. Yang. The pit's calling with a
possible cardiac trauma in the field.
Five minutes away.
Don't try and be a doctor, Bob.
Just make sure my idiot interns
don't screw up.
Give the IV
heparin. Don't butt in.
Let's go.
Dr. Russell. Dr. Kepner, trauma.
Trauma, of sainted memory.
Actually, we're trying
to save the department,
I was wondering if I could
talk to you about some ideas.
Got your e-mail.
"Proposed budget cuts."
Nice try.
Well, I think you'll
see that a 2%...
Okay, numbers
don't really matter. I...
Ever been to a TED conference?
I haven't. Inspiring.
Finest minds of our
generation under one roof,
sharing stories of
mind-bending innovation.
That sounds great but...
Innovation is what's
gonna save this hospital...
Okay. Not this penny saved,
penny earned crap.
Okay, but...
Good to meet you, Dr. Kepler.
Kepner.
This is a mess. I don't
think we can fix this primarily.
Can you check for back bleeding?
Cahill? Me?
Yeah, you're holding the
clamp. If you can't do it, then...
Okay.
He doesn't have any. Okay.
Which means he has
poor collateral flow.
We're gonna need a shunt.
I can put it in if someone will
get me a Rummel tourniquet.
Thank you.
Sorry. I used to do that.
Hmm. It's like
riding a bike, huh?
Yeah, if the bike's
going 200 miles an hour.
That's what makes it fun.
Yeah, damn right, it does.
So why did you
stop in the first place?
Yeah, Hunt, I got your page.
You're worried
about a brain bleed?
Yeah, we didn't get a
chance to do the scan.
His carotid blew.
Is that Kepner? Cahill.
Dr. Shepherd, hi.
So instead of telling
us how to do our jobs,
now you're just doing them?
That would be more efficient.
No, she was in the right
place at the right time.
She probably saved his life.
I got lucky.
Lucky for this guy his
chain saw slipped today.
Tomorrow he'd be dead already.
What do you got?
Skateboarder versus car.
Late teens. Didn't have ID.
The kid was slaloming
hills with a buddy.
Was nonresponsive in the field.
His last systolic was 70.
Heart rate tacking
along in the 130s.
EKG shows some changes,
so I suspect cardiac trauma.
Okay, I need a portable
X-ray up here, stat.
I need a 12-lead, and
let's get a TEE bedside.
Right away. Ready on
three. One, two, three.
Murphy, set up the TEE. Got it.
Type and cross for six units.
Hang two units of O-neg
as soon as possible.
Hey, what's your buddy's name?
Rich. Rich Campion.
Does he have any
allergies that you know of?
Is he on any medications?
I don't know.
Look, is he going to be okay?
We're doing everything we can.
No breath sounds on the right.
Someone set up a chest tube.
On it.
It looks like a
mediastinal hematoma.
Could be an aortic transection.
We need to move fast, people.
BP's still dropping. Scissors.
Yeah, he's crashing.
Where is that blood?
Right here, doctor.
He has a medical ID.
It must have broken off.
Okay. What's it say?
What's he allergic to?
Oh, God.
What is he allergic to?
Okay, stop.
He's a Jehovah's Witness.
We can't give him blood.
They're prepping the
OR for a bloodless surgery
so we'll need to
recirculate his blood.
So we'll put him on
a cell saver machine,
and then continue
the hypertonic saline,
colloids, and factor VII to pump
up his intravascular volume.
We're seriously repairing an
aortic transection without blood?
Yeah, we have no choice.
We could use blood.
We could also be arrested
for assault and battery.
Very funny. I'm not joking.
There are protocols in
place for people who won't
or can't accept
supplemental blood.
We do bloodless
surgeries here all the time.
Have you ever done this, a
bloodless aortic transection?
No.
Dr. Radnor to
labor and delivery...
I hear you. I did.
And...
Alex.
You don't have her walking yet?
There's no talking to that girl.
It's dark in there. Really dark.
Karev... I'm serious.
That girl turned me
into a suicide risk.
I'm gonna move her myself then.
Excessive force,
bad cop's go-to move.
Oh!
You know what
makes a bad cop bad?
When the good cop's namby-pamby
approach gets us nowhere.
Then bad cop has to set a limit
and ends up looking
like a big meanie.
A good cop's approach
takes time and patience.
Bad cop is a notorious hothead.
If she's going to insist
on wearing dresses,
she has to wear tights.
I'm gonna go lie down.
His vitals are worse.
How's the cell saver coming?
Almost ready.
Do we have surgical glue? Yes.
Avitene? Yes.
Okay, I want two bovies set up.
- I'm on it.
Joy, get my headlamp
ready. Here it is.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Where is my gel
foam and thrombin?
We're trying to keep
blood loss to a minimum.
We need a whole bunch more.
Okay, hypertonic saline?
Factor VII? Check. Check.
Cell saver ready? Check.
Okay, let's go
before he bleeds out.
I can't cut. He'll
lose too much blood.
What do we do?
We'll go in percutaneously.
Get the OR ready for
an endovascular repair.
Let's move.
Excellent, Dr. Grey.
19 more to go.
You're gonna choke, Grey.
You'll choke and die,
and I will dance and sing.
Damn it. Damn it!
The mesh is bunching
up at the pubic tubercle.
You know, I still
feel that you do not...
I understand this
can be tricky at first,
but once you get the hang of it,
you'll see why a dozen
hospitals around the country
have already
adopted this approach,
and I've already had
inquiries from a dozen more.
Check! Excuse me.
Okay. All right.
That's the right idea.
But... But... But what?
Well... Check.
Check! WOMAN: Check!
Hey, don't beat around the bush.
Tell me what you don't like,
'cause it looks perfect to me.
Okay.
Take a look at what
Dr. Grey is doing over here.
You see how she doesn't
rush, cut the mesh just right?
See, now when done properly,
the mesh will fit perfectly
and not require extra
sutures to hold it,
thereby reducing the risk
of future complications.
So do this over, pay
attention to the details,
and take your time.
I would be happy to give
you some pointers if you'd like.
That bun in the oven may give
you job security, Meredith Grey,
but it does not make you
immune from a smack in the mouth.
Rich is still in surgery.
Dr. Yang sent me
down to talk to his family.
Well, how... How's he doing?
It's touch and go.
They're gonna take
him back up to the CCU.
Is his family here?
Dude, like...
Dozens of them. Lord...
You know, I swear, we
hung out practically every day.
We have the same
shift at the skate shop.
And he never once
mentioned to me
that he was a Jehovah's Witness.
He never talked about it.
Father of all mercy...
I kind of don't think he is.
Well, maybe it was
just a personal thing.
Maybe, but I mean, if you...
If you believed in something
so hard that you would die for it...
Would you keep it a secret?
Wouldn't you at least tell your friends?
Yeah. Yeah, I guess.
I should... Look, I gotta...
I gotta get out of here.
Will you... Will you
call me when he's out?
Sure. No problem.
With which we ourselves
are being comforted by now.
Blessed be the God and
father of our Lord Jesus Christ.
We can't repair the
carotid under tension.
It'll pull apart.
Or clot. It's tricky.
We can't use one of
these vessels to patch it.
The chain saw chewed
everything up pretty good.
I could take a piece of
saphenous vein from the leg...
Yes. Good. Good.
Go ahead. Prep
the leg. All right.
Scissors and betadine, please.
Right away, Doctor.
So I hear somebody's
nose came off?
Can I have a headlamp, please?
Almost. Take a look.
Well, I would if
we could find out
where we're keeping the
headlamps these days.
And what should've
shaved off half a second
has now added five.
Thank you.
Gauze, please.
Oh, sorry. Meant
to just say "gauze."
That "please" just cost
me a tenth of second.
All right, Avery. That's enough.
Chief, you know
this is all about
turning over the tables for her.
I mean, I feel like I'm
working the dinner shift
at a Jumbo Burger
in here. Dr. Avery...
She should just replace us
with surgical robots, really.
I mean, that's essentially
what she's asking us to be.
Shh. Bless you.
You don't tell us
how to run an OR
if you don't
actually work in one.
That's all I'm saying.
You can tell Dr. Pantsuit
hasn't been in one in years.
Until today.
Well, I can repair this post-op.
So, just give me a
shout when you're done.
Thank you, Doctors.
Best of luck.
Mm-hmm.
I thought I was gonna be fired.
Sorry about that.
It's fine.
It's easier if
there's a bad guy.
My people just care
about this place.
I know. I know you're all upset,
especially you, losing your ER.
But I also know that without me,
you'd lose this entire hospital.
So if you need to blame
me instead of thank me,
I'm fine with that,
because I will
know who saved it.
I've saved a dozen
before just like this one,
and no one thanked
me for those either.
Let's add a CPK to his next blood
draw. What was his last hemoglobin?
Four.
The guy's on fumes.
Try and stimulate blood
production by giving EPO.
Or we could give him blood
and cut out the middle man.
We can also give
IV iron-dextran.
Thanks, Bob.
We can give him iron?
How is that logical?
We can give him the components
of blood, just not blood?
We have to respect his wishes.
What wishes? He
can't tell us anything.
His friend didn't even know
that he was a Jehovah's Witness.
Yeah, it's not the kind of thing
you talk about
at the skate park.
I'm just saying, he's 19.
How can he even
know what he believes?
When I was 19,
I was a completely different
person than I am now.
I wanted to be a radiologist.
Wow. I feel like I'm
seeing a whole new you.
Start his EPO and keep
a close eye on his crit.
Right away, Doctor.
So you're fine with this?
Even though he could
die, you're fine with just...
It doesn't matter what I think.
He had an alert. It was
very clear, no blood.
I don't get to have an opinion
about it, and neither do you.
So there's nothing we can do?
Yeah, there is.
We can talk to the family.
Good luck.
Simmi, I need you to take my
hand. I'm gonna help you sit up.
You're gonna swing
your legs to the side
and you're gonna stand up.
Now.
I don't give you
permission to touch me.
Like, bodily. I'll scream.
Simmi, if you don't move,
I'm gonna have to say
that you're acting
against medical advice.
We will discharge
you, you will go home,
and you will rot, okay?
The muscles around
your new hips will atrophy,
and you will probably
never walk again.
Why do you care?
Because I'm your doctor
and I worked very
hard to help you.
Wouldn't it suck if
you didn't help me?
If you went through all of that
training to become a big doctor,
you came up with a plan,
you did my operation, you
did it just right, just perfect,
you made me so
I could walk again,
but I didn't,
wouldn't you feel helpless,
like nothing matters?
No matter how much
you care, how hard you try,
how badly you want something,
you will never have it
because everything is
totally out of your control.
Feel that?
Couldn't have done
it better myself. Yes!
Yes, indeed.
Okay, all right,
people often ask me
how I can focus so
much time on hernias
and maintain this
level of excitement.
Well, now you see.
Perfection is exciting.
Yeah.
Hear that, Grey? I'm perfect.
Look at Miss
Slow-and-Steady over there.
Can't even bother
to participate.
No, seriously, Grey, you okay?
Yeah, yeah. I just need to...
Darn it.
Something's wrong.
You're right. I got
comfortable and flip,
and the universe is
smacking me down for it.
I'm not immune. I'm not safe.
Wait, wait. Grey,
stop. What is going on?
There... There's a flutter.
It's... It can't be right.
Sweetie. This is
not a bad thing.
What? It's not?
No, it's good.
It's so good.
Your baby's kicking.
Oh.
He's lost a lot of blood. I'd
say more than half his volume.
He'll make new blood.
It takes about four days
to make new blood cells.
He may not have that much time.
What would really help
is a blood transfusion.
No. No blood.
If you're worried about
disease transmission,
I can assure you that all of our
blood is meticulously screened.
It's not that we don't
trust your blood. We just...
We believe that
life is a gift from God
and we don't try to
sustain it by taking in blood.
Let me be perfectly clear,
your son's condition is critical.
Without blood, his organs
will start shutting down.
And once he starts that spiral,
there is nothing we can do.
Oh, dear God.
We are juggling all kinds
of substitute measures,
but nothing is as good as blood.
As his surgeon, I urge you
to let us give him the
best chance we can.
Let us give him blood.
We have seen amazing
miracles through prayer.
If it's God's will...
So you won't allow blood,
even if it's gonna save his life?
'Cause prayer... Murphy.
We appreciate all
you're doing for our boy.
But your blood wouldn't save
his life. It would condemn him.
Living with it would be so much
worse for him than dying without it.
We understand.
We will do everything in our
power to keep your son alive.
Thank you.
Colvin said I was insulting
him and everyone in his field.
Beck said she doesn't
talk to fund-raisers.
And... And Springfield
basically had me
agreeing to give him money.
And then Russell... You
talked about the numbers?
No.
April.
I didn't. I mean, just
a... Like barely at all.
We don't have a lot of time,
but I'll see what I can do.
There's Redmond.
Hey, hey, Tim.
I saw your little Howie today
when I was dropping Zola
off at day care. Man, he's cute.
Thanks. Yeah, he's a kick.
Yeah, Zola's at
that age where she's
just putting everything
in her mouth.
Yeah, we're not quite
there yet. Just you wait.
It's like, Legos,
magnets. Really?
Anything that is a
choking hazard, they find it.
Jeez. Yeah, well, lucky for us,
the ER is right downstairs
from the day care.
Yeah, that's for sure.
Wait, isn't that closing?
Yeah, that's what I
wanted to talk to you about.
Dermatology has two fellows.
Now if we could
just cut one of them,
maybe we could possibly...
I hate her.
Who?
My intern. Why?
Look at her, all mopey-faced
just 'cause she didn't get her way.
We were never mopey-faced.
We just sucked it up.
Why aren't you
in your skills lab?
Because the baby kicked.
Wouldn't stop kicking, actually.
Jerk. No, it's good. It's great.
Kicking is a good thing.
Maybe I should kick my intern.
Maybe my baby's kicking
because it wants a granola bar.
That's possible.
You want to stop right there.
You tried to give
blood instead of fluids?
He's not stupid, you
know, the eyeball.
He has eyes.
And a zoom lens.
Rich is circling the drain,
and he doesn't have to be.
We are giving him
everything we have,
just like the family requested.
Yeah, I know. And
they're praying. Awesome.
You never administer anything
to a patient without my orders.
You think that because
you've been here all of,
what, six months, you know
everything? You know nothing.
On the timeline of
doctoring, you are an amoeba.
I thought that he
deserved a chance.
You have passion. I get it.
You still have to do what I say.
I am your boss and I am
trying to save this patient's life.
Now get out of here.
You're off my service.
I just... Now.
I'm sorry.
What are you gonna
do, get her fired?
She didn't do anything.
There's nothing to tell.
She's right, you know?
He's circling the drain.
Yeah, I know.
Okay.
Ready?
Fingers crossed.
Yes.
The sutures will hold.
There will be no bloodbath.
Okay, let's go, Doctor.
Remove your clamps.
Dr. Cahill?
Okay.
Okay, good.
I totally wasn't sure
that was gonna work.
I get it. I get it.
But you did great.
I'd never have thought you'd
spent a day outside of an OR.
Oh! Thank you very much.
Good God. I have to go.
I've... I've lost a whole day.
You're all right if I...
No, no, we're not done.
But it's pretty
straightforward...
No, we need to finish debriding.
We need to put in drains, close,
then you get to tell the
family that you saved him,
he's alive because of you.
And then they get to thank you.
And that's the best part.
10 blade, please.
I'm saying, they always cut
the lowest on the
totem pole first.
And we're below that.
I've been emptying
urine bags all morning.
You gotta stop.
All these cuts,
the reconfiguring,
this is designed to
make the hospital
run more efficiently
in the future.
So? That means Cahill
is planning for the
hospital to have a future.
If you're gonna have a hospital,
there's one thing you can't cut.
Doctors.
Crap. My patient's coding.
See that? We save lives, people.
We are smart,
young, vital doctors.
You're right.
If she's planning
for the future...
We are that future.
You hope.
'Cause you can talk all you
want and work hard, hustle,
you can empty more urine
bags than the next guy.
The future, kids,
is completely out
of your control.
Jeff. How's the research coming?
Save it. Your sidekick
already made the pitch.
Not gonna happen. Come on.
Your team can watch
the TED talks online.
It's not about the talks.
It's about the networking.
The real... This isn't about me.
This is what's good
for the hospital.
Everyone can benefit from
the ER, the patients especially.
Mm.
You know what might open
my heart to your cause?
Your parking space.
My space is right next to
yours. It's not even an advantage.
In fact, you're five feet
further from the door.
I don't want to swap.
I want 'em both.
I don't want you
dinging my doors.
What?
I want both spots so I
can park in the middle.
How's your sister, Jeff?
Really?
Really? You're
really gonna go there?
Well, I'll never forget
how grateful you were
when I clipped her aneurysm.
And you said,
"If there's anything I
can ever do for you..."
This is just plain bullying.
Say good-bye to TED, Jeff.
I still want your parking space.
May as well swallow your
poison berries now, Webber,
because I am the
girl who's on fire.
Check.
Very good, Dr. Webber.
Let's just...
I'm... I'm confused.
Where the mesh?
I didn't use any.
I wanted to give you a
look at the Webber method
so you can see just
what you're missing.
It's lovely, but...
Isn't it?
See, when I use
the relaxing incision
to oppose the tissue
without tension,
I achieve the same result
without the use of mesh.
But this method will no longer
be performed at Seattle Grace.
The method we learned
today is the accepted method
for open primary
repairs hospital-wide.
Because we're cogs
in an assembly line,
churning out product
over and over,
standardized across the country.
Don't you think every patient
deserves the same standard of care?
And how good can that care be
when we see 50
patients in a day?
What are their names?
Who are their families?
With that kind of volume,
who in the hell knows?
As long as you can slap a
sign on the door that says,
"Over ten million served,"
who the hell cares?
You're missing the point.
The patients don't matter.
What matters is... I didn't...
Obviously, I didn't
mean that. Okay?
We are only concerned about
hernias, right now, I mean.
See, that... That
is really quite good.
In the months to come, I think
everyone should follow your lead, okay?
Okay. Keep it up.
Still in v-fib.
How long has it
been? 26 minutes.
Push another epi and
charge again to 200.
Charging.
Clear.
Still nothing. Damn it.
Uh...
Charge to 200 again.
Clear.
Okay, I'm calling it.
Time of death, 6:42.
He didn't have to die.
All they had to do was
let us give him blood.
And he still could've died.
The CCU is full of people we
pump full of blood, and they still die.
People die.
You know, what you did was wrong
in about a hundred
different ways.
And I plan on telling you
all of them, just not right now.
'Cause right now, I have
to go talk to the family.
Hey, show's over, Bob.
You can change the channel.
Hey.
How'd it go?
Oh, for God sakes.
I mean... Okay, see,
Officer Hard-Ass?
Your approach doesn't
always work either.
Hey.
You need to get up now.
You need to take a few steps
and remember how it feels.
And I know... I know
how hard this is.
But you want this. You do.
You don't know what I want.
No? Okay.
I lost my leg.
Less than a year ago.
And I was scared and in pain
and I thought that I
would never be able to do
the things that I
like to do anymore.
But I did.
I operated on you.
Wow.
They send the cripple in to
teach me how to live my life.
Okay. Okay.
You know what?
You can be scared
and you can be pissed
and you can lie here
like a garden slug
till you die for all I care.
But you will not, not,
become a monster
that takes everyone
else down with them.
You will treat people
with kindness and respect.
And you will
start with yourself.
And you will start
by standing up.
And you will do so by
the time I count to three,
or I will drag your
ass out of this bed.
So, one...
Two...
Three.
Okay. You got it.
You got it. You got it.
Okay. Okay, I
got you. I got you.
All right. Good. Good. Good.
Wow.
Take a step.
Great. Look at that. You got it.
Good. Good job.
All right. Look at you.
Oh, my... He's gonna live?
Mm-hmm.
Thank you.
This is who you really
should be thanking.
If it wasn't for
her... Thank you.
Thank you so much!
God bless you. Thank you.
Hold the elevator, please!
Oh.
Off to celebrate, are we?
I get it.
Well, change can be rough.
But once you get used to it,
you'll never believe you did
a hernia repair any other way.
And if I may say, that sweatshirt
is quite becoming on you.
It's itchy.
I did forget what a rush it is.
Yeah. What, saving someone's
life? Yeah, it's not bad.
You know, we could do that
again tomorrow if we had an ER.
We figured it out.
We can save the ER.
We got each department
to make some cuts,
and I'm gonna have
to park in Tacoma,
but it is going to work.
I'm sorry. You misunderstood.
No amount of budget
cutting or shuffling
is gonna save your ER.
Or your hospital,
for that matter.
You're getting us ready to sell.
What?
A buyer is going to
save your hospital.
I just need to
make it presentable.
I'm sorry. What? It's...
You're staging it, like a house.
Exactly.
And the ER is like
the shag carpet.
It's gotta go.
Sorry.
I had a wonderful time today.
To really be efficient,
you have to eliminate
what doesn't work.
You have to figure
out what's important...
What are you gonna do?
You mean right now or...
Or both. Whichever.
Right now I am
going to drink a lot.
That's all I know.
Can I buy the first one?
Yeah.
And hold on tight...
To the things that matter most.
Wow.
I felt that.
Wait.
Oh!
You got a soccer
player, I think, right there.