♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
Oh, what about peonies?
Peonies could be good.
I have no idea.
It's your mother's wedding,
and you don't know
what kind of flowers
she wants?
Bizzy made it abundantly clear
that this wedding
is for Susan.
Okay. Then what would
Susan want?
Again, I have no idea.
Ugh. You're being petulant.
Well, I am entitled, Nai.
I am throwing a wedding
for my mother
and her...
Lesbian mistress/lover.
My mother. Okay?
Who, by the way,
never thanked me
for saving the life of her
lesbian mistress/lover.
I told you, if you want
something from that woman,
you have to ask her for it.
All right. How about this?
"Bizzy, stop being a lesbian
and go back to your husband.
"Stay in the closet--
your very large,
well-decorated closet."
Homophobe.
I know, right? But only
when it comes to her.
I mean, if it were you,
if you wanted to marry
your lesbian mistress/lover,
I would throw you a parade.
I would march on the capital
until it was legal.
But with her, I mean, what--
what is wrong with me?
Why am I being like this?
Well, she's your mommy.
My mommy? Mommies are warm.
My nanny was warm, but she...
She's my bizzy.
Which is exactly
why you are being like this.
Look, you always thought that
she was cold and hard,
and she's about to do something
warm and wonderful.
She's about to pledge
her love...
Which means you might actually
be wrong about her,
which means she might
actually be your mommy.
All right, Susan--
she likes understated elegance.
Okay. Then let's find
an understated, elegant flower.
You came.
You saw me.
Now cross it off your list.
I'll see you in six months.
See?
I can't deal with this.
Lisa, Lisa,
wait, wait, wait, wait.
He drinks cognac like
it's water, he only wears
that stupid track suit that
I bought him 20 years ago,
and he sounds like he's ready
for the tubercular ward.
But if he doesn't give a damn,
then why should I?
Well, why don't you
bring someone in
to help out around here?
Oh, he's got someone. Simone.
She's hiding in the bedroom
because she knows
how much I detest her.
She doesn't help.
She indulges him.
I miss my mom.
Yeah. She was, uh,
an amazing lady.
I'm sorry. I have to go.
You know how you can tell
if a politician is lying?
His lips are moving.
You know what
that sound is?
Too many cigars
and too few walks.
Go drum up business
somewhere else, smart guy.
This place is filled
with veiny old biddies
who would love
your attention.
Why don't you listen to me?
You knew esty.
Without her, what have I got
to look forward to?
Hey.
Hey, enough with the zipping
and zapping. I'm hungry.
Oh, hi.
Hi.
Oh, Simone,
this is, uh, Sam Bennett.
He was esty's doctor,
and now he's a pain in my ass.
I was gonna grab Abe
some lunch.
Can I get you anything?
No. No, thank you.
Uh, go to langler's,
all right?
It's the best pastrami in L.A.
now that my deli is closed.
But that's like being
the world's tallest midget,
but still--
w-why don't I buy us all
something a little more healthy,
uh, like, uh,
Turkey sandwiches?
I'm running low. Uh, uh,
get me a couple of bottles of--
milk.
Yeah.
Got it, handsome.
You know,
she's not helping you.
Sure she is.
You know how long
it would take me
to shuffle over to
the liquor store and back?
At least let Simone bring you
up to my office.
Let me see what's going on
with that cough.
Thanks for visiting.
I was raped...
In my office.
Physical pain
was gone in a week.
The feelings...
I get scared sometimes.
And I get sad.
The days feel longer
than they should.
And I'm having trouble
sleeping.
You're depressed.
I said I get sad.
Okay.
I can't, uh...
Cooper's wonderful.
He's the best.
But I can't, uh...
I try,
but I can't have sex.
Mm.
Every time we try,
I get this picture
in my head.
I'm lying on the floor...
And that man's on top of me,
but I'm not watching
from below.
I'm above him...
Like a spectator
to my own rape.
Why do you think that is?
Why do you think
that is?
There it is.
Psychobabble.
Ask a question.
Get a question back.
Whole thing's ridiculous.
I told Cooper
this was a bad idea.
And can I be honest with you?
I don't want you in my head.
I don't need you in my head.
I agree. Talk therapy--
it won't help.
I'm...
Prescribing
a cocktail of drugs.
A combination
of antidepressants,
mood stabilizers,
some tranquilizers,
just to take the edge off.
Now your mood, your sleep,
your energy,
it'll get better.
Now I've written
four refills,
so you're good
for five months.
Good luck.
Lungs are clear.
Vitals look good.
Did you ask him?
I didn't want to impose.
Ask me what?
Our wedding--we would
love for you to come.
Imposing. You're imposing.
Oh, not at all.
It would be an honor.
I'll be back later, and i'm
looking forward to a dance.
I think he has a thing for you.
I'm with Sam.
For now.
Dr. Rodriguez is from
a prominent family
in South America--
very wealthy.
I'll keep that in mind,
bizzy.
I'm simply saying that it's
as easy to fall--
I love Sam.
You don't choose
who you love.
Right, ladies?
You should see
how he's living, Nai.
The girl who's taking care
of him doesn't clean,
lets him drink, eat,
smoke all day.
Well, so tell his daughter.
She was there.
I walked in on them fighting.
He doesn't listen
to her either.
I thought they had a better
relationship than that.
You remember how we used
to think of him as a--
as a charming curmudgeon?
Well--
now he's just a curmudgeon?
Yes.
Oh, well, maybe he's happy
like that,
or his version of happy.
No. He deserves to be
taken care of.
Sam, it's wonderful that you
still care about Abe.
But what Abe wants to do
with the time he has left,
that's his business.
Hey, what's going on
with Violet?
I mean, is she too cool
to call me or what?
She just has all these
meetings with her publisher.
- Your friend Larry's in the wrong line of work.
- What do you mean?
He's a pharmacist
not a therapist.
Who's Larry?
Dr. Larry Cannon--
my best friend
and a brilliant psychiatrist.
You have a best friend?
What are you, 12?
Yeah. Mm.
You're seeing a shrink?
Good for you.
Not good. All he tried to do
was push drugs on me.
Wait. What do you mean?
Did you try talking to him--
you think I hauled my ass
across town to sit in silence?
I tried.
He wasn't interested.
There's enough drugs there
to paralyze an elephant.
Oh, this makes no sense.
Larry isn't a pill guy.
He pioneered
narrative talk therapy.
He taught it to me.
It's the basis of my practice.
Narrative--
that's using the story
of people's lives, right?
Larry wasn't interested
in my stories.
He just wanted to write me
a scrip.
Maybe he thought you needed
to be stabilized
before you started talking.
That sounded bad, right?
Yeah, it did.
Charlotte, I'm sorry.
Look, Larry's been traveling
a lot, and, uh,
I don't know what's going on,
but I'll talk to him.
I'll explain you weren't
looking for pills.
But you can't give up
after only one session.
I can, and I will.
Dr. Dyson,
dial the page operator.
Y-You know you really
don't have to come
to their wedding.
I like weddings.
Susan goes
in the "win" column.
That's always
worth celebrating.
You know, I'm not sure
I ever said--
I was just doing my job.
It was important to me,
and you were willing to try.
I'm not sure
I could say no to you.
Okay.
I'm with Sam.
Mm-hmm.
You know I'm with Sam.
You have to stop.
I am not interested.
Well, if that were true,
you wouldn't care
that I flirt with you.
Okay.
You are not hearing me,
and i--
I need to go.
You do realize that I didn't
even plan my own wedding.
Because I did.
You're returning the favor.
I get that you want to give
Susan this wedding,
but it's...
Okay. You know what?
I don't get it.
Based on your sham of a marriage
to the captain,
I mean, you clearly don't
take vows that seriously,
and we all know
you're a cheater.
Thank you, by the way,
for passing that down.
I think we both know that
infidelity is not genetic.
And if we agree
it's learned behavior,
you certainly didn't
learn it from me, dear,
because you had no idea
what I was up to
until long after you'd made
your own mistakes.
It really is time
for you to grow up
and accept responsibility.
For the past 20 years,
I've had my proverbial cake--
homes, husband,
children, jewels,
ladies auxiliary--
and that whole time,
the love of my life waited
patiently in the closet
because that was my way.
I almost lost Susan,
but she's healthy now,
so this time we do it her way,
and she wants a wedding.
I'm a lesbian, dear.
Deal with it.
I just want
to get a schedule.
Hey. I didn't expect
to see you here.
I didn't expect
to cough up a lung,
so there you are.
You want me to examine you?
Uh, no.
I just came here for
the "expectant mother" magazine.
Uh, you don't
have to come in.
You sure?
An audience
makes him nervous.
Okay. Uh, right this way.
Just tell him
Dr. Wallace called again.
W-a-l--look, just tell him
to call Sheldon
as soon as possible.
Yes, thank you.
Do you have any idea
how long it took me
to convince her to go?
We had one shot at this.
Cooper--
no. Charlotte's not like us,
Sheldon.
She doesn't share every feeling
and vocalize every thought.
She comes from a family
of mutes.
Her dad never said he loved her.
Her mother denied
she had a drinking problem
until her liver imploded.
So for her to be willing
to speak to somebody
about the rape--
I know you're upset--
no, no, no, she needs this.
She doesn't sleep.
She's always
looking over her shoulder.
Look, I'm sorry,
but this...
This isn't the Larry I know.
You said he was the best.
He is the best.
Larry is the reason
I became a therapist.
Okay, watching him
connect to people,
UN-unraveling their problems,
you know, it was inspiring.
So what happened?
I don't know. I don't know.
But I'm gonna find out.
Okay, so...
Hotel's booked.
Flowers are done.
Music...
Do you have the final count
for the caterer?
Oh. Well, bizzy has
no friends here,
and I don't think
Susan has friends.
Uh, the captain
is clearly not attending.
Oh, and my brother
e-mailed this morning,
saying that he didn't come
to bizzy's first wedding,
so he's not coming
to her second.
So I guess...
That just leaves us,
except, um, for Violet
who's in New York, so...
Uh, that's ten.
No, no.
11. Dr. Rodriguez,
he's attending.
Why--why did you
invite him?
I didn't. Susan did.
Why? What's the difference?
I don't know. I just--
I saw you in the hospital
flirting with him.
N-No.
No, Nai.
He was flirting with me.
I was very uncomfortable.
Nai.
All right. He--Dr. Rodriguez
asked me out ages ago.
But I told him that I am
in love with Sam.
Well, clearly,
you weren't very convincing.
Okay, Nai, come on.
Stop, all right?
I'm already insane enough with
bizzy breathing down my neck.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I just, uh...
When you told me
about you and Sam,
I just didn't think that
you guys were gonna last.
I thought...
Look, um, I'm not bizzy,
and I am not criticizing
or doubting,
but your relationship with Sam
is real now.
And...
When it gets real,
that's usually
when you screw it up.
Well...
Not this time.
Chronic obstructive
pulmonary disease.
Big medical words
don't scare me.
Hey.
The better-looking
Dr. Bennett.
Sam told me you were here.
I just thought I'd come in
and say hi.
Or he dragged you away
from something more important
to play good cop
and tell me all the things
that I have to live for.
I'm old,
but I'm not stupid.
Abe, now, our--our only
interest here is helping you.
Unless you can raise
the dead...
Look, uh, we realize that
we can't replace esty,
but we can help you find
somebody better than Simone.
Someone who can cook, clean.
You sound like Lisa.
Well, maybe that should
tell you something.
Esty and I...
Simone and I are...
We're doing just fine.
Insurance card.
Oh, insurance card. Um--
oh.
Um...
Here you go.
Thanks.
No problem... Mr. Nussbaum.
Um, I actually--he--
I work for him.
And he's, uh, he's older,
an older guy.
He's a patient
of Dr. Bennett.
So I can--i can--
I got this. Thanks.
So this is why
you never answer your phone.
The Chinese have been playing
mah-jongg for a thousand years,
and I just discovered it
a week ago.
How amazing is that, huh?
What's more amazing
is that little drug cocktail
you wrote Dr. King.
Oh. Lovely lady.
Killer smile.
Charlotte's a colleague
and a friend. I sent her to you
because she survived
a traumatic sexual assault,
and you sent her packing
in five minutes.
Not empty-handed.
Since when do you
replace talk therapy
with drug protocols?
Sheldon,
they come to us distraught,
emotionally void.
And we listen.
We take it all in,
interpret the data,
and then we respond
using whatever experience
we have.
I don't understand.
The cycle repeats itself--
breakthrough, relapse--
over and over and over ag--
talk therapy is a sham.
That's crazy.
We help people.
By sharing our insights?
We're not helping anything.
No.
These guys do.
Sheldon, we are machines.
Everything we do
is controlled
by chemical neurotransmitters
in our brain.
Crank up the serotonin,
and we feel euphoric.
Dissipate it,
and we feel depressed.
It's not that simple.
Drugs have a place in therapy.
But it--
it's not in isolation.
Human interaction is critical.
You...
You've spent your entire life
committed to talk therapy.
Yo-you've--
you've helped thousands
of patients.
I was wrong.
Everything that I taught you,
everything that you've built
your practice on
is a lie.
Is black wrong?
I mean, it's a wedding,
not a funeral.
You know, but it is L.A.
what would you want
yours to be like?
My what?
Your second wedding. What would
you want it to be like?
I don't know.
Okay, I have to
tell you something.
Not because it's important,
but because...
I don't want you to hear it
from somebody else
and misunderstand.
Do I want to hear this?
Eric Rodriguez
flirted with me.
He's been flirting
with me.
But I did not flirt back.
Well, what does that mean?
I don't know.
I don't know. I just...
I just thought
that you should know.
And now I do.
She had probably
a dozen credit cards
with your dad's name
on 'em.
Why am I not surprised?
You think your dad
has any idea?
Even if he knew, he wouldn't
care. She's pretty and flirty.
You think that matters to him?
Well, he's still
a man, Naomi.
After my mom died,
he became a different person.
It's like,
the more help he needs,
the farther away
he pushes me.
And to settle
for that Simone...
Well, she's not taking
good care of your dad,
and now with the credit cards,
you should get rid of her.
And then what? He can't
be alone. He needs help.
We'll help you find
someone else.
Do you want to talk
to Simone,
or should I?
Can you just tell her
to stop what she's doing
and try harder?
Lisa--
please.
I can't deal with him.
But someone has to.
Did you say anything
to upset him?
You're not really
blaming her?
No. No, it's just, maybe
he felt that talk therapy
would be ineffective
in this specific case.
Talk therapy is ineffective.
Are you and Larry working
for the same drug company?
What is the point
of sitting on a couch
and blabbing back and forth
when emotions
are controlled by chemicals?
When your car is out of gas,
you don't whisper in the tank
to get it moving.
Talk therapy has 70 years
of empirical studies
backing its effectiveness.
But what you do
in a year of therapy
can be accomplished in a day
with a little yellow pill.
Talking
doesn't have side effects,
risk of dependency,
negative interactions.
You of all people
should know that.
Well, maybe he was
trying something new.
I mean, he wouldn't be
the first doctor
to have a change of heart.
A change of heart I get.
But a complete 180
after 25 years?
What did he say
when you confronted him?
He shut me down.
And?
You let him get away
with that?
Susan?
W--where'd she go?
I discharged her
an hour ago.
She said she and your mother
were checking in
to the four seasons.
Well, no one called me.
Where are you rushing off to?
I make you uncomfortable.
No.
W-Well, ye--
okay, yes, you do.
I'm in love with Sam.
So you keep saying.
He's your friend.
Doesn't that bother you?
Does it bother you?
Yes.
Shame.
I'm sorry.
No, don't be sorry.
I'm fine.
I thought the therapy
might help.
Why did he have to be
a kook?
Char, it's okay.
I'm fine.
It's fine with me.
What if...
What if I'm never ready?
Don't think about it.
Don't worry about it.
When it's right,
you'll know.
I can wait.
You can't wait.
I can.
And until you're ready...
I...
Have this.
Yeah.
Hey.
What are you doing over here?
Just a change of pace.
Huh. Well...
Dinner for one?
Yeah. Well, I figured
you'd, uh, you'd be late.
Since I haven't seen you
all day, and you didn't call,
it might be more accurate
to say
you guessed
that I would be late.
Or... you hoped
I would be late?
Listen, um...
You asked me
last night about...
My second wedding.
Yeah. That, uh, I didn't
mean anything by that.
That w--you were planning
a wedding, and I was just--
it was just--i was just asking
a question. I just wanted to--
well, I thought about it.
Whoa. Okay. Answer.
Should we?
Should we get married?
Let's get married.
Wait. Okay, wait.
No, don't answer now.
Is this coming off
the Eric thing
and the--and the--
and the flirting--
no. You are my best friend.
I love what we have together.
Just think about it.
Okay?
You've turned your back
on talk therapy.
It's everything you ever
stood for and believed in.
And now you're...
How can you just walk away?
It's simple. All these years,
I've been wrong, Sheldon.
But I finally figured it out,
and I'm content.
I like the new me.
The pills...
Have helped me let go
of some dark emotions that were
kicking around upstairs.
Larry, what the hell
are you doing?
Do you even know
what you're taking?
I'm a doctor, remember?
Mm. Finally,
you're seeing the light.
You're not getting these back.
Give me those.
Hey, now don't get greedy,
shelley.
There's something
very wrong with you.
I am ten times the shrink
that you are.
I am fully qualified
to make a diagnosis.
Not on yourself.
You honestly think
that you are equipped
to evaluate me?
I have an I.Q. Of 170.
I have 53 published papers.
I have written six books.
What have you ever done?!
Huh?!
Please let me help you.
We can talk about--
no talking! No therapy!
You don't know what I know
so you can't see it,
but I can.
See, I know!
Tell him!
Tell him to listen!
He won't listen!
He just keeps talking!
Okay. You're friends
with Addison.
You're like a little sister
to her. You--you know her.
Are you accusing me
of something
or asking me something?
Addison proposed.
Wow. I-I...
Yeah.
Didn't see that coming.
Uh... well, congratulations.
Do you think she's crazy?
I guess I should take back
my congratulations.
I'm not even sure she meant it.
Like, maybe she didn't mean it.
But what if she did?
Wait. You didn't answer her?
Last week,
she wanted to have a baby.
This week,
she wants to get married.
No, wait. Stop. Back up.
Addison proposed,
you didn't answer her,
and now you're here asking me
if I think she's crazy?
You guys look so happy.
What--what is the problem?
I ju--no, we are happy.
I-I ju--i don't know
if there is a problem exactly,
but... I know
that this ain't right.
Okay.
So--
so...
How do I let her down easy?
Hey, Sheldon.
You don't look so good.
Everything okay?
No, Cooper.
Everything is not okay.
Look, I'm sorry.
It's just...
I spent the whole night
looking for Larry.
Went to his office, went to
his house--he wasn't there.
Something happen?
We were having dinner
in a restaurant,
and he--he just went...
Cuckoo?
The proper term
is a psychotic break.
Is he dangerous?
Should you call
the police?
I was hoping
not to get them involved.
Sheldon, the man's
treating patients.
Or supposed to be,
anyway.
Do you have a choice?
I got a message
you wanted to see me.
Is it about Abe's cough?
Because I told him
he has to use that inhaler--
stop talking.
I know
about the credit cards.
What else have you stolen
from him?
Nothing. I mean--
tell me the truth, or i'm
going to call the police.
It's just the credit cards.
And I didn't even put much
on any of 'em.
The job pays like crap,
and it's a lot of work.
And I just... it's not easy
taking care of that guy.
He yells,
he has mood swings,
and I didn't even want
to take it,
but I have loans.
Get out.
Get out. Walk out
of this office right now.
And don't ever go back
and see Abe again.
You know, just so you know,
he loves me.
He won't press charges,
and...
He'll want me back.
♪♪♪
Hey, you have a minute?
Oh, uh, I-I was trying
to get out
to see Olivia
before she goes to bed.
Well, I, uh, I have something
that I want to tell you.
Well, I mean,
I don't want to tell you,
but I need to tell you
or I should--
speak.
Okay. Uh...
I, uh...
I proposed to Sam.
I asked Sam to marry me...
And, uh, well,
and now--
stop talking.
I have--
I have been supportive,
and I have been friendly,
but i--
I am done
being polite about this.
Addison, you suck
at relationships.
You--you take other people's
men, and--and now that
you have some man that wants to
cheat with you, you're tempted.
That's why you asked Sam
to marry you.
Nai, i--
no, no, i--no. I-i--
as your friend, Addison,
I cannot hold this in anymore,
and as Sam's ex-wife...
♪♪♪
You--you have to go.
No. No, Nai,
we need to talk about this.
No. No. I am--
I'm done talking.
She was stealing
from you, Abe.
I've got underwear
older than that kid.
You think she was fooling me?
I like to look at her ass.
So it cost me a little?
Why do you give a damn?
Because I was trying
to protect you.
I don't need protection.
But you do need help.
I wish I didn't.
I wish to god I didn't.
For my whole life,
I was the help.
♪♪♪
Esty's parents
were immigrants.
They never had any good work,
so I took two jobs--
one stocking shelves,
one cutting meat--
to give them something extra.
Esty was working, too,
but then once Lisa came,
I-I didn't want her to have to,
so I put off opening my deli
so she wouldn't worry.
Then when my Lisa got older
and we had a foothold,
esty wanted
to go back to school.
So I spent less time at work
and more time as a chauffer--
soccer practice, band concerts,
whatever she needed.
And I saved so that when Lisa
wanted to go to brown,
the money was there.
Barely, but it was there.
Then when...
Esty got sick...
♪♪♪
♪ and time,
it moves so slow ♪
I am the help.
♪ With you ♪
♪ so ♪
♪ I ♪
♪ lie ♪
The bulgari.
Definitely the bulgari.
You've wanted it
since you were 4.
I'll probably have to pry it
out of your cold, dead hands.
Can you please make sure
that Susan's dressed?
We're doing photographs
before the guests arrive.
Mm.
Susan.
I'm in here.
Hey. Uh--
oh.
Uh, bizzy is ready
to do the pictures, so she's--
and she wants to know
when I'll be dressed?
Yes.
Give me ten minutes.
Okay.
Uh, do you need anything?
No, I'm good. I'm good.
Okay.
Addison.
Yeah.
I just wanted to tell you
how grateful I am,
we both are,
for everything.
Thank you.
It's nice for at least
one of you to acknowledge.
Bizzy doesn't...
Well, you know her.
Yeah, I thought I did.
But with you, she's...
I don't know. I just never knew
that she could, uh--
love?
She loved you the second
that you were born,
but intimacy has to be
worked on both sides.
Whoa.
Oh. Oh. Oh.
Are you okay?
Oh. Uh, yeah.
No, I'm fine. I'm fine.
Susan, what's going on?
I'm not better, Addie.
I'm bloating
and I'm weak again.
And it feels like...
I did
before I was diagnosed.
I know the cancer's
come back.
No. Dr. Rodriguez wouldn't
have discharged you
if that was the case.
He wanted me to stay
and do tests,
but I didn't give him
a choice.
Don't be mad. Please.
I need today.
Bizzy and I both do.
No, that's not a good idea.
All right?
If the cancer's back,
then we need to fight it.
We can post--we can delay your
wedding. We'll get you back--
Addison, listen to me.
I signed a d.N.R.
No delays, no more doctors,
no more exams,
no extraordinary measures.
And you can't tell bizzy.
Susan, i--
no.
Your mother and I...
Just give us today.
You all right?
I need to ask you something.
A-And I need you
to be honest with me.
Okay. Shoot.
Do I screw things up?
Oh, yeah.
Seriously? I mean, you know
what I'm asking, right?
Absolutely,
and the answer is yes.
When things get difficult
or scary in a relationship,
you screw it up.
Y--well, you said
to be honest.
I was just coming to tell you
how beautiful you look.
You knew about Susan.
She's sick,
and you discharged her anyway.
She wanted to be here
with your mother.
Yeah? Well, she should be
back at the hospital
where we could help her,
and hopefully
give them more than this.
That's not
what Susan asked for.
Addison...
It's time, dear.
♪♪♪
Thank you, dear.
Mm.
Well, you did it.
Actually, you did it.
The wedding was lovely,
Addison.
You think
we're ever gonna do this,
actually get married?
I do.
Me, too.
Hmm.
Just don't ask me when.
I wasn't going to.
You're not gonna believe
what...
I think bizzy
just thanked me.
Wow. Well, congratulations.
Yes.
Sam...
I was scared.
I am... scared.
Of what?
Of us.
Of us not working, of me not
giving it a chance, everything.
I don't want to ruin it,
not with you.
So instead,
you asked me to marry you?
I...
Yeah.
You know,
you could take it back.
No. I don't want--
Addison...
You can take it back.
Okay. I take it back.
Okay.
Let's drop!
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ come on ♪
♪ Shake, shake ♪
♪ I'll take you home ♪
What happened with Larry
is not your fault.
I know.
But I should've
seen it coming.
We can't always see
what's closest to us.
He needs help.
I know.
Sheldon, he needs real help.
I can't do that.
If Larry were a patient--
he's not. He's my mentor
and my friend.
All the more reason.
He could lose his job
and his license.
It'll destroy him.
He's your mentor
and your friend.
♪ Will you move her
like that? ♪
♪ Come on, shake, shake,
shake, shake, a-shake it ♪
♪ shake, shake ♪
♪ shake, shake, a-shake it ♪
You okay?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine.
I, uh, was just thinking
about Abe.
Yeah, he's alienated Lisa,
and he's trying as hard
as he can to do the same to me.
Did you ever think that maybe
he just doesn't like you?
Well, I am
the pain-in-the-ass doctor,
so yeah.
Yeah.
It's Lisa, though.
He loves her
as much as he loved esty.
I think he's just scared
of being a burden.
Well,
sometimes fear makes...
You push away
the people you love.
♪ Now if she does it like this,
will you turn her like that? ♪
Sometimes it makes you try
to pull them even closer.
♪ Now if she moves like this,
will you move her like that? ♪
♪ Come on, shake, shake,
shake, shake, a-shake it ♪
Thank you.
♪ Shake, shake,
shake, shake, a-shake it ♪
Well...
Are you leaving?
Time to be
the pain-in-the-ass doctor.
♪ Shake, shake, a-shake it ♪
Hey. About before--
shh. Dance with me.
♪ Shake, shake, a-shake it ♪
♪ Shake, shake,
shake, shake, a-shake it ♪
♪ shake, shake,
Mind if I come in?
If I say yes,
you wouldn't listen.
May as well save my breath.
I'm not alone, Abe.
Hi, daddy.
Has it been
six months already?
Come on.
Don't be like that.
Like what?
Don't push her away.
She's not your enemy.
You love her.
She's family,
which means she's supposed
to be here, no matter what,
even if you say
you don't need her
or don't want her to know
that you do.
Ah, don't listen to him.
He's very dramatic.
I want you
to come live with me.
You'd hate it.
So would I.
I wouldn't.
And neither would Barry
or the boys. We'd love it.
No.
Why?
Did you tell her to sucker me
in to another rant?
No, sir.
But he did tell me what
you said, and you're right.
You've always been the help,
to mom and to me.
But now that can change.
I won't do that to you.
I can't.
Well, you know what?
I'm not asking.
She's not askin'.
Daddy, please.
Let me help.
Daddy.
Hey.
Too much champagne?
I was just going
to freshen up.
You kissed off
all my lipstick.
Sorry.
I wasn't complainin'.
I just wanted to get another one
in before you reapply.
I'll see you out there.
You okay?
I'm fine.
I'm really fine.
Should we get a room?
We don't need one.
♪ I may not always love you ♪
♪ but as long
as there are stars above you ♪
♪ you'll never need
to doubt it ♪
♪ I'll make you
so sure about it ♪
♪ god only knows
what I'd be without you ♪
Ah, Sheldon, come on in.
I'm cooking dinner.
I'm not hungry, Larry.
Hey, your loss.
I'm making carbonara sauce
from scratch.
You've had
a psychotic break.
Nonsense.
I-I had an off day.
Hey, but now that you're here,
all that's gonna change.
Now what are
you drinking, scotch or wine?
♪ ...I'd be without you ♪
I'm sorry, Larry.
You son of a bitch!
No, get off me!
Get off me! Ow!
Don't--don't fight them,
Larry.
Ow! How could you
do this to me?
Ah! Get off of me!
Hey, you're hurting him!
You need to stay back, sir.
Let us do our job.
I'm your friend!
♪ So what good
would living do me? ♪
♪ God only knows
what I'd be without you ♪
♪ god only knows ♪
♪ what I'd be without you ♪
♪ What I'd be without you ♪
I took it back.
My proposal.
You can do that?
I don't know.
But I did.
Oh.
I don't know.
Maybe you're right.
I hope not, but... I'm gonna
make it work with Sam.
I will.
♪ God only knows ♪
♪ what I'd be without you ♪
Are you gonna be okay?
♪♪♪
Yeah.
God,
what is wrong with me, Nai?
So many things.
Okay, look at them.
♪♪♪