If you don't know how to use a
computer, we will teach you here.
Most jobs require at least
basic word processing skills.
We try to get you up
to 50 words per minute.
We also have a course in how
to talk to someone in an interview.
Stuff like what
employers are looking for,
how to turn negatives
into positives.
We can also provide clothes
for the interview if you need them.
People donate shoes
and suits all the time.
What if I had a
history with drugs?
That is nothing
to be ashamed of.
Many of our clients have
struggled with addiction,
and if you want to get
clean, we'll help you do that.
And what if I have a kid?
No one to help you?
If I need someone to watch her
while I'm in a class or on an interview,
could you help with that?
We do not provide child care.
Actually, it's something
that comes up often.
I would love to
be able to do it.
I just don't have the resources.
But it's definitely
on the wish list.
Okay. Okay, uh,
thank you. I'll be back.
I have to take this.
Yes, please come back.
We'll get you started.
It was nice to meet
you, Benjamin.
Hey, Oscar.
Ugh! That is too bad.
Did they tell you why?
Yeah.
Mmm-hmm.
Well, look, you know what?
Sometimes you just don't get the job.
Oscar, I've got
to call you back.
Uh...
Uh, uh...
Benjamin! Benjamin, wait.
Oh, my God.
Somebody call an ambulance!
Why am I watching
you cut your hair?
If I do it at home, I'm the
one who has to clean it up.
I was referring less to where
it's happening and more to why.
New life, new look.
Does that mean you
like your new life?
If you're asking
if your job is safe,
that depends on what you have
to say about the file you're holding.
It doesn't seem
like much of a case.
Although, I'm sure I'm wrong.
You are. Tell me why.
Guy collapsed after
being on his feet for hours
on a hot day without
breakfast, so that's really weird.
ER found nothing wrong, then I
decided I should test his wallet.
He's rich? That's why
we're taking the case?
No, we're taking
the case because
no one knows
what's wrong with him.
And he's rich.
Dr. Adams.
Give her the file.
This is my only copy.
My MO depends
upon the use of a team.
Definitionally, that involves
more than one person,
so I really have no choice.
Give her the file. You
can't afford a team.
Adams is free.
And I'm referring both to her
availability and her price tag.
New girl meet newer
girl, and vice versa.
You said we were
meeting for coffee.
Well, when someone
asks if you want coffee,
they obviously don't
just mean coffee.
Wait. Did you think I
was referring to sex?
Would you shut the
blinds on your way out?
I thought you were
referring to talking.
Talking about medicine.
Specifically, as it refers to the
guy whose name is on the file
she still hasn't handed you.
I'm not working, House. I'm in the
process of looking for a paying job.
And in the meantime, there's
no way a do-gooder like you
isn't volunteering
all over town,
ladling kittens, spaying soup.
There's a free
clinic in Trenton.
Well, think of this
as today's free clinic.
Only with fewer
bums with herpes.
I don't think we actually
have much of a case.
I think it's just dehydration.
What happened the
last time another doctor
told you I was
wrong about a case?
I lost my job.
But you saved a life.
Is an ultrasound really necessary?
I'm feeling much better now.
A sudden collapse at
your age can indicate
a deterioration in
the heart muscle,
a pretty serious condition.
It could also just
be dehydration.
Next time, you could probably
drop the undercover act.
I walk in in a suit, and they're
gonna put their best foot forward.
Also I don't own a suit.
You give away millions,
and you don't own a suit?
I gave those away too.
One day I was writing a
check to my landscaper,
and it suddenly hit me,
$6,000 to take out plants
and put in different plants
so I can look at them.
Shouldn't I use that money
to do something important?
And by money, you
mean all your money.
I started with $10 million,
and then I couldn't think of
a reason not to give 20 or 40.
I figure I can live
on $25,000 a year.
One room apartment, bus pass,
thrift stores, bare necessities.
I still have my
software company.
And when I make more,
I'll give that away too.
He's nuts. He's generous.
There's a neurological issue.
He's getting rid of everything.
His echocardiogram was
negative for cardiomyopathy.
Head CT showed no signs
of stroke or hemorrhage.
He has one pair of pants!
Most people with
his kind of money
are commissioning oil
paintings of their Yorkshire terrier.
Benjamin is sacrificing his
own comfort to help others.
That's 'cause helping others
is his Yorkie oil painting.
That's good, not sick.
That's naive and sick.
You really want to improve
things, you do it through policy.
This guy empties his
pockets, what really changes?
That's right. All those babies
with AIDS, they're just using us.
My parents had $800 between
them when they got here.
They scraped and borrowed
so we could go to good schools.
And I worked my ass off.
No one gave me a handout.
It makes me work harder.
Rebuttal.
What's your evil plan?
I object to your cynicism.
It's been earned.
That's what I object to.
New Dean of Medicine has
an ethical obligation to come in
with a completely open
mind about all employees,
thus letting me blithely run
roughshod for at least four weeks.
My theory is that you're
running a battery of tests
to convince him that
you've saved his life,
and then con him into funding
you to hire back your team.
What? Your old team?
What? This is your new reality.
You've got your office,
you've got neighbors,
you've got one
employee, one volunteer
until she finds actual paid
work or gets sick of you.
I talked to Chase and Taub.
They're willing to come back.
What about Thirteen?
Not a good choice. She's not a
long-term, because she has no long-term.
Not taking your calls?
She will.
Discharge the patient.
Unexplained loss of consciousness
could be cardiomyopathy,
global anoxia,
subarachnoid hemorrhage...
Dehydration. He was given
fluids, and he got better.
And I'm sure your tests
have come up negative,
or you'd have
shut me up already.
Which means he goes home.
There is a symptom.
Extreme altruism.
You've got two choices, House.
You can recognize
that your patient is just
a very nice, healthy
guy and send him home.
Or you can consider
altruism a symptom,
in which case, you
cannot take his money.
Send him home.
And check with admitting for
the net worth of all new patients.
I'm not coming back, House.
Technically, you're
back right now.
I need you to stop calling me.
The first 17 messages
were cute, but...
I'm putting the
band back together.
Interesting that you've
never showed up at my place,
what with your
love of annoying me
and your inability to
take no for an answer.
I'm guessing ankle monitor.
Guilty as charged. Literally.
I'm not a doctor
any more, House.
The job went away
but not the profession.
You look healthy,
so that's not it.
You met a boy or a girl,
fallen in love, wanna be happy.
You've decided to enjoy
what time you have left.
You're going to Thailand.
Girl. And Mýkonos.
Turns out I like boring.
No, you want to like boring.
But if you actually
liked boring,
you would have figured that out
in fifth grade when you were bored.
Please, stop calling me.
No.
You showed up to tell me that
you don't want to hear from me.
That's a mixed signal.
And I'm gonna choose to listen to
your actions rather than your words,
'cause they're more honest.
I'm a little confused.
The test is designed to
determine if your nerves are...
No, I meant you're running
a test and discharging me?
Was I dehydrated or not?
I think so. But out of an
abundance of caution,
my colleague has taken it
upon herself to do one more test.
All right.
You scare me a little.
Why?
I've been considering applying
to Doctors Without Borders,
going overseas awhile,
and that seems like a
huge sacrifice, but you...
You don't scare her.
You make her feel guilty.
You like your
life the way it is.
Most people give the
minimum they have to give,
so they can enjoy
what they have left.
I guess my minimum
is just higher than most.
Complete recruitment
and interference pattern.
His leg muscles are fine.
I feel, uh, funny.
Where? My chest.
You're tachycardic. Your
heart's beating too fast.
Unbelievable.
Patient got tachycardic to 185.
We pushed 18
milligrams adenosine.
There's definitely
something wrong with him.
Which is awesome. Now,
there's something to cure,
which means there's
something to be
disproportionately
financially grateful for.
Morning. Got you coffee.
Thanks.
Arrhythmia could easily
have caused the collapse
that landed Father Teresa
here in the first place.
Oh, it's fine. Keep it.
We looked at his
heart yesterday.
Didn't see any
structural abnormalities.
I'm thinking occult
long QT syndrome?
What about Whipple's?
If it was Whipple's, there'd be some
kind of neurological involvement.
You don't think defying
human nature is neurological?
Racing heart, medical condition.
Bleeding heart,
stupid condition.
Are you saying that
because you believe it,
or because it's in your
financial best interests
to think his generosity
isn't just temporary?
I'm told that some
people are just nice.
I'm trying to
embrace that wisdom.
Benjamin's been taking allergy
medication the last few weeks.
Long QT syndrome can
be medication-induced.
Flush him with saline. Get
rid of the antihistamines.
Then do an EKG.
No, wait. I'll do the flushing.
And take the damn two dollars.
She hasn't even
sipped the coffee.
I just got so angry, you know?
So I made a terrible mistake,
and now, I'm trying
to start my life over.
To help people the
way I always wanted.
But my department got
defunded, and it's my fault.
I just can't stand to think of all
those patients going untreated
because I don't have the
resources to do my best work.
How about I help you out?
How do you mean?
I'll give a million dollars as
an endowment to the hospital
earmarked for Diagnostics.
Wow.
I'm an opportunistic ex-con who
just gave you a two-minute sob story
as step three in my master plan,
and you've offered
me a million dollars.
Which was step 17.
Is that bad?
Ethics are not my strong suit.
Hypothetical.
If I'm offered oral sex from a
sexaholic, do I have to decline?
Don't answer yet. Saying
"no" will cause both of us pain.
Saying "yes" will cause
both of us pleasure.
You can't take sex
from a sexaholic,
you can't give
booze to an alcoholic,
and you can't take
this guy's money.
I could be wrong about the
symptom. I'm wrong all the time.
Taking money from a sick
person is ethically suspect at best.
What is this? Canada? All we
do is take money from sick people.
We work for it.
I'm working.
How much?
$20.
Well, what if it was?
It's the same principle.
$20, a million,
what's the difference?
Actually, the difference is
pretty much a million dollars.
He came up with
the figure, not me.
Crap. Got a patient with
end-stage renal disease.
Her heart can't
support dialysis.
She needs a transplant but...
You tuned out as soon as it
stopped being about you, didn't you?
What? I got to go.
It's all moot. The patient
probably has long QT.
He's probably just a
really, really decent person.
They exist, right?
You can't take the money, House.
Is long QT bad?
It's a tough thing to control.
Is there someone
you want me to call?
There's someone
I would like to call.
She's the same person
who won't take my calls.
My wife.
When I started giving
away the money,
I hoped she'd want
to do it with me.
She didn't.
I miss them.
I have two little boys.
Having a family doesn't exempt
me from social responsibility.
But family comes first.
But should it?
I know that sounds weird.
But if someone
is related to you,
does that empirically
make them more special,
more deserving than anyone else?
Yes, it gives you
a responsibility.
My boys have a roof over
their heads. They're not starving.
I pay court-ordered
child support.
And frankly, it's
more than they need.
I love them more than anything.
I can't justify buying video
games and private schools
when other people's
children are starving.
I hope one day
they'll understand that.
Your hands are trembling.
Is it the electrodes?
Are you in pain?
No. What's happening?
I'm not sure, but it's not
what we thought it was.
So arrhythmia,
fainting, muscle tremors.
Plus unfortunately,
mental changes.
I still don't think
it's neurological.
God bless you.
He lost his wife and kids, 'cause
he couldn't stop giving money away.
He lost his wife, because she
couldn't accept not being filthy rich.
She's not drinking
the coffee either.
Drink it, don't drink it. The point
is I gave it to you, so we're even.
Even? It was a gift, an insignificant
token. There was nothing owed.
That was the whole point.
Why?
"Why?"
Yeah. Why?
She's the crazy one.
So a guy gives everything
away to strangers, sane.
Girl who doesn't want
anything from strangers, crazy?
You're not a stranger.
And your perverse
view of the world is
making you force a
neurological component
onto an obviously
cardiological...
Your parents didn't
love you enough,
so you need to
prove your superiority.
Or they loved you too much, so
you need to prove your humility.
Or it's just rich guilt. I'm
betting on the last one.
There's a whole list of drugs that
could have caused his symptoms.
I doubt the guy would
spend money on drugs
when there are orphans
out there without cable.
Anyway, he'd be getting
better right now, not worse.
Could be polyarteritis nodosa.
That comes with a rash.
Echovirus.
Virus, virus, virus...
Fits his physical symptoms.
And could, but doesn't necessarily,
cause personality changes.
Works for everyone?
Start him on antivirals.
And, Adams, when you treat,
and he gets better and doesn't
give Bob Cratchit Christmas Day off,
you owe me a coffee.
Click the third
tab from the left
and find a box that
says "previous entry."
You get a drop-down
menu that's sorted
by patient name and department.
Thank you. I
appreciate your help.
You're gonna read too
much into this, aren't you?
No. Not at all.
We're going to
fundamentally disagree
about what it means to read
too much into this, aren't we?
Yes, absolutely.
Look, I thought about what you
said, and I realized you were right.
Great. See you tomorrow morning.
No, you won't.
Afternoon? I can't think
of another interpretation.
Shut up. Look, I'm not sure
what you were trying to achieve.
I'm never quite
sure, but you were
actually a friend to
me when I needed it.
I don't want to come
back to work for you.
But I was wrong to try
to push you out of my life.
Everything has gone blue.
That's not supposed
to happen, right?
Stay there. I'm coming.
No, you don't have to do that.
Although if you did come, maybe
you could swing by the Hunan Palace
and get some Lo Mein
and a Szechuan Beef.
That is six miles out of my way.
Okay, then, I guess I'll just get
something from the hospital cafeteria,
which is where I get all of my
meals since I can't go anywhere.
Fine. I'll get the food.
You're a peach.
I started the last
round of pleconaril.
Can you do me a favor?
A favor?
You want me to return these?
Give them to someone? Wear
them while you masturbate?
I want you to have them.
That's not a favor.
It was a two-for-one sale. I couldn't
resist. I need to justify buying them.
They're $120.
My car's in the shop. I'm
short on cash this month.
I can't pay you back.
The first pair were
$120. These were free.
You do know I punched the
last person that pissed me off?
Was it Santa?
What's your patient's status?
Better. We're discharging him.
Good.
Hey, hey. Why do you care?
Specifically. Although, I'm
curious about a general answer too.
Your guy just signed up to donate a
kidney to my patient with renal failure.
Did he meet your
patient with renal failure?
No. He heard the nurses talking
about her, that she was short on time.
I was wrong.
Don't say that. House,
she really needs this kidney.
He's not better. His
mental status is declining.
Or he's doing an amazing
thing for another human being.
I thought it was an
ethical no-brainer
that we can't take
stuff from sick people.
I changed my mind.
He's still sick.
His symptoms have gone away.
Not all of them. Offering an
organ to a stranger is a symptom.
A couple dozen people a year
make undirected kidney donations.
How many of them are also in the
process of pauperizing themselves?
If the guy threw himself on
a grenade, he'd be a hero.
If it saves a life, who cares?
You do. Yesterday when you
made the exact opposite argument.
If there's even a
chance I'm right,
it'd be dangerous to give
his kidney to someone else.
More dangerous than complete
renal failure? My patient needs this now.
Why do you want to
give away your kidney?
There are 70,000
people in this country
on the active waiting
list for a kidney,
and less than 10,000 dead
people a year to give them one.
Yeah, if only we could kill
60,000 more people a year,
all would be golden.
I'll give you your money.
See? Crazy.
Being a live donor has risks.
I looked it up. The risk is one in
4,000. I could die during surgery.
Which means if I don't donate,
I'm valuing my life at
4,000 times someone else's.
It's not like I want
to be cut open
and have a part of me taken out,
but I've got two, and this woman
has none. She'll die without it.
Perfectly logical.
People with mental
deficiency can be logical.
Just like sane
people can be illogical.
This kidney thing is the only
evidence you have that he's sick.
I'm going to let him be a donor.
Dr. House, it's not a symptom.
Come back after you're
convinced that I'm healthy,
and I will give you your money.
No, you won't.
We have time for one more
test before we move him.
What test?
Whatever test will prove
that it wasn't echovirus...
Virus, virus... And he's
not cured, obviously.
I've been saying all along
this could be Whipple's.
Causes arrhythmia,
tremor and mental changes.
Bad idea. There's no joint pain.
Where's Adams?
We thought the case was over.
She has a job interview.
Why is she here?
Because I called her.
Bigger question
is why that worked.
I'm here because I have time,
and you have a crisis and...
We're too busy
for rationalizations.
Patient made a big
downgrade in his personal life.
He's probably not
eating all that healthy.
Magnesium deficiency?
Wait until they take him
back to his room, draw blood,
and do an expanded
electrolyte profile.
No, he hasn't had anxiety
or any trouble sleeping.
I think it's Whipple's disease.
Bad idea. He doesn't
have joint pain.
Joint pain is common
but not definitive.
Whipple's explains
all of his symptoms
including the
personality change.
And it would
respond to antibiotics,
which is why he
started to feel better,
which doesn't mean
he's not still sick.
You were right. Counts for
nothing if you can't defend it.
Book a procedure room,
do an upper endoscopy,
and run a PCR
test for Whipple's.
Guilt.
You feel guilty about leaving.
Yes, I think that little of
you and that much of me.
You're nothing without me.
Not leaving me,
leaving humanity.
I'm going with my
girlfriend, the woman I love.
To have fun.
You're trying to
make me feel guilty,
because you're
saving lives here.
I think that's great. I'm
proud to have been a part of it.
But now, I just
want to be happy.
Well, no one's
unhappy in Greece.
It just appeared in
the last few weeks.
He's having trouble
holding a pencil in school.
Does it itch?
Get anything different lately,
new baseball glove, new kitten?
The neighbors put in a pool,
so he's been spending
a lot of time over there.
But if it were
something in the water
it would be
everywhere, wouldn't it?
It is in the water.
He's allergic to chlorine?
No.
He's allergic to Summer Lilac.
That's my lotion,
and it's not in the pool.
No, it's on the
palms of his hands.
In the pool, is the
neighbor's daughter
or the neighbor's hot wife.
Here's some lube.
Sorry. Too late
for your eyesight.
Endoscopy didn't reveal any
lesions in the small intestine.
I'm running the PCR test now.
I found it in my office.
Appears to be a gift.
That can't be good.
Damn it.
You got her the job interview.
And that was supposed to be
the end of it. I don't take charity.
Good for you, you loon.
I don't like owing
people things.
So either you're so insecure
that you feel like you need to
always have the upper hand,
or you're so arrogant that the
notion of a favor is insulting to you.
Or it's your family, some
kind of immigrant pride thing.
I'm betting on the last one.
I just don't like it. It
makes me feel icky.
That's the reason? Ickiness?
You never even
tried to analyze this?
That's even crazier
than the gift thing.
House. There's no
sign of tropheryma DNA.
It's not Whipple's.
We did what we could.
You sure you want to do this?
Relax. This is gonna
make me very happy.
Dr. Simpson, heart rate's
140, and pressure's dropping.
Get him adenosine, stat.
Patient's unstable.
Surgery's off.
Arrhythmia's back. He's on
heparin and stable for now,
but this could put him at
risk for stroke or embolism.
Maybe he got bit by a spider.
The symptoms can take
up to three days to manifest.
He'd have localized pain.
LCDD.
Almost always hits the kidneys.
Ah, Dr. Foreman,
perhaps you can help us.
I can't decide
whether to take out an
I-told-you-so ad in the
New England Journal,
or stay classy and just
spray-paint it on your car.
You're off the case.
That seems like an overreaction.
You dosed him. You couldn't
stand losing him as a patient,
so you faked a symptom
to prove yourself right.
That's idiotic.
Sorry. HOUSE: Don't apologize.
I don't know if
you're power-crazed
or paranoid, but I
know she's right.
Two lives are in
the balance here.
House, I worked for you for seven
years. I know how you operate.
So when I see symptoms magically
show up right when you need them...
And I was your
boss for seven years,
and I know what a suspicious,
micromanaging hard-ass you are.
Why would I do this now, knowing
you can send me right back to jail?
What did you give him?
Nothing.
You can't prove otherwise.
So why don't you do
the smart thing here?
You're off the case. You no
longer have access to this patient.
You can't let him do this.
He's the boss.
And he's right.
I assume you dosed the patient
because you're really certain
he has a neurological condition.
I assume you're interpreting my
actions in the best possible light
because you didn't get the job.
What's with you and Park?
Nothing.
I expect my people
to lie better than that.
Either you're getting her gifts
because you want
her to like you,
in which case, I don't like you.
Or you're getting her
gifts to screw with her,
in which case, I will be teaching
you my secret homie handshake.
I just... I thought
it was interesting
she couldn't accept that coffee,
and I wanted to see
how deep it went.
But now?
Oh, now, I just wanna win.
What was in the box?
Gift certificate. The spa.
That's not going to do it. You're
up against a lifetime of training.
If you wanna win,
you've got to do
something she can't
possibly reciprocate.
You've got to push her
neuroses to the point
where even she
thinks that she's crazy.
One more favor, and I promise
I'll leave you alone forever.
Or I'm lying.
Either way, it's more interesting
than whatever you're doing now.
Can I help you?
I'm his wife.
We're separated.
I heard he was sick. I
just wanted to see him.
He's giving a kidney to
someone he's never met?
He wants to, yeah.
I know he's talked about you.
He's been alone all this time.
I'm sure it would mean
a lot to him to see you.
I wanted to spend
my life with him,
but I need to feel like he loves
me more than other people.
Like he loves our kids more.
Maybe that's selfish.
I should go.
Was that my wife?
I don't know.
Are you the guy,
the kidney donor?
There was a problem,
but I'm gonna try again.
Um...
To give it to the same lady?
She needs it.
Okay. Never mind.
Wait.
What do you want?
Uh, it's nothing. It's just...
I have polycystic kidney
disease, and I need a transplant,
and they say I don't
have much time.
So when I heard that
you were willing, I just...
But I'm glad it's
going to someone.
I'll give it to you.
But you already promised
it to someone else.
I have another one.
Saving one life is good,
saving two is better.
You give away two
kidneys, and you die.
I could live on
dialysis for years.
Yes, and then you die.
And then I could donate
my other organs, heart, lungs.
I could save four
or five more lives.
Foreman's going to
need a diagnostician.
This guy is crazy.
Arrhythmia, muscle tremors,
and yes, mental changes.
If his heart doesn't rupture, he's
liable to rip it out and give it away.
You know, the
down vibe in here is
totally ruining my
Charlie's Angels fantasy.
And that haircut
isn't helping, either.
Seems like Graves disease
or some other thyroid issue.
Is she on the team
now, like, forever?
His thyroid levels were within
normal range when he was admitted.
Could be Coxsackie B virus.
No pericarditis.
What about porphyria? It's
a little weird without the rash,
but it fits all of his
other symptoms.
And if it's acute
intermittent porphyria,
that would explain why his
symptoms keep recurring.
Unlikely, but it's
possible. What else?
I said, "What else?"
Oh, for crying out loud.
There, that's better.
Now, what else?
Well, if there's nothing
better than possible,
then possible gets
upgraded to probable.
I'll start him on hematin.
No, I'll go.
So what's the answer?
Are you now on the
team, like, forever?
I don't know.
Because I was thinking
of ordering t-shirts.
I don't know, House. I mean,
what am I supposed to do?
I trained to be a doctor. I know
how to take someone's pain away,
how to make a stopped
heart beat again.
We've brought people's
kids back, their husbands.
So guilt?
Yes, you were right.
You're always right. I just...
I have the skills
to help people.
Is it okay for me to walk away from
that because I wanna just have fun?
Obviously not.
How's your patient?
She died a few hours ago.
Thirteen's back.
No department, no money,
and somehow, you manage
to con her into hanging around.
I have a gift.
What?
It was a con.
The patient was faking?
No, I was.
I brought him in here under false
pretenses just to get his money.
I ordered a bunch of random
tests to keep him here.
One of them was a head
CT which uses iodine contrast.
You think he's
allergic to iodine?
No. Again.
Just don't interrupt me.
Thirteen was right.
This is a thyroid issue.
He has Plummer's disease.
He has a nodule in his thyroid.
It produces excess hormone.
Not enough to test abnormal, just
more than his brain was used to.
Just enough to make
him irrationally generous,
make him vulnerable
to overheating.
Then you pumped
his body full of iodine
and kicked him
into thyrotoxicosis.
I said don't interrupt.
But yes, you're right. We take
out the nodule. He'll be fine.
Two days, one surgery.
I now accept that
you are all better.
Where's my money?
You made me sick.
You were already sick. I just
made you much, much worse.
Seriously, the money.
You're not giving
it to me, are you?
When you're facing death,
some things come into focus...
My wife...
You love your family.
You want them back.
Your altruism was
always a symptom.
No, it wasn't.
I'm still gonna...
Give less? How much less?
Just enough to spoil your kids?
No.
But they need it more
than people with TB
or children in
Indonesia with no eyes?
Diagnosticians
with hearts of gold?
I don't want to give you
money because you're an ass.
I was an ass last week.
I love my family. I
want to be with them.
That doesn't make
me a bad person.
No.
It makes you a healthy person.
My mechanic called. Said
the work's been paid for.
You mentioned your
car was in the shop.
That's $4,500.
Smile and say thank
you, or I get you GPS.
You win.
Thank you.
Your car's getting fixed.
You were right. She went for it.
Good work.
Need a lift tomorrow?
Your car's still in the shop.
I don't take charity.
I'm just glad it's over.
Nothing is ever over.
Thirteen.
Need a minute.
You're fired.
Now what? House, I'm starving...
I'm not joking.
You're fired. Don't
come in tomorrow.
House...
I can work with people
who've got nowhere else to go,
people who've got
something to prove,
people who just get
off on weird cases.
Who I can't work with
is someone who's here
so she doesn't have to feel bad.
You're trying to save me.
Yes, I think that little of
you and that much of me.
Okay.
Bye, House.