It's almost 11:00. She needs
a lot of sleep these days.
Please, Mrs. Bardach, I
haven't seen her for a week.
I'll see how she's
feeling. Thank you.
You know what to do.
All done? Yeah.
I scrubbed for 45 seconds,
did the nails, all the way down
to the elbows, the whole deal.
Are you sick? No. No, no.
Cough? No.
Sore throat? No,
no. I just, I just...
Sometimes I sneeze when I
look at lights. I always have.
I'm sorry, you better... I would
never get her sick. Please.
A mask.
Got me by the
bouncer. She's crazy.
She's let me out like six
times in the last two months.
Every time's just to go to
the hospital. I'm a prisoner.
It's okay.
It's ugly. No.
I wasn't looking at
the scar anyways.
Take off your mask.
If your mom comes
in here, she...
Hey. Give me a
kiss or I'll kill you.
Your skin... Are you okay?
Melinda, can you...
What's wrong? What's
wrong? Can you breathe?
wrong? Is it your heart?
What's wrong? Mrs. Bardach!
Melinda, Melinda, I don't
know how to use this.
I've never used
one of these before.
What did you do to her?
Cuddy called.
I know. I saw the caller ID.
Young girl, anaphylactic shock.
You answered?
Turns out, that's
what stops the ringing.
It's a weird case.
I thought you did the dishes
last night? It was your day.
I did. Those are
new. Midnight snack.
For a midnight snack,
you made a pot roast,
the same pot roast
I made last night.
Yeah.
Actually, it was after midnight.
Today's your day, right?
You want me out
of here. I get it.
No, it's fine if you stay.
The place I was gonna move,
the guy never called.
Otherwise I'd already be there.
I said it's fine if
you stay. Yeah.
That's why you're
making me miserable.
Maybe I just wanna make sure
you do your fair share around here.
That... What's weird about it?
The girl with the allergies.
Yeah.
She's immunocompromised.
What are you doing?
What? You asked me... You
knew that I was interested.
That gives you a
valuable bargaining chip.
You could've had me
doing dishes for a week.
Okay.
The allergic reaction happened
while she was in a clean room.
Why does she have a
clean room in her home?
Heart transplant. Immune
system's in the toilet.
So Mommy builds her little angel
a John Travolta-quality bubble.
Six months after the transplant.
She doesn't need to be
confined to a clean room.
Six months without putting out,
Dr. Cuddy doesn't need to wear
thong panties, but it's not our call.
I was wondering when you'd
get around to my panties.
She's had four days of workups.
They've tested everyone who
came anywhere near that room,
everything in the room.
It's like an Agatha
Christie mystery.
Maybe it's not what was
there, it's what she was doing.
Exercise allergy. Love it.
What sort of exercise
could a strapping young man
and a nubile teenage
nymphet possibly...
Mom was in the
room within seconds.
So the boyfriend brought in
an allergen and is lying about it.
Or the girl snuck out,
and she's lying about that.
Or the parents are lying
about the room being clean.
These are your big
ideas? Somebody's lying?
Hasn't let me down yet.
Recheck Mom, Dad, the girl,
the boy, the room and the home.
Any of you have a new
soap, a detergent, perfume?
No, no. Barbara's really
careful about that stuff.
And you haven't
been outside recently?
How could I? I'm
trapped up there.
You're not trapped.
It's just safer...
They won't even tell me the alarm code.
Just tell her I can go back to school.
Until we clear this up...
Fine. Find out what I'm allergic
to, and I'll stay away from it.
Then I can go back
to school, right?
It's up to your parents, but,
medically, there's no reason...
Told you.
Could I speak to you
outside for a second, please?
You know, this is hard
enough without you in there...
She asked me my opinion.
She is 16 years old. Lie to her.
When I was eight,
my mom, she hated...
I know. I need to loosen
up. I'm overprotective.
I saw Finding Nemo. I get
it. I don't need another story.
But you're not just
being overprotective.
You're one of the most
overprotective parents I've ever seen.
She has the best private
tutors. I let her friends visit.
I'm not going to apologize.
Just giving you my thoughts.
She almost died three
times during her childhood.
Penicillin, bee stings,
peanuts. I've seen her file.
Six months ago, we leave her home
alone for the first time on a weekend.
She goes out, buys one chocolate
chip cookie. Peanut butter in the dough.
She's forgotten her EpiPen.
She drives to the hospital,
passes out, has an accident.
Steering wheel crushed her chest.
She ended up losing her heart.
So when you say to me that
I'm one of the most overprotective
parents you've seen, please,
please introduce me to the
ones who were more protective
so that I can find out
what they're doing right.
She's allergic to having
a sucky social life.
Give the parents a break. They're
just trying to keep her healthy.
Everything in here's
labeled "Hypoallergenic."
Check it anyway.
Cameron.
This place is cleaner
than her hospital room.
No alarm on this window.
That's a 20-foot drop.
You can get to the tree from
here. There's some bark scraped off.
Sure, heart-transplant girl
swung down there on a vine.
Maybe she was hooking
up with Tarzan and Cheetah
down by the elephant graveyard.
Or Jane stayed in the tree
house, and Tarzan came up.
Okay, I spent most
of the night, Friday.
But if her mom finds out
about that, she will totally freak.
You guys had sex?
Yeah, but, you know, I did everything I
could to make sure she wouldn't get sick.
Latex allergy?
What do you mean, like
a condom? We didn't...
You had unsafe sex?
The whole "unsafe" thing
didn't tell you something?
Yeah, but, I mean, look. We didn't,
like, plan on it, you know? It just...
I don't know. We're in love.
We've been dating for two years.
Practically a lifetime. How
about a semen allergy?
We're gonna need a semen sample.
You can use the
bathroom over there.
Right. How do
I... Aim and shoot.
And no thinking about
Dr. Cameron. We'll know.
We should tell her parents.
Why stop there? Call the cops.
Melinda's a minor.
And if we nip it in the bud here,
teenagers will never again have sex.
The parents will find out
when they get the bill anyway.
So you're fine with them finding
out as long as you don't have
to tell them
personally? Pretty much.
Too bad it's not you giving the
sample. We'd be done by now.
Test was negative.
No semen allergy.
Boyfriend sneaks in to get his freak
on the night before the anaphylaxis.
I don't buy that it's
unrelated. He loves her.
He did everything he could to
make sure she wouldn't get sick.
What does that mean?
Love is an emotion certain people
experience, similar to happiness.
No. Maybe I should give
a more relatable example.
Oh, snap.
What did he do to protect her,
Brillo Pad his privates?
I assumed he washed
and he... Oh, good work.
Assumptions are so much
faster than actual questions.
You the boyfriend?
I need to borrow you.
What is going on?
Don't worry. I'll return him in
roughly the same condition.
Did you take anything to stay healthy?
Something stronger than an apple a day?
Is he okay?
He's just tired from being in a
coma so long. What'd you take?
Don't worry. He can
keep a secret. Right...
Antibiotics? Penicillin?
Any of those names ring a bell?
Yeah. My friend Elliot, his
dad had, like, a whole bottle that
he hadn't finished, so I swiped it
and took a bunch for, like, a week.
I mean, there's no way I was gonna
risk breathing germs on Melinda.
This is the one downside
of teenage sex. You're idiots.
You almost killed your girlfriend.
She's allergic to penicillin.
What, do you think there was still
some on my lips? I brushed my teeth.
Think lower and more fun.
I mean, it can go
through your stuff?
Totally, dude.
There's this administrator here,
whenever she gets sick, she
just gives me the prescription.
But, you know,
they tested Melinda.
They said she wasn't
allergic to my stuff.
Yeah, four days later.
By that time the penicillin
was crusting up a sock
at the bottom of your hamper.
Do you have to tell
her it was my fault?
No.
Great part of being a grownup,
you never have to do anything.
You're releasing her? What
happened? What did you find out?
Tests on your house ruled
out any environmental allergens.
Yeah, but what caused this?
We believe it's highly unlikely
that this set of circumstances
will repeat itself. What
set of circumstances?
It's good news. She's healthy.
But you might wanna talk to...
Cameron!
I can't breathe.
Getting the epi.
Give her the shot!
No murmurs, no friction rubs...
What are you waiting for? Quiet.
She's coughing up white sputum.
Crackling two-thirds
of the way up.
Look at her neck.
Please, she is vomiting.
Would you give her the shot?
It's not an allergy.
It's her heart.
What's the good news?
What's the bad news?
Congestive heart failure.
Is which?
Good news. Why?
I don't know. It just
sounded like you.
New puzzle piece, always
good news. What's the bad news?
We've got two puzzle pieces
from two different puzzles.
Seems that way.
What if her anaphylaxis
wasn't anaphylaxis?
Toxicity from the anti-rejection
meds could cause a seizure
and then heart failure.
And get cured by a mommy-wielded
EpiPen? It's anaphylaxis. What else?
What if they really
are two puzzles?
You think she had two unrelated
rare conditions in one week?
We explained the anaphylaxis.
What do you mean "we"? I did.
At least I thought I
did. Maybe I didn't.
Still, it was all me.
And heart problems aren't so rare for
someone who's had a heart transplant.
I say we assume House was
right about the anaphylaxis.
It is tempting.
Heart failure could be either
infection, coronary disease, or rejection.
Sorry.
There's a reason they call it
the whiteboard. It's not my rule.
What ties both these
conditions together?
Okay, we can all stare at
each other, or we can investigate
what caused the heart
failure. Just the heart failure.
You wanna give me
that black marker?
There's no fever, so
it's probably not infection.
Or no fever because she's
been on immunosuppressants
for the last six months.
Let's do a CT, get a heart
biopsy, and then redo...
- Anything?
- Not yet.
So I hear you don't want
teenagers having sex.
Teen suicide rate isn't
high enough for you already?
I just think those
two are brats.
The girl undercuts her
mother any chance she gets.
Yeah, it's the daughter's fault.
It has nothing to do
with Mom infantilizing her.
Good point. Explains why
parents who don't pay attention
get such nice,
well-adjusted children.
What's this?
You think it's vegetation? Yeah.
The kind made of muscle
that opens your heart valves.
It's nothing. She's clean.
It's good news.
You don't show any signs
of coronary artery disease.
So what's next?
Well, blood work to rule out infection,
and then a heart surgical biopsy
to rule out rejection.
But you don't think you're gonna
rule out both things, do you?
No.
I'm gonna lose
this heart, right?
Hopefully we'll find
the problem and fix it.
You'll keep your heart
a long time. How long?
There could be drug breakthroughs
that allow you to keep it for decades more.
Yeah. That's the answer my
cardiologist always gives me.
I looked it up on the web.
It's like five or 10 years, right?
That's about the average.
That's why I
need to have a life.
Why can't you convince my
mom to let me go back to school?
Melinda, you've got bigger worries
right now than missing school.
Until we figure out what's
wrong with your heart,
the safest place for
you to be is right here.
Where's
the hooker, I assume?
Right up here, buddy.
You said you'd hang the
stethoscope if you were having sex.
I didn't say it had to
be with another person.
Can you think of anything
that would tie together
anaphylaxis and heart failure?
No. I was waiting
out there for hours!
Yeah, well, I need a lot of foreplay.
And then there's the cuddling afterwards.
Any way that anaphylaxis isn't
anaphylaxis even if it responds to epi?
No. Oh, no wonder
you were in the mood.
This month's New Jersey
Journal of Cardiology.
Have you seen the centerfold?
There's no way those valves are real.
Any chance that the heart
failure could be unrelated to...
No. If you need time alone to
work, you just have to say so.
You don't have to lie
about it. Lying's more fun.
Being lied to...
Not as much fun.
Please have an answer to
this question. What's for dinner?
You still haven't
done the dishes?
You want one of these? I think
I got a couple of blueberries.
Oh, nope. Sorry, just one.
Well, don't look all weepy.
You got a problem with me, deal
with it. Short my sheets or something.
Biopsy was negative
for rejection. Thank God.
And what about the blood
tests? Showed no infection.
So we still don't know what
caused her heart failure.
Let's just be happy she
doesn't need a new heart.
Mrs. Bardach, it could have
just been a one-time thing.
So she has an allergic
reaction and heart failure,
and neither of them
can be explained.
Are they doing any
more tests on her? No.
She's not here.
Notify local hospitals, cab companies,
the state troopers, and local cops.
Any security officers
off duty are back on duty.
We're on it.
And I'm gonna need some pictures.
And go through those drawers.
And I want at least two people
going over the surveillance tapes.
Will that work?
Are those all her clothes? Yeah.
She's obviously still in the
building. So where did she go?
What does she want?
See her boyfriend?
She didn't take her phone.
She wants to be outside.
If you're trying to scare
your parents, great job.
Can we go back now?
I hate her.
When I was eight
years old, I was sick.
Not really sick, but the
point is, my mom, she could...
She was like this before.
Home by 9:00 every night.
Can't go out on the
weekends. Can't do sports.
Transplant just gave her
what she always wanted.
Melinda, you had heart failure.
This is kind of an insane
time to be criticizing your mom
about being overprotective.
I know. I mean, this is
what makes it even worse.
All of her craziness, it just...
It makes sense now.
Everything's gonna be all right.
I didn't even try
to get outside.
I was too scared. Come on.
Whoa, whoa, Melinda.
Please walk back towards me.
Why?
Please.
It feels kind of weird.
It's called steppage gait.
Is it serious? Not necessarily.
All right. Stick your
leg out. Hold it up.
She was under anesthesia for
the biopsy. If she lost oxygen...
CT ruled out brain damage.
Put your leg down. Relax.
Why is her leg
twitching like that?
Fasciculation. Is that serious?
It's paralysis,
and it's ascending.
She's gonna lose
the use of her legs?
To start with.
It's ascending fast. She can
hardly extend her leg now.
At this rate, it'll be up to
her lungs in a matter of days.
So, anaphylaxis,
heart failure, paralysis.
We couldn't put the first two together. I'm
guessing we can't put all three together.
Tick paralysis?
Could also explain the
anaphylaxis, maybe even the...
Penicillin allergy explains the
allergic reaction much better.
Particularly because tick paralysis
is usually accompanied by a tick.
We did two comprehensive
physicals looking for insect bites.
Can we put any two
of those together?
How about we stipulate?
You argued that there must be
something to connect all three symptoms
you mocked us for
not figuring it out,
and finally you let us discuss
the paralysis on its own
because it's what's
gonna kill her.
Now, it's ascending. Her MRIs are
clean, so rule out stroke or aneurysm.
- ALS, MS?
- Progression's too quick.
Spinal lesion from
leukemia? Too slow.
- It's most likely Guillain Barré.
- She's immunosuppressed.
What about botulism?
Not unless she's been walking on
her hands the last couple of days.
Botulism paralysis is
descending, not ascending.
Could be a virus. West Nile, even
polio with her immune system shot.
Get an LP and do
PCRs for the viruses.
And get an EMG to
check for Guillain Barré.
Foreman's right. We gotta
find out why she's paralyzed.
But not before staring at
me dumbly for a few seconds.
We ran more tests
on your daughter.
We took a lumbar puncture,
got some spinal fluid.
Then we brought it to the
lab to look for infections
that could be
infecting her brain.
We also did an EMG to check
how her muscles and nerves
are responding to
electrical impulses.
Unfortunately, her muscles are showing
increased weakness above the knee.
You mean she's getting worse?
The LP and PCRs ruled
out polio and West Nile.
We think it's Guillain Barré.
The body's immune
response goes haywire
and starts attacking
the peripheral nerves.
It causes muscle
weakness and paralysis.
How bad is it?
It's serious, but Guillain Barré
usually responds very well
to plasmapheresis.
You see, the plasma, the
clear liquid part of her blood,
contains most of the
antibodies which are overreacting
and attacking her
nervous system.
The machine spins
her blood in a centrifuge
and separates parts of
the blood based on weight.
White blood cells are the
heaviest, then the red cells,
then platelets and plasma.
We discard the stuff
that's causing all the trouble
and return the good blood cells
back to her body in a replacement fluid.
If it works, we'll see
results in a couple of days.
You didn't get any messages
for me last week, did you?
Nope.
That's funny. The
guy finally called back.
The place I lost, he said
he left three voicemails.
Gotta pee. Which I never
got, if that wasn't clear.
He must be lying. You
wouldn't want to live with a liar.
You erased my messages? Yep.
Decided I wanted you to
stay. Told you that, didn't I?
You're miserable, and you're
lonely, and you're gonna trap me here
to keep me every bit as
miserable and lonely, too.
Yeah, and you're
happy, happy, happy.
Okay. Hey, I'm obviously going
through a rough patch here.
Wife leaves, tends
to bum somebody out.
Do you know where my pee went?
You're missing some?
No. Came out of me and went right
into the toilet. Now, why would that be?
You're William Tell.
You could pick an apple
off someone's head?
No, it's because there was no
clear plastic wrap over the toilet.
The stuff's in the kitchen.
You had plenty of time.
All that was missing was the
will. This isn't a college dorm.
It could be.
We're not 18!
So what? What did I do to you? I
scammed you into doing the dishes,
I made you sit on the
steps. I didn't kill your puppy.
I did not make you miserable.
Oh, so this is therapy?
No, it just makes me smile.
All right. I'm finding a
new place tomorrow.
Right. But not tonight.
Well, I figure you wanna shave
my eyebrows while I'm asleep.
I wouldn't wanna deprive
you of that last smile.
You're not going anywhere.
You're gonna sit on my
couch and depress us both
because you just can't admit
that it's over with your wife.
That's right. I'm
here on vacation.
Have you gotten a lawyer yet?
That... That's not... Have
you even called one?
As long as you're
here, it's just a fight.
But as soon as you get a
place, then it's a divorce.
Everything sucks.
Might as well find
something to smile about.
Reflexes are marginally weaker.
The paralysis is getting worse?
Sometimes it takes a few treatments
for the plasmapheresis to work.
Why do these things
keep happening to me?
Dan's back.
Hey, baby, did you
hear that? Dan's here.
I don't wanna see him.
I'll tell him to come
back later. No.
Mommy, stay here, please.
Of course.
Is she doing okay?
She's sleeping.
I'm sure she's exhausted.
Mood swings are common
with the anti-rejection meds.
No. She's had mood
swings. This isn't it.
This is... She's given up.
I know you think I'm...
This isn't what I wanted.
She's always fought with me.
Ever since she was a baby,
she was so damn stubborn.
But I never
wanted her like this.
I just wanted her safe.
LEWIS: Doctor! Doctor!
She can't breathe. She can't
even get a whole sentence out.
She's using the
accessory muscles.
O2 sat's down to 90.
Lungs clear? Yeah.
Does your tongue feel
swollen? I can't... no...
Is it itchy? FOREMAN: No hives.
It's not an allergy.
Lips are cyanotic.
We've got to intubate.
What are you doing?
Pushing lorazepam.
She's not getting enough oxygen.
We've gotta assist her breathing.
What was that? Was that
a reaction to the treatment?
It's the paralysis.
It's reached her lungs.
Melinda's dying.
We're all dying. How fast?
Too fast for Guillain Barré.
Cuddy wants to get her an
MRI to rule out a spinal lesion.
Cuddy? What's she doing on this?
The family lost
confidence in us.
I don't blame
them. I'll be right in.
It's like she got poisoned
with a nerve agent.
Glue inhalation. Would explain
why she hasn't admitted it.
Tox screen was clear for pot.
Middle-class heart transplant
patient's gonna huff glue?
Pesticides? CAMERON: This
time of year, they're not spraying.
This girl's tough. She
gets what she wants.
She's deprived of human contact.
She gets herself a backdoor man.
Or in her case, a side-window boy.
What else has she been deprived of?
She's on a special diet
because of her allergies.
The boyfriend brings the hot beef.
He also brings a side dish, botulism.
This paralysis is
ascending, remember?
Not if the heart problem's
really a paralytic problem.
Why would she admit
the sex and not the food?
She didn't admit anything.
He admitted the sex, and
we didn't ask him about food.
Get me a rat. You have a rat.
What? I'm not gonna kill Steve.
Only way to confirm this,
inject a rat with her blood
and wait for it to get
all botulistic on your ass.
In the meantime, I'm going downstairs
to browbeat a scared dying teenage girl
until she breaks down like
a scared dying teenage girl.
You're up early. Cuddy
needed a consult.
We're checking for spinal
lesions from leukemia.
Yeah, I know. Fits perfectly.
Unless this is the patient with
the anaphylaxis, the heart failure,
and the paralysis, in which
case, you're wasting your time.
We wanted a second opinion.
Second? We must have
given you at least eight.
Okay, well, here's
nine. Botulism.
Listen to me, have you
eaten anything abnormal?
Any canned foods? No.
You sure?
Lying to your parents is
usually the right thing to do,
but there is an impending
death exception.
Don't talk to her like that.
You're right. She never
lies. I was being rude.
When your boyfriend snuck
in on Friday night... Surprise.
Perhaps he got you
some sexy little treats, huh?
Some honey or some edible underwear,
some massage oils. Come on, anything.
We didn't... Yeah, yeah.
We know about the sex.
Turns out that Danny's
little Danny is full of penicillin.
That's what caused
your anaphylactic shock.
You didn't tell us
that was what...
No. It was... He took
clindamycin, what I use...
He said he was on penicillin.
I saw the bottle. That's
a non-penicillin antibiotic.
If the antibiotics didn't
cause the anaphylaxis...
It's still on the table.
Everything is connected.
What did we discuss?
What was the differential?
Cameron said...
When Dan came to your house that
night, he go through any tall grass?
Climbed a fence.
What are you doing?
Your daughter had two
visitors on Friday night.
One of them is still in the
room. She has tick paralysis.
Dan tracked a tick onto his
jeans, which wouldn't be a problem.
But being a teenager, Dan
couldn't keep his tick in his pants.
We already checked her.
Now I'm checking her.
Tick bites don't ordinarily
cause anaphylactic shock.
This girl's allergies
are not ordinary.
House, get out of here.
We have to re-intubate her,
get her into the MRI.
The time course is perfect.
The bite itself sets off an allergic
reaction. Venom takes four days to kick in.
Heart's vulnerable,
hits that first,
then a day later sets off
the ascending paralysis.
Except that ticks
aren't usually invisible.
They are until you find them.
Oh, no. That's dandruff.
Okay, well, that wasn't
nearly as dramatic as I'd hoped.
It just means the next
time will be even better.
What's happening? That's
the tick venom ascending.
Either that or you stressed her
into heart failure. BP's dropping.
Heart rate, 47. I'm
administering atropine.
She's gonna need a
transvenous pacing wire.
Okay, magical tick hunt is
over. Only real doctor stuff now.
This is just gonna get worse.
Ticks produce more
toxins the longer they feed.
She's gonna be dead in an hour even
if you pump her heart full of jet fuel,
unless you let me find the tick.
Could he be right?
The only thing I know for sure is
that your daughter's heart won't last
another 20 minutes
without treatment.
Okay, I just need one final instruction.
When I find the tick on the autopsy,
do you want to know?
I'm thinking not, probably
make the coping easier.
Stop talking to them!
Page Borsisky in cardiology.
Get her team down here stat.
Get them out of here.
Get House out of here, too.
Dr. Wilson, I could
use your help.
Well, I don't know if the dopamine's
enough. She may need inamrinone lactate.
Why? What's that? She doesn't...
She might need stronger pressors.
They don't have any in radiology.
Inamrinone can cause
arrhythmia and thrombocytopenia.
Not inamrinone could
cause death. Death's worse.
We have to get
her up to the ICU.
Cardiac team to ICU stat.
Sorry, a little crowded here.
House, get out of the elevator.
You're welcome to
wait for the next one.
You got her? Got her.
As long as we're stuck here, this
might be a good time to look for that tick.
Turn the elevator back
on. Just be a minute, honey.
Atropine's wearing
off. So inject her again.
That's just temporary.
Temporary's fine.
We're not hanging wallpaper.
We've gotta get her upstairs
and put her on norepinephrine.
It wasn't penicillin. You still think
the symptoms are unconnected?
We've gotta take care
of her heart before...
You wake up in the morning,
your paint's peeling, your curtains
are gone, and the water's boiling.
Which problem do you
deal with first? House.
None of them. The building's on
fire! We treat her symptoms, she dies.
We find the cause, she lives.
That tick is an IV drip of poison.
We unhook it, she'll be fine.
This is my last atropine.
Last us about three minutes.
Let's get her gown up.
Her heart rate falls below 35,
we're getting her to the ICU.
I'm not gonna let her
die in this elevator.
Where are they?
Get maintenance
up here, right away.
Ear canal's clean.
Left foot's clean.
If it's not here, we've
only got... Heart rate's 46.
It's here. Looks like a mole or
a freckle, something we missed.
Check the armpits.
Dr. Foreman's an excellent
doctor. He'll be able to handle it.
Yeah? You know that from experience?
You lose a lot of patients on elevators?
The maintenance guy said
it didn't just stop on its own,
that they hit the
emergency stop button.
Well, I'm sure he
must be mistaken.
Perineum. We checked it.
If we get her upstairs,
we still... Maxilla.
Checked.
Down to 38. We don't have
a lot of time. We can still...
Eyebrows, eardrums, pubic hair.
Checked, checked, checked.
We checked everywhere! It's not...
Thirty-five.
We gotta get her to the ICU.
We haven't found the tick yet.
We already kidnapped
her! You wanna add murder?
We've looked over every inch of
skin on her body, House! It's over.
Hey, is that the first
time you had sex?
With all the other stuff going on
down there, she might not have realized.
- You sick, miserable...
- What are you doing?
Oh, my God!
See? Told you it'd be
even more dramatic.
Push norepinephrine. Get
her heart back to normal.
She'll be completely
cured by tomorrow.
Foreman, let's get
her into the ICU.
Inamrinone was a stupid idea
unless you wanted me to
get that girl in the elevator.
Oh, I wouldn't do that.
Wouldn't respect you if you did.
Wow, looks like somebody
filed halfway through your cane
while you were sleeping.
Reflexes back to normal.
Heart's looking good, too.
I'll send in the nurse, we'll
get you transferred out of ICU.
You'll be discharged
in the morning.
Thank God. I just
wanna get home.
And back to school on Monday.
I'm not ready.
You're ready.
I'm sick, Mom.
You're not sick.
You're gonna go to class,
and you're gonna see your
friends and your boyfriend.
What's this doohickey?
A brassiere. You know
about those things.
You're a big boy now.
Well, I've never run
across one like that.
It's brand new.
Revolutionary uplift.
It's explained to
you. I know. I know.
I have acrophobia, which
gives me vertigo and I get dizzy.
What a moment to find out
I had it. Well, you've got it.
There's no one to
blame. Why quit?
You mean, and sit behind
a desk? Chair-borne.
It's where you belong.
What about my acrophobia?
I called a divorce lawyer today.
Does that mean you're leaving?
At some point.
You might not want
to sit exactly there.