In the early days of medicine.
Surgical students were
perfecting sawing technique
on three branches.
Because when looking at
on a exposed bone
in an amputation,
human instinct is to recoil.
Not cut.
Why did we ever stop?
I mean, I know why we stopped,
but still...
- Yeah.
- Why?
Well, the important thing is,
we have un-stopped.
They needed students
to get out of the habit
of listening to instinct.
♪ I been kept out,
yeah, they pushed me down ♪
Shut it up.
Don't wake the baby up.
That's something I never
thought I'd say.
Well, we have to go.
Betty's got school.
- ♪ Light it up on fire ♪
- And something I never thought I'd hear.
I know, it's crazy, right?
I mean, this... it's...
I don't even know what to call it.
- It's working.
- Mm.
Feels right. Why name it?
♪ Whoa-oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Come this far ♪
♪ Whoa-oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
Good morning, Mr. Fireman.
Good morning, Mrs. Fireman.
"Mrs. Fireman"?
Yeah, well...
you're not
Chief of Surgery anymore,
- so what do I call you?
- Mm.
Mm.
♪ Had my face painted
all black and blue ♪
♪ You gonna come at me,
I'm gonna come at you ♪
I miss you.
But I didn't even
get to see you last night.
Why do you have
to leave so early?
Why do you have work
so late?
♪ But winning's not enough ♪
♪ I need to burn it ♪
- ♪ Light it up on fire ♪
- Mm.
- Come on!
- I'm sorry!
A lot of our training
it breaking instinct...
♪ ...to only go this far ♪
- ♪ I didn't come this far to only ♪
- ..developing new habits.
♪ Go this far ♪
♪ I didn't, I didn't ♪
♪ I didn't come this far, no ♪
♪ Whoa-oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh-oh-oh-oh
♪ Come this far, yeah ♪
Don't react to bad news
in front of patients.
Don't show fear
when faced with uncertainty.
♪ Come this far ♪
When you're looking
at that exposed bone...
cut.
♪ Ooh, yeah ♪
So, the trick is trying
to stay human
when we've shut down
all those gut feelings,
all those messy instincts.
Is that DeLuca
on that bike?
Does he always
look like that?
Yes.
No.
♪ I didn't come this far
to only go this far ♪
You should totally go there
with DeLuca.
Yeah, you should totally hit that.
But that phrase is kind of gross.
I agree,
and I apologize.
I'm just saying that,
you know,
if you wanted to date him,
I-I wouldn't mind,
you know,
even though we,
you know...
I'm j... I'm fine with it.
I encourage it.
Well, thanks, I think,
but...
I'm kind of off the market.
I mean, Owen and I haven't
exactly slapped a label on it,
but, uh,
there's been a fair amount
of other kinds of slapping.
Ew.
Yeah, no.
Now I'm sorry.
♪ I didn't, I didn't come this far, no ♪
Are people looking at us?
I feel like
people are looking at us.
- No one's looking at us.
- Okay.
Well, looky here.
Congratulations on
the fellowship, Wilson.
Or is it, uh, Karev?
Karev.
Like the chief.
Yes, the, uh,
new interim chief.
Oh, I, uh,
got you a present
for your... first day.
Wow.
I mean, this is gonna be weird,
but I heard you wanted
this job, so...
Yeah, well,
I offered experience,
wisdom, countless hours in the OR,
and not to mention that
less tangible quality,
which is that I know
what the hell I'm doing.
But, clearly, Bailey was looking for...
For what?
Something else.
Uh, this is who you need.
Uh, the new guy was looking
for the new chief...
understandably, he thought
it might be me.
Link. Ortho.
Alex Karev.
How can I help?
I want to make prosthetics
that look like this.
Superheroes.
Kids will freak out for them.
I can adjust
the, uh, skin color, costume.
Sky's the limit.
Wow, it's incredible.
Right?
Wave of the future.
Not to tell you
how to do your job,
but I think
this is where you, uh,
ask him how much money he needs.
Yeah, thanks.
Uh, how much?
Just less than 500 bucks each.
Approved.
But, uh,
we need a better 3-D printer,
and that's 65 grand...
Ohh, steep.
Order it. I'll sign.
- Sweet! I like it, Karev.
- My kind of chief.
Yeah. Firm, decisive,
and here
I thought Bailey just picked you
to make herself look better.
Dr. Altman, Teddy.
Hey. It's me. Again.
Um, things for getting
really complicated over here.
So, if you could call me back,
please, before it's took late.
Morning, Doctors.
Wow, okay.
Pants feelings.
"Pants feelings"?
Well,
what would you call it?
What's his story?
Ortho. Not married.
And not unattractive.
You should totally hit that.
Lost?
Oh, still new.
I'm looking for the fastest way
to the ER.
Oh, I know a shortcut.
Lead the way.
What have we got?
Table-saw accident in shop class
over at Barrow High... sent blocks
of wood flying into the students.
Is Mr. Buckley okay?
He just kind of fell over
in the middle of the demo.
Yeah, we're gonna
find out for you, okay?
- No, I got this one.
- Couple more rigs just landed,
- and I hear there's worse coming in.
- Okay.
Is this the teacher?
Dave Buckley, 60s,
partial amputations to the right
third and fourth digits.
Kids said he was trying to guide
a student's hand
at the table saw when he
suddenly lost consciousness.
- Why?
- Page Ortho.
They're gonna want him in the OR.
- Webber, you got him?
- Let's get him inside.
All right. Easy. Easy.
What the hell is taking
them so long?
Can we move a little faster,
guys?
Hey, we didn't want to bump it.
Bump what?
Why?!
Clear trauma one!
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 15  Episode 03
Episode Title: "Gut Feeling"
Cece Colvin,
- day eight of dialysis...
- Skip the introductions, Taryn.
We're all friends here.
Good morning, Cece.
Dialysis again?
Maybe you could waterboard me
or hit me with a lead pipe
just to mix it up.
Well, you don't want to lose
your place on the UNOS list.
Okay, but you know the drill.
You work on me,
I work on you.
Let's get the, uh,
dialysis solution.
So, where were we?
Childhood.
Your mother was quite successful.
That must've been intimidating.
- Is that a question, Cece?
- You tell me.
It was intimidating.
Feel free to elaborate.
It was very intimidating.
- Don't tug on that.
- Sorry.
Dr. Grey...
saying "yes" to me was not
the end of the process...
it was the beginning.
One-word answers do nothing for me.
Well, I have to pace myself.
I mean, there are
a lot of questions.
Now, we don't want to lose
that port, okay, so watch it.
What was the best quality
you got from your mother?
I would say, uh...
ooh, a strong work ethic.
Which is why
I have to go.
You did hire me, right?
Yes, Cece. I did.
But I did not realize there
would be so many questions,
and I do have other patients.
Helm, let's make sure
she's not fluid overloaded,
and keep
rechecking her labs, okay?
Will do.
Take care, Cece.
All right.
Let's do you.
Uh...
my mother was very intimidating, too.
You have
the new insurance mandates?
Yep, right here.
Uh, and you know
the budget meeting
- was moved to...
- Wednesday.
- Thursday.
I knew that, uh...
Got it. Right here.
You should start de-stressing.
Well, then, the baton is passed.
I'll leave you to it.
Happy first day,
Interim Chief.
Yeah...
- Are you nervous?
- No.
I mean, the only thing
that would make me nervous
is if you were nervous.
- Are you nervous?
- No.
It's just, um...
You hired me 'cause I'm good,
not 'cause you think
I make you look good, right?
Correct.
I have trained you.
I have entrusted to you
my patients, my doctors,
and my staff
because I believe
in your abilities,
and that belief
fades a little every time
you open your mouth.
So, stop,
and step up.
Chief?
- Yeah?
- Yes?
Uh, just... just, you know, checking in.
I'm supposed to stay with the chief.
So, do I stay with...
- Her.
- Him.
Oh, no.
Uh, you have my office.
You have my parking space.
And, therefore,
you have my Dr. Roy.
Heavy's the head, Karev.
I'm relaxing already.
Dr. Madigan to...
You got 22 bones
in your face and skull,
and you managed
not to break a single one.
You're lucky, dude.
Excuse me, sir? Doctor?
Hey, hey, careful there, buddy.
Lean back down.
Is Mr. Buckley awake yet?
Do you know
why he collapsed?
Was it, like, his heart or s...
Sorry, we don't yet, son.
Um...
you know
if anyone's called his family?
Doesn't have any family in town.
- His daughter lives in...
- Maryland.
She lives in Maryland.
And I know you have rules,
but we're all just
really worried about him.
He's a great teacher
and a friend to my son.
So, if you could
just keep us posted?
Oh, we'll update you
when we can.
Dr. Webber, you're gonna
want to see this.
The teacher's blood alcohol level.
I honestly didn't know
it could get that high.
Well, I guess
we know why he collapsed.
He was blind drunk.
He knocked over a kid...
Into a table saw.
We need medical in here now!
This kid is bleeding!
I'm so sorry, ma'am.
As soon as we know more.
Son of a bitch.
- Wow.
- Geez.
Pierce, take a look.
The teeth have penetrated
deep into the right chest,
next to the auxiliary artery.
We placed
a chest tube for a hemothorax.
We're gonna
want to do an angio first
to make sure nothing
got yanked around in there.
DeLuca, will you page
Dr. Avery and tell him
we're gonna have to reschedule
that scar revision?
Wait. He left already. Right?
Left?
No. To where?
He took a leave of absence.
He e-mailed all of us.
He handed off
all his patients.
I mean, Plastics is kind
of scrambling, to be honest.
"Leave of absence," right.
So, where'd he go, anyway?
The schedule's a mess,
I know,
but don't take it out on me.
It's our new chief's
first day.
He needs time to learn...
- how to read.
- Uh, Frankie, I certainly hope
you never spoke about me
this way.
- I never needed to.
- You don't need to now.
You see a problem, fix it.
No commentary necessary.
Good morning.
Hi, um,
I-I have cancer fusion cells,
I have innervated electronic
prosthetic skin.
Just, you know, to kick us off.
This is all wrong.
Karev has scheduled
three-hour surgeries
in... 1 and 4,
and 3 is sitting empty
when you could be...
You know what? Mnh.
I should just...
do my gastric stim
now.
Yeah.
That'll smooth out this whole board.
Um.
Oh, look at
your navy blue scrubs.
You want in?
Wait. No, no, no. Karev.
Sure.
Or we could get started
on my fellowship
that you paid for.
Yeah, great. We'll talk about it
during surgery.
It's Karev. Not Wilson.
Let's prep for a lap chole,
and I'll be down in a moment.
Right away, Dr. Grey.
- Hey.
What's up with this e-mail
from Jackson?
- Where did he go?
- I didn't get an e-mail.
Oh, I would hope not.
Yeah. I got a voicemail.
He didn't say exactly
where he was going.
Just said he needed to take
a step back from his whole life
and try to see the bigger picture.
I feel really...
I'm really, um...
"humiliated"
I think is the word
I'm looking for?
I'm an award-winning surgeon,
and I pay someone
whose job it is to find me
a sex life.
That's humiliating.
I think the word you're
looking for is "enraged."
Yeah, that's it.
That's the word
I'm looking for.
Dr. Chism to Pediatrics.
- Dr. Chism to Pediatrics.
- It was a table saw, Mom.
- He fell into it. I don't know!
- Uh, Doctor, is there any news on our son,
- Kevin? He's had the table saw...
- I don't know, Mom.
We got a call.
We understand the teacher
may have been impaired.
- What? Impaired? Like, drunk?
- Oh, my God!
Or high?
And he's using power tools?!
That's... That's not okay.
- Mom, the teacher was drunk!
- Is he in surgery already?
- I need an update on my son!
- I'm sorry.
I was paged on a peds consult.
I don't have a lot of
information right now.
Then can you just point me
to whoever's in charge?
- Uh, that's you, boss.
- Yeah, I know, all right?
Get these people out of the ER.
Tell them we'll update them
as soon as we know anything.
I-I'll see what I can find out.
Folks, we need this area clear.
Please head to the waiting area.
Right this way.
I need an update on my son,
Kevin Gailis.
And I will get that for you
right away, sir.
Yo, dude, a little help.
Nosebleed, huh?
I can't seem to stop it.
That sounds like a rough night.
Been there, trust me.
Have a seat.
Okay, you want to apply pressure
and keep your head forward.
I'll come back to pack it.
And lay off the nose candy.
I'll check on you in a bit.
This guy.
This the guy? He's drunk?
Drunk?
No.
Well, your blood test says otherwise.
Cops want to talk to him.
Well, it looks like he's gonna
lose a few fingers.
I need to get him straight
up to the OR
to salvage what I can.
All right. Keep me posted.
The police want to talk to him
as soon as you're done.
How?
How did this happen?
You know how it happened.
And you need to take
responsibility for your actions.
All right,
let's get him up to the OR.
You need general anesthesia for this?
Um, no, I can just
numb his arm with a block.
Um... I've been
where he's been.
I'd like to talk him
through that if I can.
'Cause the more sober he gets...
the worse it's gonna feel.
DeLuca, where did they go?
Kevin's BP is still borderline.
I just updated his parents,
and I'm meeting Hunt in the OR.
You mean angio.
I told him to get an angio first.
I don't think so.
Hunt said straight to the OR.
When did it become okay
to just run off without
telling someone first?!
It's not okay!
Grab and elevate the fundus.
Got it.
Dr. Grey,
Cece's dialysis fluid output is cloudy.
- White count?
- 16,000 with a left shift.
Gram stain and culture the fluid
- and start her on antibiotics.
- Right away.
Anything else, Helm?
Uh, Cece wondered if I could,
uh, ask you about your father
while I'm here...
Get out!
Okay, keep lateral
traction on the fundus.
Make sure Mrs. Jarvis gets
neuro checks every two hours.
No problem,
Dr. Shepherd. I'm on it.
Dr. Patacky...
Can I help you?
Dr. Shepherd?
I'm... I'm Link, new head of Ortho.
Dr. Lincoln.
Right. Um, welcome.
Uh, yeah, I've seen you around.
I would love to pick your brain
about nerve graft
transfers sometime.
Uh, well, I have a few minutes
between surgeries...
I can't. I got to cut off this
drunk shop teacher's fingers.
Um, how about tonight?
Tonight?
As in after work?
Brains and bones...
hardly seems like work.
But, yeah. 8:00?
- Are you asking me out?
- I am.
- I don't even know you.
- Well, we can fix that.
I heard you like Italian.
I know a great new spot.
I'm sorry, you heard?
Heard where?
Maybe I shouldn't answer that.
Maybe you should.
Okay. Pierce, you ready
for proximal control
of the subclavian if we need it?
You see any vascular injuries?
It's difficult to say.
I needed an angio.
There was 750 of blood
in the chest tube.
I made a judgment call.
Are you seriously mad about that?
Am I seriously mad?
You know...
I am.
I am seriously mad
because you can't just
disappear with my patient.
My patient,
and we didn't disappear.
- We came to an OR.
- How's it going in here?
Uh, well, there's
no obvious active bleeding.
We're looking at
a pretty big hematoma.
Yeah, I won't keep you.
I'm just wondering
if I should expect any more
romantic advances today,
or if Dr. "Link" was it?
Link? I don't understand.
- Wasn't asking you.
- Um, just... just Link.
Are you sure?
Because you also tried to cram
DeLuca down
my throat earlier today.
- What?
- DeLuca?
If someone's gonna be serenading
me after work, I'd like to know.
Uh, like I said, it's just Link.
Ah, thank you.
I would say,
"It's the thought that counts,"
but I'm not sure
what the thought was.
Cram me down her throat?
Look, we got
an active bleed here.
Can we focus, please?
Clamp.
It's called peritonitis.
It means we cannot
use your abdomen for dialysis
because it's infected.
We can't use
any of your other ports
because they're closed
from your other surgeries.
Well...
then I will welcome the break.
This is potentially
a serious complication, Cece.
I know,
but that's your job.
I'll do mine.
May I speak to Dr. Grey alone now?
I have some private questions.
Of course.
This is a teaching hospital, Cece.
Okay.
We'll talk sexual proclivities
in front of your student,
if that's the way you want it.
That is not anything I want
to talk about with anyone.
My main priority right now
is getting you back on
this dialysis.
My port's not the only thing
closed off in here.
Rongeurs.
This is gonna sound worse
than it feels.
God, I-I hope all the boys
pull through.
Oh.
I know you do.
I know.
What you're feeling
right now...
the fear, the guilt,
hurting the people
that you love the most...
that's what rock bottom
looks like,
but only if you admit
that you have a problem.
Kevin, he gets scared of the saws.
The sound. I was trying to help him.
I-I slipped. I-It... It was an accident.
Look, how long do you want
to keep telling that lie?
Isn't it exhausting?
How many more people
do you need to hurt?
I-I slipped. I-I-I swear.
Alcohol does tend
to affect one's balance.
Dr. Webber, I think that's enough.
How's it going in here?
Cops need a timeline.
- 10 to 20 years, I'd say.
- Would you give it a rest?
Half an hour, Chief. Cut, shave, close.
What's going on?
Just trying to offer this man
some help is all.
I told you... I don't drink.
I-I-I don't drink!
That boy has a sawblade in his chest.
- You have to own what you did.
- I didn't.
I-I-I wouldn't...
An innocent boy is fighting for his life.
Webber, I really think I have
things under control here...
- The least you can do is tell the truth!
- Enough, Dr. Webber!
You're gonna lecture me, Karev?
I trained you when you didn't
know your ass from a scrub room.
And now I'm your chief,
and I want you out of this OR.
Your mentor?
Fun first day.
So, this electronic skin
not only helps amputees
regain the sense of touch,
it's an elastomer
that reforms covalent bonds...
Oh, yeah,
hold that thought.
Uh, hey, my gastric stim patient
needs to go to recovery.
May be a little while.
This morning shift was down
a couple nurses,
and it never got covered.
- What? Why?
- I would tell you,
but I don't want to speak badly
about the chief.
- Karev!
- Yes, ma'am. Yeah.
No, not you,
your husband.
He knows to look
at the OR staff report
in the mornings, right?
I don't know
what my husband knows.
I don't either, it turns out.
I need to go check some things.
I'm just gonna e-mail you stuff!
Try a 60-second sonication.
I did that yesterday
while you were off in the OR
drilling burr holes,
and I was feeling neglected.
Oh. Well,
if you want a change of pace,
I've got an epidural abscess
you can take off my plate.
Shepherd, I don't work for you.
I'm your research partner
and your sometimes lover.
One time.
It was one time, Tom.
Yeah, but who knows
what the future holds?
Did my sister put you up to this?
No, but I like the way you think.
Can we invite her? 'Cause...
Okay, why is everyone
against me and Owen?
I mean, I know that
we hurt each other,
but now we are
un-hurting each other.
That's a good thing, right?
I mean, life happens.
Life comes around.
- Life surprises you.
- Life is boring.
- What?
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I meant, uh,
this conversation's boring.
It's boring me, but it makes
the epidural abscess,
uh, sound thrilling, so...
What? Is it something I said?
I don't like being alone.
The chest-blade kid
is still in the OR.
The other shop-class kids
have been discharged.
Uh, the cops
want a time-stamped copy
of the teacher's tox screens.
A guy came in with a nosebleed,
but I took care of that.
And these are more
purchase-requisition forms.
Charge Nurse, dial 80.
Find me a pen.
Excuse me, Doctor.
I'm Ava Krug, Arthur's mom.
We spoke earlier?
Oh, yes, yes, uh,
is your son all right?
Yeah, he's fine.
He's fine.
We're just staying to see
how Kevin comes out, so...
Well, we promise to give him
the best possible care.
We've got two of our finest surgeons.
And to check on Mr. Buckley.
It's terrible
what that teacher did.
It's just unconscionable.
That's what I wanted
to talk to you about.
It just doesn't make sense.
Alcoholics are very good at their job,
until they aren't,
and until they take responsibility...
I know. I know drunks.
Arthur's dad is one,
and my dad was one.
I know the signs.
I was at Mr. Buckley's
daughter's wedding last year,
and he got tipsy
off two sips of champagne.
He's not a drinker.
And he's the only decent guy
in Arthur's life.
It j...
It just doesn't make sense.
I miss you.
- What?
- I miss working with you.
We had a rhythm.
You know, we had a shorthand.
What do you know about
alternative dialysis access?
Uh, I-I did read a study
in which certain enzymes
helped improve the longevity
of vascular access.
- Send it to me.
- No, in mice.
Human trials are still years away.
But this is what
I'm talking about!
You and I,
bouncing ideas off each other.
- Steal me back.
- I can't.
You know,
Bailey's not your boss anymore.
In fact, you are her boss.
So, you could tell her
that you're taking me back.
No.
But we work so well together.
You know, Bailey's technically
not your boss, either.
I mean, a fellow is not a resident.
It's more like a partnership.
So, you should just
tell her what you need.
- What if I piss her off?
- I don't know.
You could tell on her to the chief.
He likes you.
Good work on controlling
that bleed, DeLuca.
- Thank you, Dr. Hunt.
- Can we not pop the champagne
just yet, please?
Is everything all right, Pierce?
Uh, you mean besides the sawblade?
I'm asking
if you have an issue with me.
Or maybe with me and Amelia?
I'm asking if there's something
that we need to talk about.
My issue is that this kid's arm
is turning white.
DeLuca.
I lost the signal. There's no blood flow.
He's gonna lose his arm
because you rushed.
Because you rush into everything.
This... This is what I was afraid of.
This is why I wanted the angio...
There wasn't time for an angio!
I'm a trauma surgeon.
I did years of field medicine,
and I saw a lot of ammo
embedded into men's chests.
I read the situation,
I made a call,
and this kid is alive
because of that call.
So, whatever your issues
that you're having,
they're not because
of my medical decisions.
I think we both know that.
Dr. Kentalky
to Allergy and Immunology.
Dr. Kentalky to Allergy and Immunology.
Hey there, Mr. Buckley.
How you feeling?
I've... I've been better.
H-How are Arthur and Kevin?
I'll check.
Um, meantime...
I know what withdrawal feels like.
Chief Karev, dial 5241.
Your 4:00 leg braces consult
couldn't wait any longer
or she'd miss choir.
Amanda Perez's dad can't believe
you missed her esophageal
Atresia follow-up
and is composing an angry e-mail.
Very disappointed.
I could do without the tone, Roy.
Did we mock our attendings?
- Never to their face.
- That's what I'm saying.
♪ In no hurry to go nowhere ♪
Why doesn't anyone tell you that,
if you take this job,
you piss everybody off,
and never get to practice medicine?
Everyone who ever takes that job
tells you that.
I'm a bad listener.
Cece says I'm closed off.
- Who?
- Cece.
- My matchmaker patient.
- Wait.
Jo told me you hired a matchmaker,
but I thought she was kidding.
I wish.
It's just there's so many questions.
It's exhausting.
I mean, why can't it just
be a fancy restaurant...
I go in, give them money,
they ask me if I have any allergies,
and they give you a steak?
That's a different service.
She wants me
to spew emotional vomit
every time I walk into a room,
and I'm not just not...
I'm not Amelia.
Where does this woman get the idea
that you're closed off?
I mean, I know I am.
But... so that's it?
I just die alone?
♪ Like it's the last time ♪
Listen, you know what?
With everything and everyone
that you've lost in your life,
you have earned the right
to pick and choose
whoever you want to let in.
Exactly.
I mean, I know it's not easy
to get to know me,
but it's not like
you can't get to know me.
Yeah, if the front door's locked,
try the back.
Or a window.
♪ Head up in the clouds ♪
- ♪ Shuffle body is moving ♪
- That's it.
What's it?
The back door
for Cece.
You are an excellent chief!
Thank you.
♪ Head up in the clouds ♪
♪ Shuffle body is moving ♪
Buckley's wasted again.
What? How?
Think you need to talk to
Dr. Webber.
The distal anastomosis
looks good.
So, let's do a quick back-bleed,
and then we can remove the clamps.
All right,
BP is stable... 110 over 75,
and I got a strong
radial and ulnar pulse.
He gets to keep his arm.
I'm not in a rush.
With Amelia or Leo. Or Betty.
They aren't a whim,
they aren't impulse,
and if they were, they were
the best impulse of my life.
I'm not going anywhere.
I know.
I know. I'm...
I'm sorry.
Mm. Um, if you guys are okay here,
I will, uh,
go and update the parents.
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
Hey, can you track down Chief Karev?
I need him to sign a requisition
before he gets fired.
- Fired?
- Kidding.
Uh, dude.
I think it's been long enough.
I don't know.
I can still taste blood.
Oh, it's nothing.
All right, let's see here.
Oh, it looks good, buddy.
Oh. Whoa.
Page... Page ENT! Or Neuro!
We need a Foley, packing, suction.
I need an attending!
All right, call a code.
What the hell's going on?
- Uncontrolled posterior bleed.
- Yeah, I got that.
Why the hell isn't this guy
already in an OR?
- Ask him.
- All right, back off.
Back, back, back, back,
back, back, back, back.
Let's go.
We need to get him intubated,
open a central line kit,
get some O neg here right away.
You... what's his bleeding time?
Clotting factors?
I-I don't remember. I-I was
juggling, like, five patients.
Did you even go to med school?
What are his labs?
- Uh, I don't...
- Did you even do a physical exam?
No labs were ever ordered.
How long has this patient been here?
Bleeding in the ER?
It's not my fault. H-He was fine.
- How long?!
- Five hours.
Yeah, I can't visualize.
I can't visualize anything.
Get me a crike kit.
And you... go put
the IR suite on standby.
You! Now! Go! Go!
You gave alcohol to a patient
under investigation by the police
for reckless endangerment.
Look, I offered it. He didn't take it.
You know how many alcoholics I've met
who've passed on a drink?
Then why is his blood alcohol
through the roof?
Are you trying to lose your license?
I was testing a theory.
After I left his room, I ran some labs.
He's got auto-brewery syndrome.
It's incredibly rare.
His GI tract contains a yeast
that ferments any sugar he eats
and turns it into alcohol.
It was probably the Jell-O.
- I've never heard of that.
- Yeah, that sounds made up.
Well, maybe that's because
I've been around the block
a few times more than
either of you.
Look, I replaced the vodka
with water, by the way.
- I'm not an imbecile.
- Oh, you got lucky.
No, I trusted my gut.
Now, that's not luck.
Well, next time your gut talks
about one of my patients,
have it talk to me first.
I'm still not apologizing.
You acted like an ass.
I was right.
That's satisfaction enough.
You've got to be kidding me.
What now?
All right.
Time for another round of epi.
No pulse with CPR.
I can't get a readout on oximetry.
What happened?
Get in here. I could use
some help from a grown-up.
We need to embolize
the spheno palatine artery.
- All right, tell me what you need.
- Trying to access the femoral artery.
I got the right side.
You take the left.
Got it.
What the hell happened?
Torrential posterior
nose bleed.
I tried to stabilize him
in the ER.
Packing, Foley didn't work.
I got an IO line in,
but the blood is barely
transfusing.
- Damn it, I can't get in.
- Me neither.
Vessels collapsed.
I'm gonna try a cutdown.
All right, stop compressions.
Without central access,
he's done.
Hold off. Hold off.
Stop compressions.
St...
Ugh. Call it.
It was just a nosebleed.
A nosebleed that brings
a person to the ER
is never just a nosebleed.
It was a mistake.
It... It was just a mistake.
I've got this.
You can go, Roy.
Not until Roy calls it.
His patient.
No.
- Roy.
- No! I'm just an intern!
This isn't on me.
Roy!
You're killin' it, Chief.
Time of death... 17:57.
So, what's it called again?
Translumbar catheter.
We just go in through the back
and bypass all
of your fried central veins.
So, you saved my life again.
Just... finding another way in.
Well, if you can keep finding
new ways to do your job,
so can I.
No more questions.
But you are going
shopping, Dr. Grey.
- Shopping?
- Most people love
to pour
their hearts out to me,
but that's not you.
So I can't start inside out.
I've got to go outside in.
I want you
to buy five great new outfits.
Break the mold.
Take chances.
Make yourself ready
for something new.
You do me... I do you.
- That's the deal.
- Okay...
I can come.
Just, uh, in case you need
an extra set of eyes.
Or I can stay here
and monitor Cece.
Do that.
- Hey.
Um...
Kevin's all set in the PACU.
His, uh, neurovascular checks look good.
Good. Um, let me know
if anything changes.
Yeah.
Hey, um, you trying to
hook me up with Shepherd?
Oh, God, um...
that was a mistake.
Um, um... I apologize.
No, I'm not mad.
I'm just surprised
you'd be into it.
Me and your sister?
With our history...
Our history is ancient, Andrew,
and it is the least
of my worries right now.
Can you just keep an eye
on his vascular checks?
Yeah.
- Hey.
Got to go shopping.
Okay.
Huh. Great.
There's showers in here.
Fellows have a lounge on three.
You kicking me out?
No.
Cool.
Roy.
No need to come in tomorrow.
Oh, thank you.
I could really use... I'm
not giving you the day off.
I'm giving you every day off.
- You're fired.
- But Bailey...
Bailey's not your boss anymore... I am.
- It was a mistake.
- It wasn't a mistake.
It was a lie.
You said
you'd taken care of the patient,
and now a guy is dead.
And you can't even take
responsibility for it.
Which means, you're not cut out
for this line of work.
- But...
- Save it, all right?
This isn't where you defend yourself.
This is where
you pack up your crap
and you get the hell out of here.
You are never setting hands
on a patient in this hospital again.
You got it?
Oh, my God.
- Oh, good. You got my stuff.
- Huh?
I sent you that stuff
on electronic skin.
I thought that's what
you were looking at.
No, I'm looking at the budget.
Where's Karev?
Right here. You're looking at her.
- I mean...
- No, no, no, I-I am the only Karev
that you should be looking at.
I'm the Karev who sold you
on the future of medicine,
the crap that you funded
with your own... funds.
We should be making magic,
and, instead,
it's starting to feel like
a big mistake.
A fellowship is a partnership,
Dr. Bailey,
and you are not holding up
your end.
It's not, is it?
It's not a partnership.
You're still my boss.
And I just lost my fellowship.
No, it is. You're right.
I've been distracted.
It has been a little hard
for me to let...
- Karev!
- Okay. Oh.
What are you doing approving
all of these requisition requests?
Oh, making people happy.
Where do you think
the money is coming from?
You can't say "yes" to
everything that they ask for.
You know, it turns out you can
and still be under budget.
Look, even with these expenditures,
I am under for the month.
That's the quarter, not the month.
Hmm?
What? W-Where do you see that?
Here. Where is says "quarter."
It says you spent
the entire quarter's budget
- on your first day.
- Uh...
Hey, I'm gonna...
I'm gonna let you guys talk.
I don't...
Hey.
I'm sorry.
I just saw Meredith.
Jackson left without talking to you?
He just left?
I wish I could blame this on him,
but I told Link about you
before I even knew.
Jackson left?
And I was really kind of awful
to Owen.
I was really...
I was very awful to Owen.
Jackson left.
Uh, yeah, he...
he said he needed to go
clear his head
or... unplug or whatever.
He has some big questions.
He needed some
big answers.
♪ Holding me close ♪
Is there something wrong with me?
♪ Begging for mercy,
forgiving the ghost ♪
'Cause I almost died, too,
and all I feel is lucky.
There is nothing wrong with you.
♪ Lay me to waste ♪
He said if he had told me
to my face,
he wouldn't have been able
to leave,
so I...
- ♪ You're so hi-lo, hi-lo ♪
- guess that's good? I don't know.
- I don't know. I don't know anything.
- ♪ Hi-lo, hi-lo ♪
♪ You're so hi-lo, hi-lo ♪
Except Jackson left.
♪ Hollow, hollow ♪
♪ And I'm so hollow, hollow ♪
♪ I'm so hollow, hollow ♪
♪ Hollow, hollow, oh ♪
Hey!
- ♪ Hollow, hollow, oh ♪
- How are you?
♪ Hollow, hollow ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Hollow ♪
Evening, Dr. Webber.
Oh, evening.
Your, uh...
Your wife still out of town?
Well, she has a few more
Catherine Fox hospitals
to christen.
You know, first few days
as a bachelor are fun.
But... after that, it's boring.
I think I'll catch a movie or something.
Hey, I don't have anywhere to be.
That's nice, DeLuca,
but I don't need a babysitter.
- Long day.
- Hey.
Where do we drink around here?
Uh, there's, uh, Joe's pub
across the street.
- You know, underground.
- Yeah, I can show you.
What about you,
Nancy Drew?
- Wanna come?
- I don't drink.
Pub have a dart board?
Pool table?
Burger? Soda pop?
You serious?
We went a couple rounds
over a patient.
Doesn't mean
we can't be friends.
So, what about those times
when there is no roadmap?
Burger sounds good.
Should we go with our gut then?
All right,
let's do it.
♪ My knees are shaking ♪
- It's right here.
- ♪ And I can't feel my hands ♪
If instinct is all we have,
it's not always a bad thing.
♪ Toes are tingling ♪
- Hey.
- You wrapping up?
Yep.
So, I talked to Maggie.
She's... Well,
it had nothing to do with us.
Hm. That's fine. I get it.
Okay, well, let's, uh,
get the kids and get home.
- ♪ Like the static ♪
- Wow.
- ♪ swimming wildly ♪
- through Are we ever
- ♪ gonna get used to ♪
- saying this stuff?
- ♪ a broken TV ♪
- Yeah, that was weird.
- ♪ set ♪
- But nice.
Nice and weird.
♪ And you say
we're only getting started ♪
It can bring us wonderful places...
Joyful places...
- Hi!
- Hello!
- Hi, Mommy!
- Hi.
Hello.
- You went shopping?
- I did!
- That's quite a haul.
- I know.
It goes against every fiber
of my being, but I made a deal.
Fashion show! Fashion show!
Okay, maybe just one, okay?
But we should get up to bed.
- It's getting late. Hi.
- Oh. Yeah.
- Yeah.
- Yay.
Fashion show!
Fashion show! Fashion show!
- Coming up?
- One sec.
And it can also serve
an important purpose.
Fashion show!
Fashion show! Fashion show!
♪ You say we're only getting started ♪
'Cause our gut is usually
what warns us...
♪ Just wait ♪
♪ I'll show you where your heart is ♪
..when trouble lies ahead.