Previously on ER:
After everything, you
don't want to tell me?
No tonight.
I was not aware
that I was flirting.
Do you still love me?
- Oh, my God!
Of course I still love you,
why would you even ask me?
Why the hell do you
think? Just talk to me!
I was in a residential
detox facility.
Are you ever drunk at work?
My husband, Dr. Kovac, and our
son are in Croatia. They've been there...
I just need to spend
some time with them.
- Second-guessing and the...
- Shut up.
Ladies, I'm so sorry.
I got to go.
- Now?
- Mm-hm.
What about dinner?
You can order room service.
Anything you want.
I'll be back for breakfast.
Simon.
Ah.
Baby, that is very,
very tempting but...
You know how devoted
I am to my work...
so we'll save it for
round two, okay?
Hey. I didn't know you were on.
Yeah, I just started.
Are you waiting
for the chest pain?
Uh-uh.
At least it's not raining.
Nope.
Okay, about Ike's
the other night, I'm...
I had a few drinks, and
I really wasn't trying to...
I get it.
You do?
Good. I don't want
anything to be weird.
I know you have something
going on with Julia. I don't wanna...
She's in Nepal, actually,
on a spiritual retreat.
- Oh, really? Oh.
- Mm-hm.
Well, good. Then we can have
some time to get it out of our system.
I mean, get over it.
- And forget it ever happened.
- Okay.
- Okay? And just get back to normal.
- All right.
- Right. MAN: Can I get
some help over here?
What happened?
She stopped breathing.
- What's her name?
- Mia.
Mia. Mia, open your eyes.
- Does she have asthma?
- No, I think it's her heart.
And last but not
least, Trauma One.
I really appreciate the tour,
I know how busy you are.
- Is that a ruby?
- Yeah.
- Oh.
- Heh.
You know, rubies
have a lot of power.
According to Vedic astrology...
they bestow courage, vitality...
- and spiritual insight.
- Spiritual insight.
- Excuse me.
- Hey, heard you got a sick one.
- Yep.
- This is Mia, her boyfriend Jordan.
- Pertinent history?
- She had a heart transplant last year.
- Excuse me, doctor?
- Simon Brenner.
Heard you're starting
today. I'm Dr. Pratt.
- Keep her on 15 liters.
- Pulse ox, 85, tachy at 135.
Set up for intubation.
- Drop, etomidate and sux.
- I'm doing it.
- She had heart failure?
- Not since the transplant.
- She's been doing well.
- Hey, Mia.
Give me a deep breath
for me. Can you do that?
Doctors, you mind
if I try something?
- Like what?
- Sublingual captopril of nitrate.
- I'm Simon, new attending.
- Sam.
- Let's start airway first.
- This is only gonna take a second.
We got to put her on
a breathing machine.
She really hated
that after surgery.
When her lungs are this
bad, we don't have a choice.
- Ready with thorazine.
- Aah. What's going on?
- Whoa, whoa. JORDAN:
You're at the hospital, honey.
Pulse ox is 95. Wow.
Those lips, those eyes, it'd be a
crime to intubate a face like that.
What'd you get me?
You all right?
We don't talk much anymore.
Like we don't know what to say.
Well, we should fix that.
I miss you, Abby.
- Abby?
- Janet.
Hold on.
I thought you'd be
waiting for me downstairs.
Oh.
Come in, I just checked the
website and the flight's delayed.
God, I wish I'd known.
I rushed over here.
Oh, I'm sorry. I just found out.
And it's like only an hour. I can
get you a cup of coffee if you want.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
- Abby.
- What?
I'm going to go.
I promise this
time. I'm gonna go.
It's been a week. He's
been waiting a week for you.
I'm not so sure about that.
You can't keep putting it off.
What if it doesn't work?
- It works as long as you believe in it.
- I'm not talking about the program.
I'm talking about my marriage.
I just... I don't
know if I can fix it.
What does it mean when a
phone doesn't even go to voicemail?
Is there an attending around?
- That would be Dr. Pratt.
- Ah.
Laverne St. John, 4th year
student starting my rotation.
- Really? With an overnight?
- Some girls have all the fun.
Why don't you get
started with Dr. Brenner.
He's in Exam Two.
- Right there. Ah.
- Thanks.
- Mm-hm.
You giving her to new guy?
He seems to know
how to do everything.
Morris, I said no.
Stop bugging me.
This is for the advancement
of science, Frank.
That's what Dr. Mengele said.
Great, thank you.
She'll be right up.
- Wanna make a quick hundred bucks?
- Does it involve a French maid's outfit?
No, I have a proposal due
tomorrow. I need one test subject.
What you have to do?
Study the effects of
conducted electrical weapons.
- Tasers?
- It's just a five second shock.
- We record all your vitals...
- Forget it.
How about for 200?
- E and B's ready.
- Can I go with her?
- It's best if you stay down here.
- Is that okay with you?
It's not like I haven't
had a biopsy before.
I'll be waiting here for you.
He seems like a good guy.
Yeah, he really is.
- How long you been together?
- About a year, I guess?
It was 14 months ago. A few
days after she got the heart.
You met in the hospital?
She was in cardiac rehab.
We hit it off pretty quickly.
He drove me to my
doctors' appointments...
made sure I had my meds.
I called him my recovery buddy.
I can't imagine
being without her.
Well, you're lucky to have
found that, especially so young.
Every day, I thank God
for bringing us together.
Let's stock continuous
albuterol at 20nl.
- Dr. Pratt.
- Hey.
Thank you for the med student.
Intelligent and
enthusiastic and docile.
I'm surprised you didn't
keep her for yourself.
Doctor, this whole
orientation shift, it's a formality.
It's wasn't really my
idea. So let's make it work.
No sense getting
in the same case.
Instead of burdening you,
I'll see patients on my own?
- If that's what you want.
- Best for everyone.
There's a trauma coming
in, want me to take it?
- Sure, thanks. Huh.
- Okay.
Hey, Sam, family in Exam 4,
they're requesting a chaplain.
- Well, who's filling in for Julia?
- I asked Father Brian.
Who's that? Temp chaplain?
No, he's Julia's
replacement. She quit.
Pratt, it's a double trauma.
All right, come on.
Let's clear two rooms.
Kelly Robinson, 69,
assisted living resident.
Victim of assault.
Chest trauma, facial lat.
- I'm Dr. Brenner.
- It hurts to breathe.
- Who beat her up?
- That old bitch.
- Because you dropped me, dummy.
- She fell backwards off a table.
Right onto my head.
- Few seconds at best.
- It was an accident.
The hell it was.
Then she started kicking
and punching like a lunatic.
Let's settle down.
- We'll get her in Trauma 2.
- I'll take her in Trauma 2.
Go ahead, you can have it.
- What was she doing on the table?
- We had a communal living workshop.
It was a trust exercise.
I'll never trust
you again, whore.
You know what? I feel like my whole life
I haven't had control of a single thing.
It's like I've just
been, like, floating.
Well, that's the disease.
Drinking takes over, it
directs your impulses.
You stay out of its
grip, you keep control.
- Yeah, well, maybe it's too late.
- All right.
Thinking like that only
opens up the way to a relapse.
- Are you looking for an excuse?
- No.
I'm not looking for excuses. It's
just how many chances do you get?
I'm already, like, two
or probably three past...
what anyone actually deserves.
So who decides how
many chances you deserve?
I don't know. Maybe he does.
Yeah, he came to see me.
Two weeks into rehab.
I was very moved that he would come
all that way for me, but, you know...
There's more to it than that.
There's some pictures when
I brought Joe to the seaside.
You didn't bring him?
I only came for a day or two to
take care of some things, yeah.
- And I thought it might be too hard.
- Probably, yeah.
What things?
You said "take
care of some things."
Uh... I quit. I'm not gonna
work at County again.
Just after everything
with my father, with you...
I was thinking I
need something else.
Are you gonna stop
practicing medicine?
I don't know. Maybe
a different area.
- Well...
- Ah.
It's like those halls
are haunted to me.
I mean, not exactly
haunted, it's just...
- I need a clean break.
- Yeah. Yup.
So I gotta go.
So I'm done here in two weeks.
And I didn't... Do you
wanna come back here?
Or should I meet you
and Joe in Croatia?
We'll see.
What do you mean, "we'll see"?
Right now it feels good for Joe
and me to be there with my family.
I think he's happy.
Me too.
Um...
Yeah, we'll see where we
are when you're done here.
- How you feel, how I feel.
- You know, Luka...
Hey, and I also hope you'll let me
know when you wanna tell me the truth.
About what?
Sats at 92.
Okay, excuse us
while we talk shop?
Okay, what do you think about
.10 in this left costal margin?
Let's do a chest x-ray
to rule out pneumothorax.
Got any better ideas?
- Are we worried about the spleen?
- I don't know.
- You want morphine?
- Fentanyl.
Why don't you head next door.
Maybe Dr. Pratt could use some help.
- But, I... BRENNER:
We're okay in here.
Laverne, what's another way
to diagnose a collapsed lung?
You hear that, you old
battleaxe, you collapsed my lung.
Screw you, you had it coming.
- How much Ativan?
- Start with two.
You're just an old tart.
- She's combative from the trauma.
- I'm not combative.
- I thought you're with Brenner.
- He sent me in here.
Senile kook. This
is all your fault.
You are rough on each other.
What are you, professional wrestlers?
We used to work together.
We were librarians.
Heh. Okay.
Is that a blown pupil?
All right, 15 liters O2 by mass.
Let's mix up mannitol
and make sure...
Do you need me, Dr. Pratt?
- What's going on in there?
- Dr. Brenner didn't like any of my ideas.
- He suggested I go to library and read.
- What?
He also suggested I use
a different eye shadow...
and do something
different with my hair.
- He what?
- Yeah.
Please don't make
us go back in there.
Call CT. She needs to be in the
scanner as soon as the mannitol is in.
Put her on a portable
monitor, I'll be right back.
And this is fentanyl. This
is the really good stuff.
I mean, for the
special patients.
While we fix you up, you're
gonna be floating in a state of bliss.
You know, I know this is your first
day and I don't wanna embarrass you...
but this is a teaching hospital.
So that means that you
have to actually teach.
You see, those guys, they
look up to us as examples.
Heh. So this is me trying
to preserve their illusion...
that you are actually
worthy of their admiration.
Okay? All right.
One more thing, keep a lid on talking
about people's hair and their makeup...
or I'll make sure Human Resources
throws you right out on your ass.
I didn't realize you were
running the floor, Greg.
Keep it up, man. And I'll make
you real familiar with the floor.
All right, guys, it's all good.
Dr. Brenner will see you now.
Hey, Pratt told me
that the chaplain quit.
You didn't mention that.
Yeah, I didn't think
it was that important.
Did she find another job?
I think she's gonna stay
in Nepal for a couple years.
A couple years. Hmm.
We broke up. Just a little
embarrassing being dumped like that.
Well, it happens.
Not really. It's new to me.
You're such an ass.
Dr. Gates, are the
biopsy results back?
Your rejection fraction dropped
from 60 percent to 25 percent.
That doesn't sound very good.
And under the microscope, we see that
your heart is full of white blood cells.
So your immune system
is attacking the heart.
It's rejection.
But you can treat it, can't
you? What do we need to do?
This medication is
to stop the rejection.
What if that doesn't work?
Don't worry, it's gonna work.
Worst-case scenario, you
go back on the transplant list.
No. Maybe there's some better
medicines you don't know about.
- Shouldn't there be a specialist here?
- Jordan.
- This is what Cardiology recommends.
- The heart she's got is perfectly fine.
It's a good heart. Just find
a way to keep it working.
- Here.
- Thank you.
- What are you thinking?
- Ahem. That I've been here before.
Hmm.
That I'm gonna have to be
honest with him about something...
I don't really wanna talk about.
Well, it's possible that
the details don't matter.
He's smart enough to know
that the behavior was a disease.
So don't tell him?
It's about what they need to hear,
not about what you need to say.
Oh. Okay. So tell the truth.
Unless it's too difficult, in
which case lying is okay.
- To omit, maybe.
- Omit.
Janet, omit is a
nice word for lie.
And it's like he
knows. He knows.
He knows there's
more to it than I told him.
- All right.
- It's...
- Easy.
- It was Kevin Moretti.
Yeah.
- Hmm. It all makes more sense now.
- What does?
When Luka came to Chicago,
he came to see me at the hospital.
- He did?
- Yeah, you were deep in recovery then.
I know he loves me, I know that.
- It's just that...
- That guy wants you healthy.
What's the problem?
My heart.
It came from his fiancée.
She got into a bike
accident, was brain-dead...
and a couple of days
after the transplant...
he started to visit,
offered to help.
And I felt so bad for
him. He was destroyed.
So he's not your boyfriend?
It didn't start off like that...
but a couple of months ago,
I realized I let it go too far.
It's my fault.
So you stopped taking the meds?
I started doing things
that didn't make sense...
because I care about him.
I wanna help
him, but it's just...
He's not the one.
Getting sober means
being honest with yourself...
and with the people you
love, and you were right before.
It means being honest
about everything.
Yeah, well, here's
the thing. I'm a liar.
I grew up lying about
my crazy mother...
and now I lie to my husband
and I lie to my coworkers.
- I lie to myself...
- Abby.
I lie to my sponsor.
I drank at work.
Okay. Oh.
Damn it.
Okay.
Displaced femoral
neck fracture, right?
You asking me?
No, that's what it is.
I'll get a hair traction.
No, I wanna try 5
pounds of Bucks Traction.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah, Sam, I'm sure.
We all lie.
I am 12 years sober.
And I can't say I know that I
won't relapse at some point.
But I sure as hell
believe that I won't.
And that is the best
thing I got going for myself.
Every day I look in the mirror
and try to tell myself the truth.
What if I can't?
You already are.
Hey, Bettina. It's Greg.
Check your cell, there's something
wrong with your voicemail.
Anyway, I'm here in the ER.
I'll be here all night, so
if you get this, call me.
- Dr. Pratt.
- I already said no.
I'll take the shock,
you fire the weapon.
- Go away.
- I got a release form.
Clearing you of any
responsibility in event of...
Okay, think about it and,
you know, get back to me later.
- Tony.
- No.
- Hey, there.
- Hey.
Dr. Gates says you're
not feeling so good.
We're giving her diuretics
to dry out the lungs...
and IV meds to increase
her cardiac output.
Well, whatever you gotta
do to keep that ticker going.
If it doesn't work, we
may need to intubate.
Just to help the lungs.
If her heart keeps failing, Mia is at
risk for arrhythmias, cardiac arrest...
Can we not talk about that now?
Jordan...
I am so grateful for everything
that you've done for me.
I've done it for us.
This past year has been a gift.
I know that.
I will know that for
the rest of my life.
But I think...
We were both at very
intense points in our lives...
and I think we got
a little confused.
Confused?
I know it's hard.
You know what?
But I think you understand
what I'm trying to say.
You know what? I think we
should talk when you feel better.
I got to go outside, I
promised I'd call your mother.
- Jordan.
- Uh...
You know she's gonna be
upset if she can't get through, so...
I'm gonna call. I'll come
back when she calls.
Jordan.
- Hey, Jordan.
- I got to make a call.
Hey, buddy, come on.
Let's go take a walk.
Let's take a walk, Jordan, okay?
And I was thinking...
of a poem before, actually.
Before, when I was getting
ready. And I think it starts:
I carry your heart in my heart.
You are a good nurse, Abby.
But you could be a great doctor.
You just need a
little confidence.
I am never without it.
Oh, my God. I'm sorry. Heh.
No.
I just can't stop
thinking about...
What she must
have gone through...
and I can't stop thinking about
how afraid she must have been...
and I can't stop thinking
about why we couldn't save her.
I just...
Anywhere I go, you go.
A compass?
I know it's corny, but it seems
we always find each other.
Oh, man.
- What?
- I'm pregnant.
I carry your heart.
I carry it in my heart.
What if I don't know
how to love it right?
Abby. ABBY: I'm afraid
I'd mess it up, Luka.
We won't.
Ask me again.
Ask me to marry you.
So.
I guess what I'm saying is, let's
just try to love each other and...
Persevere.
- Chuny, have you seen Brenner around?
- In Trauma.
He's playing peacekeeper
with the two ladies.
Great.
As someone once said:
"To forgive is to set a prisoner free,
and realize that prisoner was you."
Michelle.
I'm sorry I hurt you.
Look, we need to talk.
And I'm sorry I didn't use
my full strength to catch you.
Now, doesn't that feel good?
Not as good as when I'm
doing her boyfriend. Ha-ha-ha.
- You lying strumpet, you will rot.
- It's the truth.
Come on, let's go. Larry,
Laverne, they're all yours.
Think those two can handle that?
Yeah, they could handle
a lot if you let them.
- That's right, you said that before.
- No disrespect.
But you're making it real
hard for me to respect you.
You're taking the procedures.
Not letting them do physicals.
- They don't know what they're doing.
- They've been to med school.
- You've either got it or you don't.
- Excuse me?
You know what I'm talking about.
Some catch on, others never get it.
Yeah, but it's our
job to train them.
That is sweet, Greg, but it's
also a complete waste of time.
- Are you serious?
- Look, I teach people that can benefit.
Ah. What about
Larry and Laverne?
Well, they're adorable and
eager and absolutely clueless.
I could spoon-feed everything I know.
It'd pass to them like a case of cholera.
So, what do you suggest instead?
Encourage them
to find new careers.
I don't know where you came
from, but this is a teaching hospital.
So if you can't accept that
everybody needs to learn...
then you don't belong here.
Okay, sorry. Remind me again.
You're not the Chief
of Department, right?
- No, I'm not.
- Okay, that's great.
So you do things your way, and
I'll stick with the way that works.
Shift's over. It's been a
pleasure, but I gotta go.
I got a date. I
got two, actually.
- Hey, I'm not the only who thinks...
- Good night, Dr. Pratt.
All right, I knew you'd
change your mind.
You ready to shoot me?
Beth and I met our
senior year in college.
We got engaged...
two years later, we'd
never spend a day apart.
She must have
been pretty special.
It seemed wrong when I lost her.
Not like it didn't happen, but
like it shouldn't have happened.
It couldn't have happened.
When I heard they'd found a
recipient, I just wanted to meet her.
That information is
usually confidential, Jordan.
I did some snooping around. You
know, I was a man on a mission.
It's all I had left of her.
First love is rough.
It's hard trying to
find that feeling again.
Whew.
When I finally met Mia...
I just wanted to stay
connected, you know?
Maybe it's time to let go.
Let go of Mia?
Let go of Beth.
- Tony, her sats are bottoming out.
- Mia?
- Hundred percent?
- Yeah, but it's not helping.
Call RT, get a vent.
- Already did.
- What's happening?
- Her breathing is getting worse.
Pulse ox, 82, on 15 liters.
She maxed out on the present.
Got to thread BiPAP.
- It's okay, you'll be okay.
- Systolic's on 70.
- Add dopamine.
- Run a five.
Hundred of lidocaine
and open the crash cart.
It's like a sterilization scene
out of some bad sci-fi movie.
If it means no more children for
Morris, it's a service to mankind.
Too late, Frank, my stuff's on ice.
- Okay, okay.
Ready, set... Hold on.
I have to record data for a
full five minutes after the shock.
So whatever happens,
do not touch me.
- You don't have to worry about that.
- No, I'm serious.
You can mess up the EKG,
skin resistance, pulse pressure...
All right. We got it,
okay? Here we go.
- One, two... MORRIS:
Wait, wait, wait.
In 1921, Walter Reed infected
his team with yellow fever.
In 1929, Werner Forssmann
catheterized his own heart.
In the spirit of these great
pioneers, I, Arc... Aah!
Oh, my God.
Hang in there, Morris. It
will only last five seconds.
Just a sting. - All right.
Has it been five seconds?
All right, all right.
Stop the trigger, Pratt!
- No, no, I did.
Definitely more
than five seconds.
- Pull the leads off.
- No.
No, it says don't touch them.
I'm trying, Morris.
This stupid thing. What the
hell is wrong with this thing?
The battery should
be gone by now.
- Oh, Greg, stop.
- No, I'm trying.
- It's killing the son of a bitch.
- He's had enough, stop it. Come on.
- Jeez.
- Archie?
- Morris?
Archie?
- Talk to us.
- Morris?
Is he breathing?
It's okay, Mia.
- It's okay, Mia.
- How are we on dopamine?
Twelve mics. BiPAP 20 over 10.
Systolic's 120.
This thing.
It's keeping you alive.
- My back.
- You wanna sit up?
- Jordan.
- I know.
I know.
Oh...
How are you doing?
I can't move.
You'll be fine in a few hours.
You depleted all the
acetylcholine in your muscles.
From one shock?
You don't remember?
Was that a standard
issue stun gun?
I had the guys in bioengineering
make some modifications.
That explains it.
What?
It was a long shock.
Over two minutes.
I'm sorry, Morris.
- Did you keep the monitors going?
- Yeah.
Send off a CBC,
chem-20, CK and troponin.
I need an EKG, ABG
and cardiac echo.
- Vitals, cue 15 minutes.
- Relax.
Nobody's ever been
Tasered this long before.
- It's publishable.
- You should get some rest.
I'd hug you guys but
I can't lift my arms.
- Hey.
- You look better.
- Feeling better. JORDAN:
I'll go home before work.
I'll call you tomorrow?
Sounds good. JORDAN: Okay.
- Hey, thanks a lot for your help.
- I think it's gonna be okay.
It's just hard thinking a piece of a
girl I fell in love with is gonna go on...
and have a life I won't be
a part of, won't know about.
You guys will still be
friends, I'm pretty sure.
It's not the same.
Heart's just an organ, right?
Whew. It's almost 6 a.m.
It's like a ghost
town in here for once.
Yeah.
Exam 4 is open. Why
don't you go take a rest.
Maybe I will.
The last time I checked,
the rack's all clear.
Well, I have at least a
good hour of paperwork.
Yep. I'm all done.
Lucky you.
Well, it's my third
night in a row.
I am pretty beat.
Well, you have time to go
rest before the shift change.
Yeah, good.
And thanks.