We're in the car, honey. We're
going to the hospital for tests.
We're in the hospital. We're
going to the doctor's office.
Can you tell me
what this is called?
You use it to get
food from inside.
Yes, but what's it called?
Is it a spatula?
No.
Good. Is it a can opener?
No. It's... It's...
You're trying to
make me look stupid.
You can go to hell! Why
don't you kill yourself?
Andres.
It's okay.
There she is.
Here I am.
Here. Come on.
You just need to answer
a few more questions,
then we're going home.
We'll have lunch, okay?
Okay.
I'm sorry.
I have Alzheimer's.
I know.
The mood swings come on
quickly, but it's under control.
Don't worry. He's actually
perfect for the drug trial.
Oh.
Thank God.
We can start as
soon as next week.
Andres! Oh, my God!
Andres?
Early onset familial
Alzheimer's. Brazilian descent.
Blood chemistries
showed high ammonia.
Vomiting stopped after the
ER put him on antiemetics.
Any recent health issues?
Just a sore throat
a few weeks ago.
How advanced is he?
Could be hyperalimentation.
Advanced enough,
but no IV feedings.
The wife shut down her
floral company to stay home
and feed him every meal
he's had in the last four years.
Do we owe this
case to your guilt
at having ignored your
own forgetful mommy?
My guilt over my mom is
why I put up with my dad.
You're taking this case
because we're running a Phase
Two trial on an Alzheimer's drug.
You couldn't round up enough
doddering, old guinea pigs,
so you need us to
fix this little piggy?
I'd like to sit in. Especially since
you're short a team member.
You mean Taub? Got him in here.
He asked for personal
days. His daughter's sick.
Isn't that the point
of having a spare?
I denied his request.
After I'd already approved it,
which you knew because
I sent you a memo.
Dr. Adams, taped under
your chair is an index card.
Would you read it, please?
"Wednesday, 2:43 p.m.
"A black pawn will
believe he's the black king
"and attempt to capture the
white head of diagnostics."
It's 10:15 on Friday.
Damn it. Look, the point
is, I saw this coming.
Dr. Foreman and I did
not always see eye to eye,
but he never had the
power to overrule me.
Now that he has the power,
he won't be able to resist
the temptation to use it.
With great power comes
great micromanaging.
And great vests.
I know you're the
better diagnostician.
I'm not gonna interfere.
I'm only here to help.
Could be transient nitrogen
load from a GI bleed.
Not if the
vomiting's persistent.
Which we won't know, because
the ER put him on antiemetics.
Take him off.
Wait. He was
puking his guts out.
We'd risk aspiration.
I'm just disagreeing,
not overruling.
So glad you're on board.
Take him off antiemetics.
Do an upper endoscopy
to check for bleeds.
It could be a bladder infection.
We'll run a pregnancy test.
I'm not pregnant.
Any type of birth
control can fail.
Not mine.
Oh, I'm sorry. You
said you were married?
Yeah. Happily.
It's okay. Sex can wane
in any marriage over time.
No, no. We've never had sex.
We kiss and cuddle, but neither
one of us is interested in sex.
You're both celibate?
No, neither of us.
Celibacy is a choice.
This is our orientation.
We're asexual.
Not quite sure what
box to check here.
You're making a mistake.
If I had the power to veto him,
given all the crap I've
put up with over the years,
I don't know if I could
use it objectively.
I do.
I can. I have.
It might be easier if
you'd stay out of the room.
I thought it'd be
different. This week.
I'm supposed to talk to his PO about
getting his ankle monitor off early.
You're saying he
should defer to you?
No. I'm just saying what he's
doing doesn't seem rational,
which makes me think it's
rational in a way I'm not privy to.
He always has a plan.
And he's always
self-destructive.
He may just be shooting
himself in the ankle.
I know it feels strange. Dr. Chase
is just looking in your throat.
We're in the
hospital. You're fine.
That's a pretty nice
trophy there, Andres.
He coached youth soccer.
Took a team that
was zero-and-six
all the way to the state
finals at Long Branch.
Hey, thanks for
doing this in here.
Switching rooms can
be very disorienting.
You take very good care of him.
I love him. Sickness
and health, right?
Upper esophagus is clear,
moving on to the GE junction.
Hi. Hey.
I'm sorry, family members
only during procedures.
I'll wait outside.
Oh, no, please, it's okay.
Joseph helps me with
my husband sometimes.
He's a good friend.
Which means not family.
Wait, we're gonna
be here a while.
Why don't you show Joseph
where the visitor's lounge is?
Okay.
What?
I'm surprised you didn't
go into the diplomatic corps.
Oh, you think they're...
No. If they're having sex,
it's probably
with their genitals.
Mallory-Weiss tear. Vomiting
must have torn the lining.
You know that close to 1% of the
population identifies as asexual?
We really got to get you laid.
If I have to plow that
furrow myself, so be it.
I've a patient who's asexual.
Is she a giant pool of algae?
It's a valid sexual orientation,
according to this
article, at least.
Yeah, I think I read that,
too. Is that Fugliness Weekly?
She's perfectly fine-looking.
Happily married for 10 years.
To a guy who loves penis
enough for both of them.
He's asexual, too.
Ran a complete physical on her.
Nothing wrong except a
common bladder infection.
Hundred bucks says I
can find a medical reason
why she doesn't
want to have sex.
You're out of your
mind if you think
I'm letting you anywhere
near my patient.
Fine, I won't go near her.
Just give me her file and any
blood samples you have left over.
No contact whatsoever.
You talk to her, the bet is void.
No contact. Plays to
my strengths, anyway.
Right now's not a
good time, House.
Not for the Dean of Medicine,
but it's the perfect time if
you're a member of my team.
Which one are you?
What did the endoscopy show?
No signs of ulcers or blockages.
But you found a tear
just below the esophagus.
Explains the bleeding.
Doesn't explain why he vomited
so hard he ripped his insides.
His liver enzymes are slightly
elevated. Gallstones could...
No complaints of pain.
Steatohepatitis would make
his AST and ATL levels rise.
Are you calling his liver fat?
Start the patient on statins,
do a biopsy to confirm.
And knock him out,
I've heard he's a wiggler.
There's no need
to put him under.
We can confirm fatty
liver with an ultrasound.
Just making an observation.
Well done. And now,
as a member of my team,
you can make the equally useful
observations that the sky is blue,
I'm wearing pants, and I'm
ignoring your first observation.
Of course.
Wait.
And there it is.
You're trying to screw
with my confidence.
Well, if I wanted to do that,
I'd tell you how much
the nurses hate you.
You're trying to get me to
define myself as a subordinate
to keep me from
ever intervening,
even if it's fully in the
scope of my duties.
Like now. This isn't
about diagnostics,
it's about what's
safe for the patient.
Do the ultrasound.
Ultrasound it is.
And the nurses love you.
You don't think I knew House
was gonna tell you to ignore me
and not do the ultrasound?
This is an ultrasound machine.
Which you're gonna use to
do an ultrasound-guided biopsy.
You've probably got
a kit stashed here...
"Cuddy Dark will waste his
afternoon chasing conspiracy theories."
You're letting him
get inside your head.
He can do a lot of
damage in there.
Dr. Chase, he
started vomiting again.
This is why we
stopped the antiemetics.
We needed to see if
it was still a symptom.
Okay.
Here. You want this?
Get your hands off me.
You're taking my head!
It's okay, Andres.
You're in the hospital.
10 milligrams of diazepam.
Already on it.
Hey! NATALIE:
I'm fine. I'm fine.
Foreman.
Blood in his urine.
We resumed the antiemetics
and increased his sedation.
He really went after her.
Maybe he found out
about her "good friend."
It was just paranoid rage.
Typical of Alzheimer's.
We don't even know if
they were sleeping together.
A few hours ago, you were sure.
And that's significant why?
Sorry, only the bleeding's
medically relevant.
No, I wasn't being rhetorical.
If they are sleeping together,
why do we disapprove?
You're pro infidelity?
She's not married.
If marriage is feeding
and cleaning someone
and limiting conversation to
repeating a few simple commands,
then I was married
to my pet rat.
And a lot of people
owe me wedding gifts.
And we're walking,
we're walking.
I don't care how sick your
spouse gets, you don't jump ship.
Alzheimer's is different. She
can't share her problems with him,
or plan for the future. The man
she married no longer exists.
Yes, he does. He's in there.
This is why you get married.
Said the divorced woman
to the divorced man.
I didn't jump ship. My husband
sank it when he cheated on me.
Commitment's not conditional.
She is there for him in the
only way that matters now.
She gave up her life
to take care of him.
Proves she's an idiot.
If she had any sense, she'd
have stuck him in a facility
and jumped on that strange...
Dr. Foreman. We were
just looking for you.
I was right about
the antiemetics.
If we kept him on
them like I said,
he wouldn't have gotten
agitated and punched his wife.
Yes, we're back to my
supposed diabolical plan
to shake your confidence.
Let's see if this helps.
If you're speaking
as a team member,
then I'd say you're a moron.
'Cause taking him
off the antiemetics
gave us crucial
diagnostic information.
If you're speaking as Dean of
Medicine, then I'd say you're a moron.
'Cause your micromanaging
kept us from doing a biopsy.
And if we had, the patient would've
been anesthetized hours ago
thus unable to go all
Chris Brown on her ass.
Unless one of your index
cards actually predicted
the guy was gonna
punch his wife,
everything you're saying
is post hoc rationalization.
Dr. Park, would you please
reach under that chair?
"The patient will
punch his wife."
You clearly wrote
that after the fact.
Dr. Adams, would you
please reach into my pants?
"Dr. Blackenshmurtz
will accuse me
"of writing about the
punch after the fact."
And look, there's
a photograph of me
holding a newspaper
dated last Tuesday.
How could I have
gotten my hands on that?
You done? Rhabdomyolysis
fits the vomiting,
pigmenturia and renal failure.
No muscle symptoms
and urine had no myoglobin.
TTP fits, though.
Start him on
plasmapheresis. Unless...
Unless I need to
say, "Mother, may I?"
And "mother's" an abbreviation.
Fresh plasma will replace
the damaged red blood cells
that are clogging his kidneys.
That sounds hopeful.
How's that feeling?
I've never been hit
in the eye before.
I feel kind of badass.
I think maybe you should go.
Look, I'm fine, okay?
I'll see you tomorrow?
Okay.
We're not having an affair.
It's none of my business.
I mean, not really.
'Cause nothing's happened, but
we've talked about it a lot and...
It's just really hard
doing this by myself.
When's the last time you
had a full night's sleep?
Um...
I don't know. Three years?
You're not gonna
get any rest here.
People who are sick
are not the only ones
who need to be taken care of.
Why doesn't Chase
have to be here?
You think he knows anything about
women who don't want to have sex?
Hormone levels are normal. This
woman seems perfectly healthy.
What does it matter if
she says she's asexual?
It's the fundamental drive of
our species. Sex is healthy.
Orgasms oxygenate the brain,
lighting up over
30 different areas
and making us forget
how boring Susie Cooper is.
That last one may
not be universal.
How about damage
to her spinal cord,
blocking the signals
from her genitals?
Sex drive is in the brain.
I suppose it could be
psychological intimacy issues
caused by childhood abuse.
She's been sharing a toilet with
the same guy for the last 10 years.
It's not the same.
Sex releases oxytocin, it's the
neurochemical basis for bonding.
And that's why men always
marry their right hands.
It's different for girls.
No, it's not. I've
tapped over 30 guys
and never wanted to
see most of them again.
I lived next to a Jewish frat.
We are veering wildly
off track. Please continue.
This woman's life is
probably better off without sex.
Eliminates most
of her insecurities,
she's immune to
most advertising,
and can have honest
relationships with men.
Not a lot of them.
We've run every test and
ruled out all the options.
You're gonna have to accept
she just doesn't want sex.
Lots of people don't have sex.
The only people
who don't want it
are either sick, dead or lying.
So maybe she's lying.
You think she's had a
boyfriend on the side?
For 10 years?
Sticking around the whole
time? It doesn't make sense.
What does...
Thirty?
Everybody lies.
Higher or lower?
Followed your advice
and took the night off.
It seems to have
done you some good.
Mmm-hmm.
Where's my husband?
He's not in the hospital.
So he just walked out?
All of the shift nurses had their
hands full with a double code.
Perfectly reasonable
explanation.
Same thing happened to me.
Couldn't find my keys for days.
The police have been
notified, I have staff searching.
You told me it
was okay to leave.
I'm sorry.
He has Alzheimer's!
It's freezing outside!
And he's sick!
I mean, you don't even
know what it is yet, do you?
The plasmapheresis
hasn't had time to work,
but TTP is our most likely...
Okay, I have to go look for him.
Hey. Don't be an ass.
Can't you see she's upset?
No, she's guilty.
Instead of being at her
husband's side, she was under you.
Okay. That's...
Yeah, he already
said I was an ass.
Personally, I applaud your
decision to step down off your cross
and get on with your life,
but your misplaced guilt
is shutting down your brain.
We need you to sit, focus,
and answer our questions.
So it's 6:00 a.m.,
patient wakes up,
and the first thing he sees...
In moments of confusion, Alzheimer's
patients regress to old routines.
So what would your husband
do on a Saturday morning?
Nothing. Be at home.
What about a year
ago, five years, or 10?
I don't know.
He trained for a marathon once.
Soccer practice. We
took a cooking class.
The soccer trophy you were
telling me about, it's gone.
Where was practice?
It was close to
here, on Chesterfield.
Okay, he comes, he thinks
he's waiting for practice.
He'd want to get
out of the wind,
but somewhere he
could see the kids arrive.
There.
Over here!
On three. One, two, three.
Nothing.
Not dead till he's
warm and dead.
Get him to the ICU.
Start him on
extracorporeal circulation.
That'll raise his temperature
too quickly, it'll cause acidosis.
We can deal with his
metabolism crashing.
We can't reverse brain
damage if we go too slowly.
Either way, if we don't get
his temperature above 95,
it's not gonna matter.
Multiple warm lavage is safer.
Do what House says.
He has no heartbeat,
he's not breathing.
How can he not be dead?
Body slows down when it
cools, but it doesn't fully stop.
We're warming his blood outside
of his body and then putting it back.
It'll raise his
temperature enough
that his heart
should naturally start.
Then we can shock
it back into rhythm.
And if it doesn't start?
Then there's nothing we can do.
You think it's possible he
knew what he was doing?
Like some part of him gets
what he's putting his wife through,
so he tried to... Kill himself?
It's what I'd do if I were him.
At least I wish I would.
I meant run away.
You think you should kill
yourself if you become a burden
to the people who love you?
If you really loved
them back, then yes.
That's really dark.
It's not naive.
I just believe people are capable
of more than you do, apparently.
We've got brain activity.
Temp's at 93. His
heart should start soon.
My dad left me alone to
care for my alcoholic mom
and raise my baby sister.
I was just a teenager.
I spent half of my
time changing diapers
and the other half cleaning
up my mom's vomit.
But it must have been important
that you stayed
for both of them.
Mom died after a few years.
It was ugly and painful, and
she went with me hating her.
My sister ended up
drinking half of her life away
and hating me
because I couldn't help.
After Mom, I had nothing left.
So do I wish Mom had used
a gun instead of a bottle?
Yes.
I didn't know.
That's why I told you.
Ventricular fibrillation.
Give him 300
milligrams amiodarone.
Be careful. Once
we establish rhythm,
any accidental movement
could crash him back into V-fib.
Clear.
We still have a long way to go.
Cold can be
protective to the brain,
but there is a
possibility of damage.
We also need to confirm and
treat whatever's making him sick.
I just gotta do a
standard battery of tests.
Blood, urine, EEG.
Is that really necessary
for a free flu shot?
Excuse me, I have to deal with
someone who's having a panic attack.
I specifically said
the bet was off
if you contacted the patient.
Exactly. You never said anything
about the patient's husband.
The deal was a medical
reason why she doesn't have sex.
I admit I was
stuck until I realized
that the medical issue
was not hers, but his.
She's lying to compensate.
It's a tale as old as time.
Boy meets girl.
Girl falls for boy.
Boy says, "I'm asexual."
Girls says, "Yeah, me, too."
Your twisted logic
can't hide the fact
that tricking a patient
into being tested
is completely unethical.
Come on. Don't you think she
deserves to know why her husband
won't bend her over
the kitchen counter?
You love all that caring crap.
You're not doing this out of
the kindness of your heart.
You're not even doing
this out of medical curiosity.
I thought I made it clear
I'm doing it for the cash.
Two people are happy, and
your natural impulse is to destroy it.
How do you know she's
happy? Did she tell you?
No, chirping birds flew out
of her butt carrying a banner.
All right, I admit that
my natural impulse
is to doubt people's
claims to happiness,
but yours is to be
a sucker for them.
You tell me which one's worse.
He just opened his
eyes a little while ago.
His heartbeat's doing well and
his body temperature stabilized.
There he is.
Is that Portuguese?
Yeah.
Honey, I don't understand.
What's he saying?
I don't know.
I tried to learn when we
got married, but I just...
It's okay, it's okay.
His body temperature is
rising. It's above normal.
Wait, I thought you said it
was stable. Why is it still rising?
I don't know.
Vomiting, liver,
kidneys and now fever.
I don't want to tell you how
to do your job, Dr. Foreman,
since telling people how
to do their job is your job.
But when your
less-than-competent
administration of this hospital
affects what's written
on my whiteboard...
Get to the point.
The word "fever." Could
come from the patient's illness,
or it could come from the
fact that you allowed him
to saunter out of your hospital
and take a nap in the snow.
He couldn't have caught a
virus while he was outside,
fever came on too fast.
The hypothermia could
have caused cell necrosis.
TTP was the diagnosis
when he walked out.
Fever's a little
high, but it still fits.
We should continue
plasmapheresis.
We're missing symptoms.
We should add language
loss and aggression.
Should we also add
forgetfulness? He's got Alzheimer's.
We've just been assuming.
Because the patient's wife
said he exhibited both for a year.
He's never hit her before
or lost all his English.
We have to consider any change
since he's been
admitted as relevant.
"Have to?" Do I need
to pull out another card?
Disseminated viral
infection, with encephalitis.
Patient complained of a
sore throat a few weeks ago.
Start him on interferon.
Encephalitis makes
his brain swell,
which causes symptoms that are
hard to distinguish from his Alzheimer's.
With the interferon, his
English should come back
and the aggression
should subside.
But you're not sure?
Unfortunately, no.
And you're not sure if he has
brain damage from being frozen?
So best-case scenario,
I just had a glimpse
into his future?
I can't take care
of him anymore.
Chances are his
mental state will improve.
You could get
more time with him.
We married six
months after I met him.
A year after that, he
started forgetting things.
I've known my husband longer
with his Alzheimer's than without.
I've watched more of him
disappear than I ever got to know.
I just can't do this anymore.
You lose.
Blood work shows
high levels of prolactin.
Add that to some peripheral
red-green confusion,
puts my money, excuse me,
your money, soon to be my money,
on a tumor near his pituitary.
Probably started
growing in his early teens.
Lowering his libido and
causing erectile dysfunction.
A year on dopamine agonists
and he'll be a sex-crazed
creep just like the rest of us.
Completely fascinated
by Susie Cooper.
I would prefer to be
paid in a single $100 bill.
Always wanted to
use one to light a cigar.
Hooray for us. We
disproved his asexuality.
We also probably
ruined his life.
He'll thank us.
Then he'll doze off.
And then, in a couple of
hours, he'll thank us again.
It could destroy his identity.
It's like a gay person being
told they're really straight.
So don't tell him.
Yeah, why bother telling a guy he
has a tumor growing in his head?
He'll notice it eventually when
it starts leaking out his ears.
It's a slow-growing tumor.
He'll probably die of
boredom long before that.
You always do this. You meddle
and force me into impossible situations.
You knew the second you told me
about this case
that I'd get involved.
You wanted me to meddle.
'Cause no matter
how much you wanted
to believe in this
chaste romance,
you didn't buy it either.
Where's that petition
House's PO sent over
about him getting
his ankle monitor off?
On your desk.
You played me.
This whole thing was
about your ankle monitor.
You weren't trying to
undermine my confidence,
you were trying to inflate it.
You manufactured
conflict with me
so, eventually, you
could let me win.
You knew it was encephalitis,
but you waited for me to say it,
because then, with
my ego boosted,
you thought I'd be in the
mood to take off your monitor.
Because I'd think
I could control you.
You're right. Take
off my monitor.
See, the beauty of the plan
is if it works, then you
think you can control me.
If it fails, then
you will actually
have proven that
you can control me.
It's pretty genius.
These are your training wheels.
If you think you're up to
this job, it's time to lose them.
Second half of my
plan might need work.
V-fib. Two rounds at 360
without establishing a rhythm.
Wait! Dr. Foreman!
Clear.
He's back.
I sure hope this
Alzheimer's drug trial
is worth a lot to this hospital,
'cause we're wasting a
crapload of time and man power
just to let this guy
watch his mind shrivel
and keep his wife miserable.
Heart attack while he was on
interferon rules out encephalitis,
but I still think I'm right
about the neuro symptoms.
It's probably
aseptic meningitis.
We would have
seen meningeal signs.
Given his abnormal mental
status, not necessarily.
Dr. Foreman! Would you
please reach under your chair?
It's just wet gum under here.
Where's the card? What card?
I'm happy to leave if you have a
better theory than aseptic meningitis.
Toxins.
If this guy went on a walkabout,
chances are he's done it before.
Wife keeps the doors
in the house locked.
There's plenty of
nasty stuff to get into
during the middle of the night.
We asked about
toxins on the history.
The wife said she was sure to clear
the house for her husband's safety.
And I'm sure she succeeded.
She's a PhD in
toxicology, right?
She's an ex-florist. Search
the home for toxic plants,
methyl bromide, any medications.
Stop. You're not infallible.
You were wrong
about encephalitis.
Just before you were.
Run CSF tests, find out
what's causing the meningitis.
You said you weren't gonna
overrule me, diagnostically.
And you said I wouldn't
be able to help it.
Apparently, you were
right about that one.
Fine. I'll look
for toxins myself.
You can't go to their house
without Foreman's permission.
Don't need it, I'm gonna talk
to the toxicology PhD upstairs.
What about gifts
from South America?
Anyone send any
fruits or vegetables?
I don't think so... No.
I'm gonna need your boyfriend
to collect samples of plants
in and around your house.
Toxins are the most...
Wait. You understand
him? What's he saying?
He's repeating "blue shack."
You know what that is?
Is it somewhere where
pesticides may be kept?
It's where we
had our first date.
Do you have a cleaning lady
who might bring her own supplies?
What's he saying?
If it's not relevant to the case, I
don't care, and neither should you.
Please.
This might be the last time I
ever know what he's thinking.
"When I saw her waiting...
"Waiting for me at the table...
"The way her eyes
looked when she smiled...
"I felt like crying.
"I knew she was the
woman I wanted to marry.
"And every time
I see her, I say...
"There she is." "There she is."
He's still in there.
What did he say?
He asked who you were.
Don't get your hopes up.
Have your boyfriend
get me those samples.
How did you even
know to look for a tumor?
Dr. House noticed
hormone levels in your blood
and consulted with
me as an oncologist...
Who cares how they
found it, okay? They found it.
Are there any side
effects to the treatment?
Some nausea, dizziness,
and as the tumor shrinks,
there will be
behavioral changes.
Like what?
Well...
The tumor interferes with
certain natural systems.
It lowers libido and
causes erectile dysfunction.
You mean the treatment will
make me want to have sex?
What if I don't
want the treatment?
I would strongly advise...
Look, you have a
brain tumor, okay?
You have to have the treatment.
Okay, look, I know
who I am, okay?
And I'm not one of them.
Hey, look, we'll adjust.
Okay? We can go
through this together.
You mean have sex? I
can't make you do that.
Maybe it won't be so bad.
It'll be terrible.
It's actually pretty fun.
From what I remember.
But you said that... I know.
I know. I wanted to
spend my life with you
and I knew that meant
making certain sacrifices.
But a girl has needs.
You dropped in the
U.S. News rankings.
With respect, Mr. Laffont, that's
only because we temporarily
shut down our
diagnostics department.
It's up and running again.
I'm actually concerned it might be
because of the change in management.
If you want my money, I'll
need to see a five year plan.
Am I boring you?
No, I just, those flowers
are from last week.
They should be dead by now.
Excuse me?
Sorry, I have to go.
It's Reye's Syndrome.
Patient had a sore throat a few
weeks ago before he was admitted.
Reye's in adults is a reach.
Not if he took aspirin.
Aspirin in adults is a reach.
Especially in a house with
locked medicine cabinets.
It wasn't in the
medicine cabinet.
The wife used to
run a floral company,
still does a few
orders from home.
She uses crushed
aspirin in the water
to make the flowers last longer.
So the husband
has a sore throat,
takes an aspirin
without her knowing,
realizes he's got a sore
throat, takes an aspirin,
realizes he's got
a sore throat...
You can stop me
whenever you like.
Have Chase start
him on steroids.
I already did.
Then why are you telling me?
Because I wanted
you to hear it from me.
There she is.
Here I am.
Your eye. What happened?
It's nothing I can't handle.
MRI confirmed macroprolactinoma.
He's doing the treatment.
And the wife?
Come on. We saved a man's life,
course-corrected two people's
wildly screwed up worldviews.
Not bad for a day's work.
I think they were happy,
even if it was based on lies.
Most happiness is.
Better to have shtupped and lost
than never to have
shtupped at all.
We can't smoke in here.
We also can't summon people
into the clinic based on a lie
motivated by a petty
bet, and yet it happens.
It's an imperfect world.
Well?
Disgustingly satisfying.
He said it was okay.
Is one of you Dr. House?
You've seen Spartacus, right?
I got an order here to deactivate
and remove his ankle monitor.
Robbie?
Hey, sis.
It's been years.
I know.
I thought of you
on Mom's birthday.
Is everything okay?
Yeah, yeah. Fine. I just...
wanted to see how you were.
I'm fine.
Bikes go faster
without training wheels.
Now get out, I have work to do.
Whoops.