Previously on ER..
Medical students
don't know anything.
It's your job to teach them,
not be their friend.
You've something personal
against this girl?
Do you think I should sit down
and talk to Dr. Carter?
You don't wanna be
confrontational from the get go.
You're getting defensive.
You don't even hear me.
Don't talk to each other.
Talk to me.
One good thing about Lucy,
she's not here.
Whatever this is, I can't fix
it. Work it out both of you.
Alright, hook her back up
to the pulse ox.
Hang 500 of saline.
'BP's 120/30. Pulse 80.'
‐ You got that second crit?
‐ It's coming.
Daddy, it hurts.
I know, honey, I know,
but they're gonna help.
Everything's gonna
be alright.
Ah, oh, can't you give
her something?
Uh‐huh, Carol, titrate another
two of morphine.
'I got the CT's.'
‐ Where's Dr. Greene?
‐ On his way.
Alright, page Benton.
We've got a splenic injury.
Well, is that bad?
Daddy, you're bleeding.
Lucy, I thought you were
gonna suture him.
He wanted to go
to CT with her.
Crit's 24 after 600cc's.
‐ The last one?
‐ Thirty three.
Alright, Mr. Sawyer, we should
really get that sutured.
Why don't you come
with me?
Okay, wh‐what's going on
and what's wrong with her?
'Your daughter is bleeding
from her spleen.'
Oh, my God.
Most splenic injuries
this size
heal on their own especially
in children.
Oh, so‐so‐so,
what do you do?
If she remains stable, nothing
except transfusing blood.
So, why don't you let
Miss knight suture that cut.
‐ I'll come find you‐‐
‐ No, no, no!
I wanna be with her.
Not until we take care
of that gash.
I want to keep her calm.
Aa‐aa‐aa Corinna, Corinna
I'm just gonna be right
next door here, okay?
‐ More nylon, Lucy.
‐ I know.
‐ Okay, I love you, sweetie.
‐ I love you.
‐ Lucy, can you get consent?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Right in here.
‐ Never saw it coming.
Ah‐ah, this van, it just came
out of nowhere and just hit us.
You're gonna to need
to sign this. Sit down.
Well, what is it?
It authorizes blood transfusion
and emergency surgery.
I thought she
didn't need surgery.
Well, probably not.
This is just in case.
Well, how long?
Ah, how long
will she have to stay?
It's hard to tell.
Do you have insurance?
What?
Uh, yeah, but I
left it in my wallet
in the glove compartment and I'm
not sure I can get to it.
Well, that's okay.
We can call.
Which insurance company
is it?
Uh, Blue...cross.
Listen, can you
do me a favor
and call her mother
in Cleveland.
I...she should, she should know
what's happening.
Do you wanna use the phone?
Um, no, no.
It's‐it's best
that you make the call.
Please.
A multi‐victim MVA,
father‐daughter.
CT on the daughter shows
a grade‐two splenic lac.
She's stable, but her crit
dropped nine points.
How's the father?
He's got a minor
scalp lac
crit of 42, awake,
alert, oriented.
‐ What's her name?
‐ Corinna.
Ah, can you take a breath
for me, please? Good.
Hi, Corinna, I'm Dr. Greene.
How are you feeling?
My back hurts.
Your back?
Not your tummy?
Where's my daddy?
He's right next door, sweetie.
She has rigors,
warm to the touch.
Probable febrile reaction
to the transfusion.
How many units
of blood are in?
That's her first.
I need saline
rectal Tylenol, 500 milligrams,
25‐IV Benadryl.
'Uh‐oh!'
'Corinna!'
BP's down to 60 palp.
Corinna?
Has this blood
been cross‐matched?
No, it's type specific.
There's pink urine
in the Foley bag.
She must be hemolyzing
her blood cells.
Yeah, she could also be bleeding
from the spleen.
Maybe both. 500cc bolus of
saline. Stand by with epi.
Alright, mix a dopamine drip.
We're sure she got
type specific?
‐ It says B positive on the bag.
‐ That's her type.
Alright, retype that blood
and the patient.
They may have mislabeled it up
in the blood bank.
Add a CBC
haptoglobin, free hemoglobin
direct, indirect coombs
PT, PTT.
What's going on?
Hemolytic reaction
to the blood transfusion.
Immune system's chewing up
the red blood cells.
Aren't you supposed
to be suturing her father.
He wants me to call the mother.
Go ask the father
if his daughter
has any history of
hematologic disease.
Now!
Add a BUN, creatinine.
Let's get..
Mr. Sawyer?
'Hey, Dr. Ross.'
Isn't it a little late
for golf?
Never too late
for golf.
‐ It's November.
‐ What'd I just say, Jerry?
You people are crazy.
Carter's going sailing.
Hey, way to go, Carter.
Hold on. You're rambling‐‐
His name is not Sawyer,
it's Nelson.
He kidnapped Corinna
two weeks ago
from her mother's,
in Cleveland.
Her mother
told you this?
Yeah, and she's on her way
to the airport.
She's gonna be here
as soon as she can.
‐ So why would Sawyer‐‐
‐ Nelson!
Why would he give you
her phone number?
I don't know, uh,
he freaked out.
He heard his daughter
might need surgery
and he'd be discovered.
Dr. Greene,
we have a situation here.
Uh, just a
second, Carter.
Are those the labs
on the girl?
‐ Yeah.
‐ UA Shows one‐plus bilirubin.
‐ Are you on?
‐ Just passing through.
So, they mislabel
the blood?
No. Cross‐reactions
to minor antigens.
We're gonna have trouble
matching this one.
'There's none
in the blood bank.'
Can I see it?
Carter, did you type the family?
I drew a CBC on the father
yeah, but he took off.
Looks like he kidnapped her.
‐ What?
‐ A bad custody case.
I talked to the mother and she's
on her way in from Cleveland.
Crit's dropping down to 22.
We got to get her up to the OR.
‐ There's no blood.
‐ What's the problem?
Right, Carter, ah, type
and screen dad's blood
and then get on the phone
and start calling
all the other blood banks.
‐ I'll try.
‐ Lucy, call this mother back.
Get the girl's medical records
and see if mom can have
her blood screened.
She's on her way
to the airport.
Get to her before she takes off.
She's bleeding.
We don't have much time.
Well, let's watch her.
The spleen could tamponade.
No, not with her crit
falling like that.
‐ That's the hemolysis.
‐ Come on, you don't know that.
You don't know
it's the spleen.
'One thing at a time.
We're looking for blood.'
'Crit's what, 22?'
We have a cushion.
Let's hit her hard
with steroids.
Carol, 500 milligrams
Solu‐Medrol.
Um, might
not be enough.
You want me to take
a look at her?
Be my guest.
Peter, you gonna stick around?
Sure. You're just gonna be
paging me in 15 minutes, anyway.
You called Doug, huh?
Yeah. It seemed pretty
complicated.
No problem.
That covers the entire state?
Sorry, I'm late.
You ready to go?
Hey, just a sec.
And what about Indiana?
Just give me two minutes.
I'm kinda tied up here.
Okay.
What are you doing
going sailing?
My uncle's boat is still
in Burnham Harbor
and John offered to motor
it in to dry dock
with me while we still
have decent weather.
Well, I heard it was
supposed to rain.
I caught the mother
at the boarding gate.
She's faxing her release
for the medical records.
Remembers Corinna
had a transfusion
for hyperbilirubinemia
as an infant.
Okay, thank you very much.
‐ Hi, Lucy.
‐ Hi.
Unfortunately, the mother
has a different blood type.
Figures. Dad matches.
‐ Exactly?
‐ To the antibody.
We gotta find him.
I'm just gonna leave
you kids alone.
Um, I've got a couple
of phone calls to make.
Uh, uh, but you've got
15 minutes, mister.
You're leaving?
As soon as I
find this blood.
Great. So I can go.
Yeah, sure, Lucy, bail.
National Blood
Registry, please.
I'm gonna go find the father.
He left an address.
He's a fugitive. He didn't give
you the right address.
My shift it over. You said
I could go, so I'm going.
Whatever.
Why do you have
to be such an ass about it?
Lucy, I don't care
what you do.
I'm gonna try and find
blood for his kid.
‐ So am I.
‐ Crit's down to 19.
Steroids aren't working.
Let's go IVIG, 25 grams
over four hours.
Come on, Doug, I gave you time
to treat the hemolysis.
Now we've gotta stop the splenic
bleeding up in the OR.
She's not
hemodynamically stable.
Okay. I'll use
the cell saver.
The serum you'd cycle would
keep destroying her cells.
Any word on
the blood?
She has antibodies
to both vel and lan.
One is found in four
out of 10,000 people.
The other, one
in 25,000 people.
She's got both,
so do the math.
You know
the father matched.
Let's hope
he comes back.
One in 50 million,
the math.
There's nothing in the Midwest,
the rare donor program
is on it, but they're not
optimistic.
We can't wait
that long.
Anesthesiologist won't put
her under with this crit.
No, that's why I wanted
to operate when she was at 22.
Right now, donor blood
is her best chance.
We'll manage her medically
till we get it.
If we get it.
Did you reach
that hematologist?
Yeah. He's on his way.
Alright, why don't you go home?
What?
You've been here
since midnight.
Yeah, but...I‐I took her.
Well, listen, you know
we've handed off patients
before. You're covered.
‐ You got three docs here.
‐ Okay.
Maybe I'll call in later,
see how things are going.
Hey, Mark? Can you use
albumin to prime dialysis?
What are you thinking?
Plasmapheresis.
I don't know
if that'll help.
Couldn't hurt.
No, you can arrange
for it to be in addition
to your pension plan.
Tax free?
Okay. You ready to go?
That's him.
‐ Dr. Carter.
‐ Yeah?
'James Middleton, Chicago PD.'
I ran that license number.
Turns out
it's a dealer plate.
'Used car lot
on Western and Addison.'
What license number?
'On the totaled
Grand Am.'
You guys called in
about a kidnapping.
Um, Jerry said
this was your case.
Oh. Oh, yeah.
Did you find the father?
Who?
They were
in the accident together.
He had us call her mom
and then he just took off.
‐ This is a custody dispute?
‐ Mom said he stole her.
‐ When?
‐ Two weeks ago.
‐ Well, is the mom here?
‐ No. She's flying in.
Okay, I'll tell you what,
why don't you have her
give me a call
when she gets here.
Yeah. That might be too late.
We really need to find this guy.
It's a lot of
"he said, she said"
with these kinda things.
He might have visitation rights
for a couple of weeks.
No, no, it's not that.
We need his blood.
His daughter
could die without it.
'Did he leave
any credit information?'
‐ No.
‐ Social security number?
No, nothing. Just an address
but I'm sure it's bogus.
Alright. I'll check it out,
try the used car lot.
Maybe I can come up
with something.
Hope so.
Okay. Line's in.
Let me get
a heparin flush.
Where's the plasmapheresis unit?
On the way down.
Daddy..
Hi, honey.
Connie, can you
get Doug, please?
Where's my daddy?
You're in a hospital.
'You were in
an accident, remember?'
Does your tummy hurt?
Where's my daddy?
We're gonna take
good care of you.
My name is Carol.
I want my daddy.
Your mom's coming.
She'll be here soon.
Daddy?
Your daddy's fine.
He's just...he's just
not here right now.
Why?
You don't remember me,
but you remember your dog.
‐ I'm sure it's only temporary.
‐ How's yours going?
Well, he's either suffering
short‐term memory loss
or saw the accident
as a last chance to back out.
Any word from
the rare donor program?
Yeah.
Two words "still looking."
You know what, I got
a friend at NIH
who's an expert
in blood banking.
‐ I'll give him a call.
‐ Great. Thanks.
Dr. Greene, ah, Carter asked
me to give you this.
He said there may be
a detective calling
you later about the father.
Is he still here?
No. He and Roxanne left
a while ago.
No, I meant the detective‐‐
'Mark, she's seizing!'
‐ How long?
‐ Almost a minute.
'I've got the phenobarbital.'
Push a third mig
of Ativan first.
‐ Yeah, Accucheck's 40.
‐ I need D‐50.
‐ What's her crit?
‐ Seventeen.
‐ Get another H and H.
‐ She's hypoxic.
Heart and kidneys
could go next.
‐ BP's 100/60.
‐ Alright, I'm gonna intubate.
‐ Push the phenobarb.
‐ Not going to do it.
We need some damn blood.
Doctor, hurry it up.
Alright.
Thanks, Jerry.
Okay. So there was
this girl named Soup.
Do not ask me why
they called her Soup.
Anyway, she was, like two years
older than us, so we thought
she was really cool,
and somehow, she convinced us
to sunbathe topless
on this deck
and I'm not
kidding you
John, my breasts were purple
and they had blisters
all over these..
Wow.
Have you heard anything
I've just been saying?
‐ Yeah.
‐ No. No, really.
What, what did I just say?
Huh?
I'm sorry. I was thinking
about that girl.
'You know, I should
really follow up.'
Thought you said
they had that covered.
Yeah, yeah, there was just
this one other thing
that I wanted to check.
Can you handle
this without me?
No. No.
Ah, come on.
It's no big deal.
Just powering it up the river.
John, you're not the only one
with a busy schedule.
I made time
for this, too.
I know, but I have to try
to find this guy.
Because Lucy's looking for him?
Lucy's probably home by now.
Right.
Come on. Get on the boat.
I'm sorry.
I'll call you later.
What?
I, I can't hear you.
A loaner.
Cars we loan to customers
to run errands stuff like that.
The owner must
have gave it out.
‐ Can I talk to him?
‐ He's in Vegas.
He's winning,
we never hear from him.
And there's no
paperwork on it?
We're pretty lax
about stuff like that.
Hey, Mort.
Leave that stuff out.
The rain's passing
through.
It's really important
that we find
the guy that was driving.
Yeah, the cops said
something like that.
I wish I could help.
I don't know what
they told you, but..
He was in the accident
with his daughter
and she's dying.
His blood may be
the only thing
that could save her life.
And there's no other
way to find him?
‐ Just the car.
‐ Gee, that sucks.
Yeah.
Ah, I'd help
you if I could, man.
Alright.
Would you give me a call?
Yeah, I'll give you a call
if I hear anything.
Hey, hold up.
Look, you say anything
to the cops, I'll deny it.
I loaned the car
to my bookie.
Your bookie?
What's his name?
He's your guy, Nelson.
I still owe some money.
He's been good
about my payment plan.
He came in on Friday,
wanted to borrow
a car for a few days
while he had his daughter
and I said sure.
Do you know how
to get in touch him?
I only met him one other time.
Then how did, how did‐‐
I placed my bets with
the bellhop at the Delaware.
There's no gambling
on the premises.
No‐no‐no,
I didn't mean you.
I didn't mean you,
but I was told that
there was a bellboy around
here who covered some bets.
Well, I thought I just
heard myself say
"there's no gambling
on the premises."
Right, not officially.
Sure.
Like there's
no prostitutes, huh?
Excuse me!
...Remember
and if you think of..
I wonder...what are
you doing here?
Look, I wasn't doing anything.
‐ No, I meant her.
‐ Just a minute.
Hey, you work for a bookie
named Nelson?
‐ I got to get back to work.
‐ Wait, wait, wait.
‐ Just a second, please?
‐ Look I told you‐‐
No, you said you knew a guy.
Just a name. Just give me
a name, please?
‐ Hey, excuse me.
‐ What is it? Money?
‐ We've got money.
‐ Let me go, man.
‐ Hey, we gotta find this guy.
‐ Look, get off me, man.
I told you I don't know
what you're talking about.
Thank you.
‐ Thank you very much.
‐ What?
He was about to tell me
about the guy who runs
bets for Nelson.
How did you even know
Nelson was a bookie?
Neighborhood gossip.
It turns out that address
wasn't fake.
It was just old.
And what are you doing here?
I thought you had a date.
No, we're having trouble finding
a blood match at the hospital.
‐ I thought it was worth a shot.
‐ Did they operate?
Not until they can get her crit
up. She had a seizure.
Hey, what kinda action
you looking for?
I can handle OTB, games,
numbers. Whatever you want.
Well, I just looking
for this guy.
His daughter's
in the hospital.
Oh, okay. See you.
No, wait,
we want to bet.
Yo, we wanna
place a bet.
It's just that Nelson
told us to talk
to a bellhop boy.
Whoa, when did he tell
you this? The Ice Age?
‐ Toby got fired.
‐ Toby?
He covers Nelson's action.
‐ So, where is this Toby live?
‐ I don't know.
He's‐he's one
of those Ghetto Boys
the butcher gets jobs
for him in the city.
The who?
This, uh, lost youth guy.
Works at a meat packing plant.
So walk in the room
and look at the name tags.
Yeah, Jerry. Can you
answer that, please?
Uh, Chuny, do you mind?
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
Jerry, what is this?
We're not moving patients,
triage is all over me.
No, no, no, only emergent
cases get on the board
until we have a free bed.
Any luck?
No. He hasn't answered my page.
I'm trying to track him down.
So, what do you want
me to do with all these charts?
‐ Where's Doyle?
‐ Hey, I'm doing my share.
You've been with the girl
and Dr. Weaver's been
on the phone for the last hour.
I'll take the LP
and the migraine.
You take the Treat
and Streets.
‐ And get Jerry some free beds.
‐ Thank you.
Benton wants to call
down Anspaugh.
‐ Any blood?
‐ Not yet.
Mark, Corinna's mother's
at O'Hare. She wants an update.
Well, just get her over here.
I'll brief her in person.
I got Lucy on line three.
She wants a status report.
‐ Carol.
‐ Yeah , I got it.
I'm holding
for John Derby, Derby, yes.
‐ Derby, the NIH Guy?
‐ Yes.
Yeah, he returned your call,
returned your page
left a mobile number.
Jerry, why didn't
you tell me?
You've been on the phone.
'Okay, thanks, Carol.'
Wait‐wait, slow down. I don't
think this is the right way.
She said it was
past the conveyor belt.
What conveyor belt?
All I see is beef.
Here, here,
whoa, God.
‐ Any luck?
‐ No. No match yet.
We're looking
for the boning room.
What exactly happens
in the boning room?
Uh, this is
the wrong way.
I didn't see
you leading.
Alright, I'll lead then.
Hey! Where are you going?
To find the boning room.
You said I could lead.
I didn't say,
I'd follow you.
Look, I didn't ask
you to come with me.
I didn't ask
I'm not with you.
I came looking first.
What does that mean?
It means
that if you were right
you wouldn't be walking
around a meat locker.
I wouldn't be walking
around a meat locker
'if you hadn't
let the guy go.'
I knew it. I knew you blamed me.
A little girl's dying, Lucy.
You can relax about you.
Hey!
‐ What?
‐ Boning room.
This city can build
youth detention centers
ten years before
they're needed
but they can't start
a job program for kids.
Prisons, yes.
Jobs, no.
Well, at this job,
apparently Toby took
bets for a man named Nelson.
Not everybody
is a success story.
Do you know
where we can find him?
Sorry, I don't
snitch on my kids.
They don't trust you,
it's over.
You want to save kids?
I got one you can save.
Crit's leveled
off at 16.
I think we stopped
the hemolysis.
Her kidneys are failing.
She's already had
two seizures.
If her spleen
is still bleeding.
She's gonna die.
No one is disagreeing
that she needs surgery.
The question is,
how long can we wait for blood?
It may never come.
Look, at some point
there's such a thing
as desperate measures.
We're not there yet.
Oh, my God!
Corinna.
Can she hear me? Corinna.
'She's been drifting
in and out.'
Maybe we should
type the mom.
I did while
I was explaining
Corinna's condition
to her.
‐ A positive.
‐ I can't give it anyway?
It's gotta be better
than nothing.
She needs a perfect match.
And Keith has it?
How typical?
He takes her,
he hurts her
and he runs away
when she needs him.
‐ Got it!
‐ What?
NIH found a match. Two frozen
units in Nashville .
'How long before it gets here?'
It'll be in the air
in ten minutes.
Alright, let's get
her to pre‐op.
'Hang on, hang on.'
'I want to be ready
the minute it gets here.'
There's number eight.
This is nuts.
Even if we find this Toby
he might not even know Nelson.
We're here.
We might as well try.
‐ Have a little faith.
‐ Have a little faith?
In what? In our ability to find
one guy in all of Chicago?
Well, then you go home.
I'll find him myself.
Yeah, right.
'Be right back.'
Where are you going?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Hi. Is Toby here?
Who are you?
Hi.
Do you live here?
Where are your clothes?
He doesn't talk much.
Are you his sister?
Who's that?
His mom.
She's sick.
That's pretty
bad cough.
Has she had it
for a long time?
A while.
What's her name?
Mrs. Price.
Maybe I should go in,
and take a look.
See if she's okay.
You shouldn't go in there.
'That's not your house.'
It's okay 'cause I'm a doctor.
Would you watch
him for a couple of minutes?
Yeah?
'Hello?'
Hello? Mrs. Price?
'Who‐who's there?'
My name is Dr. Carter.
I just saw your boy outside.
Don't be afraid.
I just came in to see
if you're okay.
Who‐who let...who let you in?
The door was open.
And I heard
you coughing.
It's uh, it's bronchitis.
'I've had it before.'
Are you coughing up blood?
'Is that blood you're
coughing up?'
A little.
Any fever?
'Has anybody ever done
a TB test on you?'
Have they done a TB test?
And they prick your arm?
You hold on, sweetheart.
We're going to get
you some help.
Ah!
What the hell
you think you doing?
‐ I'm just trying to help.
‐ Yeah, right.
'I told you not
to come in here.'
Ariel, go home
and stay there.
‐ I need to call 911.
‐ Yeah, if you're lucky.
Look, I'm a doctor.
That woman has tuberculosis.
It's highly contagious.
I want her on 100% oxygen, ac‐14
title volume 250.
Set up two blood‐Y's now.
Who's on for anesthesia?
‐ Babcock.
‐ Alright, let's get him here.
‐ Where are we going?
‐ OR three.
Find me when the blood
gets here.
I'll meet you in there, Peter.
Ma'am, ma'am,
you can't go in here.
We are taking
her straight to the OR.
‐ Well, what do I do?
‐ Just Wait out here.
Someone will come
and talk to you.
She won't lose more
blood during the surgery?
The other doctor said
she had a low blood count.
'I know, that's why
we're waiting for donor blood.'
Hopefully, we can get
her count up high enough
to operate safely
and stop internal bleeding
and prevent any further
blood loss.
And she'll be okay
until then?
I talked to toby's sister.
She says he hangs out
at a mini‐mart up there.
Alright. Hold on, We need to
wait for the paramedics.
‐ What paramedics?
‐ Woman in there with active TB.
She's got a lil' boy. The whole
project could be infected.
‐ She thinks he's there now‐‐
‐ Just give me a second.
‐ Okay, I'll go myself‐‐
‐ No. We should go together.
I'm going now.
God forbid, you should listen
to me and learn something!
What do you think, I don't
want to learn things?
‐ Not from me.
‐ 'Cause I disagree with you?
Lucy, I have experience.
You could at least respect that.
Carter, I'm just trying
to find this guy..
‐ What?
‐ That's him.
Mr. Nelson! Wait.
Mr. Nelson!
‐ Wait!
‐ Nelson!
Nelson!
‐ Sorry. Emergency!
‐ Hey! Hey!
Hey, Where do you think
you're going?!
No, no, no!
I gotta stop that guy!
‐ The fare's a buck fifty!
‐ Let me go! Nelson!
'Wait, nelson!'
Nelson.
Damn it!
Go back down there
and buy a fare‐‐
Congratulations! You just killed
a little girl.
Fare's a buck fifty.
Buck fifty!
There's your buck fifty.
‐ Hey, you better back off, pal!
‐ Alright.
Son of a bitch!
The blood bank's deglycerolizing
and thawing now.
It'll be 20 minutes.
‐ Crit's down to 15.
‐ Put her under.
‐ I don't wanna waste any time.
‐ Your call.
‐ You okay, Peter?
‐ Yeah, yeah, yeah, I'm fine.
Listen, get Anspaugh in here.
Come on, come on. Lets move.
I didn't even know
Nelson had a daughter.
She doesn't have
much time, Toby.
It's really important
that we find him.
He just picked up
his money
and said he might be leaving
town in a couple of days.
‐ You can't call him?
‐ He pages me.
‐ From where?
‐ Different places.
You were runnin'
numbers for the man
and you can't
tell them where to find him?
It ain't like
we friends. It's business.
Hell, what if I get pinched?
You better hope
you don't get pinched.
If he knew Corinna's condition,
he'd want you to tell us.
I am telling you.
I don't know how to find him.
If I did, I'd go myself.
Alright.
What about, uh..
...other business contacts?
He has guys at ballparks
to take last‐minute action.
'Yo, wait a minute.'
He got this uncle, a grounds guy
at soldier field.
Uncle Joey.
Crit's down to 14.
‐ How long do we wait?
‐ Here she is.
‐ Is that it?
‐ Bad news.
Come on,
don't tell me.
There were small holes
in the bags.
'We couldn't tell
until I took thawed.'
‐ Did it happen here?
‐ Could've happened years ago.
'There's no way
to tell if the blood'
has been exposed to bacteria.
Oh, damn!
We should give it
to her anyway.
What, you want to make
her septic, too?
No, Peter's right.
We can't transfuse.
So, now what?
Peter?
'I think we've arrived
at your desperate measures.'
No, no, no. I want to talk
to Detective Middleton.
Maybe he went home
for the day.
No, please don't
put me on hold.
You know, the cops
wouldn't have gotten this far.
How far have we gotten?
Uncle Joey?
These kinds of people
don't talk to the cops.
Where did you learn that?
Detective school?
We're close.
We saw him.
I know, I know. I don't want
to blow it either
but you got to know
when to ask for help.
Hi, yeah.
No, I don't know
if it's technically considered
an active case.
Hello? Hello?
‐ That might be him‐‐
‐ Hi. Yeah, I got you.
No, no, I said I don't know
if it's considered an act..
Hello? Hello?
I just charged this battery.
Joey!
Joey?
‐ Who's asking?
‐ We're not the cops.
'Course not. I already
got you made for the FBI.
We're looking
for your nephew.
His daughter's in the hospital
in critical condition.
We need his blood
to transfuse her.
‐ Whose blood?
‐ Keith Nelson, your nephew.
Keith Nelson's not my nephew.
Everybody calls me Uncle Joey.
‐ But you know him?
‐ Yeah, he's a good guy.
You know where
we could find him?
No.
When's the last
time you saw him?
Uh, a couple weeks ago.
We almost beat the rams.
Do you have any idea
where he might be?
It's really important.
What's today? Thursday?
Well, sometimes he goes
to the cockfights.
‐ Cockfights?
‐ Yeah.
You know, two roosters
pecking each other to death.
Where?
Used to be
on the South side.
‐ I stopped going.
‐ You got an address?
No.
I could draw you a map.
Okay, linea alba
is incised.
Toothed forceps.
Metz.
‐ You ready, Peter?
‐ I hope so.
Be fast, huh?
She won't tolerate much more
than 100cc blood loss.
Go right
for the splenic artery.
Okay. Be standing by
with lap pads and suction.
BP 110/70.
Let's keep it that way, Peter.
Alright.
Here we go.
Excellent.
Peritoneum looks dry.
Retractor.
Bovie.
Divide the gastro colic ligament
and we'll enter
the lesser sac.
Okay, got it.
Whoa! Whoa!
Suction, suction!
She's hemorrhaging!
Lets move.
Lap pad!
Released tamponade
on the hematoma.
‐ BP's falling.
‐ Vascular clamp.
Can you visualize
the spienic artery?
No.
What ever you do, don't
clamp off the pancreas.
Okay, suction, suction.
I can't see a damn thing.
Alright. Lose the clamp.
Compress it with your finger.
150cc blood loss so far.
Pressure's down... 70/50.
'Come on, come on.'
Damn. Come on.
Are you sure this is
the right place?
Yeah. The map says
it's across the bridge
and past the second
freight station.
What are you doing?
There's no one here.
They probably
don't advertise.
There's a light
on up there.
So, what, we're breaking
and entering now?
Unless you got
a better idea.
Not if you brought
bolt cutters.
No. I can give you a boost.
Like you said,
we're here.
Might as well check it out.
‐ There you go.
‐ Okay.
‐ I can't.
Yeah, you can.
I got you. Go ahead.
Up and over.
You got it.
There you go.
You did it.
How many fences
do they need?
You got to keep out
the riffraff.
You want to go back
and get your jacket
'cause it started
raining again?
No cars.
Do these people walk
to their cockfights?
I don't know
if I trust Uncle Joey.
He seemed too easy.
What, you quitting on me?
Hold up. Let's
check this out.
‐ Can I ask you something?
‐ Sure.
What made you decide
to come looking for Nelson?
Well, the girl needs help.
Yeah, but you see a lot
of people who need help.
'Whoo.'
Why'd you come out here?
‐ I don't know.
‐ Ooh.
I feel responsible.
It's not your fault, Lucy.
That's an easy thing to tell
yourself when things go wrong.
No, I shouldn't have made
you feel that way.
Truth is, you're the only
med student
I've had that's showed
any promise.
Do you see anything?
No, just a lot of dirt.
Hang on a sec.
I think I see something.
Hang on. What is that?
Is that a ring?
What kind of ring?
Carter!
Oh, my God.
Are you okay?
‐ 'Dr. Carter, are you okay?'
‐ No.
Can you tell me your name?
Do you know your name?
I know my name, Lucy.
‐ I think I, um..
‐ What?
I think my shoulder.. I think I
dislocated my shoulder.
Are you sure?
Yeah. Anterior dislocation.
I don't think it's broken.
We got to get
you to the hospital.
Sensation's intact.
‐ And I got a pulse.
‐ Okay, you stay right there.
I'm going to get some help.
No, wait, wait.
'That'll take forever.'
Can you move?
Can you get down?
Let's just do it here.
Yeah.
Okay. What?
Did we go over
shoulder reductions?
‐ No.
‐ We should've gone over that.
You did one that day, when you
weren't talking to me.
Alright, you're gonna pull
my arm..
'...really hard.'
‐ Yeah.
‐ Until you hear it pop.
‐ Just like that?
‐ I hope so.
‐ Isn't that gonna hurt?
‐ Oh, yeah.
Okay.
Ready?
Just commit to it.
Pull hard.
Two, three.
‐ Stop!
‐ What? What? What did I do?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
‐ We need countertraction.
‐ Okay.
Alright, I know.
Alright, stick
your foot in my pit.
‐ What?
‐ My armpit.
Your armpit?
'Just be
very careful.'
You said commit.
That's right.
Are you sure about this?
‐ One‐‐
‐ Just do it.
Two, three.
BP's up to 100/80
with saline.
Alright,
the distal clamp is on.
Now, let go with your
finger, Peter, slowly.
Okay. It's looking pretty good.
Dry as a bone.
Crit's down to 12.
No further bleeding.
Kids can tolerate low crit.
PVC's?
What's her potassium?
Uh... 4.2 pre‐op.
‐ Run of five.
‐ Lidocaine, 30 milligrams, IV.
‐ What is it?
‐ Could be cardiac ischemia.
V‐tach.
No pulse.
Alright, bring in
the crash cart.
Come on. Charge it to 80.
Hurry up. Crit's too low.
She's not getting
enough oxygen to the heart.
Here we go. Clear.
‐ Still V‐tach.
‐ Charge it to 160.
Clear.
Should've just
let you jump the fence
and drive the jeep around.
Do you think Uncle Joey
had the wrong night
or he was just
pulling our leg?
I don't know. Maybe we should
double back.
There's a light up there.
John..
Dr. Carter.
I just want you to know
that I do respect‐‐
Ow!
I'm sorry.
I'm so..
That I do respect you and that
you're a good teacher.
And you must be a good person
otherwise you wouldn't
be out here.
And I'm sorry,
I'm so stubborn sometimes.
Stubborn can be good.
Not when it's defensive.
Got us out here,
didn't it?
Is that good?
Most people would have given up
a long time ago.
In fact, most people
would never have gone looking.
I might have given up
if you hadn't come.
‐ Thanks for coming.
‐ Well, I didn't come for you.
‐ I came for the patient.
‐ No, I appreciate it.
It was very valiant of you.
No, really? They didn't
need me at the hospital.
I wanted something to do.
Well, you just said that
you came because I was stubborn.
I meant, we were stubborn.
‐ Oh, my God.
‐ What?
'I am so sorry.'
My jeep.
It didn't look that
far from the bridge.
Indiana didn't look
that far from the bridge.
‐ Are you cold?
‐ I'm starving.
Hey, let's grab
something to eat.
I'm going to call a cab first.
Sometimes they take a while.
‐ If they come out here.
‐ Someone's on the phone.
We're out in the middle
of nowhere.
Middle of nowhere is the other
side of the skyway.
‐ Sorry.
‐ I'm going to order.
Okay, make it quick.
‐ Cheeseburger quick enough?
‐ Get it to go.
Honey, everything's to go.
Uh, let me have
two cheeseburgers
and...two orders of fries.
No fries for me.
That was my order.
Would you like
something?
Yeah. A cheeseburger.
Another
cheeseburger.
Long day?
You might say that, yeah.
'So, I'm going
to call a cab'
and then check with the hospital
and then I thought
that we might call Toby.
Toby, yeah.
He was real helpful.
He said he'd think about it.
He'll probably deny
ever even knowing the guy.
So, what do you want us to do?
‐ You want me to say it first?
‐ What?
We're never gonna
find this guy.
There's gotta be
some other place we can try.
Yeah, there are millions
of places we could try.
That's the problem.
Let's just hope
they found that blood.
‐ I'm calling the hospital.
‐ Get a cab first.
Want anything to drink
with that?
‐ Yeah, let me have a coke.
‐ Anything for the boss?
‐ Who?
‐ The boss. The missus.
Your girlfriend?
No. Not my girlfriend.
'John.'
Come here.
‐ What?
‐ Come here.
Whatever you say, pal.
Toby got an address on Nelson.
Toby. You just called Toby?
I thought we just decided‐‐
I wasn't gonna
argue with you.
You got an address?
I hear you had
a scare in the OR.
I thought
she'd be gone by now.
I just wanted to check
on her before I left.
Well, she's going
into renal failure
but she's too unstable
for dialysis.
She had arrhythmias
on lidocaine
and she had
a breakthrough seizure.
It's a miracle you got
her through the surgery.
Yeah, we know
it won't do any good
if she can't have
a simple blood transfusion.
Now I get to stand around
and watch her die.
You want me to
talk to the mom?
Yeah.
Okay.
Good job, Peter.
Yeah.
This is the address?
Toby said this
is where he gets his mail.
What is he, a hobo?
So, this must be
his trailer.
Do you see anything?
Just five minutes.
I'm done peeking
through windows.
I can't believe Benton
operated without blood.
That's what
the OR nurse said.
That's a good sign, right?
Nah. She still needs it.
Mr. Nelson!
Mr. Nelson,
are you in there?
Should we go in?
If he was leaving town, why
would he leave his trailer open?
Depends on what kinda hurry
he was in.
So we should
find something.
Make sure this
is his place.
Looks like they had eggs
for breakfast.
Are these
racing forms?
Ah, these don't look like
construction plans.
What kind of guy
brings a kid to a train yard?
Well, maybe he had
nowhere else to take her.
Could have left her
at home with her mother.
We don't know
the whole story.
We know he walked out
on her.
Well, in his mind,
he gave her up
so she could get treatment.
He didn't know
how bad off she was.
I don't care.
You stick around
for your kids.
Sometimes it's not
that simple.
I never even met my dad.
He was 19 years old
when I was born.
Probably thought
he'd screw it up.
Might have been the best thing
for me and my mom.
I'm sorry.
Didn't mean to get personal.
No, I'm just saying sometimes
love can be complicated.
I'll give you that.
There's a message here.
'Let's hope
it's a good one.'
'Inga, are you there? Pick up.'
Yes.
'Okay, I don't know if you got'
'my message or if you been'
'to the hospital yet.'
'I'll try you again at work.'
'I'm across the street.'
'Call me on my cell phone.'
Leave the number.
'It's important.
It's about Corinna.'
Leave the number.
Damn it!
So, who's Inga?
His girlfriend?
It's across the street.
Across the street
from where?
And what is she doing
at the hospital?
Checking on his daughter.
We find her,
we find Nelson.
Randi? You talked to Randi?
'Yeah, she said
she'd look for her.'
That's alright,
we'll be there in five minutes.
More like eight.
Listen, you take the ER
I'll take the ICU.
And page if you find anything.
Otherwise, we meet in the lobby.
Right.
Hey, you know your,
your fare's up to $84.
Yeah.
You two got enough cash
to cover this?
‐ What do you have?
‐ I got 20. What about you?
We're going to need
to stop at an ATM.
Do we have to stop?
Can't we get
some petty cash,
or something?
Oh, wait. There's..
There's one right across
the street from county.
Where?
Across the street
by Doc Magoo's.
Across the street..
Nelson said
he was across the street.
There was music playing
in the background.
Do you think
he's at Doc Magoo's?
‐ You see him?
‐ No.
Excuse me.
Have you seen a guy
in here mid '30s
talking on a cell phone?
Every night.
‐ John?
‐ Yeah?
Men's room?
'I want to see her.
Can I see her?'
Soon as we get this started.
Just sit there
and roll up
both of your sleeves.
I can't believe
you found me.
‐ No kidding, huh?
‐ Thank God. Thank you.
I was trying to get
some news.
I didn't know
how bad she was.
‐ Inga never called back?
‐ How do you know Inga?
‐ From message your machine.
‐ You were in my trailer?
‐ We were everywhere.
‐ Got the donor bags.
I can't do this.
‐ Can you do this?
‐ Yup.
'I‐I thought
she'd be okay.'
Her mom could handle it.
Dr. Greene's in sicu
with the girl.
I told them
you're coming.
Try and get a BP.
I didn't know
this could happen.
I mean, how did I know
this could happen?
Got it.
Hook it up.
I thought I was helping her.
Hey, you're here now.
‐ The blood'll help, but‐‐
‐ I'll kill him.
You can take his blood
and then I am gonna kill him.
'Hey, we're coming
through there.'
Get that gurney
out of the way.
‐ Oh, thank God.
‐ Talk to me, Carter.
We found Mr. Nelson
next door at Doc Magoo's.
One unit donated.
Another one filling.
Alright. Has this been screened
for viruses?
They tested the draw
from this morning. It's clean.
Believe me, if I knew
there was a problem, I‐‐
'Someone page Benton.'
Kit, get this hung.
'Repeat a crit
in 30 minutes.'
Check the phenobarb level.
Corinna.
'Corinna,
I'm here, sweetie.'
'ET Cuff's leaking.'
I'll change it over a catheter.
She's gonna be okay now, right?
It's hard to say.
What she has is..
...multi‐organ system failure.
What does that mean?
She's been deprived of oxygen.
'She's in a coma.'
'It's been hard
to treat her seizures.'
'She has three
intravenous medications'
'to stabilize
her heart rate'
'and, uh..'
'...and her kidneys
have shut down.'
But his blood
will make her better, right?
A lot of damage has been done.
Hey.
‐ You look like hell.
‐ Thanks. So do you.
So, what is that,
a clavicle fracture?
'Anterior dislocation.'
Long story, right?
Long story.
Yeah.
I better get out of here.
I'm on at 6:00.
Hey, good job
keeping her alive.
Bloodless surgery.
That's a first time.
You should put that shoulder
in an immobilizer.
Hi.
I thought you went home.
No. We're on in an hour.
It's better not to sleep
unless you can get
at least three.
I wouldn't sleep anyway.
Her crit's up three points.
'But the renal failure
may be permanent.'
That's if she wakes up.
I thought we were saving her.
No.
We were giving her,
her only chance.
‐ That's not good enough.
‐ It has to be.
No..
...it doesn't.
Some patients get to
you more than others.
I know.
But when you do everything
that you can..
Sometimes even more than
you thought you could..
You gotta walk away knowing
you fought the good fight.
You fought
the good fight, Lucy.
Tomorrow, you'll
fight another one.