Previously on ER:
To prove I'm a good guy,
know what I'm gonna do?
I'll let you sit in front, play with
the siren. And I'll buy you a coffee.
I have two and a half months
left. This baby's not coming till then.
- Pain. Gush of blood.
- We're going to the O.R.
Come on, little
guy. Give me a cry.
Pulse is less than 60.
Let's bag him. Intubation tray.
We can wait for you to clot or can
start thinking about a hysterectomy.
Is Dad gonna hurt us?
Now we gotta stay
together. The three of us.
I'd rather we were all dead.
I'm losing it.
I don't... I can't even drive.
You're the only person
I could think of to call.
I don't know. I'm, uh,
somewhere close to Waukegan.
There's a Phillip's Diner
and, um, a gas station.
Yeah.
Okay, thanks.
Hurry up, okay?
All preemies have the
same five problems:
Infection, hypotension,
hypoglycemia, tachypnoea, cyanosis.
Your guy has four out of five.
White count's up, he's
on dopa and dobutamine...
and we're needing higher
pressures to ventilate.
How high?
Pips at 32.
You're pummeling his
lungs. He's gonna get BPD.
Abby.
Luka, listen to me.
It's hard enough
being a parent in here.
You're gonna have to trust me
to do what's best for your son.
Abby?
Any questions?
No.
I've been here before.
Do you want me to wheel
you back to your room?
- You shouldn't stay out of bed that long.
- I know.
I've given that "watch
and wait" speech...
and never realized
what a load of crap it is.
Well, it's just the reality.
And I can't shut my brain off.
I keep thinking, "Why's
the dopa at 17 and not 20?
And did they check the
tube position? And..."
I can't see his eyes.
I need to know
what color they are.
They're blue.
Um, Neela asked me.
She wants to come and visit.
No, I don't want any visitors.
I don't wanna see anybody.
Abby. Abby, Abby.
Oh, thank God.
Oh, I came as soon as I heard.
- You're not running.
- They're gonna send me to jail.
For what? Killing a scumbag?
He's better off dead.
I was in the car.
I could have driven away.
I went back to kill him.
And that's the last time
you're ever gonna say that.
You hear me? There's only
two people who know here.
You and me.
You fill out a rape report.
You tell the cops you
shot him in self-defense.
- You think that will work?
- That's what happened.
Do you understand?
It's what happened.
Serial crits and foot
pulses, q.30 minutes.
Hey, any word on Sam?
The police are
still looking for her.
You want the walls
eggshell or white?
Do I look like Martha Stewart or
the chief of staff? I've got work to do.
- What's with her?
- I guess she has to pay for the repairs.
- Oh, Ray, is this your writing?
- Mm-hm.
Yeah, linebacker from
Northwestern. Looks like rotator cuff.
No MRIs if you've got
a metal plate in your leg.
The tech's gonna go over that.
You're lucky I caught this or
it would have been a mess.
I better enjoy myself the next few
weeks because you're gonna be a pain.
- Hey.
What time is it?
It's time to go home.
You've been here all night.
- I should go and check on Abby.
- No, you should go and get some rest.
Gallant's parents will
wanna see you today.
No, I'm not going over there.
Neela, go home.
The dopa's at 17,
mean's hanging around 25.
Two out of six. Systolic
ejection murmur on exam.
- Translate into English, please?
- Hold on, wait.
There's a murmur?
Get the echo. Let's take a look.
- I don't understand.
- It's okay. I'll explain later.
Your daughter was a star
student when she was here.
Really? She never
gives herself any credit.
All the good ones never do.
Is that the heart?
Oh, my gosh. Look at that.
It's just beating
away, isn't it?
- I didn't tell her to come.
- It's okay.
- Are you sure?
- Isn't it amazing?
Seems like she's on her meds.
- Hey, Neela.
- Hi.
I know you can't eat in here, but
maybe you can take a break in the hall.
- How's he doing?
- We don't know.
- What about you?
- I'm okay.
You can see all the ventricles
and things in the heart.
That is just astonishing.
- Who's that?
- My mother.
- Mom.
- Yeah?
- Maybe you wanna meet my friend.
- Hi.
Maggie Wyczenski.
Neela Rasgotra. I've
heard a lot about you.
- Mostly right to left, T-R jet's 3.4.
- What are T-R jets?
Blood flowing the wrong
way through the heart.
Couldn't it be the pulmonary
pressures haven't dropped?
- Elevated from the RDS.
- Wait, wait, wait.
Something wrong
with the baby's heart?
- We don't know.
- What do you mean? You're gonna fix it.
Well, we can't just
fix it. He's premature.
He's gonna be here for weeks.
Oh.
All right, then we'll just wait.
It's all right.
We'll just wait.
James Clivus, 39, fell 20
feet scaling Tribune Tower.
- He gets better reception up there.
- Cell phones are just a cover.
What's with the tinfoil?
Amplifies frequency bands
allocated to the U.S. government.
The Pentagon says it's for
communication, but that's a lie.
- Vitals?
- Distal deformity on the right LE.
Hey, Mayday. Heard
about yesterday.
Glad to see you're okay.
Yeah.
What's with her?
- What?
- Her husband was killed in Iraq.
- Are you kidding me?
- Do you think we'd joke about that?
We ceded control to the
search engines. I gotta go.
- Just calm down.
- I gotta go.
Let us check you out.
Don't think I don't
know what you mean.
Hey, there's Sam.
- You got this?
- Yeah, I got it.
It's impossible if we produce...
- Honey, are you all right?
- Yeah.
I'll be punished for this.
Oh, my God.
Well, how did you get here?
A friend dropped me off.
I need a rape exam.
Oh, honey.
So, what do you
call that thing again?
It's a PICC line.
It allows us to give nutrition and
medicines without sticking the baby.
It's kinking or something.
Oh, wait. Maybe you
should let Dr. Raab do that.
Uh, will you step back?
You're making it harder for him.
It's okay. You're doing fine.
You don't want students
working on your son.
He's a Resident, not a student.
What's that?
PVCs. It's the tip of the
catheter tickling the heart.
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry, but
you pulled back the line, right?
Of course he did, Abby.
Pull back the line.
All right, uh, 2:37, PVCs.
What's the deal with the notes?
I'm writing everything down,
so I can look it up later on.
Last night, I was reading
about smoking and prematurity.
- Do you...?
- I quit two years ago.
I know you did, but you work so
hard, and stress can be a factor.
Are you blaming this on me?
No, I'm not blaming you.
I'm not blaming anyone.
My grandson is on a...
- Ventilator.
- Ventilator, and I need to understand...
Maggie, she fell. People were
shooting and she fell, okay?
Look, you can ask
yourselves why all day long...
but in the end, the
answer doesn't matter.
- Miss Lockhart.
- Yeah?
Uh, we're about to start a
lactation seminar in the pump room.
If it's not a good time...
No, it sounds great.
I'll go with you.
Great.
Okay, here we go.
Hey, Joe.
These go between
the boob and the tube.
- You know what I mean?
- Mm-hm.
It's pretty self-explanatory.
You seem hesitant.
She is.
Breast milk is best for babies.
Well, she knows
that. She's a doctor.
I think I just need
a little privacy.
Okay, yeah. I'll
get you a screen.
- Well, she seems nice.
- Yeah.
Um...
You too.
What?
I need you to...
Oh, Abby, I've been
through all of this before.
- I don't think so.
- Yes.
Have you had a C-section, a
hysterectomy and a premature baby?
- No, I haven't, but...
- I didn't think so.
Abby. Look, I can...
I'll meet you outside.
- I think that you...
- I would like to meet you outside.
- All right.
- Fine.
- Fine, I'll meet you outside.
- Thanks.
They have a boy or a girl?
Boy.
He's in the NICU.
What about Jerry?
He was shot through the
chest, but he's pulling through.
Okay, you'll feel a little
pressure while I get the cultures.
Haleh, send off for
HIV and hepatitis titers.
No problem.
Sam, can I get you some water?
I'm... I'm okay. Thanks, Haleh.
You know I knew that he stole
TVs and video equipment...
but I just never thought he'd
be capable of anything like this.
It's not your fault.
Yeah? It feels like it.
Well, it's not.
Do you know where
Steve and the others are?
Did they catch them?
They're dead.
All of them?
All of them.
Not a good place to take a nap,
buddy. You could drown out here.
Track marks everywhere.
No way we get a line in.
- I'll throw in an EJ.
- Yeah, right.
Hey, I just spent a month in
the ICU. I can do it in my sleep.
You got a bad batch of heroin
there. Knocked you on your ass.
- I hate when that happens.
- That's not funny, man.
Say, "Ah."
- What the hell is that?
- Narcan.
Sublingual? Are we
authorized for that?
What? I can't hear you.
- That's not in our scope, man.
- I got the base online.
- Hello?
- County General on Alpha 1, go ahead.
Electrocuted juggler, self-inflicted
toe amputation, kerosene ingestion.
What...? What is this?
People will do anything
to stay out of the rain.
We've got three near-drownings and
this board hasn't changed in over an hour.
No, no, no, Gates.
You cannot put in an EJ.
- Why not?
- It's out of your scope of practice.
- Ten minutes out.
- I'll see you then.
- What was that?
- Unresponsive overdose.
Ten minutes out with
one cocky-ass paramedic.
ER said okay on the EJ.
- They did?
- Yeah.
Hey, they know me there.
They trust me, unlike my partner.
Look, if you're lying, I
promise you I'll sell you out.
- How's my boy?
- He's hanging in there.
I've been reading to him all morning,
and I swear to you, he recognizes my voice.
Vent wean, uh, isn't working.
They had to crank the O2 up to 70.
Take that coat off, Dr. Kovac.
We don't need the nasty
ER bugs in the NICU.
Sorry.
Have you two made a decision
about the Fludrozalone trial yet?
- Yeah.
- No.
Fludro...
- What is it? KOVAC:
Fludrozalone.
It's a new drug they're studying
for use in persistent hypotension.
Baby Joe is over 1500 grams.
- He's a perfect fit for...
- For your trial. We know. We know.
We're still making a decision.
Spontaneous intestinal perf,
fleeting neurodevelopment delays...
Theoretical risk, Abby.
I don't wanna subject our child to
an experimental protocol when we...
Because he still doesn't have
an adequate blood pressure.
Yes, but why just dopamine? Why
not dobutamine and an epi infusion?
Don't micromanage.
- Don't you. Don't.
- I won't. Okay.
Okay, why don't I just
leave the consent form...
just in case you
change your mind?
- Excuse me.
- Mm-hm.
She's just trying to give
him the best possible chance.
- She's been pushing this trial.
- Come on, Abby, that's ridiculous.
- Is it?
- Why assume the worst about people?
It's not about me
being negative.
You need to pay attention
and wake up. It's our baby.
Hey.
- Luka.
- Abby?
Do you believe him?
I think... I think he's right.
You don't know the
first thing about it.
Maybe this drug would
turn everything around.
I know it's tough, but
we have to consider it.
Now, sometimes you
have to use your instincts...
Shut up, shut up. Please,
please, just shut up.
You know, I didn't
ask you to come here.
I didn't ask you to be involved.
Maybe you should just leave.
Okay.
Hey, Dori, can you find out when
the lab runs pertussis assays?
Every day but
Tuesday and Sunday.
- What did you do, mug a pimp?
- Ha-ha.
Yeah, your dad says hi.
How are you all
surviving without me?
Just fine. Hard
as it is to believe.
I got six hospitals to add
Maxanoxx to their formulary...
and now they're sending
me to Vegas for the weekend.
Vegas. Sweet.
Hey, put a bet down for me.
Hey, Pratt, can you get a
consent for the lid-lac sedation?
Sure.
Not until you sign the discharge
for Gonorrhea Grandma.
- Need any help?
- No, it's just the usual mess.
Nothing I can't handle.
Okay, I don't just mean today.
I, uh... I want my job back.
What happened to Vegas?
Vegas? Do I look like Vegas?
- Kind of.
- I'd hate Vegas.
Where's Weaver? She's
been ignoring my calls.
She's busy with some admin crap.
Nineteen-year-old male
found down in an alley.
- Probable overdose.
- What do we got?
Pulse, 84. Systolic, 86,
after a liter into the EJ.
EJ? I told you not to do that.
- You're dead.
- It's flowing great.
- Ought to thank me.
- I ought to report you.
Dr. Kovac was running the floor
when Clemente had his meltdown.
Yes, he was.
He was there the day that
Clemente and his girlfriend came in.
I believe so. I'd have
to check the schedule.
Yeah, he was.
He was there the day he
signed off on the diabetic...
whose family is bringing a
multi-million-dollar lawsuit against us.
Donald, where
you going with this?
I've drawn up a press release
announcing Dr. Kovac's dismissal.
You're firing him?
There was negligent
management here.
Shouldn't we give him a
chance to defend himself?
Too late for that. I'd like everyone
to look this over before I send it out.
- This sounds right.
- Works for me.
Look, I am the one
who hired Dr. Clemente.
But you didn't keep him here.
You even said that you warned
Dr. Kovac to get rid of him...
but he ignored you.
That's not how it happened.
Oh, Dr. Weaver.
- Not now.
- Uh, rehire me, please.
I'm efficient. I'm a
walking encyclopedia.
- I said, not now.
- I'm not trying to toot my own horn.
But had Jerry wound up in the
hands of Barnett or Lockhart...
he'd be rapping with Tupac now.
- Morris, I can't help you.
- I know I look good in this suit.
But I'm not an
ass-kissing company man.
- I'm an ass-kissing ER man...
- I said, I can't help you.
- Dr. Weaver, wait.
- Will you listen to me?
You get off the floor. You're
embarrassing yourself.
I don't care. I'm
desperate, please.
Then stop it.
I can't rehire you, because
I am no longer chief of staff.
Third of Narcan.
Still no response.
This isn't an overdose.
- And I need a little cricoid here.
- I got it.
I wasn't talking to you, Gates.
All right, got it.
I'm in, bag him.
Run of 10. Systolic's only 78.
Hundred of lido, half amp
of epi and 50 of mannitol.
He doesn't have a head bleed.
Pratt, we don't know what this is.
Until then, keep your mind open.
- Add a gram of ceftriaxone.
- Throwing the kitchen sink at the guy.
V-tach, no pulse.
- Damn it.
- Starting compressions.
- Strip looks weird.
- Why?
It just doesn't
look right. Look.
Ah. ST depressions and U
waves. He's hypokalemic.
Sam, F 40 of KCL.
All right, charge to 200.
Come on. Clear.
- Still V-tach.
- Resuming.
- What about periodic paralysis?
- What?
- Potassium's in.
- I got it wrong. I had to go look it up.
It's a zebra, Gates.
Three hundred, clear.
Something about
being common in Asians.
Treat with beta
blockers, not KCL.
Metoprolol.
- May I?
- Well, we've got nothing to lose.
Right.
Fifty mgs going in. The condition
could have stopped his breathing.
Okay, holding compressions.
Back in sinus.
Wow, periodic paralysis. Way
to pull that one out of your ass.
Sometimes you have to try
everything. Even the kitchen sink, huh?
Pratt, call the ICU.
Stay with him until
he gets upstairs.
- I need to talk to you.
- No, Morris.
No, it's an emergency.
I mean, not like an "emergency"
emergency, but it's important.
- Find me later.
- I want...
- I need my job back.
- Later.
They didn't have sugar,
so I brought the fake stuff.
They don't allow coffee in here.
No one's looking.
You know, um...
when Eric was
about 3 months old...
he got this really terrible
strain of pneumonia...
and ended up in the ICU.
Do you remember that
at all? You were so little.
His kidneys were shutting
down, and the doctors said...
he wasn't gonna make it.
Oh.
Your father and I fought
because he wanted us all...
to say goodbye to him.
He even dressed you up and
brought you down to the hospital.
Don't you remember any of that?
Well, I wouldn't stand for it.
I didn't care what the doctors said.
It didn't matter what the doctors said.
I wouldn't give up. I couldn't.
Ma, I'm not like you. I
think we've proven that.
Yes, you are.
Yes, you are, Abby.
You are like me.
You have to find the strength
to get Joe through this...
so you can take
him home with you.
I don't know if I can.
Oh, Abby, you've spent your whole
life getting strong enough to do this.
- Hey, Abby.
- Yeah?
I know the Fludrozalone trial scares
you, and trust me, it scares me too, but...
No, stay.
Sometimes the long shot, you
know, that weird kitchen-sink thing...
sometimes...
Sometimes it really works.
- What if something goes wrong?
- What if it goes right?
We can't take it back.
I know that.
Okay, let's do it.
I hope you're right.
Day of life, 15. Day seven
of the Fludrozalone protocol.
Baby's off pressors.
Weight's up.
Thirty-seven grams.
Excellent.
DC the antibiotics.
Decrease the labs to q.o.d.
And Baby Joe is now
officially a feeder and a grower.
We'll take that as compliment.
He's so alert. Look at him.
- Eyes wide open.
- Yeah.
- I wonder what he's thinking.
- Get a life, Mom.
Oh, gee, thanks.
You haven't been out of here...
for more than a few hours
over the past two weeks.
- Two of you go away for a while.
- I don't know.
I'm here.
That's obnoxious.
The nurses keep yakking.
- Well, you could just ask them to stop.
- Oh, just go.
Let's take a walk.
It will do us good.
You're leaving her here?
She'll be okay.
Has anyone got any tape?
How far was the gun from him?
About 10 inches or so.
That's in the
detective's report.
That's funny because there was no
gunshot residue on Mr. Curtis' body.
In fact, the autopsy shows...
you would have had to have
been at least 5 feet away.
Well, maybe I was
further. It's hard to say.
Big difference between 10
inches and 5 feet, Miss Taggart.
Mr. Evers, can I call you Byron?
You're a very sharp guy.
You got a bright
future ahead of you.
You think your boss is gonna
want you chasing your tail...
over a guy who shot up a hospital
and raped this woman here?
Maybe we should call
my boss and ask him.
You think?
I talked to him just this morning, in fact.
We, uh, confirmed our dinner for 7:15.
We go to Gibsons every
second Thursday for the rib eye.
This guy was murdered.
- My job is to prosecute the law...
- We're not talking about the law.
We're talking about time and
money and how you're wasting both.
Now I'm gonna give
you this opportunity...
to drop this right now,
on your own, okay?
Do you want me to handle
it over a steak and a martini?
Have you looked at the mail?
- Nothing too urgent.
You should maybe
check the electric bill...
because the water
was cold this morning.
How's it going?
Hey.
It's a little bit better today.
- Just get off?
- Yeah, I'm exhausted.
I'm gonna go and grab some dinner
at Ike's and then go home and crash.
Hang in there. ABBY: You too.
How's she doing at work?
Seems to be fine.
- She's still in your place?
- Yeah.
She hasn't found anything.
I'm never there. I
should just give it up.
Well, you don't have to
make any decisions right now.
But we're a family. We can't
just keep having slumber parties.
Have you thought
about what I asked you?
I have.
Uh, and I haven't.
It's okay.
I'll convince you later.
We have a great life together.
I don't need a ring or a white
dress to prove that I love you.
I'll take love.
We can save marriage for later.
Luka.
I hope she's okay.
Who? Neela?
The NICU nurse. Your
mother was driving her crazy.
Excuse me. Something's beeping.
- Not anymore.
- Well, you didn't even look at him.
Sat wasn't picking up.
It happens all the time.
Uh...
Excuse me.
Uh, something's wrong.
Dr. Raab needs to take a look.
Miss Wyczenski, the team's in Radiology.
They'll come by when they're done.
Well, that could take hours.
If you overreact to every
little blip and bleep...
you'll make yourself crazy.
Well... - Page Dr. Raab. - What?
Why isn't anyone listening to
me? Page Dr. Raab, page Dr. Raab.
- I'm not supposed to.
- His belly's too big.
- His breathing's too fast.
- You need...
Don't tell me to calm down. I
don't care what Dr. Raab is doing.
She needs to get down here
and take care of my grandson now.
They're putting
the tube back in.
- He's bradying down to 70.
- Miller, 130.
- Mean BP, only 24.
- What happened?
- I knew something was wrong.
- Okay, what happened?
Bolus, 20 cc's, and
.2 of epi ready to go.
He was blue, Abby.
- Luka?
- Free air in the abdomen.
- He perfed?
- Good thing your mom was watching.
Is this because of
the Fludrozalone?
- No way of knowing.
- This could be fixed in surgery.
Spontaneous intestinal
perf is one of the risks.
It's one of the things
that happens to preemies.
Check his breath sounds. It can
be many possible explanations.
- It doesn't matter.
- It matters to me.
Dr. Anspaugh's
waiting in the O.R.
Okay, he's all yours.
What's happening?
Where are you taking him?
We'll remove any damaged tissue
and attempt a primary anastamosis.
No Residents. We don't want
any Residents cutting on this baby.
Call the chaplain
and have him meet us.
- You don't have to do that.
- You wanted the baby baptized.
You said it was important to
your family. Call the chaplain.
- Ready, one, two, three.
- Two, three, face off.
- She's a pro.
- One more.
Ugh!
That's what I'm talking about.
- That's what I'm talking about.
- All right, I've gotta go.
No, we'll walk you out.
It's okay.
- Whoa, careful.
- I think we need to get you a cab.
No. Why don't you go and
play some pool or something?
- Pool.
- Why would we play pool?
You want fries or onion rings?
- Vegetables.
You drank a milk
shake an hour ago.
You're not driving, are you?
- No, I'm not.
- Then we'll take good care of you.
- Oh, come on.
Boys, back to the
frat house. I got this.
- Dude, you got a problem?
- No, she's a friend of mine.
- Right, doc?
- Yes.
Thank you. He's
gonna take me home.
- Oh, thanks a lot.
- You little bitch.
What did you say?
Tony, easy, man.
Tony. Easy, man, easy.
All right. Okay, okay.
- He gets the message.
- All right, I got it.
All right, I got it. I got it.
We're gonna leave.
And, uh, you fellas
are gonna go home...
and sleep it off or
whatever you wanna call it.
Dissect free the vessels
to the diseased ileum.
Isolated. Mixter clamp.
Systolic's only 22.
I'm bolusing again.
We thank you, God, for the support
and skill that surrounds and sustains life.
Mobilize the hepatic flexure.
We are thankful that we
are known to you by name...
Careful. I don't want him
third-spacing all over the place.
No, really.
- You didn't have to do this.
- I know.
Are you a boxer?
You know, you should go to bed.
Oh, you can sleep
when you're dead.
That rhymes.
- Beer?
- No, thanks.
Neela, the last thing you
need right now is another drink.
You know...
You've got a mean left hook.
I like that in a man.
Do you like Sergio Mendes?
I don't really know.
I used to think he was really
corny, but his album is really cool.
Neela, you are gonna have
such a headache in the morning.
- Ow! Ow.
- All right.
I have to go, okay?
Zadro's still in the rig.
- Oh, he can come up too.
- No, no, no.
You'll lay down
and I'll leave, okay?
- No, please don't go.
- I have to go.
I'm sorry.
I don't wanna be alone.
Is there anyone you can call?
I don't have anyone.
Check his status. MAN:
Repeat ABGs. 6.98, all metabolic.
I can't do this. I can't pretend
everything's gonna be okay.
Abby, all the bad things
you've seen, let it go.
I can't believe I let
myself get talked into...
Stop it.
I spent a month in the NICU.
- I know how this ends.
- Abby.
You have a lot of great qualities,
but optimism is not one of them.
- Whose fault is that?
- Yeah.
All right.
I did not create a good
environment for a child to grow up...
believing things would work out.
But you're not a
child any longer.
You're the mother now.
And that baby down there needs
you to believe he's gonna be okay.
Bradying down to the 60s.
Another round of epi.
- Guys, he's gray.
Point-two of epi.
Four hundred of calcium,
10 cc's of fam now.
God, I'm trying. I'm
really, really trying.
I'm trying.
Hey, cath lab's waiting
on your Rollerblader.
You need to finish the chart.
Where are you going?
I'm going to get beer. It looks
like Weaver ordered lemonade.
- For graduation?
- Yeah.
She's no fun since
she's been demoted.
I thought Kovac was gonna
take the flak for everything.
- I guess it all came down on Weaver.
- Lucky us.
Hey, um, have
you talked to Abby?
I think they want
privacy for a while.
Okay.
- Tell her we miss her, okay?
- Okay.
- The paint has streaks.
- Streaks?
I don't see any streaks.
If you stand here in the light,
you can see it has streaks.
- Neela, what's it look like?
- I see streaks.
Hey, Mayday.
- How are you?
- Great.
Look, I'm really embarrassed...
Don't. I'm glad it was
me that took you home.
Jones, this is for you.
McCrary, this is for you.
Intern orientation.
I wouldn't wish it on anyone.
- Yeah.
What are you doing here?
Yo, Gates.
Want me to take this or put
this in the lost and found for you?
Oh, I don't do the whites.
I'm into natural fibers.
You know, Gates,
you've always bugged me.
But you're in my ER now,
so put on the damn coat.
- You're a new intern?
- Mm-hm.
- Did my last paramedic shift yesterday.
- You're kidding me.
Guys, get your photos
taken for your new ID badges.
I look forward to working
under you, Dr. Rasgotra.
Anyone hear from Jerry? He
was supposed to be discharged.
Just spoke to him, he's getting a
massage from a home-care nurse.
Your big daddy called.
Wants you to meet him.
Really?
Courtesy of Maxanoxx.
Oh, come on, buck up, Morris.
Be glad you don't have to spend
summer teaching pelvics to the interns.
- No, you're lucky, Pratt.
- Yeah, right.
I clean vomit from my
shirt while you fly first class.
Corporate jet, actually.
Sounds corny, but I never
appreciated how great it is...
- to have a job that really matters.
- That suit matters, Morris.
That day with Jerry
was so terrible...
but also kind of the best
moment of my life, you know?
Look at me now. It's so silly.
Well, you know,
you're doing a service.
I mean, you're educating
the medical community for...
Oh, it's a load of crap,
Greg. We all know it, okay?
I sold out to the man.
- I guess you never spoke to Kovac.
- He didn't return my calls.
Well, he is pretty
preoccupied these days.
I guess I can always try
doing this somewhere else.
At least I figured out what's important. I
know I wanna practice medicine again.
I gotta go do my thing for
the Critical Care Department.
I'll see you around.
- All right, man.
- That waffle-iron thief left AMA.
- Hey, you know where Kovac is?
- No.
What are you doing here?
Well, the DA determined
it's justifiable homicide.
This is over.
I can't believe it.
Every day I keep thinking
they're gonna come arrest me.
Well, stop worrying about it.
Just focus on Alex, hm?
You talked to him about it?
Uh, he knows his dad is gone, but
I need to talk to him more about it.
You're a good mom.
I just want to tell
you that in person.
Anything else you need...
The key here is the
glucuronyl side group...
which gives Maxanoxx higher
specificity for the Alpha 1 receptor.
Why invest in a course of Maxanoxx
when we have cheaper drugs...
for pulmonary edema
that are effective?
Well, you'll see here that a subgroup
of patients had .4 fewer ICU days.
But there was no difference
in the overall outcome.
Do you know what one day
in the ICU costs taxpayers?
I mean, this hospital, society.
Morris, may I speak
to you out here now?
Not a good time, Dr. Pratt.
Uh, you'll save money
in the long run. Trust me.
It's an emergency.
Excuse me a moment.
What? What is it?
Can't you see I'm working?
Kovac is gonna
offer you the job.
- Oh! Oh.
- Hey.
You know what, stick with
Lasix. Maxanoxx is a scam.
You know, it's great Kovac
offered Morris that Attending spot.
Well, he's like a stray dog.
He'd just keep coming back.
You know that
blunt chest trauma?
I stuck a needle in the heart. Got
half a liter out of the pericardium.
- That's not bad for an intern.
- Well, I had a good teacher.
Have you two met?
Oh, yeah, I've seen you around.
Hey, I'm Tony Gates, intern.
Ray Barnett, R3.
Maybe you can show me how
to do an open pericardial window.
I could show you how to do that.
If you'll excuse me.
You know, I hear
she had a roommate.
Never tried to sleep with her.
What a dill weed.
- So can I call you Kerry now?
- I don't think so.
Why? We're colleagues,
we're contemporaries.
Hey, no touch, no touch.
- Luka.
- Hey.
- Sorry I'm late.
- I didn't think you were gonna make it.
I had to see it for myself.
Archie Morris and Greg Pratt.
- Attendings, huh?
- Is Abby coming?
Uh, she wanted
to, but not tonight.
How's she holding up?
She's okay. She's doing okay.
It's almost time.
Call a cab?
It will be here any minute.
So, uh...
When are you coming back?
Oh, my God, is
that an invitation?
I guess it is, yeah.
I mean, the, uh, signs and the
notes were a little crazy, but, uh...
I couldn't have gotten
through this without you.
Oh, you would have found a way.
You're a fighter.
You've been fighting me
since the day you were born.
I'd say, "Honey, wear the cute, little
pink dress," so you wear the jeans.
I'd say, "What a nice little drawing
you've done," and you'd throw it.
I told you to be a lawyer
and you became a doctor.
My greatest hope would
be this little guy causes you...
as much agony and
pain as you've caused me.
It would serve you right.
- I gotta go.
- Uh, hey.
You don't have to
go today, you know?
You'll be fine.
Mom?
I love you.