Previously, on
"The Resident"...
You guys must have a name
- picked out by now.
- Giorgiana Grace Hawkins.
Conrad Hawkins?
There's been an accident.
Brought your favorite person.
Ready?
Almost.
Will the candy really
run out?
Not a chance.
Daddy?
- Yes, Bubble?
- You got me
- the best costume ever.
- Oh, mm...
♪ It's just another
daydream... ♪
Which ones do you like?
I like all of them.
You only have two feet,
Bubble.
These socks are sparkly.
For tonight.
Okay. That's a good call
on the sparkles.
This restaurant we're going to
is pretty fancy, huh?
- I know what I'm gonna have.
- Oh, yeah?
I'm gonna have spaghetti
and ice cream.
Mr. Giraffe will, too.
Oh, well,
I don't know about that.
What's that on your finger?
This? Just a scratch.
I'm okay.
I'll get the first aid kit.
♪ Now I'm spinning ♪
♪ I'm spinning in a dream ♪
♪ Drift off
to another place... ♪
There. All better.
Mm, thank you.
Looks like someone has
her mother's touch, huh?
Are you going to the hospital
where Mommy used to work?
Ah, you remember, sweetie.
I don't work at the hospital
anymore.
I have a private practice now,
because I want to spend
more time with you
and Mr. Giraffe.
- Oh, look who's here.
- There she is!
- Maggie!
- Hi!
Hey. How are you?
Her bag for the park
is ready to go.
Call me anytime.
Thank you.
I will see you tonight
for our dinner date.
Mwah!
Have a great day at work.
- Let's go to the park.
- Thank you.
I think you might be
the first cover boy I ever slept with.
Oh.
Well, congratulations.
You know, if you liked that,
I'll be on CNN tonight.
- Hmm.
- 8:05 hit time.
Sorry,
I don't really watch TV.
My Lyft is here.
It's good to see you again.
Good to see you again.
Good morning.
Yes, it is.
Someone's in a good mood.
- Mwah.
- Another night at Dr. Austin's?
One text led
to another.
So, you both, uh,
working late again today?
- Yes.
- Yeah.
Have a good day.
You, too.
Dr. Bell?
Sorry to interrupt.
I can see
you're meditating.
Sorry.
I'm Rachel Plec's daughter.
I just, I wanted to thank you
for helping her.
You are a miracle worker, truly.
Yeah, well, your mother was
a very strong woman.
She...
she never gave up.
And neither did we.
Well, so, Dr. Austin works here,
too, right?
Could you maybe get him
to sign this?
Ladies and gentlemen,
thank you for being here
for the Warrior MMA Bantamweight
Main title Fight Weigh-In.
Dr. Voss.
Thanks for coming.
Of course.
How's the elbow feeling?
Still tender
when I make a fist.
Remember to do
your forearm stretches tonight
for better blood flow.
- I will.
- Mm-hmm.
Wish me luck tomorrow.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
...with her
last two fights ending in TKOs...
If this is about my clothes
creeping onto your side
of the closet again,
I'm not going to apologize.
No, I've made a complete and
total surrender on that front,
believe me.
Wise. But that's
not why you're calling me.
I hope you're having fun
at the weigh-in.
Well, with Hayes retiring,
I would like to be considered
for chief of surgery.
Looking to pull
a Grover Cleveland.
I know I've done
the job before,
but it just hit me
I still have a lot to offer,
and...
I think I need to show some of
these other doctors what's what.
Oh, I'll consider you,
but there are other candidates.
And remember, this is me as CEO
and not your partner.
Of course.
We'll talk later.
Bye, honey.
Dr. Sutton.
How many times
do I have to call you
because these ICU doctors
won't give my patients
enough pain meds?
Look, I know
it's not your fault, Kit,
but this is your hospital,
and if my patients
can't get relief...
- It complicates their recovery.
- You want to go right now?
- Let's go.
- That's all you know how to do.
- Come on. Come on, let's go.
- Talk, talk, talk...
How do you expect me
to do my job
when not everyone
is doing theirs?
I've got to go.
*THE RESIDENT*
Season 05  Episode 06
Episode Title: "Ask Your Doctoro"
Aired on: November 09, 2021.
I just feel like crap, you know?
Relax.
By the time the stock price settles,
we'll be all cashed out.
Can you
be more specific?
I don't know, like, headache,
heart was racing, stomach hurts.
What? No.
I'm talking to my doctor.
Yeah, doctor.
No, it's not serious.
Is it serious?
That's what I'm trying
to find out.
Trust me, that's not
gonna be a long-term trend.
We'll just see how things
play out in after-hours trading.
Blood
pressure's elevated.
My 11:15 just got moved up.
I got a gut feeling about
this pitch, man... who knows,
this time next year,
we could be riding a unicorn.
Mr. Nye...
Hey, they can waste
all the money they want
so long as it's not mine, right?
He'll call you back.
Your symptoms are likely being
caused by elevated tyramine.
An interaction
between what you ate
and your antidepression patch.
If you want to avoid a stroke,
steer clear of the cheeseboards.
Okay.
So... we're done?
- Thank you.
- Yes, sir.
You feeling okay?
I'm a doctor, so...
You don't look like a doctor.
Yeah, well,
I did struggle on the MCATs,
but I am a doctor.
You work here?
In the kitchen, yeah.
Let me guess,
vegetable did you in.
You should see
the turnip, right?
I can take a look if you want.
Don't bother.
I, uh...
I got diagnosed with cancer
a few months ago.
It's in my chest
and my lungs.
Sorry to hear that.
Doctor says
I have a year, tops.
So, this cut isn't
my biggest problem.
Diagnosis sucks,
but I don't want you
to lose your finger
on top of that, so...
That wound is more
than I can treat here,
but... let me take you
to a hospital nearby.
No, no. I...
I'm still paying the doctor
who told me I'm a dead man.
I got a kid to think about.
It's a public hospital.
They won't leave you in debt,
I promise.
How can you be sure?
Used to work there.
About me and your sister,
I hope it's not too weird
for you.
You mean the fact that
you've basically seen me naked?
Great. Thanks.
I didn't think about that.
Don't worry,
I could not care less.
You know, you and your sister
are very different.
Padma said
before she came to Atlanta,
she was a guide
on the Appalachian Trail.
Yep.
And before that,
she was leading
a wellness retreat
for rich people to de-stress
in beautiful places.
Oh, well, I could use that
right about now.
30-year-old female.
130/90.
Blunt trauma to the back.
Man, she sucker-punched me.
That's what's up.
But y'all gonna see on TV
when I crush that lollipop
in the ring.
She's been like
that all the way here.
All right, on my count.
One, two, three.
Oh, I've seen you before.
- You're a fighter.
- Nah.
I'm just your average three-time
bantamweight MMA champ,
ESPY winner,
Strikeforce, Iron Fist.
You wanted a consult?
Ms. Rodriguez felt paresthesias
in her bilateral
lower extremities.
Man, do you know how many times
I've been hit?
- I'm still here, aren't I?
- Ms. Rodriguez,
I'm Dr. Sutton.
We train just as hard
for these moments as you do
for yours, so be quiet.
I like her.
Airway intact. Pulse is strong.
Can you feel me
touching you here?
Not really.
Hang on. I got something.
Yeah, we have a palpable mass
in the mid-epigastrium.
It shows up on the FAST as well.
CT now.
I'll meet you there.
Congrats on the book.
Oh, thank you.
You read it?
No, no.
Too busy operating,
just gearing up
to be chief again.
Oh. Well, I hear Kit
is still considering candidates.
- Mm.
- I would know. I am one.
I'm surprised
you can find the time,
given all the books
you're signing.
Yeah, well, no one can be
too busy to give Chastain the...
the visionary leader
it so desperately needs.
You know, someone
who's still got that... fire.
Couldn't agree more.
Look who
decided to show his face.
As if anyone could get enough
- of that face.
- Eh...
How long has it been
this time?
Uh, since that asthma patient,
I think.
Aw. That was a month ago.
We miss you.
I miss you guys, too.
Oh, enough to come back?
You never know,
I might sneak
back and torture
you guys again.
Conrad knows as long as I'm CEO,
he always has a place here.
Thank you.
I'm just dropping off a patient,
last name Tellenbaum.
He's in the waiting room.
Jackson Tellenbaum.
Hand injury, huh?
And diagnosed
with metastatic lung cancer
at Atlanta General.
He's been avoiding doctors
since
because he has
no insurance, so...
We'll take care of him.
Who's the new attending?
He looks familiar,
like this intern
- I tried to train.
- Same bit, huh?
I recognize the shoes.
Yeah, well, you know,
unlike you, the rest of us,
you know, we don't have all day,
so bring it in, baby.
- Did you get the office with the shower?
- I did.
It's a necessity
with these hours.
But I will admit,
it is way more fun giving
the orders than getting them,
- especially from you.
- I bet.
I bet.
Good to see everyone.
Whoa, whoa, not so fast,
Mr. Concierge Doctor.
Let's go take a walk.
Here we see champ
Tamiko Rodriguez
getting knocked to the floor
during
- a weigh-in brawl.
- At least I got the shot.
Coming up, we'll show you
what led to it.
Do you have
advanced non-small cell lung cancer?
What if you
didn't have to give up?
What if you could live longer?
Halcipride could give you
good days.
Happy days.
More days.
Ask your doctor
if Halcipride is right for you.
Chemo drugs need to be
prescribed by an oncologist.
I can get you a referral
to someone at Chastain.
Gonna wrap your hand now.
- How long for a referral?
- Usually three or four weeks.
Weeks?
Come on, guys.
The ad said Halcipride
can really help me.
- Hmm?
- And it's here, right?
Can I get a sample?
No, but I can get you
that referral.
Dr. Feldman.
Just sit tight, okay?
Uh...
I need to get
you a tetanus booster.
Be right back.
I only have a minute.
Oh. Good news.
I found
this guerilla taco truck
parked right by Chastain today.
- Want to grab lunch?
- I wish I could.
I have to take notes
for my attending, and then round
- on my post-op patients, so...
- What happened to your cardamom?
You always leave it
by the butter.
I do.
So, you and Dr. Austin,
is that, like...
is that, like, a thing now?
What?! No, definitely not.
I'm just curious.
It is, like,
third time in two weeks, so...
Leel, I came here to see you
and meet Devon two months ago,
and I have basically had
this entire apartment to myself.
So... no, I am not looking
to get serious with a doctor.
Not in this lifetime.
Dr. Devi, DVT waiting on you
in Bay 9.
I'll be with them next.
Hey, I got to go. Bye.
Dr. Voss asked me
to tag in.
Oh, did she?
Yeah, I've reviewed
our MMA champ's records,
and Ms. Rodriguez has
a family history of cancer.
And that abdominal mass
may indicate a lymphoma
or hepatobiliary tumor.
So we'll need our best hands
on hand.
So you joining has nothing to do
with the tweet-storm of love
coming for any of us
who save this superstar?
No, you know, unlike some,
I'm not the kind of surgeon
that needs validation
outside the hospital.
Oh, says the man who had
his own surgical tool,
supplement line and TV show.
- Am I missing anything?
- Gentlemen.
All right, she has
an abdominal aortic aneurysm.
Six centimeters.
And it's likely to rupture,
given her hypertension.
That's odd,
considering we see triple A's
in mostly older men
and smokers.
That's why.
She has bamboo spine.
Ankylosing spondylitis
can often be associated
with triple A.
T3 through L4 is
almost entirely fused together,
with a column 3
unstable fracture at L1.
- It's a miracle she got out of bed.
- Her pain tolerance
- must be off the charts.
- We do a staged repair.
Once you complete
the triple A,
I'll perform a posterior
stabilization and fusion.
I'll join you, Dr. Austin.
Both of us for a triple A?
Is that necessary?
Better safe than sorry.
Fine.
Let's all go break the news.
Pain I can handle,
but ten months of me in bed
while everybody replays
the video
of me getting knocked
on my ass?
You won't last one round.
Your aneurysm is
on the cusp of rupturing.
And your spine is too brittle.
One punch at the wrong angle,
it could snap your back in half.
So to fix my spine,
you want to break it yourself
and then put it back together
like some LEGO set?
Yeah, find some other toy
to play with.
Leave now,
and the only question
you'll be asking yourself
the next time you hit the floor
is why you didn't listen to us.
Want to replay this moment
in your head
for the rest of your life?
Ms. Rodriguez?
Can I get a photo?
What's your name?
Ella. I want to fight,
like you do.
She seem a little young
for MMA?
And can you come
to my birthday party?
Photo, yes.
Birthday, no.
Say hi to my docs.
They're gonna fix me up
so I can get back in the ring
for you.
Isn't that right?
Sir?
You're not allowed
back here.
Where's the Halcipride?
- H-A-L-C-I...
- You need to leave now.
Nobody's leaving
until I get it.
So, how many Saudi princes
have you treated this week?
That was one patient one time.
- Any Real Housewives?
- Why?
- You want me to get you an autograph?
- Hell yeah.
Look, I just want to be sure
that your talents
aren't being wasted on giving
B12 shots and laxatives
to the rich and famous.
Yeah, most are neither.
Actually, a lot need to pay
on a sliding scale,
or they can't make it
to the hospital
because they have family,
so they just need more flexibility.
Oh.
How's the little lady?
Perfect.
GiGi and I have
a dinner reservation tonight.
Mm. That's nice.
Ah, I can't even remember
the last time
I got off
when the sun was up.
And I bet
you wouldn't change a thing.
There is one thing.
Well, we had
some good times here.
Yeah.
Yeah, we did.
I think about you guys
all the time.
It's actually annoying how much
I think about you guys.
Well, you're
a big concierge now.
So I want some dinner
reservations, concert tickets.
- Hey, everything all right?
- Got a code silver.
Time to shake off a little rust.
- What's going on?
- It's the patient you brought in.
He was asking about
some cancer drug he saw on TV.
I told him
I couldn't just give it to him.
It's out of stock anyway.
And now he's blockaded himself
in there with the pharmacists.
He won't let anyone out
until he gets the drug.
And he has a weapon.
Atlanta PD are on the way.
Conrad, who is this guy?
I just met him today.
He needed help.
I brought him in.
What-what drug?
Halcipride. New targeted therapy
for stage IV lung cancer.
I read the outcomes.
It costs, like,
five grand a week
and only gives patients
a couple of extra weeks at best.
I've seen the ads. They make it
seem like a cure when it isn't.
For a desperate man, who knows
what he'll do for more time?
I'm not sure
what Jackson's gonna do
when the police show up,
but my instinct says
he's not dangerous to anyone.
I think I can keep things
from going from bad to worse.
Hold on.
You're not going in there alone.
Jackson's my patient.
I brought him in.
So just...
just let me handle it.
Someone has got to be with you
in there to have your back.
Even if I agree to this,
he won't let anyone in
without the drug,
and it's still on its way
from Atlanta General.
But he doesn't know that.
Jackson, it's Dr. Hawkins.
We got Halcipride.
Three-month supply, okay?
Jackson?
Slide it through the door.
You gotta let them go.
Bring it in, then they go.
Okay.
Are you all right?
Okay, toss me the bag.
Them first.
Fine. Go.
- You back up!
- Whoa. All right.
Give me the bag.
What the...
No. What the hell is this?!
- No, you stop.
- Hold on.
Hand me the blade
and we can talk.
We just want
to try to help.
Jackson, easy, easy.
The drug is coming.
Let's just talk.
Let's find a way out of this
before the police get here.
Okay?
You said
you got a kid, right?
Boy or girl?
I've got a son.
He's almost eight.
He lives in Iowa
with his mom now.
I've just been trying
to sock away money
since the split, just...
give him the things
that I never had.
But I can't make things right
unless I get more time.
Jackson, getting cancer was
out of your control.
But what you do now,
that is up to you.
I said I'd make
sure you left here whole.
Help me
keep that promise.
Mr. Tellenbaum,
this is Atlanta PD.
Is everything okay in there?
Thank you
for trying to help me.
I didn't have much time
anyway.
No.
Hey, can we get
some help in here?
Over here in Trauma Bay One.
He took out part
of his internal jugular,
but he missed the carotid.
I'll get access.
Get me an 18-gauge.
All right, and type and cross
four units right away.
Jackson? Jackson?
Jackson, you with us?
He's in hemorrhagic shock.
Can't tamponade the bleeding
without impeding
the venous return;
he needs an OR.
- Heart rate 130.
- We don't have time to stabilize him.
Xavier, page Vascular
and Anesthesia.
- He's coming to the OR now.
- Let's go.
- I got it.
- Take it.
Let's go. Transport!
I'll maintain pressure.
Get the elevator.
This way, Officers.
- I got fresh clothes in my office.
- Thank you.
All right, we got, what,
four hours before he's out
of surgery and under arrest?
Let's come up with
a treatment plan,
try and buy this guy some
more time to see his family.
And I'll get his medical
record from Atlanta General.
Good.
On your way to
an emergency surgery, I hear.
Indeed I am.
Neck versus box cutter.
Yeah, vascular repair
like that's gonna take
maybe three, four hours.
Well, don't you worry about it,
Randolph,
I will make our triple A.
Oh, there's no need to rush.
I can take good care
- of our prizefighter myself.
- I'm sure you can.
Are you okay?
I'm pretty sure there's still
blood in places I can't see,
but yeah.
Well, I'm glad you're okay.
I am now.
Oh! You guys
should probably close the door
- if you're gonna, you know...
- What are you doing here?
I brought lunch. Also...
I got scolded by a Dr. Nolan
on the way in here.
And can I just say, I don't like
the way he talks to you.
I don't see how anyone
can mix you two up.
I mean, you're spontaneous
- and-and carefree, and you're...
- Oh.
...the love of my life.
What did Dr. Nolan say
to you, exactly?
Something about neph.
Nephews?
Necrophilia, maybe.
I don't know. Sorry.
But I remember his tone,
and he reminded me
of Uncle Ojasvat. He was mean.
This is why I don't like when
you just show up randomly.
Because somehow it always
makes more work for me.
- Leela...
- Thank you for lunch.
It's been a day.
She'll be all right.
Hey. You can keep it.
Thanks.
Jackson's medical records.
- Oh, nice.
- If he's EGFR positive,
we can consider afatinib.
Unless he has
an additional mutation.
Yeah, T790M.
Then we add...
- Osimertinib.
I forgot how much fun you two
are when you get together.
I'll start by reconfirming
the pathology report
and the genetics of the cancer
and see whether he's a candidate
for targeted therapy.
Sounds like a plan.
Keep me posted.
Oh, wait. Hold on a second.
Look at this lung biopsy report.
Necrosis compatible with
necrotic tumor tissue.
Compatible with,
not diagnostic of.
So, because he had
a lesion in his spine,
enlarged lymph nodes
and a lung nodule...
They concluded
it was cancer.
Have you seen
his fingernails?
Yeah.
When was the last time
you saw a stage IV
metastatic lung cancer patient
without clubbing?
It happens, but rarely.
I think it's possible that
Jackson doesn't have cancer.
It's possible.
It's also a leap.
I'm just saying
it's worth digging deeper.
Maybe
he was misdiagnosed.
- I got the page.
- Her aneurysm ruptured.
She's struggling
to move her legs.
Cauda equina syndrome.
- Is your schedule clear?
- I'll clear it.
Let's do this.
So if it's not cancer,
Jackson's issue could be autoimmune.
Inflammatory. Vasculitis.
- We're missing an infection.
- Histoplasmosis.
Could explain his lung nodules,
but he has no history of travel
the past few years.
Okay, then that would also
eliminate blastomycosis,
coccidiomycosis.
Yep, but doesn't rule out
abscesses.
Right.
Okay, so, we have
three possibilities,
all treatable.
Yep. We add tests
to his pre-op labs,
get the rest drawn in the OR.
How much time do you have before
your dinner date with Queen Gi?
Uh, hour and a half.
Two, tops.
All right, I'll rush
these tests.
Dr. Bell.
Finished already?
Fast and flawless, as always.
Shall we?
Bovie to me.
I have the better angle.
Chu, angle the
head down 15 degrees.
I prefer we keep it at ten.
Uh, 13 it is.
Resecting the aneurysm.
Dr. Chu, would you wake me up
when Dr. Austin is finished
so I can insert the graft?
You boys done?
Just finished.
Randolph.
AJ.
She's all yours, Dr. Sutton.
I have a break in my schedule.
You mind if I stick around
and watch you do your thing?
Plenty of seats.
Uckle up.
All right, pedicle screws
and rods on my left.
Osteotomes, burr, rongeurs
on my right.
Let's get the Wilson frame
and flip her.
Hey.
What's so important you needed
to see me right now?
Tell me what you think. Ha!
The guy who just sold it to me
drove it around the Badlands
for three months.
It already has a bed,
fridge, stove and...
...two solar panels.
Check it out.
You're gonna live in that?
Yeah. Lots of people are
living the van life now.
It gives you total freedom.
And this thing is so cozy.
Padma...
I'm thinking Charleston, maybe,
and then the Keys.
I know you don't get
that much time...
How long can you keep
doing this?
Doing what?
Exactly.
What are you doing?
I...
Look, I know this seems
like it's fun and everything,
but don't you think it's time
you put down some roots?
Or maybe a root?
You know what,
forget it.
I'll check it out later.
I threw your milk out last week.
It was five months old.
And I would have noticed sooner
if I wasn't lacto.
What's your point?
When was the last time
you even had a meal at home?
- We order in.
- To the apartment you're never at?
With the boyfriend
you never see?
- I see Devon all the time.
- At work.
Where you always are.
When I first came to Atlanta,
I was only gonna crash
with you a few weeks.
I stayed because I love you.
And, Leel, you don't eat.
You barely sleep.
- All you talk about is medicine!
- That's the job.
I'm a doctor.
I'm literally saving lives.
And what about your life?
Look, Leel,
I am so proud of you.
You do things every day
that I can't even pronounce.
But I remember a girl who did
a lot of other things, too.
She dreamed up crazy cartoons
and went shopping for
the ugliest antiques
we could find.
Do you have any idea
how hard it is for me
to do what I do in there
every single day?
But I'm doing it, Padma.
When was the last time you took
even five minutes for yourself?
You gotta go.
Hey.
Aw... I remember that look.
Lab results were negative.
For all three and the cultures?
I'll take that to him, thanks.
All right,
so we broaden our search.
Check a glucan
and galactomannan.
Look for brucellosis,
actinomycosis.
I will keep searching.
You have a dinner date
with a very special lady.
Let me know.
I will. Come on,
I'll walk you out.
Hang on a sec.
Does he look
hyper-pigmented to you?
I remember that look.
Last pedicle screw.
Now we finish the fusion
and realign vertebrae.
I heard you and Bell
are competing.
Well, I wouldn't call it
much of a competition.
My two cents?
The best chiefs command
the most respect of their peers.
That's you.
Thanks for the two cents.
Besides, I've heard
a few stories.
Probably more skeletons
in his closet than yours,
if you ask me.
We're losing motor signals.
Her spinal
cord is getting impinged.
Pituitary rongeurs.
- Everything okay?
- Just trying to find the source.
Could be a bone fragment.
Oh, this isn't working.
She'll be permanently
paralyzed soon
if we don't relieve
the pressure on her cord.
What's the move?
A Hail Mary.
But I'll need an extra
set of hands. Page Dr. Voss.
They told me motor signals
went out.
Sensory signals, too.
I need to bring her out
of anesthesia.
The wake-up test?
She could move
and disrupt the instruments
in her back,
causing even more damage.
It's our only shot
at finding out
if her loss of signal is related
to a dislodged probe
or another issue.
We're running out of time.
Lighten anesthesia.
Pulling back on the propofol.
Tamiko?
This is Dr. Sutton.
You're in surgery.
Don't worry,
everything will be okay.
We just need your help.
Blink if you understand.
Good.
Now blink if you can feel
a touch on your right leg.
Hang tight, okay?
We can't keep her awake
for long, but I think
we should perform a distraction.
And improve the correction
of the spine.
Worth a shot.
- Distractor's in place.
- I'll loosen the locking bolt.
Let's push.
Let's try that again.
Blink if you can feel
a touch on your leg.
Signal's coming back.
Nerve pressure's relieved.
You did great.
Now we're gonna put you
back to sleep and finish up.
That was quite the show,
Dr. Sutton.
Show's not over yet.
A full exam after surgery
will tell us more.
Ask your doctor if Halcipr...
Guess I won't be running through
the fields anytime soon.
These ads don't do our patients
any favors.
There's a reason almost every
other country in the world
bans them.
But when the FDA eased
restrictions in the '90s,
drug companies jumped at
the chance to market their drugs
to as many people as they could.
So all too often, they present
biased or incomplete
information.
And mislead people
to ask their doctors
for drugs they don't even need.
And no drug is
for everyone.
And Halcipride, hmm,
that drug...
that drug won't help you,
Jackson.
Because
you don't have cancer.
Your labs
confirmed our suspicion.
You were misdiagnosed.
What you really have
is tuberculosis.
H-How?
TB can look a lot
like cancer,
and it can travel anywhere,
even your spine.
And it can travel
to your adrenal gland.
That's what caused your skin
to darken.
Which is what tipped us off.
The best news is
we can treat it.
Thank you.
So you're gonna need to be
on several medications, okay,
for the next six months.
How much is that gonna cost?
We checked. It's affordable.
Once you're discharged,
you'll be put under arrest,
but until then,
you're still a patient,
so let's focus on
you getting well, okay?
Thank you.
Look, I get why you left,
but I just feel like,
you know, this is what
you were meant to be doing.
Ah, I miss it, man. I do.
It wasn't my plan to leave,
but GiGi is my everything.
She's waiting for our dinner.
I can make it.
She comes first now.
I'm so sorry.
I mean, for all of it.
Just know that
you and Nic
are... missed every day.
Good work today,
Dr. Hawkins.
You, too, Dr. Pravesh.
You, too.
Night, Devi.
- Hey.
Do you have five minutes?
Sure. Why?
♪ I got the feeling,
I got the feeling of love ♪
♪ High on the feeling,
high on the feeling above ♪
♪ Up on the feeling,
up on the feeling of love ♪
♪ I got it, I got it ♪
♪ I got the thing,
ooh, you got me feeling good ♪
♪ Feeling, feeling good. ♪
All right.
- She's still got it.
- That's impressive.
You won't be
back in the ring for a while,
- but you will be back.
- Good.
'Cause that lollipop
that put me here
needs a lickin'.
I know you're both eager
to find out
who our next chief of surgery
will be,
so I'll cut to the chase.
It won't be either of you.
- Are you serious?
- Excuse me?
You've both made remarkable
contributions to Chastain.
But for you, AJ,
chief would just be
another feather in your cap.
And, frankly,
you don't have the time.
And, Randolph, you've already
done the job once.
Yeah, which means
I have experience,
which is hardly
a detriment to...
And you quit because
you didn't like it.
It was too time-consuming
and bureaucratic.
- You want to cut.
- True that.
You only wanted the job because
you didn't want me to have it.
No, I-I wanted it because...
I wanted it.
Gentlemen, I respect that
you're both competitive
and in it to win,
but I have made my decision.
An unfortunate one,
no doubt,
but one I will respect
nonetheless.
Thank you, AJ.
Well, maybe it's for the best.
How so?
Because there's a woman
that I've been seeing
for a while now, and, uh,
we kind of have
a good thing going.
- I-I think she'd agree.
- Would she?
A little less time spent at work
might mean more time with her,
if she can get away.
I'm afraid that safety report
on her desk
might keep her late tonight.
She's worth waiting up for.
If it's not me and it's not AJ,
who's the next chief of surgery?
Me?
You're a tireless,
if sometimes bossy,
advocate for patients.
But I expect nothing less.
You're also a leader,
and you work well with others.
You will build consensus,
not bully.
A style I like.
I'm certainly flattered...
Of course, the admin burdens
are not insignificant.
You'll have to adjust
your surgical schedule,
manage fragile egos
across the department...
Not always an easy task...
But you would have a real hand
in shaping this place.
Of course, if you need
more time to...
I'm in.
Good.
So, exactly how cozy
is this thing?
Only one way to find out.
- All right.
- Be careful.
It's really cool.
Look, about earlier...
You're not wrong.
I know. But do you really
want to take advice
from a girl who lives in a van?
Well, you'll be happy to know
I have tomorrow off.
- All day?
- All day.
♪ Lane between here ♪
♪ And the Tennessees... ♪
- I drive, you sleep.
- Okay.
♪ Unassuming ♪
♪ I could stand ♪
♪ To be the one ♪
♪ If we're so unassuming ♪
♪ You could stand
to be the one. ♪
Hey.
How was she?
Perfect, as always.
- Daddy!
- Ah!
Oh, sweetheart.
See you next time.
Mmm...
Welcome to Le Petit GiGi.
Mademoiselle,
please take your seat.
- Here's to our new chief.
- Good for her.
- And good luck to her.
- It's a thankless job.
- I should know. I did it.
- All that paper pushing.
- Departmental complaints.
- Managing inferior surgeons.
- No, thank you.
- We are beyond that.
- Yes, we are.
- To us.
- Ah.
I thought, just this once...
Ice cream!
Oui.
- Yes, please.
- Mmm.
So...
what did you do today?
Learned how to draw
a rhinoceros.
You did?
Oh...
Mm, yes. I see.
Hmm, well done.
How was your day, Daddy?
It's the best day I had
in a long time.
Captioning sponsored by
20th CENTURY FOX TELEVISION
and TOYOTA.
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
Sync corrections by srjanapala