Dr. Marcel exemplifies
the selfless dedication
we here at Gaffney pride
ourselves on.
Confident, creative,
future of medicine, this guy.
Do you ever wonder
what it would have been like
if they hadn't made us
put Vanessa up for adoption?
I made it
very clear to Grant
that I am not interested
in reconnecting with him.
You felt the need
to tell him that?
I didn't want there
to be any confusion.
Samir offered me
a spot on his team.
In the Philippines?
This is my calling.
It's been a while.
15 years.
If you have anything
that you want to say to me
after all this time...
I'd like to try
my best to listen.
No, problem.
Come on.
That's what
I'm talking about.
Morning, Ethan.
Morning, Hannah.
Hey, I'm gonna
hit the showers.
I'll grab you a juice.
Thanks.
You two seem to be
getting along.
It's not like that.
We're just friends.
If you say so.
What about you?
How are things with April?
Mmm, to be honest,
it's much easier
the second time around.
It's like we got all the big
arguments out of the way.
That's great.
Yeah.
You know, it turns out,
we were walking down
the same path this entire time
and just didn't know it.
I think with Hannah and I,
our... our paths diverged
a long time ago.
Well, at least you got someone
to spot you in the gym.
Zach, you've got incoming.
You're going to
treatment three.
Okay.
Dr. Charles,
I don't seem to
have an attending
at the moment.
Do you mind looking
after Zach?
Uh, sure.
Cesar, talk to me.
You're going to three.
Renee Chapman, 50 years old.
Neighbors called it in.
Said she fell trying
to scale a fence.
Husband's on his way.
BP 120/80, heart rate 72.
She's experiencing
some mild confusion.
GCS 14 with
a possible head injury.
Whoa, what is this?
Not my fault.
Talk to whoever's
in charge of scrubs.
Zach.
There are no scrubs here.
We're completely wiped out.
At least we still have
patient gowns.
Well, what are we supposed
to do about surgeries?
There's no way to maintain
a sterile environment
in street clothes.
Well, Goodwin's
working on it.
Meanwhile, we're gonna
have to make do
with what we've got.
What about us?
I can't see patients
dressed like this.
Mags, this isn't gonna cut it.
What do you want me to do,
knit you a sweater?
Maybe I've got
a change of clothes in my car.
Actually, why don't we hit
the hospital thrift store?
Maybe we'll find something
presentable.
That's fine, but make it fast.
I want the rest of you
back in the ED now.
Seriously?
Yes, and no complaints.
I'm already short a doctor
with Vanessa gone.
Okay, Ms. Chapman.
Good news is,
your chest X-ray
looks clear.
No rib fractures.
If it's okay with you, I would
like to send you for a head CT
just to be
on the safe side.
Would you mind calling
Radiology to let them
know we're on our way?
I want it out of me.
You want what out of you?
Where's Dr. Blake?
You know, Dr. Blake doesn't
actually work here anymore--
I want it out of me!
What do you want out of you?
It's not mine. Get it...
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Oh, God.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
A little help here?
Get it out of me!
Hank, 5 of Haldol now.
Now.
Get it out!
Here, you can see the areas
of white starting to clear.
I take it that's a good thing?
I'd still like to do
a follow-up chest CT,
but I think your body is
taking well to the new lungs.
Any questions?
Yeah.
What is going on here?
What do you mean?
Well, you're dressed
like one of my engineers.
Believe it or not,
we're out of scrubs.
So, uh... what,
somebody screwed up?
Laundry issue. Every time you
think it can't get worse.
I'm sorry, they need me
downstairs in the ED.
I'll check back
soon, okay?
Thank you, Dr. Marcel.
You bet.
Jack. Okay.
Crockett.
Yeah.
We need to talk
about Baltimore.
Baltimore?
Wait, the transplant
conference?
Mmm-hmm.
They had a keynote drop.
You might want to throw
together some slides.
What's the topic?
Ischemic preconditioning.
Wait, that's--
Pamela Blake.
Apparently,
she had a setback.
Took a leave so she
could return to rehab.
Lucky you.
How come I don't
see any scrubs
coming off this truck?
There was
an electrical short
in the Cicero plant
last night.
Took out a whole
bank of dryers.
But I thought we had backups
in the warehouse.
I don't have
any drivers
available.
You know something?
You are a veritable
laundry list
of excuses today, Harry.
I know that we are
in the process
of negotiating
our new service contract,
but please,
please tell me you're not
holding my scrubs hostage.
Ms. Goodwin,
maybe you should
go talk to your CFO.
For a thrift store,
I didn't do so bad.
I don't know.
I feel like
a bank teller.
No.
I'd say more like a
substitute teacher.
Oh!
Okay, this is ridiculous.
I'm changing back into
my workout clothes.
Help! Help!
What's going on?
We're doctors.
She's having a baby.
Hey,
what's your name?
Maya Safro.
Hi, I'm Dr. Halstead.
Is it okay
if I remove this?
Okay, mind if
I check you out?
Okay, what's your
due date, Maya?
Two weeks around Thanksgiving.
This is your first baby?
Yes. Oh...
Deep breaths.
We'll get you inside so we
can take a look at you.
Are you the father?
I'm her neighbor.
She called me for a ride
when her water broke.
Here we go.
Let me help.
She stabbed herself?
Oh, my God.
Fortunately, we were
able to restrain her
before she did
any real damage.
Mr. Chapman.
Dr. Marcel.
I assisted Dr. Blake
on Renee's kidney transplant.
Oh, of course. I remember.
Where's Dr. Blake?
Unfortunately, she's moved on,
taken a... a new position.
What do we know?
Seems like Renee experienced
some kind of
paranoid delirium.
What, like a, uh,
a psychosis?
Of sorts. Yeah.
Well, this is not
like her at all.
I mean, you can
ask Dr. Marcel.
She has such
an ordered mind.
Mathematician, right?
Yeah, top of her field,
fluids and mechanics.
In fact, she's being
awarded the Abel Prize
in Oslo next month.
Wow.
Seth, can you think of
any changes to her behavior
in the last few months?
Yeah.
It started, like,
about a month ago.
She was confused,
agitated.
Huh.
Hey, Zach.
Did you include
a complete metabolic panel?
Let's also make sure
we get that head CT too.
Yes, sir.
Hey, she's gonna be
all right, right?
Look, we're absolutely
gonna get to the bottom
of this, all right?
Probably just a good idea
to wait for some
of these test results
before we start looking
at next steps.
Any pregnancy complications
we should know about?
Besides some
bizarre cravings,
it's been relatively smooth,
but I just have to say,
I'm, like, itching
like crazy today.
I'd be worried
if you weren't.
At this stage,
your hormones
are running wild,
and itching is totally normal
in a full term pregnancy.
Hey, are you the guy
that brought her in?
Security is about
to tow your van.
What?
Hey, Gus, sorry!
Uh, thanks again!
All right.
I'd like to do
an exam.
Hey, Maya, anyone
you'd like us to call?
Unfortunately not.
I moved down here
for school in the spring,
and all my family's
up in New York.
And the baby's father?
Not in the picture.
Okay.
Aw, I love your socks.
Thank you.
Could you put
your heels more
in the stirrups?
Yes.
All right.
You know, I was gonna hold off
on the sex of the baby,
but I only made it
to week 15.
I just couldn't wait
to meet her.
Well, I've got
good news for you, Maya.
Your wait is over.
You're about six
centimeters dilated,
which means
this little girl
is coming today.
Oh, my God!
Congrats, Maya.
All right, now I'm
gonna do an ultrasound
to check on the baby.
Okay?
Okay.
So Maya, it appears
your baby's breech.
What does...
What does that mean?
It just means that
her head's facing
the wrong direction.
Well, she's gonna
be okay, right?
Oh, yes.
It's very common.
It just means we need
to deliver via C-section.
You mean like surgery?
Yes, but don't worry.
It is totally safe.
And you can be
with us and awake
the entire time
if you want.
Okay. Okay.
Okay. Hey, Doris.
Yeah.
Can we open up
the hybrid OR?
Yeah.
Hey.
Where'd you
get the scrubs?
I do my own laundry.
Every night?
Every night
for precisely
this reason.
Is that some kind
of navy thing,
the way
you were trained?
Flanked by a bunch
of Dudley Do-Rights.
Awesome.
Ethan, Kai, incoming.
Courtney,
you're going
to Baghdad.
Talk to me, Court.
36-year-old inmate stabbed
in the anterior lateral
right neck in County.
Bleeding stopped
with direct pressure.
Intubated en route with sux
and etomidate, GCS 3.
All right, looks like
there's no active bleeding.
Let's get him ready
for a transfer.
Everybody ready?
Ready, one, two, three.
Heart rate 94,
BP 130/87.
Sats 100%.
Breath sounds are bilateral.
Let's get him on a ventilator.
Uh, did I hear something
about an inmate coming in
from Cook County?
Someone get me an X-ray.
Yeah, shanked in the neck.
Oh, you'll love
this coincidence.
His last name is Archer.
Sean Archer.
Yeah, it's a small world.
Yeah.
Wonder who
this guy pissed off.
No active bleeding.
A big old hematoma
in the neck, though.
Here, let me
look at that.
X-ray's here.
Hold.
Hold on. I'm feeling
something in here.
Let's get a neck
X-ray as well.
Make sure there's no
retained foreign body.
Hey, D.
Not now. Not now.
Renee's test results.
Thyroid function is good.
No endocrine problem.
CT head is clean.
Yeah, no family history
of mental illness either.
No?
No.
So far, anyway,
no organic explanation
for Renee's psychosis.
So where does
that leave us?
Wait.
What immunosuppressant
is she on?
Tacrolimus.
Oh, crap.
What?
Cyclosporine wouldn't work?
Well, we tried that
pre-transplant,
but Renee was allergic
to everything in that class.
The tacrolimus
was our last option.
Why do you ask?
We suspect that Renee's
psychosis is being caused
by the immunosuppressant
that she's been taking
to protect her new kidney.
Her tacrolimus?
Are you sure?
We've just about ruled out
every other possibility.
But the surgery
was ten months ago.
As strange
as it might sound,
reactions like this
can occur even...
even years after surgery.
So we should just take her
off her meds then, right?
I wish it were
that easy, Seth.
But without the
immunosuppressants,
Renee's body will reject
the new kidney.
After all this time?
Unfortunately, yes.
So what are we
supposed to do?
Well, the next step would be
to try an antipsychotic.
There's a drug
called olanzapine.
We would like to start her
on a small dose of it
and see if that helps.
Hey, Seth. Don't worry.
We're gonna get this
under control, okay?
Damn.
Looks like the shank
must have broken off
in his neck.
Right, can we get him
up to the OR, please?
What are you standing
around here for?
Just do it.
Tell the OR that
I'm bringing up
the neck exploration, okay?
D.
Yeah, one second.
Sorry, can we get
the shackles off him?
He's not going
anywhere, all right?
Dean, Dean, Dean.
Hey, Dean.
What is it?
Sean's in jail?
Last time I asked,
you said he was out west.
What's going on?
It's a long story.
Okay, I promise I will
get you caught up.
I promise.
Okay.
But I got to go scrub now.
I cannot stand here.
Neil's on call
in trauma today.
Let's let him operate.
He's as good as it gets.
This is my son, Ethan.
Exactly why you shouldn't
be doing the surgery.
Come on, man.
You know I'm right.
All right, hey,
don't worry.
I'll stay with Sean
the whole time, all right?
Yeah.
All right.
I do think
we have room
in the budget for that.
So if you take a look at...
I'm sorry, Sharon.
Uh, excuse me, Sharon?
Fred's on a call
with the board
for the next hour or so.
Is there something
I can help you with?
Well, I don't know
if Mr. Meacham
has heard or not,
but we didn't get our
delivery of scrubs today.
Fred is aware, yes.
Maybe you should
ask him to come out.
Is this really
an emergency?
Young man,
scrubs are critical
in maintaining
the integrity of our
operating rooms.
We still have
surgical gowns,
correct?
And what do you
expect them to wear
underneath? Uh...
He should know that
besides putting our staff
and patients at risk,
we're opening ourselves up
for potential lawsuits.
We should cancel
all elective surgeries
until we iron this out.
That would be a big hit
to the P&L.
That's why
I'm here to see
Mr. Meacham.
I'll call your office
as soon as this breaks up,
Ms. Goodwin.
Thank you.
Ta-da.
Trail mix.
Vanessa's favorite.
The kind
with dried pineapple
and chocolate in it.
And I wrote her
a little note too.
Aw.
I hope she knows
how much we all miss her.
If she doesn't,
she will by the time
she gets this package.
Hmm.
Hey, sweetie.
Hey, Ben.
What are you
doing here?
Student of mine fell off
the jungle gym.
Ambo said they were
taking her here.
Name's Mira Holloway.
Oh.
Yeah, she's in treatment 4.
Come on.
Doctor looks
no older than Mira.
Aw, she's in good hands.
Don't worry.
Ms. Goodwin,
is this really all we got?
I'm sorry.
Yes, it's the best we have.
It's kind of itchy.
Yeah, they're fine.
We'll make do.
Why are you looking
at me like that?
It's okay. I was
just worried about you.
Renee,
how are you doing?
Can you, uh...
Can you tell me how
you're feeling right now?
How long have I been here?
Since this morning.
You had a fall.
You had the Zoom with Oslo,
but I had it all rescheduled.
Oslo.
The Abel prize.
They're handing it out
next month?
That's nice.
You know what?
Seth, I think we should
let your wife rest
for a little bit.
Renee, we'll be back
in just a few minutes, okay?
Okay.
What's wrong with her?
Well,
the olanzapine has pretty
severely obtunded her.
Obtunded?
I'm sorry.
It just means
that she's slower
to react to stimuli.
It's not an uncommon
side effect.
This is gonna
wear off, right?
The thing is, Seth,
is that when the tacrolimus
is in play, like it is
with this side effect,
that the pharmacology just
becomes a lot more delicate.
But we can
lower the dose.
She's already had
the lowest dose.
And frankly, her affect
is just extremely
pronounced already.
Did I read somewhere
that aripiprazole
has a less sedative effect?
Would that work better?
You know, at this point,
it's worth a try.
So why don't we
let the olanzapine
clear her system
and then give her
some aripiprazole
and see if we get
to a better place?
This suit is
driving me nuts.
Tell me about it.
I'm schvitzing
like crazy.
Okay, I can see the baby.
Almost there, Maya.
The baby flipped
to transverse back down.
What does that mean?
Just means she's
a little stuck.
It's gonna take
a bit longer.
Grab the bandage scissors
and extend the
uterine incision.
Mmm-hmm.
Hey, Dean.
Yeah?
It looks like we got
another prisoner coming in.
What?
Baghdad!
Deke Niemann,
37-year-old male
blunt trauma to the chest,
abdomen, and back.
Ended up in a physical
confrontation with
a correction officer.
Bastard got me
with a baton.
Cermak transferred
this one over.
Here is the X-rays they took.
I'll pull these up.
On my count, one, two.
Easy, man!
That hurts.
Hold on,
we have to recuff him.
X-ray's up.
Hemopneumothorax
on the left.
Get a chest tube tray.
Prep and drape.
Push 100 of fentanyl,
2 of Versed.
One of your coworkers
trucked this guy
up pretty good.
Totally justified.
He had a weapon in his hand,
was considered
armed and dangerous.
A weapon?
Was this the guy who--
Shanked the other guy, yeah.
We're ready for you, doctor.
Help me, doc.
I can't breathe.
I can push
the chest tube
if you want.
No.
I got it.
Renee.
Honey!
What... What's
wrong with her?
I mean, she's...
she's catatonic.
Waxy rigidity.
I don't understand.
She's having an even
more extreme reaction
to the aripiprazole.
Will it get better?
Unfortunately,
it's this class
of drugs, right?
These anti-psychotics
that typically
mitigate this very unfortunate
side effect of tacrolimus.
And sometimes they work,
sometimes they don't.
So she's never gonna
get back to her normal self?
As long as she's taking
this immunosuppressant,
it's unlikely.
I can't believe this.
Getting this new kidney
was supposed to give
Renee her life back.
And now today...
I cannot watch my wife
suffer like this anymore.
I want to take her off
the immunosuppressant drugs
once and for all.
Uh... Seth. Seth, come on.
Uh, we talked about this.
Her kidney won't survive.
I don't care.
Think about everything
Renee went through.
All those years on dialysis,
you really think
she wants to get
back to that?
I know my wife.
If she had to choose between
her body and her mind,
it's not even close.
You're serious about this?
Renee waited six years
for someone
to give her that kidney,
and you just want to...
What, you want to kill it?
Okay, okay, so what if
we remove it and put it
back into the donor pool?
Is that possible?
Well, I mean,
that would be
unprecedented.
We'd have to go
to the ethics committee
with that.
Seth, I really think
we need to slow down here,
and at the very least,
give Renee a chance
to weigh in for herself.
Look at her!
She cannot make
this decision.
I have her advance directive.
It's my choice, right?
She is certainly impaired,
and if you have
the advance directive--
Uh-uh. No.
This is what
she would want.
Remove the kidney.
Give it to someone else.
Sorry, you're
going to have to find
another surgeon.
I don't want anything
to do with this, okay?
No, no, no, I'll tell her.
Okay. Sharon,
it's Cheryl.
Hmm.
Says that you're all set
for tomorrow at 10:45 a.m.
with Meacham.
No, no, no. Uh-uh.
Hey.
Tomorrow?
Doesn't Fred realize
this can't wait?
You're kidding.
No, no. That's all.
Thank you.
So?
Evidently, he has
a 2:00 tee time.
Hey.
Good news.
They get the blade out?
Yeah, tied off the
external jugular,
and Neil's confident
it missed his esophagus.
Sean's gonna be okay.
Thank you. Thanks.
How's Mira doing?
Evidently, her X-rays
look good.
Zach's talking about
possibly running some
more tests, though.
Oh.
There's a whole lot
of trail mix in there.
Yeah, it was kind
of Vanessa's thing.
It's gonna cost a fortune
shipping it to the
Philippines, though.
Hey, Maggie.
Oh, good,
I see you haven't
sent that box off yet.
I just found the perfect thing
in the back of my closet.
Vanessa's gonna love it.
My old varsity jacket.
Oh.
Of course, you always
wore it more than me,
but hey, you also looked
better in it, too, so.
Hey.
Um...
This is my husband, Ben.
Ben, this is Vanessa's
biological father,
Grant Young.
Well, it's a pleasure
to meet you finally.
Likewise.
Hey, hey. Whoa, whoa.
Where are you taking him?
CT scan.
On whose orders?
Dr. Choi.
Hey.
Hey, what's, uh...
What's with the chest CT?
I'm looking at the
post-insertion X-ray.
I'm concerned there's
still a hemothorax.
I placed that chest tube.
It's fine.
I'm sure you're right,
but there could be
a retained clot.
A CT will give us a better
image of the damage.
Oh, you didn't think about
running it by me first?
We both know you can't
be the doctor of record
on this patient, Dean.
Come on.
Look, if anything
were to happen--
What are you saying,
that I can't remain objective?
I know I couldn't
if I were in your shoes.
Look, man, maybe you're
a better man than me,
but why put yourself
in that position?
It's a good thing you're not
wearing my shoes then.
If you can't stand down,
I'll have to take this up
with Goodwin.
Please don't make me
do that.
Here she comes.
Oh. Got her.
Oh, hey.
What a sweet baby.
Yes, she is.
We'll get her cleaned up.
You okay?
Yeah, it's just this suit.
Say hi to Mama.
Maya?
Maya.
Maya! Maya!
Bag her!
She was fine
a second ago.
Heart rate's
down to 60.
Amniotic fluid embolism?
She's not coagulopathic.
I mean, it could be,
but it's not a classic AFE.
Hold on.
Snoring respirations.
Check her pupils.
Pinpoint.
I think she might
be OD'ing.
An overdose?
How is that possible?
I don't know,
but we need to
get Narcan now.
Now!
Maya?
Are you with us?
Yeah. Yes.
What happened? What happened?
So you're really
heading to the links?
Aetna's senior VP
is in town.
Said we've got
a pressing matter.
But we've got
pressing matters
here as well.
The surgical scrubs, right?
I was told
we found a solution.
Hazmat suits?
More of a Band-Aid
than a solution.
Yeah, whatever you call it,
it'll do for now.
Fred,
I don't know
if you're aware,
but the hospital's kind of
falling apart lately.
And it's not a good look
when the guy who's supposed
to be holding the glue
is off working
on his handicap
on a weekday.
Lakeview Linens is trying
to jam a 30% increase
down my throat, Sharon.
The hospital just can't
roll over and accept
terms like that,
not if you want to keep
the doors open.
Scrubs are something
we can do without for a bit
if we need to.
You're wrong.
Besides maintaining
a clean and safe
environment in the OR,
they give our people
a sense of purpose,
instill our patients
with the confidence
that we know
what we're doing.
That lowly piece
of clothing
has an incalculable effect
on the healing process.
I can't work with
incalculable, Sharon.
I need a number.
You know, I don't have
any good options here.
So I'm gonna recommend
that we postpone
all elective surgeries
until this thing is resolved.
Forty-eight hours. Please.
I know they'll cave.
I'm sorry, Fred.
I don't have a choice.
I swear, I've never done
a drug in my life.
And of course, I would
never do anything
to harm my baby.
I'm not here to make
any accusations.
I promise.
We just have to do
our due diligence.
Is this gonna keep me
from taking my baby home?
We're gonna
do everything
we can to try
and stop that
from happening.
Yeah.
Let's start by running
a few tests,
and we can take it
from there, okay?
Look, Maya, you have been
through so much today.
Just try and rest.
We'll be back to check
on you soon, okay?
So?
If I had to say,
she's telling the truth.
So no need
to call DCFS?
Not yet, anyway.
She consented to testing,
so we can run a hair sample,
which will tell us
if this really was a one-off.
I'll report back.
All right.
Thanks, Nellie.
Yeah.
I just don't get it.
How can she
be fine one minute
and OD'ing the next?
I mean, there was probably
a certain amount of adrenaline
that kept her alert,
and then baby came,
and the effects
of the drugs hit her.
Yeah, but what drugs?
That's the million dollar
question.
Yeah.
You've still got that rash?
It's like they sewed those
suits out of poison ivy.
Try popping
an antihistamine.
I'm gonna go check
on the baby.
So the, uh,
the ethics committee
is mulling it over.
And get this:
Organ Donors of America
already found an HLA match
for Renee's kidney.
So it's happening.
Well, who knows?
I mean, you know,
ethics committee
tends to bog down
when the surgeon of record
goes missing, you know?
Won't weigh in.
I'm guessing from
your tone, you, uh...
You think this is
the right thing to do?
I think it's better
than the alternative.
If Renee goes off the
immunosuppressants,
her kidney
won't survive, right?
At least this way,
somebody else
might really benefit.
You know, Renee's transplant
was the first time
Pamela showed me
how to resize a renal artery.
She had this great cheat
where she would split
the artery to match the size.
Mechanical genius.
Always was
a brilliant surgeon.
Who may never
operate again.
I made a decision for her,
and look what happened.
I know this is complicated
for you, okay?
But you cannot
let what happened
with Pamela
affect how you
approach this case.
But from where I'm sitting,
Seth's a good man.
Got his wife's
best interests at heart,
and most important of all,
he knows her mind.
And what if he's wrong?
Buddy, I just don't
really think that it's
our place to judge that.
Hey.
Chest scan came back
for our friend over there.
Confirms a whole bunch of
rib fractures and a retained
hemopneumothorax.
Yeah, with the
mild right shift,
looks like his chest
is still under tension
even with the chest tube.
Was the tube
placed properly?
Yeah, but it's clotted off.
Not tidaling.
We need to replace it.
Heart rate's in the 40s.
He's bradying down.
Start bagging.
Check for pulse.
No, I don't feel one.
All right, tension
pneumothorax.
Start CPR.
Thoracotomy tray.
All right,
hold for a second.
Whoa! Feel that rush of air?
Still no pulse.
He's fibrillating.
Give me
the internal paddles.
Charge to 50.
All charged.
All right.
Clear.
I got a rhythm.
Pulse is back.
That was fricking
insane.
Call the OR.
Zach's saying
he won't discharge Mira
until she gets an MRI.
Well, he's just
dotting his I's
and crossing his T's.
It doesn't mean that
she's not doing okay.
Yeah, well, it's causing
Mira's mom a little anxiety.
And why is it
taking him so long?
Well, Ben, you do know
that we're short staffed.
Right?
I'm sure that Radiology
will get to Mira
as soon as they can.
You know, if I knew
this place was gonna be
this unresponsive,
I would have told the ambo
to take her to
another hospital.
Wait, am I sensing
a bit of a hostility here?
Does this have to do
with Grant bringing in
that jacket in today?
Not at all.
Why would I be
bothered by that?
You shouldn't be.
Really?
I do seem to remember
you telling me
that you weren't
gonna have anything
to do with him.
Ben, this isn't about me.
It's about Vanessa.
Yeah.
It's always
about Vanessa.
Hey, Maggie.
Sorry to bother you.
You got a second?
Yeah, she's free.
Yeah, Joe.
Hey, your C-section, Maya.
You got a tox back?
No, not yet. Why?
Well, get this,
I was talking
to security,
that guy who
brought her in.
When they were towing his van,
they got a hit on his tags.
PD took him into custody.
Turns out he was
transporting carfentanil.
Maybe Maya
got exposed.
Well, maybe we all did.
We went into that car
to pull her out.
It could be why
you were itchy all day.
Nothing to do
with the hazmat suits.
We need to get you
into decon.
Where's Will?
Will?
I'll get the Narcan.
Hey, hey, no, no, no,
no, no. Hey, hey, hey.
Will, Will, Will...
Stay with me.
Come on.
It's on his shirt.
Here you go.
Hey, come on.
You okay?
Shh. Stay down.
Stay down.
Mmm-hmm.
We need to
decontaminate now.
Yeah.
Okay, come on.
Hey, you okay?
Yeah, I think so.
The first half hour
is when you
feel it the most,
but after that,
the drug should
clear your system.
Yeah. You should
probably go first.
I'm not letting you
out of my sight.
Oh, come on.
What's the big deal?
How many times have we
seen each other naked?
Hey.
Thanks.
It's crazy.
We're right back
where we started.
What do you mean?
Well, when we first met,
you were Narcanning me.
I guess we're even.
There's no need
to keep score.
Here you go.
A recipient giving up
a perfectly healthy kidney.
Twenty years in this biz,
and I've never seen
anything like this.
Yeah.
Thanks, Crockett.
Dr. Hutchins, thank you
for taking such good care
of my Mira today.
And you, Mr. Campbell.
Your husband's a saint.
Thank you.
That's what they tell me.
Yeah.
Ben, listen.
I got to run...
But--
If I'm gonna make
bowling league.
I'll try not to wake you
when I come in.
Prepare to be excited.
Come on.
That's all of 'em. We'll have
the rest here tomorrow.
Thanks, Harry.
I thought you said that
you struck out with Fred.
I thought I did.
Oh, man.
So what happened?
They got here sooner
than I wanted.
I was hoping to be here
for the big surprise.
So this is all your doing.
So it turns out these guys
are in discussion with us
about upgrading their fleet.
I, uh,
spoke to the president,
made it clear
that I wouldn't
feel good doing
business with a company
that's trying to chisel
a civic institution
like Chicago Med.
And they promised
that they wouldn't raise
their prices anytime soon.
Oh, that's very nice.
Thanks, Jack.
Just trying to help.
Oh, hey, let's get a shot
with these scrubs, yeah?
It'd be good for your
social media feed.
Ready?
It's nice to have
a guardian angel.
Yeah, but not really
a viable business strategy
for the long run, is it?
No.
So if I'm hearing correctly,
I was experiencing psychosis
due to the immunosuppressants,
but the antipsychotic
had a dulling effect.
That's right.
And you decided
that removing my kidney
was the best solution?
Honey, I didn't know
what else to do.
My mind to me an empire is.
I would have
done the same thing.
God, I--
Though I guess
we have to get used
to all of this again.
We'll get
through it together.
Thank you for taking
such good care of me.
I love you.
So the drugs
were on my socks?
Yeah, we think that
they were slowly
leaching carfentanil
into your skin all day,
which is what
caused you to overdose.
I just can't believe this.
You know,
Gus dealing drugs,
I had no idea.
What about the baby?
Thankfully,
she was not exposed.
We know that this might
not have been the birth
you had planned for,
but the good news is that
you and baby
are healthy and safe.
Thank you.
Thank you both.
I never thought I'd be
so relieved to pull on
a pair of scrubs.
Are you hungry?
There's this great new
burrito stand over on Lake.
I think I'm gonna
try to hit a meeting
on the way home,
just be on
the safe side.
You are welcome
to join if you want.
Ah, that's okay.
After today,
I'm pretty sure
I'm never gonna touch
this stuff again.
See you tomorrow?
Good night.
Okay.
Guy get out
of surgery yet?
Yeah.
He'll be kept in the ICU
a couple of days
before they, uh--
Discharge back
into custody.
Yeah.
Boy, some father
I turned out to be, huh?
Let my son drop
out of my life
for 15 years,
let him drop into addiction,
prison.
And just today,
I helped save
the life of a guy
who tried to kill him
and who very well
may try to kill him again.
Yeah?
I mean, I had...
I had exactly one job...
Protect my boy.
And I failed.
I could tell you that...
That you didn't have a choice,
that we took an oath.
But I don't think
that'd be much comfort.
How come you
didn't let me know
what's going on with Sean?
I was ashamed.
Yeah.
Okay.
Hey. Hey, Dean.
Yeah.
It's Sean.
Come on.
All right.
He's ready to extubate.
Kai, I can do that.
It's all right. I got it.
Please.
This is my son.
Oh...
Where am I?
You're in the hospital, Sean.
You just got
out of surgery.
Dad.
It's gonna be okay,
my boy.
You're gonna be okay.
It's gonna be okay.