Previously, on
The Good Doctor...
I'm covering the ER today.
Gonna be a madhouse.
Yeah.
This Emergency Room and
everyone in it is now under quarantine.
A serious respiratory virus
has infected three patients.
Take me to the hospital.
We are going to
your appointment,
and making sure your think
melon remains tumor-free.
I no longer have
an immune system...
My donor is on his way, right?
Why are you answering
our donor's phone?
Because he's here in quarantine.
My wife's in there. I
need to get in there.
If something happens to me,
our son needs someone
to take care of him.
- Put your mask back on.
- Why?
Because I'm infected.
On the bright side, I think
I'm growing on Morgan.
Dr. Reznick...
Morgan...
He doesn't need to die.
- He signed a DNR.
- He shouldn't have.
We're gonna get
his donor's marrow.
You need surgery, now.
There's no operating room.
We will have to improvise.
Use your finger
to plug the hole.
Now, what? Dr. Lim?
It's back.
Help my son! Help my son!
Three-eleven bus.
$2.35.
Left on Blossom Hill...
Kellan!
Right on Cottle Street.
Dr. Murphy?
Left on Santa Teresa...
I think there's something
wrong with him.
We'll get you a mask.
Can we get this
pregnant woman a mask?
Kellan, can you
hear me? Breathe!
It's empty.
Kellan!
Right on...
Dr. Reznick needs you.
He's not answering.
Dr. Murphy...
Don't yell, it'll
only make it worse.
Okay. What should I do?
Tell him about the surgery.
Give him every detail you can.
Santa Pete has a torn IMA.
He's hemorrhaging
into his belly.
His BP is at 87 over
54 and dropping.
A saphenous vein graft.
We can repair the IMA with a graft
from the saphenous vein. We just...
I don't need a diagnosis, I
need an extra set of hands.
Get me a 2-0 silk, vascular
clamps, and an 11 blade.
Clear.
Charge 200 joules. Clear.
We just saved his life
and violated his rights.
We should lose our licenses.
You won't.
You were following the
instructions given by an attending.
No, I wasn't.
Let's get him stabilized,
so I can go to
Andrews and talk to him
about getting him some marrow
so this wasn't a waste of time.
Put your lips
together and breathe
like you're blowing
out a candle.
I can't.
Kellan. Deep
breaths. Deep breaths.
You're a doctor, right?
Any update on the virus?
- Do I have it?
- No.
No rash, no fever.
This is your asthma.
- When can we go home?
- Your lungs are hyperinflated.
They better send in more doctors,
because that weirdo melted down.
Everybody, shut
up. Shut the hell up!
We have multiple people
in serious condition,
including a senior
doctor and my son.
Your questions are
gonna have to wait.
I need a nebulizer.
It's in isolation with
the infected patients.
I'll order one in from pharmacy.
No time.
- Making your own nebulizer?
- Something like that.
- You broke in?
- No.
Dad, I saw the Taser.
I didn't use it.
Just threatened to.
That was dumb.
Long deep breaths.
You got her on maximal oxygen?
Yeah, her vitals have
recovered slightly.
The CDC is sending a PCR test
based off the virus in
the Malaysian outbreak.
So, what's their
treatment protocol?
Antiviral, steroids,
inhale nitric oxide and
anti-etanercept antibodies.
That's what we did for the
two plane patients and Tyler.
We got to Dr. Lim sooner.
That should make a difference.
How's Dr. Murphy?
He's fine.
I saw his breakdown
on the security feed.
Better. He's closing
on Santa Pete.
Do you have a strategy
for dealing with it?
Dr. Park and I can...
Park's in there?
When did that happen?
Just a few minutes ago.
He came in to help his son.
Perfect.
You're still here?
What did they say?
Very kind of you.
No wonder you and
Shaun get along so well.
What did they say? Did the
new tests show anything new?
They need time to
process the CT images.
Send them off to Dr. Blaize.
So you might've been wrong
about your cancer coming back?
No.
No?
How can you know you're not wrong
if you don't know you're not wrong?
This is how they do it.
First they tell you it
might be something,
and then they order new
tests to test the previous tests,
only to inform you that it was
what they suspected all along.
Very effective way
of breaking bad news.
Okay.
And if your tumor really is
back, what does that mean?
It means that I had surgery
and let them pump radiation
into my brain for nothing.
It means that my memory loss
is because my brain is dying.
It means that I probably
have a year, maybe 14 months.
Enough meaning for you?
What are we gonna tell Shaun?
Nothing.
Saint Bonaventure's opened
up a room for family and friends.
You wanna come?
We expand the quarantine.
We move our marrow
donor and our patient...
If the donor has the virus,
his marrow will transmit to your
immunocompromised patient.
He'll be dead in hours.
As he will be
without the transplant.
We create a sterile
pathway from the ER
into this procedure room
using polyethylene sheeting.
No, you won't.
The only people
taking any risks here
are my people, the
patient and the donor.
And this hospital and everyone
in it if you screw anything up.
But my larger objection
is, it won't work.
That procedure room
isn't negative pressure.
Which leaves the virus free to
escape to the main vent system.
I'll figure something else.
Janitor's closets.
They're negative pressure because
of the cleanser-sterilizing agents.
Don't want those odors and
toxins to disperse to patient areas.
Here.
That closet doesn't have
room for two patients.
We could do the extraction
there, but not the transplant.
We could use this linen
room in the basement,
which is also negative pressure,
and connect to the janitor's
closet through this laundry chute.
Once the bone
marrow's extracted,
it could travel through the
laundry chute into the linen room,
where you could
do the transplant.
Dr. Murphy?
Update me on patient status.
Santa Pete's vitals are stable.
No sign of post-op infection.
Toby is in Bay 3
receiving an IV drip.
Ester's ST...
I think you're overloading him.
No, when he's
dealing with medicine,
he's not distracted
by everything else.
It helps. Keep going, Shaun.
Ester's ST depressions
have improved.
That should help, too.
Ester's ST depressions have
improved and Viola's water broke.
What? When?
It appears quite recently.
Given you're only 36
weeks gestationally
and there is no
sign of infection,
the baby should be able to
stay in utero for at least 24 hours.
If the quarantine
is done before...
You're not gonna fall
apart again, are you?
I don't think so, Viola.
The buzzing is gone and
there is much less yelling.
Except you.
It was the buzzing
and the yelling?
Not the fact that we're
trapped with three people
who have died from a
highly infectious disease?
That's not something
to worry about.
I either have the
virus, or I don't.
And based on past national
quarantine mortality rates,
we have a very good
statistical chance of surviving.
But I didn't know that I
would fall apart the first time,
so I may be wrong.
Here you go.
You always talk like that?
Like what?
Just say whatever you're
thinking when you're thinking it.
Yes, it's good to be honest.
Wish my dad was like that.
Dr. Park is very honest. He
always shares his opinions.
Opinions, and then
there's feelings.
Your dad doesn't tell
you that he loves you?
What?
Well, he's just not
really there for us.
He did just risk his life and his career
to break into a quarantine to help you.
It's true.
But most kids want their dad there
even when it's not life-and-death.
Sorry for your loss.
Status?
O2 sat is 92.
Respiratory rate is down to
16. Your lungs sound clear.
Keep pulmonary edema to a minimum
with conservative fluid management.
Use Furosemide so
my CVPs aren't drained.
Absolutely.
I love this place.
I always said I'd be
doing this till the day I died.
Ta-da.
We started your treatment early.
You'll be back to repairing late-night,
drunken head injuries in no time.
I forgot to call my
mom on her birthday.
I forgot to do a lot of stuff.
Tyler was sweet.
He was a good guy.
Best to put him out of sight.
It's not a healthy
reminder for either of us.
Tyler's mask had a tear in it.
It's possible the virus is
droplet-based, not airborne.
Blood or saliva
could've made its way
through his mask from
the airline passengers.
Unfortunately, until we know
for sure, we're still on lockdown.
But I'll let the CDC know.
Do you have a minute?
Is it urgent?
Not really.
Kel...
What's up?
Why'd you move away?
I'm a resident. You go
where the job takes you...
They don't need
doctors in Phoenix?
This was an excellent
opportunity for me.
And it's less than
a two-hour flight...
You had my baseball
schedule for months.
And you came for one game,
and you were on your
computer the entire time.
I had exams the next day.
So, why'd you bother coming?
Good. Slowly. Good.
As delicious as
these ice-chips are,
I think I'm ready
for some solid food.
Did they send in any cookies?
Dr. Murphy was very
clear. No food until you fart.
Just imagine they're
straight from the North Pole.
Bob, are you ready?
Of course.
I'm doing a bone
marrow extraction,
and I need an extra set of
hands to handle some bloody stuff.
Separating bone and
fat from stem cells.
Who here isn't freaked out by
what I just said and can help?
Ester's a doctor.
- You're a doctor? Why haven't you...
- Veterinarian, retired.
Blood is blood. Follow us.
Fetal heart rate is still
between 130 and 140 BPM.
Contractions, 17 minutes apart.
What's happening? Is it my baby?
Viola's BP is 180 over 100.
She may have preeclampsia
and an oncoming seizure.
We need to induce labor.
No! He's not being born in here.
We are waiting for quarantine to end.
Your placenta isn't
getting enough blood flow.
We need to get him out.
This is going to be your
first baby. And mine.
Start bronchodilators.
Dr. Lim, can you hear me?
O2 sats are still dropping.
Push paralytics.
Starting intubation.
I'm getting resistance bagging.
I gave her hyoscine.
Hello? What's going
on? What's going on?
Lim's O2 sats are crashing.
Her lungs aren't inflating.
They're filled with
fluid and secretions.
- Pick up the phone.
- I got my hands full.
Villanueva, pick up the phone.
Okay, show me what's going on.
She's in full respiratory failure,
she needs more pulmonary support.
Get her on BiPAP. That
might buy us some time.
Or we take her lungs
out of the equation.
We put her on ECMO.
Oxygenate her blood outside her
body. Her lungs will have time to heal.
We can't do ECMO in the ER.
We aren't supposed to do
abdominal surgery in the ER either.
Please, walk me through it.
Prep an area over
her femoral vein.
That's very loud.
- Any crowning, Dr. Murphy?
- No.
She's dilated at six centimeters
and I don't feel the head.
It's been seven hours since her
water broke. The baby's stuck.
Use Leopold's maneuvers to
identify the location of the baby.
The fetus is transverse.
He's lying roughly 30
degrees to the left side.
We can't deliver the baby.
What? Why not?
We need to turn the baby.
We need to do an
external cephalic version.
Or a C-section. I have
assisted on several.
In operating rooms with
an experienced attending.
We are not doing a C-section
here. Tilt her bed. I'll grab the gel.
Okay.
So, when...
What? When what?
I get not telling him
when he's in quarantine,
he's got enough
on his plate, but...
Never.
You told him when you
were first diagnosed.
Yes, and that was a mistake.
He forced you to take
tests that saved your life.
Well, no, as it
turns out, it didn't.
And he became so obsessed and
distracted that he nearly killed a patient.
He's your friend.
I'm his mentor. It's not
his job to take care of me.
Make sure you turn the needle, so
you're getting marrow from all sides.
Aspirate slower. If you
pull fast, it's more painful.
Hang in there, Bob.
I deserve a little pain.
You're his dad.
You're saving his life.
I took off before my son
even knew who I was.
Traveled in crappy vans
to stay in crappy hotels
and play crappy music.
All so I could earn
enough to get high.
You're here now.
By the time I got up
the nerve to face them...
My ex was dying.
God willing, I did it in
time to save my son.
Dr. Melendez, Chris'
vitals are bottoming out.
His secretions and
lung sounds are worse.
I don't know how much
longer we can wait.
Administer Levophed
and prep him for transplant.
Dr. Park, Chris is
in hypotensive crisis.
Go faster.
Fast as I can.
You ready, Dr. Murphy?
Yes, I can feel the head.
We need to rotate
in the same direction.
Deep breaths, Viola.
Yeah. Okay.
Hold on, I can't do this!
Squeeze my arm hard as you can!
The fetus is moving.
The head is facing the cervix.
One more push. We just need...
Stop!
Placental abruption.
She's hemorrhaging.
Baby's heart-rate
is decelerating.
I need two large-bore IV
lines. And start two units PRBC.
And please page an OB-GYN
to supervise my first solo surgery.
This is terrible. This is
not how it's supposed to...
This is excellent.
Dr. Garcia will be supervising
me for the C-section.
She's the director of
obstetrics and gynecology here.
I'm sure she's much more
qualified than your personal OB-GYN.
Relax, you're gonna be fine.
What's the status?
Nerve block is in.
And I gave her a
liter bolus of saline.
Throw some ChloraPrep down,
and make a five-centimeter
Pfannenstiel incision.
Ten blade.
Chris is prepped. I'm
starting central line now.
How's he doing?
Pressure is 90 over
50. O2 sats are 85.
Heart rate is at 110.
Ready when you are.
One more and we're good to go.
I'm on my way.
I'm scrubbing in.
Call me the second
you're ready for the drop.
Abdomen is open. Retraction.
Suction.
Baby's BPM is 110 and dropping.
What's happening?
Dr. Murphy, do you
see the uterine wall?
Blood pressure is dropping.
Dr. Murphy, the uterine wall.
Dr. Murphy?
You need to make a gradual
shallow incision and cut through it.
You do not wanna nick the baby.
- What's happening?
- BPM is 95.
Dr. Murphy, please! Please!
Dr. Murphy, should
we turn up her oxygen?
- Dr. Murphy, you need to make the cut.
- Dr. Murphy. Dr. Murphy.
- Okay! Dr. Murphy!
- Dr. Murphy...
Is the baby okay?
No! Quiet!
Everyone, quiet! I
need to concentrate!
I can see the head.
- Is my baby okay?
- He's not breathing.
We need to start CPR now.
Get a pediatric Ambu bag,
and start two-finger
chest compressions.
There's something wrong with Viola.
She's hypotensive and tachycardiac.
She's bleeding out.
You should tell him.
Look at that.
Another reason why you
two are so good together.
Neither one of you are
willing to drop a thing.
He deserves to know.
"Deserves"?
Is that how things
work in your world?
People get what they deserve?
Shaun deserves to be toyed with?
- Who's toying with him?
- You.
I'm his friend.
You whisk him away on a road
trip, kiss him, and then leave town.
Now you pop back into
his life, move in with him.
Shaun's not some
hamster you get to play with,
and then not think twice about
it when you forget to feed him.
You're gonna hurt him
again, you know that.
I know that.
I'm gonna let this slide
because you're dying.
I'm gonna take this outside.
Bubble wrap.
Need to make sure it doesn't
break on the trip or the landing.
Dr. Melendez, we're ready.
Copy. Deposit the marrow now.
The marrow is intact.
We're good to go.
My chest. It really hurts.
- He's going into cardiac arrest.
- What can I do?
His IV's blown.
The tip broke off.
It must be in his heart.
Come on.
Dr. Murphy, the rules of
medical priority are clear.
Focus on saving the mother.
Dr. Murphy, you
need to stop, now.
Dr. Murphy?
We can save them both.
Get me a liter of
saline, a plastic bag,
some surgical tape
and Kerlix gauze, please.
Who knows CPR?
- In health, they made...
- Come with me.
Two fingers right here
in the middle of his chest.
Press down twice per second.
Every 15 seconds, stop
and squeeze the bag.
Twice...
Please don't press too
hard or you'll crush his heart.
Okay.
You're making a Bakri tamponade
balloon for Viola's bleed?
- Yes.
- What is that supposed to do?
It will control the bleeding by
applying pressure from the inside.
- How's the baby?
- I don't know if this is working.
- I just...
- Don't stop.
Are you ready, Dr. Murphy?
Feed the end of the pack
slowly through her cervix.
Once you reach the fundus
of the uterus, start inflation.
Clear.
That's the fourth one.
- I have to crack his chest.
- Here?
Get me rib-spreaders and a
ten blade from the crash cart.
Marrow's in.
Heart-rate's 84. BP is 100
over 60. Vitals look good.
I'm sorry about before.
Are you gonna tell Shaun
you got some good news?
What makes you
think it's good news?
Because you apologized.
The cancer's not back.
That's great.
It's not great. It's
okay, it's not great.
I have meningitis from
the CSF leak in my head.
I have to have surgery
pretty much immediately.
And no, I am not telling Shaun.
You're right about one
thing. You're not his friend.
Because friends tell
each other everything?
And you're a lousy mentor.
Friends are there
for each other.
And mentors teach,
they don't hide the truth.
I'm just looking out for him.
He's not like you, he's
not like everybody else...
No, he's not.
But he's also not some helpless
child who constantly needs protection.
He's an adult. A very
smart, caring adult.
And you could really use
someone like that right now.
It's not working.
She's still bleeding.
Keep injecting saline.
Vitals are 80 over
60. Heart-rate's 110.
Stop CPR.
I need to see if he
can breathe on his own.
Is everything okay?
No. His lungs are filled
with fluid. He's drowning.
Get the pediatric
laryngoscope, stat.
- Dr. Andrews, she's still...
- It's not Andrews. Can I see her?
MAP is holding steady at 65,
but she was dipping into
serious hypoxia for a short bit.
Can I see her?
Good work taking care of her.
Thank you.
The baby has meconium
aspiration. Suction catheter.
Is that bad?
Fecal matter has
settled in his lungs.
It's blocking his airway.
Did I do something wrong?
You most likely
dislodged some of it.
Without that he would
have suffocated by now.
Clearing his airway.
It's the most important
moment of my life,
and I'm not there with Viola.
This is the way it used to be
done, the men waiting outside.
And now we know better.
Now we know what matters.
Do you think your grandfather
loved your father any less...
Shut up!
Ignore him, he's just a grouch.
Shh!
Is that...
I think you've got
yourself a new alarm clock.
Congratulations!
I'm a dad!
Yeah.
He is okay.
A Christmas miracle.
Thank you.
It's Lim.
Could I get some water?
ECMO... That was a ballsy move.
Ester Blum?
Pete Bailey?
Your PCR and serology came
back negative for the virus.
You're officially cleared.
We're going home.
Only Ester can go home.
You're going to post-op
recovery for another day.
I'll keep you company.
There's someone I wanna
see up there anyway.
On Dasher, on Dancer,
on Prancer and Vixen.
You are stable.
No sign of marrow rejection.
We will be monitoring you
over the next few weeks,
but remission is a
very real possibility.
I don't know how
to thank you enough.
I guess I should thank
my dad, too. Is he here?
There was a complication
during extraction.
Bob's heart stopped.
We did everything we
could to revive him, but...
He died.
What?
We are so sorry for your loss.
Are you Chris Santos?
My name is Ester.
I was with your
father when he...
He mentioned that
he had a lot of regrets.
But it meant a lot to him
that he could help you.
I heard you were a big
help during that delivery.
They needed extra hands.
You asked me why I
let you and your mom go,
why I didn't fight harder.
It's because I wasn't
a good person.
I wasn't a good father.
My dad had this mantra.
"Be like stone, never cry."
If I got emotional, or upset,
he'd repeat it, "Be
like stone, never cry."
It made me stronger, which
wasn't always a good thing.
Spent my life
living behind a wall.
Which meant your mom got
to live with that wall as well.
And...
When we split up,
I felt like a failure.
Moving away helped
me hide from that.
My father's voice
is still in my head.
But I'm working on
getting it to be quiet.
I love you, Kellan.
I always will.
Kellan!
Mom.
Are you okay?
I'm fine. I... I helped
deliver a baby.
Oh!
He was amazing.
It's good to see you, Mia.
How was it in there?
The guy I worked
on didn't make it.
Merry Christmas.
I don't think I'll
forget this one.
Me neither.
The idea of you not being
around wasn't okay with me.
Who would I drink bourbon with?
I think my bourbon days are
behind me for a little while.
I'll wait.
Shaun!
Hi.
You must be exhausted.
And hungry.
All the sandwiches they
gave us had pickles in them.
Oh, that's no good.
How about we go to that
24-hour breakfast place
and get some pancakes?
I would like that very much.
- Hello, Dr. Glassman.
- Hello.
- I delivered a baby.
- Yes, we heard.
I'm sorry I couldn't drive
you to your appointment.
How did it go?
I have meningitis.
I have to have surgery later today
to fix the CSF leak in my head.
I thought you should know.
That's good.
Meningitis is definitely
not as bad as cancer.
It also explains
your memory-loss.
Now you can get
your license back.
Shaun, would you mind
if Glassy gave you a hug?
I think that would be very nice.
I'm very proud of you.
Have yourself a
merry little Christmas
Let your heart be light
From now on our
troubles will be out of sight