I don't remember a lot.
There's something
I wanna ask you.
You've helped me
through a very difficult time.
Do you love him?
He slipped the ring
on your finger
when you were unconscious.
It doesn't matter,
because it's over.
And, you!
Get out of my life.
Dr. Manning?
Agent Lee told me
what was going on.
Hi, April.
I've got your test results.
You couldn't tell me
over the phone?
Well, I just thought
we should discuss this
in person.
Okay.
Good news.
Your thyroid
and pituitary tests
were completely normal.
And your HSG X-ray shows that
your fallopian tubes are open.
Okay. So, what's
the bad news?
Your AMH and antral follicle
count are low.
And your FSH is high.
Even though you're
only in your 30s, that
indicates that there's...
Early onset menopause?
I like to call it
exactly what it is.
Low ovarian reserve.
I'm the reason we
haven't gotten pregnant.
Spontaneous pregnancy
isn't impossible.
Dr. Patchefsky,
the miscarriage a few years
ago and now this?
Ethan wants a baby.
I can't...
I can't give him one.
April, this is far
from hopeless.
Ethan should get tested, too.
And then the two of you
might want to discuss IVF.
IVF?
Mmm-hmm.
I'd recommend
starting sooner than later.
With low ovarian reserve,
you may not be responsive.
So, I go home and I tell Ethan
I am going through menopause,
and even with IVF,
I still might not be able
to get pregnant.
Couples work
through this, April.
Was the gym crowded?
What?
You were gone a long time.
Oh... Yeah,
it was crowded.
Do you really have to leave?
Yeah.
How can the Navy
make you go for two months?
Six weeks.
I told you, doc
on a carrier had an MI,
sounds pretty serious,
they called up a reservist.
"The Expectant Father?"
Just looking to the future.
God, Ethan.
What?
I have to get ready for work.
Morning.
Hey.
How'd you sleep?
Great.
How's your pain, honey?
You're not dressed.
Yeah. Thought maybe
I'd stay home today.
Please don't try
and talk me out of it.
Okay, I won't.
Thank you.
You're getting good
at this marriage stuff.
Fourth time's
a charm, I guess.
Danny...
I want you to remarry.
But I'm happily
married to you.
Danny?
Wait, what are we having
for breakfast, honey?
What do you want?
I know you heard me.
Pancakes it is.
Ben?
Do you mind if
I share with Maggie
what I'm finding?
Please do.
You are running a fever,
103.2, and you're
tachycardic...
Rapid heart rate.
Of more concern,
your white count
is really low, 2.2.
And your platelets
are at 35, also low.
So, not good.
No.
I'm sorry, Ben.
Not good.
I'm so tired.
Why don't you get some rest?
You let me know
if he has any
trouble breathing,
and we'll increase
his oxygen, okay?
Make him as comfortable
as possible.
Hey.
Dr. Manning, I'm sorry
to bother you.
What's up?
Um, a, uh...
I'm not sure how
you wanna handle this.
A pediatric patient of yours
has just been brought in
for a scheduled surgery.
Okay, I'll go
see the patient.
What's wrong?
Well, it's, uh...
It's Phillip Davis'
daughter, Sophie.
I mean, I know
that you and he...
Whatever happened
between her father and me,
Sophie is still my patient.
Right.
Sophie has had multiple
procedures to correct
congenital tricuspid atresia.
Why don't you come up
and help me examine her?
Okay, yeah.
Okay.
Dr. Manning?
That night at the accident...
Natalie?
It was just like this.
Do you love him?
It's weird,
some things are starting
to come back to me.
Phillip was there.
And some FBI agent.
And she wanted...
I can't remember.
Dr. Manning?
Yeah?
The family's waiting
to see you.
Uh, okay. Let's go.
Dr. Manning?
Yes.
And this is fourth year
medical student Ms. Curry.
Hi. I'm Cheryl McFarland,
Phillip's sister,
Sophie's aunt. This is
my husband, Jeremy.
Hi.
I'm sorry,
um, do you live here?
Streeterville. Why?
Phillip said he
didn't have any
family in Chicago.
Phillip says a lot of things.
He's a pathological liar.
Oh, um...
May I ask, where is he?
I don't know.
He asked us to meet him
at the hospital. When we
got here, he was gone.
I don't understand.
He left Sophie.
He... He isn't coming back?
I doubt it.
Well, you know what?
All that matters
right now is Sophie.
So, why don't I take a look?
Aw. Hey, there.
There she is.
Hey, Mike.
We got your labs back.
Hmm?
He's still kinda out of it.
Makes sense.
You're uremic.
My kidneys.
Afraid so.
Dialysis problem.
Your catheter's clotted off.
That why he feels so lousy?
Yeah.
My brother's been
on the transplant list
for over a year.
I... I'd give him my kidney,
but I'm not a match.
Well, the good news
is that there was
no sign of infection.
So, if a kidney
becomes available,
you can have the surgery.
We're gonna get you
through this, okay?
All right.
So, how are you feeling, Dan?
Okay. Better.
Good.
He had us so worried.
He's never
passed out before.
When you brought Dan
into the ED yesterday,
he was in a diabetic crisis.
Uh, blood sugar 640,
pH 7.23.
The ketoacidosis
is what caused you
to lose consciousness.
But with the insulin drip
and IV fluids, your numbers
are looking better.
Thank God.
What about his kidneys?
I am concerned. I want
a nephrologist to see you.
Excuse me.
Your patient's on the list
for a new kidney, right?
Yeah. He's had a hard time
managing his diabetes.
Wrecked his kidneys.
Well, we might have
one for him.
"Might"?
Direct donor situation,
but it's complicated.
We have a patient downstairs
who also needs a kidney.
His brother's willing
to donate,
but isn't a match.
But turns out,
he is a match
for your guy.
So, if somebody from your
guy's family matches our guy
and is willing to donate,
then our guy's brother
will donate his kidney
to your guy.
Quid pro quo.
Domino transplant.
Bingo.
They both go home
with a kidney.
We just need a match.
I'll present the offer.
Great.
Jordy Collins, 16-year-old
male with Down syndrome,
motor vehicle collision.
Yeah, we're going
to Baghdad. Is it okay
if I take your pulse?
Yeah.
I'm his dad.
We were rear-ended.
We were going to the rink.
I think he got whiplash.
I ice-skate.
That's really cool.
I can't ice skate
to save my life.
Doris.
All right, on my count.
One, two, three.
This is a big hospital.
Sure is.
We're gonna take
good care of you.
Jordy, anything else
bothering you
besides your neck?
Uh-uh.
Good. Chest X-ray.
Dad, anything
in Jordy's history
we should know about?
No. He's a healthy kid.
I like to hear that.
Okay, I'm gonna listen
to your heart.
Yeah, Jordy, your heart
sounds real good.
Squeeze my hand, would you?
Ooh, you're strong.
This is a big camera.
It's gonna take
a picture of you.
Won't hurt a bit.
Okay.
Everybody, clear.
Coming up.
Hey, chest looks good, too.
I'm gonna take
this collar off
and see what's what. Okay?
Okay.
All right.
Ow!
Sorry, buddy.
Now we'll put that
collar back on.
You know, it could
still just be whiplash,
but I wanna make sure
there aren't any
other injuries.
With your permission,
I'd like to send Jordy
for a CT of his head and neck.
Sure.
Great.
Let radiology know, Doris.
Right.
We're gonna fix you up,
get you back on that ice.
Okay.
I'll check on you in a bit.
Hey, Dan.
Martha, Bill.
Hi.
This is Dr. Marcel. He's been
treating the other kidney
patient I told you about.
Am I a match to him?
Is Dan gonna get a kidney?
No, sir,
you are not a match.
But, Mrs. Schiller, you are.
So, I can donate?
Yes.
Wait. Hold on.
Mom, I don't want you
taking the risk.
With your blood pressure...
And that means
that my son
will get a kidney?
Yes. From my
patient's brother.
Wait.
Dan, I am your mother.
It's a kidney. It's nothing.
What if something happens?
Honey, you're my baby.
I can't imagine
life without you.
When you have
children of your own,
you'll understand.
I'll give the
transplant team a call,
get things started.
Hey, did you hear
the good news?
Yeah.
All right. Can we talk?
I'm busy.
But it'll just take a second.
About your reaction
to the book earlier,
I know you're anxious
about not getting pregnant.
Let's just forget it.
No, here's the plan.
I have some time
this afternoon.
I'll go see a urologist.
What? Why?
Get a semen analysis.
Make sure I'm not
shooting blanks.
Oh, my God. Ethan,
why do we have to talk
about this all the time?
Look, I just
wanna make sure
I'm not the problem.
There is no problem!
Look, I'm not saying
there is,
but just in case.
Oh, my...
I'm so sick of this!
Sick of what?
The pressure!
I don't even know
if I want a baby anymore.
What are you saying?
April!
Hey, there, Jordy,
good news.
CT scan is normal.
Can I go skate now?
Jordy competes.
Special Olympics.
Wow.
Well, maybe you can
go skate. Tell me,
how are you feeling?
Real good.
Hands feel funny.
What?
Tingly.
Really? Both hands?
Uh-huh.
What does that mean?
I'm not sure.
You feel that?
Uh-uh.
Squeeze my hand.
Not so strong now, huh?
No.
Okay, Jordy,
I wanna run one more test
before you go.
It's another type of scan
called an MRI. Dad?
Okay.
Don't worry, Dad.
I'll be okay.
You're a champ.
I'll, uh...
I'm gonna put that order in.
Okay.
Jeremy and I have
decided we're going to
try to adopt Sophie.
I'm really happy
to hear that.
Maia.
Sophie's hit
all her milestones,
and her saturation
is looking good at 85%.
Uh, this is Dr. Frisch.
She will be doing
Sophie's procedure.
Hello.
Did you know that
the patient's father
has instructed
that if Sophie arrests,
we are not to resuscitate?
What?
A DNR?
You mean, you're just
supposed to let her die?
What, no, I...
I can't believe this.
Are you sure?
It's right here
in the chart.
Why would he do that?
He wouldn't.
I mean, he couldn't...
Yes, he could.
Sophie's not perfect.
That makes her too much work.
But he's been
so devoted to her.
I've seen him
take such wonderful
care of her.
Because he was
getting something
out of it. You.
Now that you're not in
the picture, he doesn't
need Sophie anymore.
What?
Look, can you get him
to change his mind?
I tried to call him.
He's not picking up. I don't
even know where he is.
Well, I'm not comfortable
performing this surgery
on a child with a DNR.
Maia...
I'm sorry.
Oh, my God.
We are gonna fight this.
Your donor's being
prepped for surgery.
We'll take you up
to the OR about an hour
into her procedure.
I can't believe
this is actually happening.
When do I go up?
Your brother's organ transfer
should take about two hours.
And then it's my turn?
Right.
Dr. Marcel,
you have the honor.
Betty, are the antibiotics in?
Yeah.
Two grams Cefazolin.
Vitals stable?
All good.
All right, let's begin.
His fever's up. 103.6.
Maggie.
I'm right here, Ben.
Let me know
if he needs anything.
Okay, thank you.
I had a dream.
I was fishing.
That sounds nice.
No.
I hate fishing.
There you go.
Hmm.
That's better.
Ben...
Is there anyone I should call?
You're the closest thing
I've got to family, Maggie.
Have you made
any arrangements?
I should have...
But I just kept thinking
about getting better.
Not about my funeral.
My folks...
Are in a cemetery
in Florida.
I'd like my ashes
to be with them.
Okay.
This doesn't
make sense. We have to
do something, Ms. Goodwin.
I'm sorry, Dr. Manning.
So, that's it?
There's no way to
overturn this DNR?
The father
abandoned the baby.
We don't know that.
And Mr. Davis left
very clear instructions.
He claimed, and I quote,
"My little girl
has suffered enough
"and if the good Lord
decided to take her,
we should let him."
That's ridiculous!
He's not even religious.
Dr. Manning, both
the Ethics Committee and
Legal said this DNR is valid.
And they won't approve
emergency guardianship.
This about
the Davis baby?
Yes.
Dr. Frisch briefed me.
Can you convince her
to do the operation?
No. And I
understand her refusal.
It's a very risky procedure,
and the baby is
likely to arrest.
Dr. Rhodes performed
the previous procedure.
That's right.
I'm sure if he were here,
he would agree to do this.
I will do the surgery.
Dr. Choi, something's wrong!
Dan?
My chest hurts.
What's happening?
No pulse. V-fib.
Start bagging.
Charge to 200.
Sir, it's better if
you left the room.
I'm not leaving my son!
Come on, Dan.
Come on, buddy,
you're gonna be all right.
Clear.
Charged.
Still v-fib. Charge to 200
again. Milligram of epi.
Still in v-fib.
Come on. Come on.
Dr. Choi...
Charge to 200 again.
Come on.
No.
Clear!
He's asystolic.
I'm so sorry, Bill.
Dan? Dan.
Dan?
Time of death, 12:03.
Okay.
Kidney is good to go.
Hold on.
His son died. Mr. Schiller
has withdrawn consent.
What?
He has medical
power of attorney and
he's stopping the procedure.
He can't do that.
He wants his wife's kidney
re-implanted.
That's insane. No.
You may not transplant
that kidney.
All right,
everybody sit tight.
This is ridiculous.
I have a kidney on ice
in a cooler and a patient
in dire need of it.
The man just lost his son,
the reason for the domino
transplant in the first place.
Mrs. Schiller gave consent.
When her son was alive.
And now, we have no way
to know if she'd still
feel the same way.
And we have no way
to know that she wouldn't.
Doesn't matter.
It's the husband's decision.
Didn't you try
to reason with him?
When he was crying
over his dead
son's body? No.
That is not what I meant
and you know it.
Do I?
All right. All right.
You two, let's cool it.
Peter, do we know
who owns this kidney?
I have no idea.
We've never had
a situation like this.
I need to consult with Ethics
and see if there's
at least a precedent.
You do realize that
we're under
a time crunch here?
I realize.
Well, until we have
a determination,
keep Mrs. Schiller stable
and get Mike Stowe
prepped for surgery.
Yes, ma'am.
Jordy, Russell,
this is Dr. Abrams,
our chief of neurosurgery.
Hi.
Jordy, your MRI revealed
a condition called
atlantoaxial instability.
Big words.
Yeah.
What it means is
that your spine
is built a little differently
and working not
quite the way it should.
Yeah. We see it in
about 25% of DS patients.
I know.
Um, is there a way
to treat it?
Why don't we talk outside?
Hey, Jordy, buddy,
I'll be right back. Okay?
Okay.
So, there're two options.
First, I can surgically
repair the instability.
But it's an invasive,
high-risk surgery.
It could fix the problem
or it could make things worse,
severely limit
Jordy's range of motion.
And the second option?
Stabilize the spine
with a halo vest.
It's a type of brace, and wait
for the whiplash to heal.
It's a much safer route,
and that's what I'd recommend.
Dr. Abrams?
Atlantoaxial instability
is congenital.
So, eventually
Jordy's gonna
need the surgery.
Right. But it is possible
to put it off for years.
Uh...
Okay. Uh, no surgery.
I don't wanna take the risk.
All right.
Thanks, Sam.
I don't know what
I'm gonna tell Jordy.
Special Olympics
won't let him compete
with this condition.
He'd have to
have it repaired.
This is gonna
break his heart.
I feel bad for that family,
but how much time
does Mike have?
He's gonna die
without that kidney.
This could be it.
Let's hope for good news.
So, legal has made
a determination.
Since Mrs. Schiller's kidney
had been removed
from her body,
the hospital is
considered its caretaker.
The Ethics Committee believes
that the kidney should go
to Dr. Marcel's patient,
as originally designated
by the donor.
Mr. Schiller's wishes
will not be honored.
Gonna go scrub.
You know it was
the right thing.
We're saving a life.
It's a little more
nuanced than that.
Ethan, don't walk away.
April, there's a man
who has to tell his wife,
when she wakes up from
surgery, that her kidney is
gone and her son is dead.
You wanna be there for that?
I know.
It's a terrible situation.
You think I don't know that?
This is the best outcome
we could have.
What, you just
want me to feel bad,
is that it?
What about you?
You been at me all day.
Look, I don't know
what's going on between us,
but maybe
it's a good thing
I'm going away.
Daniel?
I thought you were
taking the day off.
I am.
And I'm gonna need
a few more.
I'm gonna take CeCe away
for a couple days.
To Mackinac Island.
Ah, well, that was always
a special place
for the two of you.
Yeah. Anyway,
we're gonna have
a party tonight.
Just for a few
close friends, like you.
Um...
Kind of a, um...
Like a bon voyage party.
Okay.
Hey, none of that.
None of that, okay?
Well, it's just...
It's just a little party.
Okay.
No, no! Fix me!
They have to fix me!
They have to fix me! Fix me.
Just keep it down, okay?
No.
Can I help?
I told him what
we were gonna do.
I don't want that!
I want them to fix me!
He wants the operation.
I want to skate!
Show him. Show him me.
Jordy...
Show him me!
Show me...
A video of Jordy skating.
I can fly. You'll see.
Look, I'll forward it to you.
I can fly.
Jordy, okay, there are other
things that you can do.
Okay, we'll find
something else that
you'll love just as much.
No. I want to fly.
I want to be free.
Ben, I'm concerned
about your chest X-ray.
The patchy
white-out indicates
diffuse airspace disease.
He's on a high-flow cannula.
It's not cutting it.
He's oxygenating poorly
and his pCO2 is rising.
He's in acute
respiratory failure.
Ben, I'm gonna
have to intubate you.
Twenty etomidate,
hundred of sux.
Right.
Okay.
Okay, Ben.
Meds are in.
I'm in.
Bag him,
and I'll call for a vent.
I don't think
he has long.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
Heart's beating.
Take her off bypass.
And she's off.
Pulmonary artery pressure
is still high.
Unless we're able to lower it,
she won't survive.
Put her back on bypass.
Eleven blade scalpel
and aortic punch.
Placing a five-millimeter
fenestration
so the extra pressure
decompresses into
her left atrium.
Pressure's still not lowering.
Put her on V-A ECMO?
Not an option,
violates the DNR.
Okay. She's in
pulmonary edema
and failing.
Must be a structural issue
we haven't found yet.
Ah, stenosis.
Prepare for angioplasty.
Look at me, I'm flying!
Fastest skate runner.
Wait, one, two... Okay, now
make a face.
Okay. One more.
No!
I can't stand it.
What do I do?
Hey, guys.
Give us a couple minutes.
This is my fault.
I was always compensating
for having a kid with Down's.
I just wanted to have
a regular boy,
so I pushed him into sports.
Maybe you did.
But he loves that sport.
Jordy's the most important
thing in my life,
he's the best thing
in my life.
I can't do anything
that would cause him harm.
I get it.
Now, I'm the one
who told you
this was the safer option.
And I certainly
understand your fears,
but maybe this
isn't about you.
Maybe it's about Jordy,
and what he wants.
Dad?
I watched that video.
He said, "I can fly."
I saw that.
And he said,
"I want to be free."
I saw that, too.
Dad?
Daddy?
Hey, buddy.
Twelve minutes.
Gotta finish up
and take her off bypass.
Final knot
on the patch is tied.
Cut the stitch.
Take her off bypass.
How's her pressure, Carl?
PA pressure...
Down to 50, was 80.
Good sign.
Mmm.
And good
ventricular function.
I believe this little girl's
health issues
have been resolved.
Let's close.
I'm not gonna be coming home
tonight. I'll leave for my
deployment from here.
Why?
I'm gonna stay
with Bill Schiller
till his wife wakes up.
I wanna be there for him.
Did you mean what you said?
About not wanting
to have a baby?
I don't know what I want.
Well, you got six weeks
to figure it out.
Maggie.
Yeah?
Dr. Lanik wants you.
Okay.
His O2 sats are 94%.
They're improving.
Look at his latest
chest X-ray.
Lungs look a lot better.
I don't understand.
He's improving?
Seems that way.
Labs are better, too.
White count up to four,
platelets up to 75.
Below normal, but
a lot better than before.
How?
Well, the only thing
I can think,
they stopped his chemo,
that allowed his immune system
to bounce back,
fight the infection.
Keep your fingers crossed.
So, are you gonna go fix me?
Yes, I am.
Yeah. You're gonna
go to sleep,
and when you wake up,
everything's gonna be okay.
Okay.
Dr. Manning?
It was just like this.
Sophie was recovering
from her surgery.
And Agent Lee...
Will loves you.
You would be a fool
not to take him back.
Oh, my God.
I have been
so unfair to Will.
All this time,
I have been so unfair to Will.
Jordy should be
back on the ice very soon.
Thank God.
Let me know
when he's competing.
I'd like to come.
I will.
Thank you!
Looks like Jordy
gets to keep flying.
If it hadn't been for you...
Mike got a new kidney.
Best news
I've heard all day.
Glad we finally got there.
Thanks for your help.
Thank you.
Are you sure
you wanna do this?
We took Danny
to Mackinac Island
when he was a little boy.
He's loved it ever since.
They gave us
a really good hotel
room rate,
because we're
going off-season.
Gave the honeymoon suite.
Oh, nice.
Oh.
Got the honeymoon suite.
Isn't that all right?
Here. Blue ones
are sugar-free.
Ooh.
I'll take your word
for that.
You know, I think it's great
that you guys are gonna
finally get that honeymoon.
Yeah.
Oh. Look who's here!
Hi, Mom.
My baby, baby.
She's here.
Hi, Grandma.
Hi, sweetie.
There's my baby.
Hey, Sharon.
Hey, Robin.
Bert.
Hey.
Uh, can you guys
excuse us for
a sec, please?
Dad?
There's my baby.
Uh, hey, Dad. I wanna
go with you and Mom.
Oh, sweetie.
Of course you do.
It's just that your mom
feels very strongly that
it just be the two of us.
I'm so sorry.
I know.
I will talk to her.
Honey, honey...
Dad. Dad. Why not?
Well, the way she
explained it to me,
and trust me,
we talked about it a lot,
is that she wants you
to remember her
the way she is tonight.
Happy and beautiful,
and surrounded
by her friends and family.
But, Dad, I'm never
gonna see her again.
Sweetie, I know
how hard it is. I do.
I just... I'm just
really trying to
let her call the shots.
You know?
And this is the way
she wants it. I...
But to not be
there and not to
tell her...
Honey,
your mom knows
that you love her.
And you know that
she loves you. And...
Hey.
Lighten his sedation.
Ben, I'm gonna
remove your tube.
Okay, okay. Okay.
Maggie...
Ben.
I'm alive.
Yes, sweetheart, you are.
Look at me, I'm flying!
Will.
I remember that night.
I was coming
to tell you that
I'm sorry for
the way I treated you.
That I was wrong.
It doesn't matter anymore.
No, it does. Because...
That's not all.
No. You don't need
to do this.
I do, I do.
Because
I came to tell you that
I love you.
And I wanna be with you.
Natalie, stop.
You told me
to get out of your life.
I know, and I am so sorry.
You don't understand. I did.
And it's been good for me.
It really has.
Will,
we can... We can figure...
No. We...
Aren't good
for one another.
All we do
is hurt each other.
There was a time
I couldn't imagine
a future without you,
but I can now.
I feel...
Free.
Will?
I'm sorry, Natalie.