Previously on ER:
- Your husband?
- I'm not married.
- Boyfriend?
- I don't have one.
Anything changes
with Jodie, call me.
- Or just call me.
- I will.
It's not over with Sam.
Not for me, anyway.
Did you realize that before or
after you had sex with Daria?
- It was a mistake.
- Oh, you still love him.
And at some level, the faculty
will always see you as little Neela.
Somewhere new, you'll be taken seriously
in a way that will not happen if you stay.
Food is here.
I have never had so
much take-out in my life.
- I thought you liked Vietnamese.
- Yeah, I like it.
There are places in Chicago with
chairs and tables and, uh, food on plates.
Ah, but no bed.
- Now, that's an excellent point.
- Yes.
We're not on for another two
hours, so we should ride in together.
Unless someone might see us.
Hmm. Being covert is
more exciting, isn't it?
Yeah.
- Oh, wait.
- No, no, no.
Leave it, leave
it, leave it. Ah!
Hello? Yeah. Really?
Yeah, that's great. Can I,
uh...? Can I take a number?
Yep, thank you.
That was Duke. The department
chair wants to meet me.
- What, uh, about the Attending position?
- Yeah, I can't believe it.
I thought I sank
myself in that interview.
Well, Dr. Corday must have
been very impressed. When is it?
- This weekend.
- This...?
That's soon. That's great.
Can you actually imagine
me being in North Carolina?
I only took the interview
to get Dubenko off my back.
I didn't actually
consider moving.
Well, that is the risk of being
a brilliant surgeon, Neela.
Everyone's gonna be interested.
- Are you leaving?
- Yeah, I should, um...
I should get back to my apartment,
grab some clothes before my shift.
But I thought we were gonna...
You save me a spring roll. Yeah?
No fractures of
the alveolar ridge.
I knew better than to
play at that shady club.
Belly's soft, no obstruction.
Lost my health insurance,
401(k) is in the gutter, now look.
- Two teeth in the small intestine.
- Thank God. Can you get them out?
Yeah, they should pass
on their own in a day or two.
Um, here. Flush discriminately.
- Poor guy.
- That's disgusting.
I gotta call my accountant.
Okay, tooth guy's going home.
Botox lady is up in Psych, and
Mr. Lam is sleeping it off in 2.
- Are you talking to me?
- No.
- Where's Brenner?
- Break room, suiting up.
Come on. I gotta go.
What did you decide on?
Gibsons or Divina Cucina?
- None. Claudia made the plans.
- Ooh, I like the sound of that.
I'm meeting her in
Elmhurst. I'm going in blind.
- I'll bet it's something romantic.
- Wine tasting?
I bet it's hot-cop-fantasy role-play
stuff. Handcuffs and whatnot.
No. Grady. I'll let you know.
What kind of operation do you
run here? My back is killing me.
I'm sorry. We're waiting on
HMO approval for your MRI.
Well, hurry it up. If I'm gonna
rot, I'd rather do it in my La-Z-Boy.
- That's the last of the Marcaine.
- All right, thanks, Cecilia.
Dilantin level on your
seizure guy came back low.
Push 500 milligrams
and I'll get him ready to go.
- That's it?
- For now.
- You know, this is... This is still weird.
- What are you talking about?
Us. We've broken up,
we're working together.
We said we weren't gonna screw up
our schedules. Some awkwardness is...
- Weird.
- It's expected.
- If that's what you say.
- Guys, listen up.
Banfield is out sick. She left instructions
to get patient-satisfaction scores up.
Tony, yours are the
worst in the department.
She's had me on
Geriatrics study for weeks.
They're not the most
enthusiastic group.
Rub their feet, work a
jigsaw puzzle. Whatever.
78-year-old male, passed out
at home, combative in the rig.
- Ten minutes out.
- Bingo.
Oh, come on. Banfield's not here.
Give me someone a little less salty.
- I got a kid mixing X and valerian root.
- Okay. Fine.
You get Dr. Gates' numbers
up, it's dinner at Gibsons.
- I'll foot the bill.
- Don't blow this for me.
Sam, you're with me.
Hey, you know department policy
about switching weekend shifts?
Depends on Banfield's mood.
Going out of town?
No. Well, maybe. Uh,
North Carolina, maybe.
Hey, my delivery was short.
Mind if I steal some Kerlix?
- Yeah, sure.
- I'll grab it for you.
- What's in North Carolina?
- Ah, not sure, really.
Nothing... Nothing...
Nothing definite.
- Yeah, there's nothing.
- All right.
- I get it. Secret getaway.
- Yeah.
Well, whoever it is, my advice?
Keep it casual, keep it fun.
- You think?
- Believe me. It's a long way down.
- Is that the rig? SAM: They
said it was 10 minutes out.
Stop. Stop!
Mom. GATES: What happened?
Check on Zadro.
- I'm Dr. Brenner.
- Joanie.
Okay, Joanie. Any
trouble breathing?
- Lucy, are you okay?
- I think so.
- Honey... Ow!
- Mom. Oh, Mom.
- What is it?
- My hip.
- Don't move, Joanie.
- That goes for you too, Lucy.
Take a big deep breath.
- Pulse rate, 120.
- I'm okay. I can get out.
Lucy? Lucy? You stay there.
Let us check you first, okay?
I need a collar.
I hit my head.
- We gotta get you on a backboard.
- Are you serious?
You're lucky to be alive.
C-spine, chest and pelvis.
- Clear bilaterally, sternal contusion.
- Ah!
- Yeah, the seatbelt hurt your chest.
- Okay. Ouch!
- Right hip tender with internal rotation.
- Mom.
- Daughter's here.
- Are you okay?
Listen to the doctors.
- She has a minor forearm burn.
- Put her in sutures.
Mom has a broken hip. Could
have an intra-abdominal bleed.
Just give them a minute, okay?
Okay, fine. We need a
HemoCue. Check Curtain 2.
- I wanna go.
- We got this. Frank has my sign-outs.
Make sure the back gets an
MRI. His HMO won't approve.
- What do you want me to do?
- Talk them into it.
Not today. Stay if you
feel that strongly about it.
- I can't.
- I'm sorry.
Pulse ox is 97 on two liters.
Set up for a FAST.
All right, your neck is fine. I just
need to sew up your forehead.
- What about Steri-Strips?
- Eh, it's well into the sub-Q.
Well, how about that superglue?
You'll have much better results
with sutures. Listen to your doctor.
- Hey, Sam, drunk driver?
- Mom and daughter. Not sure why.
I hope they're okay.
Dr. Gates, that old guy
with syncope is here.
- Go. Someone else can stitch me up.
- Okay. I'll come back to check you out.
I need a signature for Dr. Gates on this
patient-satisfaction form before you go.
- It's already filled out.
- Just sign it.
Leo Malcolm, found at home.
Unconscious on the
scene. Woke up after a liter.
Mr. Malcolm, I'm Dr. Gates.
You know where you are?
Some fleabag
hospital, looks like.
Tachy at 118. BP,
98/40. Sats, 97.
Heart's beating fast.
Does anything hurt?
I'm fine. Man can't take a nap without
Big Brother knocking at the door.
Motion detector. No
movement for an hour...
paramedics get a call from
the monitoring company.
- May as well get it over with.
- I feel the same way.
Dr. Gates?
I mean, welcome to County,
sir. We're so glad you're here.
- Acetabular fracture.
- That's bad?
You broke the
socket of the hip joint.
We can reconstruct it surgically,
but you'll need to stay at the hospital.
- How long will that take?
- A week. Another month of rehab.
No, I can't. I have Lucy.
If the pelvis doesn't heal, you'll
develop arthritis, chronic pain.
- You could need a total hip replacement.
- All set.
I got a tetanus shot, Mom.
- Your daughter is very brave.
- She's my angel.
I don't know what happened. I mean,
one minute we were driving along...
and the next, my car won't stop.
You're lucky it happened
in front of a hospital.
God's plan, right?
Right. Right, Mom.
- Excuse me. Dr. Fazzio's on the phone.
- Is he approving the MRI?
Fork over the 4 grand, he says
you can do anything you want.
- Unbelievable. I'm ordering it.
- Hey, careful, Archie.
Let's not stick a patient with a huge
bill for an unauthorized procedure.
Hey, Lucy, have you ever
seen a newborn baby close up?
I'll take you to where
they're sleeping.
- It's okay. LUCY:
Okay. I'll be right back.
I've been looking after
her alone for so long.
You never expect
something like this to happen.
Well, we can hold off on surgery while
you find someone to take her home.
- Do you have any family nearby?
- Uh, my mom died when I was in college.
Do you have any friends that
can take her? Uh, siblings?
I have a brother, Stuart, but
we haven't talked in a while.
Last I heard, he
works a bar on Cicero.
I can call him if you want.
If he's reachable,
we need to try.
Look, Lucy was 3 the
last time we saw him.
He shows up late one
night, says he's in trouble...
he needs a place to
stay, regroup, whatever.
When we woke up,
he was long gone.
He'd stolen cash from my wallet
and my mom's wedding ring.
My family's gotten
pretty small since then.
I have a neighbor that looks after
her sometimes. We can just ask her.
Okay.
- What labs do you want?
- CBC, BMP, and a blood culture.
Oh!
All right, mid-epigastric
tenderness.
Yeah, your stomach would hurt
like this too if I pushed you like that.
- There's nothing wrong with me.
- Systolic only 88.
- So this doesn't hurt?
- Don't be so disappointed.
Little stick here.
- Ah, ah, ah. That's it, I'm out of here.
- Where you going?
- I'm going home.
- No, come on.
- Get out of my way.
- You're not going anywhere.
- Do you want me to call Dr. Brenner?
- I got this.
The paramedics would
not have brought you here...
if they thought
nothing was wrong.
Your heart's beating way too
fast, your blood pressure's very low.
Let me help you.
I'm fine, you know. I'm fine.
Finger.
Everyone wants to help me.
- Draw some blood, will you?
- What? Hold on. Wait.
My daughter, you know? - Mm-hm.
She got these computers
all over my house.
Couldn't even go to the can
without this little light blinking at me.
She's worried about you.
Yeah, she should have let me
go to the assisted-living place.
At least there, I wouldn't
be bothering nobody.
Let's order an abdominal series.
- What's that?
- Take X-rays of your belly.
- I'm fine.
- No, no. Come on.
Look, if it's clear, I'll
call you a cab. Deal?
Deal.
No fever, no neuro deficits. An
epidural abscess is a long throw.
Worsening pain, not
relieved with vicodin.
We should image him
before he's paralyzed.
Of course. But
it's not our call.
Somebody called this
guy about his sister.
You're Stuart Moore?
- Joanie was asking about me?
- Yeah, I called you, yeah.
Must be bad, man. I'm
the last person she'd call.
- Okay, she's back here.
- Uh, Dr. Brenner?
Frank, his sister is in
Trauma 1. Would you mind?
Look, Dr. Fazzio promised
he'd be down in the next hour.
If he doesn't approve it,
call my cell. I'll deal with it.
- Fine.
- Really? I can go?
Hallelujah. Thank you.
Hey, Sam. I, uh,
talked to Dubenko...
about the Roux-en-Y with the
robotic surgery system next week.
- You got me in? Cool, thanks.
- Mm-hm.
We've seen you
upstairs quite a bit.
Yeah, I'm taking as
many O.R. shifts as I can.
I'm not really having a
great time down here.
Tony. Breakup.
- Oh, well, you seem to be managing.
- For the most part. But you know him.
You know. We had coffee.
He apologized, I yelled...
then we both decided we
didn't want it to affect our jobs...
- so that's that.
- I'm sorry.
It's okay.
From now on, I am keeping
my work life out of my "life" life.
Well, sounds like a plan.
- You were done loaning me money.
- So you rob me?
My car was in the shop, Joanie.
That is not what I'm talking about. I
am talking about what you did to me.
You want your half of Mom's
ring? The ring was a joke.
What is he doing here?
I did not want him called.
I'm sorry, but we called your
neighbors, they're out of town.
It's him or foster care.
- She'd be better off with strangers.
- We're fine.
CT can take her.
- Everything okay?
- My brother needs to leave.
Call CT. We're gonna
take her upstairs.
If something's happening
with Lucy, I should know.
Why should you know?
You don't deserve anything.
Okay, you know what?
Here. Have a nice life.
Get out!
Stuart, I'm sorry about
all this. I didn't realize...
- Yeah, look, it was my mistake to come.
- Look, your sister's sick.
- Someone needs to take care of Lucy.
- That ain't me.
- Hey.
- Sam, he's not interested.
- I'm leaving.
- You're just gonna walk away?
- It's what she wants.
- Not what your niece wants.
- What do you know?
- She needs someone.
Stuart.
Lucy's not my niece.
She's my daughter.
So Joanie's not her mother?
I don't know where her mom is.
She took off when,
uh, Lucy was 3.
And Lucy has no idea?
I haven't exactly been around.
Yeah, I know.
Look, I didn't know
what I was doing.
I wasn't supposed to have a kid.
I figured leaving her with
Joanie was the best I could do.
Well, uh...
Asking your sister to raise
your child, it's a pretty big favor.
I guess that's why I didn't ask.
Joanie's in trouble.
She needs your help now.
I got a tiny apartment.
I play guitar at a bar.
I can't take care
of a 9-year-old kid.
Hey, maybe you'll
surprise yourself.
I doubt it.
Uh, look, I gotta go, so, uh,
tell Joanie I had to go to work.
- Uh, maybe I'll come visit later.
- Sure.
So?
He's not gonna do it.
Call foster care when
you're done with the CT.
It's been over an hour. You
were gonna call me a cab.
- The results are on their way.
- Huh.
Hey, look. I got lightheaded
and I fainted, ain't no big deal.
Why can't you understand?
Whatever you have,
Leo, let us try to fix it.
Ah, I'm sure you will.
Hi, I'm Dr. Rasgotra. I'm sorry
to keep you waiting. I got tied up.
I've got the O.R. standing by.
- Free air under the diaphragm.
- It's most likely a perfed ulcer.
He's been taking large doses
of ibuprofen for his arthritis.
- Do you have any belly pain?
- No.
The NSAIDs could be
masking the symptoms.
Uh, Mr. Malcolm, air in
the abdomen is not normal.
We need to go in, find the
perforation, and repair it.
Go in? NEELA: Mm-hm.
Lady, I'm 78 years old.
There is some increased risk
associated with surgery at your age...
but there's every reason to
believe there will be a good outcome.
If you don't do this
operation, you could die.
What are we waiting for?
Cancer? I've seen that.
No, thank you.
- Are you sure this is your decision?
- Yes. No, thank you.
- His daughter is here. GATES:
Have them hold on a second.
Look, Leo, this is one
relatively routine operation.
- You could be home in a few days.
- That's what they told my wife.
Two years later, she was still in the
hospital, tied to hoses and machines.
I can't do that, man.
You get to stay here
and watch all the action.
We're going to see inside my mom?
- Yeah, it's pretty cool.
I can do a 3-D reconstruction.
Wow.
- How are you doing?
- A little dizzy.
It's probably the morphine.
Will I be able to meet the
foster family before she goes?
Of course.
- And she can visit me here?
- Yeah. Every day.
Two weeks is gonna
fly by, you'll see.
She deserves better than Stuart.
Does she remember him at all?
She knows that she has an uncle.
She knows that she met him
once. That he lives in the city.
My brother...
He wasn't always like this.
But I'm worried that if I'm stuck
here, he'll use it against me.
He could use custody to blackmail
me for money. It's what he does.
But you're her mom now.
Not legally.
I always thought adoption
was just a formality.
I never thought that
I could ever really...
lose her.
You won't.
Joanie, he's not coming back.
So, what happens now?
Well, if he's refusing treatment,
there's nothing we can do.
Nothing? This is a hospital.
You can't just let someone die.
It's his choice.
It's been one battle after
another since my mom died.
Trying to move him out of
his house, give up his car.
Feels like I should
know how to do this.
Sometimes, people make this kind
of decision when they're depressed.
Maybe we can have
him talk to somebody.
- Like a psychiatrist?
- We can offer counseling, medication.
I know he's not
ready to say goodbye.
- Hi, Archie.
- I'm late, I'm sorry.
- Don't worry about it.
Come on in. MORRIS: Oh.
- Nice place. Here, these are for you.
- Aww.
- I have a surprise for you.
- Yeah? What kind of surprise?
- Hey, are those cupcakes?
- Yes.
And balloons. I like
balloons, I guess.
Archie, this is my mom,
Olga. My sister, Lorraine.
My cousins Bianca,
Javier, Gabriella, Jose.
And these are my
grandmothers, Carmen and Alicia.
- Hey. I'm having Psych see Leo.
- What? Why?
If we can have him
declared incompetent...
we can have power of attorney
transferred to his daughter.
He's not incompetent.
He doesn't want treatment.
If not incompetent,
then depressed.
It's natural. It's part of
the process of letting go.
If a 25-year-old kid refused surgery,
you'd get Psych involved just like that.
It's his right to decide...
whether he wants his last years
spent in and out of hospital beds.
You have to respect his
wishes. Here you go, Frank.
Isn't it ridiculous to file four
copies of the base-station report?
Gee, that thought has
never occurred to me.
Neela. Uh, just put the rest in
the break room. I'll deal with them.
Also, your father of the
year is out there in Waiting.
Stuart Moore? He came back?
Yeah, I'm watching my wallet,
suggest you do the same.
Car crash in the ambulance
bay, dysfunctional family drama.
- Yeah, listen, I was... About Duke.
- Yeah, I'm sorry about that.
I don't know why I was going
on. I guess I got caught off-guard.
It's a big move. You're probably
right to be a little hesitant.
- I was thinking maybe we could...
- I booked my flight.
- You did?
- Lucien switched my schedule.
He said if I couldn't come up
with a better reason than nerves...
- Of course. That's good.
- It's just an interview, right?
No need to make
any big life decisions.
- I'll see you later.
- All right. Bye.
- Need some help here!
- Mom.
- I need some help!
- Mom, wake up.
- I need a doc... Dr. Brenner.
- Mom?
Dropped her pressure,
dropped her sats, lungs are wet.
Pink frothy sputum. Pulmonary edema.
- Congestive heart failure?
We're helping her breathe.
She might have bruised
her heart in the crash.
BiPAP, 40 of Lasix, titrate,
dopamine, and set up for an ultrasound.
Calm down, okay? Calm down,
step aside and let us do our job.
Thirty on 15. Let's see if
we can avoid intubation.
- Multifocal PVCs.
- Hundred of lidocaine.
Mommy, please talk to me. Mommy.
She's sleeping, Lucy.
Her oxygen level is low.
When the heart isn't pumping
well, the lungs fill with fluid.
- BiPAP is on.
- Diffuse hypokinesis.
- Ejection fraction, 20 percent.
- Looks dilated cardiomyopathy.
- Can't be from the crash.
- What's happening?
Your mom's heart isn't doing its
job. We're trying to find out why.
Run of six on the monitor.
- Did she present in failure?
- No.
Couldn't handle the two
liters of saline we gave her.
- Mommy.
- V-tach. Charge to 300.
Stop! SAM: You're charged.
All right, clear.
- Could someone get her out of here?
- All right, clear.
- No change.
- No! No! Mommy! Mommy!
I wanna stay! I wanna stay!
She was down for two minutes,
came back after the third shock.
Yeah. Okay, that sounds good.
You call me when you're ready.
- Was that Cardiology?
- Fulminant myocarditis.
Heart biopsy is gonna tell
us if it's treatable with steroids.
What about the hip surgery?
We'll keep her in traction, give
her lungs a chance to dry out...
before we subject
her to anesthesia.
I put the little girl in the break
room. Social Service is on their way.
Jeez, poor kid. Two weeks
is scary enough, but a month?
And if the biopsy
shows scarring...
The brother's out in
Waiting. I'll speak to him.
- We are not sending her with that guy.
- He's the father.
He deserves to know if his
child is gonna be sent off.
- He didn't mind abandoning her.
- That was six years ago.
- This is different.
- You think?
Hey. It was a slow night.
- How did the surgery go?
- She hasn't had it yet.
We discovered Joanie
was in heart failure.
- What? From the car crash?
- No, it's something else, I think.
We're running a test now
to assess the damage.
Stuart, your daughter was with
Joanie when she needed CPR.
And she's scared.
And she needs a
place to stay tonight.
Yeah.
All right.
- Is my mom okay?
- Uh, she might be upstairs for a while.
Lucy, there's someone here
to see you. This... This is Stuart.
Your, uh, mom's told
you about me, I think.
A little. You're my uncle?
You probably don't remember,
but, uh, we met when you were little.
Yeah. It was a long time ago.
I've been busy. I, uh...
Stuart here is a musician.
Really? That's cool.
What kind of music?
- Uh, rock, mostly. You like music?
- I like The Police.
Tsk. What? Come
on. The Police, really?
My mom and I like the
song about dinosaurs.
- You ever, uh, listen to The Clash?
- They're all right.
- Liz Dade is here.
- Okay.
Um, Lucy, do you mind if I, um,
leave you guys alone for a minute?
- No, it's okay.
- Okay.
You know, your mom and I used to
listen to The Police when we were kids.
We had it on a cassette
tape. You know what that is?
We used to blast it so loud.
Drove your grandma crazy.
That's Stuart Moore?
- Yeah, he's the father.
- Technically.
That's what the
birth certificate says.
No criminal record, no history
of violence, no record of abuse.
Given the gravity of Joanie's condition,
he's a candidate for temporary custody.
- If he wants.
- I think he will.
You can't show up after six years
and act like nothing's happened.
I'll interview him. Get a sense if he
can handle it. But, yeah, he's the father.
- What about Joanie?
- She knows Lucy best.
She'll need to sign off.
And, Sam, we are not gonna
add to the stress of her illness.
I think it's a mistake.
Check this out.
Here it comes. All
right, you ready?
Sing that part with me.
That's it.
So, uh, her nephew's
7th birthday party.
Seven years.
Boy, what a fun age, huh?
Just running around
with other 7-year-olds.
Come on. Come on.
They don't speak English.
Kind of wish I knew that.
- You speak Spanish?
- No, not really.
I'm fine. Come on.
Okay, you know?
That's my cousin, Rogelio.
He always does this.
Don't worry. We'll
just serve the cake.
Superhero Gary is, like,
Philip's favorite TV character.
If he sees this, he'll freak.
- What can we do?
- I don't know.
Superhero Gary! Superhero Gary!
Greetings, small children.
You're not Gary. - Nice tights.
It's, uh, a beautiful day
in the neighborhood.
A beautiful day for a birthday.
- It's somebody's birthday.
- It's Philip's birthday.
It's somebody's
birthday. Philip. Yes.
- What a rip-off.
- Ahh!
- How old are you, Philip?
- You're not Superhero Gary.
Of course I am. Yeah,
I'm Superhero Gary.
I'm the strongest
man in Chicago.
With the... Behold my
biceps of superness.
- Boo! Those are fake.
- Your hair looks different.
- And his legs.
- Superhero Gary has man legs.
These are my bionic legs, yes. For
leaping buildings in a single bound.
- What's a bound?
- It's... Don't do that.
- Get him.
- Okay, Philip. Seriously.
- You guys. Come on. Stop.
- Get him!
- You guys.
- Stop it.
How are you feeling, Joanie?
- Better.
Satting well on BiPAP,
switching her to 10 liters by mask.
I felt like I was drowning.
Over a liter of urine
output with the Lasix.
You get the results?
Joanie...
most of your heart muscle has
been replaced by scar tissue.
I don't understand.
- A virus attacked your heart.
- A virus? What kind of virus?
Well, it could have
been a cold or a flu.
Something in the last
12 months, perhaps.
- How does something like this happen?
- It's extremely rare.
Now, unfortunately, the
damage is irreversible.
Now we'll wait to see if your
heart responds to IV medication.
But if it doesn't, we may have
to put you on the transplant list.
Mom. Mom. Mom.
What about Lucy?
I'm gonna take her, Joan. - No.
Just for a couple of
weeks, till you're better.
It's a lot of
responsibility. Every day.
- He knows that.
- It's more than just watching her.
There's an old woman in my
building. She can help out if I need it.
- Is that cool, kiddo?
- It's cool.
- We'll catch up for lost time.
- Stuart.
Hey.
I can do this.
Let me prove it to you.
- You don't have to if you don't want to.
- I want to.
Here we go again.
What did the psychiatrist say?
He says you're not suicidal,
you're not depressed...
and you have the right
to refuse treatment.
Finally, a doctor
around here who listens.
Refusing treatment
is the first step.
- We need to walk you through the rest.
- The rest of what?
He means the hospice, if
that's the path you're choosing.
Yeah, it is.
Contents of your bowel
could spill into your abdomen...
and, uh, cause a
massive infection.
Get through your blood
stream, infect your lungs.
- Which we will treat with antibiotics.
- Fine.
Blood pressure could, uh, drop so
low that fluid could get into your lungs.
We'll give you medication
to keep you comfortable.
- If you have to.
- Morphine.
Which will make you out of it.
You won't be able to see, talk.
Your daughter will watch
you lose the ability to breathe.
You wanna put your
daughter through that?
Tony.
Can you step outside, please?
- What was that?
- He's making a mistake.
You think scaring him
is the best solution?
- What choice do I have?
- Let it go.
Hey.
- What is it?
- I wanna apologize for earlier.
I watched my wife turn into a
corpse before my very eyes.
What makes you think that I can't
handle a little shortness of breath?
Hey, you, uh,
religious or something?
Huh?
You afraid that God's
gonna get mad at me?
It's not about that.
Why can't I, uh, show my
family that I'm still strong?
That I can, uh, leave this
world with some kind of dignity?
You wanna protect
your family. I get it.
Yeah. I sat with my
wife for two years...
waiting, watching her disappear.
I did that so that my
family didn't have to.
Two years.
And then, when it was over, she
didn't even remember who I was.
Now, what kind of
cruel joke is that?
Leo, you don't have
cancer. We can fix this, man.
Yeah. You did what you needed
to do. Now you just let me do mine.
I was talking to your
granddaughter, Alyssa.
She's going to, uh,
Wisconsin in the fall.
Civil engineering.
Building cities. Must be a
tough field to get into, huh?
She said she talked about it
when she was a kid with you.
That you wanted
to do the same thing.
They never had anything like
that when I was in the Navy.
She's got more
opportunities than I ever had.
- You must be proud.
- Oh!
I'm proud of all
my grandchildren.
They always remember
what they come from.
You know, I have a daughter.
- Oh, yeah?
- Mm-hm.
Haven't always done the
right thing, that's for sure.
Seeing you with your
family, meeting them...
and the way they look up to you,
all that you've accomplished, it's...
- You figure it out as you go.
- Yeah.
The college, the
classes, the career.
You've talked to her about
that your whole life. That's cool.
- And she's doing it.
- Mm-hm.
She's doing it. And she's doing
it not just for herself, but for you.
She's gonna graduate, and
she's gonna look out there...
and you're not gonna be there.
Is that how you want it to be?
You're buying me dinner.
- Holy Moses.
- Morris?
Dislocation of the left elbow...
needs post-reduction
films and an ortho consult.
Come on, kids.
I'll show you where they
reattached Evil Staxx's arm...
after I threw him
off the Sears Tower.
These are from the
county, state and DCFS...
saying that you agree to the terms
of the four-week custody arrangement.
It's a lot of forms.
Here's a map and
directions to Lucy's school.
You're responsible for
getting her to and from.
I got her pediatrician's office.
She's got an annual physical
scheduled in two weeks.
Why...? Can't some of this
wait until Joanie's better?
It's important to keep her
routine stable during the transition.
You need to bring her here every
day. Contact with Joanie is vital.
- How am I supposed to work?
- You'll figure it out.
Call me if you
have any questions.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Now, this is nothing
you can't handle.
Listen, uh, Lucy's with your
sister until we take her upstairs.
Why don't you go and
pick up some food?
Ike Ryan's is a block down.
Grab yourself some dinner.
- All right.
- All right?
- You need money?
- No, man. I got money.
I'll see you in half an hour.
And, um, this is a bench.
Yeah, where people wait to
hear matters of life and death.
Oh, and this is one of Superhero
Gary's favorite nurses, Sam Taggart.
Sam, this is Claudia
and her whole family.
Hi.
- "Superhero Gary"?
- Kid's birthday party.
Gates has got Neurosurgery
coming down on your patient.
- What patient?
- Your back-pain guy.
- BP dropped and he can't move his legs.
- He's still here? Excuse me.
Two liters of saline wide
open. Temp spiked to 103.
BP, 85/50. Oh,
good. Here he comes.
What the hell?
- Can you feel this?
- No. I can't move my legs.
Spinal shock. I'll
throw in a central line.
Why can't I move my legs?
You have an infection.
- Costume party?
- Seventh birthday.
Sats are down, 87 percent.
Okay, 100 percent
non-rebreather.
Mix Levophed,
four migs in 500 ccs.
Vanco and
ceftriaxone are hanging.
Introducer and guidewire.
Neurosurge will meet us in
MRI. GATES: I'm holding an O.R.
We need to take you to Surgery
to prevent permanent paralysis.
- Oh, God, I'm gonna be paralyzed?
- Well, we hope not.
Don't worry. I got you.
Okay, let's roll.
The clock is ticking.
- You're our hero.
- Coming though.
- Lucy? Lucy?
- Yeah, Mom?
Do you have your backpack
and your sweatshirt?
- Yeah. Don't worry, Mom.
- Okay.
Hey, listen.
You be a good
girl, okay? All right?
I'll see you tomorrow.
Okay.
- I love you.
- I love you more.
Come on.
Good night, guys.
- Bye, Dr. Morris.
- Happy birthday, Philip.
You know, impersonating a
superhero is a misdemeanor.
- It is?
- Mm-hm.
And resisting arrest
will only make it worse.
I guess I'm in big trouble.
- I guess you are.
- Ooh.
He probably went to get
his place ready for you.
We can wait out here for
a few minutes if you like.
He's not coming.
How do you know that?
I could tell.
It's kind of cold out here.
I'm okay.
How long is she gonna be here?
It's hard to say.
I hope it's not too long.
Me too.