Don't you pull
out, you dumb-ass.
I asked you a question.
I just don't wanna play anymore.
Oh, you think I like
waking up at 5:30 a.m.
in the morning for 10 years
to drive you to a cold arena?
My toes are frozen,
my ass is numb.
That damn coffee machine
gives me heartburn
all freaking day.
Wake up, Dad. I'm not
gonna make the NHL.
Not with that attitude.
You wanna end up
working in a factory
like me and your Uncle Don?
No.
No, you're damn right you don't.
You want a good job,
you gotta go to college.
If you want to go to college,
you'll need a scholarship.
I mean, you're a
bright kid and all,
but you're not gonna get a
scholarship with those grades.
Well, maybe my... My
grades would be better
if I wasn't playing
hockey all the time.
Oh.
Dad!
It's okay, keep it.
Nice tip. It's New Year's Eve.
He's got a long
day ahead of him.
Sounds okay to me.
Drive around Manhattan...
listen to the radio
talk to people,
no brain surgery.
Ha-ha-ha. Very
funny. It's weird.
You know, I've sent a couple
thousand people to the O.R...
And...? And I've
never been myself.
Well, you're a virgin.
I still have my
appendix, my tonsils.
The only general
anesthetic I've ever gotten
was in the dentist's chair.
Well, it's no different,
really. Oh, sure.
Pull a tooth, have
my skull sawed open.
It's pretty much the same thing.
I mean the anesthesia.
Except for that part
where they wake me up.
At that point, you'll know
things are going well.
Yeah. Right.
Are you ready?
Let's do it.
Come on. We gotta
get them out of there!
Cut the battery.
No. Take my dad.
We gotta get you
out to get to him.
All right.
Blunt head trauma,
open tib-fib fracture.
Dad? Dad, you okay?
Start a line... I
don't know. You?
I think I'm... I'm
hurt pretty bad.
Easy.
Paul?
Let's get 'em.
Paul!
Paul, you hear me?
How are you doing, sir?
What's wrong with my son?
He's going to the hospital.
What's your name?
Uh. Dan Harris.
Can you tell me what
day it is, Mr. Harris?
December 31st.
That's good. Let's
get a C-collar.
I need another backboard. Paul!
Pupils equal and reactive.
Okay, let's roll him.
Did you pass out?
I don't know. It
happened so fast.
Are in you in pain?
That air bag gave my
chest a pretty good shot.
Another two of morphine.
You're doing a ride-along.
Residency requirement.
I've been putting it off.
I thought you'd make
a good paramedic.
Ha-ha. That's funny.
Dan Harris, auto versus garbage
truck. Restrained passenger,
air bags deployed.
I cleared his neck on the ride.
My son, Paul Harris.
Did they bring him here?
Yeah, I think so.
We'll find out for you.
You taking any medications?
No.
You got any drug allergies? No.
This the other MVA? MALUCCI:
Yeah, 46-year-old male...
Any past surgeries?
Appendix, when I was
a kid. Where's Paul?
That's his son.
Weaver's got him in 2.
Who's Weaver?
End of the line,
Mr. Harris. Good luck.
What? You're leaving?
Yeah. Gotta save
some more lives.
One, two, three.
Let's get a 12-lead
and cut these clothes off.
All right, C-spine,
chest and pelvis,
trauma panel and a UA.
BP 130/92, pulse 116.
My wife just bought those pants.
Have you ever been
in this hospital before?
No. I haven't been in a
hospital since my son was born.
Twenty cc's of 1
percent lido with bicarb.
Ooh. That's cold.
Who's your family doctor?
Ow. Ow-oh.
Klizowski at the
Morgan Family Clinic.
What are you doing?
Putting a tube in your
chest to reinflate your lung.
I got a collapsed lung?
It happens with
your type of injury.
But you'll breathe
easier once it's in.
Thora-Seal's ready.
Is there anyone we can notify?
Uh, my wife, Debra.
All right, 28 French. Do
you have the number?
Uh, I can't remember.
I... I got it on speed dial.
She works...
She teaches at, uh, Our
Lady of Perpetual Hope.
Let's culture the bone.
Got an extra Foley kit?
Gram of Ancef and 100 of gent.
Paul! Give me a large Kelly.
Paul! Dad. Is that you?
Uh. Can you...?
Can you open that
door? I-I need to see him.
What are you doing?
This is the father.
I'm right here, son.
Irrigation saline,
sterile four-by-fours.
Hey, Dad? Yeah, they...
They just stuck a
freaking tube in my chest.
I'm in. Hook me
up to low suction.
I'm okay, though.
You know, your mom's
gonna be really pissed off
about her truck.
I'm gonna tell her you
were driving, okay?
Hey, Cleo. Need some
Xeroform over here.
Paul? Don't be scared, Paul.
I'm not. Be strong now.
Be strong.
He's gonna be okay, right?
Looks like a tough kid.
Yeah. Yes. He is.
Are you finished?
Yeah. Just need you to...
sign this.
It's a power of attorney.
Something goes wrong...
Something goes wrong, what?
No heroic measures.
No ventilators,
no feeding tubes.
If there's no hope of
meaningful recovery.
You're going to be fine, Mark.
Elizabeth, you're a surgeon.
You know that...
That you're going to be fine.
You don't want
the responsibility?
It's unnecessary.
I don't want to
end up like that.
Now you're being dramatic.
So if I end up in a
persistent vegetative state...
Fine.
Fine. Give it to me.
What's in the Thora-Seal?
Uh... minimal blood loss.
Oh, good. No hemothorax.
Mr. Harris? Yes?
Need you to sign this consent
for treatment for your son.
Where is he? Radiology.
What's he doing there?
We had to get x-rays of his leg.
He'll probably need surgery.
Can't you just put a cast on it?
The bone penetrated the skin.
But there's no joints
involved, and it's midshaft,
so it'll probably heal nicely.
Okay, Mr. Harris, I gotta
take you for a head CT.
What's that?
Head CT? Um, CAT scan.
It's a picture of your brain.
It's pretty standard
after you hit your head
and lose consciousness.
Did you tell her yet? Who?
Weaver.
Oh, um... No, not yet.
But... it's part of my
New Year's resolution.
Uh-huh. No, really. It is.
You okay?
Am I bleeding? No.
I'm fine.
Did you call the furnace guy?
Yep. Last week.
Is he coming over?
You don't want
the pipes to freeze.
Well...
Larry let him in.
Who's Larry?
You know, Larry
Corbin, the neighbor.
In the blue house?
No, in the brown, actually.
I'm sorry.
No. No, it's my fault.
Oh, damn.
You're gonna have to
put on scrubs anyway.
Scrubs?
You were planning on coming in.
Uh... don't you think
Burke might object?
You're probably right.
It's gonna be pretty
crowded in there.
Mark... do you
want me to come in?
No, I'll be fine.
You go get cleaned up.
I can finish this.
I'll be right back.
Okay.
I've never been so
claustrophobic before.
Happens to a lot of people.
Is everything all right?
Looks good,
but a radiologist has
to review the films.
Can I sit up? Sure.
Let me know if
you get lightheaded.
And we contacted the school.
They're trying to reach Debra.
Oh. God, I hope she doesn't
get in a car accident
rushing over here.
Hey, can we see Paul
before his operation?
That depends on when
the orthopedic surgeon
can schedule the surgery.
Oh, it's just his leg, right?
No, he had a head trauma.
Trauma? What do you mean trauma?
Well, he hit his
head... just like you did.
He's stable now, but we observe
head injuries very carefully.
You mean, he could be unstable?
I'm sure he'll be
fine, Mr. Harris.
Oh, God. She's gonna
think it's my fault again.
What?
Our first son died of SIDS.
He'd be about 20 now.
I'm sorry.
Yeah, he was 3 weeks old.
I'd sent my wife
out, you know, to...
get some rest,
you know, for herself,
for a couple hours.
The baby had been up
all night, finally fell asleep.
I must have dozed off myself.
Because I didn't wake
until I heard her scream.
She had come home to find
Nathan had died in his crib.
Well... I mean,
we didn't have the baby monitors
and stuff like you do nowadays.
I mean, she didn't blame me.
But I know...
I know that she thought if
she had stayed home that night,
he'd still be alive.
There's no way you
could have known.
Stick out your tongue.
Show me your teeth.
Repeat after me:
Ready to rock 'n' roll.
"Ready to rock 'n' roll."
And that we are.
So...
you know the procedure,
you've had your meds.
Anything on your mind?
That's why I'm here.
You won't see me in there,
but, uh, I'll be talking to you.
Good luck.
We don't need it.
But thank you, Mark.
So, what are you here for?
I'm Leo.
I'm Mark.
What are you here for?
I've got something
growing on my heart.
I'm not sure how
to say it right.
Myxoma? No. But
it sounds like that.
Teratoma? How did you know?
I'm a doctor. Yeah, right.
Doctors get sick too, you know.
I got something
growing on my brain.
What do they do for that?
Same as you.
Operate. Take it out.
Does it hurt? They
told me it wouldn't hurt.
You'll be asleep the whole time.
And when you wake up...
if you're sore, they'll
give you medicine.
This sucks.
It'll be over
before you know it.
It still sucks.
Yeah.
Is Trauma 1 still open, Randi?
No. Blast injury
to face coming in.
Some guy testing Roman
candles for a New Year's eve party.
I have to park you here until
I find you a room. I'll be back.
Uh, thanks.
Ask you?
No. I've been
waiting three hours.
♪ And surely Ye'll
be your pint-stowp ♪
♪ And surely I'll be mine ♪
♪ We'll tak a cup ♪
♪ O' kindness yet ♪
♪ For auld lang syne ♪
Happy New Year.
Okay, okay, okay,
Gordy. Back to bed.
Hey, Randi. Randi. Get
Blue Beacon on the phone.
They cannot deny authorization
for a retinal-artery occlusion.
Excuse me?
I got a page for
a surgical consult.
A guy in Curtain 2 has
a beeper up his rectum.
- What?
- Has it on vibrate.
Can't figure out how
he slipped it in there.
Ma'am?
Never underestimate
the elasticity
of the anal sphincter.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
You... You're the doctor...
who's taking care of
my son, Paul Harris.
The car accident?
Yes. Is he, uh...
Is he all right?
Well... They've arranged to
have him sent up to the O.R.
Yo, Dr. Weaver, we need you now.
Sats are dropping. To what?
Seventy-four. He
was getting sleepy.
- But now we can't wake him.
- Heart rate down to 50.
Paul! You want atropine?
Push a milligram.
Rapid induction... Paul!
Number 8 ET tube.
Paul. WEAVER: Let's go.
BP's 90/60.
Bag him on 100
percent. Paul. Paul!
Call for a vent.
Cricoid pressure.
I'm in. Bag him. Paul!
Do you hear me? Be
strong, Paul! Don't quit!
Hey, Mr. Harris.
Feeling any better?
No.
No? Well, you got
a collapsed lung?
Blood bank's low.
Weaver wants everybody to
donate before their shift's over.
I always do. Well, that's
very generous of you.
That, and I get
drunk for half as much
when I'm down a pint.
Take it easy. Uh, yeah.
Good news. Mr. Harris,
your CT looks normal.
I know, but this...
This... tube you stuck
in my chest is killing me.
Yeah? Abby. Give Mr. Harris
here another 5 of morphine.
We're gonna admit you,
and monitor you
for a day or two.
And then we'll take that,
uh, tube out. Okay. Okay.
Listen, uh, did you
find out anything at all?
Um, his oxygen level
was low for a while.
We're not sure why.
Is that your son? Yes.
What are his sats? Hundred
percent after intubation.
GCS is 10.
What, uh... What's that mean?
Um, it could be...
a bruise to the brain.
But we won't know for
sure until after the scan.
Well, when is that?
Any minute now.
Mr. Harris?
Yes? I'm Officer Darcy.
How you doing?
Uh, well, I've been better.
I have to write
an accident report.
Can you tell me what happened?
Well, I...
You know, I-I-I
honestly don't remember.
One minute, I'm driving the...
car with my son.
And then... the next minute,
the paramedics are
just dragging me out.
That guy came out of nowhere.
You failed to stop
for the red light.
I would never do that.
No, it wasn't my fault.
Several witnesses say it was.
Guess it's too late to
change my mind now.
Would you? No.
They took that kid in
for a teratoma resection
while you were gone.
He was pretty freaked out.
I'm sure they'll be here soon.
Okay. Time to go.
Okay, you need help?
Nope. I've got it.
You gonna go see a movie?
I'll be right outside.
Hey. Your hands are like
ice. Do you want a blanket?
Mark?
Mark, are you okay?
If I don't make it through...
Sh. Don't talk like that.
If I don't make it...
I left you the life insurance.
It'll pay for the house,
for you and the baby.
I'm sorry, Mark. I
can't go through here.
I love you, Elizabeth.
I love you too.
You're going to be okay,
and I'll see you
very, very soon.
Okay, Mr. Greene...
I'm gonna lower your head now.
Jesus. This is my
last guy. You done?
No, man. I gotta pull a double.
Happy-freaking-New Year, huh?
Tell me about it.
All this for me?
Yep.
Slide on over to
the table for us.
Okay, Mark.
I'm Dr. Hammond,
your anesthesiologist.
And you'll be looking at me...
and talking to me
throughout the surgery.
Okay?
Okay.
For the burr hole,
I'll need a Midas
Rex with an M-8 bit.
Then I'll switch to a
V-1 for the bone flap.
Excuse me, Dr. Burke?
Uh, you said you'd give
me a little something
to take the edge off.
Excuse me, Dr. Burke?
So, what? It's a coma?
It's not what you
think of as a coma.
He's having what we call
"purposeful movements."
And the CAT scan
shows there's no sign
of hemorrhage
or skull fractures.
You know, he's... unconscious,
but if you'd like
to talk to him,
I'm pretty sure he'll
be able to hear you.
Hey, son.
It's time to wake up now.
You ready to go home?
Well, you gotta open your eyes.
Every day I used to do
this to get him up for school.
Sometimes he'd fake it...
until I tickled him.
Son...
be strong now.
Mark? Mark?
Hey, Mark? Mark? Hey, Mark?
Mark.
Breathe for me.
Let's check the lapel mike.
Testing. One, two, three.
How you doing there?
Testing.
Tell me your name.
M... Mark.
Mark what?
Mark Greene.
Hi, Mark.
I'm Dr. Malcolm from Neurology.
How many fingers?
Can't see.
He needs his glasses.
Elizabeth?
Fingers first, Mark. How many?
Three. Good.
Elizabeth?
I thought you might
like some company.
Nice hat.
Thanks.
All right, Mark.
I'll be doing the
language testing
while Dr. Burke maps the brain.
I have an itch.
Where?
Behind my knee.
May I?
Sure.
Left or right?
Left.
Okay, Mark. Name
the months of the year.
January, February
March, April...
Ah.
That's it. Little lower.
Uh, May, June, July...
Mr. Harris? Mr. Harris?
Your wife is here.
Dan?
Debra.
What happened?
We got hit by a garbage truck.
O.R.'s ready.
No. You said he'd
wake up on his own.
Yeah, the surgery's for his leg.
We'll take him up to
the O.R. in a minute.
He looks so big just lying here,
doesn't he?
Remember I used to
hold him in my hand
and rock him to sleep?
Yeah.
Used to think I was
gonna drop him.
Remember that? Yep.
Hey. Paul.
Debra, I ran a red.
We were arguing about
him quitting hockey,
and the music was really
loud like it always is, and
I don't know.
I must... have missed
the light change. It...
Honey, it was an accident.
Debra, I... I'm sorry. Don't.
Mr. Harris. You all right?
Ah, I think this tube is
getting my chest again.
Maybe we should
get you back to bed.
No. I wanna stay
here with my son.
Malik. I think you'd
feel more comfortable
if you were lying down.
No. No. I wanna
stay here, damn it.
How's your breathing? Debra.
Having any chest pain?
A little.
Yeah... He needs a 12-lead.
No! I wanna stay
with my son. Ten liters.
Let's get a BP.
Debra, I'm sorry!
Give him a nitro spray if
his systolic gets over 100.
So sorry.
Trumpet.
Hammer.
Dolphin.
Guitar.
Tent.
Pachyderm.
Another name for this one?
Elephant.
It's Dr. Burke, Mark.
You're doing great.
We're mapping
out Broca's just fine.
Glad to hear it.
Four milliamps, please.
Catapult.
Thermometer.
Bulldozer.
Hesitation on that one.
Got it.
Window.
Hesitation again.
Try to read the card, Mark.
How are you doing there, Mark?
Mark?
My...
thumb.
He's diaphoretic.
I don't...
good.
Elizabe...
He's seizing. Oh, my God.
Cool saline, please.
Sats are 92.
What's happening?
Electronic
stimulation-induced seizure.
Dousing the brain with
saline should cool it down.
Mark, you said
you'd be home at 5.
Mark. It's now 9:00.
Give him some Ativan.
We can't sedate him,
or we won't be
able to talk to him.
Cancel the surgery.
Try propofol.
Well, what else can you do?
Give it a minute.
Too severe.
Mark! Mark!
He's postictal. What now?
Can't resect the tumor
until he's awake and alert.
Mark. Mark, it's Elizabeth.
Wake up.
Mark, come on home.
Mark, we need you
to talk to us. Mark.
That's a good
gag with the scope.
He might be lightening up.
Mark?
Come on, Mark.
Come on, buddy. Try
and wake up. Mark!
Ah. No response
to painful stimuli.
His eyes are open,
but he's out of it.
How long since the seizure?
Half an hour.
Still no significant
change in GCS.
Well, maybe we
should just close up
and come back in a few days.
In a few days? You've
just opened his skull.
Hey.
What...?
What's going on out there?
You had a seizure
during mapping, Mark.
We had to wait.
I'm okay.
Keep going.
You heard the man. Dr. Malcolm?
Okay, Mark.
Name things that
start with the letter B.
Baseball.
Broccoli.
Brazil.
Bamboo.
Burke.
Brain.
Broca.
You okay?
Fine.
How you feeling?
Okay.
I'm sleepy.
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
Come on now, Mark.
Things that begin with B.
Uh.
Baby.
Boy.
So you think we're
gonna have a boy, do you?
Just a hunch.
We could find out if you like.
Let's...
Let's wait. See.
Well, then we have to argue
about boy and girl names.
What about Jesús?
Jesús?
That's Jesus.
Jesus Greene.
I'm sorry, Mark, but I need you
to work with me here. More B's.
Okay.
Bobby.
Bill.
Bradley.
Bubba.
Any more pain, Mr. Harris?
Not since you put that
stuff under my tongue.
MVA with pneumothorax.
He had some chest pain,
but responded very
nicely to the nitro.
I'm going off duty.
Dr. Kovac here is gonna continue
to manage your care.
He flipped his T waves
in the anterior leads
waiting for a tele
bed. Is that bad?
You could be at
risk for heart attack.
We need to admit
you for observation.
Uh. Did they start his surgery?
My son.
They took him to the
Operating Room for his leg.
But nobody's told
me how he's doing.
Dr. Kovac can
find that out for you.
Good luck, Mr. Harris.
Happy New Year.
Were you having chest
pain before your collision?
No, I do... I don't
remember anything.
Did you pass out?
What do you mean?
With angina, you can
get an irregular heartbeat.
And that can cause
you to pass out?
Yeah.
Because your heart doesn't
pump enough blood to your brain.
What? Could that have
caused my accident?
It happens a lot.
So it wasn't my fault.
What?
The accident.
Probably not.
I gotta talk to my wife.
Does your chest hurt?
Like a son of a bitch.
Malik, I need some help here.
Pressure's down to 80 systolic.
ST elevation on the monitor.
Mix up the dopamine.
He's having an MI.
What's an MI?
A heart attack. Oh. Gee.
We need to go to
the cath lab now.
What are... What are
you gonna do there?
You got a blocked
artery on your heart.
We need to open it up.
First, I gotta talk
to my wife. Wait.
Dr. Burke. He's awake.
Hey, Mark. Do you
know where you are?
Hospital.
That's right.
You're in Recovery.
What's the date?
New Year's Eve.
And who's that?
I've never seen
her before in my life.
She's pretty darn cute.
Hold out your hands.
Wiggle your fingers.
Okay. Now wiggle your toes.
Very good.
How did it go?
Fantastic.
Resected the tumor
with clean margins.
Chemotherapy wafers are in.
You see? You
made it. I told you.
Now get some rest, both of you.
I'll be back in an
hour for a neuro check.
Do you remember anything?
Something about...
baby.
We discussed a boy's name.
We're gonna have a boy.
God!
Feels like someone
parked a Volvo on my chest.
He's still throwing PVCs.
Could be his chest tube.
Try to reposition.
I need to talk to my wife.
I'll explain what
happened. Just relax.
Oh, God.
Me and my son...
had to be arguing
when this happened.
How old is he?
Fifteen.
Part of being that age.
He needs your support the
most when he wants it the least.
You a dad?
No.
Mrs. Harris would
like to come in.
For a minute.
You look like a nurse.
Paul's awake.
Is he okay?
Yeah. They... They
took the tube out,
and... he's breathing
on his own, and...
Well, he's asking
for a cheeseburger.
Oh... God.
Thank you.
Hey, honey.
What happened? You okay?
I got a blocked artery...
on my heart.
I guess those sliders
finally caught up with me.
Yeah.
Well, the docs figure
that the blockage
made me pass out this morning.
That's what caused the accident.
Oh, God.
I'm... really sorry
about downstairs.
I just...
He was lying there, and, uh...
And you thought I did it again.
Dan, stop.
I think it's time for
visiting hours to end.
Mrs. Harris.
Tell Paul I'll see him in a bit.
You better.
I'm going on break, Dr. Corday.
Can I bring you back a
frozen yogurt or something?
No, thanks. I'm fine, Terry. Oh.
I have to go now. I'm late.
Hey. It's good to see you
have your sense of humor.
I suppose that's a good sign.
Mark? Mark?
I left the oven on.
He's off the monitor.
I know. I know. He's altered.
Now, where are my car keys?
Can you give him some Valium?
I don't have an order for that.
Lie back down, Dr. Greene.
No. No, the lasagna,
it's gonna burn.
Look... he needs sedation
and a stat head CT.
No, I need to leave right now.
I can't take your orders.
You're not on the staff.
He could have an epidural bleed.
Get Dr. Burke.
He was called to an
emergency consult.
What do you think this is?
What's going on?
Trauma patient had a
coronary thrombosis.
Yeah. Why wasn't I consulted?
Cardiology is handling it.
Yeah, I can see that.
What about our glycoprotein
2B3A inhibitor study?
He didn't meet the criteria.
I decide who meets the criteria.
What? You mean, I
didn't have to have this?
On a low-fat diet, you
wouldn't need any of this.
Damn it! What's wrong?
There's a dissection
in the left main.
Nice work, Jack.
What... What's wrong?
What's happened?
The catheter made a small
tear in your blood vessel.
What? He's
dropping his pressure!
Multifocal PVCs.
Hundred of lidocaine.
Looks like a
surgical patient now.
Up dopamine to 20 mics.
Notify the O.R.
Wh-wh-wh... What's wrong?
You've had a complication.
The only way to save your
heart is bypass surgery.
Open-heart surgery? Yep.
When? Right now.
Can't we talk about this?
Let's go. Go, go.
Mm-hm.
Hey, Mark.
You had us a little worried.
No. No sign of post-op bleeding.
But the steroids
made you a little crazy.
What did I say?
I've heard much worse.
Look, I'll check
on you in a little bit.
Call me if you need
me, okay? Mm-hm.
Mark, I'll be right
back. All right?
Dr. Burke.
Hey.
Pressure's down
to 70. Dr. Karis.
Put him in Trendelenberg.
Squeeze in two units.
Get me a staple remover.
A liter out of the chest.
Get him off the vent.
Bag him at 100 percent.
Tell the blood bank
we need another six.
Splash him with Betadine.
Open a thoracotomy
tray. Wire cutters!
He's tachy at 130.
Ready for rib spreaders.
He's ruptured his aortic trunk.
Side-biting clamp.
I'll see you in Recovery.
You're not coming with me?
You're with the
surgical team now.
Say goodbye to Dr. Kovac.
Good luck.
I don't want surgery.
Well, you don't
really have a choice.
I want a second opinion.
You could get that,
but you'd be dead
before a doctor
could examine you.
All right, let's move!
We got no time!
I wanna be cutting
in five minutes.
Okay, we're gonna
scoot you over now.
Ready and lift.
Mr. Harris, I'm Dr. Babcock,
the anesthesiologist.
Are you allergic to any drugs?
Uh, no.
Are you taking any medications?
Just the stuff they
gave me today.
What's he on, Shirley?
Uh, dopamine,
lidocaine and nitro.
Ever have a bad
reaction to an anesthetic?
Mr. Harris?
No!
Why isn't this guy under?
I had to throw in an art line.
Gown me.
You're the guy in
the Emergency Room.
Dr. Benton does it all.
You were in a
collision with your son.
Yeah. You're gonna
go to sleep now.
No. Wait, wait, wait, wait. I
got a bad feeling about this.
Pump primed and ready? - Set.
No. I'm not gonna
make it. I know it.
You'll make it.
You gotta tell my
son something for me.
You can tell him
after the operation.
Not if we don't
get in there soon.
Uh, please, tell
him that I love him.
And that I'm very proud
of him more than he'll...
All right, let's tube him.
Okay, let's go.
The clock's ticking,
his heart isn't.
Okay, Mark.
Follow my finger with your eyes.
Mark, follow his finger.
Mrs. Street?
Why don't we go to
the Waiting Room?
Sorry.
They'll call you with updates.
How. Okay.
What were the three things
I asked you to remember?
Huh? The three items. Remember?
Um... giraffe,
beach ball, 123 Main Street.
Three for three.
Do you know what
happened to him?
Who?
The heart kid.
Uh, they got him to the O.R.
It's touch-and-go.
I'm gonna have somebody
from Psychiatry talk to you.
No, thanks.
I recommend it
to all my patients.
Depression suppresses
the immune system.
It can hinder recovery.
Don't need a therapist.
Could get this Foley out.
Well... If you have
urinary retention...
Nurse can throw another one in.
Mark.
The sooner I get it out,
the sooner I can walk.
Sooner I can walk,
the sooner I get out of here.
No offense.
Okay, I'll take out the Foley.
Bathroom privileges?
Only if somebody walks you.
You're a lucky guy, Mark.
There has never been a
more successful treatment
for your tumor.
If you believe that...
and mobilize your
inner resources...
you're going to survive.
Time of death 2048.
He didn't make it.
No.
But I did.
Yeah.
You fixed my heart.
Yep.
I didn't even know I
had a heart problem.
That car accident
saved my life.
You never heard
of a yearly checkup?
Hey, son.
You okay?
Yeah, I feel like I got
hit by a truck. Again.
Did you sleep well?
Yeah. Except when you
were yapping in my ear,
asking me to wake up.
I notice you didn't listen.
I was in a coma.
You know, you
always got an excuse.
Hey, son.
I guess this means, uh...
you're not gonna
play hockey anymore
this year, huh?
Well, they said
the cast will be off
in six to eight weeks.
Uh. Your leg's
broken. It's weak.
Let it heal.
Well, I mean, I'll be
doing physiotherapy.
Maybe we can start
running together.
Trying to give me
another heart attack?
You gave me a scare, Dad.
You too.
We're under a minute, Dick,
and Times Square
is raring to go.
Some rocking New
Year's Eve, huh? Hm.
It'll do.
When are they gonna come
take this damn Foley out?
It's been over three hours
since he put in the order.
Oh, I think she's busy
with another patient.
I can't wait any
longer. I gotta pee.
Then go.
Mark.
Come on. You know how to do it.
I can't believe I'm doing this.
I don't think I can order those
for a patient ever again.
Are you sure you're up to this?
Nature calls.
Easy. I got it.
You're not supposed to do this
on your own, you know.
Once I get in there...
can I stand on my own?
No. You can sit. Ha.
Okay. Let me try. All right.
Ooh.
See? It's not a race.
You just be careful.
Okay. Small steps. Mm-hm.
I know. Small steps.
That's it. See, you're doing it.