.
[Dramatic music]
♪ ♪
- ...off his liver
from the stab wound--
he's dumping blood.
- Get him on the table.
- Three, two, one, lift.
- Vitals?
- 95 over 50,
tachy at 140.
- Chris?
Chris.
Hey, you're bleeding
too much, okay?
I need to open you up.
- Etomidate's in.
- He go unconscious,
or was that you?
- No way to know.
- Sats are dropping.
88...
80.
- Is he tubed yet?
- Not yet.
- Let's get more blood.
- Two bags on the transfuser.
- Damn it, I can't get it in.
- I'm gonna thread a wire
up to you through the neck,
help guide the tube down.
Central line kit?
- Just give me a few seconds.
- I don't have a few seconds.
[Rapid beeping]
- Heart rate's falling.
Giving 1 of atropine.
- I can't see it.
Got it.
[Rapid beeping continues]
- I'm in.
- Give me a knife.
Get Dr. zanetti in here
right now.
- Heart rate 50.
- Hang in there, Chris.
[Dramatic music]
Great. Open more laps
and keep 'em coming.
I'm gonna need around 20.
Keep up with me.
If we don't pack him fast,
he will bleed out and die.
[Dramatic music]
♪ ♪
- Is he still bleeding?
- Liver's packed.
- How many units is that?
- Four blood,
four plasma.
- Send six more to angio,
we're coming soon.
- If there's any left.
What? He's type ab.
I'm just saying.
I don't blame you
for kicking yourself right now.
- For what?
- For not taking him
straight to angio when he
first came in this morning.
- He had a penetrating
liver trauma
with no collateral injury.
A wound like that usually
stops bleeding on its own.
The chest tube was dry.
I made the right call.
- Maybe, but we'd sure have
a lot more
type ab in the bank if you'd
made the wrong one.
♪ ♪
Keep suturing, Dr. rhodes.
That diaphragm's
not gonna repair itself.
All right,
let's get a vac on him.
You ready?
- Almost.
Let me clip it.
Done.
Get him to angio.
- Whoa, did you just
swipe my splenda?
- What?
No.
I mean, yes,
but it's yours?
- Not technically.
Only if you believe
in being considerate
to other people.
- [Sighs]
Oh, okay, well, here,
you can have it.
- No, that's okay.
Sarah Reese.
Reese--I'm gonna
remember that.
- No, seriously,
you can take it.
You don't have to--
- Dr. choi?
- Jessica pope.
She was found by fire
with a bag over her head.
Resuscitated at the scene.
In a coma ever since.
- Attempted suicide?
- Or murder.
Pd's investigating.
The thing is her bone marrow
biopsy just came back.
No stem cells.
Nothing.
Looks like it was
blasted by chemo.
- Cancer patient.
Might explain suicide.
Let me know if anything changes.
- You got it.
- How is she?
- The same.
It turns out she
was on chemo.
What do you guys
know about her?
- Not a lot at this time.
- That's all that was
salvaged from the scene.
- That's her personal
belongings--
a couple of books,
receipts.
We processed them,
didn't find anything useful.
- Hey, Daniel, why don't
you take a look at this?
- Never know what
you might find.
A lot of receipts.
Organized.
Getting ready
for tax season.
- Guys?
Forensics just came in.
They only found her prints
at the scene.
There's no signs
of foul play.
All the evidence
is pointing to suicide.
- Excuse me, guys.
Hey.
- What's up?
- Can I ask you
a doctor question?
- Sure, come on.
- Um, herrmann.
- Yeah.
- If he'd come in
on your watch,
would you have waited so long
before doing anything?
- That's a tough call.
It's been a while since
my surgical residency.
And, you know,
i wasn't there
for the exam,
so it's hard to say.
- Yeah, just in general.
- In general?
Yeah, I probably
would have gone in.
But, uh, again,
i wasn't there.
- Right.
Thanks.
- Don't.
♪ ♪
- Hey, what you got?
- Hey.
Don't forget our date
this afternoon.
- We don't seriously
have to do this.
You know, I did go
to med school.
Oof.
[Groans]
He's gonna be a kickboxer.
- Thank you.
Nat, I'm your
birthing buddy.
Which means I take you
on every tour
and watch you sign
every form
this hospital and the state
of Illinois demands.
- Hey, nat.
- Hey.
- Wait a second.
You have
an 80-year-old woman
to go see in treatment 5.
- All right.
- I thought will said
you were a pediatrician?
- I am--
- combined pediatrics
and er residency,
which mean she sees
everybody.
- Hm, fancy.
- My birthing buddy.
So what else did will
tell you about me, huh?
- Huh?
Nothing.
I mean, nothing.
- Hi.
I'm Dr. Manning.
- Hi, I'm Michael.
- Temperature 101.
Mrs. shepperd,
how are you feeling?
Mrs. shepperd, how long
have you had this fever?
Are you her son?
- Uh, yes.
But I don't live here.
I just flew in this morning.
- Does your mother
have dementia?
- Not that I know of.
- When was the last time
you spoke to her?
- Uh, maybe three months ago?
Her birthday, I guess.
Honestly, I don't know much
about what's going on with her.
They are treating her
for mouth cancer.
Last I heard,
it was going okay.
- I don't see anything.
Although it's possible
it's cleared.
Do you have the name
of her doctor?
- No.
- All right.
Well, we need to find
the source of her fever.
Could be a simple
urinary tract infection,
which would also account
for the disorientation.
I'll start her on antibiotics,
but I want to run some tests.
Hopefully, we'll get her
feeling better soon.
A nurse will be in shortly.
- Thanks.
- You're coming with me.
My baby brother.
Now he is here to learn,
so don't go easy on him.
- Always toughest on family.
Remember that last
third-year that rotated here?
- The one they admitted
into psych
because he was picking holes
into his skin?
- No, the one that hanged
himself with his stethoscope.
- You guys are funny.
- No, they're serious.
Where's Sarah?
I want her to show him around.
- I don't know.
Oh, hey, Reese.
April's little brother
needs a tour.
- Does she have
to call me that?
- Okay.
- Mm-hmm.
- Hi.
Be there in a minute.
- No change in her labs yet.
Let's run another test
in four hours.
- Dr. choi?
- Yeah?
- I heard about
the bone marrow depletion.
It's the focus
of my research.
There are so many discrete
causes and variations.,
I thought we could run
a few extra tests
to rule out any possible--
- whatever you think, Reese.
Titrate her nor epi
to keep her map at 60.
We'll need to up the rate
on her vent.
- Okay.
- I'm not convinced.
- About what?
- Jessica pope
had a confirmation
for a round-trip ticket
from Paris
six months from now, okay?
Presumably
when she's in remission.
A person--a conservative,
responsible person--with cancer?
They don't do that unless
they have high hopes.
Right?
So she's sick, but she thinks
she's getting better.
Why would she kill herself?
Something's hinky.
- "Hinky"?
Did you just say "hinky"?
- Humor me.
Women almost always
leave suicide notes.
Where's the note?
- Well, maybe it was destroyed
in the fire.
- Or maybe it wasn't a suicide.
- Have you been binging
on "mannix" again?
- You don't like it,
stop sending me
box sets for Christmas.
- All right, okay.
Next year,
it'll be "sanford and son."
- Dr. halstead?
Do you think
that your policeman brother
might do you a little favor?
- This place is ginormous.
Good thing I got GPS.
- Oh, it won't do you any good.
Radiology's right above us.
Between the mri
and the fluoroscope,
there's no way you get
an accurate signal around here.
Uh, here we go.
Uh, excuse me.
I need a mass spectrometry
right away on this sample.
- A mass spec?
- Yes, and if I could
get that stat.
- And you want it stat?
- Yeah, see,
we have this patient--
- Joey!
- Yeah?
- Got a request
for a mass spec.
[Foreboding music]
♪ ♪
- Oh, hey, Joey.
- Reese.
- Um...
About that splenda thing...
We've got a woman
who is in a coma,
and I really need
to figure out why.
So if you could just please
do this for her...
♪ ♪
- Okay.
- Okay?
Wait, really?
You will?
- Yes.
- Seriously,
thank you so much.
And just to--just to reconfirm,
we need that stat.
- I heard you.
♪ ♪
- Jay got it from will.
He said if it was him,
that's what he would've done.
- Well, so...
Does that mean
none of this should've happened?
- Sounds like it.
I'm gonna go find out.
[Air expelling]
- How much blood is coming
from the vac?
- About 250 mils.
Pressure's still low.
- You think it
might've helped
if you hadn't waited
so long?
- Excuse me?
- If you'd operated on him
when we brought him in.
Not waited.
- Are you talking to me
about medicine right now?
- I'm talking to you
about my friend.
- Look,
I'm gonna say this once.
Because he is my friend too.
I did what was right.
- Well, some of your
fellow docs don't agree.
[Tense music]
- Really?
Odd that they would share that
with you and not me.
♪ ♪
- Your patient,
herrmann, he's stable?
- He's still on the vent,
but, yeah.
- In the O.R.
when I said what I did...
You know that I'm only hard
on the good surgeons, right?
- Is that right?
- Yeah, I'm not gonna change
because we're sleeping together.
If you've got some
male power thing
where you can't get it up
unless I constantly applaud
your surgical prowess...
- Did you say something to fire
about me mishandling him?
- What?
- You heard me.
- You think that I would do
something like that?
- Somebody did.
[Dramatic music]
- [Chuckles]
If you think for one second that
i would undermine a colleague,
no matter how I felt about
his choices...
♪ ♪
Maybe I need to
reassess this.
♪ ♪
- Sorry to ask you this,
but Dr. Charles,
he's on a thing
about that attempted suicide.
He's not buying it.
- What's not to buy?
You heard the report.
There's no signs of foul play.
- I know.
But could you just take
one more look?
Turn over a few rocks?
- Ugh, come on.
♪ ♪
- All right, how about a pound
of smoked trout from calumet?
- All right,
two and you got a deal.
- My man.
- Shut up.
- You're my hero.
[Beeping]
- Mass trauma incoming.
- Dr. choi, Baghdad incoming!
- Baghdad. Noah, with me.
- Dr. choi, uh, what--
- get used to this.
Gunshot.
The one thing you can always
count on in Chicago.
What do we got?
- 22-year-old male,
shot in the left lower back,
no exit wound.
140 over 80, heart rate 60,
minimal blood loss.
- Okay, those are good numbers.
Abc's intact.
On my count.
One, two, three.
[All grunting]
Get his clothes off
and roll him over.
Chest and pelvis X-ray, kub.
- Got it.
- Get him dressed.
- Yes, Dr. choi.
Here.
Get an h and h
and let's dress.
You're gonna need to call
for a rudder.
♪ ♪
- Log roll.
- [Grunting]
- No exit wound.
So our first job is...?
To find the bullet.
Minor shrapnel but no missile.
Log roll.
Blood in the rectum.
Where do you think
the bullet is now?
- In the rectum?
- Remember the X-ray.
On the ground
or in his underwear.
What's the problem
with holes, Anthony?
- Things come out
of them, Dr. choi.
- Things come out of them.
Sir, are you still feeling
any pain?
- [Grunts]
- 5 of morphine.
- [Grunting]
- Whoa.
Wait, hold the morphine.
Where does it hurt?
- My leg.
- How did this happen?
- Chump just shot me.
- What were you doing
when you got shot?
- I'm doing business,
but the buyer thought
he could stiff me.
So I decked his ass.
Next thing I know he pulls
a strap, so I bolted.
- Thigh and leg films, now.
Now where's the bullet?
- X-ray clear!
- His thigh?
[Beeping]
- Knee.
Got him while he was running,
leg flexed all the way up.
No pulse.
Bullet could've lodged
in the popliteal artery.
Let's get him to ct
for an angiogram--go!
- Hey, they gonna catch
this guy?
- The buyer?
Just be happy you'll live
to sling another day.
♪ ♪
- I'm sorry, Dr. choi.
I've been up reading about
gunshot wounds,
but it's just--
- hey.
Not the last gunshot
you'll see.
♪ ♪
- What's going on?
- Fever's up,
pressure's down,
and now she's not responding.
- Could be the sedation.
But she's also uremic,
acidotic,
and her bun's
through the roof.
Something's not right.
All right, let's get
this picc line out
and broaden her to zosyn.
- Okay.
- What's going on?
- She's got a urinary tract
infection, okay?
But the antibiotics
aren't touching it.
More importantly,
her kidneys are shutting down
and we don't know why.
- What do you mean
you don't know?
- Mrs. shepperd?
Carol?
- This is bad, right?
Can't you do something?
- We're giving her fluids,
antibiotics,
and medication to increase
her blood pressure.
- Will that work?
- Have you been able to find
any recent history?
Any records we can check?
Anybody you've been able
to talk to?
- No, I told you, I don't know
who to talk to.
I haven't been around.
- Look, I'm not blaming you,
okay?
But I just met your mother
this morning,
and I'm working
without a history here.
- Excuse me, sir.
♪ ♪
- [Sighs]
- Hey.
Uh, got those tests on
Jessica pope that Reese wanted.
Have you seen her?
- Man, that was fast.
- I said I'd do it.
I did it.
Where is she?
- Uh, in radiology.
Yeah, but I'll make sure
she gets them.
- Hey.
How's herrmann doing?
- He's still unconscious.
Looks like hell.
- Cindy must be out
of her mind.
- She's hanging in there.
Hey, by the way,
there's a guy in here,
I swe--dead ringer
for your brother.
- That's 'cause
he is my brother.
- They're really gonna
let Noah become a doctor?
Does he know an ass
from an elbow yet?
'Cause I swear I saw him
flailing around back there.
- All right,
it's his first day.
He'll be fine.
- Okay.
Well, at least he's got
a big sister
to turn to when
he needs someone
to show him
how it's done.
- Yeah, he does.
- Someone responsible.
Conscientious.
- Learned it from
the girl scouts.
♪ ♪
- Meet up with me tonight.
Dinner?
♪ ♪
[Chuckles]
- Okay.
[Elevator bell rings]
♪ ♪
[Machinery beeping]
- The neupogen's not working.
Let's give her 80
of methylprednisolone.
- Okay.
- Um, Dr. choi?
- Yeah?
- Test results
on this patient.
- What is this?
- A mass spectrometry.
To get a fingerprint of
everything her body's absorbed
over the last several days
as well as some key biomarkers.
- How'd you pull that off?
Good idea, Noah.
- I-i--yeah.
Yeah, no problem, Dr. choi.
Just wanted to help.
♪ ♪
- Turned over some rocks
on the Jessica pope case
like you asked me to.
- And?
- Had the documents lab restore
some papers from her place.
And they found this.
♪ ♪
- Thank you.
[Heart monitor beeping]
♪ ♪
Dr. Charles.
- Suicide note?
- Mm-hmm.
But she didn't do it
because she was sick.
- "My fault
because I trusted him.
"I'm a fool.
I can't live
with this betrayal."
- Maybe a lover?
- Is this the whole thing?
- That's all they could restore.
- What's going on?
- Jessica pope.
Suicide after all.
- Really?
Because I just got
some very weird test results.
They confirm she's dying
from an overdose of chemo.
- What's weird
about that?
- The results also show that...
She never had cancer.
♪ ♪
- Just a very weird case,
you know?
Turns out Jessica pope
did try and commit suicide.
But that's not
what's killing her.
It's an overdose of chemo
for a cancer she does not have.
- She was misdiagnosed?
- And over-treated.
- Someone needs to have
their license taken away.
- Yeah.
At the very least.
- Once you begin labor,
a small monitor
will be placed
on your abdomen to assess
the fetus's heart rate.
- Which she just said
five minutes ago.
- In some cases,
a small electrode
will be placed
on the fetus's scalp.
This might be a bit
uncomfortable, and yet--
- and yet you have
flat-screen tvs
and still use a pulse ox
instead of capnography.
Can we go?
- Shh-shh-shh.
- I know you
medical professionals
like to think you already
know all this, and maybe you do,
but it wouldn't hurt
to let those
who are here to learn
have that chance.
How about showing them
a little respect, okay?
- We were just wondering
if you knew that
internal monitoring increases
the risk of an infection
without offering a comparable
amount of clinical benefit.
- Her mother was a midwife.
She grew up with this stuff.
- We're also wondering why,
if you really want
to respect these women,
you'd have them
stand around for an hour
while you talk about
how the TV can play
soothing sounds of nature.
Because if they stand around
much longer,
these babies are gonna
start dropping out
right in front of you.
Then you're gonna hear
some sounds of nature.
- Good point.
You are so right.
We should keep this moving.
Let's go take a quick look
at the maternity ward.
- Come on.
Let's get out of here.
- Yeah.
- I was paged?
- Hey.
- Oh.
- Look...
This isn't an excuse.
I am just trying to give you
a little context here.
I have a father,
whom you met,
who's made it his life's mission
to undermine me.
Maybe that's made me
a little sensitive at times.
- You have trust issues.
- You could put it that way.
- I can handle that.
How is he?
- He's stable.
[Cell phone beeps and vibrates]
I got to go.
- Dr. rhodes to the ed, stat.
- What do we got?
- 25-year-old witnessed seizure
in the street.
She was clipped
by a swerving car.
Gcs 3,
intubated in the field,
102 over 60, tachy at 110.
- Prep the table,
let's get him on the monitor.
- H and h also.
- All right, on my count.
One, two, three.
Give me a laryngoscope
to confirm the tube...
- Doctor?
- X-rays of the chest
and pelvis,
then to ct for a pan-scan.
- Yes, doctor.
- This isn't a trauma.
She went down
before she was hit.
- But we don't know
the damage.
She was hit by a car.
- Because she had a seizure.
- She's tachy.
Sats are down.
- 500 milligrams of Keppra.
- Yes, doctor.
[Dramatic music]
- She's got a chemo port.
- I'm telling you,
the money's in the seizure.
We got to figure that out.
Get a cbc, cmp, hcg,
and a tox screen.
Tell ct we're going for head
only, not the whole body.
- No, tell ct that we're going
for the whole body.
Now.
Must be nice,
having so many opinions.
- I have opinions about how
i handle incoming patients.
I don't like that qt
on the monitor.
- On it.
- You by any chance share
those opinions
with your brother?
- What, herrmann?
Look, Jay asked,
so I told him.
♪ ♪
- What's happening?
- Can you come this way, please?
- No!
Dani!
- Come this way with me.
[Machine beeping erratically]
- She's in v-tach.
- 70 over 30.
She's crashing.
- I can't get a pulse.
- Start compressions.
Give me the paddles, now.
- We're losing her.
[Heart monitor flatlining]
- Charge to 200.
Clear!
Both: Clear.
[Defibrillator thumps]
[Heart monitor flatlining]
- Milligram of epi.
- 1 of epi.
- Clear!
Both: Clear.
[Defibrillator thumps]
- Stay with us, Dani!
For the baby!
[Heart monitor flatlining]
[Defibrillator powers up]
- Clear!
Both: Clear.
[Defibrillator thumps]
[Machine beeps]
- What's--what's that?
What's going on?
[Continuous flatline]
- Another milligram of epi.
Now.
[Continuous flatline]
- Dr. rhodes--
- now.
[Continuous flatline]
♪ ♪
- 1 of epi.
- Stop compressions.
[Machine stops]
♪ ♪
Time of death, 16:21.
- No!
[Sobbing]
♪ ♪
[Sobbing loudly]
- You take credit
for the labs I ordered?
- What?
- The mass spec was my idea.
- Okay.
Um, I'm sorry.
- "Sorry"?
- Yeah, okay?
Look, it just came out.
I don't know why.
I was just nervous and
i just wanted him to like me.
- What about me?
- Come on.
You know how med school is.
It's so competitive.
Okay, look,
I'll do whatever it takes
to make things right.
- You'll tell Dr. choi?
- Yes.
I promise.
- You better.
- Look.
Wait, wait, wait.
Don't tell my sister.
Please.
- Hey.
I heard about your patient.
I'm sorry.
- 25 years old.
Early ovarian cancer.
Girlfriend didn't know
any details.
Said Dani didn't like
to talk about it.
- So young.
- Yeah, it gets worse.
Girlfriend's pregnant.
- Oh.
- Whoa, what the--
what's that all about?
- My patient's son.
He's gonna have questions.
- And you don't have answers.
- 80 years old in renal failure,
unknown cause.
- Any other history?
- She's being treated
for an oral carcinoma,
but standard chemo protocol
should not box her kidneys.
- So what are you gonna do?
- Dialysis?
- And avoid him forever?
Look, you know who you
could talk to?
Who you might really
be able to help?
- Who?
- Dani's girlfriend.
Come on.
- The pregnant one?
Who just lost her partner?
I'm supposed to understand
and have some special piece
of advice 'cause the same thing
happened to me?
Where is she?
- Let's go.
[Somber music]
♪ ♪
- I'm Dr. Manning, Natalie.
I heard about what happened.
I am so sorry.
- [Sobbing]
- I understand.
- [Cries]
♪ ♪
- You wanted to see me?
- Yes, come in.
The patient
that was hit by a car...
- Yeah, Dani frank.
- I'd like to expedite
the autopsy.
- Everything I did
was by the book.
She was nonresponsive, and until
i could rule out a bleed--
- not questioning
your performance for a second.
Dr. choi's patient,
Jessica pope.
She's dying
from an overdose of chemo.
- And we know Dani
had a chemo port.
- And she seized before
she was hit by the car.
Could indicate an overdose.
- Dr. Charles wants
to make sure
these two cases
aren't related.
- Okay.
Yeah, I'll get pathology on it.
[Suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
- Did you tell severide what
i said to you in confidence?
- What?
- About herrmann?
- You never said
that was in confidence.
- Great.
In the future, do me a favor.
Don't ask me any more
hypothetical questions.
- Fine.
Then don't ask me
to bring you any more
sensitive materials
from police investigations.
♪ ♪
- Her pressure's been dropping
since the dialysis started.
- She might be too weak to
handle it because of her fever.
♪ ♪
Turn her levophed up to 10.
- I should've been there
for her.
Maybe this wouldn't
have happened.
- You don't know that.
♪ ♪
[Machines beeping]
- Now what?
- Her pressure's bottoming out.
- O2 sats 92...89.
- Turn her levophed up to 20
and stop the dialysis.
- Hey, what's going on?
- She won't arouse.
She's not protecting her airway.
Someone get me a crash cart!
- We need to intubate.
- Copy.
[Machine beeping]
Scope.
[Suspenseful music]
- She's biting down.
Give me 20 of etomidate,
100 of rocuronium.
- Copy.
[Machine beeping]
- She's dropping!
- 20 of etomidate.
- Come on.
- 100 of rocuronium.
O2 down to 87.
- Got it!
- O2 down to 84.
83.
- Give me some cricoid pressure.
♪ ♪
- Can you see the cords?
- Uh-huh.
♪ ♪
I'm in.
- 81...
[Air hissing]
84.
88.
91.
97.
100.
- She's stable.
Take over bagging.
Hook her up on a vent.
Excuse me.
♪ ♪
- Dr. halstead tells me
that your chemo patient,
despite your continuing efforts,
continues to decline.
- Carol shepperd.
Yes.
- Dr. choi has a patient
in similar circumstances,
though it turns out that she
never had cancer at all.
- You know,
now that you mention it,
Carol has oral cancer,
but I've never been able
to find a tumor.
I thought maybe it had cleared.
- I think it'd be a good
idea to run some biomarkers,
just confirm she had cancer
in the first place.
- You think there might be
a connection
between Ethan's patient
and mine?
- I hope not.
♪ ♪
- [Sighs]
How'd it go today?
- What, somebody say something?
- No.
I'm just asking.
- Uh, today?
It was fine.
Yeah, it's just, um,
I'm trying to memorize
these emergency protocols.
You know, all the flow charts
and decision points.
I don't know when to shock,
when to give meds, like,
how many joules,
what's the doses--
- okay.
Look, it's not so much
about memorization
as just thinking logically.
V-fib.
We shock because electricity
resets the current.
But in asystole,
there's no current.
So we push meds instead.
- See, you just have a way
of putting things.
Okay, hey, um, how about
i bring over pizza tonight,
and you help me study?
- Noah, you're gonna be fine.
- No, I'm not.
I'm drowning here.
Really.
Please?
I need you.
- All right.
- Oh, thank you,
thank you--
- [grunts]
- I love you too, April.
- Hey.
Any change on herrmann yet?
Think you can get him off
the vent?
- We are waiting on
the next round of labs before--
[beeping]
- Code blue.
- Room five.
- Hey, guys, get in here!
He was fine a second ago.
[Machine beeping]
- He's not ventilating.
- Airway pressure's 40.
♪ ♪
- I don't hear great
breath sounds on the right.
- Pulmonary embolism?
- He's deviated
to the left.
I think
it's a tension pneumo.
- But he's already got
a chest tube.
- Yeah, I know.
Give me a 3-inch
16-Gauge angiocath.
- You sure about this?
- Back off!
He has air in place
of a collapsed lung.
It's squeezing
the other lung shut.
♪ ♪
[Air expelling]
- Airway pressure's
back down to 26.
♪ ♪
- Yup.
Chest tube's clotted up.
- Good call, Dr. rhodes.
♪ ♪
[Cell phone rings]
- Rhodes.
Yeah, I'll be right there.
Set him up for another
chest tube.
I'll be right back.
- Hey.
Thank you.
- Yeah.
♪ ♪
Hey.
- Hey.
Look, I wasn't there
when herrmann came in.
It wasn't my place
to say anything.
I shouldn't have.
♪ ♪
- Gentlemen.
- Dr. Charles.
♪ ♪
Dani od'ed on chemo.
That explains why she seized
in the street.
- That's not the troubling part.
Yeah, she was loaded up
on chemo.
But this woman...
Never had cancer.
♪ ♪
- Two patients in one day
overdose on chemo...
And neither had cancer.
- Which, I must admit,
does seem suspicious.
- Well, it could be
a new oncologist
in town making
incorrect diagnoses.
- Or even just mixing up
a few charts.
- Yeah, but even then,
why the overdoses?
And on the same day?
- What do we know
about these women?
- Jessica's note said
she felt betrayed.
- And Dani's girlfriend
said Dani was upset
about something,
but wouldn't talk about it.
- Something was going on
with both of these women.
- Yeah, but we don't have
any medical records,
no information
that might link them.
I'm gonna to get in touch
with some local oncologists,
see if there have been
any problems with their chemo
or if they've had other patients
in the same condition.
Thank you.
- Sure.
- You're gloating, Daniel.
You know mannix
would never gloat.
- Oh, yeah, he would.
I wouldn't,
but he would.
- Hey.
Did you hear?
Herrmann woke up.
- That man's a fighter.
He's gonna pull through.
- Calls for champagne.
Maybe we can get into Morton's.
- Can we do it another night?
- Second thoughts?
- No.
- Yeah.
Well, what?
- I have to help Noah study.
- Noah?
- How about tomorrow?
- Never changes, does it?
- What?
- April, you've been putting him
ahead of you your whole life.
You should be the one
with the stethoscope.
- I have a stethoscope.
- You know what I mean.
I'm not--
you wanted to be a doctor.
You're twice as smart as him.
You're just doing this
to put him through med school.
- You know my parents.
You think I had a choice?
It was always the boy
who was gonna become a doctor.
- And I get that.
I understand.
But you're grown up now.
When does it stop?
- You know what?
Thank you for your concern,
but I'm fine,
and I don't need your advice.
[Soft dramatic music]
♪ ♪
- Two mass specs, one day.
Some kind of record.
- What?
- I just delivered
another one.
They made it sound like
a really big deal.
You must be
some kind of hero now.
- Hmm.
Yeah, not exactly.
- See you.
♪ ♪
- Hey.
I know you got
those results back to me
way faster
than humanly possible.
- You said you needed them stat,
like, 600 times.
- Hey, tomorrow, can I buy you
a cup...Of coffee?
[Sighs]
♪ ♪
[Machines beeping]
- Hey, she opened her eyes.
That's good, right?
- Mrs. shepperd?
Can you hear me?
She is still
in kidney failure.
And her infection
hasn't cleared.
That's why we're still seeing
the delirium.
But, yes,
that is a good sign.
- If she does get better,
should I bring her to New York?
Or would she be
too sick to travel?
I could consider
staying here a while.
- You can figure
all that out later.
- I want to do something.
Something to help her.
- I understand.
Just sit with her.
Be with her.
♪ ♪
- I'm here, mom.
I'm here.
♪ ♪
- Natalie.
- Yeah?
- Carol shepperd's
biomarkers just came back.
She never had cancer.
- You're sure?
So she is just like
Ethan's patient.
- And Dr. rhodes' patient,
Dani.
That's three today.
- Oh, my god.
- Three women
all cancer-free
overdosed on chemo.
Somebody's doing this
on purpose.
- Do you think
a doctor's doing this?
Giving false diagnoses
and overdosing?
- I do.
- It's a long way
from "do no harm."
I've called the police.
They're on their way.
[Suspenseful music]
♪ ♪