♪ Mm-mm ♪
- ♪ Mm-mm ♪
- The organs in the human body
have entirely
different functions.
The cells
which make up those organs
act independently
of each other.
♪ Mm-mm, mm-mm-mm ♪
♪ Down at the bottom
of the deep, deep well ♪
But in a healthy body,
seemingly independent cells
quietly depend on
the functioning of the others.
♪ Dark so dark,
it's hard to tell ♪
♪ Pain from night
and night from hell ♪
♪ Down at the bottom
of the deep, deep well ♪
Because when one system
stops working...
♪ Mm-mm ♪
..the others
can't function for long.
♪ Mm-mm ♪
♪ Mm-mm, mm-mm-mm ♪
- ♪ Down at the bottom ♪
- Jackson!
♪ Of the deep, deep well ♪
Jackson.
- I'm here, Maggie.
- Jackson!
Maggie, I'm here!
Jackson! Jackson!
Dr. Pierce,
did you call for help?
- Oh, no, no. Down the...
- Help! Over here!
No, no, i-it's Jackson.
- He's down there. I don't know
- Okay. Okay,
- what happened.
- You stay on the road.
Grab the climbing gear!
Okay.
♪ Sin's gonna wash
in the morning light ♪
- Hello?
- Yeah, yeah, down here!
Down here!
They were climbing.
Give me your hand.
- He fell, and I caught the rope.
- I took over,
but he's dead weight.
I got no leverage here.
- Is he alive?
- I don't know.
He has to be.
Alright. Uh...
Tie him to an anchor point.
I'm gonna attach a Prusik.
I'm gonna slide in here, okay?
Alright.
Let's go.
Alright, dig your heels in.
We're gonna pull.
Ready?
- Yeah.
- Pull!
- Go.
- Good, good, good. Pull.
Keep pulling.
- Go!
- Pull!
And the person
who I trained,
the person I mentored,
fired me.
Without a word of apology
or regret.
And my own wife said nothing
to defend me,
not one word.
Look, I-I-I know
I have my part in this,
but I do not see me
forgiving anyone but myself
anytime soon.
I did it myself.
I take full responsibility
for my actions.
Andrew DeLuca had absolutely
nothing to do with it.
Okay.
What now?
We go to the police?
No. Now you go home
and I do what I do.
I go home?
Will they
let Andrew out?
After the charges against him
are dismissed.
And then what?
Well, we'll schedule
a hearing.
You'll be
deeply repentant.
You'll get a few weeks
of community service
at a free clinic,
and you'll pay a fine.
And what about
my medical license?
That's up to the board
if they want to pursue action,
but I'd say
it's highly unlikely.
So I just go home.
Yes.
- Is there a problem?
- No.
I just... I did
this long, dramatic goodbye
with my kids.
Well,
this is good, man.
This is a good thing.
She's getting
the help she needs.
Yeah, well,
it's just...
I have a history
with some people
who had that kind of help,
and it doesn't help.
Jo's not those people,
and she isn't
just a fighter.
She's Rocky.
She's Ali.
She'll get better.
Let's talk about
something else.
I think
Amelia dumped me.
You think?
Little hard to tell.
Hi.
Somebody wants to meet
his baby sister.
Leo, Leo.
Look, look.
This is your little sister,
Allison,
and, Allison, this is your
big brother, Leo.
Leo, being a big
brother is such an important job.
Oh, uh, Hunt, Shepherd,
I have incoming trauma.
Well,
I just had a baby.
- He just had a baby.
- Yeah.
I'm aware. She's very cute.
Congratulations.
I still need you to come.
Altman, you're excused.
What...
Are you serious?
Due to criminal activity,
Meredith Grey,
Alex Karev, and Richard Webber
no longer work here.
What?
And Andrew DeLuca's
in jail.
What do you mean
"criminal activity"?
- Incoming trauma.
- Now.
What do you mean
"criminal activi..."
Would you?
Oh. Oh, yeah.
Uh, sure.
Hey. Hi. Okay.
Oh. Oh, boy.
Okay, okay, yeah.
Okay. Hi. Oh.
- Bye. We gotta go.
- Okay. Yeah. Goodbye.
Okay. Okay.
Okay. I know.
Oh, I...
Hey, help.
Nurse?
Let's see. Look at this.
What's this? Wh...
You...
You had the baby!
I-I tried to reach you.
I-I didn't hear from you.
And then I had the...
The Spidey Sense, and...
Oh.
Look at her.
Wow.
What a beauty.
And that is little Leo Hunt,
am I right?
You must be so tired.
You need a hand?
Come here,
little Leo Hunt.
Come here.
Wait, so, tell me... What...
So, tell me... did she get
back together with your daddy?
Is that what she did?
Yes, she did,
didn't she?
Did he ride in
on a white horse
and make
all the right promises?
I think he did. Yes, I do.
That's what I think.
Oh, Tom, please don't...
Don't... don't blame Owen.
This is... This is me.
This is... It's my fault.
I'm just...
You know, you are...
You are
such a wonderful man.
Oh... Oh, I know I am.
I'm funny and I'm smart
and I'm kind when I want to be,
generous with my money
and with my tongue in bed.
So, you will regret
this decision,
and when you do...
I'll still be here
because, uh,
I'm in love with you,
and I don't think this thing
with Hunt's gonna last.
And in the meantime,
we are friends.
- Okay?
- Ma.
Yeah, do you want me to take
little Leo back to daycare?
Yes, please.
Yeah?
He's crazy about me.
Come on, little Leo.
Let's go back to daycare,
you and me.
You fired them?
What do you suggest
I should have done?
Anything
but fire them.
Mari Prishna, 34,
GCS 15,
open right humerus fracture
with extremity paralysis.
Okay.
Page Lincoln and Kim.
What do we got?
Jai Prishna, 35, GCS 11,
with a left open femur fracture
and right
lower leg deformity,
secondary to a fall
over a cliff,
thready pulse.
Systolic's in the hundreds.
Okay.
Uh...
Uh,
you two hurt, or...?
No.
We're fine.
*GREY"S ANATOMY*
Season 16  Episode 01
Episode Title: "Nothing Left to Cling To"
And we're good to go.
He wanted to cut off my leg.
I didn't want to,
I suggested that it was
the safest course of action.
- But then you were wrong.
- But then
I was a miracle worker.
After he begged you
and cried.
You love me because
I'm a sensitive guy.
Alright, can we let our interns
do their job now, please?
Qadri?
Mari Prishna, 34,
seven days post-op
after she was
a warrior goddess
and saved
her husband's life.
Dr. Avery
was the warrior.
He saved Jai.
I mean,
if he hadn't come along...
No, Mari,
you caught the rope,
and you held it for hours
on a broken, shredded arm.
You saved his life.
We did a debridement
of her wound
and then put in
a right humeral plate.
So, today will be
her brachial plexus surgery
for definitive
nerve repair.
Uh, I'm checking in my wife...
Josephine Karev.
You need
to drive around.
You say goodbye there,
she goes in on foot.
I hate
that I did this to you.
Did what?
- Became another name
- Yeah.
On your list
of crazy women.
Listen, for the record,
you are way saner
than any woman
I've ever dropped off
at a treatment center.
Look,
it's 30 days.
You go in, you talk about
your feelings or whatever,
and I get to come visit you
on Saturdays.
You don't have to.
Alex, we're not even
legally married.
We never filed
a license.
You have an out,
and I guess I'm saying
that I love you enough
to understand
if you want to take it.
Bipolars, please.
Look at
the posterior cord.
I have no idea
how she hung onto her husband
for that many hours.
I'm thinking
I would have let go
at about the 20-minute mark,
if not sooner.
Sounds about right.
Okay, so, clearly,
we have had a misunderstanding.
Can we talk
after surgery?
I'm happy
to talk now.
I'm not
listening.
And I don't
care.
I like you...
a lot.
I would like
to keep seeing you.
What I don't want to do
is bury myself in you.
You know
what I mean?
No,
he doesn't.
He doesn't?
You don't?
Of course he doesn't. You're not
speaking in a language
any dude could possibly understand.
They're not wrong.
I would like
to go on dates with you
and get to know you better
before I'm all in,
because I have a history
of going all in too fast,
and I would like
to change that.
Better?
- Better.
Better.
Can you
come back later, please?
Okay.
She won't stop crying.
She just...
She won't stop crying!
Alright, Teddy, listen.
This... This is crazy.
- Just come home with me.
- No.
No, I am not
going back home
to the house
that you bought for Amelia.
That's not the way
you and I are supposed to
start our lives
together.
I know it.
I know it in my soul.
What, and this hotel room...
This makes sense to your soul?
My soul
needs a shower,
and our baby
needs a diaper change.
Okay.
Thank you.
Shh, shh, shh, shh.
Uh, hello,
I'm, uh, I'm Dr. Webber...
From the health app?
Oh, please, come in.
Okay.
Dumbledore.
Dumbledore, stop that.
Stop it.
Stop that. Stop that.
Sorry about that.
Yeah.
This is Lolly.
Hi, honey.
So, she's got a fever
and a headache
and a sore throat,
and this morning,
we were at the park,
and we were playing.
I'm not really...
sure what happened.
She seemed fine.
Oh, my God.
Well... I guess maybe
she has the flu.
I...
I'd say maybe.
Hey.
Shepherd was able to do
a complete repair
of Mari's nerves.
That's good.
How's Jai?
He's improving,
actually.
How's that ankle?
It's a little better.
Good.
How about us?
How are we?
Hmm?
It's been a week,
Maggie.
We agreed...
To let
our tempers settle
before we talked further
about...
You abandoning me
on a dark and foggy road?
That walk that I took...
- That walk you took?
- ..ending up saving two lives.
Is that what we're calling it
now? That walk you took?
You left me
in a car
on an unfamiliar road
i-in the woods,
surrounded by...
fog and bears
and wolves.
There were no bears.
Why...
None that we could see,
but I could hear them!
This is why
we should wait to talk.
Yeah, got it.
Dr. Grey's bleeding heart
got the better of her,
but she is
an award-winning surgeon.
She saves lives every day,
and she...
Did you bring an actual violin,
counselor?
- Judge...
- Dr. Grey,
you're a partial owner of
Grey-Sloan Memorial.
So why commit
insurance fraud?
Why not just pay
for the surgery yourself
or do it for free?
Repentant.
Your Honor,
the little girl has cancer.
She needs hundreds of thousands
of dollars' worth of care
over a period
of years,
and I didn't think that her
very proud, hardworking father
would accept charity
from me.
And I didn't think
he should have to.
The system
should've supported them,
and the system
is broken.
Do you regret
your choices?
To the extent
that I can,
knowing there's a very sick
little girl out there,
- who's beginning to feel better.
- Your Honor...
I've heard enough!
She has three kids.
Don't throw her
in jail.
Help!
Somebody help my husband!
Help! Help!
Help, help!
Somebody help me! Help!
We were just talking, then he started
acting strange... - Call in a code.
...and he stopped talking,
and I can't wake him up. Jai!
- I got a pulse.
- Jai, please wake up.
Rapid response.
Wake up. Jai.
- Crash cart and intubation tray!
- Jai.
I'm on it.
Give me the mask.
Wake up.
Please wake up.
- Jai.
- 100% oxygen.
- Pushing saline.
- Please wake up!
Please wake up, Jai.
You put Tom Koracick
in charge of me.
I put him in charge
of all Catherine Fox Foundation
hospitals.
He's Chief of Chiefs.
You said
you would have my back.
I did
have your back.
I sat here silently
while you fired my husband
and two of your most effective
department heads.
Because they had
broken the law!
When I was 15,
I stole a lipstick
just to see
if I could get away with it.
Do you think
that means
I shouldn't
get to practice medicine?
What? That's a false
equivalence, and you know it!
My husband
is working for an app!
He's making house calls
like it's 1965.
He leaves the house
before I wake,
he goes to sleep at night
before I get home,
and if our paths happen to cross
in the daytime,
he avoids eye contact.
That's what
standing by you cost me...
My marriage.
So Tom Koracick
is my punishment.
I am living
with cancer.
I don't have the energy
I once did.
And all the things
you used to bring to me,
you will now
bring to Tom.
- Tom is a world-class surgeon
- ..I know what he is.
DeLuca?
You want
to explain yourself?
Yeah, you fired
several doctors,
and other doctors quit
in solidarity.
But I've been cleared
of all my charges,
and I think
you might need my help.
Cocky.
DeLuca.
This...
This is cocky.
You want me to leave?
I can leave.
Just get to work.
You really a doctor?
I might be.
It's still undecided.
What did you do?
Robbed a bank.
Really?
No.
I keyed
my ex-boyfriend's car.
Oh.
Did he deserve it?
Oh,
he very much did.
So,
I got this mole.
Think you could
take a look?
Heard about Jai.
Yeah, radiology says
he has watershed infarcts,
which makes no sense
in this case.
He's 35,
he could do an Ironman,
and he just
strokes out.
- Out of nowhere.
- Did you do an echo or a V/Q?
Of course I did,
Maggie.
I...
I'm trying to help.
Jai was hanging on the edge of
a cliff with two shattered legs,
and Mari hung onto him.
She hung on so hard
that a tree sliced through
the nerves in her arm
and almost cut it off.
But she hung on,
pulled him
from the brink,
like the edge of
certain death.
And then we show up
and we bring him back here
and we put him through
excruciating surgeries,
and now he's on...
life support,
somewhere between
alive and dead.
So, I'm wondering
if she should have...
back at
that cliffside,
if she should have
just...
..let him go.
Because there's
something inside him
that... we can't find.
Hell,
we can't even name it.
There's something there
that's broken
beyond... repair.
In this metaphor,
am I the thing
that is broken beyond repair?
Am I the thing that,
um...
..should just be
thrown over a cliff now?
No.
Not you, Maggie.
Us.
So, you're still
broken up?
That's sticking?
It's very,
very sticking.
I think I deserve
better than someone
who regularly
abandons me
for, you know,
trees.
Right?
So, yeah, it's sticking.
You're okay,
right? I mean...
Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
We're fine.
I mean, we're friends.
Our parents are married
to one another.
So, yeah.
Friends.
Or like siblings.
We're definitely not
like siblings.
Mommy, can I wear this
to school?
No.
Because Mommy needs that
for... work.
Aren't you
supposed to be in there?
They tried
to take a selfie.
They climbed all the way
to the top of a mountain.
They made it up
through rain and fog,
and then they tried
to take a selfie,
and he stepped back
and slipped.
He was a miracle,
and now he's...
..not.
And we don't know why.
And that...
Just...
It hurts my body.
It makes me ache.
Hey.
You okay?
- Uh, yeah.
- Baby?
Oh, she's fine,
I think,
but, um,
I don't know where Teddy is.
Have you seen her?
Uh, she panics and she brings
the baby here sometimes.
Why?
Because she doesn't
trust me.
B-Because everything I do,
everything I say, is wrong.
New baby.
That's hard.
Yeah.
Oh, God.
When we got Leo, it was hard,
but it wasn't this hard.
No, motherhood is hard
no matter what,
but giving birth
is a beast.
I mean, it's a beast
that changes your whole body
and your whole mind
and your whole heart forever.
Hormones are insane,
so just be patient.
Yeah.
I offered
to milk her.
What?
She had a clogged duct
and she was in pain,
and I... her...
The heat pads weren't working.
I just... So you
offered to milk her?
Yeah.
In those exact words?
Wh...
I was just
trying to help!
What?
And you said you are available
to start immediately?
I am.
And may I ask why?
Why I'm available?
Why you're interested.
Why I'm interested
to be your chief of surgery?
You've worked
at Grey-Sloan Memorial
for a very long time.
You are well-regarded
and well-respected.
Well...
Well, thank you.
But this job
is enormous.
Our new investors are looking
to turn around a hospital
that is ranked last
in Seattle.
This takes vision and...
Vision
and experience, yes.
Some experience,
sure.
But, Dr. Webber,
aren't you considering retiring
anytime soon?
I am not.
Hey.
Hi.
Dr. Avery.
Jackson, please.
Victoria. Vic.
Right, right.
Vic.
I never thanked you.
I should have.
Oh, God, no.
No.
No, my patients
would have been roadkill
if it wasn't
for you.
Well,
how are they doing?
She's doing well.
Actually, really well.
Uh, he's not as well
as I'd... like.
- I got you.
- Oh, thanks.
But, uh, still,
thank you.
Oh,
just doing my job.
- Yeah.
- So...
Uh,
you know what?
I'm going to grab
a burger at Joe's.
Yeah, I like burgers, but, um...
...maybe
some other time?
Deal.
When you tried so hard
to talk to me and I couldn't,
I felt shame, fear,
and pain.
And what was that shame about
for you, Jo?
That I lost the ability
to receive the love
that he was offering.
Tell him.
That I couldn't receive the love
that you were offering...
and, um,
I pushed you away.
I'm sorry,
and I'm afraid that I won't
be able to regain your trust.
Alex?
Did you do
your homework?
Oh.
When you didn't talk to me,
it made me feel...
"I felt."
Nobody makes you feel anything.
Those are your feelings.
When you shut down,
I f... I felt fear.
I still do.
Can you talk a little more
about that fear?
Alex...
You've had enough pain
and crazy
to last you a lifetime.
You deserve someone
who doesn't
break like glass
and need
to be swept up
and shipped off
to places like this.
Do you think
that person exists?
I think some
are s-stronger
than other... others.
Jo, you've had
a depressive episode
caused by intense trauma,
and even though
our society tells us
places like this
mean we're broken,
I think the truth is
coming to a place like this
makes you stronger
than most.
There was
an episode of hypotension
in the second surgery,
but we got that under control.
Mm. That is unlikely
to cause a stroke.
I know.
Try this.
If I eat any more, I'm gonna
have to unbutton my pants.
Hot.
Okay, new game.
Name three things
that you have never done,
but you really
want to do.
Ooh.
Good one.
Um...
Okay.
Surf a 20-foot wave...
um,
- ride a camel through the Sahara...
- Mm.
..and, um...
cure Parkinson's.
Now you.
Same question.
Okay.
Mm.
Go to a psychic medium
and talk to my dead father,
get licensed
in scuba diving,
and have sex
with more than one person.
You've never done that?
You have?
I lived in Venice Beach
for a year.
So did I.
And you never
had a three-way?
They're offered up
like mints in Venice Beach.
Hmm.
I had
a medical practice there.
Oh.
Yeah, I...
worked in a bike shop.
Fat embolus.
What?
In California,
we had a patient.
Muscle Beach
body builder,
shattered his femur,
just like Jai.
He didn't wake up
from surgery.
It looked like
it was a stroke.
Turns out it was
fat embolism syndrome
from the
long bone injury.
There was
a telltale rash.
Did you check Jai
for a rash?
Wait!
- Just stop! Just wait!
- What are you doing?
- Extubating.
- Why?
This is
his worst fear.
He doesn't want
to live like this...
Hooked up
to machines.
We're climbers.
People have accidents.
We've talked
about this.
We're both
way less afraid of dying
- than just being kept alive on...
- He has it.
- Has what?
- W...
Link, that's it.
That's the rash, under his arm.
Is this reversible
at this stage?
Wait, what... what rash?
What does that mean?
It means maybe
we can wake him up.
A fat embolus?
That man didn't have an
ounce of fat on his body.
Right.
I mean, it's the fat
from the bone marrow
in long bones
like the femur.
- Bone breaks, and...
- Oh.
..that fat can travel
into the bloodstream,
which can get lodged
in the brain,
and... it looks like
a stroke.
I never get to know
how the people I rescue
do in the end.
We run into fires
or pull people off of cliffs,
and then
we hand them off to you,
and then we run into
some other fire. So, it's, um...
it's nice, I guess,
to know how he's doing.
I hope
he wakes up.
Yeah, me too.
I...
am just getting out of
a pretty serious relationship.
Uh, me... me too.
Did you love her?
I did, yeah.
Me too.
And, um,
he... he died.
Oh, I'm really sorry to hear that.
Yeah.
Me too.
So, probably...
...not the very best time
for either one of us
to be starting something new.
Yeah, probably not,
because we're both
supposed to just feel miserable
for as long as possible.
So...
Well, if you're gonna
put it like that...
Well...
All the way down
to the corner!
Dr. Grey?
Is that you?
Suzie Wilson.
I'm the classroom mom
at Zola's school.
Hi, Suzie.
Hi.
What are you
doing here?
Is this
some sort of volunteer thing?
Something like that,
yeah.
Oh, I just love that.
Love that you're doing this.
I always wondered why
we never saw you
volunteering at school,
but now I get it.
This is
really nice to see.
You know, Suzie,
when working moms
don't volunteer at school,
it's usually because
we're working in the daytime
and parenting at night,
so we generally don't have time
to participate.
Grey!
This is not happy hour!
Get back to work
before I tell the court
you're in contempt!
Nice to see you,
Suzie.
I appreciate everything you do
for Zola's class.
Go!
I got it!
Hey.
Aren't you still
on maternity leave?
I hate maternity leave.
Which is... I know.
There are women
the world over
who would kill
for the privilege
of being able
to stay at home
with their newborn baby
and know that they have a job
to come back to.
Mm.
I know that
I should be grateful,
but I hate it.
Owen called me a cow
the other day.
He did what now?
He offered to milk me.
Yeah, I don't even know
what to do with that.
I have a brilliant mind
with no opportunity
to use it.
So,
I-I came to work.
I'm not working,
but I'm at work.
Tell... Bailey, tell me...
Tell me.
Come on, tell me a little bit
about work, please.
I fired
all my favorite people,
and my least favorite person
now has power over me.
And the anger
I feel...
The righteous anger is...
it's exhausting.
I think I might be
a terrible mother.
For what it's worth,
I hated
maternity leave, too.
And I am
an excellent mother.
What do you want?
Well, that's a nice way
to greet your mentor.
Coffee?
I'd love a cup.
Applied for a job
last week
with
Pacific Northwest General.
Did they call you?
Put you down
as one of my references.
I don't know.
You don't know?
I don't answer the phone
if I don't recognize the number.
You don't check
your messages?
You know,
I hate your generation.
I hate any generation
other than my own.
Same.
Eh, I'm not gonna get
that job.
The woman doing the hiring
is a child.
She practically
called me grandpa.
Well, can't you get your wife
to do something for you?
No.
Where is your wife?
Does she let you
live like this?
Eh,
she's out of town.
Is she coming back?
I don't know.
You know,
so you got to get it.
What?
The job at Pac-North.
I mean, it's still open.
I just checked
this morning.
Wait,
the job's at Pac-North?
Of course it's still open.
Nobody wants to work there.
- No, you want to work there.
- Why?
Because you could
turn it around.
And if you get the job,
you can hire me.
Look, Dr. Webber, I really want
to help you, but...
Oh, look at yourself,
Karev!
You're drowning
in your own filth!
I'm not asking you
to help me.
- I'm asking you to help yourself.
- Alright, stop yelling at me.
This is my house,
and I don't
work for you anymore.
Here.
You're worried about
your marriage?
Give your wife
a reason to come back home.
They've been doing this every day
for a week, and nothing has changed.
It's an experimental protocol.
You have to give it time.
I don't want
to give it time.
I want them to stop.
I promised that I would never
let this happen.
We promised each other.
Stop. Stop! Stop!
Stop! Stop!
- Hey. Alright.
- Stop!
Hey,
what is going on?
I don't know
what to say.
What if this
makes him just better enough
that he can't die?
What if... What if this
makes him just better enough
that he is just stuck in
this body for another 20 years?
My husband is living
his worst
- nightmare!
- Mari, Mari, Mari, look at me, okay?
I know it's easier
to imagine worst-case scenarios
than it is
to hold onto hope, alright?
But we are not
there yet.
Do you understand me?
It is not the time
to give up on him.
Will you tell me
when it's time?
Yes.
I promise I will.
Hi, Mari.
Thanks for coming.
How are you, um...
Please don't ask me
how I'm doing.
Mari, there's something
we want you to see.
Come on.
I found a place
for him.
It's a pretty nice
long-term care facility.
Didn't smell quite as bad
as the other ones that I saw.
Oh, my God.
Is this real?
Is...
Are... Sorry.
Is this real?
It's real.
He's fragile,
but his cognitive tests are good.
Hi.
Hi, Jai. Hi.
- Hey.
Thank you.
Hi.
♪ When I heard your voice ♪
- I love you.
♪ The distance
caught me by surprise again ♪
I love you.
♪ And I know you claim
that you're alright ♪
♪ But fix your eyes on me ♪
♪ I guess I'm all you have ♪
You came.
♪ And I swear
you'll see the dawn again ♪
You're here.
There's something
I have to do.
It's a little cheesy,
but I'm gonna...
♪ Well, I know I had it all on the line ♪
I don't want an out.
You hear me?
You offered me
an out,
and you were right.
I was scared.
So, I thought about it,
and what I know for sure now
is I'm a better man with you.
♪ You'll always be
my only guiding light ♪
I want
to be your husband.
I want you
to be my wife.
♪ Relate to my youth ♪
I did the work here,
but I'm not magically fixed.
I can't promise
that it won't happen again.
I don't care.
I love you.
♪ But don't just slip away ♪
I want to grow old with you,
no matter what.
For better
or for worse.
In sickness
and health.
♪ Don't just hurl your words ♪
Marry me again,
please.
♪ From on high ♪
Yes.
- Yes?
- Yes.
Yes.
♪ You'll always be
my only guiding light ♪
♪ If we come back
and we're broken ♪
I listed the house.
And I already have a Realtor
looking for a new one,
and I have
about a hundred house listings
for us
to look through,
and I put us in
the suite upstairs
'cause this room
is ridiculous.
I already ordered
room service,
and Leo
is with my mom tonight.
♪ Give us something
to believe in ♪
You listed the house.
Being a new mom
is hard,
and it is way harder
when you try to do this
all on your own.
I love you.
Teddy,
I want to help.
Let me help.
♪ 'Cause I know I had it all
on the line ♪
Thank you
for listing the house.
♪ You'll always be
my only guiding light ♪
Ah,
Dr. Shepherd.
Ah.
Call me Amelia.
Amelia.
I've been wondering
if you would come see me.
You have?
Well, I've noticed
the changes in your body, and...
the fullness
in your breasts.
Oh. Wow.
I, uh... didn't know
it was mutual.
M-Mutual?
I mean, I kinda had a crush,
but I didn't know if...
Anyway.
Um, this is weird.
Because I'm seeing Link,
but he knows I'm here
because I'm wondering
if, uh...
Ah.
This is awkward.
Um...
Amelia, okay, are...
Are you here for your pregnancy,
or just asking
for a ménage à trois?
Not pregnant.
No, no.
I've just gained
a little weight.
No. And I'm not really
asking for a ménage à...
No, I am.
I was.
I... just...
Sounds a little dirtier
in French.
I, uh... I just...
I've been feeling
these, like, curiosities.
Uh-huh.
And, um... surges.
The sexual cravings
can be very intense
during pregnancy.
I-I'm not pregnant.
No, I've just been...
eating a lot.
Link eats a lot.
Listen, uh...
Oh, my God.
When was your last period,
Amelia?
Oh, my God.
♪ Everyone, everyone ♪
♪ I've ever met ♪
♪ Hasn't yet ♪
♪ Made me feel ♪
♪ Like you ♪
♪ Everything, everything ♪
♪ I've ever seen, doesn't mean ♪
When did that happen?
When did...
When did, uh,
what happen?
Please don't be
intentionally obtuse.
Vic and I are friends, Maggie.
Come on.
Friends with benefits?
No, actually.
No, or not yet?
♪ High and dry ♪
♪ Why does your love
leave me so high and dry? ♪
Her fiancé
was my patient.
- ♪ You leave me so high and dry ♪
- He died.
I know.
It's, um...
It's none of my business.
I agree.
Right.
♪ Tell me lies, tell me lies ♪
'Cause I don't like you...
and you
don't like me.
We're not friends.
- ♪ So if you love me ♪
- So it's none of my business.
♪ Why don't you tell me? ♪
♪ Why does your love
leave me... ♪
Just as organ systems
are codependent for survival,
so are human beings.
Studies have shown
that our happiness and health
depends upon our relationships
not just functioning,
but thriving.
♪ Tell me ♪
Pac-North?!
You're going to work
with Alex Karev at Pac-North?!
♪ Tell me if you really... ♪
You stood by
and watched Bailey fire me,
so you don't get to judge
where I work now.
You betrayed me,
Richard Webber.
You chose your loyalty
to Meredith Grey
and her criminal enterprises
over your loyalty to your wife
and her foundation,
and now you want
to humiliate me
and go work
at Pac-North?
I'm sleeping
on the sofa.
Sometimes the best we can do...
...is bear each other's burdens
and ease each other's pain.
So, Zola overhears
the school-mom
tell the teacher
I'm a criminal,
and then she asks me
how to spell "criminal."
So, that was fun.
Listen, I'm...
You know, I'm healthy.
My kids are healthy.
- And I'm not in jail.
- Yes.
I'm getting exercise.
It's quite meditative,
actually.
You sort of just
pick up the trash,
one piece at a time,
and I'm helping the city,
I'm helping the planet.
I still feel
a sense of accomplishment.
So, it's kind of like
a roadside vacation, then.
Exactly.
- I want a roadside vacation.
- Right?
Maybe I'll go
rob a store or something.
Please don't do that.
What is it?
It's a letter
from the medical board.
They're going to pursue action
against my license.
There'll be a hearing.
And hold each other's hands
in the dark.
♪ You leave me so high and dry ♪
*GREY"S ANATOMY*
Season 16  Episode 01
TiTle: "Nothing Left to Cling To"
Sync corrections by srjanapala