Previously, on
The Good Doctor...
I'm your neighbor. I'm in
the middle of Uncharted
and I'm dead.
Can I borrow some triple-As?
This is kind of silly,
isn't it? Our relationship.
That we're hiding it.
We don't have a
relationship. We have sex.
- You're late.
- No, the bus was late.
I did nothing wrong. The bus...
Yeah. This is gonna
work out great.
So, you're treating
him like anybody else?
Do you have any idea how
many patients he's scared
- the crap out of today?
- So, teach him.
I'm teaching you both.
That he doesn't belong.
I hear you got Shaun off
scut and back into surgery.
You figure you give him a little
authority, he'll screw something up.
Either way. If he succeeds,
I'm the guy who just backed him.
And if he fails,
I'm the President.
Hello. I've looked everywhere.
All right, I'm here now.
We'll just keep looking.
Maybe we'll find it.
Why is the furniture in
the middle of the room?
I know I packed it. I made
a list. Star-tip screwdriver.
Look, it's checked.
It's checked.
Maybe you threw it out with
the newspapers you used
to pack the dishes.
I packed with bubble
wrap. It's safer.
And you can see through it.
Of course, you did. Shaun,
there's a hardware store up the road.
You can buy a new one.
I don't want a new screwdriver,
I want my screwdriver!
Stop it!
It's the middle of the... I'm
sorry. I shouldn't have yelled.
Let's just take a
moment. Sit down, please.
You know what? We... You
can use this for now. Okay?
I can't stay here.
Of course, you
can. It'll be fine.
I can't stay here. The
dishwasher doesn't dry,
the shower drain has
someone else's hair in it...
And the crisper drawer
keeps coming off the track.
I assume that's
what you were fixing.
I forgot.
Of course, you forgot.
It's understandable.
You've been working your
ass off. You're exhausted.
You're under a lot of stress.
There's a super in the building.
You can call him anytime.
Just make a list of the
things you need repaired.
Later, Shaun.
Later. Later, Shaun!
Go to bed now.
Go to bed.
Thirty-six years old,
22 weeks pregnant.
Ultrasound at 16 weeks revealed
a tumor on the fetus's tailbone.
Mom's got antiphospholipid
syndrome. It makes surgery high-risk.
It also makes pregnancy high-risk.
She's had three miscarriages.
We need to do an ultrasound and
MRI to measure the tumor's growth rate.
Late bus doesn't explain
why you're showing up tired
after you just had 12 hours off.
We're all tired. Our
last shift was 36 hours.
I'm not interested in debating
the shift schedule with you.
But I am curious why you always
feel the need to defend him?
We're all on the same team.
Yes, but you're
all quarterbacks.
And when training camp is over,
there's only gonna be one starter.
The crown rump length of
the fetus is 21.5 centimeters.
And the diameter
of the tumor is...
10.6 centimeters. Half
the size of the fetus.
The tumor's grown.
It's not cancer,
but it is monopolizing
the blood supply,
which is weakening
the fetus' heart.
I'm sorry, but there's no chance
it would survive long enough
to be viable.
The safest course is to
terminate the pregnancy.
If we were interested
in the "safest course,"
we wouldn't be on our
third second opinion.
Please, Dr. Melendez, we
want whatever will save our baby.
Dr. Wright told us
you've done fetal surgery
to remove this
type of tumor before.
And without the tumor,
our baby would be healthy.
Your antiphospholipid syndrome makes
a long surgery extremely dangerous.
There's a high
chance for blood clots
which could have fatal
consequences for you.
We're willing to take that risk.
Saving the fetus doesn't do any
good if the mother dies in the process.
I've had three miscarriages.
If I have to go through that
again, I might as well be dead.
- Barb.
- It's true.
No, it's not.
You're the strongest
woman I've ever met.
We'll get through this.
We will. And, and
then we'll try again.
We could manage clotting risk
preoperatively with an infusion
of unfractionated heparin.
Never contradict me in
front of a patient again.
I didn't. I agree with your
assessment of the risks.
I suggested a way
we could mitigate them.
Not in front of the patient.
We're not in front
of the patient now.
I was just reading about a new
technique for transesophageal
echocardiography monitoring.
If there is a cardiac issue, it
would give us an early warning.
Let's get her prepped. ASAP.
I want JL on anesthesia.
And let the neonatal
nursing supervisor know
that I wanna do
a full run-through.
Damn it.
Yes? Well, we're a
little busy up here, too.
All right. I'll send someone.
Andrews is covering
for Lim in the ER.
He has a patient who
needs a boil lanced.
A plastic surgeon
can't lance a boil?
Plastic surgeons can.
Chief surgeons don't.
You and Murphy.
What? It was our ideas that
convinced you to do the fetal surgery,
and now you're punishing
us with Andrews' scut work?
Well, you're not
getting punished.
He is. For being late. Again.
But I don't trust him
alone with a patient,
and since you like to defend him
and seem to know how
to communicate with him...
Hurry back.
Olivia Hartman?
Yes, ma'am. I mean, Doctor.
- You're 18?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Where's the boil?
- It's, um, it's down there.
Down where?
Shaun. It's on her labia.
Hmm. Is it painful?
Like I used a bowling
ball for a tampon.
Okay, well, it shouldn't
hurt that much.
Okay if we take a look?
Okay. If you just scoot down
and put your feet in the stirrups.
Right.
The swelling is
fairly localized.
Extreme pain that's out of
proportion to the visible injury
could mean you have
necrotizing flesh-eating bacteria.
What?
I'm gonna use the heparin
preoperatively and a TEE monitor.
Still not enough. The risk of
a heart attack, or a stroke...
Was thoroughly explained. The
patient still wants the surgery.
She wants it? Or you want it?
Yes, saving a fetus's life
would be good news for me.
Any other questions? Or insults?
Relax. I'm not insulting you. Of
course, you wanna do this surgery.
But you do surgeries like this,
some patients are going to die.
And then our department's
success rate goes down.
And then our funding goes down.
And then you can't
do surgeries like this.
So, if your judgment is
clouded in any way, just...
It's not.
Okay.
I'm sorry, I know this hurts,
but I really do need to insert
the speculum for
this part of the exam.
If I really have what he says,
does that mean you
have to cut off my...
No. No. As I said, the abscess
is most likely the result of an
untreated chlamydia infection.
We'll drain the abscess, give
you antibiotics. You'll be fine.
Ow! I'm sorry.
The inflamed Bartholin gland is
causing the ischiocavernosus muscle
to spasm and pinch
the labial nerve.
You need to start with a
more upward angle. Can I try?
I think it's
better if I do this.
Ow.
Yeah. Okay. Fine.
Should we call your
parents? Let them know...
No.
I'm 18. I'm an adult.
Even adults need
emotional support.
Someone to drive
them home after surgery.
I'm gonna take a
taxi. I have money.
There's nothing to
be embarrassed about.
Twenty-five percent of college students
contract an STD before graduation.
I'm not embarrassed,
and I know all about STDs.
I get tested every 30 days.
There's no necrosis on
the vaginal wall or cervix.
You got it in already?
Yes. It's definitely not
flesh-eating bacteria.
- I was wrong.
- Thank God.
You do need surgery to drain
the Bartholin gland abscess.
Why do you get an
STD test every 30 days?
I have to. For work.
I do porn.
The umbilical is 19 inches,
which will allow us to remove
the fetus via cesarean
and rest it in its mother's lap
while I excise the tumor.
Now, the hard part will be
reinserting the fetus afterwards.
We can't overstretch
the uterine wall,
and we must be certain that
every suture is tight enough
to handle four more months
of kicks and thrown elbows.
Do you have a minute?
- Can it wait?
- No.
I don't wanna do it.
Have you talked to your wife?
Yes, but she's not
thinking rationally.
You heard her say she'd
rather die than lose this baby.
I'm sorry, but husbands
don't have veto power
over their wife's
medical decisions.
A husband can't stop you
from operating on his wife,
but a father can stop you
from operating on his child.
What kind of porn?
I'm sorry, I was too busy
doing all the labs and imaging
she needed for surgery. I
forgot to ask for her resume.
I just mean, is she
an actual actress,
like in stuff
with a story, or...
Do they even make porn
with stories anymore?
Sometimes.
You watch porn?
Why wouldn't he?
- I don't know, he just seems...
- He's a guy. All guys watch porn.
You finished with
Andrews' patient?
No. It wasn't a boil.
It's a large Bartholin gland abscess
that's pressing on pudendal nerve.
Which apparently does
interest a chief surgeon.
We're gonna assist Andrews
when he drains it in the morning.
We just thought we'd
check back with you.
Go home.
And sleep. Not play video games,
or whatever it is keeping you up.
I don't think it's video games.
You can head out,
too. It's been a long day.
- But what about...
- Fetal surgery's been put on hold.
What? Why?
Go home.
Once the fetus is
removed from the uterus,
one could argue that
it becomes a child.
That's ridiculous.
There are numerous
legal precedents...
That guarantee the
mother's right to choose.
It's her body. It's her control.
I'm completely
comfortable going ahead
- with this surgery.
- As am I.
I never was, and I
certainly am not now.
I'm sorry, until we're certain
there is no liability connected
to parental consent,
neither am I.
Well, the one thing I think
we can all agree on is that
the mother has the
power to do nothing.
And if she doesn't
terminate, or have the surgery
to remove the tumor...
A fetus with a massive tumor
will die inside a patient with APS.
And the mother
would die, too, right?
So, we do nothing
and they both die,
or we can do something that's
legally and ethically complicated
and maybe they both live.
The board has
approved the surgery.
Thank you.
- Barb, please...
- Mark, stop.
- If you loved me...
- No. No. Do not say that.
No, it's true. If you
really loved me...
I'm trying to protect
you because I love you.
I don't need your protection.
I need your support.
We'll start prepping you
first thing in the morning.
Try and get some sleep.
Thank you.
I still can't believe it.
That 18-year-old
college students do porn?
She's not the type.
And how do you know
what "type" she is?
You just met her, did one
medical history and pelvic exam.
What?
Nothing.
No, go ahead.
Tell me all the
reasons why I'm wrong.
I volunteered at a
shelter for runaway teens
when I was in high school,
got to know a lot of sex workers.
They're not all the same,
but they do have
the same armor.
I don't believe it.
You think I'm lying?
No. No. I think you
just opened up to me,
actually shared
something personal.
It was high-school community
service. It's not a big deal.
Oh, no, it's a big deal. This is
huge. I am peeling the onion.
Shut up.
Actually it's more like
hacking through a coconut
- with a dull machete, but...
- Dull is right. Very dull.
It feels good, doesn't it?
Should do it more often.
How about you stop
worrying about what I won't do,
and just enjoy what I will.
Do you think she's
of sound mind?
You really wanna talk
about work right now?
She's basically threatening
to commit suicide.
She's not suicidal. She's...
She's just desperate to have a
child. This is probably her last chance.
She could adopt.
- It's not the same.
- Really?
- Don't think there's a difference?
- No, I don't.
Carrying a fetus in your
body for nine months.
You don't think that creates
a unique relationship?
I think every
relationship is unique.
Yeah, of course.
- What are you saying?
- I just think it's selfish.
I mean, for her to
go through so much,
to put your husband
through so much,
just so you can have
a certain experience
when there are other ways.
Yeah, okay.
But you want
children though, right?
And we've talked
about this before.
Yes, I want children.
But our children. Like,
from you getting pregnant.
Yes.
But what if that doesn't happen?
What if I couldn't get pregnant,
or if I decided that
I didn't want to?
That I wanted to adopt instead?
Is there something
you're not telling me?
Actually, there is.
When we're in meetings together,
don't ever call my ideas ridiculous.
- Come on, I'm being serious.
- So am I.
Okay. You're right, I'm
sorry. It won't happen again.
- Jeez, you scared me.
- What are you reading?
- Nothing.
- Can I read it?
- No.
- Why?
- Because.
Because.
Why?
Because there's nothing
to read. Just pictures.
- Where'd you get this?
- Colleen Myers.
Her dad has so
many in his closet,
he doesn't even notice
when she takes a few.
She's pretty.
She sure is.
It's bedtime. That
means lights out.
I missed my stop.
I missed my stop!
Lynwood Place.
I need to get off
at Lynwood Place.
Then you should've
been paying attention
when I stopped at Lynwood Place.
The next stop's gonna be even
further away, so if I were you...
Shaun? Are you okay?
Yes.
Are you waiting for someone?
No.
I'm horrible at directions, too.
Every time I exit a BART
station, I walk, like, three blocks
before I realize I'm
going the wrong direction.
You're lucky I actually
made it to the gym.
I like to go when
it's not crowded,
but it's so hard to motivate
after work. Half the time I end up...
You stink.
I know, I'm disgusting,
but I can't shower there.
I'm terrified of foot fungus.
Hey, you know, as long as
we're tossing out truth grenades,
you suck at being a neighbor.
First, you take back your
batteries, and then you wake me up
in the middle of the night, stomping
around and banging on pipes.
What the hell's up with that?
My sink drips. I couldn't
sleep, so I tried to fix it.
Then I couldn't find my
screwdriver, which made me anxious.
You kept me up because you
were anxious about a screwdriver?
Yes. I was very anxious.
You're funny.
I stink, you're anxious.
You always say exactly
what's on your mind.
Just the total
opposite of most guys.
It's nice.
Good night.
And don't go fixing
any faucets tonight.
That's Armen's job.
This is a list of repairs I
need for my apartment.
Number 33.
What the hell is your problem?
Sorry. Hello, my name is Shaun
Murphy. It's very nice to meet you.
No, it's not nice to
meet me at 12:40 a.m.
Yes.
Dr. Glassman said I can call you
anytime I need something fixed.
Who the hell's Dr. Glassman?
He's the president at San
Jose Saint Bonaventure Hospital.
I'm a surgical resident there.
Well, I don't care if you're
Saint Bonaventure himself.
Unless it's a fire or a flood,
I only work 9:00 to 5:00.
I'll try and come back
tomorrow between those times.
Yeah, you already woke me
up, just give me the damn list.
It's my fault. I should've known
you would take what I said literally.
It's okay.
Actually, you know what,
Shaun? It's not my fault.
It's your responsibility.
You're smart.
You should be able to
use your common sense.
When somebody says something,
you should figure out
what they really mean.
And when things don't go
exactly how you expected them,
then navigate that.
There's a thing called a
personal support worker.
Think of it like a
home-help aid...
No, thank you. I can
take care of myself.
Everybody needs a
little help now and then.
I'm thinking of asking
them to give me one.
I've lived by
myself a long time.
In Casper, Wyoming.
Everybody looked
out for you in Casper.
Everybody looks out for everybody
in Casper. This is San Jose.
It's a big city. And residency
is a whole lot more demanding
- than medical...
- I don't need an aid.
- We're just talking about...
- I don't need an aid!
- Okay, okay.
- Okay.
We'll table it for
some other time.
Let's enjoy our breakfast. Okay?
Mr. Allen.
I'm trying to convince
her to save herself.
I don't wanna roll the
dice with my wife's life.
But she does.
We're gonna start prepping her now
and she goes into the OR in a few hours.
I understand why she's
desperate, but not why you are.
If she dies, it's your fault.
And what if she lives?
You're gonna have a wife
and child who need you,
and you keep driving
her out of your life.
I'm not desperate,
I'm confident.
Which should
make you feel better.
Retraction.
I'll make the incision and I want
you to insert the Word catheter.
Good job on the pelvic
exam, Dr. Murphy.
With all the swelling, it
couldn't have been easy.
Thank you.
How do you know who...
- I have my ways. Like Santa.
- I told him.
Hmm. No presents
for you. Insert the drain.
But I'm curious. How can a guy who
can't even shake a co-worker's hand
be comfortable
doing a pelvic exam?
People squeeze
too hard. It hurts.
Send this to the
lab for culture.
So, I'm guessing
you're not that into hugs.
I don't like to be squeezed.
And what if it's
somebody you like?
Or somebody you love?
Have you ever had a girlfriend?
I almost kissed a girl. Once.
Well, you know what they say,
if at first you don't succeed...
Are you trying to mock
me or encourage me?
I'm trying to get to know you,
so I know when I should mock
and when I should encourage.
When's the right
time to mock you?
Press harder on that abscess.
It should've drained by now.
Something's wrong.
The gland's evacuated, but
the swelling's not going down.
Heart rate and BP are stable.
Can I get a little
more light, please?
- Damn.
- What is it?
The swelling isn't going down because
there's a mass beneath the abscess.
And it's not just pressing
on the pudendal nerve,
it's totally engulfed it.
- That's bad.
- Very bad.
You're done already?
We were able to
drain the abscess.
I already feel better.
That's only because
of the pain meds.
The reason the pain was so severe
was because it wasn't just an abscess.
There's a perineal
myoma underneath.
What's that?
A fibroid tumor.
It's not cancerous, but it is
wrapped around the nerve.
We need to remove
the tumor, but to do that,
we will have to sever the nerve.
You'll lose all feeling
in your genitals.
I'm so sorry.
I knew it.
God's punishing me.
No, absolutely not. This
is just a random growth...
- You're religious?
- Yes.
Or at least I used to be.
I haven't thought about
God in a really long time.
But being in here...
Are you sure you don't
want us to call your parents?
No, I couldn't bear to
see the look on their faces.
Especially my dad's.
Well, that's what
parents are for,
so you don't have to
do these things alone.
Could you tell your
father you're a whore?
You made a mistake. That is all.
Patient vitals?
- Stable.
- Fetus?
Stable.
Okay. Is everybody ready?
Knife.
Retractor.
Okay, cutting into the uterus.
TEE is showing
anterior-wall hypokinesis.
Systolic pressure,
90. Get me a Swan.
- Cardiac function is decreasing.
- She's having
a heart attack. I need
you to close the incision.
- On it. Needle driver.
- Get a fluoroscope in here!
I'm gonna prep her
for a balloon pump.
Barbara.
There was a complication
during surgery,
a blood clot blocked
an artery in your heart.
We were able
to catch it in time.
- And my baby?
- The fetus is stable.
The MI happened before
we opened the uterus.
So, we're right back
where we started?
You just had a heart attack.
I don't care.
There is no other option now.
If we don't terminate
and the fetus dies in utero,
the resulting clots will
overwhelm your heart and brain.
Which is exactly why
we need to try again.
What are you talking about?
You need to remove the tumor.
You begged me not to
do the surgery before.
I thought I could
talk her out of it then.
Now I know I can't.
Either you do it, or she dies.
Before, if we got sued, we'd at
least have one of them on our side.
But now, with
them both aligned...
Can they sue us
for not operating?
They could argue that
we abandoned care.
We're still offering care, just
not the care that they want.
Which is your fault.
If you hadn't offered
her hope to begin with,
we might have been
able to reason with her.
- How's the pain around the incision?
- Five out of 10.
I'll up the dosage.
Any chest pain?
No. My heart
actually feels fine.
Good.
If she doesn't wanna terminate,
there's nothing we can do.
- So, we just send her home to die?
- It is her decision.
We could tell her we were
going ahead with the fetal surgery,
but when's she under...
I'm gonna pretend
you never said that.
If it's the only chance
to save her life...
This is exactly what
I'm talking about.
You wouldn't lie to
convince a suicidal person
to climb down off the ledge?
Knowingly lying to a patient
about a major medical surgery...
Hey, hey, hey!
Lying to a patient is one thing,
performing surgery
without their consent...
- It's unethical and illegal.
- And insane.
I just... I don't wanna do this.
It's not our only option.
You want me to attempt
the fetal surgery again?
If it's the only way
to save her life.
Well, the first time, it was
the only way to save her life,
but a second heart attack one
day after the first will kill her.
Maybe not. I am so sorry to
interrupt, but I have an idea.
What if we kill her
before she kills herself?
We'll stop your heart and
put you on a bypass machine
for the duration of the surgery.
You can't have heart attack
if your heart's not
beating to begin with.
It takes the most significant
danger off the table.
But aren't the clots a
danger to her brain as well?
This doesn't completely
eliminate every risk,
but it does reduce
the biggest one.
Thank you.
We'll do it first
thing in the morning.
You fixed my sink.
Do you know how to tell time?
You fixed my sink!
You're welcome. Now go away.
It was not on the list!
The faucet, it was not on the list.
You weren't supposed to touch it.
So, after I fix everything
you woke me up for,
then I go out of my
way to fix something...
It was not on the list
because I'd already fixed it.
Well, you fixed it wrong,
because it was still dripping.
I need it to drip. At the same
rate as my sink in Casper.
It was too slow before. Now I have
to fix it all over again. It's not fair.
I'm done. If you
don't like your faucet,
or anything else in
your apartment, move.
If you knock this door
again after 5:00 p.m.,
I'm gonna knock your teeth out.
I wish I was a slave
to an age-old trade
Like ridin' around on rail
cars and workin' long days
Lord have mercy on my
rough and rowdy ways
Call it one drink too
many Call it pride of a man
But it don't make no
difference if you sit or you stand
'Cause they both end in
trouble and start with a grin
We do it over and
over and over again
Oh, oh, oh
I am on my way I am on my way
I am on my way
back to where I started
California, Oklahoma
And all of the places
I ain't ever been to but
Down in the valley
with Whiskey rivers
These are the places
you will find me hidin'
These are the
places I will always go
places I will always...
Nerves are like pipes.
- Shaun, this isn't...
- We need to sever the pudendal nerve
to excise the myoma, but
if we reconnect the ends...
The tumor is four
centimeters in diameter.
That's way too wide of a
gap to reconnect the ends,
and nerves don't stretch.
We don't need to stretch it,
we can connect the distal end
of the pudendal nerve to the
branch of the femoral cutaneous nerve
from her inner thigh.
Would you rather lose
feeling in your thigh or genitals?
Thigh, definitely.
Is he right? Can we do that?
It probably would've been better
to discuss this prior to meeting
with the patient, but,
yes, I think it could work.
Cut the suture.
The grafted nerve is in place.
Let's see if it will conduct.
Conduction electrodes
are in position.
Send a pulse.
Again.
Okay, Murphy. We
get it. Your idea worked.
Good job. Both of you.
- Thanks.
- Thank you.
I'm guessing Melendez
doesn't let you know this enough,
but you both are
doing a great job.
And if either of you needs
anything, even just to talk,
my door's always open.
4-0 Vicryl.
Yes, Doctor. Four micra.
She's on bypass.
Cross clamping the aorta.
You ready?
- Flush the heart.
- Flushing.
Let's prep her for C-section.
Dr. Andrews?
The operation went perfectly.
But I don't feel
anything down there.
You're still on the
meds, so it's gonna...
It's going to take six months to a
year to regain complete sensation.
It'll take a while for your
brain to figure out what we did,
but the grafted nerve
is fully conducting.
- You're gonna be fine.
- Thank you.
- Can you do me a favor?
- Sure.
Call my parents.
Absolutely.
Knife.
Bovie.
How are we on bypass?
Dr. Kalu, you still with us?
Yeah. Central venous pressure's
good, bypass oxygen tension is 200.
Good. I'm repairing
the fetal sacrum
and then we'll put this
baby back where it belongs.
Baby?
That's the first time
you didn't call it a fetus.
Just an expression.
I told you.
Yes, you did.
You're gonna need to stay in
bed for the next four months,
but both you and your
son's prognosis is excellent.
Hey, we wanted
it to be a surprise.
Oops.
Rookie mistake.
Yes!
We are definitely
celebrating tonight.
Whoa, whoa. Screw sleep,
Murphy. You are coming with us.
Where are you going?
- Out. We're gonna drink.
- I'm not thirsty.
- Don't be an idiot.
- Hey.
I just meant... Come on, mate,
you just saved an
18-year-old girl's sex life,
and I saved two
lives. We are drinking.
Come on, Shaun.
- Okay.
- Cool.
There's nothing holding me back
Thanks.
I have to go home now.
It'll be okay. Don't worry.
We won't stay long.
Not really into hesitation
Pulls me in enough
to keep me guessing
And maybe I should
stop and start confessing
Hi, Shaun.
Hi, Colleen.
I heard Steve showed
you my dad's magazine.
Did you like it?
Don't worry, I'm not
gonna tell anyone.
It's nothing to be
embarrassed about.
All guys like
that kind of stuff.
You wanna know
a secret about me?
I think you're really cute.
You smell like bubblegum.
I know. It's my lip gloss.
Come here.
Come here, silly.
Do you think I'm pretty?
I like you, too.
I'll show you mine, if
you show me yours.
Come on, I'm curious.
You must be curious.
Can I have a kiss?
I want to know
what it feels like.
I'll give you a kiss
if you show me.
Show you what?
You know, pull down your pants.
- No.
- Come on, Shaun.
No. I gotta go.
Oh, my God. I can't believe
you were about to pull it out.
No, I wasn't.
Like I'd ever kiss a
creepy weirdo like you.
Leave him alone. Come on.
Baby, there's nothing
holding me back
All right, guys, a toast.
To us. Because we rock.
Nothing else need
be said. Cheers.
Cheers.
I feel so free when
you're with me, baby
Baby, there's nothing
holding me back