Oh, God. Oh, no.
Something wrong?
All right, people,
who ate my salad?
Keep looking, Peter.
It's there. Yeah.
Damn it, it's not in here.
The ignition's shot.
Somebody took it.
No. I need someone
to fix it today.
Thank you.
I think I'll shove my
sister in front of a train.
She burn out your
ignition switch?
Yeah. I had to
hot-wire it to get to work.
You know how to hot-wire a car?
Learned it from one
of Chloe's boyfriends.
He's in Joliet.
Grand theft auto.
Oh, God!
We got a rollerblader coming in.
Bashed head again.
Five minutes off.
This place is a mess, man.
Doesn't anybody
ever clean it out?
Jerry? Jerry...
don't turf me a
patient without a chart.
I'm sorry. I thought...
don't apologize. Just
do your damn job.
Ignore him.
More charts. That's great.
Any more exciting,
I'll check myself in.
Dr. Ross... Yeah.
Rescue 61's bringing in a woman
with severe head trauma.
All the neurosurgeons
are tied up in the O.R.
Divert the woman to St. Luke.
So, uh, who died and
left you Chief Resident?
Mark's got the flu.
I'm covering.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Saint Mark is out?
Must be pneumonia.
Hiya, Peter.
Sarah.
You two excited?
Announcement's today.
I know how to read
a calendar, Haleh.
What announcements?
Starzl Fellowship.
Maybe you noticed
Dr. Benton's a little anxious.
Dr. Ross, they needed
your DD-5 20 minutes ago.
I will send them four
pints of my blood.
What is a DD-5?
It's the shift status report.
You're supposed to fill it out.
How does Mark do all of this?
He puts in four
hours after every shift.
That's it. Jerry, I will do
anything to get him down here.
I'll put him on a drip.
I'll give him my
next four paychecks.
I don't care how sick he is.
Phone...
don't answer it.
It might be Craig.
Who's Craig?
Judge Franklin's other clerk.
Yeah?
Call him back.
Hello?
Hello? Hello.
What the hell?
She called you from the street?
35th, over in Bridgeport.
Mark?
Look, are you certified
or do we need to
call in a counselor?
I'm certified.
She say anything?
Yeah. Not to touch her.
Jamie?
I'm Carol Hathaway. I'm a nurse.
Can I take your coat?
It's kind of warm in here.
There you go.
Todd knows my boyfriend.
He said Jack told
him to pick me up.
I shouldn't have gone with him.
I should've stayed home,
but he was a friend of Jack's.
I let it happen.
It was my fault.
It's okay. You're safe here.
It's going to be okay.
Is it?
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.
What are you talking about?
It was incredibly inappropriate.
Please. I snapped
at a desk clerk?
He's not a desk
clerk. He's Jerry.
Well, he didn't do his job.
He didn't kill anyone,
Div. He lost a chart.
All right, I promise, I'll never
snap at a desk clerk again, okay?
This morning it was the cashier
at Starbucks.
Well, I-I don't know, um...
What is wrong?
Well, what's wrong is
is that you're wasting my time,
and, uh, and I'm
late for rounds.
Dr. Lewis, call on two.
Susan Lewis.
You're not coming?
You promised you'd
bring an ignition switch.
Never mind.
I know someone
who could fix your car.
I'll worship you forever.
Maybe you could just
help me get into an O.R.
Hmm... I think
they're up on Three.
Dr. Benton always forgets me.
Carter, important
lesson in life...
He who asks, gets,
he who doesn't, doesn't.
Coming through, coming through.
Carter!
Let's go.
Kenny, Mike, 17, passed
out at school. Vitals are stable.
Kid's a wrestler
at St. Robert's.
Susan, I need a pill-push.
I don't think there's a surgeon.
Let's go. LEWIS: Got it!
Get the history on this kid?
I don't know.
Okay.
All right, people, let's
take him and shake him.
On my count. One, two, three.
Lily, do a dextrose stick.
Carter, get another
line in. Let's move.
Let's get a CBC, lytes,
and let's tox screen him
for the works. Let's move.
Hypotensive, 70/60 and falling.
Glucose normal.
He's in trouble.
Are those PVCs? Rhythm strip.
Could be a nodal
rhythm with a block.
Why would he be having those?
All right, Susan,
it's your call.
What the hell is this?
I don't know.
A 17-year-old kid
with heart trouble...
It doesn't make sense.
Uh-oh. Extra beats.
He's going into arrhythmia.
What do we do now?
What exactly am I signing?
Title to your car...
Belongs to me now.
We have a 300-pound
diabetic in Two.
She's in ketoacidosis.
All right, see if there's an
endocrinologist upstairs.
Mm-hmm.
You are late, Mookie James.
Guards wouldn't let me in.
Well, you just get here earlier.
J-o-b, job.
That means be on time.
Don't sweat me.
Hey, how much money
these doctors make anyway?
30,000 a year.
That's all?
Mm-hmm.
Underpaid, overworked.
Get used to it.
Pressure's still falling. 60/45.
All right, central line is in.
Blood's back.
No drugs, but his
lytes are screwed up.
What's his potassium?
It's a 2.0.
All right, piggyback
20 milliequivalents,
and keep on eye on the EKG.
Why is his potassium crashing?
It could be hyperaldosteronism
or Bartter's Syndrome...
Carter, put that damn book down.
Any word on his family?
Or, uh... cirrhosis.
Heart's racing. Looks like SVT.
Rate's 240 and climbing.
We got to stop
this. It'll kill him.
Okay, rapid bolus
adenosine, six milligrams.
Nothing here. No constricting.
It's not coming down.
Let's shock him.
Hit the sync switch.
100. Charged.
Clear!
Pulse?
Faint. I'm barely getting it.
Shock him again. 200.200.
Clear!
Still no pulse.
We're losing him.
We have to get this guy's
rate down. Send it up to 360.
Ready.
Clear!
Give me a pacer. I'm
going to overdrive him.
You're going in blind?
You know, I'd love to
wait for a fluoroscope,
but I don't think this young
man would appreciate it.
Carter, come in close.
You're not going to
see this every day.
Let's get a line. Here you go.
He has to float the catheter
into the heart very... slowly.
Pacer captured.
Push it up to 300.
All right, now
bring it down slow...
very slow.
Slow.
Is that smoothing out?
Normal sinus rhythm.
Call me when he wakes up.
Last count, I filled
out 306 forms.
It's not even noon.
You finish the shift report yet?
What are these
abbreviations for?
This column... What's T.W.D.?
"Truly weird doctors."
Thank you.
How does Mark do this?
What is he, a machine?
You ready for another round?
Just give me one minute.
I knew you were a lightweight.
It's so great to
see you so happy.
I never felt like this before.
I'm good at something.
Franklin loved the rewrite
of my zoning opinion.
They look at me
differently now...
The other clerks
and the secretaries.
I like it.
I didn't understand
about you, Mark...
How you love to go to work.
Mmm...
Thank you for
staying home today.
I'm feeling a little guilty.
You're entitled to a day off.
You didn't take a
single sick day last year.
Ah, ah... let the
machine get it.
It might be Craig.
He's supposed to give me
notes on my new opinion.
Please leave a
message at the tone.
Mark, it's Doug.
You're probably in the
bathroom throwing up right now,
but I'm sinking here, buddy.
Dr. Ross, they're calling
about that shift report again.
Tell them I will get to
it when I can get to it.
Mark, if you ever had
any feelings for me at all,
if there's a glimmer
of friendship,
then you will haul your
ass off of that sickbed,
and you will get down here,
and you will rescue me.
I am not kidding there, buddy.
What is this? What is that?
I'm dying here, pal.
So, if you're awake,
and you could call me,
I'd appreciate it.
Now I'm feeling really guilty.
Mark, how many times
did you cover for Doug
last year?
Eight? Hmm?
Ten?
Mmm...
Anybody ever do it to you?
I've never been raped, no.
My mother always
said I was asking for it.
Jamie, look at me.
You said no,
and that's enough.
Nobody wants to be raped.
We have to take some samples...
Swab for semen, pubic hairs.
It's called a rape kit.
Doctor going to
put his hands in me?
No. No, I do it
with another nurse,
but the police will have
to take photographs.
He's not bad... Todd.
Been nice to me.
We have to do a rape kit now.
What's Jack going to say?
Not going to
believe Todd did it.
It's not your fault.
Are you hearing me?
Yeah. Can you tell me
when the results of the Starzl
are going to be announced?
So how we supposed to find out?
They're going to be posted?
Good. Maybe you
can just tell me if I...
Hello? Hello?
What are you so cheerful about?
I love watching you worry.
This is Mookie James.
You remember Mookie?
Yeah.
This is Dr. Benton.
He's going to be
your supervisor.
That means, if he says,
"Jump," you ask, "How high?"
Got it?
Yo, what's up?
Follow me.
Here. Put these gloves on.
You're going to need them.
Take everything out.
If it's green, it goes.
If it smells, it goes.
I want you to check
expiration dates.
Look for mold. Look for anything
that can crawl out
of here on its own.
Then I want you to scrub it all
from top to bottom. You got it?
I want to be able
to eat Sunday dinner
off of this thing.
Let's go. What?
I'm a janitor?
What did you think you
were going to be doing...
Performing brain surgery?
We got a cop in Trauma
2. Gunshot, superficial.
All right. Come on, let's go.
Don't take all day.
How you doing?
You okay?
Yeah, I'm okay, yeah.
This will just take a minute.
Just relax.
There you go.
So, you got a boyfriend?
Uh-huh.
What is he, like, a doctor?
Yes, he is.
Must be great.
You make lots of money.
That's it.
Why am I doing this?
I want my name in the
paper, I'll go kill myself.
You listen to me.
You're going to
get through this.
You'll move past it.
Yeah.
Sure.
So I put in a new
ignition switch
and some leads there for you.
By the way, why ain't
the lady doctor paying?
I'm going to get
that from her later.
$198.50, Doc.
For that kind of dough,
I hope she's good-looking.
She's a friend.
Yeah.
Mmm. It's Craig.
No, don't get it.
It could be Doug.
Hello?
Mark?
Sorry.
Hi, Doug.
How are you?
Um... a little better.
My fever's down.
What are you doing?
Um... just raiding
the refrigerator.
Well, you're eating.
You must be better.
You sure you don't
want to come in?
Um... I don't think so.
I thought Jen was in Milwaukee.
Um... actually, the
judge she works for,
he had to fly to Washington,
and so she got the day off.
Just one day,
huh? It's been, what,
two weeks since
you saw her last?
Three.
Three. That's right.
Okay. Well, I better let
you get back to being sick.
We wouldn't want you to...
wouldn't want it to
turn into pneumonia.
Thanks, Doug.
What?
Mark is very sick,
at home, with his wife.
Oh.
Hi.
I'm John Carter.
What are you doing?
I was feeling better.
I needed some exercise.
I don't think exercise is
such a great idea right now.
You had a major coronary
event this morning.
You a doctor?
No, I'm a med student.
Dr. Lewis tells me
you're a wrestler.
I used to wrestle.
Junior varsity,
college, at Penn.
Oh, yeah. Great coach.
I read about him in the Trib.
Making your weight class okay?
Sure. Easy.
I didn't eat sometimes
to make mine.
Boy, I was tired a lot.
Me, too.
So you're not eating.
No, no. I eat plenty.
That's weird.
Your blood tests
look like you're
not eating at all.
I was there this morning,
and you almost died.
I'm okay.
I'm in good shape.
Uh-uh. How much did you lose...
Eight, ten pounds?
You must be cycling up and down
between every match.
I have a match against
Western next week.
The team's counting on me.
I think you should
tell Dr. Lewis the truth
so she can admit
you to the hospital.
Please...
I have to be on the team.
You've got a problem.
It's a kind of anorexia.
And, if you keep starving
yourself between matches,
it is going to kill you.
Has he been coughing?
No, he just won't eat.
Usually he eats like a
horse. He never stops.
You put anything
in front of him.
He's not picky.
It's okay.
He's going to be fine.
Temp's 100.2
All right, Ben, I want you
to take a deep
breath for me, okay?
Mm-hmm. One more time.
All right.
He has a sore throat.
That's why he's not eating.
Could it be croup?
He had it as a baby.
He's a little old for that.
Let me get some X rays,
make sure it's nothing serious.
It hurts.
I can't eat.
I know, buddy. We're
going to fix you right up.
Okay? All right.
I'll be right back.
Have an intubation
tray standing by
in case he gets worse.
Doug, some irate internist
is looking for your scalp.
Something about
assigning one of his patients
to the resident on call.
You take Ben to radiology,
and you stay with him.
You let me know if
anything changes, okay?
Right through here.
Your son is on his
way, Mrs. Benton.
On his way? Where?
He's coming to see you.
It's the stroke.
Some days she's
a little out of it.
Carter...
Hey, Walt, what's up?
Hey, Ma. How you doing?
My foot hurts.
Yeah, I know. You
sprained your ankle.
Walt, she's in a
lot of pain. man.
You should have taken her
to Emergency. It's a lot closer.
I thought you would
want to take care
of your own mother.
Petey, when did you
grow that mustache?
Three years ago, Ma.
Don't you have to be
somewhere, Carter?
No. Actually, it's kind of slow.
Carter? You got
people in Tennessee?
On my father's side.
I think his people
owned our people.
But you're a nice boy.
You come to Thanksgiving dinner.
She doesn't mean that.
No. You come to dinner now.
You promise.
I promise.
Okay, Ma.
Let's go take care of that foot.
Morgenstern wants
you in the O.R., Peter.
Mesocaval shunt.
Ma, I'm going to have
to see you later, okay?
Dr. Carter here is going
to take care of you.
Walter, don't even start, man.
I got to go.
Would you excuse
me for a second?
I'll be right back.
Where are you going?
I thought you might
let me go with you.
Mesocaval shunt.
I ought to learn, and
maybe I could help.
Well, I asked you to
look after my mother.
I could have a nurse do that.
You said yourself
it was only a sprain.
Well, still, I want you to
clean those lacs in two
and stitch them up.
See if my mother
needs anything to eat.
She doesn't eat enough.
Go. Let's move.
Headline news!
Guess who's leaving us?
Starzl Fellowship winner.
Good guys win?
Cancel the champagne.
Excuse me.
What is this, a
funeral or something?
Dr. Langworthy's
a year ahead of me.
I didn't expect to win.
Schedule.
Thanks.
When can you come back?
Not before Thanksgiving.
Can you come up next weekend?
No. I work both days.
I've got Wednesday.
We do oral arguments
on Thursday.
We do a lot of briefing
on Wednesday nights.
That's where you always are.
It's almost seven years, Mark.
They say you get an itch.
Yeah.
All the time.
I don't think about
anybody else.
Susan Lewis?
We're just friends.
Uh-huh.
What is this?
You projecting?
Where else can we do it?
I want to have
memories to hold me
for the next couple of weeks.
Kitchen table?
It's your grandmother's.
What would she say?
Worked for Grandpa.
Let the machine get it.
Let me out of here!
Get your hands off me!
I can't stitch him
if he won't settle down.
Get your hands off me!
I'm a citizen of a free country!
Mr. Randall!
Your head is bleeding.
Let me go!
Mr. Randall...
Mr. Randall?
Take him to Exam Two.
Get Cvetic down
here to look at him.
He might need assessment
for suicide and depression.
Sure.
Thanks.
How long are you going to
pretend I'm not here, Peter?
That's fairly self-centered
of you, Sarah.
I'm working.
Yeah.
Um... congratulations
on the, um... Starzl.
I'm sorry you didn't get it,
but I'm glad I did.
Would you rather
someone else had won?
I really wasn't
that invested in it.
You wanted me to
lose if you couldn't win.
Peter...
I'm a year ahead of you,
and I could help you
be a better surgeon
if you'd let me.
You know what your problem is?
No, but, um...
I have a feeling
you're willing to tell me.
Losing to a woman.
Oh, come on.
The truth is, you
want to sleep with me.
Then you wouldn't
be so threatened.
Sarah, um...
not only don't I want
to sleep with you,
I've never even
fantasized about it.
Obviously, you have.
Yeah, right.
Excuse me.
Look, I... I just
want to leave, okay?
Um... why don't
you want a doctor
to take care of your head?
What are you, a shrink?
Shrinks.
They tell me I'll get over it.
My wife gets smashed
against a streetlight,
and my son gets
his head cut off,
and I'll get over it real soon.
You know, there's, um...
nothing wrong with
being angry, you know.
I don't need this
patronizing crap.
You think you're
real important, hmm?
No one... no one denies
your pain, Mr. Randall,
but self-pity isn't the answer.
I'm, uh...
I'm ordering Mr. Randall
committed for 72 hours.
Take him to Five.
Put him in restraints.
You're locking me up?
You dumb bastard!
Who do you think you are?!
You can't do this to me!
I can drink all day long!
What's that about?
Oh, I committed him.
What?
Mm-hmm.
He's a drunk.
He's a dangerous drunk.
He tried to hit me.
Did you do a full psych exam?
He's a pathetic
drunk. I didn't have to.
What's wrong with
you? Are you trying
to destroy your career?
What if he sues?
Well, screw him.
What if he does, huh?
Are you busy later?
Want to do some
Italian or something?
Carol?
Mm-hmm?
You got a minute?
Yeah. Excuse me.
The police lab called
about the rape kit.
Yeah?
They said there are
four different pubic hairs
in the samples.
Hers and three others.
Will you cover for
me for a minute?
Sure.
Jamie, who else
was there last night?
There were three other
types of human hair
in the samples we took.
The police are going to ask you
the same questions I'm asking,
so, if you want me to
help, you have to help me.
I was with Todd,
like I told you.
And who else?
I don't remember.
Have you told me
anything that's true so far?
Yes!
I went over to Todd's,
and he had two friends there,
and I didn't know them,
and we were drinking.
And then what happened?
I don't remember.
Anything?
No.
No!
Christ, no!
I don't remember it.
I was drunk.
And there were these guys,
and I was pushing Todd away.
And this other guy... oh, God!
Oh, God!
Okay. It's all right.
It's okay.
Shh. It's okay.
I don't remember.
I am the acting Chief
Resident of this E.R.
So why don't you go
back up to the sixth floor.
Aren't you late for a golf
game? Or is it tennis?
Doug, the McCabe kid
stopped breathing. Trauma Two.
Damn it.
Lydia?
Call Anesthesiology
and get an E.N.T. surgeon
down here now, please.
He's hypoxic.
Epiglottitis.
Coming through.
50-Year-old crasher,
collapsed lung.
Let's go.
Oxygen SAT 70 and dropping.
Laryngoscope.
How long has he been out?
Less than a minute.
Sore throat...
this came on fast.
Waiting room.
Where's the mother?
I can't even see his cords.
Connie, see if we can get
an air bubble.
Yes, Doctor.
There's a lot of
swelling in there.
Suction.
This tube is too big.
I need a smaller one.
Diminished breath
sounds on the right.
Hyperresonant.
Okay.
We got a tracheal shift.
Oh, no.
Tension pneumo.
Doug needs a small E.T. Tube.
Where the hell are they?
Bottom drawer.
What's Doug got in there?
Epiglottitis.
Six-year-old.
Give me a 14-gauge needle.
Come on.
Let's go.
Got it.
Congratulations, Mr. Kalman.
You're going to live.
He's swollen shut.
Yeah.
Carter, do me a favor.
Take this needle.
How long has he been out?
Coming up on two minutes.
What about a needle crike?
Not yet.
What are you doing?
I'm going in.
I said not yet.
Haleh...
hook up a 3.0 E.T. tube
hub to a cath and bag him.
Hyperventilate him now.
O2 SAT's up to 95.
All right. Start him
on 750 milligrams
Ceftriaxone I.V., Q-12.
Son of a bitch.
You lose a fellowship, so
you have to prove something.
Dr. Benton, otherwise
known as God.
You couldn't get the tube in.
I had plenty of time
to crike him myself.
Another 90 seconds, that kid's
brain would have been mush.
Right. 90 seconds,
and it's my choice.
The kid's alive.
He's my patient.
So it's okay if he dies, right?
Oh, so you're the only person
that can keep him alive?
It was a judgment call, Doug.
One I should have let you make.
You lost a fellowship
today, Peter, not a patient.
You know what I looked
like in there? Hmm?
In that interview?
I made a fool out of myself
in front of Morgenstern.
You saved two
lives in five minutes.
That's not a bad day.
Don't give her a hard time.
Just take her statement.
Jamie?
What's going on?
Jerry, have you seen
Jamie Hendricks?
Who?
The girl who was raped.
I think she just left.
My mom's dropping Rachel
off in about 20 minutes.
We should get dressed.
Are we pretending?
I think your mom
knows that we have sex.
She doesn't like to be reminded.
Let the machine get it.
Hi. We're not here.
Please leave a
message at the tone.
Hi, Jennifer. It's Craig.
The judge read
your new opinion...
Hi. I'm here.
He liked it?
That's great. Mm-hmm.
Why don't you call him back?
Let me get it out. Yeah.
Okay. Morrison v. Kentucky.
If you look at the form
selection clause arguments,
I think you'll see that the
jurisdictional issues apply.
I know the Supreme
Court settled it,
but the arguments
are very similar
to the ones we're using.
Well, use some
imagination, Craig.
Yes.
Go to page three.
Mm-hmm.
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
Oh, Dr. Ross.
This is our new
E.R. aide, Bogdana...
No. Bobdana... What is it?
No. Bogdanalivetsky.
Right.
How about "Bob"?
Bob?
Yeah. You see, you're answering
to your new name already.
Bob. See, that's cool.
Cool. Bob.
I'm taking Mr. Randall
downstairs. His meds are back.
You got to sign him out.
Okay.
Dr. Cvetic know about this?
Thank you.
Uh... what's going on?
You seem much better.
Yeah. It, uh... happens
when you sober up.
That was a nasty gash.
Yeah, uh... I
walked into a door.
Uh... what are we doing in here?
Going for an elevator ride.
A doctor with a sense of humor.
That... that's a treat.
Go home, Mr. Randall.
Uh... I thought I
was in for 72 hours.
You seem much calmer.
Call a cab. Go home.
Thank you.
Hey, Walt.
Hey. You got car trouble?
No, I, uh... no.
Pass me a wrench, will you?
Five-eighths.
Man, would your dad be surprised
if he could see me now
running his business
and you a surgeon?
Did you hear about that
fellowship thing today?
Yep.
Well, if you got it,
I'd hate to see the look
on your face if you didn't.
Yeah, well, I didn't get it.
No kidding.
You know, Walt,
man, it's hard to lose.
Yeah, well, most
of us are used to it.
Your trouble is, Pete, you
got most of what you want.
And, when you don't get
what you want, it hurts more.
Yeah? So, is that wrong?
It's just a little selfish.
You got a hard shell, Pete.
You don't let anyone in.
Just like your dad.
I wouldn't worry
about it though.
You're basically a good guy.
Give me a hand with this.
Jamie?
Go away.
What happened?
What are you doing here?
A lot you care.
Jaimie...
I don't know where to go.
My boyfriend doesn't
want me to come home.
He doesn't believe me.
Maybe I could
have fought harder.
I let him do it.
How could I let him do it?
Nobody will believe me.
You said no, didn't you?
I did.
Then you have to finish this.
You got to take care of things.
If you don't,
they come back.
They always do.
I don't know.
I know.
Come here.
Come on.
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.