You have a patient waiting. See?
I'm waiting for a follow-up.
If you're talking
about Mr. Casdin,
he has a deceased
sticker on his file,
as do all the other follow-ups
you have scheduled for today.
Whoops!
I had colds all winter.
I've been in this room a
while, but it's spring now, right?
I feel run down, like maybe
something big is coming on.
Run down? Come on, give
me something. Sore throat?
No. Runny nose?
No. I know it sounds
weird, I'm a nurse,
but could you run maybe
a CBC or a thyroid...
Dr. Cuddy, need a consult!
Until she stops seizing,
may as well go back to my
office and get my diagnosis on.
She's urinating on herself.
She's having a seizure.
If she hadn't peed...
It's green.
Interesting.
Thirty-five-year-old woman.
Head of nursing
in an old-age home.
Neurological symptoms and "P"?
Oh, green pee. I get it. Nice.
Neuro is also written in green.
Does that mean she has green
neurological symptoms as well?
From now on, I'm gonna use
two colors. Green indicates irony.
Pseudomonas infection.
She'd have a fever. Toxins?
Why are we taking this case?
Welcome, Your Lordship, we were
just preparing your morning briefing.
Sorry I'm late,
and, yes, green pee does meet
the only diagnostic requirement
you care about.
It's interesting.
But is it worth us
taking this case?
"Us" aren't taking anything.
I'm taking. You're accepting.
Okay, I accept. She
has adult-onset epilepsy,
and she really likes those
St. Patrick's Day beers.
Go check out the house and
the office for toxins and infections.
Her neuro exam was normal,
no subsequent seizures.
It's not life threatening.
It's not important.
Luckily, neither are you.
You okay? Fine.
You and House this morning?
The way you were arguing?
Airing disagreements
doesn't qualify as arguing.
Come on, man, I'm just
trying to help. We're friends.
There are 400 Japanese teenagers
you were playing
Halo with last night
you're better friends with.
Your avatar should ask their
avatars how they're doing.
I consider you a good friend
even if we don't hang
that much outside of work.
I wasn't arguing with him.
You kind of were.
Fine, I was. And you know what?
I was right.
You got conned.
Methylthioninium chloride.
Notable side
effect, green urine.
She's a nurse, she
knows the dosage,
knows how to fake a seizure.
She pees pea soup and gets the
warm attention of doctors all week long.
She's a Munchausen,
and you're her mark.
So your insight is based on
discovering an anti-Alzheimer's
drug at an old-age home.
No good reason it'd
be sitting on her desk.
You ever tried to pee on
yourself in public? It's not easy.
Sorry, I rushed the Jewish
frat, we peed in private.
For good reason. I
can spot a fake seizure,
which means this
was real, which means
her problem is phenol.
Carbolic acid?
Yeah, maybe she
accidentally inhaled some
at a gout treatment
facility, circa 1890.
It's still in some
antiseptic throat sprays.
She's been chugging it
all winter for her colds.
Phenol explains the
seizure and the urine.
She'd have to drink
five bottles a day.
Which is why I'm sure
you won't have trouble
discovering the evidence of it
when you search her house. Bye.
And you can start her on charcoal
hemoperfusion for the phenol poisoning.
Seriously?
Oh, you were lying
about the throat spray.
That does make more sense.
So why are you
wasting Taub's time?
Because I don't want him to
know that I'm wasting my time
disproving his fake
seizure theory. Zip!
Chris?
Chris Taub, right?
Neil Zane.
I was two years under you
at Collegiate High, remember?
Sure.
So you are some
big doctor here now?
I'm a doctor. You?
I was speaking at an econ
course over at the university.
I tripped and banged my leg.
I have some time. Come with me.
Hi. Tests back?
Head CT was negative.
What about a thyroid uptake
or abdominal ultrasound?
Sure. How about I flash some
lights in front of your face first?
You want me to
have another seizure?
We're gonna have
to give up the room
unless we can confirm a problem.
Okay.
Damn it!
Oh, God. Please
forgive me. I'm so sorry.
What are you worried about? You'll
have maybe a night in jail for fraud.
I have to go tell one of
my employees he was right.
I'm not a Munchausen. I'm
gonna die unless you help me.
You'll have to come up
with something more original.
A cat predicted my death.
Cats make terrible doctors.
Oh, no, wait, that's
women. You're screwed.
How'd you slip?
I've had this dizziness
problem for a while now.
You get checked
for labyrinthitis?
On antibiotics for a
week. No difference.
Lie down a sec.
Whoa, whoa, I'm dizzy.
That's normal.
So what are you teaching?
Entrepreneurship.
I'm a CEO. OstTech Industries.
We make medical devices.
All right. You can sit up.
So, did that tell you
anything? Did I...
Oh, my God.
You just cured me.
I figured you had a tiny
calcium deposit in your inner ear.
I just shifted it around.
I've seen three
doctors for this.
I'm buying you
dinner. Forget it.
Come on. I'm also an investor
in a club, we'll make it a night out.
Well, I'm married, boring.
I know some married
people who aren't boring.
A few years back,
I was one of them.
Good luck, Neil.
If you're gonna kill me and
rape me, please do it in that order.
This is the cat. Debbie.
Have you heard of her?
Debbie? Sorry, but
without a last name...
She was on the news.
We found her as a kitten.
She lives in the nursing home.
She only sleeps next to
people when they're about to die.
Ten patients in the last year.
And then yesterday, she did it to
me while I was sitting on my couch.
Please. The whole staff, the
doctors even, we all know this is real.
Can you come back later?
I have some business I'm
conducting with the Prince of Nigeria.
Just watch this video.
It'll prove I'm not lying.
Dr. House, I am begging you.
Chest.
Quick, before she goes without
attention for eight seconds.
House.
She's faking. The
cat told me. Listen.
Soft breath sounds.
Means it's bronchospasm.
You can't fake that.
Debbie the cat spends most of
her time just prowling the halls,
the queen of her own private
world. HOUSE: I gotta say,
I don't think the
changes they've made
to American Idol
really work for me.
When Debbie climbs on a
patient's bed and goes to sleep,
we call the loved ones
and tell them to come in.
You wanna treat
her? She's a nut job.
Don't we all have quirks?
Aren't those eccentricities
what make us human?
It's like Debbie's here on Earth
to bring people to the other side.
The doctors that we spoke
to also agree that the cat...
Nut jobs get sick, too.
So you think this
cat story is nonsense,
and you admit she faked
her earlier symptoms,
but you still think
she's actually sick now?
Well, anything would sound
ridiculous if you said it in that voice.
Confirm she's faking or I'm
gonna have to kick her out.
There's that voice again.
I'll give you 24 hours.
Consecutive?
What are you doing?
No, Mr. Bond, I expect you
to die. Bronchospasm. Go.
Bronchitis. No cough, no fever,
and Blofeld didn't
smoke a cigar.
He might have. Dude had
a lair, means he was rich.
Rich people enjoy a good stogie,
sometimes send them as gifts.
Hey, Taub, did that sound like
I was awkwardly trying to
segue into making a point?
Yes.
Emphysema. FOREMAN:
Lungs were clean on the CT.
Dogs can be trained to predict
diabetic comas, epileptic seizures,
they can smell cancer. It is
possible there's something to this cat.
It's more possible it
was just a coincidence.
Ten million nursing homes,
hundred million pet cats,
one of them was bound
to pick a few winners.
Debbie was able to predict
there was something wrong
with the patient before you
were. Is that a coincidence, too?
Maybe the cat didn't predict anything,
it might have caused the deaths.
We should've
listened to Ted Nugent.
Yeah. It could be cat scratch
fever, or visceral larva migrans.
Maybe it didn't kill everyone
at the nursing home,
but it may be killing Morgan.
The worms hop from the cat to
the cat lady's lungs. I could buy that.
Those cigars were for me.
Hey, that reminds me.
Why is some fancy CEO
sending you a box of Cuban cigars?
Is it related to your
money worries?
What money worries?
Extrapolating from the fact that
he's been skipping his morning muffin,
I'd say that he lost almost all
his money in the market last year.
I'm on a diet.
I'm also extrapolating from the
online portfolio you forgot to log off,
but it's mostly the muffins.
Scope her for
worms in the lungs.
We could help out in there.
Yeah, it takes at
least four people
to look inside a crazy woman's
lungs for imaginary worms.
So, you're in a good mood again.
Do you need another speech
about what a great friend I am?
I'm telling my wife we
don't need to downsize,
but maybe we do.
You really lost all that money?
I don't care about the money,
I just feel bad for Rachel.
She married a guy in one
situation, ended up with another.
That's hard on anyone. Thanks,
makes me feel much better,
hearing my wife's a gold digger.
No, I just meant she married
this master-of-the-universe
successful surgeon,
and now he's basically a
flunky for this mad scientist,
who saves lives, so that's good.
There are no worms in the lungs.
What else could
cause bronchospasm?
Severe acid reflux.
No esophagitis, it's not reflux.
Why are you
pushing a crash cart?
Because patients sometimes
crash, and they haven't yet invented
a crash tractor for me to drive
wildly around the hallways.
Why are we in the
coma patients' room?
You actually think the cat is
going to predict someone's death?
No. I know the cat is not
going to predict anyone's death.
And then I will have
scientifically disproved...
You didn't keep this
patient despite the cat,
you kept this patient
because of the cat.
You're scared
there's something to it.
If I could prove the non-existence
of an omniscient God
who lovingly guides us
to the other side, I would.
Cat version will have to do.
Are you scared?
Cats' brains are
always in alpha mode.
The few scientific tests that have
seemed to confirm psychic phenomena,
that's where it takes place.
Please tell me that you were
kidding, so I won't have to fire you.
I was kidding.
We still have a
human patient, right?
Airborne allergens possible?
Skin test was negative.
Lungs may be more sensitive.
Or House just screwed up.
If you misinterpreted the breath
sounds as soft instead of loud,
it's laryngospasm
instead of bronchospasm.
Which she can get from
a simple panic attack,
which she was having.
I also heard the lung sounds,
too, Taub. You saying I screwed up?
"Screwed up" is maybe
too harsh, but yes.
Don't you wanna
check their charts?
Of course not, this
is a double-blind.
I don't want to even subconsciously
signal to Teddy which one's the sickest.
Her name's Debbie.
Are those welts
on that guy's arm?
Were they here when we got here?
He has a severe cat allergy.
That never happened.
Look at Debbie.
Good news, Mr. Limpert.
When you don't die tonight,
you will finally have done
something good for the world,
as opposed to your
life as a fireman.
Foreman's airborne allergen
theory makes the most sense.
Do a methacholine challenge
on Catgirl to check it out.
I told you to get
rid of Death Cat.
You see a cat?
I see a litter box.
This is a disability, Dr. Cuddy.
I can't make it to the men's
room... You pee on the mice, too?
Well, now, you see, the mice
actually prove that I don't have a cat.
Are these...
Are these the genetically
modified lab mice from oncology?
Genetically
modified for tastiness.
Get rid of the cat, and
get rid of your patient.
My team is doing a
methacholine challenge.
Your team just completed
a methacholine challenge,
which came up negative.
Who told you about
the test? Taub?
I'll never say. But yes.
Her airway's clamped
down. I heard it.
We kick her onto the
streets, it could happen again.
Wish there was a "lawsuit
cat," it could warn you.
I'm sorry, but if you
won't escort her out,
I'll have to get
security to do it.
You're joining me
for a goodbye smoke.
I don't smoke.
Fine, if you don't want the
seventh graders to think you're cool.
I went through your purse.
Horoscopes, good-luck charms.
You went to a good
college, good nursing school,
so you weren't always
a superstitious idiot.
I'm not a superstitious...
How about four
years, that sound right?
That's when you switched
from the family insurance plan
to the one you're on now.
I was married, I got divorced.
Two years before that,
you got chickenpox shots,
which you only get in
adulthood when you have a kid.
Or I should say
when you had a kid
because no kid has
come to visit you.
Which all makes me think
something bad happened.
It was my stepson, Timothy.
What happened?
He was in school.
He was having his morning
snack, and he choked.
And the teachers saw it, and they did
everything that they were supposed to.
He shouldn't have died.
You wanna make it make sense.
What's wrong with that?
It's meaningless
is what's wrong.
What's wrong is that it doesn't
do a thing to bring your kid back,
or put you and your
ex together again.
Rash on your neck.
Probably not enough for Cuddy.
Can't breathe.
Hey, Doc.
Breath sound soft to you, Doc?
Hooray, you're officially sick.
Churg-Strauss fits
best. Here's the plan.
Taub, change the litter box.
This is pathetic.
You're still punishing me for calling
you out on the green urine lady?
Nope, this is for
ratting me out to Cuddy.
I'm not asking you to apologize,
just scoop some poop out of a box.
Just clean it.
Let House do it. FOREMAN:
Yeah, that'll happen.
He won't just continue to let
our room smell like cat pee.
I'll clean it next time.
I'm out of here.
Now that you've delivered that important
lesson, I'm gonna go test the patient.
Whoa!
What, you think your
bag's going to die now?
Now you're punishing me
because you think I'm superstitious?
What do you care? It's not so
much about me caring, per se,
it's more about me wondering
why you're such a credulous idiot.
Thirteen, start the patient on
steroids for the Churg-Strauss.
Unless we have something
we need to argue about?
This is good stuff.
The best.
It's made from the
distilled sweat of
recently-laid-off
hedge fund managers.
Aren't you happy
you came out tonight?
Yeah. I wasn't actually going to,
but not the greatest day at work.
I used to have
an office like this.
Used to?
When I was a plastic surgeon.
But one day, I took
stock of my life and...
Oh, screw it.
I had an affair with the
daughter of one of my partners.
They signed a non-disclosure,
I signed a non-compete.
And the funny thing is I wound
up telling my wife anyway.
You like your job?
Same as you, same as
everyone, it has its ups and downs.
You're lying to
make me feel better.
Yeah. It's the best. I'm in charge,
you know. I'm a kid with toys.
Speaking of which, what
do you think of the prototype?
It's amazing.
You gotta make it a
half-inch smaller, though.
You serious? I got small hands,
6.5 gloves, like women surgeons,
which are your
fastest-growing market.
Me and the girls would have to
use two hands to hit the switch.
Why do I bother paying
the idiots that work for me?
Put down that
crap you're drinking,
because I am breaking
out the really good stuff.
What's wrong?
I went to the
bathroom. My urine...
Green again? It's brown.
I didn't do anything. Honest.
I'm just a girl who can't say no
It is possible
she's still faking.
She didn't fake
the bronchospasm.
You think she's faking
some stuff, but not other stuff?
Maybe she's Unchausen?
I'm just saying the brown
urine doesn't make sense.
What? Nothing.
We've ruled out every
possible cause for brown urine.
No blood in the urine,
liver and kidneys fine.
Brown could be fecal. Fistula.
We checked.
How do we know the
urine is still brown?
Had to be. Once
you've gone brown...
If we've ruled out everything
that can make the urine brown,
what if it just looked brown.
If the green dye never left her
system, what plus green makes brown?
Purple.
Strep bovis infection
from colon cancer.
Paraneoplastic syndrome
would explain the bronchospasm.
We scoped her when
we checked for the fistula,
there's no tumor.
Oh, no.
I wasn't scared by
the umbrella, either.
What? Not everything's
about you, Kutner.
I realize it's stupid. I just
don't know everything,
I don't want to invite... Great.
I thought your superstitiousness
had to do with your
folks being killed,
but "you're stupid"
works just as well.
Why is there a ladder here?
Whoops. Forgot that one.
Scopes don't work as well as
pillcams. Give her one, find the tumor.
Come with me, Tiny Taub.
Sorry, I was late again. I've got a
long commute from the poorhouse.
Knew it when I hired you.
You'd eventually miss the money,
being the big shot like
your new CEO friend,
if that nightclub stamp on
your hand is any indication.
Don't worry, I'm
not quitting. I know.
A guy who signs a non-compete instead
of just telling his wife that he cheated
doesn't have the guts to quit.
Bad example. I did tell her.
From guilt, not from courage.
And bravely running to
Cuddy behind my back,
and arriving heroically
late every day.
Cowards make lousy employees.
Well, maybe you're a
coward, maybe you're quitting.
Either way, I'm screwed.
You'll note how Faster,
Pussycat! Kill! Kill!
Has snuggled up by
coma guy over there.
More importantly, she
did yesterday as well.
And he's still breathing.
We done?
Thank you for showing me this.
But maybe she's just confused
in this new environment.
In 1844, a preacher
in upstate New York
added up some dates in the
Bible and predicted Jesus' return.
His followers gave
away all their possessions
and showed up in a field.
Guess who didn't show.
So the preacher said
that he miscalculated,
and they went right
back the next month,
but with more followers.
Every time he was
irrefutably proved wrong,
it redoubled everyone's belief.
I know I sound just like them.
But I also know you're wrong.
Something terrible is
gonna happen to me.
You trying to prove
to her she's not dying?
That would be dumb,
as she might be dying.
This woman lost her kid.
Why are you attacking beliefs
that give her a little bit of comfort?
I don't care if her superstitions
make her feel better.
I just want her to
think more clearly. Oh.
Maybe that can make
her as happy as you are.
Where are we going?
Experimenting.
Stop it, Dr. Wilson. It's
just not cute anymore.
You already experimented
on the coma guy.
Haven't you proved your
point? Not to the patient,
and not to the
millions of idiots
who drooled over that news
item about the magic cat.
Why are you so
obsessed with this?
Can't you just call her an
idiot and leave everyone alone?
Hey, look, kids, therapy cat.
You're a liar. Therapy
animals are dogs, not cats.
Aren't you feisty?
This one's special.
If she likes you,
interesting stuff happens.
No. Okay. Kids, playtime's over.
You know what,
this is a good thing.
Because either you're
starting to doubt yourself,
which is healthy, or...
I don't believe in the
legend of Goodbye Kitty.
Or you're starting to give a
crap what other people think,
which is just
another way of saying
you give a crap
about other people.
I'd love to hear more of your
theory, but I don't give a crap.
Also, the pillcam's back.
Polypoid. Raised edges.
Raised edges are
actually necessary,
since that's the
opening to the appendix.
How many times are we gonna
watch this? There's no tumor.
Oh, my God,
the Death Cat is attacking
your legs, you're gonna die.
Maybe it has something to do with that
little red dot dancing around down there.
Oh, my God, the death laser
is attacking your
legs, you're gonna die.
We're wasting time
looking for cancer.
She's still walking around,
she's still pretty healthy,
maybe it's something minor.
Maybe we're not wasting time.
We wouldn't have
seen a flat lesion.
Skin cancer could have
metastasized to the intestines.
Cool.
Check for melanomas.
Here, kitty, kitty,
kitty. Come here.
Here, kitty.
What? KUTNER: It's not cancer.
We found spider
veins on her back.
They weren't there
when she came in.
Spider veins means Cushing's.
Could cause an abdominal
disturbance, brown urine.
But the bronchospasm?
Cushing's myopathy.
It's uncommon, but...
Wait a second.
You didn't wake me up to tell
me a symptom that's not killing her.
What else is going
on? I think she's dying.
I just told you, it's
Cushing's. We treat...
I don't mean because of the
spider veins. Mr. Limpert died.
If that's my high
school gym teacher...
It's your coma patient.
He was stable for a
year-and-a-half, and he just died.
The cat was right, House.
Here, puss, puss,
puss, puss, puss.
Say "puss" one more time. It's
the sixth "puss" that really does it.
You're right. Sulking
will solve everything.
That cat sat on my lap, and
that cat knows something.
You believe it now? Yesterday,
it was all a coincidence.
Yesterday, it was, till I
unintentionally proved it wasn't.
Patient must have Cushing's. We
have to figure out whether it's based in...
A cat's nose is powerful, could
smell liver or kidney failure.
Exactly. Except that if you'd
glanced at the nursing home files
I had faxed over this morning,
you'd know that most of the
patients' livers and kidneys were fine.
What else? The
MRIs aren't telling us
if the Cushing's is in
her adrenals or her brain.
So check her ACTH.
The cat's vision is at the
blue end of the spectrum.
ACTH is 11.7.
It's too close to tell.
And we can't treat
the wrong organ,
'cause that won't
solve anything.
She could have a cortisol
storm, could kill her.
Well, maybe, as the senior
fellow, you could have made sure
that my doors were closed so that
I could be concentrating on the cat
instead of looking for the cat.
You all right?
Your nose.
What'd he say?
Sounds like he said, "Do
you like cranberry juice?"
Crap.
Cheaper than fake blood.
And more cran-tastic.
Don't ever leave my
door open like that again.
You're playing pranks and
this woman could be dying.
So have Chase do a
venous sampling in her brain.
If he finds
something, it's there,
if he finds nothing,
it's the adrenals.
I'm not who I used to be.
I'm scared. It's
not a way to live.
I wanna come work for you.
Jeez, Chris, you didn't think...
I didn't mean to imply that
I could hire you right now.
You said you
needed guys like me.
I know, but you
don't have an MBA,
and I just hired a
Chief Medical Officer.
Then let me invest in
that laser scalpel start-up.
I got money saved,
not a ton, but...
We put in a two-million-dollar
minimum for the first round of financing.
Look,
I guess I could take you
on, on a smaller number,
but you have to understand
it wouldn't be
some quick payoff.
Yeah, I know. I know it's not
gonna change my life overnight.
I just need to
start changing it.
Okay, then. Let's start.
What exactly are you hoping to
find inside your dead coma guy?
Catnip, chew toy... I don't
know, that's why I'm looking.
Your patient had a cardiac
arrest during the venous sampling.
We got her back, but
her heart's still tenuous.
That tell us anything?
She's weak, possibly dying.
So nothing.
What about the
ACTH? Slightly elevated.
It confirms the Cushing's
is in the brain. Go.
Are you sure that
it's Cushing's?
You'd expect central body
obesity, she's in good shape.
If it had a normal presentation,
there wouldn't be a cat involved.
So it's the brain,
means the next question is whether
to remove her pituitary right now...
That's not a question for me,
that's a question for the patient.
Now present both
sides, let her decide.
All right.
I've got to stop telling
you my theories.
You always just try
to prove me wrong.
You mean the theory about Cuddy's
ass getting bigger at the full moon?
I confirmed that one,
photo's on my blog.
Normally, you'd be
up in the patient room,
hectoring her on what to do,
instead you're up to your elbows
in some irrelevant dead guy,
who may or may not be
connected to a magic cat,
because you want to prove
to me that you don't care.
Case is over. I'm exploring
a scientific mystery.
I put up with your obsessions,
I even encourage
them, for one reason,
they save lives. I don't
know what you're doing now.
Cushing's means your body is
overproducing a hormone called cortisol.
The recommended course of
action is to suppress it with drugs.
And that will cure it?
Just treat it. It
could come back.
The only permanent solution is
to cut into your brain and
remove your pituitary gland,
but surgery's dangerous.
Your heart stopped on
the table once already.
I want the surgery.
This thing is gonna kill
me if I don't kill it first.
Because of the cat?
Do you wanna tell me
what an idiot I'm being?
No.
I really believe that there are
things that science can't understand,
that there is a role for faith and
prayer, but it's in the waiting room,
not the OR.
There's a reason I got sick.
There's a reason for all the bad
things that have happened to me.
I don't know what that reason is,
but I know that if there isn't one,
if there's no greater
purpose in the world,
then it's not a
world I wanna live in.
I'll schedule an operating room.
You're early.
I'm not staying
long. I'm quitting.
You got a new job? No.
Well, then you're not quitting.
I'll see you back here tomorrow.
You're not accepting
my resignation?
Easier this way.
It avoids the whole thing where
you panic, run back and grovel,
and I punish you, and
then take you back.
Bye.
Bring donuts. Everyone
loves those bear claws.
Here, puss, puss,
puss, puss, puss. Puss?
Mr. Taub?
I've been waiting 15
minutes. Where's Neil?
Neil doesn't work here anymore.
But he's the CEO.
I'm sorry. I wish I
could help you. Sorry.
This is crazy. I'm
investing with his company.
He doesn't have a company.
He worked here, but he
was a receptionist, a temp.
Where is he? He's in custody.
I really am not supposed
to say anything else.
I went to high school with him.
That's what everyone
else thought, too.
I'm guessing you also
cured his ear problem?
Did you give him the money yet?
No.
I was right,
and more satisfyingly,
you were wrong.
It was coincidence.
That cat was not
predicting deaths,
it was just trying to keep warm.
Yes, dead people are
renowned for their warm glow.
They are if they're feverish,
like three of the patients were.
Or if they are wasting
away, like the other eight.
Wasting doesn't... It does,
if it means someone sticks
a heating blanket on you.
Congrats. Because of your
crazy obsession with this cat
you've solved a
completely trivial mystery.
Completely trivial?
My God, it's clearly
only partially trivial.
Debbie climbed on Morgan, too,
which means she was overheated.
So what causes flushing,
mimics every Cushing's symptom
except central body obesity?
Cancer.
A corticotropin-producing
carcinoid tumor of the intestine.
But your pillcam
didn't find anything.
Means it must be somewhere
the pillcam couldn't go.
The appendix.
Congratulations. You
probably saved her life.
You definitely saved
her needless surgery.
Yes, I did.
What's the OR extension number?
Just curious.
Thank you.
I wouldn't come here for
thanks, that would be ungracious.
It's more about gloating.
You were about to cut
out a piece of your brain
just to chase some
crazy superstition.
But I didn't.
You didn't didn't do
anything. I stopped it.
And what made you do that?
Science. Logic.
Reason. Pick any three.
A cat chooses that exact
moment to sit on your computer.
Maybe that's science
and logic and reason,
or maybe it's something else.
You're an idiot.
I looked up the preacher
from New York State.
His followers never faded out.
They became the
Seventh-Day Adventists.
A major religion. That man
changed the course of history.
Because his followers
were as deluded as he was.
Maybe he just gave
them something to live for.
Feel better.
Kutner!
Cat pee on my chair?
Blood on my face? Fake blood.
You pay for the dry-cleaning.
Why are you still alive?
I'm not sure.
I guess he was impressed
you stood up to him.
And got a cat to
pee on his chair.
Yeah. A cat.
See you tomorrow. Yeah.