I've seen a lot of surgery
residents come and go in my time.
And they're all
addicted... to surgery.
It comes before food, before sleep.
It becomes the most important thing.
- What?
- Nothing.
- Well, go away.
- You look nice.
Go away!
The only thing.
What they don't know,
is that living on that high...
can eat them alive.
- I can't do it.
- Of course you can.
- I'm gonna hurl again.
- OK, please don't,
'cause I just got the
last puke out of your hair.
Why do I have to do this?
I'm not a public speaker.
It's not my thing. I
hate Derek Shepherd.
All you have to do is talk
about being a great surgeon.
To a giant room full of
people. From a giant stage.
Oh, God, with a microphone.
Some make it through, they
come out on the other side.
They survive with
their sanity intact.
They become better
doctors and stronger people.
I didn't.
I broke.
I didn't kill anybody... and I
give thanks for that every day.
But I hurt people.
And scared the
hell out of myself.
I'm 45 days sober today.
I am Richard,
and I am a grateful
and recovering alcoholic.
I was told, if I went to rehab,
my job would be waiting for me.
Pending board approval.
I'm sorry, Richard.
You know what? Maybe
they'll reassess in a few months.
I'm authorized to offer you a position
as an attending general surgeon.
- You want me
to come work under you?
- Yes. That's the stipulation.
Thank you for the offer, but
no. I'll figure something else out.
Richard. It's lecture day,
and I have an open spot.
Lecture day? You
brought that back?
I understand if you
don't want to come back.
But if you're really leaving this
place, don't leave the way you did.
Give one last lecture.
Good morning.
Good morning, everybody.
Good morning. I'm excited.
Are you excited?
This is a teaching hospital.
We learn a lot by doing.
But we can also learn... we should also
learn from other people's experiences.
Their losses will save you losses.
Their mistakes will save you mistakes.
Their victories
will inspire yours.
Let's pay close attention.
This is gonna be good.
Dr. Miranda Bailey.
- Good morning, everyone.
- Morning.
- Ow!
- 'Morning, Dr. Yang.
What the...?
If I have to stand
here, you have to listen.
Eyes forward. Answer a
question right, you get a chocolate.
Doze off, you get beaned in the face.
Ask Dr. Yang. My aim is exceptional.
2003. I'm three days
into my intern year.
Anyone?
Alicia Tatum, status
post-oophorectomy three months ago
now presents with fever
and non-focal abdominal pain.
OK, what does her workup show?
Multiple stones
and wall thickening.
Excuse me?
Multiple gallbladder
stones and wall thickening.
Would you recommend we
do it open or laparoscopically?
- Laparascopically.
- Uh...
Who said that? Who said that?
Sir.
- You've had
a pretty rough go of it?
- Nothing helps the pain.
I've seen more
doctors than I can count.
Hopefully we'll
be the last. Eight.
We're gonna get to
the bottom of this, OK?
Let's prep her for surgery.
You.
- Uh... Mandy.
- Mandy? That's
what you're going with?
Boy, your parents wanted
you to work for it, huh?
Draw some blood and
take her for her pre-op X-ray.
- I was wondering...
- Blood draw is too much for you?
- No, I can draw blood,
I just wanted...
- You don't have wants or needs.
You're an intern, the bottom
of the surgical food chain.
I'm a resident. I've
been here three years,
you've been here three days.
Do the math. Draw her blood.
Is she shaking?
Hm?
She's definitely shaking.
- OK.
- - She's doing her pee dance.
She does it when she has to pee.
OK, well, is she
gonna pee right now?
Hm...
Oh, no, that's not the right...
OK.
Beautiful. Um...
In my third year as
a resident, I was...
Can't hear you!
In my third year as a resident,
I was presented with a patient
named Sunder...
Atluri, a 28-year-old grad...
student from India.
- Hey, I'm from ortho,
I was paged?
- You were paged by me.
Alex Karev, you have
to put me on this case.
Here's a news flash, overly enthusiastic
intern guy, I don't have to do anything.
- Come on, you seem
like a cool person.
- You don't know me.
You look like a cool
person. I need cool cases.
Ever since the elevator
thing and heart guy, it's just...
Wait, that was you?
You're the heart
in the elevator guy?
Sure, let's go with that.
You're not at all
how I pictured you.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- I heard the story.
The heart in the elevator. It
was basically Rudy, you know?
Dorky guy makes good. But
you're not dorky. You're hot.
Maybe I was dorky before I
saved the cop in the elevator.
Maybe my unbelievable skill under
pressure transformed me completely.
- Hm. Did it?
- Does that turn you on?
No, but this does.
Um...
Good... good morning.
Once upon a time...
long before I was
chief of surgery...
even before I was an attending,
I was a resident, right
here at Seattle Grace.
Just like you.
You learn from everything
in your residency.
The patients, the
nurses, the attendings.
But you don't realize how
much you learn from each other.
1982. You all were in diapers.
- Give me the chart on 2314.
- - Yes, doctor.
So, Dr. Russell, I hear
you shot a 74 last week.
You should come to my
club when you have a day off.
I used to play there with your
father. We'll see if you measure up.
- Oh, I'd love to, sir.
- Do we get any path back yet?
Nothing's grown
out of the cultures.
I checked them this morning,
sir. I went to the lab myself.
- So, Dr. Russell,
is he still febrile?
- Where is it?!
Where's that damn crash cart?!
I was checking his wound when he
went into SVT with respiratory distress.
I can cardiovert him out of
it. Charge the paddles to 100.
Charge paddles?
What's going on here?
He's here for a hernia surgery!
- What's happening?
- This is no job for a nurse.
- I'll take it from here.
- You know I'm not a nurse. Back off.
Clear!
Dr. Ellis Grey.
Two-time-Harper-Avery-Award-winner
and my colleague on this case.
A case that changed my life.
Look around.
The biggest influences in your
life are sitting next to you right now.
- This is gonna
get more interesting.
- Yeah.
The late Dr. Ellis Grey was
known as a groundbreaker...
a lion.
She was the best this hospital
or most hospitals have ever seen.
But back then, she
was known as "sugar"...
or "nurse"...
or nothing at all.
This man came in for a simple
hernia repair, and he's getting sicker
instead of better. You people
better figure out why, and fast.
- Guess it's just
you and me, kid.
- Surprise, surprise.
Oh, crap!
Come on. Oh, come on.
- Come on.
- Oh!
- Come on, come on, come on.
- Just talk!
- Hm?
- Just tell us what happened.
OK.
There was, uh, this patient.
He wanted to get
his club foot fixed.
But I had a different idea.
You told him he could walk?
Yes. I was in the Peace Corps! I've
seen polio, I've studied the procedures.
- You're privileged.
- Sir?
Your application, I remember it.
I'm saying you grew up privileged
and that privilege made you arrogant.
And arrogance in an unseasoned
surgeon is a very dangerous thing.
Sir, I didn't make this
promise lightly. I can do this.
Did you promise him you'll try,
or did you promise him he'll walk?
Arrogant.
All right, Dr. Torres.
You'll live and die on this.
This is your career
at Seattle Grace.
He's such an ass!
Dr. Gracie didn't like your
infectious process idea,
but I think that's what
it's got to be, right?
Gracie wouldn't know
his ass from his finger.
Is "ass" the word of the day?
There was mild
hemolysis on his CBC.
Anemia? Rhabdo? Was
there any hematuria?
No, but there was
some yeast in his urine.
A contaminant. Maybe the
hemolysis was just a bad blood draw?
Every day?
That doesn't seem right.
This hemolysis
thing is a red herring.
I feel it in my bones that we're
going down the wrong road.
You're right. I feel
it in my bones too.
Get your mind out of the gutter.
How can I do that when
I'm tearing your clothes off?
Think of the possibilities for
post-op fever: wind, wound, water.
Water! The yeast.
I think I got it!
Single most important step
in the treatment process.
- Anyone?
- Physical exam.
- No. No chocolate for you.
- Lab and radiology evaluation.
Oh! Come on, people, now
you're embarrassing me.
- Patient history.
- Thank you! Catch!
There isn't much inflammation,
but there are a lot of gallstones.
Dr. Baylow, what
causes gallstones?
- High fat diets
are a huge contributor.
- Yes, fatty foods and...?
She's vegan.
- Who's talking?
- I'm sorry, sir.
- Keep it down or get out of the OR.
- - She's vegan.
- She is?
- Yeah.
She has had severe reflux most
of her life until she discovered,
when she was 15, that
a vegan diet helped.
Her ex-boyfriend,
who broke up with her
after her last surgery,
was a vegan chef.
Well, that's quite a history
you have there, doctor.
Dr. Baylow, your intern
is doing a hell of a job.
Uh...
Listen, you little moppet,
you hang me out to dry like that
in front of the chief
again, I will end you.
Your career, your future, your
life. Do we understand each other?
If it were up to me, you'd be
doing scut until your hair turns grey.
Oh, wait a minute.
It is up to me!
We're not allowed to beat you with
sticks, so we punish you with scut.
We do it today, and
they did it back in my day.
- Dr. Grey
and I did mountains of scut.
- Mm-hm.
Testing tissue samples was
boring, but it's how we found out
our patient had a fungus
called cryptococcus.
Have you traveled recently
to a tropical country?
Like Taiwan? Or Argentina?
No. I've never even
been out of this country.
Do you live near a bird aviary?
Or are you around a lot of pigeons?
- No.
- What kind
of questions are these?
We asked his
girlfriend to step out...
because we knew we were gonna have to
ask some pretty uncomfortable questions.
We suspected he might have GRID.
Does anyone know what GRID is?
- AIDS.
- That's right.
- But in 1982 it was known as...
- Gay-related
immune deficiency?!
You think I have sex with
men? Are you out of your minds?
What kind of doctors are you?
- You're sick!
- Sir, just calm down.
We're not passing any judgment.
They're standard questions.
- Get this thing out of my arm!
- Sir, get back into bed.
- You still need the antibiotics -
I'll get the antibiotics elsewhere.
From real doctors. I did
not come here to be insulted.
And don't think I won't talk
to your superiors about this.
This was early 1982.
We hadn't seen a case
in Washington State. Ever.
San Francisco
only had five cases.
We didn't know what it was, and because
it was isolated to the gay community,
the government
wasn't funding research.
Does anyone know when the HIV
retrovirus was finally discovered?
Uh, 1983, but there
wasn't a test for it until '85.
That's right. It was so new even our
attending didn't know how to handle it.
GRID? You accused a patient
in my hospital of having a disease
that hasn't even been proven
to exist. What were you thinking?
That patient wasn't even a gay!
He's threatening to sue
us for slander. Good job.
You're on probation.
Both of you.
Patient's getting harder to
ventilate. Did you hear me?
- I heard you! Shush.
- Did you shush me? Don't shush me.
- You need to start to wrap up.
- Wrap up? I just got started!
We've been working
for eight hours.
I'm trying to be meticulous,
make sure I'm getting good
compression. I think it's gonna work.
- I'm pretty sure.
- "Pretty sure?"
He's got pericarditis
and lung disease.
He's getting unstable.
Dude. Do you want him to walk, or
do you want him to keep breathing?
Successes or failures,
which teaches you more?
Failures!
Yeah, but that was a
gimme, don't get too cocky.
The patient was discharged, and a
month later she was back in the ER
in the middle of the night.
Right lower quadrant pain,
fever, vomiting...
Symptoms consistent with...?
Appendicitis!
You get a chocolate 'cause that's
what I thought, but don't eat it yet.
Pay attention.
I diagnosed Alicia
with appendicitis,
and Dr. Webber decided that appy
was going to be my first solo surgery.
Mobilize the cecum.
There you go.
- Not bad, Dr. Bailey.
- Thank you, sir.
I'm glad you decided to
come to Seattle Grace.
You were a strong applicant.
People are excited to have you here.
Surgery's a shark
tank. Sharks have teeth.
Make sure you're a shark
too. And not a minnow.
Sir, are you referring
to my height?
No, I'm not. God made you short.
Who made you quiet?
Um...
That, unfortunately, is a
perfectly healthy appendix.
- What?
- No infection. No inflammation.
The whole lower right
quadrant looks good.
- Sir, I'm... I'm so sorry.
- Shake it off, shake it off.
If you never get a negative appy,
you're not doing enough appys.
That's just part of the process.
All right. Let's take it out,
and we'll get ready to close.
I didn't want to
close, but we had to.
So...
We took the patient
to surgery again and...
Wait, no...
Hang on.
You were there. Help her.
That's when we saw the
dude do the thing with his foot.
You know.
The surgery was more
difficult than I anticipated.
I was able to do the tendon
release, but your lungs and heart
weren't able to withstand any
more time under anesthesia,
so I couldn't do
any more than that.
I understand. When
do we start again?
Sunder, I'm saying I...
I think we don't.
Well...
Now, I don't understand.
Look at this. Look at my foot.
Watch it.
You did that for me.
Since I was seven, I have
never been able to do that.
I've always been different.
I've always been stared at.
I want to walk.
I want to stand straight up.
I believe you can do the rest.
Please.
Please try.
No surgeon likes
giving up on a patient.
Dr. Grey and I liked
it even less than most.
But when a patient refuses
treatment, you're done.
I mean, we were done.
That's what we thought, anyhow.
I put in the NG tube, doctor.
OK.
Dr. Grey. Looking
beautiful as usual.
Flattery will get you to an on-call
room in five minutes or less.
- You're on.
- Mommy! Mommy, look!
That's supposed to
be for her birthday.
She was crying. She misses you.
And I got desperate.
- Richard.
- Thatcher. How are you?
I only have a few
seconds. Show me your doll.
Dr. Grey, Dr. Webber,
stat to Emergency.
- I gotta go, Thatch.
- Mommy, don't go!
Take her. Thatcher,
I have to go!
- Meredith.
- Mommy, no!
Mommy? Don't go.
Dr. Grey, Dr. Webber,
stat to the ER.
Kaposi's sarcoma.
Your GRID patient
from a few months back.
Handle it!
I'm sorry I... You were right,
you were right about everything.
Please.
Help me.
A healthy appendix.
The third surgery for this patient
with unrelenting abdominal pain,
fatigue and muscle
pain. Now what?
Test for zebras,
uncommon diseases.
- OK.
- Do an ANA for lupus.
- Lupus, yeah.
- What about lead? You test for lead?
Good, good. See,
sometimes it's not easy.
Sometimes you have to be your patient's
advocate and push to get things done.
Excuse me, uh, Dr. Baylow,
Alicia Tatum is being discharged with
nothing but a note for a psych consult?
She's sniffing around for
pain meds. She's depressed.
Well, yeah, months of severe
untreated pain can be... depressing.
- OK, smarty pants.
- I just thought maybe
we could test for lupus or lead
poisoning or even hemochromatosis...
We're not ordering
thousands of dollars in tests
for something that could be
cured with a big dose of Prozac.
- But...
- What are we doing with Alicia Tatum?
Turfing her to
psych for depression.
Cut her open three times and didn't
cure her pain. Wouldn't you be depressed?
Of course. Before she goes I
thought we could test for lupus
or lead poisoning or
maybe hemochromatosis.
Hemochromatosis?
Now you're thinking.
Good work.
Oh, my God, I think
that's an intussusception.
I've never seen one
before in an adult.
Well, I suppose we'd handle it
the same way as with a kid, right?
Dr. Gracie? What would
you do in this situation?
Quite frankly, nothing.
I wouldn't operate.
This patient's a lost
cause. He's got GRID.
It's called AIDS now.
AIDS. No one knows what's
causing it or how it spreads.
You want me to risk the health
of my staff, my own life, for a guy
with a death sentence?
No. I'm not doing it.
I recommend you
don't do it either.
We took an oath. We're
supposed to be healers.
Ten years ago you wouldn't even
have been allowed in this program.
Don't you dare tell me
what kind of oath we take.
We'd hit a wall.
And, um...
We planned a
number of procedures.
But, um, uh, then...
Then I gave you
that rousing pep talk.
You know what? He totally did.
What if I had quit in the
elevator? What if I had frozen?
I had every reason
to freeze, I'm an intern.
I never had my hand
in a heart before.
No reason for me to think
I'm not gonna do anything
but kill that cop faster.
- But you didn't.
- No. I didn't.
I cut him open, I cross clamped
the aorta, stuck my finger in the hole
and I stopped the bleeding.
It was seamless. I was perfect.
So pretend there's a blackout,
you're stuck in an elevator,
and your guy's bleeding out. What are
you gonna do? Are you gonna just quit?
What was the result? Did she
test positive for hemochromatosis?
- Nope.
- What about Lyme disease?
Lyme disease, negative.
Celiac disease, negative.
Every test I could
think of, negative.
So I did what I've told you
all to do when you get stuck.
I went to the library,
and I hit the books.
I hit 'em hard.
I was raised to be
polite, you know.
Don't raise your voice.
Have respect for people
higher on the pecking order,
be generous to those below...
I was not raised to be a shark!
Does that make me a
minnow? Am I a minnow?
- I really don't know.
- I'm a minnow.
And not because of my height.
Because I'm a minnow on the inside.
This is a sad
state of affairs, Joe.
Hell, we weren't noble.
We were just more
arrogant than the rest.
And had more to prove.
Your CT showed that your
bowel has twisted in on itself,
probably because of Kaposi's
lesions in your abdomen.
It's a pretty rare problem but
we can take care of it with surgery.
Will Dr. Gracie be
doing the surgery?
I'm afraid you're stuck with us.
He's scared, isn't he?
Just like them, outside.
I can see them...
pointing, mumbling, staring.
Screw them.
I don't blame them...
for being scared.
I'm scared too.
I used to be scared that people
would find out that I was gay, and...
Now I can't even
hide it anymore.
I'm a leper...
an outcast, an untouchable.
No one will look at me.
No... No one will touch me.
And I want to hate everyone
for treating me this way.
But how... how can I hate them
for being scared when I'm
the one that's been living a lie?
This is your chance to
change that. Have this surgery.
- Let us operate.
- What's the point?
No one recovers from this.
- No one lives.
- For all you know,
there could be a cure for this
thing tomorrow, or next week.
Let us operate.
We spent days trying to make
things right, trying to figure out
the best strategy.
So we researched.
And, uh, practiced
and practiced and...
eventually, we were ready.
- Retract the rectus femoris.
- - What about the nerve?
BP just dropped, and he's
tachycardic! Torsades on the monitor!
Oh, my God.
Pericardial tamponade?
Sounds like.
Damn it. OK, nobody
panic. Page cardio.
Alex, we need to do a
subxiphoid pericardiotomy
to drain the blood
squeezing the heart.
It's a version of what
you did in the elevator.
- So get a scalpel...
- I can't.
What do you mean, you can't?
You already did. Take the scalpel.
- I can't.
- The patient is crashing, Karev!
- Do the elevator thing!
- I can't! I've never done this!
It wasn't me! I'm not the heart in
the elevator guy! It was O'Malley!
OK.
No. This is fine. We're fine.
- And you. You're doing this.
- But I haven't...
Because you haven't doesn't
mean you can't. Take the scalpel!
OK. Uh...
Make a six-centimeter-long
incision...
over the xiphisternal junction.
Good.
We knew what we
were doing was risky.
These days, we know
that AIDS transmission
requires the exchanges of bodily
fluids. But back then, we had no idea.
Can you get it get it from casual
contact? From the air? From surgery?
No idea.
Poor guy, living
a lie for so long.
Yeah. Shame.
We're living a lie too.
- What?
- We shouldn't be doing
- what we're doing. We have to stop.
- No.
We're not the lie. Our
marriages are the lie.
This, us... this
is what's right.
We should leave them, Richard.
You leave Adele and I'll leave Thatcher.
I can't. You have
a daughter. I can't.
And neither can you.
You don't have to go in
there, I can do this alone.
You have Meredith
to think about.
You're just like
the rest of them.
You have a different skin
color, but you're just like them.
- Ellis...
- I gave birth
to a child, Richard.
That makes me a mother,
it doesn't make me inept,
it doesn't make me less of a woman,
it doesn't make me less of a surgeon.
No matter how much
everyone wants it to.
All my research didn't help.
Dr. Baylow sent the patient home.
So I thought she'd won. I thought
maybe I wasn't cut out for this game.
But a couple months later...
Alicia?
- Thank God, a familiar face.
- What happened?
The pain got really bad.
They said maybe I have
some sort of obstruction
or something from the other
surgeries. They want to go back in
and take another look.
Mandy, I don't think
I can take it anymore.
Please tell me this
surgery's gonna help.
They're gonna find
something, right?
Oh! Don't touch her!
I know you're here to
take her to the OR but...
Don't touch her.
So you canceled your resident's
surgery. Isn't that a little bold?
She was worried about
adhesions, right? Gimme candy!
No adhesions. No candy.
And it wasn't bold,
Grey, it was stupid.
But in this case, it
was also necessary.
Where do you get off
canceling my surgery?
- When I...
- You work for me, got that?
You listen to what I have
to say. Are you at all familiar
with what surgeons
do, Dr. Bailey? We cut.
Yeah, rebook Ms.
Tatum for surgery.
Dr. Baylow, you wanted to go
in and explore her obstruction?
She doesn't have
any signs of adhesions!
Just because she's
had previous surgeries
doesn't mean you shouldn't
actually look for another cause.
She has a pseudo-obstruction
that can be resolved with an NG tube.
And if you'd looked further and, I
don't know, talked to your patient,
you would have discovered
that, along with abdominal pain,
she also had weakness,
palpitations, numbness, skin changes,
and her urine is intermittently
dark. Ringing any bells yet?
Your patient, who's been
sliced nine ways to Sunday,
has porphyria. If you
had diagnosed it earlier,
she could have avoided
getting her ovaries taken out.
And her gallbladder. And yes,
yes, I took out her appendix.
I, too, am at fault for not
looking at the whole person.
But you know the difference between
you and me? I learned something from it.
I learned when not to cut. I
learned to listen to my patient.
How could you have
not learned in three years
- what it took me
three months to learn?
- Dr. Bailey.
And the reason I had her chart
was because you ignored my pages
and she needs to get
started on hemin right away.
You put it in her IV. You
give it daily for four days...
- Dr. Bailey...
- The patient gets better.
The patient doesn't get prodded,
probed, scoped or cut open
- like a Thanksgiving turkey,
you supercilious fool!
- Dr. Bailey!
My office. Now!
We did a series of shorter
surgeries so his lungs and heart
could withstand the anesthesia.
It was grueling for the patient
- but worth it in the end.
- Show them the X-rays.
Oh, yeah, so cool.
OK. Um...
These are the before.
And these are the after.
Wow, yeah.
Yeah, it was... It was amazing.
I mean, after the final
surgery, we were just...
We celebrated that night.
Man, did we ever celebrate.
- Mm! Wait, cone of silence.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. Whatever.
I knew I was in big trouble.
It is my job to make
sure that my residents
are supported and
treated with respect.
Of course, and I am so sorry...
You have said
enough for one day.
- Sorry.
- It's my job.
So we're gonna sit here with you
wearing that terrified look on your face
for a respectable amount of
time, so Dr. Baylow and her friends
can assume you've had your
behind handed to you on a platter.
You're gonna make a hell
of a surgeon, Dr. Bailey.
Lose the smile.
The patient survived the
surgery, but eight months later
he came back with PCP pneumonia.
He died a week later.
Dr. Grey and I, well...
Well, um, I won't speak for her.
But I lost the sense
that I was a superhero.
And I really started to think
of how dangerous it all was.
It changes you. This work.
Your patients. Your colleagues.
You change each other.
You don't ever think
you'll lose your way...
but what happens
in this hospital...
just remember why you came here.
You said it the day you
graduated from med school.
You took the physician's oath.
Remember it.
Tape it to your locker.
To your bathroom mirror.
'Cause it is too easy
to lose your way.
I solemnly pledge to consecrate
my life to the service of humanity.
I will give to my teachers...
the respect and
gratitude that is their due.
I will practice my profession...
with conscience and dignity.
The health of my patients will
be my number one consideration.
I will respect the secrets
that are confided in me...
even after my patient has died.
I will maintain by all
the means in my power...
the honor and the noble
traditions of the medical profession.
My colleagues will be
my sisters and brothers.
I will not permit
considerations of age,
disease or disability, creed...
Ethnic origin, gender...
race, political affiliation...
nationality, sexual
orientation...
social standing...
or any other factor to
intervene between my duty...
and my patient.
I will maintain the utmost
respect for human life.
I will not use my medical
knowledge to violate human rights
and civil liberties...
even under threat.
I make these promises
solemnly, freely...
and upon my honor.
The job offer still stands.
Think about it...
and let me know.
We'll see.
To Philip.
May he rest in peace.
You can't toast a dead Irishman
with a soda pop, Richard.
- Get this man a vodka, Frankie.
- Oh, yeah. Coming right up.
You know I can't stand
the taste of that stuff.
It's time to learn.
You're a grown-up,
Richard. It's time to act like it.
I can't leave her, Ellis.
I can't.
We'll see.