♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
This music, it's so...
Is that a review
or a contraction?
Both.
It's resonance therapy.
Combined with acupuncture,
it's gonna get those
contractions under control
and make you feel
more comfortable.
Well, it's a good thing Matthew
couldn't make it today...
Because he would hate this.
It's soothing.
Okay.
You know, when Dr. Bennett
did the I.V.F.,
she let us bring in
our own c.D.
What'd you put on?
Well, the first time we just
picked all these songs
that we used to love
in high school.
And then...
The second time
we used this muzak that was
supposed to relax me,
but just made me feel
like I was having
a gynecological appointment
in an elevator.
And then the third time,
we just picked every song
that we could think of with
the word "luck" in the title.
And it worked.
Ah.
You okay?
Don't worry.
It's just--it's been like this
the past couple of mornings.
I think baby Langston does not
like breakfast burritos.
Okay. You start your torture,
and I'll just run a tune--ah!
Ah! Ooh.
Okay, hang on.
Send Naomi in, please.
Sorry. It's not usually
this bad.
Mm.
Okay,
focus on your breathing.
Ooh.
Slow and deep.
Shira, what's wrong?
Strengthening contractions,
a minute apart.
Oh!
Oh, this could be real labor.
At 25 weeks?
Can you make it stop?
Well, we can,
but we're gonna have to
get you to the hospital.
I'm all wet.
I think my water just broke.
It's blood.
Thanks.
Hey.
I was
just thinking about you.
Oh, yeah?
I'm trying to figure out
what to wear to Maya's wedding.
Oh.
Uh... whatever.
Sam, women don't do well
with "whatever."
Well,
what are you gonna wear?
What?
Uh, I have a million things
to do to get ready,
and picking out a tie is not
high up on the list.
What is high on the list?
I have to write a toast.
Oh, I'm good at toasts.
Yeah, I know. I know that.
I-I knocked on your door
last night,
hoping that you could help...
But I-I wasn't home.
Yeah.
Look, you, uh, you don't
want this to be weird.
And--and I'm trying
to make this not weird.
But, uh, you weren't--
you weren't home.
Yeah. I was... out.
Look, Sam,
I'm just gonna say this,
and hopefully,
you're gonna understand,
and it won't be weird
and...
I'm seeing someone.
Addison.
There's an ambulance downstairs.
We need you.
It's an emergency.
It's a placental abruption.
This much blood, the placenta
could be completely detached.
It's gonna be hard
to control the hemorrhage
and get that baby out
fast enough.
Oh, no, please.
He's not ready yet.
We're gonna do everything we can
to keep the baby inside.
Do you have any terbutaline?
I don't know if we do.
The book says that he's
the size of a cucumber.
There's no terbutaline,
no magnesium sulfate.
Can she make it?
I can already feel
the baby's head.
No, no, please.
This baby's coming now.
No!
We're gonna get you into surgery
and get your bleeding stopped.
Your husband's on his way.
The baby?
Dr. Montgomery's with him.
He was so small.
Will he be okay?
She's gonna do everything
she can for him.
But will he be okay?
I didn't feel... anything
'cause the doctor...
And I was counting...
They didn't Nick his brain
or anything, right?
You know, they go in
through the groin
for a hernia repair,
so I doubt it.
I just think ike has a little
bit of an anesthesia hangover.
Dr. Scott.
Hey. I'm so sorry, buddy.
They made me scrub in
on another surgery
right after yours.
Wasn't nearly as cool,
though.
So everything went okay here?
Yeah, absolutely.
I sutured in a mesh patch.
Gonna last him a lifetime.
Great. So how long is he
gonna be kinda...
Oh, he'll be himself
in an hour or so.
I am myself.
Listen, just let him,
uh, rest a while.
I'll swing by and check him.
You're gonna be outta here
before dinner.
Thank you.
Take care.
Oh, man, I'll tell you.
I jacked up my back.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Yeah, I was playing that,
uh, computer tennis game.
I realize
it's a goofy injury.
But, you know,
the last few days
I've been, uh, eating
fistfuls of ibuprofen
just so I can stand up
in the O.R.
Actually, man,
would you mind, uh,
writing me a prescription
for a couple of oxy?
Oxy a little heavy
for a gaming injury?
Ah, it's just two or three,
just to get me through
today and tomorrow.
Then I'm gonna take
the weekend off and rest up.
Hey, listen, if--if--ow.
If it's a big deal,
don't worry about it.
I'll suck it up.
Hey.
You want
to grab lunch later,
away from here?
I can do that.
Oh, hey. You know--
you know Charlotte king,
don't you?
Yeah.
Oh, is he the doc that--
yeah.
Oh, I see.
I hope this isn't
gonna be a thing.
It's not a thing.
Okay. Great.
I'll call you later.
Mm.
Problem with this?
Not a thing.
You don't rsvp two days
before a wedding.
I'm sorry. My friends
have never done this.
You better watch that tone,
young--
all right. We're gonna
talk about this later.
I don't even care
if they come.
If it's gonna be
this big a deal--
enough about the wedding.
Well, if you're done,
she has an appointment.
You okay?
He looks like his head
is about to pop off.
Don't tell anybody,
but around here,
it always looks like your dad's
head's about to pop off.
I guess I should be happy
he's coming at all.
I'm sorry about your mom.
She's making me feel like
I'm doing something wrong.
Did you try
talking to her again?
Well, you know, I-I know
how hard this is.
I mean, I remember.
You know, Heather and her mom,
they never got past it.
But with your mom...
I think you should try again.
I don't think
my dad would like it.
He's mad at her.
Well, it's your wedding, Maya.
Does he really need
all of that?
He weighs less than 2 pounds,
so we need to keep him
under the lights to regulate
his body temperature.
We're also trying to correct
a pretty serious
electrolyte imbalance
that's causing convulsions
and exacerbating
a cerebral hemorrhage.
His brain is bleeding?
How can he have
so many problems?
25 weeks is just the cusp
of viability.
Addison, his abdomen
is distended.
Yeah, we did an X-ray.
He has
necrotizing enterocolitis.
I-I don't know
what that is.
It means that
not enough blood is getting
to his digestive tract.
His intestines are dying.
Is that something
you can fix?
He'd need surgery
to try to resect his bowel
and save some of the intestines.
Matthew.
So this surgery...
Can we do it now?
Uh, that's up to
Dr. Montgomery.
You need to understand
that it wouldn't be
just one surgery.
There would be a whole series
of surgeries.
And in between, he would need
to eat through a feeding tube
and breathe with the help
of a ventilator.
He'd be suffering.
And even if we did manage
to keep him alive,
it's unlikely that we could give
him any kind of normal life.
You need to consider if... this
is something that you want.
What's our alternative?
Ending his life?
Yes.
That's not a life--
shuttling back and forth
between the O.R. and nicu,
being kept alive by machines,
his system
overloaded with drugs.
He's their child,
and none of us can say
we know what's gonna happen.
Odds are you're right.
I am right.
There have been cases where
severe enterocolitis resolves.
So you're on the side
of miracles now?
I understand why they are,
and I'm not gonna
fault them for it.
I am not faulting them,
but...
That baby is suffering.
He's only
a couple of hours old,
and you can already see it
in his face.
You can hear it in his cries.
He's in pain.
Letting go is not giving up.
It would be them
putting the baby's best
interests ahead of their own.
Naomi?
You know, kids don't come
with guarantees.
They come with problems.
These problems
can't be solved.
A lot of problems
You just... you learn
to live with it.
No one should have to live
with this.
No, we're not gonna tell
the coles what to do.
They have to decide
what they can live with.
But I'd have to do
the surgery,
so I need to decide
what I can live with.
Corinne... hey, what are you--
what are you doing here?
Oh, I told Maya I'd pick
her up. She came in to do--
a prenatal appointment.
Yeah, I know.
I'm taking
my daughter-in-law-to-be
on a mini spa day--
massage, facials,
and then a test run
for her makeup and hair.
Uh, i--
I'm just trying to
make this special for Maya.
I think the wedding
will be special enough.
Well, if we just go through
the motions,
do you really think
it will be?
I-I know this isn't what
you or Naomi wanted.
It's--it's not
what I wanted, either,
but it's
what's going to happen.
So I've made peace with it
as best I can,
and now I feel
we should make this
as positive an experience
as we can for the kids.
So is Maya here?
It's not a thing,
but the guy's a surgeon.
Who's dating Charlotte.
That has nothing to do
with the fact
that he hit me up
for a prescription.
He barely knows me,
and he's asking me for narcotics
that would slow him down,
impair his judgment.
Well, look, look, look.
I am on antidepressants.
Sometimes it makes it hard
to focus, which is not ideal
when I'm in therapy.
Sam's on allergy meds.
When he ups his dose,
it knocks him out.
You just have to hope that
someone's gonna be responsible.
Do--do you have any reason to
think that Scott wouldn't be?
Nothing concrete,
but when he saw
that I was uncomfortable,
he backed off fast,
and it felt practiced.
Well, he--I've heard
he's a good surgeon.
He seems like a good guy.
What, you've met him?
Oh, she had him to the house,
didn't she?
My god, she gives it up fast.
Cooper, y--
- what, what, am I wrong?
- He has not actually been to the house.
He's just...
Picked her up there.
But I don't think
that they're--
yeah, well, you're just
saying that to be nice.
But she is bringing him
to Maya's wedding.
He's her plus one.
I have the list.
I have all the lists--
caterers, deejays, florists.
I am knee-deep in wedding,
and the sad part is, I have
never had one of my own.
That is sad, but back to me.
No one told me that plus one
was an option.
Cooper, the wedding
is in two days.
If you are thinking of
scaring up some random hoochie--
oh, no, I'm thinking about
inviting jordana Sampson.
Is she back in town?
Mm-hmm.
Cooper, no.
She's not random
and she's not a hoochie.
I know, but she's--
exactly.
You didn't take that
personally, did you?
Is there a reason I should?
No, no.
Then I won't.
Me either.
It's
a professional disagreement.
Yes.
So... are you
still good with...
Yes. I think so.
I don't know.
I told Sam this morning
that I was seeing someone.
I thought we weren't gonna--
no, we're not. It's just--
he came to my house last night.
I wasn't home.
I didn't want to lie to him.
You didn't tell him
it was me?
No, no.
You haven't told anyone,
have you, like Violet?
I... I wouldn't even know
what to say.
Because... this...
Mm-hmm.
With us...
We're just...
Just getting through
what we're getting through.
Mm-hmm. We're just
helping each other...
Mm.
Helping each other feel good.
Really... really good.
Want to see
if that door locks?
Maya.
What are you doing here?
I want you
to come to my wedding.
Even though you're not proud
of me, I know you love me.
Of course I love you.
Do you think it would be better
if I didn't get married?
Yes.
I-I... I don't know.
It wouldn't.
I'm just trying to do
the right thing, but I need you.
You needed me
long before this,
but somehow, even though
I tried, I wasn't there for you.
And so for me to sit down
in front of god
and everyone we know
for a formal, public reminder
of how badly I screwed up
your life, i--
that's not
what my wedding is.
That's what
it would be to me.
The whole time we were
trying to get pregnant,
Matthew kept telling me to
visualize what it would be like
when we were in the hospital,
when we were finally a family.
Yeah.
After a while,
I-I wanted to stop.
It's just too hard,
you know?
And it just felt like
it was never gonna happen.
But Matthew...
He kept promising it would.
He called the baby
"our dream deferred."
Oh, like the poem.
Langston Hughes.
Yeah.
We're English teachers.
Can i--can I hold him now?
Oh, we can't--
we can't take him out.
Even for a minute?
I'm sorry.
So how soon
can we do this surgery?
I told Matthew,
at the rate the baby's bowel
function is deteriorating,
you'd have to do
the operation today, right?
It's what they want
for their child,
and I told them, if anybody
can help them here, it's you.
Dr. Montgomery...
Please.
I'll book an O.R.
He was supposed to discharge ike
almost two hours ago.
We kept paging him.
I'm really sorry.
I said Dr. Scott
was probably busy
sewing someone's brains
back in.
Well, there might have been
an emergency
where he was sewing
somebody's something back in.
Still--
no, i--he should not have left
you hanging. I'm really sorry.
All right.
You're all set to go.
I hope that follow-up
is the only thing
that he's careless about.
I heard there was
a problem with your patient.
No. Actually, there's
a problem with your boyfriend.
He asked me for oxy
this morning, now he's M.I.A.
And you're assuming what?
He has a bad back.
Well, as his girlfriend,
I'm sure
you're very sympathetic.
But as chief of staff
of the hospital where he works,
I think
you should be concerned
about how he's treating it...
If it's his back.
If you want to make
a formal complaint, do it.
That's what I thought.
Hey.
You working on the toast?
Trying.
Look, Sam,
about what I said--
we don't need to talk about it.
It's none of my business--
no, Sam--
Addison, please.
Not today, okay?
I-I c--i can barely
get through this.
What do you want to say?
I want to tell them stop,
you know,
and don't make this any worse.
I just tried
to give that speech.
A patient of Pete's
gave birth to a preemie--
25 weeks, just...
So many problems.
Best-case scenario,
it lives in the nicu
until I can't do
any more surgeries
or give it any more drugs.
Are you and Pete in sync?
You said
it was Pete's patient, right?
Right. It is.
But we're not in sync.
I am a-about to go remove
most of the baby's
intestinal tract
because the parents
are hoping for a miracle,
and Pete doesn't want
to take that away from them,
and I couldn't say no.
So I gotta clear my schedule
and head back to the hospital.
Well, I get that--doing things
you don't want to do.
I'm supposed to make
this big speech
that makes everybody
feel good about the wedding...
Pretend like everything's okay.
Sometimes
we have to pretend.
Eloping?
Oh. No, no. I'm just taking
the dress to get steamed.
It's--it's Maya's.
I figured.
Yeah. Well, you know,
it should be a pretty odd event.
You know, uh, Cooper's bringing
jordana Sampson.
She's back?
Oh, wow.
I know.
Y-You're not bringing
someone else are you,
a-a plus one?
Uh, because among other things,
I'm the rsvp girl,
so, um, I'm just,
uh, making sure.
Nope. Just me. You?
Same.
I'll see you there.
Hey. You were supposed to
discharge ike Holden.
I had to come over here
just so they could go home.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
It's my... my back.
It was killing me.
I-I laid down.
I guess I just went out.
Come on.
I know what you're thinking.
You think because I asked you
for a-a courtesy prescription,
what, you think now
i'm--I'm a drug addict
who crashed out here?
Tell me you haven't
taken anything.
I-I took one oxy.
I don't have
any other surgeries scheduled.
Oh, that's the line?
As long as you're not
cutting someone open,
anything short of that,
it's okay that you
show up here like this?
Listen, I'm really sorry
that it bothers you that i'm
seeing your ex-girlfriend.
It bothers me
that you couldn't do your job
right now and you're still here.
I have never had
a single problem,
in this hospital
or any other.
You want that to change?
Are you threatening me?
I think you should go talk
to my colleague--Violet Turner.
She has a lot of experience
treating people with addiction--
You want me to see a shrink?
Convince her you don't have
a problem, I will lay off.
And if I don't?
We will let
this hospital sort it out.
You know,
somehow I think Charlotte's
already decided about me.
Maybe, but I haven't.
How's it going?
Addison?
There are no clear margins.
The entire bowel
is involved?
There's nothing left
I can save.
Is there anything
you can do?
I can close him up.
But he survived
the surgery.
Yes, he survived, but--
then there must be
something you can do.
Your baby doesn't have
a functioning digestive system.
So before
I could do anything,
I'd have to put
a central line in
through his stomach
to feed him.
And how long would he
have to have that?
Permanently.
And although I was able
to stop the cerebral bleed,
we have to assume
that there is
at least
moderate brain damage.
But you don't know that
for sure.
No, I don't know that
But it's more than likely
the case.
Just like the longer
we keep him on a respirator,
the more likely it is
that he'll have retinal failure
or that he'll go blind.
I'm not saying
there aren't miracles,
but at a certain point,
it's not fair to the baby--
to Langston--
to keep waiting for them.
What are the odds?
I want to know the odds.
Of a baby like Langston
living outside the nicu?
Less than 1%.
But it could happen?
And it's our decision?
Uh, yeah, it is.
But he's in pain.
And with so little
to hope for, I'm sorry,
I'm not comfortable
performing another surgery.
Are there other doctors
that we can get to help us?
Yes, you could find someone else
to put in a central line.
Then that's
what we'll do.
Will you please help us?
I'm sorry.
I understand if you want
to go a different way,
but I can't.
So are the--
are the drugs something new?
"The drugs".
The drugs
are the occasional oxy
that I take
when my back flares up.
You know what? Here you go.
Take 'em, toss 'em,
eat 'em.
Do whatever.
That tell you
what you need to know?
Uh, well,
the fact that you are carrying
narcotics in your pocket
tells me that you may have
a more serious problem
than you're admitting.
It's funny how much you sound
like your buddy Cooper.
This has nothing to do
with him.
This has everything
to do with him.
He resents
my dating Charlotte.
He can't seriously
call into question my judgment
or my hand skills
or anything else that matters.
So he's trying to make me out
to be some kind of junkie,
and you're helping him.
I'm just asking questions,
trying to understand.
And I'm certainly
not forcing you to stay here.
No, Cooper is.
You're free to leave.
I do that, he makes an issue
of it with Charlotte.
Does that worry you,
Charlotte knowing about this?
I'm not an addict!
Why are you so angry?
I don't know.
Well, maybe we can
keep talking,
find out
if there's something there.
I'm a good doctor.
Which is why you should also
stop seeing patients
until we get a handle on this,
whatever it is.
And how do I explain that,
to Charlotte,
to the doctors who refer me,
the patients
I already have scheduled?
It will be easier than trying
to explain what happened
if you hurt someone.
I can help you
if you want me to.
Okay.
Hey.
I called you last night.
Oh, sorry.
No, no, no, I just was worried
about you after you walked out.
I'm okay.
Okay.
Well, for what it's worth,
I agree with you.
Enough is enough.
Yeah.
Addison--
No. No, no.
- What?
- Not in my office.
I was just trying
to be a friend.
Well, just, you know,
be a friend from there.
Will this help?
Hey, Sam,
you got a minute?
I wanted to talk to you
about the wedding.
Uh, talk to Violet.
No, no,
it's not a Violet thing.
Not now.
No, now, Sam.
Look, I-I get that this
is hard for you, okay?
But it doesn't change the fact
that Maya's
gonna get married tomorrow,
and you signed the paper
so that she could,
and now you're making her
feel like crap about it.
I will be there at the wedding.
I will walk her down the aisle.
Okay, but showing up
and acting like this?
I mean, it's no better
than what Naomi's doing.
And someone has to be there
for her, to be happy for her,
to--to support her, and if
it's not either of you--
I'm trying.
Try harder.
Oh, hey.
Where you going?
I am going to pick up
Maya and dink's wedding rings.
It's just another thing
that I can check off
this list of errands I never
thought I would do for anybody.
Hey, uh, before you go...
So should I be worried
about Scott or...
If I thought he was dangerous,
I would report him.
That's all I'm gonna say.
What?
Were you talking about me?
No.
You were talking about Scott.
Look, I am not gonna say
anything to either one of you.
And you shouldn't.
Unless of course you care
about the health and safety
of any of the patients
he might treat at the hospital
where he works,
cutting them open.
Which, roughly translated, means
"please, violate privilege
to give me some dirt
on my ex's new man."
I-I don't care
about you and him.
I do care that he's
probably smart enough not to
trigger Violet's duty to report,
which means he's gonna
have to hurt someone
before anyone
takes action here.
I'm--I'm not getting
in the middle of this.
You know who needs
therapy here? You.
Cooper Freedman.
Yeah, ike Holden
is my patient.
What happened?
And who's doing
the surgery?
Sam.
How's Maya doing?
How do you think
she's doing?
She's getting married
tomorrow,
and you're
not gonna be there.
Where are you gonna be?
I'm going to...
I'm going to napa...
With William.
Wow.
I don't expect you
to understand--
of course I understand.
You think I don't want
to do the same thing,
just run away
from all this?
But I can't, because someone
has to be the adult here.
And you left that to me.
I didn't mean for this
to be like this, Sam.
Just like
you're not gonna mean
for Maya to start going
to Corinne with her problems
or for Corinne to be
the one she wants around
when the baby comes,
and then in a little while
for Corinne to be the one
she starts seeing
as her family.
Because if you keep doing
what you're doing,
that's what's gonna happen.
So grow up. Do your job.
Be a mother.
Now what?
Tell me you are not
doing this surgery.
Ike has significant ischemia.
If I don't restore
the blood supply, he could die.
Now I don't know what he's
told you, but this happens
in a small percentage
of hernia repairs.
I didn't do anything wrong.
You don't have to explain
the medicine to me.
Just tell me if you've
taken anything today.
You're kidding.
You do realize
your ex-boyfriend has issues?
Tell me there's nothing
in your system.
No oxy, nothing.
I don't have time to play games
while a kid's on the table.
Stop.
Dr. Barker, I said stop.
I talked to Dr. Graham
at county,
who said he'd take over.
Do you think he's good?
♪ Ivan sits alone ♪
I trust
Dr. Montgomery's judgment.
♪ On the couch ♪
He's good.
Graham's good.
♪ Licking his paws away ♪
Hey.
Hi.
♪♪♪
Everything we wanted for him,
all the silly dreams
we used to talk about...
We were gonna expose him
to great books and art.
And he was gonna grow up
to be so cultured.
And one day people like us
were gonna teach kids about him.
♪ Running down the stairs ♪
♪ once again ♪
I know that's gone now.
♪♪♪
But that's not what matters.
What matters is...
He's ours.
And I just want him
to understand
that we're still here for him
and that we love him.
A child can feel
his mother's love.
He knows you love him.
No, he doesn't.
He can't, because I've
never even touched him.
Well, there is a way...
For you to hold him.
Don't say that.
Shira, I wouldn't, ever,
if I thought
there was any hope.
But at some point, you have to
know when to let go.
♪ Now the guests are gone ♪
Could you?
♪ Ivan dreams upon... ♪
Um...
I'd hope
that I had the strength
to do what my child needed,
no matter
what the cost to me.
♪ Dog stars ♪
♪ dog stars ♪
We should.
No. No.
There's a chance.
Look, I'm not letting go.
♪ ...stars ♪
♪ Dog stars ♪
Look at you. Fillmore's not
gonna know what hit him.
I--I'm gonna leave you to have
some time alone with your dad.
Check on the groom,
make sure he brushes his hair
and knows how to tie that tie.
I'll see you at the church.
It's going
to be wonderful, Maya.
I promise.
Whew.
I know this isn't
what you wanted,
but... please...
Be happy for me.
I am. I am.
Honestly?
Honestly, i'm--
I'm a little worried.
But if this is
what you want--
I do.
Okay, well, then you need
to know that I love you,
I will always be here,
and that I'm gonna help you
make sure that ultimately,
this is gonna be wonderful.
Okay?
Hey.
How's Scott?
Trying to get better.
Checked himself in
somewhere last night.
I hope he does. I do.
You want to say
I told you so.
But I won't.
Life's hard.
You shouldn't judge.
Everybody needs
some kind of a crutch.
So I don't wind up
sitting next to a 15-year-old
texting the whole time,
would you mind if I...
Don't be an ass, Cooper.
Make room for the girl.
Hi, I'm jordana Sampson.
Here.
I can't.
Sometimes when you
want something so badly...
And you get it...
Even if it's only
for a minute...
You don't want to let go.
I understand that.
It could change.
I mean, he could...
He could get better.
You're hurting him,
and your job as a parent
is to make sure
that nothing hurts him.
I love him.
Then let him go.
I thought...
I can't believe
mommy's really not coming.
I thought she'd be here.
I know.
I hoped she would.
Okay.
I think it's time to go.
Yeah.
Mom.
My mother gave this to me
on the day
that I married your dad.
So...
This is your, um,
your something old...
Borrowed and blue.
Thank you.
And for
your something new...
I bought it
for your 16th birthday.
I always wanted one
when I was a girl, so...
"M.b." Maya Bennett.
I hope
you'll keep the name...
And remember
where you came from.
Okay.
Now you're ready.
Tell me
she didn't destroy her life.
Tell me I didn't.
Oh, Nai. Look at her.
Maya may be
a lot of things right now,
but... she is not destroyed.
Have each of you chosen
to come here today
and declare before god
and his church
your decision to
become husband and wife?
I have.
And who give this woman
to be wedded to this man?
Her mother and I do.
♪ I've got beginner's luck ♪
♪ never was there
such a smile ♪
♪ such eyes of blue ♪
♪ I've got beginner's luck ♪
♪ lucky through and through ♪
♪ 'cause the first time
that I'm in love ♪
♪ I'm in love with you ♪
Hey.
Thanks.
It was what you deserve.
♪♪♪
Uh... you, uh,
you save me a dance, okay?
♪♪♪
I was not waiting
in that line at Sam's.
And Addison has much nicer
skin care products.
Your little friend spilled
bruschetta on my dress.
Oh, I'm sure
she didn't mean to.
Of course she did.
Yeah, you're probably right.
Why'd you bring her?
Why do you care? I mean,
apart from the tomatoes.
If you'll excuse me,
I have to take this dress off
and clean it.
Mm.
Uh, first off, I'd like to thank
everybody for coming.
I know I speak for Naomi
and Corinne
and Maya and dink
when I say that we feel
so very blessed
that you all came and shared
this special event with us.
Seeing Maya
in this wedding dress,
I'm struck by what a beautiful
and elegant young woman
she has grown up to become.
And I know
that moving forward,
this image of her
will stay with me,
the same
as another image of Maya
in a different
pretty white dress
has stayed with me as well.
The dress I'm talking about
was white,
but it had red and blue
abc's all across the front.
I, uh, I remember,
I came home one evening
after a-a marathon
of kids' parties and whatnot,
and little miss Maya
was not quite ready
to take her little dress off
and get in the bath.
So we went to her room
and hung out on her floor,
started talking.
And out of nowhere, she told me
that when she grew up,
she wanted to marry me.
So, uh, I said, "why?"
I asked her, I said, "why me?"
And she looked up at me,
and she said, "because, daddy,
you are my anyway friend."
Now at the time,
I didn't know what that meant.
So Maya had to explain to me
that an anyway friend
is the one person in your life
who, no matter what
they say or do,
no matter what they've
been through with you,
they love you anyway.
So my sincerest hope
is that for Maya, dink,
and for dink, Maya,
is that anyway friend.
Because no matter
how old you are
or what your responsibilities,
if you have love...
Real, unconditional love...
I think you can make it.
So... to my anyway friend
and her anyway friend.
May you not only make it...
But enjoy it.
♪ for I've got ♪
♪ beginner's luck ♪
♪ the first time
that I'm in love ♪
♪ I'm in love with you ♪
Thank you.
Hungry?
Oh. Well, I'm just seeing
how good everything is.
It is my food...
My flowers...
The place... the music.
This is my wedding.
♪ ...beginner's luck ♪
♪ there never
was such a smile ♪
♪ or such eyes of blue ♪
Hey.
♪ The thing we've begun ♪
It was
a beautiful speech, Sam.
♪ ...than a pastime ♪
♪ for this time is the one ♪
Sam?
When you
slept with Mark Sloan...
I didn't really
say anything.
But Pete...
He's my friend.
♪ Lucky through and through ♪
He's my friend, just like
Naomi is your friend,
but... I guess that doesn't
really matter to you.
Sam--
please.
It's my daughter's wedding.
I'm trying to be happy.
So I'm gonna
put this aside.
But, um...
I don't want to see you.
♪♪♪
I'm gonna go dance
with my daughter now.
♪♪♪
May I have a dance
with my daughter?
♪ The thing we've begun ♪
♪ is much more
than a pastime ♪
♪ for this time is the one ♪
♪ where the first time
is the last time ♪
♪ I've got beginner's luck ♪
♪ lucky through and through ♪
♪ 'cause the first time
that I'm in love ♪
♪ yes, the first time
♪ oh, the first time
that I'm in love ♪
♪ I'm in love with you ♪
♪ I'm in love
with you ♪
♪ I'm in love with you ♪