One more shot! One more
shot! Come on! Dribble!
Come on, come on, come on.
Five, four, three, two, one!
Slam-dunk.
We're going to see
Joanie on campus.
Oh, yeah? That's good.
I'm glad to see you getting out.
- What time you getting him?
- Roger will pick him up at 4:30.
Roger? BENTON: Yeah.
- Why?
- His cousin's having a birthday party.
- His cousin on Carla's side?
- No, on Roger's.
So it's not his real cousin.
Well, anyway, he
wanted him there. So...
- So he's setting the schedule now?
- Jackie, we've already had this argument.
It's important to
the guy, all right?
- I'm sure he misses Reece.
- More importantly, Reece misses him.
But you're just confusing him.
Roger isn't part of his family anymore.
Ah, Jackie, I'm just giving him time.
That's something you should understand.
I didn't mean, uh... Jackie.
Say bye-bye to Daddy.
That's right.
I'll have him ready at 4:30.
Keep her pressure above 90.
When did she spike the fever?
- Dad, how do you program numbers?
- Read the instructions.
When was her last dose
of imipenem? Well, find out.
- Pretty big hammer for post-op fever.
- Her kidneys are shutting down.
I'm missing algebra, you know.
Just testing.
So, Rachel, Katherine
has to leave at 5:00.
- Yeah? GREENE: So
Ella should nap until 6:30.
But if she wakes up crying, give her 4
ounces of breast milk from the fridge.
- You put it in the Avent warmer and...
- For two minutes on low. I know.
Yeah. Yeah. Who's
the ID fellow on call?
What?
- You're sparkling.
- So?
- You starting a trend?
- Dad, everyone wears glitter.
I'm pulling up right now.
Mix some dopamine. I'll
be there in five minutes.
Okay.
- Good luck.
- Thanks.
Sorry about the detour, Rachel.
Which entrance?
- What?
- Your school. North or south?
Oh, um...
How about a few blocks away?
- I thought you were late.
- I am, but...
Just don't wanna be
seen with the old man?
No, it's just, you
know, the van.
- I'm not even breaking a sweat.
- Aerobic activity is a secondary benefit.
Primary effects are
strength and balance.
Good Warriors.
Now down to Cat and Cow.
This is doing
nothing for my back.
Did you try some Tylenol? - No.
- Take some. CARTER:
I avoid pain medication.
If you're gonna be macho about
pain, then you can't whine about it.
Downward-Facing Dog.
- How's your grandma?
- Her doctor did an MRI, MRA...
stress echo, carotids.
Everything's fine.
- He did all that in one day?
- It's rich-lady service.
She's been very smug
about the whole thing.
Straighten your legs and exhale.
- Good.
- I got singled out.
- If it's too hard, don't push it.
- No. It's no problem.
So, what's the deal
with you and the nurse?
Nurse? LEWIS: Abby.
What do you mean?
It just seems like
there's something there.
We're friends.
- You're shaking.
- I know. I'm going back to Cow.
It's actually kind of
undefined with Abby.
- She just broke up with Luka.
- I get it.
- What?
- You don't want to be the rebound guy.
Not exactly. TERRY: Good.
Downward-Facing Dog now,
with your left leg extended in the air.
This is sadistic.
Pretend like you're
playing Twister.
- Uh-oh.
- Are you breathing?
Are you seeing the colors?
- Oh, boy.
Carter? Carter!
I've got three people heaving
and we're out of emesis basins.
Central Supply is
slow today. New runner.
What happened to the old one?
Nurses complained about
not having emesis basins.
County General on
Bravo 1. Go ahead.
I think I twisted my knee
doing that damn Locust position.
It's "Lotus," like the flower.
That explains why it hurts. I
was doing the Grasshopper.
Ha, I give up.
Good morning.
- Is it raining?
- Oh, no.
Susan dragged me
to this torture session.
We got an apartment fire. One major,
four minors. Mostly smoke inhalation.
- Uh, ETA's 10 to 15.
- Page the Burn Unit.
Tell the fellow we got one sick player.
Can you clear the Trauma rooms?
Well, they're gonna
have to puke on the floor.
- There she is.
- Who?
- Central Supply.
- Oh. Hey.
Excuse me. We're
completely out...
of emesis basins, and I
need at least 10 liters of...
- Hi.
- Hi, Abby.
- Luka got me a job.
- Oh, he did?
Yes. He knew I was out of work, so he
called me last week about this opening.
- It was so nice of him.
- He's... He's nice.
Yeah.
- Do you know where these go?
- Yeah. The linen closet.
- It's down the hall, to the left.
- Thank you.
And, uh, oh, I'm sorry,
do you need something?
I'll get the Ringer's. Could you
bring down some emesis basins?
Oh, what are those?
Barf bins.
- Vomit buckets.
- Oh.
Systolic BP's
70. Febrile to 104.
Bolus a liter of saline and
change all the IV and central lines.
But you... You
did that yesterday.
We need to do it again, in case
they're the source of the infection.
I've never seen her so bad.
- It's reversible.
But we will need to start her on cardiac
medication and dialysis immediately.
Put her on a machine?
Her kidneys aren't removing the toxins
from the bloodstream as they should.
- No, no. If this is her time...
- It's not. Not yet.
Jacy, start the dopamine and
titrate to a systolic above 90.
She's a DNR, you know.
She never wanted to end
up the way my dad did.
I understand.
She always said, "Push me over a
cliff before you put me on any tubes!"
April, her kidney
failure is temporary.
She could bounce back
after a few treatments.
It's worth trying.
Page the nephrologist
and the dialysis nurse.
- You really want to do that?
- Yes. Now.
The fire was right
outside our door.
- Eden was choking.
- She was holding her daughter.
- Broke the fall.
- And my legs.
Deformity in the right
tib-fib. Left femur looks open.
- Surgery and Ortho?
- Took your daughter in. She'll be okay.
- I'm sorry. You wanted me to wait.
- Everyone's safe.
- Here. Lean on me.
- I'm good.
That ankle doesn't look so good.
- I don't wanna crush you.
- It's okay. I'm used to it.
- How is it so far?
- Everyone's been very friendly.
Yeah, we like her.
- Has someone showed you around?
- I keep getting lost.
Yeah. Don't be
afraid to ask for help.
- I need some help.
- Oh, sorry.
- Want to have lunch?
- But you're busy.
No, 1:30. Find me.
I was halfway up the ladder,
and she panicked and jumped.
I think I would panic too.
- Can you bear weight on it at all?
- I'm fine. Just get me a bag of ice.
- You've got some burns too.
- Yeah. Occupational hazard.
Okay, no blistering.
Skin's intact.
Polysporin, then
dress with Kerlix.
- We'll probably need a splint for him.
- Uh, we're out of fiberglass.
I'm gonna have to
call Central Supply.
- I was gonna tell you.
- Uh, wow. Ow.
Tenderness of
the fifth metatarsal.
You thought firefighters
were tough guys, right?
Your secret's safe with me.
Let me take a look, Eden. Can
you tell me if your throat hurts?
Trauma panel, C-spine,
chest and pelvis.
Lateral C-spine, chest,
AP pelvis and Foley.
- Is that my daughter?
- Yeah.
- Is something wrong?
- I don't think so.
Conni, can you have Dr. Greene come
in and talk to Ms. Mintry when he can?
- What do we have? CARTER:
A two-story fall without LOC...
multiple fractures.
- Who's this?
- This is Carmen.
- Follow the light.
- Systolic's 90.
- Let's run another liter NS.
- Pupils equal, round and react to light.
I'll do an ultrasound to check
for signs of internal injury.
- Mrs. Mintry?
- Yes.
Eden inhaled some smoke.
And she has some
scrapes. That's all.
Uh, can I see her?
- Wait!
- What?
Your stethoscope. You
haven't cleaned it since using it.
Alcohol wipe, please.
We wanna keep her
on oxygen for a while.
Eden seems more concerned
about your dog than anything.
- Okay?
- He jumped out the window...
before we did, then ran off.
- Mm-hm.
- I'm sure he'll make his way home soon.
- Breath sounds clear bilaterally.
Dr. Carter, could you start
the ultrasound, please?
Mm-hm. ABG, carboxyhemoglobin.
Titrate 10 of morphine and 10
liters humidified O-2 by mask.
- How's Mrs. Wilson?
- Ah, not good.
She's not responding
to antibiotics or pressors.
Did you try ampho?
She's still in
multi-organ failure.
Do you mind? I'm
talking with my husband.
I need to watch
you at all times.
Fine! Watch!
- I'd like to deck that woman.
- Infection Control?
They feel the need to
follow me around at all times.
Mark, I can't lose
another patient like this.
I know.
When did you last clean your
stethoscope between patients?
She's justifying her job.
- ICU?
- Oh, damn it.
- I can't let this happen again.
- You can't save everyone.
I shouldn't kill everyone
either, should I?
That's okay, I'm gonna
wait for the doctor.
- Don't be embarrassed.
- Uh-uh.
I really messed it up.
- Let me see.
No! No, I need the doctor.
After you've been
seen by a nurse.
What I got to show you,
you don't want to see.
Yes, but I can't help you
unless I see what the problem is.
The pro... The problem is
that I got a bum pair of scissors.
Take the towel off. I'm
not gonna be shocked.
- You can't say that. You haven't seen it.
- I'm a professional.
I'd never agree to this if I didn't
think I might bleed to death.
Wow.
The pain is, like,
wrapped around my head.
Did you drink last night?
- There were a lot of parties on campus.
- Is that a yes?
I never felt this way
from being hung-over.
I woke up all achy, and
I keep getting the chills.
- Sounds like the flu, Laura.
- That's what he said.
You saw Dr. Mau?
- He asked me, like, a thousand questions.
- Okay, I'll be right back.
Sophomore at U of I woke up with a
hatband headache, fever and myalgias.
History includes childhood chickenpox,
ER visit for food poisoning two years ago.
What are you doing?
In this position, there's
hardly any pain at all.
- Tylenol, I'm telling you.
- Yeah. We need to talk.
Stand up. Let me see.
- You know, I can help you with that.
- Ah, pass.
Uh, hold still.
Patient carries an Epipen
for allergy to Hymenoptera.
- History of yeast infections.
- Cut to the chase.
- What's the diagnosis?
- A viral illness of unknown etiology.
The flu. I agree.
- Ibuprofen and drink plenty of fluids?
- Sounds like a winner.
- Next time, sign up for it, Stanley.
- Sorry.
- How does this feel?
- Mm, not as good as squatting.
Hi.
- Fresh pot.
- Great.
- Did you do the splint in 2?
- Not yet, but I'm going to.
So, um...
- Listen, um, about Nicole...
- You don't have to explain.
- I want to.
- No, really.
It's none of my business.
It just seems like you're going way out
on a limb for someone you barely know.
- She lost her job.
- Yeah, but is that your problem?
Why not help?
Is she, like, your
girlfriend now?
I got her a job, that's all.
So it's not like
she's living with you.
She's living with you?
Just till she can save some
money for her own place.
- She was staying at a hostel.
- So?
So she's a sweet
girl. I'm trying to help.
You don't have
to help everybody.
What's your problem?
Nothing.
- Still fighting?
- No.
Luka has a new project.
- Oh, like what? Coin collecting?
- Nicole.
That cookie girl,
she works here now.
- Why do you care?
- Well, I don't.
- What? I don't.
- Okay.
BP's holding at 80. Another
run of ectopy on the monitor.
Seven beats. Lidocaine, 70 milligrams,
IV push. Start a drip at 4 cc's an hour.
Have the crash cart nearby.
- Are you sure?
- Stop saying that and do as I ask.
Run of V-tach.
Pressure's
dropping. Systolic, 59.
After the lido, get
ready with procainamide.
- What are you doing?
- Treating my patient.
- Do I have to push the drug myself?
- She's a DNR.
- I can save her.
- You have to respect her wishes.
If we can support her
till I find the source...
M.A.P. down to 40.
- Start CPR.
- No. Jacy, hold compressions.
Peter, this is none
of your business.
- V-fib. BENTON:
Look at that woman.
Look out the window. That woman
wants to sit with her mother. Let her.
- I can help her.
- No, you can't.
Agonal.
Hi. CHRIS: How you doing?
- Is it still wet?
- Yeah.
- What do I do when my foot itches?
- You live with it.
Can I get you something?
Water, Popsicle?
- How about a soda?
- Sure.
Your boyfriend get
mad if I buy you one?
- Well, I'm not thirsty, but thank you.
- Come on. Live it up.
- Is this the surgical consult?
- Uh, yeah.
It's... It's a delicate, um...
All right. So,
what's the problem?
She didn't tell you?
Rick tried to
circumcise himself.
All right. Ice and
sponges. Let's have a look.
I'm not nuts, okay?
You didn't consider
having a doctor do this?
I thought I could take the
pain. Snip, snip, done deal.
You know, there's no medical
reason for circumcision.
- There's a personal reason.
- There you go. All right.
Apply direct pressure.
Laceration's 2 inches,
no damage to the glans.
- So, what now?
- Well, you're halfway done.
I can finish the
job or sew it up.
- Can I ask my girlfriend?
- Would that be the personal reason?
She's a neat freak.
- Foreskin just didn't do it for her.
- Sure. Why don't you call her.
Either way, we can do it
upstairs, treat it as plastic surgery.
- You want a Psych consult?
- No, I just think he's stupid.
Not to mention devoted.
You passed out.
Someone called 911.
People can't mind
their own business.
- Sorry, am I too early?
- No, have a seat.
- Your blood doesn't seem to be clotting.
- I have a factor-lX deficiency.
Do you get regular doses
of factor somewhere?
Children's. I guess I
missed a couple of rounds.
- Mary, call Hemo/Onc.
- Sure.
It's very important
that you go every time.
I know. I just couldn't
get there lately.
- What's your dose?
- Twenty-one hundred units.
- See if the pharmacy has that much.
- I'll go check.
- Do they have bag lunches here?
- I don't know.
Some hospitals do.
Okay. After the factor, I want
to clean and irrigate that hand.
- Is there someone we can call?
- No.
- Parents?
- Okay. Let's start an IV.
- I have a Port-A-Cath.
- For how long?
- Two years.
Couldn't stand the
needles every day.
Okay. We'll use that.
- I'll bring you a sandwich.
- Thanks.
- Oh, that thing.
- Yeah. It ate my dollar.
- You want to borrow one?
- No, I got it. Thanks.
So is it hard working
with Dr. Kovac?
- Carter told me.
- Oh.
- Sorry, am I not supposed to know?
- No, don't worry about it.
- Yeah. Dating at work can be messy.
- Yeah.
- Abby?
- Want some change?
Uh, the girlfriend of the guy is here.
- What guy?
The self-circumcision.
- Your patient?
- Yes.
- Sepsis.
- Bad luck you've had.
- Did you find any nidus of infection?
- No, not so far.
No abscesses or localized
infection anywhere obvious.
Would you check the
bowel anastomosis?
You believe there was a leak?
I'm trying to find the
source of these infections.
- Do you mind?
- No. I'll check.
She was a very nice woman.
For the record, Dr. Corday, I don't agree
with what people are saying about you.
You know, all this talk about the
breast-feeding and the sleep deprivation.
- That part's true.
- Well, I mean:
"Motherhood's
interfering with your work."
- That's sexist crap.
- Yeah, well...
- it's not a woman's world, is it?
- Not until they perfect cloning.
Right.
I thought you went
to the bathroom.
I'll let you know what I find.
- I can't believe you did this.
- What do you mean?
- You said that you wanted me to...
- I know what I said, but it's so extreme!
So are we repairing or removing?
- What do you say?
- I don't know. Whatever's less traumatic.
Well, it's 50-50 now.
Well, I, uh...
I mean, I might as well
finish what I started.
- Don't you think?
- I guess.
Okay. Well, we'll get you up to the
O.R. as soon as there's a room available.
Nurse, do you have a second?
- Sure. What is it?
- Outside.
What? What are you doing?
I'll be right back.
- He'll be okay, right?
- Oh, yeah. They'll fix it.
You'll never know. I mean,
except for the foreskin.
- This should never have happened.
- I thought this was what you wanted.
Not really.
I only said that because I
wanted to break up with him...
without hurting his feelings.
- Abby, we need you!
- Okay, hold on. I'll be back.
Got a gag. BP,
130/70. Pulse, 100.
- Did he take anything?
- This is the roommate.
- Does he use drugs?
- No.
He drank a little at a party
last night, but he was okay.
- Did he say anything today?
- Just that he felt sick and his neck hurt.
- Stiff?
- He thought he slept on it funny.
Okay. On my count.
One, two, three.
Skin feels hot. Let's
get a rectal temp.
See this? LEWIS: What?
- Petechiae. They don't blanch.
- Oh, my God.
- Sats are dropping to 91.
- This is meningococcus.
What's that?
Get TB masks and
post-exposure meds for everyone.
CBC, Chem-20, Accu-Chek,
blood cultures times two.
This could be all
over his dorm by now.
- Where do you go to school?
- U of I.
- Get an LP tray. Where's Carter?
- He's in Exam 3.
Get him. Get him now.
Get me a 16
French, triple lumen.
Carter? Carter, Lewis needs you.
- What is it?
- Some kid has meningococcus.
All right, take
them out, Stanley.
Okay.
- Ceftriaxone going up.
- Meningococcemia?
Can you intubate?
Twenty-eight of dexamethasone.
You induce yet? LEWIS: No.
Twenty of etomidate.
Give me 120 of sux.
- Did our flu girl go to U of I?
- Yes. Laura Avery. I presented her to you.
She needs to be tapped.
If she's been exposed as long
as he has, we're out of time.
She was discharged. - What?
You said she had the flu.
- We need to find her.
I'll do it. Tube him. Prep
a Swan-Ganz catheter.
She was in Chairs waiting on a ride.
- Mau.
Okay, he's loose. Give me
some cricoid pressure, Malik.
Go check Triage. Find out the name
of her dorm and send an ambulance.
Was there a unit? - Yeah.
What did they say?
- An hour at least.
I found the introducer,
but not the catheter.
We need to monitor
his pressure here.
Well, nothing's where
it's supposed to be.
Frank, where's the girl
that was in Curtain 2?
- Mm, pretty college girl?
- Yeah.
She asked where to
buy some orange juice.
- Where did you tell her?
- Cafeteria, where else?
Whoa.
- Oh. Oh. Sorry. Sorry.
- Slow down!
Just be polite.
- "Yes, ma'am. Please, ma'am."
- All right.
Where'd you put the
Swan-Ganz catheters?
- The what?
- Swan-Ganz catheters.
- Uh, they told me in the Trauma Room.
- They're not there.
- I thought that's where I put it.
- Well, show me.
- You got it?
- Yeah. Here. Here's the cordis.
You want me to set
up for an art line?
Either. I'll take either.
- Got it!
- No. That is the introducer.
It looks like a
big, yellow snake.
Get me somebody who
knows the difference.
She's new, Carter.
It's her first day.
This kid is dying here.
- I'm sorry.
If you don't know what
you're doing, get out.
Here it is. Don't yell at her.
- We're losing time here.
- It's not her fault he's sick.
Flush the ports.
Damn it.
Laura! Laura!
Laura!
- Hold on!
- What is it?
Stay right there.
I'm coming down!
If she left a note, you
shouldn't have been late.
I did tell her about the party. Take it
up with her. I don't have time for this.
- Nanny?
- No, Roger.
- He's my new shadow.
- He should meet Carmen.
What do you have?
Revision of a failed circumcision,
25-year-old. Don't ask.
- You?
- Splenectomy and a pilon tib-fib.
Mm.
Listen, uh...
- I'm sorry about earlier.
- Ah, it's okay.
Uh, I thought I
could beat the odds.
Look, I know you're stressed out
with the new baby and everything.
What's that have to do with it?
Not to mention the head-trips
that's going on around here.
My fuse would be short too.
Have you ever seen me do
anything wrong? Lazy? Sloppy?
No.
Look, I think you're
just having a bad run.
That's not very comforting
to my next patient.
Elizabeth, if I needed surgery
or Reece did, I'd come to you.
- BP's down to 60.
- How much fluid is in?
Eight. We're gonna put
him into pulmonary edema.
Dopamine's maxed
out. Levo's at 20 mics.
There's no place
to put the pulse ox.
God, this kills fast.
V-fib. CARTER: Crash
cart. Charge to 300.
He's young. Let's give him a
chance. Come on, Andy. Clear!
Charge to 360. Go get
the conducting pads.
And clear.
Okay, Laura.
You're gonna feel
pressure in your lower back.
- Can I call my mom?
- As soon as we're done.
It's long-distance. Omaha.
Uh, is he gonna be okay? Andy?
They're working on
him. You know him well?
Everyone knows him. He's on
the soccer team, really popular.
Spend time with him lately?
Laura? STANLEY: Fluid's clear.
- Laura?
- Well, we sort of kissed last night.
- Did you kiss anyone else?
- Why?
Andy has a very
contagious bacterial infection.
We need to know who
might've been exposed.
I usually only kiss
one guy a night.
Do you think Andy
shares the same policy?
I don't know. Last night was
the first time I talked to him.
Dr. Lewis?
What? What is it?
I can't pay for this.
Don't worry. Half of
our patients can't pay.
And if there's a follow-up or
anything, I don't even know where I'll be.
- Your tox screen is positive for opiates.
- Well, my joints bleed. It hurts.
- What drugs do you do?
- Demerol, if I can get it.
And if not, heroin?
- I don't see tracks.
- It's not a regular thing.
- Do you use your Port-A-Cath to shoot?
- All right, look.
- You know, I didn't ask to come here.
- That's not what a Port-A-Cath is for.
Hold on. Hold on. Let
me call someone for you.
Tsch, there's no one to call.
- Let's talk about rehab, then.
- Ha, I don't think so.
I'm not done with your hand.
I can't leave it open like that.
Please?
- Is ham and cheese okay?
- I'm not picky.
- There's fruit in there too.
- Thanks.
Wait here. I need to
get another suture kit.
- Why were you fighting?
- He's using his catheter to shoot drugs.
- It has to be removed.
- Can you do that?
- You all right?
- Me? Yes.
Dr. Carter was under pressure.
- That's okay.
Don't you think he would find
some other way to do drugs?
He was given the catheter
for clotting factor, not heroin.
This is Dr. Lewis again from the
ER in Chicago regarding Laura.
Please call me right away.
Okay, I'm in. Bag her.
- Where's the vent?
- On its way.
Her pressure's dropping.
More dopamine?
No. We're running
in the antibiotics.
- Portable chest?
- Sure. Check the tube.
Not that it makes much
difference. It's a waiting game now.
Not so fast. You don't
want to give her a pneumo.
- I missed it.
- I missed it too.
- You didn't see her. CARTER:
Well, it presented like the flu.
- You call the college?
- Mm-hm.
Student Health is giving
antibiotics to everybody in the dorm.
- And the people at that party?
- They'll get the word out.
They don't want an outbreak.
Abby, 600 milligrams of rifampin...
- for anyone on the meningitis cases.
- It makes me sick.
- Better than dead.
- Here you go.
- There she is.
- Sorry. I got busy.
- Thanks.
- Now all you need are crutches.
Do I have to? ABBY: Mm-hm.
Nurse's orders.
- Can I ask you something?
- Yeah.
- How late are you here tonight?
- Hmm. One more hour.
If I were gonna see you
again, I'd be more subtle.
But would you like to go
for coffee or something?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm not available.
- There's a boyfriend.
- Uh, well...
- You don't know?
- I don't know.
But thank you.
Pressure's steady.
Can I have a
little room, please?
I have to see the field.
- And I have to work.
Careful. Mommy's watching.
Releasing the
splenophrenic vessels.
Let's pack it in with lap pads.
Small vascular clamp.
Mobilizing the
spleen. Bowl, please.
Let's isolate the hilar
vessels. We'll ligate.
Did you touch the
circulating nurse?
For God's sake.
- Of course not.
- It looked close.
Carmen, get out. - What?
I've had it with your
intrusive pettiness.
I'm doing my job.
No. You are driving us all
crazy. Now, leave the O.R.
I can't do that.
Well, then we'll call
Security to assist you.
- Shirley? SHIRLEY:
Are you serious?
I've never been more serious.
- Catfight pending.
Dr. Corday? They want
you in Romano's office.
I'm operating.
He said to have you scrub out
and to escort you, or I'm fired.
I'll take that spleen.
Don't follow me.
Isn't Surgery supposed
to take your messages?
- Let me guess. Roger or Jackie?
- One of each.
- Sounds like they're feuding.
- Let them.
I don't think I can.
- Just temporarily.
Is he okay? BENTON: Yeah.
He should be sore
for a week or so.
- And he'll work like normal?
- Should be just what you ordered.
Uh, Sarah didn't have an
issue with the circumcision.
I was trying to let
him down gently.
- Let him down?
- I didn't want to hurt him.
You need to go upstairs
and tell him the truth.
- Mm-mm, three weeks.
- No. Now.
I backed over a guy's cat once
and stayed two more weeks.
- This has got to be worth at least three.
- Do whatever you want.
I'm so bad at relationships. I
can never just say what I feel.
I know what you mean.
- You do know I was in the O.R...
- Sit down, Elizabeth.
No, thank you.
This is Edwin Bane, Cook
County Health Department.
Dr. Corday.
- It couldn't wait? ROMANO:
Dr. Bane is an investigator.
So it's an investigation now.
Unfortunate record you've
accrued lately, Dr. Corday.
Yes.
- We are a little baffled by it.
- As am I.
Did something turn up in my cultures?
- No.
Does Carmen have a
problem with my technique?
- We're looking at other theories.
- Other theories?
It has to be more than
a statistical anomaly.
What do you think is happening?
Well, if I knew that,
I'd have fixed it by now.
And there's nothing
you want to tell us?
Uh...
- What are you insinuating?
- The next step is a criminal inquiry.
Ah, I beg your pardon?
All four of these patients
were elderly, in marginal health.
- Yes.
- All die of post-op sepsis...
under your care. And
on at least one occasion...
- the family asked you to euthanize.
- No! No...
Adrienne Tanzi?
Uh, there was discussion
about the quality of life.
Um, I'm sorry. Am I being
accused of something here?
Doctor, you wouldn't be the first angel
of mercy to help end patients' suffering.
Uh, hold on, doctor. I
thought you were fact-finding.
I am.
So if there's something you want
to tell us, you should tell us now.
Like what? That I'm going around
with a syringe full of bacteria...
infecting these
people on purpose?
All right, that's
it. Let's adjourn.
The Chicago Police
will be contacting you.
You might want to think
about hiring counsel.
- Is that your dog?
- Yeah. Speedy.
He's lost.
Somebody order crayons?
- Oh, thanks.
- You're welcome.
Did you finish your shift?
I'm waiting for Luka.
- Uh, is it always like this?
- Pretty much, yeah.
- I really admire what you do.
- Oh, you get used to it.
No. I meant you.
- I always wanted to be a nurse.
- Really?
At the hospital where my mother died,
the nurses treated me like their daughter.
They gave me ice cream
and dolls to play with.
- They were like angels. KOVAC:
Have you seen my patient?
- Which one?
- Wes. The one you met.
- Uh, I talked to him maybe an hour ago.
- Mm, he's gone.
You finished stitching
his hand, right?
Yeah, but the social
worker has to see him.
Maybe he didn't want
to get that tube removed.
I didn't tell him I
wanted to do that.
Oh.
- Did you?
- No. I didn't say anything.
Abby, if you see Adele, could
you tell her that my patient eloped?
Sure.
Don't worry. He'll be okay.
He's on the street with a serious
coagulopathy, drug habit, no money.
- Well, if he left home, I mean...
- What?
And stayed away this long,
maybe he doesn't want to be found.
Rachel?!
Damn it.
Rachel!
It's okay, sweetie. It's okay.
Oh.
It's okay. It's okay. I know.
Oh, it's all right, darling.
He's cute, but don't you
think he should cut his hair?
Rachel, turn off the music
and get off the phone!
- Two seconds.
- Hang up!
I gotta go. My dad's
wife is freaking.
- What's wrong?
- You're supposed to be babysitting.
- I am.
- Ella was screaming.
- Oh, sorry.
- Did you feed her?
- I wasn't supposed to until she woke up.
- Well, she's up now, isn't she?
You want me to feed her now?
Yes, I want you to feed her now.
Listen, I want you
to be responsible.
To think about something
other than yourself.
I said I was sorry. I
didn't hear her crying.
You didn't care to listen.
You were playing that crap...
and talking about
rubbish to your friend.
If you're so worried, then why
don't you stay home with her?
I mistakenly thought that you
were reliable enough to do it.
Well, then forget it.
I'm calling Lynn back.
- No, you don't.
- Elizabeth!
- Warm up that milk.
- No!
- Now!
- She's your kid.
- You're living in my house.
- You can't tell me what to do.
Oh, yes, I bloody well can.
You know what?
You need to chill out.
This is my house. You
can't talk to me that way.
Boy, my dad sure can pick them.
Rachel, you do not want to battle
with me. You'll lose. I guarantee it.
Your shift's over, isn't it?
- Yeah.
What are you, a
med student again?
I sent him home.
I loved being this age, having a crush
on a guy, finally meeting him at a party.
She probably went home all excited,
wondering what would happen next.
She has a chance.
Yeah. I just want to
be here whichever way.
Don't stay all night, okay?
Dr. Lewis, there's a woman
on line two calling from Omaha.
Thanks.
- Good night.
You make me drive
all the way over here?
What is your problem?
You'd know if
you'd take my calls.
- I have 100 things to do during the day.
- More important than your son?
More important than
refereeing you and Jackie.
I was 20 minutes late. She
uses that to keep me from him?
We need to rethink the
visitation thing. It's complicated.
- It's Jackie who's messing things up.
- Jackie is his aunt.
And I'm his father!
- His what?
- I'm one of his fathers.
Look, Roger, I, uh...
I appreciate you
caring for Reece.
I thought this time was
important to make a transition.
- Transition?
- But right now, you know what?
You need to let go.
Peter, look, I'm willing to work
out a schedule or something.
No. Reece has one
father, and that's me.
We both know that's
not true, don't we?
Carla said you're not his
real father any more than I.
- You want to back up with that.
- So don't think you can just dump me...
- like, uh, you're more important to him.
- I am more important to him.
You don't call me anymore.
You don't come near the house.
Stay away from Jackie and
stay the hell away from my son.
- Are you gonna do it again?
- Seriously, I think it worked.
It feels much better.
- Needles in your back?
- Yeah. It was a bonus.
I didn't realize you
were a masochist.
Whatever works.
I should run home
and get my whip.
Yeah, you do that.
- You almost off?
- Uh, yeah, 15 minutes ago.
What are you still
hanging around for?
And miss this late-night stroll?
It's starting to get a
little chilly out here.
I got asked out
by a fireman today.
- Really?
- Mm-hm.
- Ankle guy?
- Yeah.
- Hard to believe?
- No.
- He's good-looking.
- Big?
- Yeah. Funny.
- Invite me to the nuptials.
All right. You
gotta help me out.
I don't know what to
do. Rub your back?
I'm just not exactly sure
what I'm supposed to do here.
I'm not exactly sure how I'm
supposed to comment on your love life.
I said no because I was
waiting for something to happen...
- with us.
- You've been waiting?
- Yeah.
- You weren't doing much...
- to move it forward.
- No, you gave me an ultimatum.
You gave me an ultimatum,
and I did what you asked...
and you've done nothing.
- What did I ask you to do?
- I broke up with Luka.
First, you didn't break
up with Luka for me.
- I didn't?
- No. Second of all...
- you didn't break up with Luka.
- Ha-ha, I'm pretty sure I did.
Well, then why do
you care so much...
about what he does
or what he thinks or...?
I dated the guy for a year.
There's gonna be some history.
Maybe too much history.
Well, yeah, I had a
life before John Carter.
If you want someone
with no history...
you're gonna have to
find yourself a virgin.
No. I'll settle for someone who
isn't hung up on somebody else.
You don't have to settle
for anything, Carter.
I talked to her.
She's at Andrew's.
- And?
- He said he'd have her back by 10.
End of a great day.
That investigator
was totally out of line.
- He all but accused me of homicide.
- It's crazy.
- What if people believe him?
- They won't.
You know what's
really crazy? I feel guilty.
- Elizabeth.
- I do.
Four people are dead. I was their
doctor, and I can't explain what happened.
Well, the answer certainly isn't
that you were euthanizing people.
Then I come back home, and
I take it out on a 14-year-old.
That's a fair fight.
She didn't do what she
said she was gonna do.
That's worth a conversation.
I'm gonna have that with her.
I don't think I can
handle this, Mark.
I was barely handling working
and looking after the baby.
You can.
- I can't.
- Oh, hey, hey, hey, hey. Hey...
Hey...
We'll work this out.
Okay?
We'll lay down the
rules for Rachel.
- We'll get you a lawyer if we have to.
- Oh, God!
We got fights ahead
of us. We know that.
But we're together.
And we got children.
We're happy.
That's a lot.
Hey.
I called your mom.
She's flying in.
You had us a little worried.