Good morning.
Admissions percentages
at top colleges
have dropped to record lows.
You thinking about
going back to school?
No. No.
I'm thinking about
our son's future.
As in starting a college
fund for the Peanut?
No, I have put the
Peanut on a waitlist
for pre-kindergarten
at McLelland Hall.
Isn't McLelland Hall that
snobby private school
in Menlo Park?
It is one of the top
three feeder schools
for Stanford University.
So, you've not only decided
he's going to college,
you've also picked
out which one.
Given our son's genetic makeup,
he will probably
be very intelligent
and will require a challenging
academic curriculum.
Or he may not even
enjoy academics.
Whatever he ends up doing
will be his call, not ours.
Whatever pre-kindergarten
he ends up attending
will be our call, not his.
Hmm.
Oh. No coffee.
Glassy still in his room?
No, I heard him leave at 6:14.
He's been so sad about
losing his house.
How can you tell he's sad?
Have you noticed
how quiet he's been?
Yes. It's been nice.
Guess he's just throwing
himself into his work.
Hmm.
Dr. Murphy, little help here?
Give tetanus booster,
clean the wound
- with Betadine, administer...
- No, we got that. It's...
We wanted a second opinion.
Uh, Victor did.
Before these young pups take
a saw to our son's foot,
I'd like to talk
to a supervisor.
The nail's bent.
I am their supervisor,
and we need the saw to cut
the nail, not his foot.
Are you good, Ricky?
You all know my angel
for the past 11 years,
- Dr. Lim.
- Oh.
Hey, Roses. And this is my
resident, Dr. Jordan Allen.
Hi! Roses?
My website's called
"More than 65 Roses."
It's what I called it when
I was diagnosed at five.
Sixty-five roses,
cystic fibrosis.
Okay.
And welcome to vlog number 458,
going out all around the world.
And what does DLT stand for?
Oh, that
would be "double lung transplant."
Whoo! Whoo!
Your new
lungs just arrived.
Oh.
I never should've
agreed to let him go.
You didn't. You just stopped
fighting with me about it.
He's running a
mild fever, 100.4.
Go where?
Church camping trip,
less than an hour away.
Camping can be very dangerous.
Thank you, Dr. Murphy.
You know, I had my first
fire-roasted s'more last summer,
so camping can also be very fun.
Thank you, Dr. Wolke.
Be careful, please.
Victor, he's a doctor.
Just try to trust...
Trust that things
will work out, yep.
I know.
You're a Warriors fan, huh?
You like Steph Curry?
I like Draymond.
A rebel. I like it.
Huh. Look at this beast.
Nice job, Ricky.
His temperature just
jumped two degrees.
Let's get a CBC, blood cultures,
and a CT of his foot
to check for damage
to the bones and muscles.
Dr. Park, how kind
of you to join me.
You paged me.
Have a seat. And, yes,
they're Herman Miller.
Cappuccino, mochaccino,
espresso, latte?
None of those are for you.
Okay, I was wrong.
This is the perfect job for you.
Your first study has,
what, 800 patients?
But since you've had
four whole days to hire
all the clinical trial
nurses you'll need,
should be easy.
I may be a little behind
and may already have
thirteen patients waiting,
but I will handle it.
With a lot of cappuccinos.
Thanks for your support.
Do you want me to
give you a hand?
I have 90 minutes
before my next surgery.
In exchange for unlimited
use of your espresso machine.
We'll see.
Poor Ricky.
He probably just has
a minor infection.
I meant the parents.
They went to two very different
schools of thought on child rearing.
It's hard on the marriage
but harder on the kid.
Everyone has different
opinions, Dr. Wolke.
Yeah, which they
really need to sort out
before having kids.
My college roommate,
who was Jewish,
married a wonderful
Catholic woman.
They had three children
in quick succession,
started fighting about how
to parent them non-stop.
See, my parents
never fought about us
because my dad didn't care,
as long as my mom got me
and my brother dressed
and out in time for chores.
Well...
No hematoma or abscess.
No explanation for the fever.
My neck, it really hurts.
Okay.
Hey. I got you.
He has tick bites on his back.
Pink, plump, and spongy.
What's that?
Pneumonia?
In both lungs.
She's lucky if she
has another week.
Ex vivo lung perfusion.
Maybe we can make the
lungs heal themselves.
That's usually used in cases
involving pulmonary edema.
Get the lungs. Meet me
in the Procedure Room.
Tick bites?
His fever, vomiting,
and sore neck...
- which could be neurological...
- It's in his brain?
Possibly, but the blood
tests were inconclusive,
so we'd like to do
a lumbar puncture
to check Ricky's
cerebrospinal fluid.
This camp just keeps
getting better and better.
Can we not do this right now?
I just want to make sure
this never happens again.
And I don't?
I care about our son every
bit as much as you do.
And yet, you keep
prioritizing fun over safety.
Yes, I care about fun,
and socialization,
self-esteem, self-expression...
Yeah, none of which are as
important as his safety.
I can't do this anymore.
Wh...
Got through six so far. Only
one with a minor reaction.
- You?
- Me, too.
So, we are 12 down, one to go.
Mr. Riggs?
Sorry.
I just drifted off.
My fault for
keeping you waiting so long.
So, how are you feeling?
Aside from tired.
Uh, just a bit achy.
Especially my knees
and elbows, hips.
And some mild jaundice.
Other than that, I
feel pretty good.
- Hello.
- Oh.
We should sort out
our differences
about child raising.
If this is about
McLelland Hall, Shaun,
- it's not a big deal.
- Oh, no, I have made a list
of 37 other potential
differences.
And I'd love to
discuss them all,
but Andrews just
approved new EMR software
and wants me to run a beta test
on it in the next 24 hours.
- Have you talked to Glassy?
- No.
He didn't come to work
today, but I got a text.
He says that he is okay.
So where is he?
It is not over yet.
Lungs are remarkably
resilient organs
when they are in a body.
Which is why we have to
convince them they still are.
We give them a blood
supply by hooking them up
to a perfusion machine,
an air supply by hooking
them up to a ventilator,
IV drips to feed
them antibiotics,
and we might just be able to
con them back into viability.
The next six hours are crucial.
How will you know
if they're viable?
Our main indicator is a
calculation called the P/F ratio.
When that reaches at least
400 millimeters of mercury,
those lungs are good to go.
Mom, relax, it's Dr. L.
Palpate to find the
L3-4 interspace.
Maybe Lea and I will not be
able to sort out our differences
about child raising and become
angry like Victor and Shelley.
You and Lea are nothing
like Victor and Shelley.
They come from completely
different worlds,
have vastly
different outlooks...
Lea and I are very
different, too.
Insert the spinal needle.
And who knows how
much they love each other.
You and Lea, on the other
hand, I know you do. A lot.
And that's all that matters.
At least, according to
the Hallmark Channel.
I'm in.
Whoa, whoa. Whoa, whoa, whoa.
The infection has elevated
his intracranial pressure.
Intubate and load him with
levetiracetam and dexamethasone
before his brain herniates.
CSF confirmed a
very rare infection
called Naegleria fowleri.
It's a brain-eating amoeba that's
caused serious cerebral swelling.
We need to put Ricky in a
barbiturate-induced coma
and surgically place a port
into the center of his brain.
Then we will flood
it with antibiotics,
which will hopefully
reduce the edema.
And he contracted
this from a tick?
Oh, no, it's contracted via
contaminated water through the nose.
So... So he got it from
the swimming hole at camp?
That's a good guess.
But Ricky's way too
anxious around water
to ever put his head under, let
alone get water up his nose.
Naegleria Fowleri
has also been found
in untreated swimming pools,
- nasal rinses, water heaters...
- Nasal rinses?
If unboiled tap water is used.
I gave him a nasal rinse the
morning he left for camp.
He had a runny nose.
That is a better guess.
Excuse me.
Riggs has fatigue, joint pain,
impaired mental acuity,
tachycardia, and
mild liver failure.
- Thanks.
- Maybe he has a pre-existing condition.
In which case he
should've been eliminated
by any remotely competent
screening process.
Those protocols were in place
before you came on board.
I'll remind the CRO of that when
I tell them, on my first day...
That their $4 million
trial needs to be trashed.
How about you save the
doomsday predictions
until after the
blood panel results?
Lab is on the way to the OR.
It hasn't been six
hours yet, has it?
Six and a quarter.
You want company?
Thanks.
Hello. Where is Victor?
Beating himself up somewhere.
I just wish that
made a difference.
Do you love each other?
Yeah. Of course.
We've always been oil and water.
That's how my dad describes us.
Victor grew up in Belgrade,
I grew up in Berkeley.
Different religions, politics,
socio-economic status.
But when I got pregnant,
we knew we had a lot
of issues to work out.
And we did.
And then Ricky was born, and...
we suddenly started
arguing over...
when can he safely
eat tree nuts?
How high should he
climb on the jungle gym?
When can he stay
with a babysitter?
Those little things
were the ones
we could never work out.
But, yes, we still
love each other.
It's just that...
I'm not sure love
is enough anymore.
Still
waiting, still hoping.
That's kinda what we
do, isn't it, Roses?
And the wait is over.
I'm sorry.
We've put you back on the list.
You're at the very top.
I deserved this.
I wanted those lungs.
I wanted someone to die.
Brecka.
Honey, should we...
Should we finish?
No.
- Hello, Dr. Glassman.
- Geez! Man!
Shaun, you might try
knocking next time,
although, you know, that
might be a little tough.
What are you looking for?
Oh, you know...
my life.
Just my life.
Not yet.
I think I'm gonna
keep at it for a bit.
Okay.
No. This is on me.
You can head home.
Thanks.
I will miss your
big-screen LED TV.
It was old.
It had a pixel line
down the right side.
Did you love Ilana?
What? Did I love Ilana?
Yeah, of course.
Did you love Debbie?
Yeah, I loved Debbie.
Where is this going, Shaun?
That wasn't enough for you
to get over your differences.
How do I know if
love will be enough
for me and Lea to get
over our differences?
Well, you won't know.
I mean, how can you
know? You can't know.
I do not like
worrying about this.
Well, look, I mean,
Lea had some doubts a
little while ago, right?
And you both got over that.
Yes, because I was
very supportive.
Okay, well, there you go.
But differences about child
raising seem to be bigger
- than normal differences.
- Well, yeah.
I mean, having a child,
I mean, that's big.
That's huge. That's a shift.
It shifts everything,
marriage, everything.
I do not want a shift
in our marriage.
Well, maybe it'll
shift for the better.
Aardy's eye.
The first thing I
ever bought Maddie
was a stuffed aardvark.
Back in the day, I
performed a 21-hour surgery.
I removed an astrocytoma
from the medulla
of the brainstem.
It was heroic. It
put me on the map.
My elective surgeries were
booked out for a year.
I was in a zone, like
playing scratch golf.
And then Ilana got pregnant.
She didn't want to stop working.
She had a real-estate thing.
She was doing very well. I
didn't want to stop working.
I wanted to stay on the map.
And then we brought Maddie home.
That first night...
everything changed.
Hmm.
Go talk to Lea.
I tried.
She had to run a beta
test on new EMR software.
Well, then, you'll have
to wait until she's done.
All I had on my DVR was
a marathon of Shark Tank.
Can't say I was in
the mood to be staring
at Mr. Wonderful's bald head,
so why not entertain myself
by watching some hot
lung perfusion action?
I'm not one to kink shame.
Coffee and cronuts
from Chaz's Bakery.
I'm happy for the company.
Noomie's not much of
a conversationalist.
-N-Noomie?
-My pet name for them.
From the Greek word
for lungs, pneumonas.
I thought it was
better than Lung-ie.
Yeah, I may be losing it.
Cronut.
- Mmm.
- Any progress?
Negligible.
I keep doing the same
thing over and over,
hoping for a different outcome.
Yeah, I'm definitely losing it.
Then do something different.
Okay.
Doubling up on antibiotics,
and we can add steroids.
This will either hammer
out the infection...
or the lungs.
How's Glassy?
Very sore and very sooty.
Mmm.
We need to talk.
About our 37 differences?
I thought of two more.
Shaun, as you know, I'm
kinda busy right now,
so you'll have to settle
for me agreeing that,
yes, we'll have many,
many differences,
but in time, we'll be able
to work them out and...
That's what Victor
and Shelley thought,
and now they are talking
about separating.
I don't know who
Victor and Shelley are.
But in any event, I have at least
two more hours of work to do tonight.
Okay.
- You're waiting, aren't you?
- Yes.
I am very patient.
You arevery patient
and very understanding.
And you were so good
with me on our babymoon.
If you could just
channel some of that...
On our babymoon, I
thought love was enough.
That's... kind of a big thing
to drop on me this
late at night.
You were too busy to
discuss it in the morning,
so I talked to
Dr. Glassman about it,
and he said having a child
will shift our dynamics.
And if it does, we can
talk about it then.
So if we can't talk
about our dynamics now,
how about our differences?
Apparently we have 39 of them,
so we're gonna need a
serious chunk of time,
and I'm pretty
sure they'll keep,
because we're kinda committed
to having a kid together,
whether love is enough or not.
Shaun, I'm just... I'm
way too tired to have
a productive conversation
about this right now, okay?
Okay.
It's time to call it.
I had a half an
hour left on my call
when she first came to the ER,
coughing blood,
vitals on the floor.
When we opened her up,
her lungs looked like
they belonged to a 70-year-old.
Didn't think she'd make
it through the night.
She was eight.
I couldn't go home.
I stayed with her that night.
And then, the next
morning, she just...
opened her eyes, looked at me,
and told me she liked
my French braid.
Once I call it...
I have to go up there and
tell her I failed her.
Got Riggs' latest test results.
Turns out he did have a
pre-existing condition...
Hemochromatosis.
So the jerk lied about
it to get into the study.
That's your assumption?
He got $3,500 to participate.
I think it's a pretty
sound assumption.
But whether he lied or not,
it means the screeners
are incompetent.
That's gotta take a toll.
Expecting the
worst of everybody.
I'd rather be pleasantly surprised
than bitterly disappointed.
And that's the worldview you want
to impart to your future child,
"Assume the worst of everyone"?
Help!
We need help in here!
What's happening?
Add a milligram of
lorazepam. He's seizing.
Because his
ICPs are in the 40s.
Cerebral edema's gotten worse.
If we don't open up
Ricky's skull immediately,
he will die.
Removing large
hemicrani skull flap.
Performing wide dural opening.
Look at the monitor.
EEG's all over the place.
He's still seizing.
Place an additional EVD and
increase propofol to burst suppress.
Eh, but he's maxed out.
If we give him any more
propofol, we could kill him.
If we don't, the seizures
will definitely kill him.
Oh. We can
remove the damaged cortex
in the left anterior
temporal lobe
using ECoG and pre-op
imaging to guide us.
Cut out part of his
brain? That's a little extreme.
It is the area
that's causing the seizures.
It'll just be a
tough sell to his parents.
Which is
why you will help.
Okay, please keep him stabilized
with iced LR to the cortical surface.
Uh...
"The country flew past
as if they were seeing it
from the windows of
an express train.
Faster and faster they raced,
but no one got tired
or out of breath."
We can save the last
chapter for later.
There is no later.
Where's Dr. L?
She wasn't ready to
give up on your lungs.
There's still a chance?
Dr. Lim thinks so.
♪ Your glass is on your side ♪
Let's finish.
♪ And tell someone you love
How much you need them ♪
♪ To be strong ♪
♪ Hold on ♪
"Chapter 16.
Farewell to the Shadowlands."
We would cut out a
small piece of his cortex.
It's already been
damaged by the infection.
Removing it may be the
only way to keep him alive.
But how would that affect him?
There are areas of the brain
that are significantly
less essential than others.
This part only impacts
his speech and memory,
probably not long-term.
So he might not be able to
talk or know who we are?
We wouldn't be able to fully
assess him until he wakes up.
Ricky's skull is open.
We should do it.
Uh, th-this is a
very good hospital,
these are very smart doctors.
And someone very wise
once told me that, uh,
"Sometimes you just have to
trust that things will work out."
Okay.
Hmm.
Hemochromatosis?
You never noticed the
symptoms until now?
Joint pain, fatigue,
mental fuzziness?
Well, I turn 58 next week.
I mean, I haven't felt
a day over 30 until now.
It is very unlikely
your hemochromatosis
went from 0 to 60 in a week.
Is it possible you gave the
screeners someone else's blood?
You think I cheated?
For the money?
No, Mr. Riggs, I'm
just trying to...
You're a blood donor
in the 20-gallon club?
Yeah, regular donor,
last 30 years.
When was the last
time you donated?
Two months ago, just before
I started this trial.
And you're not allowed to donate
while you're in the trial.
Well, see, that's the downside.
I actually enjoy those cookies.
I'll make sure you get all the
cookies you want, Mr. Riggs.
Don't you think it's
time to come home?
No.
Well, in that case...
I wanted to make you
something delicious
like you've made us,
but I'm not a very good cook,
and everything's closed.
So, I hope you like
hot-dog-flavored potato chips
and Nutty Buddies.
Mmm.
Yeah.
Nail polish?
Father-daughter time.
Maddie insisted that
she paint my fingernails
a sparkly rainbow color.
The next day, my first patient
was very uncomfortable.
That's when I realized I forgot
to remove the nail polish.
That's a nice memory.
Oh, sit. No, sit, sit, sit.
So many memories.
The Halloween Maddie
wanted to go as a ham
because we'd just seen
To Kill a Mockingbird.
But she wanted the ham to be
made out of an actual ham.
And then, one night, the
wind was blowing so hard,
it blew her bedroom door shut.
She was convinced that
her grandmother's ghost
had come back to visit her.
Wanted to sleep in our bed
for the next two weeks.
You didn't come here just to
feed me junk food, did you?
I thought you might
need someone to talk to.
I'm fine.
Hmm.
I know someone you
should talk to.
I know.
But this was easier.
Mmm.
Hot dogs should not be a flavor.
"All their life in this world
and all their
adventures in Narnia
had only been the cover
and the title page.
Now, at last, they were
beginning chapter one
of the great story
which no one on earth has read,
which goes on forever,
in which every chapter is
better than the one before."
♪ Coming home With
your song In my heart ♪
Checking in.
Need me to up your morphine?
Couldn't hurt.
♪ ...in my heart ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Coming home with
your song In my heart ♪
Hey, I changed my mind.
About the vlog.
Wonderful.
♪ Cry out in the cold ♪
♪ Chasing hours
And your hand... ♪
Go for it.
Hey, Roses.
I'm back.
The DLT didn't really work out,
so...
this is gonna be my last update.
I wasn't even gonna do this.
I was gonna flip
off Dylan Thomas
and go gently into
that good night.
But...
I couldn't leave
without saying goodbye.
And that...
it's okay to be hurt...
I am...
that my life's been cut short.
But the upside to all of this
is that I feel something
I never thought I would.
It's gratitude.
I'm grateful to my sweet mother
and
to the people who
keep hope alive.
Like Dr. L and...
♪ ...with your
song In my heart ♪
Crash cart!
She's in full
respiratory failure.
- We need to intubate her.
- No.
We need to let her go.
Noomie hit 402. Get
Brecka to the OR.
The lungs are good.
We should intubate.
Yes.
- Ricky?
- Dr. Murphy!
Ricky, can you hear us?
Hello.
Do you know where you are?
Do you know your name?
I'm Ricky Pavlovic.
I'm in the hospital
because I stepped on a
rusty nail at church camp.
But I would still like to
go back there next year.
Welcome home, Noomie.
So Riggs is a
lifelong blood donor.
Which totally
eliminated his symptoms.
Until he started this trial.
He's not allowed to
donate till it's over,
so there was nothing
wrong with the protocols,
nobody was incompetent,
and Riggs isn't a big fat liar.
In fact, he's a legit hero.
Maybe my worldview does
need a little adjustment.
I prefer Italian roast.
Noted.
Ready to take Noomie
for a test run?
That's what she
named your lungs.
It was a weird night.
Start small.
♪ I see all the
light That lifts us ♪
- ♪ Hitting on the edges
Of our wings ♪
♪ Choirs of stars
Gathered before us ♪
♪ To light the path
Beneath our feet ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
♪ Hey, courage Be my compass ♪
♪ Start a fire deep within ♪
♪ 'Cause I run With
everything And nothing ♪
Thanks for coming.
We should talk.
♪ ...where to begin ♪
♪ We fall ♪
♪ We fly ♪
♪ We'll all be, we'll all
be We'll all be alright ♪
Number 39,
dietary restrictions.
Other than breast milk...
Oh, I felt a kick.
♪ We'll all be We'll all be ♪
- ♪ We'll all be alright ♪
- Oh!
This is very exciting.
Come here.
Think of all the new
memories waiting to be made.
♪ We fall ♪
♪ We fly ♪
Hey, let's go home.
♪ We'll all be, we'll all
be We'll all be alright ♪
Number 39, other
than breast milk,
I don't think that Peanut
should have any dairy
products before six months.
Easy peasy. Number 38?
♪ We'll all be We'll all
be We'll all be alright ♪