Almost half of this country
doesn't go to the doctor
when they should.
Many don't have access,
but a lot of others,
they just don't want to.
♪ The end's in sight now ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ No one left behind ♪
♪ And you don't ask why ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ We all are safe here ♪
Because they don't believe
anything is actually wrong.
Illuminating exchange.
Any Maggie sightings
today?
Uh, well, I sent Zola up
with food.
She refused it.
We'll know when to push.
I wish I could just
stay in bed.
I actually might.
I might go back to bed.
No.
Not doing that.
I'm gonna be brave.
I'm gonna face this.
First chance I get.
Rigorous honesty.
What are we
talking about?
♪ In the spotlight ♪
♪ Stand up, cuz,
you're in the spotlight ♪
Um... may I?
♪ You were made for it ♪
- I'm Cormac Hayes.
- Amelia.
And... God, yes.
I-I mean... yes,
that is...
very helpful.
♪ Ooh ♪
Dr. Grey.
Morning.
Hello.
Coffee?
♪ Ooh ♪
Me?
- Yeah.
- No, I'm good. Thanks.
Very good coffee
for a hospital.
Or for anywhere,
really.
Yeah, Seattle is kind of known
for its coffee.
It's, uh, better
at the cart outside.
Right.
Noted and appreciated.
That is
a very well-wrapped gift.
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ La, la, la ♪
Hey!
Plastics needs to look
at the facial lac in bed 6.
MVC victim in trauma 2
is about to go up to CT.
I've got ortho on the way
to assess the girl in bed 4.
- Dr. Altman?
- Yeah?
Uh,
what are you doing?
- I lost my engagement ring.
- Oh.
Oh, no!
Isn't that, like,
some sort of...
- Hunt family heirloom?
- Yes.
Ugh. That's why I never take
mine off except for surgery.
I'll...
I'll keep an eye out.
You told me to take
some time to think,
which I didn't like, because
two people who are together
should think through things
together.
Look, I-I did a routine lap appy
on a patient,
and she's
not getting better.
She's post op day three,
she's fevering,
she's got
a high white count.
I did a sepsis workup.
It all came back negative.
Okay, well,
I'll think on it.
In the meantime,
I think you should fill Bailey in.
Yeah.
Speaking Italian...
Hey.
You know, I didn't dump you,
Meredith, so...
you don't have to miss me.
Coffee smells good.
You okay?
Coffee smells bad?
Uh... baby's kicking?
You woke up this morning
with a deep knowing
I'm not fatherhood material?
Link, I hate this.
I... I'm not sure
that I have the ability
to convey
how much I hate this.
But I promise you,
no blood test can change
the way I feel about you.
It's just a matter
of some cells.
I... still have no idea
what you're talking about.
I am more pregnant
than I thought.
Okay...?
Which means there is a chance
that you aren't the father.
It took me a few days
to work up the nerve
to tell you.
We're talking about Owen,
right?
Yeah.
Does he know?
I'm talking to you first.
Because I don't need
a paternity test
to know that I want
to be with you.
I love what we have.
I love your kindness
and I love our ease
and I love that you
make me laugh all the time
and you have yet
to make me cry.
I'm in love with you,
Link.
And the genetics
don't matter to me.
But I have been sitting with it
for a few days,
and you haven't.
So...
Take some time
to think.
Welcome back,
Dr. Bailey.
Quick update on the residents...
We've removed Simms' trach
and started him
on a soft diet.
Helm's chest tubes
were removed,
and she actually took
a couple steps today with PT.
Parker left
for neural rehab,
and Schmitt was discharged with
a couple weeks' medical leave.
Sounds like
you're pretty busy.
Yeah, I am.
So, why are you
glued to my side right now?
I was hoping you could weigh in
on an appy patient of mine.
She's post-op day three.
She's been giving me
more questions than answers.
Mm. Lead the way.
Dr. Bailey. A funny thing
happened yesterday.
I came to your office
for a budget meeting,
and you weren't there.
I took some personal days.
Even when half your residents
are on bedpans?
That's great timing,
Chief.
I-I asked
some of the other departments
to lend us
some residents
for surgical floor
and ICU coverage.
- They were happy to help.
- Even so,
next time
you want to take a vacay,
run it up the flagpole,
as in me.
D... Uh, thank you.
- Mom?
- Yes, honey?
Can I be done?
Just a few more times, sweet girl.
You got this.
Oh. It's her therapy.
I know it looks nuts.
Mei I. was adopted
from an orphanage,
and she was recently diagnosed
with attachment disorder,
so we've been doing
this crawling therapy
because it's supposed to
rewire her brain.
But you got to do it every day,
and you got to be
super consistent with it
every day.
Hi.
I'm her sister.
It was an appendectomy.
You said it went without a hitch.
So, um,
why are we still here?
Take this. Please.
She's been spiking fevers
every night.
Yeah, I know.
I'm asking why.
- And I have brought our
- Mom? Yes, sweetheart.
chief of surgery to help
determine that.
- Uh, here. You, too, sweetheart.
- Here.
Dr. Bailey,
Suzanne Britland.
- Hi.
- Good morning.
Ms. Britland,
how are you feeling?
- She has a sore throat.
- He has a sore throat.
It's just a little sore.
I'm probably
just getting a cold.
It could still be
from the intubation.
Could be.
I know that the answer
is probably "no,"
but is there any way
you could just send me home
with some antibiotics?
Not until you've been fever-free
for 24 hours. I'm sorry.
Oh, it's just, the kids are
missing so much school.
Well, I can take them
to school.
- No!
Okay.
It's okay.
Their dad died
last year.
He had a migraine,
and then when it got really bad,
we took him to the ER,
and the doctors told us
we could go home
and he would be fine,
and then...
..he very much wasn't.
We are running
a fresh set of labs,
and we hope
to know more soon.
Okay.
Dr. Grey.
Hey.
So,
elephant in the room...
I'm not sure what Cristina
said to you, but...
- Who?
- ..I...
..never mind.
Who did you say?
Never mind.
Are you coming
to the pit?
- What?
- The pit.
- The what?
- The ER.
You call the ER
"the pit"?
- Yeah.
- Why?
I don't know.
Oh, my God! Kai?
What's happening
to him?
What do we know?
17 years old.
He came in with
shortness of breath.
He just started
coughing up blood.
- We need suction and an intubation tray.
- Help him, please!
We should set up for
an emergency bronchoscopy also.
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 16  Episode 11
Title: "A Hard Pill to Swallow"
Sync corrections by srjanapala
The door is frosted,
and the curtains were drawn.
You can't see inside.
Was I wrong?
What are you doing here?
Um, well, I was thinking
about taking you to breakfast,
but, uh,
now that I see you,
um, I'm thinking eat in.
How's pancakes sound?
What?
I didn't know
you could cook.
Please.
Hey!
Hey.
What's, uh...
What are we...
Oh. Oh, wait.
Are you meditating?
- I'm sorry. I can...
- No. No, I was...
Amelia said
the baby might be Owen's.
What?
Somebody help me, please!
All these blue pajamas, I can't
get any help over here?!
- Oh, sorry. The ER's this way.
- What happened?
We'll go get your hand fixed up,
and I promise you can punch me.
Okay,
what happened?
I'm trying to rush Chuck
to the ER,
and I accidentally slammed
his hand in the cab's door.
Wait. Why were you
rushing to the ER?
Oh,
because of the fish.
There's a fish
inside of there.
What, like... like,
part of a fish or a bone or...
No,
an entire fish, sir.
- Okay, Link, with you...
- Later.
Spilling blood
everywhere.
Kai's bronchoscopy was
surprisingly clean.
We didn't see any bleeding
in his lungs,
just some inflammation.
Isn't that good news?
Not exactly.
Dr. Grey did an EGD.
She found the source
of the bleed in his esophagus.
We're just not sure
exactly why he's bleeding.
Everything was normal
at practice.
He started hacking up
like crazy.
I mean,
Kai's never sick.
Kai's the best
on the team.
He's got the fastest 200
in the school's history.
Does he drink or smoke?
No way. All he cares about
is his swimming.
This bleeding...
You can stop it?
We stopped it long enough
to get your son up to CT,
so we'll keep you posted,
okay?
All the places in the world
to put food...
and yet, no food.
How do you people
eat here?
Three kids who eat
like a pack of wolves.
Richard, you don't
have to do this.
What am I doing here?
Forgiving me or... or...
putting me back together.
Whatever this is.
It's called... eating.
And I don't deserve it.
Especially not from you.
We just hired
an amazing psychologist
at Pac-North.
She's excellent with sur...
with surgeons
who kill their cousins
and get sued
by their uncles?
I'm sorry. I'm...
I shouldn't...
I...
I'm useless and mean
and depressed and awful.
This is why I just...
I want to be alone.
Can... Can we just go back
to that?
Can we go back to you just not
even being able to look at me?
Maybe we start
with coffee.
Hey. Hey!
- Hey.
- Hi!
What are you doing here?
I am on my day off,
and I want
to take you for lunch,
and I want to see you.
And...
I want to talk
wedding plans.
- That's so sweet.
- Mm-hmm.
Mm.
I'm sorry.
I lost
your engagement ring.
I lost the ring
that your grandfather
brought back from France
after he helped liberate Paris.
And I knew that this is such an
important ring to your family,
and I wasn't gonna tell you,
but then I knew
that you were obviously
gonna notice and...
- Teddy, Teddy, stop crying.
- It's okay. It's okay.
No! No! It's... It's not.
It's not okay.
This ring means everything
to you.
Maybe a little.
More to my mom.
You know,
she's gonna kill me.
Or you.
S-She's not gonna know,
okay?
We're not gonna say anything
because we are going to find it.
Okay?
Okay, we'll look together.
Okay.
Alright,
what happened, exactly?
The bar had an aquarium.
Alright, so we're winding down
Chuck's bachelor party.
You know what I'm saying?
It's his bachelor party.
So, we start
daring each other
to swallow fish
from the aquarium.
You know how it is...
End of the night?
- Yeah. Okay.
- No.
I honestly worry for
your entire gender sometimes.
Anyway, he grabbed
the biggest one.
We didn't think
he was gonna do it.
We're like,
"He ain't about to do it."
He gulps
the whole damn fish,
and I guess
the fish didn't like that,
so the fish start fighting back,
start slapping...
just start going crazy,
and it goes in deeper, deeper.
We tried to pull it out.
It would not come out.
And then
it kind of puffed up.
That... doesn't sound like
a goldfish.
Yeah. No.
And according to this X-ray,
this thing's got spikes.
And then I got scared
because I thought
he was gonna choke or puke.
Or that the fish
could be poisonous.
I didn't even think
of that.
I'm-a call the bar,
see what kind of fish it was.
You think you'd have better luck
just writing it down?
Oh, yeah.
Write it down.
"Please don't tell
Roxanne."
Yeah,
that's his fiancée.
She told us
not to do anything stupid.
- Hey. - Aptitude is like
having a talent for something.
Great.
Okay, what do we got next?
Ooh. "Penultimate."
Uh, uh...
I don't know.
"Guys, that was
the penultimate concert."
Wait, was it the second-to-last
concert you ever saw?
'Cause "penultimate"
means "second-to-last."
It does not mean
"super-extra ultimate."
- Mom, the doctors.
- What? Really?
Vocab homework. Did you know
that "penultimate" means...
"Second-to-last."
Yeah, I knew that.
Excellent. Any chance you also
know what's wrong with my sister?
Well, the labs showed your
white counts are way up again.
It's likely just an abscess
developing in your abdomen.
We'd like to monitor you
one more night,
get a CT in the morning
if things don't improve.
No!
No more days!
- Okay, come on, guys.
We listen to the doctors. - Okay, okay.
We are not big fans
of hospitals,
'cause, you know...
last time.
So, we are keeping
brave faces,
but we would very much like
for last night to be
my penultimate night
in the hospital.
Ding, ding, ding!
See, that is
the correct usage.
Lock it in, Matty.
Well, I can't see
why we need to wait,
so, DeLuca,
let's get her a CT now.
Okay.
His friend called the bar.
The bronze catfish.
The spines do give off
a low-level toxin
when attacked
by other fish.
Or being swallowed
by a dumb-ass human.
But it's not enough
to worry about, so...
So...
..you're not freaking out?
What?
No.
No, it doesn't really
change anything, right?
Except for, like,
everything.
If it's Owen's kid, he's gonna
want to be in his life.
He's gonna want
to raise him, right?
Allison's awesome,
so Owen's got great genes,
he's a veteran dad by now,
and he's engaged to Teddy,
so the kid'll have,
like, eight parents.
It's all hypothetical,
anyway.
Amelia doesn't want
a paternity test.
She says
it doesn't matter.
Wai... What?!
And you're okay with that?
Oh, wait, wait, are you doing
that thing where you pretend
to be all cool and evolved
and optimistic
but you're secretly
losing your mind?
Nope.
You can love her
And be mad at her
at the same time.
Both things can be true.
Yesterday,
I made coffee in here,
and then
I washed my hands.
So, you're sure
that it's here?
I think.
Wait. Wait.
You think?
Teddy, are we even
in the right lounge?
Yes, yes, because I showed it
to Meredith in here,
and she said
that it was beautiful.
Well, that's great.
Oh, hey.
You're... operating
on a sink.
Yeah, we're looking
for a ring.
You haven't seen one,
by chance, have you?
No.
Uh, maybe
we should, um,
maybe we should
call maintenance.
Yep. I don't think
it's down here.
Okay.
Are you okay?
Hey.
U-Uh... dizzy.
A... little dizzy.
It happens with,
um... anxiety.
- You... You should sit down.
- Yes.
I think
I should sit down, too.
Why are you anxious?
I-I'm worried about...
..your ring.
- Teddy?
- Yeah?
Leo just threw up
all over daycare.
We should...
I've got a couple of boys
at home this age.
I had to read
a whole book
about how their brains
haven't fully developed yet.
It's the only way
I could manage to forgive them.
For what?
Everything they do.
I came home the other night,
and the oldest one
was throwing a tennis ball
as hard as he could
over and over
at the younger one's head.
The game was,
could his brother dodge it
before he got
brain damage?
Sorry.
I shouldn't laugh at that.
Listen, Grey, uh...
the other day...
it was kind of a tough day
for me.
I get a bit dark
this time of year
because it's, um...
it's when I lost their mum.
Cancer.
So, um...
you know,
I hope we can...
start over.
Sure.
How long ago
did she pass?
Uh, two years ago
last week.
Two years is tough.
Yeah.
Gets better.
Not all the way better,
obviously,
but...
a little bit better.
Look at the inflammation
in his lungs.
I mean... you said
he was an athlete.
These are the lungs
of a 60-year-old smoker.
I've seen this before.
I bet you a naggin
he vapes.
Vaping? No way!
He follows
all the training rules.
This is no time
for secrets, lads.
If you know
something...
I mean, yeah.
He vapes.
Half the school does,
though.
And, I mean,
it wouldn't hurt him.
It's not like
smoking.
How is it
not like smoking?
There's no smoke.
Your lungs are meant
to inhale air, not smoke
and not vapors
filled with chemicals.
Look.
See there?
That's what a normal lung
looks like.
That's your mate's lungs.
Does that look safe
to you?
Damn. That's disgusting.
Disgusting?
It's more than disgusting.
People are dying
from this stuff.
Go and tell your friends.
I mean it! Go!
Go and tell
half the school
they're turning their lungs
into rubbish dumps.
Get out of my face!
Go!
You said "dying."
Is my son dying?
No. He's not.
But with his lungs
in this bad a shape,
our only definitive option
is to repair the esophagus
and remove part of the lung.
Remove p...
Well, it's not
our only option.
I mean, we could try to stop the
bleeding by coiling the artery.
Then he would lose
less lung capacity.
Yes, but it might not
be enough
to prevent more bleeding
in the future.
That's true.
But if it were my kid,
I guess I would just rather
take the least invasive
option
and try to not cut
a piece of the lung out.
That sounds safer.
It is safer, and it
preserves lung function.
Then that's what I want.
Okay.
We'll get back to you.
In that case, Dr. Grey,
I'll defer to you.
Well, no. I mean,
I didn't mean
- No, please. You should do it.
- That I...
Okay.
Rubbish dumps, huh?
You really like
terrifying these parents.
I was trying
to terrify the kids.
Richard, I just want
to be alone.
I want to be alone,
too.
But I came here
to find out why you quit.
Maggie, you're family,
and you're hurting,
and you're hiding
because you lost Sabi.
You've lost patients
before.
Not like this.
Maggie, she was practically dead
when she came in.
Her only shot
was with you.
Richard...
let's not pretend...
Look, the reason
I couldn't look at you
isn't because of
what you did to Sabi.
It's because of
what I did to you.
I...
I sent you in there.
I knew that it was likely
that you would lose her,
but I wanted to give her
a fighting chance.
She wasn't a lost cause,
Richard.
I made a mistake.
I didn't check her ACT
with the perfusionist.
I, uh, I didn't...
know that the protocol was
different at Pac-North.
I just assumed they'd tell me,
and they didn't.
Sabi is dead
because I didn't ask.
I told her I was the best,
I told her I was brilliant,
and I-I couldn't
even be clear in my OR.
I was arrogant,
and I was blinded by emotion,
and now Sabi is dead.
And I can't change it,
and I can't fix it.
And I can't go back into an OR
and pretend I belong there
after what I've done.
Please, just go.
Please.
- What'd he have for breakfast?
- Oatmeal.
He probably caught something
from that kid Lucas.
I swear, he is Patient Zero
for half this hospital.
You know, getting an X-ray
probably wasn't even necessary.
Well, you said that he didn't
seem like himself this morning.
Well,
I say a lot of things.
See?
What?
You are mad at me
about the ring.
I'm not mad.
I'm just...
You are. You're practically
biting the air as you speak.
What? I'm...
Images should be coming up now
on the monitor right there.
Great. Thank you.
- Is that...
- Yep.
Oh, Leo.
You ate my ring.
Okay.
There it is.
Deploying the coil.
Nice.
Steady coming back.
You know, if you wanted
to do this yourself,
I did offer you
the option.
I didn't want
to do it myself.
This isn't the first time
I've seen lungs
destroyed by this stuff.
That's how
I recognized it.
Very often,
there is a rebleed.
Yep. There it is.
Damn it!
The tube's only a temporary fix.
We need to open him up.
Okay, wait a minute,
because maybe I can deploy another coil.
He doesn't have a minute.
The coils have failed.
This is exactly
what I was talking about.
Prep his chest
for a thoracotomy.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't be sorry.
Tried it your way.
Now help me with mine.
Damn it.
It keeps breaking
into smaller pieces.
Every time
I think I've seen
the craziest, dumbest things
a person can do...
the ER's just like,
"Hold my beer."
Maybe he had
reservations.
Maybe this is
the sort of thing
he would never do
in a million years,
but he was in the moment.
He was feeling good
and... and... and happy,
and his friends had just
thrown him this great party,
and he didn't want
to let them down.
So, he was just
in this impossible situation
that couldn't be avoided.
Except... if he just didn't
swallow the fish, man.
Right. Okay.
Drill.
Stapler.
Good exposure
of the fistula.
Full disclosure...
This isn't the first time
I've had the debate about whether
to coil or resect, either.
No? So, I was wrong
but I'm not alone?
- Thanks.
- No.
Last time,
I was on your side.
Woman in her 40s, vaped like a chimney.
I was convinced I could coil
and stop the bleeding,
even though my colleague
adamantly disagreed.
I didn't even get as far as you did
before everything went sideways.
Specimen.
Who was the colleague?
Head of
the Klausman Institute.
Dr. Yang.
Absolute nightmare.
Oh, wow.
I do not like it in here.
Feels like...
the inside of a coffin.
You know, I've never actually
been in a coffin, but this is
definitely how
I pictured it feeling.
We're almost done here,
Suzanne.
There's no signs of abscess
in the right lower quadrant.
So, whatever this is,
it's likely not your screw-up.
Oh.
So, I-I heard right.
Nurse told me my chief was
doing follow-ups on an appy.
Seemed too crazy to be true,
but here we are.
I guess it makes sense,
though.
Ease yourself back
into the real work. Y...
Everything okay?
Not really,
but thanks for asking.
What?
I'm calling a code.
Oh, get her out. Get her out!
Code Blue.
Blood pressure's
dropping.
Mm. JVD.
And muffled heart sounds.
She's got
cardiac tamponade.
She's not gonna make it
to the OR.
We need to aspirate her
right here.
Okay, give me an 18 gauge needle
on a syringe.
Betadine.
Come on, Suzanne.
Inserting the needle.
Come on. Come on!
Come on. Suzanne, come on!
Those kids need you.
I managed to remove
all the spines.
You're likely gonna
experience some discomfort
in your throat
for the next few days.
And your hand
is repaired.
Uh, but I need to have you
follow up with me
in a couple of weeks.
Hey, so, you guys, uh...
You guys are smart.
You're doctors, right?
So, how do I
tell Roxanne?
I mean, what should I
tell my fiancée?
Maybe just tell her
the truth.
She might think
it's hilarious.
No, she definitely won't
think it's hilarious.
I don't know, man.
She looked past that time
you crashed her Volvo
into that pond
or when you sorta
got her dad arrested.
No known predators,
Chuck!
Hey, babe!
The bronze catfish has
no known predators, Chuck!
She knows.
Would you two like a little privacy?
Yeah.
No known predators.
That means you have
worse survival instincts
than any other creature
on Earth!
You are dumber than
a turtle!
Y-You are dumber
than a chicken!
You are dumber than
a frog!
- Is he gonna live?
- He'll be fine. - Yeah. - Mm-hmm.
You may have to modify
the tux to fit over the cast.
No, there's not gonna be
any kind of tux.
I just needed to know
that he was gonna survive this
so that I wouldn't feel guilty
for leaving him.
Whoa!
Babe, I... come on.
I mean,
they... they dared me.
Last month, my mother
offered me $10,000
to push the wedding back
a year.
One year.
I told her no!
I said it was just
'cause she couldn't see you
for who you are.
But it turns out
it was me.
I couldn't see you
for who you are
because the sex is good
and because
you make me laugh.
And I just keep excusing
your unbelievable stupidity.
I keep making excuses
for you.
You about to leave him?
Because I ate a catfish?
Damn it.
No.
I am leaving you
because this is not
the life that I want.
And when someone shows you
who they are over and over,
you're supposed to
believe them.
The CT revealed
no abscess or infection
from the surgery,
but there was fluid
around her heart,
which we were able
to remove.
So, she's okay?
She's gonna be okay?
It was
a temporary measure.
Unfortunately...
we still don't know
the cause.
Well, how long
'til you do know?
We're sending the fluid
we aspirated from the heart
to the lab.
We'll also send
new blood cultures.
W-We'll keep looking,
but at this point,
we just don't know.
I-I'm so sorry.
Mommy, Mommy!
Mei Mei!
Oh, no, no, no, no! You can't go in there!
Hey, hey! Come back!
Mommy, I want to go home.
Let's go home.
Okay,
back away from her, Mei Li.
- I'm sorry. We can't risk infection.
- Hey.
Sweet girl, look at me.
Look at me.
I'm here.
I'm alive.
I'm not dying.
I'm not sick
like Daddy was sick.
And these doctors...
Oh, baby girl,
these doctors...
They are the best.
They're the smartest.
They're gonna
figure this out.
♪ It's walking out on a wire ♪
Right?
- Thanks.
- I'm sorry.
Right?
Are you gonna figure this out?
♪ It can turn ya into a fool,
it can feel so cruel ♪
Oh, boy.
You guys have been through
so much already.
I can see that.
Uh, and...
and yes.
We are going to
figure this out.
Put every brain on this
you can find.
Create a war room.
We're not letting
that mother die. You hear me?
I'm on it.
♪ It can give you hell ♪
♪ Or pull ya through it ♪
♪ Yeah, hope may disappoint us ♪
♪ But we hold on anyway ♪
What is this?
It's called food.
Let's see what it's like
to actually eat some.
How did you even
get in here?
You know, you all should
really move that spare key
to under
a more convenient rock.
I nearly
threw my back out.
Please.
Please, just...
just yell,
just be mad at me.
Okay, I liked her.
I-I-I really loved
the idea
of finally having
one of those big families
like I saw all my friends
growing up with
when I was a kid,
and I only got her for one day,
and then she was gone.
But you...
you lost your niece.
And probably your brother.
I destroyed your family,
and they deserve to sue me
for everything that I've got.
Why don't you
make yourself useful
and open the flour,
would you?
Guess I can see
who I inherited my distaste
for sharing my emotions from.
When, uh...
I was only 10 years old...
when my mother died.
I don't remember much,
you know,
but I remember
I was temperamental sometimes.
A "hot head," she called it.
But she wouldn't send me
to a time-out
or... make me sit and think
about what I've done.
She would go
to the kitchen
and she would make us both
some pancakes,
and she'd say,
"Let's talk about it
after you've had
something to eat."
She didn't get a chance
to teach me much.
But it's a lesson
I'll never forget.
Ah, let's see.
I've been doing it
over and over again.
I've been... going over
every second of Sabi.
I've been replaying in my mind
and just...
wondering what
I could have done
better, smarter...
- faster.
- It's not on you.
Family doesn't operate
on family, Maggie.
I knew better.
I put you in that OR anyway
out of desperation.
I made a mistake.
And now Sabi is dead.
And you'll never
make that mistake again.
That's what you say
to interns
who... who have lost
their first patient, not to...
They're human.
And imperfect.
Like you.
No one has ever
had to tell me that before.
Then let Sabi's legacy
be that.
She taught you
what years of school
and residency
and countless hours
never did.
Maggie, you have insurance
for this.
They'll settle with Chris.
It won't bring Sabi back,
but he'll feel like
he's got some justice for her.
And he needs that.
Every surgeon I know
goes through this.
And if you quit now,
you'll be quitting
on all those lives
that only you can save.
And I know
Sabi wouldn't want that.
I wish I could've had
more time with her.
Well, ask me
anything you want about her.
No. Richard,
I am not gonna make you...
No, you know, truth be told,
talking about her
is about the only thing
I want to do right now.
Okay,
you don't have to stay
if you need
to check in downstairs.
No, I'm staying.
I feel awful.
Listen, we know
where the ring is, Teddy,
and it's not
perforating anything.
He's gonna be fine.
I mean, kids do
this kind of stuff, you know?
We see cases like this
all the time.
I know, Owen,
but I feel awful.
I mean, your grandmother
and your mom all wore the ring,
and it's survived
in your family for years,
through wars
and depressions,
and I couldn't even
keep it for a week.
'Cause you're tired
and overworked, you know?
Could have been
a lot worse.
You know, at least you didn't
leave it inside a patient.
Yeah, well,
now it's inside our child.
Teddy, I shouldn't have given
you the ring in the first place.
You're a trauma surgeon.
No, but I-I want
to wear the ring.
I love the ring.
And...
And I-I love you.
Okay.
- You have a necklace.
- Mm-hmm.
And you have an A for Allison
and an I for Leo.
How about
we add a T and an O
and you can wear your entire
family around your neck?
Okay?
And we're gonna
keep that ring in a safe
for special occasions,
okay?
I have never
loved you more.
Do you smell that?
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Rock...
You know what? I got it.
This one's on me.
- You sure?
- Mm-hmm.
- 'Cause it's...
- I know. Go.
Let's do this.
Kai's condition
was too advanced
to successfully coil
the bleeding vessel,
so we had to open him up,
do the partial lung resection.
It's going to be
a difficult recovery.
In time, he will
be able to swim,
but not competitively,
I'm afraid.
That stuff...
It's flavored
like French toast, right?
Mm-hmm.
I always smell
French toast.
I feel like an idiot
I didn't know.
They're targeting kids.
It's flavored like cotton candy
and bubble gum, as well.
You're not an idiot.
They're evil.
Thank you
for saving my son.
Don't worry.
I won't rub it in.
I'm sorry.
Listen, when I was
on the other side of this,
Yang drove me mad.
She'd leave me notes all over
the place every day for months.
"I was right.
You were wrong."
Little pictures
of resected lungs.
Well,
sounds about right.
Wait, you know her?
I, um...
W...
Um... I gotta go.
Most patients put off
facing the truth as long as possible.
And we get it.
We do it, too.
We ignore things.
We stay under the covers.
We don't pick up
the phone.
Ah. I thought you'd have
some work to catch up on.
You... You probably need
to do some unpacking,
shake the sand out from
the beach, do some laundry...
I wasn't on vacation,
Tom.
I sat in my house
for three days.
I didn't get out of bed,
I drank chamomile tea,
and I cried my eyes out
because I had a miscarriage.
That happened,
I'm sad about it,
and I'm taking care
of myself.
Any questions?
- You could have told me.
- I just did.
W... Light a candle.
What?
When my wife...
Uh, my ex-wife, uh, Dana...
She miscarried twice
before we had David.
Once at 10 weeks,
once at 18, which was...
Well, I mean, you know...
You know how it was.
I mean, people have
this idea that, uh...
you just get over it,
that, uh, you know,
you're sad and you move on.
But... that wasn't
my experience.
Wasn't
my wife's experience.
So every year, still,
uh, on what would be
their birthdays,
I, uh,
I light a candle.
They took with them
little pieces of our... hearts,
and those pieces
will never be...
replaced.
So, maybe, uh...
light a candle.
Yeah.
We don't face the music
and all that crap.
♪ Mamma,
you have shown me love ♪
You paged me
to the plant room.
Never a good sign.
When someone shows you
who they are,
you're supposed to
believe them.
Someone said that today,
and it... it kinda hit me.
We're doctors.
There are tests.
If there was a question
who the father was,
I should have known that
from the beginning.
You're right.
I'm not always...
measured.
I'm not ever
I'm a little bit chaotic.
I fly
by the seat of my pants,
and I... don't think things
all the way through,
and...
..sometimes
that hurts people.
I'm sorry
that I hurt you.
♪ Nothing here
could block your truth ♪
There are a bunch of people
involved in this.
And they deserve to know.
I deserve to know.
♪ I'm captured
by the good you do ♪
And if we do
find out...
that you're not
the father?
I want to be the guy that says,
uh, it doesn't matter,
but I don't know yet.
I don't know
how much it matters.
I guess...
I-I think we should...
take it
one step at a time.
Gather information.
So much for me
never making you cry.
But the longer we hide,
the worse it can be.
So, open the test results.
Hey.
Have the hard conversation.
I got your text.
Say what you mean.
Hey, maybe
we should go to dinner
and clear your head
a little bit.
Her name's Suzanne,
she's got two young kids,
she's a single mom,
and I think she's dying.
Okay.
Are these from today?
Yeah,
she crashed on me.
I had to aspirate
a cardiac tamponade... in CT.
I don't get it.
It was a simple appy,
a no-brainer case,
and... and now,
I mean, look at all this.
She's...
She's getting worse.
And I don't know why
or how to help her.
Hey.
Andrew, look at me.
Walk me through it.
From the beginning.
- Good or bad...
- Okay.
..you may be surprised
at what you find.
You're right. Okay.
She was post-op,
day three...
♪ Whoa, whoa ♪
♪ Have no fear ♪
Oh.
How was your day?
Uh, uneventful.
Dr. Wells from Pac-North called,
looking for you.
Said you didn't go to work.
I didn't.
I was... trying to convince
Maggie to go back to work.
And that took you
all day?
Yes.
♪ Have no fear ♪
Catherine, this isn't gonna work
if you don't trust me.
Who said this is working?
Well,
what are you saying?
Richard...
I think it's time for us
to have
a much bigger conversation.
♪ Beloved ain't enough ♪
And at the very least,
you'll know
what you're dealing with.
Sync corrections by srjanapala