.
♪
- A passing is not an ending.
In the words
of the "Bhagavad Gita"...
"The soul cannot be
cut down by any weapon
"nor burnt by fire,
drenched by water,
"nor withered by the wind.
"We are not slain
when our bodies are slain.
We have never not existed."
- Some of you, many of you,
probably don't know about Vijay
is that he was born
before the separation
of Pakistan and India,
which led him
to become an officer
in the military, a soldier...
♪
A soldier who became a healer.
The healer who became...
- So slow.
And when I say slow, I mean the
man was practically glacial,
but those methods extended
to his bedside manner.
He would talk to his patients,
take his time,
and not because he was slow
but because he...
- Listened,
and he taught me that, uh...
you can search and search
for the answers, but sometimes,
sometimes all you need to do
is just be still
and be ready
to receive the answers,
to...
to catch them out of the air.
- Like that fly ball
that hit him right in the face.
Vijay was the absolute
worst softball player
in our league,
but, man,
Vijay running bases...
maybe it was
from playing cricket
back in the day,
but the old dude...
- Was the only doctor
to say "hello" to me
on my first day
at New Amsterdam.
I think that he knew
what it was like
to be a new physician
in a new country.
It was a simple gesture,
really,
but it meant the world to me
to be seen, and I suspect...
- Karen Brantley, you might
want to leave the room
for this one, but...
Vijay and I once snuck a
patient into another hospital--
yeah--to get him the care
that he needed.
♪
And then we had
to sneak him back.
- I didn't realize
that instead of ignoring me
when I wanted answers...
he was actually preparing me...
leading me
to not need him at all.
♪
- I just, uh...
Oh, God.
I, um...
- Light and love to you.
- You'll be forever
in our hearts.
- I'm gonna miss your wisdom.
- Thank you for blessing us.
♪
- Goodbye, Vijay.
- You know, he's still here.
- We all carry him
inside of us everywhere we go.
You can still honor him
if you need to.
- Got any prayers
you recommend?
- I was thinking lunch.
The Hindu mourning tradition's
a beautiful gesture.
By feeding others,
we feed our own grieving souls.
- There you go.
Hey, what about
the other chaplains?
- Oh, what other chaplains?
I'm all that's left.
- What?
What do you mean?
What about Reverend Salazar
or Rabbi Cohen?
Reverend Salazar
was so overworked
by the pandemic, she resigned.
- She did?
- Rabbi Cohen passed away
while helping others.
- Here you go.
- But I do what I can.
What else can we do, right?
Ooh.
- You okay?
- Yeah, enough about that.
Tell me about
jolly old England.
England.
England is, uh--it's great.
It's everything
I hoped it would be, you know?
And more, if I'm being honest.
I feel kind of guilty
saying that,
especially today,
especially here.
- Never apologize for embracing
what life shows us, Max,
especially joy.
I think that Vijay
would approve.
- I hope so.
I think I'm doing everything
Vijay would've wanted.
You know, I'm slowing things
down a little bit,
spending more time with Luna,
reading in the park,
feeling the grass under our...
Be right back.
Hey, hey, you all right?
Would you like a sandwich?
- Thank you.
- Sure.
- Help!
Someone help!
- Chaplain Alpert.
What happened?
- I don't know. He just fell.
♪
- Male, 30s, no ID.
Blood pressure is 210 over 135.
We pushed six milligrams
of Ativan and got nothing.
- Okay, okay.
Uh, Walsh, Turan, trauma one.
- Turn him around.
- One, two, and...
♪
- Push two milligrams
of Ativan.
- Were maxed out.
- Levetiracetam?
- Loading dose in.
- Starting a continuous drip.
- Okay, up his Phenytoin drip?
- Last time the paramedics
did that,
his blood pressure crashed.
- He won't survive
another hypotensive episode.
- Okay, I'm running
out of options here, guys.
♪
Load Phenobarb.
- Seriously?
- You want to induce a coma?
- I don't see another option.
- On it.
♪
- You know him?
- It's Rohan, Dr. Kapoor's son.
.
- Incoming!
Help.
- Excuse me?
- I got a 58-year-old.
Post collapse in the field.
He's stable for now.
- Okay, triage this way.
- Oh, uh, is Dr. Bloom on?
I can---
- Triage this way.
- Okay.
♪
This is not triage.
This is a waiting room.
- Brand-new.
- I'm sorry.
This is Chaplain Alpert.
He needs a full workup,
heart monitor, oxygen...
- Okay, please use
our automatic kiosk,
where you can enter
your insurance information,
credit application,
and an optional
patient satisfaction survey.
Once we have
all your information,
we'll call your number
based on a personalized
seven-point evaluation.
Okay?
♪
- So where did they, uh--
where did they move
the chemo lounge to?
- They didn't.
It was eliminated.
- Eliminated?
But the patients loved
that lounge.
They used to play
cards in there,
listen to music, laugh even.
- Dr. Fuentes thought the room
took up prime floor space.
- Prime floor space?
For what?
- This--
top-of-the-line surgical suite.
- This used to be
our hematological research lab.
- And now
it's a surgical suite.
- Okay, so where
did they put Dr. Shaffer?
- Dr. Shaffer got let go...
since we stopped
all of our stem cell trials.
- How did any of this
get past Dr. Wilder?
- Dr. Wilder?
She's been signing
these changes away
with a smile on her face.
- I want to give you
the benefit of the doubt,
and I want to be respectful,
but I'm not going
to stand idly by
while you gut the department
that I built and love and--
- And is still here, all of it,
just hidden from view.
- What do you mean?
- Welcome to the resistance.
Shut the door.
♪
- Mr. Ehrlich?
- Inside.
♪
- Oh.
Hi.
- I used to have one of these
when I was a kid,
but I remember it
being more fun.
- You're, uh--
you're Jack Ehrlich?
- Yeah, your 11:00.
- Where are your parents?
Did you--did you bring them?
- They drove me, but I told
them to grab a coffee.
They can be
a little oppressive.
- Oppressive?
- I really need your help,
Doctor.
- Okay.
Okay, what seems
to be the problem?
- I want to be emancipated.
- Huh.
How old are you?
- Almost nine.
- Which is eight.
- Okay, sure,
but hear me out.
I'm a straight-A student,
spelling bee champ.
I've been playing the piano
since I was two, so I'm ready.
- Wouldn't living on your own
require an income?
- No, because if you get
emancipated before you're 18,
your parents
have to pay child support.
- That's, uh...
- I Googled it.
- Right.
So you would buy
your own clothes,
your own food,
do your own laundry.
- I'd live close enough
to my folks so they could help.
My mom would still do
my laundry,
and my dad
could still cook me dinner.
I'm eight.
I'm not crazy.
- Hmm.
- You know,
there's coffee inside?
- Uh, yeah.
Yeah, I just wanted
to get some fresh air.
- You're trying to avoid me.
- Isn't that what you wanted?
- Us aside,
what I don't want
is for you to leave
this hospital because of me.
This ED depends on you.
If you leave, this department
and your patients will suffer.
I've been through
breakups before.
I can handle you being here,
us working together.
I have issues with you,
but the way you run an ED
isn't one of them.
- Why are you doing this?
- Because I'm not gonna be
your reason for leaving.
- You're not.
It's me.
-  Stop.
I'm not gonna
let you quit, okay?
I'll reapply for my residency.
I will find another hospital.
- No.
- Then stay.
♪
- What about Spotify?
- No.
- Pandora?
- Uh, let's get through this.
All right, there,
the graft is holding.
Let's close up Mr. Wilson.
- This is Mr. Villa.
Mr. Wilson was
three patients ago.
- Sorry, everyone.
- Cut yourself some slack.
Thanks to Veronica,
I'm starting to feel
like I'm on the line
at a GM plant.
- You know, I wouldn't mind
if we got to do anything else,
you know, like remove a tumor,
stabilize a spine.
Who do we got next?
- Uh, Jason Forbes.
63...
- Don't say it.
- CABG surgery.
- Oh, come on.
- Maybe you should talk
to Veronica?
- And say what?
That these symptoms
could've been managed
by low-cost medication,
but, no, instead
they're referring them to us
for needless
and expensive surgeries?
- That'd be a start.
- Forceps.
- 58-year-old man,
status post-cardiac arrest
and resuscitation in the field.
- Max?
- Chaplain Alpert
needs our help.
- Uh, Walsh, take the Chaplain
to curtains for a full eval.
What's with the jacket?
- What's with the waiting room?
The very first thing you ever
said to me was get rid of it.
- Veronica.
I was forced to reinstate it
when she slashed pay.
Staff naturally left, and then
Veronica cut the number of beds
to match the decreased
staffing levels.
- Let me guess--time to care
went through the roof,
so you had to put in
a waiting room.
- Then, ironically, I had to
hire more people to staff it
and, tragically,
not the people that I fired.
So I ended up
spending more time
and more money on training--
- Why didn't you tell me?
- Max, why would I?
You're not here.
- The Chaplain has severe
carotid stenosis
with right-sided heart failure.
- Okay.
Let's get surgery down here.
- I already called them.
- Hey, if you need anything--
- We're good.
It's good to see, Max, really.
♪
All right, what's the latest?
- Scans and labs
showed no sign of a brain bleed
or multi-organ failure.
- Okay.
- His BUN
and creatinine levels, however,
are through the roof
with a bicarb of 18.
- Okay, let's correct that.
- Bicarb, right away.
♪
.
- All right, so emancipation.
- Yes, and I'd prefer
if you didn't try to talk me
out of it.
- Oh, no, no, not trying to.
Not my job,
just trying to understand.
Come on, hit me back.
So, uh, were your parents
abusive at all?
- No.
- Okay.
Do you feel unsafe
or threatened?
- Nope.
- Any other member of your
family make you feel unsafe?
- You're on the wrong track,
Dr. Frome.
- Thanks for that.
Um, okay, pivot--
do you love your parents?
- Yep.
- And they know
that you want to leave?
- They do.
- How do they feel about that?
- You're on the wrong track
again, Dr. Frome.
- All right, okay,
I'm starting to get that.
Maybe you can steer me
in the right direction?
- I'm not here to talk
about my problems.
I'm here because
on advice of counsel.
- You have a lawyer?
- Two and they're total sharks.
They're gonna file a motion
for emancipation
in conjunction
with my child-support action.
And they want a shrink
to support their claim.
- I see.
- So, if I sense
you're trying to steer me
away from my stated goal,
I'll shut down
and run out the clock.
- You'd do that?
- Try me.
♪
- The narrowing
of his carotid arteries
is obstructing
the blood flow to his brain.
- Endarterectomy?
- That's what he needs.
- So when can we schedule it?
- I can't.
I don't do them anymore.
- What--since when?
Chaplain Alpert has been here--
- I know, for a long time.
And he's helped us through some
of our darkest days.
- He has, and now
it's our turn to help him.
- I want to,
but it's out of my hands.
- Out of your ha--
Floyd, you head the department.
Are you seriously telling me--
- I'm telling you this.
I'm doing the best I can under
the impossible circumstances
to keep even the most basic
procedures in this hospital--
- If we don't act now,
he's gonna die.
- Well, then send him
to Baptist.
- Baptist?
- Baptist--they'll do it,
and they'll do a good job.
- Baptist is
a private hospital.
A surgery like this is gonna
cost 100 grand--you know that.
Even with insurance, he will
never be able to afford it.
And if we can't take care of
our own, then who the hell can?
- There is no
"we" anymore, Max.
That's how it works
around here now...
If it even works at all.
♪
You're better than this.
- Am I?
♪
- What the hell happened?
- BP spiked.
He's going into SVT,
Pushing beta blockers now.
- No, wait.
- He can't wait.
He'll go into heart failure--
- Push six milligrams
of adenosine instead.
- Why?
- Just do it.
- Copy.
♪
- I got your tox screen.
- Thanks.
There's a significant increase
of amphetamines.
Apparent overdose.
If we had pushed beta blockers,
we would've killed him.
Good call, Dr. Bloom.
- Yeah, good call.
♪
- So you're basically running
a shadow hospital?
- Bingo.
- What about our research lab?
- Oh, it's not gone.
It's just, uh, moved offsite.
Secretly folded
into another lab
that we outsource
our biopsies to.
- Look at you,
you little rebel rouser.
I didn't know
you'd be so clandestine.
- Hey, we're just continuing
the tradition
that you and Max started.
How can I help?
- Chaplain Alpert
needs an endarterectomy
to save his life,
but guess what--
we don't do those anymore.
- You got my text.
- You know, he's given
everything to this hospital,
and we can't give it
back to him?
We can't give him the dignity,
the--the...
Why are we in the morgue?
- Because we're gonna save
the Chaplain's life.
- We are?
Welcome to the resistance.
♪
- Oh, there's my
holistic-wellness chieftess.
Please, have a seat.
- Thank you.
You saw my request.
How could I miss it,
being as large
and inflated as it is?
- I prefer to think of it
as aspirational.
Well, wanting an entire floor
of the hospital
certainly qualifies.
What's wrong
with your current situation?
- "Low ceilings and tiny rooms
cramp the soul and the mind."
- Dostoevsky.
- Yes, wow.
Um, oh, my gosh.
People usually just think
I'm quoting Deepak Chopra.
- Not me.
That's why I hired you.
So you want more space
for acupuncture
and for meditation.
That's a pretty big ask,
but I think
I can make that happen.
- Really?
- Why ask
if you didn't think I could?
- I--no, I'm--
Wow, wow, that's--that's great.
This is, um--thank you.
This is a dream manifesting.
- Good, good.
- Now, while that's
gonna help your department,
I'm gonna ask
a little something of you
that's gonna help
the whole hospital.
- Yeah.
No, anything I can do
to help push that
rock up the mountain.
- So what do you know
about the so-called resistance?
♪
- Yeah, it's funny that
you should ask about that.
♪
.
- You got the faster car, man.
This isn't fair.
- Come on, come on.
- Come on. No!
- Yes!
Die, purple loser!
- That was very unkind.
- But it was fun.
- Yeah, yeah, it was fun.
Do your, uh--do your parents
let you play video games?
- Yeah, they're not monsters,
but they think
I'm wasting my time.
- What would they rather
you be doing?
- I don't know.
Accomplish things, I guess.
- You are accomplished.
- Not enough.
They're always
worried about my future.
It's not like we're rich,
you know?
They want me to skip grades,
be in the same class
as 12-year-olds.
12-year-olds are weird.
- That's got to suck--
feeling like
you're giving it your all,
but you're still not enough.
-  Which is why I figure
it's better just to get out--
better for me
and better for my parents.
Oh, you have a lot of games.
- Yeah, I do.
In fact, how would you feel
about coming back next week
and giving me
another butt kicking?
- I see what you're doing,
Dr. Frome.
- We're just talking.
- You're building
a therapeutic alliance,
hoping to lean me away from
my desire to be emancipated.
- Well, that is
very astute, Jack,
but you are dead wrong,
all right?
If we meet, I won't be leading
you anywhere.
Whatever we do in here,
whatever you want to play,
we play.
Whatever you want to
talk about, we'll talk about.
It's your time, not mine.
- But what if nothing changes?
There's no epiphany,
no breakthrough?
- Yeah, sometimes there isn't.
- Then it's just wasted time.
- Who feels the need
to accomplish now,
you or your parents?
- One hour a week?
- One hour a week, just...
wasting time.
- That's gonna be
very challenging.
- I know, right?
♪
- Hey.
- Hi.
How's Rohan doing?
- Better.
Yeah, he's gonna make
a full recovery.
It's just a matter of time.
- And how's Lauren?
- The truth?
- Preferably.
What are these?
- They are black beauties.
Amphetamines.
It's Rohan's.
I didn't.
- Okay.
Okay, all right.
This whole place
is like a trigger for me,
you know?
And not even my sobriety.
It's like my sanity.
I want to leave.
I mean, I need to leave.
But Leyla...
Leyla said that she would
basically quit if I left...
that the ED needs me,
New Amsterdam needs me.
- Well, that--that doesn't seem
very fair.
- Fair.
Who says I deserve fair?
♪
- Lauren, whatever you've done,
you've got to let that go.
You have to forgive yourself.
♪
- I can't.
I don't want to.
- So you just want to keep
punishing yourself, do you?
- Because that's what
I deserve.
♪
- Lauren...
look at me.
♪
Come here, sweetheart.
Come here.
♪
Now, you listen to me.
If you need to leave
for your sobriety
and for your sanity,
then you go.
Do you understand?
♪
Because nothing
is more important.
♪
- Clamp.
- Hemostat.
-  What am I doing here?
- A CABG procedure
on Ellen Greenfield?
I'll make sure
not to tell her you asked.
- Meanwhile, Chaplain Alpert
needs a surgery
that I can do in my sleep.
- You did what you could.
- Did I?
For every CABG we do,
there are ten patients
like Chaplain Alpert that get
either transferred or ignored.
That's the definition
of a bad system.
It needs to stop.
- So stop it.
You're the chair
of surgery, right?
- You don't think I've tried?
Sponge.
World-class facility,
resources,
experience, and for what?
So people can do
jerry-rigged procedures
in whatever empty room
they can find?
- That's not really happening,
is it?
♪
- Forget I said anything.
I'm sorry, I got riled up.
- Floyd,
patients could get hurt.
Patients could die.
♪
- Unless we help them.
- Kind of feels like
you've done this before.
- We have, but never
a procedure this risky.
♪
Uh, everyone,
look at me, please.
I need you all
to consent to the following.
You're all here
of your own free will.
You are aware of the medical
risks of this procedure.
And you know by performing
surgery in this place
under these circumstances,
we are all
putting our jobs on the line.
But every one of us here
feels a duty
to save this man's life.
♪
Let's get him intubated.
- It's okay. It's Reynolds.
- How do you know for sure?
- I know him.
He's here to help.
♪
Thought you were gone.
When I heard the resistance
was in the morgue,
I thought, "Isn't that poetic?"
And I just had to come
and see it for myself.
♪
And here you are.
How does that saying go?
Uh, "Liberte. Egalite..."
What's the other one?
♪
Busted?
.
- Welcome back, Chaplain.
How you feeling?
- I'm feeling...
like I just had surgery.
- It's 'cause you did.
A very successful one.
- I'll give you both
some privacy.
- Thank you, Dr. Morgan.
- Ah, nearly 30 years,
you'd think I'd know
every doctor in New Amsterdam.
- Well, you do.
This isn't New Amsterdam.
This is Baptist.
- You mean...?
- You needed help that, uh...
we weren't able to give you.
I thought
I could make it happen,
but, um...
my hope
for New Amsterdam was...
You needed the best care
possible, and I got in the way.
Sorry.
- Come on,
it'd be sorry if I had died.
- Then again,
maybe I have, huh?
This view...
And this bill...
- No bill.
♪
- Excuse me?
- Baptist--
they started a fund
for medical professionals--
anyone who works in health care
that can't get
the care they need
at their own hospital, which
is systemic, unfortunately.
But this hospital--
they stepped up.
♪
- Max, thank you.
- Now go live your life.
Embrace the blessings
when they come.
Time to go home, Max.
♪
- Hey.
How you feeling?
♪
- Ashamed.
- Mm-hmm.
You know, part of me thinks
you should feel that way.
This was a day
about your father.
You made it about you.
Was that your intention?
♪
No.
Okay.
♪
Then I, uh, have to ask you
a hard question.
♪
Were you trying
to end your life?
- Does it matter?
- It does.
- Why?
- Nothing about me
was good enough for him.
And...
he was right.
I was desperate for his love,
and all I could do
was disappoint.
- He loved you very much.
No, he did.
He loved you.
It was just his...
♪
It was his expectations
that prevented him
from showing it.
Showing it the way
that you needed him to.
♪
I miss him.
- I know.
♪
I know you do.
- But I really do believe...
That if he had lived
a little bit longer...
You two would've found
your way back to each other.
I believe that, Rohan.
- Well...
We'll never know,
now, will we?
♪
- I think that's up to you.
- How?
♪
- Everything your father was,
everything that he could be...
that's in you.
No, it is.
It's inside of you.
His life is in yours.
How are you gonna live it?
♪
Sorry I'm late.
- The "resistance."
The resistance.
Ignoring mandates,
conducting illicit surgeries,
risking the accreditation
of this hospital--
- It was me!
- I authorized
the Chaplain's surgery,
and I was going to lead it,
so you do not need
to punish anyone else here.
♪
Please accept my resignation.
- No, Dr. Wilder, I do not
accept your resignation,
because, unfortunately,
your surgeries generate
a staggering amount
of revenue for this hospital.
- Yeah, but I will not stay
here under these conditions.
- Well, actually,
I think you might.
Otherwise,
I'll have to report you
to the AMA for what you did,
and then they'll strip you
of your license,
and it will get
very, very messy indeed.
- No, no, that's enough.
Hey, you are entitled
to call us out, that's fine,
but you don't get to--
- I don't get to what,
Dr. Frome?
Do my job?
Which unlike you, Dr. Frome,
I happen to take
very seriously.
- Oh, do you?
- And, actually, while I have
you, let me ask you this.
How many scheduled patients
did you see today?
- Um, scheduled?
- Scheduled, yes, mm-hmm.
- One.
- Well, actually, I know that,
because while you were
playing video games,
the other five
were rescheduled.
That's revenue
straight out the door.
I just don't know
how much longer I can drag you
by the ear
before I see some semblance
of professional behavior
from you.
- I called
each of those patients,
and I rescheduled them.
- As of now, you are no longer
chair of your department.
Sorry, has to be done.
- No, what?
What?
- Dr. Bloom, you were going
to resign today as well.
Is that correct?
♪
- I was going to...
but after everything
I've seen today...
I'm staying.
- Well, unfortunately, that's
not your decision to make.
So I happily accept
your resignation,
and I sincerely thank you
for everything that you've done
for New Amsterdam.
♪
Mia..
Mia, Mia...
If you weren't
the sole practitioner
of holistic medicine,
I would have no choice
but to relieve you
of your duties as well.
You had the chance
to come to me
and to tell me the truth.
And you chose not to.
♪
But I'm going to give you
a second chance,
against my better judgment.
But I certainly hope
you follow the lead
of Dr. Reynolds in the future.
♪
You had the courage
to come forward
and to alert me
about the resistance.
Not just for your patients,
but for all the patients
at New Amsterdam
because you saw
that there was a possibility
of doing them harm,
and our oath states
that we must protect them
at all costs.
And for that, I'm grateful.
So please send me a list
of the surgeries
you would like restored.
And let's certainly hope
this never happens again.
And if you'll excuse me,
I have a hospital to run.
♪
- Uh--
- ♪ The Devil's
in the basement in my home ♪
♪ Flight of stairs...
♪
♪ He comes for me
when I'm alone ♪
♪ Collecting debts
that I don't owe ♪
- Hey.
- Floyd, have you seen Ma--
- ♪ Follow me down
where the waters run deep ♪
♪ I'll let you drown
in the worst of me ♪
♪ If my intentions are good,
why can't I come clean? ♪
♪ If heaven's above,
where does that leave me? ♪
♪
- Out of the night
that covers me.
Black as the pit
from pole to pole.
♪
Thank whatever gods may be...
for my unconquerable soul.
♪
In the fell clutch
of circumstance,
I have not winced
nor cried aloud.
♪
Under the bludgeonings
of chance...
my head is bloody
but unbowed.
Beyond this place
of wrath and tears
looms but the horror
of the shade.
And yet, diminished
of the years
finds and
shall find me unafraid.
In matters not
how straight the gate,
how charged
with punishments the scroll.
I am the master of my fate.
I am the captain of my soul.
- ♪ Will I ever
breathe again? ♪
♪
♪ Will I ever breathe again?
- Heard about the meeting?
- From everyone.
I keep thinking there's
something I should do, but...
I try to remember that
it's just not my fight anymore.
- No?
- Let's grab Luna and go.
What is it?
- I can't let you.
I can't let you leave.
- Helen--
- Because you're wrong, Max.
Of course this is your fight.
After what I saw today...
This place...
these patients, our friends...
they're all losing.
They're fighting back,
and they are losing...
because you're not here.
- I did everything
I could, Helen.
I did everything I could,
and so did you
to try to leave this place
better when we...
And it didn't work out.
And I have
to make peace with that.
- No.
No, forget peace.
This is war.
So you need to stay here,
and you need to fight.
You need to fight
alongside our friends.
for this hospital.
You have to fight
for my legacy and yours.
And when you win...
and you will win...
then you get your ass
on a plane,
and you come back to me,
do you understand?
- What if I lose you?
♪
- Losing me is impossible.
Now you get in there...
and you show them
what you're made of.
♪