Oh, God.
The flight rotation was, like
the highlight of my residency.
You'll be fine.
I'll be thousands
of feet in the air
in something shaped
like a baked potato
with a frat beanie on it.
Actually, it's only
hundreds of feet.
Oh, God!
Don't they have
ambulances in the sticks?
They don't have a trauma center
in Boone County.
So if it's bad, we go.
How far?
50, 60 Miles.
Oh, no. Didn't you know
this was a requirement
for your residency?
What was I thinking?
All right, deep breath.
Let it out slowly.
Okay.
My knees won't move!
Come on. Stay low.
Dee McManus, Susan Lewis.
Hi.
First flight?
The sum of the angles
in a triangle equals
180 degrees, right?
Mm-hmm.
Hey, Carol.
Hi, uh, Doug.
Hi.
Doug Ross, this
is William Litman.
William is my lab partner.
No kidding.
How's it going?
You know, I have an
intuitive 19th-century
Euclidean mind.
Congratulations.
It's actually crippling
to the understanding
of the geometric
projection of the universe.
I'm flunking out.
So, what are you working on?
I used to be pretty
good at physics.
String theory. It explains
the multi-dimensional
curvature of time and space.
Oh.
"Oh" is right.
So, the Riemannian manifold
is N-dimensional space
that locally looks like
M-dimensional space
when M is less than N.
Situation, one five Yankee.
We're at contact
point five miles...
Susan, take a look.
It's beautiful.
W-what are you doing?
I'm hyperventilating.
Leave me alone.
Oh, God.
You should really
check out the view, okay?
'Cause it helps you
set your gyroscope.
What was that?
It was the pilot.
He was just
adjusting the rotor pitch.
Absolutely normal.
Right. Normal.
I got a visual on you, Air-Vac.
Do you read?
There it is.
Oh, man.
We're first on scene.
We're going to need
the o-neg and blood y's.
There's a field to your 5:00.
Oh... God.
Oh, God.
Oh, oh, God.
Stay low and
watch the tail rotor.
We got five victims.
A truck and a van hit head-on.
Two ejected, three are trapped.
Where's fire response?
Two engines and an
ambulance are en route.
ETA?
30 Minutes. They're
all volunteer out here.
We'll triage first. Susan,
you check the car.
It's all right, sweetie.
Oh, my God!
It's okay.
Please get us out of this car!
Okay.
Yes, I'm still holding
for authorization.
Hello?
So, Dallas by three, you think?
ER, Hold on.
I don't think, Bubba. I know.
ICU's got no beds until 1999.
And they're sending
us two vents.
Terrific.
Way to go, Mr. Gomez. Good job.
Chuny, we need
more ivacs in three.
Patrick Brazil, Metastatic
prostate cancer.
Cough, fever, two months
progressive weakness.
BP 150/70.
Gave 300cc's of saline.
He's a no-code.
Inn's full. Exam four.
I've been Mr. B's
caretaker for 22 years.
He wants to be
cryogenically preserved
when he deanimates.
He wants to what?
Be put on ice when he croaks.
Frozen? Like a popsicle.
He's been waiting eight years
to join Mrs. B.
In their suspension capsule.
Easy, now. One, two, three.
His wife's been
frozen for eight years?
Yes, it was their
50th-anniversary present
to each other.
Faint pulse, poor
respiratory effort.
They want to be preserved
together so that they
can come back in the future
just like those
dinosaurs in that movie.
Isn't it romantic?
Let's hang a Dobutamine drip,
start at ten mikes per kilo
and titrate to a
systolic of 100.
Settle down, Mr. Sotcheck.
Rescue 116's bringing
in a rule-out MI.
We're swamped.
Who's covering
Haleh's vacation shift?
Got a float coming at 9:00.
The last nurse who floated down
here hid in the
bathroom all day.
Who is it?
Sterling, from Med-surg West.
Rhonda Sterling?
Yeah. What's wrong with her?
She's a floor nurse.
Oh, come on, guys.
Give her a chance.
I'm not baby-sitting her.
Me, neither.
Fire's out!
What's your name?
Gail. She's only ten days old.
Is she all right?
She's moving and crying.
Those are good signs.
I'm Dr. Lewis.
What's your name?
Zach.
Uh-huh.
Gail, does your neck hurt?
Is he all right? Gail?
Please help him.
Get a c-collar on her.
Sir? Sir, can you hear me?
That's brain matter.
Guy's a goner.
Let's get him on oxygen.
Where, Zach? Your neck?
No. No!
Does this hurt?
David? David!
Where's my husband?
Gail, where are you hurt?
My... my right leg and my side.
David, please!
Dr. Greene's working on him.
My husband's a doctor.
He has to check on the children.
Susan!
He's a pediatrician.
Go. I'll stand by.
Okay. I'm going to go
check on your husband.
I'll be right back.
The trucker's gone.
I need you over here.
He's still moving.
He's pulseless, with
massive head trauma.
I've got a tension
hemo-pneumo that we can save.
Needle him, left side.
He's decompressing.
32 French.
This guy's a pediatrician.
Really?
Yep. His family's in the van...
Wife and newborn baby girl.
Both stable.
There's a boy about
eight years old...
Leforte two facial fracture.
I'm worried about his airway.
I'm in. Hook it up
to the Foley bag.
He's hemorrhaging.
Grab two units o-neg
out of the cooler. Okay.
I'll start a line.
Please! What about my baby?
Gail, we're getting you out.
Hang in there.
Yeah, I'm still holding.
Hey, you like Green Bay,
minus seven, over Washington?
I thought the World Series
was over. Excuse me.
Hang on one second.
Please don't tell!
Please don't tell! Mommy!
Where do you want him?
Don't tell my mom, please!
Curtain area three,
end of the hall.
Don't tell her! Don't tell her!
Don't tell her, please!
No! Don't tell her!
Uh...
Carol Hathaway.
Carol...
Hi.
I was pulled off my ward
and assigned down here.
Rhonda, right?
What patient do
you want me to take?
Well, actually
we share patients here.
Let me show you.
Over here are the patients
that are waiting to be seen.
Nursing orders are
flagged and put over here.
So, when you're
going to have a...
I'll take Mr. Washington.
Where is Curtain Area Three?
There.
Thank you.
Secure his head.
All right, we need
to start a second line.
Got it right here.
Dr. Lewis, the boy
stopped breathing.
Oh, my God!
Go, go, go.
Watch his c-spine.
Keep in-line traction.
You're in the way.
Uh... there's too much blood.
I need suction.
6.0 Tube.
Another 6.0.
That was it.
Damn it.
Okay... 5.5.
Mark, I need your help!
Get him on the chopper.
David!
We're taking care of him, Gail.
Please don't let him die!
I can't see. Turn it up.
It is up.
There's better
control in the chopper.
Let's bag him and move him.
Ready?
One, two, three.
Doctor, I need
you to start this I.V.
Okay.
Go on. I'll check
it out. Thanks.
What's up?
She needs an I.V.
I tried and missed.
Oh, usually we try a few times
before we call a doc...
Especially an intern.
Up in Med-Surg,
we call the doctor
when we miss.
All right, I'll do it.
Mrs. Fesmire needs 20
of KCL in her I.V. in Three.
Why don't you go do that?
Where's the potassium?
It's in the med room under "P."
I can see the vocal cords.
I'm in.
I'll be right back.
Susan!
All right, Fred. Fire it up.
How much longer?
20, 30 Minutes.
Gail, we're taking your
son and your husband
to County General
Hospital by helicopter.
Are they all right?
They're stable now, but they
need to go to a trauma center.
How will I know what's
happening to them?
I will get word to you, Gail.
Oh, please! Oh please!
I promise. I promise.
Oh, God! Oh, God!
Are you okay?
Uh... yeah.
It's Dr. Greene calling
from the whirlybird.
Why hasn't Mrs. Fesmire
gotten her potassium?
I'm on break.
I'm getting to her.
This is County General
on Beta Two. Go ahead.
We're incoming on Air-Vac
One with two major traumas.
Seven-year-old boy and
his dad, both multiple trauma.
Never mind that.
Grab Lydia and Chuny
and tell them to clear
the trauma rooms.
Go ahead, Air-Vac One.
I'm going to need a vent.
Good-bye, Mr. B.
You will keep him cold until
they come for him, won't you?
So that he could
be with his wife?
Mm. Okay.
Please. Sure.
Thank you.
Should I clean out the fridge?
What have you got?
Dad's got a hemo-pneumo
and a head trauma.
Seven-year-old had
an obstructed airway.
He's getting shocky.
Good job, Susan.
What?
I said good job.
Draw up meds.
Go.
Watch that I.V.
fluids wide open.
Let's get a cross-table, CBC.
Type and cross for four units
and dip a cath urine.
Move that.
Draw up a saline
flush, crash cart.
Where is the saline?
BP's only 65 palp.
Pulse 160. Thready
Whoa. He's waking up.
Hey, Zach. Hi. I'm Carol.
That tube in your throat
is helping you breathe.
Set up for a lavage.
Want a gas? Yep.
Blood gas kit, top drawer.
Got it. You do that.
All right.
See if you can
give me a hand.
Okay.
We got a bloody tap.
Page Benton.
See if the Dad'll sign
a consent form for an ex-lap.
Put that o-neg on
the rapid infuser.
He conscious?
He's responding to pain.
Dr. Herlihy
open your eyes.
Somebody needs to sign
his son's surgical consent
if he can't.
We'll do it.
BP's low, 70 palp.
Pulse ox is only 85.
Lydia, ask Jerry
to track down the
number of the hospital
in Boone County where they're
taking the mother and the baby.
I promised I'd let her
know how they are doing.
Did the heart sound
seem distant to you?
What are you thinking?
Tamponade?
Hang in there, Zach.
Will you hold him still?
He's scared to death.
He's got to be sedated.
Get him versed,
one milligram I.V.
Where is it? Top drawer.
It's clotted.
I need that saline. Let's go.
Zach, we're going to
to give you something
to help you sleep, okay?
It will help you sleep.
All right, here we go.
Hold him.
Whoa!
What was that? Does that hurt?
It hurts.
Are you sure
that's saline?
Oh, my God!
That's potassium.
How much went in?
Uh... about a quarter cc.
Insulin and glucose?
Where is it?!
Second drawer.
Okay, hold on.
It's probably not
enough to stop his heart.
I think we're going to be okay.
What do you got?
Got a seven-year-old
TC, Passenger, space intrusion
airway compromise
at the scene, intubated.
Peritoneal lavage was positive.
BP's crashing, 60 palp.
Pericardiocentesis tray.
Go ahead.
I'll draw up a central line.
Okay.
Hook an alligator
clip to an EKG lead.
Use V-1.
Not mine.
Uh, it's the patient's.
He's a doctor.
It might be his office.
Why don't you try
dialing the number?
Susan, Jerry called
Dwight Hospital.
The wife and baby
haven't arrived yet.
Are they on their way?
I don't know.
Well, find out.
What do we have?
Blunt abdominal trauma
Hypotensive
Intraperitoneal Hemorrhage
confirmed by lavage.
Probably his spleen.
Facial trauma, intubated
in the field with an RSI.
H and H is 11, 32.
Type and cross four.
650cc's of saline.
Versed on board.
Way to go, Carter.
All right, let's take him up.
Can I tie?
Where are his parents?
Second unit's in.
You've got his
partner to take call?
Right. Okay.
Okay, we'll let you know.
40cc's non-clotting blood...
Out.
Dr. Herlihy, you've
been in an accident.
You're in the ER.
BP's back up...
120/80. What do you got?
I'm worried about
an intracranial bleed.
Is he stable enough
for a head CT?
Nurse goes with him.
Am I on call?
No. You're a patient.
You were involved in
a serious traffic accident.
An accident?
Your son, Zach, has
just been taken up
to surgery.
Surgery?
He was injured
in the accident.
Accident? What accident?
Get a rush on that head CT.
Zach, everything's
going to be okay.
We could have killed that boy.
I got confused.
You have no business
working the ER.
You think I don't know that?
I want you to restock supplies
for the rest of the day.
I don't want you
anywhere near my patients.
Yes, this is Carol
Hathaway in the ER.
Clear a CT room, please.
Where's the number
for chopper dispatch?
Mark, can I run
something past you?
Sure.
I've just got a sweet
old guy who died
and I don't know what to do
about his cryogenics request.
His what?
He and his wife
bought a tank for two
so they could be frozen
side-by-side when they died.
Where's his wife now?
In the tank.
Oh.
I have an 800 number
for a cryogenics
company in California.
Call it.
Yeah. Still holding.
What?
Nothing.
Yeah. Yeah, page me
as soon as you know.
Helicopter's standing by.
We may have to go back
and get the wife and the baby.
Okay. De Bakey.
5-0 Prolene on a castro viejo.
Retract caudally.
Retractor.
Splenic vein's repaired.
What about this pancreas?
The tail has most of
the devitalized tissue.
I'd resect rather than do a
subtotal pancreatectomy.
Good. I agree. Metz.
How would you
repair after resection?
Interrupted
horizontal mattresses
and a figure eight in
the pancreatic duct.
Go ahead. Do it. De Bakey.
3-0 Silk on a needle driver.
Anything else to do?
Irrigate, run the
bowel under control
insert a Jackson-Pratt drain
through a separate stab wound
and, uh, use cautery
instead of a scalpel
to minimize bleeding.
And after that?
Close. Keep it simple.
Do exactly what
you just described...
No more, no less.
Okay. All right,
cut the suture,
three millimeters
no longer.
Irrigate, normal saline.
Make sure it's warm.
Park her in the hall
until we can clear an exam room.
Jerry, you seen Susan?
Yeah, she got paged
to chopper duty.
You're kidding.
What's up?
I need ice, lots of ice.
Huh?
California cryonics
said to put him on ice
till their local rep arrives.
They'd better hurry.
McMANUS: Dr. Lewis.
Susan!
Are you sure you're all right?
Yeah. I want to bring them in.
I'll go.
No. No, I'm fine.
Really? You can
stay here with Herlihy.
No, really. I'm okay.
Dr. Lewis! We've got to go!
May I?
Hmm?
See your orders.
Okay.
John, will you take these to ICU
and make sure
they're carried out
as meticulously as written?
Sure.
Peter, care to join me
in a sarcoma resection?
Uh, yeah, yeah, I'd love to.
Good. Gant can
cover in trauma call.
Scrub in in 45 minutes.
Don't you just love her?
Where's Zach?
Where's my husband?
Your husband was
unconscious for quite a while.
He woke up confused
and disoriented.
He has a head injury?
What about my son?
He's in surgery.
Don't worry, Gail. Your
family's in good hands.
Move. Move.
Does this hurt?
Ah!
Yeah.
BP's okay. 115/65.
Get a c-spine, H and
H, type and cross for four
and dip a cath urine.
Got a good set of lungs on her.
Respiratory rate's kind of high.
Who knows with all that crying?
It's 60. Pulse 160.
Abdomen's distended
but she's been
taking in a lot of air.
Do you want a pedes
surgery consult?
Yeah. Get a baby-gram,
CBC, and a gas.
Hey, darling, are you hurt
or are you just
mad at the world?
What'll it be?
Do you believe in reincarnation?
Sure. Why not?
Next life, I'm coming back
as Cindy Crawford.
Could you do us a favor?
A deceased patient of mine
wants to be cryogenically preserved.
We got to freeze a dead guy.
You got any ice?
Neck looks okay.
CT was normal,
but dad's still altered
so they're doing an MRI.
Why did they take Megan away?
She's next door.
It's crowded in here.
We called upstairs.
Zach's out of surgery.
He's going to be all right?
He's in ICU.
I'll check on him
as soon as I can.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
I need my husband.
Please. Where...?
David. Please, where's David?
Please.
Her abdomen's kind of firm.
She swallowed a lot of air.
It's a tough call
with a newborn.
What should we do?
All right, what is it, Gant?
Well, I'm not sure. Abdomen's
persistently distended
she keeps crying and the
resps are high, in the 60s
but the BP, pulse
and color are okay.
Why didn't you drop an NG?
We considered it...
Stool guaiac.
In such a small baby?
Do it off the rectal
thermometer.
You didn't do a full
surgical evaluation
of the patient, Dr. Gant.
Shh, shh.
It's positive for blood.
All right, prep a cutdown
tray, type and cross
for two units and page Keaton.
Where's her mother?
Trauma one.
Dr. Ross and I thought it
was an equivocal exam.
Ross is a pediatrician.
If you don't know what you're
doing call someone who does.
Hi. I'm Dr. Benton.
Your daughter
has internal injuries
that's going to
require an operation.
She-she's only ten days old.
It's okay.
Dr. Keaton will be with her.
And, look, she's the best
pediatric surgeon in Chicago.
Now, we need your consent
for what's called an
exploratory laparotomy.
Where's my husband?
I want him to sign for it.
Her husband's a pediatrician.
He can't do it right now.
He handles all the
family medical decisions.
I don't know
anything about this.
You can do this, Gail.
I don't know.
Your baby needs it.
Okay.
Cutdown tray.
Use a Volutrol.
We may have to transfuse.
Gant was on track.
I just talked him out of it.
Hang D5, quarter normal.
What do you think, Peter?
She has an acute abdomen.
Hi, pretty girl.
Vitals?
BP's 80/40, pulse 160
resps 65, temp's 101.4.
Pulse ox?
Oh, what blue, blue eyes.
92 room air.
Oh, Teacup, that's too low.
Let's get her on O2,
four liters by mask.
Did you appreciate the
periumbilical redness?
The abdomen's a little tense.
No, no, I missed it.
Well, it's easy to miss.
Why a cutdown?
No veins.
22 Angio.
This was a nice pickup, Peter.
Thank you.
Ah, yes.
There we go.
Wow. I couldn't
see or feel a vein.
Well, it's just a matter
of knowing where it is.
Let's get her a
cross-table lateral
and check for free air.
She may be perved.
Any thoughts on antibiotics?
Well, since you don't need
anaerobic coverage on newborns
I'd go with amp and gent.
You've been reading.
Dennis, since you did the trauma
assessment why don't you scrub in
and follow the case through.
Uh, Peter, let's talk to mom.
Good girl.
There you go, Mr. Brazil.
Shrimp cocktail time.
Hubert Skinner,
California Cryonics.
Mr. Brazil.
Do you have some kind of I.D.?
It's all there.
Give him 10,000
units of heparin, stat.
I'll pack him up
and we'll be on our way.
Is he a doctor?
I don't think so.
What do we do?
Well, the heparin can't
hurt, him being dead and all.
In the newborn
I use a transverse
abdominal incision.
The rectus is thin, so
there's less pain post-op.
Adson,
we're using a respirator,
so atelectasis isn't an issue.
Exactly. Zap
that little bleeder.
Cautery.
15 Blade.
If there's a perforation
we should get a gush of air
when I nick the peritoneum.
Yep, there it is.
She's easier to ventilate.
Very little bleeding.
Dennis, why do we want to
keep bleeding to a minimum?
Transfusions are dangerous.
You can't type and cross match
the blood as quickly
because of the baby's
fetal hemoglobin.
There it is... perfed jejunum.
You're teaching
your interns well.
He's in and out.
MRI was normal.
Dr. Herlihy, do you
remember my name?
Where's my wife and kids?
I'm Mark Greene.
Your family was involved
in a traffic accident.
Your wife's in the ER
with a tib-fib fracture.
Zach had facial trauma
and hemoperitoneum.
He's out of surgery, in ICU.
Was it his spleen?
No. Pancreatic injury.
What about Megan?
Megan just went up
to rule out
intestinal perforation.
Why? What happened to her?
She was in the
accident with you.
What accident?
Dr. Herlihy, do you
know my name?
No.
Should I?
It's okay. It's okay.
Gently.
To repair, we use a 4-0
silk interrupted. Hufnagel.
The field looks dry.
You don't need a
two-layer anastomosis.
Cautery alone gives
you hemostasis.
Let's irrigate.
Warm saline, please.
Dr. Keaton, Zach's
abdomen is distending.
Any change in his
vitals or pulse ox?
No, but he might
be bleeding again.
Damn.
Peter, you think you're
ready to finish alone?
Yeah.
Nothing fancy. Just close.
Yeah, yeah. Okay.
All right, people, let's go.
Thank you.
One more. Thank you.
His abdomen is more
distended than before the surgery.
Has he regained consciousness?
No. No.
Four by eight.
Okay. Thank you.
All right. Completely dry.
What's that?
Oh.
Oh, looks like a little fibrin
debris on the liver surface.
Should I call Dr. Keaton?
No, no, no. I'll clean it up.
Come on.
Okay, got it.
All right, let's close
the peritoneum first.
3-0 Vicryl.
Mm-hmm.
Now...
Retract medially.
Cut.
Mm-hmm.
Good.
There's a little blood.
Where?
Oozing from the liver
where you just touched it.
Alright, Uh... I'll put
a little pressure on it.
You suction.
Gently, okay?
Damn it!
It's still oozing.
All right, I don't want to
close while it's bleeding.
I'll put a stitch in
for hemostasis.
4-0 Chromic on
an s-h. Now, move.
Thank you.
Come on. Here we go.
All right.
Retract caudally.
Come on, Gant, retractor.
Is anesthesia standing by?
I called them.
You're right.
He is distended.
Vitals?
Stable. BP's 90/60.
Pulse is 96, pulse ox is 99%.
Should I clear an OR?
Hang on.
Disconnect the NG from the wall.
Yep.
Sometimes, you get
an erosive gastritis.
Hook it back up.
Clots can block the NG,
Causing acute dilatation.
Irrigate it out and
crisis resolved.
It's just experience, Doctor.
She's still bleeding.
I can see that.
I'll put a gelfoam
on the bleeding site
and you apply pressure.
Come on.
Do you want me
to get Dr. Keaton?
No.
Suction.
All right, I'm going to oversew.
2-0 Chromic on an S-H.
Heart rate's
starting to fluctuate.
Give me a bolus of
normal saline, 40cc's.
Damn it!
The liver's so fragile my
stitch cut right through.
I should be getting Keaton.
I'm going to take a bigger bite.
Gant, retract this
way. I can't see.
Pulse ox is falling.
You need to get
this baby off the table.
Bag her faster, damn it!
I'm getting Keaton.
No.
Go! Go!
You really think it'll help her
to see her husband like this?
Megan's still in
surgery, Zach's in ICU.
And your husband
just got out of X-ray.
He's okay?
His tests are normal
but there's still
memory loss.
Could it be permanent?
Probably not.
You can see these
things in a concussion.
But... but it might be.
We'll just have to wait and see.
Blood loss?
100cc's.
That's a third of her volume.
Damn it. What the hell
did you do to her liver?
I just tried to peel
away some fibrin debris.
Cut me a one centimeter
square of gelfoam.
Move.
2-0 chromic on an S-H.
It started to ooze. Clear!
You ripped away
the liver capsule.
No way to control the bleeding.
I'll have to resec
the left lobe.
Peter, handle the suction.
Dennis, retract distally.
Cautery. Crank it up to 18.
Pulse and BP. Are destabilizing.
We'll have to transfuse
with unwashed o-neg.
80cc's. 2-0 Chromic.
Keep them coming.
She's bradying down. Rate's 80.
You've got to get out.
3-0 Vicryl for the
peritoneum and muscle
and staples for the skin.
David?
Oh, my God. David.
What happened to you?
Didn't you tell him?
We did, many times.
Zach's condition has stabilized.
He should wake up soon.
Zach?
It's okay. It's okay.
What about Megan?
Dr. Benton's closing right now.
That's wonderful news.
Was... was there a truck?
Yeah.
Yeah, there was a truck.
What on earth were you thinking?
I told you, there was debris.
And I told you not to
do anything but close.
Look, in my
judgment... I felt that...
I didn't ask for your judgment.
Perry, Dennis, set up a vent.
Call up respiratory and
get a blood gas right away.
Does that say "chicken belt"?
Conjunctivitis.
I hate chart QA.
What?
Nothing.
Thanks for helping
me in the chopper.
No problem.
Things can get really
pressured in here.
It just isn't a place
for someone who
isn't experienced.
I can't have you
work here again.
Zach?
Oh, God.
Can I touch him?
Sure.
Zach, honey, it's Mommy.
I'm going to stay right here
until you wake up.
What about Megan?
No one from
surgery's talked to you?
No.
Okay, I'll go find
out what's going on.
Thank you.
Carter...
Why hasn't anyone
been down to talk to her?
I don't know.
Benton was closing
her an hour ago.
Blood gas is improved.
Not by much.
Um, could you
excuse us, Kit, Dennis?
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
I should never have
left you unsupervised.
There are nuances
in neonatal surgery.
The liver's more
friable in newborns.
I wanted a clean field
before I closed.
Yeah, you said that.
It seemed appropriate.
What's at issue here
is that you ignored
my specific instructions.
No, I didn't ignore anything.
I followed standard
operative procedures.
Look, I've done it at
least a dozen times
in other patients.
This is not another patient.
This is an infant.
Outside. Now.
You don't know anything
about pediatric surgery.
Look, I felt it was necessary...
Are you unwilling to
learn from your mistakes?
It doesn't say in the
text not to stitch a liver!
It isn't in the text!
You didn't know what
the hell you were doing.
The second you
realized you screwed up
you should have called me.
Why did I find three
stitches in there?
Because I was trying
to... I'll tell you why!
Because you arrogantly and
blindly think you have all the answers.
If that baby dies, it'll
be my responsibility
but it will be your fault.
Dr. Keaton, she's crashing.
Pulse ox is 86, heart
rate's down to 45.
Decreased breath
sounds on the right.
Atropine, .04.
Sounds like a pneumothorax.
Chest x ray.
Don't need it.
Increased transillumination
on the right side.
It's a pneumo.
Chest tube tray.
This is no longer
a teaching case. 12 French.
She's going to
need a repeat ABG.
Pulse is up to 72
but it's thready.
Dynamap's not registering a BP.
Get ready with that thoraseal.
She's arresting! Heart
rate's down to 20.
Damn.
Start CPR.
Epi, 1 to 10,000.4
Atropine, .08 milligrams.
How's the blood gas?
Ph 7.3, PO2 45
PCO2 30 and 100% oxygen.
We're going to have to
put her on an Ecmo bypass.
Kit, call the tech. Get two
units O-neg to prime the system.
I'll cut down to
the internal jugular.
So do we bring her
back up to the OR?
No, we're going to
bring the OR to her.
Dr. Greene?
Dr. Herlihy.
What time is it?
8:00.
PM?
Where's my family?
Your wife's upstairs
and both the kids
had laparotomies.
A bed opened up for you in ICU.
How'd they do?
Well, your son's out of surgery
in ICU.
I don't know about
your daughter.
How do I find out
about my daughter?
Well, I'll check for you.
Thank you, Dr. Greene.
Mark.
Pedes OR called.
His daughter
decompensated in surgery.
She's crashing in NICU.
She's still flatline.
Repeat .4 Of epi.
Go ahead, Kit. How
long has she been down?
22 Minutes.
Is the ecmo circuit primed?
Yes.
Good. I'm ready.
Venous connection first.
Arterial.
Turn it on.
We've got a heartbeat.
And a pulse.
Faint.
She's pinking up.
Okay, let's get a repeat gas.
We need to anticoagulate her.
Kit, heparin, 150 units IV
Start a drip at
ten units an hour.
How can we anticoagulate her?
We have to or
her blood will clot
in the ecmo circuit.
Yeah, but won't she bleed out?
We have to hope
that she doesn't.
I'll dictate an
operative report.
Meet me in pedes
ICU In five minutes.
ICU?
Yeah, we've got
to tell the parents.
Peter, how'd it go?
How's the baby?
Not good.
Dr. Benton.
You didn't sign the code sheet.
Hey, we're all human.
You know, we all make mistakes.
Any other words of wisdom, Gant?
You're a real prick,
you know that?
Mrs. Herlihy,
this is Dr. Keaton.
She's the doctor who operated
on both Zach and Megan.
Mrs. Herlihy, uh, Megan
had a perforated intestine
from the accident.
When we operated to repair it
there were complications.
Wh-what are you saying?
Well, she's in the
NICU now on a device
that helps her heart and lungs
oxygenate her blood.
There was bleeding
during the operation
and she went into shock.
Then her lung collapsed
and finally, her heart stopped
but we got it started again
by putting her on
a bypass machine.
Is she going to die?
She's in extremely
critical condition.
It's...
it is a possibility.
The Lord is my shepherd.
I shall not want.
He makes me lie down
in green pastures...
He...
The Lord is my
shepherd, I shall not want.
He makes me to lie
down in green pastures.
He's...
Dr. Benton?
I can't remember the words.