Number one rule of
surgery is limit exposure.
Good.
Keep your hands clean,
your incisions small
and your wounds covered.
I've removed the tumor
and placed the catheters.
Now, I'm going to flood the
abdomen with heated chemo.
It allows a greater
concentration of drugs
to be delivered directly
to the affected area,
and the heat helps
target the cancer cells
while leaving the normal
cells virtually unaffected.
OK, start perfusion.
OK. We'll place him
in Trendelenburg,
then reverse Trendelenburg
as we agitate the abdomen
to make sure that the chemo
really washes everywhere.
- OK, she saw me. Now I can go.
- She's just getting started.
I have a headache.
I need coffee.
I have a cure for a headache
that doesn't involve coffee.
- I'm leaving. There's a seat there.
- Thanks.
OK. Ooh, yeah.
I've never seen a hot
chemo lavage before.
- It's fascinating.
- I thought you were leaving.
The chief asked me to
finish out my contract,
which has a few more weeks.
Number two rule of surgery
is when rule number one stops
working, try something else.
What I said I didn't mean.
You mean offering to trade Owen
like a horse or a baseball card
or a stale peanut butter
sandwich from your lunchbox.
It was...
- It was thoughtless.
- Fine.
Fine. Cristina, let's
just forget about it.
Because sometimes,
you can't limit exposure.
Sometimes, the injury is so bad
you have to cut and cut big.
- No!
- Yes!
- No! If you report him...
- He's an alcoholic!
If you report him, it'll
be the end of his career!
You don't give people any room!
Flaws are unacceptable
to McDreamy.
- Don't McDreamy me.
- McDreamy is being a McAss!
He's an alcoholic! How long has he
been drinking? Since the holidays?
You want to take notes so
you can show it to the board
so they can offer you his job?
You want his job. You
know it, and I know it.
I'm the head of neurosurgery. I
have a responsibility to this hospital.
- Admit you want to be chief.
- I'm done having this argument.
I'm going to the board,
I'm reporting Richard.
Post-it!
- You can't call Post-it.
- I am calling Post-it.
Because I told my secret
about my friend to my husband,
not the head of
neurosurgery. My husband.
Which I have to be able to do.
So the laws of
Post-it clearly prevail.
- This is wrong.
- Post-it.
- The chief...
- Post-it!
Fine. I won't tell.
Fine.
Damn it, you just
make me want to...
Izzie's coming home.
I have to tell Alex.
I won't go to the board.
I won't say a word.
Just think about what I said.
OK.
- Alex, Izzie's coming...
- Izzie's coming?
- Home.
- Crap!
Izzie leaves and
Mark gets a kid,
and you two decide
the best way to deal
is to get drunk and mash
your genitals together?
No freaking way you get to
judge us or give relationship advice.
Besides, you were a total dirty
mistress, like, two weeks ago.
- Are we calling me
a dirty mistress?
- That was two years ago.
And his wife didn't have cancer!
Because I've only been with,
like, six guys in my whole life.
Alex and I, we've done
it before. I was recycling.
It was like good
for the environment.
Izzie's gone, I was
horny, she was there.
Crap! I am a dirty mistress.
Oh, God, you're gonna tell Derek
and Derek will tell
Mark that I'm a whore!
No, I am not going to tell
Derek, and neither are you.
You're not gonna say anything.
We are keeping our mouths shut.
Izzie is coming home.
No one needs to know.
Hi.
Know what?
There were no sterile
supplies in the OR last night.
- I heard.
- Surgery came
to a complete stop
- for a full hour.
- Central Supply and Maintenance
are understaffed and the
autoclaves have been breaking down.
Anything else?
Richard...
- I want to help.
- I don't need your help, Derek.
The sterilizers are
up and running, so...
Not the hospital. You.
You stopped operating.
You're not teaching
anybody but Meredith.
I'm wondering if...
If you need some help.
No shame in asking.
You know that.
You can help.
By doing your own job.
And letting me do mine.
- Anything else?
- No.
I'm done.
So I went to the trailer.
- I don't live in the
trailer anymore.
- Yeah.
So...
Meredith called me and told
me you might be moving on.
- Iz...
- OK, just...
Wait. I realize now
I was wrong to blame
you for getting fired.
I'm sorry. It wasn't your fault.
I don't wanna have some
big talk. I gotta go to work.
I have a PET scan later,
so maybe I'll see
you at the hospital?
- Is everything OK?
- Yeah.
I found some residencies
with open spots and applied.
They all just want to
make sure I'm stable.
One of them is close.
It's in Tacoma, so...
we'd be OK.
I could commute
from here, and...
I know you don't want to
have some big talk, but...
I have to get to the hospital.
That place sucks these days.
You should be happy you
don't work there anymore.
Hmm.
- Sorry.
- Don't be.
I am happy. I'm
gonna work in Tacoma,
and it's gonna be awesome.
You're gonna be jealous.
- You're operating?
- I am.
A Whipple? That's big.
I say go big... or go home.
Uh... Excuse me, sir? You're
taking Dr. Bailey's Whipple?
- Is that a problem?
- No, not at all.
No, I'm the resident on the case.
I'm thrilled to be assisting you.
- I'll be assisting you, right?
- You can open.
That way Dr. Grey will be
fresh when she dissects the neck
of the pancreas
from the portal vein.
- That's the hardest part.
- It's a fifth-year procedure.
It's what we've been practicing.
I'm telling you, you're ready.
But if you don't
think you're ready...
No, I'm ready. I'm ready.
- What's going on?
- Hunt's got an MVC in here.
- Use a hand?
- What?
- Can I help?
- You know what
you can do first?
Make that stop!
Dude, stop singing!
I'm trying to get you to understand
the seriousness of the problem.
I've lost my upper
register completely.
Dr. Karev, this is
Mr. Mafrici, your consult.
I just need some antibiotics.
I open in Tosca in a week.
- And he gave me bronchitis.
- I did not give this to you.
Take a deep breath.
He teaches piano to children.
I can hear them hacking
away during their lessons,
and then he comes in the
house and touches things.
Stop talking. He's got decreased
breath sounds on the left side.
- He needs an X-ray.
- Can you take him?
Page an intern.
I don't have time.
Hunt took him up. Said
thanks for your help.
You got time now?
- You're hot.
- You're hot, too.
No, you're "hot" hot.
Oh, OK. Thanks.
No, you have a fever.
You have a fever.
- What is that?
- What?
- Oh, my God!
Pox! Pox! You have chicken pox!
Teddy. Turns out she loves Owen
and thought she came here to
be all, you know, Teddy and Owen,
but there's me, and now she's
pained and threatening to leave,
so I told her she
could have him.
- What?
- She's an amazing teacher.
And I'm happy again.
And I'm in the OR,
and I'm feeling like myself.
And, of course,
I didn't mean it.
I mean, I love Owen. I love him.
But that means I don't
get to have her. So...
Maybe I meant it?
OK, here's the thing.
You can't talk like this.
- It's like, I get you.
- Yeah.
But other people don't.
So you can't talk like this.
I mean, it's crazy. It's like...
if you tell someone
their baby is ugly.
They know it, you know it.
Everybody knows it.
But you don't talk about it.
OK, but you're
saying surgery, right?
Gun to your head, you'd
choose surgery over Derek.
I'm saying don't talk about
this. Don't talk about it to Owen.
Little Grey? That's the world-class
specialist you wanted me to see?
OK, Little Grey has had
the chicken pox vaccine.
I snooped in your personnel
file. I, on the other hand, have not.
Nor have I ever
had them as a child.
You're a pediatrician.
- How have you never had...?
- I'm a pediatric surgeon.
I don't do little
diseases on little people.
I do big surgeries
on little people.
You know what? This is
ridiculous. I'm going home.
Hey, hey, hey!
You're not going anywhere.
You're highly contagious now.
You leave this room and touch
doorknobs, elevator buttons.
Then you'll be the
outbreak monkey.
- I'm going to kill you.
- I love you.
Stop scratching. You're
just gonna make it worse.
And then you're gonna scar.
I gotta get my hands
in a body again, Mer.
I think I'm gonna get
an offer from Oregon,
but I can't take it. It's too
far. I can't do that to Alex.
I gotta get this Tacoma thing.
You know what would help?
A call from Derek Shepherd,
head of neurosurgery.
- Hey.
- Hi. Talk to him.
- Talk to me about what?
- She's up for a job in Tacoma.
- She wants you to call.
- Tacoma isn't ranked
in the top 20.
Yeah, but it's close. She
can repair things with Alex.
Fine. Have her get me the
number. I read the board.
The chief is doing a Whipple,
and you're scrubbing in.
Well, you can stop
worrying. He's fine.
He hasn't operated in months,
and his first surgery back
is a seven-hour procedure with
a 20 percent complication rate.
First, you were worried
that he wasn't operating.
- Now, you're pissed he is...?
- I don't trust him anymore.
- Meredith?
- Post-it.
He's fine. He's fine.
I thought it was infection.
Right? Like pneumonia?
- That's one of
the possibilities.
- What are the others?
Fluid could also indicate...
Yang. Karev made the
diagnosis. Let him talk.
Heart failure and cancer could
also cause this much fluid to occur.
Cancer? Would you
have to remove my lung?
Aaron, he just said
cancer is only a possibility.
- I sing. It's my entire life.
- Besides me.
What you meant to say was that
singing was your entire life, besides me.
You heard the chief
is operating today?
Uh-huh.
Took my Whipple and
is having Meredith Grey
do the pancreatic dissection.
A procedure that I performed
for the first time just last year.
The chief's judgment...
is not clear and rational.
- There's nothing I can do.
- You're the only one who can.
I performed intraperitoneal
hyperthermic chemo this morning.
I kept looking
up into the gallery
to see if the chief was there.
That was a big deal for me.
Anyway, he wasn't there.
And I don't know why I
thought he would show
because the truth is...
he's gone.
And he's been gone a long time.
Arizona thought some work might
take your mind off your itching.
Scratching will take
my mind off itching.
Take off my gauze paws.
She said that you'd say
that and that I should say no.
So how about we start with the
tibial plateau fracture, room 2240?
Hey, hey.
I'm an attending,
you're a resident.
As your superior, I'm
ordering you to take them off!
She said you'd say that too.
Technically, I'm on
her service today,
so she's my boss, not you.
We have the Lisfranc
fracture, room 2211.
Please, let me scratch!
Just for five minutes.
- It'll scar.
- I don't care!
I don't care. Scars are hot.
Scars are bad-ass.
Scars are poetic.
- I am begging you, Little Grey.
- No.
- Please don't call me
Little Grey.
- I'm in pain!
Down to the core of my being
pain, I'm going crazy pain,
scary, "will this
ever go away" pain.
Do you get that? Do you know
what I mean when I say that?
Because this pain is need to
scratch an itch that I can't scratch!
The pain of a thousand
itches! And it's making me crazy!
Not funny crazy, bad
crazy! OK? Dark crazy.
Make a suit out of someone
else's skin crazy. OK?
- Pain, Little Grey. Pain!
- I had sex with Alex!
I had sex with Alex.
Which I regret. Completely.
Because I'm in love
with Mark. I think.
I'm scared I can't
handle the daughter
and the baby and the Mark's
- gonna be a grandpa thing.
- Why are you telling me this?
I'm in pain, too,
is what I'm saying.
I get your pain,
don't you see that?
I do feel your pain
because I'm in pain too.
I have pox between
my butt cheeks.
Your "pain" does not
begin to compare to mine.
Get out! Just out!
Out, out, out, out, out!
- What are you talking about?
- She's on this thing.
If you had to choose between
the thing you love, surgery,
and the person you love,
which would you choose?
You would choose Izzie, right?
Because you're gonna get back together.
- Shut up.
- Why do you have to choose?
Doesn't matter. You just do.
Which is it, surgery or love?
- I want both.
- That's what I said.
- You can't have both.
- Why the hell not?
- Why the hell is he here?
- I said he could be in here
because he's in
the Whipple, too.
Whatever. Once again, you cannot
have both. You have to choose.
Choose what?
My... My PET scan got
pushed back an hour.
So I thought I'd
join you for lunch.
OK? That. You
have to give up that.
Learning the procedure, tuning
out the world until you get it,
like, you know,
doing the procedure
is the only thing that matters.
If you don't get
to do it, you'll die.
That's what you have to give up.
- For what?
- Love.
- Why?
- That's what I said.
That's not the point! You
know you couldn't do it.
You know you'd
choose a procedure.
Fine, if I had to choose, gun to
my head, I would choose surgery.
OK, well, thank you!
Is that so hard to say?
I don't know why is it so
bad to say that out loud.
Because it's crazy.
- How...?
- It's crazy.
Surgery, it's just a job.
It's just a job. It's the
thing you come home from,
not the thing you come home to.
And if you lose your
job, you get another one.
'Cause there's always
another one. But...
if you lose your love...
if you think you're
losing your love...
then suddenly
nothing else matters.
This is what you guys
talk about during lunch?
I'm with them.
Love comes and goes.
Surgery doesn't.
Results are back.
- You choose love.
- Yes! I just did
a perfect dissection without
lacerating the portal vein.
You gonna do that little
fist pump in surgery too?
The tests showed a
malignancy on your left lung.
It's called pleural
mesothelioma,
and it's a cancer that surrounds
- the lining of your lung.
- So what?
- You cut out his lung?
- Best case scenario,
we won't have to remove any
lung tissue except the tumor.
Aaron, did you hear
that? That's good.
Jeffrey, I'm not deaf. What's
the worst case scenario?
We get in there and the
damage is too extensive
and we have to remove more.
- My whole lung?
- That's the
worst case scenario.
But yes, it is a possibility.
But it's also possible they
won't have to remove any.
- OK? So let's stay positive.
- Will you please shut up?
I can't take your cheerful
little voice shoving
positive thinking down my throat
when my life is basically over.
People do recover from things
like this, then they go on to...
- What? Go on to what?
- Live.
I won't have a
lung. I'm a singer.
So you see my problem?
- You can direct, you can teach.
- Like you?
I'd rather die than spend
two hours every day listening
to mediocre music
majors doing their scales.
I know this is a lot to take
in, and if you need time to talk
- or get a second opinion...
- I want my lung.
Dr. Altman.
I'm big, too big.
I don't fit in airplane seats,
and as Jeff's always telling me,
my feelings don't
always fit the situation.
If my food is overcooked
in a restaurant,
I get enraged. I
want to kill the waiter.
But I don't. I politely ask
him to take my meal back
and bring it to me
the way I asked for it.
I spend my days making
myself smaller, more acceptable.
And that's OK because at night,
when I go onstage, I get
to experience the world
the way I feel it.
With indescribable rage
and unbearable sadness
and huge passion.
At night, onstage,
I get to kill the waiter
and dance on his grave.
And if I can't do
that, if all I have left
is a life of making
myself smaller...
then I don't want to live.
I don't.
And believe me, honey,
you don't want me to live.
Are you stealing
sterile supplies?
I need sterile instruments.
I'm not gonna get caught
with my pants down
because this
hospital can't get...
I get it.
I wanna do something.
Something that I think is...
I have a responsibility,
but I just...
- What's stopping you?
- Meredith.
Ah!
The other half of
the twisted sisters.
Is that what you call
Meredith and Cristina?
- The twisted sisters?
- Yeah.
Well, that fits.
So this... this thing...
I could come
out of it looking...
pretty bad.
Like I did it for the wrong
reasons. Like I did it...
for myself.
In my experience,
nobody goes into a battle
because they want
to win a Purple Heart.
You do the right thing, and
sometimes that gets you a medal.
Sometimes, it gets you killed.
How do you know
it's the right thing?
When it's the best
thing for the most people.
The thing that keeps
the most people alive.
How you doing?
A little claustrophobic.
Focus on your breathing,
that always helps.
Alex, I have to know.
When Mer called, she said
you were moving on. Have you?
Moved on?
I slept with someone.
Damn it, Alex.
We'll get through it.
- Are you still there?
- I'm right here.
Can you hold my hand or
something so I know you haven't left?
I can't reach your hand.
- Oh, yeah.
- I can hold your foot.
A foot is good.
Look, Derek, I'm busy. I have
a surgery in less than an hour.
You want me to drink that?
No.
But I believe you will.
I'm gonna go, and
you're gonna drink it.
You're gonna try not to.
But, in the end, you'll drink it.
I also believe that this
won't be the first
drink you drank today.
This tumor is huge. I've
never seen pleura this thick.
- Like a watermelon rind.
- Damn it.
I'm gonna have to get rid of the
lung, the diaphragm and pericardium
with this tumor. Yeah.
That's what I need to do.
That's what's advisable
for optimal survival.
But that's not what
we're gonna do.
We're going to
remove the visible tumor
and we are going
to treat the lung
with intrapleural
hyperthermic chemotherapy.
Karev, find out what Bailey
used in the procedure this morning
and gather everything I need.
Yang, help me remove this tumor.
This morning, Bailey said hot
chemo lavage was only indicated
- in abdominal surgery.
- Sugarman at the Brigham
has been researching its applications
as it applies to pleural mesothelioma.
And he's a singer.
And he needs his lung.
You look like hell.
Chicken pox. Stay
back, I'm contagious.
I had them when I was six.
What...?
Aah...
Ow... How was LA?
Addison nicked one
of the uterine arteries,
but she was able to fix it.
Sloan's OK and the
baby's gonna be OK, too.
Good.
I slept with Addison.
- I gotta tell Lexie, right?
- No.
It's Lexie. She's so good.
- How do you lie
to a girl like that?
- Lie.
- Really?
- Really.
- Yeah.
I hurt.
- I got you covered, kid.
- What are you doing?
I'm gonna help you.
Oh, my... Oh, my.
- That's amazing!
- No scar.
No, keep going.
Thank you. Thank you,
thank you, thank you.
You saved the lung?
The whole lung?
- Yes.
- OK. Well, now what?
Now, the work really begins.
This is gonna be a long
recovery. But he should be fine.
Does it make me awful to say
that I'm slightly disappointed?
I guess I was sitting
out here thinking,
now he's gonna be
like the rest of us,
who teach and direct
and do all the things
he finds so demeaning.
You know what's demeaning?
Loving a man,
taking care of him,
doing his shopping,
making his meals,
making sure his
humidifiers are clean,
'cause God forbid his
humidifiers aren't clean.
What's demeaning
is loving a man...
who thinks so little of you.
He's got an army of nurses, so if
you wanna walk out of here, you can.
We'll take care of
him. You can go.
I love him.
- You should hear him sing.
- Nobody sings that well.
He does.
See that stitch there? You just
made the dude diabetic for life.
OK. Shut up. I'm trying to
concentrate until the chief gets here.
Dr. Webber apologizes.
He got caught up in some
sort of administrative something.
So let's dig in. Patient ready?
Yeah. We are all
prepped and ready.
- Just waiting on you.
- Dr. Grey, care to open?
Actually, I was gonna
open, Dr. Bailey.
OK. Sure.
Dr. Webber was going to let me
do the pancreatic neck dissection.
- So I've prepped...
- I don't believe
you're ready for that.
I'll be doing it. You're
welcome to observe.
- Go ahead.
- Ten blade.
Sorry you didn't get a
chance to do the procedure.
Something came up, it happens.
Not surprised about
Richard, though.
You're not a dumb person,
but you're acting like one.
I am not going to turn him in.
Tacoma passed on Izzie.
I did my best. Just too much
history. Too many red flags.
If I went to the board,
they'd make me chief.
First thing I'd do is
hire Stevens back.
It's your choice.
It's up to you.
That should be me.
Don't be jealous. They're
just friends. Best friends.
I had the chicken pox. I
told her I hadn't because...
I find her miraculous.
Breathtakingly stunning.
Just...
I can't stop looking at her.
And I was afraid with the ooze
and the fevers and the scratching...
I wanted to stay in
the sexy part of things,
so I lied to my girlfriend.
And now...
- he makes scratching
look sexy.
- Mmm.
He makes everything look sexy.
So you get it.
You didn't have to
do that, but you did.
- You get it.
- What are you talking about?
I'd choose surgery over a guy.
I'm not gonna apologize
for it. Especially to you.
You didn't have
to save his lung.
The right thing would've
been to remove it.
But the patient was clear that he
didn't want to live without his gift.
And you get that.
I choose my gift.
I want to be great. And
I want to learn from you.
I choose my gift.
Hey, how'd your surgery go?
- Great.
- See? And you were all worried.
You're a rock star. Speaking
of which, do you know
- if Derek has talked
to Tacoma yet?
- No, I don't.
OK. Good. I just got my scans
back and they're really good.
So it'd be great if he could mention
that I'm officially not dying of cancer
when he talks to them.
I'm gonna get this job, Mer.
I'm gonna get this job and get
Alex back and be myself again.
I can feel it. OK, I'm
gonna go get Derek
and show my scans
before he calls Tacoma.
OK. You know, I'll go tell him.
Derek. And you go tell Alex.
OK.
OK, fine. You can
go to the board.
Just...
Sorry. Car crash came in. I
got here as soon as I could.
That's OK. It gave
me time to get drunk.
- So, what's the occasion?
- I thought Beth was an idiot.
- If we're being honest here.
- I didn't know that we are.
Maybe not an idiot, but
just not good enough for you.
- So how long you been here?
- You know, I'm sure
- that it wasn't easy for her.
- Teddy.
But do you know what
she said to me once?
She said that once you guys
were married, she was done.
She was done teaching,
and she was just gonna
start making babies.
And I remember thinking to
myself, "Wow, does Owen know
you have, like, zero ambition?"
Then there's Cristina, there's
Cristina, who is exactly the opposite.
I mean, it'd actually be
funny if it wasn't so... just...
not funny. I mean, I get it.
She... she is beautiful and
talented and kind of amazing.
- She's right. I get her.
- I'm calling you a cab.
I get her, but she was
willing to trade you.
For me.
If I stayed, she said
I could have you.
- How was your surgery?
- It was good.
It was... it was fine. It was...
You want to see?
I'm so... I'm so glad!
I'm so glad.
- It's like it never happened.
- Yeah. But it did.
It all happened, Iz.
You got cancer
and we got married.
And you died and you
lived again. And you...
You left and you came
back. And we got through it.
I got through it. And
I'm on the other side.
Iz, I love you so much.
And I...
Until I met you,
I used to think I just
wasn't a good guy.
Growing up in my family,
that's what they told me.
But now,
after all of it, I know
that I'm a good man.
And I thank you for that.
Because I know now that I'm
good enough not to deserve this.
Not to have to feel like this.
Not to love you so much
that I almost hate you.
I deserve someone who will stay.
I'm happy you're OK.
And I'm happy about your job.
And I want you to go.
And be happy. And not come back.
Meredith?
I'm sorry about the surgery.
I got caught up with paperwork.
You don't have to apologize.
You don't have to
apologize for anything.
In surgery...
the healing process
begins with a cut...
an incision...
the tearing of flesh.
Where have you been?
You just disappeared.
I left you, like, ten messages.
Are you drunk?
- Wait. What? What? What?
- You make me sad.
You think that a surgery
is gonna make you feel.
You think a successful career
is gonna make you happy.
You think you know things.
You know things and
nothing else matters.
No one else matters.
People do matter. I matter.
We...
We matter.
So you don't get
to toss me aside.
I won't let you.
We have to damage
the healthy flesh...
in order to expose
the unhealthy.
It feels cruel.
Hey.
Uh...
- How did Sloan's surgery go?
- I slept with Addison.
Thank God. 'Cause
I slept with Alex.
I was feeling so...
Well, you know
how I was feeling.
Which is why this
is great. We're even.
We've kind of
canceled each other out.
- You slept with Karev?
- Yeah.
While I was dealing
with my sick daughter?
While I was hurting?
Well, you weren't hurting.
You were sleeping with Addison.
You broke up with me. Left me.
And you just... Wow.
I...
I can't even look
at you right now.
And against common sense.
Do you know what it took
for me to make this happen?
Please tell Derek
I'm really sorry.
This isn't about Derek.
It's about me. It's about us.
You don't just walk
away from people.
You don't just
throw people away.
I can't, Meredith, OK?
I can't be here! Please!
Please try to understand.
I have to start over.
I need to start over. OK?
Please don't go.
- This is your home.
- No, it's not.
Not anymore. It's just a place I
worked. I can do that anywhere.
But it works.
You risk exposure...
What are you doing?
You'll get the chicken pox.
So I get the chicken pox.
For the sake of healing.
And when it's over...
once the incision
has been closed...
you wait.
Did you see him before he left?
No. I didn't think it
would make it easier.
For him or for you?
This is the best thing for him.
You know that.
It's the only thing.
Let's not pretend
you did this for him.
It's just you and me here,
Derek. You did this for you.
In the choice between surgery
and love, you chose surgery.
- You chose ambition today.
- So did you.
You knew he wasn't ready
to go back into the OR,
but you wanted to do
that surgery so badly,
you were willing to overlook it.
- We're the same.
- You wait,
and you hope that
your patient will heal...
that you haven't, in fact...
just made everything worse.