Previously on ER:
Anything for my roomie.
Congratulations.
- Thank you. It was
supposed to be a secret.
Everybody was saying you were
getting puffy. I had to defend you.
It's a part-time job.
Flexible hours. Good pay.
You and Alex would be more than
welcome to come live with me. Move in.
You'll need to undergo an, uh, evaluation
by the Impaired Physician Committee.
You're serious.
- Yeah, well, I don't need that, okay?
- I do.
Oh! Don't shoot.
Sorry, did I wake you?
I, uh, couldn't find my laser
pointer, I had to root around a bit.
Yes, I ate all your cereal at 4 a.m.,
and, no, there's no milk left either.
- I'm a terrible roommate.
- It's gonna be fine.
I've known about this
conference for two months...
so the fact that I'm this unprepared
two hours before is quite unsettling.
You don't wanna over-rehearse your talk.
You should just wing it, keep it fresh.
Wing it? This isn't
open-mike night, you know.
- Crap! You know, I blame this on you.
- Me?
If you hadn't made me watch
every horror film from the 1970s...
I might've gotten
some work done.
Not every horror film,
just the devil ones.
- You're a bad influence.
- Oh, thank you.
Hey, come here.
You got a little...
On your...
You know, I haven't pulled
an all-nighter since... Ever.
- I've never pulled an all-nighter.
- It's good for a person now and then.
Not for me. I'm used to being
in control of these situations.
- What situations?
- I'm usually so organized.
Uh, Dubenko's
gonna kill me if I'm late.
Well, um, don't worry
about the cereal.
Okay, it's not about
God, it's about tradition.
Religious tradition.
- What's wrong with that?
- Nothing.
If you're religious,
but I'm not religious.
- Okay. You ever been to a baptism?
- Yes, I have. I thought it was weird.
- Weird?
- Yes.
The ritualized, spiritual purification
of a baby kind of freaks me out.
You thought that was
bad, you should see a bris.
- Hey, Rodney.
- Hey, you.
And you, I heard the
good news, congratulations.
Thank you. Two coffees, please.
- You want decaf, right?
- No. Regular, black.
Look, I was baptized, so were my
brothers, my cousins, my parents.
Baptism's what we do in Croatia.
But it's an initiation into a
club I don't wanna belong to.
- It would mean a lot to my father.
- Thank you.
Thanks.
There's no evidence that a moderate
amount of caffeine will harm the baby.
- American Academy of Obstetrics says...
- Please. Stop changing the subject.
Yet people feel the need to curtail
my caffeine intake. Why is that?
It's a little water, a prayer, and a
chance to make other people happy.
- I don't know. There's something so...
- What?
So Rosemary's Baby about it.
Victor Clemente.
All these people here
for drug testing too?
Oh, yeah, you can't tell me that.
Of course you can't tell me that.
- Midstream, in the cup.
- All right. Thanks.
Sample collection
has to be witnessed.
- I'm not trying to pull anything fancy.
- Sample collection has to be witnessed.
What are we, in fascist Germany?
All right, fine. Witness this.
It's okay, honey. You
know you wanna look.
I have a budget committee meeting
until 9:30, page me if we get a trauma.
What? Carter called?
Yeah, you were with an
epistaxis. I didn't wanna bother you.
It's a nosebleed. You
could've pulled me out.
He'll call back. Didn't
seem that important.
If you're not sure,
transfer calls back.
- I'll decide what's important.
- Oh, hey, Luka.
- Sign Kerry's card for me.
- How's she doing?
Good. A little stir-crazy,
she's starting rehab soon.
- I'm sending flowers from the department.
- Nice.
I need someone to
parlez-vous a little Español.
Inez is off, Marquez isn't in yet. Goiter
girl's been waiting for a translator.
Get Clemente.
- He's back?
- Yeah. Should be.
If he's not here in
10 minutes, call me.
Hey, I heard they sent
Clemente to Atlanta for diversion.
- Let's hope.
- He's on house arrest.
- They're letting him come to work?
- Special arrangement.
- It's his first day, he's already late.
- Ten bucks says he doesn't show.
Okay, pirate guy with
testicular pain, Ray.
Abby, you get fever-rash, I
will take dog bite to earlobe.
Wait. Switch that. No, you
take dog bite, I'll take the rash.
We wouldn't wanna risk our
baby getting a TORCH infection.
What?
- TORCH infection. Herpes...
- I know what it is.
- It wouldn't be good for our baby.
- Why do you keep calling it our baby?
I don't mean our
baby, like you and me.
I mean, like, our baby. All
right? Like an ER mascot.
- This baby isn't anyone's mascot.
- Come on, don't go away mad.
Good morning.
Bagels anybody?
- Hey, Dr. Clemente.
- Excuse me.
- Excuse me. Anybody?
- Come on. Let's clean the board.
Hello.
Um, I think I've just
committed suicide.
A little stick here.
A gun's certainly the most reliable
method, but it's against my politics.
Overdose just seemed
like the way to go.
Slow, tidy, not a lot of fuss.
I suppose I have to be
placed on a three-day hold now.
I don't get it. If you're trying
to die, why come in at all?
Who wants to die alone?
All right, Mr. Sadler.
Let me get you an acetaminophen
antidote and call a psychiatrist, okay?
That sounds great.
- Yikes.
- No kidding. Some real pathology there.
- He's so calm it's scary.
- Hmm. More like sociopathic.
You guys got one to present?
- We're good.
- Mucomyst, charcoal, waiting on a tox.
- I'll page Psych.
All right.
Twenty-one-year-old,
discovered near UIC.
- Multiple stab wounds neck and shoulder.
- Vitals?
Pulse, 97, resps, 32, sat, 93.
- I came to pick her
up, found her bleeding.
- Sam, what's open?
- Trauma 1.
Oh, well, well. If it
isn't the elusive Dr. K.
Vic, we'll have to catch up
later. Abby, come with us.
Hey, you're busy. Don't worry.
- Stay here and run the board.
- Got it.
- What happened?
- Knife wound, lacerated trachea.
Hi. I'm Dr. Lockhart. Can
you tell us your name?
Nimet. Please, I can't breathe.
Hang in there, we're
gonna take care of you.
- Frick.
- I'm here. Everything's gonna be okay.
Abby, you take the airway. Sam, get
another line. Ready? One, two, three.
I'm scared.
Don't try to talk. Just let
the doctors take care of you.
Sats only 84.
Zone three stab wounds with
clear tracheal penetration...
and an adjacent pulsatile mass.
The police are here.
- How's she doing?
- Not right now.
Stridor with what appears to
be an expanding hematoma.
- Haleh, can you stay?
- Yeah.
- You know her?
- Oh, she's my girlfriend.
- I need to take a statement.
- Now? Can't this wait?
Just tell them what you
can. It won't take long.
- She's hyperventilating.
- Pulse is taking a dive.
Nimet. SAM: Sats only 78.
- She was just talking.
- What do you guys want?
Okay, uh, 75 ET, mac
two, etomidate and sux.
No paralytics, could
be a tough intubation.
Are you trying to make it tougher?
- No.
If you can't get the tube...
it'll be hard to bag
through a lacerated trachea.
- I'll get the tube.
- Systolic's 81.
Hey, baby, does
this look infected?
Tote bag? NEELA: Uh, no.
That's a wrong
answer. You want this.
- Okay.
- Nineteen, twenty, twenty-two. Yeah.
Come demo the
LifeWind. Free trip to Miami.
Uh, no. Thank you.
Um, excuse me. Can I
get a nonfat latte, please.
Coming up.
- You familiar with the Violet 4000?
- Excuse me?
It's a new cataract emulsifier
for use in the operating room.
Foam?
Never mind.
- More cricoid.
- I'm pressing as hard as I can.
All right, towel roll. The
cords are too anterior.
Okay, let me get that.
Haleh, suction.
You want suction or
cricoid? I can't do both.
- Let me take a shot.
- No, that's all right. I'm in.
- I don't think you are.
- Oh, come on.
- Sat's only 72.
- Abby.
- Call Surgery, she needs a trach.
- Paged already.
- Page again. I almost got it.
- Heart rate's dropping.
Damn it.
- Where's the defibrillator?
- Counter.
- I got it. It's heavy.
- I got it. I'm already...
- Pulse, 23.
- Atropine, one mg now.
Starting compressions.
Hey, if you want me to jump in.
- I'm fine.
- You don't have to do that.
- Enough. I'm having a baby, get over it.
Let me do my job.
Amp of epi, right away.
Seen the Wood's lamp? These Morgellons
are supposed to be autofluorescent.
What? Are you speaking English?
My patient thinks some fiber-producing
bug's crawling on her. She brought some.
- It's lint.
- It's fibers produced by the Morgellons.
Delusional parasitism. DC her
home with a referral for counseling.
There might be therapeutic
benefit to looking at them.
Make her think I'm taking
her complaint seriously.
It's schmootz, okay? It's schmootz.
Spend time on patients that you can help.
What? Hey, guys. Guys, okay.
Okay, look, I know my time
off left you short-handed.
Hey, no worries.
Okay, I'm sensing, uh...
If there's anything you wanna
ask, you wanna get off your chest...
- It's all good, really. MARQUEZ:
Chest pain, need a doc.
Exam 3's open.
Holy crap, it's
like I'm in a vise.
- Vitals?
- Pulse, 92. BP, 110/65.
Five of MS, get him on O2.
- You forgot the 12-lead.
- Getting to that.
Aspirin, oxygen,
beta-blockers, morphine.
- It's cookbook.
- Did somebody say morphine? Unh!
- Call the cath lab.
- Yeah. This isn't our first MI.
- Any word from Surgery? SAM:
Trauma's still in with the liver lac.
What about
Cardiothoracic? Try them?
- They're doing a triple A.
- What, and that's all we have in-house?
Big surgical conference this week,
skeleton crews at all the hospitals.
- Here's your tube.
- Come on, Nimet.
Abby, your GI bleeder is
altered and the crit's down to nine.
Two units of O-neg, and tell GI
to scope him before he codes.
- Okay.
- This guy needs central access.
Go ahead. I mean, if you
want. We're okay here.
- Sats are coming up.
- Hold compressions.
- Back in sinus, 72.
- Is she gonna be all right?
This tube is helping
her breathe right now...
but she's gonna need
surgery on her airway.
- Have we tried Head and Neck Service?
- I'll give them a call.
- The girl's mom and brother are here.
- Oh, Nimet.
I'm Dr. Kovac.
What's he doing here?
- Hey, let's just be cool, all right?
- Get out.
Get the hell off of me! - Hey!
Settle down, guys. Settle
down, guys. Settle down. Hey.
How dare you come here?
You're not family. Stay
away from my sister.
Please, for Nimet's
sake. Show some respect.
How's your first day back going?
It was great. Well,
good. Really, really good.
- My day pretty much sucked.
- Yeah?
I pretty much lost it
in a code this morning.
Isn't it funny that one
minute your whole life...
everything is in order
and then wham...
split-second event and the whole
thing just starts to spin around?
I know exactly what
you're talking about...
People at work, I mean, they see
this sliver of what you're about...
and make it all
about that one thing.
I know. They jump to
all sorts of conclusions...
They don't know
what I'm going through.
They're making all these assumptions,
but they only see what they wanna see.
Why must men always resort to
violence to settle their differences?
My son idolizes his sister, but he's
never liked this boyfriend of hers.
Our surgical team is working on another
critical patient now, but Nimet is next.
- Trauma Room. MAN: I'd
like to speak to Sam Taggart.
This is she.
Yeah? Who's this?
Yeah, well, where the hell do you get
off calling me here? I'm working, idiot.
Uh, since when did we get personal
calls transferred back to the trauma rooms?
I'm sorry, that might be
my fault. Is everything okay?
Yeah, nothing that winning
the lottery couldn't help.
Sorry about that. I'm going
to clean your son's cuts now.
Thank you.
Don't worry, küçhük hanim.
I won't leave until we
can walk out together.
Her name, Nimet,
it means blessing.
It's lovely.
Her father called her Madame
Curie, because when she was born...
she was looking at us so intensely,
like she was studying her parents.
We thought she might
grow up to be a scientist.
Is he coming in?
He died when Nimet was 5.
He was a reporter
for the newspaper.
Kidnapped and shot by
the Turkish Hezbollah...
while I was pregnant with Mahir.
I had to leave.
Had to raise my
children in a country...
where they wouldn't be
killed for speaking the truth.
I understand.
I only spoke a few words
of English when we arrived.
Had to work two jobs.
Well, I know how that is.
Trying to adjust. To fit in.
It was worth it. She thrived.
Earned a full
scholarship at UIC.
Journalism, like her father.
You've done well
by your children.
I've tried.
Neela.
"The utility of the seat belt sign
in predicting mediastinal injury.
Neela Rasgotra, M.D., 3
p.m., the Sunflower Room."
Sunflower Room. Sounds happy.
Ha, ha. Holds 200 people.
There's a lot of interest in your talk.
Lucien, hello.
Tim, hi. Nice to see
you. How are you doing?
I'd love to catch up, but I've
gotta go mediate the trauma panel.
Looks like an interesting
group this year.
Very. And wait...
Now, why aren't you on it?
That's weird. Too bad.
Ha, ha. Timothy Weisner.
There's always one ass in the audience
determined to look smarter than you.
He's that guy. You have his paper,
right? He's gonna ask you about it.
- Okay.
- Yeah, not enough love in the sandbox...
needs to hear his own work
cited in other people's talks.
What? Relax, you'll be fine.
I, uh, played a tangerine in a
Christmas play in primary school.
Lost my footing and rolled off
the stage. I'm having flashbacks.
Oh, no. Just relax. Read your
slides, don't go too fast, and...
Well, memorize table three of the
Weisner paper and you'll do just fine.
Oh, I brought you this.
Take one of these.
It's a beta-blocker.
It's okay. I always take one before I talk.
Takes the edge off the catecholamines.
Go on.
I told you, over-golding is
hazardous to your health.
Your skin will never heal if you
don't give it a chance to air out.
I did like you said, I
kept it off for a week.
- Make it a month this time.
- Ray. Neela called, said it was urgent.
Another week of Keflex,
give the bling a break.
- I gotta be me, man.
- Yeah.
Neela wants you to go to her
locker and find the Weisner paper...
in the February 2005
issue of Trauma Annals...
and fax it to her at this number.
She said you'd know what it's about.
I do, and I do.
She said if you do this, she'll
watch any '70s movie you want...
even the extended version
of Dawn of the Dead.
And this came back
on your overdose.
- You're sure this is right?
- I even had them repeat it.
- How you feeling, Mr. Sadler?
- About the same.
But I suppose I won't feel
much till most of the liver dies.
That's not gonna happen.
Your acetaminophen
level is almost undetectable.
That's strange. I
know that's what I took.
Could there have been
anything else in the bottle?
No.
But, uh, that doesn't
change the course of action.
You still have to
keep me on a hold.
- At least until Psychiatry sees you, yeah.
- Yeah, that makes sense.
So, what happened in there?
- Nothing.
That wasn't nothing.
She shouldn't be
with someone like that.
- He seems like an okay guy to me.
- He's a jerk.
He lives in Dorch...
it's the jock dorm.
Something bad
happened there last term.
What do you mean something bad?
A girl got gang-raped.
It was in the news.
They never figured
out who did it.
And you think
Frick was involved?
They all knew what was going on.
I'll be right back.
Where's the boyfriend?
Uh, staying away for now,
out of respect for the family.
Her brother doesn't think
he's such a good guy.
Well, I'm sure the police are
investigating all possibilities.
The phone call before?
Oh, it's nothing. Uh,
Surgery's still tied up?
Yeah.
- Anything I can do?
- No.
I enrolled Alex in this tutoring
program where they, you know...
help with homework in the afternoons
and then keep him out of trouble.
- Sounds good.
- Yeah, it's...
You have to pay for the whole term
upfront, so I maxed out my Visa and...
Now I'm a little
late on my rent.
- Do you need...?
- No, it's, uh, okay. We're fine.
We're gonna be okay. But thanks.
This thing has been transmitting
for 20 minutes. Is this normal?
The machine is archaic. It
prints on rolls instead of sheets.
And forget about confirming
if it's been received.
This is just press and pray.
Yeah, right. Okay, could you send
this from the department office?
- It's important.
- I'm not your personal secretary.
Please. I have six patients ready to
dispo, I haven't presented any of them yet.
Fine. I'll have a turkey
club for lunch. Thank you.
- Thank you.
- Hey, you need to present?
Oh. It's okay. That's cool.
No, what do you mean? I just
heard you say you needed to present.
Right, and I already started
with Kovac, so I'll just wait for him.
Okay.
Okay. X-Ray, I'm not
feeling the love, man.
- What's the problem?
- No problem.
No, seriously. What's
the deal? What's going on?
- I don't know what you mean.
- Yeah, you do.
You've been giving me attitude all day,
and it's getting a little old, frankly.
So what? I had a messy situation
with a girl, and that's all it was.
- So can we leave it in the past?
- Your personal life? It's your business.
Oh, you wanna know
the whole story, huh?
Mm.
Okay, here it is. Here it is.
I had the weekend off,
we went a little crazy.
There was some weed,
there was some blow.
You're a musician,
you know what it's like.
- No, actually, I don't.
- So, what are you, in a Christian band?
Just forget it, okay?
I'm not gonna let you forget
it. Let me tell you something.
I want you to know that I never
showed up to work high once.
- Not once. Do you understand?
- Want a medal for that?
Where do you get off
being so self-righteous?
I've seen you stumble
out of Ike's plenty of times.
So, what? It's cool to be obliterated
on ETOH but change the chemical...
all of a sudden, I'm a scumbag?
You're right. It's not fair.
Listen, let's me and you
get something straight, okay?
I've been evaluated by the committee.
And you know what? I'm in the clear.
Like it or not, I'm
back at County...
I'm your Attending, and you better
start showing me some respect.
Take the history, examine that patient,
and present to me in 10. You got it?
He's definitely got some axis two stuff
going on, but he's not actively suicidal.
- I'm sending him home.
- You're kidding.
No. Negative tox screen, doesn't
seem to have any plan to try it again.
It's a la casa. Bye-bye.
- You're comfortable discharging him?
- No.
Not exactly, but the psych
ward is full, and I can't hold him.
- I'll put a formal consult in the chart.
- Excuse me.
You will refer him for
outpatient counseling.
Sure, but the next available
appointment is in 14 weeks.
Excuse me. Sir?
What can I do
for you, little lady?
We're looking for a doctor
named Archibald Morris.
And who is we?
Type and cross the
thalassemia kid...
I want post-reduction films on the
tib-fib before the ketamine wears off.
You got it.
So how's it going?
Oh, it's going great.
Going real great.
I just wanna thank you for making
the effort and easing my reentry.
- Good to have you back, Vic.
- Glad to hear it.
If I didn't know, I would
think you're avoiding me.
I'm not avoiding you, I've
been bouncing all day...
between patients and
administrative crap.
- Budget committee, admission...
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You're important.
I get it, I get it.
Sorry we didn't roll out
a red carpet for you...
Nimet's tanking again.
Right.
Can't get the sat above 80, and
she's getting really hard to bag.
Suction. Zone three
stab wound to the neck.
- Systolic's only 72.
- Will someone explain, please?
Can't ventilate at all.
Hematoma's expanding. It's
dislodged the tube. Let's crike her.
No, no, too dangerous.
Lesion's low. If we cut
into it, she can bleed out.
Good point. Let's go to Plan B.
- Sam, call the perfusion team.
- What?
- Heart rate's dropping.
- What does that mean?
Putting her on a
cardio-pulmonary bypass.
You need an O.R. and a
surgeon. We don't have either.
- We're gonna cannulate, we'll bypass.
- You can't do that.
If we work quick, we'll get her on before
she suffers permanent hypoxic damage.
- Get a Resident.
- I'll find Abby.
- Tell me what's happening.
- The bleeding is blocking her airway.
- We can't get oxygen into her blood.
- Oh, God.
We'll get her on a heart-lung
machine so we can buy more time...
before we can get
her into an O.R., okay?
- Whatever you think is right.
- Brady to 45, lost the pulse.
- Starting compressions.
- Mahir, you should wait outside.
- Mom.
- Go.
Nimet. Nimet, you're a
strong girl. You're a brave girl.
Don't leave me. Don't give up.
Okay, what's this about,
kids? I'm a doctor, very busy.
- You're Archibald Morris.
- Yeah. What do you need?
You better have a seat.
Here's the deal.
We four live with different parents,
but we all share the same dad.
We're not supposed to be able
to find out the identity of our father.
But the Donor Sibling Registry allows
us to find out the identity of each other.
So I got in contact
with them via e-mail.
And it actually turns out that little
Max here is actually a computer genius.
- What's up?
He hacked the system at the sperm
bank and found our father's name.
Archibald Morris.
So are you donor 140
from the Chicago CryoBank?
Huh?
Did you donate any sperm
between 1991 and 1996?
Ha. Did I ever. Heh.
Oh, my God. I'm...
I'm your daddy.
Mr. Sadler.
Being a sitter for crazy people
seems like a really boring job.
Well, guess what, Barry.
- You and the sitter can both go home.
- What?
You convinced the psychiatrist
it's safe to discharge you.
- No.
- You're free to go.
Well, what about these?
Mr. Sadler, you took what?
Three, maybe four pills?
- Two.
Yeah, but a gesture is a
gesture. I was suicidal when I did it.
The psychiatrist is convinced
you're not gonna try it again.
What if I'm homicidal? You have
to keep me if I wanna kill people.
Barry, ha, what's going on?
The thing is...
I, uh... I need to stay here. I
can't go home this weekend.
- Why not?
- I just can't.
You're gonna have
to do better than that.
I'm in love with
my best friend's girl.
Ha. It happens.
You'll get over it.
They're getting married tomorrow.
I don't trust myself not to...
- To what?
- Object.
Or worse.
Lock me up till the
wedding's over, please.
I'm begging you.
I'll talk to Psych again,
see what I can do.
Barry...
- does she know?
- Who? Helen?
Yeah. Have you
told her how you feel?
God, no. That would be crazy.
Still in PEA. Resuming
compressions.
It's okay, Nimet. It's
gonna be all right.
Got a flash. ABBY: Introducer.
- You ever done this before?
- Nope.
All right, give us
some room. Come on.
I'll be right here.
Just listen to my voice.
It seems a little
unconventional.
- Okay. Fine, what's the alternative?
- Somebody call Surgery again.
Still working in an open
chest five minutes ago.
Did I tell you Mrs. Kalter's daughter
has 14 bridesmaids in her wedding?
We'll oxygenate her
blood till Surgery's ready.
- It'll be awesome.
- If she doesn't bleed out.
- Threading easily.
- Nine yards of silk organza.
- Hook me up, Lockhart.
- Does Surgery know we're doing this?
- They're not available. We can't wait.
- Silk flowers all around their neck.
You must get better so you
can help me with the embroidery.
- PH is only 7.02.
- Yeah, well, we got nothing to lose.
Okay. Good flush.
You're such a good
girl. Such a help to me.
Sat's hanging in the 60s.
Come on. This is taking too long.
- 0 silk.
Okay.
Unclamping venous.
Unclamping arterial.
Ready.
Okay, mark the time.
Okay. Pump is on,
four liters per minute.
Okay, you can stop.
Color's better already.
Full flow, baby. Sweet. Ha, ha!
Sat's coming up. Ninety-two.
Is it working?
Her oxygen level
is improving, yes.
Thank you. Thank you for
saving my daughter. Thank you.
Up to 15 percent of all deaths
following motor vehicle collisions...
are caused by injury
to the thoracic aorta.
I... Uh...
We set out to
document the incidence...
and utility of the seatbelt
sign in predicting...
Is there anyone from
audio-visual support here?
Unseen they suffer.
Unheard they cry.
In agony they
linger. Alone they die.
Rats have rights.
- I would like to point out...
- Rats have rights.
- Rats have rights. Rats have rights.
- That our study didn't involve any rats.
Rats have rights.
- Ray, meet my kids.
- Your what?
Yeah, I needed cash in
college, donated to a sperm bank.
Best job I ever had.
I'm Hana. MORRIS: My eldest.
Stole her mom's car, drove 60 miles
without a license to get everybody here.
Michael is the regional "Dance
Dance Revolution" champion.
Melia is a professional jump roper,
and my boy Max is a computer whiz.
What's up?
- It's nice to meet you all.
- Yeah, I'm just giving them the tour.
All right. Uh, these, uh,
are the trauma rooms, okay?
This is where Daddy saves lives.
- Cool.
- Abby, come meet my children.
- Not now, Morris.
Okay, she hates kids.
- How's she doing?
- Stable for now.
- Where'd the family go?
- I made them get something to eat.
- It's gonna be a long night.
- Yeah.
Uh, okay, I kind of
snapped this morning.
- It's okay. It's hormones.
- No, I hate that excuse. I just...
I just wanna say that I know you
were trying to help, and I apologize.
Apology accepted.
It's just strange
being pregnant.
It's so weird having such a
personal thing be so public.
Well, for me, being pregnant was
something everyone was ashamed of.
My parents didn't want
me to leave the house.
I think it's nice that everybody
wants to share in this with you.
Luka.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
- Tell us what's happening.
- Seventh unit, platelets, FFP going up.
Wide open at the femoral.
Somebody explain.
What has gone wrong?
- Heparin's off, right? Heparin's off?
- It's off.
- Okay, one gram of protamine.
- Please, you have to help her.
Can't get her mean above 30.
She's losing blood
faster than we can put in.
In order to put Nimet
on this machine...
we had to give her a
medicine that thins her blood.
A side effect is internal bleeding.
That might be what's happening now.
If you stop the
medicine, she'll be okay?
- That's what we're hoping, yes.
- Whoa, acidotic, 6.8.
Try one amp of bicarb and one
gram of calcium. Let's go. Go, go, go.
Pupils are fixed and
dilated. No corneal, no gag.
Why? There's no head trauma, and
no reason for a spontaneous bleed.
Heparin-induced thrombocytopenia
can cause acute intracranial hemorrhage.
She's been on heparin
for less than an hour.
It doesn't make sense.
Does it make sense?
Check the oxygenator.
Get another ACT.
Volume's too low. No flow.
She's lost some basic
neurologic reflexes.
- What does that mean?
- We think that she's bled into her brain.
Stop it, Mahir. I can't hear
the doctors. Can you fix this?
No, we can't.
Her brain is gone...
and as soon as we turn the
machine off, her body's gonna die too.
Come back. Nimet is
strong, she can fight.
Stop, Mahir. Stop right now!
This never would've
happened if she stayed at home!
- You should have made her stay.
- Enough!
Please! There must be
another machine or something!
I'm sorry.
I'll give my own blood.
It was a good idea, Vic.
Yeah. Yeah, if it
had worked, right?
You gave her the only
chance she ever had.
Yeah. Yeah.
I'm sorry about the beta-blocker.
Ten milligrams was probably a bit much.
The fainting part just
makes for a better story.
You know...
I once ate a hash brownie before
giving a big talk in Amsterdam.
I mistakenly thought that it
would take an hour to kick in.
Suddenly, I was up on a stage,
completely out of my head...
lecturing to a roomful of
biochemists in a faux French accent.
Okay. I feel better.
Today was a complete disaster,
but at least I didn't bring it on myself.
No, no, no. You
were the victim...
of a truly astounding confluence
of technical problems...
miscalculated pharmaceuticals,
and rat activists.
As crazy as that sounds, that's totally
in sync with my life at the moment.
Well, your life sounds
pretty interesting.
Oh, no.
I know I may appear
to be this kind of wild...
spontaneous girl who
plans a wedding in a day...
and sits here getting drunk
with her Attending in a hotel bar.
But I'm not.
I'm boring, really boring.
All I wanna do is hang out
at home with my roommate.
Your roommate? Dr. Barnett?
- Yeah, Ray.
- Well, that's nice.
It's good the two of
you get along so well.
Yeah, we do.
Maybe that's what I need.
You know, I was
thinking of getting a dog...
but a roommate's probably
easier to housetrain.
Are you ready for another round?
Uh, no. No. Thank you, I, uh...
I should get going.
- It was worth a try.
- Yeah.
I need to go over organ donation
and explain about the coroner.
- I don't wanna rush her.
- No, of course not.
This might take a while. Maybe you
should go home. Don't wait for me.
Um...
I've been thinking, and if it's
that important to your family...
I'm fine with the baptism.
A little holy water never
hurt anybody, right?
Well, Archie, this was
fun. I'm glad we came.
Wait. You're not
leaving, are you?
I was gonna take you all
out for burgers and shakes.
Sorry, can't.
I gotta get everyone home before
8 or our parents will start to worry.
Well... I mean, what's next?
Now, I wanna take you guys
to ball games, Millennium Park...
movies your parents won't
let you see, there's so much.
Perhaps. Um,
we're all pretty busy.
I don't know when I'll be able to
steal my mom's car again, so...
Somebody hid the
digital on the code cart.
Oh, great. Frank, thank you.
- I wanna take a picture.
- Really, we gotta run.
Please, two seconds.
Come on, please.
Okay, everybody say freak.
- Samantha.
- Hey.
I'm glad you called.
Where's all your stuff?
Oh, I thought we were gonna
conduct an interview first.
I thought we already did.
- Hey, how was it?
- Endless.
Well, I'm making a
stir-fry. Beer or wine?
Neither. I'm exhausted
and already drunk.
All right. Here.
Taste this. Fresh
water chestnut.
Crazy, huh? Thought
they grew in cans.
All right, well, I rented The Omen,
and I was too scared to watch it alone.
- Ray...
- It's better than The Exorcist.
I promise it's a classic.
That's what you said
about The Exorcist.
- True, but...
- Ray.
- I know, you're tired.
Okay, look. I know you
don't like devil movies.
- It's the last one, I promise.
- I think I should move out.
- Why?
- I think we both know why.
Where's Mahir?
I don't know.
I'm afraid for him.
He just needs some time.
I'm sorry to bother
you with this...
but, uh, you need
to sign for her things.
This is the hardest thing
for any parent to experience.
How do you protect them
from all the evil in the world?
You can't. No matter
what you do, you can't.
Mahir was beaten up at school
after 9/11 for being Muslim.
They called him a terrorist.
Ever since then, he became
very strict about his prayers.
He cut himself off from everything
except his fundamentalist friends.
He wanted the same
thing for his sister.
There's a park down
the street where we live.
I close my eyes, and they're
just little children on the swings.
- Oh, God. I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
- It's all right. It's all right.
I brought them to this country
to find justice and freedom.
But I lose two children today.
- Two children. Oh, God.
- Mahir... Mahir will be all right.
I can't pretend that I don't
know what I know in my heart.
He loved his sister.
But he thought she was disgracing
the family, disgracing herself.
Oh, God.
Doctor, doctor, doctor.
Doctor, tell the police
to search my house first.
They should look into
Mahir's room for the knife.
Oh, God.
This was an honor killing?
Yes. Yes.
That's what they call it.
But there is no honor here.
What the hell are you
still doing here, man?
Downloading the picture of
my kids from the ER camera.
Really photogenic,
aren't they, huh?
I'm gonna use this one
for my Christmas card.
I don't know. I hate
Christmas cards, man.
Hey, you wanna go grab
some dinner together?
Uh, no. My oldest boy, Michael,
DJs an online radio show.
- I wanna check it out.
- Why don't we listen to it here?
No, I can't. After that I
gotta brush up on my trig...
so I can help Melia
with her homework.
She's 10 years old, she's
smarter at math than I am, huh?
- Family really keeps you busy, huh?
- Yeah, but it's worth it though, right?
So you, uh, heading home?
I heard your apartment
got pretty messed up.
No, it's fixed. I mean, that's finally
what it took the landlord to paint it.
Okay, then. Cool.
Welcome back, Vic.
- You have a good night.
- You too, man.