Mark?
Mark, I'm cold.
All right, Dad.
I'll get you a blanket.
Did you get any sleep?
You look awful.
I'm fine.
I need to turn up
your oxygen, Dad.
If you still have
trouble breathing,
I'm gonna have to
put you on a mask.
No mask.
We'll see.
You ought to go back to work.
Maybe later.
I wanna make sure
you're comfortable.
In that case, how 'bout a drink?
What?
I've got a hankering
for a bloody mary.
Your mother used to
make them for brunch.
I don't think that's
such a good idea.
Why, you think
it's gonna kill me?
With or without Worcestershire?
Without.
But I'll take a dash of Tabasco.
John? Yeah?
What's all the racket?
Oh, sorry. I'm just trying
to get back into shape.
When did you get this equipment?
Couple of days ago.
I didn't mean to wake you.
You know me, I'm
up with the birds.
How did you sleep?
Like a baby.
Good.
Well, I'll let you get
back to your regimen.
Toast and coffee for breakfast?
I feel like pancakes today.
Well, I think we
can manage that.
Morning.
Is everything all right?
I only got your answering
machine last few days.
Aw, I'm really
sorry. It's been crazy.
Tess had a bad cold. The
kitchen was being repainted,
so we've been
staying at my mom's.
Well, anyway, happy birthday.
Luka, they're beautiful.
I picked them from my garden.
M-my neighbor's
garden, actually.
How did you know
it was my birthday?
I have my ways.
Dr. Kovac, we need
you. GSW coming in.
See you later. Okay.
Looking sharp, Carter.
Where you been?
Uh, I was actually checking
out, uh, condos in Lincoln Park.
Very trendy. And expensive.
Too many damn
yuppies, if you ask me.
You're a yuppie, Dave. No way.
Young urban
professional. That's you.
I am not. Hey,
chief, am I a yuppie?
No, but you will be
when you grow up.
Look, Dr. Greene
won't be in tonight.
I need somebody to
cover his shift again.
Carter, Malucci?
All night? Yeah,
you can flip for it.
I'll do it. You will?
I'm the senior Resident.
It's my responsibility.
Thank you, Dr. Carter.
You can nap later.
Malucci'll cover for you.
Dr. Weaver, your EMS
meeting's been changed to 10.
This morning? Yeah.
Where's Carol? Over there.
Carol!
You didn't hear me calling you?
No, what's up?
Okay, I need the
paramedic compliance data
on aspirin and chest pain.
Okay, I'll get to it.
I put a memo in your box
last week. You didn't see it?
Oh, God, Kerry,
I must've forgot.
The meeting's in two hours.
I know it's a lot, but I need
you to compile the data.
I will. I will get to it.
You'll do it? I will do it.
I made you some French toast.
You want the TV on?
No.
Okay, Dad, lean forward.
You in pain?
Ugh! When I take a breath.
Probably pleurisy
from the pneumonia.
We'll try Toradol.
This oughta make
you feel better.
Hungry?
No.
Come on, why don't you eat?
For me. Huh?
Just take one bite.
Please?
Aww, I'll eat.
His lungs are still wet.
What did you give him?
Lasix, nitro and
morphine. Excellent.
But his blood gas shows he's
acidemic and retaining CO-2.
His pulse ox is dropping. 85.
He's tiring out. Conni,
set us up for an intubation.
Mr. Remmes, we're gonna put
a tube down your throat, okay?
Anything to help me breathe.
This one's a little tough.
Have you done a COPDer before?
Never tubed anybody.
Well, time to step
up to the plate.
Hey, I heard you guys had a
patient in respiratory distress?
We're on top of it.
I was about to take Abby
through an intubation.
Good. Then we can
try this new Airway Cam.
Abby, if you don't mind.
Slip this right
around your head.
Then as she intubates,
we'll be able to see
exactly what she sees on the TV
and make any adjustments.
Cool.
You ready, Abby?
Yeah. Hi, Mom.
Dave, why don't give
your patient 20 of etomidate
and start bagging him?
Right.
Everything looks okay.
No bleeding?
Nope.
Good, now I can go home.
You vomited blood
and fainted at work.
The IV needs to
stay in a while longer.
But y-you said I could leave
if everything checked out.
Yes, but your
potassium level's low.
We need to replenish it.
Where'd you put the lab slip?
Uh, the printer's down.
I got it off the computer.
You've wasted enough
of my time already.
Nurse, get my clothes. Whoa.
What's wrong?
Nothing. Just a little dizzy
from sitting up too fast.
Your pulse is weak, which
means you're dehydrated.
You can go after
this fluid runs in.
All right. But that's
it. Then I'm outta here.
Okay.
Lydia, can you assist
me in making sure
all of Claire's discharge
papers are in order?
Sure.
Her gag is absent,
tooth enamel's eroded,
she's severely malnourished.
She's anorectic and bulimic.
I don't want her leaving.
What can we do?
We'll get Psych to
put a hold on her.
What do you got?
Hammer vs. scalp.
We're going up to CT.
Have you seen Carol?
Not since early
this morning, why?
She's supposed to be
working on my paramedic data.
Did you page her? Twice.
It's her birthday.
I bet some of the
nurses took her
to Doc Magoo's for breakfast.
Certainly hope not.
All right. Go for it, Abby.
Scissor the mouth apart.
Enter on the right. Sweep
the tongue to the left.
Slide that bad boy
all the way down.
Hold on. Just advance slowly
until you see the epiglottis.
See it.
So can we.
A little bit more.
Now lift it up with your tip.
This is pretty cool,
Carter. I gotta admit.
No, wait, wait. Lift in the
direction of the handle.
You could have a lot of
fun with this camera, huh?
See the vocal cords.
Good, now pass the tube.
Good.
Wasn't so hard.
It's easy when you
got a good teacher.
You're right.
Dad, you're wheezing again.
You want another
breathing treatment?
No.
Having any chest pain?
That last stuff
worked pretty good.
Just mixing up your antibiotics.
Damn it!
What?
Broke.
Ow! Now what?
Cut my hand.
You're bleeding on the floor.
Yeah, yeah, I know.
Shouldn't you keep
pressure on that?
I know, Dad.
Keep your hand above your heart.
That's supposed
to stop the bleeding.
You need stitches.
I'm not leaving you here alone.
You're the doctor.
The circulation in your
leg is poor, Mr. Fulton.
We need an arteriogram
to check your blood flow.
When my dad first
came, the doc couldn't feel
a pulse in his foot.
When was that?
About a month ago, right?
The doctor took the
dead skin off his toe,
told him to soak it,
gave him some ointment.
My shoe didn't fit right.
Rubbed my toe raw. Ha!
The toe is gangrenous now.
And you have an
ulceration on your leg.
We will have to operate.
How bad is it?
We'll probably have to
amputate below the knee.
Amputate? SON:
How could this happen?
That first doctor gave
my dad some pills
and told him to take aspirin.
We never knew this
could be this serious.
Remember who
treated your father?
Some foreign guy.
Kovac? Yeah.
Dr. Kovac.
Lydia, I'm off to Mark's.
Is it his dad?
No. Mark cut his
hand. He needs sutures.
Peter's covering for me.
Make sure Psych comes
down here to see Claire.
Don't worry. She's
not going anywhere.
I put her on on a slow drip.
She's got a couple
hours left on that bag.
Thanks.
I'm still massaging the data.
I'll make the
presentation in June
with three months'
worth of figures.
Okay, thanks.
Carol, where you been?
Daycare. Tess has
been cranky all morning.
I just postponed my meeting
'cause I didn't
have your report.
I didn't get to finish it.
You're the paramedic liaison.
You're supposed to
stay on top of stats.
I know, I've just
been incredibly busy.
You shoulda given
the job to another nurse.
I can handle it. Okay, look.
I know that your
babies take a lot of time.
If you need to cut
back on responsibility...
No, I'm fine.
You sure? Because I can't afford
to have things fall
through the cracks.
I can handle it.
Good.
Carol? What?
Delivery guy dropped
this off. I signed for it.
Oh, God. It's, uh, from Doug.
Let's see. What did he give you?
Animal crackers.
That's a weird birthday present.
No.
It's this thing we used to do.
Whenever he'd go to the store,
he'd come back with a
box of animal crackers.
And I'd always put one
in his Christmas stocking.
Kind of like a tradition, huh?
I think I'll take the
foreign body in the eye.
Carter's got it.
Then I'll take the
hip dislocation.
Carter's got that one too.
Tell Dr. Carter if he wants
to see all the patients,
I'll be happy to go home.
He left you Mr. Barclay
in Chairs. Wound check.
Swell.
Mr. Barclay? Finally.
I've been waiting
for three hours.
This thing's
draining like crazy.
Malucci, your CHF
guy dropped his sats.
You have to go back to Chairs.
What's taking so long?
My patient just
stopped breathing.
Would you take
this guy? Yeah, sure.
I burnt my arm last week
cleaning out the furnace.
Hurt like a son of a bitch.
Why don't you remove
the gauze? We'll look.
Hey, doc.
Excuse me.
Kenny Lattimer, four.
Been seizing for 20 minutes.
No response to two of
Ativan. Please help him.
Don't worry, Mr. Lattimer.
We'll take care of Kenny.
Yosh, prep the Pedes ER and
draw up another two of Ativan.
Hey, I was here first!
Ativan's on board.
Draw a CBC,
Accu-Chek, cath a urine.
Pulse ox is dropping, 92.
Has Kenny ever had
seizures before? Never.
He's always been healthy.
Could he have ingested
any medicine, poison?
No, we... We keep
everything locked up.
He complained of a sore
throat last night, that's all.
Any fever this morning?
Just a little. I tried
to get him to eat,
but he only wanted to sleep.
Then the next thing I
knew, he was shaking.
Push 600 of phenobarb
over 10 minutes.
We've got to stop this.
You want to intubate?
Only if his sats keep dropping.
Blood glucose is
really low. It's under 40.
Seizures can lower
the blood sugar.
Push 50 cc's of D-25
and get Weaver now.
Dr. Kovac?
Yes.
Do you remember seeing
a patient, Chet Fulton,
African-American, early 60s,
came in about a month ago
with a vascular insufficiency
and an ulcerated toe?
Do you have his chart?
Uh, yeah. Mr. Fulton's
back with gangrene.
Yes, I remember him.
I débrided the wound
and gave him Trental.
Sorry he's back.
Well, now I have to do a
below-the-knee amputation,
which could have been avoided
if he had been seen
in Vascular clinic.
As you can see in the
chart, I made the referral.
Uh, he's a high-risk
patient with no insurance.
He lives alone. He
needed follow-up.
And I provided that. I made
an appointment with Vascular.
I can't be responsible for his
medical care outside the ER.
But did you put him on
the nurses' callback list
or did you phone him yourself?
Do you call back every
patient you see down here?
The ones at
high-risk I do. Really?
Older African-American men
are at high-risk for amputation.
They're not treated
aggressively.
You should know that. I do.
Well, then why
didn't you call him?
What are you saying?
There's more to
emergency medicine
than treating and
streeting patients.
That's one more thing
you don't have to teach me.
- How long's he been seizing?
- Thirty minutes.
Load him with Dilantin, 300 mg.
What's his blood
sugar? Still under 40.
Push another 50 of
D-25. I don't understand.
How can the glucose
level still be so low?
Could be an insulinoma
or a metabolic disorder.
Haleh, give me an ammonia,
an insulin level
and a uric acid.
Seizure stopped.
Okay, start him a dextrose drip.
Check blood sugar
every 20 minutes.
His brain can't tolerate
another seizure.
Why isn't he awake?
It's normal for him to sleep
after something like this.
But he will wake up, right?
Why don't you stay with him?
Otherwise, he
might be frightened
waking up in a strange place.
Thanks. Thank you.
Thanks, doctor. Thanks.
Get a head CT and an EEG.
What are you
thinking? I don't know.
The D-25 should've
corrected the hypoglycemia.
Something else must be going on.
Check the labs, make
a differential diagnosis,
start hunting for zebras.
Okay.
Hey, Chuny, is
this your patient?
No, he's Carol's.
Can you change the
IV bag? It's empty.
No, I got a guy
puking all over Exam 2.
Carol. Your patient in
Curtain 3 needs a new IV.
Oh, yeah, right.
Hey, Carol. It's not like
you to let an IV run dry.
I'm sorry.
Is there something
bothering you?
I'm fine. Are you sure?
If you have a problem
with me, Kerry,
just go ahead and say it.
Don't get so defensive.
I'm just asking what's going on.
I'm taking care of 10 patients.
I have two babies up in daycare.
And you're
constantly on my back.
Stay on top of things and
I won't bother you again.
Forty-five-year-old guy
crossing the El tracks
tried to beat the train.
Got knocked down
but not run over.
Lucky guy. BP is 80 over 40.
Gave a liter of saline,
intubated in the field.
When is somebody
gonna look at my arm?
I came all the way
here on the bus...
Would you just take a seat?
And three...
We got a couple
rib fractures here.
BP's 75 palp.
All right, let's prep
for a central line.
This guy's gonna
need some fluid.
Absent-breath sounds.
This dude's got a pneumo.
Hey, chest-tube tray.
Hold on, I'm
prepping for Carter.
Why does it take so
long for a wound check?
'Cause this guy's
trying to die on us.
Get out of here!
Soon as I pop this baby in,
his pressure will shoot back up.
You can't assume that.
He could be losing blood.
Malik, stand by
to fluid resuscitate.
Did I ever tell you the story
about my first chest tube?
Love to hear it, but
sick people await. Ciao!
Cliff-diver hit the
rocks. What a mess.
I'm in. You done, Dr. Carter?
Not yet. MALIK:
Pressure still 75.
So much for your
chest tube, Dr. Dave.
Could be blood in the belly.
Malik, get me an ultrasound.
That guy just stole
my rig! What guy?
Your wound-check patient.
Oh, that sucks.
You're good at this.
Thank you.
The way you did the sub-Q layer,
you hardly need
to close the skin.
That's the point.
Is he giving you a
hard time over there?
No, David.
He's being a very good patient.
Huh.
Okay.
We'll remove those in five
days. Shouldn't leave a scar.
Thanks.
Keep it dry for two days
and put a plastic
bag around your hand
when you take a shower.
I know.
I know you know.
Looks like he's having
difficulty breathing.
Should I give him
another treatment?
I can't breathe.
But I can still hear
every word you say.
Can I make you some lunch?
I'm not hungry.
But stay.
Have some tea.
I'd like that.
Huh.
Heard you've got
an unstable patient.
Blunt chest trauma.
Tension pneumo.
Still hypotensive
despite a chest tube.
Probably cracked his spleen.
- Hold on.
His neck veins are elevated.
I'm worried about
fluid around the heart.
You should be
worried about the belly.
Let's check for a
cardiac tamponade.
I'd be checking the
belly. You're right, Carter.
He's got a big effusion
around the heart. Go for it.
Why don't you give me a spinal
needle and an alligator clip?
Here. Now you
can check the belly.
Watch for injury current.
Belly's looking pretty clean.
You're hitting the
heart. Pull back.
I've got good return.
Okay, pulse is stronger.
Need another
syringe? I think I'm okay.
Why don't you
call for an ICU bed?
Good job, Carter.
Dr. Weaver? Yeah.
I did a Medline search
on the boy with seizures.
And? Hypoglycemia,
elevated ammonia,
and no ketones are
consistent with M-CAD,
a rare metabolic disorder.
Get a Genetics consult. Talk
to the parents. Good pickup.
How you doing?
Okay.
Look, uh,
I'm sorry I came
down so hard on you,
but I depend on you.
You were right. I need to
be more on top of things.
Carol, you're the
best nurse here,
but something's
going on with you.
I-i-is there anything
that I can do to help?
Not really. I just need some
time to figure a few things out.
I've worked with
you for five years.
I know you.
I hate my life.
I Mean, I... I love my work.
And I love my daughters, but...
How did I end up raising
twins by myself? It's just...
You know, I think
you need some time.
I think that you
have some sick days.
Used 'em all up.
If you check, you'll find
you have some extras,
which you can use
whenever you like.
Thank you, Kerry.
You said Kenny would wake up.
Your son's genetic
disorder prevents him
from burning fat for energy.
When he got sick, his
blood sugar dropped,
and that caused his seizure.
Is he gonna have brain damage?
We should wait for
the results of the EEG.
I don't understand.
Kenny was born here.
Why didn't someone
tell us he had this?
Unfortunately, Chicago
hospitals don't test
for these rare
metabolic disorders.
Are you saying
other hospitals do?
In some states.
If we'd have known,
is there anything
we coulda done?
Dr. Chen, please.
Tell us.
If you had given
Kenny sugar water
when he fist got sick,
you could have
prevented the seizure.
Sugar water?
Oh, my God.
Hey, just sent our
patient up to the O.R.
Hope you didn't cause
any myocardial damage.
Not to worry, Dave. It was
as easy as threading a needle.
Hello? I'm in the ambulance,
bringing in some sick people.
What unit is this?
How the hell should I know?
I was on my way to
Mercy for a wound check
when they flagged me down.
Who is this? Joe Barclay.
That's your wound-check guy.
Hey, this is Country General.
What the hell are you doing?
Heading back. I got people
here puking their guts out.
Ate some bad kielbasa.
Is that the jerk that
stole my rig? Yeah.
Are the patients stable?
I don't know, man.
They're puking.
Okay, don't let them
puke on the floor.
I just cleaned my rig.
I'm gonna let you take this one.
You've already established
a relationship with the patient.
Call me if there's any change.
I will.
David, I'm leaving now.
I have to get back
to the hospital.
A doctor's work is never done.
I'm afraid so.
Wait.
I have something
I want to give you.
Mark, get that little green box
out of the top dresser drawer.
It's not necessary.
I know.
These belonged to Mark's mother.
I gave them to her
on her wedding day.
I want you to have them.
I can't.
Please.
They're lovely.
Thank you.
Don't just stand there.
Help her put them on.
She looks... beautiful,
doesn't she, Mark?
Yeah. She does.
Hello, Jing.
No, it's Jing-Mei.
What's the matter? You
seem upset. Somebody die?
We should be
screening babies here
for rare metabolic disorders.
What are you talking about?
I took care of
a little boy today
who had a seizure
because we didn't give him
a $25 test when he was born.
Well, if we tested for every
genetic disorder in the book,
we'd spend millions of dollars
to identify a tiny
handful of kids.
Oh.
But if I had known what he had,
I would have treated
him differently.
I might have been able to
stop the seizure more quickly.
Don't blame yourself.
It's a question
of allocation of
precious resources.
We have to draw
the line somewhere.
We should offer the tests.
Well, we can't afford it.
Why don't you explain
that to my patient's family?
They're in the PICU,
waiting to see if their son
ever comes out of a coma.
They wouldn't stop puking.
Strong radial pulse here.
This guy is stable. ABBY:
Belly's soft on this one.
We got a father/daughter
MVA. Can you give me a hand?
These guys are fine.
Start a liter of saline
and titrate five to 10 of
Compazine. Come on, Abby.
Come with me. Can I
get my wound checked?
You'll get your wound checked.
Rear-ended at moderate
velocity while stopped at a red.
Six-year-old girl in the back
seat complains of neck pain.
I wanna stay with my daddy.
Dr. Dave is gonna
take good care of you.
Dave, work her up.
Abby and I'll take the dad.
Driver's a 35-year-old
male, no seat belt.
Knee versus
dashboard. Facial lac.
Was the wife informed?
They're divorced.
She's in Pittsburgh.
Daughter was here
visiting. Dislocated knee.
My knee hurts like
you wouldn't believe.
Had six of MS.
Let's give him another
ten of morphine.
Ever reduced a patella? No.
Well, you will now.
Did you see my patient?
I'm just finishing the note.
Thank you.
Don't thank me yet. I'm
removing the Psych hold.
You can't be serious.
This young woman's
starving herself to death.
She might be. But
I can't compel her
to stay against her will.
She has a job,
she's not delusional,
and she's not an
immediate threat to anybody.
She could go into
kidney failure, arrythmia.
What's it take to
get her treatment?
Her consent. Lots of people
do bad things to themselves.
They smoke, drink,
they eat fatty foods,
drive without seat belts,
but we don't lock them up.
So we're supposed to
stand by and do nothing?
Claire has the right to make her
own decisions, even bad ones.
Well, there's gotta
be something I can do.
If you can convince her to stay,
I'll admit her to
the Psych ward.
Otherwise, discharge her
after you've buffed her up.
Is the water too warm, Dad?
No, no.
Where's Elizabeth?
She left a couple of hours ago.
You have to go to work.
No, Dad. I'm gonna
stay right here.
Okay? Here.
Lie back.
Having any pain?
No. No.
You all right?
Yeah.
You look tired.
What...? What is that soap?
Plain old Ivory.
That's what your mother used.
I remember.
Every night when
she would tuck me in,
she'd give me a kiss
and I could smell the soap
on her face.
This used to be my job.
What's that?
Giving you a bath
when you were a baby.
I didn't know that.
You're a good doctor.
The day you became a doctor...
was the proudest day of my life.
Shhh.
It's okay, Dad. You
don't have to talk.
Shhh.
I love you, Mark.
I love you too, Dad.
Shhh.
Shell, you doing okay?
Yeah. When can I get up?
As soon as I take
a look at your x-ray.
Lily, send off a
CBC, dip a urine
and check a bedside crit.
HemoCue's in the other room.
That's two of Versed.
He's pretty relaxed.
All right, I'll keep
the hip flexed.
Now, keeping the
knee in extension,
you're gonna apply gentle
pressure direct and medially.
Like this?
Perfect. How you
guys doing in there?
Kid's stable. He's
clearing the neck.
What have you got?
Six-year-old with a minor MVA.
Probably just a whiplash.
I took a lateral C-spine.
About to do my secondary survey.
Careful. Ungh!
Don't!
Oh, it's okay, Shelly.
We just have to
examine you, all right?
We'll... We'll cover
you with a sheet.
Whoa. What is it?
She's got bruises on her thighs
and blood in her underpants.
Could be a urethral injury
from a pelvic fracture?
Lily, we need a plain film
and a cystourethrogram.
Hold on. Hold on.
Does this hurt, sweetheart?
No.
There's no pelvic fracture.
You've got some blood
in your underpants.
Did you hurt yourself?
I wanna go home.
Uh, Shelly, we're
here to help you.
I just need to ask you
a few questions, okay?
Okay.
Has anyone ever touched you
where you go to the bathroom?
What happened?
Sometimes my daddy
plays a game with me.
It's okay. You can tell us.
It hurts.
Well, don't worry, he's never
gonna hurt you again, okay?
Sick son of a bitch!
Take it easy! What
are you doing?!
He molested his daughter.
What?! She's got sign of abuse!
What are you talking
about? I never touched her.
Mr. Burke, I'm
sorry. Dave, outside!
Abby, Malik, please
keep an eye on things.
You cannot go off on a patient.
He raped his daughter.
You don't know.
Call Social Services
and have Cleo do a pelvic.
I'll assist. Not after
what just happened.
That little girl trusts me.
That's a really bad idea.
Well, I'm gonna assist.
Okay, you'll
feel a little sting.
I heard Kerry was
out for your blood.
She was pretty upset.
I can talk to her if you like.
Oh, no, we worked it out.
You'd think she could cut you
a little slack on your birthday.
Do you have plans to celebrate?
Oh, no. I don't like to leave
the girls with a babysitter
when I've been at work all day.
No problem. I can cook
you a birthday dinner.
Even do the dishes.
Okay.
Better get these
things to the lab.
Dr. Chen?
Is everything okay?
The doctor upstairs told me
that Kenny may have
permanent brain damage.
I'm so sorry.
This is Kenny's
baby sister Emma.
The sitter dropped her off.
She's beautiful.
I want you to give her that test
that you talked about.
Please.
I can't force her to stay,
but I was hoping that
she'd listen to you.
I love my daughter. I'd
do anything to help her.
I'm sure you would.
She's exhausted from not eating.
My God.
She's skin and bones.
You told the mother?
I had no choice.
She's over 18.
She has a terrible disease.
I had to do something.
"I would not like
them here or there.
I would not like them anywhere."
"I do not like green
eggs and ham.
I do not like them, Sam-I-am."
You're gonna feel my hands now.
"Would you like them in a house?
"Would you like
them with a mouse?
"I do not like them in a house.
I do not like them
with a mouse."
"I do not like
them here or there.
I do not like them anywhere."
That's good. Almost through.
She's got bleeding from
complete transection of her hymen.
Can we keep reading?
Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
"I do not like green
eggs and ham.
I do not like them, Sam-I-am."
Hey, Carter, you
wanna order dinner?
Going to Lucky Moon.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Get me kung pao chicken,
mu shu pork and
a side of egg rolls.
Wow, you're hungry. I'll
save the mu shu for later...
65-year-old with chest pain.
Just dropped his pressure to 80.
He's got ST elevation
in V-1 through V-4.
His lungs are wet.
I'm gonna tube him.
Lily, start dopamine.
Pulse ox is 82.
All right, I'll bag him.
Do you want me
to call the cath lab?
Yeah, tell them
we've got a hot MI.
He's tachy at 130.
Damn it. Get me some suction.
You want cricoid pressure? Yeah.
Your kid with multiple
bee stings is crashing.
I'm in. Bag him. You
want me to take it?
No. Get this guy's pressure
up and take him to the cath lab.
Pressure's down to 75 palp.
Should I increase the dopamine?
No, hold on. There's
a pansystolic murmur
I didn't hear before.
Mitral regurge?
No, a parasternal thrill.
Could be septal perforation.
Why don't you get me an
8 French cordis introducer?
Putting in a central line?
Then I'll float a Swan.
We don't do those down here.
We don't have any Swan modules.
Get one from the ICU.
It's against policy.
I just to sample a little blood
from the right side of his
heart to make the diagnosis.
Come on. Carter,
we can't do this.
Fine. I'll do it myself.
I'm getting Dr. Kovac.
Kerry, did someone page me?
I did.
Mark's father passed
away a little while ago.
How's Mark?
He's all right.
He... He said that
he would call you
as soon as the
funeral home leaves.
I'm going over there
as soon as I finish up.
Peter's still on call. Would
you mind asking him to cover?
Not at all.
Dr. Corday, we
need you right now.
I'm leaving. I want
this IV out now!
Claire, please don't do this.
She won't listen to reason.
Claire, you're anorectic.
You need to be hospitalized.
That's not what
the shrink told me.
We can't force you to stay.
You could die without treatment.
Take this damn thing out!
All right.
All right, Lydia, remove the IV.
I never said that you
could call my mother.
I'm an adult.
I can do what I want.
You're right, you're
right. I'm sorry.
I'm only trying to save you.
I don't want your help.
A friend of mine died
today fighting for his life.
You want to leave?
Fine. Kill yourself.
If you don't give a
damn, neither do I.
Discharge her.
There. I'm in the RV. Lily,
draw blood from the distal port.
Blood's bright red. I knew it.
This guy's got a
hole in his heart.
Leaking oxygenated
blood to the right side.
Pressure's still low.
Start a Nipride and
call the O.R. Tell them...
What are you doing? I
told you to get this guy
to the cath lab.
I'm advancing to
the pulmonary artery.
We don't do Swans in the ER.
I told him that.
This guy should be
getting angioplasty.
He would've died
in the cath lab.
What are you talking about?
I used the Swan to sample
blood from the right ventricle.
It's bright red. He
perfed his septum.
What about his MI?
They can bypass him
when they fix the rupture.
Grab those IVs, would you?
Put 'em on the pole,
the O.R.'s waiting.
We're supposed to work together.
Next time you tell me
what you are doing.
Okay.
Can't you give me something?
Just a couple more sutures.
Then they're taking you to jail.
Ow! You're hurting me, damn it.
- Sorry.
Make him stop. He's killing me.
Dr. Malucci, your
patient's in pain.
He needs more lidocaine.
Well, I did an
infraorbital block.
You must've missed the
nerve. Infiltrate locally.
Well, if I do that it'll distort
the wound edges, so...
Infiltrate subcutaneously
or I'm gonna take over.
Fine.
You do it.
Dr. Chen, we keep
meeting in such odd places.
You paged me for a consult?
Yes. But first, I wanted
you to meet Mrs. Lattimer.
She's the mother of the
little boy I told you about.
Oh. Oh, hey, hey, I'm, uh,
terribly sorry about your son.
Thank you.
I told Mrs. Lattimer that
we would test her baby girl.
That's an excellent idea.
Dr. Chen was telling me
that if hospitals
screened every newborn,
hundreds of lives
might be saved.
And since the test only costs...
You know what? I'm sorry. I
have a hot appy waiting for me.
If you can show me
where my consult is...
Oh, this is not a
surgical consult.
It's not?
No.
I'm sponsoring a petition
to have County General
offer expanded
newborn genetic testing.
I told Mrs. Lattimer and
she wanted to meet you.
Though Kenny didn't get tested,
at least some good
will come out of all this.
Mm-hm.
Dr. Romano, if
you would just sign
on the bottom page...
Well, like I tell
all my Residents,
what's good for
County... is good for me.
Kerry, have you seen
Carol? Not in a while.
Please tell her
I'm looking for her.
Okay. Thanks.
Dr. Carter, I heard you
performed quite a heroic save.
Oh, just doing what I
thought best for my patient.
We have Attendings here for a
reason: to supervise Residents.
Fine. No, it's not fine.
Don't perform dangerous
procedures alone.
Is that clear, John? Yeah.
ETA is five minutes.
Copy 43. See you in five.
Okay, I'll be setting
up Trauma 1.
We got multiple stab wounds
to the chest coming. Interested?
No, thanks.
How's that little girl doing?
Cuts will heal. See
you tomorrow night.
See you.
There you are.
I was looking for you.
You all right?
I've been up here thinking.
Yeah. Birthdays can
make you do that. Heh!
It's been... quite a year.
Yeah. For me too.
I'm looking forward
to the next one.
Luka, I'm sorry, I don't think
I can have dinner
with you tonight.
Did I do something wrong?
Oh, no. No, it's not you. I...
It's me.
I'm sorry. I gotta go.
Mark?
Hi.
I'm so sorry.
Can I help with anything?
Not really.
Called all his Navy
pals in San Diego.
I just got off the
phone with Rachel.
Got some forms to fill out.
His taxes.
Mom used to do his taxes,
so they're kind of a mess.
And his house.
Gotta sell the house.
I promised him that I...
I wouldn't sell the house
when he came out here.
But I don't...
I don't see a reason to keep it.