- Previously on The Resident...
- No pulse.
The strut in the
valve is shattered.
Seven QuoVadis heart valves.
I want to put them through
the pulse duplicator.
The valves aren't strong enouh
for a younger, active patient.
Mark Truscott, FDA,
Product Regulation.
I know that my firm is
engaged in a wide-ranging fraud.
You are not a team player.
My sister, she OD'd on Oxy.
You almost died today, Jess.
You got to start
making better choices.
So let's start now.
- Go home!
- I can't.
Priya's there.
No wife and no home.
♪ ♪
Now, use your ears
as well as your eyes.
You're more likely to hear
a bird before you see it.
Listen for the call of
a cerulean warbler.
I saw one the last time I
brought a group to this spot.
Most handsome
little blue fell...
Hello, juvenile blue heron.
And perhaps a wood duck as well.
Swerved right
off the road there.
Ran the plates.
Belong to a Julian Booth.
Open it up.
Car's empty.
Let's see if search and
rescue can find a body.
Did you check the perimeter?
♪ ♪
Okay, one more thing.
Last question, I
promise. Hoop or stud?
Stud, hoop?
You pick. They're both great.
You nervous?
My first job interview
since rehab?
Yeah.
I have your prep material.
Partner CVs and briefs
on high-profile cases
and clients at the firm.
And what they're
looking for in a paralegal.
Five hours till go time.
Thank you so much for
putting that together, Nic.
It's my pleasure.
This is exciting, Jess.
This could be the beginning
of a whole new life for you.
- Call me when it's done.
- I will. Yeah.
- Good luck.
- Bye, thanks.
You need to pull all
QuoVadis valves now.
Because of one resident's
science experiment?
The valves worked fine when
simulated for older patients,
but when I mimicked the blood
flow of active younger ones...
- Like Bradley.
- They shattered like glass.
Look, it's very clear that a
defective QuoVadis valve
killed Bradley, not these hands.
Well, your mentor, Abe
Benedict, swears by them.
- Explain that.
- Easy.
He's on the QuoVadis payroll.
- What are you talking about?
- ProPublica.
It's a site you need to
make your home page, Bell.
They have a feature
called Dollars for Docs.
It lists every dime
every doctor takes
from medical device companies.
Every dime to every doctor.
Well, that-that...
that proves nothing.
Billions of dollars are given to
doctors every year by industry.
It's standard practice.
QuoVadis paid
Dr. Benedict a small fortune
to push products
that kill people.
Look, I know, as
a fellow surgeon,
you are not gonna stand
around and allow our doctors
to use products that
cause harm to our patients.
Okay, well, uh, here's
how I want to proceed.
I-I want to take you off
all high-risk procedures.
- High-risk procedures
are my thing, Bell.
- I understand,
but if you want to
prove it's the valve
that caused Bradley's death,
you need to keep
your record clean.
You need to take
the easy layups,
the bread and butter procedures.
And while I do that?
You have my word
I will look into this.
Here is your skinny latte.
Get me a meeting with Gordon
Page. Tell him it's urgent.
So?
What's so urgent that it
required a face-to-face meeting?
I received some
information today
suggesting your heart
valve may be defective.
Wh-What information? From where?
Well, one of our
doctors tested the valve,
and they're convinced you
have a significant problem.
It may cause sudden death.
Look, this is absurd.
- We do all our own testing.
- Right.
Have you done
follow-ups on patients
that have received
QuoVadis valves?
What's the mortality rate
at six months or a year?
Naturally, some of them die
due to underlying
diseases or surgical errors.
Well, and some
device manufacturers
use that fact to hide
device problems.
Is that what you're implying?
No, I'm-I'm... no. I'm
not implying anything,
but I want to see data
on the safety of the valves.
And if it doesn't exist,
QuoVadis has to pull
them from the market.
I'm sorry, are you, are you
asking me to issue a recall
during the run up to our IPO?
Oh, yeah, while you do
more testing. Yes, yes.
Okay. Yeah, um, okay. I've heard
just about enough of this.
You can't tell me how
to run my business.
Who the hell do
you think you are?
You came to me
desperate for money,
so I made you an opinion leader.
I put you on my board.
I arranged speaking fees
to get you out of whatever
trouble you were in.
And I'm grateful.
I asked no questions. I
asked nothing in return
except for loyalty to me.
And to our product.
Ugh, this is an extremely
disappointing conversation.
I made an investment in you.
Earn it.
Hey, Jess. What
are you doing here?
Okay, all right, be honest:
do I look like a paralegal?
Right? It's just an
interview at this point,
but thank you. Wish me luck.
Good luck.
Hey, I got your text. What's up?
I just, I changed outfits
and I wanted to show you.
This, this is better, right?
What do you
think? It's-it's softer.
It's more approachable.
Well, yeah, I like
it 'cause it's mine,
which you borrowed
without asking.
What are you doing?
You're supposed to be
at your interview.
Oh, yes, and I missed the bus.
Can I borrow 20 bucks for a cab?
- I'll pay you back. I promise.
- Yes, hurry up.
I'm sorry. You're
the best sister ever.
- I love you. Okay?
- Got it.
I'll call you after.
Hey.
She's very... happy.
What's that supposed to mean?
Opioids can cause euphoria.
I-Is Jessie being tested?
Unbelievable.
First, I'm codependent,
now I'm not doing enough.
Conrad, Jessie's fine.
We're actually in
a really good place.
Okay.
Take a deep breath.
Our time on this earth begins
and ends with a heartbeat.
It is the first sign of
life within the womb,
and it is the last organ to
stop functioning in death.
The best part is feeling
like you're actually there.
Is it the seat of
our emotions? No.
- Do I want you to be...
- Virtual reality lets me attend
all my med school classes
and practice virtual surgeries.
But I do miss seeing patients.
Eh, new lungs
could change all that.
You would finish your
fourth year of med school,
maybe even come
here as an intern.
I can't think of
anything more amazing.
Yeah, all right. Here
we go, here we go.
Take a big breath. Blow
it out forcefully, sweetie.
Conrad, these are
Eloise's parents.
Florence and Dan
Camden, this is Dr. Hawkins.
- Hello.
- I've asked him
to do a complete workup.
Before we can move forward,
we need to be certain Eloise
is still healthy enough for
a double lung transplant.
We heard the donor is
already here at Chastain.
Can I ask who she is?
She's a young woman
who died of an opioid overdose.
That's awful.
I'm sorry. And
here I am, so happy.
Oh, it's okay.
You can have sympathy for
the donor and still be grateful.
Because the donor was an addict,
there is a very small
risk of complications,
but don't worry, the organs
have been through testing
to ensure they're safe.
When we thought a donor
might not come through,
Dan and I were tested.
We're both a match
and we can each supply
a lobe of our own lungs.
- Would that be better?
- Mom, we've been through this.
That would put both
of your lives at risk.
I've lived with
CF all of my life.
50 pills a day, hours
of breathing treatments.
Dad works three jobs to
pay for all my medical bills.
Mom has had to
take care of me 24/7.
Uh... they have suffered enough.
The donor lungs are
going to work, I'm sure of it.
As you can no doubt tell,
this case is personal to me.
I've been Eloise's med school
mentor since her first year.
Oh, she's frail, Kit.
- I hope we're not too late.
- I know.
Without new lungs, she
won't live another year.
And that would break my heart.
They found Julian's car.
We now go live to the
scene of a breaking story.
Earlier this morning
birdwatchers stumbled
across a car submerged in water.
It's registered to a local
woman, Julian Booth,
who's been missing
for some time.
Dive teams are now
looking for a body.
Hey, Conrad, what's up?
They found Julian's car.
Where?
Pulled it out of the
Chattahoochee River.
Did they find her body?
Still searching.
Devon,
she could have made it out of
the car. Until we know more...
Then where is she?
- Why haven't I heard from her?
- Look,
no matter what happens,
we're all here for you.
Whatever you need.
Thanks for the call.
How long have you
been in the hospital?
Three weeks.
I know you're scared,
but you're not alone.
Look... that's me.
I was diagnosed
with cystic fibrosis
when I was six weeks old.
I need a new heart.
I heard. The nurses told me.
I need new lungs.
The doctors are
gonna help us both.
Eloise.
Hi, guys.
This is Jeannie.
Hello, Jeannie.
Can we borrow Eloise
for a few minutes?
Sure.
- Will you come back?
- Absolutely.
Let's take the limo, shall we?
Where to?
Your room.
Your parents want to
hear what we have to say.
I think, somehow, I'm going to
need more oxygen to handle this.
I don't like the
look on your faces.
We have the
results of the tests.
Unfortunately, your
previous labs have worsened.
You now have extremely
elevated liver enzymes,
clotting factors, and
blood sugar levels.
Okay, I've been in
med school long enough
to know what that means.
I'm no longer eligible
for a lung transplant.
Usually, that would be the case,
but we've found a
potential solution.
A lung, liver and
pancreas transplant.
A triple transplant?
How did this happen?
Eloise's cystic fibrosis
has caused liver failure
and pancreatic insufficiency,
on top of her respiratory failure.
A triple transplant...
sounds impossible.
It's dangerous, rare,
but not impossible.
This operation has been
done successfully before.
How many times?
Once, in Canada.
Without this surgery,
how long do I have?
Not long, Eloise.
Weeks?
Maybe a little bit more.
It's okay.
- This isn't over.
- Mm-hmm.
We know what we have to do.
Can we get all three organs
from the donor we already have?
Yes.
Now, we just have to
convince the ethics committee.
Kit?
Come here.
You okay?
No.
This is awful.
I put a brave face
on it for the family.
Oh, but, my God, Conrad.
Where in the world are
we gonna find a surgeon
crazy enough to
even take this on?
A triple transplant?
Dr. Austin can't do
it. Bell assigned him
to low-risk surgeries.
We've been doing
stents all morning.
And you know I
am royally sick of it.
This quarterback is
coming off the bench.
There's no way.
Please, Randolph, as a
friend, just hear me out.
This is deeply important to me.
It's bad for Austin.
It's bad for Chastain.
I mean, I mean,
it looks like a...
Just a crazy publicity stunt,
and the ethics committee
will never allow it.
You chair the committee, you
can persuade them. I'll help.
- We can double-team them.
- Kit, I'm-I'm sorry.
I... It's-it's out
of the question.
You go ahead
and try if you'd like.
But I... I can't help
you on this one.
Mr. and Mrs. Basilico?
How are you doing?
Nicolette Nevin. Aw...
Jessie's older sister.
Do you remember, Eric?
Of course. You had blue hair.
I did. Teen years. How's Letty?
Maybe you'd like to see her.
She's gone, Nic.
Multiple doctors confirmed.
They're keeping her on the vent
because she wanted
to be an organ donor.
Apparently, she's donating
to a young woman here.
What happened?
Opioid overdose.
She's struggled with addiction
since her senior
year in high school.
I know that Letty tore her
ACL at the state championship.
Yeah, and her
doctor gave her Oxy.
They were handing
it out to everybody.
I know.
She never really got sober,
although we thought she did.
I really thought she'd
make it this time.
I didn't see any
signs she was using.
I did.
She wasn't eating
much, she'd lost weight.
Her moods were
all over the place.
She'd be anxious, on edge,
and then she'd be up, so up.
Why didn't you say anything?
I didn't want to see it.
What are you doing?
What'd you do with the
money I gave you, Jess?
I told you, I used it for a cab.
You're lying.
Did you even go to
that job interview?
So what if I didn't?
Whole thing was your idea.
I don't want to be a paralegal.
Stop going through
my stuff, Nic. Hey, quit it!
Quit lying to me! I
know you're using.
- God, I've been so stupid.
- You are insane.
You know that?
Completely insane.
I am not the problem
here, you are.
Hey! Give me that,
you controlling bitch!
Okay, I know what you
think, but it's not true, okay?
I-I keep these in
case I need them.
Stop. Just stop!
There is a huge amount
of pressure on me.
And you are in my
face day and night.
So, yes, I-I took a
few. Sometimes, okay?
Be-Because of you!
Y-You are driving me crazy!
This is my fault?
Unbelievable. Yeah, it's always
my fault with you, Jessie, huh?
Oh, poor little Nic.
Always a victim.
Jessie... Jessie,
stop. Listen to me.
You are using, and
you are in trouble.
Remember your friend
Letty from high school?
She's at Chastain, Jess.
She's dead because she OD'd.
I don't want that to be you.
- No.
- It's true.
Come with me to
Chastain. I'll show you.
I don't believe you.
Fine. Fine.
Either way, pack your bags,
'cause you're going to rehab.
I'm not going anywhere.
Then get out.
Get out.
I'm done, Jess.
I'm done trying to save
you. I'm done enabling.
I'm done worrying.
That's enough.
And if you die... I
won't feel guilty...
'cause I gave you every chance.
So, here, you want your pills?
You need them
that bad? Take 'em.
Take 'em, Jess.
I can't stop you
from killing yourself
if that's what you want.
When I come home, I
don't want to find you here.
- Can I help you?
- Yeah, I'm a friend of Julian's.
Tell her she's a week
behind on her rent.
She's not returning my calls.
Um, when was the
last time you saw her?
I don't know. Over a week.
She left the cat all alone.
I've been feeding it,
but it's driving me crazy.
I bet.
That's actually why I'm here.
Julian asked me to
come pick up the cat, but
I forgot her key.
If you let me in, I can
take the cat home with me.
Here's the key.
Thank you.
All set.
Hey.
Come on.
This, my friends, is what
you call a paracentesis.
It's pretty gross. Look
left, and you can see
Dr. Hawkins is removing fluid
that's collected in my abdomen.
You don't have to
stream this, Eloise.
People want to
know how I'm doing.
I've live-streamed all my
procedures for the last year
to med students and the
cystic fibrosis community.
As you can see,
my belly is shrinking.
Maybe I'll finally get some abs.
It also means that I'm
in severe liver failure.
I came in thinking I
was getting some lungs.
Now, we've learned that I
need a new liver and pancreas.
So, I will have a triple
transplant and make history.
Okay. Feel better?
- Yeah. Thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
- My pleasure.
Oh.
Dr. Austin and Dr. Okafor
are gonna be your surgeons.
Wow. We are honored.
It's Dr. AJ Austin in the flesh!
I love your lectures.
Thank you.
"Our time on this earth
begins and ends..."
And ends with a heartbeat.
Hi, Eloise.
I have a consent
form for you to read.
After the surgery, you'll
be on dozens of new drugs.
I'm sure you have concerns
about rejection and...
I may have a chest tube,
breathing tube, feeding tubes,
Foley catheter, and central
line for weeks, maybe months.
But I've got a life to live.
- I just have one question.
- Mm-hmm.
Can we livestream my
surgery to med students?
Uh...
Not the best idea,
under these circumstances.
But... since it's so rare,
whether I live or die, isn't
there a lot to learn from this?
Tell you what.
We'll talk to the bigwigs.
And for the record...
I'm cool with it.
Okay.
Hang tight. We're getting close.
Just one more hurdle left to
cross: the ethics committee.
Ah...
Look, we can keep going
around and around
about this all day,
but the problem is,
two lungs, a liver,
and a pancreas
could go to four people
instead of just one,
all of whom have a far
better chance of survival.
This is an exceptional person.
She's a top medical student
who'll make a great doctor.
We understand how you feel.
But all of our patients
are equally deserving.
Of course they are.
And the other candidates
will get organs, too,
just not from this donor.
They'll have to wait
a little longer, but
they'll still be next in line.
You're talking about a
five percent success rate.
These odds may be long,
but they are not impossible.
And it doesn't
account for variables,
- like the skill of the surgeons.
- Eloise started a nonprofit
to empower children
with disabilities.
She works for
access to medications
for those who can't afford them.
She's touched so many lives.
Dr. Bell, we're deadlocked.
This is up to you,
and you are worried
if this doesn't succeed,
it will be a blow to
Chastain's reputation.
But no matter what,
we advance science
and we open new possibilities
for thousands in the future
who could benefit
from this kind of surgery.
We can't just give up
and say it's too difficult.
It will never be
possible if we don't try.
I remember a surgeon
who took on the
toughest surgeries
in the state of Georgia.
Who gave hope to
people who had none.
Who had no fear.
He would have
jumped at the chance
to advance the science
and make medical history.
We are taking a
really big risk here.
But we are gonna
try to save this life.
No second chance
when it comes to
a Donation after Cardiac
Death. When that heart stops,
those organs stop
getting perfused with blood
and quickly become unusable.
When we hit that OR, we got
to be lightning fast to save them.
I thought no surgery
could scare me anymore,
but my heart is in
my throat this time.
Letty's heart has stopped.
All right, let's get
this show on the road.
No, not so fast.
We still have the five-minute
buffer to make sure
- the heart's actually stopped.
- I think Dr. Austin
is aware of the IOM guidelines.
Just a reminder to
do the right thing.
Let's dance.
Luckily, the Raptor's fearless.
Thank God. We need his courage.
- Sternal saw.
- 10 blade.
Catheter.
Cannulate.
Preservation fluids.
Fast and furious, baby.
Checking the liver...
and the pancreas.
They both look viable. Yours?
Lungs are not viable.
There's black discoloration.
A rare complication.
The nodules must not have
been detected during imaging.
We can't use these lungs.
We're done.
Remove the liver and pancreas.
Put them on ice.
There's another option.
This can't be over
before it starts.
It's not. You've already
been established
as lung donor matches.
We are gonna use a lobe
of lung from each of you
and the liver and
pancreas we just procured.
- If you agree.
- Of course,
but she'll only have
two lobes of lung.
All she needs is
And they will expand over time.
Better than her diseased ones.
Much better than
her diseased ones.
But they haven't been
prepped for surgery.
They haven't fasted, they could
aspirate when they go under.
Anesthesia can do a
rapid sequence intubation
to limit the risk of aspiration.
Let's get you both to pre-op.
If we don't move forward,
we may never have
another opportunity like this.
You're our daughter, Elo.
The board has agreed
to livestream the surgery,
but only to Eloise's
med school classmates,
- just a limited feed.
- Like she said,
no matter what, it will
be a great learning tool.
This just went from
an incredible long shot
to virtually impossible.
Well, then, we'd
better work a miracle.
There's an entire family
in there counting on us.
Hey, I'm on call for thoracic.
Said you guys could use a hand.
Welcome to the team, bro.
Hmm.
Diseased liver and
pancreas removed.
So far, so good.
Donor liver and pancreas,
ready for implantation.
Mom and Dad are stable.
Here we go.
How many people
are watching this?
Not many.
Probably just the gunners.
They're finishing the
liver and pancreas.
We need the right
lower lobe of lung.
The lobe's harder to
remove than we expected.
Mom has some adhesions
to the chest wall. Stapler.
Transecting the
segmental branches
off the pulmonary artery.
Get Dr. Austin. Now!
One order of lung to go.
- Mom's crashing. They need you.
- Get this to Okafor
and Bell to implant.
Page Dr. Weiss, tell
her to come close up.
Have we activated massive
transfusion protocol?
Yes. I've been trying to
repair the pulmonary artery,
but the damage is extensive.
Artery forceps to me.
Dr. Austin needs you
to implant the lung.
- Where's Dr. Austin?
- He's helping with the mom.
- She's bleeding out.
- What?
You stay. I'll go.
What's happening?
It's impossible to see anything.
We need to convert to open.
10 blade.
Retractor to Bell.
Put your finger on
that proximal P.A.
Getting the lung
out of the field
will give us a better view.
Looks like the lobe got damaged.
Implant the lung with
Mina. I'll fix the bleed.
3-0 Prolene.
On my mark, let go
and I'll sew this up.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
Go.
Suction. Lap.
Had to check on a patient.
- How we doing?
- Florence lost a lot of blood.
- They're working to save her.
- Eloise?
They're putting in Florence's
right lower lobe now,
but it may be damaged.
Eloise can't live
with only one lobe.
Dad's lobe on
the left looks good.
Mom's lobe on the right
shows some contusions.
Let's hope this works.
Dr. Chu, get the Ambu bag.
♪ Pack up ♪
Inflating the lungs.
♪ I'm straight... ♪
The moment of truth.
♪ Oh, say, say, say ♪
♪ Oh, say, say, say... ♪
Again.
♪ They don't love
you like I love you ♪
♪ Wait, they don't love you... ♪
Again.
I'm getting a lot of resistance.
- Is something wrong with
the tube? No, no, I checked.
Maybe it's reperfusion injury.
♪ Wait, they don't love
you like I love you... ♪
- We should check her airway.
- All you.
♪ Made off ♪
♪ Don't stray ♪
♪ My kind's your kind ♪
♪ I'll stay the same ♪
♪ Pack up ♪
♪ Don't stray... ♪
Hmm. Plug at the carina.
♪ Say, say, oh, say, say... ♪
Got it, try again.
♪ Wait ♪
♪ They don't love
you like I love you... ♪
Fingers crossed.
♪ They don't love
you like I love you ♪
♪ Maps ♪
♪ Wait ♪
♪ They don't love you
like I love you, wait ♪
♪ Wait ♪
♪ They don't love
you like I love you ♪
♪ Maps ♪
♪ Wait, they don't love
you like I love you ♪
♪ Wait ♪
♪ They don't love
you like I love you... ♪
Mom's not out of the woods yet.
You go, I'll close.
♪ Wait ♪
♪ Pack up ♪
♪ Don't stray ♪
♪ Enough. ♪
How do you feel?
Like I was just born.
Like I'm the luckiest
person in the world.
It's never been like this, ever,
just breathing.
My parents?
Hey, Elo.
Your dad's procedure went great.
Your mom...
There were some complications
with the pulmonary artery.
It can happen in
difficult surgeries like this.
- Recovery's not gonna be easy.
- But...
we believe she can make it.
Oh... Mom.
Mom, I'm here.
Right here, where you've
always been: beside me,
helping me.
Mom, can you hear me?
You're famous.
Just think how much
more insufferable you'll be.
I wouldn't count on it.
I have recently
dined on humble pie,
and it's a flavor I
will not soon forget.
That surgery was insane.
I mean, we're all
proud of the work we did
and are happy for
Eloise and her family,
but that could have
ended very badly.
A triple tragedy.
Skill certainly played a
large part, but so did luck.
It was practically a miracle.
Check it out. Our next surgery.
What are you gonna do?
Uh, we are going
to perform a flawless
aortic valve replacement.
- With a QuoVadis valve?
- A-A QuoVadis valve? Excuse me?
There are no QuoVadis
valves on Chastain shelves.
Are you telling me...
Bell pulled them?
Every last one.
We've got the old reliable
valves back for good.
- Well, today is
truly miraculous.
- Mm.
Bell, of all people,
did the right thing.
You pulled the
valves. Are you insane?
It was the right thing to do.
And I believe, eventually,
you'll agree with my decision.
This is way out of line.
Obviously, there will
be consequences.
You'll regret this, Dr. Bell.
Long day.
A great day.
I'm leaving, Dr. B. Uh, don't
forget you have that dinner
with the CEO of
Atlanta General at 8:00.
I canceled it. I have surgery.
Ah, that's a nice change.
See you tomorrow, boss.
To you.
Thank you for what you did.
Thank you.
Allow me.
It's a good look.
Yeah, I just had it pressed.
You've reached Mark Truscott,
Director of the Center
of Devices at the FDA.
Leave a message.
You broke into Julian's place?
Not exactly.
The landlady let me
in to get Julian's cat.
Don't ask.
- And you just took
her phone bill.
- Yes.
Look at the last number
that Julian called.
On the 3rd, the day
I saw her in the park.
The day she disappeared.
I tried the number
about an hour ago
and I got an answering machine.
It was an office at the FDA.
Julian was a device rep.
She probably called
them all the time.
Or maybe she found something out
and she was trying
to blow the whistle.
Look, you said it yourself.
Bradley died because
of a defective valve.
He was my best friend.
Did QuoVadis know
the valve was bad?
If so, they killed him.
Julian told me that
something was wrong at work.
She felt like everything
was falling apart.
What do you think she meant?
I think she was in danger.
Did they kill her?
Did she run away?
I don't know.
Something is up with QuoVadis.
Let's figure out
what to do next.
♪ All my worlds ♪
♪ And fault. ♪
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH