They train doctors. Slowly.
They watch us practice on frogs
and pigs and dead people,
and then live people.
They drill us relentlessly.
They raise us like children.
And eventually, they
take a cold, hard boot
and they kick us
out of the nest.
I have great faith
in you. Great faith.
I can because I chose
you. I trained you.
I've watched you work.
I know what you can do.
That's why today's different. The
training wheels are coming off, people.
I'm throwing down the
gauntlet today, people.
I've got a million dollar surplus,
and one department gets it.
You know what you need
and I know what you need.
Now, I want to know what you want.
And I'm gonna keep the residents busy.
Very busy. So that'll give you
time to put your best foot forward.
- Navy scrubs?
- Attending scrubs.
You are attendings today.
Run the cases. Take point.
But don't be a fool. If you get
in over your head, cry "uncle."
Until then, congratulations.
You've just been promoted.
Um, Chief Webber? Sorry.
I-I didn't get any scrubs.
This is for fourth-year
residents only, Grey.
It's just a regular day for you.
Fine. If they're gonna be attendings,
that makes me chief resident.
- That makes you
our scut monkey.
- No, it doesn't.
Does... Does it? It doesn't!
The attendings aren't going anywhere.
We're basically just playing dress-up.
Yeah.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
- Are you sure this
is a good idea?
- Of course it is.
We all did it. It's the
evolution of the craft.
The passing of the torch. The
lifeblood of the training process.
Here you go. Here you go.
Pray, people. We want
God in the building today.
- What time are we pitching you?
- Yeah, is there an order?
You people are adults. You decide
the order. I decide whose department
gets the million dollars.
I love a good dogfight.
He can be intimidating.
Once you get in the room.
- Really?
- Oh, yeah.
When I pitched my cartilage
research last year, he was all ticked off
'cause I had a typo in
my table of contents.
- You had a table of contents?
- Yeah.
What? I love a
good dogfight, too.
Ruff!
It's my case. You gonna
hand me over the chart?
What factors would lead a patient
to want breast reduction surgery?
Neck pain, back
pain, balance issues.
- Hand it over.
- Keep trying.
I don't know.
Maybe she's a prude.
Doesn't want everyone staring at her
all the time. Maybe she's embarrassed.
No. But you're getting warmer.
- Hi, I'm Dr. Karev.
- Mindy Gruberman.
- Nice to meet you.
- I can work with that.
She's not the patient.
Dr. Robbins. You'll be
on my service, too, huh?
Dr. Karev's gonna be
our team leader today.
Excuse me.
Honey, quit futzing with
the gown and come out here.
The doctors want to see you.
What's up?
Ms. Radigan, you're still having these
headaches and ringing in the ears?
All day long. It's
driving me crazy.
It's caused by a build-up
of fluid in your skull.
So, what we will
do is insert a shunt,
and that will relieve the
pressure on your brain.
What do you mean "we"? You're doing
the actual tube part in the brain, right?
- Not them?
- Excuse her. She's a school teacher,
she talks to everyone like they're
hiding gum behind their back.
It's all right. She can ask questions.
Dr. Grey and Dr. Avery are residents,
they're very talented. One of them
will be performing the procedure,
- and I will be observing.
- A trainee?
Cutting into Ellie's brain? No.
I know it sounds like a leap, but
these doctors study and assist for years.
At some point, we
have to let them operate.
- It's how we make new surgeons.
- Let them learn
on someone else.
Who? Someone who's too
scared to interrogate the doctors?
They have to learn on someone,
might as well be an old lady.
You're my old lady.
This should be my call.
I won't let them move a muscle
without my direction and approval.
You're a teacher,
Joanne. Let the kids learn.
She's my life. She has
been my life for 40 years.
Do you hear me?
I hear you.
Radiology, contact...
- Who gets to cut?
- I want to get a look
at both of you
with a drill before I
decide who gets the shunt.
Skills lab seems
like a fair way to go.
Competing with the wife.
Like that's not a stacked deck.
Well, it's a game, really.
So all you have to do is win.
Which you won't.
I don't like the idea of
teenagers getting plastic surgery.
If the growths were on his
face, you wouldn't have a problem
- with him wanting them removed.
- Yeah, but I
might have a problem
- with Karev removing them.
- I'll give you that.
- Oof! What happened?
- Karev's about
to do a gynecomastia
- surgery on a 13-year-old.
- Oh, Karev's fine.
He's done way bigger
procedures than that.
You two would just rather worry about
him than about your, uh, presentations
- to the chief.
- Oh! I'm not worried.
The money's going to the tiny humans.
No one ever says no to the tiny humans.
Oh. OK.
- What?
- Well...
You're not gonna cry, 'cause
you find the chief intimidating?
- No!
- Good!
- Good. OK.
- I have work to do.
Bye.
What, are you trying
to psych her out?
Ortho needs the money.
She and the friggin' tiny humans
have all the help they need already.
- I'm getting the money. Let it go.
- Oh, OK.
- Why wouldn't I?
- Well, because you never
prepare for anything,
you think you'll get by on
your good looks and charm
and the brilliance that
pops off the top of your head.
Yeah, 'cause it always works.
Mm... Uh-huh.
Roy Henley, 57, was
admitted two days ago
with severe wheezing from
pulmonary hypertension.
- Which basically means...
- I can't breathe for crap.
We're gonna run some tests that
should help us decide how to proceed.
You can run all the tests you
want. But what I need is new lungs.
My doctor said I was gonna need
'em one day, but I was too healthy for it.
I bet I'm not too healthy now.
Dr. Yang?
We'll run some tests.
Uh, Mr. Henley, you listed your
daughter as your emergency contact.
- Is she here with you today?
- No, she lives
over in Aberdeen.
- I don't want to trouble her.
- Is there anyone here with you?
I'm a tough old dog. I
don't need a chaperone.
Sir, your condition is serious.
It might be time to
trouble your daughter.
- We think he's
a transplant candidate?
- Do we?
At this point, I don't think there's
anything else we can do. Right?
Dr. Yang? Do you agree?
I don't know.
- You don't know if you agree?
- - He'd have to be approved
by the transplant team
before going on the waiting list.
- Do we convene a panel?
- Yang, do we?
I couldn't say.
He's running out of time. I say
we convene the panel for today.
OK, convene the
panel. And then what?
I get some interns to order
Mr. Henley's tests. On it.
Dr. Yang. "I don't know"?
I'm here, I am trying,
but taking point...
I am not asking you to be in an
OR. I am asking you to say something.
To participate. We're
at a crossroads, Yang.
A crossroads where you
either get in the game...
or I tell Richard it's
time to send you home.
Imagine. Seattle Grace.
The hospital that made
heart surgery obsolete.
That's a big claim.
If the five million Americans
who suffer from heart failure
could simply just regenerate
their own damaged hearts...
It sounds like magic, but
it's possible. It's happening.
Dr. Altman, stem cell
research is on the cutting edge
of every field of
medicine. Why cardio?
Well, Cardio and Neuro are
the beacons of this hospital.
They're what put you on the map.
But you know what? You
can't give this money to Neuro.
Neuro isn't even really a department.
It's just one strong surgeon.
You're better off putting your
money onto a deeper bench.
- What do you mean?
- Well, Shepherd, he's
like a charismatic cult leader.
He's very appealing and he's got a bunch
of people hiding in his shadows. But...
Don't get me wrong,
he is a great surgeon.
And he can pull off a flashy
procedure. But is he cultivating talent?
Is he taking the time to teach your
residents, knowing when to push
and dishing out tough love when
they need it? That's the hard part.
I don't know, maybe Shepherd
just doesn't like competition.
He tried to fire me. Not that
I'm holding a grudge or anything.
Well, not much of one, anyway.
I'm, uh...
I feel like I should
have stuck to my notes.
- Is Teddy saying
you could be fired?
- Sounded that way.
Well, is she trying to
scare you? Is it working?
- I don't think so.
- Oh! Damn it.
- What's his problem?
- Derek's got us competing
for a brain shunt insertion.
The egg is the skull.
You can break the shell, but
you can't break the membrane.
- Damn it!
- I feel bad for him.
He's kind of losing it.
I shouldn't be in
charge of anybody.
Just put one foot in front of the
other. Just get through the day.
Grey! You broke
my concentration.
Sorry. Um, hey. Post-ops look
good, so if there's nothing else...
Oh, could you discharge 1224?
And his chart needs to be dictated.
Uh, yes. It's gonna have to wait
until after I check on Torres' knee girl,
turf the window jumper to Psych,
remove a june bug from
some kid's ear in the pit,
write meds for screaming kidney
stones guy and then deliver labs
- to my goiter lady.
- Stop bragging.
I can't. I was born
for this kind of day.
No. Stop.
Seth. No.
- OK? This can
wait a couple years.
- Mom!
You said this was my decision!
You said after my bar mitzvah,
I'd be a man and I could decide.
That is because we thought by
13, you'd make the mature decision.
You can't cut off the
parts of your body
that you don't like, all right? I don't
like my thighs or my saggy arms
or my chin, but if we all
cut off the parts we don't like,
- we'd all have nothing left.
- Mom!
Seth! Your father has the
exact same chest as you,
and nobody thinks he's a woman.
Would you please talk to her?
I'm calling your father.
They call me Booby at
school. Man-boobs, Double D.
Some kid keeps hanging
a bra on my locker.
I'm starting high
school in a year.
It's gonna be all new
people. I just wanna start over.
I wanna be normal
like everyone else.
Why can't we just
skip the panel?
We know I need the lungs.
Not everyone makes a
good transplant candidate.
If someone can't reliably
take their anti-rejection meds...
- I can.
- Or has severe disease
- in another organ...
- I don't.
There are just
a lot of indicators
as to whether a
person is strong enough
- to survive the surgery.
- I wanna know what she thinks.
The one with the
sourpuss on her face.
I don't have a sourpuss.
This is just my face.
It's true. It is just her face.
You think I'll pass the panel?
I couldn't say.
Cheer up, sourpuss.
You're young,
you got your health.
I think you're doing
all right. Both of you.
Practically kids, and doctors, no
less. I bet your dads are really proud.
I'm from a small town. A farm, actually.
So yes, my dad was over the moon
- when I became a doctor.
- What about you?
Karev. Seth's
mother just came by
saying she wants to pull the
plug on the kid's procedure.
- That your idea
of taking point?
- I'm gonna talk to her.
I spent two hours consulting
with this family last month.
Ten minutes with you,
they're ready to walk.
Pediatric surgery is 80 percent parent
management, Karev, you know that.
I'm handling it.
Megan, hi. I'm Dr. Grey. Just
checking in to see how you're feeling.
Megan. Meg!
- She doesn't hear well
when she's texting.
- I can hear her.
Where's the other
doctor? Dr. Torres.
Oh, I'll be checking you
today. How's your knee?
- Is the, uh, pain any better?
- Look, you seem really sweet,
but this whole, like, super busy,
messy-hair, running like a banshee thing
you have going doesn't
exactly inspire confidence.
I mean, you don't
even know my case.
Meg Whealon. Age 28.
Tibial plateau fracture
caused by a bicycle accident. At
least, that's what you told the ER,
but you told Dr. Torres
that you were
going 30 miles an hour, which
makes me think that you were
on your boyfriend's motorcycle. I'm
gonna guess he has a license for it
- and you don't.
- This is off
the top of your head?
I memorized your chart. Your
fracture was fixed with elevation
and percutaneous screw fixture.
You are allergic to penicillin.
Currently on blood thinners to
make sure you don't develop DVT,
and if you'd just talk to me about
your knee, I could adjust your pain meds
and be out of your hair.
She's good.
- You're good.
- I'm busy. But I can handle it.
Every doctor in this hospital needs
trauma training. Disaster training.
You've got a strong department.
No, not just my staff, everyone.
Eleven people died in that shooting.
Eight of them never had a chance.
But the other three
could have been saved.
Charles Percy had a gunshot
wound to the abdomen.
Miranda Bailey did everything
that she was trained to do.
She gave him fluids, controlled
the bleeding, applied pressure.
Then she tried to get him
to an OR. But she couldn't.
And so he died. A doctor with
disaster training would have been able
to assess that environment more quickly
and known an alternative escape route.
Dr. Bailey was not
trained to do that.
Neither are 90 percent of
the doctors on your staff.
She'll remember him dying
in her arms the rest of her life.
And I'll remember it. And you'll
remember that we could have saved him.
We failed her.
And we failed Charles
Percy. One of our own doctors.
I can't face that.
I can't face that ever again.
Can you?
I'd like to expand the
burn unit at Seattle Grace.
Make us the go-to destination
for serious burn victims.
I'd also like to upgrade us to a
real nationally renowned center
- for cosmetic
reconstructive surgery.
- Two sub-specialties?
The revenue from the cosmetic
center helps support the burn unit.
One hand scratches the other.
It's a nice idea, and an awfully
ambitious plan for a million dollars.
And a tremendous amount of work.
I'm not seeing anyone right now.
I'm not sleeping with nurses.
Residents, attendings... Nobody.
So I'm an untapped
source of raw power.
I'm telling you, I have
the energy of ten men,
so with your million dollars
and my untapped stores,
we can move mountains.
Are you excited? I'm excited.
Leave. Right now. Just...
Just...
Mrs. Gruberman, every
surgery has its risks,
but this one is pretty simple.
It'll make your son feel a
whole lot better about himself.
If the surgery is really a
good idea, I would like to hear it
- from Dr. Robbins
and Dr. Sloan.
- Look, I'm...
No. I will speak to
Dr. Robbins and Dr. Sloan.
Cristina! Cristina, Roy's labs.
He's got fungal pneumonia and his
creatinine clearance is dangerously low.
If it gets any worse, we're
looking at renal failure.
I'm surprised he was
sitting up and talking.
After surgery, couldn't the
immunosuppressants kill him?
- Maybe.
- Well, OK. If we don't recommend him,
he dies. But, uh, if we recommend
someone who won't survive,
then it's just a waste of an organ
that could have gone to someone else.
- What do you think?
- I don't know.
You need to know. We have to have
an opinion, we called the stupid panel!
We have to stand up in
front of Teddy, and the chief
and a room full of doctors and
recommend whether this guy lives or dies.
And it's right down the middle
with this guy. Like a trick question.
It's a trick...
Fine. Forget it.
The right opinion,
the only opinion that matters,
is Teddy's. So I will just
figure out what she
thinks, and I will say that.
OK.
Don't you care at all?
Come on, you gotta care.
- No, you did not say that to the chief!
- - Oh, God.
It's your fault, you know.
You psyched me out.
- What? All I ever do
is support you.
- Oh, look at that face.
- That's her game face. She's in it to win it.
- Huh?
Oh! Hey, Karev! Did
you talk to Seth's mother?
She's thinking about it. She
may wanna talk to you guys again.
- Way to handle it.
- I can't force her
to listen to me.
Keep your face in that
book. It'll inspire confidence.
Oh, my God.
OK, that's getting in
someone's head. I'm just honest.
- Um, I'm up with the chief. I gotta go.
- Knock him dead.
Oh. Wait, here. I brought
you tissues, just in case.
Thanks.
- You have a sickness. You do.
- Hm? Oh.
OK, 30 seconds. If neither one
of you breaks the membrane,
I'm gonna have to
judge you on precision,
so make sure your
initials are clean and clear.
- Dr. Shepherd?
- Yes.
Stop talking!
Five, four, three,
two, one, time.
What do you got?
Oh. Not bad. What
about you, Dr. Avery?
- I just wish I had more time.
- Oh, really?
- You did your whole name.
- What?!
You conned me!
I don't know what
you're talking about.
He hustled me! He went
through two dozen eggs
and made me think I
didn't have to practice.
If you didn't practice, Meredith,
you were over-confident.
Dr. Avery, congratulations.
You have the surgery.
And then I would take the remaining
money and invest it in resources
for less invasive
pediatric cancer surgeries.
Even the smallest change could
dramatically improve the lives
of so many children.
Wouldn't that be amazing?
That is a very compelling and very
focused presentation, Dr. Robbins.
- You seem surprised.
- No. Not at all.
Did you think I
was going to cry?
- Yeah.
- Yeah. Um...
Torres suggested that I
was going to cry as well.
I think that we should all try to wipe
the crying thing out of our memories.
It happens very rarely,
it's embarrassing,
and, frankly, I think
I've got it under control.
And the fact that my colleagues see
me as the type of person who would burst
into tears in the middle of an
important professional situation,
well, that doesn't make me
weepy, that makes me mad.
Like, violent. It makes me
want to punch someone.
And, you know, I'm the
daughter of a Marine, sir.
So I was taught to hit as a child, I
was taught to hit fast and hit hard,
so you only have to hit once. Now,
I feel like hitting a person or a wall.
No, a person!
Mm...
Let's just circle back to
the sweet little children.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
I like the dark blue scrubs
on you. You look good.
You OK?
My patient deserves a doctor.
You don't have to cut.
Nobody's asking you to.
I know that. I know what's being
asked of me and I'm doing it.
OK. I got an idea. And
I think it's gonna help.
You and me, we're gonna
go outside into the alley
behind the hospital and
you're just gonna kick my ass.
You're gonna knock
the living crap out of me.
There you are.
I knew you were
in there somewhere.
At the end of this day, good or
bad, we're gonna go home together.
Whatever it takes to get him
home. I just wanna get him home.
- Um, two to three more...
- Thirteen is young
for plastic surgery.
But your kid's not gonna grow out of
it. He's already gone through puberty,
and his father's had the
same condition his entire life.
If he had weight to lose, I
would advise diet and exercise.
But your kid doesn't have a
weight problem. He has breasts.
He needs excision
of the glandular tissue.
And yeah, it could wait till he's
older. But he's a dude with breasts
and he's headed for high school and
there's no reason he should be subjected
to the psychological damage that comes
from years of taking schoolyard crap.
You want your kid to be a man?
Let him make his own decisions.
Any other questions?
- Hey. I got a page. Is everything OK?
- Something's wrong.
First, she had a
headache and then...
I can't see.
Everything is blurry.
- OK, look right here.
- I am freaking out.
Tell me I don't
need to freak out.
The left side of my
body feels weird.
I thought it was because I
fell asleep on it, but it's tingling.
- OK, squeeze my hand.
- She had knee surgery.
- What the hell is going on?
- I don't know yet,
but I'm gonna order a head CT, and
I'm going to page for a Neuro consult.
Looks like you're gonna get to
see another doctor today after all.
The minute I hand you
this drill, you're on your own.
You may have hustled Dr. Grey,
but you better not have hustled me.
This is not a game.
This is a real brain.
I got it. I'm ready.
Dr. Shepherd, Lexie Grey is
paging you for a consult repeatedly.
I'm in surgery. Dr. Grey?
Well, are you sure? I wouldn't
want to be over-confident.
- Cardio is not my thing.
- What?
Neuro is my focus.
And this is cardiothoracic
and I've had relatively little
experience with cardiothoracic,
and I'm pretty sure I'm gonna walk
in there today and humiliate myself.
Or humiliate you. Or
Teddy, or the chief.
Really, anyone who could
possibly be humiliated by my failure
is gonna be humiliated today.
He was admitted two days ago.
Teddy could've convened a
panel yesterday, but she didn't.
- She doesn't think
he's a candidate.
- No, she doesn't.
So just say that,
and you'll be fine.
Everyone will be fine,
except for Roy,
who will be dead.
Wow. Way to kill a happy moment.
Where's Shepherd?
I paged Shepherd.
- You got me.
- You her boss?
There's something
seriously wrong here.
I need you to go to the waiting
room right now. Right now.
Sir, come with me.
OK, um, she's post-op day
two from a tibial plateau fracture.
She was fine all day,
fine. Then ten minutes ago,
she started complaining
of headache, blurred vision
and tingling on the left side of
her body. I ordered a stat head CT.
I cannot believe that
you're the Neuro consult!
- Is she on blood thinners?
- Yes, for DVT prophylaxis.
She's got a brain
bleed. Let's book an OR.
- How didn't I see this coming?
- Did you check her platelets?
- Yes.
- And everything was normal?
- Until now, yes.
- OK. You checked her platelets,
you got a CT, you called
Neuro, you did everything right.
The only thing you're doing wrong
is standing around talking about it
wasting time while we should
be getting her to the OR.
You totally sounded
like an attending.
Right? Let's page Shepherd 911.
Great.
Dr. Shepherd, it's Dr. Grey
again. Meredith Grey.
Just passing the
ventriculostomy tube now.
- Almost there.
- Take your time, Dr. Avery.
- You wanna make sure...
- Damn it! Damn it, damn it, damn it!
Are you kidding me? Are you
kidding me? What did you do?
And that is why the future
of Ortho is in xenografting.
You think I'm nuts.
You're thinking, "I don't want
some cow ligament in my leg.
- That sounds wacky!"
- Is that supposed
to be my voice?
No. That's the voice of
the average baby boomer.
I was hoping for
something more...
inspirational.
For... For example, Dr. Robbins
suggested that we take...
Oh, yeah. The tiny humans.
- What?
- Arizona is nicer than I am.
- I'm sorry...
- She's more patient.
She went to Hopkins, she's
more renowned in her field,
she's a much better lesbian. I mean, I
was sort of a late bloomer in that area.
But she's got this whole
circle of lesbian friends.
It's like this sub-culture.
And, uh, I'm always just...
I'm always just
a little bit left out.
Just a little bit talked down to,
because I have a long history
of enjoying sex with men, which I
don't think is something I have to
apologize for. Whatever,
I'm just... She's just... She's...
- She's just better.
- So you want me to give Ortho
a million dollars to level the
playing field in your relationship?
Also, for the xenografting.
Which, as I mentioned,
is the future of
sports medicine.
Can I ask you something?
Are you one of those, uh, you
know, what do you call 'em...
When someone's really
smart, like a genius,
but they're a little different?
Like they don't know
how to talk to people?
- Are you asking me
if I'm autistic?
- That's the word.
Oh, come on.
You barely said
three words all day.
Don't be offended.
You're a tough nut to crack.
I like that about you. My
daughter's the same way.
- Were you able to make contact?
- Yeah. She's not coming.
I'm not all that surprised. Messy
divorce, she sided with her mom.
I hate it, but I get it.
And life goes on.
So it's just you
and me, sourpuss.
Dr. Yang, the, uh,
panel is gathering now.
Yeah, I'll be right there.
Hold on one second.
Hold on. Here you go.
Thank you.
This is gonna go my way, right?
They just don't send
people home to die.
I want to live.
We'll let you know.
- Is there anything I can do?
- I don't know, Avery.
Is there anything you
can do? Thank you.
Where are you?
We're having a problem.
I'm fixing it now.
I've got a post-op Ortho patient
on DVT prophylaxis with
a subdural hematoma.
Derek, she's got a blown pupil.
I'm not gonna be
there for a while,
- so take care of it yourself.
- What?
You wanted a solo surgery today?
Now's your chance. Take point.
- I need loops and a headlight.
- Here you go, doctor.
OK. Scalpel.
If I root against him,
that make me a bad guy?
The patient's a child, Mark.
All right, Karev. You got this.
If you don't, we're right here.
All right, people,
here we go. Ten blade.
OK.
You're letting Kepner
lead the transplant panel?
Yang's been useless.
She's no better than an intern.
- Did you just stop
that bleeder?
- Uh-huh.
How did you even
know to do that?
- Hey. Sorry I'm late.
- It's OK.
Lexie made a good call,
I've got it under control.
- What do we got?
- Let me finish, Derek. I got this.
Yes, you do.
- I'm gonna find
a cure for Alzheimer's.
- The cure for Alzheimer's.
- With a million dollars.
- With a million dollars,
- it's a start.
- You're talking
about a clinical trial?
- A clinical surgical trial?
- Yes.
Start-up costs alone,
never mind the FDA, Derek...
Today, I watched Meredith perform
an emergency craniotomy by herself.
She was perfect. She's
got her mother's talent.
She's got her
mother's looks, Richard.
What if she has her
mother's disease?
Ellis was young when it started.
Every time Meredith forgets her keys
or asks what day of the week it is, I...
When that million dollars runs out,
investors are gonna throw money my way
for the same reason I'm gonna
throw everything I've got at this trial.
Because their dad
has it. Or their wife.
Breakthroughs don't happen
because of the medicine.
Real breakthroughs happen
because someone is scared to death
to stop trying.
They're gone?
Well, there's some swelling, but
that should go down with some time.
I don't have boobs.
- I don't have boobs?
- You don't have boobs.
- Mom?
- She was scared.
Now, she's just happy you're OK.
- You're the man.
- No, you're the man.
Roy Henley has end-stage
pulmonary hypertension.
He has reached the point of
no return, and, at this point,
nothing short of a lung
transplant will save him.
Unfortunately...
Unfortunately, his cultures revealed
that he has fungal pneumonia,
his liver enzymes are worrisome,
and on top of everything else,
his creatinine
clearance is only 75,
which means that he is
on his way to kidney failure.
The immunosuppressants after
surgery could very likely kill him.
And so, with regret,
I conclude that he does
not belong on the waiting list.
Dr. Kepner, if you don't
believe he's a candidate,
why in the world would
you convene a panel today?
That is a very
good question, chief.
I did think that he was a
candidate, earlier in the day,
but the longer I
looked at his criteria,
- the more glaring it became.
- It became glaring,
the more you looked at it?
Well, also, uh, new
facts came to light. Um...
The patient has
no support system.
No one to take him for post-op visits
or make sure he complies with his meds.
Earlier in the day, he
said he had a daughter,
but later it came out
that they're estranged.
- That's not a reason.
- Dr. Yang?
Do you have something to add?
No.
You don't believe that having
a support system in place
is an important
factor in this decision?
It's one factor.
But this guy is borderline,
that's why we're here.
We could talk about
his criteria all day.
His creatinine clearance
is low but not critical,
and his fungal pneumonia
is bad but treatable.
I mean, he's borderline.
But I've been involved
in 27 transplant surgeries.
And every time, the patient's will to
fight is just as telling and Roy has it.
If we give him the lungs, it won't
be a waste, 'cause he will live.
I know it.
So how am I...? What am
I supposed to say to her?
That I botched the insertion
and then I punctured the vessel?
- Or maybe that
an error was made?
- You don't tell her anything.
You made a mistake.
It happens all the time.
I had to yell at you because
that's my job. My job now...
Our job now is to go in
there with smiles on our faces
and tell her the surgery was
a success, because it was.
- Hey! How are we?
- There they are! Our heroes!
The ringing stopped. It stopped!
- That's fantastic news.
- And the kid did good, right?
The kid did good.
I'm kissing you now.
'Cause I was wrong,
but in this moment,
I am in love with you.
Oh! Thank you.
We were supposed
to be a team today.
You told me what to say and
then you just turned on me?
I didn't plan it.
I'm not used to failing.
Neither am I.
You OK? All right.
I know you think recommending
him was the wrong decision.
I'm sorry, but I
just didn't agree.
Cristina, in a case like
this, the right decision
is making a decision. That's
what we do, that's the job.
You formed an opinion
and you argued for it.
And you weren't alone. The
panel voted to put him on the list.
Congratulations.
You were a doctor today.
Talk to me.
Um, there is a broken CT
machine in the basement.
Next to it is a broken argon
laser and a broken fluoroscope.
I think a million dollars
would repair all three of them.
And there might even
be enough money left over
to put a new nurse on the night shift,
which is what our patients really need.
That's it?
That's what you got for me?
That's your best idea?
This assignment couldn't
have been clearer. Inspiration.
Good old-fashioned competition,
not you coming in here telling me
I need to fix what's old and broken.
Um, I would love to go to Paris.
But you don't see me sitting
around, planning my Parisian vacation.
It sounds nice,
but I am a mother,
and what I really need to
do is get my kid to preschool,
get the laundry done,
put food on the table.
I can do a big tap dance here
about how I'm gonna change the
face of medicine with a million dollars,
but you can't do anything
with a million dollars.
A million dollars is nothing.
That's a dream. This is real life.
Preschool. Laundry. Food.
I'm realistic. Change
the face of medicine.
We need to fix the medicine
that we already have.
We need a new night nurse. We
need these broken machines repaired.
Let's not go to Paris. Let's
go to the grocery store, chief.
And while we're being honest,
why are you wasting our
time with this exercise anyway,
when you and I both know
you don't have a million dollars.
Well, things may be a little different
around here in the next few weeks.
Look at that.
Now, I can't call you
sourpuss anymore.
Give me your arm, Roy.
I have to draw some blood.
We all want to grow up.
We're desperate to get there.
To grab all the
opportunities we can.
To live.
We're so busy trying
to get out of that nest...
we don't think about the fact
that it's gonna be cold out there.
Really freakin' cold.
Thank you, sir.
Congratulations. Good job.
Because growing up sometimes
means leaving people behind.
- Congratulations, doctor.
- Thanks.
Oh, damn it. Where are my keys?
- They're in your hand.
- Oh!
And by the time we
stand on our own two feet...
we're standing there alone.