Previously on The Resident...
Facing our new reality, the
Cain Center for Neurosurgery.
- There's good news.
- My cancer's in remission.
I have a shot at
getting my life back.
Dr. Torres here is a
magician in the OR.
Go be one of those
celebrity TV doctors,
make a lot of money, wear
nice clothes. You'd be great at it.
Three different patients.
All with organophosphate
poisoning,
all on 3B Life.
The only link that we do
have is your supplement.
- We need to call public health
and warn them about it.
- That's ridiculously premature.
But if we wait,
people could die.
- Dr. Hawkins, welcome back.
- Nice to be back.
Leaving me out of
the loop on Hawkins
is a sign of disrespect
to the surgeon
who's made more rain for you
and Red Rock than anyone else.
Not as much as you used to.
Everyone has an expiration date.
Good morning, everyone.
Today, we open up
the doors to the most
advanced neurological
institute this country's ever seen.
Or at least the most expensive.
Red Rocks stands to
make $1 million a day
on surgeries alone.
No wonder they were so
quick to open this place.
- Hey.
You hungry?
I'm not here to eat,
I'm here to work.
Red Rock packed in so many
patients, they need more nurses.
I've got a bad feeling
about this place.
I'd like to extend a warm
welcome to all of our donors
I see out here today.
It's your investment
in the future that's made
this institute possible.
Well, if it makes you feel any
better, today's my admin day,
so I'm stuck on desk duty.
- All papers, no patients.
- Well, you know what they say,
"With great power, comes
boring responsibilities."
You have an office,
Chief Resident. I have no pity.
You have no idea how
bad I am at scheduling.
Please, come help me.
- Nope.
- Out.
The brain is the
new frontier for us.
Treatment and diagnosis...
I feel like I'm sending
you off to the wolves.
I'll be fine.
It's the wolves I'm
worried about, not you.
It's gonna be thrilling,
- but most importantly...
- Hey.
It's gonna be groundbreaking.
Go get 'em.
Thank you all for
being here today.
Now, if you'll excuse
me, I have to go scrub in.
Is it me or is it cold in here?
Yeah, I already
called maintenance.
They said it should
be warming up soon.
Anyone know where
the butterfly needles are?
I think I saw them
in the supply closet.
- Top shelf, far right.
- Ah.
Sorry. I'm still getting
the hang of this new
EMR software. It hates me.
I gave up and
faxed in a request.
- Faxed?
- Girl's got to do.
Um, I'll be right back.
Annie.
Nic. Oh, no, don't worry,
I'm not a patient. Still
cancer-free, thankfully.
I'm here with Lucy.
Lucy, this is Nurse Nevin.
She helped me
through my own surgery.
- Hi.
It's nice to meet you.
I started fostering
a few months ago.
Thought about doing
it for years, but I guess
cancer was the kick in
the pants that I needed.
Oh, that's amazing.
What brings you in?
Headaches, throwing up,
tingly feet... Should
I keep going?
The doctors found a brain tumor
a little over a year
before I met Lucy.
Because of the
size and the location,
they said that a watch
and wait approach was best
- until it got worse.
- Which it did.
A few days ago,
Lucy fainted in the cafeteria
at school during lunch.
I took out half of the
salad bar on my way down.
My hair still smells like ranch.
But they did an MRI,
and now we're just waiting
to hear back on
the surgical plan.
Well, it says here, uh,
that she's scheduled
for a tumor resection
this afternoon
with... Dr. Cain.
Of course.
The surgeon who saved
me operating on my little girl
in this amazing new hospital.
I'm really glad
she's in good hands.
Why don't I join
Lucy's team today?
- Yeah, we'd love that.
- Yeah.
Great. Me, too.
♪ ♪
I'm looking forward to operating
with you again, Dr. Okafor.
First, we need to get in
and out of this patient's room
- as quickly as possible.
- I prefer to take my time.
Really get to know a
patient before surgery.
Where they're
from, what they do.
- Clearly he hasn't met them yet.
- Nope.
Enough!
The entire hospital
can hear you.
Would you give it a rest?
Professor, this is Dr. Torres.
He'll be joining our team.
It's a pleasure to meet...
Listen. All day he crunches,
piles up his dirty clothes,
orders take-out food at all
hours to stink up my room.
- Our room.
- Oh, now you can hear me?
They both have end
stage heart failure,
and they both need a heart.
Same blood type, heart size,
and immune system compatibility.
But that's all they
have in common.
My side, my rules.
Hey, check it out.
I just finished this one.
It's part of my series.
I call it,
"Angry Little Man Who
Definitely Needs to Chill."
- Nice.
- I'm an artist.
Yeah, if no one
pays you, it's a hobby.
Oh, come on, Professor.
Real artists don't
do it for the cash,
they do it to help
show people the truth.
Hey, that's right. I
make art to move people.
Why don't you find yourself
moving to a different room?
I swear, if I have to spend
another day in here...
You don't. We're here
because a donor heart
is on its way from Savannah.
And since you're
top of the list,
we've got you scheduled
for surgery later today.
Thank God.
I was worried that
if I died in here,
that kid's face would be
the last thing I ever saw.
You should be so lucky.
Thank you for having me on.
Don't thank me.
Your publicist called
in a favor at network.
And we're back
in five, four, three...
Anyone tired? Want more energy?
Yes!
Yes, of course you do.
Well, my next guest says that
his new supplement might
be just the thing for you.
Dr. Bell, there are a lot
of supplements out there.
What makes 3B Life different?
3B Life is a proprietary
blend of nutrients
designed to fortify
your whole body.
- I take it myself every day.
- I figured you did,
or you wouldn't have
put your face on the bottle.
Yeah, uh...
You know, I've worked
in hospitals for 40 years,
and I'm sorry to say,
we are unhealthier
today than ever before.
Half of all Americans
are uninsured.
And, you know, I remember
a young man came in
with liver failure, and
he was uninsured,
and couldn't afford
a doctor's visit,
so there was nobody
there to tell him
that his disease could
be easily managed
with lifestyle and
diet, and by the time
he came in...
It's too late.
Yeah, and I see so
many patients like that.
People that want to take
control of their own health,
but they... they
just don't know how.
And they don't know
who to trust. And that's...
that's why my
face is on the bottle.
Hello?
You were great.
Very real. Very human.
Regina.
You all right?
Remember the patients
from Atlanta General
with organophosphate poisoning?
The ones that may
have taken 3B Life?
Why?
One of them just died.
- This is not our fault.
- I need you to both relax.
Well, you didn't just
go on national television
and tell two million people
that 3B Life is the best
thing since penicillin.
Okay, you don't actually
think that our product
caused a man's death?
No. I don't want to believe
that we're responsible
any more than you do.
What happened has
nothing to do with our product.
We tested our
facility. It's clean.
- Our ingredients are safe.
- I know.
I know they are.
I'm just gonna see if I can
get the man's records sent over
from Atlanta General
just to confirm
whether or not he
was even taking 3B.
Social media's blowing up
about your Pierce appearance.
Mentions on Facebook
are strong. Twitter, same.
Even the trolls like you.
So you can expect
a surge in sales.
No, no. Let's just
delay shipments...
Stopping shipments could
make people ask questions.
Well, that's a chance we have
to take. I... We have to exercise
an overabundance of caution
on the small possibility
that we may have
injured someone.
I am sorry a man died,
but it could've been
an allergic reaction,
or an underlying condition.
Who knows, maybe
it was just his time.
Well, maybe isn't good enough.
I need to check on the others.
- Others?
- Let's just get back
to Chastain.
Hey! I saw you
on TV this morning.
You make us proud, Dr. B.
I'll catch up with you
in a couple minutes.
How'd you get his
medical records?
A friend at Atlanta General.
The autopsy will
happen later today.
30-year-old male. Diagnosed
with organophosphate poisoning.
Treated with atropine, 2-PAM.
Full recovery,
until this morning.
Yeah, he was about
to be discharged,
they found him
in cardiac arrest.
- And what am I looking for?
- Anything unusual,
an allergic reaction,
some underlying condition
that might've caused his death.
You mean something
other than your supplement?
Look, I've reviewed
all their files looking for
any another possible cause.
I just, I'd like you to
re-examine all three.
Dr. Pravesh already did
a very thorough workup,
- detailed history...
- You have a way of
seeing what other doctors miss.
Just take another look,
that's all I'm asking you to do.
If I found out it's 3B Life,
you know I won't keep quiet.
I need to know.
Let's just try and make
sure nobody else dies.
I'll be awake for the surgery?
Your brain tumor is
near your speech center.
Being awake allows me to
avoid the brain tissue which is
critical to your
ability to speak.
But you'll be able to talk
and see what's going on.
- Will it hurt?
- No.
You won't feel a thing.
There are no pain
receptors in your brain.
Well, that's good.
What if I have to sneeze?
Then we'll get you a tissue.
Now, I'd like to
be there with her.
I'm sorry. There are no
family members allowed.
But you'll be there, right?
Absolutely.
I'm sure we can
arrange something.
I can't believe my new heart
is actually in the building.
Your long wait is over.
We've seen your heart,
and it looks perfect.
Oh, thank you.
You're a little warm.
Ah, I feel fine. It's
probably just excitement.
Yeah. Probably.
We'll check back on
you soon, all right?
The professor's
temp is 100.1 now.
If it reaches 100.4,
we'll have to temporarily
take him off the
transplant list.
All right. Get two cultures
and start him on
empiric antibiotics.
- I don't want to take a chance.
- It could just be a bad reaction
to one of the medications.
Maybe. But we need to
keep a close eye on him
over the next few hours.
Hey.
- Hey.
- Sorry, am I interrupting?
Not at all. We just finished.
Okay, tonight I am
drinking all the drinks.
Oh. What's wrong?
What isn't?
I want Chem-7s every four hours.
Strict ins and outs. Page
me with any new symptoms.
If anyone sneezes, I
want to hear about it.
You think I missed something?
No. Everything I've
seen indicates you made
the right diagnosis and gave
all three the right treatments.
Then why reevaluate?
- Bell.
- Yeah.
He is looking for a way out.
- Mm, maybe.
- I know that he had your back
when you got fired, but
the man has gone from CEO
and chief of surgery
to the basement.
How long until he goes
back to being the guy
that would do anything
to save his own skin?
I say we give him the
benefit of the doubt.
Right now, people taking
Bell's supplement are in danger
of getting just as
sick as these three.
Once you discovered
they were all taking 3B Life,
how many more
questions did you ask?
- I'd made the connection.
- I get it. I probably wouldn't
have asked any
more questions, either.
But now someone's dead,
so we have to. You with me?
All right. Let's go fishing.
Wait.
It was the supplement?
That's what I get for buying
something from the
shopping channel.
I buy stuff from
there all the time.
Just bought the
kids a trampoline.
You think we can get a refund?
We're not positive it was
3B Life that made you sick.
For now, don't take it again.
Oh, I feel fine.
The nurse said I was just
about to be discharged.
The food here is
making me retain water.
I can't be puffy
before my next shoot.
My oldest is in the school play.
And if I leave now, I
might be able to make it.
A patient at a another hospital
who was on 3B Life, they...
they recently passed away.
Oh, my God.
Now, this didn't
happen at Chastain,
so we have limited information.
Whoa. So you think
we're in danger?
It is possible. Now, this
man initially recovered
after treatment just
like all of you, so that
has us concerned that you could
relapse and get very sick again.
Which is why we need
you to stick around,
so we can monitor you.
And fill out these
questionnaires
about your last two weeks.
I know there's a lot
in there, it's annoying.
But we need you to be as
detailed as humanly possible.
This is vital.
You expect me to remember
what I ate five days ago?
And what kind of pesticides
are used on my neighbor's lawn?
Look, I get it. This
seems ridiculous,
but it could save your life.
We need to figure out
what made you sick,
and if this has to do
with 3B Life or not.
Every detail matters
for you guys right now.
I can't believe I paid
for express shipping.
Please, Dr. Okafor.
Take it again.
- It's not gonna change.
- Try.
Sorry, Professor, but
you have a bona fide fever.
Which means that
we're gonna have to put
your transplant
surgery on pause.
But I've been waiting
here for months.
My heart has finally
arrived. Please.
If it's an infection, the immune
suppression that you require
after the transplant
might be fatal.
We have to wait for
the fever to go down
and for your blood
culture results.
Okay. Okay, t-then we wait.
Yes, but, unfortunately,
the heart can't wait.
By the time we get your results,
the heart will no
longer be viable.
We're sorry,
Professor. We really are.
The donor heart will
have to go to the next
recipient on the list.
Oh, no.
What? Why is
everyone looking at me?
Doug, how are those
questions coming?
Doug, can you hear me?
Call a code blue!
We need help in here!
Code blue, room 5916.
What the hell happened?
I don't know. We
both just saw him.
He was fine five minutes ago.
Okay, pads are on. Pads are on.
V fib. Charge to 200.
And clear. Shock.
All right. Come on.
Uh, I'll go check on Cynthia.
I'll see what's
going on with Raj.
Thank you.
Update.
We put Mr. Corson back
on atropine and 2-PAM.
This is exactly what happened
to the guy at Atlanta General.
He seemed to be getting
better then, all of a sudden,
- he crashed.
- What about the other two?
Scared, but okay for now.
And 3B Life still appears to
be the only possible cause.
We don't know that for sure.
The only way to be certain
that you're not risking
more lives is to issue a recall.
When patients get the right
diagnosis and treatment,
they don't usually recover
and then get worse.
And why is only one of
these three reacting like this?
Well, every person
has a different
physiological
response to poison.
Organophosphates are known
to have an intermediate syndrome
that show up a day or two later.
I think something
changed between the time
Doug finished his treatment
and when he coded.
The answer is in
there somewhere.
I'm gonna give Doug
a trial of diuresis.
Good.
You all right?
Well, I just heard that St.
John's brought in two cases
of organophosphate
poisoning this morning.
There's three more at Emory.
And the more hospitals I
call, the more patients I find.
And I'm-I'm not positive
they were on 3B Life...
This isn't isolated.
I'm gonna order
some send-out labs.
Hey. You're that doc
on the supplement.
What the hell, man?
You made me sick.
Hey, what's in those
supplements, man?
Hey. You're hurting people. Hey!
Hey.
Look, I know we haven't
exactly become friends, but...
I'm way younger than you. Okay?
- So I-I totally deserve
this heart, all right? Let's go.
- I have a PhD, for crying out
loud. And I'm a late bloomer.
My greatest work
is still ahead of me.
I thought it was supposed
to get warmer, not colder.
I heard Chastain is sending
over more blanket warmers.
I just had to substitute
oxacillin for Cefitaxe.
I mean, the amount of money
that Red Rock spent on this place,
you'd think they'd be
stocked with critical antibiotics.
How many times do I have
to reboot this new software
before it stops freezing
up? Should we place bets?
It'll be a miracle if we
make it through the day.
Where's Cain?
Last week, I was
operating on a young father
whose seizures
were so devastating,
he couldn't hold his child.
- So what I did with that...
- Dr. Cain. Do you have a second?
That's one of our nurses
who I will be with shortly.
It's about a patient.
Excuse me.
I think we need to push the
surgeries a day, maybe two.
And why would I do that?
Because this place isn't ready.
We're missing
medicine, uh, I mean,
the staff doesn't know
how to work the software.
We can't even get
the thermostat to work.
Growing pains are
part of the process.
This is different.
Someone could die.
Everything seems to be
running smoothly to me.
That's because you're
distracted. You're more focused
on the donors than you are
on your patients, like Lucy.
I will handle both. And
I will see you in the OR.
Are you ready for one of these?
Ew.
I love it. We'll match.
Yes, we will.
- Love you.
- I love you.
Take good care of him.
I will.
I said no.
When the agency asked me
if I wanted to adopt, I said no.
You know, after my
son passed away,
I never thought I'd ever
leave the house again.
Let alone raise another kid.
But fostering one for
a while, I could do that.
Most parents won't consider
a kid with medical problems.
It's a lot to take on.
You know, Lucy lost her parents
in a car accident
when she was four.
She was bouncing around
foster homes ever since then.
She never had a room of her
own until that first night with me.
Sounds like Lucy
has it pretty good.
Me, too.
I love that little girl.
And now...
You can't imagine
life without her.
She deserves a
real family again.
I think she found one.
Man, I thought his eighth
album took it to a whole new level.
- Track 14?
- Oh, yes, sir.
- Where the horns come in.
- And that drum solo?
It's heaven.
I got to say, it's nice to
finally cut with a surgeon
who appreciates
a little hard bop.
Dr. Okafor is not a fan?
Would you believe I agreed
to be her mentor anyway?
Just her mentor, huh?
I kind of got the impression
the two of you were maybe more.
No, our relationship
is strictly professional.
Good to know.
We need to start
thinking about a recall.
Uh, I, um...
I need to get some air.
- Andrea, let's just talk.
- I-I'll be right back.
So...
this is where we are now.
Do you want my
professional opinion?
We're not paying
for your silence.
Wait this out.
We...
we have one dead;
there's another critical.
- When more get sick...
- If more get sick,
I can help you.
- How?
- We spin it.
All the press needs is
a simple blood sacrifice.
Someone who is close to
the top who can take the fall.
You're changing the subject.
Won't be you who goes broke.
You're suggesting I throw
Andrea under the bus.
She took advantage
of a respected doctor.
You were focused
on your patients.
You trusted her too much.
In case you hadn't noticed,
my face is on the bottle.
Nobody is gonna believe
that I'm not responsible.
The truth is what you make it.
Getting you out of
this mess you're in,
this is why you pay me.
It's why other people who
are in far more trouble than you
have paid me.
Andrea can start over again.
She'll recover.
You won't.
Anyone who tried 3B
Life and stubbed their toe
is coming after you.
And the public will not be
kind, and they will never forget,
unless...
you let me help you.
How are you feeling?
I'm good.
Thanks.
- Probes.
- We should wait for Dr. Cain
before moving forward.
He told me to go
ahead and start mapping
- if he got held up.
- I understand, but...
Mind if I join?
Hi, Dr. Cain.
Hello, Lucy.
I'll take those.
Lucy, before I
remove your tumor,
I'm gonna map out your
brain like we talked about.
This is the part
where you keep talking
while I test the tissue, okay?
- Okay.
Annie told me that you
sang in your talent show.
Yeah. It was so much fun.
My friend Sam juggles scissors.
- I sang.
- What song?
"Baby Won't You
Please Come Home."
It's my fave.
Annie says I sing it almost
as good as Bessie Smith,
but I don't think I come close.
How is he?
Aaron's transplant went well.
Well, I don't want
to be envious.
But I am.
Your cultures came back.
No obvious infection.
Your fever hasn't returned.
- You're back on the list.
- It's too late.
When they admitted
me, the doctors told me
I had maybe six months.
And that was six months ago.
I don't have time to wait.
We don't know that.
Doctors aren't fortune-tellers.
You and I both know the odds
of another heart coming my way
before I die.
You know why I hate those?
I see a lot of reasons.
They remind me that I'm alone.
So now, here I am in my...
little room,
where the only person
who comes to visit...
is just doing her job.
Go.
Well, the press
are on their way in.
But I want you
to think carefully
before you make all this noise.
What about my offer?
Come in.
The responsibility is mine.
Doug's responding well
to the atropine and 2-PAM.
I'm still waiting
for send-out labs.
Just give me a
little bit more time
before I have to give you a
definitive answer on everything.
Do you know...
I only ever had one job...
before I became a doctor?
I worked the register at
my family's hardware store
since I was a kid.
And I would watch customers
walk in and out all day.
They came to see my father...
because they knew he
wouldn't overcharge them
or try and sell them
something they didn't need.
♪ ♪
They knew he was a good man...
worthy of their trust.
I worked so hard
all my life to be
seen like my dad.
But I didn't do
enough to be like him.
Thank you for trying.
Elijah stacks cups.
I mean, it's not
really a talent,
but they let him do it.
- What's that noise mean?
- Uh, that's your heart rate.
We just don't want
it to get too high.
She just hit the 150s, and her
temperature is rapidly rising.
Cooled fluids and
IV acetaminophen.
Started that ten minutes ago.
She's not responding.
I think this might be
malignant hyperthermia.
- I'm really hot.
- Get the dantrolene.
- What's that mean?
- It's just special meds
for this kind of situation.
Hey, Lucy, why don't
you sing that song
you sang for your talent show.
- Now?
- Yeah.
Yeah, just pretend
like no one's here.
Just... close your
eyes and sing.
- Okay.
♪ I've got the blues ♪
♪ I feel so lonely ♪
♪ I'd give the world ♪
♪ If I could only ♪
♪ Make you understand ♪
Where's that dantrolene?
- ♪ It surely would ♪
- It's not here.
- ♪ Be grand ♪
- I'll check the other OR.
You keep singing, Lucy.
♪ It surely would be ♪
♪ Grand ♪
♪ I've gotta telephone ♪
♪ My baby ♪
♪ Ask him, won't you
please come home ♪
- ♪ Oh ♪
- What are you doing?
Emergency in OR One.
♪ Baby ♪
♪ Please... come home ♪
♪ Baby, won't you ♪
♪ You please... ♪
♪ Come home ♪
- We need to cancel the surgery.
- Almost finished.
She needs to be intubated.
If we don't slow
down her metabolism,
we risk her life.
We need to stop.
We will not stop.
All right, hanging cold saline.
♪ Please come home ♪
- All right.
- ♪ Oh ♪
♪ I have ♪
♪ Tried in vain ♪
Dantrolene going in.
♪ To call ♪
♪ Your name ♪
Temperature's coming down.
Lucy?
Should I keep going?
You have a beautiful voice.
Yes, Lucy, can you
sing us another verse?
- It sounds so sweet.
- Yeah.
♪ When you left,
you broke my heart ♪
♪ That will never make us part ♪
♪ Every hour of the day ♪
♪ You'll hear me say ♪
Baby, won't you please ♪
♪ Come home ♪
♪ Every hour of the day ♪
♪ You will hear me say... ♪
Aaron.
The surgery went smoothly.
Your new heart
is functioning well.
The nurse stopped the
propofol an hour ago.
He should be awake by now.
Can you open your
eyes for us, bud?
Blown pupil.
Pressure's a little high.
He's relatively bradycardic.
Explains hypertension.
- Cushing's reflex.
- He's having a stroke.
We need 50 grams of IV mannitol!
And to get him to CT.
Somebody page Dr. Austin now!
- Stroke?
- Cardiopulmonary bypass,
blood thinners... It
all put Aaron at risk.
Well, is he okay?
No.
He's brain-dead.
Stroke is a known complication
of the transplant process.
Aaron was unlucky.
We did everything we could,
but the injury was catastrophic.
Sitting in this room...
wondering if each
day will be your last,
it's hard in ways that you...
you can't understand
unless you've lived it.
Like we did.
Poor kid.
Stuck in here with me.
I could have gone easier on him,
and... instead, I made
his last days harder
than they needed to be.
We think there's something
you should know about Aaron.
He loved being your roommate.
What?
Yeah. When we tried
to separate you two,
he begged us not to.
He said he would
die from boredom
without you on the
other side of the curtain.
I think in a weird way
driving you crazy kept him sane.
You're not just saying
that to make me feel better?
Aaron was also an organ donor.
I-I get the heart?
You can do that?
Reuse of a transplanted heart
is complicated.
This will be the
heart's third home
in the last 24 hours.
Every time a heart
is transplanted,
reperfusion injury occurs.
Increasing the chance
that your transplant
course could be a rocky one,
but we will do everything we
can to minimize those risks.
♪ ♪
Make yourselves comfortable.
Dr. Bell will be in shortly.
Hey.
There are no more tests to run.
It's time to send
Cynthia and Raj home,
which means... discharge papers.
Why did Doug get
worse and not the others?
I still think we're
missing something.
Uncertainty is part of the job.
I won't tell you
who taught me that,
but he seems to have forgotten.
You guys really
need to do better
with those hospital gowns.
Can't wait to get out of here,
get back to the gym.
That's a pretty dress.
They were getting
ready to leave.
Okay.
- Keep going.
- Doug and the man
at Atlanta General,
they both got worse.
And they were getting
ready to go home.
Wait a minute.
Get back in your rooms.
♪ ♪
Doug, glad you're
feeling better.
We need to examine your skin.
I'll start at the top.
I'll work my way up.
Thank you for coming.
I thought we already
examined him.
That was before he coded.
What exactly are we looking for?
That.
A subtle maculopapular rash.
That doesn't sound good.
I need to see the
clothes you wore
when you came into Chastain.
On the couch.
Bingo.
Where'd you get these?
We've prepared a statement.
It wasn't 3B Life.
Uh, let's take five.
Initially, we focused
on what the patients ate,
but it wasn't consumption
that made them sick.
- It was absorption.
- Absorption...?
- From what?
- Their clothes.
All three shopped at the
same boutique clothing store.
- Jacket.
- When clothes are shipped
in a truck with chemicals,
one spill of a pesticide
can contaminate
the entire delivery
without anyone realizing.
It's happened before.
But they were all on 3B Life.
All three patients, on
their questionnaires,
stated that they ordered
your supplements
from the shopping network
after your appearance.
They also said that
same shopping network
ran ads for this boutique
clothing store constantly.
So these caused the
organophosphate poisoning,
not 3B Life.
You're off the hook.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God, it
wasn't us. I-I knew it.
I told you. I...
I knew it.
We won't be needing
these anymore.
Dr. Pierce.
Hi, Dr. Bell.
You think dealing with
patients can be a pain,
try dealing with a TV producer.
Mm.
You left in a
hurry this morning.
It was a hell of a day.
Your coat's over there.
Appreciate the call.
I could've had it sent
over, but I wanted to...
talk to you face-to-face.
You know, most
doctors come on my show
and they just talk product,
but not you.
I liked what you had to say,
and my audience loved you.
Well... thank you.
Well, not a lot of
people know this.
I'm gonna retire.
And I'd like to float
your name to the network
for a possible trial run.
Do a couple of guest spots,
see how it goes.
You interested?
My commitments at
Chastain are full-time,
and, uh, I'm very
happy in the OR.
But why reach one person at a
time for the rest of your career
when you can reach
millions with that?
From what I saw,
you know how to use it.
You know, I-I know
a dozen doctors
who would kill for
this opportunity.
Uh...
why me?
My producer keeps
bringing in these kids
right out of med school.
Great smiles,
no experience.
An audience can smell bull.
What they want is
someone they can trust.
Someone like you.
To pitch softball stories
about antioxidants?
One day, coffee
can prevent cancer.
- The next day...
- it can kill you.
It's entertainment.
Well, you're not wrong.
So, if you don't like the
way it's done, change it.
My producer's gonna call you.
Think about it.
Thanks, guys!
♪ ♪
And we're back in five,
four, three...
Professor, how you feeling?
- Grateful.
- Your new heart
is performing well.
At this rate, you could be
out of the hospital in a week.
Let's not get
ahead of ourselves.
We were able to reach
one of Aaron's relatives
from out of town.
She'll be in tomorrow
to pick up his things.
Tell her...
I'd like to buy those.
You hate them.
I do.
But they remind me of
what I don't want to be.
I think they'll help
me make a change.
Well, Aaron was
an artist after all.
Yes.
Yes, he was.
Before we go,
we have to wedge
the PA catheter.
You know what?
Why don't you two round
on the rest of our service?
I'll finish up here.
♪ ♪
How is she?
Well, she woke up for a minute
but then fell asleep
mid-sentence.
Well, that's perfectly normal.
Her recovery will
take some time.
However long it
takes, I'm here for her.
Please, thank Dr. Cain for us.
Of course.
♪ ♪
She nearly died.
But she didn't.
Because we got lucky.
Don't believe in luck,
just talent and fate.
Caution isn't weakness.
Risk is part of the job.
So you risk a little
girl's life? Why?
To impress some donors?
Again, nobody died.
Even when we do everything we
can to prepare, things go wrong.
What chance do our
patients have if we don't?
They deserve better.
There's a reason they don't
name buildings after nurses.
Midtown.
Overpriced.
- Doll's Head Trail.
- Overrated.
- Botanical Garden?
- Boring.
Okay, come on. There's got to be
at least one place on my list
that I should
check out in Atlanta.
If you want a good time,
you want to go to Inman Park.
I will check that out.
We could check it out together.
Tomorrow night.
You drive.
No open-toed shoes.
♪ ♪
♪ Give me the ♪
♪ Blood from your eyes ♪
♪ My spine ♪
♪ Is shaping hurt ♪
♪ Erasing time ♪
♪ The way it feels ♪
♪ But nothing burns ♪
♪ Years of room ♪
♪ Yearn to moon ♪
♪ You were right ♪
♪ Deliver the blood ♪
♪ From your eyes ♪
♪ Give me the blood ♪
♪ Deliver ♪
♪ The blood from your eyes ♪
♪ Years of room ♪
♪ Yearn to moon ♪
♪ You were right. ♪
Captioned by Media Access
Grou p at WGBH access.wgbh.org