As surgeons, we're trained
to consult with each other,
to get opposing views.
Non-cardiogenic pulmonary edema.
Aortic pulmonary dissection.
Yes! No. Wait,
no. That's not right.
Well, what I'm saying is,
I finally understand
the complexities
of post-obstructive
pulmonary edema.
Uh-huh.
We even encourage patients
to seek second opinions.
Because I've been
up since 4:00 a.m.,
studying for the
boards with Callie.
Since 4:00 a.m.
I haven't seen my husband
or my baby since yesterday.
I don't even care, because
Callie blew my mind.
She blew my mind.
My hair is on fire.
I mean, literal flames
shooting out of my head.
Mmm-hmm. Yeah. That's really...
Whatever. You know what?
I'm gonna catch up with you later.
I mean, she's that good.
I am gonna kill the boards.
I am gonna make
the boards my bitch.
Yeah, boards, bitch,
got it. Because I...
Ow!
What are we doing? Nothing.
But why seek a second opinion
when you know that you're right?
You look weird. Why
do you look so weird?
I do not look weird. You were...
Talking about...
Uh, the boards.
I was talking about
what a good teacher
Callie is, and you
weren't listening.
No, I was listening.
What did I say?
'Cause if we're
honest with ourselves...
Cristina?
Surgeons are more like cowboys.
Your hair is fire,
Callie is that good,
the boards are your bitch.
I gotta go.
We're more likely
to go it alone.
The boards are my bitch.
Hey. Guess what.
I'm on Peds today. Babies. Yay.
The NICU, not the nursery.
It can get pretty intense.
Oh, well, nothing is as intense
as working on
Derek's lost causes.
It's like a death
march up there.
I mean, I call time of
death on a daily basis.
What do we got today?
Well, you ever seen a baby
that weighs less than a pound?
Uh, no, because babies that
weigh less than 16 ounces
don't survive.
My God.
He's the size of a soda can.
14 ounces.
But he's growing.
That might just be
bloating from the fluids.
Well, let's take a look.
How you feeling, Morgan?
I'm the least of my worries.
You must be Chris. Cardio
resident at Cleveland, right?
You talk about me?
You don't talk about me?
Oh...
You guys haven't had any
time to pick out a name yet, huh?
No, we, uh...
Yeah, we should do that.
Any thoughts?
We probably should wait a
few weeks, don't you think,
until he can see and hear
and breathe on his own?
14.3 ounces today.
I told you he was bigger.
Let's see how that changes
his outcome predictor.
Outcome predictor?
Yeah, it's a formula
for micro preemies
that determines their
chances of survival.
We don't use it here. Why?
Nope.
Chance of survival,
still a whopping 13%.
That's why. It
freaks parents out.
Morning.
Dr. Robbins, 14.3 today.
Well, at least that's
headed in the right direction.
On the other hand,
we got the x-rays back,
and he's developed NEC.
His bowels are rotting, and
unless we get in there and fix it...
The mortality
rate of that surgery
is over 50% in a
preemie this size.
Survival rate for treating NEC
surgically has gotten way better.
Guys, hold on. Listen,
you've got plenty of decisions to
debate down the line, too many.
All right? This
one's a no-brainer.
You don't operate, he's
gonna die. Simple as that.
Dr. Karev is right.
Well, I guess we have no choice.
I will see you at
lunch, all right?
Oh, Dr. Bailey, is the dumbbell
tumor still on the books?
Yes, all good to...
Is Meredith out sick today or...
She came in early to
study with Torres. Why?
Um, no, no reason. It's
just that she usually...
Drops Zola off. So...
Um, I'll see you up there.
Okay.
Say good-bye...
So if you could take a
look again at chart 9C,
you will see the
potential effect that, uh...
I'm sorry. It's not 9C.
Um...
Where is it?
Anyway, um...
As you can see...
It's really cool.
I just need a minute to find it.
I have 3-D models of stem cells,
so you can see them working
together to grow a heart.
I just need a second to find it.
No problem.
Dr. Altman, we have your material.
It should be enough to go on.
Oh, okay. Well, um...
Just please remember
that this research can save
tens of thousands of lives,
so...
Please consider it carefully.
What do we got?
Espresso machine exploded
at a coffeehouse on Roosevelt.
Got a 24-year-old female
with second-degree burns
on her chest, neck, and face.
Oh, God. Is my face melted?
Is that a large-bore
IV? IV's in the left arm.
That's not what I asked you. You
should've put in a large-bore IV.
It's a 20 gauge.
Do you want me to...
I'll do it myself since
I want it done right.
What's your name?
Angie. Is my face melted?
No, Angie. Try and
relax. Get a burn kit.
Thirty-seven-year-old
male, hypotensive in the field,
resolved with fluids.
Open proximal humerus fracture
and multiple lacerations and abrasions.
An espresso machine did this?
Blew him clear across the
shop and into some shelves.
And the parts that didn't
hit him went through the wall
and into the next store.
Okay, let's page
Dr. Torres and Dr. Hunt.
All right. He's got shrapnel in
his chest. Let's page Cardio.
Mmm-hmm.
Angie. Is Angie okay?
Who's Angie? Is that your wife?
My barista.
Adele?
Adele!
Oh, God.
Oh.
Adele.
Are you okay, honey?
Oh.
It was a fiasco.
Oh, it couldn't
have been that bad.
It was precisely that bad.
No, but it's stem cells. It's the
future. I mean, they know that.
No, it's dead, just like my
husband, who is also dead.
There's a theme
here. Are you noticing?
Teddy... Whatever. I don't care.
The nice part about
having a dead husband
is that you stop caring
about anything at all.
You should ask Owen
to put in a good word.
The Chief of Surgery can have
a lot of pull in these decisions.
I don't talk to Owen Hunt.
Out of the way, Grey.
I need to get in there.
We've got a white out on
the right. Yang, chest tube.
Sure.
Rough night last night? Hmm?
You didn't come home.
Oh, yeah. MVC. I texted, but
you must have been asleep.
Okay, Devin, we are gonna
give you some pain meds.
And we're gonna put a tube in
your chest that will drain the blood,
and you will start
to feel a lot better.
I just ran into Teddy.
She said that she blew her
pitch to the board this morning.
It might be nice if you
backed her up, you know?
Put in a good word.
Pulse is faint on the
left. I need a CT angio.
Okay, Devin, once we get this
tube in, we're gonna take you to CT.
Do you have any family
we need to contact?
My parents are old. I
don't want to worry them.
If you could just let
Angie know I'm okay.
She's probably worried.
I'm sorry. Who's Angie?
Uh, the burned
barista in trauma one.
Dr. Grey,
Dr. Webber's in the ER.
Yeah? No, he's in the ER.
I checked the
over-pressure valve.
It was fine.
Or was that yesterday?
Oh, God, is this my fault?
Did I melt my own face off?
Nothing's been melted
off. Try to stay still, please.
I mean, they can't expect
me to monitor the machine
and handle the
morning rush, right?
I really need you to stay still.
I mean, it's too much
pressure, this job.
Not enough pay and
way too much pressure.
I mean, you guys have no idea.
We're fixing your
face. That is pressure.
Now if you could do
us both a favor and...
Dr. Avery, go get us
some more bandages.
Now.
Sorry about that.
Continue to clean here.
I'll be back in a second.
Okay, Doctor.
You yelled at a patient
and a paramedic,
two people you do not want to
piss off. What's your problem?
I'm sorry, all right?
I've just been so tense.
I'm studying for the boards.
We've been
studying. You'll do fine.
I can't do fine. I have
to do great. I'm an Avery.
Are you getting any?
Did you just ask
me if I'm getting any?
When was the last time?
That's none of your business.
Just tell me. I won't judge.
I am focused. There's no time.
There's always time.
My mother used to have
trouble with the stove, too,
and then she started
getting lost driving,
and then she started leaving the
house in the middle of the night.
Adele's fine. And
we're managing.
Rose Ridge is top-notch,
great doctors, great facility.
Yeah, I know, I know.
We're just not there yet.
Any deeper, and this burn
could've retired you from surgery.
Yeah, I'll look into it.
You're just trying
to shut me up.
Yeah, how am I doing?
I don't have pull many places,
but I'm kind of a big deal there.
So if you need me to
make a call for you, I can.
Good. Only a little of
the bowel is necrotic.
There should be more
than enough to salvage.
Maybe his dad
should factor spunk
into his stupid algorithm.
He's a fourth year. He knows
just enough to be annoying.
Well, he's acting like
the baby is already dead.
But look at him. He's a champ.
You're like a little
Muhammad Ali, aren't you?
Someone's peppy.
She's on a vacation from
lost-cause brain surgeries.
She needs to have
some fun today.
You know what's really fun?
Removing dead bowel.
You want to make the cut?
Really? Are you sure?
Yeah. Get over there
before I change my mind.
Okay, the tissue
rips really easily,
so only press down as hard
as you would need to cut a hair.
So Torres and I assessed his
shoulder, and I mean... Wow.
So we both agreed...
Yeah, let's just do this. Sir.
We're gonna take a scan
of your chest and your arms.
So just try and relax.
My friend Angie, is she okay?
She's got some bad
burns, but she'll be fine.
It's my fault for going
in during the rush.
She gets too
flustered around me.
And the sexual tension's
been building for months...
You know, a look
here, a smile there.
It can be hard to focus with all those
pheromones buzzing around you.
I should've known it's
become dangerous.
Okay, well, let's get you and
your pheromones into the scan.
Yeah, lately, she's been
taking it to another level,
adding these foam leaf
designs on top of my coffee...
Handmade, just for me.
It'd be great if I could send
Angie a cappuccino or something.
Let her know I'm doing okay.
Nicely done.
So now what?
Even if he stabilizes,
he's looking at years of
procedures and surgeries.
His parents are residents.
They can't both
quit, and medical care
for a little guy like
this is expensive.
You really know how to take the
fun out of a party, you know that?
Damn. Looks like he's
in cardiogenic shock.
Push epi and atropine.
Did I...
No, no, no, no. You did
just fine. It's just that...
He's brady'ed down to 52.
Grey, start CPR.
His heart hasn't stopped.
With preemies, we start CPR
when the heart rate goes below 60.
Now use two fingers,
light pressure. Go.
We get seven major
newspapers here every day,
as well as live readings
from local authors.
Oh, look, Adele,
a mystery section.
She loves mysteries,
don't you, honey?
Our librarian reads a
chapter every day after dinner.
Actually, we're just
finishing Death on the Nile,
so if you know who done
it, keep it to yourselves.
Should we check
out the gymnasium?
We just added a piloxing class.
Every room is different,
but they all have their own
instant call button for attendants,
your own bathroom, and
a nice view of the grounds.
I'll leave you two alone, so you
can look the place over on your own.
If you have any questions,
I'll be at the front desk.
What do you think, Adele?
It's nice.
But it's too small for us.
You're a doctor. You said
that you could afford a house.
We certainly couldn't
possibly start a family here.
Richard...
Where would the nursery go?
You're right, honey.
It's too small.
I said I'd get you a house.
Let's go.
I got it.
Got what? The grant.
Four million to grow
hearts from stem cells.
You got it?
I'm gonna grow hearts.
Can you believe it?
Oh, God, Teddy, that's amazing.
I must have not done as
bad as I thought this morning
unless... Or I charmed them
with my fumbling desperation.
I have no idea. I
don't care. I got it.
We were able to cut out
most of the necrotic bowel,
but then he went into CHF.
Oh, my God.
Morgan, he's 24 weeks old.
Born 16 weeks early.
This shouldn't be a
shock. He wasn't ready.
But there are a few
things that we can try
to help oxygenate him better.
And then hopefully,
he'll get stronger.
We could use liquid ventilation.
Which could cause hypocarbia.
We could put him on a
high-frequency oscillator.
Which could cause air trapping.
Or we can put him on ECMO.
Which, just to get
ahead of you, Chris,
we don't think he would
survive at this stage.
Okay, but before we do anything,
we just need to know how
aggressive you want to be.
I think we stop.
We stop right now.
There are plenty
of options. We...
We should use them.
These are his chances
of survival right here.
This is reality.
Now you're a
doctor. Think like one.
If you had a patient with odds
like that, would you operate?
I'm sorry about
earlier. The way I...
My behavior was
completely unprofessional.
No, I'm sorry.
I was freaking out.
Look at you two, getting along.
You date doctors, Angie?
Do not listen to this man.
He thinks I need to be set up.
He does need to be set up.
He's shy, needs a little push.
Devin is heading into surgery.
He wanted me to give you this,
tell you not to worry, etcetera.
So, here.
Devin?
The guy from the accident.
Okay. I...
You know, the customer
you flirt with every day?
I'm sorry. I have
no idea who he is.
Sweet, nerdy type.
You put those foamy leaves
on the top of his coffee?
I have to make those
leaves for everybody.
It's a new company policy.
I'll take it.
Get your own.
That's not my point.
I can't believe that they're
not gonna do anything.
I mean, they are basically
giving this kid a death sentence.
Chris just wants to get
back to his residency,
and Morgan is too weak
to even think straight.
The parents have
made up their minds.
Just let me eat
my food in peace.
Ali doesn't even have any
parents, as far as I can see.
And you know what?
She is your intern.
You need to step up.
Give me those.
She won't shut up.
No, I'm studying.
Okay, look, all I am saying...
Look, let it go, Lexie.
All I am saying is,
parents did not decide
his treatment plan,
doctors did. Math did.
Get your own.
Hey, so it turns out Devin
needs a thoracotomy.
Your surgery.
Remember Devin,
likes coffee, is in
love with his barista?
What about me? Remember me?
Hey, um...
Have you hit that?
Which that?
That, the brown-haired that.
Mmm...
That with the brown hair and
the nice ass and the perfect...
Teeth, yes. Have you?
No. Mmm-mmm. She
only goes for the attendings.
Next year.
Did you see that?
What?
The way that woman
looked at me and Zola.
Derek, we're hot doctors with
babies. Women are gonna stare.
I think she's racist.
Oh, I get it.
You're worried about
bridging the cultural divide.
I know all about it.
That's why I learned Spanish.
You know she
doesn't speak Spanish?
Oh, but she shall.
You shall.
See? Bridging the divide.
How's it going with
your better half?
He's uptight, worried about
the boards, snapping at patients.
I'm trying to get
him laid, but...
I'm talking about Julia.
Oh. Of course.
She's...
She's good, thanks.
She's doing well.
Good.
Hello.
Hey.
I have to listen to his chest.
Hey, Ali. How you doing?
Why do you call him that?
It's for the preemie
babies without names
or the ones with weak
names, like Felix or Claude.
You know, we like to
give them fighters' names,
like Boris or Butch or... Molly,
you know, to help
them weather the storm.
I like that.
We'll take what we can get. Hmm.
How are his lungs?
Well, they're still wet,
so I may up his Lasix.
His pulse ox isn't great either.
Uh, where's Chris?
I don't know.
He keeps saying that he's making
calls, updating his family, but...
I think he just can't be here.
Do you think we're
doing the right thing?
Well, as a doctor,
I look at Ali's odds, and
I'm not very optimistic.
But...
Hey, I've seen
parents who, uh...
They don't think like doctors.
They see things that we don't.
I'm not gonna tell
you what to do,
but I will say this,
Ali, he's got a...
He's got plenty of
doctors in his corner.
You make sure he's got a parent.
Dr. Karev.
We're thinking of
naming him Thomas,
after my dad.
Is that tough enough?
Tommy? Tommy's good.
You paged?
Uh, yes. When you finish
your surgery with Torres,
I need you to check
on my post-op patients.
I'm going home.
Something happen?
Adele's not having a good day.
Rose Ridge, Richard.
I'm telling you, you
really should look into it.
We went to Rose Ridge.
Rose Ridge doesn't have
anything that I can't give her.
Rose Ridge is not the answer.
She burned your hand.
You think you can
handle this, but you can't.
I know. I have
been through this.
The difference between you and
Ellis and me and Adele, Meredith,
I made vows to Adele,
vows to cherish her
and be true to her,
in sickness and in health,
vows that I have
broken time and again.
The least I could do
is honor her in sickness
and give her the
home that she deserves
and the best care there is.
She stays home, and
if necessary, so do I.
Did you have any
pets growing up?
Uh...
A fish tank, couple of
hamsters, two dogs, why?
I'm just trying to get to
know you better. That's it.
Okay.
What were your dogs' names?
Well, let's see. Uh, there
was Buster and, um...
Pickles. Pickles
was a schnauzer...
What's your mother's
maiden name?
Are you hacking me?
I need the nurses' schedule.
I don't schedule the nurses.
If knew anything about
how this hospital was run...
You know the nurses' schedule.
You are April Kepner.
You know everything.
Anyone in particular?
Uh... Um...
Emily someone.
Emily. Let's see.
Ah. She was on days in the CCU,
but then she switched to nights
in the surgical ICU.
Handling traumas,
which is weird,
but Dr. Hunt signed off
on it, so it should be fine.
Hey, if I see her crying or
bleeding, I'll come after you.
Hacker.
Iliac artery is mobilized.
Okay. Let me get in there.
You know what might be fun?
I have no idea
what might be fun.
A play date with Zola and Tuck.
Oh! Uh...
Well, Tuck's five,
and Zola's, what, one?
One and a quarter.
But it's more like she's
three. She's very mature.
Well...
Playing for Tuck
means throwing things,
breaking things, shooting
things at people and things.
I don't think Zola would
survive a play date with Tuck.
Yeah. It's probably not a
good idea. Forceps, please.
There's gotta be some kids
down in day care closer to her age,
even if they aren't as advanced.
I don't want her
to feel out of place.
It might be nice if she
could hang out with...
Kids who...
Have the same...
Same roots.
Roots?
You know...
Okay, let's just
resect the tumor.
The oscillator isn't the answer.
Then liquid ventilation. It
could improve his lung function.
Morgan.
You are his dad, not his
doctor. You can't just give up.
It's not about giving up.
He's still alive.
It's about doing
more harm than good.
How is letting him
die good, Chris. How?
I know you.
Deep down, we're both
thinking the exact same thing.
Tell me what we're
thinking, Chris.
We're thinking that getting
pregnant was an accident,
that this baby should
not be alive right now,
that its chances of survival
or having any kind of life
worth living are slim to none,
that doing every damn
thing we can to keep it alive
is just so that we can feel good
about ourselves after he dies.
Now can you admit any of that?
Just go.
You can't cut me out
of these decisions.
I'm not cutting you out.
I'm offering you an out.
What are you saying?
I'm saying, take the out, Chris,
because maybe you
can't admit it now,
in the light of day,
but you want it.
How are you doing
on your end, Torres?
How are we doing, Grey?
Uh, good. I'm just finishing
up this arterial repair,
and then I'm
gonna put in the rod.
It's bad enough the girl he
loves has no idea he exists.
Now the TSA is gonna
hassle him for the rest of his life.
Burned barista
doesn't know who he is?
Nope. Never even heard of him.
Where are we?
Dr. Altman?
He's fine. Shrapnel's out.
Good.
Did you all hear that
Dr. Altman got a huge grant
for her stem cell research?
I did. Congratulations,
Dr. Altman.
Thank you.
I hear that Dr. Silverman
at Wake Forest
has been doing great
work in stem cells.
Maybe you should
give her a call...
If I wanted your advice
on my specialty, Dr. Hunt,
I'll ask.
Once Teddy's done with the lung,
you can get at the other arm to
get out the remaining shrapnel.
All right. Okay.
Here. I'll help you finish.
I've got it. No,
no, it'd be easier...
I said I've got it.
Now back the hell off.
You're an attractive woman.
Who? Uh, me?
You and Avery spend a lot
of time together, don't you?
We do, yes. Uh... But
we're just study buddies.
I mean, we're not, you know...
He's an attractive guy,
nice bone structure,
hypnotic eyes, etcetera.
I guess so?
Have you noticed how
uptight he's been lately?
Uh, like I said, we're
study buddies, so...
Study buddies should
help each other out,
relieve some of that stress.
Maybe extend that
buddy relationship.
Extend? Um, I don't...
You're two attractive people.
Any thoughts on how
to alleviate that stress?
We could go for more walks?
Walks are good.
Walks are nice.
I was thinking, since
you're already study buddies,
you could extend
that relationship,
become the other
kind of buddies.
Are you...
I am.
Dr. Sloan!
Everybody wins.
This is sexual harassment.
You know that, right?
I think of it as sexual
encouragement.
Think about it, Kepner.
Take one for the team.
You got her the grant money.
Look, I know you did.
You have to tell her.
It'll help things
between you guys.
No, it won't. All
right, then I'll tell her.
No, you won't.
You can't let her
treat you this way.
When Henry died, you
were just doing your job.
You're not a bad guy.
How do you know?
Look...
Sometimes, you just lash out.
It might not be rational or fair,
but you do it
'cause you have to.
If she needs me for that, if
she needs a punching bag,
a bad guy to point the
finger at and help her cope,
then let that be me.
Fine, you can be a martyr,
but you still have to be the Chief.
And what happened
in that OR today,
that should never happen again.
We were able to repair your
lung and fix your shoulder,
but you're gonna need months
of rehab. How are you feeling?
Like I got hit by a dump truck.
Yeah, it's gonna feel
like that for a little while.
But don't be afraid to use
your PCA pump for pain meds.
So has Angie come by the room?
I didn't miss her, did I?
Angie has no idea who you are.
What?
That's ridiculous.
She knows my order.
I don't even have to say it.
That's her job.
The accident.
She's confused.
She knows me.
We have this thing,
this flirtation.
What did she say?
Tell me exactly what she said.
That she doesn't have
any idea who you are.
That's exactly what she said.
You've made up this
whole thing in your head.
No. You don't understand.
I do.
It happens.
I mean, you see one thing
and you think it means
something that it doesn't,
and pretty soon, you're
acting like it's real.
You have to stop.
You have to just...
Stop.
This should improve his cardiovascular
and pulmonary status, right?
That's the plan.
When will we
know if it's working?
In a couple of hours.
But you should go
rest. We'll update you.
Chris left. I'm all he has
now. I'm not going anywhere.
Well, it's better
if you go rest.
It can be hard for
parents to watch.
I appreciate the concern,
but I'm a doctor, too.
Let's do this.
Oh, God.
What's up?
Hi.
Um...
You paged?
I wanted to...
What?
Hey, what are you
doing? Cristina...
No, you can spare 15
minutes. I don't have time.
No, I'm working in the
ER. No, we'll be quick.
I don't have time. So fast.
Cristina, I don't...
So, so fast.
Damn it. Damn it.
I don't have time.
Owen...
- Mrs. Webber...
- Get back.
Adele? WOMAN: Put that down!
Get out!
Sweetheart!
Adele!
Get out of my house right now!
Make her stop!
Adele!
Listen to me. I'm here.
Get away from me!
Look at me, honey.
I'm calling the police!
Adele, it's me, your
husband, Richard.
Get back!
It's me, Richard.
Don't hurt me.
Look, I'm your husband, Richard.
Please go. Please leave.
My parents will be here.
They'll be home any minute.
It's me, Adele, your
husband. I'm your husband.
I'm your husband!
How's he doing?
He's holding steady for now,
but we won't know anything
for a few more hours.
I had to know before I left.
Sure.
I'd stay, I would.
I would, but I've got people
working doubles covering my shifts,
and we're in the middle of a
clinical trial right now, and...
You know how it is, right?
Thank you.
Do you have a problem?
Excuse me? Oh, no.
It is 2012.
You want to be
shocked by the sight
of a white man
with a black baby,
you're about three
decades too late!
I'm sorry. Don't listen to him.
What is wrong...
She's unbelievable.
She was not staring at you
because daddy's white
and his daughter is black.
She was staring at you two
because daddy has nice hair,
maybe perfect hair,
but for whatever reason,
his daughter's hair
is 31 flavors of wrong.
It's hard on the eyes.
Look, you are white, but
your daughter is black.
Do your baby's hair!
What are you doing? Stop it. Ow!
What's the plan?
You have bony, sharp fingers.
What plan? There's no plan.
Your plan, which
makes it our plan.
Whatever it is, I need to know.
Are you plotting a
murder, a nuclear attack?
It's fine. I'll get on board. I'm
sure you have a good reason.
But just let me know. You're
starting to freak me out.
I think Owen is cheating on me.
Did you see something?
No.
Did someone else see something?
Did he do something? No.
Well, then how do you know...
I don't know. I
don't know! I just...
Know.
Cristina...
You know what? I am...
I'm being crazy.
I'm crazy, right?
This is totally...
I'm crazy. I'm just...
We're having a
hard time, and I'm...
I'm making it into... I'm crazy.
I'm... I'm crazy.
Okay.
I really think
he's not cheating.
I know that.
Julia has a friend.
She's pretty.
Uh...
A little brooding and
tattoo-y for my taste,
but, pretty.
Bet you're into that
sort of thing, huh?
For the last time, I do
not need a girlfriend.
Who said anything
about girlfriend?
One double date. Help me
out with a third-wheel situation.
So, so tempting,
but no, thank you.
All right.
But you need to
get out there, man.
Doing yourself a
huge disservice.
I had a girlfriend, all right?
Now I just can't.
I don't want to.
What do you mean, you can't?
You still love her.
You still love Lexie.
See you tomorrow.
I can't wait to
get back to Neuro.
At least with lost causes,
you know where you stand,
and the patients can tell you
when they have had enough.
I don't know how
Morgan can bear it. I...
I don't know how any of you can.
Come here.
Jolene Jordano, 1
pound, 4 ounces at birth.
She's 12 years old
now. She's a goalie. Uh...
Benji Gellerman, 1
pound, 2 ounces at birth.
He's 9 years old,
plays the trumpet.
This one, Hannah Slavin?
I worked on her myself.
She looked like a hamster
when she came out.
Her dad just called, said
she took her first steps.
Some of them survive.
What happened?
Did you have an accident?
Richard, your hand,
did you hurt your hand?
I'm fine. I'm fine.
Did I hurt your hand?
Um...
You know, how about some dinner?
I'll heat up the lasagna.
I have Alzheimer's.
Don't I?
Yes, sweetheart.
You do.
Rose Ridge, it...
It seemed like a nice place.
We went there this
morning, didn't we?
Yes, we did.
I think it's best
if I were to go live there.
You don't have to do that.
I mean, you can stay here.
I like having you here.
I liked it there.
Your home is here with me.
I'd rather be there.
Okay, sweetheart.
Okay.
You can seek the
advice of others.
Is that right? Am I stroking...
And I pull it up? Yeah.
Surround yourself
with trusted advisors.
There you go.
Like that? Mmm-hmm.
Gather, yep. Gather, good.
Hi.
Hey, Meredith.
Did you know Zola has a kitchen?
Yes, Derek.
I know all about Zola's kitchen.
Now I want... Do I turn it?
Gather everything in.
Pull the kitchen up.
But in the end, the
decision is always yours.
And yours alone.
And when it's time to
act, and you're all alone
with your back
against the wall...
The only voice that matters
is the one in your head.
Cristina?
The one telling you what
you probably already knew.
The one that's
almost always right.