Okay. Juice and
coffee all ready.
Should I take the
banana bread out?
Yes, please.
She left her hotel
22 minutes ago.
She should be here any minute.
Don't give me that look.
You're the one who insisted
on showering together.
I thought it would save time.
When are you going
to learn, Shaunie?
I'm irresistible.
That is very true.
She's here.
Hi!
Hello, Claire. It is
very good to see you.
Would you like coffee or
freshly squeezed orange juice?
Coffee, please.
Oh, my God.
He is the cutest.
- Look at the little cheeks.
- I know.
How are things at
Centro de Salud?
Great.
I've managed to make
a ton of improvements
- since you were there.
- Did you get a new CT machine?
Yeah, and an MRI.
Also, we opened a
prenatal clinic,
and I've instituted
a bunch of protocols
to decrease Hospital
Acquired Infections.
And on the personal front?
Uh... that is a
work in progress.
But good.
I told Lea about the
lump in your breast.
It was before I convinced you
to have your surgery here.
Not a HIPAA violation.
I hope you also told her
that the biopsy was negative.
It's not cancer, so there's
nothing to worry about.
He did. I reserve
the right to worry.
But let's save the
medicine for later
and focus on more important
stuff like Latin lovers.
Oh. Oh, is that banana bread?
That smells amazing.
Resistance is futile.
We have ways of making you talk.
That was a nice
start to the day.
A fantastic start.
What are you gonna wear?
I know it's just City Hall,
but it feels like we should at
least wear something special.
We can't get married
at City Hall.
- Alex, we've been over this.
- I know.
And you say you don't
care where we get married.
I don't. But you want to
wear something special,
because you want our wedding
to be special like I do.
I don't want to
delay our adoption.
You won't have to.
I'm gonna give you the
wedding you deserve.
Something beautiful and
impressive like you.
In four days? As
impressive as me?
Impossible.
Challenge accepted.
This is a Thomas Keller recipe.
I found it online.
Wow. Smells delicious.
And
your morning dose.
Also delicious.
When I was little, I used
to dream about being a chef
at a really nice restaurant,
and now I'm gonna
make it a reality.
I know I'll have to
start at the bottom,
but I can work my way up.
Hmm. I'm glad you're
feeling better,
but, you know, you
have to focus on today.
I know. I'm gonna get clean.
- You're gonna get professional treatment...
- No.
It's the only way. And
it's the only way forward.
No, it's not. I
don't want methadone.
I hate meetings and
sharing with strangers.
So we'll find you a
program that works for you,
but getting sober is the point.
It's the only point. You
can't make this a solo act.
I'm not alone. I have you.
I'm not an addiction specialist.
No, but you are a neurosurgeon.
- That's better.
- Hannah...
You are controlling my doses.
We'll taper off a
little each day.
It's not that simple.
Even if you stop using,
it's a Band-Aid.
Eventually, you're gonna relapse
unless you get treatment,
and I think you know that.
If I break the rules again,
you can kick my ass out.
I don't want to kick you out.
I-I... Nobody's kicking you out.
I want to help.
Well, then we can
do this together.
Please, just give me a chance.
33-year-old male,
struck by lightning.
Second degree burns and a
possible fractured spine.
- A spinal fracture from lightning?
- From falling off a roof.
He was working construction
when he got hit.
- Can't feel my legs.
- Push IV fluids.
Let's get trauma
labs and an EKG.
Can you tell me your name?
- Clint.
- Nice to meet you, Clint.
I'm Dr. Allen. I'm gonna
take good care of you.
Take the trauma shears,
cut his clothes off.
Oh.
- Hi.
- Hey.
Oh, it's so great to see you.
You, too. I wish it was
under better circumstances.
Oh, I'll be fine. It's
just a tiny benign lump.
Hi, Dr. Brown. I'm
Charlie Lukaitis.
It's very nice to
meet you, Charlie.
Shaun speaks really
highly of you.
- Really?
- I have been fair,
but not overly complimentary.
Shaun, I was being nice.
You could try harder
to do the same.
- Thank you, Dr. Brown.
- Oh, call me Claire.
Okay, I'm sure the new MRI
you acquired is excellent,
but we should do a
stereotactic biopsy
and breast MRI.
Instead of a mammogram?
New research shows
that breast MRI
are more accurate
for younger women
with denser breast tissue.
I was about to say that.
Sorry, I'm working on
controlling my impulsive speech.
It just seems you're eager
to demonstrate your knowledge
as med students
are supposed to do.
Thank you, Dr. Brown.
I mean, Claire.
Now you are being too nice.
Those are punctate burns at
the entry and exit points
connected by second
degree linear flash burn.
What are all these red lines?
- I'm not s...
- Lichtenberg figures.
The electric shock causes
extravasation of red blood cells
from the capillaries.
It'll heal with
minimal scarring.
Hi. I'm Dr. Lim.
I thought Dr. Park was on today.
He's taking a personal
day... wedding planning.
Can you wiggle your toes?
Alright, nice.
The loss of sensation
in your legs
is a temporary keraunoparalysis.
It'll disappear over
the next few hours.
Get spinal CTs and trauma
pan scan to confirm,
then we'll debride the burns.
Are you ready to
take Mama to work?
Yeah?
Hello?
Glassy, you home?
Oh, my God.
I am so sorry. That's my fault.
I was seasoning the skillet,
and I left for like a second
to take out the trash.
I'm Lea, Aaron's neighbor.
It's nice to meet
you. I'm Hannah.
I'm Aaron's niece.
I'm just visiting
for a couple weeks.
I'm so sorry if I
woke you guys up.
Oh, it's alright. I w... I
was just heading to work.
I should, um, open a window.
So, you'll have to lie facedown
- with your breast centered in the frame.
- Okay.
Is it harder or easier
this time being a second-year?
Um... bit of both.
Yeah. What about you, Chief?
How are you liking
the big chair?
I like it.
Fewer resources than here,
but also fewer restrictions
and more control.
Mm. Sounds like a good fit.
Hmm. Oh, speaking of.
Shaun showed me your
Lamborghini in the parking lot.
I know. I know. I'm an idiot.
No, I was gonna
say good for you.
I thought you hated sports cars.
Oh, I mean, I still do, but
I know that you loved them.
And you just didn't want
to seem ostentatious.
Mm.
No, I'm happy you've
stopped worrying so much
about what other people think.
Whatever you left
here searching for,
it's clear you found it.
Maybe we both did.
We're looking for
white-speculated
enhancing masses like... there.
1.72 centimeters.
A 3-centimeter
incision should...
Did you and Claire used to date?
W-We were just good friends.
With benefits.
I knew it.
Does Jordan know
that she's here?
Uh, I don't know.
Also, that hardly matters
since I'm not dating Jordan.
Oh? I thought you wanted to.
I did.
But we decided to
just be good friends.
Her and Perez, her ex-boyfriend,
text every day since Asher died.
It was wrong.
No, it's not wrong.
It's just a choice.
The biopsy from
Guatemala was negative,
but our biopsy from
earlier came back positive.
Claire has breast cancer.
- Sorry I didn't come by earlier.
- Hi!
Park is out, and I
had to help Glassman
get some stuff off his plate.
- It's still not an excuse.
- It's fine.
I'm here now to assure you
you are going to be fine.
Shaun briefed me on your biopsy,
and we went over
your MRI together.
You are in the perfect hands.
Ooh. Tell me about being
co-president with Glassman.
Mm. It's been interesting.
Collaborative.
By collaborative, you
mean you get stuff done,
and then he tells you how you
should have gotten it done?
Oh, you have one of
those in Guatemala?
Just one? I wish.
- Oh, I miss the old days.
- Mm.
You mean when you were
a Ducati-riding badass?
Hey, I do not need a
Ducati to be a badass.
- Mm.
- I just need...
- More sleep?
- I was thinking more sex,
but sleep is good.
Tell me about it.
Sometimes I wonder if I...
Hold that thought.
- To be continued.
- I'll be here.
Hey, we need to talk.
Hello, I need to get Claire
prepped for her surgery.
There's a girl living
in Glassman's apartment.
She says her name is Hannah
and claims she's his niece.
He does not have a
niece named Hannah.
I know, but she had a key
and her clothes were there.
He had a patient last
week named Hannah.
She was a homeless drug addict
who needed
cervicomedullary surgery.
Why would he let a homeless
drug addict live with him?
I...
don't know.
I have to go.
The MRI confirmed the mass
is under 2 centimeters.
That's only Stage 1A.
With your hormone profile,
you should be responsive
to hormone therapy
after the surgery.
You probably won't need chemo.
Do you disagree?
No.
Tell me if you do.
I'd rather get the bad news now.
I agree completely.
I was just thinking
about someone else.
But I will be focused in the OR.
Another 10 milligrams morphine.
Sorry.
I just need to remove
the necrotic skin and tissue
to avoid infection.
That's okay.
It hurts 'cause I'm alive.
Never taking that
for granted again.
Good for you.
I never should have even
started working construction.
Take a couple deep breaths.
Maybe just not outside
during a thunderstorm.
I used to have a band.
Even put out a couple EPs,
but we just couldn't break out.
I got a day job, turned 30.
Next thing I know,
I'm a foreman for
a roofing company.
Sometimes, big decisions are
just a bunch of small ones
you don't even realize you made.
I just feel like
I should recommit.
You know, I could
eke out a living
playing clubs and bars.
I'd rather look in
the mirror and know...
I'm the person I want to be.
A curvilinear incision
along the natural crease
line of the breast
gives the best cosmetic result.
Who were you thinking about?
You told Claire you were
thinking about someone else.
I shouldn't talk about it.
Raising the flap with a
wide margin around the mass.
Did I say something
inappropriate?
I wasn't thinking about you.
- Was it...
- Charlie.
He said he doesn't
want to talk about it.
Send this to pathology.
The tissue orientation is
marked with ink at 12:00.
Dr. Kalu, your suture
spacing is quite excellent.
You can close.
Suture with vicryls
and monocryl, please.
Is the Hannah who's
living with you
the same Hannah you
treated for Chiari Zero?
Yes.
Seven ball, corner pocket.
Sh-She is a drug addict.
Who I am helping.
Helping her detox?
She's a patient
under my care, Shaun.
That's all you need to know.
If she's a patient,
that means you are
continuing to treat her
while she is living with you.
- How?
- Shaun...
Are you prescribing her opiates?
I'm helping her get sober.
I can't have her go out on
the street and buy drugs.
Prescribing her oxycodone in
this situation is unethical.
- I'm aware.
- And possibly illegal.
- You could lose your medical license.
You need to make her leave.
I'm not giving up on her. But
thank you for your concern.
How long has he been seizing?
Over four minutes.
- Then give four milligrams lorazepam.
- Already did.
Then give four more and
one gram levetiracetam.
He's got a mass in
his frontal lobe.
- Could it be from the lightning strike?
- No.
In fact, the lightning probably saved
his life, putting him in the hospital.
He has that seizure anywhere
else, he'd probably be dead.
A supramaximal resection
might get at all.
- If we're lucky.
- And if we're not?
It'll likely progress to a
glioblastoma and kill him.
We had our first
official date here.
She jumped on stage
and tried to join Cory
Henry's backup singers.
She loves music,
and this would be
the perfect place.
Yeah, I'd love to help you,
but I got bands
booked every night.
Couldn't you reschedule one?
I-I'll pay their fee, cover whatever the
difference ends up being in your gate.
I mean, name your price.
Sorry.
But I think you're
gonna have to choose
between immediate
and meaningful.
The glioma is in your
posterior frontal lobe
near the motor strip.
We have to be very aggressive.
If we leave any tumor behind,
it could grow back
as a glioblastoma,
which could be terminal.
Okay.
Because of the
placement of the tumor,
we may need to cut into
your eloquent cortex,
the area of your brain which
controls motor function.
Are you saying I won't
be able to play guitar?
It's possible.
Alive is alive.
I'll take it.
I am going to tell Dr. Lim
about Dr. Glassman and Hannah.
I don't think
that's a good idea.
He'd probably consider
it an even worse betrayal
than when you ended
his surgical career.
I was right about that,
and I am right about this, too.
He could lose his medical
license. I am saving him.
Shaun, I don't think it's just
about helping a former patient.
What else is it about?
You know why he helped
you back in Wyoming?
Because he knew I needed help.
Of course.
Also... his daughter
had just died.
He was grieving.
Maybe he did for you what
he couldn't do for her.
What does that have
to do with Hannah?
Hannah's a drug addict,
just like Maddie was.
I think some of this is
Glassman dealing with his sense
that he failed his daughter.
After everything he's
done to support you,
don't you think you should
let him help Hannah?
Dr. Glassman... is only
putting himself at risk,
which I guess is okay.
I won't tell Dr. Lim.
Okay.
I'm thinking an awake craniotomy
with intraoperative
motor brain mapping.
Respiratory failure leads to
brain edema and herniation,
air embolism, intraop seizures,
just to name a few of the risks.
He was struck by lightning
and remembered who he was.
A guitarist.
I don't want to take
that away from him.
Big swing.
I think I'm gonna do it.
You seem amped up about this.
It suits you.
You need to keep him playing
guitar during the surgery.
If his playing gets worse
during motor mapping,
then you can't cut
into that area.
If he keeps playing well,
then it's safe to cut.
Digale a Dr. Maldonado
que cubra esos turnos...
Esperemos la semana que viene.
Me ten go que ir.
Gracias, Imelda.
Your pathology just came back.
We didn't get clean margins.
Now, you're already on the
board for this afternoon.
We'll perform a re-excision,
removing a wider margin
of the breast tissue,
followed by a sentinel
lymph node biopsy
to see if it's spread.
But
if it has
well, then, who better
to take this on?
You grew up in a trailer park.
You were raised by
a bipolar mother.
Went to a top med
school on scholarship.
Then you were recruited to be
chief of surgery in a country
where you didn't even
know the language.
Now, two years later, you, uh
you speak perfect Spanish and
you've overhauled the hospital.
You are an unstoppable
force, Claire Browne.
And on top of all of that,
you are kind, compassionate,
and [chuckles]
heart-stoppingly beautiful.
Cancer doesn't stand
a chance against you.
Forgot how great your
bedside manner is.
And my Spanish is
far from perfect.
Play guitar during surgery?
The risk of
complications is higher,
but an awake surgery
is the only way
to ensure full post-op function
of your fine motor skills.
We test each resection area
and get immediate feedback
before removing any tissue.
And won't it hurt?
You won't even feel it.
Any song requests?
Thank you for coming.
So, what does she want?
She doesn't want anything.
She doesn't know I'm here.
I want your help. I'd like to
stage an intervention for Hannah.
You think we haven't tried
that... multiple times?
Well, let's try again.
Your daughter needs your help.
What do you know
about my daughter?
She came to me with Chiari Zero.
That is a malformation
of the brain
which causes persistent and
sometimes very intense pain.
That's why she started
on the oxycodone.
Can that be treated?
My colleague already
performed surgery.
It was a complete success.
She had brain surgery?
Is she still in the hospital?
She's staying on my couch.
It was there or the streets.
So she's using in your home?
Yes, under my supervision.
I wrote her a prescription
for oxycodone,
which I'm administering
on a schedule.
You're her new drug dealer.
Her first night in my
apartment, she OD'd on fentanyl
fentanyl that she
bought on the street.
Street drugs right now
are Russian roulette.
What I'm doing is much safer.
I could call the cops on
you. Do you know that?
Tell me something...
is it just the drugs?
Are you also sleeping with her?
If I were doing that,
would I be calling you?
Can we please stop
with the nonsense now?
I'm trying to save her life.
The only way she
turns this around
is if she hits rock bottom.
- Rock bottom.
- Mm-hmm.
I kicked my daughter
out of my house.
And I told her,
"Do not come back
until you're clean and sober."
The next time I saw her
was on the coroner's table.
Well, I'm very sorry.
But Hannah is not your daughter.
And the only person that
can save Hannah is Hannah.
But she has to want the help.
And that's never gonna happen
as long as you
keep enabling her.
I heard your second
surgery was boring
just the way we like them.
I'm still a little sore.
That's why I brought this.
Oh, thank you.
Oh, yeah, that is much better.
Bless you.
Now, show me that baby.
Oh, she is gorgeous.
The spitting image
of Winston Churchill.
She, too, will one
day rule an empire.
Park looks so happy to
be her dad. Doesn't he?
And as soon as we get married,
we can finalize the adoption
and make it official.
Way to bury the lede! Congrats.
When's the big day?
Sometime this week, actually.
- Do you want to come?
- Absolutely.
Oh, I'm just glad
that Park is making
an honest woman out of you.
Me, too.
I can't believe how close I
came to letting him get away.
Hi.
- Hi.
I'm making Coq au vin.
I found a bottle of
Burgundy in the cabinet.
I hope you don't mind.
We're celebrating.
Celebrating?
What are we celebrating?
I got a job
at L'Amour, as a hostess,
but it's one of the best
restaurants in the city,
and I can work my way up.
Wow. That is amazing.
I am very, very proud of you.
Thank you.
I'm proud of me, too.
Mmm.
Oh. Time for your pill.
Um, after my shower.
This has to simmer for
30 minutes, anyway.
- Those aren't mine.
- Please don't lie to me.
I found them in your jeans.
Why were you going
through my stuff?
Well, obviously, I
can't trust you, can I?
I want to get clean.
I do. I just...
You're making me go too fast.
We're gonna get you treatment.
I'm gonna take you, and
we're gonna go, and...
No, I told you, I'm
not going to rehab.
It doesn't work!
- It's the only thing that does work!
- I'm outta here.
- I'm gonna flush it right down the toilet.
- Stop. What are you doing?
That's mine. Stop it.
- I paid for those. Stop it.
- Too bad.
There you go.
Okay?
This is your fault!
How could you think
giving me more pills
was gonna help me get clean?!
How is it my fault?
I'm giving you too many drugs
or I'm making you
kick too fast...
Which is it? It can't be both.
I hate you!
- No, you don't.
- Yes, I do!
I hate you. I got to go.
You can't leave.
Like hell, I can't.
If you leave, you're g...
you're gonna end up dead.
Is that what you want?
This isn't working.
- I have to go.
- Okay. Alright. Alright. Alright, alright.
Your pathology report
hasn't come back yet.
Oh, that wasn't why
I, um... why I texted.
What's been on your mind?
You're not very good at
keeping secrets, Shaun.
I... can't tell you.
Do you want to? Yes, I
think you could help.
I've never betrayed your trust.
Dr. Glassman is
prescribing oxycodone
to a teenage drug addict
who is living with him.
He says he isn't concerned
about losing his medical license
or going to jail,
but he should be.
If I don't understand
his decisions,
how can I stop him
from making bad ones?
Oh.
When I was a kid, I...
I didn't even ask
why my mom used.
I was too busy
trying to survive.
But now, I think what
my mom needed most
was one thing in her life
without an "if" attached.
With addicts, everything
becomes conditional.
A home, a job, even love.
They only get them
if they get clean.
Dr. Glassman told Maddie
she could only come home
if she got sober.
Then she died.
The "if" killed her.
The drugs killed her.
And a car accident
killed my mom, but
sometimes I can't help but feel
if I'd told her I loved
her unconditionally
she would still be alive.
So, Dr. Glassman needs
to keep giving Hannah
unconditional love, even
if it risks his career?
I think so.
And if I want to
help Dr. Glassman,
I need to help Hannah.
How?
I-I'm sorry, Shaun.
I don't know.
But if someone told me
the day we met outside,
when you were soaking wet,
barely able to communicate,
that you would become
a top attending,
a wonderful husband and father,
I wouldn't have believed them.
But you have grown so much.
You're really, really good
at helping people, Shaun.
You're gonna figure
out how to help.
I've missed this.
Me, too.
Ojemann stimulator.
Beginning motor mapping.
No motor arrest.
Mark area one safe
for resection.
Area two not safe for resection.
Are you okay, Clint?
I think so.
Can you keep playing?
Continuing motor mapping.
Totally clean margins,
lymph node negative,
no more surgeries.
You are good to go.
Oh, that is fantastic.
Oh, thank you.
I'm so glad I got
to see you again.
Me, too.
Seems like you're
back where you belong.
I wasn't gonna come back.
I, um...
I-I told Shaun
that I'd just get the
lumpectomy in Guatemala,
and then he told me
that you would be here.
You know, since being back,
I, um, think about
you all the time.
Not like I didn't before, but...
I don't know why I
couldn't commit to you.
I think I was just
young, stubborn.
It's okay.
We got all of it.
You'll need to do
some radiotherapy,
but it shouldn't interfere
with your music career.
Well, I'm not sure
any crowd will compare
to playing with
my brain exposed.
Thank you so much.
You look upset, like
you have been crying.
Are you okay?
No.
Hannah bought pills
on the street.
I don't know what to do.
I can't help her. I tried.
I-I don't want to...
I don't want to fight anymore.
Do you want me to stay with you?
No.
I'm gonna go for a walk.
Thank you. Thank you.
Who are you?
I am Dr. Shaun Murphy.
Dr. Glassman's... son.
Not biologically.
Dr. Glassman helped me
like he's helping you.
So, basically, we're
both broken toys
that are supposed to replace
the daughter he couldn't fix?
Dr. Glassman didn't fix me.
He loved me.
I'm not like other people.
Other kids called me weird.
My parents didn't want me.
So, that was how I saw myself.
But Dr. Glassman saw
that I could be more.
And now I see myself
as so much more
because Dr. Glassman loved me
unconditionally.
I am still different.
I will... always have autism,
but now I'm proud of that.
You will always be an addict,
even if you stop using drugs.
But Dr. Glassman
sees you can be more.
Why can't you?
Mm. It's after midnight.
I know.
Joelle's on her way to babysit.
Why?
I borrowed your favorite dress,
gave it to the dressmaker,
so she'd have the right size.
I haven't looked.
I'm not supposed to
see it until later.
We're getting married now?
2:00 a.m. was the only time the
perfect venue was available.
Idle Time Jazz Bar, where we...
Had our first official date.
You're amazing.
I'm glad you're here.
I know I'll always be an addict.
But I'd like to be more.
I know I need rehab.
I'd really like it
if you could still
be here for me
after rehab.
Like you were for Dr. Murphy.
As long as I'm here,
I'll be here for you.
We have to find you
the right program.
I am a president of a hospital,
so I should be able
to pull some strings.
Mr. Big Shot.
You better believe it.
To always support your
boundless ambitions.
To never complain,
no matter how many
times you make me listen
to the same show tunes.
And most of all, I...
I vow to be the
man and the father
and the best friend
you and Eden need.
Always.
Well, I think I
was the last person
that knew we were
getting married tonight,
so I didn't write any vows.
But the truth is
that I will never be
as romantic or as
sweet as you are.
But I will never
stop loving you.
Or stop teasing you because
I know it turns you on.
Shaun and Lea, the rings.
With this ring.
I thee wed.
With this ring, I thee wed.
Alright, you two. Now, smooch.
♪ Yeah, raise your
glass to the ceiling ♪
♪ There's true love, there's
true love in the building ♪
- What is happening?!
- ♪ Hope y'all catching the feeling ♪
♪ I know you catching
the feeling ♪
- ♪ Something borrowed ♪
- ♪ Something new ♪
- ♪ Something old ♪
- ♪ Something blue ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ You're just too
good to be true ♪
♪ Can't take my
eyes off of you ♪
♪ You'd be like
heaven to touch ♪
♪ I want to hold you so much ♪
♪ At long last,
love has arrived ♪
♪ And I thank God I'm alive ♪
♪ You're just too
good to be true ♪
♪ Can't take my
eyes off of you ♪
♪ I need you, baby ♪
♪ And if it's quite alright ♪
♪ Unh, you know I
need you, baby ♪
♪ To warm the lonely nights ♪
♪ Unh, to warm the
lonely nights ♪
♪ I love you, baby ♪
This is perfect.
I know.
♪ Oh, pretty baby ♪
♪ Don't let me down, I pray ♪
♪ Now that I found you, stay ♪
♪ And let me love you ♪
♪ Oh, baby, let me
love you, okay ♪
♪ There's no reason to even
talk about last night ♪
♪ I'm trying to love you and
turn you on like a flashlight ♪
♪ And I ain't never gon worry
bout what yo past life ♪
♪ We gotta kid, we gon raise
her up like the gas price ♪
♪ When we locked eyes, the
feelings was originally lopsided ♪
I'm glad I came back. Me, too.
♪ You covered up your heart
so I had to go find it ♪
♪ You can't find love mixed
with all that pride in ♪
♪ Yet you think you'll be the
one that I could confide in ♪
♪ You mine, then ♪
Scotch, please.
Tequila, stat.
Cheers.
Hannah told me about your talk.
Her parents are taking
her to rehab tomorrow.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
You have grown... a lot.
As a doctor, as a
father, as a man.
Thank you. I have.
My cancer is back.
It's progressed
to a glioblastoma.
There are... new experimental...
No, no, no, no, no, no.
It's terminal.
I'm dying.
Amir will be here in a minute
to take you to your hotel.
Or we could go
back to your place.
I can't.
Not if it's gonna be
a one-night stand.
It's not gonna be
Oh.
You okay?
Oh, yeah. I just feel
a little bit sick.
Yeah, you feel warm.
You didn't drink
anything, did you?
No, because of the medication.
Claire?
Claire? Clai...
Hi. Are you Jared?
St. Bonaventure, as
fast as you can drive.