The body is a
bundle of possibility.
Every time we cut one open,
we're faced with a
series of decisions.
Some choices are made for you.
You don't have to knock.
Morning. How'd you sleep?
I'm not doing
this another night,
not sleeping on that
damn couch again.
Great. You shouldn't.
You've got a perfectly
fine bed right here...
I have been really nice, April.
All right, but it's
time now, okay?
I told you a week ago
to look for a place to live.
You haven't. Because
we have a place to live.
So, today, I'm gonna book
you a room at the Archfield.
Tonight, I will come home,
I will help you finish packing,
and, tomorrow, I'm gonna
wake up alone, in my bed.
For better or for
worse, Jackson.
For better or for worse.
But for the most part,
surgery is a
choose-your-own-adventure.
I'm here. I'm here.
I know you're mad. I am
so, so sorry. We can go.
Amelia's not here. Ha!
Amelia's the late
one. It's not on me.
Oh, um, I got the mail. I think
that your contract is in there.
Come on.
I'm the good sister.
Chief of General Surgery. Yay.
Shut up, I'm here. Whoo!
Okay.
Are you naked?
Oh, my God.
I won't be in five minutes.
Don't you wear panties?
No way. She likes to breathe.
Please tell me your naked butt is
not on the seat of my brand-new car.
Are you done
looking or are you...
Amelia, my children
sit back there.
You only have a problem
if they lick the seats.
Do they lick the seats?
She did not just say that.
Just start the car
and drive already.
If I didn't care so much
about the planet for my babies,
this carpool would
not even be happening.
Meredith finally got
her contract. Whoo!
It's official.
Lady chief trifecta.
Way to go.
The house of lady chiefs.
Sister lady chiefs.
Put a bra on!
What was that? Hmm?
What was what?
That face, you just made a face.
I don't make faces.
You did. You just
made a face like this.
No, I don't think so.
You made a face.
Sadie, what's up?
Can I go home now?
Did you poop yet?
Alex, come on.
I'm eating, I'm walking. I'm
gonna miss the entire third grade.
You poop, you
go, that's the deal.
And what did I say
about calling me Alex?
I'll call you Dr. Karev when
you say I can go home, Alex.
You're making that face again.
I didn't make a
face, I just, um...
There's a party for, uh, someone I
know who's getting married, Ethan.
Ethan is getting married.
Who's Ethan?
Maggie's ex-boyfriend, Ethan.
From radiology, exceptional
ass, even in scrubs.
Come on, they dated for
like six months last year.
Right, you were AWOL.
So, someone invited you
to your ex-boyfriend's wedding?
That's so rude.
Maggie, you okay?
About what? BOTH: Ethan.
Oh, what? Oh, please. Uh...
Good for Ethan.
What do I care? I have surgery.
Yeah, she's not okay.
Breathe.
Hi, Laurie, Mason. I'm
Dr. Robbins, this is Dr. Warren.
How are we doing? Good.
He's good. I'm
being split in half.
And our OB's on vacation.
Okay, can I look at
the ultrasound, please?
Don't tell us the sex.
Twins wasn't surprise enough?
It was for me. He was thrilled.
Oh, wow.
Uh, it looks like
they're fighting to see
which one's gonna
come out first.
Okay, so you need
to page Karev 911.
Okay, let's get these
babies out of here.
Dr. Karev, I was
told to come find you?
Yeah, you're with me
today. I'm swamped.
Just try to keep up.
With you on peds?
Great. Is that a problem?
No, no.
What, you hate
kids or something?
No, I don't hate kids. Uh...
What, then?
Just peds isn't my first
choice as a specialty.
Shouldn't have said that.
Perfect, she gives me the one
who hates kids. Thanks, Mer.
All right, pick up whatever
labs I've got pending
and meet me in L&D.
I don't hate kids.
You got it. Push, push, push.
You got it, hon.
All right, we
have a little girl.
Okay, I'm here.
We have a girl. Can we see her?
No, there's another baby
right behind her, okay?
So, we just have to...
Hey, congratulations,
I'm Dr. Karev.
All right, here we go, Laurie.
Apgar's six.
Baby's jaundiced and
in respiratory distress.
All right, call the NICU.
Tell them to have an umbilical
line and vent on standby.
Okay, Laurie, push, push.
Push, push. Okay.
All right, and
there's a little boy.
Hey, you got him?
Yeah, I'll see you in CT.
Can we hold them?
Um, yeah, not just yet.
Babies are looking
a little jaundiced,
so Dr. Karev's gonna
take them up to the NICU
and see what might be going on.
Laurie, you did great.
Oh, wow.
When did you find out?
This morning.
How do you feel?
Like I want to puke.
What did Alex say?
I haven't talked to him yet.
You have to talk to him. Do I?
It's not like I wanted
this to happen.
Jo, you have to talk to him.
I know.
The boy's in CT 2.
Come on, come on, come on.
Got your labs. What
are we dealing with?
Newborn twins.
Don't talk to Deluca,
he hates kids.
What do you have against
kids? I don't hate kids.
Scans up yet?
No, they're coming.
Deluca hates kids. Hurry up.
Could be wrong.
We could be wrong.
About what?
Um, pull up the
little girl's now.
And for the record,
I don't hate kids.
Deluca, just shut
your stupid mouth.
Damn it.
Can you tell me
what just happened?
You see that? Uh-huh.
The boy has a
tumor on his liver.
So does the girl, same tumor.
Both invading the
kidneys, both causing
early heart failure.
What happened is they have to go
tell a mother and a father
that both of their
newborn babies are dying.
Both of them?
They're just babies.
This has to be
some kind of mistake.
They can't have cancer.
You can't be born with cancer.
Hepatoblastoma is a
common liver cancer in kids.
It's also very aggressive.
The tumors are already
causing problems
for your kids' kidneys,
hearts, and lungs.
That's why I'm
recommending liver transplants.
Oh, God.
We asked not to
see the ultrasound.
We didn't want to know the
sex. We wanted to be surprised.
Did we... No, no.
Laurie, this is not your fault.
Your OB likely
wouldn't have caught it.
It's okay. It's okay. Uh...
Just...
What do we do now?
The next step is that we get
them on the universal donor list,
and we try to find them donors.
What about us? Can we be donors?
Absolutely, we'll test you
to see if you're a match.
Yes, right now. We want to.
Warren, Deluca,
make that happen,
and I'll see you
down in the pit.
You should know that
they are in very good hands.
Dr. Karev is amazing.
Hey.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
Do you want to have kids?
I don't, uh, know.
Yeah, I... Do you... Now?
Or ever?
I don't know, just is it
something that you want?
Yeah, now or ever.
God, Alex, it's a simple
yes-or-no question.
What the hell is going on?
Nothing.
I just...
Hey. Hey.
You're a department head. Will
you take a look at this contract
for me and tell me if
anything looks weird to you.
Sure.
There it is, the face.
What face?
Maggie made a face,
and now you're making a face.
What is it about my
contract that makes people
make that face?
You know what, I...
I don't like talking
money with friends.
We're not talking money, Callie.
Are we talking money?
I think they lowballed
you a little. A lot.
Why do you think that?
Because I make a
lot more than you.
Yeah, like a lot more than you.
Like a lot more.
Well, how much? Meredith.
Give me a number.
And I just think,
like, can't you just be
civil and rational?
But she won't listen to
anything I have to say.
Now she's decided
that this is the hill
that she's got to die on.
Of course that hill is
my living room, so...
Look, yeah, I'm
with Robbins today,
and Karev has these
twins, so I need...
Oh, yeah. Yeah, yeah, no, go.
Okay. Yeah.
Hey, look.
Uh, if, you know... If you
need to get out of there
or you need a
couch to crash on...
Oh, no, no. Not a chance.
Thanks, but no.
She's out tonight.
'Cause I mean, if
I leave, she wins.
You know, she does
not win my living room.
See? I mean,
that's not civil, right?
Little girl's going
into renal failure.
Boy's lungs are
crapping out fast.
Maybe we'll get lucky and
the parents will be a match.
Jo hit me up about
having kids today
out of absolutely nowhere.
Is that what happens? You
shack up, and then suddenly
your ovaries go into overdrive?
Aw, I think you'll
be a good dad.
Your babies will be so
foul-mouthed and dirty and cute.
I just didn't think
we were there yet.
I don't know if I am.
Definitely didn't think she was.
Alex.
What? What if
you're already there?
What if she's asking 'cause
she's already knocked up,
and she's just
testing the waters?
Why would you even say that?
We tested the parents.
The results are back.
Mason, you are a match
to do a directed donation.
Thank God. Okay.
That's good, right?
Why don't you look
like that's good news?
Um, Laurie,
I'm afraid that you're
not a viable candidate.
We still have
one. I'll split it.
I'm afraid we can't.
The lobe of your liver
that we have to take is...
We'll need two donors.
Wait.
What happens if
we don't find one?
One of the babies dies?
We're talking to UNOS,
and we're hoping...
I don't want to hope.
I want to know that I
won't have to choose
between my babies.
Laurie, shh, it's okay.
It's not okay.
Don't tell me that it's okay.
At least there's
something that you can do.
It's not your fault.
Look, we have one.
Let's just be grateful
that we have one.
I know it's not my fault.
You wanted to be surprised.
You didn't want to know the sex.
Okay, they said it wouldn't
have made a difference...
Well, maybe it would have!
Maybe there was something
that I could have done then...
I am their mother, and I
can't do anything to help them.
Stop yelling at me
for being able to.
It's not my fault. Well,
then, you decide, Mason.
You tell these doctors
which one of our children
has to die because...
You're not deciding, I am.
You can't make a
decision like this.
You shouldn't have
to. That's why I'm here.
I'll evaluate, I decide.
The baby that I see is
stronger, is doing better,
has the better chance to
thrive will get the donation.
And the other one?
Will get the next one.
And we will do everything
that we can to find it.
And the rest you put on me.
Bailey? Bailey
did you like this?
I mean, who knew
Bailey was the man?
Mmm, you know what?
They lowballed you
'cause you're an in-house hire.
They knew you
wouldn't push back.
I thought the offer was fair.
I mean, for me, it
wasn't about the money.
Bailey said she needed me.
The job just fell in my lap.
Uh-uh.
No, you earned that job, okay?
You need to go
back and renegotiate.
I can't, it's too late.
I already accepted the offer.
No, walk in there and
demand what you deserve.
Men do it all the time.
They walk in, they
adjust their man parts,
they get more money.
Mmm-hmm. Yeah, we all did it.
I did it real good.
I mean, I got...
I make a lot more than you.
I know. You said that.
Okay, so, I mean, what's
the worst they can say? "No"?
I mean, I'd just go
back to my old job.
No. You can't go back.
You'd have to move
to another hospital.
Maybe another state.
Maggie, what do you think?
Oh, don't ask me.
I make terrible choices.
I can't be trusted.
I could be having sex right now.
What? Six months of
my life dating that man.
Six months, that
is an investment.
What? MAGGIE: He was nice.
Ethan. Oh.
He was funny, he
was cute, he was sexy.
He was sexy, right?
Mmm, very.
He was. Sweet ass.
No idea.
Empirically sexy.
And the sex, I mean...
First prize in the
talent competition
and the long jump,
if you know what I'm saying.
But, you know, he spit just
a little bit when he talked,
and he said, "All-timers"
instead of Alzheimer's.
And I got bored. And I
slid away, I let it fizzle out.
And then within
another six months,
he finds someone else
he's ready to spend
the rest of his life with?
I get that. That can happen.
I make terrible choices.
I leave things behind and
just let the bridges burn.
I did it with Ethan,
I did it with Dean.
Oh, my God.
I did it with my entire life.
One day, I chose to learn a
little bit about my birth mother.
Cut to, I live in her
house with her daughter,
and I work with the kind
stranger who fathered me,
and I left behind an entire life
and family that
no longer exists.
My parents are divorced.
My childhood home is sold.
My mother is in Hawaii
making soups now.
I have no home.
It's like I flew to this planet
on an exploratory mission,
and the Earth blew up behind me
and I can't go back.
And now I'm here
with you aliens.
Except I'm the alien,
and I'm all alone,
and I have nothing,
and no one wants me.
That...
You got us. We want you.
I can't have sex with you.
No.
You're a Cylon.
This is Galactica.
I really do like her.
She makes me
not the crazy sister.
What do you think
they're paying her?
Why are you doing that?
Because people eat dinner.
Not people who are moving out.
April, you're supposed
to be packing.
I'm not leaving because I
told you I'm not giving up.
If you want to trade nights
on the couch, we can do that.
But I'm not moving
out of my home.
It's my home. It's my...
Oh, I hate that you are
forcing me to say this stuff.
April, okay, it's my
name on the lease.
It's my place. You moved
in, and you moved out.
No, I didn't move out.
I went away, and
then I came back.
And I am sorry.
I am truly sorry that
I wasn't here for you.
But I thought if we
had some space...
I need space now!
You see?
Right now, I really just wanted
to have my burrito
and go to sleep.
Save it, I made dinner.
What is it, boiled bunny?
'Cause you sound crazy.
Okay, I feel like a hostage.
But like a reverse hostage
where the kidnapper
just follows me everywhere
and won't leave my damn house.
You know what they call that?
Marriage.
And it gets hard, but
you don't just leave.
You don't just stop.
You do. You do just stop.
You know what they call that?
Divorce.
What?
Tomorrow morning, when you go to
work, I'm having the locks changed.
Yeah, tomorrow night
when I get home from work,
I'm bringing a crowbar!
Listen to yourself.
Two babies, two
tumors, one liver.
How's Karev supposed
to make a call like that?
Well, first,
he'll try to avoid having
to make the call at all.
He'll try to find another donor.
Call UNOS every 20 minutes
until they have something.
He'll bug UNOS...
And call every hospital,
their transplant teams...
Comb the hospital,
every hospital in Seattle
for a matching liver.
Then he'll do a physical
evaluation of each baby
to look for any
other malformations,
see which one seems
healthier overall.
Then he'll do a
full lab work-up,
go over and over the results,
look for any other possible
co-existing problems,
like a kidney disease
or heart anomalies.
At this point, he's hoping
to find something wrong.
Hey. I'm here.
And if he's smart,
he's got someone
double checking his work.
And then it's down to
the tumors themselves.
What's the distance of the
tumor of the Cantlie line?
Eight millimeters.
Yeah, I know I just
called, but this infant
is on a timeframe,
so if you just...
Yes, I'll hold.
Check and recheck every scan.
See if they involve
more than one lobe.
If there's infiltration
of other structures.
You just don't give up
until you find your answer.
Yeah.
How can I help?
Take a look at the labs again.
We're screwed. The
labs are the same.
The staging is the same.
Both tumors are
causing renal failure.
Okay, what about the measurements?
The girl's tumor's bigger.
The boy's is smaller, but it's
invading the left hepatic vein.
One's too big, the other
one's too complicated.
It's a dead freaking heat.
You need food and
a shower and sleep.
You need to walk away
for a minute. I'm serious.
Let's go. Go.
Try UNOS again. Yeah.
Hey.
All-nighter?
Yeah.
And I need to go back, I just
need a couple hours' sleep.
Can we talk?
Yeah.
Okay, yeah.
Are you... I found this...
When I was unpacking,
I wasn't snooping.
I know it's kind of none
of my business, but...
I picked it up. And then I
just couldn't put it down.
Okay, this.
You have babies?
No, no, these were embryos.
With Izzie?
Listen, Izzie wanted
to freeze her eggs.
She needed them fertilized.
I did it, she froze them.
That's all. "That's all"?
Yeah, then she left me.
That's all. You can toss it.
So, you wanted to
have babies with her?
Yeah, I...
I don't know, I mean, it was...
It was 100 years ago.
I'm just asking because
when I asked you
if you wanted to
move in with me,
you said that you did
and that you could
picture a life with me,
but you never said
anything about babies.
You said, "Maybe
we could get a dog."
Do you want a dog?
No, I want to know
what we're doing here.
I love you, and you love me.
I know, but when I look ahead...
Why are we looking ahead?
If you had or maybe you do have,
for all I know, a
bunch of Izzie babies
walking around with
your face on them...
And why are we doing it now?
And I'm just the
"Let's get a dog" girl?
I'm wondering what you
think we are, what you want.
Look, I didn't have
babies with Izzie.
My role in that whole thing
was with a cup and a magazine.
But you would have.
You wanted to.
She was worth it to you.
But when I ask you if
you want to have babies,
you're all, "I don't
know, yes, no, maybe."
She was my wife.
We were married.
That's my point.
What am I? She had cancer.
She didn't even know if
she was gonna be able to
after the radiation.
No, don't do... What, I
have to get sick to figure out
if you're gonna
go all in with me?
And now you're gonna go.
Yes.
And you're right, it's kind
of none of your business.
And I'm not doing this!
I'm not talking about babies
that I didn't have with Izzie
or may or may not have with you.
I have two real babies
I'm responsible for
at the hospital right now.
I have enough
kids to take care of.
Hey.
How did you negotiate
your contract?
What?
I mean, what did they offer? You
were coming from private practice,
so you had a salary
you could leverage.
How much was that? Mer, stop it.
Well, just tell me.
I won't tell anyone.
If one of your kids had to die,
which one would
you choose and why?
Well, Bailey because
he kept me up all night.
But ask me tomorrow,
it might be Zola.
Why? What's going on?
I have two newborns
who need a liver transplant
and one liver. Oh.
The other one won't
survive until tomorrow.
Well, you have
to run all the tests.
Yeah, every test is a tie.
There's no medical
question anymore, Mer.
They're just kids now,
and I got to decide whether
the boy lives or the girl lives.
I mean, Alex, you really
have to trust your instincts.
I don't know, Mer.
If I was one of these
kids, with my family,
where I came from, I
wouldn't have bet on me.
I would have looked
in my crystal ball
and seen a druggie
or a burnout or...
I would not have seen me as
the guy who makes the decisions.
I would not have
seen that coming.
I mean, what if one of
them becomes a serial killer,
the other one's gonna
cure Alzheimer's?
That's not your problem.
I mean, it's just like
raising your own kids.
They're gonna be who they are.
We just have to try to give
them the best shot we can.
Hey. Hey.
The twins' lungs are filling
with fluid. You're out of time.
Screw it. I'm not
making this call.
If there's a decision to be made
about withdrawing
care from an infant,
Bailey can do it, she's the
chief. She can do it, not me.
No, no, hey, no, no,
Alex. What are you doing?
I have been watching you,
I have been in awe of you
stepping up for these
babies, for these parents
in a way that...
Do you remember the
first time we ever talked?
Really talked.
We were on a plane, and we just
picked up a transplant
organ from a kid who died,
and you were upset and pissy
because you thought that I didn't care.
But I thought... Wow.
"This guy could do it.
"He cares enough
about this work.
"This guy has it."
And I knew that day, Alex.
And today...
I have been so proud of you.
And so now you
can't hand it over
to somebody else
because they're yours,
and they need you,
and you can do it.
And you have to because
if you give it to Bailey,
you won't be able to look at
yourself in the mirror, I promise you.
You'll always wonder what
kind of doctor you could be.
This is the job, Alex.
And it's why you get
paid the big bucks.
Mason, this is Dr. Bailey, I've
asked her to perform your operation.
To remove the lobe of
your liver for donation.
And who will get it?
Well, the test and the
scans were inconclusive.
I need to open up both babies.
I need to see both
tumors up close.
And then I'll decide.
You have to?
In order to make the best
choice, the right choice,
or we risk losing them both.
And we're racing the clock,
so I need to take them now.
Wait, wait! They
don't have names.
We're not letting them
go before we name them.
She looks like an Emma.
She does.
Hi, Emma.
Daniel. Daniel.
Emma and Daniel.
What do you have
against kids anyway?
God, nothing.
Okay, I don't hate kids.
It's not the kids,
it's the parents.
All right?
I was an EMT right
out of high school.
I loved it.
It's why I went to med school.
My second call out, it's an MVC.
A woman's in the front seat
bleeding from a neck lac.
And she's holding her
little toddler, who is DOA.
She wouldn't let him go.
And I'm trying to
stop her from bleeding,
but she just held on.
And cried.
And the sound she made...
I thought, she's gonna cry
like this for the rest of her life.
So, I decided right
there, no peds for me.
And not because of the kids.
I don't want that
responsibility over a parent.
And, yeah, maybe that
makes me a lousy doctor,
or maybe I'm just
not strong enough.
But...
I get to decide what
I'm best suited for.
Right?
I mean, don't I get to decide
what kind of doctor
I'm gonna be?
Yeah, you do.
You have to.
Fifteen blade, please.
Scalpel.
And 10 blade.
Push bovine to
30. More lap pads.
That's what I needed to see.
All right, hold on, don't move.
I need a little more retraction.
Good. Hold right there.
Do you see where she's got...
Wait, yeah.
Yeah.
What do you think? Okay.
It's Emma. The
liver's going to Emma.
All right, there you go.
But I need you to do
the transplant for me.
I want to try a primary
resection on Daniel
and see if I can save
the liver he already has.
At least buy him more time...
- Alex.
I want to save them both.
But can the child
even withstand?
Probably not. I mean,
he's de-sating on me,
and I've already maxed
out meds, but I swear,
if I don't try, he'll
be dead by tonight.
I want to try.
Suction.
Retract here.
Hey, Karev's
throwing a Hail Mary.
Suction.
Why you furrowing
your brow at me?
I would think that
you, of all people,
this hospital's first
female chief of surgery,
would fight for a
woman to get paid
at least as much as any man.
This is about Meredith Grey.
I mean, if you do not value
her enough, then just...
It is inappropriate
for me to discuss
the salary of another employee.
She deserves more,
and you know it.
I do, and don't
ever suggest to me
that I do not
stand in sisterhood
with the other
women in this hospital.
You've never been
4'11" tall and overlooked
and called "girl" by
your male colleagues.
You don't know. I am
woman. Hear me roar.
But I've already mentored Grey.
I've already taught her
what she needs to know.
And now that I'm
chief of this hospital,
it's not my fault
if she's not used
the skills that I taught her.
And it's not my job to be giving
away money when it's not asked for.
You have coddled her.
Yes, since Derek, you have
coddled her, and I won't do that.
No, she needs to rise.
And she needs to rise on her own
so she knows she
can rise on her own.
Because...
You may not be here
the next time she falls.
She needs to fight for herself.
Okay.
This is what a
feminist looks like, sir.
Oh, how's the little girl?
Good. She's back in the NICU.
Perfect anastomosis, and her
kidneys have already bounced back.
But how's he doing?
That's a good
resection margin, right?
Yeah. I see you got most of it.
It's decent, it's
just really close...
All right, I just need
to get this last...
Suction.
Suction. Hepatic
vein's leaking. Clamp.
Another clamp.
No, no, come on.
Was it a bad call
trying to resect?
No. No.
It was the right
call, just a bold one.
You know, this would have
happened during his transplant surgery.
Mmm-hmm.
Karev chose the right twin.
Another clamp.
You did it? You did it.
What? ALEX: Damn
it, he's arresting.
Push .02 of epi and
another 50cc of blood.
Come on, buddy. Come on.
BP's dropping,
persistent bradycardia.
Try it .08 to the ET tube.
Come on, we're losing him.
But you had him.
He won't get him back.
No, he won't.
I'm gonna close, stapler.
But you've got a rhythm.
Those are agonal
beats, they won't last.
So, what do we do?
Just push more epi, right?
He's maxed out on
epi. His heart's too weak.
No, you can't just
stop, okay? What else?
There's nothing else.
Nothing to do but wait.
Oh, Alex.
You have a beautiful baby girl.
The transplant went very well,
she's now recovering
very, very smoothly.
Laurie, we did everything
we could to save the boy.
No.
Despite our best efforts,
the tumor was too strong...
I'm so sorry.
Dr. Cohen, NICU.
What is it, Grey?
We need to talk
about my contract.
Mmm-hmm.
You said I deserved to
be your chief of general.
That I made your job easier.
I was happy, I was grateful.
That doesn't change the
fact that I earned this job,
and I worked very hard for it.
I need to feel as valued
as you say you value me.
I need to be able
to look in the mirror.
This is just not enough.
Do you have a number in mind?
Yes.
I can make that
happen. Is that all, Grey?
Yep. That's it.
Okay, thanks.
Grey? Yeah?
Well done.
Dr. Karev.
You pooped? I pooped.
Let's get you out of here. Yes.
Thank you for not
changing the locks.
Things got a little
crazy last night.
Maybe you're right. Maybe
I'm being a little crazy.
But is it really crazy?
To try like hell to save
the one thing in the world
that matters most to you?
I love you, and
if fighting for...
When you're faced
with the tough choices,
it comes down to you.
What can you live with?
What can you leave behind?
Towels are in the bathroom.
Anything else you need?
No, no, no. I'm fine,
thank you. Okay.
It's only for one night.
He shouldn't have to
sleep in a hotel, it's...
- Two more, please.
- You got it.
Here you go.
Dr. Pierce, um, I'm off shift.
Just having a quick
one before I head home.
It's fine, I have no home.
That planet exploded.
You know, I don't hate kids.
I just... BARTENDER:
Another round?
Hate it when they die.
Hey, we have that in
common. Here you go.
Hey, can I ask you something?
Hmm?
Do you ever wonder
why people should trust us
to just decide, like,
the most important
questions of their lives?
I mean, you're just a
person just like them, right?
But suddenly, you're
given this incredible
responsibility to just...
You have really pretty eyes.
Uh... Thank you.
Right or wrong,
you have to decide.
What you're willing
to go down fighting for.
You okay?
Yeah.
Look, about last night...
No, you said it's none
of my business, so...
Well, it's not and it is.
Look, I get mad,
and you get squirrely.
I do not...
No, you get squirrely
when someone says
they're gonna be there, and
then you think maybe they won't.
That happens. You're allowed.
Okay.
I'm not going anywhere.
And if...
Having a kid is what
you want, then...
I can be ready.
I'm ready, let's do it.
Let's make a baby, right now.
Are you out of your mind?
We're not having a baby.
I'm in the middle
of a residency.
You are never home.
And what about us?
We haven't even traveled.
And what happened to
the dog? Let's get a dog.
No, do not come near me.
We are not making a baby.
No.
Mmm. Woof.
The choice is yours.