♪ Whoa-oh, whoa-oh, whoa-oh-oh
Surgeons are
put through rigorous tests
just to get in the game.
We endure decades of
anxiety-provoking acronyms --
SAT, MCAT,
USMLE, ABSITE.
And if we pass that gauntlet...
♪ We were not meant to be
...we are rewarded with the
need to log 850 surgeries
and take an 8-hour
multiple-choice and oral exam.
There's almost no time
to take in the victory...
or even a nap.
Oh.
I didn't really peg you
for the private jet
and limo type.
Don't worry.
I will never send you
a private jet or a limousine.
Okay.
Catherine Fox sent both,
but thank you
for doing this here.
Well, you found me
the perfect recipient,
so I should be thanking you.
And I've never been in a stretch
limo, so it's a win/win.
Is that it?
Hey, Dr. Miranda Bailey.
Mm-hmm.
Meet Dr. Nick Marsh.
Hi.
I'm not a hugger,
but I'm gonna hug you.
Oh!
May I hug you?
Yeah, of course.
Oh. Thank you.
We need this.
Yes.
Grey-Sloan needs this.
Thank you!
They're ready to do
the ICU conversion.
Mm.
Oh, and are the residents
prepped and ready?
They are ready
but not prepped.
Good. I like an element
of surprise.
♪ You just keep on kicking
dirt in my eyes ♪
Why are we standing
out here?
That's a live organ.
Let's move!
Right.
♪ Tell me your lies
♪ Ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh,
ooh-ooh ♪
Ow!
Mom, what --
what are you doing here?
What is this?
Your mail.
It's been piling up.
You need to come in
for the residency review today.
Yeah, I got the e-mail.
I'm busy.
So you're just good
that our program
is being slaughtered
on social media?
What are you talking
about?
#GSM sucks its residents dry.
#GSM should be #ashamed.
#GSM is abusive
and will murder you.
Ow.
But you may not
have seen them,
but I'm pretty sure the Medical
Accreditation Council did.
Oh, my God.
Levi...
I know you've been hurting,
but I've worked too hard.
I have worked too hard
to let them come in
and just shut down
our program.
So please, if you have
any fight in you,
any at all, get up.
And come to work
just for one day!
If not for yourself,
then for me, please.
No.
Mom!
Now, I can't tell you
what to say
to the accreditation council,
but they will be assessing
the attendings
as well
as the residents,
so if they do question you,
keep your answers
short and sweet,
focused on the success
of the program.
Do we know what questions
they're going to ask?
It's a complaint-driven
site visit,
so they'll want to check
our case logs,
observe our residents,
review our curriculum...
...and verify we are all staying
on top of our certifications.
Do we know who complained?
No, and we're not allowed
to ask.
Well, how are
we supposed to show
our teaching skills
with the residents
on grand rounds today
with Grey and Marsh?
Grand rounds today
is a miracle.
Groundbreaking medicine,
visiting surgeons,
extraordinary
teaching opportunities --
see, that's what makes
Grey-Sloan Grey-Sloan.
And what happens if
they're not as impressed
with us as you are?
Well, the program
goes onto probation
and potentially
could be shut down.
And that record would be
visible to the public.
So we could lose our residents
and our patients.
Yes.
No.
Because we are going to
show them who we really are --
one of the top five teaching
hospitals in the country
with a world-renowned
surgical program.
So, go fill in your departments
and your fellow attendings.
Now go impress somebody!
♪♪
Ay-ay-ay-ay.
Oh, no. You are scheduled
to be first interviewed.
Uh, well,
it's not gonna work.
And why not?
My physician assessment
is in half an hour.
You're doing that today?
Inconvenient timing but I'm not
in control of the schedule.
W--
I think you're
all gonna see something
you haven't seen before.
Hi.
So, this is Mason Taylor.
He was declared brain dead after
being struck by a drunk driver.
We're just
procuring organs?
How is this a grand rounds?
Do you two have questions?
Um...Um...
Uh, oh, yeah, uh,
if he's the donor,
then what's
in the cooler?
Oh, I'm sorry.
Did I not mention
that Mr. Taylor
will also be the recipient?
We're giving him a kidney.
We're donating a kidney
to a brain-dead recipient?
Did the kidney donor family
consent to this?
The kidney donor is a pig --
farm-raised,
genetically modified.
We're doing
a xenotransplant.
You're putting a pig kidney
into a human man?
That's right.
A brain-dead human man?
- I --
- Perez?
I'm just so confused.
Um, how do I explain to the team
reviewing our residency
that you are unavailable?
Just tell them the truth.
Look, I am the director
of the residency program.
I requested this assessment
myself.
That speaks highly
of the standards
to which
we hold ourselves,
and the residency council
will appreciate that.
Will they?
I hope so.
You can hope, or you can
postpone the assessment!
Look, I see your worry --
okay? --
and I understand it.
But we have flown
a world-class surgeon
and a neuroscientist here
according to their scheduling.
I went out of my way to find
someone who doesn't like me
and won't be biased,
which wasn't easy to do
because
I'm pretty popular.
Okay, let's just take
a deep breath, Bailey, okay?
- You are my residency director.
- Ah.
Our program is being assessed
as to whether or not
it should be allowed
to continue.
Now,
what if you don't pass?
Richard Webber.
Uh, uh, David, yeah.
Thank you for coming.
Wait,
he's your evaluator?
I wanted someone
as unbiased as they come.
Plus, I'm an expert
at judging people.
I can spot a tremor
from a mile away.
He doesn't have
any tremors.
Well, we're also
looking for
any intellectual tremors,
if you will.
Less obvious than the physical
but equally significant.
He doesn't have
any of those either.
Dr. Bartley is as good
a neuroscientist
as you will find in these
contiguous United States.
And together, we will be
the judge of that.
Chief Bailey.
Jamarah Blake,
Medical Accreditation Council.
Yes.
Yikes.
Busy day.
Shall we?
Yeah.
♪♪
Mnh.
Hey! Richard.
I just wanted to wish you luck.
And how'd you know? I said nothing.
I grew up with an extremely
withholding mother.
I can squeeze information
out of "good morning."
Thank you, but I don't --
I don't need any luck.
Just a time machine.
Cool.
Way to poke holes
in his trust in me.
Well, he doesn't have to
trust you,
he has to trust himself.
And I have been helping him
do that
in his weakest moments
for years.
- Mm-hmm.
- He has to pass this test.
I-I am not saying
don't be truthful.
I'm just saying he's important
to this hospital and to me.
How long have you...
I'll show you the skills labs,
simulators, residents' lounge,
as well as our lecture hall
where we hold our didactics
and grand rounds.
But when
do you have us scheduled
to speak with
the residents directly?
I was hoping to start with
Dr. Schmitt.
They are, uh,
actually observing
a groundbreaking
medical innovation today.
♪ Temperature cool
Okay, everyone say,
"Thank you, Mason."
♪ So tell me
Mason here wanted to
donate his organs,
but UNOS ruled it out due to
his history of cancer.
So instead, his wife consented
to donating
his whole body to research.
Listen, 17 people die
each and every day
waiting for
a kidney transplant.
If this works,
we could say goodbye
to long transplant lists
in just a few years.
So...
Thank you, Mason.
Good.
Alright.
Now, what does this one do?
Oh, whoa, okay.
Wha-- Oh, I got it. Okay.
♪ "If you love me,
give me mula" ♪
♪ Man, I had nothing,
so it shocked my head ♪
Is this the first time
anyone's done this?
Yep. Who can tell me why
we're working on a dead man?
First, do no harm.
Exactly.
We can't experiment
with a xenotransplant on anyone
who has anything to lose.
And why are we attaching
the kidney to the groin?
So that you can see
the kidney
while you're assessing
its performance.
We'll actually see the kidney
darken if rejection happens.
Also, the groin is
close to the bladder,
which provides a good blood
supply through the iliac artery.
Wow. Correct.
Mm.
I don't care what
Dr. Grey says about you --
you guys are
a pretty sharp group.
♪ The sound got me cruisin'
You have one minute to make
that side look like that side.
Well, I'm not a toddler.
Again, we'll be the judge
of that.
And go.
♪ You wanna rock, rock,
rock your mind ♪
♪ You wanna slide, slide,
I'll slide to your side ♪
It's impressive that
you're still bringing in
innovative cases
when you've lost --
let me see -- um...
seven physicians
recently?
Well, we've had a lot
of retirees this year.
- Ah.
- Mm-hmm.
So did Dr. Hayes,
chief of peds, retire?
Actually, he moved
back to Ireland.
I was told
it was a family matter.
Yeah.
Huh.
We have urine.
He peed!
We got urine!
Oh, my God!
Okay, I'm gonna
give them this.
Dr. Bailey,
we have urine.
Yeah! So we heard!
Uh, D-Dr. Grey,
this is the team from
the accreditation council.
It's nice to meet you.
Uh, it's a big deal.
So, obviously the residents
are very excited.
Th-The residents
are always enthusiastic
when they work with
Dr. Grey.
Well, I would imagine so.
And it seems like a rare
opportunity these days.
You're a busy woman,
Dr. Grey.
I am.
I actually have
a liver biopsy to get to.
It's a pleasure to meet
both of you.
- I'll see you soon.
- Nice to meet you.
Mm. So, Dr. Bailey?
Yeah.
Who's next?
Yes.
What about this one?
"When #GSM residents #suffer,
patients suffer."
When was the last time
you knew me
to do anything right
on a computer?
Mom, you can't just criticize
my workplace --
and with so many
unnecessary hashtags!
So now it's
your workplace again?
Oh, Mom!
I do not need you
to fight my battles.
Sweetheart, you walked out
of your job,
you broke up
with your boyfriend,
you sit down here all day
and all night
playing video games.
You don't go outside.
You need help, Levi.
And how does it help me
for you to trash-talk
my training program?
You never should have been in
that operating room by yourself.
They never should have
put you in a situation
where you could
single-handedly kill a man.
Every surgeon eventually
loses someone on the table.
Keyword being "eventually."
Not before you're prepared.
You're never prepared!
Not before you're trained!
They experimented on you!
That is how medicine
evolves, Mom.
That is how
teaching techniques evolve.
They experiment.
I am the one who failed
the Webber method,
not the other way around!
You are still a student.
Oh, Mom.
You were holding a scalpel
without a teacher in the room!I --
And you don't have to think
that that's wrong, but I do!
I do, and I have the right
to warn others!
Oh, God.
Mom!
Oh, my God.
Mom.
Oh, my God, Mom.
Mom. Hey.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Okay.
911.
What's your emergency?
Hi, yes. My mom -- she f-fell
down a-a flight of stairs,
and she's unconscious,
unresponsive,
and her respiratory rate's
around 24.
What's the address?
357 Northside Drive.
She, uh, also has shortening
and internal rotation
of the left leg,
which means a possible
femoral neck fracture.
Just hurry up, please!
Mom?
I'm so sorry, Mom.
It's gonna be okay, okay?
I'm sorry.
Just stay with me.
Purple.
Green.
Uh, yellow.
Orange.
Uh, bl-- red --
I mean, blue!
Uh, uh, I missed one.
Uh, may I try it again?
On a good day,
I miss three.
Our brains don't like
incongruent information.
That's why this test
is a good indicator
of attention capacity
and processing speed.
And you actually did
quite well.
We have decades of muscle memory
in our brains,
and this damn Stroop test
is asking us to ignore it.
Of course, as surgeons,
we have to process
a lot of information
in a short amount of time
as we operate.
I know this.
And I know that
there's a difference
between slowing down a bit
and being a danger in the OR.
I appreciate that.
Aging as a surgeon is
a special kind of humiliation.
We watch doctors
with half our experience
whipping through procedures
with their agile hands
and their nimble brains.
Then part of our job is to find
and recruit the next you,
which can be
a fun challenge,
but can also be
a real ego-buster
while you're waiting
for them to determine
your footsteps
are worth following.
Sounds as if you're speaking
from experience.
Well, uh,
I -- I -- I --
I imagine
it would be hard.
♪♪
I knew it.
I knew it!
I said it from the first time
you brought her to Minnesota!
You're trying to poach
Meredith Grey!
A+ on the reasoning skills
section.
♪♪
Yes, I did my residency
at Tufts,
where I became
an attending.
Well, Tufts is one
of the nation's
most renowned institutions.
What brought you back
to Grey-Sloan?
Also a renowned
institution.
Well, yes, that,
and my former teacher
is one of
the chiefs of cardio here.
Mm.
And I've always wanted
to work with her again.
There's no one like her.
- Dr. Pierce?
- Yes.
Also your wife.
Do you make a habit
of dating your students,
or was your husband
the first?
Excuse me?
Was your relationship
on record at Tufts?
No, we didn't ha--
Wait.
I'm sorry.
I don't see how this
is relevant
to our residency program.
There have been some
reports that there is a history
of inappropriate sexual conduct
here at Grey-Sloan,
so we have to be thorough.
Well, I can assure you
that our relationship
is in no way
inappropriate.
Are we done here?
Did you know Dr. Pierce
was a child prodigy?
♪♪
Dr. Hunt, your mobility
looks good.
I heard about
your accident.
Now, we have an excellent
PT department.
Oh, so, when do you think
you'll be able to operate again?
Soon.
Soon. Uh.
A few more sessions of PT.
Okay, great.Mm-hmm.
Uh, Dr. Hunt's experience
as a military surgeon
has been a huge asset
to our level 1 trauma center.
And, uh, he's been
overseeing a study --
In burn pit illnesses
in military veterans.
Yes, I've read about that.
Now, a few of the patients
involved with the study
died recently.
You're still able
to move forward?
There were -- There were --
There were -- There -- There --
There were some deaths.
There -- There were
several deaths,
but that's because
burn pits kill people.
I-I-I-I thought
we were here
to talk about
the residency program.
♪♪
It's a great program.
I left a job
with the Seattle Mariners
to work at Grey-Sloan.
That was a big change.
Turned my life upside down,
you know?
I used to live life on the road,
free and easy.
Now I have a baby and, uh,
a completely shattered heart,
and an apartment
with no furniture.
I'm sorry.
What was the question?
♪♪
Okay, get the biopsy, call me
when the results come in.
I want to see those cells
myself.
Satellite pharmacy 2622.
Excuse me, are --
a-are you Dr. Marsh?
Yes.
Yeah, we spoke
on the phone.
I'm Jan Taylor.
I-I-I came straight
from the airport.
My husband, Mason...
Yes.
I'm very sorry
for your loss.
I need to see him.
Is he still --
can I see him?
Unfortunately, no.
I'm sorry.
We can't risk exposure.
No.
I-I don't accept that.
He's my husband.
Whoa.
No, no, no.
I need to see my husband!
It's okay, it's okay.
Jan, listen.
You can see him.
You can absolutely see him.
Um, you can say goodbye.
Just not right now.
No, no, please.
Please let -- let me see him.
Let -- L-Let me see him.
Jan...He's my husband.
Listen to me.
Listen, l-listen, listen.
Listen to me, okay?
Remember
what we're doing here, okay,
what you consented to.
If this works, it could save
thousands of lives --
thousands.
And I know
you've lost everything.
And I can't imagine what
you're feeling right now,
but if you go barging
into the room, it is done.
It is over.
He beat cancer!
He beat cancer.
And he gets himself killed
crossing the street!
I understand.
Oh, my God.
♪♪
Oh, my God!
Mm.
♪♪
I know.
And I'm sorry.
Oh, my God.
♪♪
Oh, no.
Oh, no, no, no.
Okay, okay.
ABCs.
"A" -- airway --
not obstructed,
but definitely having trouble
with "B" -- breathing.
♪♪
Increased resonance
on the right side.
Jugular venous distention.
Oh, my God.
Her trachea's deviated.
Mommy, you have
a tension pneumothorax.
I need help!
Where's the ambulance?
Where are they?
Oh, God. Okay.
Okay.
Hey, Mom, it's okay.
They're on their way.
I'm right here, okay?
Okay. Exactly what is the point
of this one?
This tests your ability
to ignore distraction
while maintaining
neuromuscular control.
Just remember you're controlling
the cursor with your movement.
Look, I'm trying!
But you just told me you were
stealing my top surgeon.
No stealing about it.
The offer nearly broke
the clinic's budget.
And you had the nerve
to mention it
while I'm in the middle
of my assessment.
I didn't mention it,
you inferred.
Our residency program
is being evaluated
on its teaching ability.
If they find out that our top
teacher's considering leaving...
Oh, you know what?
Uh...
Uh, you know what?
Respectfully,
you're gonna have to start this
over again, all right?
A-Are you mad
that I told you,
or are you mad
that she may accept?
It's an incredible opportunity
for her, Richard,
and she's a Grey!
She is bigger
than just one hospital.
Schmitt,
I'm in the middle --
Dr. Webber, it's my mom.
Oh, God.
Mom, stay with me.
She fell down the stairs.
The ambulance is taking
forever to get here.
Schmitt, talk to me.
Did you find --I found a knife!
Can you sterilize it
with something?
Um...yes.
I have alcohol wipes.
Okay.
♪♪
Schmitt?
Uh, Dr. Webber, I don't --
I don't think I --
that I can s-stab my mom
with a knife.
It is not a knife.
It is a makeshift scalpel.
And you
are not stabbing her.
She is a patient who needs
a thoracostomy.
I've seen you do
dozens of them.
Okay. Okay.
Um.
Okay.
I'm sorry, Mom.
Um.
♪♪
All right.
Um, all I have are --
are some little scissors
to get into the chest wall.
Okay. That'll do.
All right,
I'm in -- I'm in.
Okay.
She's breathing better now.
Nice job, Schmitt.
Oh, my God.
Oh, no. Oh, my God.
What is it?
Uh, it's a hemopneumothorax,
not just a tension pneumo!
Schmitt, I need you to stay calm.
Okay.
Seattle Fire Department!
Oh, thank God.
I'm down here!
♪♪
Ah, Dr. Wilson.
Yeah.
Hey, these are members of the
Medical Accreditation Council.
See here.
Oh. Uh, well...
There is, um, no better
residency program
and no better chief
than Dr. Bailey.
Then why did you leave?
My husband left me, and then
I had a nervous breakdown --
not in that order --
and then there was a pandemic.
So I just needed a change.
Okay. Did Dr. Bailey try to
dissuade you from this decision?
Um...
she absolutely did.
Oh.
You did five years
of surgical residency,
a fellowship
with Dr. Bailey,
uh, two years as
a general surgery attending?
That's right.
And just threw it all away
to start over again?
I use my surgical training
in my current residency
all the time.
It's where I learned
to think on my feet,
make tough choices
under pressure,
pivot when
circumstances change.
And respectfully, there is
an arrogance and superiority
that surgeons have
when discussing obstetrics.
I feel it reflected
in this line of questioning,
and I resent it.
But in summation,
there is no better
residency program,
and there is no better chief
than Dr. Bailey.
Excuse me.
I have a mom at 7 centimeters.
Okay.
Uh, next on my list
is Dr. Richard Webber.
♪♪
Yes, um...
Why don't, uh, uh,
you two take your break?
And I will go get him.
Mm.
Did they start a line?
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Mom?
They put her on O2?
Yeah.
Did they bandage
the wound?
Yes, sir.
ETA's about 10 minutes.
Could you call
cardio and ortho?
Have a chest-tube tray set up
and portable X-ray.
Yeah, I got it, Schmitt.
Thank you, sir.
Hey, ugh,
it is not going well.
Please tell me you passed
because --
Levi Schmitt's mom took
a bad fall down the stairs.
Hemopneumothorax,
possible hip fracture.
He's on his way
with her here now.
Why do I get the sense you're
not telling me the whole story?
Has Meredith
spoken to you yet?
♪♪
Hey.
Blood pressure -- fwwt! --
plummeting.
Oh.
The blood flow's not strong
enough to perfuse the kidney,
so he's not making urine
anymore.
I sent the residents
out for labs and coffee,
but, really, I sent them away
so I wouldn't scream at anyone.
Did you try a bolus?
Multiple.
Plus atropine.
I maxed out on dopamine.
Epi?
Maybe.
I don't know.
I just --
I need this to work.
His wife's waiting to see him,
and among other things,
it'd be really nice
to give her some good news.
The worst part about this job
is telling families
that their person
didn't make it.
And you have that,
on some level,
in every single case.
Yeah.
Unless this works.
If this works,
maybe in a few years...
I don't know.
I don't know, I don't know,
I think it's why
you shake in your sleep.
I do?
Just a little bit.
I put my hand on you,
and it stops.
No one's ever told me that
before.
Hey.
You let me hug you.
You're taking that job
in Minnesota.
Couldn't even tell me
yourself?
Couldn't give me
that much respect?
No, I haven't even
made a decision yet.
This program raised you!
I raised you, taught you
all that you know.
T-Then made all the concessions
that you needed
so you could split your time
between here and --
and -- and David Hamilton.
And -- And then, even with all
of that, you'd be so selfish
as to leave in the middle of
a historic physician shortage
with the residency program
hanging on --
by a thread?!
Bailey.
Y-You're j-- Yeah, no,
you're that girl, huh?
That same
little girl
that's following
her handsome attending
all around the hospital,
right?
Breaking all the rules.
Having sex in cars.
No one and nobody else
matters.
It doesn't matter
that he's your boss,
not that
he's already married!
No, enough!
Enough now!And d--
Yeah, okay, okay. Let's just
take a minute here, okay?
Stop! I already know
where you stand.
No, you stop!
Don't you speak to him
that way!
Why are you speaking to me
this way?!
He's here
doing us a favor!
Bailey!
Whoa.
I got her, I got her.
- Okay. Sit down. Uh-huh.
- Yep.
- Let's page cardio.
- Okay.
Bailey?
Huh?
I need Bailey to be okay.
She got in your head.
She's been in my head
since I was an intern.
Mm-hmm.
Never seen her go off on me
like this before.
Not on anyone.
Mm-hmm.
Now she's got you
re-thinking Minnesota.
Yeah, well, she had a heart
attack when she heard about it.
That looked more like panic
to me.
I hope you're right,
because I need her to be okay.
Because I -- I --
I do love her.
I do not like her very much
right now,
but I do love her.
I know.
So, your -- your --
your husband was married
when you first met him?
Don't really remember
that part of the story.
It was a lot more complicated
than that.
But she just told the truth
about how she sees me.
She put a finger on
what I couldn't.
You can't stay at the place
you did your residency forever
because that's how people
see you --
they see you
for who you were,
not as the person
you've become.
Dr. Marsh.
Yeah.
Mason's catheter --
it's full.
EKG looks good.
No ST or T-wave changes.
Your rapid troponin
is negative,
so this was not
a cardiac event,
but, Bailey, you are obviously
very stressed out.
You need to slow down.
I'll slow down tomorrow.
Today, I have
a residency program to save.
Why is this all
falling on you?
Where is Richard?
Having an unnecessary
assessment!
What?
Oh.
This is how
today's gonna go?
People accidentally
telling people things
that they should have
already known?
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
But, Bailey, Bailey!
What?
Calm down!
Come on.
Deep breaths.
Ah.
You are marching steadily
toward another M.I.
You need to do --
Do less. I know.
Mm-hmm.
But that's not an option.
This program is falling
apart on my watch.
I know. I'm --
I'm stretched too thin,
and then we took thin
even thinner
with the addition of
a toddler to our family.
And then I heard
Meredith might be leaving,
and I lost it on her,
which may or may not
have been fair to --
Wait, wait, wait.
Meredith what?
Oh, you've got to
be kidding.
Hey.
How's it going?
I can't tell you
how he's doing on the test.
Mm.
But do you think...
he maybe has dementia?
Or a drinking problem?
No.
Very much no.
Why?
Because he walked out
of his assessment.
He took a phone call,
and he left
without a word
of explanation,
which was disrespectful,
at best.
It also showed
a lack of judgment,
which is not a great sign.
Yeah, I've done a lot of things
that lacked judgment.
Hi.
Seriously?
What, I'm not allowed to laugh
at funny things anymore?
What did I say
that was so funny?
Hi.
I'm Kai Bartley.
You must be
Scout's dad.
Link.
Atticus Lincoln.
Wait.
You've met Scout?
Your name is Atticus?
Don't.
Excuse me.
Don't protect me.
No, I'm not
protecting you.
I'm protecting myself
from having to watch
another one
of your hissy fits.
My hissy fits?
Mm-hmm.
Dr. Webber,
why are you --
Uh.
♪♪
Schmitt?
57 years old,
status post-fall
down a flight of stairs,
sustaining
a tension hemopneumothorax
with a flail chest and likely
a femoral neck fracture.
Pneumo relieved by
a home thoracostomy but --
Okay, trauma one's ready.
Move, move, move.
We were just i-in a fight,
and then she slipped,
and she fell down the stairs,
and I-I feel like
it's all my fault.
What -- No. Schmitt, no.
You saved her life.
Now let Altman and Link
finish what you started.
Dr. Webber, I want to
go with my mom.
You absolutely cannot go.
Richard, you need to finish
what you started.
Dr. Webber, I can't just wait
and do nothing.
Uh, can I finish?
I'd recommend it.
Okay.
My mom wrote
those things.
She wrote that
this program breaks people
because I was broken,
and then we got into a fight,
and s-she fell,
and -- and now she might die
just like Devon did,
and all of it's my fault.
All of it. It's all my fault.
It's all my fault.
It's all --
It's all my fault!
It's all -- It's -- It's --
It's all my fault.
It's all my fault!
♪♪
You said five rules.
That was only four.
♪♪
♪ Don't go borrowing trouble
♪ That's what you used to say
♪ But we don't keep in touch
the way we used to nowadays ♪
♪ Your eyes are not as bright
♪ As I remember them to be
♪ The light inside's grown dim
♪ And that's hard
for me to see ♪
Richard Webber,
general surgeon,
Fox Foundation
chief medical officer,
and residency director
at Grey-Sloan.
♪ The white stripe
running through your bangs ♪
♪ A long, twisted spire
Levi Schmitt,
fourth-year, um, resident.
Grey-Sloan has been
a training ground
for hundreds
of successful surgeons.
♪ I understand why you stay
♪♪
♪ You may be here today
I started as a sub-I
under Dr. Webber.
♪ But, tomorrow,
you're a ghost ♪
My f-first day wasn't, uh,
exactly stellar.
Meredith Grey.
Miranda Bailey.
Hell,
I trained here myself.
When I was a resident,
I thought saving a life
was the highest calling
to aspire to.
Then I started teaching.
♪ Someone strong enough
to love you when you're wrong ♪
My -- My glasses fell
into a patient.
But I learned,
and I got better.
Because Dr. Webber
didn't give up on me.
There's something
uniquely fulfilling
about training future
generations of surgeons.
He taught me how to do
lap choles
and the importance
of a square knot.
You see them
show up wide-eyed.
You nurture
and nudge them.
You watch them achieve
and stumble
and grow and soar.
He also taught me
how to persevere
and learn
from my mistakes.
I know that this review is
supposed to determine whether
he's a competent surgeon
or effective teacher.
I'm sure the methodology
behind it is well-tested.
I asked for an evaluation
to see if it was time
for me
to put down my scalpel.
Years ago, I took an oath --
do no harm.
I stand by it.
♪♪
I don't want to retire.
I love being a surgeon.
And I love teaching.
You all know what you're doing.
Just don't kill anyone.
I'm done!
But I also know
that Richard Webber
helped me save
my mom's life today.
♪♪
♪ You'll be wrong
if you were thinking ♪
Or I -- I hope so.
♪ Like dewdrops in the dawn
I hope that
we saved her life.
But even more,
I believe in the power
of medicine and science.
I don't even want to
think about
what could've happened
without him.
So if I need to step down
in order for future generations
to keep training here...
♪ When you're wrong
♪ Someone strong enough
to love you ♪
...then I will.
♪ When you're wrong
♪♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh
♪ When you're wrong
♪♪
♪ Ooh, ooh-ooh-ooh
♪ Oooh, oooh
♪ Oooh, ooh, oooh
♪ Oooh, oooooooh!
♪♪
I appreciate you
letting me finish.
And for taking the statement
from Schmitt.
Oh, it certainly
can't hurt.
It's also not necessary.
You passed.
Flying colors.
Congrats, Webber.
Mrs. Schmitt's head CT
was negative.
Oh. Uh-huh.Teddy and Link
are almost done.
She's gonna make it.
Wow.
Thank you.
I --
Well, thank you.
Well, don't thank me.
You're the one who passed.
He passed?
Mm-hmm.
You passed!
Oh.
Oh!
Not everyone gets another chance
in the OR.
♪♪
Take advantage.
I'm sorry about earlier.
I was worried about him.
That's okay.
I get it.
He's your David.
♪♪
Mm.
Hi. Uh, so, I can
show you more things.
Um, our plant room,
which --
Actually, Dr. Bailey,
we've seen enough.
Okay.
Please.
We have reviewed hundreds
of these residency programs,
and we can usually tell
pretty quickly
when they're not working,
and that's even when the doctors
and the residents
are very well-prepped
for my visit.
I see.
And based on my visit today,
I can unequivocally say
that when it comes to
resident well-being,
that Grey-Sloan's
surgical department is...
well, one of the best
that I've seen.
Despite long hours
and hard work,
the residents seem genuinely
excited about their work.
And your attendings --
they care enough to be nervous
about these meetings,
which is a good sign.
The sense of community,
the sense of family
is completely palpable.
And Dr. Webber?
Well...
he's impressive.
He is.
Mm.
What I saw
in person today
was almost enough to override
what I see on paper.
But not quite.
As caring
as you of all are,
you simply do not have
enough surgeons
to maintain
an effective teaching program.
D-Dr. Bailey, it, um...
it hurts me to say this,
but I am going to have to
place Grey-Sloan's
residency program on probation,
effective immediately.
We will provide a list
of specific improvements
that need to be made,
and we'll be back
for another review
in a few weeks.
A few -- A few weeks?
We always give hospitals time
to rectify matters
before we shut down
their residency programs.
Good luck, Dr. Bailey.
Researchers studied why some
people perform better on tests.
Okay.
♪♪
They found that
it's not necessarily
related to intelligence.
Some people become anxious
during exams...
and divert mental energy
toward anxiety
instead of expending it
on finding the right answers.
Others have a better grasp
of how tests work.
♪ I'm standing
at the riverside ♪
They use process of elimination
and other techniques
to help them make
better choices.
♪ I'm longing for
the other side ♪
♪ Where does the river flow?
Some people study harder.
They start early,
make flashcards...
♪ Where does the water lead?
...rely on repetition
to retrieve answers
when they need them.
♪ The place inside of me
♪ Where I will never
be alone again ♪
Well, you were right.
Bailey's okay.
Okay, good.
I spoke to Maggie.
She didn't know about the offer,
either, so...
Can I bring her in?
Yeah.
Um, one second.
Maybe this will
cheer you up.
Wow!
Yes, wow.
500 cc.
Epi -- it works.
Thank you, Mason.
Look at you,
changing the face
of transplant medicine.
No, no, no, no.
Look at us.
You needed that win.
I did.
♪ Where does the water lead?
Bring her in.
Okay.
Yeah.
♪ Me and my sorrows Hi. Ready?
♪ The place inside of me
Okay.
It's okay.
Oh, my love.
Okay.
Did -- Did it work?
The organ thing, did --
did it work?
It worked.
It was a minor miracle,
but Mason here,
he -- he made it happen.
♪ Floating away
Please.
♪ Along with the sea
♪ I find my way home
♪ Après minuit ♪
You hear that, babe?
♪♪
You made it happen.
It's okay.
♪♪
I'm gonna be okay.
♪ I'm drifting
down the riverside ♪
♪♪
♪ I'm drifting down
the riverside ♪
♪ No weight, no gravity
I am...
♪ Like a child
in a mother's womb ♪
I'm ready to --
I'm just --
I'm ready to...
start over.
I'm definitely ready.
♪ I let the water take
♪ Me to the other side
I'm gonna
take that offer.
Really?
Yes, really.
♪ Where I'll never
be alone again ♪
Tests don't always measure
how much you know.
♪♪
They measure how well
you take tests.
♪♪
And tests certainly don't
measure your worth.
♪♪
But knowing that
doesn't make it hurt less
when you don't succeed.
♪♪