When I invited you
over to my apartment,
I was thinking that
maybe we were...
Is this okay?
Sully, you with me?
Cancer's getting
worse, isn't it?
Maybe Lynne and the kid would
be better off without me.
Stop. You gotta get treatment.
Alzheimer's is tricky to accept.
I keep reminding myself of that.
I just wanna know what's
going to happen to me.
It's gonna be all right.
Take it easy. Watch your step.
You got him?
Yep? Okay.
Bert, are you okay?
Oh, my goodness.
What? How is he?
Just mild inhalation
injuries, a bit confused.
We're gonna take him to
Med to get checked out,
but we don't think it's
anything too serious.
Okay.
Make sure the dog gets out.
Don't worry. I'll get it.
We didn't see a dog.
He doesn't have a dog.
What do we know about
how this happened?
Uh, the guy next
door saw the smoke.
By the time he got over here,
the stove top burner was on
and the kitchen had
gone up in flames.
So he did this?
Looks that way.
Ms. Goodwin, as a friend
in my years, I've been
on countless calls
involving forgetful older folks.
I don't think I need
to tell you this,
but we got pretty lucky here.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
Hello, hello.
There he is. Today's
the day, my man.
It's really happening, huh?
Oh, yeah, donor team's
made the delivery.
Brand-new liver is all yours.
What do you say?
You ready, Colin?
Dad said I could have
all the ice cream I want
when I get to the recovery room.
Oh, did he now?
Within reason, of course.
Ice cream, huh? What's
your favorite flavor?
Mm, I think cookies and
cream is the best one.
Good choice.
So as discussed, the
liver's a perfect match,
but the donor is an adult.
It will work, right?
Yeah, after we do
a bit of resizing
on some of the
anatomy, absolutely.
I've already convened
the transplant committee
to review my plan.
Okay? It's merely a formality.
Hey, Colin, what do you say?
Get your pre-op labs
started and go from there?
Yes, sir. I'm ready.
- Okay, buddy. All right.
- Thank you, Doctor.
Yeah, you got it. I'll
see you later, all right?
- Dr. Marcel?
- Yeah.
It's Bert, Ms.
Goodwin's ex, incoming.
Hey, Zach, start
the boy's workup.
Yeah, you got it.
You're going to T4.
- What happened?
- Kitchen fire.
He inhaled a lot of smoke.
Hey, Violet, talk to me.
Some carbonaceous sputum but
no loss of consciousness.
15 liters of O2 on a face
mask, satting at 100%.
I told you I'm fine!
Hey, easy there, Bert.
We just wanna get you
checked out, buddy.
Nice and easy on my count.
Ready? One, two, three.
Easy, there you go.
Get him on the monitors, please.
Thanks, Violet.
- You got it.
All of us over at 51 have got
your back if you need anything.
- Thank you.
- You got it.
What happened?
Well, he got confused
and put an electric tea
kettle on the stove.
Take a deep breath for me, Bert.
There you go.
Okay, good.
Let me get a chest
X-ray in here.
Lungs are good.
Carboxyhemoglobin is down,
and he's satting fine.
I'm hopeful he escaped
any permanent damage.
Uh, Ms. Goodwin, we, uh
we got the transplant
committee meeting.
Oh, right. I totally forgot.
Yeah, I'd postpone, but
we've got the liver on ice.
- No, go.
- You guys, go.
I'll keep an eye on him.
- Okay.
Thanks, Dan. I'll see
you up there, okay?
Okay.
You all right?
I knew he was losing
a step, Daniel,
but I never imagined
anything like this.
Morning, Dean.
Uh, it was until
the albatross of med
student rotations.
Ah, there they go.
Seems the feeling's mutual.
Well, if they're avoiding me,
I must be doing something right.
Dr. Archer, you're up, and
you're going to Baghdad.
You don't scare me.
Donald Canter, 40 years
old. Severe chemical burn.
He was working with
some hydrochloric acid
when there was a spill.
- Oh. How bad are we talking?
- 90%-plus TBSA.
The burn unit doesn't
have any more beds,
so they're sending down one
of their nurses to run point.
It's not pretty.
Let's get him on a vent
and start calculating
his fluid requirements.
- Jackie?
- Hey.
Didn't you work last night?
Well, we're still shorthanded,
so I picked up a double.
All right.
Dr. Archer, this
is Nurse Nelson,
Jackie, from the burn unit.
All right, working
on his fluids,
and we'll get in orders
for sedation and pain.
All right, infection
risk is sky-high,
so let's all get
into protective gear.
Wait. What is this?
Does the patient have
any more injuries?
Not that I could see.
- Jackie.
- Damn.
- Are you okay?
- Oh, yeah, I...
I caught my arm
on the door frame
as I was leaving the house.
The Band-Aid must
have fallen off.
I'll just... I'll
get another one.
- Want me to take a look?
- No, no, no, I'm fine.
Maggie, I'm fine.
- Okay.
- It's all right.
Nicely done.
I'll give Colin and
Bill the good news.
- All right.
- Okay.
Resize using a split-segment?
Seems like a bit of a leap,
even for a cowboy
like you, Marcel.
Yeah, well, I've done it before
and have no doubt the
boy's vessels are adequate.
If you're wrong,
you'll fry the liver
before he even
walks out the door.
And you can explain that
to the next patient on the
list who was passed over.
Well, as you know,
we're dealing with a
non-small cell lung cancer.
Plan is to shrink the
tumor before surgery.
We start with chemo today,
six infusions over the
course of six weeks.
Then we'll reevaluate.
It sounds like a
walk in the park.
Just try to relax.
I'll be back shortly.
Thank you, Dr. Washington.
Rip, baby on the way.
Tell me I didn't wait too long.
Hey, you're here now.
At least I'm not
the only dumb one.
What's your problem, anyway?
- What are you talking about?
- Asher.
I thought you two
were going out.
I don't know. We're colleagues.
Exactly.
She's a doctor, you're a doctor.
She doesn't know about
how I grew up, juvie,
my psych diagnosis.
Look, I can't imagine she'd
find that very attractive.
As much as I pee these days,
might as well live
in the bathroom.
So you get to the bottom of it?
Trying.
What's the matter with you, Rip?
She's a doctor, you're a doctor.
Ah, I see you guys
planned this ambush.
Well...
Oh! I... I felt a gush.
Um, maybe my water broke?
Yeah.
We've gotta get
you down to Hannah.
I'll take her. You're
not going anywhere.
Just sit down.
Just... just take
good care of her.
- Yeah.
- I got this.
Carboxyhemoglobin is improved.
Oh, thank goodness.
And Maggie wanted me to tell you
that room is his as
long as he needs it.
So what are you thinking?
Tara has offered to take him in,
but with the toddler, I... I
don't think that's happening.
David lives out of state.
Michael travels too much.
And to be honest, even if I
thought they could handle it,
I don't want to
burden them with this.
Just for the record,
old buddy of mine
runs a memory care
unit in Cook County.
I can't.
I'm sorry, I just haven't
had a second to think.
I get it.
Thank you.
You say a door frame did this?
I know. It's crazy.
I've been trying to get Carl
to replace the strike plate
for weeks now, but...
How is Carl? I haven't
seen him forever.
He's... uh, uh, yeah,
he's... he's doing...
he's g... he's okay.
He's still out of work.
- I'm sorry.
Yeah.
He had a thing lined up,
but, uh, it fell through.
And honestly, I just...
I try not to talk
to him about it
because he's always
in such a mood.
Uh, you know what, Maggie?
Thank you for the patch-up.
I... I gotta get
back to my patient.
- All right.
- Thank you.
Okay.
Hey, Colin.
How you doing, bud?
- I'm doing all right.
- Yeah?
Everything okay?
Yeah, Colin's white
blood cell count
came back as elevated.
And he appears to
have a slight fever.
What does that mean?
It seems he's
developed an infection.
I-infection from what?
Yeah, that's what we
need to determine.
Hey, Colin, have you
noticed a sore throat
or a cough by any chance?
Mm, not really.
Yeah, any pain or
discomfort anywhere?
Mm, nothing besides my toe.
Your toe?
He stubbed his toe on a
dresser a couple of weeks ago,
took off some skin.
- Nail's ingrown.
- Uh-huh.
Some bacteria must've gotten
trapped under the cuticle.
Is this... is this
gonna cause a problem?
You know, with his transplant?
Yeah, in some cases,
an infection can
impact eligibility,
but I don't see anything
here to worry about.
We'll get him started
on IV antibiotics,
and as soon as his fever breaks,
we'll get him back up
to the OR as planned.
That is, if you're
still up for it, Colin?
I'm ready. Okay, good.
All right, we'll get
those antibiotics going
and check in soon.
Pound. I'll see you, okay?
All right, let's start with
2 grams cefazolin, please.
Excuse me, Dr. Marcel?
- Yeah.
- Sorry. Um, I, uh...
I... I appreciate you putting
on a brave face for Colin.
But are... are you sure
there's nothing to worry about?
Look, Bill, I know how
you must be feeling,
especially since we've seen
Colin get passed over before.
If he doesn't get this liver,
I'm afraid he won't
be here long enough
to get the next one.
I'm gonna make sure your
boy gets that liver.
All right?
- Thank you.
Okay.
Dr. Charles, you have a moment?
What's up?
Do you remember Jackie
from the burn unit?
Yeah, she's in Baghdad
today with overflow, right?
Yeah, she showed up with a
cut on her arm this morning
and had some story that
didn't really add up to much.
And when I pressed her on it,
she insisted that she was fine.
Oh.
She's been working a
ton of double shifts,
and I know that her
husband's been through a lot.
She's been so
distant these days.
There's just something
that feels off.
Are you worried about abuse?
I don't know.
The last thing I wanna do is to
sound the alarm unnecessarily.
Then let me see if I can
come up with an excuse
to, you know, sidle up
to her and check in.
- Thank you.
- Of course.
Yeah.
Okay, are you having any
pain or contractions?
No.
I mean, I don't think so.
To be honest, with Sully,
I've been a little distracted.
I get it. You've got
a lot on your plate.
Um, I'd like to check you out.
I'll give you some privacy.
No, can you stay?
Sully can't be here.
- Yeah.
- Great.
Okay, a little bit of pressure.
Yeah.
All right, well
the good news is,
is that your cervical
stitch is still in place,
but that gush that you felt was
definitely your water breaking.
Wait. Are you sure?
'Cause we thought that last
week, and I just had a UTI.
I see free flow, which
means the amniotic fluid
is gushing from your cervix,
and the blue confirms it.
So I'm... I'm in labor?
No, thankfully.
Your cervix does not
look effaced or dilated,
and we wanna keep it that
way for as long as possible.
So I will give you steroids to
help develop the baby's lungs
and magnesium to
protect his brain,
but we will need to admit you.
No, I can't.
I... I have to go
look after Sully.
Don't worry. I got him.
In fact, I told him
I'd keep him updated.
No.
I don't want anything to
interrupt his treatments.
Okay, try and get some rest.
We'll check back on you soon.
Great.
What was Colin's last temp?
100.5.
We're already hitting it
with a high dose of antibiotics.
Dr. Morris is working
with the donor team.
They're asking what
we're going to do.
Nothing.
I told you, I'm...
I'm... I'm handling it.
Well, I don't doubt that,
but the liver's already
been supercooled
for close to 20 hours.
If we release it now,
we still have time for
it to help someone else.
There's gotta be
something that we can do.
All right, let me
talk to Morris.
I think there might be a
way to buy some more time.
Okay.
Hey, Jackie.
Dr. Charles.
I was just wondering,
do you have any kind
of ETA on the, um
on the patient's wife?
ETA?
Do you have any idea when the
patient's wife is getting here?
I just wanna make sure
that I'm here as well.
Oh, um, uh, maybe an hour.
So, uh, how you
been? You all right?
I'm fine.
- Here.
- Thank you.
Hey. So what do you think?
- Distant.
- Right.
Definitely. I mean,
barely there, right?
I mean I would say,
like, almost numb.
Which arm did you say
that the cut was on?
Um, the left one.
Right.
I thought I saw her pressing
on it before I left.
Really?
When you were bandaging her up,
did you notice any other
wounds or injuries on her arm?
No.
The thing is, like, cutting,
not necessarily the first thing
we see with abuse, right?
Cuts can, of course,
be self-inflicted.
Wait, you mean like, self-harm?
It... it... it kind of fits.
Yeah, but we're
talking about Jackie.
She's a powerhouse. She's
been in Med for years.
I...
I did my certification with her.
The burn unit is brutal.
I mean, every day, she's
taking care of people
who are in excruciating,
horrific pain.
Who wouldn't shut
down after a while?
You're saying that
she's cutting herself
to feel something?
Well, in her case,
it would be more like
distracting herself.
Okay, let's just assume
that you're right.
What do we do?
Well, I mean ideally,
we get her to open up.
And based on the evidence,
she's not that interested
in talking to me,
but a fellow nurse, friend,
could be a different story.
Yeah.
Can I help you?
Uh, sorry.
Don't mean to bother
you, Dr. Archer.
But I was just trying to
get a feel for the day.
And anyway, um,
treatment to Mr. Manofsky,
unexplained weakness,
B12 deficiency.
He recently just had
a dental procedure.
Perhaps the two
could be connected
if he has undiagnosed
pernicious anemia.
Huh.
All right, and how would
we test your theory?
We could check his homocysteine
and methylmalonic acid levels.
Dr. Archer, I need
you in treatment five.
His name is Paul
Talbot, 42 years old,
septic from kidney stones,
needs to be intubated.
All right, thank
you. Do me a favor.
Have the lab run an MMA on
our guy in treatment two.
You got it.
You're with me. Let's go.
Oh, wow. Oh, okay.
Thank you!
I've been so excited
for this rotation.
I'm a little nervous.
Yeah, I don't need
your life story.
Just keep up with
me and do as I say.
Meds are in.
All right, slugger.
You're up.
Me?
Well, I already
know how to do it.
Oh.
- Any day now.
- Right, okay.
He's desaturating.
Okay, you think maybe
you wanna get this done
before he suffocates?
Okay, sats are
down to 85, 84, 82.
He's starting to Brady down.
- Get out of here.
That's it. You're out.
- Wait. No, it's...
No, no, you're out.
That's it. Stop. Out.
All right, I'm in. Bag him.
Tough day?
Me? No.
I'm okay.
What happened?
That's the thing.
I'm... I'm not sure.
I mean, I know what
I'm supposed to do.
But before I could
even move, I just...
I start to doubt myself and
I worry about the patient.
I just freeze.
And you get a little
criticism from your boss.
Yeah. He kicked me
out of the room.
But he's right.
I screw everything up.
Look, this is your
first time in the ED.
It's a hard rotation for anyone.
It's gonna be okay.
Hmm?
- Mm-hmm.
Chin up.
Dr. Archer.
Ah, Ms. Goodwin. I
heard about Bert.
I'm sorry.
Thank you, but we need to
talk about your med student.
Oh.
I...
the kid froze up, and
I called her on it.
It's not my fault
she's fallen to pieces.
Have you given any thought
of the pressure this
young lady is under?
I'm not here to
be her therapist.
I'm here to make
her into a doctor.
Well, she can't do that
if you make her regret she
ever went to medical school.
This is a teaching hospital.
- Mm-hmm.
Dr. Archer, our
job is to nurture,
not to cull the herd.
Okay.
Excuse me.
My name is Joan Canter.
I'm looking for my
husband, Donald.
I'm Dan Charles and
this is Maggie Lockwood.
We've been helping to
take care of your husband.
Maggie is gonna take you in
to see him in just a sec,
but I just wanna prepare you.
His burns are severe.
He's on pain medication
and he's sedated,
but you can sit with him
and talk to him and let
him know that you're here.
- Ah!
- Okay, okay. Hey, hey.
Hey, what happened?
It's his toe. He just
started screaming.
Oh, God.
Looks like there's some
pus underneath the cuticle.
Give me a hemostat and
some ethyl chloride.
Can you put on your
brave face for me, Colin?
We're gonna get you
fixed up now, okay?
- Ow.
- It's okay, it's okay.
We're gonna do a
little numbing agent
on your... on your toe, okay?
It's gonna take the pain away.
Okay, that's good.
We're gonna relieve the
pressure, all right?
Take a deep breath
for me now, okay?
All right, it's gonna
all be over in a second.
There you go. You're
doing great, bud.
Just like that.
Almost there.
There you go.
Okay.
How's that? That feel better?
Yeah. Yeah? Good.
All right. Okay.
You did so good.
Dr. Asher, we need you.
- What happened?
- I don't know.
There's a pain in my belly
moving around to my back.
Squeeze my hand.
Okay Lynne, those pains
that you're feeling
are contractions.
You're in labor. I'd
like to take a look.
Yeah, but I'm only 30 weeks.
I know.
Just breathe. Breathe.
Okay, we've held off
as long as we could.
But you are dilated.
The stitch is beginning
to tear your cervix.
We need to remove it.
- Should I call up L&D?
- No, there's no time.
Let's get her to the hybrid OR.
No, I can't. My baby
needs more time.
Lynne, listen to me,
you're already bleeding.
If I don't remove that stitch,
the contractions are
gonna push the baby,
but he has nowhere to go.
It could tear your cervix
or also cause your
uterus to rupture.
Oh, my God.
No!
- What happened?
- He coded.
Was down ten minutes,
three rounds of epi.
Nothing we could do.
Oh, my God.
Mrs. Canter, I'm so
sorry. Sit over here.
Mags, can you get her
a bottle of water?
Yes.
- Here.
- Don, no!
Why don't you come
sit down over here?
No!
I got you, I got you.
I'm so sorry.
Jackie?
Jackie, are you okay?
Oh, Jackie?
Oh, sweetie.
We need some help in here!
Hey, what the hell is this?
- She's in labor.
- Why didn't you come get me?
Shut up, Sully! I
told them not to.
I need to cut the stitch,
but I can't see anything.
It's too bloody. Sponge stick.
S-she's bleeding? What the hell?
What's happening to her?
Little help here, Mitch.
Oh, God.
Sit down, shut up,
and hold her hand.
Hey, hey, hey.
- Hi, baby.
- Hey.
How's she doing?
She's stable, woozy.
She's, um, taking the fluids,
but she's already talking
about going back to work.
Oh, man.
So no mention of what... what
happened in the bathroom?
Nothing.
- Yeah, well...
- She's so defensive.
That's the denial.
What do we do?
Mags, there's a whole lot
of help for her out there,
but it just works so much better
if we can get her
to ask for it, okay?
So I say that we let
the IV do its work
and then maybe 15 minutes or so,
go in there and... and
have a chat with her.
Yeah.
Hey, Daniel, there's a bed in
the convalescent ward for Bert.
I'm gonna head up to see how
soon I can get him in there.
- Keep me posted?
- Yeah.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Whoa.
- Come here, come here.
Sit down, sit down, sit down.
You have anything to eat today?
You're a diabetic, all right?
- Yeah.
- Not a good idea.
Excuse me.
Can you get Ms. Goodwin
orange juice, please?
I've got so much to do.
Right, and you're
gonna get to it.
But first, we're
just gonna sit here
until we stabilize
your blood sugar, okay?
In through your nose and out.
- How's the head?
- I can see it.
Done. Stitch is out.
Okay, Lynne, you
are fully dilated.
I need you to give
me a big push, okay?
You're about to meet your baby.
- Okay.
- Here we go.
That's good. I see the head!
Okay, one more big
push, one more big push.
There we go. He's out.
I got him.
Shouldn't he be crying?
Huh? What?
- He's not breathing.
- Oh, God, no.
No, no, no.
- Do something.
Okay, start compressions.
We need a tube and surfactant.
No.
No, no.
- It's gonna be okay, baby.
It's gonna be okay.
Hey, hey. It's gonna be okay.
No, no, no.
Oh, my God.
No, what's happening?
What's happening? Is he okay?
Surfactant.
Please. Please, please, please.
Meds are in.
Come on.
Oh!
He's good.
We're parents. You did it.
You did it, baby.
- Thank you, thank you.
So what, you're just gonna
hide in here all day?
I didn't think you'd want
me back on the floor.
Well, you're no use to me
with your nose buried in a book.
I know, I'm... I'm
sorry. I was just...
I-I'm sorry. Never mind.
No, no, no, no, no,
no, no, that's okay.
Go ahead. Tell me.
I, uh, I wanna hear.
It's just...
I'm so afraid that I'm
gonna do something wrong.
I'm the first one in my
family to go to college.
My parents took out loans.
They've sacrificed so much.
And you're afraid
you'll let them down.
Well, look, if I were to judge
you solely on your smarts,
I'd say you're gonna
be a good doctor.
It was the inaction
that is the problem.
What was it Gretzky once said?
You miss 100% of the
shots you don't take.
Who's Gretzky?
Who's Gre...
Never mind. The point
is, you're a student,
and mistakes come
with the territory.
And that's why the other
doctors and I are here,
to keep you from
killing someone.
But you've gotta
take those shots.
100.3.
Okay.
Hey, Bill, listen.
Temp's gonna break soon, okay?
I'm not giving up.
All right?
- Okay.
- All right.
Thank you.
- Hey.
How's the boy?
Yeah, fever's
starting to plateau.
Well, unfortunately,
we're out of time.
I just spoke with Dr. Morris.
He's convening the
transplant committee.
He's insisting we
release the liver.
- Are you feeling any better?
- Yeah.
Can we, uh, can we
wrap this up now?
Yeah, um, you do realize
that you fainted?
I know.
Yeah, I've... I've
been really run-down,
you know, with my
diet and my schedule.
You of all people, you
should know about this.
Yeah, but you were bleeding.
I know, my... my cut from this
morning, it must have reopened.
Yeah, I saw the other cuts.
I don't know what you think
you saw, but I'm fine.
Jacks, I saw the other cuts.
And I think that you're
doing it to yourself.
All right, well, I'm
done talking about this.
Jackie, the only reason
we're here, we're just
we're worried about you.
So you put him up to this?
Jacks, because we are friends
and because I care about you.
That's why we're here.
Jackie, can I, um...
From my perspective,
I don't know how you do it,
the extraordinarily difficult
things that you're faced with
every day, the pressure you
must feel to keep it together.
You know, no wonder
you're looking for a way
to deal with all that pain
that you have to absorb.
I don't... I don't know
what you're talking about.
The reason that Maggie and
I are so concerned about you
is that the coping
mechanism that you developed
has brought you to a
very dangerous place.
We can do this however
you wanna do it.
Like, we can just talk about
a little paid time off.
Nothing has to go
on your record.
How dare you, you
condescending prick.
You're gonna sit there
and you're gonna tell me
what's inside my head?
And you're gonna threaten
my job in the process?
I don't need your help.
I'm going.
Look, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Jackie. I...
I can't let you do that.
Jackie, Jackie.
- What? What?
I have determined that
you are a significant
danger to yourself
and I have no choice but
to hold you for 72 hours.
What?
- I'm... I'm very sorry.
- Jacks...
- No, no, no, no.
You can't... you can't do that.
Jacks, you know it's true.
- No.
- Jackie, you know it's true.
- You can't do this to me.
- You know it's true!
Hold her.
- No, come on, guys.
No, get off... get
off me. Maggie.
Maggie!
- Jacks!
- Get off me. Get... stop it!
- Maggie!
Maggie! You can't do this to me!
He has a fever. The
infection is systemic.
With a new liver,
his body will be strong
enough to fight it off.
You're wasting
everyone's time, Marcel.
We have another
candidate lined up,
and you refuse to acknowledge
that your patient is no
longer a viable option.
Colin won't survive
without this liver.
You understand that?
He very well may
not survive with it.
We're talking about a
young boy here, Justin.
He's got his whole
life ahead of him.
It's tragic.
But
it doesn't change the facts.
I'd like to know if anyone
else in the committee
has something to add.
Given that there is no consensus
and the liver has
already been allocated
to Dr. Marcel's patient,
the decision is yours
to make, Dr. Marcel.
Why did we even
bother with this?
So what'd they say?
What? Can the
surgery go forward?
Oh, my God.
Uh, wait.
No, no, you... you
have to go back.
You have to go back.
Bill.
You... you... you
have to go back.
You have to explain to
them that he needs this.
He won't survive without it.
Bill.
I made the call.
What?
Why?
His infection, fever.
No, no, no, no.
He's not strong enough, Bill.
He won't survive the surgery.
You promised me.
You... you... you... you
you... there, you told
me, you promised me.
You said you could save him.
You said that.
I thought I could.
I'm so sorry, man.
You... you...
I'm sorry.
Lungs look good,
oxygenating well.
He'll be in the NICU
for a little bit,
but you have a strong
and healthy baby boy.
I've never seen
anything more perfect.
Okay, let's get you back.
You need to rest and
take care of yourself.
I'm gonna stay a little longer.
Okay.
Never too early to
teach him a right hook.
Hannah was incredible today.
Yeah. Yeah, she was.
You weren't so bad yourself.
Look, Rip, maybe becoming
a dad has made me soft,
but
you're not that kid anymore.
I mean, part of
him's still in there,
kicking my ass
whenever I need it.
All that juvie and psych
stuff, none of that matters.
Look at what you did.
You're a freaking superhero.
Hannah should be so lucky.
Excuse me, Dr. Archer?
Yeah.
There's a patient in
T7, headaches, nausea.
Her symptoms could point to
meningitis of unknown origin.
And?
I think we start with
a lumbar puncture.
Well, it makes sense.
Do you know how to do an LP?
No, but I was hoping
you'd show me.
Lumbar puncture.
Step one, position the patient
on their side, knees to chest.
Step two, place your thumbs
mid line to the spine.
Go away. Leave me alone!
Mister, can you
please calm down?
We're just taking you
to a different room.
No!
No, no, leave me alone! Go away!
Hey, shh, shh. What happened?
I'm not sure.
We were starting to transfer
him to the convalescent floor,
and he got really agitated.
Bert, look at me.
Hey, look at me. Look at me.
- Sharon!
- Yes.
Shh. Yes, it's Sharon.
I'm here.
- Sharon.
- Yes.
I want you to take me home.
Okay. Take me home.
All right. I'm here.
Okay, okay, okay.
Sit down for me.
Sit down. Sit down.
Sit down.
Take...
Take... take me home.
I will.
Take me home.
I will, okay?
Yeah? Okay.
- Okay.
Yeah.
Jackie?
Jackie, can I...
Yeah.
I'm sorry you've been
put into this situation.
The only thing we wanna
do is to help you.
I'm so tired.
So tired.
Thank you.
Yeah.
I... I thought that...
I thought he's going upstairs.
He's coming home with me.
Really?
Yeah, he, uh
he started sundowning, Daniel.
He got scared
and... and confused,
and I was the only one
who could calm him down.
Okay, okay.
But, um, what about you?
What about... what
about your job?
What about your life?
Well, you know, I'll
get a caregiver,
someone who could be
with him when I'm not.
I hope I don't need to tell you
this is not a long-term
solution, okay?
I'll manage.
Thank you, Jonas.
All set?
Asher.
- Hmm? Oh.
- Wait up.
How's Lynne?
- Uh, resting.
How about Sully?
Over the moon.
You were great today.
I think you got fans for life.
You know, it is easy to imagine
you and Sully getting
up to no good.
Yeah, well, how much no
good might surprise you.
Look
the truth is, I
was an angry kid.
I spent some time in juvie,
lots of mandated therapy,
even got myself a diagnosis,
impulse control disorder.
All of this is just to say...
I really like you.
And if I haven't completely
scared you off...
I'm not concerned
with who you were.
I like who you are.
Dr. Ripley, there you are.
We've got incoming.
Pedestrian versus auto.
Okay, bud.
If you're ready, these
nice people here,
they're gonna give you a ride,
get you settled back home,
make sure you have
everything you need.
Am
Am I gonna die?
Listen, Colin...
Let's just... let's just get
you home get home, kiddo, okay?
Come on.