'80s night should
be banned.
You had a blast.
I didn't say
it wasn't fun,
but that decade
was a crime against fashion.
Tonight's club
is my pick, my vibe.
Ooh, which is?
Sophisticated ladies.
I can work with that.
Shaun?
Hmm?
Sure you don't feel
left out?
I use the time to study
less invasive
bowel resection
techniques.
Please be home by 11:30.
Hm.
He's got you on
a curfew?
Sex schedule.
Our window
ends at midnight.
It's like I slept
on gravel.
Well, that explains
your snoring.
Your mattress
should be burned.
It's time to end
the sleepovers
and for you to ditch
the bachelor pad.
You asking me
to move into your place?
I'm asking you to move
into a new place...
With me.
No neutral zone
to run to after a fight.
Making up's
the best part.
Well, it can't hurt to look.
This is Trent,
his mother, Carrie.
Signs of severe infection
on his left index finger.
I'm ordering a CT.
Sutures are inconsistent
and crude.
It's a minor upgrade.
I installed a magnet
in my finger.
Were you having trouble
holding forks?
It's body art.
Yeah, he's 17,
immune to common sense.
Art seems like
a poor descriptor
given the ugliness
of the infection.
The more appropriate term
is "biohacking."
I put Neosporin on it and took
ibuprofen for the swelling.
That's worked before.
Before?
Show them.
Hmm.
You wanted to see me?
Dr. Glassman,
this is Kayla Quinn.
She's been diagnosed
with major depressive
disorder
as well as chronic
neuropathic pain
from a neck injury
six years ago.
The pain and depression
are besties,
uninvited guests
that travel together,
make it so I can't work,
can't get out of bed,
can't even think.
That's why I'd like to do this
before their next visit.
An anterior cingulotomy
seems like the...
Excuse me.
She is a smart,
charming, successful
woman whose life...
Nice ambush.
She's had over a decade
of therapy,
five classes
of anti-depressants,
and non-invasive
neuro-modulation,
including C.E.S.
and full-on E.C.T.
She's desperate
for real relief
from her pain
and depression,
and she's well aware
of the risks.
Get me a complete medical
and psychological history
and a couple of residents.
We're just gonna
talk about it.
Not sure who's
struggling more,
the overwhelmed,
super-critical mom
or the sad,
self-harming teen.
Trent called it
an upgrade.
He's not trying to self-harm,
he is trying to self-improve.
Well, whatever
the terminology,
he cut into his finger
with an X-ACTO knife.
Okay. His technique
was primitive,
but considering
he lacks formal training
and used only one hand,
I am impressed.
Don't be.
Bony marginal erosion.
If the infection spreads,
he could lose that finger.
For starters.
It's the modern equivalent
of a lobotomy.
"Modern" being
the operative word.
We'd be burning lesions
into a key brain center.
That could alter
her personality,
impair
cognitive function...
Her depression
and reoccurring
acute pain
are already doing that.
Cingulotomies are effective
in 67% of patients
with Kayla's symptoms.
With a 20% chance
of adverse effects,
like loss of creativity,
it could be a big deal.
This is Kayla Quinn.
She launched
her own company
at the age of 18,
made millions designing
scrunchies and bangles.
I discussed this
with her.
Her focus
is quality of life.
Now, I'm sure
she feels that way now,
but once it's done,
it can't be undone.
Are there any alternatives
that Kayla hasn't tried
or should try again?
Okay.
Let's do the surgery.
Wait, possible amputation?
The infection
is in the bone
beneath the magnet.
It would have been better to
have brought him in sooner.
I'm a single mom.
Trent... Trent's father
isn't in the picture.
You made sure of that.
I got divorced last year.
Trent and I
were adjusting.
But then he started
hanging out with
these idiot biohackers.
Thanks, Mom.
We should remove
the infected implant
and start Trent
on IV antibiotics.
What about
the other implants?
Shouldn't you
take them all out?
No! The other implants
aren't infected.
Okay. This is not a decision
you get to make.
Once a patient is 16,
it is hospital policy
not to perform a surgery
that's been refused
unless that surgery is
medically necessary.
Leaving in
the other implants
means Trent's still
at risk for sepsis
and septic emboli.
Dr. Wolke is correct.
With your consent,
we can physically compel
the surgical removal of
all your son's modifications.
Good luck.
I'm outta here.
Trent.
Trent!
This is much easier
than chasing him.
Head frame is secure.
Stand by with
the Gamma knife.
Dr. Glassman,
please stop what you're doing.
This is Justin Quinn,
Kayla's conservator.
I have full authority
over my sister's
medical treatment,
and I won't allow
this surgery.
Kayla sees
her psychiatrist weekly,
and I check in
with her daily,
but clearly,
this is not
a weekend getaway
at a cabin in Tahoe.
A chance e-mail from
our insurance tipped me off.
She's never lied
to me like this.
I was 12
when my parents died.
My memories of them
don't seem real,
just clips
from a movie.
It was
our grief therapist who first
diagnosed her depression.
I was 22
and so out of my depth.
Justin and I
used to do
everything together.
It was us
against the world.
I called him Bro-dad.
She was
such a creative kid,
so talented.
She just had a vision
and wanted to run with it.
Who knew scrunchies
and glitter bangles
could be a business?
Just took off.
Eighteen years old,
all that money
and no guardrails.
She was out of control.
Clubs every night,
the booze, the drugs...
I couldn't help her.
I couldn't stop her.
It was during a blackout that
I fell and injured my neck.
Everything just got
worse after that.
The arrests piled up,
underage drinking,
possession, DUI.
I thought she was
going to prison.
The judge agreed to
a diversion program...
She's nearly O.D.'d twice.
...called me
a danger to myself.
The judge ruled
she was incompetent.
Put my brother in charge
of everything.
He took away my life.
The conservatorship
saved her life.
All I needed
to piss off my parents
were fishnets
and heavy eyeliner.
Of course
you were a goth.
How many times
did you see The Cure?
Four.
Robert Smith was, like,
leader of our tribe.
Every lonely teen
needs a tribe.
I was lonely,
but I was not a rebel.
My rebellion
was just being honest.
My family
preferred the lie.
Meanwhile Trent is
damaging his relationship
with his mom
and his body.
That is not his fault.
She is his mother.
Mothers should
try to understand
their children.
Nice thought,
but teenagers are asses.
Scientifically proven.
Their prefrontal cortex
is underdeveloped,
leading to
excessive risk-taking
and lack of impulse control.
Margins in
the soft tissue look good,
but keep an eye out
for the infection.
Let's close.
Mr. Quinn.
Your sister's suffering.
It's a roller coaster
with her,
good days and bad days.
But your solution is to
fry part of her brain.
She could
lose her creativity,
her personality.
Her pain,
her depression.
Maybe.
Those other doctors
ran me through
the risks
and the numbers.
What if I could show you
how Kayla's issues are
hard-wired in her brain?
An fMRI could demonstrate
how the part of Kayla's brain
that handles emotional
and pain response
is functionally
abnormal.
It'll assure you that
"frying her brain"
means only frying
the part of her brain
that isn't working.
And it'll get you both
off of the roller coaster.
The scan's harmless.
Okay, do it.
I've got it. Oh, see?
I can spin it around.
I need to do
a post-op exam.
Oh. You have modifications.
I'm Dixie.
My right hand got messed up
in a car accident.
I had RFID chips put in so
I could unlock my front door,
store my medical info,
and do some
pretty cool tricks.
Are you attracted
to Dixie?
Are you concerned you'll
be less attractive to her
without your implants?
We're just friends.
I host a monthly
biohacker meet up,
and Trent's
become a regular.
The only people
who get me.
You found your tribe.
Incision sites look good.
Right wrist please.
It was not
until I came to work
here at St. Bonaventure
that I felt like
I was part of a community.
I've read about implants
that can operate prosthetics
and an
occipital lobe electrode
that receives visual images
for sightless people.
Oh, these technologies
are very exciting.
It's so cool, right?
I was thinking I should
be an engineer
and I can design tech
for people like Dixie.
Oh.
How's he recovering,
Dr. Murphy?
Hmm, oh, hello.
The surgeries went well.
Finger looks free of infection
and bacterial cultures
remain negative.
We still need to do an MRI
to assess his joints,
but I'm optimistic.
Great. Then once I'm 18,
I can get all my mods back in
by the pros who did Dixie's.
Meaning the tattoo artist
at the strip mall.
Tattoo parlors require
a public health permit.
Yes, that would be
much safer than
doing it himself.
Rain check for tonight.
Surgery?
A new patient reminded me
I need to spend more time
on my business ideas,
less time on the dance floor.
I see a sparkle in your eyes.
What is the product?
My ingestible sensor
that monitors gut bacteria
as it travels through
the GI tract.
Gross yet cool.
How are you gonna
collect the data?
Ideally,
real-time monitoring.
I'm looking at wireless
open-source programs.
You could
connect the sensor
with a smartphone
via Bluetooth.
That would be amazing.
But that code would be pretty
complicated to write.
Not for...me.
You'd have time for that
on top of your IT work?
Says the second-year
resident looking to disrupt
the med-tech business.
Ah.
I wouldn't be able to pay you,
at least not up front.
We could divvy up
the spoils.
75%, 25% final offer.
Hell yes, partner.
Welcome aboard.
Put this
on your calendar...
May 2025,
yacht shopping.
Okay.
Yes!
Dr. Murphy?
Please stop
encouraging Trent.
Your interest
in his body modifications
comes across
as an endorsement.
Oh, I am interested.
Why would I pretend
that I'm not?
Not so long ago,
we were talking about
amputating fingers.
Someone has to talk
some sense into my son
before he does this again.
I'm happy to have
a chat with him.
He seems to connect
with Dr. Murphy.
If you talk to him,
he might listen.
I...would not be
very good at that.
Kayla,
next I'm gonna ask you
a series of prompts
to help us map
your brain activity.
I'll do my best.
Think of a nice memory.
Something from
a happy time.
You didn't like any
of the apartments
I sent you?
As predicted,
altered limbic activity
in the connections
to the cingulate cortex.
The apartments
are okay.
I'm shocked you're
so easy to please.
You're such a quibbler.
"Hate art deco."
"Low ceilings equal doom."
"Berber carpets
hurt my feet."
Well...
Kayla, now I need you to think
of an unpleasant memory.
Take it as a compliment
that I'm so picky.
Picky's fine,
passive not so much.
Send me some links.
More abnormal connectivity.
We're getting
motion artifacts.
She's moving around.
Kayla, can you try
and hold still?
I'm sorry.
Can we please stop?
Kayla? Where does it hurt?
Mm-hmm?
Everywhere.
It's back.
You never came to bed.
We were supposed to have sex.
Sorry.
Our sensor keeps
running out of power
halfway through
the digestive tract.
It's not on the schedule,
but we could have sex now.
I have to shower.
I shower first.
Okay. I will be flexible
and make you coffee.
Thank you.
Good morning.
How's Kayla?
In pain and on the edge of
a full depressive episode.
I upped her gabapentin
and started a low-dose
ketamine IV.
Smart.
Hmm.
You know we'll have to
get her off the ketamine
before we take another shot
at finishing the fMRI.
Do you not want to
move in with me?
I've been busy.
I have other patients.
Allow me to present
multitasking.
Look at that.
Three-bedroom,
two-bath,
courtyard building
with a pool.
We'd have a guest room for
Kellan, a shared office,
and it's 10 minutes
from the hospital.
Well, looks like
the master bedroom window's
overlooking the courtyard.
I know. Nice.
Not nice. Loud.
Then show me one
you do like.
Oh, hell no.
I'm gonna
update the brother.
You paged me?
Good morning, Shaun.
Lea and I missed
our sex night.
It is not a good morning.
Agreed.
Mine started with
a distraught mother
whose son
you refused to advise
against biohacking?
What he chooses to do
when he is 18 is up to him.
True, but you
could advise him
against the dangers
of further mods.
Trent enjoys
the connections
he has made
in the biohacking
community.
You really think
the emotional benefits
of belonging
outweigh
the physical dangers
for this kid?
Teens do many
dangerous things.
If he injured himself
skateboarding,
should I advise him never
to skateboard again,
which could alienate him from
his skateboarder friends?
Is there a potential
for medical harm?
Yes.
Then remind
your patient of that.
You have no trouble
being honest.
I'll do it, only
because you're my boss.
Case in point.
Justin's refusing to let me
finish Kayla's fMRI.
He thinks her being
in the hospital
is what triggered
this latest episode.
He...
He's totally dug in.
It's a judgment call.
Legally, it's his judgment.
I need you to talk to him,
get him to change his mind.
Because?
You're the surgeon.
If medicine could
persuade him,
we'd be in
surgery right now.
So I should just
give up?
I don't know.
Do you want to?
No!
Okay, then don't.
Go find another tactic.
Okay.
No, no, no.
I do the surgery,
you do the selling.
Okay, fine.
Look at it this way.
The brother has been
cleaning up after his sister
for years, right?
So instead of trying
to change his feelings
about the surgery,
maybe change his feelings
about his sister.
Future modifications
could result in sepsis,
severe arthritis,
pseudo-tumor formation,
nerve damage and paralysis.
Suddenly you're a guy
in a drug commercial...
"Side effects include
insomnia, rash,
dry cough, and death."
Sounds like
my mom got to you.
She tried.
It didn't work,
but then she went
to my boss.
That did work.
I think that it is nice
your mother cares about you.
Mine did not.
Mine used to.
My dad used to
travel a lot for work.
He was always off
pitching to investors,
conferences in Vegas.
And me and my mom
would hang out
all the time.
Every weekend,
she would take me
to the Boardwalk.
Never said no,
no matter how many times
I wanted to
ride the Cyclone.
The Cyclone
made me nauseous.
Now she's just
working all the time.
And whenever
we're together,
she's angry.
Never stops nagging me.
She doesn't
like you biohacking.
I don't think she'd like
anything I do.
Ohh, aah.
Is it your finger?
No, it's my wrist.
Kayla's biggest trigger
isn't being in the hospital,
it's your control
over her life.
I reviewed her
history in detail,
and over
the last five years,
Kayla's major depressive
episodes coincide
with major
life decisions
that you've made
on her behalf...
Changing meds
and moving homes,
making decisions
for the business.
You're saying
this is all my fault.
She's saying that being
in charge of my own life
would be better for me.
Until you get drunk or O.D.
That was years ago.
I'm not that person
anymore.
Because I've been
protecting you.
Because
the conservatorship works.
That argument means
I'll be in this forever.
If I'm doing well,
it proves you right.
If I'm a mess,
proves you right.
I'm tired of this, Justin.
I'm tired
of living the life
that you want me to.
You pick out my doctors,
you search my cabinets,
you test my urine
for drugs.
We can talk about relaxing
some of those things.
No! No.
I'm done negotiating
over my own life,
of having what
you think is best
rammed down my throat.
Kayla...
Think acting
like this is gonna
change my mind
about the surgery?
It shouldn't have to.
It's my life!
It's my messed-up brain!
This place is bad for you.
I need her discharge papers.
Stop telling her what to do!
Stop telling everyone
what to do!
Kayla, please...
Shut up!
I need 10 milligrams
of Haloperidol.
Stop it. Shut up.
The LED light
you've installed
in your right wrist
has irreversibly
damaged the joint.
You will never
regain full function
in your hand.
You'll need
physical therapy
until you can compensate with
your non-dominant hand.
Damn it, Trent.
How many times
did I tell you?
Thousands, okay?
But I'm such an idiot,
and I never listened.
I never said
you were an idiot.
I said to stop
hurting yourself.
Maybe some
family counseling
could help?
No, she's the only one
who needs counseling.
She's the one
who failed as a parent.
Your choices
are not my fault.
But I'm stuck
with yours.
Like how you
tossed Dad out.
He walked out on us.
I didn't want you
to hate him.
I hadn't realized that
the alternative was hating me.
Your father
was a schemer.
He kept flitting from one
big idea to the next,
chasing fantasies instead of
taking care of responsibility.
That's a lie.
You're a liar.
He was a self-absorbed
narcissist
who cared more
about himself than us.
That's not true!
Trent...
Leave me alone!
Get out!
Lidocaine to numb you.
I figured you'd want me
to feel every stitch.
I'm used to being
the bad guy.
Bad guys don't
give up their lives
to care for
their little sisters.
Thanks for seeing that.
You feel that?
People idealize
what it's like
being a kid,
but, really,
childhood blows.
Being told what to do,
where to go,
how to behave.
Spoken like someone
who had a terrible childhood.
It wasn't my wheelhouse,
or my parents'.
Kayla's first try
at growing up,
she flamed out.
Doesn't she deserve
a second shot?
Maybe.
Leave it to Kayla to choose
elective brain surgery
for a maiden voyage.
Scares the crap
out of me.
Tell her that.
Jerome's
birthday is coming up.
I need to find him
a great gift.
Please don't distract me.
I am looking for a surgical
solution for Trent's wrist.
That's valiant,
but he's about
to be discharged.
I need a gift that says
"I'm really into you,"
but, mm,
without overdoing it.
We could attempt
a partial wrist fusion.
Not for another year.
Trent's still growing.
Jordan mentioned
you have some super cute
race car pajamas.
I could get
Jerome a pair.
They are classic cars,
and I'd prefer not to discuss
my sleepwear at work.
We could give Trent
a course of Methotrexate
to combat...
He'll adjust
to the bad wrist.
The bigger problem
is that mother and son
act like they
hate each other.
I have no idea how
to fix that.
He's managing
his feelings by turning
himself into a cyborg.
Trent is not
becoming a cyborg...
But maybe he could!
I can fix Trent's wrist.
This experimental surgery
uses a customized implant
to replace his wrist joint.
He will have
full use of his wrist.
Also, he will
be very happy,
because he'll have
a one-of-a-kind
body modification.
E-Experimental?
Would it be covered by
our insurance?
Mm, n-no.
I-It is quite expensive.
Which means I'm getting
a second mortgage
to pay for it.
If Trent keeps getting
other modifications,
could that cause problems
with this device?
Yes, his body could
reject the implant.
Okay, but...
Thank you...
Trent should
be able to follow
the post-op regimen,
including
no further modifications.
Or he'll keep seeing it
as a cool hobby
which allows him
to stick it to his terrible
and controlling mother.
I can fix
your son's wrist...
...with your consent.
No.
Looks like our sensor's
gonna poop out
before it gets pooped out.
Maybe if we take another look
at the component specs.
I have drawn up
a list of house rules
that apply to Dr. Allen
when she is working
at our apartment.
One, no work
on scheduled sex nights.
I can get down
with that.
Two, no brushing teeth
in the kitchen sink.
Agreed.
Three, do not wear perfume.
Four, do not speak
in a loud voice.
Five, please avoid
eye contact.
Shaun...
I'm not finished.
Avoid eye contact?
Mm...
Yes.
Shaun, do you not like
having me at your apartment?
I don't like having
anyone other than Lea
at the apartment.
With Lea, I feel safe.
I am not obligated to
follow the guidelines
around social interactions.
By the time
I'm done with work,
I have had enough
of following guidelines.
Shaunie, I never knew.
We can work
someplace else.
The apartment
is half Lea's.
I am very happy
she has found
a friend and partner.
Dr. Allen...
...you are part
of my tribe.
You are welcome
in our home.
As long as you
follow the rules,
including,
six, I am allowed
to ignore you
when you are there.
Does it ever feel to you like
we go round and round,
but we always find our way
back to this same, sad place?
I remember when we
first got here.
You were 12
on a school field trip
to the Municipal Garden.
And I got there
and watched you
sketch roses.
So confident,
at peace,
innocent.
Then I had to tell you
Mom and Dad were dead.
I swore that I'd do
everything I could
to keep you from being hurt
like that again.
I know you're just
trying to protect me.
I'm protecting me, too.
I've been so scared
that I could lose you.
During the fMRI,
Dr. Reznick asked me
to think of a happy memory.
Silvertop, Nevada.
Yeah.
You and me on that river
in the canoe.
That cabin
was such a dump.
It was.
And we were only there
'cause I screwed up
and forgot to sign you up
for that camp.
Camp Capistrano.
Yeah.
That was the first summer
after Mom and Dad died.
You had an excuse.
That was a good trip.
Best vacation
I ever had.
I want that again.
We can always go back.
Not the trip.
The freedom,
that happiness
without the next bout
of pain and depression
landing over me.
This is my chance.
Please let me take it.
Okay.
I'm dying to take
this next step with you.
Says the guy who's
sandbagging the search.
It's the money.
Between
Kellan's college tuition
and my med school debt,
there's not much left
at the end of the month.
And on top of that
my credit's a mess.
This is just
about money?
Just?
If you can't afford it,
I got you.
I pay my own way.
Always have, always will.
Your financial issues
are no reason to put
our plans on hold.
An easy thing to say
when you've never had
to worry about money,
but some of us have had to
live in the real world.
And if you had
the money and I didn't,
you wouldn't want to
improve both our situations?
This isn't about
the real world.
It's about your pride.
I have your prescriptions
and therapy referrals.
I can do it.
Then do it.
I'm guessing this
is my fault, as well.
Okay.
The way you behave
is very confusing
and frustrating.
It doesn't make sense at all.
You criticize
every choice Trent makes
and never ask
why he's making them.
See?
You deliberately
made choices you knew
your mother
wouldn't approve of,
and then were very angry
when she didn't approve.
Even he thinks you took
your biohacking too far.
She's been mad at me
since Dad left.
Oh, that's not true.
Yes, it is.
You don't like me.
You don't
like my friends.
I don't understand
your friends.
You never tried to.
You're just mad at me
because...
You're stuck with me.
I have been mad,
but not at you,
at your father
for leaving.
Afraid I couldn't take care
of you or support us.
You were so hurt
when your father left.
All I wanted to do
was make you feel better,
but I just...
I was too damaged
and jealous of
your new friends,
when I should've
been grateful.
But I was afraid of
losing you to them.
After all,
you like them.
You're my mom.
I'm not supposed to
like you.
Come here.
Can I do the surgery now?
You are gonna
like this.
Time to prep you
for surgery.
Before I go, um...
I got a little inspired.
I'll hang on to them
for you.
Ready?
Yeah.
Carpal resection
looks good.
What did you say
to change Carrie's mind?
I'm not sure.
I tried to understand them.
Maybe you could do
me and my father next.
Carpal and radial bones
prepped for the upgrade.
I'd say you
get the honors.
Resolving conflict
is a crucial skill
for an attending.
Nicely done.
Placing carpal ball onto
the distal component.
For the next few days,
expect some headaches
and fatigue,
but the post-op symptoms
should quickly pass.
Kayla, how do you feel?
Strange.
Something's missing.
The pain.
And I think I'm still me.
Bro-dad.
** You were listening to
The Dark Side of the Moon
** I could barely
see your eyes...
We have to
go see a judge.
** Psilocybin
in a hotel room...
It's time I was just
your brother.
** I'll be your brightside
Baby, tonight
** Tonight...
The arthroplasty
fixed Trent's wrist
like I said it would.
You will need
significant therapy,
but your prognosis
is good.
And you better
take this seriously.
Take your meds,
do your rehab.
Invite that friend of yours,
Dixie, over for dinner.
Really?
Well, she seems
interesting.
These are the schematics
of your wrist implant.
The engineering specifications
are quite interesting.
Thanks, Dr. Murphy.
** You're stranded
on the bridge
** You're crying for your kids
** I'll be your brightside
Baby, tonight
** Tonight
** Tonight...
I'm glad my key
still works.
It was about my pride.
And I used that
as an obstacle,
instead of
being honest with you.
I'm sorry.
It's a big step,
but let's keep talking.
I'm sure I'll get
over myself, in time.
Can you do it
in a month?
Because I found a house
that I love.
Gorgeous.
Mm.
And at that price,
it should be.
I would be very grateful
for a studly roommate
who could cover
the utility bills.
What about rent?
I was thinking services
rendered, like...
Shirtless lawn mowing,
shirtless pool cleaning,
shirtless meal prep.
Well, certain studly men
would argue
if we don't start on
equal footing,
it'll never be
our house.
It'll be our home,
because we'll make it that.
A pool?
What about a hot tub?
Our power issue
is a software issue.
Because your data domain
requirements mandate
a specific chip that
requires way more power
than we can actually...
** I could see it in the air
** Every word was like smoke
from a cigarette...
What if the sensor
had bad manners?
Shuts down when
it needs to rest,
ignores what
doesn't matter.
It works, it rests,
it works, it rests.
We could extrapolate
between the data points.
That could double
the sensor's life.
You're pure
inspiration, Shaun.
I am ignoring you.
** I'll be your brightside
Baby...
** Tonight, tonight
** Tonight **