- Our DNA is made up of
four nucleotide bases.
The sequences of these
bases is what determines
our unique genetic code.
Everything from
dimples to eye color,
to tolerance for spicy food
can be found in our genes.
- What's with the
fancy breakfast?
- I woke up and couldn't
get back to sleep,
so I made my specialty.
- I didn't know
you had it in you.
- Yeah. Eat when
you can, right?
- All right, let's go.
Let's go, people.
- Hey, you're the one
who's not ready.
- Genetic makeup can also help
ascertain risk for diseases,
so, it stands to reason...
- London is an
incredible opportunity.
- If we want to
minimize the risk...
- OK.
It feels like maybe
I should go now.
- I said that you could use
my lab equipment for work.
I didn't say that I was ready
to hear more about the thing
that you're abandoning me for.
- Could we find a way
to change our genes?
And if we could...
are we sure we should?
- Good morning.
- Morning.
- ♪ Ain't no other
place I'd rather be ♪
- God, I miss this bed.
How long have you been up?
- Four hours.
Maggie, when we were
in the OR together,
we pull things off
no one else can.
- I know.
- We work in sync,
and we communicate,
and we constantly know
what the other one needs.
- If we can do that in there,
then we should be able
to do that all the time.
Come with me to Chicago.
We will get settled, and
we'll find a therapist.
- Maggie, I don't
have a job there.
- But you'll find one.
- Because you're going
to get it for me,
just like you did
here at Grey Sloan?
- I didn't get you a job.
You had to interview
with Richard and Bailey.
- They met with
me because of you.
They didn't come to
Boston and recruit me.
I'm... I'm earning respect here,
and I'm finding my footing here.
- So you're saying...
- I'm saying don't go.
All right? Look, I know
that it has been rough,
and we have both
said some things,
but there's enough good
between us to fight for it.
Stay here with me.
Fight for us.
- Winston, I've been offered
the opportunity of a lifetime.
- OK.
I am steady.
I'm committed.
You know why?
Because I work hard to be
nothing like my father.
Your birth mom is Ellis Grey.
The genius is baked in.
There will be other
opportunities,
but the rest of it is
baked in too, Maggie.
So you have to fight.
You have to work hard
to be nothing like her.
I hope you stay.
- Ah, morning.
- Good morning.
- Morning!
- Well, hello, Dr. Miller.
How is the turtle?
- Very healthy.
- Excellent.
Bailey,
how are you doing?
- Ah... well, my two teenaged
boys and pre-schooler
are in a rental home with
white walls and white carpet.
Kissed that security deposit
goodbye after the first hour.
My phone is no longer ringing
off the hook, at least.
There's that.
- Well, I have asked security
to increase their presence
around the daycare.
- Oh, not necessary.
- Bailey, these people knew
where Tuck goes to school.
The hospital's daycare
is an obvious target.
- Which is why Pru
isn't going back there.
Ready for rounds, baby girl?
- Let's go to work.
- Ah, stat!
- Stat!
Let's do it.
Ooh, ooh. Important.
Very important.
Let's go. Let's go.
- Well, you look rough.
I never said I was a liar.
- I haven't slept in two days.
- Well, at least
you're not babysitting.
I really need to
get out of peds.
You want anything?
- You buying me coffee?
Nope. Not anymore.
Trauma in the pit.
- Amelia, can we just pretend
like I'm not leaving and
that you are not mad at me?
I really need to talk.
- Oh, thank God.
Yeah, I need to
talk, too. You first.
- This morning Winston
basically called me Ellis.
- Was he trying to
start World War III?
- He actually wasn't, which
is what made it hurt more.
He wants me to stay.
- OK, so the Ellis
thing... He called you
a cold-hearted monster,
but he wants you to stay.
- I thought he was
just saying that to put
my ambition and career first,
but yours is way meaner.
Uh.
Kai is you, and I'm Winston,
so I don't know
whose side I'm on.
- Say more.
- Yesterday, Kai announced
that they are moving to London.
That was after they came
here and made me fall
even more in love with
them, just for extra sting.
- I think I might have done
that to Winston last night.
- I don't want
them to go. I...
I want them...
I want them to prioritize
me. I wanna matter.
- You do matter, Amelia.
You matter to me.
You matter to Kai.
Winston feels abandoned.
- I asked him to come
with me to Chicago.
- Well, I can't go to
London. I have Scout.
- Winston did call me cold.
Ellis was cold.
Do you think that's
what he meant?
Do you think that Kai is cold?
- Kai is anything but cold.
Maggie, you are
anything but cold.
Saving lives is a noble pursuit,
but it's also one
that makes you happy,
and that is not a
word I have ever heard
associated with Ellis Grey.
- Do you think you could
give Kai the same support
you just gave me?
- Definitely not.
Go.
Be happy.
- Hey, your shoelace is untied.
Yasuda, are you wearing
two different shoes?
- I have two different feet.
Here we go.
What have we got?
- Lindsay Allyn, 37.
Status post fall in the shower.
Negative LOC.
Hemodynamically stable,
but has left-sided motor
and sensory deficit.
Patient with a known
history of Ehlers-Danlos
and a C1/C2 cervical fusion.
- Well, it happened.
My head finally fell off.
- OK. Let's page
Dr. Shepherd. Let's go.
- How long have you
had the heightened
sensitivity, Ms. Barrett?
- Uh, Tobey. On and
off for a few cycles,
which is why I thought
it was hormonal,
and then I started
getting this, um...
dis... discharge.
- Discharge?
- From my... my nipple.
- Adams, can you grab
me a new penlight?
This one is dead.
- Uh, sure.
- Thank you.
There's nothing like
describing my nipple discharge
in front of a cute
guy.
- So, is it both
sides or just one?
- Just the right side.
- OK.
- Is that normal?
I mean, I just switched
birth control pills
a couple of months ago.
Do you have any idea
how embarrassing it is
to leak all of your
shirt during a deposition
in the county jail?
- Mm.
- The correctional
officer thought
I was smuggling something in.
- Like what?
- Girl, I don't
know. Contraband?
Vodka? Milk?
I don't know.
I am constantly trying
to prove to the partners
that they can count on me.
Being the only woman and
the token Black girl,
I can't have leakage.
- We're gonna get
you checked out.
- Thank you.
- Of course.
Be right back.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
- Dr. Ndugu, you missed
quite the party last night.
I tried to get
Dr. Millin to join,
but she claims
she's not a singer.
- You've been here all night?
- Yeah, I wasn't leaving
this one by herself.
Music helps with healing, or so
someone on the internet says.
- Music must be working
because Nola's labs
and vitals look fantastic.
We'll move her
from the ICU today.
- And where's Dr. Pierce?
- Probably busy with
final paperwork.
She was able to extend her
stay for Nola's surgery,
but her flight leaves tonight.
- Oh, I guess I thought
maybe she'd change her mind
and stay an extra day or two.
- Nola is in excellent hands.
You should be back
on tour in no time.
Hey, there she is.
How are you feeling?
Why does she sound like?
Nola?
- Call a rapid response.
- Nola.
- I'll increase her O2.
- Oh, my God. Nola?
Nola?
- It looks like your fall
caused the metal instrumentation
from your previous spinal
fusion to break off,
and your C1 and C2 vertebrae
are now compressing
your spinal cord.
- Can you just put them back?
The fusion was to
fix something called
atlanto-axial instability from
my connective tissue disorder.
- Well, we'll need more
imaging to see the full extent
of the damage, but the
traction should help
while we come up with a plan.
- Lindsay!
- Sir, you can't just...
- Wait, what hap... I'm
sorry, what happened?
- This is my brother, Carlton.
He asks a lot of questions.
- Hi.
- Yeah, I'm her
primary caretaker.
I'd like to be added
to the HIPAA forms,
wherever those are at.
- We share a duplex.
He's kind of the
Kramer of my life.
- Hey, look at me.
They told me that you
fell in the shower?
I mean, is there something
wrong with the safety handles?
- No, no, no, no,
I just slipped.
- OK, but you're
supposed to sit.
- I know.
- That way you don't slip,
right?
- We need to order
a head CT with total spine.
- Yasuda, CT.
- Copy.
- I'm OK.
- Code blue. Code blue.
- Ah, dammit.
- What is that on her neck?
- She developed a blood
clot around her jugular.
It's preventing the blood
from draining from her head.
We need to reopen the incision.
- No, no, no.
I want Dr. Pierce.
- We need her out of here. Now.
- Page Pierce!
- Get her out. Scalpel.
- Are you gonna
do it right here?
- We have no choice.
All right.
The anastomosis is leaking.
Got it. All right.
Hold it right here, tight.
We have to get her to the OR.
- Oh, Adams. Here, follow me.
Pru, this is Dr. Adams,
and he is going to take you
to get a snack in the
cafeteria... no candy.
- Uh... what? I'm supposed
to just take her with me
as I see patients?
- No, now.
You are going to ask Dr. Smith
to give you something
to do that does not
directly involve patients,
because I'm needed in the OR
for small bowel resection.
- OK, wait, Dr. Bailey,
I don't think I'm
the right person for this job.
- Oh, no.
You are a Shepherd,
which means that you are
one of approximately
1,000 siblings
and nieces and
nephews and cousins
and children of all ages.
And you definitely,
know how to keep
one adorable little girl out of
trouble for a couple of hours.
OK? Go ahead, sweetie. Go.
There. There we go.
- I...
- Yeah. There.
Yeah, let's go get some candy.
- Oh, I didn't know
you were coming today.
- Oh, just some labs.
- Oh, well, I can come with you.
- Richard, we both agreed
that I'd let you know
if there were any major
changes of procedures.
These tests are routine.
How'd it go with Maggie?
- Oh, it hasn't yet.
I hope she didn't already leave.
- Without saying goodbye
to you? She wouldn't.
- Well, our last conversation
didn't go too well.
- She'll come around.
That's what it
means to be family.
- Well, I sure hope
that's how she sees it.
- She will.
How's
everyone this morning?
- When can I have real food?
- Grayson, say
good morning first.
- Morning.
- I'm just going to need
to check your ostomy, OK?
I know the broth is bland, but
I need to see how you tolerate
the clear liquids first.
You guys heading out?
- Yeah, we need to go
get Grayson's cousins
from the airport.
- Tell them to enjoy
the Mariners game.
Get some pizza, too, since
the bar mitzvah is canceled.
- Only until it's rescheduled.
- It won't be the same.
- It's getting harder
for Zayde to travel.
- It's a big trip from Brooklyn,
even for his favorite
great-grandson.
- I'm right here.
I can hear you.
Tatele, you'll do it later.
With or without me,
it will be great.
- OK, let's go.
We'll be back this
afternoon. Promise.
Eat the broth,
and I'll sneak
you a bagel later.
OK.
Come on.
Bye, sweetie.
- Mrs. Friedman, a word?
- Here we go, Luna bear.
- Have a nice day Thank you.
Checking in?
- Um...
- Ma'am?
Can I help you?
- Hey.
- Hey, what are you...
I... I thought that
you had a consult.
- I shuffled things.
I want to be here
with you two. Hm?
Wait, am I late?
- No, we're just...
We're checking in.
- I'll take her.
Come on, Luna.
- Sometimes there are bone spurs
in the cord from the vertebrae
trying to stabilize itself.
With the revision, we
will release the pressure,
and the paralysis should
resolve itself pretty quickly.
- Shouldn't take too long.
Lindsay, just stay still
for us, OK?
- Kind of my only option.
- I thought Ehlers-Danlos
was mostly stretchy skin
and hyperflexibility.
- There are different types,
and it presents
differently in each person.
Oh. Hand me her labs.
- There is soft tissue
edema and stranding,
also, mild atlantoaxial
displacement.
- Damn it. She
has eonsinophilia.
I've seen this before.
Lindsay is allergic to the metal
that they used to
stabilize her spine.
The screws and plate
have to come out.
We're not gonna be able
to do this revision.
- So, what? We just
leave her like this?
Paralyzed?
- You want to throw
a bar mitzvah?
- Yes.
- At the hospital?
- In the chapel?
- And the lobby
for the reception.
Please, Chief, his
great-grandfather is here now,
but he won't be for much longer.
- Who is gonna set all this up?
- Hey, heads up.
The cafeteria has chocolate
peanut butter brownies.
- Oh, most cafeterias are
completely nut-free now.
- Ohh, uhh... Are
you allergic to nuts?
- What do allergic mean?
- Dr. Pierce, can I ask you
a question about a patient?
- I'm not even supposed
to be here today.
- Oh, you're really leaving.
Have you already
turned in your badge?
- What do you got?
- Did a breast
exam on a patient.
I think I felt a lump.
- Tobey Barrett?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, prep for an ultrasound
and a possible biopsy.
I'll be there to supervise you.
- Thank you.
- Ooh, Adams.
- No, ah, ah! No,
no, no, no, no.
No, no. Sorry.
- What do you see, Dr. Miller?
- Nothing.
- Exactly. Neck
exploration's complete.
Now, we can start to
repair the venotomy.
Irrigation.
- I don't understand.
I was watching the surgery.
I mean, I was in the gallery,
but I saw on the monitors
you and Dr. Pierce had
perfect anastomoses.
They weren't too loose,
they were precise,
they were well aligned.
How does this happen?
- Any sudden
increase in pressure,
if Nola held her breath, if
she moved ahead too fast,
if there was any bearing down,
if you create enough pressure
in the body, the weak
parts will just burst open.
Sometimes you can do
everything perfectly,
it still doesn't matter.
- You want me...
- Sew in the patch graft.
Unless you want to go
back to the gallery.
Yeah.
You're gonna wanna
take very small,
evenly spaced, bites.
Don't use too much force.
Good.
- Hey, can we
pretend for a minute
that you are not going to
London and I'm not mad at you?
- No.
What do you need?
- Because you're allergic
to the steel screws, we
can't just replace them,
so we have to remove them,
and then posteriorly,
fuse your C1 and C2
vertebrae together.
- With what?
- We'll 3D print a matrix
of coral and stem cells,
so your body will use it
as a scaffold to fuse the
vertebrae without any metal.
- OK, so, hold on. It's
just one piece of bone.
How is she gonna move?
- She will lose some
mobility in her neck,
but it will stabilize
the vertebrae,
and it will reduce the swelling.
- I don't think that
you should do this.
I don't. It sounds
like science fiction.
I mean, who puts coral
in people's necks?
- Well, technically,
it's calcium carbonate.
It's a precursor
to bone formation.
- Wait till you find
out that the stem cells
come from abdominal fat.
- It is cutting-edge technology,
but one of the most published
neuroscientists in the world
happens to be in this hospital
the very day that your sister
needs this kind of expertise.
- Yeah.
Yeah, well, with all due
respect, cutting edge
just sounds like a
fancy way of saying
experimental and expensive.
- Yeah, well, they're
not asking you, Carlton.
You just don't want me to have
a chance at more independence.
- You couldn't take
a shower without
falling out of your chair.
- I was shaving, OK?
I fell because I
was shaving my legs.
If you must know, I had a
date, and I was getting ready
and I bent over a weird
way to get the right angle
on my knee, and I fell.
You happy?
- You had a date? With who?
- None of your business!
And I don't need you
constantly reminding me
of my disability, OK?
Trust me, I'm aware.
This is my decision,
and I'm getting the surgery.
- Yeah.
- Can you print the coral now?
- These are the saddest
balloons I've ever seen.
We're throwing a bar mitzvah.
It's supposed to
be a celebration.
They should look like they're
about to pop, not drown.
It's going great, Chief.
You're the best.
Oh, Yasuda, help these two.
I've got to figure out if
there's a semi-decent DJ
in this hospital.
- Are we supposed to be
surgeons or camp counselors?
- Ah, says the one-man
Babysitters Club.
Where are you going?
- A woman came in
paralyzed, and Dr. Shepherd
is 3D printing a vertebrae
so we can do an
awesome spinal fusion,
while saving her life
all on the same day.
I'm taking a power nap.
- What about the surgery?
- Dr. Shepherd is
still printing,
and I just need 20 minutes
to complete one REM cycle
while the caffeine kicks in.
- On Call room is the other way.
- What if she has
CMV or encephalitis?
- Well, she hasn't been
vomiting or had a fever.
- But it could be a tumor,
like an acoustic neuroma.
- Then we'll be grateful that
it's benign and resectable.
- Yeah, but it could
be cancerous, right?
Like... like nasopharyngeal
or something.
There are leukemia
patients that sometimes...
- Jo.
I know this is a
little like saying
stop needing oxygen to live,
but let's not panic.
We need to take it
one step at a time.
- Wilson, Luna.
- Yes. Yeah, that's us.
Hey. Come here.
Come here. Ohh.
Will you come with us?
- Yeah, of course.
- OK.
Come on. Come on.
- Do you visualize the needle?
- Yes.
- Good.
Now, study the
ultrasound, as you guide
the tip of the needle
toward the center
of the hypoechoic mass.
- It's bad, isn't it?
You found something
bad, didn't you?
- On appearance, it
looks suspicious,
but we won't know anything for
sure until we get the results
of the biopsy back.
- I just got on this
huge case at my firm.
They might be
arguing in front of
the Washington Supreme Court.
This was not in my plans.
I mean, I thought this was
some weird, little infection,
and I would go home
with an antibiotic.
Can I try an antibiotic
to see if it goes away?
- An antibiotic, unfortunately,
won't work for this.
- How is this happening?
I go to the doctor regularly.
I mean, sometimes
I miss it for work,
but I always reschedule,
and I do the self-exams
in the shower.
It's just all feels lumpy.
How was I supposed to know?
- Tobey, you have
dense breast tissue.
You did everything right.
What Dr. Griffith
found was small,
so it might have been difficult
to feel during your last exam
- I feel like I'm being punished
for working so hard,
for always putting it first.
My mom is gonna say I
should've had kids earlier,
that a career is not gonna
make me smile in 20 years.
- Yes, it will, if
it's the right one.
I don't mean to
contradict your mother.
- Please contradict my mother.
- You loving your job,
that is a beautiful thing.
Don't ever let anyone
make you wrong for that.
It does not make you cold,
it makes you passionate.
And you are not being punished.
Even if this turns
out to be malignant,
you have options.
You have good options.
You are so on top of
everything that you came here
immediately, and that means
there's a chance that we might
have found something early.
Not everyone has that chance.
You're gonna be OK, Tobey.
- We'll be back with the
biopsy results shortly.
Try to relax until then.
- OK.
- Just get those to pathology.
- Yeah.
If it does turn
out to be cancer,
I can't be the one to tell her.
- Yes, you can.
Good doctors connect
with their patients
for all kinds of reasons,
and you see yourself in Tobey,
so she'll trust you.
My mother died of it...
Breast cancer, and we
did not catch it early.
And it was long and painful,
and it took her away from me.
It took her away from
a life that she loved
and that she had waited
too long to claim.
I'm just really
missing her right now.
I hope I'm doing her proud.
- There's no way you're not.
You are one of the best
teachers I've ever had.
I hope I get to
learn from you again.
You know,
a watched 3D
printer never boils.
- Our patient was lucky that
you happen to be in town
when she took a fall.
- She is, isn't she?
- Well, I think our patient
was lucky to have had
a loved one nearby to help.
- I think our patient is just
trying to live their life,
but they can't because
their loved one
is obsessed with being needed.
- So you're saying
our patient is being
oppressed by being loved?
- Should we go over
the surgical plan?
- Uh... fine.
- Yes.
- OK.
- A little higher.
Good. No, no, lower.
Perfect.
How's that' looking, Pru?
Pru?
Ah, damn it. Pru?
Has anybody seen the kid? Pru?
- Well, I guess the gift shop
doesn't have a Judaica section.
- Pru?
- That's not better, is it?
- Where's Yasuda?
She's supposed to
be scrubbing in.
- Oh, I'm not sure,
but if you need an
intern, I'm available.
- Let's go.
- Thank you.
- She's OK.
- She's gotta stop
doing this to me.
- Nola is being moved
back to the ICU.
You can go and sit with her.
- OK.
Thank you for saving her twice.
Thank you.
- I'm glad you're
staying at Grey Sloan.
I'm glad you're not
going to Chicago.
I want to be on your service.
Today was amazing. Your
technique is amazing.
I want to learn from you.
I need to learn
from you. So...
- I'm not being
disloyal to Grey Sloan,
and I'm not going to
apologize for being ambitious.
- Did my husband call
you too ambitious?
- Not exactly, but it felt like
it and not in the good way.
- That man. He's been around
ambitious women his whole life.
He wouldn't have
it any other way.
- You are a trailblazer.
- I am. So was Ellis Grey.
- Yeah, right.
You... you knew her, too.
- Not really.
Our paths would cross at a
conference here or there.
There weren't as many
female surgeons back then,
and a group of us would
arrange our flights
so we could have
a drink together
that last day, but not Ellis.
She was always jetting off
to her next big surgery
or research.
She wasn't going to let a
little thing like friendship
or camaraderie get in the way.
- Coldness is in my genes.
- Not coldness. Focus.
Ellis Grey saved a lot of lives.
Maggie, you are so much more
than Ellis' pure ambition.
You are kindness, caring, honor,
fairness, friendship, love.
I happen to believe that
you carry those traits
in your genes as well.
- Richard.
- Oh, that man loves you
like you're the best
part of him and Ellis.
In all due respect
to your parents,
I don't think a day goes
by when he doesn't wish
that he and Ellis
were both brave enough
to follow their hearts.
If only so, he would
have been a part
of your life so much sooner
- I do wish I had
known him longer.
- Child, you are moving,
you're not dying.
We're going to still
see you.
- I had the terrible
broth, and I'm fine,
Can I please have
something real to eat?
- I think you might want
to wait on the solids.
I got something better for you.
- Why are you holding
my nice shoes?
- I talked to your
parents, and they agreed
that since everybody
is here together,
there's no point in
postponing your bar mitzvah.
So we're throwing it for you
today here at Grey Sloan.
- No.
- What do you mean?
- Are you crazy?
I'm not having my bar
mitzvah at a hospital
like some bubble boy loser.
- That's not what I...
- I said no!
No bar mitzvah.
- No. No, no, no, no.
No. No!
- Suction.
- Are you ready for fusion?
- Why wouldn't I be?
- You're angry, and I just
want to make sure that whatever
it is you're angry about,
it's not going to
affect our patient.
- Do I seem angry, Kwan?
- Is this a trick question?
- Kai is taking a job
and moving to London
to start a new research team.
So we either have to do oceanic
long distance, or break up.
- Well, for what
it's worth, I heard
they've added a bunch of direct
flights from Europe to Sea-Tac.
- Kwan, I don't even know
how you got into this OR.
Just pass me the damn matrix.
- But, um...
it was nothing.
It was a... It was
just a little...
It was nothing.
- Like Dr. Pierce
said, you have options.
Breast cancer is incredibly
treatable these days.
- But I don't... I
don't know where to go.
I don't know what to do. I...
I always know what to do.
- I do.
I know what to do.
- Right.
I'm sorry.
- Take your time.
- ♪ We were born to
last until the end ♪
- You did so good, Luna bear.
Luna, hey, hey, I love you.
- Sorry for the wait,
Mr. And Mrs. Wilson.
- Oh, um...
- Oh, no.
- We're just friends.
- Right.
So we did the BAER
test, which is the...
- Brainstem Auditory
Evoked Response.
- We're both physicians.
I'm an OB.
- Well, then you know
premature babies like
Luna run the risk
of later complications.
We'll have to
continue our studies,
but it does appear that she
has progressive hearing loss.
I'd like to run an OAE.
She can be asleep for that,
if that makes things easier.
That would be my next step.
Any questions?
- I'm not going down there.
I'm not...
- OK, well, so what if a few
of them come up here, then...
Your cousins or your Zayde?
- What?
Talk me into it?
No, that won't work.
I'm supposed to be
eating sushi and cake.
I'm supposed to dance
with Eloise Schurmann.
I have to wear a suit with
pants that cover my butt.
- You can wear pants.
- I wanted to stand
up on the bimah
and show my family and friends
in school how proud I am to be
Jewish, especially my Zayde.
He wasn't able to have a
bar mitzvah in Germany.
He's always saying
how important it is
to be proud of who we are.
I can't do that like this.
- Well, sometimes things don't
happen like you plan them.
Look, part of becoming a man
means learning how
to handle that.
It's like what they
say in the Torah,
you have to leave room for
the magic that only happens
when you let things
look different than how
you imagine them.
- The Torah doesn't say that.
- I'm sure it says
something like that.
What if you did it
together, with Zayde.
This could be his chance to
become a bar mitzvah with you.
- Ah, there he is.
Are you ready to reel
into manhood together?
- You and me.
- Now, tell me, which
one is Eloise Schurmann?
- The one in the pink dress.
- Ohh.
Eat. Eat. You're looking pale.
Now, wheels up.
- God bless you and keep you.
- Mazel tov, everybody!
- Mazel tov!
- Heard Nola is doing well.
I think Viv is going to
be your groupie soon.
- She'll be way too busy
once they're back on tour.
I crushed it in there today.
Crushed it.
I wish you were there to see it.
- You don't have anything
to prove to me, Winston.
I thought about
everything you said.
- You did?
- Ellis stayed with her husband,
and by all accounts, that's
why she became so bitter.
She was ambitious before
that, but never cold.
She stayed.
She made everyone miserable.
My mom did the same thing.
She stayed with my
dad for a long time,
even though she was in
love with someone else.
Both of them, they didn't
follow their hearts.
They didn't follow their guts.
They didn't bet on themselves.
They stayed to keep the peace.
They stayed to keep
other people happy.
My heart is in my work, Winston.
I don't think I'm cold,
and I don't think
you're a coward.
I think that...
I think we did the best we
could and that neither of us
is to blame.
I love you,
but I have to go.
- I love you, too,
but I have to stay.
- She did great.
Her spinal cord was intact, and
the swelling is coming down.
She should regain function
within a few days.
- I know I can be
a pain in the ass.
You know, when I was little,
I would follow her around
everywhere... to the mall,
football games, movies,
and I'm sure it feels
a lot like that to her
now that I live next door.
But when she first
got sick, you know,
I watched this person that
I knew start to fade away,
and I told myself
I would do whatever
it took to bring her back.
- You know, I got
a younger sister,
and she can be a pain in my ass
all the way from Los Angeles.
- I know she needs independence.
I know she wants it.
I just... I guess I wish
I could fix it for her.
- Yeah.
Maybe you should talk to Teddy.
Kai could be a good
fit here at Grey Sloan.
- Oh, nice job with
the decorations.
Glad you got to
practice your dexterity,
while I was repairing
an anastomosis.
- Actually, I got to
assess on a cutting-edge
cervical spinal fusion.
- Because you stole it from me.
- Ya snooze, you
lose. Literally.
- You better sleep with
one eye open, Kwan,
because I'm coming for you.
- Ah, not worried,
because I know you sleep
with two eyes closed.
- Yasuda.
- Dr. Hunt, I am so
sorry about today.
- No excuses. Get
your act together,
or you won't see the inside
of an OR for at least a week.
- Richard. Richard?
I've been looking for you.
- Yeah, me, too. Um...
Listen, your move, it's
caught me off guard.
You have every right
to pursue your career,
and you don't need
me to affirm that.
- I know, but it feels nice.
- This is... this is for you.
It holds business cards.
- Oh! Oh, I thought it was...
- It's a miniature version
of the bench where I learned
that I had a daughter.
My life was forever
changed in that moment.
I hope you remember me
when you look at it.
- Richard, I'm not going to
need a bench to remember you.
- ♪ Good to see you ♪
- ♪ Nice to meet you ♪
♪ Again ♪
♪ Hello ♪
- You double fisting?
- One for me, and
one for my date.
It looks like she
found another guy.
- Well, isn't that just my luck.
- ♪ Ooh ♪
- Wow. This is really great.
- Personally, I
prefer a vanilla cake.
- No. I mean the bar mitzvah.
Grayson is having
the time of his life.
- He's dancing with
the girl he likes.
- You know, I think
you should consider
a peds fellowship, Schmitt.
I mean, you connect with
kids, you listen, you care.
It's rare.
- Hearing aids are, like,
invisible these days.
Look, it's wild.
- Can you... can you just not?
- I'm just saying technology
has come a long way.
There's tons of info out there.
It's not as scary as it seems.
- Yes, it is, Link.
It's extremely scary.
- I'm sorry, just
trying to balance out
the doom clock that
I know is going on
in your head right now.
- Because my child
is going deaf?
I don't... I don't
care if technology
has come a long way.
This girl has been
through enough.
She doesn't deserve to have
to go through this, too.
I just...
I need to wrap my
head around this
before you go all cheerleader.
Thank you for being here.
- You're right.
London is too far
for long distance,
and I spoke to Teddy.
Nothing is definite, but...
- You can't quit
your job for me.
- No, I didn't.
She's expecting some
research funding.
You could move here.
- Amelia, we work because
of the long distance,
because you get to
spend half of your time
with Scout and the
other half with me,
and the two don't overlap.
- So is it about my kid?
- No...
From the minute I told
you about London, which
is the biggest career
opportunity of my life,
you have made it about you.
There were no words
of encouragement,
no congratulations,
no acknowledgment
of how hard I worked for this.
This is about you and me
being at very different
places in our lives.
I love you.
That is still true.
But...
- But.
That's what people say
before they abandon you.
- ♪ But when we grow ♪
- Segments of our DNA strand
can be turned on or off by
our behaviors and environment.
- How did your test go?
- OK.
I'm telling the truth.
I promise.
It's just that
Meredith left and
Maggie is leaving,
and the idea of just losing you,
I just can't fathom it.
- I hope to be with you
for a very, very long time.
But the only thing
I can guarantee
is right now, and right now, I
want to dance with my husband.
- ♪ We hope, we hope ♪
- So why not change the
expression of our DNA
and make it our own?
- ♪ We keep on
moving ooh, ooh ♪
♪ And while the world's
spinning around ♪
♪ We've got both
feet on the ground ♪
♪ We keep on moving ♪
♪ Oh, ooh ♪
- Because who we
are isn't determined
just by what we inherit...
- ♪ Oh ♪
♪ We keep on moving ooh, oh ♪
♪ We keep on moving ♪
♪ Oh, we keep on moving ♪
- But by what we
choose to do with it.
- Fantastic.