- Previously on The Resident...
- You may not realize
this yet, but we're a thing.
Where can I get an
amazing present for Priya?
I'll take that one. This
will definitely work.
You do whatever
the hell I tell you,
no questions asked.
You came in here
ready to save lives,
but today, you
saved a brain stem
- 'cause you didn't listen to me.
- You look well.
- Atlanta suits you.
- Why are you here, Dad?
I'm looking for worthwhile
investment opportunities.
Making you CEO was the
smartest thing we ever did.
I want to introduce you to your
new boss, Marshall Winthrop.
♪ You feel like summertime... ♪
Thank you for busting me
out of that hospital room.
This is what you
need. Fresh air.
No, no, no, don't. I got it.
People will have to take
care of you for a while, Micah.
Relax and get used to it.
Yeah, the invalid
thing? Not my style.
You're ten days
out of major surgery.
Yeah. I get that.
But you know.
What's wrong?
No one wants to talk
about what's ahead for me.
Tell me the truth.
What's the average life
expectancy of someone
after a heart transplant?
You're not average.
You're young and you're strong.
Micah, we almost lost you.
Let's just enjoy this moment.
Right here, right now.
Isn't life beautiful?
You are what's beautiful.
♪ Do love me, do love me, do,
do love me, do love me, do... ♪
Oh!
Priya, we have to
discipline this dog.
Bad doggy.
Bad, naughty little
baby puppy-wuppy.
- That showed him.
- Jellybean has got to be
at the wedding.
No, no, not the wedding.
We were having
such a nice night.
Have you arranged for
someone to teach you Bhangra?
A Bollywood dance
would be so much fun.
You can do it for me, can't you?
All right.
You have to make sure
the fish isn't overcooked.
Three minutes a side.
And then... taste this.
Mmm.
This new night nurse
keeps texting me
about her COPD patient.
It's good, though, right?
I hope so.
Are we talking about
the same thing?
- Chastain.
- Veggie kabob.
Delicious.
Mullins is out of the ICU.
- Hey.
- Give that back.
- Hey, hey.
- Give me my phone.
- Date night, date night.
We are off duty.
Oh, says the guy
who's never off duty.
♪ All I wanna do
is let you shine ♪
♪ Do love me, do love me, do ♪
♪ I love you, do love
me, do love me, do ♪
♪ Do love me, do love me, do ♪
♪ Put no one else above you ♪
♪ Do love me, do love me, do. ♪
Who was she?
Love of my life.
Turned out to be a
psychopathic doctor
who poisoned her own patients.
She's in jail for murder.
You have a nice night.
♪ Mm, mm, mm ♪
♪ Mm, mm, mm, mm ♪
♪ Oh, no, the vertigo's coming ♪
♪ Can't keep me on my feet ♪
♪ God knows I'm
trying to be someone ♪
♪ My vision's failing me ♪
♪ I live like I'm
dying tomorrow ♪
♪ God gave me one last chance ♪
♪ To take all the time
that I've borrowed ♪
♪ And make a new man ♪
♪ Feels like I'm burning out ♪
♪ Wondering why it changed ♪
♪ Bring back this life of mine ♪
♪ 'Cause it left with you ♪
♪ Take it day to day ♪
♪ I'm trying ♪
♪ Trying to block the memories ♪
♪ In my head ♪
♪ They said pain,
it comes in waves ♪
♪ So dive in ♪
♪ They weren't lying ♪
♪ There's no denying it ♪
Uh, you look a lot like her.
- I can make you forget her.
- Don't talk.
Your voice, it's not the same.
You're under
arrest for solicitation.
♪ I knew that it
will come for me ♪
♪ So why try to run? ♪
♪ I knew it will come for me. ♪
♪ ♪
Here you go. Should fit.
Thanks for arranging bail.
I just made CEO. Can
we keep this quiet?
We need a not guilty verdict.
If you're convicted
for solicitation,
the law says you
have to report the arrest
to the state medical board.
♪ ♪
♪ Yeah... ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ You've got to show me love ♪
♪ Heartbreaks and promises ♪
♪ I've had more than my share ♪
♪ I'm tired of giving my love ♪
♪ And getting nowhere... ♪
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Look out!
Hey. You okay?
Help, I...
I-I can't breathe.
Someone call 911.
Teenage male, blunt
abdominal trauma.
Pullman Yard, the meadow.
Roger that.
Medivac Midtown, we have a call.
Call received.
En route to Pullman Yard.
Medivac Midtown just
got a call to Pullman Yard.
See if you can beat
them to the scene.
Copy you. AirMed Atlanta
turning around and
heading to Pullman Yard.
AirMed Atlanta just launched.
They're trying to
poach a call, but we can
- get there first.
- On my way.
You'll be fine.
Where the hell is the ambulance?
What the hell?
Look, there's two of them.
There's three of them.
You're okay. Just hold on.
AirMed Atlanta again?
- What are you doing here? This is our call!
- Pullman Yard is zone three.
- AirMed Atlanta has zone three.
- Oh, you poached
off the police scanner.
- That's the third time...
- Yeah, after you took
one of ours last week.
Okay, we got you, buddy.
You'll be in the ER in no time.
- What's your name?
- Jack.
Jack? All right, where
does it hurt? Right here?
Severe abdominal trauma.
All right, Jack, I
need you to keep still.
We're gonna put a collar on you.
Two weeks ago, Piedmont Park.
- Tell me that wasn't you.
- Okay, that was me,
but that was because
that patient needed help.
Today I got here first!
- Southeast Air Ambulance One...
- Hey, hey, hey. Wait, wait!
We have patient,
inbound to Chastain Park.
All right, it's on, Mina.
Oh, no, no, no.
- Oh, okay, all right. That's the best you got?
- You won.
- Serious question right now.
- Oh, laugh while you still can,
my friend.
Very serious question:
is that all you got?
- Good job.
- Dr. Pravesh. Just the man
we were looking for.
Time to grow up
and be a role model.
First year med students.
- Aw.
- Green as new mown grass.
They get to tour the hospital,
and guess who has the honor
of showing them the ropes?
Oh, no. No, no, no, no, no.
Please, I have, I
have patients to see.
Take them with.
Impart your wisdom.
- Be their Conrad.
- Conrad 2.0.
Uh, no. No. No.
Hi. Aaron Holt.
Hey.
- Justin.
- Okay, okay.
Hi. All right. Uh...
Yes, thank you.
You wanted to see me?
No.
He did.
In my opinion, it's
wholly inappropriate
for a third year resident to
attend a meeting between the CEO
and the chairman of the board.
We're discussing recent
unfortunate events at Chastain.
Residents are on the
frontline of patient care.
I want my son's input.
Conrad, if you had a magic wand,
what would you do first
to improve the hospital?
Easy, weed out
problematic staff.
Starting with a resident
who breaks the rules
whenever he damn well pleases?
Excellence comes
from the top down.
What is your plan
- to balance the budget,
Dr. Bell?
- Increase volume.
Screen patients, cut those
at risk for nonpayment.
Every single one of those
ideas threatens patient safety.
This is a business,
it's not a charity.
No money, no mission.
Okay, you want to go
there? Yeah, let's go there.
- How much does he make?
- A million five.
A million five. Why does
Dr. Bell make a million five
when the average hospital
CEO salary is $600,000?
I'm not average.
The CEO at Atlanta
General makes $3 million.
We both earn every penny.
You have no idea
what this job entails.
All ten floors of this
hospital rest on my back.
There are 30 departments,
45 surgeons, 200 internists,
ten CT scanners that do not
and will never
pay for themselves.
And while you are feeling
the pain and triumph
of helping a relative few,
I will be thinking of ways
to raise or cut a dollar
so that I can keep you working,
nurses attending,
janitors cleaning,
those machines humming,
so Chastain's patients
keep breathing.
Exhibit A.
A medevac
helicopter coming here,
and not Atlanta General.
Why? Because I pushed Chastain
to buy that air transport
company so it brings patients
to our top-of-the-line,
level one trauma center.
Perfect example of
profits over patients.
Air ambulances used
to be run by the county.
Now they're for-profit. You
know how much we charge
for that ten-minute
flight? 40 grand.
You could fly around
the world ten times...
Insurance pays.
It's not our problem.
News flash. Millions
of people are uninsured.
That flight could
equal bankruptcy.
- Would they rather be dead?
- Well, that's the option...
- Your money or your life?
- Gentlemen, enough.
I set up this meeting
to find solutions.
Chastain needs
revenue to make payroll.
It also needs to be a
beacon of excellence.
You both have a point.
You're gonna have to
learn to work together.
How long have you been diabetic?
Since I was ten. Three years.
Because you're a minor,
we have to wait on your mom.
Okay.
Take a seat, and when she
gets here, come back, okay?
14-year-old male,
skating accident,
abdominal trauma, BP 80/40
- and dropping. Pulse is 126.
- All right, Trauma Ten.
- What's his name?
- Jack Alderwood.
- Jack, where's the pain?
- Everywhere.
- Jack! Ja... T-That's our son!
- All right, on a scale...
Sir, we're gonna take
care of him, I promise you.
- We just need some space.
- The doctors
are taking good
care of your son.
On a scale of one
to ten, ten being
- the most severe...
- Ten. Can't breathe.
Okay, here's my credit
card and insurance.
- Let's get you
to registration, okay?
- Right now. One, two, three.
We need another large-bore IV.
Hang one liter normal
saline, get blood ready.
Trauma to the upper abdomen.
He's distended, diffuse pain.
Okay, hang in there,
buddy. You're doing great.
His FAST is positive. Free fluid
everywhere. He's bleeding out.
Hang two units O
neg. Don't worry.
We're gonna take care
of you. He needs an OR.
- Where's Nolan?
- Bowel surgery. Busy for another three hours.
- Who's available from trauma?
- I am.
- You're cardiothoracic.
- Well, actually,
I'm triple board
certified... Cardiothoracic,
general and trauma. I'm also IFR
licensed on a twin engine plane,
and I can scuba
dive up to 150 feet.
Kill me now.
All right, he's out.
Let's get him to OR One.
Let's look in on your very first
patient. And don't be nervous.
There are no wrong answers.
Mr. Warden, these
are medical students
rounding for the
very first time.
I'd like them to
listen to your heart.
Would that be
all right with you?
- Sure. Have at it, Doc.
- All right.
Heart sounds are
notoriously tricky, but they are
a key diagnostic tool.
So, what do you think...?
I can clearly hear a diastolic
rumble with an opening snap,
which is indicative
of mitral stenosis
secondary to
rheumatic heart disease.
Actually, I hear a crescendo
decrescendo systolic ejection
murmur radiating
to the carotids,
with soft S2 and
precordial thrill.
You know, I kind of just
think it sounds like Ken-tucky.
And sometimes, it
kind of sounds like
Tennes-see, Tennes-see,
- Tennes-see.
- What do you think?
Um... I didn't really
hear anything abnormal.
I thought I was in for
gallbladder surgery?
You are. You have a
perfectly normal heart.
Are you sure? I distinctly
heard a diastolic...
Thank you. Let's go.
It's, uh, pretty quiet up here.
Couldn't we go to the ER, OR?
See some trauma, you
know, blood and gore?
It's your first day. Just
do what I tell you to do,
- no questions asked.
- Heads up.
There's a device rep
in the conference room,
luring in doctors to hear her
sales pitch. Free Thai food.
Oh.
Come on in, guys.
- Have some food.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm. You're welcome.
Come on in, Doctor.
I'm Julian Booth,
device rep for Quovadis.
Hi. Uh, Dr. Pravesh.
Um... Devon.
I have some cool
gear to show you.
Let's see what you might need.
You're not a surgeon.
How do you know that?
It's my superpower.
I can guess a doctor's
specialty at a glance,
even before they know it.
Take your medical students.
Born rad. Destined
to spend his life
inside windowless rooms
with imaging machines.
He does look like a submariner.
Mm-hmm.
Okay, what about
that one over there?
Peeds.
No way. My money's on derm.
No, I'm right.
That is impressive.
Good, right? And your shy
one will probably cure cancer.
All right, the one
on the end here.
Annoying gunner... neurosurgeon?
No. He'll get his MD,
skip residency and head
straight to Silicon Valley.
That's what all the gunners do.
They invent devices like these.
Artificial sphincter.
You laugh,
but the urologist
who came up with this
hauled down $40 million.
- You're kidding.
- Medical devices
are even bigger than pharma.
Pacemakers, cardiac caths,
cochlear implants,
artificial knees, skin, hips.
I was a dancer until one
day I was hit by a car.
It shattered my pelvis.
A total hip replacement
gave me my life back
and made me a true believer.
You're interested in ER, right?
Okay, now you're
batting a thousand.
You won't be just
a doctor, though.
You're too smart for that.
All the best ones do
more than one thing.
Maybe you'll
invent one of these.
No. I'm good.
- Thank you.
- You never know.
$40 million.
Jack came through the
splenectomy with flying colors.
- Thank God.
- Oh.
I don't know what we
would do if we lost him.
He's the center of
our world. Jack is
the brightest, kindest...
This boy is the only thing
that pulled us through when...
Amber, Jack's sister, passed
two years ago from a brain tumor.
Am I okay?
- Yes, darling.
- Hey, buddy.
You're gonna be fine.
Isn't he, Dr. Hawkins?
Yeah. Jack, we had to do a
procedure to remove your spleen.
Spleen filters blood, helps
your body fight infections,
so you'll need a regular
schedule of vaccines,
but other than that, you
won't even know it's missing.
Hear that, Mom? It's okay.
She worries.
Why don't you two get some
food while I do a post-op on Jack?
Okay, okay.
And thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
Looks like you have
a touch of jaundice.
Is that serious?
Not necessarily.
Tell me about your
weight. Any changes lately?
You're a thin guy.
I just dropped ten pounds.
I wasn't even
trying, but I like it.
How were you feeling before
the accident? Everything okay?
I have been having some
back pain, but it's no big deal.
Probably pulled a
muscle roller dancing.
Show me where it hurts.
- Ow. Ah.
- I'm sorry to hear
about your sister.
Any other history of
cancer in the family?
My grandfather died young.
I never knew him.
Colon cancer, I think.
And Mom had breast
cancer, but she's okay now.
Have to run a few more
tests before I can let you go.
I'll go write up the orders.
Can I help you?
Hey, call security.
We got a drug seeker.
Hey! Hey!
Okay, every doctor needs
to know how to place an IV.
I want you to
practice on each other.
Good work.
This is child's play.
Did all summer in my
Dad's neurosurgery clinic.
Steady. Steady. Steady.
See, this is why you're
going into radiology.
Steady.
Just watch.
- Feel it. Touch it. There you go, you feel that?
- Uh-huh.
- That's the vein. That's where you want to go.
- The pulsing thing.
- Mm-hmm.
Lower your hand.
Can I get a new partner?
He-he can't find the vein.
Maybe I can help.
Here.
Try this.
It uses infrared
to find the vein.
- Here you go.
- Oh.
- There you go, that's
it right there. See it?
That right there?
Yeah.
Got it.
I did it.
T-This device rocks.
- Whoa!
- Oh!
You have to remove
the tourniquet first
before you withdraw the needle.
Apply pressure
to slow the bleed.
All right.
There you go.
Everything is gonna
be perfectly fine now.
Whoa! Whoa, whoa,
whoa. Whoa, whoa.
- You all right? Okay.
- Mm-hmm.
Amazing catch, Conrad.
Don't tell me I guessed right.
You ordered a CT with a
pancreas protocol on a 14-year-old.
How in the world did you know?
Uh, the family
history was a red flag.
It was a long shot,
but I had to check.
Jack has pancreatic cancer.
I know you may not
feel lucky right now,
but you are.
The accident brought
you into the hospital,
and Dr. Hawkins caught it early.
Am I gonna die?
There is every reason to
believe that surgery will be
a total cure.
If we get him to
Houston tonight,
will MD Anderson
have a room for him?
Okay, please let me
know as soon as possible.
- Thank you.
- Mr. Alderwood.
Randolph Bell, Chief of
Surgery, CEO here at Chastain.
I'm so sorry to hear
about your son's diagnosis.
Now, you should know
that Chastain's cancer wing
- is state of the art...
- No, no. MD Anderson
is a top five cancer center.
Only the best for Jack.
We need to get him
there as soon as possible.
I understand. You know,
we do have a connection
to a helicopter company
that can handle the
transfer to the airport.
They're not cheap.
You might want to check
- with your insurance first.
- No, money is no object.
Well, I'm glad we could help.
The next step is
to stage the cancer,
check for metastasis, make
sure Jack's lymph nodes are clear.
Okay?
Thank you.
Baby...
You're gonna be okay, okay?
♪ ♪
- What's up?
- There's a young girl
running around the
hospital. About 12 or 13.
I caught her stealing
from the drug cart.
I think she's in withdrawal.
She's blonde, pale.
- I'll check Five East.
- Thanks.
Hey.
Check me out.
I got it, I got it.
No, Micah, don't!
No, I'm fine,
I'm fine, I'm fine.
I just twisted it a little bit.
- That's all.
- There's someone in here!
- Mina, hurry!
- Go.
Go. I'm fine.
I see legs.
Okay. Careful, careful.
Oh, my gosh.
She's alive. Let's
clear her from the door.
- Call a rapid response team.
- Yeah.
Nic!
She's in here. She's diabetic.
Oh, my God.
She was looking for insulin.
- Is she in DKA?
- Probably.
She tried injecting herself,
but she was too late.
All right, let's get her out
of here and find a vein.
If we don't get access,
she's gonna code.
Hey. Just got the call.
What do you need?
She's dry.
- Want me to do a central line?
- Yes, but not here. Not sterile.
- Let's get her a room.
- I discharged 5027
earlier this morning.
Should be clean now.
Okay, go to the
crash cart at the end
of the hall. Get
me a central line kit.
And ask a nurse to help you. Go.
- Okay. One, two, three.
- Three.
No, no, no. Here, here,
here. Just take that.
Got it.
- But he said get a nurse.
- I got it.
Pulse is tachy at 130.
Here.
This is a Foley catheter kit.
This is for urine. I
told you to ask a nurse.
No kit, no choice.
We have to do an EJ.
All right. I'm gonna crank the
bed down so she's headfirst.
Prepping for an IO in
case you can't get access.
Prepping for an EJ.
Swab, please.
We're in.
All right, let's hang
fluids. Two liters to start.
- Wait. Let me get
the blood first.
- Okay.
Glucose, 583.
Bicarb, undetectable.
PH, 6.8. She's DKA.
A little longer in a coma,
- she would have died.
- Let's get her to the ICU.
She still might.
You're Dr. AJ Austin. I'd
recognize you anywhere.
I'm sure you have a job to do,
but salespeople should not be
roaming the halls of Chastain.
The AJ Austin who did an
ascending aortic reconstruction
with a coronary
artery reimplantation
in two hours, skin to skin.
I might be that guy.
Okay, I am that guy,
but I'm still not buying.
No agenda, I swear.
I'm just a fangirl.
Dr. Benedict at Atlanta
General told me all about you.
Said you were the best
student he ever had.
You know Abe?
Quovadis has a fantastic,
new left atrial appendage
occlusion device.
Dr. Benedict has been
putting it in for the past year.
I can show it to you
if you're interested.
All right. You got
about five minutes.
- Lead the way.
- Great.
I have your lawyer,
Mr. McCrary, line two.
All right. This
is a private call.
There's no need to take notes.
Yeah?
Turns out your
hooker cop was wired.
We aren't gonna get
a not guilty verdict.
The arraignment's first
thing in the morning.
We'll try to plea bargain.
Look reasonable and contrite.
Judges want to see a defendant
who knows he's made a mistake
and won't make another.
Micah?
Are you okay? I...
I'm sorry I had to
leave you like that.
I'm fine.
I don't want to
be a distraction.
You're a doctor.
I understand you have
important things to do.
You are important.
This isn't working.
I see what's going on.
So do you.
We may be a thing, but
we're a brand-new thing.
And this is not what
you signed up for.
I can't be a burden.
Dr. Okafor,
please report to OR One.
Dr. Okafor, please
report to OR One.
I must go now.
But I am not agreeing with you.
No big decisions until
we make one together.
Conrad. Jack's lymph
nodes look clear.
The cancer is most likely
localized to the pancreas.
- Okay, that's good news.
- But the trauma.
The accident, it looks
like it started a bleed
on the tumor itself. Right here.
It was too small
to pick up before,
but there it is.
Stop!
He can't fly.
The helicopter's waiting.
His tumor is bleeding
into his abdomen.
He needs to have
the surgery now.
You put him on that helicopter,
he dies before he
gets to Houston.
Okay, patient's name
is Jack Alderwood.
Confirmed.
Procedure is partial
pancreatectomy.
Surgeon is Dr. Albert Nolan.
- Consent form signed?
- Signed and in the chart.
All right.
Partial pancreatectomy.
Isn't that right up your alley?
I've done over 500
of these in my career.
More than anyone
else in Atlanta.
Maybe more than
anyone in the country.
Yeah, well, CEO is
an important job, too.
At least, I think it is.
It is.
I still miss the OR.
Just keep me updated
on how this goes.
I'm here if they need me.
Yeah, you got it, boss.
Where are your med students?
I sent them home.
I'm done babysitting.
Thank you, Carol.
That's too bad, Conrad. Oops.
- I mean, Devon.
- I'm not Conrad.
And they're sure not me.
That gunner nearly killed Abby.
Didn't your first patient
end up brain-dead?
The kid who screwed
up is still here.
He's in the ICU watching
them work on Abby.
Thought you should know.
Hang in there, sweetie.
O2 sats dropping.
She's in respiratory failure.
Uh, we need to intubate.
Get the kit.
They're putting her on a
vent. She may never recover.
We all make mistakes.
I've made plenty.
What matters is that
you learn from them.
Poor thing. We got
her name, Abby Arlen,
but we still can't
find her parents.
- I'll go find them.
- Good. Go.
Okay.
Pancreas is fully exposed.
Prepare a specimen cup
for tissue sample.
They're doing a
resection of the pancreas,
which is a bitch.
The organ is like Jell-O.
Soft, warm Jell-O.
You cut it wrong, the
whole thing falls apart.
You got to cut out that
tumor, leave yourself margins,
keep the tumor cold
when you walk it...
Speed walk it,
double-time... To pathology...
where the pathologist
runs a stain,
puts the specimen
under a microscope,
and looks for those nasty
little cancerous mites.
But you got to do it fast;
time is of the essence.
Our boy is still on the table.
Uh, margins not clear.
Pathologist says to keep going.
It means they didn't
get all the cancer.
They have to take another
slice of the pancreas,
and start the whole
process all over again.
Margins still not clear.
What's going on?
There's hardly
any pancreas left.
They'll have to
remove the entire organ.
Worse still. They
have to resect parts
of the gallbladder, the small
intestine and the bile duct.
It's a Whipple procedure.
Even I've only done a
handful of Whipples in my life.
Dr. Nolan cannot handle this.
You know who
has to do this, right?
Oh, the prince walks into my
office without even knocking.
Let's not make this
harder than it needs to be.
I'll make it as hard as I want
to every single time we meet.
I don't care who your father is.
We have an emergency in
OR One. The Alderwood boy.
Pancreatic margins keep
coming back cancerous.
He needs a Whipple procedure.
Back in the day,
you were the unsurpassed master
of the Whipple, but we both know
an appendectomy
patient died in your OR.
Your complication rates
are through the roof.
Can you do this
procedure safely?
I can do it flawlessly,
and it's not your call.
Right angle, Cooley
scissors to me.
Team HODAD.
The surgery was more
radical than we'd hoped, but...
it went off beautifully.
Thank you, Dr. Bell. And
thank you, too, Dr. Hawkins.
Ah. The most important thing
is that Jack is
likely cancer-free.
And I'll roller
dance again, right?
Absolutely.
Jack, unfortunately,
due to the nature
of your surgery,
you will be a diabetic for
the rest of your life, but...
Maybe not the rest of your life.
Scientists are working on
growing organs in the lab.
Some day, we may
get you a new pancreas.
Okay, and who are you?
Ms. Booth works
for Quovadis Labs.
It's a cutting-edge
medical device company.
I'd like to show you
our new insulin pump.
The drug is delivered
continuously over 24 hours,
and that keeps your blood
glucose levels in range,
even overnight.
How much is it?
Around ten grand.
We'll take it.
Great.
Is that our new
uninsured patient?
I hear she could end up
costing Chastain a fortune.
That's one way to look at it.
Or you could see
a 13-year-old girl,
who's fighting for her life.
Her name is Abby.
According to her mom,
she loves astronomy and Beyoncé.
She's a straight A student,
and got diabetes
when she was ten.
Her mom works two jobs
but still can't
afford the medicine.
It's over $2,000 a month.
So Abby didn't want
her mom to know
that she needed more insulin.
Started rationing her
doses and ended up here.
She gonna make it?
Maybe.
Is there any way this
could have been prevented?
Technically, the
hospital's a non-profit.
In order to keep our
tax-exempt status,
we're supposed to have programs
that benefit the community.
- What are we doing now?
- Nothing.
Not true. We have
health fairs and flu clinics.
- All kinds of...
- Window dressing.
The price of insulin has gone
from $21 a vial to $275,
and the drug hasn't
changed one bit.
That's a 1,200% increase,
and it's destroying
people's lives.
Mina and I have an idea.
Let's hear it.
What about an outpatient
clinic for the uninsured,
with community outreach.
I used to volunteer for one run
by Partners in Health in Boston.
We'd love to start
something like that here.
It could have helped Abby;
we missed that chance.
We can't miss
chances like that again.
With what funding?
How much would this cost,
and how much would it save?
I need to see data before
making a commitment.
Is that a polite
way of saying no?
I told you we need balance.
Patient safety and
financial stability.
So get us numbers,
we'll have a look at it,
maybe bring it up at
the next board meeting.
Okay.
I can't say that was a win.
It wasn't a no, either. Your
father left us an opening.
Yeah, I'll start putting
together the numbers.
Okay. Hey.
Hey.
Maybe it's a good
thing that he's here.
Maybe things will be different.
I'm still giving you an out.
And I'm not taking it.
You'll go to rehab,
and you'll get better.
No big decision until then.
You sure you
want to wait for me?
♪ ♪
You told me the judge would
show mercy for a first offense.
Luck of the draw.
We caught a hard-ass.
And this will be reported
to the state medical board?
Not exactly.
By law, you now
have to self-report
your conviction
for solicitation.
Here are the forms.
You're the one who must report
this to the state medical board.
You mean, if I
don't file the forms,
they'll never know
I was arrested?
The only way
anyone would find out
is if they went to
the police department
and requested a copy
of your criminal record.
Who is ever gonna think of that?
I'm a doctor.
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH