Surgeons don't compromise.
Derek Shepherd.
Multiple hand fractures
with a median nerve injury.
Arizona Robbins,
open femur fracture
with resultant
above-knee amputation.
Lexie Grey, deceased.
Mark Sloan, deceased.
This doesn't include extreme...
We defy death. We
exceed perfection.
We operate for 17 hours
straight if we have to.
Wish for me to extend
their deepest condolences.
How is... How is the
investigation going?
Have they found
what caused the crash?
The investigation could take
years. That's why we want to help you
put this tragedy behind you.
I think you mean, your clients
would like to put it behind them.
So I am authorized at this time
to propose a
one-time settlement.
Bayview Aeronautics
takes your loss seriously.
Now the settlement
agreement must be unanimous,
and it releases
Bayview Aeronautics
from any and all other claims,
known or unknown, but...
Most important,
it will allow you
to put this painful
time behind you
and move on with your lives.
We aren't built to settle.
But that doesn't mean we won't.
Wow. OWEN: Yeah.
That's a lot of money. Mmm-hmm.
And they need an
answer in three days.
Oh. Uh...
Okay.
How you been? Okay.
You?
I'm fine.
Good.
So...
You'll call me when you decide?
Yeah.
Should we settle?
Should we not settle?
I don't know.
We should go to sleep.
Do you want to keep
the lights on or off tonight?
On, please.
Do you know what this
money could mean for us,
for Sofia?
I mean, she won't have to
take out loans for med school.
We'd be taken care of.
You and me and Sofia.
I think that's what
Mark would want.
You know what I want?
More than anything?
I want to know
what you're thinking,
what you want.
Just...
Okay, well, the home health
care nurse will be here soon.
Try to be nice.
Don't throw things
at this one, okay?
Just...
Let her help you.
Okay. I'll see you tonight.
Hey, Alex.
Why did an intern just
give me a compliment
on the crown moldings
in my empty house?
Are you still sleeping there?
Chicks like it better
than the on-call room.
Okay, that's disgusting.
Now I have to have the place
tented. Give me back my key.
You don't even
live there anymore.
What do you care? Key. Please.
Hey, you guys.
Can you believe we're
in the attendings' lounge?
April, what are you doing here?
Oh, uh, Hunt came and
got me on the farm in Moline.
I was giving the pigs their
breakfast, and I turn around,
and there's Dr. Hunt,
offering me my job back.
He didn't tell you guys?
Did anyone else see
Dr. Hunt in the barnyard?
When he appeared unto
you, was he glowing at all?
April?
Hunt hired her back.
We think. It might
have been Jesus.
I thought you went to Tulane.
Yeah. No, I changed my mind.
Hey, you people are attendings.
You do not change
clothes in front of everyone
like animals or interns,
because nobody
wants to see all that.
Apparently Kepner does.
What?
No, I don't. I wasn't...
Gotta go. Me too. Welcome back.
Glad you're back.
I am back...
Too.
I'm also glad
to be back.
Okay.
Morning, Dr. Bailey.
I cannot get used to having
them in the attendings' lounge.
Well, I'm still getting
used to having you in here.
Dr. Yang. Famous and infamous.
Come on in and take a load off.
You took a break.
I did.
Some R&R. Yes.
Feels good,
doesn't it? Fantastic.
What'd you see? I went
to the Mall of America.
I rode the roller coaster.
I purchased jeggings. I'm
ready to get back to work.
You went on the Internet and
searched "Mall of America."
I am gonna be a team player. I
mean it. I heard what you said, sir.
Then put on some
scrubs, young lady.
Thank you.
I saw you have a
laser revascularization...
You'll be working with
Dr. Thomas for now.
I'll believe team player
when I see it, Dr. Yang.
I got your text. What do we got?
16-year-old kid, fished her out
of the sound, sailing accident.
You mind? Sorry.
Why are you following me?
I'm your intern for the day.
Well, hello, intern.
You have a name?
Jo Wilson.
Nice. I like chicks
with boys' names.
Karev.
What? I do. It's hot.
Stop sleeping with your
coworkers. It ruins them.
I slept with you.
And now I no longer
sleep with men.
Roxie Meyers, 30,
here for excess skin removal
after a 100-pound weight loss
two years ago.
117 pounds.
Frank.
I can't help it if
I'm proud of you.
And we've set up a consult
from general for
the hernia repair?
I did, yeah.
Hey, I'm it.
I am... I'm your consult.
Okay. Hi.
Dr. Kepner is going
to repair your hernia.
Hi.
So I'll just need to go
over some incision points.
Honey, could you...
They want me to
take off my robe.
Roxie, this is a big operation.
I want to know everything
that's gonna happen to you.
Frank, please.
This is my fiancee,
love of my life.
You guys do a good job, okay?
Of course.
I'll be right outside, babe.
Okay.
All right.
Now I'm gonna start
with some incisions here.
And here. The man's a saint.
We've been together two
years and we still haven't...
You know, had sex.
I mean, when we cuddle,
when he squeezes me here,
it makes me cringe.
I just want to feel pretty.
You're already pretty.
You sound like Frank.
Do you have any questions
for me before the surgery?
Just one. When? I'm sorry?
I think she wants to know
when she and Frank...
When can I jump his bones?
Your incisions will be
healed in about two weeks.
So after that, you and Frank
can be as physical as you like.
Two weeks? Okay.
Wow. I just got butterflies.
Okay, Emery, we're gonna
need to take a look at your leg.
You and you, start
cutting off the splint
so we can see what we've got.
- I can't feel my foot.
Can you tell us what happened?
Yeah, this massive wave came
up and the mast crushed my leg,
and then... And then
Pickle just rolled over.
Pickle? My boat.
God, I can't believe I lost her.
Why can't I feel my foot?
Okay, who else was
on the boat with you?
No one. I'm doing a solo
sail from Mexico to Alaska.
Oh, my God. Doppler. Doppler.
Is that...
Her tibia and fibula, I think.
What's wrong? Everything's fine.
Just try to stay calm, okay? Do
you know where your parents are?
I sailed here from
Mexico by myself.
I don't need you to
wait for my parents.
Tell me what's happening.
I'm not getting a pulse.
Okay, Emery, I am so sorry,
but we might not be able
to save your foot, okay?
No! Your injury's very severe.
It's mangled and
there's no blood flow.
Give her five of morphine!
Oh, my God. Oh,
my God. Oh, my God.
She moved her toes
with a nearly severed foot,
so the tibial nerve's
probably still intact, right?
So, Dr. Torres, you think
you can actually save the foot?
Well, when we get in there
and do some nerve testing,
we'll be able to assess
the damage better.
I spoke to her parents.
Their flight gets in late tonight.
Great. Do you want to scrub in?
Hell, yeah.
All right.
This might take a while.
I need you to stay back
and monitor my pre-
and post-ops. But...
I had hoped since I was the
one that saw the toes move,
I'd hoped that I...
But you need me to monitor
your pre- and post-ops.
Got it. Great.
You could've let her scrub in
or stand in the
back and observe.
Why? Because she has joy.
I like joy, excitement,
happiness,
people looking at
me like I know things.
She practically squealed
when I mentioned nerve testing.
There needs to
be more squealing.
I can squeal if you want me to.
That sounds dirty
and inappropriate.
Which I hear is your
specialty these days.
I brought a Tater Tot hot dish.
You didn't!
Rina also brought
Tater Tot hot dish.
It's Pop Pop's favorite.
I know it is, love.
That's why I brought it.
Okay, you know Pop
Pop has an enlarged heart.
So he can't be having
a Tater Tot hot dish.
Not even a bite?
It's his last meal.
No, you get a last
meal before they kill you.
We're not planning
on doing that.
Dr. Yang.
Hi, Dr. Thomas.
Never show up in Mr. Patel's
room during visiting hours.
Now you tell me.
Are you still planning on doing
the ventricular
reduction surgery?
Yes, I spoke to him
about it this morning.
Wouldn't an LVAD be in order?
An LVAD is a Band-Aid.
Ventricular
reduction is a repair.
You'll be hacking off
working heart muscle.
So that what's left can
work more efficiently.
This is an extremely high-risk
procedure when there's a simple fix.
People die from this surgery.
Not when I do it, they don't.
How does such a tiny
human make such a big mess?
Should we settle?
It's a lot of money.
We could stop work,
travel for a while,
show Zola the world.
Zola wants to see the park
and the pond and the
turtle that lives in the pond.
Okay, so we don't settle.
Not settling means
what, years of litigation
and thousands of dollars
looking for answers?
And it's not gonna
bring Mark or Lexie back.
Traveling the
world sounds better.
Yeah, it does.
Hey. What?
So you realize,
Zola's sleeping...
And all we're doing is talking?
You're right.
I can do that... Something
about that right now.
Let me get that
little... What is this?
Ow! Ow!
There's a block
under my... Okay.
Shh! Don't wake
her up. Be quiet.
Okay. Shh.
Hey.
Uh, we...
We should agree
on the positioning
for the incisions
for our surgery,
so that I can have good
visibility for the hernia.
Yeah. Um...
I'm gonna go in
here and then here.
Great. Good. Okay.
That looks good. Good.
So you staying here or a
hotel? What's going on?
Uh, yes.
Here until I find a place.
Yeah.
I didn't call you, April,
because I didn't...
I'm revirginizing.
It's... It's a thing,
revirginizing.
It involves a lot of prayer,
which I had time to do in Moline,
staring at the 'N SYNC
posters on my wall,
which kind of makes me think
of Jesus as Justin Timberlake,
but my pastor says
that's totally fine,
you know, as long as
I'm still talking to him,
keeping the lines of
communication open.
Okay, April, you...
It's my second chance, Jackson.
And I didn't think I'd get one,
but then Dr. Hunt showed up in
Moline and offered me my job back,
and that was my sign
that I get to recommit
myself to God.
I can accept his forgiveness
and... And have a second chance.
A do-over, you know,
without all the mistakes,
just slate wiped clean.
I am... Revirginizing.
Yes.
Which is really
your way of saying
that you want to pretend
that you and I never happened.
No, that is not...
It's... It's... It's
not that simple.
Okay. That'll do it.
Thank you, Doctor.
Dr. Yang.
How is the great surgeon
from Seattle on this fine day?
Great.
You can't fool me.
I am a reader of faces,
and your face tells me...
This is one of the finest
cardiothoracic centers in the country.
I came here to do innovative,
cutting-edge surgeries with you,
not ventricular reductions with
Thomas is what my face tells you.
Look, everybody
has to take a shift.
Babysit the old man.
Put your time in, and I'll see
to it that you join me in the OR
very soon.
On something good?
Well, I'm consulting on
a guy with mitral regurg.
Are you doing a
mitral annuloplasty?
Probably.
And I'll relocate the tip of
the posterior papillary muscle.
Are you serious?
As a heart attack.
Cardio humor. Oh, yes, sir.
I am laughing,
just not externally.
Let me see a smile then.
No, let me see
the great Dr. Yang
turn her frown upside down.
Better.
I hope you won't be
offended if I tell you
that you have a very nice smile.
Look at this!
Kepner is doing
an umbilical hernia
her first week back.
Uh-huh.
She failed her boards.
She was fired, twice.
The closest that girl has
been to an OR in months
is what, the Moline
large animal vet?
Her head is not in the game.
She has other things on her mind,
things I don't even
want to think about.
So... What, you're gonna
pull her off the surgery,
do it yourself?
Don't be ridiculous.
I'm getting her a babysitter.
Hey, Cristina. April's back.
Yeah, I heard.
Owen went to a pig farm?
So you're talking to Owen?
Yeah, about the settlement.
Hey, what's up, Yang?
I'm about to be
accomplice to a murder.
I always knew you'd
find your specialty.
What are you...
Actually, I know,
let's pretend this
never happened.
What...
What?
Show me. Show me.
Dr. Bailey, all respect,
but I can handle a
hernia repair on my own.
Well, you've been
working with pigs.
Maybe she's worried you'll
slaughter someone out of habit.
So have you thought
about the settlement?
What do you want to do?
I don't know.
Whatever everybody
else wants to do.
I'm a team player, Mer.
Apparently, so am I.
We were able to restore blood
flow to your daughter's foot.
So it looks like we're
gonna be able to save it.
It'll be a long, hard
process, but she's tough.
She sure is. You have no idea.
Mom, look.
That's a beautiful boat, but...
Yeah, they want to donate it
'cause they heard
about the accident.
I think we need to wait and
hear what Dr. Torres has to say.
No, if I get back out there
within the next two weeks,
I can still make it before
the weather gets really bad.
Or I could just
amputate your foot,
and you could be up
and out of here in a week.
Or I could get you
close to full function back,
but it means a series of pretty
big operations over a few months,
and you have to stay
off the foot completely.
Fine. Let's do it.
Actually, you guys
have to give consent.
Well, is...
Just say you consent.
Yeah.
I bought you a coffee.
Wow. Thanks.
You have a nice smile.
Thanks.
And, uh...
Just beautiful...
Eyes.
You know, if you want to drab...
Grab a drink later or...
Okay. I know this
Mexican place...
Okay, okay, okay,
you're flirting with me,
which is really sweet
or would be really sweet
if you were into ladies,
but I'm guessing that
you're not a lady lover,
'cause you also look
terrified that I might say yes.
You're poking a bear,
a very horny bear.
And what would you
do if the bear said yes?
And there you'd be,
trading sexual favors for...
I don't know what it is
you want from me, so...
You're gonna have to tell me.
I was wondering if
it would be possible
to scrub in on
your next surgery.
Okay, A, never trade sex
for scrubbing in because
that's just skanky.
Save it for actually
getting to cut.
And, B, you're giving
coffee to the wrong person.
Alex, your intern
brought you coffee.
Cool.
I was wondering if
it would be possible
to scrub in on
your next surgery.
That's not gonna happen.
But, hey, grab me another
coffee. That was great.
Go.
Shoot. This defect's too big.
I'm gonna need
some mesh. Suction.
Here's an idea.
Let's just pretend
that the patient never
even had a hernia,
then you wouldn't
have to do anything.
Would you stop? This
is not a joke to me.
No, you said you're
pretending that...
What are we talking about?
If you would just listen.
I'm not pretending
it never happened.
What never
happened? It happened.
I know it happened. Could
someone just please...
But now I am wiping
the slate clean.
By acting like it
never happened. No!
- What never happened?
- Nothing!
I...
Oh...
My...
God.
Hey. Derek.
You... You doing a consult?
No, actually, I have
a question for you.
Do you remember
the Donna Drake case?
About six years ago,
mother of twin girls.
Remember it? I can't ever
forget it. I won't ever forget it.
How much did the hospital
end up settling with the family?
Ooh. Wow. It was a lot.
I can check the exact amount,
but it was definitely
the largest settlement
that I can remember.
Because it was our
fault that she died.
It's pretty standard.
The bigger the mistake,
the bigger the payout.
They offering you a
pretty big settlement?
Yeah.
Yeah, they are.
So you'll meet with
everyone else tomorrow,
see what they want to
do, and that's that, I guess.
I mean...
I guess I want to go with
what everyone else decides.
Okay.
Oh, there is this woman
with, like, the most
nasal voice you've
ever heard of.
She does the code calls
here. They're unintelligible.
I mean, everyone
understands 'em, but to me,
it's like a foreign
language. That's funny.
Yeah. You got...
You gotta hear it.
Sure.
You know what? Just
wait. It'll happen any second.
Okay.
She was a virgin.
I know that.
You defiled a virgin.
Stop hitting my head. I...
I will go full crazy
on you. All right?
I am a grown ass man.
She's a grown woman.
Yeah, but she's...
She's what, April Kepner?
Believe me, she is grown.
I didn't manipulate her.
I didn't defile her or trick
her. I didn't take her virginity.
She... She gave it to me.
All right? This isn't about
something I did to her.
This is something we did
together, and she can't handle that.
So she is praying...
To Justin Timberlake,
apparently.
And I'm pissed.
And... It's a mess.
So just stop hitting my head.
So Alex is a diseased
man-whore again,
and April Kepner
is no longer a virgin.
Wow! I missed a lot
with that plane crash.
Yeah, you missed a whole lot.
The chief banged my mom.
What? The...
Owen banged...
Webber. Webber.
Dr. Webber banged my mom.
Oh.
Oh!
Oh, my God. Yeah, I know.
Well... If it makes you feel any
better, he banged my mom, too.
That makes me feel worse.
Just let her come down
here for a little while.
Did you check the
I's and O's on 31-50?
I did this morning.
She doesn't stop
crapping and peeing
just because you
want to watch a surgery.
Go and check them again.
What is your problem?
My problem is,
I have 40 patients
on my service.
The new PEDs
attending is an idiot,
and I need help.
So until your wife comes
back to the hospital,
I need my interns
to actually work.
My wife is disabled.
My daughter's father is dead.
There's nothing we
can do about that,
but this money will
pay for Arizona's rehab.
It would take care
of our little girl,
Mark's little girl.
This is a huge amount of money.
It's a life-changing
amount of money.
All right, so you're
saying we take it.
I'm just saying,
you don't walk away from
a number like this, right?
Well, I'm still
talking to Cristina,
but I think she'd
want to take it, yeah.
Mer?
Yeah. I mean, I guess, yeah.
Derek, what do you think?
It has to be unanimous.
What do you say?
I say, we have until tomorrow.
I googled you.
I know how to do it
even though I'm old.
I know what googling is.
I googled you, and it said
that you were in a plane crash.
Am I talking to myself?
I would rather talk
about the medicine.
Okay. Notice how I close
without using felt pledgets.
You impressed? I know you are.
You're just too
prideful to admit it,
but that's okay. It comes
together impeccably.
I didn't think that
was possible.
I mean, I've tried to
suture myocardium before
without synthetic patches
and couldn't get it to hold.
Yes, well, the trick is
to use a double layer of
zero vicryl. It's my signature.
I'm the only one in the
country who can do it
because I've devoted
my life to doing it.
I don't go home to
family and chitchat.
I go to bed thinking
about this technique.
So... What is your
signature move?
Oh, I don't...
Life is short, you know?
You've seen that yourself.
So you better get at it.
There it is.
Now if you had put
in your beloved LVAD,
he would've died waiting
for a heart transplant,
which would never happen.
This way, Bo Bo
has a chance at life.
Pop Pop.
What? Speak up.
Uh... Nothing, sir.
The settlement meeting
is at 8:00 tomorrow night.
Are you gonna go?
Mmm.
You're going,
so I don't have to.
See how that works?
I'm going to speak for Mark,
who can't speak for himself.
See how that works?
You should be at that meeting.
You should speak for
yourself. I wasn't there.
I... It's not a decision I
should be making for you.
You weren't shy about
making other decisions for me.
What's different now?
I mean, I think
you're on a roll.
I can't do this.
Say it, 'cause it was perfect.
"It's not a decision that I
should be making for you."
Say it. Stop.
Say it again.
"It's not a decision that I
should be making for you!
"As opposed to
hacking off a limb.
"That's the kind of decision
I should make for you."
Fine. Don't go. I will
make all the decisions.
Just so you know,
I'm gonna vote to take
the settlement for Sofia,
because Mark would
want her to have the money.
I think Mark would want you
to pick up your daughter
when she's crying.
I guess he's gonna have
to deal with disappointment,
just like the rest of us.
Mer, we chopped up this
heart, and it was amazing.
I mean, you should see how
this guy handles myocardium.
Are you sleeping with him?
What? No. He's like 100.
You know who did sleep
together? April and Jackson.
No way. Kepner did it?
She did it. Finally.
Except she's not doing it again.
What do you mean?
Clean slate.
She's revirginizing.
Oh, please.
No, she's there, he's there.
All she has to do
is hear his voice,
and she's not gonna
be able to think straight.
All right, now keep in mind,
there's still a lot of
swelling and bruising.
It's okay, Roxie.
It's more than okay. It's...
There's nothing to squeeze.
Hey, Rox, the cafeteria
was out of lemonade,
so I got you... Oh!
Oh! Sorry.
Hi.
Hey.
I'm sorry. I gotta
go. Excuse me.
Dr. Karev, I've rounded
on your pre-ops,
your post-ops,
I've run your labs,
and I'm updating
your charts right now.
What about my consult on the
JRA kid? You schedule that yet?
No, I haven't had a chance to...
You kidding me? Stop
with the charting. Do it now.
Or don't.
No, I'm... I'm
sorry. I'll schedule it.
God, I can't believe I'm
crying in front of my boss.
I told myself that
I wouldn't do this.
Look, I'm not supposed
to be this person.
I don't fail.
I was valedictorian
of my high school,
graduated cum
laude from Princeton,
I was first in my
class at Harvard.
How am I not getting this?
I've somehow
become the loser intern.
I blew the appy with Dr. Grey,
you've been piling on the scut,
so clearly I pissed
you off somehow.
You get scut because
you're an intern.
That's what interns do.
It's the best way to learn.
And...
You haven't pissed me off.
I haven't?
No, I'm just...
Dr. Torres may
have told me not to...
Flirt with you
because it may be possible
that I dated a couple
of other interns.
You mean Heather. Yeah, her.
And Leah. Yeah...
And Susan, Stacey, Tina, Irene.
Don't worry about the flirting.
I have absolutely
no interest in you
since you've already screwed
every one of my friends.
I should go.
8:00 a.m. tomorrow.
I'm doing a Nissen.
Don't be late.
Mrs. James, I just checked
on Emery. She's doing great.
And she promised to take
it easy before her follow-up.
She's lying.
A sailing company donated
a new boat, and she took it.
She's going back out there as
soon as you let her out of here.
What? She's
always been like this,
headstrong, independent...
Okay, if she goes out there
before this is healed properly,
she'll lose that foot.
Maybe you could keep her here.
Say that she has to stay
here while she recuperates.
I can't keep her here
without medical necessity.
If we stop her from
sailing, she will hate us.
So let her.
Stop being scared
of your own daughter.
She's 16. She
named a boat Pickle.
She's a little girl.
Be her parent.
She needs you to be the bad guy.
I could get in a lot
of trouble for this.
The plane's aft broke
away from the main cabin.
The tail was
recovered in zone one.
That's a keel beam.
It was recovered in zone
two, about half a mile away.
And that's the R-3 cabin door.
What happens to all this?
What happens if we settle?
I'm sorry I ran off
like that. I just...
So I am not gonna
pretend it didn't happen.
I can't do that.
I know. I... Me either.
I can't stop thinking about it.
The more I think
about it, the more...
The more I try not to think
about it, I'm thinking about it, so...
Yeah, I know.
I know.
Do you want to get married?
Uh, what?
Because if you're serious about
this whole revirginizing thing,
that means that the next
guy that you sleep with
is probably gonna
be your husband.
Right? That's what you want.
And I am not ready to
be anybody's husband.
And I really don't think you're
ready to be anybody's wife.
So let's remember
that it happened.
Make sure it doesn't
happen again.
Unless we want it to.
Unless we are...
Ready.
I'm... I can't...
I can't be near
you or I might...
Me too.
Okay, so we...
We stay away from each other...
For... For a while.
Okay.
Um, so I'm just gonna...
Walk away now.
Bye.
Oh, God.
It is a horror movie
inside this microwave.
A horror movie. They are...
Entitled, ungrateful children,
and they should know better.
Not that I care. I don't
care. I'm done caring.
Okay, so what's really going on?
Tuck let go of my hand.
What?
Tuck. He let go of my hand.
I took him to his first
day of kindergarten,
and I was, you know,
ready for the tears
and the good-bye, and
how hard it was gonna be,
and he just let go of my hand.
He didn't even look back. He
walked in, saw a toy he liked,
and didn't look back.
I called his dad.
He was busy.
He's getting married again.
And she's very nice.
I... I like her.
Whatever. He was busy.
So I called Ben,
and he was studying up
to observe his first
laparoscopic surgery.
He was so excited...
Everybody's moving on.
And I'm here, doing
appys and choles,
'cause that's what a general
surgery attending does,
appys and choles.
While everybody else is
off conquering new things,
I'm stuck.
And I didn't care. You know,
I mean, this was my choice.
I'm not even sure I noticed...
Until Tuck let go of your hand.
Till Tuck let go of my hand.
You know what happens when
someone lets go of your hand?
What?
You get it back.
It's a good thing.
You know, interns
let go, and Tuck let go,
and even Ben let go.
And they're all still there.
They all still love you.
But it means you
get your hand back.
It means you have time...
Not to wash the dishes.
To do something
with, to get out there,
to find diseases to cure,
to take it to the next level.
Hell, it means invent
the Bailey Method.
But you gotta get out
there, do something.
And don't look back.
Yeah, we're meeting in an
hour about the settlement.
Have you decided?
No, I don't care.
So... Do you want to think
about it some more or...
No, no, I just... Settle or
don't settle. It doesn't matter.
You know, whatever the group
wants to do is fine with me.
Okay.
I'll call you and
I'll let you know.
No, no, don't. I mean,
just send me a check.
Or, you know, I'll... I'll
get the lawyers to call.
Okay.
We can't keep doing this.
I know.
I'm here now.
So...
Bye.
Arizona, I've come to get you.
You're going to this meeting.
It starts in 20 minutes.
Arizona?
Where are you?
Oh, my... Are you
okay? Where's the nurse?
I didn't like her.
So I fired her.
Great. Great. That's just great.
Why are you...
I thought...
That I could
get to the toilet...
On time by myself.
Apparently, I was wrong.
Did you fall? Are you okay?
Do I look okay?
I am sitting in a
pool of my own urine.
I'm putting you in the
shower. No, just get out!
Hey! Do not talk to me that way.
Please! Please
get out! Arizona...
Did you hear me?
You did this!
I can't even pee by myself!
Yeah, and it's a problem
because you now stink!
This bathroom stinks!
Get off of me!
I am not sharing my home with
anybody who smells like this!
Get off of me! Get off of me!
Get off of me!
I have nowhere else to go!
This is my life now, too!
You know, I was, too.
In a plane crash.
In Vietnam.
Everyone on board the plane died
but me.
I never...
I never have told anybody about
that around here. You know, it's...
Would you like a smoke?
Oh, I don't smoke.
Oh.
Me neither.
Not anymore.
I mean, these things
could kill you, you know?
What?
Well, you know...
It seems like...
Everything kills you these days.
Yeah.
Sorry.
So we've all agreed and we...
No. Wait.
We can't do this.
I saw the plane. I
went to the hangar
and I saw the
pieces of our plane
laid out on the floor
like a jigsaw puzzle.
If we agree to settle,
they do the investigation,
and we can't do
anything with the results.
Bayview Aeronautics will take
the results and act accordingly.
Oh, I'm sure you'll
be very thorough.
Big companies are always
very good about self-policing.
Mistakes happen,
Derek. Accidents happen.
We make mistakes
that can cost lives, too.
Yes, we do.
But when we do,
we have M&Ms,
we pore over the files,
we make sure it
never happens again.
And we try to make sure
future patients never have
to go through that grief.
They don't have to sleep
with the lights on every night
because the
darkness is too much.
We just can't stand
by and let this happen
to other people's
Lexies and Marks.
We have to do
something about it.
We have to make this right.
If I could interject
for a moment...
Be quiet.
Your decision does
have to be unanimous.
She said, be quiet.
Callie, what are you thinking?
My advice at this time...
Shut up.
You're not one of us.
You don't know. You have
no idea what we've been...
Derek's right. We
shouldn't take the money.
We can't take it.
When we follow our hearts,
when we choose not to settle,
it's funny, isn't it?
A weight lifts.
The sun shines
a little brighter.
And, for a brief
moment at least,
we find a little peace.