Most people hate hospitals.
But not the interns.
For them, the hospital
is a magical place.
It's poetic...
The rhythm of the machines,
the crackle of a trauma gown.
It's a place full of promise,
excitement,
surprises.
It's a place where
dreams can come true.
Just look at them. They're so...
Fresh and shiny.
Laughing, talking.
It's pathetic.
They're pathetic.
I can't believe we
used to be them.
Why are they
still staring at us?
Just keep busy and look cool.
Come here.
Shane's right. Just gotta focus.
On what, your boobs?
Breast awareness is the first,
most important
part of breast health.
My cousin thought that
she had breast cancer once.
But it turned out
it was just a big zit.
Hey, if you need
a breast exam...
I don't.
Are they still out there?
Rounds are in five
minutes, freaks.
Coast is clear.
Oh, thank God.
You're on peds, right?
Do you want to
switch? I'm with Yang.
No, I am not feeding your
creepy obsession with Karev.
Well, guess you'll be stuck
watching me outshine
you all day, Murphy.
Don't take it personally.
Yang loves me.
No way I'm trading. I've got
outpatient surgery with Kepner.
Sounds like I'll
be cutting all day.
Kepner... Dud of attendings.
No way you're doing
something that cool.
I like Kepner. She's the only
one who's actually nice to us.
'Cause she's the dud.
Well, I'm in the pit
with Medusa today
if anybody wants
to trade with me.
Nope. No.
No.
You're late. I hate late. NICU.
Who's presenting?
I guess I am.
Samantha Morgan,
three months old.
Born with idiopathic
neonatal cardiomyopathy.
She's currently status 1b
on the heart transplant list.
What did I miss? Is there
any update on a heart?
I know how hard it is
to just sit here and wait.
But sometimes
that's all we can do
until a heart becomes available.
Seventy-seven days.
That's how long she's
been on the list already.
But who's counting, right?
She'll get a heart.
I know she will.
The good news is, your
daughter's stable for now.
Oh, no, she's not...
He isn't...
I'm not, um... Laura
and I met here.
Our kids were born
about a week apart.
My son Rhys is right over there.
We're both doing
all of this alone.
It helps to have a
second set of ears
to hear all the medical jargon.
My turn next?
Yes.
Rhys Rutstein, status 2
on the heart transplant list,
born with a
single-ventricle defect.
Post-op from
receiving a central shunt
and recovering very well.
It's possible you might
be able to take Rhys home
sometime next week.
Home? Next week?
Ah, yes. There's no reason
Rhys has to wait for a heart here.
Oh, Noah. That's amazing.
Oh, I'm not...
I don't think I'm
ready for this.
I mean, I am, but...
Home...
Without all the doctors
or nurses or you...
You can do this. You and
Rhys are gonna be just fine.
We'll check in with you later.
Dr. Yang, did you read
the recent West Coast
Surgical Journal article
on central shunts?
They listed some very
compelling statistics.
No, I didn't.
I'll get you a copy.
Check out the new girl.
I was gonna call her Droopy.
But maybe Perky now.
Or Doc.
Hey.
Damn. Look at that thing.
What do those run, like, 5k?
I don't know. It was a
gift. Oh, from daddy?
No. All right.
Don't get defensive,
princess. Just a question.
Here.
What's this?
That's your job this morning.
I'm on my way into surgery.
But little Carter
Kaynig in room nine,
he swallowed some crayons.
Crayons aren't toxic. Don't
we just wait for them to pass?
That's exactly what his
parents have been doing
for the past eight days.
Bowel's impacted.
The kid's in a lot of pain,
and he won't be passing
it on his own, so...
You don't want me to...
Start digging, princess.
Oh. You might want to
take off your watch first.
Dr. Kepner.
I'm here, I'm
ready, I'm excited...
Stop right there.
That... All of that
fake enthusiasm...
I see through it,
and I don't appreciate
insubordination.
Okay? So just order these
by date of appointment made.
Uh... Okay.
Problem?
No, no, no. It's just...
Outpatient surgery.
I was hoping I'd be doing
some surgery on the outpatients.
Oh, you'll be cutting.
It's lump and bump day.
Yay?
This hospital likes to schedule
all of its outpatient mass
and growth removals
on one day.
So one lucky surgeon
will find herself
carving out glorified
pimples for 12 freakin' hours.
It's called whittling.
A hillbilly with a
pocketknife could do it.
Come with me.
Mr. Publer?
Pube-publer?
Pu-publer?
We're seeing all of them today?
Oh, this is just this morning's.
Sharpen your
pocketknife, Jethro.
Mrs. Crossley's getting
a pacemaker today
for a complete heart block.
Barring any complications,
she'll be going
home this afternoon.
What'd they say?
I'm going home
later today, honey.
Sorry. He's deaf in one ear.
We'll be prepping
you for surgery soon.
It should be a fairly
simple procedure.
Well, I wasn't planning
on staying here overnight.
No one's arguing
with you, honey.
Okay. See you soon.
I took the liberty of
reserving OR 3 for you.
I know you prefer it.
And I e-mailed you a list
of Mrs. Crossley's
latest rhythms
for reference.
Perky...
Man the NICU.
Check my post-ops.
Grumpy, scrubbing in.
Ah, look at that.
Guess I'm scrubbing in.
What are you doing?
Uh, I'm sorry. I
was... I was just...
Never mind. I don't
care. Go away.
Help. We need a doctor. Help.
Sir, sir. Just calm down.
Please. Just tell
me what happened.
I think we killed
Bigfoot. Bigfoot?
Yeah.
I was just having a
go at some whitetails,
and I heard this scream.
You shot someone?
I didn't see him. I swear.
It just happened so fast,
and then I saw this
thing coming at me,
like... Like a monster.
Did you shoot him again?
I may have fired a warning shot.
And I was just headed into town
and it jumped into the road.
I tried to swerve, but...
Wait. You shot Bigfoot?
And then you ran him over?
Yes.
Well, where's
Bigfoot now exactly?
You're doing great.
Ultrasound shows
the baby has C.D.H.
I'm sorry. What?
Congenital diaphragmatic hernia.
He may not be able to
oxygenate well when he's born.
Well, why didn't
you page Dr. Karev?
He's in surgery. He sent you.
Okay. Okay. Um,
how old is she...
The mom? 15.
Don't just stand
around watching.
Do something. My baby's in pain!
Could you page
Dr. Karev again, please?
I can't do this.
I can't do this. Yes,
you can, Kimmy.
One last push. Here we go.
You're doing okay.
Okay.
Watch the monitor.
He's so small. He's just...
What do we do? What do we do?
You're the surgeon,
hon. You tell us.
Dr. Wilson, what do
you want us to do?
Okay, okay.
His sats are low.
We need to intubate.
Get me a laryngoscope
and intubation tray.
It hurts.
It's okay, sugar.
It's okay. Right?
Everything is okay?
Okay, hand me a size 4 ET. Tube.
No, no, no. A smaller one.
Sats are dropping. There you go.
Okay, hang on. His
epiglottis is floppy.
There's no time to hang
on. What's happening?
Somebody want to tell
my baby what's happening?
If I could just get
this tube to pass.
Dr. Wilson...
Got it. Got it. I got it.
You're doing just fine. Okay.
Now what's next?
Um, I think that...
How about suction?
And maybe you want to
put in an umbilical catheter.
Yes. Right. Yes.
And please page Dr. Karev again.
I'll page him.
Guy's crazy, wearing this thing.
It's like he wanted to get shot.
Brooks, get over here
and help with the cutting.
Did you cut him?
Don't cut my ghillie suit.
His what?
It's army issue. Best
damn camouflage there is.
Yeah, for war. Not hunting deer.
We wear orange
coats for a reason.
Oh, I got it. I got it.
You know, I myself
prefer hobbies like
stamp collecting or crochet...
Something that doesn't
involve guns and...
Helpless little creatures.
Brooks, escort the gentlemen outside.
- Okay.
This way.
Hi, Dr. Torres, we just heard
back about the cadaver nerves,
but the longest they
have is seven centimeters.
Oh, damn it. We
need more than that.
Okay.
No blood in the pericardium.
There's definite
abdominal guarding.
Brooks, reach in my left
pocket. Get my phone.
Go into my phone book.
Go to "Shepherd...
Nancy, Amy, Liz and Kate."
Call all of his sisters.
See which one's
willing to donate a nerve.
First one that bites, grab me.
Okay, Derek was very clear.
He wants to use a cadaver
nerve for his hand surgery.
You're on sister duty. Go.
You're sure you don't need
more hands, you know, in here?
We got this. Nope.
We got it. We
should turn him over.
Yes. See if there's
an exit wound.
Yeah? Okay.
Fill me in. Baby born
with C.D.H. I intubated him.
But the SATs are still low.
Ah, it could be
pulmonary hypertension.
You ever hooked a
baby up to ECMO before?
I never intubated a baby
before five minutes ago.
Okay, we hook up
catheters into his neck,
pump his blood into
the ECMO machine,
which puts in oxygen, and
takes out the carbon dioxide.
Then it cycles it all back in.
Okay.
You need to make sure
that you get good borders
so we can send this to path.
Whoa. That's...
Whoa.
What do you mean? What's "Whoa"?
I don't know. It
just keeps coming.
You don't know?
Hi.
I know how scary
this must be for you.
But I want you to
know that we are taking
really good care of you, okay?
Dr. Ross...
A word.
What was that?
I don't know, but
it's disgusting.
You were, like, a magician
with a handkerchief.
Ross, these lumps
are attached to people.
Scared people.
You need to acknowledge
that fear and ease it.
You look them in the eye,
you talk to them like you care.
Imagine if it were
you and I was pulling
a wormy handkerchief
out of your flesh.
I... I'm sure you think
this is beneath you.
Okay? I get it.
I know you guys
call me "the dud."
But that doesn't mean
that these patients
don't deserve your
respect and care,
no matter how crappy you feel.
Do you understand?
I...
I think so.
Enough with the attitude.
Hello?
And here you go.
I'll see you soon.
Dude, I am a rock star.
I just rocked a pacemaker
post-op dictation on my own.
That is how much Yang trusts me.
That's cool.
Not as cool as this maybe.
That's disgusting.
Yeah. Hey, have you seen Leah?
'Cause I have some
more gloating to do.
Oh, yeah. I just passed
her. 9-1-1 in the NICU, I think.
What do you see?
Is that an effusion
around his heart?
How could he have
C.H.F.? He has a shunt.
His shunt might be leaking.
He's tamponading. What happened?
He was fine, and then
he just... He wasn't.
It's okay. It'll be okay.
Let's prep him for transport.
What can I do? Do you need
another set of hands in there?
I need you to keep an eye
on my patients and call the OR.
Tell them we're coming up.
Huh. Look at that.
Guess I'm
scrubbing in this time.
The bullet's torn
through the colon.
We're gonna
have to re-sect this.
Um... She belong to any of you?
Brooks, do I look like
I enjoy multitasking?
What's the report?
I left messages for
Kathleen and Amy.
Nancy hung up on
me. I called her back.
She hung up on me again so
I'm guessing that she's a "no."
But I did talk to Lizzie,
and she might be in.
Also, she wanted to know
what size Zola wears now.
And I thought maybe a
2T, but that's just a guess.
Anyway, can I scrub in?
Meredith.
I just got a call from Lizzie.
She's under the impression
she's gonna donate a nerve
to me.
Yay!
Not yay.
I thought I made it clear, I
didn't want my family involved.
Well, a live donor
nerve is preferable,
and it's definitely
easier to find.
My hand, my
sisters, my decision.
The longer we wait,
the less chance we have
that it will work.
And we need this to work,
sooner rather than later.
Sounds like a no-brainer to me.
But what do I know?
I don't have sisters.
Who'd you get to make the calls?
Call them all back
and undo what you did.
Now.
Don't undo a thing.
You're doing great.
You've isolated the
jugular and the carotid,
avoided the vagus nerve.
Now you need to put in a
venous drainage cannula.
I hadn't even...
He's coding. Switch with me.
You need to do CPR while
I hook the kid up to ECMO.
At the same time?
How will that work?
Start the compressions now.
Stop.
Go.
Keep going.
Stop.
Okay. Keep going.
Go.
How long have we been going?
Twenty minutes.
Stop.
Karev, I heard you
had a crash ECMO.
You need my help? You
need me to take over?
No, no, just connecting
it to the circuit.
Okay.
Initiate bypass.
We did it.
Son of a bitch.
And it seems like only
yesterday that I was
showing you how to do your
first pulmonary hypoplasia.
I hope you're
taking notes, Wilson.
He's one of the good ones.
So what's next?
Well, now that he's
hooked up to ECMO,
the baby needs to
be monitored 24/7.
Gonna be a long day
and a longer night.
You might want to go
grab a power nap, princess.
Why do you keep
calling me princess?
Have you seen yourself?
You see anything?
Looks great so far, ma'am.
What is it?
Hi.
I know this must be
scary for you right now.
I want you to know we're gonna
take really good care of you, okay?
There's just a little
gross... Growth... Bump
on your...
Bottom.
Excuse me.
What do you do
when you need to...
Sorry.
When you need the
lab to fast-track a...
A specimen?
What is wrong with you?
That lady has the most
disgusting butt scab. It's just...
Oh, my gosh. You're a child.
Tell the lab to...
Tell them that I said
to push this to
the front of the line.
We're gonna need
those results stat.
Would you mind doing it?
Nope. Yours.
Leah's a shark.
Don't know why
Yang can't see it.
Oh, how great does this feel?
Hit me, vitamin D.
Mama needs a power nap.
I smell crab cakes.
We're by the kitchen.
No, it's not crab
cakes. It's meat loaf.
I love/hate it so much.
Oh, man. It's like
Vegas in there.
No idea when it's day or night.
Sun, meet Shane. Shane, Sun.
Nice change from
the black hole of sepsis
I've been staring at
for the past half-hour.
You should see the thing
growing on this one woman's ass.
It is so nasty.
Wouldn't bother me. I am
just fine with nasty things.
Although all Karev does
is call me "princess."
What is that? I don't
act like some priss, do I?
Am I prissy?
What?
I am not prissy.
How do you like that?
You spit like a priss.
Stop.
Just let it go to voice mail.
I can't handle another
raging Shepherd sister.
Actually, I think
you should take this.
It says "Bigfoot. 9-1-1."
I'm here. I got your
page. How can I help?
Oh, sorry, sorry. That was me.
I needed Grey. I forgot
you had her phone.
Well, maybe I can
help since I'm here.
I could... I could
irrigate that wound or...
Are you gonna get that?
Hello. Dr. Grey's
phone. Heather speaking.
Oh, hey, Lizzie.
Yeah, I know. She just
keeps getting cuter every day.
Um... Okay.
I'll ask.
Great. Bye.
What did she say?
That Zola's the
cutest niece ever
and she's wondering if
you're visiting for Christmas,
'cause there should be snow.
Okay. What about the nerve?
Uh, she's getting back to me.
Hi, again.
Mmm-hmm. I understand.
It is a lot to ask.
Hey, hang on.
Heather Brooks.
Hi, Kathleen.
How did you get my
cell phone number?
Sorry. Hang on.
Yes, Liz.
I have Kathleen on another line.
I don't know if she
booked her flight yet.
Please don't make me
repeat all of that to her.
Sorry. The other line's going.
Hello. Oh, hang on.
Dr. Grey, it's
Dr. Simpson's office.
They want to confirm
your ultrasound.
Hang up. Right now.
Oh, is Rhys out
of surgery already?
No.
I just... I couldn't wait in
the surgical waiting area.
It's where I found out my wife
had died. It's not my favorite place.
Oh. I'm sorry.
They'll page me when it's done.
And in the meantime,
I get to watch Laura play
solitaire on her phone.
I'm addicted. It's pathetic.
She never takes her
eyes off the screen.
You know, I don't even know
if she knows what I look like.
Big nose, receding
hairline, tiny, beady eyes.
Well, I've been told I
look like George Clooney.
Dr. Edwards, I've got UNOS
on the line for Dr. Yang.
Oh, my God. It could
be Samantha's heart.
Or it could be a routine call.
This is Dr. Edwards.
Part of my job is to
keep you from letting
your emotions get away from you.
Remember?
But, yeah, it
could be her heart,
and by the end of the day,
she could have a
chance at a real life.
And Rhys is gonna
get out of surgery.
He's gonna be fine. Wait. What?
And they're both
gonna be regular kids.
And you and I are gonna keep
being there for each other...
'Cause I can't imagine going
through any of this without you.
I mean, I... I can't
imagine life without you.
How is that for not letting my
emotions get away from me?
Okay. Good-bye.
Was that... Is there a heart?
I'm... I'm gonna
go find Dr. Yang.
Dr. Yang,
I just received a
call from UNOS.
A heart's available.
We have an hour
to let them know if we want it.
We want it. Call
them back right away.
Charge to 5.
Is there a heart for Samantha?
Mr. Rutstein,
could I talk to you?
Uh, what is it? Is Rhys okay?
He's still in surgery.
He's in critical condition.
Oh, God. It's gonna be fine.
Mr. Rutstein, could I
speak with you privately?
I'll be outside if
you need anything.
No.
Stay. I want you
here. I need you here.
Rhys has gotten worse,
much worse, causing
his status to change.
He's been moved to the
top of the transplant list.
There is a heart.
Our team is harvesting
it as we speak.
But if it's in good condition,
it's not going to Samantha.
It's going to Rhys.
Dr. Stein, call dialysis.
Don't even try to get in
on the transplant. It's mine.
We don't have to do this.
The fighting, the
competing, it's...
What's wrong?
You worried that Yang's
starting to like me better?
Please tell me that
heart is on its way.
The harvest team will
be here in 30 minutes.
Good.
What's wrong with your face?
I had to tell Noah his
son gets a transplant
in front of Laura.
It's like I personally
stole her daughter's heart.
An equation decides
where the heart goes,
not us. I know.
Scrub in on the
transplant, Grumpy.
It'll cheer you up.
"Gosh. I'm so sad and sensitive.
"I really could use some
cheering up, Dr. Yang."
Nicely done.
You're saying, the baby needs
that machine to stay alive?
Well, for now. ECMO, it
works a little like bypass
to give your
grandson's heart a rest.
For how long?
'Cause my friend Nikki's
having a party for me on Friday,
and I'm supposed
to bring the baby.
Kimmy, your baby will be
here a lot longer than Friday.
How much longer? Weeks? Months?
It's hard to know at this point.
I'll have to call Nikki.
She ordered cupcakes and stuff.
Mom, where's your
phone? Oh, here.
Kimmy, would you like to
go in and see your baby now?
No, thanks.
Are you sure? You
won't hurt anything.
I can wheel you right
up next to the bed.
It's not like he's gonna
know who I am or anything.
I'm tired. Can I just
go back to my room?
Sure, baby.
Oh, I can't believe we didn't
get through everybody today,
and now... I am on lumps
and bumps again tomorrow.
Still, we got
through a bunch of...
Word of advice.
You want to avoid lump
and bump day again,
just make sure you
pass your stupid boards,
or you will always
get stuck doing...
Sorry.
You can go, Ross. That's all.
You want me to help tomorrow?
Don't mock me, Ross.
It's been a long day. Just...
Get outta here.
Oh, my God, congratulations.
No!
Did the doctor call back?
Yes.
To confirm your appointment
for the eight-week ultrasound?
So you know that?
I do?
Okay, let's be clear.
You never heard
anything. You know nothing.
And you don't ever mention any
of this to anyone, ever. You got it?
Is there anything else
you would like to say
before we drop this subject
for the rest of eternity?
Congratulations?
I can't wait to scrub in
on something like that.
That should be me down there.
Look at that.
Yang just ligated
the pulmonary artery
with one stitch.
She's incredible.
Yes, she is.
You sure you're not
asleep with your eyes open?
You've been staring
at that kid for an hour.
She didn't even want to see him.
She cared more about her
best friend's stupid pizza party
than seeing her child.
Well, she's 15.
It doesn't matter. She oughta...
You don't know her story.
Not everybody lives in a
perfect little world like you.
I never said my
world was perfect.
Oh... Princeton,
Harvard, perfect G.P.A.
Look, not all of us go
to Ivy League schools
or drive fancy cars
or rely on our
richy-rich daddies
to bankroll our
pretty little lives.
Some of us have to
overcome more than others.
I know that.
So... Get over it, princess.
You're in no position to judge.
Did you also know that I
blow my nose with $100 bills?
Ha-ha.
And my one-year-old birthday
cake was made out of caviar.
Gross.
Also, in one of the rooms of
my obscenely big mansion,
instead of paint, I just
lined the walls with mink.
Shut up.
It's true.
Guess how many
fireplaces I've got.
Four.
Twenty-seven.
Well, 28 if you count
the butler's room.
But, please, he's the help.
Explains a lot.
Obviously, the next 24
hours will be critical, but so far,
he is the poster
child for transplant.
Do an ABG every two hours
and monitor his pH level.
Hey.
We've been waiting
for a heart for months.
Her SATs aren't budging.
She's dying.
I sit here and play solitaire
because I can't watch my baby die.
And I...
That was her heart.
That was her heart, and you...
I want to be happy for you.
But right now I can't.
I just can't.
Oh, give me that coffee.
I'm so tired right now, I'm
sleepwalking. Which I do, by the way.
In college, I sleepwalked
into this guy's room,
and when I woke
up, we were doing it.
Ew.
No, he was hot.
Oh. Where did you get that?
The coffee cart's closed.
Would you judge me if I told you
I stole it from a nurse
when she wasn't looking?
She's a stealer, too.
Little baby hearts.
No wonder you guys
get along so well.
Aren't you supposed to be
with Karev in the ECMO room?
Yeah, but I keep falling asleep,
so he sent me out to walk
around and wake myself up
because a tiny,
fragile baby's life
is in my very tired hands.
That's frightening.
No, it's not. It's awesome.
All the attendings are asleep
right now, and we're in charge.
We're saving lives.
I'm making phone calls.
Uh, lifesaving phone calls.
And you're removing warts.
And saving lives.
And she's stealing
surgeries from me.
Stop complaining.
This is it, you know?
We're surgeons.
We're no longer med students
waiting to be surgeons. We're...
Help! Someone help us!
What the...
Oh, my God.
Oh, hell, no.
God, I love this job.
Mr. Crossley, you need
to put your wife down.
I've got her. Just
let go of her ankles.
I'm not putting her down.
If I put her down, she goes out.
Sir, we're doctors. We can help.
Show 'em, honey.
I can't feel a pulse.
Starting CPR.
I'll grab a crash cart.
I'm picking her back up.
Sir, sir. You need to back away.
Found one.
What the hell?
Now get us a real damn doctor!
So, Mrs. Crossley,
you went home,
you were feeling fine,
you had a coughing spasm,
and then you passed out?
Yes. She slipped when
I tried to pick her up,
so I just grabbed
her by her ankles.
And she regained consciousness.
Please tell me I
don't have to spend
the rest of my life upside down.
Oh, no. Your coughing episode
knocked the ventricular lead
from your pacemaker loose.
We're gonna have to open you
back up and reposition the lead.
This is it, people.
Your chance to scrub
in on one of the coolest,
most innovative
surgeries you will ever see.
Was that a yawn? Avery,
did you see a yawn?
Brooks, you're out.
But...
If you can't handle
one overnight shift,
you can't handle this surgery.
Look alive, people.
All right. Now the rest of you
will each get a chance
to examine our patient
before we move on to the
skills lab portion of the contest.
Dr. Avery, will you
bring in our patient?
Now Dr. Torres and I
will be performing
a nerve transplant
on Dr. Shepherd's injured hand.
We need an intern we can trust.
And that's saying a lot,
because we don't trust
any of you people yet.
Wilson, you're up.
I'm not gonna bite you, Wilson.
Right.
And you're done.
Edwards.
Did you do a proximal or
a distal repair the first time?
You should know the answer
to that by looking at the scars.
You're done.
Ross.
Hi. I'm Dr. Ross.
Yeah, I know who you are, Shane.
I know. I was just...
Do you have any pain with
prehension or pronation?
Yeah. It's getting
worse, though.
Okay.
I know this must
be scary for you.
It would be for
me. That's for sure.
But Dr. Torres and Dr. Avery,
they're really talented.
They're gonna take
really good care of you.
I know it.
Okay, we're done.
I've selected our winner.
Ross is the only one
who actually treated
the patient like a patient.
Congratulations.
You're on the team.
Thank you.
Thank me later. He gets grouchy.
It's true.
All right. You can leave now.
Mrs. Crossley's
mine. I'm prepping her.
Not if I get there first.
Hey, no running!
Oh. Damn it.
I'm prepping her. Not you.
Looks like I'm the one who's
got the portable monitor.
I'm the one that's got
her leads. I got the chart.
Excuse me. Can I...
You don't get to
steal this from me.
You stole the
transplant from me.
I'm sorry, but I...
Gimmie!
Can you guys just
hold on one second?
Too late. I'm done.
Oh, my God.
Pull it out. Pull it out. What?
You hooked her O-2 to the IV.
No, no, no, no, no. If an air
embolus gets into her heart,
it'll kill her. What?
Oh, my God. Oh, my
God. Oh, my God. Oh, my...
What's going on?
They're trying to kill me!
That's what's going on.
Kimmy, hey.
If you want to get
up to the NICU,
the south elevator's
actually a little bit closer.
I could take you
there... That's okay.
Were you discharged already?
Where's the damn elevator?
My shift's not over for
another couple of hours.
What time are you coming back?
You don't have to
talk to her, Kimmy.
I...
I'm not coming back.
Wait. What? Of course you are.
Whoa. Hey, hang on.
You can't just leave.
You have a baby. She
has a baby upstairs.
He's one day old.
Yeah, and he's all messed up.
- So you're just gonna...
- You can't...
You can't abandon him.
No, you can't. No.
No! Let me on.
No. You don't want
to mess with me.
You don't want to mess with me.
No, stop. You can't
walk out on that baby!
You can't do that!
Get off me!
No! Let her go!
No! Hey, let 'em go.
You're crazy! Let 'em go.
Yeah, stack the
pallets over there.
Why aren't you in the tunnels?
Interns always hang
out in the tunnels.
This place smells like fish.
We've got a
delivery in a minute.
Look, I don't know
what your deal is,
but you can't go around
assaulting patients.
She was abandoning her baby.
Then let the cops handle
it. It's not your job, princess.
Stop calling me princess!
My mother left me at a fire
station when I was two weeks old.
I got bumped around
foster homes till I was 16,
when I took matters
into my hands
and started living out of a car.
I parked it behind the
gym of my high school
so I could sneak in and
use the showers before class.
My home ec.
Teacher... Ms. Schmidt...
She let me do my
laundry there for free.
And, yeah, I got into good schools
because I worked my ass off.
And when I walked across
that stage at graduation,
I didn't have a cheering section
filled with my
richy-rich family.
I had one person... Ms. Schmidt.
That's it.
She's the one who gave me
this watch when I got the job.
Her son works for the company.
It is a nice watch.
Thanks.
This was not just my fault.
It sure as hell wasn't mine.
You could have killed her.
I understand
competition and drive,
but you two,
you need to figure out
how to work together,
and you better do it fast.
You're both off my service.
I'll do you one better.
You're both banned from the OR
until further notice.
Thank you.
Guess what.
Butt-scab lady was seen
by oncology last night.
The mass was malignant.
They said I might have got it all.
What are you doing here?
I told you I'd come help with the
rest of your lumps and bumps today.
Who put you up to this?
Because nobody slums it
down here unless they have to.
I'm here because I want to be.
All I ever wanted
to be was a surgeon.
And now Torres just
chose me to scrub in
on one of the coolest surgeries
I'll ever see because of you.
You gave me 27 solo
procedures yesterday.
At least one of them
saved a woman's life.
I'm grateful for this job
and I'm grateful to you.
I'm hardly slumming it.
So I'm gonna glove up
and I'm gonna help
you with your lumps...
And you're gonna like it.
Okay. Fine.
But you get the nasty-smelling
green one in bed two.
I'm off Dr. Yang's service now.
But I wanted to come
by one last time to...
I'm sorry, but...
Could you excuse
me for just one minute?
Yes.
You okay?
They say there's still a
chance he may reject the heart.
He won't reject it.
This happened before.
It has nothing to do...
Hey, you.
Yeah, you.
Dr. Shepherd.
Did you or did you not shut
things down with my sisters?
Don't bring Brooks into this.
You brought Brooks into this.
They are your family
and they want to help you.
Right?
Oh, oh. You're asking me? Yes.
Um, they seemed willing to help.
Of course they want to help
me. I practically raised them.
But if my sisters find
out that I need help...
Look, who did you call so I
can call and shut this down?
Don't tell him that.
Don't tell her not to tell me.
All right, enough.
You know that live nerves
are better than dead ones.
Even I know that,
and I'm an intern.
And you. You put me in a
really awkward position today.
You just threw me to the wolves.
Not that I'm comparing
your sisters to wolves.
But, oh, my God.
They're out for blood.
They are furious with you that
you didn't call them yourself.
And they told me some things.
Okay? Unkind things.
And now I know stories
about you. And you, too.
I know things about both of
you that I don't want to know.
I don't want to be in on
your secrets or your fights.
It makes me really,
really, really uncomfortable.
Let me guess. Your parents
had a messy divorce...
And always put you in
the middle. Am I right?
How'd you know that?
Lucky guess. Lizzie.
One of the wolves.
Good to see you, Mer.
I hope you got some
baby pictures handy
because I did not
take the red-eye
just so my brother could hack
my nerves into hamburger meat.
There don't have
to be harps playing
or birds singing or rose petals
falling from the sky...
I have never been
this tired, ever.
I have a jacket.
It's so far away.
I just want to go home.
Hunt really put you
guys on probation?
And there are definitely days
when the romance is dead.
But...
If you look around...
Coming through!
Things are pretty amazing.
So stop for a second.
Enjoy the beauty.
Feel the magic.
Drink it in. MAN:
Watch your back!
'Cause it won't last forever.
The romance will fade.
Things will happen.
People will change.
Out of the way! Out of the way!
Love will die.
But...
Maybe not today.
I can't believe
they used to be us.