So, here we go.
What letter
are we up to now?
J's.
So, "Jeremiah" if it's a boy,
or "Jacinta" if it's a girl.
Hmm.
Jeremiah Sexton-Jenkins.
I like it.
Oh, my God, it's a boy?
Or Jacinta Sexton Jenkins.
You're having fun
torturing me
by not telling me the gender
of the baby, aren't you?
A little, but hey,
if I can wait 21 more weeks,
so can you.
Dr. Rhodes?
Page me if you need me.
Case coming your way.
Window washer fell
33 stories.
Should be DOA,
but still alive, barely.
Thirty-three?
Press will be
all over this.
Hospital PR's
gonna be involved.
Get ready
for your close-up.
Okay, who's next?
Damian Butler.
Damian Butler?
That's me.
Oh, God.
Won't be
much longer.
I just have the flu.
It's low priority.
I get it.
Sir?
Maggie, how many
minutes out?
They're here.
Baghdad's prepped.
Thanks.
Justin Pepper, 23,
long fall,
axial load injury
after his window washing
platform gave out.
GCS 3. BP 70 over palp.
Heart rate 135.
All right, that long a fall,
we're looking at injuries
to the brain, spine,
chest, and abdomen,
let alone long bone fractures.
Maggie, I need extra hands
and an OR on alert.
Done.
What's he got
for IV access?
Sixteen gauge
on both arms.
All right,
very gently, everybody.
On my count,
one, two, three.
Good luck.
Thanks.
All right,
likely cavitary bleeding.
Wheeler, get a groin line.
Start the MTP.
Hang two units of O-Neg
on the rapid transfuser
until we type and cross.
X-rays... I need chest,
pelvis, and C-spine.
And let's get
the ultrasound over here
to FAST his belly.
Lungs are clear.
I'm gonna start
the groin line.
Help me reduce
this leg fracture.
Come on, come on.
One, two, three.
X-ray.
All right, step back.
Pelvis down.
C-spine.
On the box.
MALE X-RAY TECH:
Chest X-ray is up.
Tension hemopneumothorax.
Trachea shifted,
venous return is down.
Give me a chest tube.
Show me the pelvis.
Got it.
Vertical shear of
the left hemipelvis,
it needs traction.
Pull up the C-spine.
It's up.
Multiple C-spine fractures.
Wheeler, how's
that groin line?
Done.
All right, chest tube's
in, too. Let's move.
Justin didn't
survive a 330-foot fall
just to die in my trauma bay.
Let's go, let's go!
Go.
FEMALE NEWS REPORTER:
Witnesses report
that Mr. Pepper clung
to his window washing
platform as it fell,
almost riding it
like a surfboard.
Physicists surmise
this likely created
wind resistance
that not only
slowed his plummet,
but also absorbed
some of the force
from impact.
That might explain
how he survived
such a horrific fall.
I'm running the bowel.
Feeling tears. Hemostat.
Pelvic hematoma and
mesenteric bleeders
are tied off.
Let's resect the bowel
quickly and move on.
GIA 80 stapler with a reload.
50% of people
who fall four to five
stories die.
Ten or 11, it's almost 100%,
so this is a first.
There's an exception
to every rule.
All right, got some
more spaces.
Who's next?
Laura Pastino.
Laura Pastino?
No, Melody Sayers.
Okay, uh, treatment Three.
I'll be right there.
I'm sorry.
No, this one's on me.
I thought I could
sneak in and see
a doctor
on my lunch break.
It's bad planning.
Okay, I'm April.
Can I get you anything?
Water?
Snack from the meal cart?
No thanks.
Not much of an appetite.
If I need something,
I'll just...
Melody? Are you okay?
Yeah, sorry.
You just zoned out.
That ever happen before?
Probably.
I'm a first-year associate.
My law firm's specialty,
60-hour weeks.
Can I see your wrist?
Yeah.
Pulse is really weak.
I'm just exhausted.
I'm gonna go home
and sleep.
I'll come back tomorrow.
Your feet hurt?
Yeah, I've just been
sitting for a while.
Do you mind
if I take a look?
Sure.
Ankles are swollen.
Pitting edema.
Do me a favor.
Stick around for
a little longer.
I'm gonna get you in.
Okay.
Americano.
Thank you.
Wow, all this
for Connor's trauma?
If it bleeds, it leads.
Help! I need help!
My husband!
What happened?
He called
me at work.
He said he wasn't
feeling well, but then...
But when I came
home for lunch,
I found him like this.
Hey, hey, can you hear me?
Thready pulse, diaphoretic.
He's burning up.
Did he take any drugs?
Could it be an overdose?
No, never.
Septic shock?
I think so.
We gotta get him inside.
All right.
I'm gonna get techs
to bring out a gurney,
and set up for central
access if we need one.
I'm gonna help you
out of the car, okay?
No, get back.
I can do it myself.
No, Nick, let him help you.
Don't let him, please.
Easy.
Nick, please, no...
Julia, Julia,
I need your help.
I know, baby, I...
I'm sorry.
Okay, okay.
My legs don't work.
It's okay. I got you.
Here.
All right. Let's go.
Dr. Choi, you're going
to Treatment Five.
Dr. Manning's already there.
Thanks, Mags.
Dr. Reese?
Oh, my...
This woman needs aid.
Dr. Wheeler!
I saw her fall
crossing the street.
When I got to her,
she was unable to speak.
I think she's
having a stroke.
Treatment Two.
Weak pulse, right side
of the face is droopy.
Right side body, limp.
What do we got?
Possible stroke.
Okay. Thanks, Superdude.
You're safe now, ma'am.
Oh, Lord.
We need a stretcher!
Right now,
your son is in shock.
There is massive blood loss
from extensive injuries
to his liver, his pelvis,
his intestines.
We've packed his abdomen
to control the bleeding
and removed a portion
of his bowel.
He's still open.
That's what we call
a negative pressure dressing.
It helps to temporize
the abdomen...
Is Justin
going to survive?
When he arrived in the ED,
he was minute-to-minute.
Right now, he is hour-to-hour,
and that is a very good
first step.
This is Dr. Rhodes.
Who is this,
and how did you
get this number?
No, my patient is very
much alive, thank you.
Sounds like the press
got to you before we did.
Dr. Connor Rhodes,
this is Evelyn Kumer,
public affairs rep
for the hospital.
She'll be coordinating
all media platforms.
So, reporters
got your number?
Yeah, they wanted to
know if Justin had died
on the operating table.
Where do they get this crap?
Who knows?
But the rumor
mill is grinding.
And you're
in the spotlight.
A man falls 33 stories
and is still alive?
People are gonna want to know,
is this a miracle or
a setup for tragedy?
Excuse me.
Until we know for sure
how this is gonna turn out,
let's stick with
"no comment."
102.7.
BP, 80 over 55.
Whoa, that's really low.
Uh, Melody, I hear
a crackling in your chest.
This means fluid is
building up in the lungs.
A symptom of the flu?
I don't think so.
The exhaustion,
swelling in your legs,
low blood pressure,
are possible indicators
of a cardiac problem.
My heart? Oh, my God.
We're gonna take a look
and see what's going on, okay?
Okay.
That just doesn't
make any sense.
I'm only 25 years old.
I walk to work
instead of taking the train.
Eat salads.
Take spin classes.
Okay, dilated left ventricle,
poor wall motion.
April, let's get her
on the monitor.
Your heart is
pumping very poorly.
Uh, I'll need an echo,
but if I had to say,
I'd guess it's
working at 20, 25%.
My heart is failing?
It's unusual
for a young woman.
Could be a thyroid imbalance,
a kidney issue, virus.
We'll figure it out.
Before you know it,
you'll be back at spin class.
I'm gonna hold you to that.
Melody? Melody?
No pulse or breathing.
V-fib, get on her chest.
Charge to 200.
Two hundred.
Charged.
Hold CPR.
Clear.
Two hundred again.
Two hundred.
Hold CPR. Clear.
I got a pulse.
It's weak, but steady.
She's breathing.
Let's get her
to the cath lab.
Great catch, April.
Had she gone home,
no way help would've
gotten to her in time.
So, it's an infection?
Fever, elevated white cells,
inflammatory markers
and lactating.
I'd say so.
Most likely a UTI.
It's common in paraplegics.
Been down that
road a few times.
Life with a catheter, right?
We may need
to replace it.
Suprapubic?
T-boned by a drunk driver
who didn't stop
for a red light.
He walked away
with a few stitches.
That was then.
We're moving on.
Brighter days ahead.
Area around
the catheter looks clean.
No obvious abscess
or skin infection.
Answer's
in the pee then.
We'll get this and blood
cultures up to the lab,
find out what
we're dealing with.
Sorry about
lashing out earlier.
I sometimes forget
I'm half a man.
No, you're not.
I'm with her.
Yeah, well,
she's one of a kind.
Not letting her get away.
Good plan.
Hey, K.
If it's a boy, "Kalani."
If it's a girl,
"Kiersleigh."
What do you think?
Pass.
Ugh!
Any word from
the cath lab about Melody?
No, but I should
hear something soon.
Okay,
I have an OB appointment.
Should be fast, though,
20 minutes, tops.
I can push it.
Or I can text you
if I hear something.
Because of the TB,
Dr. Lee likes to see
me every two weeks.
Though, text me
about Melody.
Mmm-hmm.
Now, go. Don't be late
for your appointment.
We haven't officially met.
I'm Dr. Reese.
Hi. Edward Thompson.
That was quite
an entrance, Edward.
Yeah, I can imagine.
The suit, elderly
woman in my arms.
Yeah.
How is she?
Uh, doing well.
Thanks to you getting
her here so quickly.
Oh, that's great.
How are you?
How are you feeling?
Okay, I think.
But I never passed out before.
What happened?
Uh, your labs
and EKG are normal.
So, I think you were just
so excited in the moment
that when it was over,
you fainted.
And where are my clothes?
A nurse said she'd get 'em,
but she never came back.
Unfortunately, we had
to cut off the costume,
so that we could examine you.
Cut it off?
You mean, it's destroyed?
Uh, yes.
Oh, God.
You had no right.
I need it.
Edward, breathe.
Breathe.
All right, nice and...
All right.
Hey, look at me,
look at me.
Just like this.
Two seconds in.
Four seconds out.
I need it.
Thirty-three stories. God.
Massive subdural hemorrhage.
Significant left shift.
Big mass effect is
crushing his brain
inside of his skull.
Well, he did fall
off a building.
Craniotomy, right?
To what end?
He's coagulopathic.
I go in and take out the clot,
it'll just re-accumulate.
No, I don't think so.
I'm actively giving him
plasma, platelets, and cryo.
Which improve
his overall chances of
survival from 1% to 2.
I'm not opening up
his skull.
I question whether he's even
strong enough for this CT,
but that was your call.
If the pressure in his brain
isn't relieved, it's over.
That's 100%.
I got him this far.
He'll get through surgery.
All the king's horses
and all the king's men,
guess they should've
gone to you.
Full costume?
Cape and all.
When Edward learned
it had been destroyed,
he was so distraught,
he could hardly even breathe.
That's a pretty
extreme reaction,
but, you know,
wardrobe and self-esteem
can be deeply intertwined.
The costume, ultimately,
it's just a symbol
that represents something
crucially important to Edward.
Our job's
to figure out what.
The inciting incident
that made it necessary,
the origin story.
You know, because we're
talking about a superhero.
Mmm-hmm.
Like when Tony Stark
became Iron Man.
Why did Billy Batson
become Captain Marvel?
Nice. Pickle.
Urinalysis is clean,
so your infection
isn't from a UTI.
Clear.
Not pneumonia.
Meds?
Aspirin, midodrine,
tramadol.
No steroids,
immunosuppressants.
No red flags.
I'll check the D-dimer.
It could be a DVT.
Yeah.
Deep vein thrombosis?
D-dimer's negative.
No clots.
Abscess then.
The hot spot
would be the sacrum.
I can't...
Yeah, I got you.
Nothing dermal.
It must be hiding
deep down.
The scar...
I'm thinking of getting
a tattoo to cover it.
He and she stick
figures riding Pops.
It's a surf spot
in Waikiki.
We took a lesson
on our honeymoon.
We stood up on our first wave.
Did you feel something?
Um, I don't know. Maybe.
Let's get a CT chest,
pelvis and abdomen.
Infection may be abdominal
or in a deep space.
Yeah. Hang tight.
We're getting closer.
We'll be back.
You felt that?
Good hemostasis.
No new bleeds.
He tolerated
the surgery well.
Appears luck's
on your side today.
If that's how
you wanna put it.
There's no heartbeat.
No.
No, no, please. Look again.
I'm so sorry.
No.
You'll need a D&C.
If there's a room available,
I can do it now.
Okay.
I need to get back to work.
April, no one would
expect you to...
I have to. I...
There's a patient
I'm worried about.
Are you sure?
Okay.
Well, you know
the nurses up there.
You just give them
a call when you're ready.
The sooner the better,
though.
End of the day.
Tomorrow at the latest.
Hey, April.
Cardiology make
a diagnosis?
Viral myocarditis.
She's only in the ED
until a bed opens up
in the CCU.
She needs
cardiopulmonary support.
Infection's that bad?
Well,
the hope is partial bypass
will rest her heart enough
to let the antiviral
meds get the upper hand.
That's doing most
of my heart's job now.
I know.
It's hard to keep
your mind from racing
to that dark place.
Is there anyone I can call?
A family?
My parents are divorced.
Mom's in Idaho.
Dad's in New Hampshire.
I'm not ready to
deal with all that yet.
But I don't wanna be alone.
Will you sit with me?
As long as you need.
Thank you.
What was her name?
Rachel. Way out of my league.
I've always
been the quiet one.
She was the opposite.
I rode her coattails,
yet she still loved me.
And then it was over.
My wife was gone.
When did Rachel pass?
Last year,
ovarian cancer.
It took her so fast.
I couldn't help her.
I couldn't ease her pain.
I could only watch.
I was useless, weak.
And the suit?
Stumbled across it online.
I don't know
why I ordered it.
But when it came,
I tried it on,
and I felt different,
stronger.
I just want to be useful.
I just wanna be able to help.
I understand. Uh...
We'll come up with a plan.
Let me talk to my supervisor.
Hey, how was
your ultrasound?
It was fine. I was just
thinking about Melody.
She thought she
only had the flu.
Yeah.
Okay.
Hey, walk with me.
The CPS working?
A-line pulsatility
is decreasing.
Heart's beating less
and less on its own.
But it's only
been a few hours.
The meds need a while
to build in her system.
And we can't
speed up the process?
We can?
IVIG and plasmapheresis.
It's method to block
Melody's immune system
from attacking heart muscle
as it tries to clear
the infection.
Well, why aren't
we doing it?
The science is unproven.
The unknowns worry me.
The risk of anaphylaxis,
additional infections,
inflammatory side effects.
Will, she already coded.
Another one could be
right around the corner.
Isn't it worth
trying anything?
Not if it does
more harm than good.
Yes, and the suit
was how Edward dealt
with his wife's death.
See, I'm concerned
that if he leaves,
he's just gonna
go get another one,
and that will lead
him right back here.
Some knucklehead will
see him in that costume
and pick a fight.
"Let's see how tough
you are, super-guy."
Hmm. It's possible,
but is he having
any suicidal thoughts?
No.
And he's certainly
not a danger to others.
He literally presented
saving a woman's life.
I mean, he just doesn't
meet the criteria for
a psychiatric hold.
Okay.
There you go.
Thank you.
Dr. Rhodes?
Dr. Rhodes, wait.
Can you tell us about
the miracle patient,
Justin Pepper?
Please, anything.
MALE NEWS REPORTER:
The people want to know.
Well, uh the craniotomy
we performed was successful.
Uh, his blood pressure
is steady.
The bleeding in his chest
and belly has slowed.
So, fortunately,
we've been able to back off
of the transfusions.
Is he gonna pull through?
Well, it is still
too early to tell,
but we are fighting
the good fight.
Now, if all continues
to go well,
Ortho will be able
to start treating
his bone fractures tomorrow.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I've got to get back
to my patient.
What the hell was that?
My patient's doing well.
I didn't see why
the press shouldn't know.
Any interaction
with the media
goes through me.
I wouldn't have
let you come out here
and grandstand like that.
What if the patient dies?
You gonna hold
a press conference then?
Hey.
Thoracic hardware's
stabilizing the spine
around the T4 fracture.
Otherwise,
everything looks normal.
Colon has descended.
It could be a colonic
pseudo-obstruction.
They are common
in paraplegics.
Yeah, but I don't see
any free air or fluid.
Hmm, the infection's gotta
be hiding somewhere.
Let's try a white
blood cell scan.
Tag some of his own
infection-fighting cells
with a tracer dye,
and see where they go.
Let his immune system show us
where the hot spot is.
Good idea. I'll get on it.
Hey, Nat.
Yeah?
When I pressed
on Nick's abdomen,
I was below
a sensory loss level.
He shouldn't
have felt anything.
His abdominal
wall is inflamed.
When you applied pressure,
it fired off a signal.
If anything,
Nick felt nausea,
but nothing tactile.
He couldn't have.
Yeah, I guess not.
103.5.
It's gone up.
What about my heart?
Improvement?
Unfortunately,
it's not responding
the way I'd hoped.
I googled "myocarditis."
Severe cases,
people needed
heart transplants.
Am I one of them?
Possibly.
But we're not there yet.
There is another
procedure we can try,
IVIG and plasmapheresis.
But I have to warn you,
there are some risks.
What do you think?
If your heart
stops beating again,
it may never come back.
This procedure,
is it an operation?
No, an infusion.
It can be done right here
in the treatment room.
I'll be with you
the whole time.
Okay.
Gram-negative bacteria?
What is that?
It's a common germ found
in water, soil, plants,
the digestive tract,
sometimes the skin.
They don't always
lead to illness,
but when they invade somewhere
they are not endemic to,
you can get pretty sick.
So, what did
these germs get into?
The muscles
surrounding your spine.
There's an abscess
at the T4 vertebrae.
Is it treatable?
Yes.
A surgeon will make
an incision in your
back and drain it.
The hardware may need
to come out as well.
We'll do it today.
You'll likely feel
better immediately.
We're good, babe.
We're all good.
There is something
else, though.
In addition to the bacteria,
the biopsy showed
a cluster of cells
that are not native to
the paraspinal muscles.
The lab is still
trying to figure out
exactly what these cells are,
but they shouldn't
be there, nor do they...
They come from my body.
So, what are you
guys not telling us?
They're stem cells.
We've been going to Mexico
to get injections to
reverse the paralysis.
I'm gonna walk again.
I know that look.
You think we're crazy.
Abandon
a state-of-the-art hospital
for a clinic in Veracruz,
but what Nick needs,
we can't find here.
And between the FDA
and constantly
changing politics
and social taboos,
we just...
But leaving the country?
There is no oversight.
The bacteria that
caused your abscess
likely came from a treatment.
To ditch the wheelchair,
it's worth it.
You touched Nick's abdomen,
and he felt it.
He felt it.
I'm gonna walk again.
And Julia and I
are gonna get back
to the life
that we dreamed of.
The one that she deserves.
Okay.
We'll set up the surgery
to have the abscess drained,
then go from there.
Okay.
Sir, is everything okay?
Nurse? Somebody?
Oh, my God.
Uh, breathe, sir. Breathe.
Breathe.
Look at me, look at me.
Two seconds in,
four seconds out. Slowly.
I need some help!
Here, here, here.
What happened?
Uh, he suddenly
grabbed his chest.
He was short of breath.
All right, possible MI.
We gotta move.
Thank you.
Edward, are you okay?
Yeah, I think.
Uh, he needed help.
Okay, well, I saw.
You saved him.
And look,
in a hospital gown, no less.
Let me help you
back to bed.
What's happening?
Asystole. Crash cart
and a chest tray.
Got it.
Take over compressions.
Scalpels?
You're operating here?
There's no electrical
activity in the heart,
so I can't shock it back.
Internal CPR is
my only option.
Oh, my God.
All right.
Come on, beat.
Amp of epi.
One amp.
Come on.
All right, we've got a rhythm.
He's back. He's back.
Quite a turnaround.
I know, right?
I was worried I wouldn't
be able to pull it off
as smoothly as you,
but it worked out.
It's a new
world for Edward.
Is it?
Deception breaks
doctor-patient trust.
We don't manipulate.
We guide.
Your ruse provided Edward
with a moment of revelation,
not the framework
to build his future on.
I mean, trust me,
the costume is not
yet a thing of his past.
Okay, discharge
papers for Edward.
I'm gonna need
a little more time.
Oh. Okay.
He feels cold.
His blood pressure
is very low.
We're pushing meds,
but his heart is
really struggling
to circulate blood
through his body.
Justin is a climber.
He always has been.
Wow.
A few years ago,
he realized that rock
faces weren't enough.
Oh, he loved his life.
It's not over.
But his heart will
fail again, won't it?
If it does, I'll restart it.
I'll keep restarting it.
That last resuscitation
was so violent.
Your son still has a chance.
Does he?
Please, no more heroics.
Dr. Rhodes, I admit,
I wanted you to
be the hero today.
And I know you did, too.
But maybe it's time
to stop.
Hey.
Got an update from
the neurosurgical floor.
They just got started on Nick.
These foreign clinics,
$30,000 a treatment,
sometimes more.
The stem cells are shipped in
from all over the world.
There's no way to prove
they're even authentic,
and the success
rates on their websites,
totally unverifiable.
Scary, I know. But still,
stem cell research
is making huge leaps.
Yeah, maybe for
neurodegenerative diseases.
But spinal cord
injuries like Nick's?
That tech is years away.
Yeah.
Just give me a second.
Will, Will,
I need you in here.
All right, I gotta go.
Melody's A-line
pulsatility is fluctuating.
This just start?
A couple minutes ago.
Is my heart getting worse?
Uh. No, better.
101. Your temp's gone down.
It means your body's
starting to fight back.
I'm gonna be okay?
Well, we'll get
another blood test,
and if your white cell count
has improved as well,
and your heart
continues to strengthen,
then I'll dial
down the support.
Oh, my God.
Oh, God,
I thought for sure...
Thank you, April.
You saved my life.
Phew!
Oh, God, I was so scared.
You're good.
I should call my parents.
Of course.
Yeah, I gotta say,
I did not expect IVIG
and plasmapheresis
to be so effective,
let alone that quickly.
You know, maybe
coupling it with the CPS...
Or perhaps, you know,
maybe the meds just finally
worked on their own.
You know what?
Who cares. It worked.
Yeah.
Yeah?
We got the win.
Yeah.
You don't seem excited.
No, I am.
It's just a long day.
Yeah, but a good one.
Nice job.
Neurosurgeon said
everything went well.
I feel much better.
It's like night and day.
Mind if I take a look?
All good back there?
Yeah. No surprises.
Great. Ready to
put today behind me.
No pun intended.
Nick, when I was
examining your abdomen,
you thought you
felt something.
You didn't, did you?
Just my wife's eyes
desperately wishing I could.
These treatments
you're getting in Mexico,
they're not working.
And given your injury,
the chances
of paralysis being
reversed is almost zero.
I can't give up.
Stem cells can turn
into any part of the body.
Instead of curing you,
they could form
a mass or a tumor.
Please, don't get
any more injections.
I have to.
I love Julia
more than anything,
but there are intimacies
that I can't provide.
Our bond is built on hope.
It's what holds us together.
So, it doesn't
matter if you believe
the treatments won't work.
Julia does.
That's enough for me.
But you're risking
your life.
She is my life.
I don't want you to share
your concerns with her.
Okay.
Good luck.
Good luck?
Ethan, are you kidding?
Nat, I've met combat vets
who have been paralyzed.
The feelings of inferiority
can be overwhelming.
If you told them
a bottle of snake oil
might help them walk again,
they'd drink it every time.
So, you agree with
what Nick's doing?
I understand it, Nat.
It wasn't real.
The situation was staged,
but your response
was absolutely real.
But I shouldn't
have tricked you.
I thought building
you up from the inside
would help you
connect to your true self,
but I realize now
you've always known
exactly who you are.
The real goal is making sure
others can see that.
What's that?
A hospital volunteer vest.
I know it's not as flashy
as your other outfit,
but around here,
there are a lot
of people in need.
Seeing you in this,
they'll know you're someone
they can depend on.
Someone who can help them.
Think about it.
Hey.
Surgery?
I have Procedure
Room Three open.
I'll schedule you in.
Come on up.
April?
April.
I saw your name on
the list for a D&C.
It was my ultrasound.
There wasn't...
I don't know when.
I don't know why.
My baby's heart...
It stopped...
It's okay.
It stopped beating.