- ♪ Di dup da dip dip dow ♪
- ♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
MEREDITH: "I needed more time."
I can't tell you how often
I've heard surgeons say this
after losing a patient.
[CELLPHONE VIBRATES]
[SIGHS]
♪ What you got is working ♪
[CHUCKLES] Not me.
Oh, damn it. [SIGHS]
They're moving Suzanne to the CCU.
She's spiking fevers again.
She's got chest pain.
It just doesn't make any sense.
I know. I just hope Dr. Riley can help.
Who's that?
You know, the... the doctor
from San Francisco I'm bringing.
UCSF? I didn't tell you?
No, but we didn't do
much talking last night.
She's supposed to be
this diagnostic genius,
and I might have used your name
to lure her here.
Ooh, resourceful.
Look, at some point, we probably
should talk about this.
We will, but you should go
save Suzanne's life first.
♪
We think in time, we talk in time...
Doses per day. Life expectancy.
Take two and call me in the morning.
- Good morning.
- Is it?
- [DOOR CLOSES]
- Aww.
- Mwah.
[CHUCKLES]
Okay, come on, come back to bed with me.
[CHUCKLING] No, I wish.
I have to go check up on that foster
kid you brought in last night.
Joey, yeah. How's he doing?
That's what I need to find out.
He doesn't even know that his
brothers and sister were taken away.
[SIGHS]
Who has to tell him?
You're looking at her.
- I'm sorry.
- No, I'm sorry.
You asked me to try
to keep them together.
Miranda, we both know that
even the chief of surgery
has no power over Social Services.
Mwah.
- Keep me posted.
- I will.
- I love you.
- Mm-hmm.
Don't sleep all day.
You always tell me
not to let you sleep all day,
- and then you sleep all day.
- Mm-hmm.
And what is a heartbeat
if not a ticking clock?
I'm gonna sleep all day.
- A clock that's always counting down.
- [SIGHS] Whoa!
Hey, I'm sorry I'm late.
Kids were sick again.
Um... what's going on?
Pac-North's been purchased.
By the Fox Foundation.
[LAUGHS] That's...
What, really?
How? Why?
Well, you see, Catherine and I
got into a fight, and now...
And...?
And now we have to report to Grey-Sloan
and interview to keep our jobs.
[SIGHS]
- An interview with...
Don't say Tom Koracick.
- Tom Koracick.
- Ah...
[CRYING]
[SIGHS] Richard,
how big was this fight?
It was pretty big.
Does Karev know?
Eh, well, he's dealing with
family issues in Iowa.
I call him and tell him
the place was gonna close,
and he texts me
a "laugh until you cry" emoji
with a party hat.
[SCOFFS]
Hey, guys, happy first day!
- Hm.
- [SIGHS]
What?
Ooh, I'm nervous!
Like it's the first day
of school or something.
Wish I had one more day in your bed.
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS]
But I guess you don't.
Aren't you getting sick
of staying at my place?
I mean, there's no room
to put your stuff.
But, like, we could find room.
No, yeah, hypothetically,
but we're not at
the cohabitating step, right?
- Thank you.
- Right.
[HORN HONKS IN DISTANCE]
I mean, look, you'll love your own place.
You just gotta, you know, find one.
[SIREN WAILS IN DISTANCE]
[SIGHS]
WOMAN ON P.A.: Dr. Dees...
Dr. Dillon Dees to ICU.
Lads, say hello to Dr. Grey, please.
Hey.
- Hi.
- Nice to meet you.
There was a time
when they loved having a tour
of whatever hospital it was
I was working in.
Now they just want to know
where the cafeteria is.
Is there no school today?
- Parent-Teacher Conferences.
- Oh.
Come on, come on, come on.
Put it back.
Did I see a certain chief resident
leave the house this morning?
Did you?
Hmm, that's interesting.
So you're back together?
I don't know. Why are you so interested?
Hmm, I'm anxious,
and I deflect when I'm anxious.
Also I'm looking for examples
of love enduring hardships.
- [ELEVATOR BELL DINGS]
- [LAUGHS]
Well, I wouldn't go that far yet.
But the sex is great.
[ELEVATOR BUTTON CLICKS]
Does that count?
Doesn't hurt.
[TELEPHONE RINGING IN DISTANCE]
Don't worry, Link's not with me.
Why would I be...
I know that you're getting the
paternity results back today,
and I know that you've been avoiding him
ever since he said
that he wanted the test,
and I know that you're not
happy about it, either,
but Link may look like
a department store mannequin,
but he is actually human,
and he gets to have feelings.
He gets to be mad.
He gets to have doubts.
He gets to be upset
that he got taken for a ride.
It was not my intention to take...
Your intention
doesn't really matter here.
What matters is
the reality of the situation,
and when two people love each other,
they just need to be given
all of the information
so that they can process it and rise.
Because if given the chance,
they will rise.
Are you going through something?
[SIGHS]
Alex, uh, hasn't been returning my calls.
He says that
he's going through something,
and he needs time,
and if I didn't know better,
I would think he was getting revenge
for when I needed time.
But, um, I know he would
never do that, so...
I'm sorry. I'm anxious, and I...
Deflect when you're anxious.
Me too.
Link loves you.
Stop avoiding him.
♪
So, who are you bringing back?
TBD.
Don't act like you haven't decided.
It's not an act,
it's a managerial nightmare.
I promise, I'll let you know
as soon as I've made a decision.
What decision?
Foundation's absorbing Pac-North
and its employees.
- Oh...
- Yep.
In that event, uh, I'd like to
make some recommendations.
About the people you impulsively fired
to set in motion a chain of events
I'm still trying to clear up?
No, thank you, I'll conduct
the interviews myself,
and make my decisions.
And here I thought
you and I were making friends.
You did? [CHUCKLES]
That's so nice to hear.
♪
Causes of undulant fever
include brucellosis,
babesiosis, typhoid, leptospirosis...
Slow down, dude.
Oh, good Lord, people.
Just because you're injured
doesn't mean you can't shower.
Dr. DeLuca said
we could only eat and sleep.
- [SIGHS]
- BAILEY: Hey, what you got?
Blood cultures and ELISA came
back negative for all of that,
and her lymph node biopsy's
clear as well.
Which means no lymphoma.
- Right.
- Isn't no lymphoma a good thing?
[MONITOR BEEPING]
[WHISPERING] I don't want
to walk back there
and tell them that I have nothing.
Well, then, figure it out,
and you won't have to.
Burn!
Be part of the solution, Helm.
And, Simms, take a shower.
SUZANNE: Matty's 13!
I should have years before
she's in the kissing stage.
- What about Scott Thompson?
- Well, that was different.
He gave me a Styx record.
Well, maybe Taylor gave Matty something.
- Wait... Matty kissed Taylor?
- Yeah.
- Taylor Olson?
DELUCA: Good morning, Hadley.
Suzanne, how are you feeling?
[SIGHS]
She's been digging up dirt on you.
It's called research.
I didn't exactly have to do
a lot of digging.
Hospital Hell.
Did you see that article?
That piece was intended
to highlight weaknesses
within the entire health care system,
and the surgeon who wrote it
actually recently came back to work here.
You're... You're not gonna find better,
more competent care
in the whole Northwest.
[FOOTSTEPS]
[TELEPHONE RINGS IN DISTANCE]
Um...
Can I help you?
[BEEPS]
- [SCOFFS]
Excuse me?
[TABLET BEEPS]
INTERPRETER: I'm Dr. Lauren Riley. Right.
I'm here for a consult
with Dr. Meredith Grey.
It's nice to meet you, Ms. Britland.
Suzanne.
And you are...
- She is our master diagnostician.
- Oh, thank God.
I'm going to ask
about a billion questions
and run even more tests.
I will annoy you greatly,
but in the end,
it will be worth it, okay?
I like you already.
I want a full autoimmune panel,
a pericardial fluid culture,
and a cytology.
Immediately!
We... We already did those.
Do them again.
And page cardio.
I need to know
why the fluid is building up,
because it will happen again.
And can you tell Dr. Grey
I'm here already?
♪
Wow.
The competence is just slapping
me in the face right now.
Okay.
WOMAN ON P.A.: Dr. Picado, 4622.
Dr. London Picado, extension 4622.
Okay, folks.
A-As you can see, I've got
a lot of interviewing to do.
I'll be as efficient as possible,
but thank you for your patience.
Chief Karev is on personal leave,
so I've been acting as interim and...
Cool story, bro.
Okay, then, first up, Dr. Webber. Yeah.
[TELEPHONE RINGS IN DISTANCE]
You'll be happy to hear, uh,
Dr. Fox was, uh, very clear.
Your job is safe.
What's that supposed to mean?
Your wife wants you here
at Grey-Sloan, big guy.
She wants you here enough
to buy a craptastic hospital
and pretend it's
[CHUCKLING] an investment.
- No.
- No?
No, I thought I could do this,
because I miss Grey-Sloan,
because I miss Bailey
and... and Meredith,
and... and Bokhee and OR 2.
God, how I miss OR 2.
But if Catherine thinks she can
just move me where she wants
like she's playing chess
and I'm some pawn...
You're not a pawn.
A rook at least. Maybe a knight.
You tell Dr. Fox she can go to hell.
Look, I... I take it back.
You are her queen!
Well, checkmate!
Synced & corrected by -robtor-
www.addic7ed.com
You don't look old enough to be a doctor.
Well, I don't always feel
old enough to be a doctor, so...
[CHUCKLES]
When did the pain start?
Well, I first heard her gasp
about 20 minutes out of Tacoma.
We came here to attend
the Seattle Ballroom Championship.
We won first place five years
in a row back in our prime.
[CHUCKLES]
Can I check your abdomen?
Sure.
[GASPS]
Oh...
You should probably know she has cancer.
Stage IV colorectal.
Didn't respond to chemo...
- So we're living our best life.
- Mm.
Wow, okay, Irene,
I think you may have
an intestinal obstruction.
I'm going to admit you.
I'll have to get a CT and a few tests.
Do you think we'll be out in time
to go to the waltz showcase?
We'll cut the line if we have to.
[CHUCKLES]
MAGGIE: My success rates far outnumber
both national and international averages.
[CELLPHONE VIBRATES]
And, um, if you weigh my outcomes against
only the top programs in the country,
- you'll find that I still outperform...
- [CELLPHONE VIBRATES]
- Um...
- Are you gonna get that?
I'm sure it can wait. As I was saying...
I'm sorry, I'm being... I'm being paged.
I don't understand.
Catherine had me re-instate
your privileges last night.
But I had to bring you in here
to, uh, kill some time
so folks out there wouldn't feel
you were being shown favoritism.
Which you most certainly are.
[CHUCKLES]
Well, thank you so much.
Don't thank me, thank Altman.
She was gracious enough
to allow you back into her department.
It's my department.
It was, then you ghosted us.
Dr. Altman has had years of experience
running cardio floors.
So, she's home with two sick kids today,
so, uh, just make sure you
keep her posted on your service.
Okay.
Yeah.
And, uh, don't keep your patient waiting.
♪
Where are they?
I told you, I don't know,
but I need you to stay still
while I finish this exam.
Joey? Hi, I'm Dr. Bailey.
I was here last night when you came in.
Do you know where
my brothers and sister are?
I...
Um, are you
almost finished here, Dr. Kim?
Pulse is weaker.
We're gonna need a CT angio
and another chest X-ray, please.
WOMAN: Right away, Doctor.
Where are they? Are they okay?
- Tell me, please!
- Joey...
Joey, your siblings were here
when you came in last night.
Um...
They waited as long as they could, but...
- You reported them.
- I'm sorry.
I'm legally obligated when the kids...
To what?
Tear apart the only family I have?
They're with social workers.
You broke them up?
They aren't even together?
I honestly don't know,
but, no, they're safe.
Right, 'cause everyone knows
the foster system is so safe.
Uh, Dr. Kim has ordered some more tests,
so let's get those done.
In the meantime,
I will call Social Services
and find out what I can, okay?
♪
Suzanne, try to keep still for me, okay?
SUZANNE: Okay.
So, you lost 25 pounds two years ago?
Were you dieting?
I had a 6-year-old and an 11-year-old
who were maniacs
and never let me sit down.
Is that a diet?
And you never gained the weight back?
No, and I was more than happy
to throw out the mom jeans.
[BEEPS]
DELUCA: Dr. Pierce, what do you see?
That's not a good face.
There's too much fluid.
I need to do a pericardial window.
Okay, I need the dummy words.
It is a procedure in which
I make a small hole
in the membrane around your heart
to prevent fluid from accumulating.
HADLEY: This is ridiculous.
Suzanne, they want to cut into you again?
If we're starting over, then we
might as well do it someplace else.
We are not starting over.
- Yes, we are.
- [SCOFFS]
I approach my patients
as if I'm meeting them on their
first day in the hospital.
You'd be amazed at what can
slip through the cracks.
They don't even agree
on what they're doing.
I'm too tired to move, anyway.
Plus, my kids really like the
mac and cheese in the cafeteria.
- This isn't funny.
- Hadley, they're trying.
Let them.
DELUCA: Thank you.
We'll be back to prep you soon.
[MONITOR BEEPING]
[CONVERSATIONS IN DISTANCE]
[TELEPHONE RINGING IN DISTANCE]
WOMAN ON P.A.: Dr. Clark to the ICU.
Dr. Annabelle Clark to the ICU.
Where is Dr. Grey?
Uh, she's in surgery right now.
She's right there.
I'll go book an OR.
[CLEARS THROAT]
- Dr. Grey?
Dr. Lauren Riley.
It's good to finally meet you.
Oh, my consult from UCLA.
SF. UCSF.
Suzanne Britland
isn't your patient, is she?
I have consulted on her case.
Um, and I'm at a loss.
And I've heard great things about you.
[CELLPHONE VIBRATES]
It was great to meet you.
If you'll excuse me, I'm being paged.
♪
You lied to me.
I prefer the word "lured."
I prefer the word "leaving."
Okay, uh, Dr. Riley, look, please,
i-if you leave now
without cracking this case,
it's gonna drive you crazy.
It'll keep you up at night.
It's too rare, we're too lost,
and you're too good to just walk away.
♪
Okay.
Uh... You. What's your job?
Mabel Tseng. Second year resident.
That's great. Uh, uh, come on in.
Tom, a word.
Please, um, patience, Hunt.
Just, uh, patience.
Yeah, um, listen, it's just, you know,
you've interviewed
all the attendings but me,
and now you're interviewing
the residents.
And it just seems a little bit like
it's some kind of a game, Tom.
Don't worry, I'll have you out of here
in time for your wedding.
When is it, again?
I... I... I can't...
Uh, Dr. Tseng,
I'm sorry to keep you waiting.
- Yeah. Right this way.
- Thanks.
- Yeah. There we go.
- [SCOFFS]
WOMAN ON P.A.: Dr. Willem...
Dr. Harrison Willem...
[VENDING MACHINE WHIRS, LIGHT CLANKING]
- Hi.
Are you lost?
Uh...
Do you know how to get to the exit?
The nurse said
I could get some fresh air.
Oh. Which nurse?
- Nurse Jones?
- [CHUCKLES]
Good guess.
I would've gone with that or Smith.
- Let's go.
- What?
- No. Where?
- Back to your room.
Your unbandaged wounds gave you away.
[SCOFFS LIGHTLY]
So you don't need to worry.
[KEYS CLACKING]
They said wit wouldn't take long.
That's right, we'll have your
mom out in less than an hour.
Where's Hadley?
She and Mei Li went to go get Grandma.
She had too much wine
at the sports bar again.
[SIGHS]
Sweetie, I think that maybe
you and I should talk about
what happened on the field trip,
with you and Taylor.
Hadley told you?! She swore she wouldn't.
Honey, why would you want
to talk to Aunt Hadley about it
and not me? [COUGHS]
The principal only told her
because you weren't there.
I don't want to talk to anyone!
Matty, wait!
She only started doing that
when she realized I couldn't
physically follow her.
♪
Never have children.
[SIGHS]
[DOOR OPENS]
Hey.
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS IN DISTANCE]
Well, I'm happy you called.
The, uh...
Are the results back?
No. Uh, no, not yet.
Um, tonight.
I'm... anxious.
Got it.
What's gonna happen?
We meet back here at 7:00,
we look at a piece of paper
that spells out
the baby's biological paternity.
What's gonna happen then?
I don't know.
Okay.
But, um, could you try to know?
What happens with us
if we find out that it's Owen's?
♪
You said that you loved me.
Was that true?
Do you want to be with me, Link?
Do you want to be in this baby's life?
[SIGHS]
You and Owen have a complicated history.
♪
I mean, you left him when you found out
that Teddy was pregnant with his baby
because you knew how much
it would matter to him.
So it's crazy to me to think that
that history won't shape your future
if Owen's the father.
And my future.
I love you, Amelia.
I do. And I...
I need to know.
Okay.
♪
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOPPLER WHOOSHING]
You hear that?
- That's your blood flow. That's good.
- [DOOR SLIDES OPEN]
[DOPPLER GRINDING]
That's bad.
If you leave here now,
best-case scenario, we amputate your arm.
Worst-case scenario, you die.
- BAILEY: Karev?
- I caught him trying to leave,
thought I would tell him
what would happen if he did.
Joey, I spoke to Social Services,
and they told me
they do everything they can
to keep siblings together, so...
But we aren't related.
So, no, they won't.
We were all in a foster home together,
and... and things got real bad,
so we ran away.
I made a promise
that we would never split up.
I know you don't get it,
but I have to go.
I lived in 12 foster homes in 5 years.
For a few months,
I had these foster siblings
that I really loved.
When we got separated,
we came up with a system.
On Wednesday nights at 7:00,
I would call their foster home,
let the phone ring once,
and then hang up.
On Mondays,
they would do the same for me.
And then I got moved again, so...
Joey, I do understand.
They're little.
And they're scared.
And we were never
supposed to be separated.
- They're my family.
- I know.
But you can't help them
if you're dead, right?
♪
Oh, I guess Koracick gave
at least one person a job.
As not chief of my department.
How's Richard doing?
Not great. How's Catherine?
Mourning in her typical way...
traveling and buying
a bunch of extravagant stuff.
When we broke up,
I went online and bought a pair of jeans.
Catherine went to Paris
and bought a hospital.
[BOTH LAUGH]
[SIGHS]
Do you think there's any saving them?
I really don't know.
I hope so.
HAYES: Dr. Grey?
You haven't seen my boys
by any chance, have you?
Um, no.
Are they hiding, or just maybe wandering?
They're just trying to torture me
and make sure we're late
for the conference, you know?
[LAUGHS]
Sometimes I think I hate them.
No, I mean, I don't, obviously.
Maybe I do.
Oh, I don't know how you do it...
the kids, the job, stay sane.
Who says I'm sane?
- [CHUCKLES]
- The city shut off my water once
because I forgot to pay the bill,
and I didn't even notice.
My daughter had to tell me.
Dr. Grey?
I'll, uh...
I'll leave you to it.
This is bad.
It's... It's bad, right?
♪
MEREDITH: Ooh,
that's a lot of mets, Schmitt.
♪
[SIGHS]
[CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING]
You pulled up the wrong year, honey.
- It's 1983.
- No, just wait for it.
- Wait for it.
- Not '82.
No, hey, here. Yeah.
Grapevine underarm turn,
right forward across,
and that's the moment we won right there.
Immaculate. You were immaculate.
Always were.
We love the Internet.
Get to watch ourselves all over again.
[CHUCKLES]
Most people hate it
for that very same reason.
- Oh.
- [CHUCKLES]
- Irene, this is Dr. Grey.
- Hi.
Have you been having shortness of breath?
Because your lungs, uh...
You said it was a bowel obstruction,
so why are we talking about lungs?
I'm sorry, it's...
[INHALES SHARPLY]
MEREDITH: A bowel obstruction
is causing your pain, Irene,
but the cancer is...
is in your liver and your lungs,
and it... it has spread
throughout your body.
B-But...
Can you operate on... on... anything?
With this degree of metastasis,
your immune system
is severely compromised,
and I'm just not sure you would
recover from a surgery.
I can't recommend it.
♪ Not afraid to close my eyes ♪
I'm very sorry.
- ♪ Life's a game made for everyone ♪
- [SNIFFLING]
You're a doctor, sweetheart.
The doctor's not supposed to cry.
I'm sorry. It's, uh... It's allergies.
Dr. Schmitt will set up a consult
with our palliative care team,
and they will make sure
that you're comfortable.
Again, I'm very sorry I don't
have better news for you.
♪ When I'm wiser and I'm older ♪
BAILEY: I asked Ben
to look into his history.
Parents died in a car accident
when he was 5.
No relatives came forward,
and he's been bouncing in and
out of foster homes ever since.
Suction.
He's a good kid. [CHUCKLES]
- [MACHINE SUCTIONING]
- He's a smart kid.
He's a straight-A student.
And he's been raising
three foster siblings
on his own for months.
So what's gonna happen to him?
Nobody wants to adopt a 17-year-old.
All they see is someone
who is basically an adult
and figure that he can fend for himself,
but he's... he's not, and he can't.
♪ They tell me
I'm too young to understand ♪
KNOX: Welcome back, Dr. Pierce.
MAGGIE: Thank you, Dr. Knox.
Back? What does he mean "back"?
Where... Where were you,
and how long were you gone?
Are you rusty?
- Because...
- No, I was, um...
I took a...
She took a break... a short break...
and now she's well-rested
and she's ready.
And, Suzanne, Dr. Pierce is
an extraordinary surgeon.
You're in very good hands.
Okay, Suzanne?
Count back from 10 for me.
Taylor Olson is a girl.
My sister thinks that Taylor is a boy,
but my daughter Matty
was kissing a girl at school.
[CHUCKLING] Which means that my sister
basically just outed my daughter,
and she doesn't even know it.
Matty must be...
[SIGHS] furious, and...
[SIGHS] confused.
And I don't know... happy?
In love?
Definitely in need
of her cool, supportive mom,
and not her uptight Aunt
who never wanted to be a parent.
And my youngest, Mei Li,
she was already an orphan once,
so she will never recover
if I don't make it off this table,
so you can't let me die.
Got that?
[VOICE BREAKING]
My kids really need me.
Suzanne, we've got you.
♪ Didn't know I was lost ♪
♪ Wake me up when it's all over ♪
WOMAN ON P.A.: Dr. Bells to L&D.
Dr. Debra Bells to L&D.
Dr. Schmitt?
Norman, hi.
I'm paging
the palliative care department.
I understand.
But before you do that,
I... I wondered...
Yeah?
[CHUCKLES]
You remind me of my grandson.
- You want me to call him?
- No, no.
He's all the way back
in Baltimore, but...
you are kind.
And gentle.
Just like him.
And that made me think
that maybe I could ask
if you could do a sad old man
a very big favor.
Literally anything.
[RESPIRATOR HISSING]
Did you identify the phrenic nerve?
Yep.
Okay, and you have good mobilization
of the pulmonary ligament?
Ooh, decompression is good.
Did someone ask you to babysit me?
You have double-checked me on every step.
- Was it Koracick?
- Wasn't anyone.
I'm just really worried about Suzanne.
Did you listen to her
when we were putting her under?
She's not here for my feelings...
she's here for my hands and my expertise,
and that is my focus,
and it should be yours, too.
♪
[SIGHS]
Surgery was smooth?
Yes.
Good.
Okay, when she wakes up,
we need to withdraw all treatment.
All antibiotics,
all antifungals, and steroids.
ALL: What?
Why would we do that?
We've already tested
for infectious diseases,
malignancies, and autoimmune disorders,
and now we're at the point
where we have to consider
there's some clue that's being
suppressed by the medication.
We need it to present itself.
Dr. Riley... [SIGHS]
Suzanne needs those antibiotics
to treat a form of infection
that we can't find.
And the steroids
to treat her pericarditis.
If we do what you're saying,
she could go into septic shock
and be dead in days.
I don't know, Maggie, what do you think?
I think it's reckless and cavalier,
and I believe that you'd be making
a catastrophic mistake.
Make sure you follow up on the path
of those pericardial fluid analyses
and, uh, keep me posted.
♪
Dr. DeLuca, you asked me
for my recommendation.
This is it.
♪
I need you guys!
Uh, well, not all of you.
I-I need those guys.
Can they come to the cafeteria with me?
Yeah, go.
[SIGHS]
♪
Hey.
Need to rest my feet.
Yeah.
Need to rest my feet
every 50 yards or so these days.
[CHUCKLES]
- You mind?
- No, go ahead.
I'm a little worried that
all the rage seeping out of me
might infect you
or trigger labor or something,
but if you're willing
to chance it, then...
Who are we raging at?
Who do you think?
- Ah.
- Mm.
He made you interview for your old job?
No, he made me wait all day,
then he made me interview.
Now he's made me wait out here again
while he consults with Catherine Fox.
And you're doing it?
- Yeah.
- Why?
[SCOFFS] Because if
I give him just one reason
not to give me a job here, then he wins.
He doesn't like me.
He doesn't want me around.
You stole his girlfriend.
Hell yeah I did. [CHUCKLES]
[CHUCKLES]
- You won.
- Hmm?
You got the girl. You got the family.
You got the whole Megillah.
Just let Tom have his fun.
Or, you know, his pain.
'Cause that's what it is.
He's lonely.
He's in pain.
How do you do that?
Do what?
Feel everyone's feelings
so deeply all the time.
[SCOFFS]
It must be exhausting.
♪
- It really is.
- Hm.
♪
[SIGHS]
[COUGHS]
[DOORS CLOSES]
Norman.
What did you do?
Can you believe Mr. Grant still fits?
- My tux.
- [LIGHT LAUGHTER]
Irene Sholman, I'll never forget
the day we met.
You were across a dance floor,
yelling at the judges
for docking you a quarter point.
[LAUGHS]
It was love at first fight.
How I got so lucky, I'll never know.
May I have this dance?
I can disconnect your oxygen.
And whenever you need to stop,
I'll be right here, okay?
[OXYGEN TANK HISSES]
I don't have a gown.
I look terrible.
[GASPS] Oh!
You look exquisite.
[LENA HORNE'S "MOON RIVER" PLAYS]
♪
♪ Moon River ♪
♪ Wider than a mile ♪
♪ I'm crossin' you in style someday ♪
♪ Old dream maker ♪
♪ You heartbreaker ♪
♪ Wherever you're goin' ♪
♪ I'm goin' your way ♪
♪ We're after ♪
♪ The same rainbow's end ♪
♪ My huckleberry friend ♪
♪ Moon River and me ♪
♪
I figured you would've been
long gone by now.
RICHARD: I've already been to a meeting.
I didn't want to go home
to an empty house.
I'm not sure where I work,
so... here I am.
Come on, you work here.
Not by choice.
I chose to work at Pac-North,
even though I resented it.
We were building a new program
from the ground up.
And Catherine took it all away
with one phone call to the bank.
This'll pass, you know.
It feels bad now, but soon enough,
you guys will be
joking about this over coffee.
Son, after Godzilla's done
stomping all over Tokyo,
the mayor doesn't
take Godzilla to brunch.
Okay, you are heartbroken,
so I'll forget the fact
that you just compared my mother
to a giant lizard monster.
[CHUCKLES]
♪
[SIGHS]
Irene, how are you feeling?
Ohh...
Any trouble breathing? Any pain?
I'm still floating, dear.
♪
Is Norman...
He's calling the kids.
Don't be sad, darling.
Don't be sad.
I've had a beautiful life.
And I'm ending it
with a beautiful partner.
[CHUCKLES]
This life, it's just never
stopped surprising me.
♪
Have you met the love
of your life, Dr. Schmitt?
♪ All my life, I read between the lines ♪
♪ Held on too tight, you know I tried ♪
♪ But in the end, it left me paralyzed ♪
♪ It's all right, goodbye, goodbye ♪
[SIGHS]
BAILEY: I hate that he's all alone.
I hate that he has nowhere to go.
I was him, and Alex was him,
and we turned out okay.
It's not hopeless.
It's just not easy.
♪ It's all right, goodbye, goodbye ♪
[DOOR OPENS, CLOSES]
You okay?
♪
There was a time when
I would have made a dance floor
for the dying old lady.
What?
Andrew and I broke up
the night of my trial,
and there was a time
when that would've meant
months of drama for me.
But instead, I went home
and went to bed, and I woke up,
and I was just excited
to go practice medicine.
I used to be a romantic.
I would've been the one
to build the dance floor
in the cafeteria.
And now you're leaving
the dance floors to the interns.
[CHUCKLES]
You're not lacking in passion,
Grey, you're just...
growing up a little.
♪
What would you do if Ben dumped you?
I'd burn him to the ground.
- Hmm.
- [DOOR OPENS]
[SIGHS] Richard walked.
- What do you mean "walked"?
- [DOOR CLOSES]
I mean he left. He doesn't want
to work on Koracick's terms,
and, honestly, neither do I.
Are we just gonna let this happen?
No!
No, I'm not gonna sit by helpless
while my family gets split apart again.
You two, come with me.
HADLEY: Wait, what?
You said Dr. Riley never gives up.
It... I-It's not giving up.
We will be monitoring you
the entire time.
You want to take my sister
off all her medication...
how is that not giving up?!
As symptoms arise, we'll treat them.
It's scary, I know.
You don't know about anything!
That article was right.
This is the hospital from hell.
Please let me transfer you.
I will find you a specialist.
If I say yes, what's going to happen?
We will remove you
from all of your medication.
And you will get sicker,
and you'll feel more pain.
I know I'm asking you
to make an incredibly difficult decision,
and I'm sorry.
I have three sisters.
The oldest one is my hero.
The youngest one is my baby.
I changed her diapers, and
I will never let her forget it.
The middle one...
...is my best friend.
And if I were in Suzanne's position,
she's the one who would decide for me,
and that's why I'm talking to you.
Your sister's immune system
is too compromised
for her to be moved safely.
And even if we could move her,
you're not going to find
anyone better than me.
You may have noticed
that my ears don't work.
But because of that,
I have learned to listen
with my whole body.
When the medications are gone,
the disease can start talking
so I can figure out
what is wrong with your sister
and hopefully, we can save her life.
[MONITOR BEEPING]
♪
You have my permission.
Withdraw everything.
Okay.
♪
[SIGHS] Hey, uh, I...
I just wanted to say
I also have a sister,
and that that was...
I'm an only child.
♪
[CHUCKLES]
Oh, thanks for coming, Tom.
Close the door.
[DOOR CLOSES]
Have a seat.
You did great work today, Tom.
JACKSON: Such great work.
But the board,
of which most of us are members,
we've, uh, come to a decision.
We're all prepared to quit.
I'm sensing a "but."
But Dr. Fox wouldn't really like that.
You know, and as you said yourself,
she wants me here.
- I mean, she wants all of us here.
- Mm.
But, uh, she will truly wonder
why you didn't do all you could
to protect her crown jewel hospital.
I mean, you've only just recovered
from the Hospital from Hell article.
MEREDITH: We could blame me for that,
or we could just remember
that I'm a Catherine Fox
Foundation award winner
and a media darling,
and, I mean, you want me here.
You can't afford to lose
all your best doctors.
And truly, your inability to see that
could cause Catherine Fox to question
the whole chief of chiefs title.
And the salary.
And the benefits.
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
♪
- Name your terms.
- We're a family.
You have joined our family,
and some of us have come
to grudgingly respect you.
But you do not get to rule
this family with an iron fist.
Yeah, you don't get to play all day,
dangling our jobs over our heads
like a carrot.
What... I...
Wait a minute. I-I already did that.
Hunt and Webber get their jobs back.
Pierce and Altman become co-chiefs,
and you find the money to cover it.
And Alex Karev and Hayes can co-chief.
Or we all quit.
RICHARD: Agree to our terms, Tom.
And then you get to just
take all the credit with Catherine.
♪
[SIGHS]
[CHUCKLES]
♪
MEREDITH: The heart beats until it can't.
[SIGHS]
Our limbs move until they don't.
[CHEERING]
RICHARD: All right!
- OWEN: Nice!
♪ If it doesn't feel right
by now, I doubt it ever will ♪
Our brains imagine futures
we'll never see.
♪ Sometimes you reach a high,
and then there's only downhill ♪
♪ Silently we keep inside
beneath the surface ♪
What's wrong?
♪ Boiling, rising ♪
I... I... I don't just want sex.
Okay.
Nico, I want... [SIGHS]
I want a dance partner.
Not the flailing arms around kind,
but the kind that takes practice and...
communion.
The kind where you're in perfect step,
and you anticipate each other's needs,
and your heartbeats are in sync, and...
Is this a poem, or are you being literal?
[CHUCKLES]
Wait, I... I... honestly, I can't tell.
[SIGHS]
We're struggling to overcome
a simple, inescapable truth...
everything ends.
♪ It was like our worlds just crossed ♪
♪ We both know that they did ♪
♪ Silently, we keep inside ♪
♪ Beneath the surface ♪
♪ Boiling, rising ♪
- ♪ Violently we fight the tide ♪
- [SIGHS]
♪ Till it turns on us ♪
But for every clock that
counts down, another restarts.
- [CELLPHONE CHIMES]
- ♪ Say what we don't wanna say, ♪
♪ But we've both been thinking
Make it easy on you ♪
_
♪ It's like we both see the shore ♪
♪ But we can't stop sinking ♪
♪ Hanging on for the sake of it ♪
♪ We fell in love for the ache of it ♪
Time goes on,
and when one thing ends,
something new always begins.
♪ And this might hurt ♪
♪