Come on, baby.
Oh, my God!
Help me!
Whoa, I got a pumper.
He's going to need an airway.
Stop moving around.
Scissors. Anybody?
We got a pressure?
70/40.
Pulse weak and thready at 150.
Buddy, you see who shot you?
You get a plate number?
He's not talking right now.
Start the O-Neg on infuser
and somebody find Lewis.
I feel a bullet.
I don't want to
die. You'll be fine.
Let's get a head C.T.
Where's Lewis?
How should I know?
Please don't let me die!
Jerry!
Jerry! Have you seen Dr. Lewis?
Curtain area three
with a heart attack.
Yo-Yo Ma plays the cello.
Get Benton out of the O.R.
Pregnant woman's coming in
with a gunshot to the abdomen.
How far out?
Two minutes or less.
Got it.
Your history suggests that
the pain may be heart-related.
Susan, Mark needs
you in Trauma Two.
Gunshot wound to the neck.
Okay, be right there. Does
C.C.U. have any beds?
Still backed up from last night.
Okay, we're going to
have to hold you down here
until a bed opens up
in the cardiac care unit,
and then we'll send you
up as soon as we can.
My baby!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Go, go, go.
B.P.'s 90/60.
Pulse is 120.
Come on, take it easy.
She's full term,
I need a fetal monitor from
L&D and doctor's scope.
Damn it!
Are you okay?
Watch that damn gurney? Damn.
We need a fresh gurney in here.
Belenzela with a "B" or a "V"?
Connie, get ultrasound in
here. Do the paper work later.
Please, please!
Is my baby all right?
Uterus tender, no exit
wounds. Let's prep for a pelvic.
Call OB.
We need a type
and cross, four units.
Where's everybody?
12 GSWs, four critical.
Glass is flying,
it's a real mess.
Pulse ox 95, BP
90/60, pulse 120.
Two hours late.
What? Carter.
Upstairs. I'm going to have
to run the blood up myself.
All right. Not dilated.
Vertex presentation.
Fetal heart rate's 145.
That's good. That's very good.
Lydia, I need you to
stay put. We need you.
I'm not done next door.
Where the hell is Carter?
Oh, God.
Oh, God, oh, God...
Oh, God! What is all this?
Traffic.
Can't you do something?
Like what?
Stop the cab.
No problem.
Keep the change.
Oh, God.
It still hurts so bad.
It started when I was
shopping for my children.
Fill that out, please.
Would you like to see
pictures of my grandchildren?
I always bring them with me.
I have four sons and
three grandchildren...
ER. Yeah.
Yeah, I'll hold.
Look at him. Isn't he darling?
Excuse me? And here's Jeff...
Where the hell is psych?
All blond and very... Excuse me.
Hang on, will you, please?
Oh, they're so...
I miss them so much.
Oh, Dr. Lewis. Bipolar.
I called psych, but there is
something wrong with her leg.
Got another gunshot coming.
Put her on the board
and hope psych shows up.
It was that
son-of-a-bitch cardiologist.
My sister met the president.
Excuse me!
What?
Thank you.
We're the new
third-year students.
We're looking for Dr. Greene.
You're a med student?
Yeah.
Anybody know how
to take a history?
Sure.
Mrs. Constantine? I
was not a cat person...
Mrs. Constantine, this is...
Harper. Harper Tracy.
This is Dr. Tracy.
Harper? Harper!
I knew someone who played
in the New York
Philharmonic named Harper.
I played with him.
You're going to go to
Exam Two Right over there.
Do you like Paul Newman?
I love those blue eyes.
All right, hang two units.
All right, Peter.
What have you got?
Full-term abdominal
GSW, no exit wound.
Baby's moving, heart's beating.
I think the bullet's
in the uterus.
Sounds like a section.
Fetal heart rate's
falling... 100.
How's mom?
80/50, pulse 140 and climbing.
Is my baby okay?
Free blood in the peritoneum.
All right, we're moving her now.
Call the O.R., let them
know we're on our way
with an emergency
section and get OB.
Peter, what happened to you?
Don't ask.
Can you handle this?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I
just need to walk it off.
You're having your baby!
Oh, no.
GSW to the head.
Two large-bore IVs,
pressure's 60/40,
bradycardic at 50.
All right, Lee, Trauma One.
What happened?
Gang fight. Nice shirt.
I'm a dead man.
Hey! Welcome back, Carter.
Hey, Dr. Carter, I presume.
What's up, Carter? Great tan.
Thanks.
Jerry! Where's Dr. Benton,
and has he been asking about me?
Yeah, once or twice,
and he's up in surgery.
Crash section...
Pregnant woman got shot.
He just limped up.
Hi, Dr. Greene!
Hey! Who is that?
Carter, I think.
Dr. Benton's student.
Well, tell him to slow down.
I am on the phone with
cardiology every day.
They claim the CCU's full.
I go up, and there
are empty beds.
We had a rule-out MI
down here for two days.
Hey, you're an attending now.
You got a problem
with another department,
You solve it.
Oh, and you've got new
third-years coming in today.
Today?
Four of them. Bright-eyed
and bushy-tailed.
And staff meeting
at 4:00, don't forget.
Forget what?
My first staff
meeting's today at 4:00.
Hey, little boss, what'd
the big boss want?
Something about me accepting
the heavy mantle
of my new position.
You set the tone?
You got the drift.
Hey, how are you set for cash?
Oh, so you need
that 200 bucks back?
I'm a little strapped for cash.
No, no, no. I'll make you
up a schedule for next week.
I thought maybe you could
pull a graveyard attending shift,
put a little extra
cash in your pocket?
Really? Yeah.
Consider it done.
Great. Dr. Greene?
Yeah. I got three lost sheep,
claim to be medical students.
I thought there were
supposed to be four of them.
One's doing a
history of a bipolar.
Should be done by next Tuesday.
All right. Uh... this way,
guys. I'm Dr. Greene.
Jerry, you got anything
of the pediatric
persuasion up there?
I've got a Scandinavian
flight attendant
with a bum ankle and an earache.
And you saved her all for me?
I love you, big
man, you know that.
Nine months pregnant.
Couldn't find the bullet?
It's got to be in the
uterus here somewhere.
Her pressure's barely holding.
There's no time to waste.
Dr. Benton.
Carter, don't bother
coming in here.
I'm sorry. I came
straight from the airport.
Retract the bladder flap.
Big storm in the
Gulf. Hurricane Phyllis.
Your student?
Don't remind me.
Nice tan.
So, student, what
is the most important
anatomical
structure to identify?
Uh... the uterus?
Ureter.
Cut that, you're in
trouble... She can't pee.
What's its name?
Carter.
Carter, basic anatomy:
what muscle forms the floor
of the pelvis?
Uh...
Levator ani. Ah!
The ovarian artery
comes off the aorta, just a...
I know the ovarian artery
comes off the aorta to, uh...
Inferior mesenteric artery.
The word "student."
doesn't that imply
that you're actually supposed
to be teaching him
something, Peter?
Hello.
I'm Dr. Ross,
and you must be...
Hulda.
What a beautiful name, Hulda.
What seems to be the problem?
I hurt my ankle, and
it hurts very much.
Let's take a look at it.
A man dropped his little
vodka bottle in the aisle,
and she slipped.
It tickles.
Haleh, lateral A.P. and
oblique views, please.
Hulda, it doesn't
seem to be broken.
We're going to get some x-rays
and we may want to
consider a cast, just to be safe.
Oh, and my ear.
It's very sore.
For many months, all this...
going up and
coming down, I think.
Yes?
Look, we're really busy today,
and I didn't know
you were coming,
so you're going to
have to park yourselves
in here for a while,
and I'll come round you up
when I get a minute, okay?
Here you go.
Harrison's Principles
of Internal Medicine.
Rosen, volumes
one, two, and three.
Start reading.
Hey, who's that?
Med students.
I gave them Harrison's.
Wow. That'll keep them busy.
I need you in Curtain 2.
Yeah, sure.
Listen, there's another student
floating around some
place with a bipolar.
Could you try and find them?
Yeah.
So who's going to
be the new chief?
You.
Yeah, I wish. Maybe
next year when I'm eligible.
Who do you think it should be?
Jane Pratt... she's smart, nice,
easy to work with,
everybody likes her.
Jane's great.
Yeah. It's your decision, right?
Well, I'll find that
out this afternoon.
You guys were roommates
for a while, right?
Yep.
Me.
How you doing, sir?
I'm not so good.
I got a headache.
It's probably the nitro.
Why is he still down here?
CCU's full again.
Sir, you're going to have
to stay down here
for a little longer,
so if you can just relax
and enjoy the peace and
enjoy the peace and qu...
Jerry! For God's sake!
Shut him up, will you, please?!
Silencio, por favor.
I'll try cardiology again.
Thanks. So, it's Jane
for chief resident?
Why not?
Carter, get ready to suction.
Here she comes.
How does she look?
She's breathing.
Color, tone, fair.
Apgar?
Eight.
Cord's cut.
Benton, you stay
with the mother.
Carter, come with me.
All right.
No exit wounds in the uterus.
Okay, Carter, see the hole?
Uh... oh, yeah, thighs.
We got through-and-through
gunshot wounds
through both thighs.
Doesn't look like
it hit any bone.
Got it! In the placenta.
Cut the umbilical line.
Good. Carter, you can
start dressing the wounds.
Rocephin and oxacillin,
250 milligrams each.
Displace the uterus anteriorly.
Check the other organs
for penetrating injury.
Hi. Hell of a way to
make an entrance.
This is your lucky day.
I'll run the bowel.
Oh, you're going
to be fine, just fine.
Yes, you are.
You jet-ski?
That's me. No way.
Haleh, diet or regular?
Unleaded.
Hey, hey. Listen up, everybody.
We don't have a lot of time.
Admin sent us
another action memo.
Excessive use of
surgical supplies.
What?
Personnel must exercise prudence
in the use of expendables
i.e., 4x4's, gloves,
surgical tape, suture kits.
Why don't I just bring a
needle and thread from home?
And alcohol wipes.
Next, ACLS.
Steph, you're up October 1st.
And, Wendy,
you've never certified.
What is it?
Don't worry, honey.
You're going to love it.
Okay, CPR re-certification.
Lily, Lydia, Haleh,
Saturday afternoon, 1:00.
This week?
Aw, man, I've got Sox tickets.
Okay, MICN ride-alongs.
Joanie, you've got to get
your hours in before Halloween.
And, Lily, if it makes
you feel any better,
I've procrastinated,
and now I have to do
a paramedic ride-along
in the next 10 days,
or I lose my certification.
Are you happy?
Mm-hmm.
Last but not least...
the hated peach.
They have stopped making
this particularly delightful shade.
Take a look at the catalog
and get back to
me with your choice.
I look bad in that green.
Carol, 47's three minutes out
and they're in trouble.
Okay, everybody, I need your
picks by the end of the day.
Most votes wins
unless I hate it,
and then, whatever I like goes.
What is this all about?
Air conditioning repairs.
Mark, hi.
Oh, hi, Jane. How you doing?
Susan told me that
she had talked to you
about my becoming
chief resident.
Well, I just wanted
you to know that
I didn't put her up to it. I
know you two are good friends,
and I do want the job, but I
didn't ask her to approach you.
No, I didn't think you had.
I hear Kerry
Weaver's interested.
Weaver over at Mount Sinai?
She'd do a good job.
I'll do it better.
All right. Thanks.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
I thought I'd left enough time.
You get here an hour before me,
you leave an hour after me,
You pre-round my
patients before I arrive,
you order tomorrow's
labs after I leave,
you check out my
surgical schedule,
and you study the
cases the night before.
What'd you get read this summer?
Schwartz's
Principles of Surgery?
Sabiston's Essentials?
Surgical Secrets?
Let me get a turkey
breast on whole grain.
Lettuce, tomato,
extra sprouts, no mayo.
Carter, you reflect on me now.
You screw up, I screw up.
You don't know the
answer to some question,
that's because I
didn't teach you.
Hey, no mayo.
What do you want, Carter?
Could I get a polish dog
with extra onions,
extra peppers,
and cheese?
A lot of cheese, please.
Surgery is the most
difficult specialty of all.
Fifteen students
wanted this spot,
and at least 100 will
want the surgical residency
that you're applying
for next year.
Now, you want to be a surgeon?
Well, then you start
acting like a surgeon.
I've got a thyroidectomy
this afternoon.
What do you know about
the arteries in the neck?
There's a lot of them.
You have an hour and 25 minutes.
I suggest you locate a Gray's
and start memorizing it.
Hi. I'm Dr. Greene.
What seems to be the problem?
I have a rash on my thighs.
Anywhere else?
Not this time.
Why don't you hop up on the bed
and we'll take a look.
Um, Ms., uh...
Sweet. Loretta Sweet.
Sweet.
Are you sexually active?
No. Mostly, I just lie there.
You use condoms?
If I owned the factory,
I'd be rich by now.
Looks like contact dermatitis.
Is that bad?
No. A little cortisone
cream will clear it right up.
You must be allergic
to something you came
in contact with.
Right.
I'd try to avoid
coming into contact
with it again in the future.
Okay? Okay.
I got two kids at
home, you know?
Is there anything
else I can do for you?
No, thanks.
Anytime.
Adult male found passed
out in his own vomit.
BP, 80/50 on
arrival. Pulse is 132.
Resps shallow at 24, tremulous.
Stopped breathing
two minutes out.
I can't ventilate him.
Cyanotic. Pulse up to 170.
That's airway obstruction.
We've got to move
him fast. Let's go.
He's had glucose and Narcan.
Daddy!
The kid found
him. He called 911.
Out of the way! Out of the way!
Daddy!
Nope.
Damn it!
Somebody get Mark in here.
We need a crike tray now.
Here. Take over.
No sign of trauma.
He's got two IVs
with saline wide open,
one liter so far.
We've sucked in 500 CCs of
blood from his upper airway.
One, two, three.
Again. One, two, three.
How much time do we have?
Almost three minutes.
Where's the damn doctor?
Daddy!
Again.
One, two, three.
We're out of time. Crike him.
Again. Harder.
Get this kid out of here!
Get him out of here!
You're not going to die on
my shift, you son of a bitch.
Come on. Come on.
I got it.
All right, hyperventilate him.
Daddy! Daddy!
All right, what do we got?
Airway obstruction. Male.
One, two, three.
Approximately 35 years of age.
Tremulous. Possible
impending D.T.'s.
Maybe septic, maybe stroke,
metabolic derangement.
Daddy! Daddy!
All right. CBC,
Chem-19, coag panel,
UA and a chest.
Push D-5 normal
saline. He's dehydrated.
Get the banana bag going.
Carol, get a blood gas.
Coming up.
Doctor!
Who the hell is that?
Some drunk looking
for a hot meal.
Doctor!
How long has he been at it?
About an hour.
It's damn irritating, isn't it?
At least he hasn't learned
how to say nurse yet.
Nice tan. Thanks.
What's that?
Anatomy of the neck.
Forget it. Too many arteries.
Exactly. I thought this
year was going to be easier.
Wait till you start
your residency.
Want to show a third
year how to start an IV?
No.
You haven't seen her yet.
I shave my legs.
I used to wax them,
but that hurts so much.
I love candlelight
and Christmas music,
and the smells...
the mulled cider and chestnuts.
I haven't had a
chestnut in years.
Hi. You the new med student?
Yes. Thank you.
Harper Tracy.
John Carter. How's it going?
I've been trying
to take her history,
but so far, we haven't
gotten past the Crimean War.
You're very handsome.
Are you a doctor?
My son's a doctor.
I play the cello.
Do you like music?
Yes. Sometimes.
This is Mrs. Constantine.
I think she has cellulitis
in her left lower extremity.
It's swollen, warm and tender.
Haydn, Bach, Saint-Saëns.
Cellulitis sounds about right.
Are you in any pain, ma'am?
The pain?
♪ The pain, the pain
stays Mainly in my brain ♪
I think she's got it.
By jove, she's got it.
She's also clearly bipolar.
Right. Dr. Lewis wanted me
to show you how to start an IV.
Pull this little gizmo out,
find your vein, go in bevel up,
skin taut,
advancing slowly
till you see a flash.
Needle out, cath in.
Thanks. Got it.
Really?
Yeah, I got it.
Madrid, Tokyo, Milano,
Buenos Aires, Barcelona.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
You hit it the first time.
Second chair.
I should have been first chair,
but the conductor...
That bastard...
Was sleeping with
a fat, Italian girl
who could not carry a tune.
Sex! Sex! Sex!
Same with my husband.
He doesn't care...
Thanks. I can take it from here.
But I could dance all night.
Okay, then, uh... great.
I would like to put the
moon under my heels,
and go flying up,
up, up into the sky.
Hey, Jerry, do you
know where the kid is
from that alcoholic
airway obstruction?
Hmm.
Thanks.
You sure it's not that one?
Nice shirt.
It's all I had.
What you doing?
Noah's fixing the VCR.
Has a tape stuck in it.
You be cool now, Noah, you hear?
Your dad's going to be okay.
I know.
He's going to have to
stay with us for a while.
Is your mom coming?
She lives in Florida.
Is there someone else
who could come get you?
My dad'll take me
home in a while.
He never stays in the hospital.
He's done this before?
And you called 911.
That was very smart.
Have you done that before too?
Lots of times?
Do you have a Phillips head?
Sure.
You really know
what you're doing.
Is he still down here?
Kayson says he
doesn't have any beds.
I think we're being followed.
Student.
Uh, Harper Tracy.
Greene, Mark.
No, actually, my
first name is Harper.
The bipolar?
Off her meds.
Psych got her back on lithium,
admitted her for
IV for antibiotics.
How's the Jell-O, Mr. Kuzner?
Delightful.
We are going to have you
out of here as soon as we can.
Jerry, how long
is it going to be
until we get this air
conditioning fixed?
A week ago Thursday.
Oh, didn't they find asbestos
in this building a
couple of years ago?
Oh, not again.
Kiss little Suzie for me.
Yeah.
Ah!
Dr. Lewis, pour vous.
A little taste from the islands.
Oh, thank you.
Dr. Greene.
Yeah?
I have something for you.
There you go.
Oh, thank you.
Carol?
Hmm?
Oh, Carter, it's beautiful.
Thank you.
All right.
Carter?
Where are my charts?
Maybe you should have saved
one of these for yourself.
Oh, but I did.
Hey.
Here you go.
Jerry, why are there
three kids in cheap ties
reading textbooks in Exam 3?
Oh, damn, the med
students. I forgot.
Dr. Greene, staff
meeting's in five.
Could you see if
they need anything
and tell them I'll
be back in an hour?
Sure. Right.
Uh, Dr. Ross, a little
taste of the islands.
Carter, you shouldn't have.
It's Wondoa. He's
the god of fertility.
Just what you need, Doug.
Come on, Mark,
I'll walk with you.
To the staff meeting?
Yeah, I'm nurse
manager. I always go.
Nice hat.
See you.
Yeah, see you.
Carter. Yeah?
O.R., let's go.
You should really
put some ice on that.
I'm fine.
I think I've got the
neck arteries down.
There's the Common
Carotid, Superior Thyroid...
Thyroidectomy's called
off. We're doing a hernia.
I hope you know your way
around Hesselbach's Triangle.
Folks, can we get started?
Please, can we start on time?
For those of you who don't know,
Mark Greene is joining
us as an attending,
now that he's
completed his residency.
Mark, have you
given any thought as to
who should succeed
you as chief resident?
I was thinking Jane Pratt
would be an excellent choice.
She that blond,
always wears sweaters?
Uh... no, brunette, tall.
She's very smart,
uh... well-liked.
Easy to get along
with, very competent.
That's pretty much how
I would describe you.
You might want to
consider someone
Who would complement
your weaknesses.
Which are?
Discipline, paper work,
administration.
Any other candidates?
She'd be my first choice.
Carol, any thoughts?
Pratt's the best
of this year's crop.
She'd take the
least baby-sitting.
Mark, you know Kerry
Weaver over at Mount Sinai?
Only by reputation.
I'd like you to meet her.
Okay.
Can we get this Ross
thing finally resolved today?
Oh, Neil.
Look, I know nobody
thinks this is important,
but I don't understand
why my pediatric
budget is carrying the cost
of an ER fellowship
for Doug Ross.
It's an ER Pediatrics
fellowship, Neil.
Okay, then put him
under my supervision.
I'll keep him in the clinic
where I'm severely understaffed,
and when there's a real
pediatrics emergency,
you can call him down.
They need him
in the ER full-time.
Then let them pay!
They're severely
under-budgeted and you know it!
I like Ross, but he
is a bit of a cowboy.
A bit?
David, he's arrogant and
dismissive of my authority.
Now, I'm warning you right now,
when his fellowship comes
up for renewal in November,
I'm not going to sign off on it.
You want him,
you find the money for him.
Let's jump off that bridge
when we get to it, shall we?
Okay, Mark,
we need to talk about who covers
the attending swing shifts.
It's a nice piece of change.
Any thoughts?
Uh, no.
I'll... I'll get you
some names later.
Next on the agenda,
we've got a JCAH
inspection coming up.
Come on, people.
This is what allows us to
call ourselves a hospital.
Help me, please!
Somebody, help me!
It's my brother. Please!
He fell off the boat.
Grab the gurney on the side.
Come on, man.
No spontaneous resps.
Come on, Jimmy.
Get an ambu-bag
and set up suction.
Jerry, Trauma 1 open?
No, air conditioning
guys are down there.
Curtain 2.
Get respiratory here
stat! He's not breathing.
Lily, we're going
to need a scribe.
Pulse ox is 80. He's hypoxic.
E.T. Tray, seven and a half.
Please, what's happening?
Sir, you're going to
have to wait outside.
Someone get these
air conditioning guys
out of here now.
Anybody get a blood gas?
Please, please.
Tracy, get over here
where you can see.
Oh, god.
Don't do this, man.
Core temp's 82.
CBC, Chem-7, coag
panel, chest film.
Don't die, please.
Are those meetings
always that much fun?
Kind of boring this week.
Nobody took a swing at anybody.
Do they always talk about
the residents like that?
Want to hear what they
used to say about you?
No.
That drunk with the kid? He's
trying to check himself out AMA.
Okay, and Mark, I knows
it's none of my business,
but Jane Pratt?
I think Morgenstern has a point.
Listen, buddy,
I didn't get a chance
to thank you earlier
for the attending shifts.
It's going to make
a real difference.
I'm kind of behind
in my car payments.
Listen, you did some of your
residency with Kerry Weaver.
Yeah, we crossed paths.
Morgenstern wants me
to consider her for Chief.
Really?
That bad?
Did you ever see Cuckoo's Nest?
I hear you're going some place.
Yeah.
Where's my kid?
Noah's in the lounge
watching cartoons.
Well, get him, we're going home.
You're suffering from
severe electrolyte imbalance.
Your white blood count is high,
and you probably have pneumonia.
I just need to sleep it off.
You need to be admitted
for fluids and IV antibiotics.
So you can charge me
5,000 bucks like last time?
Let's talk about last time.
Paramedics found you
drowning in your own vomit
on the living room floor.
Your son called it
in, just like today.
Where's my damn shirt?
We had to cut it off you.
I paid 30 bucks for that shirt.
Who's going to pay
me for that, you?
Somebody... I swear to God,
somebody's going
to pay for that.
Find that shirt.
You're not going anyplace.
I don't know why,
but for some reason,
that boy cares about you.
Why don't you stay,
get straightened out,
give Noah something
to be proud of?
He's not warming up fast enough.
He's in V-fib.
Damn it, let's shock
him. Two hundred.
Clear.
Harper, clear.
Nothing. Three hundred.
Clear.
Man, someone get
them out of there!
Hey! Hey! Get down out of there!
What?
Come down now.
Three-sixty.
Clear.
Hey...
We've got a beat.
Hey, Davey,
are you okay?
What are the borders
of Hesselbach's triangle?
There's some kind of vessel.
Deep inferior epigastric.
A ligament? Poupon?
That's a mustard.
Poupart's ligament
and the rectus sheath.
You didn't get one of Dr. Hick"
questions right, not one.
Maybe because that's
because you told me
we were doing a thyroidectomy.
You embarrass me in
front of another surgeon,
and you'll spend
the rest of your sub-I
suturing bagel
cuts and baby falls.
Rescue 47's on its way.
The gang shooting this morning...
Somebody shot the shooter.
Uh... Dr. Greene?
Heard a lot of great
things about you.
I'm, uh... Kerry Weaver.
Oh. Hi. Hi.
I'm Mark. Sit down.
Oh, thank you.
Just eating something.
So, Morgenstern
says you're going to need
a lot of help around here.
Really?
Going to finish those fries?
Oh, no.
Uh, when do I start?
All right, people, we all set
for this guy's airway? Yep.
What happened?
Some guy fell through the
ceiling, landed on a patient.
You're kidding? Broke two of
the patient's ribs and his own leg.
15-year-old male, shotgun
to the chest at close range.
No vitals, no
pulses, no nothing.
This the shooter from
the pregnant lady?
So they say.
And go.
His chest is a mess, you guys.
Carter, CPR, six units
O-neg. Let's move.
Tube's leaking.
Asystole.
Oh, man! I think I just
punched right through his ribs.
Skip it. Let's tube him.
Amp of epi.
Carter.
Seven and a half.
I'm kind of rusty at this.
Find the cords and
thread it through, Carter.
Do it now, Carter.
Pull it, pull it, pull it.
All right. Let's crack him.
Ah! I got it.
Spreader!
Carter...
Retract that lung.
Here we go.
Come on. Just take a
deep breath, all right?
Okay.
I need you to stay
on your feet here.
He's totally dry.
Trendelenburg!
I think I'm going to be sick.
No, you're not.
Come on. Internal CPR.
He's fibrillating.
Damn! His right
ventricle is hit.
Twenty-five. Clear.
We got a beat.
Nope. It's gone.
Fifty. Clear.
Asystole.
Well, that helped a lot.
Man, smells kind of like
a barbecue in here, huh?
Oh, God.
Welcome back, Carter.
Oh, no. Please...
He's going to be okay.
Thank you.
He, uh... he does have
a couple of broken ribs.
All right. That's it.
Good try, people.
He was dead before
he came in the door.
Who's got the death bundle?
I'll get it.
You all right?
Good. Sew him back
up, nothing fancy.
I'll see you in the morning.
- 00 a.m. sharp.
And, Carter.
Prostatectomy in the morning,
adrenalectomy for a
pheochromocytoma
in the afternoon.
Hi, guys.
Here's your equipment.
The kid make it? No.
It's Hathaway, right?
Yeah.
This is Shep. Raul.
See you around, Hathaway.
Oh. Hey, guys.
I have to do a ride-along
for my MICN re-certification.
Do you mind if I tag along
with you some time next week?
Sure. You bet.
Anytime... Hathaway.
What?
Nothing.
It's not like that.
I didn't say a thing.
So, Nurse Hathaway,
what are you doing tonight?
I thought maybe I'd rent a
movie, make some popcorn.
Sounds good to me.
Maybe I'll bring a pizza.
I don't remember inviting you.
No, you didn't.
I invited myself.
Hello! Night, all.
Good night.
Cardiology still hasn't taken
my rule-out MI to CCU.
Susan, I can't miss this train.
What's the point of
having a cardiac care unit
if you can never
get anyone into it?
If I don't make it
to Union Station in 25 minutes
I'm going to be walking
home to Milwaukee.
Mark, you need to do something.
I will. I promise.
First thing Monday, okay?
I heard you hired
Kerry weaver as chief.
That's definitely a move
in the right direction.
You didn't hire Jane?
No, I didn't.
Were you going to tell me,
or were you planningon
letting me read it off the board?
It was my decision,
and I made it.
I got to pick Suzie
up from daycare.
Oh. Hey, Dr. Greene,
those medical students
are still down in Exam Three.
You want me to send them home?
Oh, God!
Hey. Excuse me.
Excuse me.
Yes, yes. You're the young lady
who helped me earlier
today, aren't you?
Mrs. Constantine.
Are you feeling better?
Well, I'm a bit tired.
Did I tell you that
I play the cello?
Once or twice.
Oh. I'm sorry.
I would like to play
something for you
as a kind of thank-you.
Oh, I don't think
that's necessary.
My son brought my cello to me.
It helps me pass the
time until I get better.
Really, you don't
have to do this.
I mean, maybe you
shouldn't do this.
Hey, you okay?
Yeah.
No, I'm fine.
Tough first day back, huh?
Yeah.
Some days, like
today, I have to forget,
or I'd never come back.
So, did you have a good summer?
Yeah.
It was great. Really.
I did a pedes rotation
over at Children's.
Spent about five weeks
kicking around St. Bart's.
Really? I always wanted
to go. Was it nice?
Yeah.
Doc! Doc! Can
you give us a hand?
Kid on a bike got hit
by a car. Full arrest!
I'll see you tomorrow, okay?
Yeah. See you tomorrow.
Okay, give me the bullet.
Hold on!
No, no, hold it! Thanks!
Chloe?
Oh, is dinner almost
ready? I am starving.
Yeah, all we got to
do is drop in the pasta,
and we're all set.
Oh. Hello.
My beautiful girl.
Hi.
Hi, prettiest girl.
How was school today?
Uh, great.
They're teaching us
how to use the Word and
the... the spreadsheets.
Honey, you want to come up,
say hi to mommy?
Okay, here we go.
We got your head there.
Oh. Oh. Here we go.
Oh... oh, no!
Oh, no!
Whoops!
There we go. There we go.
Oh...
Yes, you're okay.
Yeah. Oh. No, no.
It's okay.
Okay.
I missed you. Yeah.
Oh, God.
What time is it?
Oh, man.
Peter?
Peter, hey, wake up.
What?
We fell asleep.
It's almost midnight.
Oh, man.
What time does he get off work?
In 10 minutes.
Hey.
Yeah?
Why don't you stay?
You know I can't.
I love you.
I'll see you tomorrow.