Previously, on
"New Amsterdam"...
Fun, right?
- Friends.
The only thing holding me back
was this voice in my head.
And Martin, the voice is you.
I want to broaden my
horizons and find out
what I connect with,
where I belong.
I felt something.
So I'm sober, who cares?
You've been lying
to me this whole time.
- Where are you going?
- To get high.
I don't even know
where you're staying.
Can you just let me know
that you're not dead?
I think you may be bipolar.
Bipolar?
Out of my way!
You got to let me help you.
What'd you do, son?
- Please, Floyd!
- Take it easy.
Please, Floyd!
*NEW AMSTERDAM (2018)*
Season 05  Episode 08
Episode Title: "All the World's a Stage..."
Aired on: November 15, 2022.
Come on, Iggy, crush this.
Get it up there! Come on!
Let's go.
Whoo! Let's go!
- Whoo!
- There it is.
Whoo! Yes.
Oh, my God. Am I vibrating?
It's just the endorphins.
Now if you puke, it just
means you're doing it right.
Nice.
Oh, man, I've been lifting for what,
two weeks now?
I feel like I've been
power lifting my entire life.
Welcome to the
grind house, baby.
- OK.
- Oh, man.
Yeah, I feel like
I'm cracked open.
I feel alive.
Like, everything is
different. I'm different.
- Yeah.
- And the craziest thing is,
is that no one
else even sees it.
Eh, most people just
caught up in their own stuff.
They're just not
looking at it right.
Don't sweat it.
- Yeah, maybe you're right.
- I am.
Good talk,
but these power cleans
ain't gonna do themselves.
- All right, all right.
- Crush it, Iggy.
Here we go. Come on.
I have been sober for
three years and seven months.
I, uh...
I actually came close
to ruining that.
Did something stupid.
I moved in with my sister,
who's also an addict.
Yeah, I told myself
that I could help her.
Be this big hero.
But all I did was hurt myself.
I stopped going to meetings.
I stopped calling my sponsor.
She became my addiction.
Thank you.
Uh, I'm Lauren, I'm an addict.
All right, got a medium
Italian coffee for you,
light foam.
Wow. For me?
My favourite. Yeah.
You know, great minds.
Cheers. Um...
Just sorry to
bring you in early.
Mm.
Yeah, true.
All right. Uh... yeah.
All right.
I would like to
begin this session
with where we left off last week,
okay?
You spoke about having
intense feelings
of brain-numbing
emptiness and depression.
They're gone.
They're gone?
- Yeah.
- Wow.
That's a big change from
what you described last week
when you said, "I'm
on the edge of a cliff
peering into never-ending
nothingness."
No edge, no cliff,
just breathing this rare air.
What a time it is to be
alive, huh, Dr. Frome?
Yeah, I'll say.
Wow.
Um, I'm really glad the
CBT exercises are working.
Oh, no, sorry.
I haven't been doing
your exercises.
Oh.
OK, wh-what have you been doing?
What changed?
I finally talked to my mum.
She acknowledged my feelings.
Even owned her mistakes.
That's your late mother?
- Yeah.
- Huh.
- How?
- Solomon helped me.
Hmm.
We don't have a
Dr. Solomon on staff.
Oh, no, he... he works here.
He's... he's just not an MD.
Oh, wait, uh, hang on.
Are you talking about
Solomon the janitor?
Yeah.
He's psychic.
Is he?
What the hell happened?
Beauty pageant.
Stage collapsed.
Okay, let's get her to Bay 30.
Uh, let's page orthopaedics.
You've come to the
best possible place.
You're gonna be
brand-new in no time,
and so will your
fellow contestants.
Porsha Grux, 16,
clavicle fracture.
Uh, okay, Walsh,
let's get her to Bay 23.
- On it.
- The Miss Teen Liberty pageant
stage may have broken,
but it will not let
it break our spirits.
Nichelle Bartley, 17,
head trauma from
falling scaffolding.
Conscious with severe bleeding.
Uh, Casey, page for backup.
Anna, you're gonna be fine.
Come on,
let's look alive, people!
Let's go! Move!
Hang in there, Candace.
You're gonna be okay.
- Where do you want me?
- Uh, over here.
Head trauma, massive bleed.
Turan, let's take care of the
girl in the sequined dress.
Let's go.
What do we got?
Compound fracture,
right tibia.
Oh, yeah, reserve an OR.
She's gonna need an ORIF.
And call anaesthesia.
Okay, yeah, we're gonna
take good care of you.
Alexa.
You're a warrior.
These are world-class
physicians.
Keep your chin up, okay?
Good girl.
Candace.
Is that your grandmother?
That's Marvel a,
the pageant emcee.
She's everyone's grandmother.
Ah! Mm.
Do you know where you are?
The hospital?
Am I gonna die?
No. Uh, try to relax.
The bleeding isn't stopping.
More pressure.
Breathe in. Breathe out.
All is well.
You're gonna be fine,
Nichelle, I promise.
Thanks, Marvel a.
We need a type and
screen and cross match.
Okay.
And that should heal nicely.
They're gonna get me.
Wait, wh... who is?
Them. The CIA.
Yeah, those two aren't CIA.
They've been spying on
me with their machine.
Make them stop.
Okay.
We're gonna get
right on that, okay?
Okay, let's order her a CT scan.
Whatever's going on with her,
it's not caused by
a collapsing stage.
Yeah.
Ladies. Ladies,
I've spoken to you
on this day and on better days.
And you know what I've seen?
Grit that won't quit.
So keep those spirits up
because the show must go...
- Grab the backboard.
- I got her head.
Okay, I need help over here!
- We're on it.
- O2 and Ambu bag.
You the medical director here?
Uh, one and only.
- How can I...
- You really think you can
get away with it?
Stealing my mum's house.
Uh, h-hold on, hold on.
Uh, is this... Is this
billing or collections?
No, it was in her will.
You're saying that your mum
left this hospital her home?
Our home.
She was manipulated to do it,
by you and your greedy cronies.
Tricked into donating
it for nothing.
Now I'm here to get it back.
'Cause I knew you were
dying to see it, that's why.
Oh, I also got us a table
at Le Bernard in before the show.
Anything for you, my dear.
Pick you up at 6:00?
Buh-bye.
What's up, my friend?
Um, listen, I have a question.
Do you remember a patient
named Joanne Danova?
Joanne, yeah.
Ugh, what a sweetheart.
We just lost her, actually.
But silver lining,
we did get the house,
so score.
What can I say,
we're good at what we do here.
Yeah, um, what... what
exactly did you say to her?
Oh, it's not like
that, Dr. Goodwin.
What we do takes
time and finesse.
Starts with a polite
correspondence...
Maybe a "Happy Birthday"
personalised from one of us,
or a "Happy Holidays."
And once contact has been made,
we develop out the relationship.
Develop out?
Um, how?
Oh.
I've got connections with
every maître d' in the city,
hookups at the Broadway houses,
and I get a great deal
from the florist on Second
because New Amsterdam fixed
the guy's trick knee
a few years ago.
You're, uh... you're...
You're preying on our patients.
Hey now, that's um...
That's very insulting,
Dr. Goodwin.
Yeah. You wined and
dined Joanne Danova
until you convinced
this poor woman
to donate her family home to us
instead of her actual family.
And where was
Joanne's actual family
during her final months, huh?
Who was there to
get her a wheelchair
when she couldn't walk?
Us.
Who was there to make sure her
final birthday was special?
Us.
Who was at her bedside
holding her hand
when she finally passed?
Hint, it wasn't her family.
Every hospital has a
department like this.
Ours just happens to
be an industry leader.
I'm currently
developing relationships
with 30 other
patients as we speak.
Me and my team, we fill
holes in people's lives
that their own families
are neglecting.
Now I ask you, is
that preying on them,
or is that providing
a necessary service?
Now if you'll excuse me.
Ms. Albans, did
you get my flowers?
Oh, yes.
I'm so glad, my dear.
Hey.
Excuse me, Solomon.
Dr. Frome.
Oh, this about the
new disinfectant?
Spring breeze. Too flowery?
This isn't about
the disinfectant.
All right, that's
good to know.
Yeah, it's about a
patient that came to me
with something
kind of concerning.
They told me that they believe
you connected them with
a deceased relative.
Oh, yeah, I did.
Um, he was dealing
with a lot of pain,
but I'm glad I brought him
some closure.
Yeah. Well, Solomon,
I... I appreciate
what I can see is a gesture
of goodwill for you,
but... but that
kind of interaction,
that interferes with
patient treatments.
- It's not good.
- Oh, no.
I'm helping.
You see, I'm... I'm
bringing them some clarity.
When these messages come,
I'm compelled to speak them.
Honouring the soul's wishes.
Okay, look, you've
been fantastic here.
Your first few weeks
have been stellar.
But, uh, whatever it is you're
claiming to do or to be,
you can't do that here.
You can do it at home
on your own time,
but not here, not with
this vulnerable population.
You understand?
You have my word, Dr. Frome.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Won't happen again.
- All right, cool.
Thanks, man. See you around.
I'm not seeing a
hematoma in her brain.
Let's go ahead and
move to the chest.
Now we just need to
make sure that nothing's
obstructing the lower region.
When I worked my first
Miss Teen Liberty pageant
in 1989, something struck me.
- Do you know what it was?
- No, ma'am.
Announcing a pageant is
just like being a doctor.
A doctor?
Don't think I can't
hear your skepticism
despite being lodged
in this titanium donut.
Yes or no? Your job basically
is to make people feel better.
- Yes.
- Well, it's the same for me.
You have CAT scans,
MRIs, scalpels.
Those are your tools.
And I have my tool.
Oh, yeah, what's that?
The golden voice, baby.
Oh, I've done game
shows, roasts.
Oh, but the pageant
is my heart and soul.
Sure, there's the fake tiaras.
That's for the audience.
But for the girls,
there are real
scholarships, good ones.
At rehearsals, I work with them.
I get to see what
makes them shine.
Life's just one big runway, no?
I get to help them find
the confidence to walk it.
That's a broken rib.
It's penetrated her heart.
Book an OR.
Could rupture at any moment.
Ms. Cole.
Hi, I'm Dr. Bloom.
Um, may I have a word?
Yeah.
What's going on
with my daughter?
Was she hit by something?
Does she have a concussion?
Your daughter's CT
scan came back clear,
which means there's nothing
going on with her head.
So what is it?
Her toxicology tests
showed that she'd overdosed
on a substance called THC.
THC? Isn't that...
The psychoactive
ingredient in marijuana.
Look, I'm really sorry that
you had to find out like this,
but kids Kearston's age,
they start getting
curious about drugs.
But you can't
overdose on weed.
I-I know it sounds crazy,
but it happens a lot these days.
You know, with all
the different ways
that marijuana is consumed,
it's really difficult to know
what it's been laced with.
But I do know.
How?
I'm the one who
buys it for her.
All right, some
good news, Nichelle.
We were able to get
your blood to clot,
and this transfusion is gonna
make you feel better soon.
You might feel a
little bit of chills,
but it's nothing to worry about.
Then I can get
back to the pageant.
Ms. Marvel a always says,
the show must go on.
Mm.
How long have
you been competing?
Since I was nine.
Must have taken up
a lot of your time.
It's a lot of
work, but I love it.
Seems like a lot of pressure
for somebody your age.
I guess, but the
pageants are worth it.
Does it ever stress you out,
you know, having to
look a certain way,
having to have a
certain body type?
Why are you asking me that?
So I'm gonna be
straight with you.
I'm looking at the
pallor of your skin,
your excessive bleeding,
and how thin you are.
Your platelet count
is dangerously low.
All of these are signs
of an eating disorder,
most likely anorexia.
I don't have an
eating disorder.
I'm not anorexic.
Hey, do you notice
anything different about me?
Your shoes?
Nope.
Did you get a haircut?
Uh-uh.
- Is there something different?
- Never mind, never mind.
I'll see you later.
Gia.
Hi, what's the matter?
Did something happen in group?
I spoke to Bryan, Dr. Frome.
He's not in pain anymore.
He truly is in a better place.
Bryan, your deceased husband?
Yes.
All thanks to Solomon.
Solomon.
You were right, Warren.
An employee from this hospital
spent a great deal of time
with your mother during
her final months.
And, uh, in that time,
she decided to legally
and of sound mind
donate her home
to this hospital.
Wh... how is that
even permissible?
I know that
that's frustrating,
and all I can say is that, uh...
For those months, whenever
your mother needed something
or someone, the
bequest office was...
Was there for her.
Because I guess...
nobody else was.
You know what these
are, Dr. Goodwin?
I do.
For the past two years
I've been deployed.
Been to places you
couldn't even fathom,
places not easy to catch
a hop out of back home.
- Sorry, I...
- Believe me,
I wanted to be
here for my mother.
It just wasn't possible.
So I did the best I could.
I... I handled her bills.
I checked in on her every
spare chance I had be...
Before she passed.
Hell, the only... only reason
I'm even able to be stateside now
is on hardship leave to
get her affairs in order.
Little did I know
that New Amsterdam
took care of all that.
No, no, no. Look, Warren...
You know what,
save it, Doctor.
Somehow you guys turn
service to your country
into a liability.
And it's gonna cost you.
I'll see you in court.
Please don't
fire me, Dr. Frome.
Solomon, I asked you explicitly
to not get involved
with my patients' care.
Look, I know, and I tried.
But this gift I have,
the ability to speak to souls,
I can't control it.
I don't know what to
say. I... I trusted you.
- You gave me your word.
- It just happens.
I swear it does.
It takes over my spirit.
It's always a vivid flash
and some jolt of a
random feeling...
Joy, guilt, a taste or a smell.
And I feel it all
in my core like...
Like a roller coaster.
And it releases me,
and the messages come.
How long has this
been happening?
Pssh.
Um, since I was a kid,
about ten.
It's passed down
through my family,
my father and his.
That's why it's second nature.
It's in my DNA.
This gift, i-it's written...
- This, um...
- In my family history.
This doesn't sound
like a gift, Solomon.
This sounds like
temporal lobe epilepsy.
Core temp 37
Celsius. On target.
DVT prophylaxis on board.
There she is.
Forceps.
On our A game, folks.
We only get one shot at this.
Just one big splinter.
Go ahead and
position the shoulders.
All right, let's close her up.
- All right.
- Suture.
Thank you.
Damn it. Come on.
Switch to a Prolene suture?
Nah, it won't help.
This heart's been fighting
hypertension for years.
The walls are too thin.
It's beyond saving.
She's gonna need a transplant.
All right, uh,
let's close her up,
get her to ICU,
and contact UNOS.
We only got a few hours
to get this woman a heart.
Do you mind if I use the COW?
Oh, sure.
I gotta order psych consult.
Yeah, you got it.
I'll just be one sec.
Mm.
It's for Miss Teen won't Admit
That She Has an Eating Disorder.
What are you supposed
to do about that?
I mean, how do... How
do you help a patient
who is so completely in denial?
Uh, these pageants, they put
so much pressure on girls.
You know, as if the whole world
wasn't already a beauty pageant.
Telling women that
they have to smile,
and have to be thin, and
have to be beautiful.
Sometimes all you can do
is treat the disorder.
And if you get lucky,
the patient will follow.
You gotta be kidding me.
New patient?
Uh, uh, was.
She just donated her
house to New Amsterdam.
Wow.
That's very generous of her.
No, generosity had
nothing to do with it.
You're supplying your
own daughter with drugs?
Do you have children?
No, I am not a
parent, but I do know
that supplying kids with
drugs is usually frowned upon.
Wh-when my daughter was 15,
she came to me, and she said
that all her friends
were all vaping weed,
trying tinctures, edibles.
She wanted to try it,
and I said no.
So she didn't.
Then at 16, she asked again,
and she said she wasn't
asking my permission.
She was just wanting
to be honest about it.
I was afraid she would
buy it off the street,
and it would be laced
with God knows what.
So I did the responsible thing.
I bought her edibles, tinctures,
weed from a reputable dispensary
to protect her.
And she's only allowed
to do it at home,
and I oversee how much she does.
This is what raising
kids in 2022 is like.
Oh, my God.
Did you know that THC,
the psychoactive
ingredient in marijuana,
it used to make up 5%.
Now it makes up 95%,
making it more potent,
more addictive,
and more bio active.
Marijuana in 2022
is not the same drug
as when you were a kid.
I was trying to
do the right thing.
I was trying to keep her safe.
Yeah, well, you know what,
buying her drugs didn't do that.
Kearston's gone.
Her bed's empty.
What?
♪ One life so it's time ♪
♪ To open up your closet ♪
♪ Life's not worth a damn ♪
♪ Till you can shout out ♪
♪ I am what I am ♪
♪ What
I am needs no excuses ♪
No...
- She leapt into traffic?
- Yep.
She was out of her mind,
thanks to Mummy Dearest.
Let's connect her to the vent.
Okay, heart's steady.
96 sat. She's stable.
Well, ortho will
take her up to the OR,
where they will stabilise
her shattered pelvis.
I'm calling Child
Protective Services.
Really?
Look at her.
I know, but her
mum meant well.
Well, you know what, good
intentions don't really
matter when your kid has to
be put back together in the OR
because you wanted them
to experiment with drugs.
You know, her future,
her potential,
it's all derailed because
of her drug-pushing mother
who meant well.
Who are we talking about here?
This girl or you?
What happened?
Nichelle was doing great
after the transfusion.
Severe abdominal pains,
then her blood
pressure plummeted.
Found a bleeder.
What is that?
Enlarged lymph nodes.
She wasn't lying.
She's not anorexic.
She has lymphoma.
There he is.
My medicine man.
Whatever you're
paying these nurses,
it's not enough.
They are fabulous.
Yeah, yeah, they are.
Glad to see you're comfortable.
How are you feeling?
Like a want to.
I know bad news when I see it.
You can give it to me straight.
The organisation that,
um, arranges transplants
refused to put you on
their list of recipients
because of your age.
So where does that leave
my chances of
getting a new heart?
Extremely low.
I'm sorry.
Oh.
Are they canceling the pageant?
No, Ms. Anders, we really
need to focus on you now...
Oh, honey, that
ship has sailed.
No, no, no, no,
you deserve a heart.
And you know what?
I'd like to talk to someone
about making that happen.
I'll see what I can do.
Thank you,
but no.
Well, at least let me try.
No special favours.
I've had my time.
Let a young person
have the heart.
I've been lifting up young
people my whole life.
Why stop now?
Okay, so your scans
came back clean,
which means we can
rule out epilepsy.
So there's nothing
wrong with me?
You're not out of
the woods just yet.
You know, something is
causing these visions.
It's a gift, not an illness,
Dr. Frome.
Just because you can't explain
something scientifically
doesn't mean it's not real.
Well, it doesn't really matter
what I can explain, Solomon.
What matters is your health.
So I would like to
run some more tests
and start on a low-dose
seizure medication
so we can pinpoint the
actual cause, all right?
Is that something
you would agree to?
Hey.
Solomon, I know that this is
something you've dealt with
for the better
part of your life,
and I know that this is...
this is a lot.
It's a lot to take
in, to accept.
But I... I would
like to help you,
if you'll let me.
- Solomon...
- I have someone here with me
who has a message for you.
- Your brother.
- So until you decide
that you want my help, my
hands are completely tied.
Short-Fuze says he's sorry.
What... what did you say?
I'm being asked to tell Grunt
that he's sorry for
the way he treated you.
He's showing me his wrist...
Uh, the left one,
does that make sense?
How are you doing this?
He says he's proud of you.
And he watches over you,
even though you
found your strength.
Stay the course.
He sees the change,
and others will too.
We are shutting down New
Amsterdam's bequest program
because the way in which
this program operates
borders on criminal.
By targeting patients
in the dementia ward,
this department has
stained the reputation
of America's oldest
public hospital,
not to mention violated
any number of HIPAA laws.
Warren Danova's mother
was grossly manipulated.
And we have the power
to make this man,
a US veteran,
whole in his grief.
All we have to do is give
him back his family home.
- Is this true?
- We had no idea
Mr. Danova's mother
had dementia,
because going through her
records would have been
a violation of HIPAA laws.
All we have access to is
what she gave us access to.
Yeah, sure, but you knew
which doctor she was seeing,
which wards she was
being assigned to.
That data was available...
What more do you need to know?
Ms. Danova was
not of sound mind
when she signed over her house.
And if you don't
want to give it back,
then I am sure we can
find an estate lawyer
who will take it back.
Joanne Danova's last
will and testament,
dated January 7th, 2020.
According to her chart,
when was she admitted
into our dementia ward?
July 17, 2021.
So for nearly
a year and a half
after the signing of her will,
where she left New
Amsterdam her property,
Joanne Danova was of
sound mind and body.
Max, the donation stands.
Thank you.
Kearston's stable.
We expect her to
make a full recovery.
I wanted to let you
know that I didn't call
Child Protective Services.
But a social worker is going
- to be reaching out.
- Are you kidding me?
Look, I understand
that raising kids
in today's environment is tough.
And I get that
marijuana is everywhere,
and it is legal now.
But here in New York,
if you're under 21,
it is considered a
controlled substance.
You said that you only
let your daughter use
in your home with a
supply you provide, right?
And that was a tincture
full of cannabis?
A single drop could
make anyone psychotic,
much less a young girl.
Maybe next time,
leave the prescribing
to the doctors.
Sure.
Yeah, that's really
gonna stop kids
from experimenting with drugs.
Thanks for your help.
Yeah, well, my mother used
to give me drugs and alcohol
when I was a teenager.
Try to win my affection.
I spent my whole life trying
to dig myself out of that hole.
You want to help her experiment,
help her experiment
with not taking drugs.
'Cause, yeah, it might not work,
but this right here,
this is the alternative.
How you feeling?
What happened?
We had to take
you in for surgery,
and in doing so, I found
several lymph nodes
that were severely inflamed.
It turns out you have
Hodgkin's lymphoma.
Cancer.
We caught it very early,
and treating it is
gonna be a tough road,
but I know that you're tougher.
I owe you an apology.
As your doctor,
I made a mistake.
I let my prejudices
inform my diagnosis.
I assumed something
that I shouldn't have
because you were in a pageant.
I was as judgy as the
people I was ranting about.
And for that, I'm sorry.
You know, for the final three,
there's an interview portion?
Want to know what my answer to
the "who inspires you" question
was going to be?
Yeah, absolutely, I do.
It was Dorothy Klenke Nash.
Ah.
The first female neurosurgeon.
She trained right
here in New York,
and started practicing in 1928.
You go, girl.
Ah, look at Orderly Brenner go.
The man's a gladiator!
And Nurse Faldo,
a vision in sage.
Tell us, Amelia, what is your
favourite part of the job?
My paycheck, Marvel a.
Lies, you tell.
She's a giver to the core.
Isn't that right, everybody?
And Nurse Zambrano,
I don't have to tell you.
You've already been blown
away by those hot pink Crocs
with the fabulous
Jibbitz on them.
Oh, and Dr. Monique,
looking so chic
in her new frames.
Mr. Reynolds, you've made
significant improvement,
but in the opinion of
your psychiatric team,
you are not yet
fully stabilised.
Therefore, you are
hereby ordered to remain
under psychiatric supervision
a further two weeks.
Ha-hang on.
That's not right.
I've done what
they've told me...
Mr. Reynolds,
you've stated your case.
No.
I didn't ask to be here.
They put me in here.
They have treated me.
Now I just want to go home.
I can take care of
myself, Your Honour.
I cannot, at this juncture,
release you to your
own recognisance.
If you have family you can
stay with who can care for you
and monitor your condition
as you continue to adjust,
I will consent to release
you into their aegis,
but that's the best I can do.
I don't have any family.
I'm all I got.
Very well. Then
you are ordered...
That's not true.
I'm his son, Your Honour.
I can take care of him.
He can come home with me.
Mr. Reynolds, do you comply?
Yes, Your Honour.
I'm sorry, Warren.
I know this wasn't
what you wanted,
but I'm not giving up the fight.
Okay? As long as I'm
medical director, I'm gonna...
Mr. Danova.
You know what, leave me alone.
Look, you don't
owe me anything,
but is it possible
to talk for a minute?
Ken, I think
you've said enough.
It's all going to veterans.
- Excuse me?
- All the proceeds
from the sale of your
mum's home is going
to New Amsterdam's
Wounded Veterans program.
Your mother was adamant
about that stipulation.
We spent a lot of time together,
and you were always at the
centre of every conversation.
She could not have been
more proud of your service.
Hey.
I may have been here for her,
but it's you who gave
her peace in the end.
I'd be happy to share
as much as I can.
Whatever you want to know
about our time together.
Yeah, I think I'll
take you up on that.
Uh, thanks again for
the early drop-off.
The daily logistics
of cop a renting
are nothing short
of running a circus.
Kid coordination is an ever
moving goal post, I get it.
This is for Sameera's
science project.
- Okay.
- So have fun with that,
- Bill Nye.
- Thanks.
- You good?
- Yeah, yeah.
Well, you know, I did, uh...
I did have to transfer
a psychic janitor
to our holistic medicine
department today, where, uh,
I think he'll actually
fit in really nicely.
- Mm-hmm.
- So, you know, I'm good, yeah.
Just one of those days.
Hm.
- What?
- You...
You seem different.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah. Uh, in a good way.
Well, thank you, Martin.
It means a lot that...
That you noticed.
- Dad!
- Uh, I got to go.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
Yeah. Bye, kids.
- Love you.
- Thanks.
Jim and Sam's "Harley Davis on"...
Hey, I want that
homework done tonight.
Welp, that's curtain call.
Our last teen queen
has been discharged.
And that is my cue to bow out.
I am heading home.
Or not.
Here we go.
- Vanessa.
- Hey.
- What are you doing here?
- Why don't you answer
your phone?
I've called you, like,
- a million times today.
- I've not had a second...
Mum kicked it.
What?
Mum's dead.
♪ To forget the
feeling I felt then ♪
Done. Amazing.
♪ And I'm up at night still
wondering if I'll ride again ♪
It was.
Mm.
Oh, um...
Like what?
Oh. Uh...
yeah, like a date.
♪ Yeah, I'm up at
night still wondering ♪
♪ If I'll ride again ♪
♪ On a pitch-black
Harley Davidson ♪