- See you Tuesday.
- How about right now?
What? What?
You wanna throw in the towel?
No, I don't wanna
throw in the... towel!
I thought that's what you said!
I'm not upset about anything!
Where the... are we going?
What are you doing down here?
I thought you usually
had lunch with Coma Guy.
This is Vegetative State
Guy. Better company.
Hey, hey, tell him
about those Sherpas
you dropped acid with in
Saint Patrick's Cathedral.
You stole my prescription
pad and you forged my name.
What did you
tell the cop? I lied.
They'd have put you
away for 10 years,
after they took your
license to practice medicine.
So, everything's good, then.
I lied. To the cops.
There is no case
unless they can prove
that either I got the drugs
illegally or I sold them illegally.
I didn't do the second, you
lied about the first. Game over.
Yeah, Tritter's just playing.
He's gonna see how clever
you are and then just walk away.
The important thing is
that you keep prescribing
the same amount of drugs
to me or it'll look suspicious.
Here's another
way to look at it,
having forced me
to lie to the police,
your first concern is
securing your drug connection.
Joining my father for lunch?
I should have called
ahead for a table.
Dr. House was just...
Enjoying a Reuben.
It's okay.
After 10 years, anything that'll
get doctors in the same room as...
What are you doing? Nothing.
What are you doing?
Chips?
Wanna see something really cool?
I saw you leaving last Tuesday.
You practically tripped over
two guys on your way out,
but you had no
problem opening doors.
It's called akinetopsia.
You can't see things
when they move.
Now, since you haven't been hit by
a bus, I assume that it's intermittent.
It's probably
accompanied by seizures,
which made me think that I
could set one off by flashing the...
God, I love this family.
I can see fine now.
I've had seizures before.
Most of the time they're small.
Doctors ran me through all
the tests. Couldn't find anything.
Any history of
epilepsy in your family?
The only things I know
that run in my family are
a lot of chutzpah and the
ability to sleep for 10 years.
Although I'm not
really an expert.
Dad never really liked my
mother's side of the family,
and after she died and he came
here I was raised by a guardian.
I wouldn't even know how
to get in touch with them.
How about your father's
side of the family?
Any relatives we
could speak with?
My father was an only child.
And my grandparents are dead.
Well, who did you put down
as the person the hospital
should contact in an emergency?
I left it blank.
There's gotta be
someone, a friend...
I have plenty of friends.
Just no one that
would care if I was here.
Say, do you mind
passing me my backpack?
Hair of the dog.
- Could be infection.
- Or a brain tumor.
Says he had a CT.
What's wrong with the
simplest explanation? Trauma?
He didn't report any injuries.
He didn't report being
an alcoholic, either.
Drinking equals falling
down equals trauma equals...
Maybe it's inherited.
How would you jump to
genetics from his EEG?
All you've got are some
vaguely epileptiform waves.
It's not his EEG.
It's his father's.
When it comes to cortical
seizures, like father, like son.
Small seizures aren't unheard of
in a patient in a
vegetative state.
Similarities are
interesting, though.
What caused the
vegetative state?
His house burned down.
Went back in to get his wife,
firefighters found
him unconscious
three feet from the
bedroom, asphyxiated.
Not an inherited condition.
Test his DNA. Start with
adrenomyeloneuropathy.
Check out the home.
He has a single bed.
They still make single beds?
It could mean he
just doesn't have sex,
though there were
condoms in the apartment.
House asked you to check
out the home for toxins.
No mold, no leaks, no pets.
MRI and LP are
both inconclusive.
Infection's still possible,
tumor's less likely, but...
DNA? The
adrenomyeloneuropathy test
was negative.
DNA test again.
Try Unverricht-Lundborg
and late-onset Lafora's.
Genetic tests take forever.
You can't just keep testing for every
inherited condition you think it might be.
Well, not me. I'll be leaving
early. But you guys can.
You said no one's been sick but
what about delivery people, repair guy?
I wouldn't know.
I work from home.
Haven't been to the
office in over a month.
Visitors?
Haven't had any.
The only person I've
seen in the last week
was the pizza delivery guy
and he looked pretty healthy.
There's gotta be
someone you're close to.
Actually, the person I
see most often is my father.
He's asleep so he can't stop me.
What is it?
I'm just feeling
a little nauseous.
I think his liver's failing.
God. Does that mean that I'm...
We need a central line kit,
two units of packed red
blood cells type O Negative.
He's unconscious and
heading for a coma.
He's at a four on
the RLAS scale.
Stop all treatment.
You think this is a
reaction to our meds?
Well, they're
obviously not helping.
Given the fact that
he's an alcoholic,
there's a good chance his liver
wasn't so hot when he came in.
Anti-seizure drugs could have
just pushed him over the edge.
We take him off those
meds, what do we put him on?
I was hoping you'd know.
It may be academic, I
just started him on dialysis.
Kidney and liver failure. Not too
many people come back from that.
Trauma's out of the picture.
Could still be infection.
Or neurological... Or genetic.
We need a better history.
Did you miss the part where
the patient lost consciousness?
L-dopa?
You're not waking Kyle.
You're waking his father.
I commend your
observational skills.
You have no reason to think
any amount of drugs will
wake a man from a coma.
Vegetative state. Much easier.
This guy's no Terry Schiavo, his
brain's all there, he moves around,
his muscles have
barely atrophied.
He's just waiting
for a fairy-tale kiss.
After I do that, I'll
stick a needle in him.
The amount of amphetamines
alone would be dangerous,
besides whatever the
hell else you've got in there.
There are reports
out of South Africa
about a pill that would temporarily
revive someone in a vegetative state.
You've all seen
Awakenings, made me cry.
I wanna cry.
Put the syringe down.
I can outdraw you,
mysterious stranger.
We don't experiment
on helpless patients.
Be reasonable. There's
no way this is gonna work.
Even if you woke him, it
would only be for a few hours.
A day, two at the most.
You're risking his life.
I'm risking getting sued,
that's the only objection here.
You'll be torturing
him and his family.
Well, good news for Legal, the
only family he's got is upstairs dying.
Hey!
I want this patient monitored
for the next 24 hours.
I want someone
with him at all times
to make sure
you didn't kill him.
I want your ass in my office.
God, I'm starving.
I could really go for a steak.
Do you know your name?
Do you know where you are?
Gabriel Wozniak. I don't
know the name of this hospital.
How much are three and five?
Eight.
Also known as half of 16, a
quarter of 32, two to the third power.
Coolest thing ever.
Any history of
seizure in your family?
No. Liver disease?
No.
How long have I been here?
I got the feeling it's
been a long time.
Interesting.
Your internal
clock kept ticking.
How deep does that awareness go?
Pick up scraps of conversations?
Do you have the vague sense
that the hospital administrator
dresses like a trollop?
Or that the new Star Wars
movies were a disappointment?
I know my wife is dead.
I don't know how long it's been.
Ten years.
What's the last
thing you remember?
The fire.
My wife was in the bedroom,
she had taken a sleeping pill.
I got Kyle out,
went back in for her.
I knew I didn't make it.
I'm sorry.
What about your wife's side of the
family? Any history of seizures there?
Your son Kyle is a patient here.
I'm afraid his condition is
serious. He may be dying.
No seizure issues on
my wife's side, either.
What about that steak?
Nobody ever answered me.
Rumor in the cafeteria was Caustic
Guy was waking up Coma Guy.
Technically,
Vegetative State Guy
was woken by, yeah, Caustic Guy.
So what happened?
I gotta get him a steak before I
can ask him any more questions.
He doesn't wanna
talk about his son?
Didn't seem to emotionally
register that his son is sick.
Brain issue?
He was asphyxiated, spent
10 years as asparagus,
who knows what damage
is in there. It's possible.
Of course there's always
the simple explanation.
Maybe he just
doesn't like his son.
Only in your world
would that be simple.
The delusion that
fathering a child
installs a permanent
geyser of unconditional love...
Maybe your father's feelings
were conditional, not everyone's.
Well, of course,
that would play into
your romantic vision of human...
In terms you would understand,
we have an
evolutionary incentive
to sacrifice for our offspring.
Our tribe, our friends.
Keep them safe.
Except for all the
people who don't.
Everything is conditional.
You just can't always
anticipate the conditions.
Mind if we talk
for a few minutes?
How many pills would you
say Dr. House takes a day?
I'm uncomfortable
setting a number.
Well, try.
Six.
A day?
Has he ever had you
write prescriptions for him?
No. What is it you
want me to say?
That he takes too many pills
and is a danger to the hospital,
or he takes too few because
he's selling them on the side?
Either one is ridiculous.
I meant the former.
You're wrong.
Can I ask what Dr. House has
done to deserve your loyalty?
He's not known as a great boss.
He's not even much of a friend.
Look how he left
Dr. Wilson holding the bag.
It's odd. You don't
know about that?
You defend him, and he won't even
tell you what's happening in his life.
I was paged.
We saw you with the cop.
What'd he want?
How many pills does House take,
did I ever write
him a prescription?
That sort of stuff.
I told him six. A
day or in a mouthful?
I was just hoping you guys
would stay consistent with...
He wants to talk to us, too?
You're next.
We've gotta tell
House what's going on.
Tritter says no. Then no it is.
Cops have a thousand ways
to make life difficult for you.
Quick. What's the kid's status?
I gotta get back to our sleeper
before he goes looking
for the orgasmatron.
See, if that were rhetorical,
it would mean that I can just
turn around and leave now,
which I'm not doing, from
which you should deduce...
He's off all drugs
except the antibiotics.
His liver's just managing
to hang in there.
He's still sliding into coma.
Your barber sucks.
Hey, Coma Diet,
I could make a fortune.
Vegetative State Diet.
Who gave you your clothes?
Dr. Cuddy.
I guess I'll need all
new ones, anyway.
Everything went in the fire.
Don't worry about it.
We use recyclable clothes now.
Wear them once, then eat them.
Your son's measles vaccination,
do you remember if he
had it, what type it was?
Man, you're a piece
of work, you know that?
You weren't gonna
tell me, were you?
I don't need new clothes.
Dr. Cuddy says my body
will adjust to the drugs,
that I'll be a vegetable
again by tomorrow.
If I'm really lucky,
the day after.
Yeah.
If I've got a day to live,
I'm not gonna spend it in a
hospital room being grilled.
Come on, where you gonna go?
Your house burned down, your
wife's dead. Business was sold off.
The only thing you have left is down
the hall, heading for a liver biopsy.
Used to be this little hole in the
wall run by a guy named Giancarlo.
Made the best
hoagies in the world.
Real Italian rolls,
prosciutto, provolone...
How far is Atlantic
City from here?
You have one day to live,
and you want a sandwich?
People on death
row get a last meal.
The state provides it.
Who's providing for you?
You got a car? Money?
You're negotiating with me.
Take out another 100 for
me. And I need your car.
I'm not doing you any favors.
You'll get it back
tomorrow. Two days, max.
Road trip.
This is like trying to
control the weather,
but I'd prefer it if you
didn't eat in the car,
I just had it detailed.
I drive. Oh, the hell he does.
Sure.
Aside from the fact he just
woke up from a vegetative state,
the guy doesn't have a license.
How about this?
Cops stop us, we lie.
You know how to do that. Chips.
It's all the drugs pumping
through his system.
Right now his reflexes are
better than Dale Earnhardt Jr's.
What's this? It says ipod.
I'm coming.
So let's talk about
toxic exposure.
What was wrong with the
old colors? I trusted brown.
Do the purple ones
have chocolate inside?
Raspberry cocaine.
This house that burned
down, where was it?
Moorestown, New Jersey.
Listen, I really need to know about
the candy because I'm allergic to berries.
You didn't mention that.
Is it significant?
No. So where else did you live?
List everywhere,
including vacations,
start with when your
wife got pregnant.
We lived in Jersey. Then we
moved to Jersey, from there, Jersey.
What are you waiting to hear?
About the little cottage in the Amazon
with the mosquitoes and the
lead paint all over the walls?
Yes.
You know what?
I didn't let you come along so you could
suck all the fun out of my one day of life.
Well, you're outta luck, because
that's totally why I'm here.
Okay, rule change.
Person with the money
makes the rules. Or in this case,
the person who's friends with the
person with the money makes the rules.
Well, you want answers
more than I want money.
All right, so here's the game.
Ask whatever you want.
But for every question I answer,
you have to answer one first.
Why would you care about
anything I have to say?
The day before I died,
I was a successful man.
I had a factory with
over 200 employees.
People listened when I talked.
I liked power.
Now, the only power I have
left is the power to annoy you.
I took Wilson's
assistant for coffee.
Why? Something Tritter said.
She told me the police think
that House stole Wilson's
prescription pad and forged his name.
You believe it?
Do you? Well, absolutely I do.
I'm just checking
how naive you are.
He's not gonna steal his best
friend's pad, jeopardize his career.
Until his best friend
says no to him.
House is a junkie.
Junkies do whatever they
have to do to get what they need.
Kyle's down to a three
on the RLAS scale.
He's only showing
localized response.
I'll call House, tell him we're
gonna need an answer soon.
Get in your right lane for 295.
And pass me the Twizzlers.
I'm curious... No, you're not.
Why would a man's first instinct
be to drive away from
the only family he's got?
No, this is no time for
you to do your thing.
We don't care about his state of
mind, we don't care if he's happy.
This factory of yours,
what did you make?
So ask me a question.
I'm thinking.
Only six left, by the way.
So sign my name. You don't
need a doctor, you need a pen.
What is up with you two?
Wilson lied to the bulls to
keep me out of the big house.
Are you out of your mind?
Well, who's he gonna tell?
By tomorrow night he's gonna
be a mindless stalk of celery.
Since I answered that
one, by the way, my turn.
What did you make
in your factory?
Luxury boats.
Have you ever been in love?
Wow!
Going right for the closets with
the embarrassing stuff. Good move.
Yes. Describe the boats.
Thirty-five to 65-foot hulls, twin
engines, parquet floors in the galley,
staterooms with queen beds.
How'd you meet? She shot me.
These boats, I assume you used
mildew-resistant paint on the hulls?
Naturally. Shot you?
Paintball. Doctors
versus lawyers.
Did you ever take your
son to the factory? Sure.
He used to run all over the
place, but it was perfectly safe.
Ever love anybody else?
No more questions,
I got my answer.
While Dad's in the office, his
son's watching them spray-paint.
And what kid wears a mask?
Mercury specifically targets
the central nervous system.
You're saying this is my fault?
Mercury poisoning
explains the seizures
and the liver's like
a big soup strainer.
The soup runs through,
chicken dumplings stay.
For soup, read
blood, for chicken...
I get it, I get it. Mercury.
Sits more or less idle
until your kid pours tequila
shooters into his liver.
When the liver goes, takes out
the kidneys, explains everything.
Yeah, it's me.
Foreman, draw blood.
Test for mercury poisoning.
Chase, start heavy
metal chelation
while we're waiting for results.
Chase isn't here.
I'll start the...
Where is he?
The lab.
How many pills
does he take a day?
It's hard to say, pain
levels vary over time...
Could be six, eight, 10.
Ever write any
prescriptions for him?
Yes. Why?
Did he tell you to?
He asked me to.
Medicine attracts people
who are attracted to power.
I know how he hates when
he is defied by a patient.
I doubt he handles defiance
from his staff any better.
Now you correct me if I'm wrong,
but I don't think Dr. House
asks for anything.
I think he takes it.
And I think that you are
stuck lying to the police
to cover up something
you didn't wanna do.
We have been up and down
St. James like a Monopoly car.
It's not here. Giancarlo
has left the building.
We can still turn around
and go back to Princeton.
No. We've come this
far, I'm getting the hoagie.
If your son does have
mercury poisoning,
there's a good chance he'll
respond to the chelation.
You might be able to have a few
minutes with him before you lapse.
Why are you so
concerned about me?
Deep inside Wilson believes
that if he cares enough
he'll never have to die.
Your behavior isn't normal.
And you would know normal?
What could he have done that
you won't forgive after 10 years?
When this is your last chance?
My son is what he is.
His mother's side,
all drunken losers.
He's gone the same way.
House told you drinking
had damaged your son's liver.
I just said that.
But you didn't hear him say that
until after we
left the hospital.
So why did you leave?
Maybe your son
takes after your side.
Seizures and an allergy
to emotional connections.
Okay, okay, okay. Enough.
We're in Atlantic City
and my time's not up yet.
We find a hotel with a casino.
BP's starting to drop.
O2-sat's down to 70.
Point-three
milligrams of epi in.
What are you trying to
do, make him bleed faster?
Check the pulse.
It's not his liver.
It's the heart.
I understand he's a French chef
but I'm sure he can handle this.
You need a 12-inch Italian roll,
oregano vinegar, no, not
balsamic vinegar, oregano vinegar.
Quid pro quo, Clarice.
Game's still on.
I thought the answer
was mercury poisoning.
What other questions
would you care about?
If you each had one day to live,
you'd look for one last meal and
House would look for one last answer.
No, can you just send
the ingredients up here
and I'll make it myself.
Last 10 years, how much
awareness did you have?
I don't know, I knew
it wasn't the next day.
I knew that...
I recognized your voice.
How often were you in my room?
No, you're wasting a question.
I have a better one.
Why steal my pad?
Oh, my God, you're
right. I'm an addict.
Thanks for opening my eyes.
No, I mean why my pad?
Foreman, Cameron and Chase's
pads are just as convenient.
But their association with you is
involuntary, they're employees.
I associate with
you through choice
and any relationship
that involves choice
you have to see how far
you can push before it breaks.
This is easy.
You ask the questions, answer
them and make tasty snacks.
Let's go try the casino.
And one day our
friendship will break
and that'll just prove your theory
that relationships are conditional
and you don't need human
connection or deserve it,
or whatever goes on in
that rat-maze of your brain.
Sorry, if I'd known he was
gonna be this annoying,
I would have stolen
Dr. Cameron's pad
and Dr. Foreman's car.
At least she appreciates
my brooding melancholy.
House's House of Whining,
state your complaint.
The patient's BP just
dropped like a stone.
Do an echo.
Mercury isn't likely
to damage the...
It didn't.
Mercury test was negative.
Do an echo.
I was wrong. Your
son's still dying.
I need to go over every
relative you ever had. Again.
And this time, forget their
diseases, just tell me how they died.
And we don't have
time to take turns.
You give me the answers,
you get a big one at the end.
You can go for
whatever you want.
Destroy my privacy, my dignity.
Your grandmother?
Heat exhaustion,
Fourth of July picnic.
The woman was 92.
Does anyone in the kitchen
know the hoagie shop
that used to be on
St. James Place?
You sister-in-law
with the diabetes.
As far as you know, is
she still alive? She's not.
She was killed in
a traffic accident
driving home from
a Phillies game.
I'm sure a lot of
beer was consumed.
The Phillies lost. Your father?
Old age. Heart finally gave out.
Your wife's father?
Hit-and-run, walking
the incontinent dog.
Hi, do you guys deliver?
Let me put it this way,
if you deliver, there'll
be a $100 tip in it for you.
Excellent.
Victory. The night is
finally going my way.
Wilson, toss me a soda.
Shall we go somewhere to talk?
House is an ass.
But he obviously
needs pain medication,
and how much pain
one person feels
is not a call the government
should be making.
So you think I'm a
bureaucrat with a badge
following some
arbitrary guideline.
Yeah, I do.
So you're saying I should
just trust him. Do you?
You're not qualified
to make that...
I'm not sure you are, either.
I've been a cop for 20 years.
And not a day goes by
that someone doesn't try to
sell me some self-serving story.
If you had my job, you'd know.
Everybody lies.
I think you've run
out of relatives.
So, it's my turn.
Why did you become a doctor?
That's the big question?
I give you complete
license to humiliate me
and that's the best you can do.
Well, okay, let's discuss the
wonder of the human body.
No, no, no. You're
a curious guy.
You like to figure things
out, why not go into research?
Why work with people when you
obviously hate people?
Oedipal fixation.
I was seeking my mother's love
and she thought that Ben
Casey was just the dreamiest...
Okay, fine. You don't think you'll
need any more answers from me?
Give me a hard time.
When I was 14,
my father was
stationed in Japan.
I went rock-climbing
with this kid from school.
He fell and got injured and I
had to bring him to the hospital.
And we came in through
the wrong entrance
and passed this guy in the hall.
He was a janitor.
My friend came
down with an infection
and the doctors
didn't know what to do.
So they brought in
the janitor.
He was a doctor.
And a buraku.
One of Japan's untouchables.
His ancestors had been
slaughterers, gravediggers.
And this guy,
he knew that he wasn't accepted
by the staff, didn't even try.
He didn't dress well, he didn't
pretend to be one of them.
The people around that place,
they didn't think he had
anything they wanted,
except when they needed him.
Because he was right.
Which meant that
nothing else mattered.
And they had to listen to him.
Thank you.
Need 20 milligrams of
diazepam in a syringe.
Heartbeat's irregular
and accelerating.
He's at 200. He's gonna crash.
Allergic reaction
to the diazepam?
Better hope so.
It's either that or
his heart's done.
What happened on
the night of the fire?
Yeah. I'm sure it's a
stressful, emotional question.
Suck it up.
My wife had taken a
sleeping pill and gone to bed.
It was Christmas Eve.
I let Kyle pop corn
in the fireplace.
He managed to knock
loose some tinder.
Wrapping paper caught on fire.
It spread so fast.
I got Kyle out and...
When I went back in for...
You're a disappointment.
You act as though you
don't need anybody, you...
You just blame your
son for what happened.
I don't blame him. He
was a 12-year-old boy.
You don't blame a
kid for an accident.
Then what are we doing
here? Why aren't you with him?
Because it wouldn't matter.
I failed to keep my family safe.
I couldn't stop the fire,
I couldn't save my wife,
now you want me to stick around
watching while I fail to save my son.
Thank you so much
for waking me up.
How did your son
dislodge the tinder?
God...
He dropped the popcorn tray.
He had been complaining it was
too heavy, I should have listened.
And the hit-and-run,
walking the pissy dog.
That happen at night?
I think so, yeah, why?
Car accident after
the Phillies lost.
Night game?
Ragged-red fiber.
It's an inherited condition.
Dropping things, muscle
weakness, poor night vision.
Makes people seem uncoordinated,
accident-prone, careless.
It's transmitted in
mitochondrial DNA
so it only passes
through the mother.
Your wife's family weren't
drunks, they were sick.
It wouldn't have
affected his liver.
The kid is a drunk.
He thinks that he
killed his mother
and turned his father
into a vegetable.
I might have a few shots myself.
Foreman.
Test his DNA for
ragged-red fiber.
It's not gonna...
Here's a thought.
Why don't we not assume that the
test is negative until we actually do it?
House, the kid has
severe cardiomyopathy.
Alcoholic, no shot
at a transplant.
So yeah, maybe you figured
out why, good for you, but
he's gonna die anyway.
I want to give Kyle my heart.
This thing, whatever it is, you
said he gets it from the mother.
My heart's fine.
And it could go on being
fine for the rest of your life.
Yeah, it's not like he's
gonna do anything with it.
Well, you woke him up once,
maybe someone'll come
up with some other answer.
We've both seen
breakthroughs no one expected.
And ragged-red fiber's
treatable, but not curable.
Even if he gets your
heart, there's no guarantee.
He's my kid.
No!
Did you really expect
a different answer?
We have arranged transplants
before when a patient is near death.
Except he isn't near death, he's
saying, "Kill me and cut out my heart."
Are you out of your mind?
Fine. I'll think of
something else.
I'm sorry.
Wilson, get out.
No.
You lied to the
cops enough for me.
Maybe I don't wanna
push this till it breaks.
Pills are the simplest.
Hanging has less chance
of damaging the heart.
I'm okay with pain.
Strangulation is better
than breaking your neck,
which means this'll be slow.
I wouldn't get to see him even
if we got in the car right now
and broke the speed
limit driving back, would I?
No.
Tell him...
I don't know what to tell him.
I think it's my turn to
ask a question, isn't it?
I don't think so.
'Cause you just asked me
that thing about the speed limit.
What do you wanna know?
If you could hear one thing
from your father, what would it be?
It wouldn't help you.
Try me.
I'd want him to say,
"You were right.
"You did the right thing."
Yeah. It doesn't help.
Hi. Hi.
I'm Dr. Wilson.
I'm Mrs. Schaffer.
I'm from Princeton.
My husband and I and our
three children live in Philadelphia.
So, do you like to swing?
No.
Well, if you change
your mind, I'm in...
House? House?
Is it room 622, 642?
622.
Yeah.
Alibi.
I figured.
They found an open
bottle of aspirin by the body.
Lucky he had a headache,
reduced trauma to the heart in transit.
Lucky.
That can't be all.
Well, you got a heart out of it.
How many organs do
you want from the guy?
I mean, my father must
have said something.
He couldn't just...
He must have given you
some kind of a message for me.
He said you were right.
You did the right thing.
Right about what?
What does that mean?
How would I know? He's your dad.
You know what I found
interesting about this case?
That it proved that people
can love unconditionally
and you can tell
yourself it's not true,
but you'll just end up in a
hotel room in Atlantic City
asking someone to
cut your heart out?
The hoagie.
You thought this guy
was emotionally confused,
and that the hoagie
was just a mask
to hide his real
feelings toward his son.
It was.
Did you know Tritter was talking
to your team while we were away?
Yeah.
And yet you moved
Heaven and Earth
to get him that mask with
mustard and prosciutto.
Which one of them told you?
All of them.
Which means that none of them
said anything I have to worry about.
Back to the hoagie.
You think that my
addiction's out of hand.
Your need to be needed is so strong
that you'll give people what they want,
what they need, what
they think they need.
I don't think my enabling is anything
you should be complaining about.
Yes, my name is
Dr. James Wilson,
account number 835687.
The ATM says I've got zero...
What does that mean, a hold?
Yeah, okay, thanks.
My accounts have been frozen
as part of a police investigation.
They can't keep
your money forever.
No, they can keep it till I agree to
help send you to prison for 10 years.
You're getting dinner.