A few days ago, I
received a death threat.
Well, did they find
out who sent it?
Not yet, but working theory
is a disgruntled employee.
I thought you looked familiar.
Think maybe people will
forget about this soon?
It's not every day you
find out your colleague
was a teen heartthrob.
Most emergency departments
don't have an OB specialist,
so I'm curious if you find
your position essential.
I just thought, as a woman,
you'd appreciate having someone
who specializes
in women's health.
As a woman, I do appreciate it.
Are you dancing?
No, I had a cramp in my calf.
Okay, listen up, everybody.
I just got confirmation.
We've got a code orange coming
in in T-minus ten minutes.
Are we ready for that?
Let me tell you
something. We better be.
Halloween night can be one
of the busiest of the year.
Be smart about triage
and resource management,
and don't get too caught
up in the pageantry.
I expect the highest
level of decorum.
Hey, stop right there!
It's gonna be a long night.
Almost there, bud.
Almost there, Coop.
Hang in there, Superman.
Hang in there, buddy.
All right, Coop.
Almost, buddy.
You're good, you're
good, you're good.
Whoa.
How did he even get it in there?
I... no... mm.
- Does that taste good, bud?
- Mm-hmm.
Two birds, one
lollipop. Right on.
Ow, Superman!
You're so strong.
Wow. Excellent costume choice.
But this tracks, right?
I mean, you never
just see one minion.
Facts.
Hey, Dr. Frost.
Oh, no.
Both: That was a close one.
What do you think?
I think you should watch
higher-quality television.
You're kind of low-key famous.
Very low-key.
Among millennial females
of a certain age.
I've never seen "Nick
of Time!" Sorry.
Thank God. We'll get along.
Yeah, we will.
Oh, I'm guessing
this was coordinated.
I wanted to be an astronaut.
Yes, but every hero
needs a sidekick.
Mm-hmm.
Well, I'm gonna hit the head.
Well, make it
quick. We need you.
Things are going well, I see.
Yeah, he's really been
showing up lately.
Showing up?
The man literally dressed
like a Ken doll to please you.
Sweetie, he's head over heels.
Mm.
Okay, the prenatal
clinic head count
is three patients in five days.
Lenox is gonna pull the plug
if we don't get
those numbers up.
Doesn't help that she
keeps us on a tight leash.
All we need is to
get the word out.
- Yeah, I hope you're right.
- Yeah.
Jackie, weren't you supposed to
go to a Halloween party
with your daughter tonight?
There was a change of plans,
so I picked up a shift.
Oh, good. We got a
code orange on its way.
Oh, well, I should get
changed quickly, then.
No, it's gonna have to wait.
I need you on the floor.
Everybody, timeline's moved
up. Battle stations now!
- You ready?
- Come on!
- Let's do it.
- All right.
All right.
Make sure you have enough candy.
Make sure you have enough.
Thank you.
All: Trick or treat!
- Happy Halloween!
- Happy Halloween, guys!
Happy Halloween. There you go.
Yeah.
Yeah, I understand,
but we have to work with
the resources that
we have available.
Well, yeah, that's a good point.
But let's keep that in
mind when we have to,
uh, tackle that
fourth quarter budget.
Yeah, okay.
Yeah. Yeah.
Well, you know,
for now, why don't we
just stay the course?
Um...
let's pick this
up in the morning.
O-Okay.
Who's there?
I've already called the police!
Ah!
That stings!
Kyle!
Oh, Kyle! Oh,
no, I'm so sorry.
Are you okay?
Come on, let's go
get your mother.
Come on.
All right, Kyle, we're gonna
hold this over your eyes.
Can you do that for me?
- Yeah.
Great. He'll be fine.
We irrigated his eyes, no
sign of corneal damage.
Just need to manage
the swelling now.
Thank you, Dr. Frost.
Of course.
Helen, I am so sorry about this.
Is there anything I could do
to make it up to both of you?
Can I have all your
peanut butter cups?
Mom, don't guilt-trip
Ms. Goodwin.
It was an accident.
No worries, Kyle.
It's a deal.
But seriously, Sharon,
someone was in your house?
That's terrifying.
- Well, I think it was.
But honestly, I've been
a little keyed up lately.
CPD is doing a full
sweep of the house, so.
Hopefully it's nothing.
- Yeah.
I saw your flyer at
the community center
about prenatal screenings.
Yes. Yes, that's right.
Um, unfortunately, though,
our clinic hours are
over for the day.
When... when are they?
Weekdays from 11:00
a.m. to 4:00 p.m.
Um, I work then. Just
about everybody does.
Yeah, I... can you come in
on one of your days off?
Um, yeah, it's been a while
since I've had one of those.
Is... is there any way
that you can see me now?
I mean, something just...
it doesn't feel right.
Yeah, you know, let me...
let me see what I can do.
Okay, thank you.
So he escaped from
the psych ward?
Yep. Name's Ted Kachler.
He's got a pretty
nasty gash on his arm
after security tackled
him at the front entrance.
We're waiting on X-rays
before sending him back up.
And why did Dr. Cuevas hold
him in the first place?
Well, the police brought
him in for erratic behavior
during a domestic dispute.
He was pretty unhinged and
paranoid during intake.
Thank you.
This is all a huge
misunderstanding.
Ted, how are you
doing? I'm Dr. Charles.
Um, Jackie has been
telling me that, uh,
you were involved in
an incident at home?
Yeah, which Becca has totally
blown out of proportion
for her advantage.
- Okay.
So Becca is your...
your partner?
Your... your wife?
Not for long.
Um, we're in the middle
of a nasty divorce,
and she is... she's
trying to sue me
for full custody of
our daughter, Ella.
Oh, well, I'm really
sorry to hear that.
I mean, divorce...
Divorce, uh, sucks.
Yeah, uh... um, the thing is,
the custody hearing
is tomorrow morning,
and I'm... I'm stuck in here.
- Uh-huh.
So that's why you were trying
to get out of the hospital?
I can't lose my
little girl, doc.
I hear you. Really, I do.
Um, the thing is Dr. Cuevas
probably wouldn't have
put you on a psych hold
without a pretty good reason.
So if you don't mind, can you
just tell me a little bit more
about what happened?
Look, I...
I lost my temper, okay?
I... I was... I was
tired, I was stressed.
I don't know.
Um, my... my... my brain,
it just suddenly glitched.
Okay, so when you say that
your brain suddenly glitched,
can you get a little
more specific about that?
I mean, was it... did you see
something or hear something
out of the ordinary, or...
No, I...
I just lost control, okay?
But I feel totally fine now.
But I'm thinking that
it's actually probably
in all of our best interests
to drill down and figure out
what's going on
with this glitch.
I don't... I don't know
what to say, you know?
I... I freaked out,
and now I find myself
suddenly in a psych ward.
- Right.
- Which I do not belong in.
Okay.
Look, I want you to try
and relax a little bit,
'cause we gotta wait
for your X-ray anyway.
But, um, we are gonna get
to the bottom of this, okay?
And I want you to
trust me on that.
- Okay.
- Good. Thank you.
Um, we'll check back in a bit.
I did Ted's intake.
He's got IBS,
asthma, hypertension,
but absolutely no history
of mental illness.
So you're thinking that
this is just a legal tactic
on the part of the wife?
It's worth considering, yeah.
If his wife uses this psych
hold against him in court,
he might not ever
see his kid again.
Yeah, but I mean,
clearly there's something
going on here, right?
I mean, Ted himself
brought up this glitch.
Sometimes people
crack under pressure.
Doesn't make them mentally ill.
- Very true.
But, uh, you know what?
I just need a
better understanding
of what's going on here
before I release him
in good conscience.
So you know, let's, um,
let's figure it out.
We already talked about this.
Tonight's gonna be a madhouse.
I don't have the space for
the prenatal lab after hours.
Dr. Lenox, she took three
buses across town to be here.
Does she have an
acute medical need?
- No, but...
- Then please send her home.
I'm sorry.
All I'm asking for
are a few prenatal
labs and an ultrasound.
How long do you
need, Dr. Asher?
Hour, tops.
Dr. Lenox, given the extremes
the woman went
through to get here,
perhaps we can
make an exception.
- Knock yourself out.
- Thank you, both of you.
You know, bending
isn't always breaking.
Bending means more
expectation to bend.
Excuse me. Can someone
please help me?
There's something
really wrong with him.
Dr. Frost, we need help here.
Hey. Let me take a look.
It's okay, it's okay.
Let's take a little look.
Baby's slightly cyanotic.
Can we get a cot crib, please?
- You're going to Trauma 1.
- All right.
Just follow me and tell
me what happened, okay?
I don't know. He just
started wheezing.
Okay, was he exposed
to cigarette smoke?
- No, I don't smoke or vape.
- Okay.
Was he sleeping near a vent?
No. He was fine
and then he wasn't.
Okay. Let's set him down.
Hey, buddy. You're
okay, you're okay.
All right.
Let's see what we got.
Okay, crackles bilaterally.
Let's get a CBC, BNP,
blood culture, X-ray,
and then swabs for COVID,
influenza, and RSV, all right?
- Copy.
- Thank you.
What's his name?
- Nate.
Hey, Nate. How are you
doing? Are you his mother?
Uh, no, I'm the
babysitter, Whitney.
Okay, well, Whitney,
I'm gonna want you
to call his mother for me, okay?
I already did.
She's on her way.
Will he be okay?
I'm gonna take very good
care of him, I promise.
Good evening. I'm Dr. Ripley.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Mary Katherine, but
people call me MK for short.
So the, uh, triage nurse
says that you've been
experiencing some
abdominal pain.
That's right.
Any chance you just, uh,
had too much to drink at
a Halloween party, sister?
I haven't had a
drink in 20 years.
And the only party I'm attending
is my weekly sewing circle.
At the rectory.
I... I am so sorry, sister.
Oh, don't be. It's...
it's Halloween night.
I get it.
So how long have you
been experiencing pain?
Off and on for about a month.
Any, uh... any dietary
changes lately?
Halloween candy is my weakness.
Well, sugar can impact health,
but, uh, it's unlikely to
cause an acute episode.
Uh, would you mind
sitting back for me?
Of course.
- May I?
- Yeah.
I think we're looking
at diverticulitis.
It's an inflammation
of the large intestine.
We usually treat it
with antibiotics.
Mm.
So how about we start with a
CT scan to get a closer look,
and uh, we'll take
it from there?
- Sounds good.
- Okay.
Uh, his name is Nate Sullivan.
He's three months old.
Uh, my babysitter...
- Lynne.
- Whitney... oh, Rip.
Uh, Nate was brought
in with a fever?
Oh, I'm... I'm
sorry to hear that.
He's in Trauma 1
with Dr. Frost.
Okay.
I'll walk over with
you so I can see him.
- Okay.
- You've... you've been drinking?
Yeah, I had a few at a
bar with some friends.
Wait, you... you
took Nate to a bar?
No, I got him a babysitter.
That's... that's
who brought him in.
Has he been sick?
No, he...
he has a little cough.
So you left a sick baby
to go get hammered?
Do... I'm... I'm not hammered.
I went out for a little
Halloween celebration.
Unbelievable.
Screw you and your
judgment, Saint Rip.
I don't need this.
I just got Nate's X-rays back.
It looks like a mild
case of pneumonia,
but I think a course
of IV antibiotics
will clear it right up.
Thank you.
So... sorry, he's gonna be okay?
I'd like to keep him
overnight in the PICU
for observation, but I
expect him to be just fine.
I already requested
the transfer.
They'll be down in ten minutes.
Thank you so much.
You got it.
What? You got
something to say?
Honestly, I'm not
sure what to say.
Yeah?
Well, if you're so damn worried,
why don't you come over and
help me out once in a while?
I'm all alone with him.
When he doesn't
sleep, I don't sleep,
so I'm going crazy.
Look at me.
Look at Mommy, look at Mommy.
Shh, shh. Hey, hey.
Please just sit for Mommy.
I just need you to sit.
I just need you
to sit for Mommy.
Look what I found, Leo.
- Look what I found.
- Hey, hey, hey.
Hey, hey, hey, hey. It's okay.
Just play your game, okay?
Okay.
Sorry, it's, um... it's
been a long day for him.
No, no, it's...
it's totally fine. I
should have asked first.
The day I... I found out
I was pregnant with Leo,
I just about emptied
the Amazon warehouse
of every baby toy and
onesie they had in stock.
I just couldn't wait.
Now you get to spoil this one.
Yeah.
I didn't, um...
I didn't take proper
care of myself.
And I've always wondered if...
if that's why Leo has
the issue that he has.
No, Olivia. Don't
put that on yourself.
This wasn't your fault.
I swore I... I...
if I ever got pregnant,
I'd do better.
I mean, that's why I'm here.
I'm on my own and
got rent to pay,
and times are hard to come by.
And I'm just... I'm
terrified that...
I'm terrified that the, um...
I just want this baby
to get proper care.
Okay. It's okay.
Dr. Charles.
What was so important that
I had to leave my brother
and six-year-old nephew in the
middle of trick-or-treating?
I don't understand.
Nurse Nelson called
and said that you
needed an immediate
consult for Ted Kachler.
Oh, right, right.
That's because, um, I do have
some significant questions
about his intake and I
could be on the verge
of... of releasing him.
And I just wanted to, you
know, consult with you first.
But you're my boss.
In what world do you
need me to sign off?
Oh, I don't know,
professional courtesy.
You know, it's your patient.
I appreciate that,
but maybe next time,
just give me a call.
Noted.
I think we might have
crossed our wires.
But look, while I have you here,
do you mind going into
a little more detail
about what you
observed on intake
that led you to hold him?
Yeah, he was erratic and violent
when the cops brought him in,
and he was screaming threats
at his wife, who was
clearly terrified.
Got it, got it.
You do whatever
you feel is right,
but I would fix his arm
and send him back upstairs.
Okay.
Well, thank you, Nellie, and
I'm sorry about the mix-up.
No problem.
Are you kidding me?
What were you thinking?
I just thought you
could talk to her.
That's not the way
it works, Jackie.
You can't just
summon another doctor
to the hospital in my name
without my permission.
I really have to
explain that to you?
I just can't stop thinking about
a little girl losing her dad.
- Okay.
Well, you heard Dr. Cuevas.
Whatever this glitch
is, it ain't good.
So for now, anyway, he's
exactly where he needs to be.
Dr. Ripley, this is
my sister, Connie.
Nice to meet you.
Thank you so much for
taking such good care of MK.
She needs to slow down.
Please stop, Con.
Are you ready to go up
to radiology for a CT?
Are you okay? You seem sad.
I'm... I'm great.
Why?
You just lied to
a nun, Dr. Ripley.
My big sis has a sixth
sense about human emotion.
You should just confess now.
Uh, can I confess after the CT?
Only priests take confession.
But you and I will
definitely have a chat.
Deal.
Okay, Olivia, I have great news.
Your red count is
within a healthy range,
your liver and kidney
function is normal,
and you are negative
for Rh protein.
That's such a
relief. Thank you.
Okay, let's just get
a quick look at baby
and you should be good to go.
- Sounds good, Dr. Asher.
- Okay.
Here we go.
Do you not know the
sex of your baby?
No, uh, I didn't do it with Leo.
Kind of old-school.
That works for me.
Is there something wrong?
No. No, nothing's wrong.
But if you're okay
with it, Olivia,
I would like to run
a few more tests.
Something is wrong.
I just wanna be extra thorough
since you came all this way.
Okay. Um, do whatever
you need to do.
Okay.
I'll put those work orders
in and check back shortly.
Mags, Olivia's baby's
heart rate's low.
- How low?
- 125.
That's the low side of normal.
Bradycardia in a fetus can
have a number of explanations.
Yeah, but in rare instances
it can also indicate
a fetal heart block,
so I wanna get
an SSA antibody test
just to rule it out.
Well, we told Lenox that
it was gonna be an hour,
and it's been two hours.
If she catches wind of
Olivia even being here...
I get it.
Okay.
So you were bitten by a bat?
No, dude.
I told the nurse I had a close
encounter with a few bats
and my mom insisted I
get a rabies vaccine.
Okay, and where did you
encounter these bats?
Kevin's house.
Educate me.
It's a haunted house in Uptown.
Back in the early
'90s, Kevin was my age.
Liked to sass the 'rents,
so eventually they chained his
mouthy ass up in the basement
and let him starve to death.
Still haven't found his body.
Okay. Looks like
you did get bit.
I didn't feel a thing.
Yeah, well, bat teeth are tiny,
so the bites can
sometimes go undetected.
But we'll vaccinate
you for rabies
just to be safe, all right?
Am I gonna die?
Well, it's almost 100% fatal
if you start showing symptoms,
but I got you.
It's okay.
Dude, my friends
are gonna be shook.
Excuse me?
My bros, over there.
Right. Okay.
Well, looks like your bros are
gonna need a jab, too, then.
Hey, uh, can I get
your eyes on something?
Yeah, sure.
It's my patient in T3.
- The nun?
- Yeah.
Are my eyes playing
tricks on me,
or is that what I think it is?
It's a baby, right?
Yeah, at least...
it was.
I've never been pregnant.
Well, even though you may not
have realized it at the time,
this image shows
us that you were
until sometime in
the second trimester.
Clearly, the fetus
did not survive.
But that's a miscarriage.
You're telling me there's
a baby in me right now?
Normally, the body
would expel the fetus,
but in very rare cases it
can be retained by the uterus
and the body launches an immune
response that calcifies it.
It's called a lithopedion.
Um, a stone baby.
But why now?
Uh, after all these years of
having no idea it was there?
Well, your body's entered
a premenopausal phase,
so the hormone changes
likely caused your uterus
to contract, which resulted
in your abdominal pain.
And sometimes this condition
can remain asymptomatic
for a lifetime.
So what happens now?
We remove it surgically.
Sooner the better.
I'd like to get you
into surgery tonight.
But, um, we can...
we can wait a day or two
if you need some time.
Tonight is fine.
I'm ready.
CPD called.
My house was completely cleared.
- Total sweep?
- Y-yeah.
I mean, they didn't find
any evidence of forced entry
or that anyone had been there.
Okay. So what now?
I mean, better not be trying
to tell you you imagined
the whole thing.
Well, who knows? But I
know how I felt, Daniel.
Someone was in my house.
- Okay.
Well, that's easy.
You're gonna sleep
somewhere else,
you know, until we figure
out what's going on.
Well, they offered a
patrol car out front.
I said yes.
- That ain't nothing.
I mean, will it make
you feel better?
At least it might help me sleep.
Where is the real injury?
The cut over my right eye.
The skin tore pretty deeply.
You are definitely
gonna need stitches.
I got clocked in the
face by a customer.
Customer?
Yeah.
I'm a performer at the Fun
Farm Halloween Night Show.
It sounds like you're
too good at your job.
Who goes to a Halloween show
if they don't want
a few jump scares?
It's what he paid for.
I'd take it as a compliment.
Really?
Well, yeah, it means you gave
an authentic performance.
Mm.
- Thank you.
- A small pinch here.
Next.
All right. You okay?
Hey, thank you
for your patience.
Can you lift your sleeve up
over your shoulder, please?
I need you to calm
down, all right?
Take a seat for me now!
Oh!
Relax!
He's biting me!
God!
Relax!
What's up with your friend, man?
- We don't know him.
- You don't?
He escaped the psych
unit a few hours ago.
He must have slipped out during
that other guy's attempt.
Come on, Kevin.
Whoa, it's Kevin.
Kevin's alive!
- Whoa!
Kev... what is
going on tonight?
Mm-mm.
God! Ouch!
Wait, so you're saying
that there's something
wrong with my baby's heart?
Your test shows
what I believe to be
an atrioventricular block.
What does that mean?
It means that your body
has developed a rare
set of antibodies
and has disrupted your
baby's cardiac development.
Oh, my God.
- Just listen.
- Okay.
We've already given you
a course of steroids
to help root out the
dangerous antigens
and now have started an IV drip
to help replace them
with the healthy ones.
So my baby's gonna be okay?
She's gonna be just fine.
Wait, she?
Sounds like someone let
the cat out of the bag.
I cannot believe
I just did that.
- Oh, my gosh. No, Olivia!
- No worries.
I'm so... I've
never... oh, my God.
I'm glad that you told me.
Thank you. Thank
you for helping me.
No, thank yourself.
Dr. Asher only caught this
because you decided
to come in early.
It could have been a lot worse
had you decided to wait longer.
Leo, you're gonna have...
wait, where did...
where did Leo go?
Wait, where did he go?
Okay, no worries.
I'll go track him down.
- Okay.
Leo.
- Stop trying to hurt me.
- Leo, are you okay, honey?
- I will not let you hurt me!
- No, Ted, we're trying to...
- Stop it!
- We just...
It's okay, Leo.
They're just trying to help him.
Leo, it's okay.
It's okay, Leo.
Okay, Leo...
What's going on here?
Leo's autistic, and
he wandered out here
and just melted down,
and he screams any
time I get near him.
Okay.
Hey, is she mad that
Olivia's still here?
No, she ju...
I don't know what
she is right now.
All those people are scary, huh?
And it's really loud in here.
You're safe, Leo.
We can stay here as
long as you want, Leo.
What, um, what happened?
After his X-ray cleared him,
a guard came to take
him back to psych
and he had a full-blown
asthma attack.
His oxygen saturation
was down to 90
and he didn't have his inhaler,
so we treated the asthma attack.
And a few minutes
later, he just...
he completely freaked out.
What... what meds did he get?
An albuterol nebulizer
and fluticasone.
- Fluticasone.
- Mm-hmm.
The, um... the nasal spray.
Yeah, you were right.
You've been right
this whole time.
He, um...
He is mentally ill.
You know what?
I am not so sure about that.
Excuse me, MK.
I'm so sorry to interrupt,
but we need to get
you into surgery.
Please pray with me.
Okay.
Now, tell me what's
been bothering you.
Me?
- Mm-hmm.
It shouldn't be about me.
It should be about you.
I can sense sadness.
That's my gift.
Please.
My, uh...
my best friend's
dying of cancer.
I'm so sorry to hear
that, Dr. Ripley.
And tonight his little boy
was brought in with pneumonia.
Actually, a babysitter brought
him in because his mother,
my friend's girlfriend,
Lynne, ignored his symptoms
and decided to party
the night away instead.
I'm not sad.
I'm angry.
Mm.
Sometimes, they're
the same thing.
I met my baby's father
when I was 19.
He was a few years older than me
and he had the most
piercing blue eyes.
They melted my heart.
We fell head over heels in love.
And like magic,
I could suddenly picture
our entire lives together.
Marriage, travel, kids,
everything.
What happened?
He fell in love
with someone else.
And that whole life I saw...
vanished.
I'm so sorry, MK.
I think Lynne pictures a life
which is now slowly
vanishing before her eyes,
which might be the most
painful goodbye of all.
Be patient with
her, Dr. Ripley.
I will.
And I hope that beautiful
baby boy of hers
feels better soon.
He'll be fine, MK.
I like when you call me that.
Believe me, Sister gets old.
What did you say her name was?
Dr. Lenox.
She knew exactly what to
do when Leo melted down.
No one ever does.
She clearly has a kind soul.
Yes, she does.
Okay, Olivia.
So you are just about
done with your infusion,
and your baby's
heart rate is strong.
So I'll need you to follow
up here every few weeks,
but I expect that your
baby will be just fine.
I'm just so glad you're
doing this clinic.
It's not usually an option.
We're really glad
you came, Olivia.
Yeah. And spread the word.
I'm feeling much better.
Uh...
but I don't know why this
keeps happening to me.
Uh, I don't know. Maybe...
maybe my ex is right.
Maybe I am crazy.
Mm, I'm not so sure about that.
Do you mind me asking,
did you happen to
have an asthma attack
when you were arguing
with your wife?
Uh, I did, actually, yeah.
And do you always
combine fluticasone spray
with your inhaler to
manage your attacks?
Actually, no. Rarely.
But, uh, she... she really
got me worked up this time.
It was... it was a doozy.
Okay.
Can you remember roughly how
many pumps you used per side?
Oh, I don't know.
Five?
I think that what we're
talking about here, Ted,
is something very simply known
as a medication overdose.
You know, fluticasone,
it's a corticosteroid,
which is a class of steroid
that has absolutely been known
to induce psychosis in people
with, you know, a
certain vulnerability.
W-wait. I'm...
so I'm not crazy?
That's what was
causing your glitch.
And we think that the reason
maybe it happened again today
is even if we gave
you the right dose,
right, that that overload
is still in your system
and it just triggered
another episode.
If it's okay with you, I'd like
to keep you till the morning
just to make absolutely
sure that all this stuff
is out of your system.
But you will still
have plenty of time
- to make the custody hearing.
- Oh.
Thank you.
Thank you so much. Uh...
You were pretty amazing
with Leo tonight.
Yeah, her mom wanted us
to thank you for her.
Well... and...
Happy Halloween.
Dr. Lenox is a mystery.
- Even possibly to herself.
- Mm-hmm.
Hey, great job with
the clinic patient.
I heard it was very
lucky that she came in.
Yes, an atrioventricular block.
I am very glad
that we caught it.
But overall, your
prenatal clinic
has not been particularly
well-attended.
What are you saying?
That maybe we should pivot.
I spoke to Violet Mikami
last week, from Firehouse 51.
She delivered a baby
mere minutes after
the mother's death,
a death that could
have been avoided
by a standard
prenatal examination.
It made me think
of Elise Thompson.
So I'm proposing a mobile unit
that could visit
communities most at risk,
'cause listen, if the
patients can't get to us,
we gotta go to them.
That would be incredible.
We need to do better by the
pregnant women that need us.
And we will.
Good. Let's talk
details tomorrow.
Oh.
I know I overstepped today.
Yeah, you did.
I'm sorry.
It will not happen again.
Mm.
I'm just still trying to figure
out what you were thinking.
Totally get on the
face of it, like,
why you wouldn't want
Ted to be misdiagnosed.
I mean, I understand...
- I've been there.
As you well know.
And, um, here's the
thing about a psych ward.
It's... it's scary.
It's heavy and it
sticks with you.
Every Halloween, I...
I take my daughter
to this big bash
with all the neighborhood kids
and I was supposed to
go with her tonight,
but Carl changed his
mind at the last minute.
Yeah, he says he's
worried about me.
Um...
but the truth is, he doesn't
want me to be alone with her.
There's always that fear that,
you know, that I'm gonna
go to that place again.
Do you, uh... do you mind
me asking, did you...
did you ever think maybe
that I had misdiagnosed you?
No.
No, there was something
wrong with me.
And I'm... I'm grateful
for what you did.
Otherwise, I don't know
if I would be here today.
Mm.
That's great.
Nate's breathing is improving.
That means the antibiotics
are working well.
When can I take him home?
I'd like to keep him
overnight for observation
just to make sure his
oxygen levels remain normal.
- Can I stay with him?
- Sure, yeah, yeah.
We'll set up a cot for
you so you're comfortable.
Thank you.
Need some company?
That depends.
Will that involve judgment and
thinly veiled condescension?
I'll leave you to it.
Thank you for
everything, Dr. Frost.
Of course. Yeah, yeah.
I'm sorry.
For how I treated you and...
For what you're going through.
And you were right.
I haven't been
there like I should.
But that changes now.
Whatever you need, I'm game.
Mitchell Ripley,
taking the high road?
Taking my head out
of my ass, actually.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
Does Sully know I'm here?
No.
And he won't, not from me.
Helen, I come bearing peanut
butter cups, as promised.
Who says guilt isn't useful?
Not me.
How's Kyle?
Milking the photos
of his red eyes
for full sympathetic
impact on Instagram.
Good for him.
Well, if there's
anything I can do.
You know, actually, there is.
I just noticed that you
have a doorbell camera.
Can I see the footage?
Of course you can.
I'll send you a file.
- Great, thank you.
- Yeah.
- Good night.