Hey!
How long have I...
Blunt force trauma to the
head did the fatal damage.
Since the accident,
he's had a continuous...
Can't get up. What's
wrong with my legs?
Hey, someone talk to me!
Hey, you don't hear
me talking to you?
Great heart for transplant.
Who?
My heart? Oh, God. They
don't know I'm in here.
Hey, genius. I think it
violates certain ethical laws
to rip the organs out
of a guy that's still alive.
Possibly certain law laws,
too. LEE: Thank you. Thank you.
Could you get back in your
bed, please, Mr. House?
- It's actually Dr. House.
- This guy's a doctor?
There's also a Navy SEAL House,
but you're gonna have
to save up for that one.
Really? Well,
that's interesting,
but you're here because
you crashed your motorcycle,
not because I need a
consult, so get back in bed.
Scraped my elbow. Just
need a truckload of Vicodin.
Whereas this guy...
He's brain dead.
No, I'm not!
So drop it.
See that? KURTZ: Minimal
brain waves don't mean he's alive.
I am alive. I'm here. Isoelectric
EEG for several hours,
no EEG response to
painful stimuli, hot or cold.
What you're seeing is
random, barely discernable.
- I discerned it.
- Listen to him. Please.
No. That's just the
amplifier's internal noise level.
It's on increased sensitivity.
No, no, no, it's not! It's me.
Then why is his eye
following you? LEE: Exactly.
Following motion is
an involuntary reflex.
No. You're a doctor,
you should know these things.
No, no. I'm not dead.
I need help. I'm here.
I also know about
locked-in syndrome.
And things are either
involuntary or voluntary.
Blink if you can hear me.
I hear you.
Oh. This is gonna be fun.
Eye movement is deliberate.
Can you blink once
for yes, twice for no?
I hope so.
Square root of nine?
He got that faster than
you. Brain is fully functional.
Where's Molly? Lee,
you were in an accident.
Lee, hit the brake. Hit
the brake. Hit the brake.
You sustained a traumatic
injury to your brain stem,
which has cut off
your brain's ability
to communicate with
the rest of your body.
Can you fix me? Where's Molly?
You still have
movement in your eyes,
so we can get you
to a rehab facility
where they can teach
you how to communicate.
No, I can't be stuck like this.
Unless the crash didn't
cause the brain damage.
Maybe the brain
damage caused the crash.
Yeah. I couldn't stop.
Why couldn't I stop?
Look at his palms. No scrapes.
He didn't even try
to protect himself.
Suggests slowed
reflexes or no reflexes.
You're not a doctor in this
hospital, you are a patient.
Yeah. And you're the guy
who wants to cut out my organs
and he's the guy who doesn't.
Get me the scans.
Stroke, cancer,
even a simple infection, anything that
insults the central pons could do this.
Then that means
I could be fixed.
You're giving him false hope.
He needs to accept
what's happened
and work on
making the most of it.
Molly.
Hey.
Don't look at me like that.
That's not making me feel better.
I love you.
I don't know how God is gonna
get us through this, but he will.
Stop it, I'm blushing.
What are you doing?
Just looking for some
reading material for the crapper.
These CTs... Get back
in your bed. Come on.
The children are in the waiting
area. Can I bring them in?
No. No, don't.
You don't wanna see them?
I don't want them having nightmares.
I don't wanna scare them, Molly.
You don't want them to see you?
It's okay. I understand.
You're gonna be
better soon enough.
You really that sure?
Why are you so sure, babe?
How do you get so sure?
Are you okay?
Never better.
Here's your burger.
If you can't bring Mohammed to
Princeton, bring Princeton to Mohammed.
It's my diagnostics posse.
Hot, dark and darker.
Talk about getting
me better, please.
What are you doing up in
Middletown? LEE: Who cares?
Buying a Gibson '57 Goldtop.
It's the guitar Duane
Allman used to play.
Next to the trauma,
the most likely causes of
a sudden onset of
locked-in syndrome
are basilar artery stroke
and brain hemorrhage.
CT was clean.
Man, those fries look good.
Certain circulatory diseases.
Guy's an active bike
rider, his heart's fine.
A well-placed tumor
could explain it.
Jeez, is the last thing I ate
gonna be the last thing I ate?
It could evade the CT, and still
show up on an MRI with contrast.
It was a melted PowerBar.
She's the smart one.
I just keep dark and
darker to fill out the quota.
If we find it, treat
it, you can be fine.
I never thought I'd be
praying for a brain tumor,
but please, dear God.
If you're praying in
there, stop it right now.
We'll get his doctor
to order an MRI.
His doctor's busy teaching him how
to blink out "kill me" in Morse code.
Luckily, I found some
forms under the mattress.
Check it out, they have
those MRI video goggles.
- I heard these were awesome.
- What do you see?
It's a beach.
Oh, look. There's Taub.
Drinking a margarita and mocking
us for driving all the way up here
- because House said "jump."
- Easy. I can still feel in here.
Excuse Dr. Kutner. He gets a
little excited about new technology.
It can get loud in there,
and a little closed off.
These will put you
in a quiet place.
You can create a relaxing
scenario for yourself.
I hope they work.
Wow.
You're in my relaxing scenario?
I guess you like me.
Either that or
you got sent here.
What, by God?
I'm not sure if I
believe in God.
You spend an awful lot of time in
church for someone who doesn't.
I don't not believe either.
It's either one or the other.
I go to church to mainly
keep my wife happy, but...
I don't know. I've never
actually thought that
God could reach
out and affect my life.
But getting a brilliant
doctor in the bed next to me...
God is also the guy who
opened his car door in front of you.
I think Molly was right.
I think you were sent
here to make me get better.
I think so.
Hey.
Hey, Dad. Making a volcano.
Yeah. You're making a volcano.
Looks like it. What you doing, baby?
What time is it?
Hope you don't mind.
My new roommate snores.
And my new room
doesn't have you.
Your MRI showed a
lesion in the central pons.
What is that? What
does that mean?
See it there? LEE: No.
Yeah, that's what they said.
But it's there, which means
no way head trauma did this.
It's cancer, causing a
paraneoplastic syndrome.
Unfortunately, your
current doctor thinks
its diffused nature
means an infection.
Now, the bad
news is the antivirals
he's got you on might kill you.
I'm not gonna die.
The good news is, if
they just almost kill you,
then Dr. Idiot will realize that
his name is not a coincidence,
and he'll let me
do whatever I want.
Thank you.
See, the irony here is,
you're kind of fascinating.
So many questions.
But if you could
answer any of them,
then you wouldn't
be fascinating.
I get it. You're a
little nuts, aren't you?
Your wife is the one
getting you through this.
Your wife and me.
Although, frankly, the MRI was a lot more
useful than four hours of hand holding.
I think.
If he had a wife,
he'd know it matters.
You're a good
guy. Easy to talk to.
Wait, something's happening.
What's happening to me?
Need some help in here.
Your patient is seizing.
Why would he have a seizure?
Because he has cancer. His
brain stem is compromised.
Why are you still arguing with
this guy? You thought I was dead.
Welcome back. And nicely played.
You almost died,
exactly as we planned.
You knew this was gonna happen?
Usually happens when you treat
cancer by pretending it's not cancer.
Right, Doctor? My
turn? It's cancer?
No, it isn't. LEE: Yes.
Small tumor in his brain stem
causing paraneoplastic syndrome.
He needs plasmapheresis.
Can you give that to him?
No, no, I'm sorry. I completely
disagree with Dr. House.
Please shut up! I don't.
Which means I can treat him.
Let him. Let him.
Is that what you want?
Absolutely.
Could you send up
a couple of bellboys?
I got the transfer papers,
plasmapheresis is all set up.
Are you okay?
Fresh infusion of
macho. You like?
I can't move, and she's
worried about his boo-boo?
What were you doing
up there anyway?
Antiquing.
Found you a late
Victorian corset.
Come by later. I'll tie you up.
He hitting on her? If she turns
around, she's into him, too.
And there you have it.
Sorry, I didn't show up in
Middletown. I didn't get the message.
Probably 'cause
there was no message.
I decided to accept
your resignation.
Uh, I thought we were
past this. I decided to stay.
No, you didn't, you
had it decided for you.
So now you're stuck
here with a boss
who knows that you
wanna be somewhere else.
Which means you're no
longer motivated to impress me.
Which means you're no longer
motivated to come up with good ideas.
Unless I'm wrong.
Save the cheerleader,
save your world.
I got it from here. LEE: I
thought you already solved this.
You thinking you might be wrong?
What's going on?
Hey, just curious.
What're you driving up to
Middletown for? Why do you care?
Why does he care?
Because I'm your friend.
I was buying a guitar.
Yeah. I heard that.
Used to belong to a guitarist
who died in a motorcycle accident.
Just reeks of you
screwing with people.
Your crash was 10 miles from the
Orange County Progressive Pain Clinic.
You live 10 miles from
Mary's Dress Shop.
And yet, that's not even
on my list of reasons
that I think you're
secretly a transvestite.
If you're going to another
state to get more narcotics...
He's on drugs? I went to
visit your ex-ex-ex-wife...
What? who lives
in Thompson Ridge.
Let her know about the extra money
you're making on the lecture circuit,
so She'll be sure to
adjust your alimony.
You wouldn't do that.
Yeah, I wouldn't do that.
Would you?
You guys are friends?
Shouldn't we be
entertaining our patient?
I performed Euripides with
sock puppets, you just missed it.
House said we should.
The mind is like a muscle.
If you don't exercise it, it'll
atrophy, just like anything else.
Whoever's with him needs
to talk, keep his mind active.
And it'll show
House you still care.
Not sure if I do.
Jeez, you're my doctor.
Then why don't you just quit?
Not sure I want to
do that, either. Oh.
Maybe you should figure it out
before House figures it out for you.
Dude, maybe you should have
your midlife crisis after I'm better.
Kutner.
We'll be right back.
Wait. Wait, what
did you just see?
Do you drink?
He's a roofer, alcohol
hardly proves your theory.
Marchiafava-Bignami
disease fits.
LFT's are normal.
Speak English. Is it fixable?
What does that mean?
- That hurts.
- No tremors.
How much do you
drink? A six-pack a day?
I hate beer. I don't
even drink beer.
Could mean he
drinks more or less,
- or maybe something else.
- It may not be alcohol at all.
Street opiates could
also cause locked-in...
I don't get high. MPPP.
Either we play 20,000
questions with every street drug,
or instead of talking to
him, we talk to the lesion.
Talk to me.
We're going to
biopsy the brain stem?
For the record, that doesn't
count as your inspired idea.
It's sort of where
I was heading.
You're gonna cut
into my head? Why?
Stop treating me like
a piece of furniture!
I have a right to
know what's going on!
Where is that going?
Blood in your urine
clogged up your old catheter.
Peeing blood? That must be
what the insecure doctor saw.
Every clue gets us
closer to the answer.
Damn it! The surgery
will get us more clues.
You have visitors.
No. No, Molly.
You can come in now.
Daddy. Daddy.
I told you not to bring them.
They wanted to see their father.
I can't even hug them.
They can handle it.
It's gonna be all right.
You're not so sure
any more, are you?
They must have told you that
it's dangerous, that I could die.
And that's why you
brought them in here.
I got an A plus on my test.
To see me before I die.
I love you, Daddy.
Daddy loves you, too.
I want to show my drawings.
Kids just want a dad.
Even if he's just a lump.
Maybe you should go now.
Oh no, they can stay.
Please, let them stay.
Bye, Daddy.
Sorry. You were crying.
Damn.
We're going to put you out,
just so we can drill the hole.
Oh, that's very
thoughtful of you.
Then we'll wake you back up.
We need you to answer some
simple "yes" or "no" questions
while we're cutting to make sure
we're not cutting where we
shouldn't. LEE: Seems to be working.
Deep breaths. In about 10
seconds, you will feel light headed.
By now, you should
be floating high...
How come I'm not better?
God's not supposed
to work in trial and error.
God's mistakes are
well documented.
If he'd done everything
right the first time,
there'd have been one
plague and zero great floods.
Those were because
of human mistakes.
You think your doctor has an
apartment on Mount Olympus?
God put me with
you for a reason.
I'm gonna be all
right still, right?
I don't know.
Lee? You with me now?
Easy questions.
You'll be done
before you know it.
Is this equation correct?
What? So if you make a mistake,
I'm not gonna know that anymore?
Are these lines parallel?
Spatial relationship's intact.
Take a look at this circle.
Is more than half of it shaded?
Of course.
Don't forget to blink. Is more
than half of the circle shaded?
Sorry. Yes.
Look at me, Lee.
Again. Is more than
half of this circle shaded?
Blink. Come on, Lee. Blink.
Foreman, back out.
I can't blink. Cannot blink.
Why aren't his eyes moving?
Two options, my
neurologist screwed up,
or else something
that the hospital lawyer
is going to have to come
up with when you sue us.
Blinking and eye movements are
controlled by a small cluster of nerves
just millimeters
from the biopsy site.
But he's still in there, right? I
mean, he just can't communicate?
It's possible.
Also possible is that the surgery
caused so much swelling in his brain stem
that he's just gone.
He had one way to communicate
and now that's gone. Well played.
Brain biopsy revealed severe damage
to the myelin sheath. The question is why.
Epstein Barr.
Picornaviruses. Malaria.
He runs a business, meets a lot of
people, could have picked up rotavirus.
Did he report having
bloody diarrhea?
Wife's not sure. Says
he doesn't complain.
- Did you ask him?
- We prioritized.
He can only blink, a real
history would've taken weeks.
If he had Epstein-Barr,
he'd have belly pains.
If he had picornavirus,
he'd have headaches.
Five other "yes/no" questions,
and maybe we'd know
what treatment to give,
and what treatment
would kill him.
Unless he's already dead.
Maybe there's another way.
Brain-computer interface,
better known as BCI.
The goal is to get you to
move that cursor with your mind.
When you think "up", the
computer records the pattern.
Think "up" enough times, it
eventually learns what you're thinking.
So, start thinking "up."
You in there?
Are you trying?
I called the ex-ex-ex-wife.
She was at a sweat lodge
in New Mexico last week.
What were you really
doing in New York?
Know how you hate it
when I meddle in your lies?
I mean, your life?
Why are you being so evasive?
Unless you have
something to evade.
Interesting.
So it's nothing to do with
you, your ex-wife, or my pain.
I was heading to the Downstate
Correctional Facility in Fishkill.
One of your hookers
arrange a conjugal visit?
It's where Foreman's
brother is being held.
This is gonna mean months
of sleepless nights wondering
if I could've done
something differently.
Maybe it's not that
I'm sick of House,
it's that I'm sick
of being scared
out of my mind to
go to work every day.
Sorry.
Did that just...
Was that you?
Are you really in there?
I knew you were in there.
I was scared.
Thank God.
I am scared.
Molly, I love you so much.
Have you had any bloody
diarrhea in the last two weeks?
Rotavirus out.
Any recent joint pain?
Epstein-Barr's out.
Have you traveled out
of the country lately?
What about inside the country?
He was in St. Louis.
Good.
Could be Missouri malaria.
We'll start treatment.
He was there.
The machine must not be working.
Hmm.
Either that or he
lied to you about it.
People do that sometimes.
For example, I just lied to
him about Missouri malaria.
Did you go to St. Louis?
I should've told you.
Why didn't I just tell you?
Down.
When you weren't in
St. Louis for two days,
I assume you were getting
some strange for two days.
So does she.
You have to tell her I wasn't.
Amazing.
A man who only has two
blips at his disposal can still lie.
I'm not lying.
If you were getting some
really strange strange,
you could have
contracted neurosyphilis.
Infection went to your
brain, froze you right up.
Good news is, it's treatable.
You'll be up and moving in
time to sign the divorce papers.
Why would I tell you the
truth about being in St. Louis
and then not tell you
the truth about this?
He just admitted he wasn't
in St. Louis in front of his wife.
And you think he's lying
when she's not even in here?
I'm liking this one more
and more. Don't fire him.
Were you out of the state?
LEE: I never left.
Were you within 20
miles of your house?
Yes.
Were you within five miles?
Within two miles?
Yes.
Did you stay at a hotel?
No.
You had to sleep
somewhere. Your car?
No.
A friend's house?
Yes.
That narrows it down,
depending on how popular you are.
Tell the wife to stop
crying, get in here.
He says that when he was
supposed to be in St. Louis,
he was staying
at a friend's house.
Really? Yes.
Let's assume that you
believe him for the moment.
Name your friends
within two miles.
Martin and Kim's?
No.
Guess someone who
doesn't have a wife.
Dave? Yes.
You got an address?
If this is where he got sick, someone
else here should have symptoms.
Not if Lee was the only one
coming down to the basement.
Furnace is rusty
but no gas leaks.
Résumés and cover letters here.
Some are weeks old, he's been
spending time here for a while.
Business wasn't going good.
I didn't want you
and the kids to worry.
I was trying to protect you.
Molly...
I wish you could hear me.
I wish I could make
all of this better.
Looks like he
temped a few times.
As a janitor. Factory
out on Route 10.
The factory foreman says they
make rechargeable batteries,
mostly for cell phones.
Big step down from running
your own business to sweeping up.
Doing what I had to do.
Metal filings.
Judging by the color,
I'd say cadmium.
Which he'd aerosolize with the
broom, then right into his lungs.
Heavy metal poisoning
explains everything.
The chelation will scrub the
heavy metals out of your blood.
If we're right about the cause,
we should see some
movement in about a day or so.
Can you put this thing on turbo?
Getting a little
anxious in here.
Somebody will
be here at all times
to irrigate your eyes,
keep you company.
Hopefully help make
the time go quicker.
My eyes still feel really dry.
Thank you for thinking "up".
For helping me
find you in there.
Man, when you
moved that cursor...
Bought my first girlfriend
a necklace, it was silver.
Cost 180 bucks. Had
to save for six months.
She hated it.
Really, seriously,
would you tell this story
to someone who could walk away?
Never bought another
girlfriend jewelry again.
Until Dr. Hadley.
You're dating her? You might
want to start all your stories with that.
Same thing. She
didn't even wear it.
The diamond thing? She
was wearing it the other day.
If she doesn't like
it, she doesn't like it.
Apparently, I suck
at picking out jewelry,
but at least have
the guts to tell me.
Okay, getting boring again.
How long till we know if
this treatment is working?
You lied to me.
I wasn't having an affair!
So, we needed money, who cares?
The last time business was
slow, you got migraines every day.
Why would you do that to me?
I'm sorry, I was
stupid, I was...
Don't go. Don't...
Damn it! Somebody put
"I'm sorry" on this
stupid computer.
My eye is killing me.
I want to keep my job.
Great. All you gotta do is
come up with a good idea.
How about we hook the guy's brain
to a computer so he can communicate?
That's a great idea.
For the guy who invented the
computer that can read minds.
Your idea was to use his idea.
You didn't come up with it.
No one else came up with it.
If I didn't re-establish communication,
we never would have found...
What's interesting is
why you're here now.
Not when I gave
you the ultimatum.
Was it something
the patient said?
I realized that what
we do here terrifies me.
And overcoming that
is the only way I can matter.
Kutner found the battery factory,
Kutner came up with cadmium.
Maybe you don't matter.
I'm gonna close your eyes
so you can get some sleep.
Hopefully, when you wake
up, we'll see some improvement.
Hope that includes
my eye feeling better.
Hand me the fluorescein stain.
What does that mean?
Epithelium looks torn.
These drops sting.
I'm going to close your
left eye to keep it protected.
I'm gonna blink your eye a
few times to distribute the dye.
Ulcerative keratitis.
It means it's not
cadmium poisoning.
Which means you
don't know what's wrong.
Again.
When was the last time
you changed that dressing?
Judging by the smell
of it, I'd say never.
He's locked-in, his
kidneys blew a fuse,
and now his eye's oozing pus.
I assume you went over
all that with your team.
Also assume they didn't
have any brilliant ideas
or you wouldn't still
be muttering to yourself.
This is gonna hurt.
Ow!
The way he's losing his myelin
makes an infection most likely.
Could be varicella.
Road debris has come to the
surface. I'm gonna have to scrub it out.
And the initial acyclovir
would've treated that.
Which pushes me towards
an auto-immune disease.
Like Behcet's.
Here, this is gonna
hurt even more.
Take two now, two later.
Oops.
Of course, if the
varicella was resistant,
it wouldn't matter what
they did up in Middletown.
Do an LP.
You've been in the ER too long.
When the patient
had a head trauma,
white blood cells only indicate
that he had head trauma.
Or you could use the
LP for something useful.
If you find polys, it's
varicella, lymph's, Behcet's.
Why did I fire you again?
You didn't. I quit.
You weren't visiting
Foreman's brother either.
Busy. Kutner's doing
an LP so I have to focus.
I had prison security check
visitor logs, phone records,
you've never had any
contact with anyone at Fishkill.
So I ask again,
what were you doing
up in Middletown?
You know what's more
interesting than what I was doing?
The reason you are so
obsessed with what I was doing.
Stop deflecting, House.
Says the deflector.
The reason I was up there is the
reason you're scared I was up there.
I was checking out
your dirty little secret.
How long have you
been sleeping with her?
How did you know?
Your only secrets are the
girls you find embarrassing.
And the only embarrassing
girl you've met recently
is the one at your
brother's cuckoo facility.
We've only been out a few times.
She's a caregiver. Like
all your other failed exes.
And someone who
takes care of your brother.
Say, who was the last person
that took care of your brother?
You think this is oedipal?
Actually I was
thinking masturbatory,
but I guess your mom
took care of him first.
So the safe course is
to gouge your eyes out.
LP stands for lumbar puncture.
We use this needle to
collect fluid from your spine.
That's a really big needle.
You're going to feel some
extreme pressure in your back.
I already feel pressure in
my front. My chest hurts.
- Sort of a fetal position...
- Something's wrong.
The best angle into your spine.
No, my chest.
Something's
wrong. I think I'm...
Pull the needle out! LEE:
Oh, God, I'm flatlining.
Call a Code.
There is no God.
You don't know
what's wrong with me.
Doesn't seem that way.
So am I dead?
Not yet.
But you're about to be.
Okay.
Charging. Clear.
Again. Clear.
He's back.
LEE: No. No. Let me go. HOUSE:
The arrest means the demyelination
hit the area in his brainstem
- that controls heart rhythm.
- You can't fix me.
I've been here for three
days. We need answers fast,
'cause this is going to happen
again. LEE: Everything hurts.
We need to get him
started on steroids.
It's okay. Just stop fighting.
Not without the
results of the LP.
She's gotta go on with her life.
The kids don't need this. I
can't do nothing for them. I can't.
God, this foot. Oh,
that really, really itches.
So we put in a temporary
pacer, it's not gonna...
Shut up! Shut up!
He's trying to talk.
Something bothering you?
If there's still tightness in
your chest, it's expected.
Is it your eye?
Why's he saying "no" three
times? You only asked one question.
Maybe he's not saying "no".
Maybe he's saying "down"?
Are you saying that
the pain is lower?
How low? Your leg?
Your foot?
Left foot?
Check his... Let me see
now. Yeah. His right foot.
No bruises, no rashes, no cuts.
Then there should be no pain.
Is it a tingling sensation?
Is it itching?
Itchy foot means liver failure.
The liver's fine, his enzymes have
been normal since we admitted him.
I didn't say failing,
I said failure.
Just like you.
Liver's like a cruise
ship taking on water.
As it starts to sink,
it sends out an SOS.
Only instead of radio
waves, it uses enzymes.
The more enzymes in the
blood, the worse the liver is.
But once the ship has
sunk, there's no more SOS.
You think the liver's fine, but it's
already at the bottom of the sea.
So dying liver released toxins,
damaged the nerves,
led to locked-in syndrome.
Now we just need to know
what's causing the liver failure.
Liver plus eye plus kidney,
most likely sclerosing cholangitis.
Oh, God, if only
Taub had said that,
it would have been
a happy ending.
Do a biopsy to confirm.
I'm gonna numb up the area
where we'll go in for the punch biopsy.
Where's the new bracelet?
She was wearing the bracelet?
You didn't notice that I was
wearing it? Because you weren't.
He noticed and you didn't?
If you don't like it, it's
fine, it's not a big deal.
I like it. That's the point.
I'd rather have it at home in the
jewelry box than getting peed on at work.
You got the patient's
urine on that arm?
When I was putting
in the catheter. Why?
You've got a rash.
The bracelet's real.
I figured. So what if the rash
isn't just a rash, what
if it's an infection?
If there were rats
in that basement,
then the liver failure could
be caused by leptospirosis.
Transfers through urine.
Rat pee to him. His pee to you.
The infection would
need an entry point.
Look for any recent
scratches, cuts.
Look. Next to his fingernail.
The infection
destroyed your liver,
which released toxins that
caused the locked-in syndrome.
You were dying of a paper cut.
I hope you're right this time.
Let's start him on
high dose penicillin G.
We found rats in your
buddy, Dave's basement.
Tested positive
for leptospirosis.
Means we're on
the right treatment.
So try moving a finger.
Your brain needs to get
used to doing its job again.
Try harder.
I'm sure you've lost hope.
I know we've told you several
times that we knew what this was,
but this time we're right.
Concentrate. Move
one finger for me.
Welcome back.
I did it.
Rat pee.
Very nice idea.
Who came up with it?
I did.
Good.
You okay with him
claiming the credit?
It was his idea, he
saw the rash, he...
If he did, he would have hung
a "Mission Accomplished"
banner in my outer office.
Don't toy with him, if
you're going to fire him...
Fact that he stole your idea
means that he cares enough to lie.
That's all I needed to know.
Rat pee. It's a very nice idea.
House, you left
this in my office.
No, I didn't.
So either I have a
hole in my pocket...
No, that's right. I
remember now. I stole it.
Because if you had gone up
there to check out my girlfriend,
you wouldn't have come back
here and lied to me about it.
You would have thrown
her right in my face.
You underestimate the
entertainment value of your obsessions.
And then there were all those
calls you weren't taking in front of me.
So I dialed the number of
the calls you weren't taking.
You're seeing a psychiatrist.
You had no right to
invade my privacy.
Is that? Yeah, it's irony.
Hey.
God sent you.
Suddenly, you're
not so fascinating.
You're spying on your team?
Prioritize, Wilson.
Is that really what you want
to torture me about right now?
I don't want to torture you at
all. I think this is a great thing,
not something you have to drive an
hour out of town to shroud in mystery.
Yeah, whining on someone's couch
is an excellent use of my time.
Maybe I'll discover that
my childhood wasn't perfect.
So your attitude about
therapy clearly hasn't changed.
And yet you went.
Which leads me to believe that
maybe something else has changed.
Maybe you think you can
change. Credit Cuddy with that.
Not much credit to take
'cause I'm not going back.
Oh, House, please.
I assume you went because
you're tired of screwing up
every chance you
get at happiness.
View contact. Delete contact.
Do not let the fact that
I found out about it...
Don't beat yourself up.
I'm not going back
because it doesn't work.
You'll end up alone.