♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
♪♪♪
What is wrong
with people, Sam?
♪♪♪
I don't know.
And I try--
I mean, I know I can't,
but I try to put myself
in Charlotte's shoes,
and I try to imagine how you
deal with something like this,
and I just... I can't.
And I keep thinking--
how do you go on from it?
How does Charlotte...
Become Charlotte again?
♪♪♪
I really...
I don't know.
And Cooper? I mean,
what about Coop?
He doesn't even know.
What if she never tells him?
I mean, what's that gonna do
to their relationship?
I mean... do you think
it survives this?
I don't know.
I don't know the answer
to these questions, Addison.
I know.
But did we do
the right thing...
Going to the police?
That I know.
♪♪♪
We did the right thing.
You're safe.
♪♪♪
Char?
I'm gonna wait here.
I got a bunch of e-mails
to get through.
They asked to see you,
not me.
Well, go on in
and find out what they want.
I'll be here.
Okay, I know you're scared,
but you've come this far.
Let's just go right in there,
find out what the news is
on the case,
and then we can get outta h--
I'm not scared.
I've got e-mails. I'm busy.
You go.
♪♪♪
Her friends Carrie and Becky
started years ago.
And I'm four months older
than Becky.
Well, everything looks
just fine.
You know, it's normal
to start your period
anywhere between ages 10 and 16,
and you are only 15, Julie,
so don't worry. It'll happen.
Here.
What do you carry
in that thing?
Just my books and homework
for all my classes,
and model u.N. Stuff,
and sheet music for jazz band,
and a soccer uniform--
she won't let me
leave it in the car.
My whole life's in there.
The most important thing's
that notebook.
I just--i like to write
everything down.
It keeps her busy
so I don't...
Sharon. Can we get
some help in here?!
Don't worry, Julie.
She's just having a seizure.
Just clear her airway
to make sure she can breathe.
Lift her jaw, open her throat.
She was late taking her meds
this morning. She was
supposed to take them at 7:00,
but she waited till after 8:30.
It's all in my notebook.
Are you all right?
- It'll pass in a minute.
- It always does.
It's okay. Hey.
I want to kill my kid.
Literally,
I want to kill him.
You know the only reason
I don't?
It's 'cause some actress
would play me
in the made-for-TV movie,
and I don't want...
Unless it was Meryl Streep.
Do you think Meryl Streep
could play me?
'Cause then I'm definitely
killing my kid.
I don't think Meryl Streep
does made-for-TV movies.
Damn it.
Sometimes kids just have
a hard time sleeping.
Oh.
And you know this why?
- I was a kid once.
- I'm taking Lucas to see Cooper.
And Cooper is gonna tell you
that you're crazy.
I'm crazy
because of lack of sleep.
Uh, someone's here to see you,
Dr. Wilder.
He--he doesn't have
an appointment.
What?
Who is it?
I think...
I think that's my brother.
Pete.
Uh, it's good to see you.
Yeah, you, too.
It's been--
a long time.
Uh, i'm--I'm Violet.
Pete's married to me,
and, uh, and we have
a son--Lucas.
I'm Adam.
It's nice to meet you.
Wow. So I'm an uncle.
Wh--um, what are you
doing here?
Well, it's about mom.
I got work to do.
Pete--
uh, listen, our--
our mother is very sick.
And she...
We need his help.
I stimulate different areas
between the electrodes
until she seizes,
and then knowing
where that electrode is,
I can pinpoint the source of
the seizures on the e.E.G.
Neurosurgeons get
all the cool toys.
How long has she
been having 'em?
Seven years.
Since a car accident.
She's had extensive
neuro evals and treatments,
- but nothing's helped.
- What is with the notebook?
She records everything having
to do with her mother's care--
meds, diet, the duration
and proximity of seizures.
That's a lot
of responsibility for a kid.
Where's dad?
He died in the car crash.
Julie seems
to handle it pretty well.
She's 15.
She's too young
to be handling anything.
Mm, Sharon shields her from it
as best she can.
The girl has
a seizure notebook, Addison.
That is not a normal life.
I got it.
Checking the tracings.
What's wrong?
She doesn't normally do that.
Give me 5 of lorazepam
- and a phenytoin piggyback.
- Right away.
You have to help her.
She's not breathing!
No. It's okay.
It's okay, mom. It's okay.
It's not
working. It's not working.
She's gonna be okay, Julie.
It's okay, mom.
Did you find it?
Did you locate the lesion?
Yeah, I got it.
It's okay.
What are you doing to me?
Pete, I swear--
I asked you
not to contact him--
and I didn't. I didn't.
But now that he's here,
I asked him to stay
in the lobby.
You should tell him to go.
He says
your mother's very sick,
that she has
a serious heart condition,
and that the care
she's getting in--i--
prison.
My mother's in prison
for killing someone.
You can say it.
I don't want to do this.
Would it hurt
to hear him out?
Yeah, it would.
I don't want to do this.
You don't
have to do it alone.
I'll be here.
I will be right here.
Hey. Um, great news.
You ready to go?
They think
they caught the guy.
He say anything?
He say what he did?
No, he hasn't said a word.
So you ready to go?
No, uh, I'm sorry.
I don't think you understand.
Um, he's in there,
so all you gotta do
is I.D. him.
You pick him out of a lineup,
and then they can charge him.
I.D. him?
Yeah.
I'm going back to work.
No. Wait, Charlotte.
No, you need to--
I need to what?
What do I need to do,
Cooper?
I-I... I'll be right next
to you the whole time.
This is your chance
to put this guy away,
and then this is over.
It's already over.
I'm not gonna do this.
You comin'?
Charlotte--
then I'll go without ya.
There's
a relatively new process.
It involves inserting a probe
into your brain
and looking for the scarring
that initiates the seizures.
The probe is triggered
to transmit radio waves,
which heat and ablate
the scar.
She's gonna burn my brain?
I'm gonna remove
the trouble spot.
The idea is no more scar,
no more seizure, but--
you can just make them stop?
But it's not that simple.
The scarring that's causing
your mom's seizures is also
very close to
the motor center of the brain.
What--what--
what does that mean?
Dr. Shepherd
can explain the risks.
Your mom could wind up
paralyzed in the arm or face.
She could have an aphasia--
difficulty speaking
or processing speech--
and in very rare cases,
there is partial blindness.
But these are
worst-case scenarios.
More likely--i cut, the seizures
stop, your mom is fine.
And if I don't do
the surgery?
Well, the seizures
could get worse.
They put you at risk
for head injury and falls.
And if they continue
with the intensity
that we've witnessed,
you will likely have
irreversible brain damage.
Paralyzed today
or demented tomorrow--
lovely choice.
How long before the seizures
cause permanent brain damage?
10, 15 years.
Well, in ten years,
you'll be 25.
So if you didn't want to do
the surgery now, you could...
Do it in a year,
five years from now.
And be that much worse off.
It depends on when you want
to take the risk.
I'm offering you a cure.
No.
No surgery.
Look, is there a chance
for an adverse result? Yes.
But... I mean,
there is a better chance
that I can make you better,
completely.
I think
that Sharon was clear.
You and me...
We're doing all right
the way things are, right?
Yeah.
Yeah, we are.
You are not a neurosurgeon.
You were promising her
a cure.
Because I can give her one
because I am a neurosurgeon.
Look, I don't tell you
how to handle vaginas.
Okay. If you cut and it
goes bad, what happens to Julie?
If I don't cut,
what happens to the mother?
Right now,
nothing they can't handle.
How risky is the procedure?
Well, it's risky enough
that the mother could wind up
paralyzed or blind,
which means that
her 15-year-old daughter
would wind up taking care of her
instead of the other way around.
I mean, look, better that
they have five or ten
good years together
than none at all.
I am offering them
a lifetime together,
not just a few years.
Does the daughter
even want the surgery?
No.
Because she's taking the lead
from her mom.
No, Amelia. She heard you.
She heard both of us,
and she made a decision.
You stacked the deck.
Stacked the deck? I gave them
my professional opinion--
like I said. You are not
an neurosurgeon.
Did either of you
tell Cooper?
- What?
- No.
Absolutely not,
Charlotte.
I didn't tell Cooper,
but I-I told the cops.
The police brought me in
to interview a guy
on the night of your...
He admitted
to having attacked a woman.
He was--he was arrested
not far from the hospital.
Sheldon knows.
Is there anyone you people
haven't told?
I...
I sent the police
pelvic washings that I took.
I know you said no rape kit,
but--
please tell me
you did not do that.
You were in shock, Charlotte.
I wanted to preserve
all of your options--
shut up.
Just shut up.
They can't just arrest
the guy?
We can't get him off the streets
without Charlotte's help.
So that's why you're here...
Because of mom?
Well, it's not like I haven't
thought about getting in touch.
I'm sure you have, too.
She's dying.
Slowly, but she's dying.
And no one in there
gives a damn.
But you can help her.
How?
You know what
a humanitarian release is,
right?
You know, I've thought
about calling you.
Whatever problems you and I have
are because of her.
But for you to show up here
after all these years
and try to guilt me
into some--
I'm not asking you to do
anything wrong. Please...
Just go see her.
That's all I'm asking.
Hey. I want you to
convince her to do the lineup.
Come on, Cooper.
Maybe she'll listen to you.
She sure as hell
won't listen to me.
It's not my place to
tell Charlotte to do anything.
She hasn't asked me for help.
Like that's ever stopped you.
It's the right thing.
You went after Katie.
I wanted revenge.
So what's wrong with that?
Well, in the end,
that would've hurt me more,
so I forgave her
and I let it go.
Well, I want Charlotte
to have the same option.
I know her, Violet. She needs
to look that bastard in the eye
and say, "it was you."
Hey.
Heard you, uh, had a visitor.
Hard to keep
a secret around here.
Yeah. I was surprised.
You, uh...
You never mentioned
you had a brother.
I haven't talked to him
in a long time,
not since my mother...
My mother's in prison...
For manslaughter.
For...
Oh. I, uh...
I can't imagine.
Now she's sick.
He shows up out of the blue.
He wants me to help her
get a humanitarian release.
Are you going to?
I don't know.
What's your mother like?
Uh... my--
I don't know.
She's, uh, she's a mom.
My mother just...
Didn't really give a damn.
Well, my mom used to say,
"people do the best they can
when they can."
Her best wasn't anything.
You think she changed?
I don't know.
Well, sometimes
people can surprise you.
Homework?
Oh.
My model u.N. Speech.
Mm. That's a lot of work...
On top of what's going on
with your mom.
I've been through worse.
My dad died when I was 5.
And suddenly, I was always
worried about my mom...
You know, how sad she was
and how much she missed him.
And I stopped being her kid.
You know, she was always
trying to keep me busy,
thinking that... you know,
then I wouldn't worry.
Same.
But then I was just
busy and worried,
and after a while, it...
Well, it was all too much.
I worry every day.
Julie, listen to me.
This procedure...
Your mom could live
the rest of her life
without ever having
another seizure.
My mom thinks the surgery
is a mistake.
And i-i...
I want what she wants.
Keep your expectations low,
okay?
And if you change your mind,
you know,
you can always leave without
seeing her. That's okay.
No harm done. You sure you
don't want me to go with you?
No, that's okay. I'll be fine.
But thanks.
Okay. Anything else
I can do for you?
When I get home tonight,
I'm gonna... want nudity,
all kinds of nudity.
Absolutely.
I'm proud of you.
What?
I need to say something that
you're not gonna want to hear.
Then how about
you don't say it?
Can you listen, please?
You got 60 seconds.
Okay.
Um...
When they prosecuted...
My rapist,
um, there was this woman
in the gallery
of the courtroom.
And she watched,
and she listened
to what I had gone through,
and she came every day.
And then at the end
of the trial,
she, uh,
introduced herself to me,
and she thanked me for, uh,
for having the courage
that she didn't have.
Turns out that he had...
Raped her, too,
about six months before.
And I stared at her
and I just wanted to...
Slap her,
because I knew that
if she had come forward
then maybe--maybe--
I would not have been raped.
Screw you, Violet.
Charlotte...
The lineup is important.
No matter how hard it is,
I can tell you from experience
that it is
the right thing to do.
Time's up. Get out.
Hi, mom.
Hi.
Hello, Frances.
I was hoping you'd come.
You look good, Peter.
You filled out.
It's Pete now.
Oh, that suits you better.
Okay. Any chest pains,
palpitations?
Adam tells me
you're remarried
and you have a son.
I'd love to hear about
your family.
Well, his wife's a doctor.
Violet. And their
little boy Lucas.
Lucas.
Mm-hmm.
That's a good name
for a boy.
Well, your chart is a mess.
Have you ever heard
any of your doctors talk about
elevated blood pressure,
high levels of cholesterol,
or triglycerides?
I hardly ever see a doctor.
They don't pay
much attention to me.
You know, when you're old
and in prison,
somebody comes and checks to see
you're breathing,
then they just move along.
Uh, and that's why
Pete's here,
'cause I told him
how they treat you in here
and--and how bad
you've been feeling.
Let her talk
for herself, Adam.
Your brother's right.
He's trying to do his job.
Just let him.
You still smoking
and drinking?
Not officially.
Some things don't change.
No matter how hard
you try.
I--it's just
that we're all together again.
You're a doctor.
And he's a lawyer.
Would you ever imagine?
It's nice.
I'm sorry. I won't...
I'm sorry.
Hey.
Okay.
Okay what?
I'll do the lineup.
I will call detective price.
When do you want to go in?
I thought I'd ask Violet
to go with me.
Oh. Why?
Well, she's been through
the system... with Katie.
I thought it would
make things easier for me
to have her there.
Is that okay?
Sure. Of course.
Whatever it takes.
She's different, right?
35 years in jail,
it changed her.
How could it not?
It doesn't change
what happened.
I'm not saying it does.
But we can't
let her die in there.
Wasn't all bad.
Remember the swimming?
She used to let us swim
in Mr. Kramer's pool
whenever he went out of town.
We were
breaking and entering.
Yeah, but it was
still swimming.
You loved it.
We all did.
A hot summer night,
just the three of us,
swimming and laughing.
Stop it.
Stop what?
Stop trying to sell her to me
like a used car salesman.
I was there. I remember
everything. That's the problem.
I remember everything.
Well, maybe she'd do it
differently if she could.
Maybe she wouldn't.
I don't know.
You know something?
You have a chance
to do something right
for this family.
So if you don't care about her,
that's fine.
But you do this for me.
Hey.
So I spoke to Julie,
and I think she wants her mother
to have the surgery now.
First of all, you had
no right to talk to her
without her mother's consent.
Second...
How do you know?
Well, it wasn't explicit,
but I could tell.
Even if you're right,
Sharon doesn't want it.
Sharon doesn't want it
because of Julie,
because you scared her
and made her feel like
she was placing her daughter
in a terrible position.
Amelia--
no, if we do nothing, Julie
is gonna wake up in ten years,
and her mother
is gonna be a vegetable.
But Julie will be an adult.
I'm an adult.
Do you think that means
I miss my father any less?
He never
saw me become a surgeon.
He is not gonna walk me
down the aisle.
He is not gonna see my kids.
I would give anything,
Addison...
Anything to have him.
You're talking about
10 or 15 good years.
I am talking about a lifetime.
If somebody would've
given me the chance
to have him for all of that...
Even if she's changed,
it doesn't mean that
what she did didn't happen.
But it also doesn't mean
she can't be forgiven.
I don't know
if I can go that far.
You forgave me.
Oh! I gotta work
on my timing.
Well, at least I got
my pants on this time.
Yeah.
Thank you.
No, thank you.
Hey, husband number two.
Step forward.
Which, uh,
cheek did he kiss?
What is that for?
For talking to Charlotte.
You did talk to her?
You convinced her?
I spoke to her.
Oh, thank you.
What time
are you going to the station?
What do you mean?
For the lineup.
Oh, Charlotte wants you to take
her. Did she not say anything?
Uh, oh. Then I will.
Of course. I will.
Yeah.
Hey.
Hi.
Your mom said you were
down here doing your homework.
Yeah, I am. I was.
I'm just--
I'm trying to figure out
if my mom's seizures
are happening closer together.
I-I-I think they are.
You take good care of her,
don't you?
We take care of each other.
She's my mom, you know?
I don't, actually.
I'm not really...
Uh, biz--my mom and I,
we're not, uh...
We're not close.
So to me, having ten
good years with your mom,
well, that seems like a lot.
But, you know,
the kind of relationship
that the two of you have--
yeah, my mom's amazing
and brave.
I don't mind doing this.
I really don't.
I'm sure that
that's true,
which is why I think
that you've earned the right
to have a say in this.
If it were up to you,
what would you want?
Number 1, step forward.
No.
Number 1,
step back.
Number 2, step forward.
Step back, number 2.
Number 3, step forward.
No.
Number 3, step back.
Number 4, step forward.
He's not here.
Are you sure?
Yes. I'm sure.
Hey.
Did she pick our guy?
She looked him
straight in the eye
and said he wasn't the one.
But she saw him.
She knows he's the guy.
Well, not anymore.
Well, what happens to Lee?
Ask him yourself.
You can't seem to get enough
of this place, can you, doc?
There's plenty of other places
I'd rather be.
Well, then you and I,
we got something in common.
You'll do it again, Lee.
You'll rape another woman.
You don't have any proof
that I did it.
And even if I did do it,
it doesn't mean I'd do it again.
You think if you keep telling
yourself that, it won't happen?
Those feelings?
They don't go away.
And when they surface? Well,
we both know what happens.
You don't know me.
That was him, wasn't it--
number 4?
No.
I saw you, Charlotte--
the way you reacted
when he stepped forward,
the way you looked at him.
That was the guy
that attacked you.
I said no.
You didn't bring me here
for moral support, did you?
You wanted a witness to go
tell Cooper that you had tried,
because if he had been here,
he would've seen
how you reacted,
and he would've known, too.
Charlotte, listen to me.
I have been through this,
and this is hard--
I am so sick and tired
of hearing about your rape.
That was 20 years ago,
and you're still talking
about it, how you got over it.
Yay, you. Is that
what you want to hear?
No, it--that--
if you ask me, you are not
so whole and normal.
You are not so put together.
You are high-strung,
neurotic,
and you stick your nose
into other people's business.
That is what you do,
and I am tired of it!
Hey.
I've been looking
at my mother's chart.
I think I found something.
All right,
I see some mild c.O.P.D.
And evidence of
atherosclerotic heart disease,
which is pretty standard
from a long-term smoker
your mother's age.
I see
recurrent idiopathic v-fib.
Well, that's a potentially
lethal condition,
and I don't see
any indication of that.
Recurrent v-fib requires
a surgically implanted
automatic defibrillator,
which they can't monitor
in prison.
If she needed it,
they'd probably just release her
on humanitarian grounds.
They won't accept a medical
recommendation from me.
I'm family. But they would
accept one from you.
I know what I'm asking.
Here's my letterhead.
Write whatever you want on it,
and I'll sign it.
All right. I'm gonna get
a drink of water.
Whoa. Whoa.
Hey, how are you?
Daddy!
What's up, boy?
Come on.
Hi.
How was your day, big guy?
Good.
You slay any monsters?
Yeah?
If I give this to Sam,
he said he'd sign it.
I think I can get her out.
You sure this is
what you want to do?
I think so.
Yes.
And you're okay
with the fact that it's--
it's a lie?
If I want to get her out,
I don't have a choice.
Well,
sometimes lies hurt people,
and sometimes
they protect people.
Charlotte deliberately
didn't identify her attacker
in the lineup. She lied.
Why?
Because she couldn't
face up to it,
and now someone else
might get hurt.
Well, my mom is not
gonna hurt anyone else.
Well, maybe yours
is a good lie.
Hey.
You ready, babe?
Dr. Shepherd's just
signing my discharge papers.
Actually, uh,
Julie has something
that she wants to say to you.
What is it?
I think you should have
the procedure.
What?
Are you involved in this?
Actually,
I spoke with Julie.
You have no right--
no, mom... no.
This is about me, too.
♪ I ain't got no use ♪
I know
that you want to protect me.
But it doesn't matter
how many dance lessons
or sports or classes
that you sign me up for...
I never stop being scared.
So I need you to take
this chance.
I need you
to have the surgery.
♪ Who'll rock the cradle ♪
What if
something bad happens?
We'll--we'll deal with it
like we always do,
figure it out together.
Because I don't want
just ten more years.
Okay?
♪ Now that... ♪
Okay.
When can you do it?
♪♪♪
Hey.
What happened?
He wasn't there.
What?
He wasn't in the lineup.
Really?
Detective price
was so sure.
♪♪♪
Well, it's okay.
We'll get him next time.
No.
No next time.
I'm done, Cooper.
♪ I'll rock the cradle ♪
♪ and I'll sing this song ♪
♪ even when the baby's gone ♪
There are still some hoops
to jump through, but I might
be able to get you out of here
before the end of the month.
You surprise me.
Why?
I didn't think
you'd come through.
Your brother always did,
but, you know,
he wants to believe the best
in people, but you--
I have to be certain...
About people.
♪♪♪
How can I make you certain?
I need to know
that you've changed.
Well, I like to think
I have.
I-I need to know...
Are you sorry
that you killed Henry?
♪♪♪
Well, maybe it was
the drinking or the drugs.
I never saw the good in him
that you did.
If I say that I'm sorry
for killing him,
you won't believe me.
You'll think I'm lying.
And if I say I'm not sorry, then
you'll think I haven't changed.
Either way, I'm stuck in here.
You see that?
So who do you want me to be,
Pete? Just tell me.
♪ ...when the baby's gone ♪
Well, I'm not even sure
that it matters anymore.
I-i--my whole life,
I just wanted you
to be my mother, but...
Well, I was never very good
at being that, was I?
But if you're willing
to do this, to help me now--
then what?
Then you'll start to care?
I don't know
what you want from me.
Do you want me to tell you
that I love you,
that I regret every single thing
I ever did to you?
♪♪♪
I don't know. I...
I just know that this...
It can't be
some kind of a deal.
♪♪♪
Don't lie for me.
And I won't lie for you.
What do you want
from me?
Nothing.
♪ It's all I can do ♪
♪ all I can say ♪
♪ I'll sing it till ♪
♪ your next payday ♪
♪ gonna sing it till
your next payday ♪
Lee has a girlfriend...
And a little boy.
He has people in his life
who he could hurt
or teach to do
some terrible things.
Why would you tell me this?
I thought you should know.
I am tired of people
telling me what I should know.
♪ I ain't... ♪
We're all trying to help.
You're not.
Well...
If you figure out
how I can...
♪♪♪
So I made a promise,
but I can't keep it...
Because, uh, as a therapist,
I know
that keeping that promise
is damaging Charlotte more than
she's already been damaged.
Wh-what are you
talking about?
♪♪♪
She was raped... Cooper.
Charlotte was raped.
So you need to be
very gentle with her,
because... what she needs
is someone to love her,
no matter what,
even if she chooses
to do the wrong thing.
♪ Ain't got a baby ♪
♪ ain't got a baby ♪
♪♪♪
Hey.
How is she doing?
Well, at the risk
of sounding immodest,
she's great.
Adam.
Why are you not helping her?
It's complicated.
No, actually, it's not.
You get the paper. You get
the right piece of paper,
and you get her
out of that hellhole.
It would be lying.
And who would that hurt, Pete?
She's old, and she's sick and--
she killed Henry.
She killed him...
Right in front of us.
She is still our mother.
She was never
a mother to us.
She deserves to be
where she is.
You--do you really
believe that?
I know it, Adam.
Look, i--
I'm to blame for part of this.
I should've protected you
from her, from all of this,
or I should've done more--
all right, all right. Just--
just do something now.
Helping her is not the same
as helping you.
She's gonna die in there.
But that doesn't mean
that you and I...
We should try
to have a relationship.
Try with her.
Come on--come on in.
Have a drink.
Violet is here, and Lucas--
how can I pretend
to be okay with a brother
who turns his back
on his own mother and on me?
Adam, i--
no, no, Pete, if you're not
gonna help her...
I'm gone.
Whoa.
Hey, Coop.
How are ya?
Can I tell you,
I had the most amazing day?
I kicked some serious
neuro ass.
I-I want to celebrate.
Hey, let's go for a drink.
Well, I can't drink,
but you can.
What do you think?
You know what I was doing
when that man hurt Charlotte?
I was drinking with you.
I was flirting with you.
So, no, I don't want to have
a drink with you right now...
Or ever.
Leave me alone, okay?
Leave me alone.
I want a baby.
What?
A baby, I want one...
Soon.
And I don't...
I don't need
to talk about it.
In fact, I don't want
to talk about it. I just...
Our life is good.
We're good.
But I just thought
you should know...
I want a baby.
I want to be a mother.
♪♪♪
And I'm not gonna be
interested in waiting.
♪ In the morning light ♪
♪ I'm gonna see it,
gonna see it ♪
♪ gonna see it right ♪
♪ yeah ♪
I did the right thing.
♪ In the morning ♪
I did.
♪ Yeah, in the morning ♪
Tell me
I did the right thing.
You did the right thing.
♪ In the middle, in the middle,
in the middle of night ♪
You're lying.
Sometimes lies are good.
Sometimes lies are not lies.
They're love.
♪ Yeah, in the morning ♪
♪ yeah ♪
♪ in the morning ♪
♪ I'm gonna see it again... ♪
♪ I wake up feeling lonely
in the middle of a dream ♪
♪ I wonder if I'm ever ♪
♪ gonna make it to the end ♪
♪ the end, the end, the end,
the end ♪
♪ and now and then I see you
in the corner of a bar ♪
♪ reflected in a mirror
with a stranger in a car ♪
♪ I promise
that I'll leave you ♪
You know.
♪ You are, you are, you are ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ in the morning ♪
♪ yeah ♪
Come here.
♪ In the morning ♪
I love you.
I am in love with you.
I will love you forever...
No matter what.
This doesn't...
I'm yours. Okay?
I'm yours.
I understand why you can't...
I.D. that man.
I get it.
You don't want
to go through that.
I understand. I do.
But he can't go free.
That man--he cannot go free.
You have to be able
to sleep at night.
to breathe,
to be you.
He can't go free.
So I don't want you to worry.
You will be protected.
I will...
Get a gun...
Make it look like a mugging.
I-I...
That man is not going free.
It doesn't matter
what happens to me.
That man is not going free.
I am not gonna let you--
♪♪♪
It's number 2.
Are you sure?
♪♪♪