To all your friends,
you're delirious
So consumed in all your doom
Trying hard to
fill your emptiness
The piece is gone
Ten-minute warning. I'm fine.
What about your
meds? Got it, Mom.
You are beautiful no
matter what they say
House!
Need you. Forget
it. I'm going home.
Hay fever? Oh, you must
be a doctor and everything.
Two minutes. No.
The purple thingie on the file
means that whoever is one of yours
which means cancer, which
means no way it's two minutes.
Fine, I'm lying. 30 minutes.
Mystery of life.
Benadryl might help.
Already did 1,000
milligrams. Steam room?
Why, Jimmy. We'll talk
about this in the morning.
I got a 9-year-old with cancer.
Alveolar rhabdomyosarcoma.
Terminal kid trumps
your stuffy nose. Not yet.
She's hallucinating.
So the rhabdo's in her brain.
Make her comfortable.
She's got about a week.
Yeah, except there is
no cancer in her brain.
Pristine CT scan, blood tests,
protein markers, all negative.
The cancer's in remission.
Which means the
hallucinations are unconnected.
Fascinating, huh?
And not that it matters, but if you
fix whatever's going on in her head,
you give her maybe another
year. Long time for a 9-year-old.
No. It'll just fly by.
Five major surgeries, a
bone marrow transplant,
fourteen rounds of
chemo and blast radiation.
If it was me, I'd just stay home
and watch TV or something,
not lie here under a microscope.
Don't worry. Anything happens
to you, nobody's gonna lift a finger.
Differential diagnosis.
On your marks, get set...
Hallucinations could be caused by...
Whoa! Wait for it.
And go.
Latent neurotoxicity from
the chemo treatments.
No, patient's last round of
chemo was two months ago.
We would've seen it by
now. Genetic component?
Nothing on mom. Dad
split when she was pregnant.
His medical history's
also clean. What a guy.
What about graft versus host disease
from the bone marrow transplant?
Infection travels to her
brain, she has hallucinations.
Blood work and LP were clean.
But where there's infection,
there's meningeal swelling.
That CT shows no
meningeal involvement. True.
Get a tox screen and an MRI.
We can do that, if you wanna
ignore what we just discussed.
Sounds good.
Toxic exposure doesn't
make any chronological sense.
I guess there is a third
option. She's making it all up
because she doesn't wanna
get in trouble for breaking a mirror.
Unfortunately we can't test
for that, so tox screen, MRI,
and you stay away from
the patient. What'd I do?
Oh, well, you'll just get all warm
and cuddly around the dying girl,
and insinuate yourself. Probably
end up in a custody battle.
Chase, you handle the mom.
Tell her that you'd just sit
home and watch TV and die,
but you've got to go
through the motions
and try to save her daughter's
life. It's a doctor thing.
What the hell is this?
Black walnut and ginger.
It's nice.
I'll just lay you down and
I'll attach this thingamajiggy.
Sat monitor. Oh, a pro.
Don't have to explain anything.
I like it.
Central line for the chemo. Yeah.
Doesn't hurt or anything, does it?
No, it's awesome.
Instead of an IV, it saves me a lot
of time and a bunch of needle sticks.
Oh, I don't think I've ever heard anyone
say they like their central line before.
All right, can I interest
you in a walk in the park?
No, thanks. Okay.
Don't want any
butterflies, either.
Doesn't matter what the walls look
like, you're still looking for cancer.
Not today. We're looking for
an infection. But I get your point.
You comfortable? Yup.
All right. Let's get
this over with. A pro.
I like it.
Whoa! Look at the time.
I should've been out
of here 20 minutes ago.
You've only been here 20 minutes.
I can't slip anything by you, can I?
There's a patient in One.
Nah, I'm taking a sick day.
Take some Claritin.
Everyone's a doctor suddenly.
Patient in One
requested a male doctor.
Balls are in your court,
doctor. Union rules.
I can't check out this guy's seeping
gonorrhea this close to lunch.
Exam Room One.
Well, it's sexist, and a
very dangerous precedent.
If people could choose
the sex of their doctors,
you gals would be out of
business. Exam Room One!
Sore throat?
Well, it's not lupus. Well, not
everyone can operate a zipper.
You know, the up,
down, what comes next?
My new girlfriend
never been with a guy
who wasn't circumcised.
So she freaked, and... Ah-ha.
And you wanted Rivkah
to feel all gemutlicht. I get it.
It's a shandah.
I got some box cutters
and... Just like Abraham did it.
I sterilized them,
which I was told...
Stop talking.
I'm gonna get a plastic surgeon.
Get the Twinkie back in the wrapper.
House. Hey, House.
Andie's MRI and tox screen were
clean. No infection, no neurotoxins.
Oxygen saturation is
94%. Check her heart.
Her oxygen saturation is normal.
It's off by one percentage
point. It's within range, it's normal.
If her DNA was off by one
percentage point, she'd be a dolphin.
We've got a patient who for no
obvious reason is hallucinating.
Since it's not obvious, I
thought we'd go with subtle.
It doesn't matter. If her
sat percentage is off,
that means her blood
isn't getting enough oxygen.
That's a problem with
her lungs, not her heart.
And a lung problem isn't
causing hallucinations.
But the lungs could lead
us somewhere that is.
Welcome to the end of the thought
process. Primary pulmonary hypertension?
Maybe PE or pulmonary fibrosis.
Could be some bizarre
case of kyphoscoliosis.
I'm going home.
While I'm resting, you guys
get some arterial blood gases,
once you confirm that she is
hypoxic, I want a plethysmography,
chest x-ray, CT and V-Q.
But if all that comes back negative,
then snake a catheter into her lungs.
Don't worry, if I don't
sleep in, I'll get bagels.
You ever had this test
before? What's it for?
This goes all the way up the
vein by your hip, into your lung.
If I find something up there
blocking anything, I pull it out. Simple.
It's gonna be easy. The doctor at
Sloan told me I had a great aorta.
Oh, you have had this test before.
Sorry. I just like hearing you talk.
I've never kissed a boy.
There's time yet for that.
There was a boy last summer.
I was at one of those cancer camps.
I just never had the guts to ask him.
You know, there's a good chance
I'm not gonna walk out of this hospital.
Even if I do, I'm nine.
Not a lot of kissing
going on in the third grade.
You will walk out of here, all
right? And you will kiss a boy.
There you go. A smile.
Will you kiss me?
No. No one will ever know.
I'm sorry. I can't.
I won't tell anyone. Listen,
you're nine years old.
I'm 30.
I just wanna know
what it feels like. Once.
This isn't your
last chance for that.
What if it is?
Please kiss me?
Bagels. FOREMAN:
You didn't sleep in.
Didn't sleep, didn't
breathe. I'm dying.
Pulmonary angiogram of
Andie's lungs was clean.
Arterial blood gases and
CT scan were also normal.
Her heart and lungs are fine.
Which gives us no explanation
for the diminished sat percentage.
Yeah, oddly enough,
sometimes normal is normal.
Sometimes we can't see
why normal isn't normal.
Get her symptoms on the board.
You're letting me touch the markers?
It's written out in my
advanced health care directive.
Should I be incapacitated in
any way, you run the board.
Then Foreman. Chase,
you're just not ready yet.
What else? Guys, I know
we sort of ruled out infection,
but if we forget the
labs for a minute,
there is one infection we didn't
test for because of her age.
Neurosyphilis. There's no way.
If the infection dipped
into her cerebral cortex,
all peripheral functions
could be compromised.
No. She hasn't
had sex. She's nine.
Maybe it wasn't her idea. I mean,
she's been around a lot of adults.
All the hospital visits, the
counselors at the cancer camps.
You think she's been molested?
And hiding it pretty well if
there's any of that going on.
Yeah. All girls who've been
molested wanna talk about it.
Break out the rape
kit. She hasn't had sex.
Why are you so sure? She
told me she'd never kissed a boy.
You read her diary, too?
She asked me to kiss her.
I rest my case.
A regular 9-year-old girl
does not have sex on the brain,
not when a doctor's threading
a catheter through her vein.
But she's not a regular 9-year-old.
She's got terminal cancer.
Cancer doesn't make you special.
Molestation on the other hand...
She wanted one kiss, before she dies.
If she's never kissed a boy,
it's a fair bet she's never had sex.
Tell that to all the hookers
who won't kiss me on the mouth.
Hey, here's a theory.
She has been molested,
seeks refuge in romantic fantasies
with older men with great hair,
and I think you left
out the punchline.
Victims of molestation learn to
work the angles, manipulate people.
You did it, didn't
you? You kissed her.
It wasn't sick. It was
one kiss for a dying girl.
One small... One small
kiss before she dies.
Thank you. Thanks.
This is exactly why you
can't touch my markers.
Go see if she's had sex. Okay.
No one's ever touched
me. We just need to be sure.
I like your hair.
I used to have really curly hair. I
always wanted it to be like yours is.
Thank you.
All right, that's
it. You're fine.
With a patient. She dying?
No. Then she can wait.
Will you excuse
me just two minutes?
If only she'd been molested.
Then we'd have something to go on.
No forced entry.
One hallucination.
Maybe it was just bad
pork, maybe there's nothing...
She's not fine.
Her sat percentage dropped another point.
Which could suggest a tumor in her lung.
Lung wouldn't explain
the hallucination.
CT scans showed
both lungs were clean.
Which means there's a tumor in
her heart. Not a chance! Give me that.
I loosened it. I opened it.
We've got an MRI and an echo
of her heart. There's nothing there.
Give me one other explanation
for low oxygen saturation.
I can't. There's only one
condition that simultaneously affects
the heart and brain, but
she... Perfect, let's go with that.
Tuberous sclerosis in a kid that
also has alveolar rhabdomyosarcoma?
Two different unrelated cancers at
the same time is a statistical no-no.
What's the rate of cancer
in the general population?
One in 10,000? Don't.
Don't start with the numbers.
Way I figure it, one in 10,000 of
them should have another cancer.
Little girl won
the lottery twice.
It happens. So you're
gonna cut her open?
Exploratory surgery.
I gotta find this thing.
You're just gonna grope around inside
an immunocompromised 9-year-old?
She could die on the table. I
know it's somewhere near the heart.
House... you've got
to do better than that.
Why are we here?
Better acoustics.
Now listen to this.
It's a mitral heart valve. No.
Get the wax out of your ears.
This is the patient's
aortic valve.
I downloaded the audio
of her echocardiogram.
What are we trying
to hear? Tumor.
They tend to keep quiet on account
of them not having any mouths.
But we could hear an abnormality
in the sound of the valve,
which would indicate the
presence of something.
The tumor, for example. If we
could tell the surgeon where to look,
this is no longer an exploratory
surgery, it's a precision strike.
Her aortic valve
sounds normal. Too bad.
Now listen to the dulcet
tones of Andie's tricuspid valve.
Normal. And this
is her mitral valve.
I don't hear anything weird.
You guys make me
sad. Listen again.
She's had one hallucination.
Why are we operating on her?
Why are we risking her life?
Because Wilson thinks it'd
be nice to give the girl a year
to say goodbye to her mommy.
Guess maybe she stutters or
something. Now shut up and listen.
Tricuspid.
Mitral.
Again. CAMERON: Wait.
There.
There's an extra flap.
I'm gonna ask the surgeon
to look at the mitral valve first.
Chase, I want you there.
I don't like reading surgeon's
reports, they're boring.
I'm not really sure I should be
spending more time with her.
She'll be unconscious.
You'll be safe.
I'll be there when you wake
up. I'm gonna be fine, Mom.
Brave kid. She even
gave her mom a pep talk.
Mature, brave. She's a wonder.
What's your problem?
These cancer kids, you can't
put them all on a pedestal.
It's basic statistics. Some of them
have got to be whiny little fraidy-cats.
You're unbelievable.
If there's not one
yellow-belly in the whole group,
then being brave doesn't
have any meaning.
Andie handles an impossible
situation with grace.
That's not to be admired?
You see grace because
you wanna see grace.
You don't see grace because
you won't go anywhere near her.
Idolizing is pathological
with you people.
You see things to admire
where there's nothing.
Yeah, well, we're evil.
You find things to admire where
you shouldn't be sniffing at all.
Like Debbie in
Accounting. She's nice.
You shouldn't know
that. You're married.
So, the little kid dying of
cancer, I shouldn't like her?
If you're dying, suddenly
everybody loves you.
You have a cane, nobody even likes
you. I'm not terminal, merely pathetic.
You wouldn't believe the crap
people let me get away with.
They found a tumor. It's in her
lung, extending into her heart.
It wasn't visible on the MRI because
it's growing along the heart wall.
Now, because of the placement,
the surgeon has to temporarily
remove Andie's heart.
It's called an explant.
They cut out the tumor,
replace any damaged heart
muscle with bovine patches.
That's a patch made
from the cow's pericardium.
It's a sac that
encloses the heart.
What are her chances?
The problem is, there
might not be enough heart left
once they remove
all of the tumor.
And if the tumor's metastasized,
there's nothing we can do.
Dr. Murphy. Just
let me tie this off.
Doctor! What?
She's got a bleed in her eye.
They got the tumor, repaired her
heart, but she bled out of her eye.
She didn't bleed out of
her eye from a heart tumor.
True. The cardiac tumor
was benign. That's impossible!
Statistically... Oh, shut up.
If the tumor's benign, that means
it didn't cause her hallucinations.
That's why I'm mentioning it.
So, the tumor's a coincidence?
This is bad. You're
starting to state the obvious.
No, you said it would be there and it
was there. It can't be a coincidence.
A 9-year-old with
terminal cancer
gets an unrelated benign
tumor growing in her heart.
Why? It's benign?
That's impossible.
Talk to Wilson. And the retinal
bleed, another coincidence?
A clot could create pressure
behind the eye, cause the bleeding.
A clot could explain the eye, but
doesn't explain the hallucinations.
A clot could cause
mini seizures.
Great. Another thing that's
not causing the hallucinations.
Post-seizure psychosis.
The brain sort of corrects itself
after the seizure by hallucinating.
The clot could explain the
eye and the hallucinations,
but what about the tumor?
Tumors the size of an octopus
wrapped around a little girl's heart
are not just a coincidence.
She's not healthy,
she's never been healthy.
What's the theory here?
This girl's body's a lemon?
Faulty manufacturing,
everything's falling apart?
The tumor is Afghanistan,
the clot is Buffalo.
Does that need more
explanation? Okay.
The tumor is Al-Qaeda,
the big bad guy, the brains.
We went in, wiped it out, but it
had already sent out a splinter cell.
A small team of low-level terrorists
quietly living in some suburb of Buffalo,
waiting to kill us all.
Are you trying to say the tumor
threw a clot before we removed it?
It was an excellent metaphor.
Angio her brain before this
clot straps on an explosive vest.
Angio was clean.
There's no clot? There's
a clot, we just can't find it.
You can't do exploratory
surgery on her brain.
Are you sure you're
not a neurologist?
Okay.
She's gonna die. Well, the
clot's not gonna go away quietly.
It could blow at any time.
Are you gonna let
them know? I guess so.
Can I come with? To tell
Andie she's gonna die?
That's very un-you.
She's such a brave girl.
I wanna see how brave she is
when you tell her she's gonna die.
Go to hell.
What would you do if you
were told you were gonna die?
I don't know, I'd be devastated.
You'd cry like a baby.
Everybody would.
She's not doing anything.
She's a rock. She's brave.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Why?
She's gone through more
than most people do in a lifetime.
So what? Does that
mean she's ready to die?
What if her bravery
is a symptom?
The clot is causing hallucinations
and messing with her emotions.
You think her bravery
is chemically based?
It would tell us where to look for
the clot. Where's the fear center?
The amygdala, near the hippocampus.
It's a big area and a busy one.
You blindly cut in
there, you'll kill her.
Only time you're gonna
see this clot is at autopsy.
Then let's do that.
Is it still illegal to perform an
autopsy on a living person?
Are you high? If it's
Tuesday, I'm wasted.
It's Wednesday.
I want to induce a
hypothermic cardiac arrest.
Once the patient's on bypass,
we siphon off two liters of blood,
perfuse the brain
while she's in an MRI.
You're actually
talking about killing her.
Just for a little while.
I'll bring her right back.
Oh, well, in that case, go
ahead. Why are we even talking?
If we do nothing, she's
dead in a day, maybe a week.
The kind that lasts.
We need FDA approval
for any surgical technique
that's used for diagnostic
purposes. Absolutely.
If we were doing anything invasive.
But there's nothing invasive...
You know, I'm not cutting into
her head. I'm just looking for a clot.
Not invasive?
You're killing her.
Don't split hairs. If
it works, she lives.
Make sure the mom understands
that this is a million-to-one shot.
I'll see that Wilson
passes that along.
The plan is
basically to reboot
your daughter.
Like a computer. We shut
her down. Then restart her.
How do you restart
a 9-year-old girl?
We cool her core body
temperature to 21 degree Celsius.
Use blankets, ice.
Sort of like hibernation?
Not quite. In hibernation, a
bear's heartbeat is just very slow.
In cardiac arrest, there is
no heartbeat. So she's dead.
Temporarily, yes.
By cooling her, we limit the risk of
damage when we remove her blood.
Not all of it, two to three
liters. Half her blood?
Then we put it back. It's
called perfusing the circuit.
In this case, her brain.
And using an MRI, we'd
have a very brief window
to hopefully see
the outline of the clot.
If it's there, and it's
operable, we go get it.
And Andie walks out of here.
Signed consent
forms. Great, thanks.
You sound better.
I stacked a combo of
Mentholatum, a few Vicodin,
and something else
which I can't remember.
Should be able to ride
the high for a couple hours.
What did Andie say? About what?
About this? I
didn't talk to her.
She doesn't need to know
the specifics of this procedure.
What if you're right about her?
What if she just is that brave?
That doesn't mean she's mature
enough to handle this kind of decision.
Either she understands, or she's
not brave. You can't have it both ways.
If she does understand,
then she deserves to
know what's going on.
I'm Dr. House. I've
seen you around.
Your mom tell you what
we're gonna try? Sort of.
Tomorrow's test
could take 10 hours.
Given your present condition,
you might not even make it through.
My mom's done a lot of
research. How do you feel about it?
If we figured maturity came
from how much time you've got left
instead of how long you've
been here, this would be your call.
I don't have a choice, right?
I could give you one.
I wanna get better.
You've got cancer.
If I fix this... I have a year.
A year of this.
A lot of people
wouldn't want that.
A lot of people would
just want it to be over.
Are you asking if I wanna die?
Nobody wants to die.
But you're going to.
The question is, how? How
much you're gonna suffer, and
how long.
I'm asking if you
want this to be over.
What would you tell my mom?
I would give her 10
excellent medical reasons
why we can't do this procedure.
I can't just leave
her 'cause I'm tired.
But you can't
stay for her, either.
But she needs me here.
This is your life.
You can't do this just for her.
I love her.
Thank you for joining me
for tonight's dress rehearsal.
Playing the part of
Andie is Morty Randolph.
For his donation to
science, we give our thanks.
Once Andie is cooled
and goes off bypass,
we have 60 seconds to get
two liters of blood out of her body,
back into her for the pictures
to find the clot in her head.
If our star is bumped tomorrow,
while my MRI is on,
these red lights will go off.
Which will mean we
have no usable test results.
No test results, it's
goodbye Broadway.
You guys'll be wearing
bad cat suits in Des Moines.
We'll have neurosurgeons
here with a view of the monitors,
cardiac surgeon there in
case we need to open her up.
Anesthesiologists, one by
the cardiac bypass machine,
one by the cooling apparatus.
Girls in the chorus, if you're
over 5'10", stick with me.
Okay, give me 60
seconds on the clock.
Show time. A five,
six, seven, eight!
Siphon off the blood
through the arterial line.
Whoosh.
Sound of blood
draining. More whoosh.
And we kill her.
Again.
Sorry, my hand slipped.
How hard can this be?
It's a little busy
down here. Again!
If we didn't have to
lavage her gastrointestinal...
Again!
We could bolt it to the table.
Gruesome and
low-tech. Kiss me, I love it.
A five, six, seven, eight!
Here you go, Doctor.
This'll make you sleep.
A lot of people. Big
musical number, kiddo.
A lot of people here to make you look
good. You're kind of freaking me out.
He gets that sometimes.
Deep breath, honey.
Okay, go!
Intubate her.
Is that one okay?
Charge.
Here.
Body temperature
37 degrees Celsius.
Start the cooling.
You, go.
She's shivering. 200
milligrams of Vecuronium.
24 degrees Celsius.
We have afib.
What? She's dead,
that's the whole idea.
Go!
One liter out.
Two liters.
Okay, put the blood back
in. Reperfuse the circuit.
Anything, people,
anything at all.
Internal carotid artery in
cavernous sinus is fine.
Ten seconds!
Vestibulocochlear nerve intact.
- Middle meningeal artery clear.
- Five seconds!
Nothing.
We're over the limit. We've
got to start rewarming her
or there'll be permanent damage.
Keep looking!
There!
I didn't see
anything. It was there.
You sure?
Four millimeters lateral to
the hippocampus, I saw it.
House, she's out of time,
she's gonna be a vegetable.
I saw it!
That's good enough for me.
They were able to restart her heart.
She's doing as well as could be hoped.
So they found the
clot? We think so.
The neurosurgeons are
attempting to remove it right now.
And when will we know
if there was any damage?
A few hours.
Four millimeters lateral
to the hippocampus.
That's where I am.
There's nothing there.
You're not there yet,
keep going. I'm there.
Are you sure you
saw... There it is.
I think I can get it.
Hi, Mom.
Oh, hi.
You're treating your
stuffy nose with cocaine.
Diphenhydramine. Antihistamine.
New delivery system. It's
a blood-brain barrier thing.
It's all about speed, isn't it? One
thing to another, never standing still.
You're pretty good at that. I
know my way around a razor blade.
It's time.
Just a couple more
rocks. Andie's going home.
Right.
The parade of the
small bald circus freaks.
Sorry, I've got a thing. I
read her surgeon's report.
Oh? The clot was
nowhere near her amygdala.
Means her fear emotions
were working perfectly.
Yeah. Yeah.
So her bravery
was not a symptom.
Yeah. I was wrong.
She genuinely is a
self-sacrificing saint,
whose life will bring
her nothing but pain.
Which she will
stoically withstand
just so that her mom doesn't
have to cry quite so soon.
I'm beside myself with joy.
She enjoys life more
than you do. Right.
She stole that kiss from Chase.
What have you done lately?
I'm pacing myself. Unlike
her, I have the luxury of time.
She could outlive you.
In case you wanna
see real butterflies.
I'm not gonna kiss you.
No matter what you say.
It's sunny outside. You
should go for a walk.
Not much for the
long walks in the park.
Now get.
0 to 60 in 2.8 seconds.
Four-stroke, four
cylinder, liquid cooled.
You gain a lot of
torque according to...
Right leg?
Your right leg?
You can still ride.
We got excellent financing
right now. It lists for ten-eight.
I'll let you steal it out
the door for ten-three.
No, thanks.
Could I test drive
one of these things?