Is Dr. Benton done with
that thyroidectomy yet?
So he's still in there?
Dr. Benton...
Carter, what are you doing here?
Let's get an ABG in 20 minutes.
I thought you were
covering the ER today.
I'm on in a few.
Listen, I need to talk to you.
Well, you better make it fast.
I've got two
admissions, a clinic
and an aneurysm with Dean Rowe.
I've been thinking about that
kidney donor case last week...
The one where I left to go check
on the patients during the debriefing.
Instead of listening to two
of the finest transplant
surgeons in the country.
Yeah, I guess so.
And I've just been wondering,
you know, I don't know, maybe...
maybe I'm in the wrong place.
Well, if you're still here
in two minutes, you are.
No, I mean surgery.
Obviously, I love it, and I
still feel very challenged by it,
but are there ever days where
you don't feel quite satisfied?
Carter, sometimes,
the patient dies.
Yeah, I know, but otherwise?
Otherwise what?
Well, it just feels like
sometimes they exist
for us to do procedures.
Well, that's what
they come here for.
And we don't need to know
anything else about them,
like how worried they are
or where they
went to high school
or whether they
like cats or dogs?
Carter, what are
you talking about?
Sometimes, I like to
know the other stuff.
What for?
I mean, if you...
Oh, damn, um... listen,
we'll, uh... talk later.
I'm telling you it was
at least 50 questions
about my family background.
Nothing like the
head of security
to make you feel insecure.
He almost withheld my photo ID,
because I didn't know my
stepmother's maiden name.
Who knows their
stepmother's maiden name?
He didn't cut you much slack
on that picture there, either.
You'd think I was walking in
the front door of the White House.
Which is easier.
I've done it.
Randi, can you get
these over to Radiology?
Now?
Unless you're doing
something urgent
that I can't quite see, go.
Yo, Dr. Ross...
Yeah?
Pedes called.
You're covering deliveries
for John Lavagnino.
Broke his kneecap
playing soccer.
Okay, good morning to you.
Oh, not for Anna.
She just had her security
clearance interview.
Oh, yeah, you get
stripped searched?
They check for track marks?
Practically, yeah.
They're cracking down
because of what
happened to Mark.
He starts back today, right?
I wish he'd take another week.
Let's make sure
we're grabbing cases.
Keep his load light
for the first few days.
I don't want him working at all.
I want him helping me plan
Carol's surprise birthday party.
Doug...
Happy birthday, Carol.
I got vomiting
and diarrhea in 4.
Happy birthday.
Thank you.
I'm taking the quadruple
bounce-back migraine in 5.
Nothing like drug-seeking
behavior to start your day.
Doug, you promised me you
wouldn't tell anybody about my birthday.
That was last year.
Yeah, and you told
everybody then, too.
At least I'm consistent.
Ugh! Hey!
All right, coffee can wait.
What's this?
Uh, it's a coffeepot.
That is not a coffeepot.
It's called a French press.
Oh, no more aluminum percolator?
No, we're going to have
great coffee, which can wait.
What's that?
Uh, the microwave.
I'm just heating up
some cinnamon buns.
The microwave.
Mm-hmm.
I always wanted a microwave.
I know.
But you would
never let me get one.
You said that it broke
down the vitamins.
I know. I'm sorry, I was wrong.
Now, just come back over here.
This is nice.
I mean, this is really nice.
What happened?
She's getting close...
Nine centimeters.
What?!
I'm all right, Peter.
She fell and her
contractions are strong.
They went from four
to nine in no time.
Why didn't you call me sooner?
Last time they gave me
that stuff, and it was fine.
Couldn't you have
done something else?
Peter, this baby's coming.
What are you talking about?
It's two months early.
I know that.
You should have called me.
I just did, hoping
that you might want
to participate in the
birth of your child.
If that's what you'd like to do,
I suggest you gown-up
and get in here.
Hi.
Dr. Greene, right?
How are you?
I'm fine, thank you.
Who are you?
Anna Del Amico.
We met last week.
We didn't actually meet,
but I was there when
you were attacked.
Oh, in the men's room?
No, in the trauma
room afterwards.
I don't remember either room,
so I don't remember you either.
I start my emergency
residency in July.
I'm doing an ER Pedes
elective until then.
That was my first day.
I'm sorry it had
to be so exciting.
No, I'm just glad you're okay.
So... welcome back.
Thank you.
Where is everybody?
Mark, what're you doing here?
Getting back to work.
Doug and Carol are
bringing in an MVA.
Hi.
Hey, Mark, how are you doing?
Mark, welcome back.
It's nice to be back.
What do we got?
Bicycle versus tour bus.
Don't worry, buddy, we got it.
All right, you
just take it easy.
Settle in, nice and easy.
Dr. Greene, you look great.
Dr. Ross, OB called.
They need you for that delivery.
They said it's kind of urgent.
Find Dr. Del Amico.
See if she can take it.
Mark, I'll talk to you later.
She's at the desk.
Who?
Dr. Del Amico...
She's at the desk.
Oh, right, thanks.
Help me shift her down.
Breathe, Carla.
Come on, baby, breathe.
You can do it.
How much mag did you give her?
Six-gram load.
Had her on three an hour
until she hit four centimeters.
Then we had to let her go.
Dorgan, scalp electrode.
Keep breathing, Carla.
You're doing great.
Dorgan... what
kind of name is that?
Irish, through and through.
We've a lot of experience
having a lot of babies.
Is she at risk for
chorioamnionitis?
Come on, Carla, breathe.
Don't yell at me, damn it!
Did you give her any
antenatal steroids?
12 milligrams betamethasone.
What about her blood sugar?
She's got gestational diabetes.
You're doing great, Carla.
You just hang in there.
It's not going to
be much longer.
You're going to be
able to push soon.
What about a second dose?
This baby's going to have RDS.
Peter, what is RDS?
It's okay, Carla.
It just means that
the baby's lungs...
They haven't matured yet.
What?
You hold her hand,
you help her breathe,
you help her focus.
That's your only job here, okay?
Now, get over there
and help the
mother of your child.
There'll be two additional
security cameras here.
And two at the
employees' entrance.
That's right.
Now, the ambulance bay
doors will be changed over
to bulletproof glass,
which we'll also add
to your triage section.
The hospital has agreed
to additional armed security
in your waiting room.
What about the bathrooms?
Any security cameras in there?
Unfortunately, privacy issues
won't allow us to do that.
Yeah, my assailant's privacy
would have definitely
been violated.
We can only do what
we can do, Dr. Greene.
Thank you, Mr. Biggers.
It's nice to see
you up and around,
but what are you doing here?
Working.
It's nice to see
you, too, Chuny.
Mark, these additional
security measures may not help,
but they can't hurt.
I think everyone
is overreacting.
What we should really
be changing is the way
we deal with patients
and their families.
Yeah, can't we keep
them out of here.
They're a pain in the ass.
Your compassion
knows no bounds, Randi.
Oh, Detective Warrington called.
He can't make it by
until later this afternoon.
Okay.
You think that's who did this...
Some patient or family member?
I think that gives
them a good reason.
Louise Pierson: ankle
X ray three hours ago.
Where is it?
Discharge orders written
over an hour and a half ago.
The chart's still here,
so the guy's still here.
Med-surg admission: 5:30
this morning... still here.
Neuro consult, ETA
7:15 this morning.
Where are they?
We keep these
people hanging around.
I'd get pissed off enough
to clobber somebody.
Before Records clobbers me,
I need you to sign
off these charts
from last week.
Okay, I got them.
I'm fine.
Push, push.
You're almost there.
Keep going, keep going.
Hi, I'm Del Amico from pedes.
Janet Coburn.
I thought Ross was covering.
He's got a teenager MVA.
This is Carla Reese...
mother... Peter Benton... father.
Hey, how're you
doing there, Carla?
You just keep on pushing,
so I can take a look
at this little baby.
Mr. Benton, how are you doing?
It's Dr. Benton.
He's a surgical resident.
What are you, new here?
Came over from
Children's in Philadelphia.
Are you a resident?
Yes, that would be correct.
How many deliveries
did you attend?
I stopped counting around 200.
We've got a late
D-cell here, Dr. Coburn.
Carla's at 32 weeks.
Any meconium? No, fluid's clear.
Heart rate's dropping.
Where's the NICU nurse?
On her way.
Down to 120.
Why isn't he coming?
He's coming, baby, he's coming.
All right, let's get
this baby out of here.
Dorgan, I need
vacuum extraction.
Why vacuum extraction?
We're at 100 here.
That's why.
Number for respiratory therapy?
3-3-9-4.
Uh... I brought
some stuff in today,
because I knew
you'd be starting back.
What are you doing?
Well, you know,
I know you're going to
be a little resistant to this,
but you'll feel a lot safer
if you carry something
on you for a while.
I don't even know
what this stuff is.
I've got cops in my family,
so I can get anything...
Electronic stun gun,
personal Taser.
I don't think so.
Well, at least take
the pepper spray.
I appreciate it, really,
but, uh... it's not for me.
I'm not suggesting that
you start packing a gun,
although that's what I do.
You carry a gun?
Under the front seat of my car.
I was at the drive-thru once,
waiting for some fries,
and this punk walks up,
sticks a knife in my face
and wants my wallet.
So I reach under the
seat, grab the .357,
stick it up his nose, and,
whoa, could that kid run.
Dr. Greene, welcome back.
Thanks.
Thanks, Maggie, but I'm
going to pass on the armaments.
Carter, are you
in the ER all day?
Yeah.
Great, because I
think I'll need your help.
I don't really have full
mobility yet for procedures.
Uh-huh, what is this stuff?
Well, I was just trying
to get Dr. Greene to...
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Sit down, sit down.
Maggie, help me!
Just sit! Just sit!
All right, I'll get a nurse.
I'll be right back.
Just don't move.
Don't touch your eyes.
That's it, Carla,
push, push, push.
Come on, Carla, breathe.
We got him.
It's okay, baby.
It's okay.
Blue and floppy.
Peter, what is it?
I can't hear him.
What is it?
What's going on?
What's wrong?
Suction.
I don't like his color.
Come on.
Come on, little
guy, pink up for us.
Come on, let's go.
What's the Apgar?
What's the Apgar?!
Peter, back off.
Let her work.
Muscle tone
zero, one for reflex.
Two for heart rate.
One-minute Apgar,
four out of ten.
What are you doing?!
You got to do something!
Peter, please tell
me what's going on.
It's okay, baby.
It's okay.
They got him.
He's got retractions.
I need to tube him.
2.5.
Heart rate down.
Eighty-five.
Start compressions.
Draw up .02 epi.
Dorgan, call the NICU.
Tell them we're on the way.
I'm sorry!
I know it's not funny, but...
No, it's funny.
My whole life is just
one big fun fest.
Anspaugh hates me.
Benton looks at me like
I'm some kind of an alien.
Well, I think those things
are in your favor, actually.
Right, thank you.
So when you were thinking
about med school, you
were willing to start over?
All that work?
As opposed to your
five, six more years
of surgical residency
you've got ahead of you?
I guess I see your point.
Carter, are you back
among the living?
Yes, absolutely.
We've got an MVA coming
in six, seven minutes.
I know it's not my place to say,
but he looks kind of bad.
Are you okay there, Carla?
I'm just going to get
everything ready for you.
I'll be right back.
Just hang in there, Carla.
You're almost there.
Peter...
what are we going to do?
Have you seen him?
I'll go check on him as
soon as I get you settled.
Just take it easy.
Shh.
It'll be a couple of minutes.
Housekeeping hasn't finished.
Okay.
One, two, three.
Rib?
Yeah.
We're going to
kick you out of here.
Normal vital signs,
oxygen at five liters.
You mind if I steal some saline?
Go ahead, help yourself.
Pupils are equal and reactive.
No haemotympanum.
Chest is clear,
abdomen soft and flat.
Pulse is 80, BP 120/75.
What's his name?
Harry Smith.
Harry, can you hear me?
Do you know where you are?
Order something.
CBC, chem seven,
type and screen.
Want a dip of urine?
Yeah, let's get a
C-spine, chest and pelvis.
Police said it was a DUI?
The guy was swerving
in and out of lanes
on the Eisenhower
only going about 35.
Then he hit a light pole.
Let's get a blood alcohol level.
There's no alcohol
on his breath.
Hey, thanks for the supplies.
Anytime.
Whoa!
Okay, get some Ativan, two migs!
Where's Tabash?
Well, he's with another patient.
What's he ordered?
Everything.
CBC, lytes, blood
cultures, what?
Yes, all that.
ABG, chest X ray?
Yes.
Dr. Benton.
Your son is stable
at the moment.
What labs have you ordered?
We've done a
complete septic workup.
No, I need to know
exactly what you've ordered...
What, uh, labs,
what antibiotics.
Dr. Benton, your
son's heart rate is 170,
and his pulse ox is
91 on 100% oxygen.
We've taken a chest X ray,
drawn blood for
CBC, lytes and ABG
and sent off a blood culture,
a urine culture, an
endotracheal aspirate culture
a spinal fluid culture
and started him on 100
milligrams of ampicillin
and six milligrams
of gentamicin.
He was hypotensive
with a blood pressure of 30/18,
so he's received
five percent albumin...
10cc's per kilo... And
we've started dopamine...
Five mics per kilo per minute.
And we'll titrate
to a map of 40.
Now, what you need to know...
What you need to share
with this child's mother...
Is that at the moment
the baby is stable,
but critically ill.
Probably has a serious
infection in his blood,
and we don't know if his lungs
can provide enough
oxygen to sustain life.
Unfortunately, we have no choice
but to wait and see
how he responds
to the present therapy.
Let's see how he's
doing in an hour,
and that's when
we should talk again.
What's your son's
name, Dr. Benton?
He doesn't have one.
Carol, hi.
I've got some good
news and bad news.
You're going to tell
me both, so go ahead.
The bad news is your
brothers and sisters-in-arms
are planning a little
surprise birthday party
for you tonight.
You did this joke this morning.
This is real,
because I got invited.
Well, I'm not listening.
The good news is I know
you hate your birthday,
so I got you out of it.
I do not hate my birthday.
You've always
hated your birthday,
so I told them you
cannot make it,
because you're
having dinner with me.
I do not believe a word of this.
How many people wished
you a happy birthday today?
Just Kerry this morning.
And how many people know
that it is your birthday?
You know theirs, right?
Yeah, we've worked
together for years.
What is the one reason
why you don't wish
someone happy birthday
when it is their birthday?
Because they're
planning a surprise party.
That's all I'm saying.
Why is it I feel you've
trapped me into this.
Trapped you?
I saved you.
You should be buying me dinner.
I'll pick you up anytime.
You name the place.
Got some gauze out here.
Okay, I'm out of here
as of an hour ago.
Randi, can you send that Carla
Reese chart up to OB, please?
Sure, I got it.
Did you say Carla Reese?
She delivered about an hour ago.
Carla?
You know her?
No, not really.
She came through
the ER a month or so ago.
She wasn't near being due.
The baby's only 32
weeks... a little boy.
Is he okay?
I don't know.
He's in the NICU.
Apgar was poor, had to intubate.
It's touch-and-go.
Is she doing all right?
She didn't have
other complications,
if that's what you mean.
I don't know how many
preemies I've resuscitated,
but somehow I still
haven't gotten used to it.
I'll see you all tomorrow.
See you.
Jeanie, were you
taking that woman
with the eye pain,
or was that Maggie?
No, I'm taking her.
I'm just about to head in.
Don't keep the patients waiting.
They might get
angry and beat you up.
Dr. Greene's on a bit
of a rampage about that.
He'll settle back in.
He just needs a
couple more days.
Hey, Mark.
Hey, Doug.
I've been missing
you all day today.
How you doing?
Feels good to be back.
Not too soon?
No, I mean, it was nice
having time with Rachel,
but a week at home
is about all I could take.
Yeah, so any word
from the police?
They're going to
come by this afternoon.
I gave them a list of names
of patients and family members
who might have had
reason to be that angry...
At least the ones
I can remember.
So you're okay with this?
Yes and no.
It hasn't been the most
pleasant experience,
but it's kind of a wake-up call,
you know, a reminder that
I can be abrupt with people,
and it will sure
as hell backfire.
Hey, Doug...
Yes.
You've got a five-year-old
with a wrist fracture in 4.
Child in pain...
Music to my ears.
I'll catch up with you
later, get some lunch?
I'm so sorry, Peter.
The chest X ray showed
a diffused, patchy infiltrate,
and the endotracheal aspirate
showed gram-negative bacteria.
He's got pneumonia,
sepsis, premature lungs
and respiratory
distress syndrome.
They just gave him surfactant
to try to open up his lungs.
How's Carla doing?
She asked me to
wait outside in the hall.
You probably haven't shared this
with anyone, have you...
Your family, people
you work with?
You do have friends, Peter...
A community.
I hope everything
will be all right.
And you need to stop
standing in the hall.
Just keep your hands
on your sides, Mr. Lensky.
I can't.
It hurts.
Yes, I think we know that.
Pulse is 130, BP is 180/95.
Pre-op labs?
Yeah.
And you've been taking
a lot of ibuprofen lately?
Uh, yeah, about
eight tablets a day.
That's because I
twisted my knee,
not because of this stomachache.
Dr. Carter,
do you have a minute?
Sure.
Connie, let's get an
upright chest X ray
and give ten of
morphine, slow I.V. push.
That'll help with
your pain, Mr. Lensky.
I'll be right back.
I'm just double-checking.
This guy's the writhing
and groaning in Exam 2
that Dr. Greene was
concerned about?
Yeah, but I didn't
know he was concerned.
He was worried the
guy was waiting too long
for a surgical consult.
Well, Mr. Lensky's got
a boardlike abdomen,
absent bowel sounds
and rebound and guarding
in all four quadrants.
A perfed ulcer?
Sounds like it.
I ordered a film.
Have Anspaugh check it out.
Okay.
Colles fracture.
Going to have to do
a closed reduction?
Yep, his dad still too
flipped out to watch?
His dad's sacked
out in curtain 3,
having self-medicated
with ten of Valium.
Well, that's helpful.
Maybe we should get
a lollipop for Russell.
Fentanyl oralet?
Mellow him out.
I'm going to have to order
it from Central Pharmacy.
Okay, well, we
can try it without.
Russell, what we're
going to do here, buddy...
I'll just get that lollipop.
Yeah, get right on it.
I want to give
it a little longer,
but basically, the
surfactant didn't do much.
He's still requiring 100% oxygen
with high pressures
on the ventilator.
Okay, well, his mother
is going to want to know
everything that might happen.
Dr. Benton, every parent in here
wants to know what might happen.
We just can't know for sure.
You know, I did a Pedes
Surgery elective earlier this year,
but I'm not up to speed
on all the, uh... sequelae.
You mean like retinopathy?
Yeah, exactly,
although his eyesight
should be the least of
our worries right now.
We need to be more concerned
about intraventricular
hemorrhage,
periventricular leucomalacia,
necrotizing enterocolitis,
and in a few weeks,
bronchopulmonary dysplasia.
All right, what do we do?
Well, I'm concerned
about the high vent pressures
causing lung damage,
so I want to switch him over
to an oscillating
ventilator, and we wait.
Hey, Dr. Greene,
you got a second?
Yeah, what is it?
I got the head CT
back on Harry Smith...
The slow-moving
MVA from this morning.
It's negative, no bleed,
but I was talking to his mother,
who was filling out
some paperwork.
She said Harry was on his way
to a preemployment
physical for a new job.
She also let it drop that
she was pretty relieved
that the cops didn't find
any marijuana on him.
Carter, is this leading
to helping the patient?
His urine is like water.
Check this out.
Specific gravity: 10-0-5.
Uh-huh, I think we
should give him Lasix.
It might be hyponatremia.
Water intoxication?
If he's worried about
a urine drug test,
maybe he thinks he can dilute it
or wash out his
system or something.
Dr. Greene, transfer that LOL
back to her nursing home.
Did you hear anything
from that police detective...
The one who said
he was coming by?
Haven't heard, haven't seen.
That's a good thought, Carter.
Why don't you call the lab
and see if his lytes are back?
Okay.
Does that hurt?
That's why Dr. Ross
gave you that shot.
Nurse Hathaway...
She's going to pull
down on your arm,
and I'm going to push.
We're going to
pop that little bone
right here right
back in place, okay?
Ready to start?
Where's my dad?
Uh...
Taking a nap.
Uh, but he wanted
us to be here with you.
He sings to me.
He sings to you, does he?
So you'll do it?
Oh, I think Dr. Ross would
love to sing to you, Russell.
Yeah, you know, Nurse
Hathaway would like to join in,
but she doesn't know the words.
Oh, I believe I do,
too, know the words
to whatever it is Dr. Ross
is going to sing to you.
Uh-huh.
♪ Hello, Ma-da ♪
♪ Hello, Fa-da... ♪
♪ Here I am at... ♪
♪ Camp Granada. ♪
♪ It is very... ♪
♪ Entertaining... ♪
Pop it right there.
♪ And they say we'll have
some fun if it stops raining. ♪
Wrap that up.
♪ I went hiking ♪
♪ With Joe Spivy ♪
♪ He did develop ♪
♪ Poison ivy. ♪
You brought me all the
way down here for this?
I think he might have
perfed his stomach ulcer.
Well, of course he has.
There's free air
under the diaphragm.
It's a slam-dunk, no-brainer.
Drop an NG, consent him
and redline him to the OR.
Carter,
I realize you needed backup,
but any senior resident
could've handle this.
So please think twice next time.
Good news, Mr. Lensky.
We'll be able to fix
you up right away.
What is it?
You have an ulcer
which has eaten
through the lining
of your stomach,
but, with surgery,
can be easily repaired.
Surgery?
Yeah, it's a fairly routine...
I can't do surgery.
Well, let me explain.
It really is the only option.
No, I feel better.
That's the morphine.
Nothing's really changed
with your condition.
Mr. Lensky, wait a
second, listen to me.
No, you listen to me.
I will not have surgery, and
you can't make me have it.
Now leave me alone.
I want to go.
Can you tell me why
you feel so strongly?
Something happen to you?
To somebody else?
Mr. Lensky, I'm
trying to help you here,
but I can't help
you if you leave,
and I can't help you
if you won't tell me
what the problem is.
Of all the stupid things...
the gallbladder.
Well, my dad was such a believer
in modern doctors,
modern medicines...
"Oh, pop this thing out.
I'll be home tomorrow."
58 years old,
and he dies having his
stupid gallbladder taken out.
And the surgeon...
All he could talk about
was how simple it was.
"No big deal."
Afterwards, he came
out to the waiting room,
he couldn't even look
my mother in the eye.
He gave us the news and
spouted some fancy medical words,
and all I could think was,
"You lying son of a bitch!"
We shouldn't have
believed him, Dr. Carter.
How can I believe you?
I stayed in there.
I talked to him about his
father's gallbladder operation.
I explained why his surgery
was going to be
completely different.
I couldn't get the guy to budge.
I don't know what to do.
Not much you can do.
It's his decision.
He needs to get to the OR...
Not to mention
Anspaugh's going to take
my head off one more time.
I know we can't
override the consent
for emergency surgery.
No, we can't, but I
read a paper somewhere
about forme fruste... ulcers
that spontaneously seal off.
Do a paper-chase search,
see what you can come up with.
Maybe I should do
a hypaque upper GI.
See what's going on in there.
Good idea.
These labs came back
for you on Harry Smith.
Sodium 115?
I don't believe it.
I was right.
This guy's been
drinking buckets of water.
He's also waking up if you want
to talk to him.
Yeah, yeah, where's Dr. Greene?
Can I get you anything to drink?
Sure, I'll take a pop
if you've got one.
So it's good news.
All the leads you
gave us came out clear.
What?
Yeah, everyone checked out.
The patients, the families?
Everyone you gave us.
There wasn't anything on anyone?
Doc, usually people are
pretty glad to hear that.
They don't like things
happening in their own backyard.
Right.
Are you okay?
Sure.
I see you made a
pretty quick recovery.
Yeah, it wasn't as bad as I
thought it was going to be.
We'll keep
investigating, of course.
Got to go.
Dr. Greene...
Later, Carter.
I was right about the
water-intoxication guy.
His sodium is 115.
He drank three gallons.
That's great, Carter.
Great, terrific, wonderful.
Admit the medicine.
It's not that it's a better
or a worse option.
It just may be the only
other thing to consider.
Babies can respond
to inhaled nitric oxide,
and it can improve
their oxygenation.
In full-term babies.
That's correct.
It's still being studied
in premature infants.
We're participating
in a national multicenter trial.
There is a small series
which showed that nitric
did improve oxygenation
by 50% on average.
Now, half of those kids did
develop bleeding in the brain,
but no one knows if
the gas caused that.
Bleeding in the brain.
There would be a
risk of retardation
and cerebral palsy.
Yeah, but if we keep
doing what we're doing now,
then there's a risk of
permanent lung disease.
Yes, and possible brain damage
if the oxygen
level falls too low.
That's a hell of a choice.
How do I make that decision?
Dr. Benton, I wish I
could answer that question
for every parent
I talk to every single day.
Dr. Tabash?
Talk it over with
the baby's mother
and let me know soon.
Okay.
Excuse me.
Mark.
I'm an idiot, Kerry.
I'm a complete idiot.
Was that the police detective
you'd been waiting for?
It wasn't an angry patient.
It wasn't a family member
of an angry patient.
It wasn't Chris Law.
It wasn't Mr. Gunther.
It wasn't that crazy guy
who was yelling about Krishna.
They checked everybody out.
Yeah.
I thought I was
remembering it piece by piece
like a puzzle that
would all come together.
But the Chicago
Police Department
was nice enough to inform me
that I am simply the victim
of a random act of violence.
You knew that, Mark,
patient or no patient.
No, what I knew is
that everything I do
every day of my life,
I do because I'm not the victim.
I treat the victim.
I cure the victim.
I watch them roll the victim out
like a piece of
meat, but the truth is
I'm the piece of meat.
Yeah, but we can't
think about that, can we,
because we're the ones who
see what goes on out there.
We're the ones who
know every single day,
some child is not going to
make it home from school,
some father is not going
to make it home from work.
But if we allowed ourselves
to think that could be us,
we couldn't walk
out of our front door.
The problem is, that is us.
No, Mark, the problem is, it
makes us like everyone else.
Dr. Anspaugh, I was
just coming up to see you.
Where in the hell
is that perfed ulcer?
We should have had him
in and out two hours ago.
Actually, that's
why I wanted to talk.
Mr. Lensky prefers
not to have surgery.
Well, nobody wants surgery.
So... what?
I've discovered he
doesn't really need it.
Of course he needs it.
There's a hole in his stomach.
If we don't repair
that perf, he's at risk
for peritonitis, sepsis, death.
If you look, there's the ulcer,
but there actually is no leak.
It spontaneously sealed
itself off against the liver.
This patient was
redlined to the OR.
Who in the hell
ordered an upper GI?
I did.
You were supposed
to consent him.
He doesn't want surgery.
He needs surgery.
Maybe not.
I found an article that shows me
that he could be
treated medically,
which is what he wants.
Do you think this is about
what he wants?
Yeah...
I guess, a little bit.
Well, you're wrong, Carter.
This job is about determining
what a patient needs,
and the best way
for us as surgeons
to meet that need.
And as surgeons, we cut.
Dr. Anspaugh, as a
doctor, if I can find a way
to do what my patient wants
that's medically acceptable,
then I think that's
what I should do,
and I don't believe I
should cut somebody open
just because I can.
It bothers me, Carter,
that this patient is
willing to risk death
rather than undergo a
simple surgical procedure,
but, you know, it
bothers me even more
that you are so willing
to help him do that.
Oh! Sorry.
Mark, I still really
need you to sign off
on these QA reviews.
I don't have time right now.
But I'm off in five.
I just wanted to get...
Lily, why don't
you just leave them
at the desk for me, all right?
Done...
done... done.
You look very nice
tonight, Dr. Ross.
Thank you, E. Ray.
E. Ray, can you
file these for me?
I'll certainly ask Ms.
Kelly if she'll do that.
Ms. Kelly?
She's our temp clerk tonight.
Why do we have a temp?
I'm sorry, Carol,
but I don't think that's
any of your business.
Okay.
Good night. Good night.
Go grab a burger?
Yeah, he is so strange.
Where did we find him?
Mark...
Nina, damn, I was
supposed to call you.
Yes, although I hate having you
think of it that way.
It's been really busy.
Good first day back?
Completely fabulous.
Did you call Dr. Gillum?
That PTSD guy?
Well, you are post-trauma.
Look, I know I need some time
to settle back
in, but it's not like
I'm a postal worker
with an AK-47.
I... I know you're not.
I'm... I'm just trying to
help any way that I can.
I know, and...
and I appreciate it.
I'm... I'm fine.
Everything's getting
back to normal.
Mark, I don't like you
trying to cover with me.
I don't like you trying to be
a shrink with me.
How's Rachel doing?
She's, uh... sleeping over
at a friend's house tonight.
Great, tell her I say hi.
Sure.
Hey, Peter, how you doing?
How is she?
Well, remarkably
well, considering.
She's a pretty strong lady.
Oh, God, Dr. Coburn,
I wanted to apologize
for my behavior this
morning in the delivery.
Thank you, but it's unnecessary.
I've never met a father
who could handle it
sensibly, calmly, maturely.
If I ever do, that's the guy
I'm really going to slap around.
Yeah.
Today was the first
day I was ever afraid.
Well, I'm glad to
hear that, Peter.
I better get back in here.
Yeah, I'll check on her again
before I leave.
Hey, Carla.
I made the bed.
Isn't that the stupidest
thing you've ever seen?
I spoke to Dr. Tabash.
He presented
another option for the baby.
I think we should consider it.
There are a lot of
serious risks involved,
so I'm going to try to
explain them to you,
and, uh, then we have a
decision to make, okay?
You don't have to change for me.
I'm not changing for you.
You said we were
going to grab a burger.
We can get some
burgers at the Pump Room.
Doug, I'm not wearing
scrubs to the Pump Room.
Okey-doke.
I don't know, I think it
would be rather daring.
Surprise!
Happy birthday!
Happy birthday, Carol!
Oh, God, I hate you for this.
It worked out well,
don't you think?
What are you doing?
Waiting for you.
Come on... right this way.
What are you doing?
Come on, come on,
just come over here.
Have a seat.
Okay.
What's this?
A little something for you.
A garage door opener.
Go ahead, try it.
I always wanted one of these.
I know.
You always said
they were stupid.
Well, they are stupid.
I don't get why a person
can't just open the damn door.
I think this is the nicest thing
you've ever done for me.
That's pretty pathetic.
I love it.
Let's have a beer.
Okay!
Ah!
This is special, Doug.
I love having 20 people over,
especially when I have
so much to serve them.
Here, peel an orange.
Will you lighten up?
They brought booze.
Okay, I'll lighten up.
I'll, uh, just have
a sip of this milk.
You just drink that
right out of the carton
like that?
What's wrong with that?
Well, it's just kind
of a guy thing to do.
So, Doug, what
is all this about?
What is what about?
This little dance
you did today...
This... this party... you.
Well, I know you haven't
had very good birthdays
last couple of years, and...
The ones I spent with you?
The ones I forgot.
And, uh... I just thought
it's time you have a nice one.
You want a sip of milk?
Yes, well, I would
love a sip of this milk.
Thank you.
Dr. Weaver.
Hi.
Can I talk to you for a minute?
Uh, sure.
I know this isn't the right time
or the right place,
but I was just curious,
um... what would be involved
with getting into
Emergency Medicine?
What do you mean?
If one wanted to
change his residency,
would you have to
redo your intern year?
Has one talked to
Dr. Greene about this?
Ah! No.
You saw how he was in the hall.
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday, dear Carol ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you. ♪
Oh, my God!
Blow them out!
There's so many
candles on this cake.
What am I, 55?
Uh, yeah!
Hold on, hold on, one second.
Oh, I almost forgot.
Oh, wait a minute.
What's that?
It's so your wishes come true.
Make it a good one!
Make a wish!
Happy birthday!
All right, Carol!
You go, girl!
You still look good!
Happy birthday!
Make a wish! Make a wish!