Okay.
You are really gonna
love these.
New patient
satisfaction forms.
Oh, damn.
"On a scale of zero to 10,
"did the nurses treat you
with courtesy and respect?"
"Did the doctors
explain things
"in a way
you could understand?"
Good morning.
Morning.
Morning, Dr. Choi.
Every patient should be asked
if they'd like to fill
one out.
Just what we need,
more paperwork.
Incoming!
All attending,
to the ED, stat.
What've we got?
Found her in a coffee shop,
unresponsive after
a fainting episode.
Initial GCS of five,
but improved to a 10 en route.
Let's go to Treatment Five.
BP?
94 over 60, heart rate 144.
Afib with RVR on the monitor.
We gave her five milligrams of
diltiazem three minutes ago.
All right, gross deformity
to the left wrist
and a pretty good lac
on her forehead.
On me.
One, two, three.
Transfer.
Chemo patient?
Looks that way.
All right,
let's get her on the monitors.
You got it.
EKG and labs.
CBC, CMP, and ABG.
Yes, Dr. Halstead.
She's got a broken wrist,
Colles fracture.
Can you tell me
how this happened?
She's still in rapid Afib.
April,
10 milligrams of Dilt, stat.
Ma'am,
can you hear me?
Can you tell me your name?
Start her on a drip.
Titrate it
to get her heart rate down.
Dilt is in.
Heart rate's coming down,
110, 106...
Do we have an ID?
Find any family?
Right here.
I'm her husband. Sal Baker.
Any idea what happened to her?
No.
I mean,
Jen just went for a walk,
and said she was getting us
all breakfast.
Is Mommy okay?
Yeah, yeah, she's fine.
Just wait right here.
All right, Bailey?
Can we talk for a minute?
Sure.
My wife has
end-stage lymphoma.
All right?
I have power of attorney,
so, I need to instruct you
that if she starts
to die again,
per her wishes,
that you do not
resuscitate her.
Mrs. Baker?
I'm Dr. Halstead.
And this is my colleague,
Dr. Manning.
Hi, how are you feeling?
Okay.
Your husband said you have
non-Hodgkins lymphoma.
Yes. Diagnosed
four years ago now.
Okay, your husband also said
that you have
a do not resuscitate in place.
That's right.
What course of treatment
have you taken?
Everything.
Actually we've learned to
keep her records with us,
just in case.
Thank you.
Yeah.
We'd like to admit you,
and to wean you off
the IV meds that are
controlling
your heart rate...
I'm sorry,
Dr. Halstead,
but absolutely not.
I won't be admitted.
Well,
just until you're stable.
You're still in Afib.
I know you mean well.
But I'd rather go home
with my family.
We understand,
but we need to set your arm,
close up that cut,
and get your rhythm
under control.
All right.
But do it down here.
I feel like
once I go upstairs,
I'll never leave.
Okay.
We'll do our best
to keep you down here.
Thank you.
Talk to me.
Fourteen-year-old boy,
three penetrating wounds,
two in the chest,
one in the abdomen.
GCS of 10.
Go to Trauma Three.
Hypotensive since we got him.
IO in his left leg.
500 mils of saline given,
but his pressure's
still crappy.
This kid get stabbed?
No.
Jumped the fence
at a construction site.
He impaled himself
on some rebar.
Jeeze.
Okay. Ready?
On my count, one, two, three.
Yeah, we got it from here.
Thank you.
April, keep bagging.
Reese, put in a groin line.
Yes, sir.
Stat trauma labs.
And bring in
the level-one transfuser.
Mmm-hmm.
Suture kit's ready.
Okay.
Line's in.
Fast. Good job.
We got to tube this kid,
quick. Think you can do it?
Yes.
Let's hang
another leader.
Dr. Choi,
Treatment One, stat.
What do we know?
Olivia Gray,
math professor,
found unconscious
at her desk at work.
Blood sugar normal,
sinus tach on monitor,
no external signs of trauma.
Still unresponsive.
Looks like she's had
a seizure.
Let's get an EKG, labs, trops
and an ABG just in case.
Put her on oxygen.
Right.
Professor Gray,
can you hear me?
Lungs are really coarse,
grab the ultrasound.
Call cardio for an echo,
order a CT head.
Just lost the pulse.
Milligram of epi.
Chest tray,
we're gonna open him up.
Reese, on it.
Okay.
Doyen scissors.
Still no pulse.
Spreaders.
Here, Doctor.
Crash cart is charged.
There's a hole
in the right ventricle.
Skin stapler.
Stapler.
All right.
He's got a rhythm back.
We need a
cardiothoracic surgeon
to help with this.
Call the OR,
tell them we're on our way
up with an open chest.
Let's go.
Got it.
Getting pretty good in there.
Queen of the groin line.
Hey, you two.
Come on, gather around!
Gather around!
New
patient satisfaction forms.
You need to get every patient
who's been treated
to fill this out.
Wait for it, it gets better,
we have
a P and P in Isolation.
Oh, yeah!
What's a P and P?
Oh!
Reese should do it.
Yeah.
She's gotta learn.
Give it to Reese.
Let's go.
P and P,
pediculosis and phthiriasis.
Lice infestation?
Among other things.
What exactly do I do?
First, gown up.
You strip him,
scrub him three times,
then put permethrin
over every millimeter
of his body.
Welcome to my world.
Okay.
Don't worry, I'll help.
Thank you.
Jennifer Baker,
cancer patient,
where're we at with her?
Her arm is set, and she's back
in normal sinus rhythm.
I'm actually looking
at her history right now.
And?
And she's been through hell
the past few years.
Yeah, but a DNR?
Is she considering her family?
At this point, she may
think it's the best thing.
I don't know.
Zoe.
Dr. Halstead.
Good morning.
I know I was supposed to
call you back, I should've.
I'm sorry.
I understand.
You're busy.
Hey, S and B has an
outstanding new asthma drug.
Would you care
for some chew samples?
No, thanks.
Listen, I read a prospectus
on a clinical trial
you're doing.
For non-Hodgkins lymphoma,
a radio immunotherapy drug.
Veltarmomab.
Very promising.
That's the one.
Listen, I've got this patient,
she's tried everything,
nothing's worked.
I'm pretty sure
she fits the profile
for your study.
I'm sorry,
but the trial is closed.
It's full.
Zoe, this woman is end-stage.
She's got a kid.
I'm looking for anything
to give her more time.
I get it, but...
It's not a...
Just try.
Please.
Let me make a call
to our medical director.
No promises, though.
Thanks.
Her labs are back.
Electrolytes are way off,
BUN and creatinine sky high.
She's uremic.
Kidney failure?
Yeah. But it doesn't
make sense.
A woman this young.
I don't get it.
Call the renal service,
she needs to be admitted to
the MICU for dialysis.
Okay.
Staple across the hole
in the stomach, and then
we'll run the bowel.
TA 55 blue stapler.
Stapler.
Dr. Zanetti. Dr. Rhodes.
Dr. Downey.
I thought they were sending
a resident.
Had a window
before my next surgery.
You don't mind?
No.
This kid just caught
some good luck.
Who butchered him?
Fell off some scaffolding.
I meant the cracked chest.
Yeah, that was me.
Hmm.
Can we get to work
on the heart?
How's the gut?
Just had to fix a hole
in the stomach but we're done.
Give the 5000 heparin.
Yes, Dr. Downey.
Get a 60 Prolene
with pledgets loaded up.
Rhodes, change your gloves.
I want you
to help me up here.
He's about to
close the abdomen.
I'll assist.
You close.
Rhodes, I want you to
fix the ventricle.
Well, Dr. Zanetti really
has more experience...
You made this mess,
you clean it up.
Unless
you don't feel up to it.
Right.
Not too deep with the needle.
You hit the AV node,
you're gonna have to
explain to the parents
why their son
needs a pacemaker
for the rest of his life.
Let me see the repair.
That works.
Close up the chest when
you're done with the abdomen,
will you?
Yes, Dr. Downey.
You don't have any tremor.
Even for a young guy,
that's pretty good.
Not that I'm jealous
or anything,
but you just received
high praise from David Downey.
Why did he have me
do the heart?
I am asking myself
the same question.
Sorry to cause you
so much trouble.
That's all right, sir.
After you bag the clothes,
take them in for analysis.
Guess I let things
get out of hand.
Hard to keep clean.
Pants too, please.
Where do you live?
Lots of places.
In the winter, Lower Wacker,
by the heat vents.
Why not a shelter?
Don't like 'em.
Too many rules.
What about my skivvies?
Those, too.
Dr. Halstead.
Yeah.
I just spoke
to the medical director.
He's going to
let your patient
into the trial.
Oh, that is great.
You might've
just saved her life.
Thank you, Zoe.
Sure.
There you go.
Mrs. Baker,
I have some very good news.
A pharmaceutical company
is conducting
a clinical trial
that you qualify for,
a new cancer drug.
I was able to get you in.
Mrs. Baker?
Sal,
can you take Bailey outside?
Yeah. Yeah, sure.
Come on, honey girl.
Let's go find something
to eat.
But I'm drawing.
All right, you can do that
when you come back.
Okay.
Oh, thank you.
The trial's oncologist
is gonna need to examine you.
I'd like to set that up
as soon as possible.
I'm sorry.
No more trials.
Mrs. Baker...
You know how I feel.
But this is very promising.
A new
radio immunotherapy drug,
very similar to Tositumomab,
which you've done before.
But this works by...
Dr. Halstead,
you're not listening to me.
I'm done.
I have tried everything.
You have nothing to lose.
Yes, I do.
The drugs make me sick
and weak and exhausted.
I throw up,
I'm in constant pain.
And my family suffers
as much as I do.
But you may react
differently to this.
It could be a game changer.
That's what the last
half dozen doctors said
and yet, here we are.
Dr. Manning?
I think we should
let Mrs. Baker rest.
I know you're trying to help.
But I can't do this anymore.
I want to live out
the rest of my life
with the people I love
and not in a hospital.
We understand.
We'll check back later.
Dr. Halstead?
Yeah,
thanks for the help in there.
What is with you?
Last time I checked,
we're supposed to be
saving lives.
She has made her wishes
very clear.
She can't just give up.
My mother died of cancer.
If she had access
to a drug like this,
she might still be alive.
Did you page me?
Yeah. I'd like you to assist.
The ED hasn't sent up
any trauma patients
in the last hour.
Isn't a trauma,
65-year-old woman,
aortic valve replacement.
AV replacement?
You want me to assist?
Work on your suturing
technique.
You could move
a little faster.
Dr. Downey,
I'm a trauma surgeon,
not a cardiothoracic surgeon.
Sewing is sewing.
I cleared this with Sharon.
Wash your hands.
Meet me inside.
Put on something nice.
Mr. Baker.
Hi, Jen's felling
a little nauseous,
so...
Pop usually
makes her feel better.
That clinical trial
I mentioned.
It's really worth a shot.
Would you talk to her?
Listen,
I know what she's gonna say.
All right,
this is off the record,
but I spoke
to the pharmaceutical rep,
and she told me they've had
some remissions,
total remissions.
Please.
You know, I would do anything
to keep my wife alive,
but she's had
so many false hopes.
Okay.
You know what, I'll try.
I'll try.
Shower felt good.
Hadn't had one
since last summer.
This cream will kill
anything we missed,
including eggs.
Yeah.
I'm not itching now.
Arms up, please.
And that should do it.
An orderly will take you
to a treatment room.
And we'll go find you
some clothes.
I'm afraid
we had to burn your old ones.
Dr. Choi to the ICU.
Your patient?
Yeah. What's happening?
Some kind of psychotic
episode.
Get away from me!
I have to do this! Get away!
Professor Gray,
I'm Dr. Charles,
I'm here to help you.
I can't have these tubes.
They're trying to escape.
Wait.
Who's trying to escape?
The numbers.
They're trying to get out.
So, you're pulling out
your catheter
to keep the numbers inside?
Okay, okay, easy, easy.
I need the numbers. No!
Easy, easy.
No, no, no!
Give it to her!
No, you can't!
You can't... No!
I need the numbers!
You cannot do...
I'm gonna lose 'em.
Olivia Gray
has bipolar disorder,
diagnosed when she was 18.
So we're dealing with
more than a medical issue.
She's unstable.
All due respect,
it's entirely a medical issue.
And she's been
dealing with her condition,
with lithium, pretty well.
For almost 20 years.
So, when we put her
on dialysis,
it allowed her kidneys
to rest, but it also cleared
the lithium from her system.
Right. Which sent her
into that manic state
we witnessed.
Olivia can't go back
on the lithium.
What are her options?
Hard to say.
You know,
each one of these cases...
Treated differently.
I mean,
her records indicate
she's tried Wellbutrin,
Prozac, Effexor.
Apparently
side effects were too severe,
so she stuck with lithium.
Well,
the side effects of lithium
can kill her.
At the very least,
she'll need a new kidney.
You, uh, had much experience
with bipolar disorder, Ethan?
No.
Look at this,
woman gives us a zero,
because her gown didn't fit.
And this guy bitches,
because he couldn't change
the channel on the TV.
We ought to get a chance
to grade them.
Threw up in
the waiting room, zero.
Peed on the floor, zero.
Ms. Goodwin.
Yeah.
Hey, uh, I just got out
of the OR,
assisting Dr. Downey,
and he said that you approved.
I did.
Why?
You'll have to ask him.
But you're fine with it?
It's Dr. Downey,
and I'm fine
with whatever he wants.
You have a problem?
Yeah.
Yeah, I do, actually.
Excuse me.
Mr. Brennan?
I got some things
I hope will fit you.
You look like a medium.
I think so.
All right.
Why don't you get dressed,
and then we'll sign you out.
So clean.
Is it okay if I lie
just a few more minutes?
I guess.
Oh, um...
Would you mind filling out
a patient satisfaction card?
Sure.
Okay.
I'll be back
in a little while.
Yeah?
Dr. Downey?
Uh...
Maybe this isn't
such a good time.
No, it's fine.
Okay.
So, look,
I just spoke with Ms. Goodwin.
Mmm-hmm.
I am a trauma fellow.
Right.
So if I'm scrubbing in
with you,
I'm neglecting
my other responsibilities.
Yeah.
Let me tell you
why I love what I do.
The heart,
it's not just a pump...
Magic.
This couple,
they were in their car,
and they're having
a terrible fight.
And in the midst of it,
they get in an accident,
the husband's killed,
and they transplant his heart
into another man.
When the recipient
of this heart wakes up...
He's...
He's very troubled.
As soon as
he gets out of the hospital,
he looks up the donor's wife.
And he finds himself
apologizing
that his last words
were so angry to her.
He wants her to know
that he loves her.
That wasn't this man talking.
That was the heart.
I like that story.
I think I remember it from
when I was in eighth grade?
Doesn't make it not true.
Dr. Downey, the thing is,
I am really more comfortable
in trauma.
Comfort is important.
Okay.
Okay?
I'll leave you where you are.
Thank you.
Code Blue.
Treatment Five.
Code Blue. Treatment Five.
Mommy! Mommy!
It's okay.
It's okay,
she's in a better place.
Did you ask her?
She wouldn't.
She's wrong. Mr. Baker,
let me resuscitate.
Will, she's got a DNR.
She doesn't have to die.
I don't know.
You want her to live.
You told me.
I don't know.
Will, don't.
Tell me to resuscitate.
Daddy!
I don't know.
Please. Let me try.
Please help her.
Will, don't do this.
Get the cart in here.
Will, stop!
I have to. April, the cart.
No.
Mommy! Mommy!
Now!
What are you doing?
Daddy.
Please help her.
No.
One milligram of epi.
Mr. Baker,
take your daughter out.
Okay, come on, honey.
No. Will, you can't do this.
Will, stop.
I'm tubing her.
Natalie, please take over
compressions.
No, I won't. Don't do this.
Doris, you take over
compressions.
No. Will, this is illegal.
I'll take responsibility.
Do it!
No.
7.5 ET tube.
Four MAC laryngoscope.
Yes, Dr. Halstead.
She's still in vfib.
I'm charging 200.
Will.
Will, let her go.
Clear.
Clear!
Will, stop!
Stop!
I said clear.
Continue CPR.
Charging to 200.
Charged.
Clear!
Got a pulse.
Good.
Get an EKG and redraw labs.
CMP and trops.
Yes, Doctor.
What have you done?
Her heart rate
is erratic.
She's going to thank me.
It's why I love fractals.
The perfect union
of math and art.
Well, the Art Institute
would certainly agree.
Did you see
the Mandelbrot exhibit?
Hello. He's only the reason
I studied Brownian motion.
Who wants to
see another iteration
of finite subdivisions?
Not me, baby.
Professor Gray, I'm Dr. Choi.
I've been treating you.
Oh, hi. Sorry, I understand
I've been a lot to handle.
I'm glad
you're feeling better.
I am.
Dr. Charles,
can I have a word?
Be right back.
Okay.
Amazing turnaround.
What did you replace
the lithium with?
Lithium.
Excuse me?
Well, Olivia and I talked
and decided that, for now,
it's the best course
of treatment.
But she can't tolerate it.
It's destroying her kidneys.
Yeah, but that's a tradeoff
that she's willing to make.
She can't be
who she wants to be
or live the life
she wants to live
without lithium.
Here's a novel idea,
how about she learns to cope
with her condition?
Cope?
Learns to control it.
Buck up. People can do that.
Dr. Choi, you saw
what a full-blown
manic episode looks like
for her.
And how much of that
is self-indulgence?
I'm just saying,
I don't think her dependence
on this destructive drug
is the answer.
Huh.
How we doin'?
Excuse me, Bailey.
I'm gonna check Mommy's heart.
Still stable.
She's off
all blood pressure drips.
We can start the process of
getting her in the trial.
We just wanna be
left alone right now.
Sure.
Dr. Halstead.
Ms. Goodwin would like to
see you in her office.
Did he tell you
to resuscitate his wife?
Her husband wants her
in the trial.
He agrees with me.
Yes or no.
Did he tell you
to resuscitate his wife?
No.
But he wanted me to.
And how exactly
did you divine that?
I couldn't just let her die
for no reason.
Well, there is a reason.
She has
a legally binding document
ordering you not to do so.
And don't I, as her doctor,
have a moral responsibility
that supersedes that document?
No, you do not.
And you know that.
Ms. Goodwin,
she was out of her mind
from the pain and the illness.
She did not understand
what this drug could do
for her.
I did.
This is not about you.
It's about her,
and what she wanted.
She...
You have put this hospital
and yourself
in an extremely dangerous
position.
I hope you understand
the gravity of your actions.
Get her out of the ED
and up to the MICU.
Dr. Manning
will be primary now.
I want you to stay away
from Jennifer Baker,
and her family.
Are we clear on that?
Yes.
Reese.
Hmm?
This isn't a hotel.
You need to get Mr. Brennan
out of Treatment Four.
Mr. Brennan,
I'm afraid you have to go.
Mr. Brennan.
Mr. Brennan,
can you hear me?
Maggie.
He dressed?
He's dead.
So, Dr. Downey
is a very strange guy.
Now what?
He got Goodwin to assign
me to him on some kind of
ongoing basis.
What?
Yeah. It's crazy, right?
Wait. Dr. Downey
asked you to assist him.
You?
Yeah.
The premier cardiac surgeon
in the country asks you
to assist him, and you pass?
I'm a trauma surgeon.
Unbelievable.
What?
No, come on,
what is so strange
about me wanting to do
what I was trained to do?
In fact,
what I was brought here for?
That's your excuse?
It's not an excuse.
Mmm-hmm.
Oh, come on, what?
I can't stand cowards.
That's how you see me?
Well, what are you afraid of?
That you're not good enough?
That you'll fail?
Is this your dad thing, again?
It's disgusting.
Is she still stable?
Nat?
She's not your patient.
Look, you know
I only did it because I care.
I told you
not to resuscitate her.
Why do you dismiss me?
What?
You say you respect me.
You say I'm your friend...
I don't dismiss you.
Yes, you do.
And not just today.
All the time.
Look, things can't always
just be on your terms, Will.
I'm tired of this.
Trauma incoming.
All attending to the ED.
58-year-old male,
restrained driver car crash,
front end collision.
GCS 12.
Vitals stable
since we got to him.
Go to Trauma Four.
Anybody else hurt?
No, he crashed into a pylon.
Looks like he blacked out
and lost control of the car.
It's Dr. Downey.
Let Ms. Goodwin know.
Dr. Downey,
can you hear me?
Dr. Downey?
All right.
Let's get him in here.
Let's get him unstrapped
and get him on the bed.
All right.
On my count, one, two, three.
All right, airway's intact,
get IVs in
and get X-ray in here.
On it.
IV's going in.
All right,
breath sounds bilaterally.
His belly's soft. Vitals?
BP 124 over 78.
Heart rate 92, sat's 100%.
Call Oncology.
Yes, ma'am.
Oncology?
This is trauma.
Maybe.
But Dr. Downey
has liver cancer.
How's he doing?
He's pretty banged up,
but remarkably,
no real injuries.
We're gonna keep him sedated
for the moment,
so that he rests.
How long have you known?
Well, he was diagnosed
six months ago.
He told me then.
He asked me
to keep it confidential.
He's not gonna be
happy about this.
What's his prognosis?
Not good.
I thought he was a pothead.
Right.
It's not a coincidence,
is it?
No.
When he realized
the seriousness
of his condition,
he decided to find someone
he could teach,
someone who had the ability
to do what he does.
So, what do I have
that all the other surgeons
in this place don't?
He saw something.
You have to ask him
when he wakes up.
Excuse me.
I just got word,
the Bakers
are suing the hospital
and pressing charges
against you.
It's called
"Wrongful Life and Battery."
Hospital counsel
will get in touch
tomorrow morning.
Am I suspended?
No.
Not that I'm not tempted.
But the hospital
can't allow even a hint
of possible wrongdoing.
So, you will continue working,
and we will support you.
But depending on
how this goes,
the board may well
decide to terminate you.
I don't understand
what happened.
He came here to die.
Really?
People do that sometimes.
They sense
they're at the end,
and they...
Just wanna die
in a clean bed.
Reese.
Mr. Brennan filled out
a patient satisfaction form.
You got a perfect score.
All 10s.
Dr. Halstead.
Hey.
I heard.
It's out there already?
I think it's awful.
You did the right thing.
At least somebody thinks so.
Well, once she starts
the drug and feels better,
she'll drop the suit.
You'll see.
Yeah. Let's hope.
Dr. Halstead?
Can I buy you a drink?
Sure.
I'd like that.
Okay.
Dr. Charles?
You got a minute?
Hey, man, what's up?
Seat?
Afghanistan.
A field hospital
in Helmand Province.
We'd been up 48 hours straight
treating casualty.
Uh-huh.
This woman came in.
She'd walked from her village
10 miles away.
Had her daughter in her arms.
A three-year-old.
Little girl
didn't have a scratch on her.
Looked like she was sleeping,
this sleeping angel.
But she was dead.
A blast wave
from a mortar round
burst her lungs.
I can't stop seeing her.
I try to cope.
But I can't sleep.
I have nightmares.
I can't stop seeing her.
Glad you stopped by.
Dr. Rhodes.
Dr. Downey.
How are you feeling?
I guess
the cat's out of the bag.
I'm sorry.
Can I get you anything?
Can I take your presence
as a good sign?
Yes, sir.
You know, the Hawaiians...
Have a deep reverence
for the sea.
They believe
it's the best medicine
there is.
They think a swim in the ocean
can cure anything.
Wouldn't a swim be nice
right now?