Previously on ER:
Couple of months from now
I'll be a first-year med student.
It's all thanks to you, Greg.
Trying to show off to Daria by making
me look small? That is never gonna fly.
Teaching interns is my job.
What do you want me to do?
You gave me great tips on our last
shift. I'm glad we're working together.
What are you doing here?
There's nothing going on between
us. We work together, that's it.
I thought we could have a drink.
- I wanna stay with him.
- I wanna push his gurney.
- We embrace the memory...
of our colleague
and our dear friend.
- They're coming tonight?
- We talked about this two weeks ago.
- It's not a good weekend.
- So when's good? Pick a date.
I'm working Saturday.
I won't be around.
They're excited, they've been
planning. They drive five hours...
to see you, see us.
- You want me to tell them not to bother?
- You better.
Doing that since you got
back. They're starting to wonder.
- Wonder what?
- What's wrong.
I got a full day, all right?
The house is a mess.
- They need clean linen.
- Look, look.
I've already set up the guest room.
We'll stay in tonight, have dinner...
- I don't have time to cook.
- Then we'll go out.
After that drive? They're
not gonna want to go out.
It's just three days.
They're your family.
And they miss you.
It's not my fault the
pipes froze up and burst.
What?
Okay, well, then you can
always pay for the hotel.
No.
No, no, no.
Yeah, well, I don't care
what the law says. I...
Okay, you know what,
forget it. Thank you, you jerk.
We have two days
to find a place...
while they fix this
stupid pipe that I don't...
You know, there is
an obvious solution.
Hey. Hey. Excuse me, sir?
You can't be right there.
I gotta go pick up a physiology
syllabus. I'll see you inside, okay?
Hold it. Hey, come on, buddy.
We gotta let sick people in. Let's go.
- Let's go.
- Come on, Jake. Let's go.
You order me around.
Don't order me around.
And today's the fourth time in three
weeks that you crashed your bike?
- Where does it hurt at, exactly?
- Right side, shoots down my leg.
- Any weakness in the foot?
- Are you for real? I could hardly walk.
- Chaz, my man, how we doing?
- Good.
I put a splint on your ankle guy
and restocked the paramedic cart.
- Already? Wow.
- I need something for the pain, damn it.
- You've already had 10 of morphine.
- It ain't touched me.
You should start taking the bus.
Not that we don't enjoy
seeing you every week...
Dr. Morris, I'm concerned
about a L4 motor deficit.
Huh? She's never
had that before.
Could be nerve-root
impingement or cord compression.
No. We should check for
cauda equina syndrome.
We're checking labs
and doing blood draws?
He's a first-year med student.
He should be observing.
Teacher's pet needs
to learn a physical.
- He's an EMT. He still works shifts.
- I can't stand do-it-all guys.
Especially ones named Chaz.
What kind of name is that?
- Chaz Pratt. Nice coat.
- Ha, ha. What's up, Tony?
Hey, Frank, page Neurosurge. I
need a stat lumbar MRI on Patty.
You mean Patty,
the pain in the ass?
We all assumed that she's full of
it but Chaz picked up a foot drop.
She may need
emergent-decompression surgery.
Nice job, buddy. Healing
and dealing, I dig it.
- Hey, you guys take her up to Radiology.
- Maybe the med student could do that.
Good idea. You know
what? We'll all go.
- I'll meet you guys up there.
- Cool.
Dude. Chaz, he's a
natural. Must be in the genes.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah, he's awesome.
- Smarter than I was.
- That ain't saying much.
Stable pneumonia, had ceftriaxone
and Zithro, medicines admitting.
Why has cellulitis guy
been here all night?
Oh, get in line. I just got
here. I haven't had my coffee.
With intractable nausea.
Ultrasound's negative,
so I'm thinking gastro.
Digitoxicity could
explain the symptoms.
- She's right. Good thinking.
- All right. Well, I'll add a level.
Why are you all dressed
up? You have a hot date?
- You're blushing.
- Dr. Banfield just suggested...
that I present myself more,
you know, professionally, so...
These are not gonna
cure themselves.
What do I gotta do to
get some damn morphine?
- Ms. McPhee. PATTY:
What's wrong with you people?
- Thank God.
- So, Chaz, you'll see a herniated disc...
at L4-L5, L5-S1, according
to our exam on Miss McPhee.
- Doctor, can we go in the booth?
- You cannot go in the booth.
Now get her in here.
I haven't got all day.
- Let me give you guys a hand.
- Go in the booth.
- You didn't switch gurneys?
- I thought he did it.
I thought you did it.
I didn't know it had to be done.
Can I get my morphine now?
How much? Does that come
with breakfast or anything?
Okay, thank you.
- Do you know any good, cheap hotels?
- Good and cheap, no. One or the other.
Hey, Sam. You think about my solution?
- Solution?
- Yeah, to your problem.
- Oh, if you got one, spit it out.
All right. I was thinking
that maybe you...
Sorry. Excuse me, Sam.
Um, Mr. Rappaport needs a TropT.
Should have been sent an hour ago.
Sorry. I don't know why the
night shift didn't tell me. I'll get it.
And if he has two
negative troponins?
Low-risk. If Cards can do
a treadmill, he'll go home.
All right, good plan.
Hey, Crash, how's it going?
Radiology called, said you owe
them 300 large for a new scanner.
- You heard about that?
- You almost killed a woman.
No, her plain films
were negative. She's fine.
Chaz, I don't know if anyone's told you,
but the M in MRI stands for "magnetic."
Thanks for the tip.
Dr. Morris, Ms. McPhee's still pretty
upset about the whole gurney thing...
but her foot drop resolved.
She's got full range of motion.
Ha! The accident must have been
some weird chiropractic manipulation.
Nice job. You cured a patient.
I should check the
carts in the exam rooms.
Through there are the trauma
rooms where the serious cases go.
Hey, Brenner, I got your
unstable angina admitted to Cards.
Thanks. Morris, Frank, these
are my mates, Collin, Roger.
These your derelict
countrymen I've heard about?
Good day.
Good day to you too.
Dr. Morris, we
got a rig coming in.
Oh, hello there.
- Dawn Archer.
- Hi, there.
- Charmed. BRENNER:
That's about it, guys.
- There you have it. County General.
- Beauty. Impressive.
Good on you. I can't believe you
guys trust the bastard with human lives.
- Us either. BRENNER:
Much appreciated, Frank.
- Where you headed?
- Big game.
- Sevens against the dreaded Kiwis.
- Rugby.
It's seven on seven against
some boys from New Zealand.
I've always wanted to learn rugby.
Maybe I could come with you sometime.
- Yeah, maybe.
- I was a kicker for high school football.
Yeah. If you ever need an extra.
No, we're good. We're all signed
out. But I'll see you guys later.
Gonna play in your stubbies?
COLLIN: Yeah. I'm true blue.
Somebody print out a
recipe for chicken piccata?
Do you read everything
that comes off the printer?
Yes. And if you need recipes, I got
some that can knock your socks off.
Keep your recipes to yourself.
Looks like maybe it's
just gastroenteritis?
Do think they'd call us down
for a non-surgical problem?
Is this about my 2-year-old with vomiting?
- Mm-hm.
- What's your differential?
- Right. So something structural like...
I'm thinking malrotation
with a possible volvulus.
How do you think we should proceed?
- Upper GI.
- You mind if I do the cut down?
- Nope. Not today, too busy.
Go back to the floor. I'll just put
in the line and meet you at rounds.
Derrek Taylor, facial and chest
trauma from a knockout in the fifth round.
How you doing, Derrek?
- Been better.
They didn't say nothing
about a southpaw.
- Dawn, what's open?
- Trauma 2's ready.
Dr. Morris, I'd like to discuss the case
of the levitating gurney at some point.
- Soon as I can.
- A broken nose.
Third time. But I feel pretty
good now, I don't need all this.
Chaz, facial trauma with LOC. We
can review the cranial nerve exam.
- Look what we got here.
- Bards, what's up, baby?
Not much, man.
Looks good on you.
You know how to assess
for mandible fractures?
- No.
- Good, I'll show you.
- Sending him to CT?
- Definitely.
- Dr. Banfield said we should jump in.
- Sure. Kaya, on your count.
Okay, 1, 2, 3.
Pleasure doing business with
you. Chaz, don't screw it up.
Trauma panel, portable
chest, head and facial CT.
Kaya, eyes, nose. Ryan, extremities.
Chaz, we'll do primary assessment.
Pulse ox 99 on 2 liters.
Sixth round I was
gonna make my move.
- You were a round late. CHAZ:
Breath sounds good, bilaterally.
- A little tachycardic?
- I agree.
Thought I had him.
Explain this sport to me.
Look at this poor man.
- Lid edema, no hyphema.
- Peripheral pulses intact.
They call it the sweet
science for a reason. It's hard.
I'm not saying it
ain't hard, just stupid.
- So what are you, a middleweight?
- Welterweight.
- You a fighter?
- No, my dad just showed me a little bit.
Mine too.
Old man won the Golden
Gloves back in the day.
CT is starting a guided biopsy.
If they can't take him
next, I'll talk to Bettina.
- We had dinner the other night.
- Yeah? How's she doing?
Real good. She's putting in work on
that program we started in Greg's name.
- You're pretty young for a doctor.
- I'm a med student.
Brainiac, huh?
Not really. I just decided
this is what I wanna do.
Looks like it's
working out for you.
Trying. It's not easy though.
- I feel you.
Septal hematoma.
I need an 11 blade.
That's okay. I'll do the
procedure with Chaz.
- Hey.
- Labs come back on taxi lady?
- What?
- Labs?
- Yeah.
Isolated thrombocytopenia.
Yeah, like you thought.
- Hematology see her?
- Yeah. They wanna start IVIG.
- Blood bank's gonna send it down.
- Perfect.
Coffee?
No. No, I get this percent-latte
thing. Thanks though.
Hey, you want a hot coffee?
It's cold out here.
I have an extra.
Here.
You wanna come inside?
Have us check you out?
- Have a shower, hot meal?
- I hate hospitals.
All right. Offer stands.
L-shaped incision from high to
low, then along the floor of the nose.
- Okay.
- Okay, if we don't drain it...
we get something called
pressure necrosis of the septum.
Go for it.
- Everything okay in here?
- Draining a septal hematoma.
Pressure down to 80 systolic.
- Liter of saline.
- Pulse ox down to 85.
Slip the packing
underneath the flap.
How are you doing, sir? Sir?
One hundred percent non-rebreather.
Intubation tray and repeat the HemoCue.
Prep the cordis for the IJ.
Tell me why we're ignoring the
ABCs of a critical trauma patient.
An emergent procedure
and the patient was stable.
- You call Surgery?
- On their way.
And who's your assistant
with the short coat?
- Med student.
- Fourth year?
- First.
- With a scalpel up a patient's nose.
Anything wrong with
that picture, Dr. Morris?
Kaya, left upper quadrant?
No perisplenic blood.
- And the subxiphoid view?
- Negative for pericardial effusion.
- I'm not getting a flash.
- I'll try.
No. Andrew.
Forty-five degree angle.
Aim for the ipsilateral nipple.
- Level 1 is ready with 2 liters.
- Soon as they get the line.
A little higher... no.
- I can't get it.
- Okay, move.
No blood in the belly. - Flash.
Chest is still clear,
pupils are still equal.
Repeat HemoCue is 14.2.
We didn't miss any internal
bleeding. He's just dehydrated.
You got lucky. All right, you,
you, you and you, with me.
Was I not clear? Now, please.
Excuse me. Dr. Wade's
a surgical intern.
In my department. I wanna
see the two of you at the desk...
soon as you're finished here.
Now is when you
acquire skills for the future.
Do not let upper-level residents
and attendings decide your fate.
You get in there. This is your shot.
Speak up for your right to be educated.
And if your supervisors aren't
respecting that right, then you talk to me.
Except for you.
You, stay quiet,
stand back and watch.
You are barely
qualified to speak.
Okay, good. Let's
get back to work.
Look, I know what
you're gonna say.
We are teachers at
a teaching hospital.
Which means we have
young kids running around...
trying to learn how
not to kill patients.
- I understand...
- Then why teach...
a first-year student a procedure
your interns should be doing?
- Chaz was an EMT.
- That's irrelevant.
He is only here to observe.
Teach your interns,
Dr. Morris. Both of you.
They learn by doing. Let them do
things. Teach, educate, delegate.
That's your job. Now
go clear the board.
Um. Excuse me, Dr. Banfield, but
we have a different culture in Surgery.
- And?
- And I supervise my intern...
as I feel appropriate and I don't
appreciate you undermining me.
Dr. Rasgotra, I prefer to
handle this at the attending level.
You have a problem, have
Dr. Dubenko give me a call.
All right. Keep him warm. Keep
the head of the bed up 30 degrees.
Hey, Sam. I wanna
ask you something.
Actually, I wasn't
so clear earlier.
About what?
- What?
- Move in with me.
You and Alex need a place
to stay, you stay with me.
No. We're not a charity case.
Who said anything about
charity? Split the rent.
- You mean, like, temporarily?
- Yeah, if that's what you want.
Your place is too small.
We have a bedroom
downstairs we don't use.
What do I tell Alex?
Alex and Sarah get along.
Me and Alex are cool.
You're insane. It's way too
soon. It would never work.
Why are you laughing at
me? You wanted to get serious.
No, I do. I'm not
laughing at you.
It sure seems like you're
laughing. You're something else.
Why do you have to do
everything the hard way?
Forget it. Forget I even
asked. Just forget it.
- Tony. CITY WORKER:
Need a little help here.
Hey, some help over here.
Excuse me.
There's something
wrong with him.
Hey. Sir? Sir?
How long you gonna keep this up?
Eight hundred bucks, Pop.
Double if I win. We need that.
Not this bad.
- Dawn, he needs three grams of Unasyn.
- I'm on it.
- Are you Derrek's dad?
- Yeah, Louie Taylor.
Dr. Morris. The CT was negative.
No bleeding in the brain. Good news.
That means you're gonna be okay.
Derrek, you have a
depressed zygoma fracture.
Basically, your
cheekbone is broken.
- But that's serious?
- It's completely fixable.
- But requires surgery.
- How long to come back from that?
Good six weeks of recovery.
You should be able to
train with headgear after that.
- Got another bout in two months.
- Derrek.
Don't start, Pop. I ain't
loading boxes for $9 an hour.
No, you'd rather continue
getting your ass beat?
Let's take one thing at a time.
We'll get you through
the operation first, okay?
Surgery should be
down soon, take you up.
Hey, Dr. Morris?
- He really gonna be able to fight again?
- Yeah, there's a good chance.
The procedure's very
routine and he's young.
- You okay?
- Spinal stenosis.
Up until a couple months ago
I was able to work full time...
you know, hit the gym
a few days a week.
We've got some great surgeons.
Yeah, I'm on the list.
Eighteen-month wait.
Derrek's got it in his head that
he's gonna make enough fighting...
get me the surgery. That
and a new car, a new house.
- Seems like a great kid.
- Yeah.
He showed a lot of promise
when he was young, you know?
Then his mother died.
He's got a lot of heart, doc,
but his record's 5 and 28.
Nothing's easy at first.
- But he keeps at it, who knows?
- Yeah, but, doc...
You know what they say about
a fighter like that? He's a stiff.
A bum. A silent offering.
My son gets paid to
lose. They laugh at him.
They throw him in the
ring at somebody for real...
who can use him to tune
up. Know what I'm saying?
And for what?
Oh, man, I was good.
And still, I was barely
good enough to turn pro.
And Derrek ain't half
the fighter I used to be.
The difference between us is
that I knew when to hang it up.
Now, he won't listen to me,
but maybe he'll listen to you.
Maybe you could talk to him.
Help me out. Give him a
real reason to stop, huh?
Due respect, Mr. Taylor,
but I can't do that.
He's a grown man.
He's got something he
wants, there's nothing I can say.
- He's killing himself.
- But he's going for what he wants.
Maybe you should think
about giving him a little support.
Excuse me. Excuse
me, please. Watch out.
- Maybe he hit his head.
- No sign of trauma.
We gonna finish our talk later?
Daria, give us a hand, please.
Um. No, actually,
Dr. Banfield really wanted...
Now please.
- What do you think he's altered from?
- Probably ingestion.
Of what? Coma's pretty deep.
- Benzos, barbs, opiates.
- No pinpoint pupils.
- Respirations aren't suppressed.
- Want me to start a line?
No, Sam can do that.
It'd be really good for
me to have the practice.
- Thank you, Daria.
- Sam, vitals.
- I'm putting him on the machine now.
- What kind of labs you want?
I want chemistry, I want
CBC, ETOH levels...
acetaminophen
and aspirin, please.
Tony. Looks like yours.
Oh, yeah.
We need to scan.
Can I have my light?
- Secure his airway.
- I don't wanna wait. Light?
- My light?
- Yes.
Um, you two have
this under control.
No. Will you stay here
and check his Babinski?
- Give him dextrose.
- No, a finger stick.
- It'll take too long.
- Whoa, whoa.
- Want me to get some Ativan?
- Yeah, two mgs.
- Okay.
- I'll mix some Dilantin.
- Oh! Sorry.
- Get the Ativan.
Dilantin load's running.
- So his tattoo means he's Army, right?
- Yeah, paratrooper.
- Same as you?
- Yep.
Let's get some antibiotics
onboard. Two grams of ceftriaxone...
and one gram of Vanco.
I think maybe we should
get him on some steroids too.
Listen, I'm sorry if I
hurt your feelings earlier.
Dr. Gates, he's waking up.
- So steroids?
- Yeah. Decadron, 10 milligrams.
Okay. Don't let me
tell you what to do.
Don't worry, you're not.
All right.
- Feeling okay?
- Huh?
How are you feeling?
Like I got my bell rung.
Yeah, you had a seizure. You
ever have one of those before?
I don't know.
Can you tell me your name?
Max.
- Your last name?
- How'd I get in here?
The last thing I remember,
I was drinking coffee.
We found you passed
out on the street.
Where's Jake?
- My dog.
- I'm sorry, I don't know. Didn't see him.
I gotta go. Where's my stuff?
- I got stuff in my duffel.
- We got it. Don't worry.
- Hey.
- I gotta go.
- No, no, no.
- Jake needs me.
All right. Oh, God. Okay.
Come on. Sit down, please.
- Jake.
- You need to stay in bed, sir.
We're gonna find
him, okay? Don't worry.
And Neuro wants us to send CSF
for prions and HSV for our ataxic guy.
What? He's stoned. What's
wrong with neurologists?
I don't know.
I've got an ingrown toenail in
3 with my name on it, so I'm...
- Hey, hey, hey. You okay?
- Yeah. I mean, why wouldn't I be okay?
- Do I not seem okay?
- No, you seem hasty.
No. No, no, no. I'm
just busy, that's all.
- Okay.
- Okay. Bye.
Hey, Frank, do you have
the LFTs on my jaundice guy?
Yeah, I'll find them.
Excuse me, Dr. Banfield? I
can't just stand by and watch.
- Here. Veal Frank-a-lini.
- I thought I told you...
You can't tell by looking at me. I
happen to be a culinary genius.
I used to cook for the guys
at the precinct all the time.
And Chicago cops know good food.
Now, this is my variation
on a timeless classic.
Veal scaloppine with a
chanterelle cream sauce.
A little touch of heaven.
Now, the key is the chanterelles.
A good chanterelle is firm.
- You don't want a soft chanterelle.
- Please stop saying "chanterelle."
Sorry.
Thank you, Frank.
You're welcome.
Hey, you. Ahem.
Russ, what're you doing here?
Didn't like the way we
left things. Got a minute?
No, I don't. I'm busy.
You should've called.
I've been trying your cell
all day. Left messages.
You just can't just
show up at work like this.
- I need to talk.
- Well, not here.
Cate.
Uh... Sorry, I can
come back later.
What is it, doctor?
My husband, Russell Banfield.
Hello, I'm Neela
Rasgotra. Nice to meet you.
- You too.
- Could you wait for me outside, please?
You know, it really can
wait, I didn't mean to interrupt.
I'm here now. Go.
Okay, so I spoke
to Dr. Dubenko...
and he feels that I should
handle our issue on my own.
- Since I'm the one...
- You know what, Dr. Rasgotra?
We'll do it your way. Make
things nice and easy for you.
And you let me know if
there's anything else I can do.
- What happened here?
- Rugby match.
- You win?
- 23-6.
I think that qualifies
as a massacre.
Can we get on?
All I need is a drink.
Yeah, I'll go and get you wrapped.
We'll get some ibuprofen and some ice.
Hey, you should celebrate with
us. Bring your pretty nurse friends.
I don't think my surgeon
friends would be interested.
We're gonna head to
Ike's. Stop by if you're free.
Maybe you could have a spot of tea.
You know, leave the real drinking to us.
Unasyn finally came
up from the pharmacy.
- Yo, med student.
- What's up, man?
- You graduate yet?
- Not yet.
How much longer you
gonna keep us here?
- He needed surgery.
- He's next. I'm sorry, they're swamped.
Isn't he an emergency?
Look at him.
- Give the guy a break, Pop.
- It's okay.
Gives me time to do a
full neuro assessment.
Chaz, will you cover that eye, please?
- Sure.
Okay, I want you to look into
my eye and not move yours.
Tell me when you
see my finger moving.
- Now.
- All right.
Tell me again when
you see it moving.
How about now?
Now.
- There's a visual-field deficit.
- Translate.
Well, your retina's fine, which means
there could be a problem in your brain.
- What?
- You said my brain was okay.
Well, it might be something
called a diffuse-axonal injury.
Doesn't show up on a CT.
Happens with repetitive head trauma.
You mean like getting
punched over and over?
Which is why you keep getting
hit by all those shots, man.
I could step in there
and take you out.
Imagine what somebody
half my age would do.
- He's got brain damage, right?
- We need to get an MRI to be sure.
- You can't keep doing this to yourself.
- I'm doing this for us.
This doesn't do
us any good, son.
- Pulse ox is down.
- What's going on?
- My chest.
Where? Where? LOUIE: Derrek?
To The left. To the left.
Decreased breath.
Get him to Trauma.
I'll get the non-rebreather.
Derrek?
Best I could do.
Got you an extra Jell-O.
Is there anyone we can contact
for you? Family or friends?
Just Jake.
- I'm fine on my own.
- Yeah, well, you don't seem fine.
No one likes to be
alone all the time.
- What do you know?
- I've been on my own most of my life.
But it's up to me to
fix that, you know?
Could I get some
mustard or something?
The incision goes along the
fifth rib, midaxillary line, all right?
Tunnel superiorly to
the next interspace.
Curved vascular clamp around the
tube. Know what? You push it through.
It's okay. Dr. Banfield said
I shouldn't touch anything.
I did the whole procedure. We'll
push it together, so you can get the feel.
Wait. Time out. He's
a student here, right?
This is a teaching
hospital, sir.
Right here, just
above the rib margin.
Right there.
- Heard you guys needed help.
- I'm sorry if this hurts a little, man.
- A little force to get through the muscle.
- Shouldn't Chaz be observing?
He's assisting.
- Feel it? Okay.
- Mm-hm.
Push it in.
Harder. A little harder.
Harder.
- Yeah.
- Pulse ox coming up, strong pulse.
Way to go, Chaz.
Now we just sew it in.
You mean, you sew it in.
Yes. 0 silk.
- Thora-Seal provides...
- Dropped in pressure again.
Five hundred cc's.
What are you guys doing?
Hang two units of blood.
I thought you said he
had a collapsed lung.
- Morris?
- We bagged an intercostal artery.
Chaz, when you
pushed the tube in...
- did it slip?
- No. I don't know. Maybe.
- He's not breathing.
- What?
Prepare intubation
tray. Page Surgery.
Derrek.
Honey, I've been out
here for half an hour.
I'm busy. You should have called. I
don't like people knowing my business.
How can you work in that?
You didn't pull me
out to talk about this.
Russ, please, my board is full.
I made dinner reservations.
Mia Francesca, your favorite.
- We are not going to dinner.
- They'll be at our place in an hour.
That's not what I meant, damn
it. I'm going to cook. I will cook.
I thought you didn't have time.
- I know what I said.
- I'm trying to make this easier for you.
By making your mother think that I
can't make dinner or keep a home?
- That won't make it easier. Believe me.
- Baby, I'm sorry. I'm just trying to help.
All right. I'll be
there at 7:30.
Come on. I can't get
control of the bleeder.
- BP's in the toilet.
- Up inside the costal groove.
- Fourth unit's going in. MORRIS:
Come on, come on, come on.
- I got it.
- All right, 120 over 80. Not bad.
- Chest tube output's down.
- Surgery's here.
- Where's Neela?
- Gone for the day.
Finger on the vessel.
- You got it.
- He gonna be okay?
- Gotta get him up to Surgery.
- What's going on?
- We tore an intercostal but he's stable.
And how'd you tear an
intercostal doing a chest tube?
Must have slipped.
It happens.
- OR's ready.
- Should be an interesting M and M.
- Stay ahead four units.
- Hey, Morris, you got a second?
Got 18 gauge in each
arm. Get something central.
Come here.
What the hell are you doing?
Chaz isn't trained to do chest tubes.
- He has EMT.
- They don't do chest tubes in the field.
- I was trying to teach him.
- By letting him kill a patient?
Put in a situation he wasn't ready for.
Not a head start, that's setting him back.
Hey, look who it is.
Got a cup of Earl
Grey waiting for you.
- You take milk with that?
- You made it.
Well, looks that way.
Maybe some chamomile
since it's almost bedtime.
Let's get you a drink.
Hey, I am so sorry that I
barged in the other night.
- I didn't realize that you and Ray were...
- Not at all. It's fine.
He and I were friends. He was
in town, catching up. It's all good.
Okay. Oh, Jimmy,
another round for my mates.
And whatever she's drinking.
Hey, Max, how you doing?
- Your CAT scan looks good.
- Okay.
So you don't remember anything
like this happening to you before?
- I forget lots of stuff.
- No head injury? Anything?
Maybe epilepsy?
Look, could I get a sandwich?
That nurse lady brought
me one but I'm still hungry.
Sure, no problem.
Can you remember
your last name for me?
I tried to see it on your
duffel but I couldn't read it.
All right.
You let me know
if you can, all right?
What about this
ink on your chest?
Paratrooper?
Oh, yeah.
Thing hurt.
I got one too.
101st Airborne.
- Screaming Eagles.
- Right.
Where'd you get yours?
This dude.
Max, do you remember
where you served?
Tal Afar.
- Hot as hell.
- Yeah. Up north by Mosul, right?
Tony?
- Homeless guy you were just in with?
- Yeah?
Neuro wants to discharge him.
Outpatient EEG and clinic referral.
He won't get his Dilantin filled.
- He'll never make it back here.
- Sam, I took care of it.
- You did?
- Pulled some strings...
and got him admitted
into the Neuro service.
Oh. Okay. Well, there you go.
There you go.
Listen. Look, I feel like...
- Hey, Mom.
You're early.
- What's up, Tony?
- Alex, how you doing?
- I'm good.
- Hey, can we go eat?
Yeah, let me get my stuff.
- See you tomorrow.
- Later, Tony.
Good night.
Daria, before you leave, can you get
a read on my pericarditis guy's echo?
Yeah, no problem. Dr. Gates?
I was just wondering.
I wanted to make sure
that everything was okay.
You know, with you and Sam.
- Yeah, everything's fine.
- Oh. Okay.
Yeah. Well, no, that's great.
It was just because, you know,
earlier, things got a little bit weird.
Not that weird, per
se. Just a little bit weird.
And so I just wanted
to make sure that...
Yeah. But everything's
okay. So that's great.
- Yeah. You good?
- Yeah.
- You sure?
- Totally.
Because you're blushing again.
Okay. I'll see you tomorrow.
Oh! Oh, hi. So you're
ready for sign outs?
After you tell me how today went.
Did Dr. Gates instruct you well?
You know what? These
are the pass ons. Good night.
Somebody had a poopy day.
- You sure?
- I don't know.
Are you sure? I mean,
what else are we going to do?
- Lot of things. We could go to a hotel.
- Mom, you hate hotels.
Hey, sorry to interrupt, but since I
am, I wanna tell you, both of you...
that I want you to
come stay with me.
Because I really like you guys.
And I know it's fast
but if it doesn't work...
then you guys can move out.
I think we'd be great together.
I think we'd all be great. All of
us. And Sarah's totally onboard.
And I have a flat-screen TV and
I live in a great neighborhood...
Tony, we were actually
just talking about it. Ahem.
We're in.
- You are?
- Uh-huh. Right?
You had me at flat-screen.
All right. Up your bum.
- Yeah, no pressure now love.
- Shut up. Shut up.
- Just don't miss.
- Don't listen.
Yeah, hold it.
- Yes. Yes. You see that? You see that?
- Oh, yes.
- Come on.
- Thank you and thank you and thank you.
Green is my favorite color.
Don't worry, it is a British game.
- Yeah. God save the queen and all that.
- She's your queen too, you know?
- Excuse me? Who invited the Brit?
- You did.
- Sore loser.
- Shut up.
Oh, what? What did you
just say to me, convict?
Oh, again. That's all right.
It's my shout. Who's drinking?
Oh, I am, if you're buying?
All right. Jimmy?
So surgery went well.
I'm doing okay then, right?
Well, your lung will heal
and so will your face.
But the damage from repeated
head trauma, that won't heal.
- See? You gotta stop this mess.
- Pop, please.
Just let the man talk.
Actually, your dad's right. Yeah,
boxing's just not a good idea.
You saying I can't
fight or I shouldn't fight?
I know you think you
don't have a choice...
- You don't know what I think.
- You want to do whatever it takes...
help your dad, to
make him proud.
But if you keep fighting, you
are risking serious brain damage.
I know I've been tough on you.
I'm sorry.
I take full
responsibility for that.
But where you go from
here is up to you, Derrek.
You got nothing to prove.
What're we gonna do, Pop?
We'll find a way, like always.
We'll figure it out.
I'll come to check on you later.
Hey, doc?
Thank you.
Dr. Banfield, I thought
you were gone for the night.
- I needed to follow up.
- You don't have to check up on me.
- I was checking up on your patient.
- Right. My patient.
Yes, who thankfully survived your
little therapeutic misadventure today.
May I ask you a question?
How can such a good doctor
be such a knucklehead?
I thought Chaz was different.
It was a mistake.
After Greg Pratt
died, I lost some focus.
I'm working on it.
Well, I hope you
find clarity soon.
Dr. Morris, good night.
Good night.
Dr. Banfield. Oh.
Glad I caught you.
Here's everything you need.
Veal, cream, chanterelles.
- You'll never find good ones. I got a guy.
- No, I can't accept that.
Please, I insist.
- Let me know how it turns out.
- And Frank.
Remember, this never happened.
Hey, man.
So how was your first day?
I'm so sorry about
that chest tube.
Don't worry. He's gonna be fine.
- And all the interns hate me.
- No.
They don't hate you. They
probably hate me, but not you.
Listen, all that
stuff, my fault.
I'm the one that
should be sorry.
It's just, every time I see
you, I see your brother.
And he was a hell of a doctor.
And you will be too, one day.
But you got a ways
to go and I forgot that.
So, today, just chalk it up.
All right, it's your first step
on a 1000-mile journey.
I really appreciate
you looking out for me.
That's what Greg used to do.
Yeah.
Hey, I'm off soon.
I was gonna go grab a
burger. Forgot to eat today.
- You wanna come?
- Sure.
- I'd like that.
- Cool.
Hi.
They're here.
- Cate, is that you?
- It's me.
Hi. MARIE: Hi.
George, get down
here. Cate's here.
Oh, so good to see you, baby.
Let's get inside, it's freezing.