No, I don't like Goldfish. No!
Turbulence.
It means anything
from a few little bumps
to a catastrophic weather system
that could knock
your flying tin can
right out of the air.
What I don't like is
how they treat you.
The comments and
backhanded compliments.
Okay, I'm gonna stop
you before you say
- something you shouldn't.
- It's my family
we're talking about.
No!
In surgery, we call
it a "complication."
- Oh.
- We've hit a snag,
a bump in the road, turbulence.
Sir, I can gate-check
that for you.
- It'll fit.
- No, sir, it won't.
I'm telling you, it's gonna fit.
I got it up here fine last flight.
I'll rephrase. I'm going to
gate-check your bag for you now, sir.
- Please find your seat.
- No!
So, you know...
you better buckle up.
The seat belt!
- No! No! No!
- Oh, goody.
At this time, please
make sure your seat backs
and tray tables are
in their fully upright
and locked positions.
As we taxi, please direct
your attention to the screens
for a safety demonstration.
- Come on. Come on.
- No!
Diego, calm down. Come on. Papa.
- Sientate bien.
- No!
-I'm so sorry. He's not
usually like this, -DIEGO: No!
But he didn't get a nap today.
That's fine. I have
three of my own at home.
No! I don't like Goldfish.
Uh, excuse me? Hi. Can I
switch seats or something?
It's just, I have a deadline,
and I need this flight to work
- and you don't even have
to move this puny kid. I'll go.
- I don't like Goldfish.
Move me to the back,
anywhere. I don't care.
- No!
- Aisle seat would be best!
Also not like the "back" back
where the seat doesn't recline...
- It's a full flight, sir.
- Worst flight ever.
Do you have a problem
with a crying child?
- I mean...
- As if his mother
isn't under enough stress,
you want to add
to it, make it worse?
I just want to focus
on my briefing.
There are complimentary
earplugs in the seat pocket.
- Use those.
- No!
Come on, let's put your
seat belt on. Please.
You might be my new hero.
This is our first
family trip together.
Bryan planned it last minute.
- No!
- Of course.
He said it was gonna
be relaxing and blissful,
but so far, not much bliss.
Excuse me, sorry.
Marisela, are you okay?
I can hear him all
the way from my seat.
You want me to take him?
- Papa.
- It's okay, go sit back down.
But I reserve the right
to switch out mid-flight,
because Mama's gonna
need a glass of wine.
Or three.
You guys weren't
able to sit together?
Like I said, last minute.
Oh. Well, do you want to?
Thank you.
I make so many efforts.
Did you or did you
not call my mom back
when she left a
message two weeks ago?
- Maybe if you made...
- Ma'am.
We're taxiing. You
must take your seat.
Right, I was... I just switched
seats, and my seat is right there.
Did you or did you
not fail to call her back?
Here.
- Oh, God.
- Right now, ma'am.
Yes. I'm sitting.
- Hello.
- Hi.
- Where'd you come from?
- 4C.
I was being a Good Samaritan and
reuniting a family. Serves me right.
- What are you doing here?
- I'm going to a conference.
National Conference on...
Operative Advances.
- Yeah, me too.
- You didn't mention
you were going.
Neither did you.
You sure you're
not following me?
What? You just found a
way to move into my row.
I should be asking you
if you're following me.
- Don't flatter yourself.
- It is a little suspicious.
One minute, some guy
with a beard's sitting there,
and next thing I
know, there you are.
Flight crew, please
start readying the cabin.
Of course.
Might not be the
worst thing in the world.
- What's not?
- Three whole days
far from home, no one
around to bother us.
I told you, we're done.
I'm not messing around.
- Not even a little
messing around?
- We agreed.
You two wanna switch seats so
you're sitting next to each other, or...
- Sure.
- No.
Cabin crew, please
be seated for takeoff.
I never travel without children.
I was so looking forward
to being on this flight alone.
This is my me time.
Please don't ruin it.
I'm just saying, sometimes
the universe gives you signs,
and this could be
one of those signs.
I know you're not asleep.
- What's that?
- Oh, sorry.
No, Ingrid, you're fine.
I wasn't talking to you.
I would be asleep if you
would leave me alone.
Why isn't she talking to you?
-Well, we got together, -Mm.
- In her car.
- Mm.
And then we stayed apart,
and then we were colleagues,
which turned into friends,
which got us back together...
sort of. Or at least, it
was going to, and then...
And then nothing.
For very good reasons.
- She has a sister.
- You cheated with her sister?
- No. No. God, no.
- No, there was no cheating
because there was no us.
She's oversimplifying it.
I'm going to stretch my legs.
What are you...
What are you doing?
You said to come in here.
- No, I didn't.
- Yeah, you did.
You did that thing
with your eyes.
- My eyes?
- Yeah, where you look
at me all...
You know. Then you
came in here, so I figured
- you wanted me
to come in here, too.
- I did nothing with my eyes.
I swear it looked like...
- There's no room in here.
- Well, I do need to talk to you.
- That's all you've been doing.
- Yeah, without someone
sitting in between us
and you closing your eyes.
Well, make it quick,
because I have to pee.
Well, you've had a lot
to say lately about us,
- about how you don't think
we should be together.
- Yes. I've been very clear.
Yes, you were and I think
I need to be clear, too.
You and I, this is something.
And I can't keep ignoring that.
- Well, you have to.
- I can't.
- Not my problem.
- Can you?
- What? Yes.
- Ignore it.
- I don't believe you.
- Well, believe
whatever you have to
believe to get out of here.
Oh!
Why? Why do we
have to ignore it, okay?
In Seattle, sure, but
Pierce isn't here. No one is.
That doesn't matter.
Why?
You know why.
Okay. Then I'll go.
You might wanna move
so I can get out the door.
I know.
- So why aren't you moving?
- I don't know.
Whatever happens, this
never happened. Got it?
- Oh!
- Hey.
- Sorry, that's, uh,
still occupied.
- Oh.
Glad someone's
enjoying this flight.
Oh. Hang on, you're,
uh, a little inside out.
- Oh. Thank you.
- Sorry. I'm jealous.
All my fiancé and I have done
today is fight about everything.
- I'm Max.
- Meredith.
Oh. This is perfect timing.
Gonna yell at me again?
- Do I need to?
- Flying is very stressful
for me.
I forgot to take my
water pill this morning,
and I have a condition where, at this
altitude, it can be very hard to breathe.
Pulmonary hypertension.
Ye... Yes. So?
So is that an excuse to shame
mothers and their children?
- Which one is yours?
- Halfway back, green shirt
by the window.
- He's handsome.
- I know.
- Also handsome.
Please make sure that your
seat belts are securely fastened.
I guess she got tired of us
talking over the top of her, huh?
What happened back
there changes nothing.
- Okay.
- I mean it.
I said "okay."
You don't like flying?
- It's not my favorite.
- Me neither.
Plane crash.
Wait.
- You were in a...?
- Yeah.
- Was it bad?
I mean it was...
we crashed and got lost.
People died. It wasn't great.
What about your plane crash?
Did anyone die or lose a limb?
You know that's how
Arizona lost her leg?
Okay, I'm definitely not
telling you about mine now.
- It can't compare.
- It's not a contest.
- Come on.
- No.
I told you mine.
All right, I was a
teenager, total idiot.
My mate's dad had one of those
crop dusters. We snuck it out.
We got it off the
ground pretty high
for about four whole minutes
before we crashed into a shed.
But that feeling of
falling straight down...
Yeah, mine was way worse.
Well, I told you mine
couldn't compare to yours.
Meredith. Meredith.
Mer, just breathe. Just breathe.
Where is Derek?
Derek!
- Oh, God.
- Just breathe! Just breathe.
Meredith!
- How you doing?
- Meredith. Meredith. Get up!
- I'm fine.
- Max, Max, get up.
- Max. Max is on the ground.
- Max?
Max? Are you okay?
Oh, God. He's not
moving. Max! Max! Max.
Stay buckled, all right?
We're not gonna be able to help
anybody else if we get hurt, too.
Okay.
Is he all right?
Okay. Listen to me.
I'm a doctor. You gotta reach
down, and feel his wrist or his neck.
- Feel for a pulse.
- I don't know how.
Just lean down
and feel his wrist.
- What's your name?
- Jay.
You're doing good,
Jay. Take a deep breath.
Just reach down, and
tell me if you feel anything.
There's two more down. There's
an older man in the back of the plane.
I think he's okay. He's
getting back into his seat.
There's a flight attendant
on the floor up there.
Which one? Candice?
Is she moving?
I think she hurt her arm or something.
Hey, Candice. Are you okay?
Yes. I mean no, but...
- Yes.
- I feel something!
- I feel a pulse.
- Okay, good.
His eyes are opening.
He's waking up.
Max, do you know what happened?
Do you know where you are?
He lost consciousness.
There could be a brain bleed.
Or he could just be groggy.
He just got slammed
against the ceiling.
Turbulence is dying down.
Sort of.
Okay, let's go.
Where are you
going? You can't go.
Just... it's okay.
Just... it'll be okay.
Just breathe into
your mask. Okay?
Oh God.
You may have broken your wrist. I
think we're gonna have to brace it, okay?
Yeah, the main
medical kit's in the galley.
- I can go unlock it.
- No, I'll go,
just tell me the code.
I'm not allowed
to give that out.
I'm a doctor.
Doesn't matter. Just...
help me up. I'll
get the kit myself.
It's only my wrist. It's not the end
of the world, okay? Just help me up.
Here you go.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
Okay, Max, I'm gonna need
you to follow my finger, okay?
On behalf of the captain, we ask
everyone to please remain calm and seated.
If you need immediate
medical assistance,
please press your call buttons.
Okay, all right. Max, I need
to examine you some more.
Can you sit up for me?
All right. No, no. No standing.
Let's just lean him
against the seat here.
- Okay.
- All right?
- He's following instructions. That's good, right?
- It is. It is good.
- You'll be okay, honey. You'll be okay.
- Okay.
All right. All right.
Can I get some tissues
please? Do you have napkins?
Okay. Great, great, great.
You're gonna be all right,
honey. You're all right.
Doing great.
Okay, I can feel the step-off
where he hit his head.
That's great. Thanks.
Sure thing. Uh, can I
help? I'm a doctor too.
Absolutely. You can,
um, go around and see
if there's any other passengers
that need immediate assistance.
Thank you. You want
to hold that for me?
- Yeah.
- Thanks.
A bunch of Band
Aids and a defibrillator
and no splint, so I can shock
you, but I can't splint your wrist.
So probably gonna have to
reset it, and then wrap it tight.
There's no good pain
meds in here, so this will hurt.
Okay? But I'll go
fast. Quick and dirty.
Quick and dirty,
I can handle that.
Here we go.
Hey, everything okay here?
Deep forehead lac.
It's bleeding pretty bad.
- We should try close it
if we can.
- I got no suture here,
but I got some antiseptic
gauze, some butterfly strips.
The luggage just came
flying out, right to us.
- We tried to block it,
but we couldn't.
- No, don't worry.
You guys did great. We're
gonna get him fixed up.
Uh, Harrison Peters.
- The other doctor
sent me over here to help.
- Oh, right on. Nathan Riggs.
- You a surgeon, too?
- I'm a pediatric dentist.
Uh, maybe I should
help with that.
All right, look. There's a
plane full of freaked out people.
I went through
residency. I can help.
Let me help.
- Head really hurts.
- Okay. Okay.
Is he on any meds? Do
you know his medical history?
No, God, I... I don't know.
But, I mean, yes, he
takes pills every day.
Um, I always joke that he has his
Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday boxes
- like my grandma used to have.
- Okay, do you know
where that is?
- Yeah.
- Mer, I got the kit.
Okay, I don't like this. I
mean, he hit his head hard.
And I don't have the tools here
to tell if he has a brain
bleed or how bad it is.
- How's his mental status?
- I mean, it's spotty.
He's awake, but he's
not making much sense.
But his pupils are equal,
round, and reactive.
Found it. Here.
- He takes these every day?
- Yeah.
Oh. Hey, these are...
These are blood thinners.
So if it's a brain bleed,
it's not going to stop.
This plane needs to land.
No passengers are allowed inside
the cockpit while we're in the air.
Okay, but get the captain out here
or get her on the phone or something.
I've already given Captain LeVantine
a full report of the various injuries,
- and she was clear...
- You're not a doctor,
- so you can't understand...
- Clear that she has no intention
of landing this plane
right now because...
We have passengers who are
bleeding. They need to be evaluated.
Because we are currently flying between
two very dangerous storm systems,
- one above and one below.
- I really need to speak to her.
There's no way to descend
without putting the lives
- of every single person
on this plane at risk.
- Call her.
Hi, captain. Hi,
yeah, it's Candice.
- Yes, I have Dr...
- Dr. Grey.
Dr. Grey here. She's asking to
speak to you about landing the plane.
- Yes, I understand. Of course. Thank you, captain.
- No, no, I need to speak to her.
Okay, she's busy navigating the
plane through dangerous weather.
- She can't talk right now.
- What about the landing?
She won't be doing that either,
Dr. Grey, not until it's safe.
Can I help you
with anything else?
- Well?
- We're stuck up here
for a while.
Okay, that's fine. For now.
Everyone seems to be stable.
- Max has regained consciousness.
- Yep. For now.
- I'm going to recline you back.
- Everything I said,
the stuff we were
fighting about earlier,
I take it back, all of it.
I thought I'd lost you, Max. I mean,
for a minute there, I thought you died.
I thought all of us
were going to die.
We didn't.
I'm so glad.
Okay, so I need to go check
on some other passengers.
I need you to rest. And,
Jay, I need you to let him.
If there are any
changes, anything at all,
any pain, any
slurring of speech,
- call me.
- I do feel better.
Don't worry. I'm here.
Good.
How's your hand?
Hit it on something. It's fine.
It hurts. How's yours?
Fine. Hurts.
You left.
And you didn't come back,
and I've been back there alone.
Um... I'm... I'm bleeding.
Probably just nicked it
when the plane fell, okay?
So we'll just get that
cleaned up for you, okay?
Mm.
One minute, that's all it takes.
We hit one bad air pocket
or cloud or whatever,
and we're all just one big
plane crash waiting to happen.
You get used to it.
Not me. I'm... I hate this.
- I'm not flying ever again.
- No, you're just scared.
Give it time.
The fear goes away, trust me.
You might be
willing to risk it again.
Hi. Can I take a
look at your head?
Okay. This might
sting a little, okay?
There we go.
Okay, Diego, look
at this boo boo.
You may need a few stitches
when we land. But that's okay.
You know what? My little girl, when she
was your age, she busted her knee open.
Do you know how
many stitches she got?
Three.
And you know what else she got?
She got a lollipop
for every stitch.
You're so good
with him. Thank you.
- Of course.
- Are you done?
Excuse me, miss?
Are we landing on time?
I really don't want to
miss my connection.
- It was already tight.
- How's your breathing? Are you having any trouble?
Weren't you talking to
the pilot on the phone?
- You have to know...
- We're still in the air,
so obviously we're not landing.
I don't think you
understand the level of stress
- that I'm feeling.
- Okay, so...
Here. Breathe into
that and sit down.
Could you grab
me a cup of water?
Or juice? Juice would be
great right now. Apple, no ice.
You do realize I'm a doctor.
His mother did
not raise him right.
We've gone through
most of the gauze.
Thanks for helping out.
Oh, it's kind of fun
treating adults for a change.
They can actually
tell me where it hurts.
They don't expect any
stickers when I'm done.
That was not cool.
This is not fun.
- This is terrible.
- No, no, no. I know exactly what you mean.
I'm gonna go sit a minute while I
can, until the next call button rings.
Yeah, of course.
Uh, is there anything
else you need?
Company maybe, or...?
- You could go check on Max.
- Copy that. Will do.
Hey, sorry. Can you... Do you
have any antacids or anything?
- I'm sure someone does. Ask around.
- Sorry. Can you touch my head?
Do I have a fever, you
think? Does it feel hot?
You too, huh?
Excuse me?
You're looking for a place to
hide so you get five minutes alone
without someone new
asking for a consult.
I just had a lady in row
27 ask for a mole check.
How's it going with
your dentist friend?
You guys seem pretty chummy.
You're one to talk.
How long were you wrapping
your flight attendant's arm?
- Oh, her name's Candice.
- Um...
It's what I do when I board a plane.
I always ask the crews their name.
It's a respect thing.
Also, it usually
gets me free drinks.
Aha.
What was your plane crash like?
I told you. It was bad.
- I know, but what was it like?
- Uh, it was cold.
So cold.
Even being numb was
cold. I could not warm up.
You know they call us
the Seattle Grace Five?
There were six
of us that went up,
and only five of us came back.
And now there are
only three of us alive.
My sister died out there.
You...
- You have another sister?
- Uh-huh.
My kid sister Lexie.
I loved her.
Anyway, it's weird.
Sometimes I feel like I'm cursed.
A lot of people die around me.
Sometimes I feel like
I'm just waiting for my turn.
I'm sorry about your sister.
It makes sense now.
What does?
The way you feel about Maggie.
How you want to protect
her. I mean, I get it better.
Well, there's nothing to get.
I mean, it makes sense,
you know, all the self-sacrifice.
You don't want to
lose this one, too.
Is it so crazy that I would put
someone else's happiness before mine?
No, but I mean, it's
not completely practical
in the long run. I
mean, at some point,
you have to think about the things
that are gonna make you happy, too.
- And you think you're it?
- Well, you haven't exactly
been backing away from me.
I told you what happened
in the bathroom...
I'm not just talking
about the damn bathroom.
- Then what?
- For months now... Look,
you try to stay away. Maybe
you even want to stay away.
But you don't.
You never do. A week
ago, you called it quits.
An hour ago, we're
having sex in the bathroom.
- Will you stop it, please?
- I will respect
whatever you decide.
Okay? But don't sit here and
pretend that you don't want this thing
- between you and me
as much as I do.
- I am married.
Uh, hey. Sorry, uh...
We need you.
You're okay. It's okay.
Wow. Okay, Max, we're
gonna get you cleaned up.
- I need some towels.
- Yeah. I'll find some.
- Excuse me.
- My head.
- Yeah, let me have a look.
- He was fine. We were talking, and he...
He got tired, so he was resting,
and then he just doubled over.
If he got better and he
suddenly deteriorated...
Okay, well, he has a brain
bleed, and it's getting worse.
Oh, God!
Get him on the floor.
Definitely getting worse.
- Here. Towels.
- He's having a seizure!
- Oh, my God!
- What else do you need?
I need the captain right now!
Do you think I'm
being arbitrary,
that I'm just trying to
get in the way here?
My patient's condition
has escalated.
I need to get him on the
ground and to a hospital now.
If I tell you I can't
land this plane yet,
it's because I can't.
He has classic symptoms
of a severe epidural bleed.
Every minute, the pressure
is building up in his brain.
I need to relieve that pressure,
and I can't do that up here.
I don't have
clearance to land here.
- You think I haven't tried?
- Well, you have to try harder!
And endanger the lives of 257
people so you can save one?
Absolutely not.
I will land this plane the
minute it's safe to do so.
No sooner. End of discussion.
Well?
She can't land
the plane right now.
So we wait?
Max isn't just postictal,
okay? The B.P. was elevated.
The pressure on his brain
is reaching critical levels.
- How much longer did she say?
- She didn't say.
Maybe an hour, maybe
two. There's no way to know.
He doesn't have
that kind of time.
I know. Listen, if we
were on the ground,
I'd be rushing him to the
O.R. or drilling burr holes.
Yeah, and if we were in
the field, we'd be looking
for a way to puncture his skull
to relieve the pressure, but...
Meredith, we're
on a moving plane.
- Meredith?
- I know there won't be much
that's sharp,
but there's got to be something.
To puncture his skull? Did I
mention the moving plane?
Where's Candice?
I'm sorry. Maintenance tool
kits aren't allowed on board,
not unless they're
checked underneath.
And there's no way
to get down below?
Definitely not. What's going on?
A drill. I need something
I can use as a drill.
Meredith, can we just
pause for a minute?
- Hey, should we move Max, or...
- Hey, you're a dentist.
Do you have any drills on you?
Sure, yeah. I always
have them in my carry on.
- I have them in a special case,
you know, like chef's knives.
- Wait. Really?
No. My key chain
has nail clippers on it,
- but that's about it.
- I've got one syringe. Ah.
I'm sorry. What?
We believe he has a brain bleed,
and we don't know when
we're gonna be able to land.
But we feel that the bleed
needs to be addressed now.
But he's fine. He's sleeping.
Why can't he just keep sleeping?
No, Jay. He looks
like he's just sleeping,
but the pressure is
building in his head,
- and if we just do nothing...
- He might not wake up?
Then why are you wasting
your time talking to me?
Do what you have to
do. Just help him, please.
We need your seats
for a medical emergency.
Thank you for your
patience. Right this way.
Let's recline him
and strap him in.
Yeah, we've got
seat belt extenders.
- Yes. Get them.
- Where do you want the blankets?
Here and here.
Ingrid, I can't guarantee you're
not about to see a lot more blood.
Yeah. No. I know. I'm okay.
- Here you go.
- Candice, did the kit
have an Ambu bag?
- I'll get it.
- Okay.
And get some more towels.
I felt skull movement
along the fracture line earlier.
I need to go in through there and
decompress the hematoma with the needle.
- You can do that?
- Isn't that bad, to stick
a needle in the brain?
Depends. If she goes in too
deep, then she could hit the dura.
- I won't go in too deep. Puts
her less than a millimeter away
from puncturing brain
matter with a syringe
in an uncontrolled,
unsterile environment.
Are you done? I'm aware of the
risks. If you don't think I can do this...
Oh, I'm sure you can do
this once, maybe twice,
but evacuating a bleed
with just a syringe?
You're gonna have to insert
that needle time and time again.
What are the odds you don't
hit brain matter eventually?
- Then don't help.
- I have to help.
- You need the assist.
- I have other people here.
Oh, other surgeons?
Look, Meredith, I'm here.
- We're gonna do this together,
all right?
- Got the Ambu bag, more towels,
and all the saline
solution I could round up.
Found it. I'm gonna
need you to bag him
- and hold his head steady.
- Got it.
Ingrid, I need you to go tell Jay not to
worry, and don't let him come up here.
- Yes.
- And close the curtains.
Candice, you go tell that captain she
better keep this plane very freakin' steady.
Okay, his pulse is slowing down.
Okay. We got to
move fast. Let's go.
Needle.
Now, there's usually
a lull after a bomb hits
before the next one
explodes. That's your window.
You just wait for
that boom, then go.
Boom.
Okay. I think it's...
good.
Saline.
Okay. Going in for round two.
Nice and steady.
Round five.
What's wrong?
It's just...
It's just, re-inserting
this over and over. It's...
I'm undoing the syringe.
You're what? You want to
hold the needle in your hand?
It's gonna save me from having to
re-insert the needle over and over again.
We've got to drain this fluid off
his brain, or we're gonna lose him.
If you move that
needle even a little,
- he's as good as dead anyway.
- Well aware. Thank you.
Okay, you put it in. I need both
hands to keep this needle steady.
Okay.
- It's not going in right.
- Okay. It will. Just untwist
it and try again.
You have that needle
inserted into his brain...
- I told you. I've got the needle.
- What if you don't?
What if I slip and it
goes right into his...
Okay, just stop
talking and do it.
- It's on.
- Okay. Good. Great.
Okay. Evacuating again.
Great.
Only about 50 more times to go.
Help! Help!
I've got this. You should go.
This is a two-person
job. You need the assist.
- Help! Help!
- We need some help.
You want me to
go? I can see if...
No. You're bagging him and
holding his head. You can't move.
Just go.
- I'll help.
- Help! Help him!
Sir, sir, is your
chest hurting you?
- Can't breathe.
- Yeah. Okay. Let's get him
into some space.
That's the guy with
pulmonary hypertension.
Okay. All right.
Lay him. Slow, slow, slow.
What's that mean?
It means the vessels around
his lungs are constricted.
He's basically
suffocating from the inside.
Yeah, I know, man. I
know. Just hang on there.
Okay, I need you
to, uh, get me the O2
and get on the speaker and ask if anybody
has some erectile dysfunction pills.
- I'm sorry. What?
- I'll open up his vessels.
- It could save his life. Go! Go!
- Okay!
Excuse me. Excuse me. Did
you say erectile dysfunction drugs?
Yes, ma'am. Hopefully
somebody on board has some.
Well...
Actually, we do.
Okay. Saline.
Hey, Dr. Riggs said you
might need some help.
Yeah. Grab some gloves.
Sit up and take this pill, okay?
Okay. I need you to
empty this into the bag.
Now I need you to
put the barrel back on
while I hold the needle steady,
okay? Work fast, but go slow.
Okay.
No, no, no.
It's okay.
Okay, no pulse. I need you to
get the defibrillator right now.
- You have to stop shaking.
- I know. I know. I'm trying.
I got it. Hold on.
- Deep breath, Ingrid.
- Oh, God. Oh, God.
I can't make it stop.
- Stop it, hands.
- We are fine. Concentrate.
You got this.
Here.
Hook it up.
I'm on.
- V fib. Charging.
- Okay. Shock him.
Clear!
Still in V fib. Charging
again. Shock him.
Clear!
Breathe. You got it.
There you go.
Oh, thank God.
Good news. I've confirmed
a safe location for us
to make an emergency landing. Please
be seated as we begin our descent.
Now she's gonna
land the freakin' plane.
Your seat belts are fastened.
It's still in there?
- Did it move?
- Looks okay. It's okay.
Flight attendants,
please prepare for landing.
I wouldn't be doing my job if I didn't
tell you all to be seated right now.
I wouldn't be doing my job if I
listened, but you should do what's safe.
I'll take my chances.
Okay.
Come on! Come on!
I'm moving too much. I
need some extra hands.
- Nathan?
- What?
I could use your help.
Little busy.
Has he had a rhythm
since he arrested?
- Doesn't matter!
- It's irreversible brain damage
after six minutes. It
matters to this guy.
If I come up there,
I lose my guy!
If you stay there,
we lose two people!
No, we won't, all right? We're not
losing anybody. We're doing that, okay?
Okay.
This is... It's moving
too slowly. I... I need...
- You still have your keys
on you?
- Yeah.
I need them.
I need better blood flow
to relief this pressure faster.
If I can snip this needle
with your nail clippers
and put this straw
over the needle...
I'm doing this.
Keep him still,
completely... still.
Come on!
Sanitizer.
Okay.
Clip the hub of
the needle. Good.
Now clip the straw.
Phew.
Over the needle, into the skull.
Please fit. Please fit.
Please fit.
Okay, okay, I need
a cup. Give me a cup.
Okay, that was amazing.
The coolest stuff I see are
kindergartners with teeth growing
in behind their teeth.
Come on.
Pulse. Does that
mean he has a pulse?
I've got a pulse.
Welcome back, buddy.
Blood. It's just blood.
The ground, Mer!
We've landed.
We're on the ground.
Nice and easy, ready? Let's go.
Remember, he seized
from an epidural hematoma.
I wrote it all down and
taped it to his chest, okay?
Thank you for keeping him alive.
Of course.
Doctor.
Captain.
Nice flying with you.
Thank you.
Thank you for fixing my wrist.
You know, should I call
you for a follow-up maybe?
Your regular doctor should be
able to take care of that pretty good.
You sure? 'Cause I fly in
and out of Seattle all the time.
It would be absolutely no trouble
to stop by and have you take a look.
It's not necessary.
Take care.
- We did it.
- We did.
- Still going to the conference?
- I think I've learned enough.
Mm.
Thanks.
I don't even know
what town we're in.
Sioux Falls, apparently.
Right.
Well, they got to
have a nice hotel.
Well, if it's not nice, it's
got to be halfway decent.
Look, we're stuck
here. We got to sleep.
But not together.
Oh, co... You just...
You just treated a bloke's
brain bleed with a cocktail straw.
You're so fearless
about so many things.
How the hell are
you still scared?
I'm not scared.
One of the most unpredictable
things about encountering turbulence
is its aftermath.
I'm making a choice. I'm
prioritizing my family, my sister.
Look, don't. Don't, please.
Don't pretend this is
still about Pierce. It's not.
- You're scared.
- Of what?
Of him.
Of letting him go.
Where is Derek? Derek!
Everything's been
shaken up, undone,
turned on its head.
At some point, you gotta let go.
I don't really wanna
talk about this.
Good. I don't want to talk.
I don't want to talk about it.
I don't want to talk at
all, okay? I just want to...
I want to move forward.
I want to live my life
'cause I'm still here.
I've still got one,
and so do you.
Don't look at me like that,
like I don't know what I'm talking
about, 'cause you know I do.
That could have been you
in that seat with no seat belt.
Yeah, but it wasn't.
Okay? I'm just fine.
And so are you.
So, if you have the choice
to avoid the plane crash,
do you take it?
Do you play it safe?
It better be a nice hotel.
Or do you get on board
and take your chances?
So, four star hotel? Five star? I
mean, how nice are we talking?
I'm not holding your hand.