Keep breathing. Nice and slow.
Now, the first couple shots will show you
if the sights are off or the barrel's bent.
Let me make this
real easy for you.
The sights are off,
and the barrel's bent.
Mmm... You're off to
the left about an inch.
That's it. Shoot
around the star, not at it.
Yes! Yes! You did it!
I didn't.
You just won your
girlfriend a teddy bear.
Cool. Which one do
you think she'd like best?
And then Thursday night, this
physicist is giving a lecture in Brooklyn.
It's about time travel and
the grandfather paradox.
I don't know if you're
busy... Okay, Henry. Henry.
Um...
Can we talk for a second? Yeah.
I'm really happy that we've
been hanging out so much.
Yeah, I like you, too.
Can you put down the bear?
Henry.
What?
I can't.
I know.
You have a girlfriend.
It's just she never seems to
want to do anything with you.
Are you crying?
No, I have allergies. I
must just be, like, tearing up.
Henry, I think that's blood.
What? I...
Thirty-five year old male cries
blood, and he's not Vampire Bill. Go.
Should we ask? Nope.
What, her?
Yeah. My favorite companion
is retiring from companning.
So I'm interviewing
her replacements.
Thank you, Butter Scotch.
Is that a family name?
How long are you gonna be
using the office for sex games?
Just so I can plan my day.
Sex? At work? I'm not a savage.
I asked for a cappuccino.
That's what this is.
No, cappuccino's got a nice, stiff
foam on it. This is wetter than... Oh...
Almost slipped there.
Well, thank you, Ms. Scotch,
but poor foaming's a deal breaker.
Could you ask the next
candidate to come in?
Initial exam showed no sign of
trauma or subconjunctival hemorrhage.
Lymphocytosis? ALC's in the normal
range, but it's in the high end of normal.
Please take a seat, Fawn.
And tell me what's your
favorite Woody Allen movie?
Annie Hall.
You're interviewing hookers but
not going to talk to them about sex?
Sex is a given. They're hookers.
Defend your choice.
It's the most popular.
Oh, so close.
We would have accepted
"Diane Keaton looks great in suits."
Or, "It's a trenchant
commentary on today's mores."
Or, "I needed the eggs."
Thanks for your interest.
To get the gig, a call girl...
Sorry, "call woman" needs a combination
of skills that I find useful/entertaining
for the remaining 57
minutes of the hour I pay for.
Lymphocytosis works. Maybe we
should take another look at the blood.
Could also be cavernous
sinus thrombosis.
Clot builds up pressure
at the base of the brain.
Re-run the patient's blood panel
and get a CT venogram of his head.
See which one of you is right.
How are you with
small appliance repair?
This cavernous sinus
thing, is it dangerous?
If Henry's got it, we can treat
with a combo of drugs and surgery.
The success rate is over 70%.
Do you want me to call
Amy again? No, it's fine.
Amy's his girlfriend.
I'm the neighbor. I did leave
a message at their number.
Do you want to try her cell? You'll
be here for a few more hours at least.
She doesn't have one.
She worries about radiation.
I could stop by on my way home.
She knows who I am, right?
You don't need to, but thanks.
Good luck. Okay.
Have you ever paid for sex?
Every guy who's ever seen a
Merchant Ivory movie has paid for sex.
No. It just seems too
demeaning to women.
Given the things you've done
to women, that seems arbitrary.
You're Chi Park,
right? Who's asking?
You called about my
guitar flyer. You're Micah.
This guy's selling a 1974 Gibson
SG Standard in tobacco for $1,250.
Yeah, actually, I came in to
tell you I already sold it. Sorry.
Oh, uh... Thanks anyway.
Blood panel results seem
pretty much the same as before.
And that guy likes you.
Maybe we should check for diabetes.
Could weaken conjunctival vessels.
And shut up.
If I'm wrong, then why
is he coming back?
My band is rehearsing tomorrow night.
You should come by and jam with us.
That sounds fun.
I'll think about it.
Great. Call me.
Park has a boyfriend.
I'll break your face.
This is the talent portion
of the interview. Okay.
You like cards,
but you can juggle.
I fail to see how this
would be a benefit to you.
What if I'm busy?
You got anything else? Sure.
CT showed no clots
or malformations.
Park and Taub ruled out
lymphocytosis and diabetes.
Well, since you have
nothing of relevance to report,
I assume that you're here to
toss your panties in the ring.
Patient's got a mysterious
girlfriend he really wants to see.
She's unreachable by phone, and
the neighbor's never even seen her.
What do you think? He's gay.
I think he's a junkie. The girlfriend
is a fix. If the guy's inhaling glue...
Can you repair a blender?
Can you bite me?
Go search the patient's home.
Well, thank you, ladies. I've seen
a lot of very talented candidates.
Got a tough decision
in the next few days.
This is the part I hate.
Well, it's not
exactly a crack den.
Doesn't exactly look like
a woman lives here either.
"To Amy. I love you."
Okay, she exists. Doesn't
mean he's not a drug addict.
It's good you're
playing it cool with
House. Once he gets
a rise out of someone...
I'm not crazy about the
whole hooker thing, but I get it.
Other than the fact that it's
exploitative and dangerous for women,
you get what you need without
any of the emotional baggage.
You're not seeing
anyone, I take it?
I've been volunteering at the
Trenton Free Clinic. Keeps me busy.
You volunteer every
night and every weekend?
No time to grab dinner?
What's more important?
Making small talk over ravioli
or helping people
who are less fortunate?
By that rationale, none of
us should ever eat again.
Well, let's just say I'm
not hungry right now.
Oh, God.
I don't think she's breathing.
You think she OD'd?
That or he killed her. Pulse?
No. I'll call the coroner.
I don't think that's
going to be necessary.
This one works
in financial district.
She can get tips. Give
you leg up in market.
What is Fudgey Gonzalez?
Ah. Imagine a Vanilla
Gonzalez from the other side.
I'm about to make a decision, but there's
still time for you to sneak under the wire.
My favorite Woody Allen
movie is Melinda and Melinda.
Our patient is not a junkie,
but he does have a girlfriend.
I call her my girlfriend,
because people understand that.
If I explained it, they'd
just think I was a weirdo.
We're not here to
judge anyone's fetish.
I'm not a pervert.
It's not like I'm more
attracted to dolls than humans.
So you don't have sex with her?
It's not just about that.
Does the doll talk to you?
I know she's not a real person.
In a lot of ways, she's
better than a person.
I can tell her things, and she won't
argue with me or make fun of me.
I come home every night, and
I know she'll be there waiting.
So is your toaster.
No one in the world has an
emotional attachment to a toaster.
But a lot of people are willing to
spend $7,000 on women like Amy.
Have you ever tried an actual...
Yeah, I'm 35. I've been in relationships.
Just none of them fulfilled me.
And one day, I saw
this website, and...
Maybe the perfect woman
is out there somewhere,
but it's not worth going through
what it would take to find her.
Amy makes me happy.
You're sweating.
It's sort of hot in here.
Not that hot.
Bleeding plus two new
symptoms, fever and neurological.
I'm not sure about that last
one. I think he's just weird.
He wasn't hallucinating. He
didn't have a thought disorder.
You don't think it's
disordered to talk to...
It's not all that different from
talking to your cat or a teddy bear.
You don't have sex with
your cat or teddy bear.
If you did, you'd probably
talk to them more.
Guy loves an imaginary being
who's never going to respond to him.
He's no crazier than
millions of churchgoers.
You think anything off about
any patient is a symptom.
This guy buys flowers, real flowers,
for a piece of plastic in a dress.
You know what's really crazy?
Living with a human being.
Someone with opinions and feelings
who gets mad just because you wanna take
salsa classes with them one night a week.
One night.
He's just running away.
He hangs out with a doll. He
never needs to fear rejection.
It's sad. HOUSE: You do
understand the irony here.
Every person in this
room has a sex doll.
At least the patient has the
stones to be honest about it.
Ooh! A metaphor.
What you didn't foresee is
that I actually do have a sex doll.
Your doll is your kids. Yours is
your parents. Yours is your charity.
They're all excuses for
not being in a relationship.
He's not wrong. And you...
I have meaningless sex
with random strangers.
Thanks for the insight, but
I stopped that months ago.
I actually had a
relationship. With a patient.
You just date whoever
happens to cross your path.
My dating is getting in
the way of my dating?
You don't go looking
for the right person.
You just shack up with
whoever's in the room.
And then you get surprised and/or
divorced when it doesn't work out.
I'm surprised you haven't
asked Adams out yet.
Uh...
For your information,
I've got a date tonight.
I'll be jamming with a
cute guy and his band.
You'll bail. TAUB: He's right.
The obvious solution is for me to
hand my kids over to your parents.
Can we stop trying
to argue the premise
and move on to figuring out
why it is you're all social morons?
You do understand
the irony here.
You're mocking us for
avoiding relationships,
but you can't handle
losing your doll.
You're spending all this time and
energy interviewing for a new one.
You're right. That is stupid.
What about the patient?
Dude's banging a sex doll,
a festering cesspool of bodily
fluids and associated bacteria.
Swab her out and
find out which one.
I need you.
Please don't quit. You're the only
hooker I know who can tune a piano.
If it's about the money, then I
can up you to three nights a week.
I'm getting married, House.
His name's Harris. He's
a certified accountant.
He loves schlocky horror
movies, and he just moved in.
We're very happy.
Well, you're happy.
Yeah, you're happy,
because he doesn't know
about your employment history.
He knows.
We've talked about it, and
he accepts me for who I am.
No. He's...
If he accepted who you were, he would
not be making you give up your career.
Women need their own
identities, their own livelihoods.
Otherwise, why was I
smoking all those Virginia Slims?
I know this is weird for you.
But you need to figure
out a way to be okay with it.
I'll miss you, too.
I feel like the
stirrups are overkill.
I've never done a pelvic on a doll
before. I'm unfamiliar with the protocol.
I'm pretty skeeved out
right now. I'm not gonna lie.
What House said back there...
House says a lot of things.
I don't just date
whoever shows up.
I mean, I did meet women in the
hospital, but they weren't just flings.
Basically, you're explaining
why you're not gonna ask me out.
That's not what I was...
Did you want me to ask you out?
Yeah. I told Park to tell Taub to
tell House to pass you that note.
It's completely clean in there.
He said he had just bathed her.
Adams, there's a swelling
beneath the skin, a three-inch mass.
Is it part of the
doll's skeleton?
It feels like a tumor.
CT showed an air-filled
mass in the doll's abdomen.
It's probably just a
chemical reaction.
Henry left her too close to
a heating pipe or something.
This guy brushes her
hair every morning,
brings home movies for
them to watch together.
You think he tosses her in a
broom closet at the end of each day?
More likely than it
getting stomach cancer.
How about clostridium?
Bacteria got trapped in an
airtight cavity, produced gas.
Doesn't explain the
neurological issue.
We can explain that the same
way we explain the tooth fairy.
Oh...
I get to play Solomon.
Cut the doll open.
We can't just destroy the patient's
property. That thing cost seven grand.
Exactly. Ask him for consent.
If he says yes, then we
get to go hunting bacteria.
If he says no, there's no need,
'cause he's crazy, and
we need a different theory.
See you. Gotta
go build a temple.
Okay.
You're sure?
It won't be able to
heal when we're done.
But you think she could tell
you what's wrong with me.
Yes.
Okay.
Should we take her
to the procedure room?
It's not a "her," which means
we can do this anywhere.
Adams.
You can know something's
not real and still love it.
I think the procedure
room might be better for this.
You are a horrible person.
All I need is to break up one marriage.
You've broken up three of your own.
You're like the Stephen
Hawking of killing relationships.
Actually, no, Stephen Hawking
is the Stephen Hawking of...
Okay, I have work to do.
Your computer is off.
Sorry, I can't hear
you over my stereo.
Why do you assume that
marriage is better than hooking?
We don't know anything about
the guy. He could be a serial killer.
Even if that were true,
it would still be a tossup.
What kind of guy
marries a hooker?
Someone who hires hookers.
And someone who hires hookers
is not exactly the monogamous type.
If we expose him as a
cheater... You're a coward.
Would a coward fight to the end to save
a damsel in soon-to-be-proved distress?
Absolutely. If what he's
afraid of is other damsels.
Your last relationship failed so
miserably, you ended up in jail.
Now you're clinging
to this hooker
when there are about three billion other
women out there who aren't call girls.
Some of whom are
attractive and intelligent.
One of whom is living in your
apartment and is married to you.
You're right.
Why am I asking you for help?
You shouldn't sleep with Chase.
Oh, thank God, you
got here just in time.
What do you have against him?
Nothing. But House has a
way of getting in people's heads.
Just like last week when he was
prying into your relationship with Chase?
It was silly then,
and it's silly now.
Why was it silly then?
I'm not 5' 9" with
curves and flowing hair,
so it's impossible for me to get
it on with a good-looking guy?
Wow. Do you resent me?
You're the quirky,
hard-working sophomore,
and I'm the evil
cheerleader who steals boys?
If you're not getting
any, it's not my fault.
Should we get the one with
the panda on it or the bird?
Good choice.
Pandas eat only bamboo.
They know nothing about cereal.
Your little girl is adorable.
Thanks. She keeps me very busy.
You and her mom
must be very proud.
Her mother died in childbirth.
Amy!
How'd it go?
We're growing cultures now,
but she looked clean, and
there was no telltale smell.
I'm guessing the lump was just an
air bubble that got trapped in the mold.
You bandaged her up.
I threw in some stitches, too. Just
wanted to make her look her best.
Do you want me to
put her in her chair?
Henry.
Call a code!
Are you looking at the apartment
with those or the transit of Mercury?
If night comes, you
will be thanking me.
They are seeking heat.
He's an accountant. How late
do you think he's gonna party?
I brought jar to pee in.
Yeah. JESSICA: We heard
crackles in Henry's lungs.
We diuresed him, but
he still needs oxygen.
Echo shows normal heart function.
Could be high output failure from anemia.
Hematocrit was rock normal.
- What is this, mushroom?
- Say mushroom, charge two dollars.
Say truffle,
charge five dollars.
Is that the man who
wants to marry hooker?
Probably. But he's
not the one we're after.
Should we ask? Nope.
Oh! How rude of
me not to situate you.
I'm doing Emily a favor.
We're gonna track her fiancé
until Dominika can seduce
and expose him as the
lying cheater I need him to be.
I'm guessing she
didn't ask for this favor.
You know, the noblest gifts are
the ones we give anonymously.
Crackles are non-specific.
Hypoxia plus bleeding could
indicate DIC or some other...
No neurological symptoms?
I knew your bleeding heart
would bring you around.
Too bad it's also taking
you off the market,
and by market, I mean Chase.
Come on, buck up, Chase.
There's always Park. Unless...
How did band practice go? Great.
Does it look like
she's lying? Kind of.
Popo needed a ride to the
doctor, and my mother couldn't, so...
You're terrified of dating,
because a previous
relationship ended
because your latent rage made
you vicious in arguments, or...
Or reincarnation.
In a past life she was Anne
Boleyn. HOUSE: Interesting.
Taub feels confident enough
to turn the spotlight on himself.
It's almost as if he
wants me to ask...
- What's her name?
- Wendy Jacobson.
Thirty three, Brown grad, family therapist.
- Nice choice.
Since you've got two
families to therapize.
First date, we didn't
discuss everything important.
It was just a one-night stand.
You're wrong. I
actually like her.
I'm gonna see her
again. Mazel tov.
Great relationships often start with
snap decisions aimed at proving me wrong.
Air bubble in the doll could
mean the silicone is degrading.
If he inhaled some
particles... Silicone deposition.
That could work. Start
him on plasmapheresis.
Now, turning to Adams,
my theory is tripartite.
Wanna hear my thesis?
It's kind of interesting.
No man comes out.
But old naked lady in 3-C is
eating a whole block of cheese.
Will this hurt? No, might
feel a little cold, though.
Crap. MOLLY: Hey.
I only have a second, but I
went to that time travel lecture.
Whoa.
That is awesome.
What is it?
It's so... Ugh... Realistic.
And it's all bandaged up.
Is it one of those
CPR things? No.
We're starting a
procedure, a little privacy...
No, no. It's good
that she's here.
Molly.
I would like you to meet Amy.
What?
I'm serious.
I know it seems
a little strange,
but she means a lot to me.
I gotta get back to work.
You just got here. Sit down.
Yeah, but I said that
I only had a second.
Enjoy the handouts.
Whoa.
Listen, I have to
admit something.
Okay.
Her mom isn't dead.
We're separated.
You're the first person
I've asked out since then.
I'm not used to
explaining. I panicked.
Which I regret, because now
that I've gotten to know you,
I like you.
It was a really
stupid lie. I'm sorry.
Was that a different baby?
No.
That was a different baby.
It's nice having you here.
I wish you could come
over and get in bed with me.
Like this?
You're talking.
That's not all I can do.
Amy, there are doctors... Shh...
I don't know.
Just put your hands on me.
It hurts.
Ah!
Pushing lorazepam.
If it wasn't neurological
before, it sure is now.
Right upper
quadrant's distended.
He's hallucinating
because his liver is failing.
Elevated transaminases
confirm liver failure.
We'll have to put him on the
transplant list in a couple of days.
It's clearly not the
silicone. Could be vasculitis.
Serologies were negative.
Yeah. If you want Adams to hear,
you might wanna not stand
so conspicuously far away.
I'm making coffee.
And sometimes I date co-workers.
Like everyone else on the planet.
Hepatic fibrosis. If it damaged his
platelets, it'd explain the bleeding.
Unexpected. I actually thought
you might agree with my theory.
Because that would
mean nothing's your fault.
You fell into relationships based
on proximity. Of course they'd fail.
But I guess I was wrong. You picked
perfect women. You just screwed it up.
How about all five of us sleep
together and the $7,000 sex doll?
It'll solve all of our
hang-ups. $7,000?
Adams suggests that we all sleep
together, and your issue is high prices.
Pretty sure she was joking.
- Yes.
I'm 99% sure that you're right,
but I would never forgive myself...
Those dolls are only $5,000. He
must have had it customized somehow.
Oh, like you didn't
check the website.
Guess we don't need to ask
how your dating life is going.
I was curious.
Hepatic fibrosis wouldn't
cause difficulty breathing.
It would if liver failure
opened pulmonary AV shunts.
Fibrosis fits. Start
the patient on steroids.
And find out how
he pimped his ride.
Why? Because I
don't know the answer.
Hey.
Foosball? Can't.
Marriage to destroy. Okay.
"Okay," as in passive-aggressive
reverse psychology?
Or as in depressed resignation?
"Okay," as in I changed my mind.
Expand.
It's morally reprehensible
and bound to fail,
but in a weird way, it's a step
forward, this thing with Emily.
Contract. It's real
without being real.
It's a long term relationship
that can't actually hurt you.
It's a stepping stone. It
means you want more.
So passive-aggressive
reverse psychology. Got it.
Try not to come
on too strong, okay.
Just get to know him
a little. Ease into it.
Why would I ease?
True, you could just walk up and
stick your hand down his pants,
but I've heard
there's a middle step.
Men want to have sex.
Not with crazy people.
Well, yes, a lot with crazy
people, but not that kind of crazy.
Well, yeah, that
kind of crazy, but...
They don't care how
crazy if she looks like me.
Okay. Easing.
Hi. Hey.
I'm Jennifer, new to
Marketing Department.
Harris. Accounts
receivable. Interesting.
Do you want to get out
of here and have sex?
Sure.
You know, I've got 45 minutes
left on my lunch break. Mmm-hmm.
Where do you want to go?
Off to a place where men don't
cheat on the women they love.
You're not invited, obviously.
Cheating? What are
you talking about?
Well, I hope you're speaking out of
some deep kind of moral relativism.
Because if... Who
are you people?
You're not Emily's fiancé.
Emily's my sister.
We called the company
that made Amy.
They said they modeled her
after some photos you sent them.
Who is she?
We met last Christmas.
She's a yoga instructor.
Totally different from me. She
loved Chopin, hated Indian food.
She changed my
entire life for 17 weeks.
My husband cheated on me.
With a girl he met on the plane
coming back from our honeymoon.
It's not easy to get
past things like that.
She wasn't unfaithful. She
didn't betray me. She just...
Just wasn't in love with me.
I know Amy's not going
to break your heart,
but she's also not
going to change your life.
That light's bright.
Sorry. What's happening to me?
Is your neck stiff? Yeah.
I think you have meningitis.
I'm not leaving the
business. I'm just leaving you.
I didn't want you to feel bad.
So, let me get this straight.
I'm being dumped by a hooker
who's worried about my feelings.
You're married. Half
your clients are married.
And you're a hooker.
My other guys sneak around.
But you'll take me into the bedroom
while your wife's in the next room.
That's just mean.
Oh, thank God.
The marriage, it's a sham.
The only real thing about it is the Green
Card she's gonna get at the end of it.
So, if you wanna get
the meter running...
It's still mean.
It's not a marriage.
It's a felony.
I've seen how she looks
at you when you're together.
Trust me, she likes you.
And I've seen how
you look at her.
Fever's up to 105. He's
not responding to meds.
At this rate, he'll be dead by
the time we get the cultures back.
Spinal fluid was full of white cells.
Meningitis could be carcinomatous.
Cytology showed nothing.
An amoebic infection would
cause fever and meningitis.
But not liver failure. It
could if he had a clot.
How would amoebas get
past his cribriform plate?
He went swimming in a
frozen lake in New Jersey?
Adams said his ex-girlfriend
was a yoga instructor.
Maybe he sprained his chakras.
Yoga nuts are way more likely
to be into alternative medicine.
He had this weird little
teapot in his house.
What was it like?
I don't know. Little,
weird, teapot-ish.
Was it like that? Yeah.
You think he drank some
sort of toxic herbal tea?
Yes, if by tea you
mean salted tap water,
and by drank you mean
poured up his nose.
His girlfriend didn't just
leave him with a broken heart.
She left him with a neti pot.
It's an Indian method of clearing
the sinuses during allergy season,
also known as now.
With distilled water, it can
act as a snot-flushing system.
With tap water, it can act as
an amoeba-delivery system
to the fluids around the brain.
Start him on metronidazole.
If he's lucky, he'll get to see his
plastic children walk down the aisle.
My neck feels much better.
Your fever's gone, and your liver
function's almost back to normal.
You should be able
to go home soon.
I'm going to have some
hospital bills to pay.
I don't suppose used sex
dolls go for anything online?
Dr. Adams?
Can I get your email?
What for?
I just thought maybe we
could see each other again.
I can't.
No, I know it's a
professionalism thing,
but you won't be my
doctor when I get out of here.
It's not that.
It's... What is it?
You said I should
change my life.
You were talking about
yourself, too. I know you were.
Henry. I think you
should ask Molly out.
I should have known
this would happen.
You're a good guy, Henry.
You deserve more than a doll.
Promise me you'll keep trying.
Okay.
Date tonight? No.
So she can't deal. There's
someone out there who can.
You just got to find her.
I'd love to prove
House wrong, but...
I ruined my marriage,
broke two people's hearts,
had two kids who are always gonna wonder
why I didn't love their mommy enough.
It's better if I just
focus on what I do have.
Give that band guy a call.
I'm not that good at guitar.
Or flirting or small talk?
I'm not as pretty as Adams. I have
stuffy clothes, and I hate my hair.
Adams works 80 hours a
week fixing bunions on hobos,
because she can't face
getting to know someone new.
Trust me, you find a boyfriend,
she'll be the jealous one.
See you tomorrow.
Do you
want to get a drink?
To annoy Park? Or
to prove House wrong?
Oh, I...
It's just I think it's
time for a change.
I don't really think that's a
good idea for me right now.
House has a way of
getting in people's heads.
Yeah. Yeah.
No, Mom. I'm still at work.
I'll be home in a couple
of hours. Love you, too.
Ready? One, two, three, four.
I fixed blender.
So I see.
I had fun seducing
hooker's fake fiancé.
Sorry it didn't work.
Yeah. I thought I'd take a break
from the whole hooker thing.
I think maybe you need
milkshake. Is pistachio.
Well, I'm going to go to
bed. See you tomorrow.