In 1963, Dr. Thomas Starzl performed
the first five liver transplants.
We know it is a departure from
existing Alzheimer's research,
but we believe it
is worth pursuing.
Evidence already suggests that
changes in the gut's microbiome
is correlated with Parkinson's.
If the same proves
true for Alzheimer's,
it could completely transform
the search for a cure.
One patient bled to death
on the operating table.
- Uh. We're happy to answer questions.
- Not necessary.
In fact, I'm sorry we dragged you
all the way from Boston for this.
But it's just that our board will
ask if we met Dr. Grey in person
when we recommend
they fund the project.
The other four died within days.
- You are asking for money, right?
- Yes.
We didn't expect an
answer so soon, but...
The board still has to vote. But
frankly, it's more of a formality,
especially given Dr. Grey's
affiliation with the Fox Foundation.
Should we set up a meeting with
Dr. Fox to discuss next steps?
As a result, the operation was considered
too dangerous to be performed on humans
and liver transplantation was suspended
worldwide for the next four years.
Hey, you almost hit me when you
pulled into the parking lot.
Maybe you should consider
running against traffic.
Thanks for the tip.
♪ Know why you're
Running under sheet ♪
I need to do a wound vac
change before rounds.
- I'll see you inside.
- Yeah.
I'm still mad at you for
getting us banned from the OR.
I didn't ask for your thoughts.
Can you not be a tool right
now? I'm trying to be nice.
- This is you being nice?
- Yes.
I'm declaring a momentary truce.
You got us in trouble, but
you're still my roommate,
kind of my friend and you
were just dumped so...
- Are you okay?
- I wasn't dumped.
- Mutual breakup, whatever. But...
- I'm fine.
You are making it really
hard to be Team Skywalker!
Wasn't exactly an auspicious start for a
surgery that has saved countless lives.
From now on, I'm waiting in the
car when we do these meetings.
Everybody knows my affiliation with
Catherine, and somebody will talk.
Should we give up now? Or can we hold out
until one thing in my life is on track?
My flight is not until 6:00, so I
can make some calls from your lab.
Our lab.
- Ooh, space.
- I think she's waiting.
- Uh, or she's on her phone.
- What about Westerly Science?
They're small and new, but they
have deep research pockets.
Did you get a cat?
I've given up on finding
a human soulmate.
Oh.
Hey, I was waiting
for that spot.
- Well, you were on your phone.
- Answering an important text.
On your phone.
There's an overflow lo...
Dr. Lewis to oncology.
Hey. Uh, and you can erase
Dorian's abdominal washout.
- How's he doing?
- Uh. He's stable for now. The poor kid's got a ways to go.
- Okay. Let's hear it.
- What?
You've been complaining about my changes
to the residency program nonstop.
So, I've got time
before my next surgery.
Maybe get all that
negativity out now
instead of sprinkling it throughout
my day, like you've been doing.
No negativity today.
I'm going on vacation.
Seems early in your
new position to be...
Going someplace warm?
Chicago.
Oh. Say hello to Maggie for me.
I will. I will. But,
uh, when I get back,
I do wanna discuss an
idea for the interns.
Don't you have a plane to catch?
Griffith, Millin, take the pit.
I'm visualizing a multi-car
crash or a construction accident.
- I need chest tubes.
- I need intubations.
And I need a foot massage.
- Kwan, you're with Beltran.
- The new peds attending?
Yeah, you know what they say about
peds without the OR? Babysitting.
Don't care. Beltran was on the team
that pioneered single-port surgery.
Way to brag about reading
the hospital newsletter.
- Just trying to stay ahead.
- Yasuda, Adams, ICU.
Uh. Millin, wanna trade? There are
a lot of chest tubes in the ICU.
- I already have most of those...
- No trading, negotiating or complaining.
Unless one of you picked up
a vanilla latte on the way?
Didn't think so.
Go!
Hmm.
This won't hurt, okay?
Good morning.
I'm Dr. Shepherd.
You must be Malan.
I'm her mom, Maria Flor.
- It's nice to meet you both.
- Nice to meet you.
Good morning. I'm Dr. Beltran, pediatric
surgeon. I'm sorry I'm a little late.
I had an unexpected delay.
- Who's presenting?
- I'm the chief of neurosurgery.
Good for you.
Uh, Malan Vasconcelos,
eight years old,
diagnosed with congenital
hydrocephalus at birth.
She's had five VP shunts to
control the CSF build up.
All vitals look good.
No signs of infection.
She's here today because her mom says
that Malan's not acting like herself.
Would you mind
if I take a look?
Miss Vasconcelos, have you noticed
any change in her motor skills?
No, she's just, um, she's just tired, like
something's off. Something's not right.
She's normally full of energy, running
around the house dancing and kicking.
Not dancing and kicking.
It's ginga and meia-lua.
- She does Capoeira.
- I got my orange belt last month.
Yeah.
Dr. Shepherd, do
you see anything?
- No...
- But that doesn't mean anything.
Well, it means I wasn't
finished with my sentence.
Uh, Maria Flor, I'd like
to take her for some scans.
She's already gone through four shunt
revisions and they all malfunctioned.
I don't want her to have to
go through another surgery.
No, I know. I know, but let's hold
off worrying until we see the scans.
Agreed. No need to exacerbate
an already stressful situation.
Kwan, uh, why don't you get her
to radiology for a shunt series?
Okay.
Hey, big trauma coming
into the back lot.
I need everyone that
does not have a patient.
- Let's grab gowns.
- Dibs on the airway.
Chest tube.
Uh, how big? I have to leave for
the airport in a couple hours.
I'll take what I
can get. Let's go.
- Steady.
- Wow.
- What is this thing?
- Nate Ardilla, 34.
His watercraft was hit
by a container ship.
He's got crush injuries to his
pelvis and right upper extremity.
Couldn't fully extricate at the scene,
but Jaws of Life are on the way.
Easy. Easy.
Is this part of a boat?
No, it's a self-propelled
floating bubble.
- I made it myself. It's cool, right?
- That's one word for it.
Mr. Ardilla, I'm gonna need
to check your injuries, okay?
Steel rims seemed like
a good idea at the time,
but now, not so much.
You can get me out
of this, right?
Let's take a look at you.
I've been working around the
clock to keep this kid alive,
and I've got a full day in the
OR, so try not to disappoint me.
Yasuda.
Dorian Cardenas, post-op day six
from ex lap with splenectomy.
Small and large bowel
repair and ostomy creation.
In stable condition after abdominal
washout and closure today.
Keep track of his coags, acid-based
electrolytes and renal functions.
And what ventilator alarms
are we watching for?
Elevated peak and
plateau pressures.
And if only the peak
pressure alarm goes off?
Tubes dislodged, or kinking.
Which means?
Don't page me. Fix it yourself.
Wait, so you just want
us to monitor him?
Oh, you want something less boring than
keeping an entire unit of patients alive?
Including a young man recovering
from multiple gunshot wounds?
I meant you also want us to
log procedures so that we...
It's-It's good. We're
good. Thank you.
- Truce is off!
- Ow!
What the hell was that?
Don't be a smart-ass to the
person who holds all the cards.
Literally.
Um, truce back on.
What's the MRN for the chart?
I really thought I was
gonna make it this time.
- You've done this before?
- Fourth try.
- Where were you headed? Bainbridge?
- Hong Kong.
It needs to sound more impressive
than Rich Doyle's record.
He set a solo record rowing
from San Francisco to Hawaii.
Wait, Rich Doyle the,
uh, tech billionaire?
Didn't he fund that floating clinic in
Tanzania? Is he your boss or something?
My wife's ex-boyfriend.-
And to be clear, she would
say he's a non issue,
but I know she thinks
about him. I mean, I would.
I'd think every day about
what my life would be like
if I married a billionaire
adventurer rather than a pharmacist
with a 401 and ten
days of paid vacation.
Nate.
Am I almost out?
This really hurts.
It's definitely a vascular
injury in the upper extremity.
If we don't get him out of there
soon, he's gonna lose that arm.
Assuming he doesn't have
massive internal hemorrhage.
Okay, I'm ready
to get out now.
Get me out of here.
Please get me out.
Nate, Nate. Hey, hey, Nate,
look at me, look at me.
- I'm Dr. Hunt, okay?
- Uh-huh. Okay.
Now, the pressure
from these metal bars
might be the only thing
stopping you from bleeding out.
So we need to be mindful
how we get you out.
We stopped the bleeding in
your arm with the tourniquet.
Next, we need to remove
this bar from your pelvis.
Then we're gonna get you straight to an
OR, but I need you to stay still, okay?
Good.
Millin, Griffith,
put another IV.
We're gonna need a gurney
and trauma supplies.
- On it.
- Can someone call my wife? Please.
Just tell her I'm here.
But maybe don't mention the part
about the bars or the bleeding.
Yeah.
- Do you hate me?
- Sometimes.
- What? Why would you say that?
- Why would you ask me that?
Because when certain people
show up at the hospital,
I'd think you'd
give me a heads-up.
You get the hospital alerts.
Plus if we hurry, we can
probably still see him.
What are you talking about?
The insane guy with
the pedal boat.
Guy tried to paddle across the Pacific
and then he trashed his appa...
- Wait, what are you talking about?
- Well, I was talking about Nico.
- Who?
- Nico. My ex.
I saw you having a whole
conversation with him.
Why is he here?
I can't tell you.
- Because it's about me?
- Because HIPAA.
Look, I gotta go. Just
stop freaking out.
HIPAA? He's your patient?
Oh. You're in black scrubs.
Why does Nico need
an ob-gyn, Jo?
Bye.
Meredith.
- Hey.
I'm so surprised
to see you here.
Well, I could say the same
for you. Are you back already?
Physical therapy.
But I'm feeling so much better.
- Are you here for a consult?
- Uh, yeah, something like that.
No one tells me anything.
Ndugu has locked me out
of the cardio charts,
and Owen refuses to tell
me that Leo is acting up
even though I am
on the same emails.
And Richard... Well, he's telling
me that I should hang in there
even though I have offered
to help with admin.
He says that I-I need to rest.
Well, you know,
Richard's usually right.
Yeah, well, no one seems to be
minding me walking on a treadmill
for a mind-numbing hour.
I'd do it.
I no longer have time
to walk or be bored.
You should come with me.
- To PT?
- Yeah.
You can get in your
steps, I can get in mine,
and you can catch me
up on life in Boston.
- You're busy. I get it.
- Yeah.
- It's always such a pleasure to see you.
- You know what? I would love to come.
- Great.
Yes.
You were at UT Medical Center?
Is that where you
did your residency?
Nope, that was Penn. Also
where I went to medical school.
I was lured to Texas by the
promise of good weather.
Dr. Shepherd, you were in LA?
Uh, for private practice.
Residency was in Baltimore
and med school was Boston.
Just say Harvard. They think if they
say Boston it sounds less pretentious.
- Where'd you go?
- St. Kitts.
Hmm. Balmy.
- Scans are up.
- Mom was right.
Malan's shunt is
no longer working.
- We'll have to replace it.
- Well, it's not working.
She's too active, and
she's gonna keep growing.
- It's gonna keep getting disconnected.
- That's the standard of care.
But we can talk to the mom about
Malan's level of physical activity.
What about an endoscopic
ventriculostomy?
You insert a scope into
the ventricles of the brain
and create a shunt
using a balloon.
It's far less invasive, and there's
nothing to get disconnected.
No, I know what it is,
but I also know that
she is not a candidate.
She's had ventriculitis, and she
has an aberrant basilar artery.
So getting a scope in
would be near impossible.
Why don't you take
a minute then?
Excuse me?
If you can't figure
it out, take a minute.
Well, it's not about figuring it
out. The procedure won't work.
And I can explain that to
you four different ways,
but I have three other
consults, a meningioma to remove
and a research meeting.
- Ah. So, impatience is your thing.
- Should I leave?
No.
I have a colectomy
for an eight-year-old,
a Wilms' tumor consult
for a 14-year-old,
and a palliative care visit
for a baby in the NICU.
You wanna swap?
I'll tell Malan's mom you're
gonna look into another option.
He is stable and alert, but please
call back as soon as you get this.
We're already out of lap pads?
Nice hair, by the way.
Needed a change.
Yeah? What happened
with you and Adams?
We're roommates, because
apparently I'm selfish.
This is where you say, "He doesn't
know what he's talking about."
Oh, I shouldn't speak for him.
What happened with you and Kwan?
- You knew about that?
- Everyone knew about that.
You know, we don't have to do this.
We've got everything. Let's go.
You asked first.
NaCl. Right.
Dr. Wells to peds ICU.
Dr. Robin Wells to peds ICU.
They look like a nice family.
You have sisters, right?
We don't have to talk.
I know we don't have to talk,
but I was just thinking that...
Where are you going?
Uh. To do anything else.
Bailey gave us explicit
instructions to...
Sit here and do math?
Well, she also said to do
about a zillion procedures
if we ever want to set
foot in the OR again, so...
Yeah, I'ma do that.
Well, I'm not leaving him.
Well, I'm not letting Kwan get
back in the OR before I do,
so, uh, page me if he codes.
Gurney coming through.
You need to head to the airport?
No, let's just get this guy out.
- Splint looks good.
- Okay, everybody get ready.
We need a intubation tray,
- blood and bicarb on standby.
- On it.
Nate, it's time to try
extricating you now.
Okay. Everybody, on
my count. One, two...
- Wait! Wait.
- Hold up.
Tell me what happens
when you lift the bar.
We can't be
totally sure, Nate.
But we have a whole team of
people ready for almost anything.
What if I die?
What if I die without
ever getting to...
You're never getting to
Hong Kong in a bubble.
All you succeeded in doing
is taking away resources from the
coast guard when they rescued you.
Not to mention the paramedics. Not
everyone gets to go where they wanna go.
I was gonna say, "Without ever
getting to see my wife again."
I wanna talk to her.
I need to talk to her.
- Is she here?
- She didn't answer. I left a voicemail.
- We don't have much time.
- Can wait a few minutes.
Try her again.
Okay.
Dr. Kwan.
Uh, Dr. Beltran
will be back soon.
No... Malan's extremely
sensitive to hospital sounds.
Would it be possible to
get her some headphones?
The ones that block out
the noise, you know?
Sometimes the radiology
department has those.
- They don't loan those out.
- I'm sure we can find them.
If it'll make Malan more
comfortable, then it's no problem.
- Thank you so much.
- Yeah.
Uh, radiology doesn't let
those out of their sight.
- It's a thing.
- I guess you're gonna have to ask nicely.
That won't make a difference.
That woman's daughter is going
through something terrifying.
If she thinks headphones will
help, then get her headphones.
And after you do that, find
Shepherd. I need an update.
Everything okay?
These are not hospital pencils.
I bring them from home.
I've had worse habits.
Well, sometimes I
pop Bubble Wrap.
Wanna tell me what's
bothering you?
No.
This new ped surgeon is pushing me
to consider an alternate procedure
to the one that I
already know works.
Will the alternate work?
I me... It's more risk
than I'd recommend.
- But will it work?
- It's beside the point.
Are you irritated with the
suggestion or the suggester?
Beltran aggravates
a lot of people.
How do you know?
I hired her.
She was known as
a boundary pusher.
Kinda like you.
Hey.
- Levi.
- Nico. Hi.
How are you?
- Good.
- How's, uh, work going at the hospital?
You'd think a hospital vending
machine would have healthier options.
- Here.
- Ah. He doesn't like raisins.
- I know.
- They're not for me.
- Oh.
- They're for our surrogate.
He's a stickler about her diet.
Can't bring myself to think
what he's gonna feed our son.
Our kitchen's already
full of baby food gadgets.
- Oh.
- I'm Jason.
Are... Did you and
Nico work together?
Um, yeah. Yeah.
- I'm Levi.
- Nice to meet you.
Are you also in ortho?
No. No.
I'm, uh, I'm general
surgery chief resident.
- Oh, wow.
- Okay. Cool.
- Uh... We should go.
- Yeah.
Erin's probably wondering
what happened to us.
- It was nice seeing you.
- Mm-hmm.
Nice meeting you, Levon.
Levon?
I mean, it's almost
easier coming to work.
I mean, try explaining to a
four-year-old why Mommy can't carry him.
Right? And Owen has
been a champion,
but he's had extra
trauma shifts.
His mom's helping out,
but she's not really the type
to play the floor is lava.
She's more into giving them a
snack and turning on the TV.
I remember during COVID, a
very smart doctor once told me
to get some rest and ask
for help when I needed it.
Look at you throwing
my words back at me.
How's Boston?
- Oh!
- Teddy!
Teddy, are you okay?
Dr. Lincoln said to tell
you he's scrubbing in.
- Millin's helping him prep.
- Is Jessica on her way?
- She's still not answering.
- He's getting more hypotensive.
Nate, the longer
you're up here,
the more likely you are
to have a complication.
If you wanna give yourself the best
shot at seeing your wife again,
we should go now.
Tell me. Whatever you wanna
say to her, say it to me.
I'll tell her as
soon as she arrives.
I love her.
That's all that matters.
I love her so much.
Everything I do is for her.
All of this was for her.
I know she married me and not Rich,
but I want her to be proud of me.
Tell her that I
know she has doubts,
and I don't want her to spend
another second of her life
questioning her choosing me.
Tell her that I'll never give
up trying to do right by her.
- I will.
- Okay.
Okay then. I'm ready.
Okay.
Okay. On my count.
One, two, three.
Okay, he's bleeding out.
Prepare to intubate. Come
on, come on, come on.
- Hang two units of blood.
- Let's go. Get him on the gurney.
Okay, let's pack the
wound and apply pressure.
Let's make sure we have
a clear path to the OR.
He's not gonna make it to
the OR. Give me your shears.
Bring me a REBOA.
We'll slow the bleeding,
and it'll buy us some
time to transport.
Come on, Nate. Come on. Stay
with me now. Stay with me.
All right. Glove me. Let's
go, let's go, let's go.
Stay with us, Nate. Come on now.
He didn't know who I was.
You guys dated for a really
long time. He's faking.
Not Nico. Jason.
They live together.
They're having a baby.
Surely they've discussed...
You?
Significant prior relationships.
It's like I didn't exist.
Do you wanna get back
together with Nico?
I'm not sure I know him anymore.
He never talked about kids
when we were together.
He didn't even want
a fake Sims family.
But apparently it's
different with Jason.
You haven't mentioned Nico in months,
and now all of a sudden you're all,
"Oh, why didn't he
do that with me?"
I don't sound like that.
- Well...
- And I don't wanna get back together.
- I...
- Okay.
Then you're just upset that his life
has moved further along than yours.
I am?
He is living with someone.
They're having a kid together.
You've barely dated.
You're living in a
loft with your coworker
with a twin sheet hanging
between your beds for privacy.
You really do hate me.
No, I'm just...
There are two main reasons
that people get upset
when they run into an ex.
And yours is, "I
am losing at life."
- Are you trying to make this worse?
- I'm just saying.
You talk about wanting to meet someone,
and you deleted your dating apps.
You talk about wanting to get into peds,
and you haven't turned in the application.
You wanna win?
Get in the game.
Finally.
You do know we were
waiting for you, right?
You told me to take a minute.
- All right. Show us what you got.
- Okay. As you can see,
Malan's aberrant basilar artery at
the floor of the third ventricle
is a huge problem.
And why is that, Dr. Kwan?
Because in order to insert the
sheath into the third ventricle...
No, no, no. Start again but like
you're explaining it to a parent.
Malan has a blood vessel
that is blocking the way,
which would make it difficult to
pass the balloon into that area
to create the shunt.
Now, difficult is
an understatement.
The vessel is positioned such
that a fraction of a
millimeter left or right
could result in major
bleeding, stroke or worse.
But you've found an
alternative route?
No... ...but we might be able
to combine this computer system
with the intraoperative imaging technology
that we use for mapping brain tumors.
We would program it to provide us with a
real-time guide, with ultra precision in the OR.
So it's like a GPS system of Malan's brain
to make sure you're on the right path?
The safest path.
- And she wouldn't need a VP shunt.
- Hmm.
- How long would it take you to build this technology?
- Me? Forever.
But I talked to our tech team
and they have it working now.
I would be willing to try it
if the mom agrees.
What are you thinking?
I'm thinking you're
much more effective
when you take your time.
Find another elevator!
We have a trauma coming!
Move out! Make way
for the gurney!
Either hug the wall or
get out of the hall!
- We found his wife yet?
- Not yet.
- Let's try again.
- Yeah.
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
- You take over pressure?
- Yep.
Type and cross him. Let's
get the blood cooler in here.
Let's raise the temp in this
room and find this man's wife.
Gown and glove me.
No time to scrub.
All right. On three.
One, two... ...three.
Let's get this wet
suit off of him now.
Let's run a TEG.
Somebody find his wife.
Let's go, let's go.
Yeah. "Small dark lesions of
the lips and oral mucosa."
Abdominal pain.
CT scan shows small bowel
mass with concentric rings.
"What is the most likely cause:
Intestinal lipoma or hamartomatous polyp?"
Thoughts?
Dorian?
Oh. Is your tube dislodged?
Hey, don't be embarrassed.
It happens to the best of us.
Oh, no. Wait, no,
no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no,
no, no, no. Dorian?
Hey, I-I need help in here.
It's just a bad sprain.
It can't hurt to take a look.
Injured during PT? I'm a cliché.
All right.
- All right.
- Okay.
Oh, crap.
What happened? Are you okay?
Oh, I'm fine. I just misstepped.
Take it easy.
Dr. Grey, I didn't
know you were in town.
Well, it's just a quick trip.
For a consult?
Yeah. I-I asked her, uh,
for a second opinion on
one of my old patients.
And you had that thing
with the house, right?
Yes. Uh... Insurance issues.
Well, it's always
good to have you here.
And I am really looking forward to hearing
the update on your research next month.
- Take care, Altman.
- Thank you.
So it's probably nothing, but
we should have it x-rayed.
I'm gonna have to run. I can have
a nurse take you to radiology.
I'm good. But I do wanna hear
why you're actually here.
I see multiple serosal tears.
Would you rather marry a
soulless tech millionaire
or the eccentric pharmacist?
Neither.
No, you have to pick one.
Lap pads.
We have an expanding
retroperitoneal...
I don't have that much
tension with my roommates.
Your roommate is a hundred.
Maxine is a young 82.
- Levi.
- Hey.
- You're still here.
- Uh, yeah.
Erin might have
gestational diabetes,
so they're testing her.
How far along is she?
Twenty-three weeks.
- Have you picked a name?
- Yeah.
Levon.
Really?
- No, I'm just kidding.
- Okay.
Hey, I'm sorry about earlier.
I corrected him in the elevator.
He felt awful about it.
He seems nice.
Have you been together long?
- Nine months.
- Oh.
If he had in his dating profile
that he was in the process
of interviewing surrogates, I
probably wouldn't have swiped.
When he told me, I freaked out.
I literally snuck out the back at
Parkside Pizza in the middle of dinner.
You left the pizza?
I was really freaked out.
I think I never realized
that I wanted to be a dad.
Maybe I felt that I
wasn't ready for it,
but Jason knew all along
that he wanted to have kids.
And the thought of not
having him in my life...
I...
I've never met anyone
in my life like him.
He sees light in everything.
And these days no
one does, you know?
Losing him just seemed a lot scarier than
the idea of having a family with him.
So.
Here we are.
I'm happy for you.
Good luck.
Thanks.
- You too.
- Hmm.
Just so I'm clear...
You told the woman
whose name is on the
building of where you work
that you stopped doing
research at her request,
- but you're still doing it?
- Trying to.
I am bored at home,
and you are living in... in,
like, a medical thriller book.
And no one else knows?
- Except Amelia.
- Amelia?
We're not actually...
in a medical thriller.
It's just so bold and exciting.
- And about to be over.
- You found a cure?
I might still be in
a medical thriller.
No, we, um...
We have no money.
We had a plan and
it fell through.
Was it Seagrade Tech? They are
pulling back on everything.
No, actually, and it doesn't
even matter who we ask
because that's the problem
with secret research.
Everybody wants
to talk about it.
- Well, I wouldn't.
- You wouldn't what?
Talk about it. Not that I have many
people to talk to these days. Thanks.
Listen, Grey-Sloan has
a discretionary fund.
It wouldn't be enough to
fund your whole project,
but you could publish an initial
report, and that would open more doors.
You would do that?
But... I mean,
don't you have to say where the
money is going? What about Catherine?
A breakthrough in an Alzheimer's cure
would go down in medical history,
like a smallpox
vaccine or antibiotics.
You just have to get far enough along
that she couldn't deny its value,
and I'm willing to
take that risk on you.
- Oh. You go ahead.
- Um, you go.
Really, it's okay.
I will grab another one.
Okay.
Dr. Shepherd, Dr. Beltran.
I know I can't scrub
in, but can I observe?
- Sit with her mother.
- You're letting her mom watch the surgery?
No.
Oh.
Maybe we should let him watch.
Even if it's just
from the gallery.
I don't do this
surgery very often.
He's on my service. You can let
him watch when he's on yours.
Where have you been?
Peak and plateau alarms
are both going off.
- You checked for obstructions?
- I did. It's clear.
And that wouldn't explain
elevated plateau pressure.
Uh... BP's plummeting.
Should we start pressors?
Low urine output, elevated
peak and plateau pressures,
low BP, increased
bladder pressure.
It's abdominal
compartment syndrome.
Are you sure he's not
bleeding out somewhere?
We need a cut down tray.
Don't let him die
while I'm gone.
Come on. Stay with me, Dorian.
Okay, if you pulled me out of
the OR for a dislodged tube...
I think it's abdominal
compartment syndrome.
Uh, low urine output, uh, elevated
peak and plateau pressures,
BP falling, increased
bladder pressure.
Should I book an OR?
No. He'll die before
he gets there.
We need to open
him up right here.
Crash cart!
Well, thank you for joining us, Yasuda.
Sorry if we're interrupting your break.
- Oh, no. Dr. Bailey, I was just asking...
- Not now, Yasuda.
Adams, gown and glove.
♪ I am always on your side ♪
Okay.
More lap pads.
I need suction.
♪ I am always on your side ♪
♪ When all of the voices
Are getting louder ♪
♪ And it feels like hope
Is a fading flower ♪
He's crashing.
Starting compressions.
Come on, Nate.
- Come on, Nate.
- Come on, come on, come on.
♪ Just keep holding on ♪
♪ It's only time ♪
♪ I'm on your side I'm on ♪
♪ Just keep holding on ♪
♪ It's only time ♪
♪ I'm on your side I'm on ♪
Time of death: 18:45.
♪ I am always on your side ♪
Is... Is she...
- Is my... Is my baby...
- She's okay.
We will need to monitor her,
but we were able
to create a space
for the fluid to drain without
putting in a new shunt.
- And the old shunt?
- I removed it.
- She'll be able to go back to Capoeira without it.
- Thank you.
- After she recovers, of course.
- Okay.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
I mean, all of you.
Thank you. Really.
Can... Can I see her?
- Dr. Kwan, can you...
- Absolutely.
You two are a wonderful team.
♪ We were warm enough ♪
Hmm. That was pretty great.
♪ Such a long time ♪
♪ A new dawn breaks ♪
- Mrs. Ardilla?
- Hey.
I'm Dr. Ndugu. This is
Dr. Hunt, Dr. Griffith.
We were part of the team
that cared for your husband.
We are so sorry.
No. Please...
Please don't say...
Once we removed the bars from his
watercraft, he started to bleed.
We rushed him to the operating
room, but it was too late.
We did everything in our
power to save your husband.
No. No, that's not...
that's not possible.
You know, I-I'm... I'm making
salmon and rice for dinner.
Uh, he's supposed to come home.
Like, he always sets
sail in the morning
and then... and then by
lunchtime something's gone wrong
and he... and he comes home.
He always comes home.
You know, I spent all this time
calling him ridiculous and paranoid
when I should've just been
telling him that I loved him.
You know, I've-I've
always loved him.
I didn't want Rich Doyle.
I've-I've always wanted Nate.
I-I should've done something.
I-I should've convinced him that...
that all that mattered was us.
And it's all my fault.
It's... It's all my
fault that he's gone.
No. No.
He knew.
He knew that you
loved him. He told me.
He said the floating to
Hong Kong in the bubble,
none of that was about you.
He wanted to prove to
himself he could do it.
And he told me if
he didn't make it
to tell you that he
loved you so much.
It's no one's fault.
He loved you.
You loved him.
That's what matters.
♪ Broken arrows ♪
♪ Conscience narrows ♪
Dr. Beltran, I finished
inputting your progress notes.
I need another post-op
check on Clayton Yung.
Okay.
Yale.
I went to Yale.
Almost a full year.
And then my mom got sick, I moved home
and then one thing led to another.
Look, I-I may not have
the fancy pedigree,
but I can assure you I am a quick study,
I work hard and I aim to be the best.
When you're not
suspended from the OR.
I am capable of more than
hand-holding a patient's mom.
If you think that
assignment was punitive
because of where you were
educated, you're wrong.
It wasn't punitive?
Of course it was.
Do you know who really saved Malan
from severe complications today?
Dr. Shepherd. You.
You and Dr. Shepherd?
Malan's mom knew that something
was wrong and brought her here.
Whether they have a medical
degree or not, moms know.
You never bet against them.
I don't care where
you went to school.
What matters is how you treat
patients, and in peds, their families.
I'm gonna need you to understand that if
you're gonna be on my service tomorrow.
Well, they don't make the
assignments until the morning.
I requested you.
See you tomorrow, Dr. Kwan.
Rough day.
I was going to the airport
because I was supposed
to meet Maggie.
But she canceled on me.
And then I took it out on
a patient, and he died.
We did everything
we could, Winston.
And we both knew
from the second we saw
those bars crushing him
this was never going
to be an easy case.
I'm sorry about Maggie.
We were supposed to talk
about what's next for us.
Just like we were supposed to do
last week and the week before.
But there's always a
consult, or a class, paper.
At what point do I stop trying?
I'm not sure there's a good
answer to that question,
but maybe the better
question is, "Why?"
Why are you trying?
That might tell you
what you need to know.
Good night.
That ex lap was mine.
Hey!
I made the diagnosis.
You didn't even
know what it was.
Is there a rule that says
the person who makes the
diagnosis does the procedure?
- Not that I know of.
- Shut up!
I was trying to be a
good friend to you,
and you repaid me
by lying to Bailey?
- I didn't tell her anything.
- Exactly.
You could've told her I was
looking for the cut down tray
or that I sat by Dorian's bedside
all day like she told us to
while you went looking
for procedures!
Maybe give him a chance to
explain before you rip into him.
He sharked me. No explanation.
It's his fault that we're all stuck
in the ICU and not in the OR anyway.
You know? And why are
you defending him?
- He was a jerk to you too.
- All right. Stop! Just stop.
I'm tired of the blame
and the finger-pointing.
It is all our faults.
I was there too. So were you.
Kwan didn't do us any favors.
We all screwed up.
There's nothing we can do except
put it behind us and move on.
We are all trying.
Why can't you?
I'm done. I don't wanna
be your friend anymore.
Find another way home.
Progress doesn't
happen overnight.
And setbacks are
all but inevitable.
I need a drink.
Yeah, me too.
Your idea. You're buying.
Sometimes it can make
you feel like Sisyphus...
Let's go.
endlessly pushing the same
boulder up the same hill.
- Okay.
- Dr. Beltran. I'm Levi Schmitt.
Oh. Are you the person I talk
to about assigned parking?
Um, no. I'm chief resident.
I'm applying for
a peds fellowship.
I-I wanted to see if I could
maybe buy you coffee sometime.
Pick your brain.
I can't right now.
But can you still help me
with that parking pass?
But where would we be if
Dr. Starzl hadn't persevered
to perfect the
liver transplant...
Ah.
If he had let the setbacks win?
Johnny?
Jaden. Jared? Jaden?
Can I, uh, please
have another one?
And her too.
It's his card, okay? Thank you.
As tempting as it can be
to throw in the towel...
♪ And I wanna feel My knees... ♪
♪ On a land you would reveal ♪
sometimes you have to take
the obstacles as they come...
♪ Fade under the veil ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
Hey. I got your text.
What's happening?
We have to keep going.
How many of these have you had?
Maybe one too many.
But I still don't
think we should quit.
Look, I know that it is gonna be
hard for us to find the money,
but what if we
could find a cure?
We gotta keep trying.
I'm happy to hear you
say that because I think
I may have found us some money.
So, I just left Teddy...
♪ The trickles we hoped in ♪
♪ Decided our fortune ♪
♪ I'm needing changes ♪
Lucas, you awake?
Can we talk? ♪ I feel
the changes coming ♪
Lucas?
♪ It's coming ♪
♪ I feel the changes coming ♪
♪ Coming ♪
and find a new path forward.
♪ Mmm, mmm ♪
♪ Mm-mmm ♪