Jessica.
Jessica. Come on. We gotta go.
- Move it or lose it, sister.
- I don't feel good.
Mmm. You don't feel
warm. My stomach hurts.
- Well, honey, if you
don't have a fever— - I
don't wanna go to school.
I can do my work at home.
Jessica, what's wrong?
Everybody hates me.
Oh, they don't hate you.
They don't even know you
because they're too ignorant to try.
I hate myself.
Jessica, don't say that.
Oh, honey. Look
at me. Look at me.
You are a wonderful,
beautiful little girl.
Don't let a few bad apples—
A few? Try my whole class.
Remember the story where the guy keeps
saying that he hates green eggs and ham?
And then at the end he
realized he really loved them?
One day, they're gonna realize
what a great kid you really are.
You just gotta be like
Sam-I-Am. And don't give up.
Okay.
That's it. Keep goin'.
Good. Nice. You're doin ‘great,
Jessica. You're doin ‘great.
Hey. Hey, Seth.
- You wanna spend the rest of class
sittin' on the bench?
- No.
Keep goin', Jess. You
got 40 more seconds.
My arm hurts. Come on. Tough
it up. You can do it. You can do it.
- My chest hurts.
- How do you think the ground feels?
Hey, Seth. Two laps. Bye.
Hey, Jess. It's just a stitch. Okay?
Just... keep breathin'. You got it.
I can't.
Only 10 more
seconds. You got it.
Jessica? Jessica?
Jessica!
Oh, my God. Hey, go to the
office. Get Miss Parsons. Now!
I'm on the playground at Finley
Elementary. One of my
students is havin' a heart attack.
Yeah, she's 10. Don't you think I know
that? Just send the damn ambulance.
Come on. Wake up.
Come on, sweetie.
Dr. Bender, call extension 2870.
You ever seen an
infected pierced scrotum?
Um, no, but I know a few people on whom
I'd like to see it happen. We need to talk.
Well, if pain's what you're after,
the penis is really the way to go.
- I'd recommend the apadravya.
- We're not talking.
Oh. It sounded like we were.
No, you're attempting to avoid talking
because you know what I wanna talk about.
Nipples? You need to get
rid of one of your people.
Absolutely. As soon as I
do performance reviews.
And then review the
reviews, of course.
A decision like this can't be made
without proper, you know, review.
Shouldn't take longer
than a month, maybe two.
Four at the most, unless
it gets complicated.
There's no way outta this.
You might as well get it over with as fast
as you can, like ripping off a Band-Aid.
Only instead of a two-cent piece of
tape and gauze, it's a human being.
- Like you care.
- Like you don't.
You have a week. Get it done.
We have a referral
from Dr. Lenkiewicz.
- Don't know him.
- He knows you.
- What's the problem?
- Heart attack.
- Definitely don't know him.
- The patient's 10.
Ten-year-olds do not have heart
attacks. It's gotta be a mistake.
Right. Simplest explanation is she's
a 40-year-old lying about her age.
Maybe an actress trying to hang on.
I meant maybe the tests were wrong.
That's what the E.R. thought.
Three C.K.-M.B.'s were positive.
The E.K.G. shows classic signs
of S.T. elevation. It's a heart attack.
She's morbidly obese. The
"morbid" part of that raises alarms.
Come on. It takes decades to
eat your way into a heart attack.
Doesn't take decades to
kill yourself. If I was that fat,
I'd be pretty tempted to
knock back a bottle of pills.
It's not a drug overdose.
The fatigue, muscle pain and
difficulty concentrating have
been bothering her for over a year.
That's because of her
weight, her depression.
That's what five pediatricians, two
nutritionists and a psychologist said.
The heart attack would seem to
indicate that they missed something.
- It's gotta be something genetic.
- What about metabolic syndrome "X"?
Insulin resistance?
Syndrome "X" could cause a stroke.
I don't know about a heart attack.
It could, if her blood
pressure was high enough.
Which is likely,
considering her weight.
Fits the symptoms. Me likee. Do a
hyperinsulinemic euglycemic clamp.
Oh, and one more thing.
I've been told that I gotta get rid of
one of you guys by the end of the week.
New sheriff. Belt tightening.
You know how it goes.
Okay. Carry on.
Some kind of game.
House's own version of Punk'd.
It's not House. It's Vogler.
We can't let it get to us.
We've gotta stick together. Why?
Are you suggesting we start
slashing each other's throats?
I'm suggesting it's a
zero-sum game. Your loss
is my win. That's not
conducive to team play.
Which is what House seems
to want. Look, I'm with Cameron.
It may be a bad strategy, but I don't
wanna give House that satisfaction.
Come on. Sick kid, remember?
She's diabetic?
No, but it's similar.
M.S.X. patients don't
respond normally to insulin,
which causes their
body to create too much,
and that leads to
metabolic abnormalities.
We're going to do a test to be
sure, but there are certain dangers.
Is this... thing treatable?
It's controllable through
proper diet and exercise.
Wait. Jessica already eats
right, and she exercises every day.
I know you've already
seen several nutritionists...
- And we've done everything
they've recommended.
- I understand, but...
Why can't any of you
doctors see past her weight?
If diet and exercise are the
treatment, then the diagnosis is wrong.
It might be. But the only way we'll
know is if you let us do this test.
It's really bad, especially at night. It's
like my heart is on fire. Like it's, um...
Oh, I don't know. Like, uh...
Burning? Exactly.
Hmm, sounds almost
like... heartburn.
So, can you give me
somethin'? Like a thesaurus?
What? I take it you never mentioned
this during any of your prenatal visits.
Prenatal?
I'm not pregnant.
Sorry, you don't get to make that call
unless you have a stethoscope. Union rules.
I know when I'm pregnant,
all right? I have six kids.
That's why my husband had a
vasectomy, and we use condoms.
Vasectomies can reverse
themselves. Condoms break.
Okay. This... is what a
woman is supposed to look like.
Okay? We're not
just skin and bones.
We have... flesh.
We have... curves.
You have little
people inside you.
Okay, okay.
I'm sorry. I guess I must have just
been brainwashed by the media...
and all those years
of medical training.
- Damn right.
- I'll see if I can find some antacids
while the nurse gets some blood.
Blood? Why?
The heartburn. Gotta make
sure it's not... spreading.
I don't want to.
The test involves some
pretty precise measurements.
If we don't know exactly how much
you weigh, we won't get the right answers.
Let me tell you a secret. When
I was your age, I was heavy too.
Were you over a hundred?
Way over. Kids in my
neighborhood used to call me "Rerun."
Rerun? He was a heavy guy from TV. I—I
used to pretend I liked it, but I didn't.
How come you're
not heavy anymore?
Ninth grade, grew five inches.
Everything kind of evened out.
You think that'll happen
to me? Well, yeah.
Your mom's tall, and you are a little short
for your age. Probably spring right up.
Obesity isn't something
you just grow out of.
I take it you've never seen a
baby? She's not a baby. She's 10.
And you figure making her feel like
crap would do her a world of good?
- Yeah, if it gets her off the couch.
- I'm sure she's already
under enough pressure.
Not from Mummy. Everything in society tells
us we have to be thin to be successful.
No. Society tells you you have to be
thin to be attractive. And guess what?
That's what attractive means,
that society likes looking at you.
I think we should be telling our kids it's
fine as long as they're healthy. Right.
You weigh 90 pounds
because it makes you healthier?
Forget it. He's just cranky because he
knows he's the one who's gonna get the ax.
So, any thoughts?
On what? Sharon's plan for Gaza?
Who you gonna let go?
I'm thinking I can convince Vogler
it would be more cost-efficient
to keep all of them. Yeah, you
should be able to pull that off.
Most billionaires aren't
very good with numbers.
It will be more
cost-efficient once I grab
Cameron's ass, call
Foreman a spade, and Chase...
Well, I'll grab his ass too.
You are uniquely talented in many areas,
but office politics is not one of them.
Don't take Vogler on.
- Separate or together?
- Together.
Increasing glucose to
6.9 milligrams per minute.
- Are you okay?
- I'm thirsty.
- Just a little bit longer,
and you'll be done.
- Like Dr. Chase.
Wanna put some money on it?
I said I'm thirsty. Just
five more minutes.
Okay, sweetheart? I'm not your
sweetheart. Don't call me that.
- Jessica, that's not nice.
- They're the ones who aren't nice.
Jessica. You're not, either. I
don't wanna do this anymore.
Jessica. Jessica, you
have to calm down. No! No!
Let me go.
Check her blood sugar. She's
gotta be getting hypoglycemic.
I've never seen her like this
before. Something's wrong.
Let go of me! Get it out of me!
Let go of me, you son
of a bitch! You bastard!
Oh, no.
She's sedated. Mrs.
Simms, don't worry.
Hypoglycemia can cause
temporary psychosis and is
a common complication
during an CH.E. procedure.
I never wanted it
done in the first place.
We understand you're upset— You were
supposed to be monitoring her condition,
but instead you were
bickering and placing bets.
I apologize if it looked
like we weren't devoting our
full attention to your
daughter, but I assure you...
Oh, please. Save your pathetic
insincerity for your boyfriend.
You're wrong. She is, in fact, pathetically
sincere. And they didn't screw it up.
- Who are you?
- I'm from the lab.
The blood tests show your
daughter was not hypoglycemic, which
means her psychosis wasn't
caused by anything these doctors did.
- So then what was it caused by?
- I've no idea.
Huh. But you’ll be happy to hear it
cannot be cured by diet or exercise.
What else could cause
uncontrollable rage in a 10-year-old?
Nothing that could also
cause a heart attack.
I assume I don't have to point out that
now would be an extremely good time...
for one of you to distinguish
yourself with a brilliant idea.
A hypercoagulable state
can cause a blood clot.
- Blood clots can cause a heart attack.
- More likely to cause a stroke,
not the psychosis.
No, you're wrong. If a clot
made it to the amygdala
area of the brain, it might
cause uncontrollable rage.
Right, because anything's
possible, but nothing's
gonna cause multiple
clots in a kid this age.
- She's fat.
- Obesity doesn't cause blood clots.
Extremely obese patients
can get a fat embolus.
Right, after they've had liposuction,
which she's clearly never had.
- How do you know?
- Because we have her medical records,
and because no plastic
surgeon in his right
mind is gonna give a
10-year-old liposuction.
Have you ever met a plastic
surgeon who was in their right mind?
- She hasn't had liposuction.
- Thank you.
But what about some other
ridiculous obesity treatment?
Like what? Diet pills can cause
heart attacks and blood clots.
- Her tox screen was negative.
- Wouldn't show over-the-counter
weight loss drugs.
Her mother wouldn't
give her diet pills. She
thinks her daughter's
perfect just the way she is.
She's lying.
Okay. You two, heparin and
warfarin to prevent further clotting.
And you find those pills.
Not diet pills.
You might wanna broaden
the search just a little.
And don’t just ask the mom.
If she hasn't mentioned
it yet, she's not— If
you’re gonna fire someone,
go ahead and do it.
But don't treat us like
lab rats, testing how
long it takes to get us
at one another's throats.
- So what should I do?
- I don't give a damn what you do.
Yes, I had noticed your
complete indifference.
You don't even offer a
medical opinion anymore.
- Who would you fire?
- Not my call.
I want your opinion.
Fine, it's you.
Either way, you're
making a choice.
Chase.
- Because he screwed up an angio
a month ago?
- Anyone can make a mistake.
Right. So it's the
money. You resent it, but
you're gonna tell me that
he doesn't need the job.
He doesn't appreciate the job.
He was ready to go three
rounds with Cameron for it.
He wants the job. He
just doesn't appreciate it.
There's nothing wrong
with just wanting to
hang out, but this is
not the place to do it.
- I'm surprised.
- You thought I'd pick Cameron?
I didn't think
you'd pick at all.
Guess he's not the "rise above the
fray" guy he'd like us to think he is.
You practically
forced it out of him.
He's scared of losing his
job, just like everybody else.
I've been thinking. You've made it
quite clear that you're miserable here.
I am not miserable.
You're not happy.
And you are? With my job, yes.
I am exactly where I wanna be,
doing exactly what I wanna do.
Think I sense a hint
of sarcasm there.
Why don't you pick yourself?
Quit? Hmm, I was wrong.
About Vogler or Foreman?
Mrs. Hernandez's pregnancy test.
Who's Mrs. Hernandez?
Either a woman carrying
an alien baby or
your newest patient.
So you never saw her with any
pills. She never mentioned anything?
No, of course not.
Would it be all right if I, uh,
talk to a couple of her friends?
Her friends? I'm not
gonna interrogate them.
I just wanna ask if Jessica
ever mentioned anything.
It's—It's pretty important.
She's very sick.
I understand. It's just, well...
Jessica really doesn't
have any friends.
Not one? I've tried to help,
make the kids include her
more, but... kids can be...
- Kids?
- I was gonna say jerks.
All the fifth-graders are
assigned an eighth-grade buddy.
Maybe you could talk to hers.
What's the status on House?
He asked for time to complete performance
reviews for everyone in his department.
And you told him no
and gave him how long?
A week. He'll do it.
Guy's never done what he's told. I
don't see why he's gonna start now.
Hi. Edward Vogler.
Is Dr. House claiming that I'm
forcing him to get rid of one of you?
I assume his goal is to stir
up antagonism toward me.
- And your goal is?
- I am forcing him.
I'll do whatever I can to ease the
transition for whoever he chooses.
- If you're feeling guilty about your decision,
there is an easy solution.
- I don't feel guilty.
Then... why approach
me and tell me all this?
I don't feel guilty. That
doesn't mean I don't feel bad.
I'm rich, but I'm still human.
I just wanted you to know...
that if there's anything I can
do for you, my door's open.
Thank you.
You're lookin' for info? Thought
you already had House all figured out.
I do. Don't know
his team though.
The ultrasound and
biopsy confirmed our worry.
The tumor is extremely
large, at least 30 pounds.
Oh, God. It's actually a
personal record for this clinic.
But it's completely benign.
There's no sign of cancer at all.
I've already spoken with Dr. Bergin, and
he's available first thing in the morning.
For what?
For the surgery.
But if it's not cancer,
it can't kill me, right?
Mmm, no. I'll have a huge scar.
I won't be able
to wear a bikini.
- You wear a bikini now?
- Yeah. You got a problem with that?
Nope. But I've never
gone swimming with you.
I knew it. That's
what this is all about.
You are trying to force me
to have cosmetic surgery.
Yeah, that's exactly why I planted
a 30-pound tumor on your ovary.
It's not gonna kill
me. The only thing
surgery is gonna do is
change the way I look.
That is the definition
of cosmetic surgery.
Uh, it would also relieve
your heartburn and discomfort.
Yeah, right. Why give an antacid
if you can cut someone up...
and make them a little
easier on your eyes?
My husband... loves my
body. He can't get enough of it.
You think he's gonna wanna touch me if
I look like I've been gutted like a fish?
That was unexpected.
Yeah, it was.
All she does during recess is
run laps around the playground.
She says she's exercising,
but everyone knows
it's just because no one
wants to play with her.
I mean, I'm only her buddy because
Ms. Ayers assigned her to me.
That does not
mean I am her friend.
I'll make sure her doctors
are all clear on that.
Thanks.
So, has she ever said
anything to you about diet pills?
- Ha. She told you that too?
- What do you mean?
I totally busted her for
taking drugs one day.
She totally lied, said that they
were diet pills her mom had given her.
Come on. Get real. No way a
girl like that is taking diet pills.
I didn't give her diet
pills. I would never do that.
Right. So it was
her imaginary mom.
She didn't take any
pills. The girl's lying.
Why would she lie? Because
she's another mean little jerk.
- Mom.
- I'm sorry, honey.
Clemmie didn't lie.
I did. I took the pills.
I told her you gave them to me
because I didn't wanna get in trouble.
Where did you get them?
I took them from the store.
Why? Why would you do that?
Because I didn't
wanna be ugly anymore.
- Oh, baby. You're not ugly.
- Yes, I am.
I know you don't think
so, but I am. I'm disgusting.
Jessica, please don't say that.
I just—I just wanted to fit in.
You know, have friends?
Or at least have one
person my age be nice to me.
Oh.
Listen, the, uh...
The pills cause blood clots,
heart attacks and insomnia.
It explains everything. We'll
keep her overnight to make sure,
but, uh, she'll be fine.
Thank you.
I can't believe she
was that desperate.
Yeah, I'm sure that if
everyone I knew hated me,
couldn't bear to look at me, I
wouldn't go so far as to shoplift.
I'm not talking about
the shoplifting. I'm
sure she didn't even
know they were dangerous.
She probably saw them
advertised on TV or over the Internet.
Right. So I guess it's the media and
pharmaceutical companies' fault now,
not the fact that she can't stop
shoveling food down her throat.
No one forced her to get fat.
- No one forced a cancer patient
to get cancer.
- Give me a break. It's not a disease.
Have you seen the latest
research? Yes, I have.
What I haven't seen lately is a
kid eating an apple or riding a bike.
You Americans can't even compete with the
rest of the world in basketball anymore,
unless, of course, it's the type you play
with a remote control on a big-screen TV.
- Right.
- Wait, wait, wait.
Are you gonna let him say that?
He insulted our basketball teams.
Oh, my God.
It hurts so bad. Please.
What happened?
- She's bleeding.
- From where?
Oh, my gosh.
Just please stop it. Please!
Diet pills brought her to
us. We gave her the sores.
You think she got a staph
infection from something here?
I'm not saying the hospital gave her the
sores. I'm saying we did, by treating her.
Warfarin-induced skin necrosis.
- Highly unlikely. We started her
on heparin before the warfarin.
- Who gave her the heparin?
- I did warfarin. She did heparin.
- Sure you didn't both give her warfarin?
Yes. I did not screw up.
Did you actually see her prepare
and administer the heparin?
'Nuff said.
You were standing right there.
I was preparing my own dose.
Yeah, right. There's
gotta be some other cause.
None that I can think of.
Let's fix the mistake.
Give her unfractionated I.
V. heparin and low molecular
weight heparin by
subcutaneous injection, stat.
Making me look bad is
not gonna save your job.
You think you're incapable
of making a mistake?
You think that I'm just
gonna roll over and take this?
House isn't gonna protect you
just because you kiss his ass.
Vogler wants to know
what he can do for me.
Hey! Stop worrying about your asses
and start worrying about the patient's.
She sleeping?
As a result of the sedatives, yeah.
Can't let her wake up. Too much pain.
"Warfarin-induced
skin necrosis."
I... have no idea
what that means.
But it says here we
gave her the warfarin.
And I do know what
"induced" means. We did this?
At this point, it's
not exactly clear.
You should probably
talk to Dr. House.
Oh. You two need time
to get your stories straight.
He doesn't tell me what to do.
So you don't just blindly follow his
commands. You're your own man.
And yet here you are, working
for a guy you can't stand.
I respect him. What
exactly is it you respect?
His attitude toward humanity?
He thinks we're all idiots and liars.
How about his attitude toward you? Plays
with you like a cat with a ball of string.
What do you want? I wanna
know if you wanna keep your job.
If he chooses to let me
go, I can live with that.
- That's not an answer.
- Are you offering to protect me?
- Still not an answer.
- I want my job.
Dr. Chase. Boss.
What was that about? He wanted to
know what warfarin is. I don't know.
Brr. Icy.
I'll definitely think twice before
correcting one of your mistakes again.
Correct all you
want. Course, it's a bit
more productive if
there's an actual mistake.
Right. I always
forget that part.
I gave her the heparin, which means the
necrosis is not a reaction to the warfarin,
which is probably why she's not
responding to your treatment. Yet.
If you didn't screw
up, then what is it?
You don't have an answer. Yet.
When you come up with
something, let me know.
I'll be in the
clinic, warming up.
I'm the only one who's always stood
behind you when you've screwed up.
Why? Why would you support
someone who screws up?
Because I'm not insanely
insecure, and because
I can actually trust in
another human being,
and I am not an angry,
misanthropic son of a bitch.
I'm sorry. You said
you weren't angry.
Who would you fire?
No one.
Not an option.
If everyone took a pay
cut and put in a few more
hours, we could all stay for
the same amount of money.
Figures you'd try and come up with
a solution where no one gets hurt.
The problem is, the world doesn't
work that way just 'cause you want it to.
Figures you'd stall and
refuse to deal with the issue.
Problem is, the world doesn't go
away just because you want it to.
Excuse me. Dr. House?
My wife saw you yesterday.
Lucille Hernandez?
Uh, he's not in today.
My wife said he
walked with a cane.
He's also got a bit of a drug problem.
Sometimes doesn't show up for weeks.
The M.R.I.'s are
rented, but, um—
Did you make a decision?
He's not gonna fire anybody.
Yes. I'm gonna cut
the pay of all four of us.
Seventeen percent
across the board will allow
you to keep us all for the
same amount of money.
I believe it's what you
suits call a "win-win".
All right, uh, i-if you can— No.
If he can work it so we keep the current
staff for the same amount of money,
what difference does it make?
It's not about the money.
This is not a
negotiation. It never was.
I need to know that
whatever I ask you to do,
however distasteful
you find it, you'll do it.
And just as importantly,
you need to know that.
What's going on with my wife?
Even if I was Dr. House,
physician-patient confidentiality
protects me from annoying conversations.
She told me about the
tumor. Yeah? She also
tell you why she's
refusing to have it removed?
I don't care about a scar. And she
can always gain the weight back.
- You want her to regain the weight?
- Yeah. I mean, only if she wants to.
Why? I've always thought she
looked sexiest when she was pregnant.
Something about knowing
she's a mother just makes
me want to— Tell her
that and leave me alone.
I did. You gotta talk to her. I couldn't
bear it if something happened to her.
The tumor is benign. Nothing's gonna
happen, except maybe some more heartburn.
What if it gets even
bigger, or it changes?
You know where to find us.
Building's not going anywhere.
Tell her it's cancer.
You obviously don't have
a problem with lying.
Oh. Way to win me over.
We got six kids. She can't
afford to take a chance.
You have kids. How novel.
That changes everything.
So if Mommy gets heartburn,
one of them might catch on fire.
Please. I don't
know what we'd do.
They are cute.
Have her come back in. What?
Your plight has moved me.
Tell your wife to come back.
The necrosis is getting worse.
Maybe because we're
treating her for the wrong thing.
- Have you found the right thing?
- No.
Then we continue the treatment, hope
it's just taking longer than it should.
A t this point, it doesn't matter
what caused the necrosis.
Or who.
- If we don't stop it from spreading,
it'll kill her before the end of the day.
What else can we do?
Get rid of it. Remove the
dying flesh before it
penetrates the abdominal wall.
Do it.
There's still a chance the heparin
treatment could start to take effect.
We're gonna wait as long as we can, but
if there's no change in the next few hours,
we're gonna have to
treat the symptoms directly.
So you can get rid of the
sores? Through surgery.
Technically, it's an amputation.
Amputation? But the sores are...
Warfarin-induced necrosis attacks
fatty tissue, mainly in the breasts.
Wait. Are you talking about
cutting off my daughter's... breasts?
- She's 10 years old.
- A radical mastectomy
may be her only chance for survival.
I'm sorry, but I'm gonna
have to ask you to sign this.
Could we talk?
What, no roses, no chocolates?
If you're here to apologize—
I'm not here to apologize.
Uh-oh.
That means you're here for
something more complicated.
Do you want to fire me?
Yes. Just waiting for an excuse.
Thank God Vogler came along. Whew.
It's the only reason I can think of why
you're insisting that I made a mistake.
Really? Because there
is another explanation.
Perhaps not as much fun
as your Freudian analysis,
but maybe you
actually made a mistake.
You're doing this because you
can't deal with your feelings for me.
I believe that you are the
only one to express feelings.
And if we're gonna look
at this from a first-year
psych point of view, maybe
you want me to fire you.
Maybe that's why you're acting
weird— You're the one being different.
You're always pushing things, pushing
the rules, pushing us. But not this time.
You jumped on this
idea like a life raft.
Not one question about
what else it could be.
No riding us for other
answers. I have the answer.
Then why aren't you watching TV
or playing your damn Game Boy...
or whatever else you have
so much fun doing by yourself?
Maybe I should just quit.
Make it easy for everyone.
Maybe you should.
Men are pigs.
You called me in to tell me...
I should've realized the
vasectomy and condoms
was overkill, but this
was too obvious to miss.
Cute kids.
Love her green eyes
and his baby blues.
- Of course, since both
you and your husband
have brown eyes— -
Where'd you get that?
From the father of three,
maximum four, of your six children.
So I'm thinking maybe the
reason you don't want surgery...
is that while your husband will
find you attractive no matter what,
all the other men you're sleeping
with might not be so open-minded.
Which brings me back to my
original thesis: Men are pigs.
You got nothing to worry about.
They'll pretty much have sex with anyone:
fat, skinny, married, single,
complete strangers, relatives...
You... are sick. So are you.
And I'm sure there are
Web sites full of men...
looking for married
women with surgical scars.
So have the surgery. Please?
Okay.
Thanks.
Why have you been
talking to Cameron?
- If House picks you,
I'll be needing a new source in that room.
- If he picks me?
Sure. Foreman's smarter.
House has got a thing for Cameron.
I've been feeding you
information so you'll protect me.
And I will protect you
as long as I need you.
And you will feed me information
as long as you need me.
I spoke with Cameron
because if I have alternatives,
I don't need you.
She's not gonna rat on House.
Foreman never said
anything about talkin' to me?
Interesting, huh?
It's been almost three hours.
Still no change in her condition.
I think we should
get her into surgery.
So what do you wanna do?
Assume that Cameron
didn't screw up.
What if it's not the
warfarin? It has to be. The
sores presented right
after we administered it.
Right, right, right.
But let's just say
it's not. Come on. Come
on. What do you got?
Can I have a second to
think? No. There's no time to
think. Just say the first thing
that comes into your head.
She's fat. Enough already, okay?
We got it. You hate fat people.
That's not what I meant. We
already considered obesity as a cause.
So did all her other
doctors. No, I mean what
if it’s not a cause?
What if it’s a symptom?
Okay. So, what could cause
obesity and skin necrosis?
I don't care if it makes
sense. Just give me something.
- Ulcers secondary to vasculitis.
- No, that's just sores, not obesity.
- Pyoderma gangrenosum.
- More sores.
Let's look at it from the other side.
What has obesity as a symptom?
Hypothyroidism? Genetics are
more likely. Her mom's heavy too.
She's not just
heavy, she's tall.
We have any history
on the dad? Yeah.
6'1".
Kid's short.
We got stunted growth, high
blood pressure, blood clots, obesity...
- It's Cushing's.
- No. Necrosis doesn't present...
In rare cases, Cushing's
can cause hypercalcemia,
which can lead to the same
skin necrosis as warfarin.
It's perfect. It
explains everything.
Except it's not Cushing's.
She's had multiple blood
tests, and none show
abnormal cortisol levels.
The hypercortisolism could be cyclical.
We didn't catch it in the right phase.
- We'll have to do another
U.F.C.— - There's no
time. We've got less than
an hour to make a call.
If we treat for Cushing's
and we're wrong, she's dead.
If we assume it's not Cushing's, she'll
lose her breast and may still be sick.
- Do an M.R.I.
- You want us to look
for hypercortisolism with an M.R.I.?
No, I want you to look for what could
cause hypercortisolism with an M.R.I.
Nothing on the adrenals.
Heard Cameron went
home. Is she sick?
Go back to the pituitary views.
- She seemed okay.
- Think she's got
another reason for leaving?
I hope so. Wait, stop.
There. What's that?
Huh. A tumor.
It's Cushing's.
The tumor causes Cushing's. Cushing's
messes with hormone production.
Hormones control
everything: growth, weight...
Can you fix it? She'll need
surgery to remove the tumor.
Once it's gone, everything
will get normal very fast.
- No mastectomy?
- No.
Thank God. The
surgery is dangerous.
The pituitary's located
between the cavernous sinuses,
basically right
between the eyes.
The area contains the
nerves that control eye
movement and the major
arteries that feed the brain.
Oh, my God.
The surgeon will approach
the gland transsphenoidally.
An incision will be
made under the lip,
through which he'll insert
a fiber-optic microscope.
Once the tumor's found,
he'll cut it into small pieces
and remove it through
the same hole under the lip.
The whole procedure should
take about three hours, and
your daughter should be
able to go home in a few days.
The sores will go away, as well
as her fatigue and the muscle pain.
She'll even start losing weight.
Jessica. Hi.
- Is that really you?
- Yep, it's me.
You look fantastic.
- She always looked fantastic.
- Yeah.
- It's been a week.
- Actually, it's over a week.
How have you guys been?
Who is it?
Chase.
No, Chase stays.
Pick someone else.
The deal was—
The deal's changed.
- Pick someone else.
- No.
Mmm.
Pick someone else, or it'll
be the whole department.
That's some bad hat, Harry.