.
- You're on my team,
that's all.
It's better this way.
- Not the way I see it.
- She's been you therapist
for years, what happened?
- I thought what I missed
was the work.
Maybe what
I really miss is you.
- Exposing the abuse
of the Vas-COM was brave.
- The Vas-COM business,
playing nice with the enemy,
it sucked, but I needed
to protect patients.
- Turns out whistleblowers
are entitled to a reward.
How about that?
- Wait, so Vasik settled
with the Feds?
- Well, there's still
some state and criminal cases
going forward,
but from our position--
- It's over, Will.
- But as whistleblowers,
you and Ms. Goodwin
are entitled
to a percentage
of the settlement.
- What are we--
what are we talking about?
- You've each been awarded
$1.2 million.
- 1.2?
Oh...
What does that even mean?
- I know it's a lot to take in,
but news like this
is a great opportunity
for you and the hospital.
- Sharon Goodwin's volunteered
to gift her entire settlement
to Gaffney's
charitable foundation.
- Insisted, really.
Now, there's no pressure,
but I'm putting together
a little press event
for the end of the day
to officially announce
the donation,
and it'd be even more impactful
if you were a part of it.
As Mrs. Goodwin said,
she didn't do it for the money.
I'm sure the same
is true for you.
- I-I didn't even know
there'd be money.
- You know,
you'd really be sending
a very strong message
to your colleagues, Will.
- Right.
- So what do you say?
Can we take that as a "yes"?
It's feeling like a "yes".
- Okay.
- You're doing the right thing.
Truly--thank you.
- Yeah.
- All right.
♪
- Dr. Scott? Baghdad.
30-something female.
Truck hit a patch of black ice.
Clipped her motorcycle.
- Vitals stable the whole time,
but positive LOC.
GCS 14.
Helmet was cracked but cleared
her C-spine in the field.
- Got it for you right here.
- Got a name?
- Not that we could get
out of her;
she's
intermittently responsive.
- On my count--one, two, three.
Get her up on the monitors.
You're gonna be okay,
all right?
I'm Dr. Scott.
what's your name?
- Right side is clear.
Left side's
a bit muffled, but...
- Bilateral, best I can tell.
Looks like there's a deformity
in the left shoulder,
possible dislocation.
Let's get a chest X-ray.
- Hey, hon?
I'm gonna take your bag, okay?
- No.
- We can't take a picture
of what's going on
with you clutching it
like that.
- I promise we'll take
good care of it, all right?
- No.
- It's okay.
- See if Maggie can get any ID,
maybe an emergency contact.
- Yeah.
- X-ray clear.
- There's a small pneumothorax
on the left,
but that left shoulder
is definitely dislocated.
Let's pop it back in
and send her down to CT
for a pan scan, all right?
Four of morphine,
two of Versed.
All right, now, we're gonna
relocate your shoulder.
It's gonna hurt
for a few seconds,
but it'll be
over before you know it.
- It's back in.
Let's get her another X-ray
and get her over to CAT scan.
You did great.
♪
Hey, Mags, you found an ID yet?
- Mm-hmm.
Milena Jovanovic. 28 years old.
- Touch what's in the bag yet?
- No, why?
What are you doing?
We already have her ID.
- Maggie...
I think our girl Milena
might be a drug dealer.
♪
.
- Abby Carpenter?
I'm Dr. Vanessa Taylor.
What brings you in today?
- Mites. I've been infested.
I can't stop itching.
- Okay, can you remove
your suit so I can take a look
at what we're talking about?
- It's been over a year now.
I've tried everything,
but they won't stop biting.
- Oh, you shaved your head...
- Yeah, I--I had to,
they were multiplying.
And it's been getting worse.
I think they've started
laying eggs beneath my skin.
- You definitely did the
right thing by coming in today.
Your skin
is definitely infected.
But, uh,
I'm not seeing any mites.
- Yeah, they're so small
they're invisible
to the naked eye.
Here.
I found this larva last night.
- Thanks, I'll have
the lab check it out.
Let's start a line,
hang a liter of saline
and give her 600mg
of clindamycin IV, okay?
- Okay.
- What's that for?
- It's an antibiotic.
I'm afraid you might be septic,
so it's just to be
on the safe side.
- Okay, fine,
but you need to give me
something to get rid
of the mites.
- I'll do the best I can.
I'll be back.
- Okay.
Have the lab
take a look at this.
And lets grab a CBC,
BMP, blood glucose,
and a tox screen.
And, uh, lets page Dr. Charles.
- Yeah.
- What are you thinking?
- Probably heroin.
Quarter key,
straight off the brick--
still compressed,
hasn't been cut with anything,
but impossible
to tell without testing.
What do we know about Milena?
- Nothing.
I tried to pull up
her medical records,
but there was no history.
It's like she's a ghost.
- I'ma call my sister.
- No, you can't do that.
- I can't ignore this.
- By law, you shouldn't have
kept digging around
in her bag after we ID'd her.
I don't know, Dylan.
It feels like you're mixed up
and you don't know
what uniform you're wearing.
- All right, all right.
I'll stand down.
Okay, but let's not be
in a rush
to give this back just yet.
- Everything okay?
- I'm fine.
I mean, not really,
but sorry to bother you.
- Not a bother.
I'm Dr. Halstead, let me
know if you need anything--
- Deep breaths.
In through your nose,
out through your mouth.
Okay, I'm gonna examine
your belly, all right?
- I thought at first,
they were just wedding jitters,
but those don't usually land
you in the hospital, I assume.
- Not typically;
has anyone seen you yet?
- Dr. Archer said it's
a bowel dilation caused
by some kind of infection?
- Diverticulitis--antibiotics
should clear that up.
- Okay.
- When's the wedding?
- Next weekend.
I wanted to do it in City Hall,
but Adam insisted
on something grander.
Now it's up to 500 guests,
and my mother-in-law
booked the entire
Shedd Aquarium for the night.
- Very generous of her.
- Yeah, well,
that's Janice for you.
Everything's gotta be perfect.
She's going to blow a fuse
when she finds out
I'll be walking down
the aisle with her son
with an ostomy bag
under my dress.
- Dr. Archer's
recommending surgery?
- He said
it's the only option I had.
- So you just signed it over?
The whole enchilada?
What are doing--
trying to fast-track
your application to sainthood?
You're crazy.
- Please, people are
making too much of it.
I want to hear about you.
What's going on with Lonnie?
- Well, as you know,
the State Psychiatry Board
frowns on therapists having
any kind of romantic relations
with their patients,
and vice versa,
for at least a year
after their last session,
and it's only been ten months,
so, not a whole lot.
That's soon enough.
What happens now?
- It's actually kinda weird,
right?
It's awkward, I--
last time I saw her,
I put something out there,
and I haven't heard
anything back.
It'd been like a week.
- Well, keep me in the loop
'cause you know
I live vicariously through you.
- You know I will.
- Okay.
- So patient in six,
you're thinking
delusional parasitosis?
- I found no evidence
of parasites.
Tox screen and sed rate
were negative.
All of her injuries appear
to be self-inflicted.
The lab did an analysis of the
mite larvae she brought in.
It was a dried pea.
- Hmm.
So CT, MRI,
no signs of striatal lesions
or--or tumors.
Any history of mental illness?
- No, not in
her medical records,
but she's certainly presenting
as delusional now.
Look, I know it's not
my area of expertise,
but I'm just not sure
what else it could be.
- Could very well be right,
but if she is
in fact delusional,
probably gonna be hostile
to the idea of even
seeing a psychiatrist, so.
We've gotta tread carefully,
and might even need
to improvise.
- They're impossible
to get rid of.
I've had to reupholster my car.
Twice.
I don't even bother
doing laundry anymore.
I just wear things once,
then throw them away.
Except for my suit, of course.
- It sounds
completely exhausting.
- There's not even
a word for it.
- And you haven't
been able to find
any medication that'll give you
any relief at all?
- My dermatologists
have tried them all.
Antihistamines,
corticosteroids.
Was your lab able to identify
what kind of mite it is?
- You know, I think we're still
working on that.
But you know, in the meantime,
I'd like to add another
more targeted drug to help you
with those bites.
Would that be all right?
- Okay.
- Okay, great.
Well, I will go find
a nurse to hang a dose,
and I'll be right back.
- Your supervisor
seems like a nice man.
- Dr. Charles, yeah, he is.
So Abby, it says here
that you first noticed
the infestation a little over
18 months ago.
- Yeah.
- Can you remember what else
was going on
in your life at the time?
- Like, uh--
like, what do you mean?
- Like, were you
having problems
in your relationships
or your career?
Had you recently moved
or relocated?
- Are you suggesting that
this is all in my head?
- No--
- You don't think I know
how to read the signs?
I've gone through
enough doctors to know
when they think I'm crazy--
I am not crazy!
How do I get myself discharged?
I want to go
to another hospital.
- What's going on?
Is there a problem?
- Yes, your underling
here is trying to convince me
that I'm crazy.
- Really, Dr. Taylor?
Could you wait
for me outside please?
♪
- Look, I'm not delusional.
- I'm so sorry about that.
Look, I'm going
to be supervising
your case going forward.
Will that be all right?
Good, now, let's see if
we can do something
about that fever,
what do you say?
- Okay.
- Thank you very much,
Dr. Taylor,
for playing along in there.
I have to say,
you were quite convincing.
- Thank you.
It's strange, though,
Abby wasn't always
so opposed to seeing
a psychiatrist.
- What do you mean?
- Well, I was digging
deeper into her file,
and it says here
she used to see one regularly
for years, you know,
till the pandemic started.
- Huh. Do we have their info?
- It's a Dr. Lavine
from The Fischer Group?
- The Fischer Group?
- You know them?
- Yeah, I am familiar
with that practice.
- It says
Dr. Lavine has retired,
so maybe I can call
someone else from the group
to see if they can
discuss Abby's history?
- You know what,
I actually have a colleague
over there, so why don't you
let me do that?
But--excellent work.
Really good work.
- Hey, Dean?
- Mm-hmm?
- You got a second?
- Yeah, sure.
I hear that's all it
took to sucker you
out of a million bucks.
- I guess word travels fast.
- Yeah, I gotta ask,
did they at least promise you
your own parking spot?
- I didn't blow the whistle
for money,
so donating
was the right thing to do.
- All right, if you say so.
So what do you need?
- Your patient,
Gretchen Cameron,
I saw you
scheduled her for surgery.
- Laparotomy is the plan.
- Yeah, I took a look
at her chart.
White count's 15
and trending down.
Antibiotics are working.
So it feels like we should
put a pause on the surgery,
try a nasogastric decompression
instead to reduce the dilation.
- You reviewed
my patient's chart?
- She was upset.
And with her wedding
next weekend,
I thought we could find
her an alternative.
- Generous with
your money and time.
- An NG decompression
with antibiotics
can bridge her
to a less invasive procedure.
We could safely delay it
until after her wedding,
and Gretchen wouldn't
need the ostomy bag.
- None of that is guaranteed
to correct any of her problems,
and any more delay
will increase her chances
of getting septic.
- Dean, I think you're
rushing the surgery--
- I don't need an E.D. doctor
second guessing my decisions.
- Surgeons and
your need to cut--
- Excuse me, excuse me.
What is going on here?
- We're finishing up here--
- Actually we're not
quite finished discussing
how to spare a patient
an aggressive surgery.
- My patient.
- And I'm just making sure
she doesn't feel
pressured into making
a decision
she's uncomfortable with.
- I see, but Dr. Halstead,
this is
Dr. Archer's department,
and, most importantly,
his patient.
I trust him
to make the right call,
and I expect you
to do the same.
♪
- Other than a small
pneumothorax in your chest,
all your scans
look pretty good.
You'll probably
have to keep your arm
in an immobilizer
for a bit, though.
I'll get you another X-ray
in an hour or two.
- The bag I was carrying,
where is it?
- We're keeping it behind
the nurses' station.
- Yeah, well,
I'd like it back please.
Ahh! Oh, God.
- Yeah, It's probably
gonna pinch for a bit.
You know what,
I can up your pain meds--
- No, I'm fine,
just get me the bag.
- Am I gonna
have to call my lawyer?
Because I know my rights.
The Fourth Amendment prohibits
the search or seizure
of a person or their property
without a warrant
or probable cause.
- All right, okay, all right.
Calm down, I'm not a cop.
- Well,
you could have fooled me.
- Hey, Maggie, could we get
Ms. Jovanovic her bag, please?
Thanks. Here you go.
- What?
You want some kind of reward?
- I'll check in
on you in a bit.
♪
Who was that?
- I don't know.
- He says he's her cousin.
- You see
that tattoo on his neck?
Pretty sure
that's Serbian mafia.
.
- Hey, big day, Andre.
New heart and liver are
on their way here as we speak.
How you feeling?
- Ready.
- Good.
- We're so excited.
- Got you a little something.
- You know I'm not 12 anymore.
- Tradition is tradition.
- So you guys
know each other then?
- Yes, Andre's familial
hypercholesteremia required
a liver transplant
fifteen years ago.
I was a resident.
- Oh.
- Back when
I thought these were cool.
- So the hope was that Andre's
transplant would reverse
his early onset
atherosclerosis,
but, as you know,
livers only last so long.
So as that went...
- Yeah, it put him
back in heart failure.
- We still chitchatting
in here?
Or are we ready
to get things started?
- Andre, Tanya,
this is Dr. Morris.
He's gonna be handling
the cardiac portion
of your surgery.
- Now, this heart I've got
for you, it's a real beauty.
There's not going to be
any problems before I hand
the reins off to these two.
It's gonna be a good day.
- Any questions for us?
- Let's do this thing.
- All right,
see you in there.
- So given Andre's
previous transplant,
I'm thinking we start
with proximal, right?
- Maybe, but we won't
be able to visualize
what shape the vessels
are in until we're open.
- Right.
- Care to comment, Justin?
- I just think it's cute
you've got
a pet general surgeon.
- Oh...
- You got something
to say to me?
- Not particularly.
You know I'm happy
to share the stage
with you, Pamela,
but this--this bogan?
I'm don't know what
he's doing in my O.R.
- Well, Dr. Marcel is
an integral part of my team.
- From your lips to God's ears.
Let's get this case moving.
- "Bogan"?
- No idea.
- Come on, let's scrub in.
- She's sleeping now,
and her fever has subsided.
- Oh, good.
- Mm-hmm.
- Daniel.
- Lonnie.
Dr. Richardson.
This is Dr. Taylor.
Dr. Richardson
is my colleague that I was
telling you about who works
at The Fischer Group.
- Oh, nice to meet you.
- Hello, doctor.
- So I'm gonna bring
Dr. Richardson up to speed,
and maybe you could just give
us a shout when Abby wakes up?
- Yeah.
- Great--great, okay.
Right this way, please.
- I distinctly remember you
being told to stay clear
of this case, and yet,
you told my patient to ask
for a
nasogastric decompression.
- She wanted
to know her options.
- So what, you just
sign your big check
over to the hospital, and that
gives you carte blanche
to do
whatever the hell you want?
- If she doesn't want
to have the operation,
you can't force her to have it.
- Well, no, but since it seems
you've made Ms. Cameron
your latest misguided crusade,
you can waste your time
with this procedure.
- It's pretty clear
what your preferred
course of action should be.
- Get Abby to take
an antipsychotic?
- You break the delusion,
you cure the symptoms.
- The trick is getting her
to take the medication.
If I even say the
word antipsychotic,
she's gonna kick me
out of the room.
- Unless you never
say the word.
- Lead her to believe it's
what, an anti-parasitic?
- Benevolent deception.
Ethically, it's justified
when four conditions are met.
One, Abby, due to her delusion,
cannot make
an informed decision.
- I think we
can both agree on that.
- Two, that harm would
likely come to her
if the antipsychotic
wasn't prescribed.
- You know, she was
this close to becoming septic.
- Three, she probably wouldn't
take medication
if presented as such.
- Well, I mean,
that's certainly my belief.
- And lastly, that committing
her involuntarily
to coerced treatment would lead
to even a worse result.
- That one I think might have
to be a judgement call.
- Nice to know I'm an
integral part of the team.
- Morris doesn't get to talk
to you like that.
That's my job.
Right.
It's just, after what
you said last week about us...
I appreciate knowing you're
still in my corner, I guess.
- Oh, well,
don't get sentimental on me.
Like I said, as long as
you keep your personal feelings
in check, you'll always have
a place in my O.R.
Always.
- Fair enough.
- Good.
- Dr. Scott?
Milena says she's leaving
against medical advice.
- I really have to recommend
that you not leave just yet.
- Thanks, Doc,
but I got things to do.
- Ok, well, uh, at least let me
get another X-ray,
just to make sure.
- She said she's leaving.
- Oh, I'm sorry,
I didn't catch your name.
- Step out of the way.
That's my name.
- Save it.
They can't do anything
to stop us.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
- Hey--hey! Milena?
Whoa! Are you okay?
Hey, hey, Milena,
can you take a breath for me?
- It hurts--it hurts.
- I'm not hearing
good breath sounds.
Hey, can you help me
get her off the floor, man?
Doris!
Need to put her back on oxygen,
and I need
another chest X-ray, stat!
- Got it.
♪
.
- You okay?
I know it feels weird.
- How long is this gonna take?
My fiancé
says he's on his way in.
I'd hate for him
to see me like this.
- Hard to say,
but I'll check back in shortly
to see how
you're feeling, okay?
- Okay.
- Oh, hey, Mother Teresa,
they left something for you.
- Thank you.
- "With our eternal gratitude,
the Gaffney Board of Trustees.
- Bet they popped
at least a buck fifty
for this basket, huh?
Could you imagine what
you would have got
if you gave them two million?
- Unfortunately,
that small pneumothorax
we spotted earlier
has become not so small.
The lung on your left side
is down 60%,
so gonna need to insert
a tube to re-expand it.
- How long does that take?
- The procedure itself?
Just a few minutes.
But we will need to keep you
at the hospital for a few days.
- Why?
- Because the tube needs
to be attached to suction
so your lungs can re-expand,
so they don't collapse again.
- No, that's not
going to work for me.
- Look, you're not walking
out of here today.
I think
you've already proved that.
- I'm not staying,
I just--I just need
a little bit more time
to catch my breath.
- Fine, I'll check
on you then.
Hey, where'd your cousin go?
- He left.
♪
- Hey, that guy left
with the drugs?
- I didn't notice, sorry.
- That's all right,
that's my bad.
I should have
called him in earlier.
- You're gonna
notify the police?
- Yeah, a mobster just left
with what I'm pretty sure
is fifty grand in narcotics.
Somebody's gotta keep eyes
on them.
♪
- I woke up with these on.
Was this Dr. Taylor's idea?
- Uh, no, it was actually mine.
You know, you were
scratching yourself,
and I just didn't want you
to aggravate
your injuries any further,
I hope that was all right.
- Oh, okay.
You know, I'm still so itchy.
Is it possible that they've
infested the linens too?
- Boy, I hope not.
You want me to ask the nurses
to swap your linens out?
- Yes, please.
- Okay.
So look--so this pandemic,
it's just been hard
on everybody.
Right, but--I don't know,
to be relentlessly attacked
by mites at a time
when you can't
leave your own home.
I just can't imagine
how isolating
this whole experience
must have been.
- Yeah, it still is.
- Right.
So--so while you were sleeping,
I went online,
and I did a little research,
and I found a drug
that I'm pretty hopeful about.
That I think
has a really good chance
of alleviating your symptoms
for good.
- What is it?
- You know Abby,
I'm gonna ask you, if you can,
to trust me.
Do you think you could do that,
just for today?
♪
- Another lat pad?
Bleeding's heavy,
can't see a thing.
- More suction.
- That's 12 units.
Blood bank's getting twitchy.
- Well, keep it coming, Marty.
- Get a move on, you bludger.
Not going to let you
ruin all my hard work
just because you can't
track down a little bleeder.
- If you're not going to help,
keep the commentary
to yourself.
- Just page me when
you're ready to close.
- Okay, so what do we think?
- High venous back pressure.
Maybe the intrahepatic cava
clotted off.
- Yeah, we'll have to take down
our caval anastomosis to check.
Okay, get Dr. Marcel
a Fogerty cath.
- Blood pressure just dropped
into the 80s.
Heart rate's up to 120.
- All right.
Yeah, she's in septic shock.
- Bolus a liter normal
saline and start her
on a levophed drip.
- What's happening?
- You're in septic shock.
The dilation's caused
a leak in your intestine.
- Transportation!
Can't delay the inevitable
any longer, Gretchen.
I'm taking you to surgery.
- No.
- He has no choice.
- Come on, let's go--come on.
♪
.
- Vessel's clear.
No clots.
- Damn, still bleeding. Marty?
- Gave him another two units,
but I'm struggling to keep up.
- Oh, come on,
we're missing something here.
- What if it's in the chest?
- Hey, what are you doing?
- Any flow problems
with the inferior vena cava
in the chest would
put back pressure
on the hepatic vessels here.
You see that anastomosis?
It's sewn too tight.
- That would explain
our problem.
- There's no way
it's strictured.
Dr. Morris doesn't make
mistakes like that.
- We need
to redo the anastomosis.
- Hold on, that's crazy.
- Marty what's our temp?
- Getting cold, 35.
- We're gonna lose Andre
if we don't act fast.
- You can
do the cardiac repair.
- Absolutely not,
you can't touch CT's field.
This is our procedure.
- Then you can get Morris
in here but I'm not sitting
on my hands while we wait.
All right?
I'm gonna get moving now.
Let's get the perfusionist
back in here,
and get me a Satinsky clamp,
please.
- Dr. Scott?
Do you mind coming
with me for a second?
- Thanks, Eddie.
Don't think we've
ever met formally.
Lieutenant Regina Jeffords.
- Yeah, I know who you are.
You work out of OCD--Narcotics.
- You're Reggie's kid, right?
Used to work under him
in the 23rd once upon a time.
Before your day.
- Yeah,
I wasn't there very long.
- Once a cop,
always a cop, though, right?
- I'm assuming this is about
the call I made to my sister?
- There was a bag
you were concerned about,
did I hear that correctly?
- You did.
- And the woman
who possessed it,
is she still under your care?
- She is. Milena Jovanovic.
I believe she has ties
to the Serbian mob.
- Is she okay?
- Yeah, she looks like
you'd expect somebody to look
whose bike got clipped
by a truck.
- Forgive me if I'm asking
a stupid question,
but is it possible
to patch up Miss Jovanovic
enough to discharge her today?
- She's still a bit unstable.
Maybe in a day or two,
I could hand her over.
- Ok, what if she's needed
on the street today?
- What the hell
is going on here, huh?
I put in a call my sister
to run something down,
and suddenly I got
Narcotics brass
leaning on me
to look the other way.
- Hey, if it can't be done,
it can't be done.
♪
- You must be
Gretchen's fiancé?
I'm Dr. Halstead.
- Hi, Adam Cunningham.
This is my mother, Janice.
- Hi.
- Last I spoke with Gretchen,
she said you were
trying to keep
her out of surgery.
- That's right, we tried to.
Unfortunately,
her infection progressed,
and surgery became necessary.
- Oh, man.
- Yeah, I'm very sorry.
- Well, ask him
about the ostomy bag.
- Oh, yeah.
Gretchen mentioned
she might need one.
I guess the question is--
I mean, will it fit
under her clothes?
I mean, is this something that,
you know,
everybody's gonna see?
- We won't really know
until she's out of surgery.
How about I go check
and see how things are going?
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
- How is she?
- Too early to say.
- I asked you to stay away
from this case.
- I was trying
to give her another option,
that's all she ever wanted.
- She's not your patient,
Dr. Halstead.
- I know, I'm sorry,
I shouldn't have interfered.
- Good.
- But I gotta
get something off my chest.
- Okay?
- Your donation.
- What about it?
- You kinda screwed me,
Ms. Goodwin.
- Excuse me?
- Now how's it gonna look
if I don't do the same thing?
- Listen, I donated
my portion of the settlement
because it was
the right choice for me.
If it's not
the right choice for you--
- I can't ask
for the money back now.
I'm in a no-win situation here.
I got into this
to right a wrong, for sure.
But I'm not exactly
financially set.
Okay, I'm drowning in debt,
and I just gave away
my life raft.
- All right, I understand,
but you can't let
your personal issues
affect you at work.
♪
- Now, you should be
on suction,
but this valve will give you
some temporary relief.
You will need to come back
and have it
switched out
as soon as possible.
- But my lung's
not gonna collapse?
- I can't promise you that.
But if you feel like
you're gonna pass out,
or if there's any chest pain,
you need to call 911
immediately.
- Yeah, okay.
- Trini, could you
give us a second?
- I want you to know that
this is not what I want to do.
But I understand
that for some reason
this is important, so...
Your instincts were right,
earlier.
I used to be a cop.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
I guess I'll never be able
to shake it.
Inside, I'll always bleed blue.
- Why are you telling me this?
- Felt like something
you might need to know.
- You mind giving me
some privacy?
I want to get dressed so I can
finally get out of here.
- Yeah, sure.
Stay safe out there.
♪
- Oh.
- You're leaving?
- I finished up
all my paperwork.
I have a busy day tomorrow.
- Well, why don't I
walk you out?
- Oh, thank you.
- Oh, hey, there you are.
Good news.
I don't know how you
managed to get Abby
to take an antipsychotic,
but it appears that
her delusion is breaking.
- Oh.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- That quickly?
- Great.
I'll be by just in a second
to check up on her.
- Well, you're a miracle
worker, Dr. Charles, thank you.
- Congratulations.
Of course, we both know
that now that Abby
is regaining her
decision-making capacity...
- We're gonna have to get
her permission if I want
to keep her on the medication.
- You're gonna have
to tell her the truth.
- Yeah.
Hey, do you mind
just hanging out
for another couple of minutes?
- How is he?
How's my Andre?
- His vitals
are stable and strong.
- The procedure took
a little longer than expected,
but my team
did an excellent job.
Your son
will make a full recovery.
- Oh, thank God.
Thank you so much.
- My pleasure.
- You can go in
and see him now.
We're gonna be
extubating him soon.
- Don't ever touch my repairs.
- You weren't there,
I had no choice.
- I'm filing a disciplinary
complaint against you,
you arrogant prick.
- You know, I'm not going
to apologize for stepping in.
Andre's life
was on the line, okay?
- No, you just
had to play hero.
- Nope, I just
had to fix your mistake--
- Oh, my God!
What the hell
is wrong with you?
♪
- Are you all right?
- Yeah.
.
- So you lied to me?
- I misled you,
and I apologize for that.
- Oh, God,
you must think I'm crazy...
- I do not.
- You weren't wearing
that jacket before.
Psychiatry?
You were
lying to me from the start.
You were afraid
I was gonna flip out.
- That's actually not
what I was afraid of.
I was afraid that you were
going to walk out of here
in no better shape
than when you walked in.
I was afraid that the next time
that you came in here,
that you were gonna
be way past the point
that any medication
could help you.
So I did what I thought
was in your best interests.
- By tricking me
into taking these?
- Abby, you're already
outside your delusion enough
to be able to talk about it.
I mean, before, you were
all alone in your head,
and now you're not anymore.
Look, there's 30 days
of medication in here,
and if you don't want
to feel the way
you were feeling before,
I strongly advise that
you keep taking them.
♪
- Wait--wait.
This is what you do?
You crack people open
with these little tricks
and then you just walk away?
- No, I didn't think
you wanted to talk anymore.
- Um, look...
This is the first time
I've had a conversation
like this with anyone
since the pandemic started.
Uh, and I, uh...
I didn't realize how
much I missed it.
- Yeah, really important
to have someone
to talk to during times
like this, right?
- Yeah.
- You don't see
regular patients, do you?
- Look, I'm gonna make sure
that you can get in touch
with me any time you want,
but I do work
in the ED full time.
- Yeah.
- There is, however,
a colleague of mine
who happens to be here today,
and among many other things,
I can guarantee you that she's
a first-rate conversationalist.
Would you like to say hello?
She's just right outside.
- Yeah.
- Hello, Abby.
- Hi.
- My name is Lonnie.
I understand you used to see
an old colleague of mine,
Dr. Lavine?
- You know Dr. Lavine?
- I do, yeah.
♪
- Hey, Gretchen.
Let's take a quick look here.
Looks good. How you feeling?
- Great, surprisingly.
This ostomy might have been
the best thing
that ever happened to me.
- I'm sorry,
did I miss something?
- I called it off.
- The wedding?
- The wedding, the marriage,
the relationship.
Everything.
Janice couldn't stand
the thought of me ruining
her perfect little moment,
and Adam, as usual,
didn't have my back.
- I'm sorry to hear that.
- It's okay.
I've had misgivings all along.
I don't think I was
ever a real person to him,
just some prop he was using
to make himself look good.
It's like I've been
living my entire life
according to someone
else's expectations.
Well, no more.
From now on,
I'm gonna live my own life.
You know what I mean?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I do.
- Honestly, I have no idea
how you kept your cool
like that.
- Oh, well, you know, I was
gonna take a swing at him,
but I thought, what good would
I be to you with a busted hand?
- Yeah, well, they are
your second-best attribute.
I was referring to your
self-assuredness.
- Ah.
- Maybe your hair.
- It's very appealing.
You didn't
hurt your lips did you?
- No.
♪
- What are you doing here?
- You said I should come
see you to have this replaced.
- Yeah, in the hospital,
I mean.
I can't do it here.
- Oh.
- All right, uh, come in,
I'll take you.
So how'd you find me?
- I'm resourceful
when I need to be.
- Mm-hmm.
- This was taken
at your police academy
graduation ceremony, right?
Navy Pier?
- Yeah, how'd you know?
♪
Guess it takes one
to know one, huh?
- Uh.
Maybe we should get going.
It's actually
getting harder to breathe.
- Hey, hold up. I gotcha.
♪
- While Gaffney Chicago
Medical Center
has certainly seen its ups
and downs in recent months,
today is unequivocally
an up day.
After courageously exposing...
- Did I miss your turn
in the spotlight?
- No.
I decided to keep the money.
Or at least most of it.
I still donated some,
but not enough to warrant
my name up in lights, I guess.
- Finally, a smart decision
out of you.
- Money to Gaffney's
charitable foundation.
I'll take some questions,
go ahead.
♪