Hey, what's going on?
What are you doing?
I didn't know you were in here.
Do you mind?
I thought you were at rounds.
What time is it?
6:35.
Oh... oh, God!
Anspaugh's going to kill me.
Where's my, uh...?
Give me my stethoscope.
Uh, here, take mine.
Did you brush your teeth?
Yes, Dad.
Did you floss?
Yes, Dad!
All right, I was just checking.
See, I told you I could
make a good breakfast.
You're wearing your
Brownie uniform.
It's Thursday.
Was I supposed to
talk to your troop today?
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
I... I forgot to
change my shift.
You promised.
I have to work today.
Can I do it next week?
I knew you'd forget.
Listen, I don't have
to work Saturday.
How about we go to Six Flags...
Ride the roller coasters?
Dr. Edson, present the case.
The patient is fluid overloaded.
I gave her a Lasix sandwich
to reduce the ascites.
Dr. Carter,
how nice of you to join us.
What would you do
with Mrs. Pritzker?
What's her problem?
As Dr. Edson has
just finished saying,
she's fluid overloaded.
Well, I, uh, wouldn't
give her anything to drink.
Let's continue our discussion
of diuresis, shall we?
Carter, what electrolyte
imbalance can result
from giving Lasix?
Hypokalemia.
Where does Lasix
affect the kidney?
At the loop of Henle.
Ascending or descending limb?
Ascending.
Where does Lasix
get its name?
I don't know.
It lasts six hours.
Ah.
Dr. Ryke, present the next
patient, please.
It looks like we've got...
Man, what did he
have for breakfast?
Me.
Hey, Carol... hey! Good morning.
Says who?
Oh, guess I'm not going to
ask how your day's going.
I got my MCAT results.
And?
I never should
have taken the test.
I don't know what I
was thinking, you know.
That you wanted to be a doctor?
Why didn't you
talk me out of it?
How bad did you do?
I don't know,
haven't opened it yet.
Are you nuts? You got
to open the envelope.
No, I'm just not in the
mood for any bad news.
Okay, I know, yeah.
I tell you what... I'll
open that envelope.
Doug! Give it back!
Hey, does anybody
have a letter opener here?
Come on, Doug...
Doug, don't you dare.
Doug...
Good morning, Dr. Einstein.
Einstein?
Excuse me?
I guess we'll have to move fast
to beat out the
other med schools.
What?
Your MCATs... I'm on
the Admissions Committee.
They sent us your scores.
Now, look, don't
consider the Ivy League
until you've taken a
good look at our program.
We'll talk later...
Maybe lunch, huh?
Oh, my God.
85th percentile.
Looks like Carol Hathaway
is going to medical school.
So you disappointed
the Brownies.
I blew it... I forgot
I had to work.
Tough being a
doctor and a daddy.
That's what Jen used to say.
I rest my case.
Mark, I put you on the schedule
for Saturday 7:00 to 7:00.
I can't... I've got
plans with Rachel.
There's no one else.
Walters and Foster
are on vacation.
At the same time?
Mark approved the schedule.
Can't you cover for me?
I've got the graveyard.
You blew it again.
Put the lancet in the pen.
Put your finger on this end
and then push the trigger.
Okay, is this
absolutely necessary?
Yeah, when you have
gestational diabetes,
you need to test your
blood four times a day.
Just get it over with.
Ow.
Okay, now, after you
calibrate the machine,
then you put in a strip
and apply a drop of blood
and wait for a reading.
Slow down.
Now, a blood glucose of 120
is where you want to be.
160 is too much.
Anything under 80
means you need to eat.
You want me to write that down?
No, no, no, no... I got it.
Okay... 210.
All right, you need
a shot of insulin.
Where is it?
The nurse is bringing it.
She'll be here in an hour?
No, she's going
to be here at 10:00.
Okay.
You'll be fine.
All right.
I got to go.
Already?
Yeah, I'm late for work.
Just go.
Hey, Carol, they need
a puke cleanup in 3.
Why, thank you, Jerry.
Your puke-cleaning
days are nearly over.
Reason enough to
go to medical school.
Who's going to medical school?
Carol.
She hit a home run on her MCATs.
No kidding... congratulations.
Don't forget us when
you're in the big house.
I haven't even applied yet.
Jerry, what are you doing?
I saw a mouse by the elevator...
soon to be deceased.
Sounds like Heidi.
Dr. Russell in the genetics lab
lost one of his
gene-knockout founders.
His what?
A genetically-engineered mouse.
He said it's worth
half a million bucks.
You're kidding.
No, there's a $5,000 reward.
Dead or alive?
Alive... Jerry, it's
worthless if it's dead.
Carol, can you watch the phones?
It's not my job, Jerry.
Well, I'm on break.
Uh, no, no... doctors
don't do phones.
How were rounds?
I got massacred.
Anspaugh?
Exiled me down here.
Ever since I second-guessed him,
he's been out to get me.
What are you doing?
I'm practicing
laparoscopic maneuvers,
in case I ever get
back into surgery.
Cool... can I try?
Yeah.
Here.
Just put your hands
through those graspers,
and you're just
trying to stack the dice
one on top of the other.
This is tricky.
Wait till you try tying knots.
Carter... Benton
needs you in Trauma 2.
Mind if I tag along?
No, be my guest.
Hold still, Mrs. Meeks.
Looks like you've got
a small fishbone down there.
Jerry, turn off the light.
I can't... I'm
looking for Heidi.
We're the only ones in here.
Heidi's a mouse.
A mouse?
Yeah, a mutant mouse.
Jerry, we're in the
middle of an exam.
There it is.
Ah, Heidi.
Don't be afraid.
Uncle Jerry won't hurt you.
Hey!
What'd you do that for?
There you go.
Open wide.
Hey, Doug, how much did you
have to borrow for med school?
110 grand.
Oh, my God.
Well, how long did it
take you to pay it off?
Are you kidding? I'll be
paying it off for 15 years.
I've got a sick kid here.
He was asleep in his crib.
I couldn't wake him up.
How long was he down?
Two minutes.
Couldn't get an I.V...
Gave epi down the tube.
Excuse me.
Joel has a
hypoplastic left heart.
They put a Blalock
shunt in last month.
He was doing fine.
What's your name, ma'am?
Andrea Thompson.
One, two, three.
I'm Carol Hathaway;
this is Dr. Ross.
Give me an armboard
and a 22-gauge Angiocath.
I'll start an I.V.
His surgeon's name is Dr. Luce;
his cardiologist is Ferris;
and his pediatrician is Vargas.
Hook up a 12-lead
and get an echo.
He's on dig, Lasix
and potassium.
Chuny, would you escort
Mrs. Thompson out of here?
No, please, I want to stay.
Carol?
All right, but you
stay back there.
We need to work.
I'm in.
Bolus 100 of saline.
Did he clot off his shunt?
He may have.
Blood gas kit.
What's that for?
Ma'am, I don't have time
to explain everything
to you right now.
She shouldn't be in here.
It's her child.
Chuny, get this up to the lab.
Bullet missed the spine.
Renal artery is intact.
More four by fours...
He's still bleeding.
Let's hang another
unit of O-neg.
Dr. Benton, Carla
Reese on the phone.
She says it's an emergency.
When I'm done.
Damn, this isn't working.
Where's the source?
Soft tissue arterials.
Lost the BP.
Third unit's in.
He's bleeding out.
Maggie, get me a
Foley and some saline.
What are you going to do?
If I insert the Foley
and inflate the balloon,
the pressure might
stop the bleeding.
All right, do it.
Foley going in.
Inject the saline.
Coming right up.
Where did you learn
this one, Carter...
Journal of Trauma?
People magazine.
Story about a little girl
who got stuck in a well
trying to rescue her puppy.
Paramedic thought this up.
What happened to the puppy?
Don't ask.
He's coming around.
All right, let's get
him back over.
I got a pulse.
All right, people, let's
get him up to the OR.
Good work, Carter.
This the gunshot?
Yeah. We'll take it.
Can I scrub in? We've got it.
Actually, Carter
figured out a way
to tamponade the
bleed with a Foley.
He saved the guy's life.
Is that so?
Hold that elevator.
Edson, take his history
and get him prepped.
Let's go.
Can't win them all, Carter.
Man, are you in the doghouse.
Got the blood gas.
7.23, pO2 is 90.
Can't get a BP.
Lost his pulse.
What's wrong?
Chest tube, trays,
tension pneumo.
What are you doing?
Carol, what's happening?
His lung collapsed.
Well, what is he doing?
He's putting in a chest tube.
Why are you cutting him?
Carol, poke a Kelly
in here, will you?
I.V.'s infiltrated.
Have to do a femoral cutdown.
Will somebody tell me what
the hell is going on here?
Cutdown tray, please.
Carol...?
Come with me, Mrs. Thompson.
I'll explain it.
No, I want to stay with my baby.
Not now... the
doctor needs to work.
Come on.
We put a chest tube
in to re-expand his lung,
and now Dr. Ross
is giving Joel fluids
through a catheter in his leg.
When the doctor's
done, can I come back?
Yes, but right now, it's best
if you wait in here, okay?
If he gets sicker, come get me.
I don't want my
baby to die alone.
I will.
Jerry, what are those things?
They're humane traps.
I borrowed them from the lab.
We're trying to trap a mouse.
Can you move
them off the counter?
There's no place to work.
Why don't you just
call an exterminator?
Because the mouse in question
is worth a half a million bucks.
I got a hot one.
Uh, Brenda Smythe.
What's the problem?
Voilà.
My wife and I
were out camping...
I needed to urinate and
I found this old bucket.
Well, let's get Mrs.
Smythe to a room.
Why didn't you go in the bushes?
That's irrelevant.
And you are?
Her husband, John Smythe.
Mark Greene.
Is Joel all right?
His blood pressure's up
and his vitals are good.
Is he conscious?
No, not yet.
I want to talk to the doctor.
He's doing an
echocardiogram right now,
but he told me to tell you
that he's given Joel fluids
and he expects him to regain
consciousness anytime soon.
I want to be there
when he wakes up.
He gets scared
when I'm not there.
I'll come and get you
as soon as Dr. Ross
finishes the test.
Okay?
Is there anything I can get you?
A cup of coffee,
something to eat maybe?
No.
Thank you, Carol.
Okay.
Why'd you let Edson
steal your thunder?
It's not like I had a choice.
You made the save.
When Anspaugh gives an order,
you smile and nod your head.
Man, you couldn't pay me
enough to be a surgeon.
Ah, it's not that bad.
Too cutthroat.
Besides, they're all jerks.
No offense intended.
None taken.
Could you get me some crutches?
I think I saw some in the hall.
Sure.
Carla, I can't just take off.
Can't you call another nurse?
Yeah...
Okay, okay, look,
just calm down.
All right, all
right, I'll be there.
I'll pick up some insulin.
I'm on my way... damn it!
Everything all right?
Listen, I got to go.
Go?
Yeah, if you have any problems,
check with Greene or Weaver.
And do me a favor... go upstairs
and check on my post-ops.
I'll be back in an hour.
Ow!
I'm sorry, Mrs. Smythe.
It seems to be really stuck.
Must have created a vacuum.
What do you
intend to do about it?
I'm thinking, thinking.
Maybe we could
grease up a Foley,
slide it in to
break the suction?
I need a church key.
What? A can opener.
Maybe the kitchen has one.
Um, Miss Wilkerson
has a Swiss army knife.
I thought you said
her name was Smythe.
Pet name.
Ah.
Ah!
Here's your bucket, Mr. Smythe.
Thank you, Doctor.
Carter? What?
It's Gunderson, the gunshot.
You admitted him
through ER, right?
Yep.
He's tachycardic,
BP's down to 60 palp.
Any surgical complications?
No, he was doing fine,
and then he started gasping.
What's he on?
Morphine and Ancef.
His tongue is swollen.
What's going on?
Looks like an allergic reaction.
Where's Edson?
In surgery with Anspaugh.
Okay, let's give epi... Three
mils of one in 10,000 I.V.
Give me a trach kit...
he's in respiratory arrest!
Betadine!
Needle.
Introducer.
Sat's falling.
I'm in... hook him up.
Pull Edson out of surgery.
I want to talk to him now.
BP's up to 80.
Hey, look, the little
guy's waking up.
Hi, Joel.
Don't be afraid, your
mommy's right outside.
He's still got a few PVCs.
Let's give him another
ten of procainamide.
Can we bring the mother back in?
I told her I'd get her.
Wait a few minutes till
the procainamide kicks in.
Carol, I got a
great case for you.
Pseudocyst with
acute pancreatitis.
I can't... I've got to
push some meds.
Let the nurses do that.
Yeah, let us lifers push meds.
You go play doctor.
It's okay... Go
ahead, he's doing fine.
All right, as soon
as he's stable,
bring the mom in.
You got it.
Wait till you see this.
She has the biggest pseudocyst
I've ever appreciated.
Now, they told me
they were going to send
another nurse at 4:00,
but I didn't think that I
should wait that long.
No, no, you did the
right thing by calling me.
Okay, and I'm sorry that
you had to leave work.
It's okay... come on.
Okay, now, pull your robe back.
I have to inject
this in your thigh.
Okay.
How often do I have to do this?
Twice a day.
Okay, now, are you watching?
Mm-hmm.
All right, now, just stick
the needle in... and push.
There you go.
I hate that push part.
Now, do you think
you can do this by
yourself next time?
Why?
Are you going
back to the hospital?
Yeah, I got to get back to work.
Make sure you eat
something in a couple of hours.
You don't want your
blood sugar getting too low.
Oh, gosh.
I'm going to have to
go to the grocery store.
No, no, what are you doing?
You're not supposed
to be on your feet.
What else am I supposed to do?
What about your sister?
Her little one has got strep.
It doesn't matter,
it doesn't matter.
I can be down there
and back in 15 minutes.
No, um...
I'll do it.
Peter, no... You go
back to work, please.
Go back to work.
Carla, I said I'll do it.
Never mind if you're
going to get snippy about it.
Who you calling?
Uh... yeah,
this is Dr. Benton.
Listen, uh, tell Anspaugh
that I had a family emergency.
I'm taking a personal day.
No, no, no, I don't
need to speak to him.
Just, uh, just give him
the message, please.
Thank you.
What happened?
Anaphylaxis.
He almost died.
What did you give him post-op?
Uh, Ancef.
He's allergic to it.
What?
He's allergic to the
antibiotic you gave him.
Didn't you take a history?
I thought you took one.
Don't give me that crap.
Anspaugh told you to do it.
Oh, I took a full history.
Patient never
mentioned any allergies.
Then why is this space
under "allergies" blank?
You better think up
an answer, Dr. Edson.
Anspaugh's going to want one.
Ow!
Just a little bit further.
There we go.
Oh, ah.
All right.
We have an excellent
faculty, Carol...
Two Nobel laureates,
and I'd say you can't
beat our attendings.
What are the primary
causes of acute pancreatitis?
Oh, Kerry, I... uh...
you're putting me
on the spot here.
Well, if you're going
to be a med student,
you better get used to it.
Um... alcohol and gallstones?
Excellent.
Now, you try.
Go on.
You feel the pseudocyst?
I'm not sure.
Sorry. Ow!
Use both hands and press hard.
Ow!
Sorry, sorry.
No, like this.
Ow!
Sorry.
You feel the cyst?
Yeah, I think so.
Order two more units
of blood for the
kid in Trauma 1!
Excuse me, Kerry.
But wait... I want to teach you
how to do an ultrasound.
Sats are falling.
Oh, my God.
He thrombosed his shunt.
I'm trying to repair the graft.
Lost the rhythm.
How long has he been down?
About ten minutes.
Why didn't you get his mother?
Doc said not to.
I'm getting her.
No, I don't want her here.
Doug, I promised.
Carol, I've got this
boy's heart in my hands.
I cannot have her in
here over my shoulder.
I'm getting her.
Is Joel awake?
Come quick.
What happened?
Joel had a blood
clot in his shunt.
It sent him into cardiac arrest.
The doctor had to
cut open his chest.
Oh, my God!
Andrea, it's really
bloody in there.
Are you sure you
want to see this?
Okay, come on.
Time of death?
11:52.
Oh! Oh, my God!
Oh, my God!
I thought he was
going to make it.
Oh, I feel awful.
I promised the mother I
wouldn't let him die alone.
There was no way of
knowing he'd go so fast.
Yeah, but I should
have been there.
Instead, I was off with
Kerry appreciating a cyst.
Dr. Ross, a kid
with a fever in 5.
All right, you want to do this?
Um... no, I'm not done yet.
Andrea, I'm so sorry.
I called the mortuary.
They're on their way.
What am I going to
do with all his clothes?
I can give them to my sister.
Would you like to see him?
Hold him one last time?
The doctor closed his wound.
I have to make a call.
The call can wait.
Andrea, I know this is hard,
but I've learned that parents
need to say good-bye.
Come on.
Don't worry, Mr. McCollum,
I'll have you
stitched up in no time.
Leg hurts like hell.
I'll get you some lidocaine.
Hey, what kind of dump is this?
There's a rat.
That's Jerry's mouse.
Tomorrow, I'm
bringing in my cat.
Board of Health ought
to close this place down.
I sure could use the time off.
What's wrong? My foot.
Are you all right?
Damn it, it's one of Jerry's
stupid traps!
Wendy, grab hold.
On my count... one, two, three.
It... it's not coming.
Where are the wire cutters?
In the suture room.
Tell Jerry to get
these things out of here
before I kill him.
Where's Benton?
He was supposed
to be back hours ago.
I heard he took a personal day.
Dr. Benton?
Carter...
Dale alerted me
that Mr. Gunderson
had a crisis earlier.
I'm glad he told you.
Anyone have his chart?
Yeah, right here.
Hmm...
A nasty little
anaphylactic reaction.
That's right.
You think it was caused by...?
The antibiotic given
post-operatively... Ancef.
Doesn't look like
there's anything
we could have done.
Excuse me?
Patient states
"No known drug allergies."
That your handwriting, Edson?
Uh, yes, sir.
Can I take a look at the chart?
Certainly.
A proper, thorough history...
Best defense
against malpractice.
Good work.
I thought this would
be more comfortable.
Thank you.
Do you want to hold him?
You take all the time you need.
You're back.
Um, he... he got a... a
button stuck up his nose.
Well, that's pretty unusual.
How'd it get there?
I was, you know, just
wiping my nose on my cuff,
and I felt an urge to sneeze,
and I inhaled the button.
The button is still on his cuff.
He changed his shirt.
Perhaps an ear, nose and
throat specialist is in order?
Perhaps not.
Why don't you lie
back, Mr. Smythe.
W... what are you doing, Doctor?
I want you to hold
the unblocked nostril closed
while I put this mask
over your mouth.
Don't worry... It's
not going to hurt.
Haleh, can you hold
the basin under his chin?
All right, just relax.
Oh.
Very impressive.
Uh... may I... may
I keep the button?
Sure.
You sit tight while I get
your discharge papers.
Can you get a Psych
consult down here
before they hurt themselves?
Amen.
I'd go with the
turkey tetrazzini.
Hey, Jackie, how you doing?
What are you doing here?
I'm shopping... What
does it look like?
In the middle of the afternoon?
I took today off.
In your scrubs?
Peter, you never take a day off.
Well, actually, I had to leave.
Carla needed me.
Is she all right?
Yeah, yeah, she just
needs to stay off her feet.
Ooh, boy, are you in trouble.
What? It's just for today.
Her sister couldn't make it.
Yeah, you may
think it's just for today,
but a pregnant woman
needs a lot of help.
When I was pregnant with Steven,
I had Walt cooking
and doing the laundry.
Jackie, it's crazy,
I'm telling you.
I mean, it's like she's
a different woman.
It's just the hormones, honey.
You know, one time...
Walt switched the channel
in the middle of Oprah.
I chased him out of the house
with a croquet mallet.
Yeah, well, I'm losing it.
I'm so proud of you, Peter,
taking the day off to
help her out like this.
Will you be able
to take off more time
from the hospital?
I don't know.
I hadn't thought about that.
Well, start thinking.
Who's Carla going to depend on
if you're not around?
Yeah.
Come on.
Let's go down to
the baby section.
You've got a lot to learn.
Looks like he got
it with an ice pick.
I'll get him undressed.
Carol, let Chuny do that.
No, I got it.
No, I want you
to assess the patient.
Start with the
ABCs, Dr. Hathaway.
His airway is patent.
His breathing shallow,
appearance dusky.
I'll get the intubation tray.
Chuny can do it.
You're going to intubate.
Okay, Carol, take a
deep breath and hold it.
If you run out of breath,
you're taking too long.
Enter laterally,
sweeping the
tongue out of the way.
Don't rock back,
you'll break his teeth.
Can you see the epiglottis?
Mm-hmm.
Good.
Okay, now visualize the cords.
Can you see them?
Pulse ox is falling... 89.
You're doing great, Carol.
Make sure you lift the scope
45 degrees.
Good job.
Let's get him to X ray.
Wow, looks like
Kerry got a new pet.
Stop it, Chuny.
You actually saw her
jam the button up his nose?
And before that, she had
a bucket stuck on her butt.
What do you think's
wrong with them?
Sounds like they're nuts.
Button extraction response time?
Um, 7.5 minutes.
Mr. and Mrs. Smythe,
this is Dr. Pomerantz.
Psychiatric consult, I presume?
Yes.
Well, we've been expecting you.
As you no doubt
have ascertained,
uh, Brenda and I are
not what we appear to be.
What are you?
John Smythe and
Brenda Wilkerson...
Um, clinical researchers.
We're conducting a study
on creative problem-solving
in emergency departments,
and we found that
foreign body extractions
elicited the greatest
range of responses.
Yes, and I must say, Dr. Greene,
you came up with the
most innovative solutions
we've ever seen.
Over at Mercy,
the button in the
nose took five hours
and two consults.
Wait a minute... They
wanted to operate.
Just who is
sponsoring this study?
Uh, an independent consortium
of health care professionals
and, uh... those in government.
The highest levels
of government.
No promises,
but, uh, you might be
contacted by... HRC.
Hillary.
Oh...
Oh, well... if she ever gets
her ass stuck in a bucket,
she'll know who to call.
Well, I'll tell her you said so.
Okay.
What are you doing down here?
Hiding.
Me, too.
You're a smoker!
A secret smoker.
Don't tell anyone.
So who died?
What?
Why the long face?
Edson falsified a
chart to cover his ass.
You're kidding.
Forgot to take
a patient history.
Patient almost died
from an allergic reaction.
Anspaugh must have
roasted his butt for that.
I didn't tell him.
You didn't?
Would you have?
Hell, yeah.
I mean, changing
a chart is unethical,
not to mention illegal.
Surgeons don't
rat on each other.
You know, it's
like the marines...
"All for one, and one for all."
That's the Three Musketeers.
You know what I mean.
No, you got to be... you
got to be a team player.
Anspaugh gave me
that lecture last week.
I think you're scared.
Well, we'll be in touch.
Bye, Super Doc.
Bye. Bye.
What a couple of kooks.
They can make you famous.
Please.
What... you could be
known at "the highest levels"
as the most innovative
doctor in the country.
Tell that to my daughter.
What'd you do now?
I stood up her Brownie troop.
Yikes.
I just can't seem
to get it together.
You mean to tell me
that "super doc"
can't figure out a way
to keep his Brownie commitments?
Carol, we've got an
intoxicated gentleman
who needs an NG tube.
You interested?
Wait, wait.
You can't go in there.
Why not? There's a free bed.
This woman needs to be alone.
Her child died today.
Your compassion is
admirable, Carol, but we've got
a board full of
patients we can save.
We need to put them somewhere.
Treat the drunk in the hall.
The drunk is a patient, too.
You've done it before, Kerry.
When there were
no beds available.
Well, there aren't any beds now.
Carol, if you're going
to be a med student,
you've got to stop
thinking like a nurse.
Well, I'm not a med student yet.
CBC chem seven.
Type and cross for four.
Hey, Maggie.
Is this the surgical belly?
Yeah, but I already
called upstairs.
I didn't know you
were down here.
Might as well get started.
What's the story?
Painter fell off his scaffold,
did a 20-foot belly flop
onto a Volvo.
They say Volvos
are the safest cars.
All right, Edson,
start a central line.
Carter, do a peritoneal lavage.
I'll get the DPL kit.
Carter...
what are the criteria
for a positive diagnostic
peritoneal lavage?
Red blood cell count
greater than 100,000,
white blood cell
count greater than 500.
And if you can read a newspaper
through the
fluid, it's negative.
I love those little pearls.
So, Dale, weren't you
going to give Dr. Anspaugh
some new information
about Mr. Gunderson?
John filled me in.
What? The patient with
the allergic reaction?
Is there more to it?
Uh, as a matter of fact,
I called Mr. Gunderson's mother
and briefed her
on the situation,
and she'll be flying
in from Louisville.
Good... looking
after the patient's
emotional state.
Is that it?
That's it.
Really? John said
there was more.
Something I should know about?
Um...
No.
DPL is positive.
I'm in.
All right, let's get
him up to surgery.
Edson, we'll start
with an ex-lap.
If he needs a splenectomy,
you'll do it.
Let's move him.
Well, you sure told him.
Liar, liar, pants on fire.
Save it.
So they teach
forgery at Harvard?
Go to hell.
What'd you say?
Look, John, all I did was
make an adjustment to a chart.
Is that such a big deal?
I don't know, why don't you
run it by Anspaugh,
see what he thinks?
I can't do that.
Sure you can.
Look, if this goes on my record,
my chances for a
fellowship are zilch.
You going to make me tell him?
John...
please.
I'll do anything you want.
I'll put in a good
word with Anspaugh,
anything.
Look, I'll make it up to you.
I don't want to have
anything to do with you.
If you ever try
anything like this again,
I'll bury you.
That's a promise.
These are resuscitation paddles.
If someone's heart
stops beating normally
or has a strange rhythm,
we zap them with
a surge of electricity
to get it going, like...
It's kind of like Frankenstein.
Mark, got an MVA coming in.
Kerry's got it, but
we need the room.
All right, who wants
to go look at blood cells
under the microscope?
I do!
All right, let's go to the lab.
Thanks, Dad.
Very creative.
So I've been told.
How would you like to go out
with the most innovative
doctor in the world?
I would be honored.
You like bowling?
"Like" may be too strong a word.
I got to take Rachel.
Maybe Emma could come, too.
Oh, it's that kind of date.
Well, that's the best I can do.
Guess I'll just have
to dust off my bowling shoes.
You own bowling shoes?
There's all sorts of things
you don't know about me, Doctor.
Thank you, Carol, for letting me
have this time with my baby.
Is there someone I can call?
My sister's on her way.
I used to say this prayer
with Joel every night:
"Now I lay me down to sleep,
"I pray the Lord
my soul to keep.
"If I should die before I wake,
I pray the Lord
my soul to take."
Oh...
You think I'm a coward?
Who am I to say?
I'm not a surgeon.
You guys got your own rules.
Maybe that's just a load of
crap and I'm hiding behind it.
I don't know what to do.
Maybe you should
talk to another surgeon.
Yeah, right.
They're all so empathetic.
There's got to be somebody
whose judgment you trust.
You think I should
talk to Benton?
I would.
How about a Heinie?
Beer?
I keep a couple in the
back for when I get off work.
You know... you're great.
So are you.
Seriously.
I mean, you're honest...
you're funny...
you're beautiful.
I don't suppose that you...
Not a chance.
Cheers.
These things cost
60 bucks apiece.
Who's going to pay for this?
Take it out of your reward.
No trap, no mouse, no reward.
He's under there.
She's under there?
Oh, no!
You killed her.
I didn't mean to.
She's still breathing.
She is?
How much is that reward?
Five grand.
Wendy, get a
pediatric O2 mask...
The smallest you can find...
And five cc's of Dopram.
And hurry!
Jerry, start mouth-to-mouth
resuscitation.
You're kidding.
I worked for a
vet in high school.
I saw a resuscitated guinea pig.
I'm not breathing
in a rat's mouth.
All right, I will, but
we're splitting the reward.
Hook the mask
up to five liters O2.
She moved!
I think she's going
to be all right.
I'll just take her
back up to the lab.
Nothing doing.
Give me the rat.
I'm taking her back
and collecting our reward.
Well, 50-50, right?
Wrong, I'll give you ten percent
for being in the room
while we resuscitated her.
Take it or leave it.
Damn it!
I'm heading out.
Is Dr. Benton
coming in tomorrow?
Yes, he asked for
his surgery schedule
and copies of his
patients' charts.
We're sending them
over by messenger.
Is this them?
Yep.
Hmm, must have moved.
Tell you what...
Cancel your messenger.
I'll take these to him myself.
I have to talk to him anyway.
Lily, are you up for
Crockett's after work?
It's nurses' night.
Sure, I'm in. Me, too.
Chuny, how about you?
Be there or be square.
Hey, I hear you intubated
a guy like a pro today.
Oh, yeah.
Kerry's been trying to
show me things all day long.
Made me feel
just like a beginner.
You know, the truth is
I'm really, really
good at my job.
So why do I want to change that?
Watch me, Mom.
Yes.
Good try, honey.
What's the score?
That would be 2-1 still.
Oh, we could be here all night.
Did you get all your
paperwork done?
Uh, I am going to
be up late tonight,
but I can access my
patient reports on-line, so...
figured it's worth it.
Easy, easy, honey.
Yikes.
So, think they're
getting along okay?
Uh-huh.
I think there's something there.
Yeah?
I thought maybe we
should do this more often.
Next time without kids.
You read my mind.
That's my job.
Dad!
I got one!
That is great.
That is really great.
There we go... it's 2-2.
One plate of spaghetti
marinara al dente.
Yes.
Just one plate?
Yeah... hospital is
sending over some charts,
so I got to, uh... go home
and prepare for
tomorrow's cases.
Why don't you do it here?
I don't have my books.
Well, I'm going to need
another shot in an hour.
Yeah, that's why I
taught you how to do it.
Fine.
Just go home.
Look, Carla...
um...
Honey, I can't be
here all the time.
You said you
wanted to be involved.
I am.
Sure.
On your terms, as always.
You ever think
about what I need, what I want?
You never asked me what I want.
What is that supposed to mean?
Nothing, baby.
Look, just drop it.
Uh-uh.
You never wanted this baby.
What are you talking
about? I didn't say that.
That's what you meant.
Just go home, because
I don't need you here
doing me no damn favors.
What?
Hey, Carla.
It's for you.
Carter, what are you doing here?
I just came to drop these by.
Oh, thank you.
Good night, Carter.
Three in the corner.
All right.
Hey, girl, didn't
expect to see you here.
It's nurses' night out, right?
I thought Weaver
was already fitting you
for a lab coat.
Yeah, well, white
adds ten pounds.
I think I'll stick to pink.
You having second
thoughts about med school?
Well, let's just say I
really like what I do.
Another round?
You bet.
I'll get it.
All right!
You want to play?
Sure.
Come on, girl.
It's a quarter a ball.
I think I can handle that.
Go for it.
All right.
What am I, stripes?
Solid.
Two in the corner.
All right.
Hey, all right!
Whoo-hoo!
♪ Everyday, I write the book ♪
♪ Everyday ♪
♪ Everyday, I
write the book... ♪