You made your point, now
how about letting us do our job?
Our point will be made when your
company stops tearing down this mountain.
Then who's gonna
feed our kids? You?
If you really cared
about your kids,
you'd want them to have air
to breathe when they grow up.
What did you say,
you son of a bitch?
You guys aren't the problem.
You're being hurt
more than anyone.
You breathe in that coal dust...
Coal is the dirtiest
energy on Earth.
Gonna need some backup.
Not enough for you thugs
to assault the environment?
Doug, please, don't.
Susan? Susan, you okay?
She needs to get to a hospital.
She's just dehydrated. We have
medics here. Let them give her fluids.
She has no pulse.
Either unhook your arm
or I'm gonna break it off.
Either way, this
protest is over.
The protest is over, come on!
All right.
What happened? You passed out.
It's okay. Just dehydrated.
You know we'll be
back. We'll be back!
Hey, stop screwing around.
I'm not screwing
around. I just can't...
I can't stand up.
I need to push back our getaway.
No, you don't. I found you a
board, perfect size to learn on.
I'm just postponing.
O'Neil, from Philly General,
wants me to get a
patient in to see House.
So?
I owe him a favor.
He's taken about a dozen of
my referrals over the last year.
I meant, so, that's five
seconds to hand House the file,
30 for him to question
your real motives,
a minute for witty comments
comparing the length of
your legs to Thirteen's...
Plenty of time left
over for the shore.
I need to make sure he
doesn't toss the file in the trash
as soon as I'm out of sight.
Babe, can't you repay
the favor on another case?
After last week, I could really
use a break from this place.
We both could.
Once I'm sure he's
really on the case,
then we're out of here.
And these legs, and every
other part of me, will be all yours.
He's seen three
different specialists.
Interesting.
Almost as interesting as you
trying to step into Kutner's shoes
just days after he
stepped out of them.
I am not shoe shopping,
I'm just trying to repay a
favor to his referring doctor.
What's the mystery?
The nutcase spends all his free time
wreaking havoc at toxic waste dumps.
Tox screen's negative.
No neurological, muscular or
cardiovascular abnormalities.
The guy cares about the
environment, that makes him a nutcase?
He's a single guy in his 20s,
he cares about getting
his hybrid waxed by girls
who care about the environment.
See? Not a nutcase.
He's probably just faking
so he can sue the cops
and get a six-figure settlement.
If he was trying
to fake an illness,
why would he consent to be seen by
the best diagnostician in the country?
Now look who's trying
to get her hybrid waxed.
We need to do a
vestibular caloric test,
see if the balance problem
starts above or below the neck.
And when I say "we," I mean you.
You're the one with a
favor to repay, not them.
I'm going to be injecting
ice-water in your ear canal.
If the resulting eye
movements are at all erratic,
then the balance
problem's in your inner ear.
Those in every room?
I think so.
Can you get rid of them?
Preferably from every room?
They use over 30 pesticides
to grow commercial flowers.
You'd think the medical
industry would be a lot more...
Concerned with medicine?
Let's fix your body, then you
can go back to fixing the Earth.
This is gonna get a
little uncomfortable.
I just spent 14 hours
chained to a tire.
Most doctors would recommend...
Our planet's headed
for destruction.
Coastlines underwater,
a million species extinct.
Whoa! Feels like I'm
tumbling head over heels.
It's normal. Sometimes
this test causes vertigo
and nausea.
Cameron just brought me a case.
Cameron is happy in the ER.
There's no way she wants her
nose back on your grindstone.
Egg-white omelet, no
bacon, whole-wheat toast.
I say it's not my
grindstone she's after,
and not her nose
she wants on it.
She and Chase are
practically living together.
What did you just order?
An omelet.
Since when do you
pass on the swine?
And wheat toast? Might as
well eat a sheet of sandpaper.
Yes, but I don't like eating the
same thing two days in a row.
Your bro's nurse not
loving the love handles?
I'm just not in the
mood for bacon,
and you are obviously trying
to avoid talking about Kutner,
which is odd because you spent a
whole week obsessing about why...
He's no longer on my team.
I'm sorry he's no
longer on my team.
There's nothing
else to talk about.
You're wearing the watch
he gave you for Secret Santa.
Five functions,
including a stopwatch
to time how long it takes
you to ask me if I'm okay.
You gonna order?
Not hungry.
It's just weird. She's
brought cases before,
but he's never made
her run the tests.
Maybe he's looking for someone
to mother him after what happened.
The only kind of
mothering House wants
involves a bullwhip, leather
diapers and a credit card.
Mommy's home.
Test made the patient lose his
lunch, but his calorics are normal,
his inner ear is fine and
he still can't balance himself.
How many normal
test results do we need
to know the patient's
a granola-filled phony?
He's not lying
about his symptoms.
And you know this because...
She changed her shoes.
If he was faking, he'd have
vomited on the other side of the bed.
Sparring with the police and chaining
yourself up for days can cause stress.
Stress screws with
the heart and arteries.
Carotid atherosclerosis
could cause a loss of balance.
Wouldn't show up on CT or MRI.
It could also be our only
warning before a massive stroke.
Do a Holter and
a carotid doppler,
see if his heart skips for
more than the Spotted Owl.
Although I didn't
say "we," if I had...
Sorry if this is
screwing up the test.
Been hiccupping a lot
lately, but not as bad as this.
How much is a lot?
And how long is lately?
It's been on and
off for about a week.
Maybe a few hours a day.
Did you tell the doctors
in Philly about it?
They didn't seem to
think it was any big deal.
Hey, so we're still leaving
tomorrow, aren't we?
I'm not sure.
The referring doctors didn't
realize that his hiccups were...
Hiccups?
With this duration and
intensity, most likely pathological,
and it could mean it's serious.
Are you avoiding me?
No.
So, I shouldn't be
at all concerned
that you're treating another
doctor's patient for hiccups
instead of going on the
vacation I spent a week planning?
There is a reason I need to
stay with this case a while longer,
but I can't tell you what it is.
So, you admit you lied to me,
now you're asking me to trust you.
Yes.
Okay.
No sign of heart
or arterial problems,
but he's been hiccupping
on and off for over a week.
Nice. I'm hooked. You can
get back to your shift at the ER,
except, as far as the ER is
concerned, you're on vacation, right?
I postponed a trip because
I'm concerned about the patient.
Explains why you ditched Chase
and came to the differentials,
not why you ran the tests.
You told me to.
Well, I'm not your boss,
something you usually take
great pleasure in pointing out.
Hey, you don't still have
the hots for me, do you?
I care about the patient and I care
about the people who work on your team,
they've been
through a lot lately.
I just thought I... Was
Florence Nightingale
and you're gonna nurse us back
to spiritual and mental oneness.
That would make sense if we were
having this conversation a week ago.
Think what you want,
that I'm here to get a job,
that I'm here to wrap
you in swaddling clothes.
Problem is, I think neither.
Because neither makes sense.
The only thing
that does, doesn't.
Pathological hiccups
plus inability to balance, go.
What she said.
Brain would connect the two.
It could if Cameron hadn't
already CT'd his head.
Empty as her
boyfriend's calendar.
What does this have
to do with Chase?
Nothing. Not sure yet.
Patient is on a jihad
against commercial flowers,
he's picketed several nurseries.
Organophosphate poisoning
can cause both hiccups and...
No GI problems,
no hypersalivation.
It's possible it's not
connected to a protest.
MS wouldn't show on the
CT, and his name is Swenson.
Scandinavians have an
increased susceptibility to MS.
Better theory than,
"He's faking it."
The clogs have it. Do a
lumbar puncture to confirm MS.
I guess we'll just continue
to twiddle our thumbs.
God, I hope that's a euphemism.
How am I supposed
to do a lumbar puncture
on a patient with
intractable hiccups?
I'm trying to figure out what
that could be a euphemism for.
You'll find a way.
You're not worried House is gonna be
pissed you're helping me do the test?
He said find a way, and you did.
How do you think House is doing?
That why you're here?
Yeah.
No, it isn't.
Even if House was messed up by
Kutner's suicide, it wouldn't matter.
He already thinks life is
nasty, brutish and long,
and misery helps
his diagnostic skills.
All of which you know,
so, why are you here?
Which answer would you believe?
If you want Kutner's
place, it's fine by me.
I could use someone else with
the stones to stand up to House.
But you've got to know that's gonna
blow up your relationship with Chase.
All I did was postpone
a three-day trip.
With Chase, to be with House.
What are you doing?
Ordering IV chlorpromazine.
This could still
be neurological.
You can cloud his mental status.
You wanna get the needle in
his spine or you wanna talk?
You and House been talking
about filling Kutner's slot?
Yeah, we went straight from
the funeral to Human Resources.
You interested in
getting back on the team?
I'm interested in knowing
if Cameron's interested.
She's been running all
the tests for House's case.
Well, she hasn't
said anything to me.
But I guess the referring doctor might
have asked her to keep an eye on him.
Do you think Cameron's
in love with House?
That is a ridiculous question.
She's in love with you.
Are you in love with House?
That is an even more
ridiculous question.
Two questions, zero answers.
I think I can
extrapolate from there.
Dr. House?
Sorry, I'm just the
zone delivery guy.
I'm Doug Swenson's wife.
His history said the
environmental kamikaze was single.
He probably didn't
want me to worry.
He told me he was in jail with
some of the other protesters.
Yeah, well, no worries there.
He's in jail a lot. Not
so often in the hospital.
I searched his e-mail, and I
found the referral to you yesterday.
You must really love your
husband, and travel by rickshaw.
Only took you 18
hours to get here.
Who eats kale? It's so bland
it doesn't even taste like kale.
I had to find somebody to
take care of our 4-year-old son.
Doug's all right, isn't he?
I have no idea.
I know he's an idiot,
and now I've learned that
he's a liar, so we're making...
Who told you that I was in here?
The doctor in the office next to
yours said that you might be here.
I got it figured out.
That mean we don't
need to do the LP?
I was talking to her. You're
not even supposed to be here.
You want us to stop or not?
What? I don't care
what you do with him.
You're not doing a
favor for a doctor in Philly,
you're doing a favor for an
oncologist in North Jersey.
I'm spying on you for Wilson?
Spying, pre-emptive
grief counseling...
Wilson sees you 10 times
more than I do, he's a better liar,
and he wouldn't have to
cancel a vacation to do it.
Good points. Also
doesn't explain the diet.
What does any of this
have to do with my husband?
Nothing.
Meet Mrs. Environmental Nutbag,
or did you keep your maiden name?
He's married?
Yep. Got a kid, too.
Double threat, eco-freak
and deadbeat dad.
House!
Sorry, parentally challenged.
No, his neck.
It's torticollis, reaction
to the chlorpromazine.
That's not just a
spasm, it's swollen.
Crunchy.
It's definitely not MS.
Crunching sounds were caused
by an air leak between his lungs.
The leak in his mediastinum could've
been caused by prolonged hiccups.
More likely it was
the neck spasm.
Most likely it was
there all along.
We just didn't notice until the
other symptoms made it worse.
So, what causes loss of
balance, pathological hiccups,
and a hole in his
Gloria Steinem?
He was protesting
a lumber mill last fall.
Sarcoid's been
linked to pine forests.
No, his AC levels are normal.
Progressive systemic sclerosis?
Guy practically lives
in industrial waste sites.
If a solvent got absorbed through his
lungs, caused an autoimmune firestorm...
Start him on IV methylprednisolone
for systemic sclerosis.
Do a full work-up to confirm.
By myself? Without yourself.
Grab a bat. Grab some pine.
Time to bring
in the first string.
Why?
You obviously want to be
here. I can't figure out why.
So I want to see where you
go when you can't be here.
You know what
vacation means, right?
You here because of House,
Chase, or overtime issues?
He's very concerned.
Chase, not House.
If it's all right with you,
I'd rather communicate with
Chase by communicating with Chase.
Are you in love with House?
You are not concerned about me.
You're marking your territory.
You shouldn't be
involved with House,
neither should I,
neither should anyone.
You and Chase are good
together. Don't screw it up.
When are you gonna stop this?
How can you ask me to stop?
You're in a hospital.
You have a son.
The steroids ought to get
him breathing normally again.
But autoimmune
diseases are serious.
Might not be a bad idea to
take some time at home, rest up.
I can't just quit.
Do you hate us that much?
I love you, and I love our son.
But why should he matter
more than everyone else's?
He does.
Why?
Because he's biologically
connected to me?
There's no rational reason.
He's our son.
And he's going to need to drink
clean water and breathe clean air.
I'm doing this for him, too.
Come on in, House.
Because who else is it
going to be at 10:30 at night?
And, no, thanks, I already ate.
I didn't ask you to dinner.
But you were going to.
And when I explained
that I'd eaten hours ago,
you were going to move
on to your real entree,
rifling through my kitchen.
Hmm.
Inviting me to
search your kitchen.
Means you know
that I'd find nothing,
or you know that
I'd find something,
so you're hoping that I'm gonna assume
the former and I won't bother to look.
Or it means it's
late, I'm tired,
I know you're here to
advance some paranoid theory
based on a single egg-white
omelet, and I'd like to get it over with
so we can both go to sleep.
Your single-omelet theory
conveniently overlooks the
grassy knoll you had for lunch today,
a vegetable and
grain gag-a-thon.
The Warren Commission found
no evidence of a second lunch,
possibly because it was
stolen from the doctors' lounge.
You're not getting any fatter,
your medical records were clean.
You checked my...
You're alone
tonight, so it's Kutner.
How could Kutner
have any conceivable...
Your patients live,
your patients die,
you float above it all
like a medical colossus.
But a fellow doctor dies...
That's brilliant.
Kutner was a wake-up call
that if I didn't eat healthier,
I might kill myself.
Mortality is mortality.
And ice cream is ice cream.
Full-fat content.
Quadruple-fat content.
Stuff you haven't eaten just
proves you haven't eaten it.
You were hoping for
evidence of stuff I have eaten?
First door on the right.
Excruciating
pain in his left leg.
Acute onset, about
10 minutes ago.
What are you doing to him?
I assume they were
checking for vascular pulsation.
Either it's negative
or he's a big wuss.
It's not a tumor or an aneurysm.
Metabolic bone disease?
Bone density's normal.
But the bone
covering might not be.
If it's osteomyelitis, an infection
eating away at his periosteum...
Explains the pain. Odds
are it's a subclinical infection
that we made worse with
the steroids we gave him.
Start him on IV antibiotics, x-ray
his legs to confirm osteomyelitis.
Cameron's already done a
full set of lower body x-rays.
Infection obviously
flared, do them again.
Even if I had changed my diet,
what possible reason could
I have for hiding it from you?
Ankle, tibia, fibula,
all look normal.
No inflammation,
no signs of osteo.
Hang in there,
we're almost done.
You and your wife,
you talk about stuff?
Sex.
No. Anything else.
Money.
I'm gonna go way
out on a limb here.
Foreman not a Chatty Cathy?
Normally, it doesn't
matter. Last week, it did.
You want to date men, good
chance talking won't be...
His femur's fractured.
That's impossible. It's the
hardest bone in the body.
And he broke it lying in bed.
How can you have a broken
femur without so much as a bruise?
Whatever broke it
had to do it from within.
Osteogenesis imperfecta?
Brittle bones wouldn't
cause hiccups,
plus we'd have seen
abnormal coloring in the sclerae.
Which leaves cancer.
Since when does bone
cancer cause hiccups?
Which means it's a bone cancer.
Or it's not cancer.
House is right. It'd be hard to
find a guy outside Chernobyl
who'd been exposed
to more carcinogens,
pesticide plants,
nuclear waste sites.
Tell Chase to repair the break.
You two prep him for chemo.
You want to blast him with chemo for
a cancer we don't even know he has?
No. I want to blast him with chemo for
a cancer that explains the symptoms.
Intramedullary nail.
Hold on.
That your House imitation?
Some late-breaking epiphany?
Just need you to get a bone
biopsy before you insert the pin.
For a broken leg?
House is prepping him for chemo.
Thought it might be worth checking for
cancer before pumping him full of poison.
Does Cameron agree with House?
Cameron's not on
the case anymore.
Oh.
Still enjoying
your day off, I see.
Why are you prepping
him for chemo?
The more interesting
question is, why do you care?
You're not even
sure that it's...
What I mean is, why
do you care from here?
You can monitor the
patient from home.
What's the difference
between here and home?
You're not at my home.
This has nothing to do with...
Any other differences?
Hmm.
There's less medical
equipment, more training bras,
and more Vegemite sandwiches.
Actually, technically,
right now Chase is here,
but that's because I called
him and you didn't know that,
and it's irrelevant to my point,
which is you and Chase are over.
You are wrong.
You decided that his single drawer
of clothes is one drawer too many.
But you don't have
the guts to tell him,
so you're emotionally walking away
instead of actually walking away,
which is stupid because only
one of those is good for your heart.
He's gonna ask me to marry him.
I was looking for some
thick socks, found the ring.
And you want to say no.
So I circle right back to his
single drawer of clothes...
I don't want to say anything.
I don't want him to ask.
Not now.
Kutner... We're all
a little freaked out.
We go home, we just
want to hug someone.
We just want to know
everything's gonna be okay.
I don't want him to propose
just because he's scared.
Oh.
She's got a headache, fever,
she's completely exhausted.
Tell him about
your chest, honey.
Her breasts are really tender.
You guys have a hot tub?
No.
So you must go to the gym a lot?
Not in years.
But maybe when you travel
on business, you zip on down
to that complimentary hotel spa.
No.
Sorry, did you just say yes?
What the hell is wrong with her?
Got a minute?
He doesn't. What's
wrong with her?
Sorry, I'm sure she's
got a medical crisis,
and I need more time to figure out
some leading questions for your wife.
What's going on with Cameron?
She doesn't want back on my team,
and she doesn't want to jump me.
Okay.
What?
You ask a question, I rule out two
possibilities, and you're satisfied?
That means you
don't want an answer,
you just wanted to know
there wasn't a particular answer.
Either you were worried that
she wanted back on my team
or you were worried
she wanted back on me.
This isn't a
medical crisis, is it?
Could be. A lot of STDs
hang in the balance.
I give up. Vinegar
compresses four times a day.
Any chance I could
just leave it at that?
No. Pseudomonas folliculitis.
It's a skin infection from crowded
and contaminated hot tubs,
which you obviously use,
but not with your husband.
Tried to help a sister out.
The nuclei were
all normal-sized,
bone cells are
well-differentiated.
No dysplasia means no cancer.
That's good, isn't it?
We hope so, although it also means we
still have no idea what caused the break.
How does it feel?
It hurts.
Is it supposed
to look like that?
No, but it's probably just
residual bleeding from the surgery.
We should be able to...
Need two units
of FFP, right away.
Oh, my God. What's happening?
He's bleeding out.
Means it's gotta be cancer.
It's gotta be, except it's not.
The biopsy was negative.
Biopsies can be
wrong, symptoms can't.
All signs point to cancer, but you
can't blast a cancer you can't find.
Sure you can. Prep him
for total-body irradiation.
You do realize that's insane.
Not unless you think the cancer's
cleverly hiding outside his body.
Steroids already weakened
his immune system.
That much radiation will kill
him before it kills the cancer.
And if he doesn't have
cancer, we could cause one,
or destroy his immune
system altogether.
The guy could die
from an infected toenail.
So you'd rather do nothing,
just let him die on his own?
I'd rather make
his cancer worse.
Give him insulin-like growth factor,
make any tumor or malignancy grow.
Grows big enough,
we can find it.
That's like pouring
gasoline on a fire.
At least total-body irradiation
is an actual treatment.
His idea is better. Pour away.
I've lost my mojo.
Have you retraced your steps?
Does your cleaning lady
check your pockets before...
I was clueless about Kutner,
I was wrong about Cameron,
Taub just came up with an idea that I
should have seen long before he did.
No one saw anything
coming with Kutner,
you hardly ever see
Cameron anymore,
and you hired Taub to come up with
ideas that you wouldn't have come up with.
And I have no idea
why you're eating carrots.
Good.
I'm losing my mind, all
you got to say is, "Good"?
House, a guy you worked with
for two years, who you mentored,
and, yes, possibly even cared
about, just blew his brains out.
You can't find the reason,
can't find the meaning in it,
because sometimes
there isn't any.
Sometimes this is all there is.
You should be losing it.
You'd be crazy not
to be off your game.
But your mojo's
right where you left it.
Just keep playing with it.
I gotta go. Help yourself.
I know this is a tough process.
At the first sign of any
tumors or masses we can...
Start saying prayers?
It's gonna be okay. Once we
can... No, it is not gonna be okay.
You're growing his cancer.
This isn't the doctors' fault.
I've exposed myself to a lot
of bad stuff. I knew the risks.
I want my life to
mean something,
and if that means
I'm destined to...
He's in V-tach, and no
pulse. Grab the paddles.
Oh, God.
Charging. Clear.
I've been looking for you.
And I've been
thinking about you.
Just hadn't reached
the looking stage yet.
Which is the problem.
You asked for a
day, I gave you two.
You told me you had a secret
you couldn't share, I respected that.
Now I don't know what's worse,
blowing off our vacation
to hang around House,
or continuing to blow it off
when he won't hang around you.
If you think I'm the least
bit interested in House...
I don't know what
I'm supposed to think.
I know this looks bad and...
I don't care how it
looks, I care what it is.
And you're not
telling me what it is.
I'm trying to trust you, but...
I just...
I need a little more time.
No.
This has nothing
to do with House.
Yeah, well, it has nothing to
do with me either, not anymore.
Let me know when I can
come pick up my things.
Nothing on the echo.
We drew a troponin level,
no signs of myocardial ischemia.
All the tests were normal.
Loss of balance, pathological
hiccups, air leak between the lungs,
broken femur, now
tachycardia. Go.
Come on, give me
something. Give me a bad idea,
maybe I can turn
it into a good one.
Fine. Open him up,
put in a defibrillator.
That's permanent and risky.
We don't even know what, if
anything, is wrong with his heart.
Redo all the tests.
In the meantime, open
him up, put in a defibrillator,
so he can live long enough
for you to finish the tests.
Balance organs, nerves,
lungs, bones, heart.
Things you use
to make bratwurst?
There's no sign of infection,
it's not a metabolic or
autoimmune disease.
It's definitely not
cancer. I think.
Definitely not cancer.
Aren't you gonna pick?
I'm thinking. Is
there a ticking clock?
You already put your money in.
You never do that
until you decide.
That's very observant of you.
Too bad you distracted me. Now
I'm thinking I might change my mind.
There's nothing
healthy in that machine.
No, there's not.
Gummi Bears. You
hate Gummi Bears.
People can change.
No.
And more importantly,
I hate them.
Oh, fine. Then I
won't offer you any.
You manipulative bitch.
You're not suddenly eating
healthy because you want to.
You're eating healthy because
you know I don't want to.
I've been mooching
food for 10 years,
so either something started
bothering you this week or you're...
Screwing with you.
It needed to be done.
After Amber died, I withdrew,
tried to change everything,
hoping I'd sort it out,
find some deeper truth.
It was a mistake.
I should have gone back
to normal, to here and now.
Because that's all we
can ever really count on.
Things need to get
back to normal in your life.
And what could be more
normal than me screwing with you,
and you figuring it out?
You manipulative bitch.
We need to put in a
cardioverter defibrillator.
It'll keep your heart beating
while we keep looking.
What does that mean?
It means, even if
we figure this out,
you'll have to stop protesting
anywhere not near a hospital.
Hi. Got a few questions.
We're about to start doing...
A hopefully pointless
medical procedure.
Your life and my mojo
hang in the balance.
Pesticides are evil, which means that
commercial flowers are doused in evil,
but plant life is
nature's answer to evil.
So you have a garden.
No. We live in an apartment.
A window box then?
No.
Potted plants?
Nothing. The
commercial growers...
Yeah, they're
evil. Yeah, got it.
House, I really don't
think we have time for this.
Your marriage sucks.
Thank you.
All marriages suck.
Your marriage sucks.
No. I love her.
He loves a tree in Oregon
more than he loves you,
but he can't have sex with it.
Unless it's that slutty
oak outside Portland.
You want to get to your point?
She's had enough.
She's gonna leave, maybe
she's just not putting out, whatever.
You gotta make it
right. Right away.
You gotta compromise
that precious flower principle.
Never.
Once.
Three weeks ago.
Our anniversary.
I missed the dinner
to be at that rally.
You planned it for months.
You were mad, really mad.
I bought you flowers.
I brought them home.
You were gone, so
was your suitcase.
I tossed them, bought
you the earrings.
Roses?
Yes.
You have sporotrichosis. It's an
infection from the thorn of the rose,
which by any other name
is still a cheap marital aid.
The flowers are what gave me...
Lesion on your eighth cranial
nerve knocks out your balance,
another on your phrenic
nerve gives you serial hiccups.
We then spread it to your
bones and heart with steroids
and insulin-like growth factor.
Please tell us that
this is good news.
It's good news for him, it's
good news for future generations.
It's crappy news for
you. He's gonna be fine.
And he'll never
doubt himself again.
There you go.
Damn. I was hoping
to interrupt something.
Your favor's repaid,
patient's cured.
He's already packing for another
Earth Day extravaganza next week.
He almost died. He can't take a
few days at home with his family?
People only change after a trauma if
they wanted to change before the trauma.
Or if they've watched too
many After School Specials.
You talking about Chase?
I'm talking about you.
You lost husband number one, no
surprise that the death of a colleague
would make you question
another long-term lease.
You teaching commitment classes?
'Cause I thought you were
too busy with your lecture...
I'm sure that was
going to be hysterical.
Let me just give
you the Cliff Notes.
Don't try to dump him
by dumping cases on me.
I told you, I never
wanted to dump Chase.
Absolutely. You
wanted him to dump you.
It's totally different,
much less guilt.
Either way, you're out
of reasons to avoid him.
Kutner was a pretty
dumb one to begin with.
I should never have
postponed our vacation.
I should never have planned it.
I found the ring in your sock.
I didn't want you to propose out
of some sort of knee-jerk reaction
to what happened to Kutner.
Well, I guess you don't have
to worry about that anymore.
I'm not. I...
I don't care how it happens,
I just want it to happen.
Are you proposing to me?
I'm proposing that
you propose to me.
After I broke up with you? After
you ruined my planned proposal?
You expect me to...
I'm not expecting.
I'm hoping.
Yes.
Solved another case,
busted Wilson.
Looks like you're
not losing it after all.