Previously on "ER.."
We're gonna take care
of you.
‐ Oh, God.
‐ What?
Are you questioning
my commitment
to this patient's
best interests?
‐ I got it under control.
‐ Yeah.
So does every
street junkie that I see
that comes
through this place.
Greg Powell. I'm the paramedic
who brought in the boy
who got stuck
in the chimney.
If you don't let me draw some
blood the easy way
They'll get every nurse
in here to hold you down
and they'll draw it
the hard way.
He simply wants to keep
an eye on me.
Don't you, Dr. Benton?
Whew! Hey. I hope that's not
all you're wearing.
It's got to be
ten below out there.
What?
How you hide all that
hair in that hat.
Must be the Eighth
Wonder of the world.
Oh, you laugh away, Elvis.
I can't believe they give me
the coldest day of the year
to do my paramedic
ride‐along.
I'm going to go
regrout the tub
and then I'm gonna
watch some daytime TV.
Springer's doing a special
on teens impregnated
by transvestites.
‐ Get out of here.
‐ Alright.
‐ Dearborn and Clark. 5 o'clock.
‐ Mm‐hmm.
‐ I wrote it down.
‐ Okay. Fine.
You know, I really
hate surprises.
I'd‐I'd like for you to
tell me what it is.
You know, I can't 'cause
I really love surprises.
Alright, then.
Dearborn and Clark at 5 o'clock.
‐ Okay. Hey.
‐ Hmm?
Say it.
Say what?
You know what I..
What I always say first.
You say it.
‐ I love you.
‐ Sounds good to me.
‐ Is that Scott Anspaugh's CT?
‐ It sure is.
‐ Hey, Jeanie.
‐ Hi.
I'm Dr. Romano.
I don't believe we've met.
Are you new
to the surgical service?
I'm Jeanie Boulet, I'm a
physician assistant in the ER.
I didn't know you were involved
in this case.
It's the chief
staff's kid, Peter.
Everybody wants
to get involved.
Dr. Anspaugh requested
I start all of Scott's lines.
Anspaugh's no fool.
You start more lines
with sugar.
‐ So, what's the verdict?
‐ He's obstructed.
‐ He's gonna need surgery.
‐ Oh, man.
‐ Thanks.
‐ Hey!
Can I get a decaf
from you?
Decaf? It's 7:30
in the morning.
I've been so jumpy
the last couple of days.
Any caffeine, I think
I'd blow an aneurysm.
That's a lovely thought.
Want to sit
somewhere else?
‐ It's the smoking section.
‐ Oh.
Fell off the gum wagon,
did you?
Ah, don't start.
Wouldn't dream of it.
What's up? You're
making me nervous.
‐ This.
‐ Ah, you shouldn't have.
Open it up.
Open that up.
When'd you guys
pick these out?
We didn't.
I'm gonna surprise her.
I told her to meet me downtown
this afternoon, and then, uh,
she and I are gonna go
to the clerk's office and get
a marriage license.
That is a surprise.
I just want
to show her I'm serious.
Well, sounds like
a big night.
And then I'm gonna
get a, uh, uh, a limo
and we're going to
the Ironhedge Lodge in Dundee
and then, at one minute
after midnight
the, uh, the
Justice of the Peace
will perform the ceremony.
‐ That sounds great.
‐ Yeah.
Now, alright,
what would make it perfect
is if, uh, if you would agree
to be the best man.
‐ You think you have to ask?
‐ Yeah?
‐ Yeah, I'd be honored.
‐ You'd do that?
What do you think?
Oh, I can't believe this.
Every other woman I ever went
out with, it was just..
You know, I..
I‐I knew it was wrong.
And now I'm gonna spend
the rest of my life with her
and...I'd, um,
I'm talking like an idiot here.
You're acting like someone
who's going to be a husband
tomorrow morning.
A husband.
Can you imagine that?
Hey, Carol!
You ready to go?
Yeah. Here,
let me help you.
What have you got here?
Saline, gauze, et cetera.
Got the fisheye
from some guy
at the admit desk,
but he didn't say anything.
Yeah, I know. It's the
same with the clinic.
County supplies
are County supplies.
Everyone else,
back off.
Whew! You got
the heat going in here?
Yeah, but Powell's got dibs
on music selection till noon.
Doris doesn't appreciate
quality musical entertainment.
I didn't know
you two rode together.
Usually we don't. I guess I just
woke up blessed this morning.
‐ Greg Powell, right?
‐ Good memory, Nurse Hathaway.
What have we got?
Lower right quadrant pain
with vaginal bleeding.
She's shocky. BP's 50 palp.
Gave two liters
of saline in the field.
Alright, let's go. Let's get a
CBC, type and cross match.
Six units to start.
Looks like a
ruptured ectopic.
Let's get her
to the OR right now!
Aren't you guys from Lady
of Pity catchment area?
Yeah.
Is there a reason you endangered
this woman's life
by bringing her
all the way to County?
It was a damn good reason.
Lady of Pity's ER is closed.
You guys are the closest
receiving hospital.
Yeah, that's ten minutes
right there.
Tell me
about it.
‐ Here's the O‐neg!
‐ Alright, hang two units.
She's hypovolemic.
Who's fighting?
I'm Spinal,
and that's Sabre Wulf.
I was doing okay,
but then he sabre‐stomped me.
Oh, he did
the fireball. I'm dead.
Hey, I want to talk to you
about the surgery.
My dad already talked
all that noise.
I know. Would you give me
a hand here?
I just want to talk to you
about it, too.
The tumor you had
last year is back.
'And they need to operate
again to remove it.'
I'm not having
any more operations.
‐ I know you're scared.
‐ 'I'm not scared.'
Just sick of all their crap.
"This is the last one,
Scotty."
"Got it all, Scotty."
Yeah.
Hey, if you don't have this
surgery, you're gonna die.
Good.
I'd rather die.
Okay.
Guess I'll have
to find someone else to share
my rinkside Blackhawks‐Islanders
tickets with then.
Nice try.
Like you're a hockey fan.
What, girls can't like
bone‐crushing
high‐sticking action?
Okay, who's Tony Esposito?
Blackhawk's goalie. Vezina
trophy winner...'70 and '72.
‐ Not bad.
‐ Yeah.
What do you care, though? I
mean, you're fixing to die, so..
So, you really got
those tickets?
'Post‐op, day two.'
Wound is granulating well
without drainage.
‐ Afebrile on cefotetan.
‐ Okay.
Next.
Lizzie! Long time, no see.
Oh, Dr. Romano.
Did you get my message?
I wanted to see
if I could be excused
from the Anspaugh
tumor resection.
And why would
that be, doctor?
I'd like to assist
Dr. Kotlowitz
on Allison's vocal cord surgery
this afternoon.
No problem. Never
had you scheduled
to work with me
in the first place.
But my name was on the board.
I thought since so much
of your energies
have been going towards head
and neck surgery
that you were considering
changing specialties.
Of course not.
It's only this case.
You have nothing
to worry about, sweetheart.
I taught her
everything she knows.
'Next.'
Ellis! Is it true Lady
of Pity's ER is closed?
No, no, not closed, uh,
but they're not accepting
paramedic traffic right now.
Well, critical cases don't
tend to be walk‐ins.
No. What's
the matter, Kerry?
I just had a 29‐year‐old woman
nearly bleed out
because she was in the back
of an ambulance
for 15 minutes longer
than was necessary.
That's a bad situation.
As a matter of fact
it's cases like hers
that forced SPG
to reconfigure
our Lady of Pity ER.
I don't understand.
Well, they had a substandard
trauma panel
and neurosurgical
coverage was spotty at best.
As soon as we can
get some new docs
and upgrade their equipment,
they should be back up at 100%.
Yeah, how soon
will that be?
I don't know.
sooner the better.
More importantly,
how's your patient?
‐ Is she okay?
‐ She'll probably live.
She had the best medical care
in the world. That's why.
She was lucky. That's why.
Mr. Dwyer, we're ready
to start the procedure.
‐ Is that a toothpick?
‐ Dr. Carter.
Yes, it is,
but in your case
this is a state of the art
medical device.
We think you may have
contracted dracunculosis
from the river water.
Dracun..
What?
Uh...guinea worm.
It's native to North Africa
and Middle East.
You get it from drinking
contaminated water.
It moves through
your system for months
and then lays its eggs
below your skin there.
Oh, wait, wait wait.
A worm has been crawling
through me for almost a year?
Yep.
Why didn't the other doctors
didn't catch this?
Well, it presents
like an abscess.
When you had it drained,
it only made it worse.
‐ Wh‐what's to be done?
‐ Controlled removal.
Ow.
‐ 'Ow!'
‐ Sorry.
Harrison says these babies grow
to be a meter long.
I really didn't need
to hear that.
I got about two centimeters.
Toothpick, please.
And a length of tape.
Oh‐ho‐ho. Okay. You want
to keep that tape down
and then come back daily
to, uh, continue the extraction.
I got to catch a 6:00 a. m.
flight to Cairo.
Why can't you just yank it out?
Because if we pull out more than
two centimeters a day
it'll break off.
I gotta put it for Combat Pay.
Hey, John.
‐ Anna.
‐ Hi, Chase.
‐ What are you doing here?
‐ I feel nauseous.
I remembered
a couple Thanksgivings ago
when we had bad pheasants and
you hooked everybody up with
uh, whatever that was.
‐ Compazine.
‐ It worked like a charm.
I‐I thought you could
give me a script.
Excuse me
for a second.
Come here.
Now, I know that you didn't
just drive all the way over here
from the loop
to get Compazine.
This isn't exactly the thing you
bring to the company nurse.
Why? Oh, 'cause you don't want
your mom and dad
to find out that you've
been shooting heroin.
I'm‐I'm not.
I mean, I..
I stopped two nights ago,
and I just, I..
I need something
to get over the hump.
Well, if you need Compazine
to get over the hump
then you're in withdrawal.
So, why don't you go upstairs
to the cafeteria
have a cup of coffee and I'll
go and I'll do the paperwork
and I'll get you
into a detox center.
You're overreacting.
Listen, you could have gone
to any doctor in this city
but you didn't,
you came to me.
I think you're
asking for my help.
I think you've read
too many 12‐step pamphlets‐‐
No, I can't even help you. If
you're gonna slam the door‐‐
No, you can help me.
You just choose not to.
Thank you!
Best thing you can do
is let him go.
Pardon me?
Sorry.
I didn't mean to eavesdrop.
It's just that a friend
of mine in med school
had a drug problem,
and I've had this conversation
more times than you
could ever imagine.
I appreciate your concern,
but I can handle this.
I know.
You don't want to talk.
But, uh, don't let him drag you
into this. He's gonna try.
I'm not going to get
dragged into anything.
Excuse me.
Cajun tofu gumbo.
And don't make
that face.
Whatever happened to beef stew
and five‐alarm chili?
Olbes is macrobiotic
Audia's trying to lose
his holiday pounds
me and Zadro are doing
that zone diet.
‐ Do you have any kings?
‐ Go fish.
I knew I should have taken
the PD exam.
Hoagies and donuts.
Those guys know how to eat.
‐ You have any tens?
‐ Uh, yes.
Carol, please, tell me
that you're a real American.
Red meat,
the occasional brewski.
I have to admit,
I'm not a really big fan
of nuts and berries.
You hear that, man? Now, that's
the voice of common sense.
Well, Mickey D's
is right up the street.
No one's
keeping you here.
Although I have to say,
Zadro brought by
some incredible
flourless carob brownies.
They were...good.
Carob. Ca..
Why bother, bro?
Powell, you really
are a caveman. Eights?
That's us.
'...68‐year‐old woman..'
More, uh, tofu for you there,
big daddy.
You know, I had a lumpectomy
and a lap choly on my schedule
before this,
but when Anspaugh says
jump,
I say, "Sieg heil."
'I'm gonna transect the ileum
with a GIA stapler'
reinforce the staple lines
with 4‐0 silk lembert sutures.
Reinforcing the staple lines.
That's very thorough.
Your British colleague is not
always so detail oriented.
I haven't noticed that
to be true.
No question, her baby blues
would look at damn sight better
over this bowel than your mug,
but you know female surgeons.
No, I don't.
Why don't you tell me.
Always something to prove.
Often at the expense
of the case at hand.
One of the things
I like about you, Peter.
You're not one of those
militant minorities.
Dr. Romano, we have the results
of the frozen section.
'B‐cell lymphoma?'
‐ Yes.
‐ Oh, damn.
I knew it.
Well, someone's gonna have
to tell Anspaugh
and I am voting
for you, Peter.
‐ Excuse me.
‐ Oh, hi.
Uh, uh, Dr. Weaver,
glad you could join us.
I was just explaining
to Dr. Ruiz here
about our plan to pursue
industrial contracts.
Can I speak to you
for a minute?
Uh, sure, sure.
I'm sorry. The ER
doesn't stop for lunch.
So, why don't you go on up,
take a seat
and we'll join you
as soon as we can.
Thanks.
What's up?
I've been doing
a little research
and it seems SPG
has closed down
60% of their trauma
centers in the Midwest.
‐ What is that?
‐ Where'd you hear that?
It's on the internet.
Well, if you had questions,
I wish you'd come to me‐‐
You know, I did.
You gave me the party line.
Well, since I don't know
where you got your figures
I can't address them
specifically
but what I can say
is that a 60% downgrade rate
taken by itself doesn't reflect
our reconfiguration strategy.
You know what, Ellis, it's me.
You can speak English.
Okay, let me give you
an example.
Kellogg Memorial
in Detroit
was a shambles
as an acute care facility.
Now it's a nationally
recognized hernia center.
Yeah, that doesn't
do you much good
if you've got
a stab wound to the chest.
Neither does a hospital
bankrupted by unreimbursed
trauma care.
So, emergency care is only
for people who can pay for‐‐
No, come on. Now you're trying
to twist my words.
Yeah, you know,
you're avoiding my‐‐
I'm not avoiding
your questions.
Look, if you're worried
about County, don't.
Trust me,
you guys are essential.
‐ You're not going anywhere.
‐ How could we?
If everyone else closes, someone
needs to handle the Trauma.
‐ Are you going to lunch?
‐ No, thanks. I'm not hungry.
What to pick, what to pick.
Oh. Um, Dr. Carter, you got
a couple of messages.
From who?
Um, they were all from your
Cousin Chase.
He says you can call
in your prescription
at De Gooyer's
pharmacy on Randolph.
Unbelievable.
Carter, I need your John Hancock
on this, please.
‐ Hey, Malik.
‐ 'Hey, Jeanie, what's up?'
You still got that friend
at startime tickets?
Yeah. Rosco.
Sure. What you need?
I need a couple of rinkside
Blackhawks‐Islanders tickets
on the 20th.
Uh‐huh. And I want world peace
and a date with Tyra Banks.
I know. No, seriously,
can he get them?
Yeah, you can get them, but you
know that's gonna run you.
That's okay.
Just ask, okay?
Well, if you're living
that phat
I might need to get
a date with you.
Hey, Chase, this is John.
You there? Pick up.
Alright, call me back
when you get this message.
I'm at work.
You know the number.
'So, Allison..'
...see, the two cords on the
screen need to touch and vibrate
in order for you
to regain your voice, hmm?
But, as it is now,
the left one is paralyzed.
So, if you understand me, blink
once for yes, twice for no.
Good. Dr. Corday.
You here to observe?
I'm actually here for Allison,
if she doesn't mind.
'Oh, fine. I was just
explaining the procedure.'
Alright, now I'm going to make
a slight incision
'but you should only
feel a little bit of pressure.'
'Okay?'
Kerry. Why aren't you at that
big SPG luncheon?
Had some work to do.
Well, everything seems to be
trucking right along though.
For the most part, sure but, uh,
this is a big step we're taking.
I agree. Thanks to you, we're
lighting a fire under the board
to institute
some real change.
Yeah, and I think we should
be 100% sure
that turning the ER over
to an outside management group
is what we want to do.
‐ Well, isn't it?
‐ On paper, sure.
Is there something
the matter, Kerry?
No. No, not at all.
I just thought we could delay
the board vote a week or two
make sure we have
all our‐‐
‐ Dr. Anspaugh.
‐ Dr. Benton.
How can I help you?
Well, we, um..
We got the results
of, uh, Scott's frozen section.
Alright.
‐ Uh, we can discuss this later.
‐ No, it's fine.
Let's see.
There's been a recurrence
of his lymphoma.
Uh‐huh.
'We got everything
that we could see.'
It's hard to know
if we got it all
until we take a look
at the tumor margins.
Do you see
any serosal seeding?
No.
What about infiltration
to the liver or spleen?
No metastasis.
Okay.
Well, continue then, and, uh..
...let me know when, uh..
...Scott is awake.
So, Kerry,
where were we?
Ha! You owe
me a dollar.
No, no, no , no,
I only smoked half a cigarette.
Half a cigarette
is still a cigarette.
You know, at the rate
we're going
we're gonna be
in Club Med by February.
No, that is not true,
because that was my last one
and I'm going back
on the gum tonight.
Oh, you know what I was thinking
we could do tonight?
‐ What?
‐ S'mores.
‐ Excuse me?
‐ Do you remember camp?
Marshmallows,
Graham crackers, chocolate.
I'd love to, but I can't, okay?
I got‐I got to do something.
‐ What?
‐ It's for Doug.
But, uh, maybe Saturday night?
Take a rain check?
‐ I'll bring the marshmallows?
‐ Oh..
‐ Dr. Greene.
‐ What's up, Carter?
I was wondering if I could have
the rest of the shift off?
‐ Why?
‐ It's a family emergency.
‐ Is everything okay?
‐ Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Just some things
I need to take care of.
‐ Alright. I'll let Doyle know.
‐ Thanks.
‐ Hey, Carter.
‐ Hey.
'What are you eatin'?'
Um...PB and J on wheat.
I thought you were on
until 7:00.
I was.
‐ You feeling okay?
‐ Mm‐hmm. Yeah, fine.
You're leaving in the middle
of your shift.
It's about your cousin,
isn't it?
I know what I'm doing.
You don't look like
you know what you're doing.
And you don't know anything
about my family
so just drop it.
Oh, God!
One more flight!
Apartment 3H!
Oh, hurry, hurry!
'Please hurry!'
In here! In here!
Oh, please!
'Hurry!'
Oh, my God, she's dead.
‐ She's dead.
‐ No! She's not dead.
Are you okay?
‐ Do something!
‐ Some help here.
‐ You have to go something!
‐ How long have you been here?
‐ 'About five minutes.'
She wasn't breathing.
‐ Get her out of here, will you?
‐ I love you!
'I got a faint pulse.
Powell.'
‐ 'Powell!'
‐ 'I'm in, I'm here.'
'Oh, God, no!'
‐ 'I love you, mama!'
‐ Oh, come on.
Let's go.
‐ I'm gonna start an IV.
‐ Let them do their work.
‐ Stand back.
‐ Come on.
Come on, please, please, please.
IV's in.
BP's 60 palp.
‐ Oh, God.
‐ She's in fib.
Alright, charge it to 200.
Clear!
Nothing.
Come on, damn it!
Come on!
Charging 300! Clear!
‐ Nope.
‐ Again.
Charging 360!
Clear!
Oh, mama. Please, help her.
‐ Nothin'.
‐ Help her, help her, help her.
Come on! Breathe!
Don't you die on me.
Don't you friggin' die!
‐ Powell!
‐ Amp of epi!
'Oh, mama..'
'I shouldn't
have left her.'
Okay, I got a pulse.
'I love you so much.
Don't leave me.'
Allison, it's imperative
that you hold perfectly still
alright?
This is the home stretch.
You're doing really well.
Alright, now.
I am going to ask you..
...to swallow for me
if you can.
'Oh, good.
Now, can you say E?'
E.
That's okay. You just need
to clear the secretions.
Alright, good.
Let's try again.
You can do it, Allison.
E.
Dr. Kotlowitz, you're a genius.
'No, I'm just doing
my job, that's all.'
You did
good, kid.
Alright, let's
prepare to close her.
Thank you.
Shh! You have the rest
of your life to talk.
Let's get a CBC.
CHEM‐7, blood gas,
portable chest and 12 lead.
Pulse are weak and thready.
Start dopamine
at ten mics per kilo.
‐ Pulse ox 88.
‐ Call respiratory for a vent.
'BP 60 palp. Looks like
idioventricular rhythm at 50.'
'I lost her pulse.'
'She's cyanotic.'
‐ We should go.
‐ I'll get a blood gas.
Come on. Let's go.
Start dopamine.
Atropine!
John, what are
you doing here?
You asked me to help.
I'm here to help.
Uh..
...that's really decent of you,
man, but‐but I'm‐I'm fine.
You left messages for me
every half an hour
and now you're fine?
Well, I just, uh,
panicked, you know.
I mean, you know
how it is when you're sick.
You‐you‐you think
the world's gonna end.
‐ Invite me in.
‐ Yeah, sure. Come on in.
It smells like
a locker room in here.
When was the last time
the maid came by?
She, uh...quit.
So...since you're here,
did you bring any meds?
No. I brought a list
of drug treatment centers.
Come on, man. I'm not one
of those Betty Ford people.
I..
I mean, half my graduating class
from Westlane's in rehab.
I mean...I'd bump
into somebody I know
and then tongues would wag.
You should take a look
at yourself, Chase.
You're a mess.
Thank you,
Mr. Blackwell.
You know, I'd love to
hang out, but I got to..
‐ I was just gonna...head out.
‐ Why don't you give me a break?
You going to answer that?
Chase, buddy, what's up, dude?
I am sorry it took me
so long to get here.
I was in the middle
of a‐a wicked squash game
and I didn't feel
my pager vibrate, so..
It's alright.
Anyway, um, I got you
a couple of grams of the usual
and check this out.
A gram of this.
Dude, this is some superb‐‐
‐ I think you'd better go.
‐ Who the hell's this guy?
He's my cousin.
Your cousin needs
to learn some manners.
‐ Anyway, as I was saying‐‐
‐ I don't think you heard me.
‐ I said get out.
‐ Whoa, whoa, wait a minute.
Last time I checked,
this was Chase's house, okay?
So, why don't you go make
yourself a‐a hot toddy
or something
and let us talk.
Chase, if you do this,
you are on your own.
Oh, you know what?
You know what?
What's it going to be, man?
D‐do you want this or not? Huh?
Yeah? Is that a yeah?
Yeah. Alright.
Gardner, you..
...better go.
Alright. Okay. Alright.
Well, you know where to find me
when mommy's gone.
Alright, you heard him.
Get out of here.
Oh!
Last epi?
'High dose,
three minutes ago.'
‐ Total time down?
‐ Thirty minutes.
Okay. Let's call it.
Time of death, 4:02 p. m.
Uh, Dr. Greene,
I'm Detective Gerald Leo
District 11, Violent Crimes,
and this is Detective Laibson.
I wondered,
could we have a minute?
What happened
to the other two cops?
Our suspect crossed
district lines.
This guy's going
all over Chicago?
Uh, this is an open
investigation.
We're not at liberty
to discuss the specifics.
Now, about Louise Dickinson‐‐
You know, I haven't heard
anything on the news about this.
A case like this has to be
handled carefully.
'We have suspects
we're looking at.'
And I have three victims
from some sick bastard.
For all I know,
there could be more
not that my local friendly
police department
is telling me
or anybody else anything.
You're gonna have
to calm down, doctor.
You're right. I'm going
to pull myself together
'cause I got to tell
Louise Dickinson's daughter
that her mother's
going to the morgue.
We need more
kerlix and saline.
Powell, are you okay?
You haven't said a word
since we left that apartment.
There's nothing to say.
Some things you never
get used to seeing.
When we got to that apartment,
you really froze.
I apologize.
No, it's not that.
I just..
If there's anything
you'd like to talk about..
Not really.
What's that?
It's her, alright.
Let me see.
Fifty five cents
off Meow Mix.
I didn't see a cat up there.
Did you?
Nope.
Someone should go
and see if it's okay.
Dr. Anspaugh,
how's Scott?
He's going to have to have
another round of chemotherapy.
How do you tell
a 12‐year‐old boy
that he's going to be in
and out of the hospital
for a painful,
debilitating treatments
for God knows how long?
It's not easy,
but you can imagine
how it is for Scott,
not knowing.
Well, frankly, he could..
We could use some help.
Scott responds to you.
So I was wondering if
you might be interested
in being a, uh..
...part‐time, private duty
caregiver for him.
What does Scott think
about this?
Well, we haven't discussed it
specifically
but I know he thinks
very highly of you..
...as do I.
If you need time
to think about it‐‐
No, no, no. Um..
No, I'm glad that you asked.
When do I start?
Can you turn
the heat up, please?
It's like a freaking
meat locker in here.
It's cranked
up to 80.
‐ I'll make some soup.
‐ I don't want soup!
I am sick!
I need something!
I'll make some tea.
I'm going to vomit.
Whoa, whoa.
Wait, wait, wait.
It's okay. Next time you feel it
coming on, use the bowl.
I'll clean it up.
Don't worry about it.
‐ Want to take this shirt off?
‐ I can't do this anymore!
I got to get
out of here!
Hey, I'm not gonna
let you do that.
Get off of me!
You are not helping me!
You are not doing jack!
The only way you're gonna leave
through here is through me.
Fine. I'll call Gardner back.
‐ Sit down.
‐ I am sick!
I need something!
You got to help.
‐ I'm going to help you.
‐ You have to help me!
I'm going to help you.
I'm going to help you, Chase.
But you got to
stick with me.
Come on! Come on.
Alright?
Yeah.
'Peter.'
Hey. How did the
Beaumont surgery go?
Very well.
Dr. Kotlowitz is optimistic.
She'll have full use
of her voice in a week or two.
Oh. Congratulations.
How about the Anspaugh
boy's surgery?
Ah, you know.
Well, as well as we hoped.
It's been a long day.
I could use a drink.
‐ How about you?
‐ No. I don't drink.
Your body's made up
of 60% water, Peter.
You must drink
something.
Come on, Elizabeth.
You know what I mean.
Well, have a lemonade
or a yoo‐hoo for all I care.
I just think it'd be criminal
to let this day end so early.
Oh, unless of course
you were going to
spend time with your son
or something.
‐ I‐I wouldn't‐‐
‐ Oh, no, no, no, no.
He's with
his mother tonight.
So?
Yeah, well. Yeah, you know,
I like lemonade.
Splendid.
‐ Can I help you?
‐ Yeah.
We're the EMS Team with County.
Mrs. Dickinson had a cat.
You haven't seen it
around anywhere, have you?
Nope.
Anyone seen
a cat around here?
‐ Sorry.
‐ Is it okay if we look around?
Sure. We're almost
done here anyway.
‐ Thanks.
Hey, sometimes they come running
if they hear a can opener.
Well, here's
some stairs.
Maybe it got
to the roof.
Come get your dinner.
I think it hissed at me.
It'll come out eventually.
Whew!
Pretty up here, huh?
I'm just glad to be out
of that apartment.
Yeah. Yeah, me, too.
Hey, you were right.
What happened back there,
it, uh, it got to me.
It reminded me of my mom.
Your mom?
When I was nine,
she hung herself.
‐ I'm sorry.
‐ Yeah.
Yeah, I was the one
that found her.
'Seeing that lady
with the ligature marks'
'and her head turned
like that'
cops all around..
I was pissed..
'...all over again.'
I'm sure she didn't mean
for you to find her.
But I did.
Then I started
feeling guilty
because I was thinking
about myself
instead of that old lady
just like my mom
was only thinking of herself.
What a sick boy I am, huh?
I thought about everybody but me
when I tried to kill myself.
‐ I'm sorry. I had no idea.
‐ Why would you?
It was a long time ago.
I just got wrapped up
in everyone else's
expectations of me.
I forgot who I was,
you know?
And now?
Now I'm okay.
I even tried to go to med school
but it just wasn't me.
You couldn't get the hang
of that nine iron, huh?
I don't know.
I opened up a clinic
in the ER this year.
'It's only open a couple
days a week, but..'
But nothin'.
That's...that's great.
‐ Yeah.
‐ You're super‐nurse.
But what about you?
Me?
What are you thinking
about right now?
I'm thinking that
it's freezing out here
and I wish that damn
cat would come out.
Yeah.
I know it's getting late.
If you got
somewhere to be..
Yeah.
No, I'm fine.
What are you
thinking about?
I'm thinking
I'm not feeling the cold.
‐ 'Yeah?'
‐ Yeah.
And I'm thinking
that cat will come out
when she's good and ready.
Probably.
And I'm thinking
if I look at you one more second
I'm gonna have
to kiss you.
Has anyone seen Carol?
Not since she went on
that ride‐along.
I haven't
seen her since then either.
N‐no one's seen her.
Alright, I'll‐I'll do that.
Okay. Bye.
If anyone sees her,
tell her to call Doug.
He's getting kind of worried.
‐ Goodnight, everybody.
‐ Goodnight.
There you are.
You leaving?
Yeah.
I put together those figures
I promised you.
Thought we could
go out to dinner
have a glass of wine,
maybe talk it over
in a more
relaxed setting.
Yeah, I‐I think I should..
...think about this alone.
‐ Here, let me give you a hand.
‐ No, I don't..
I‐I'm fine, thanks.
Kerry, what can I do to make
you feel better about this?
Delay the board vote.
Come on, we've worked on this
for three months.
I'm perfectly
willing to give you
whatever information
you think you need
but delaying the vote at this
late date just isn't an option.
I can't support something
I don't believe in.
And it seems that SPG is putting
profits ahead of patient care.
Synergix provides the most care
for the most people.
And if that means giving
them an Oldsmobile
instead of a Rolls,
then so be it.
Decent health care
shouldn't be a luxury.
That's right. It shouldn't.
And that's what we give people,
decent health care.
‐ And nothing more?
‐ "More" bankrupts hospitals.
I can't be part
of an organization
that lowballs people's lives.
That's a cheap shot.
Oh, man.
I just need time alone
to think about this.
About Synergix or me?
Come on, let me
give you a ride home.
‐ We'll talk this out.
‐ I'll be fine, thanks.
Kerry, don't do this.
'I don't care if the computer
says it was processed.'
'Cause I phoned
the script in hours ago.
Well, if it was processed,
then I would have the meds
in my hand right now,
wouldn't I?
Yeah, I'll hold.
Want some of this?
Finally.
‐ Hey.
‐ Anna.
What are you
doing here?
You, uh, called in
a prescription for Compazine.
You're gonna need
more than that, trust me.
‐ Come on in.
‐ Thanks.
‐ Chase.
‐ Hey, Anna.
Sorry I‐I didn't tidy up.
Uh, no problem. You should see
my brother Hank's place.
It's a Superfund site.
I got, uh, Clonidine
and Propranolol.
Propranolol?
Yeah, I, uh, borrowed it
from the ER.
I also got
your saline
'and rectal Compazine.'
Rectal?
Do I get my choice
of doctors?
I think that's
the sort of procedure
you should keep
in the family, okay?
Okay, I'm going to
get this started.
'Okay. This will lower
your heart rate'
'and blood pressure and take
the edge off the jitters.'
You'll be okay.
Visualize the bull's‐eye,
lean into the throw and..
...release.
It's easier said than done.
Try it.
No, you're too stiff.
Wait a minute.
There you go.
Nice aerodynamic form.
Now a small movement
with the wrist and..
Well, that's not bad.
Can I get you folks
some refills?
Uh, yes, I'll have
another Newkie Brown.
‐ Uh, a Perrier.
‐ You got it.
‐ Are you an alcoholic?
‐ Excuse me?
'Is that why
you don't drink?'
Oh, no. No.
Are you a Muslim? I notice you
don't eat pork either.
Uh, no, I've got
nothing against liquor.
I just..
I don't like the taste.
So, it's not
a control thing?
No, of course not.
You know what?
You should try a Pimm's.
It tastes just like, uh,
Ginger Ale and fruit.
No. No, thank you.
Oh, you're so resistant
to new things, Peter.
I tell you what,
we'll shoot for it.
Whoever gets closest
to the bull's‐eye
picks the next round.
If you get it, I'll even drink
that frog water of yours.
‐ How's that?
‐ Oh, yeah, right, that's fair.
I mean, you've done this
all your life.
I've never done this.
Okay. I'll throw mine backwards
with my eyes closed
and you can
shoot yours straight.
‐ Oh, yeah, you will?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
Alright. You got
yourself a deal.
Come on, watch this.
Look at this aerodynamic thing
that you were talking about.
See? Whoo‐whoo.
'Oh!'
‐ Okay, okay.
‐ Okay.
Here we go.
Alright.
♪ ...lasts forever
and everybody wants to.. ♪
Whoa!
‐ Hey, Jeanie.
‐ Hey.
What are you doing awake?
You need your sleep.
I kept my end of the
deal with surgery.
‐ What about you?
‐ What do you mean?
Blackhawks, Islanders.
Right.
Center ice.
That is so cool.
So we got a date?
Yeah.
Thanks, Jeanie.
Sure.
‐ You have a good sleep, okay?
‐ Are you leaving?
Well, not if you
don't want me to.
It gets kind of creepy
in here at night, that's all.
Well, why don't I just sit here,
then, until you fall asleep?
Thanks, Jeanie.
Thanks.
Sure.
These are great photos.
Those are
Chase Carter originals.
‐ Really?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
Gritty stuff.
Not what I would have expected.
Well, he's got
a lot of talents.
I guess that's why this is
all so hard to understand.
Yeah, well, this happens
to all kinds of people.
Yeah.
Um..
...before, when I said
that I had a friend on heroin
I wasn't being
completely honest.
No?
How so?
Um...it was my boyfriend.
I've done the detox dance
more times than I can count.
How come you didn't
cut him loose?
Mmm. It's not that easy
when you love someone.
No.
No, it's not.
Do you think this
is the worst of it?
I wish.
Well, you were right.
I don't know
what I'm doing.
No.
You're doing great.
Thanks for coming.
What are friends for?
♪ Oh I just can't deny it ♪
♪ I thought
of quitting baby ♪
♪ But my heart
wasn't gonna buy it ♪
♪ No no no no ♪
♪ If I don't think
everything is worth a try ♪
♪ I'm gonna roll myself
up in a big ball ♪
Whoa.
♪ Roll myself up
in a big ball ♪
♪ And bye‐bye bye‐bye ♪
Whoo.
Oh, I guess
they're kicking us out.
Yeah.
That's life.
Yep, that's life.
Neither one of us is
in any shape to drive.
Listen, I didn't mean
to get you drunk.
It's just, uh,
I've never seen that happen
from two Pimm's before.
Thank you.
I, um..
I should call us a cab.
I'd, uh..
Uh, I'd invite you
back to my place but, um..
...I fear
I'd be taking advantage.
My head is spinning.
I'm..
I should just get some sleep.
Mmm, mmm.
It's probably best.
Taxi!
Okay. Now,
when you get home
I want you
to drink plenty of water
and if you have any aspirin
or B complex, all the better.
Okay. So, uh, where
can I drop you?
Oh, it's okay.
I'll get my own cab.
‐ You sure?
‐ Uh‐huh.
‐ Hey, Elizabeth.
‐ Mm‐hmm?
I had a really good time.
Yes, uh...it was delightful.
‐ Goodnight.
‐ Night.
I've been waiting
for you all night.
I'm sorry.
I got...I got wrapped up.
I called here,
but you weren't home.
I was on the corner
of Dearborn and Clark.
Right.
I called the hospital
and the firehouse
and they both said that
unit 57 came back on time.
Yeah, I was talking
to Greg Powell.
Um...he's the paramedic
on my ride‐along.
It was a really tough day
for both of us and, um..
'It was just one of those things
where you start talking'
to someone you hardly know and
you start telling them things.
Mm‐hmm.
Talking to him
all night?
We got coffee,
and we talked
and since then
I've been walking.
In this cold?
‐ I needed to think.
‐ About what?
About you and me and..
...the engagement, and the vows
and the rings and, uh..
I think we're
rushing into this.
I don't think
we're ready.
I'm ready.
'But you aren't?'
When I was...talking
to Greg Powell
it got intense
and, um..
And I kissed him.
It didn't go
any further than that
'but it was one
of those moments, you know.'
‐ Uh‐huh. Uh‐huh.
‐ I didn't want it to..
Okay, that's good. I just..
Was here.
I just wanted to make sure
you were safe and sound.
Doug...I am so sorry.
Yep. Me, too.