Previously, on
"The Resident"...
No way.
Is that the guy
who killed Phoebe?
He saw us with the FBI.
You want a baby
more than you want me.
I want you, but I also
want a family one day.
So what are you saying, then?
This is it?
Yeah.
Job well done.
Call me when you're off.
I'll meet you here this evening.
FBI?
As long as I decide
to stay at Chastain,
they're giving me
an armed escort.
Good. You need that protection.
I used to have an extra room,
but now it's Gigi's.
Thanks for letting me
crash here last-minute.
I don't get it, man.
You guys always seemed
really happy together.
I guess there was
a problem all along.
Something big we never
talked about, and...
when we started talking...
Hey, you mind
if I use the bathroom?
Shower is all yours.
The whole place is yours.
I'm gonna take Gigi
to preschool.
Hey.
...if there's any way
I can help.
You already have.
You know where Devon is?
I keep texting him,
- he's not responding.
- He's probably on his way.
He slept on my couch.
What, you don't spend
enough time together?
I think he just needed a place
to crash for the night.
Well, I need him now.
We lost another ER doctor.
- What do you mean?
- Sad day.
Cade gave notice.
Just up and quit.
You mean she's gone?
Clearing out her locker.
Were you gonna say goodbye?
Of course I was.
I took your advice, slept on it,
made a decision.
Maybe it was the right one.
I certainly don't want you
to be in danger.
No more Go Team, huh?
No more torturing Irving.
That's what I'll miss the most.
And Hundley. She's awesome.
I'll miss you.
We never really
had a chance, did we?
I thought we had a chance.
I hoped to break through
the limits I've put on myself
about getting close to people.
I wanted it to be different.
We did everything right.
We went straight to the FBI,
played by the rules,
it just still wasn't enough.
You still need to leave.
Look, I stay,
the moment I let my guard down
is when they'll get me.
Where will you go?
If I told you,
I'd have to kill you.
I tried to warn you, Hawkins.
I always disappear.
Always.
Nurse Allen to
Residential Services.
Residential Services, please.
Bye.
Bring it in here.
Ugh, I'm gonna miss you.
- Oh.
- There. It's always too perfect.
What's going on?
- I'm out of here, friend.
- No way.
Way.
You guys are the best.
I mean that.
Then don't leave us.
Ugh, I should have
just snuck out.
This is too hard.
I love you all.
I'll walk you out.
Just this once.
This will be twice now.
You're getting soft.
Oh, and now
I'm letting you open
car doors for me?
This is new.
Could have learned to like it.
I'd say "let me know
where you are," but...
Yeah.
We were a good team.
Yes, we were.
I'll be thinking of you.
Stay safe.
Yeah, that's the idea.
Get down! Get down!
You're okay. I got you.
- Tell the ER to prep a trauma bay.
- Got it.
Multiple gunshot wounds,
thready pulse!
Am I dying?
You're not gonna die.
I'm not gonna allow it.
Just hold my hand.
I don't want to die alone.
Open your eyes.
Open your eyes. Open your eyes!
*THE RESIDENT*
Season 05  Episode 21
Episode Title: "REisk"
Aired on: May 03, 2022.
Okay, deep breath.
Wait, Doc, let me guess.
My lungs sound like
Rice Krispies or Velcro...
It's always one of the two.
It's hard to tell
if you keep talking, but yes,
Those are both key findings of
idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis.
I should have
an honorary medical degree
after these past two years.
I've seen every kind
of doctor there is.
Well, except for a gynecologist.
He refused to believe
the diagnosis for ages.
Well, I didn't feel like a man
with a terminal disease.
Except for this cough.
- They told us he was...
- What, finished?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, not a chance.
I am far too mean to die.
So, Doc, is it finally time
for a transplant?
I think so, Mr. Miller.
I've looked through your records
and besides IPF,
you are a young and healthy guy.
You got a strong support system
here from Lola.
So, as far as I can see,
you are an excellent candidate
for a lung transplant,
and I think we should do
everything we can to get you on
that list as soon as possible.
"Young and healthy"?
Did you hear that, Lola?
I like this man.
He should be a guest
on my podcast.
How about it, Dr. Pravesh?
You get me new lungs
and I will make you a star.
The next, uh, Dr. Oz.
That'll be a pass for me.
You a fan of my show?
You know, sadly,
I just don't have much time
for entertainment these days.
Well, my podcast
isn't entertainment.
I'm sure it's great...
Attention, please.
Active shooter alert.
Please remain where you are
and await further instructions.
- Repeat...
- I-Is this a drill, Doctor?
Please remain where you are
and await further instructions.
Thank you.
There was a shooting
outside the hospital.
The ER is closing, but
you're gonna be safe up here.
I'll keep you updated,
but in the meantime,
a transplant surgeon's
gonna come by to evaluate you
and discuss next steps
to get you on that list, okay?
Yeah.
Weak carotid.
She's in hemorrhagic shock.
I want every unit
of uncrossmatched blood
we have in the hospital now.
On it. Go.
Blood.
We got you.
Irving.
Can you get central access?
Generous with the lido.
Subclavian it is.
What happened?
Was it random
or a patient or what?
Definitely not random.
Conrad, I don't think
she's protecting her airway.
We're gonna have to put in
a breathing tube.
It's temporary.
I need to tell you, blood...
We've got transfusions coming.
Don't worry.
We've got you.
She's out.
Are you sure you're good?
Good.
- E.T. Tube.
- Mm-hmm.
Advancing through the cords.
Let's get the vent on her.
I got it.
No chest rise on the left.
I don't hear any breath sounds
on that side, either.
I got the page.
What do you need?
Penetrating bullet wound
to the left chest,
another two in the abdomen.
- She needs a chest tube.
- I'm on it.
Tell me how I can help.
Units of O neg are waiting.
Grab them.
Doctor, are we safe in here?
- Sandwich! I'm hungry!
- I heard a doctor was shot.
- Oh, my God.
- Special Agent Garcia, FBI.
I've come to put
the Chastain ER under lockdown.
Nobody comes through
these doors for any reason.
Atlanta PD will be here in five.
All doctors and nurses
are to show ID.
And I want all of these
people out of here.
But these are patients.
That's our waiting room.
Not anymore.
- Come on, everybody.
- Let's go.
Hospital security to the ER.
Hospital security
to the ER.
Line's in.
All right, I've got
three units and a bag
- of platelets and plasma.
- You got 'em?
She's got free fluid in the
right and left upper quadrant.
She's bleeding into her belly.
Simple pneumothorax.
Minimal blood in the chest.
All right, some good news.
No pericardial effusion,
looks like
the bullet just missed
her heart and vessels.
But the other two hit her
abdomen, shattered her spleen.
I just heard. Any head trauma?
I don't know.
She needs a baseline neuro exam.
Just heard from Bell. He's pulling up.
All right, OR I will be ready
in 15 minutes.
- Anesthesia will be waiting for you.
- Billie?
I need to know.
- What?
- Is her neuro exam okay?
It's not like Nic.
You fix the rest of her,
that brain will be just fine.
All right, let's prep her for surgery.
Let me know
how I can help, please.
Hospital's on lockdown.
Go to the ER at Atlanta General.
- I'm the CEO.
- Surgeon.
Go.
How's she doing?
We stabilized her enough
to go to the OR, but it's bad.
This is related
to the Medicare fraud ring.
Yes.
Are we still keeping
that a secret?
No.
There's no need
for secrets anymore.
Cade was a whistleblower.
She was working with the FBI.
Blew open a mob operation.
And they came for her.
Okay, then.
We were just about to take her
to the OR when her pressure
and sats dropped.
We're behind on resuscitating
her with blood products.
Well, let's get a pressure bag
on that blood.
All right,
another unit going in.
There's no increase
in abdominal free fluid.
She must be bleeding
somewhere else.
No blood in the chest tube.
She's desatting.
Raise it to 100% on the vent.
Temp?
102.4.
She wasn't febrile before.
Stop the blood.
Hawkins, she'll bleed out.
No, she's not just losing blood.
- Her body's also destroying it.
- Transfusion reaction.
Yes, she tried to tell me
something about blood.
She must have a rare type.
And we can't take her
to the OR like this.
Any more blood could kill her.
- Okay, thanks.
- Talk to me.
The blood bank confirmed it.
Severe hemolytic
- transfusion reaction.
- Didn't she get O negative?
Yes, and that would be fine
for most everyone else,
but Cade reacted to it
because she has
a very rare blood type: Rh null.
Well, I hope they're prepping
Rh null for the OR.
I mean, that's where
she needs to go now.
We don't have any,
and I bet that no one else
- in Georgia does, either.
- If you operate
and can't transfuse her,
odds are, she won't
- make it off the table.
- Yeah, but she's losing blood
from her spleen and who knows
where else as we speak.
If I sit on that,
she'll die, for sure.
It's a risk we have to take.
All right, here's the plan.
You take her to the OR,
remove her spleen.
Get in and out
as quick as possible.
- Damage control.
- Yeah, I'll take out her spleen
and fix whatever else
could kill her,
but this is
a temporary solution.
And then bring her back to
the ICU, keep her abdomen open.
Uh, so we're ready to get back
into the OR as quickly
as possible.
Once we get compatible blood.
- You want me in there?
- No, there's no need.
What we're doing right now
is just a Band-Aid.
It's quick and dirty.
But there will be
a much larger surgery
to put all this back together
as soon as we get the blood.
- I will need you then.
- All right.
Let's get Dr. Devi to assist.
Is she here?
- I wouldn't know.
- I'll page her.
And I'll ask Billie to start
the hunt for compatible blood.
Well, tell her
to pull out all the stops.
I mean, I'll do
what I can in there,
but that blood
is what's gonna save her.
Bell's on deck.
I need you in Cade's OR.
I'll be there. Will she be okay?
Don't ask questions. Just focus.
The world doesn't stop.
I've got a patient.
He's kicking up a fuss.
He needs an expedited
lung transplant eval.
- Can you do it?
- Well, I'm all yours
until they find blood for Cade.
Pulmonary fibrosis.
Meets BMI criteria,
otherwise healthy.
Jimmy Miller. The podcast host?
- You've heard of him?
- Yeah. He's a nitwit.
He's a performance artist.
Says anything to get attention.
Anti-government, anti-gluten,
whatever sells at the moment.
- Presently, he's anti-vax.
- Look,
all transplant recipients
need to be vaccinated.
For the flu, hepatitis...
Hepatitis, shingles,
polio, pneumonia,
COVID, diphtheria,
pertussis, yada yada.
After a transplant,
the meds we give you
to keep you from rejecting
your new lungs
also make it hard for your body
to fight off infections.
Leaving you vulnerable
to any number of things
that could destroy
the precious lungs we give you.
These are my risks
to reject or accept.
I will take my chances.
You can hold on to your position,
but the cost
is we can't list you.
Transplant programs
simply can't give
an organ to someone
who refuses
the necessary vaccines.
Look, there's got to be an
exception for a guy like Jimmy.
- No exceptions.
- We can explain the science, right?
There is no reason
to fear vaccines.
They are the single greatest
success story in medicine.
Prevention beats any treatment
by light-years.
Yeah, this is about
my principles.
Really? Is it
about your principles
or is it about
remaining a hot topic?
Hey, don't talk
like that to Jimmy.
We're not
forcing him to do anything,
but the bottom line is
you don't get a rare resource
like new lungs
if you're not vaccinated.
The risk of infection and death
are too high.
Donated organs cannot
be wasted on patients
- who will not live to enjoy them.
- Hey.
My mind is made up.
I will never get vaccinated.
I came as quickly as I could.
OR 1.
Cade's already on the table.
Bell needs
an extra set of hands.
Look, I know this is not the
right time, but I'm guessing
you heard about me
and Devon and I just,
- I hope you're not angry.
- I'm not angry, I'm stressed.
- We all are.
- It's not something I wanted.
Leela, it's your business.
And right now,
I'm focused on Cade.
Of course.
That's where my focus is, too.
Sorry for the delay.
I couldn't believe when I heard.
Well, she has
lost a lot of blood already,
we have none to transfuse
and when we open,
she will bleed more.
Of course, we would
all prefer that Dr. Sullivan
not bleed to death
on this table.
So our goal is to keep
blood loss to a minimum.
We have no reserve.
All right, then.
10 blade to me.
Damn it. No.
Dr. Devi, uh, take your hand
and plunge it toward her back
to find her spleen.
When you take it out,
the bleeding will slow.
I'm-I'm where her
spleen should be. I can't find it.
- Dr. Bell, take over.
- It's o-it's okay.
Take the retractor.
I got it.
Okay, now clamp it.
This is personal for all of us.
That's all the more reason
not to panic.
You've got this.
Now staple it off.
- Good.
- Okay, spleen's out.
The bleeding is slowing.
But the pressure's still dropping.
She had multiple gunshot wounds.
Run the bowel.
- There might be a perf.
- Already on that.
I see one.
Okay, we'll cut out
the damaged bowel.
We're getting cold here.
She's hypothermic.
Okay, that's all we can do.
We're out of time.
There's no time
to repair the bowel.
So we'll staple it off
on both sides.
We're going to leave her bowel
in discontinuity?
We will reconnect it
when we come back later.
Jessica, give me
all the lap pads you've got.
Let's jam them in there.
We have to stop the bleeding.
No, I said Rh null.
Okay, I understand.
Call me back
if you find any matches.
- How is she?
- Out of surgery.
Alive, but barely.
Where are we with the blood?
I called up and down
the East Coast. Nothing.
Rh null is one of the rarest
blood types in existence.
And even if we find blood,
who knows how far away it'll be.
Seattle.
I just got off the phone
with Cade's emergency contact...
Her father...
He is a peds surgeon
at Seattle Children's.
He has the same blood type.
- When can he get here?
- He's taking the red-eye,
and he's gonna land at 6:50 a.m.
That means
she'll be without blood
for the next 16 hours at least?
Cade knew she had
a rare blood type.
Wouldn't she have
banked some of it?
Yeah, but not here. I checked.
She wasn't planning
on staying here long.
Where's the last place
she worked?
Atlanta General.
How is she?
We managed a splenectomy
and removed the per fed section
of the bowel,
but she's lost too much blood
to do a definitive operation.
So until then, her bowel
has to be disconnected.
Her abdomen has to remain open.
We're doing our best
to find blood.
We have to figure out a way
to work in the same hospital.
It's been less than 24 hours.
It's gonna be hard,
but we just have to stay focused
on being civil.
I know we can do that.
- How's she doing?
- She's a bloody mess.
- They find the shooter?
- The FBI is still looking.
Has your phone
been ringing off the hook?
I'm trying to head that off.
I have a press conference
in 20 minutes.
I am so glad you were here
to be the one
to handle Cade's surgery.
Bullet wounds, FBI,
a doctor shot in the street?
Life is fragile.
- I'm so grateful for you.
- Oh, me too.
You know, poor Cade. As far
as I can tell, she's got no one.
Conrad's there for her.
- I can handle this.
- Well, we'll handle it together.
All I'm saying
is I can run point
if you want me to.
I know this is nothing like Nic,
but she is a friend
and a colleague
that we want to save.
- The situation's got to be a trigger.
- No.
Not even close.
We can save Cade.
- Okay. How?
- Billie was right.
Cade did bank her own blood.
She moved it
with her every time
she switched cities. There are
two units at Atlanta General.
They're on the way now.
Great news. Did you tell Bell
to get the OR ready
for when it gets here?
On my way to do it.
All right. I'll stay here
and keep an eye on her vitals.
Great. Remember, we have
to watch her drainage, too.
Tells us what's going on
in her abdomen.
- If it starts filling up with blood...
- I know all this.
I got it.
The lockdown of Chastain's ER
created tremendous stress
on the Atlanta hospital system.
I'm relieved to say
that we are now open.
But our ER doctor who was shot
is in critical condition.
Dr. Voss, since you're refusing
to save Jimmy Miller's life,
would you consider transferring
him to another hospital?
- Jimmy Miller? I...
- What if someone
made a directed donation?
How does Chastain respond
to the accusation
that you are punishing Miller
for being anti-vax?
Are you denying a patient
life-saving organs
- because you don't like his politics?
- Are you?
I'm here to discuss
an act of violence
against
a health care professional,
not Chastain's policy,
which is consistent
with policy
throughout the country,
requiring vaccination
for transplant listing.
- Is this a UNOS requirement?
- Jimmy Miller is
the father of a young child.
Would you let him die?
- Who the hell is Jimmy Miller?
- He's a podcast host followed
- by millions.
- Who apparently
has been podcasting
from his room,
painting himself as the victim
of the deep state's
vaccine requirements
for transplantation.
He needs new lungs,
but he's anti-vax.
Since we can't list him here
for a transplant,
- I'd like to transfer him someplace else.
- Well,
I called Atlanta General.
And, as with most hospitals,
their rules
are the same as ours.
What a circus.
On a day when we don't need
any more chaos.
Look at this.
I'm in my hospital room
at Chastain Memorial
here in Atlanta,
where doctors
are refusing to list me
- for a lung transplant.
- Oh, sorry.
Why? Because I won't
get vaccinated.
Now, they say that
I'm the perfect candidate.
They say that
I'm running out of time.
And yet they're
going to let me die
because I will not give up
control...
...of my own body.
Nurse, help! Someone!
I can't breathe.
He had a coughing fit
and couldn't recover.
He needs a stat
portable chest X-ray. Call RT
and get him on a noninvasive.
And give him 40 of furosemide.
Drying him out
a little bit won't hurt.
Help him!
Just wait outside the room.
We will update you
as soon as we
get things settled, all right?
I love you.
All right, Jimmy.
- Just take some deep breaths.
- And this is
gonna do some of the work
for you.
It's gonna help you breathe.
I lied before.
Get me lungs.
I'm vaccinated.
Cade's banked blood is here.
Just in time.
There's one unit
in each of these.
Help me open them up. Quick.
They're frozen shut.
Cade must have banked them
a long time ago.
Got it.
All right.
Now let's warm 'em up.
The bags are leaking.
We were careful.
How did that happen?
Plastic must have cracked
when it thawed.
Blood was frozen too long,
and now all of it
is contaminated.
Are we out of options?
Both units lost? Okay,
just let me know what I can do.
- He was lying.
- Who?
Jimmy Miller. Podcast host.
He's fully vaccinated.
He blurted it out
when he couldn't breathe
and felt what it's like
to be dying.
Which means he technically
meets our transplant criteria.
I even have
his vaccination records.
That was his only barrier.
We need to list him.
We cure saints and sinners both.
Given the choice,
we err on the side
of second chances.
Yeah, but since we can't
reveal to anyone
that he's vaccinated,
even his wife...
The public is going to think
that we're violating
our own rules.
It doesn't change the fact
that he's now in compliance
with our requirements.
I'll deal
with the fallout later.
We have far bigger problems.
Cade's banked blood is unusable.
- Oh, no.
- And the Red Cross
is coming up empty-handed.
They're broadening their search,
but we all know
how long that takes.
What if we don't
give her blood at all?
Devon is proposing
we use Hemoglobin 2.0.
Yes. It is a blood substitute
synthesized
from cow hemoglobin
that can carry oxygen
- all around the body.
- Yeah, I'm familiar with it.
Supposed to save soldiers
in combat
who didn't have access
to transfusion.
- Key words, "supposed to."
- Yeah,
exactly. I mean,
blood substitutes can be toxic.
Kidney damage,
heart failure, death.
And they're not approved
by the FDA.
I'm not crazy about the idea,
but Cade will die
if we don't do something.
The anecdotal evidence
is promising.
The Cleveland Clinic recently
used a similar blood substitute
on a patient
with hemorrhagic shock.
Saved her life.
I can connect you
with the head of the company.
We're gonna need the FDA to get us expanded access and fast.
Slow down. Let's just take
a beat and talk this out,
'cause the risks
are considerable.
Her lactate's climbing to five.
Crit is still falling,
and creatinine's up
to two. I mean, what are we
waiting for, for her to code?
Well, let's say
we give it to her
and she dies
and the Red Cross comes through
moments later
or her father arrives in time
- to give blood.
- Every moment
with a blood count this low
is another moment
her organs aren't perfused.
Brain included.
I'm with Conrad.
It's a temporary solution,
but we can't
just sit on our hands and wait.
All right.
Let's get the process started.
Okay.
Hey.
What's the good word?
We're gonna list you for lungs.
Oh! Thank you, doctors.
Jimmy, you were right.
They changed their minds.
- Our policy hasn't changed.
- We only list patients for transplant
if they've been vaccinated.
But you made an exception.
Of course
they made an exception.
- They felt the public pressure and...
- No exceptions.
But if you didn't change
your policy
or make an exception, then...
Are you-are you
saying Jimmy's vaccinated?
- We did not say that.
- HIPAA privacy rules
prohibit the release
of protected
health care information
without consent.
- Oh, my God.
- Uh, Lola, take it easy.
I knew you lied
about a lot of things.
It's like a game to you.
But you lied to other people,
not to me.
At least, that's what I thought.
Tell me the truth right now.
Have you been vaccinated
all along?
Jimmy Jr. got the measles
because of you!
No shots for your own son?
He nearly died because
it turned into pneumonia.
And I had a blood clot
from COVID,
and I was in the hospital
for weeks,
and you were vaccinated
the whole time,
you son of a bitch!
HIPPA doesn't apply to me.
So the whole world will now know
what a liar you are.
Lawyer up.
I'm divorcing you.
Bet it'll be extra sore
with this many jabs.
One vaccine down, five to go.
Well, you're making
the right choice.
Oh, I regret
I didn't make it sooner.
At least
I can do my part to help.
Stop some of the damage
he caused.
"Vaccines: Guess who got them?
Begins with 'J' and ends with 'immy.'"
Plenty more to come.
I'm gonna get back at that man
using the only language
he cares about.
All right, hit me again.
- Dr. Conrad Hawkins?
- Yeah.
I got your HB 2.0.
Just need to see your ID.
Thank you
for getting here so quickly.
You caught a break.
I was at Emory today.
You're a first-time user, yes?
Yeah, but I've read up on it.
Start slow.
- Monitor her heart rate, blood pressure.
- Pressure will shoot up quick.
You don't want her
to stroke out.
Once you give it, your lab
may refuse to run the samples.
They'll say they're hemolyzed.
Tell them to do it anyway.
Uh, ignore the crit.
Trust your hemoglobin.
Don't look at her sat, either.
That's gonna drop.
It's not real.
Get a blood gas.
- Text me with any questions.
- All right, will do.
And, uh, don't forget to snap
a photo when she's better.
I collect them.
Thank you.
She's maxed out
on nor epinephrine
and vasopressin.
I'll hang an epi drip.
All the pressors in the world
aren't gonna do anything
if she hasn't got any blood.
I'm gonna hang
another bolus of albumin.
Maybe buy us some time.
It's here.
All right.
Time to make a miracle, gents.
Damn it.
Her sats are dropping.
It's not a real reading.
The HB 2.0 interferes
with the probe's ability
to measure her oxygen level.
She's okay.
Just wait.
That's the best pressure
we've seen
- all day.
- Okay, this is her window.
I'll get the team
to meet me in the OR.
They've got her, Conrad.
I hope so.
What are you most worried about?
That I decided on the HB 2.0
too soon and she'll have
some complication.
You didn't have any other
choice. We both know that.
I'm very worried about Cade.
But I'm also worried about you.
Devon already covered
that territory.
I'm okay.
Are you really?
I think the question
everyone's thinking
and no one is saying is...
How personal is this, Conrad?
- It's personal for all of us.
- That's not what I'm asking.
Are you in love with Cade?
No.
Are you sure?
What do you mean?
She knew she had to leave,
so we didn't go there.
She put up barriers
to protect herself.
So did I.
What are your barriers?
Ah, it's obvious.
It always comes back to Nic.
Something stops me,
and it's not just with Cade.
It's with...
It's with others, too.
What stops you?
I'm not sure.
Am I protecting myself, maybe?
'Cause I can't face
another loss like that.
And-and...
do I feel like
I'm cheating on Nic?
I don't know. Um...
All I know
is that whatever I feel
only goes so far.
And then the walls come up.
Maybe you just need
a little push.
How's it going?
They're prepping her
as carefully
as they can.
But I think they're ready now.
Those laps pads are all
that's staunching the bleeding.
Pulling them out
could unleash a torrent.
If it does, her survival
depends on that team.
Okay, on three.
- Let's do it.
- One, two, three.
I need suction in here.
2-0 stick tie to me now.
Stitch. Suction. More suction.
All right, bleeding is coming
from the lesser sac.
I need better retraction.
Our pressure isn't pretty, team.
I'm giving
more blood substitute.
Damn it, the bowel's
more injured
than anticipated.
I'm gonna try and save it.
Stapler.
We got a bleeder
at the head of the pancreas.
And at the stump of
the splenic artery. I need to tie it off.
I'm dangerously close
to the SMA. More suction.
Come on, I need help here.
She made it through the night?
Yeah.
Do you think she'll live?
I don't know.
But if she does,
the question is
is she gonna have
permanent brain damage?
We're going to extubate her now.
We're gonna know more soon.
I want to be hopeful,
but she lost so much blood.
That's a sickening thought,
given how Nic died.
It's like he wants to
relive what happened to Nic
and rewrite the ending.
I wish we could rewrite
our ending.
I never saw it coming.
I want us to find ground
we can stand on somehow
so we can work together.
I can't imagine that right now.
I guess we're both...
...hurting.
"Liar, liar,
super-vaxxed pants on fire."
"How many people died
because he lied?"
- It's a temporary reaction.
- Yeah,
well, dishonesty
is a self-inflicted wound.
Sure, it brought you fame,
but the truth always comes out,
and now you have to deal
with the reactions.
They're talking about me.
There's no such thing
as bad press.
And I know
how to deal with this.
They need a new villain.
Lola will fill that bill.
Ah, let me guess.
Because she went public online
and called you out
as vaccinated,
- you're going to say she's lying.
- You know how many people
who say they're anti-vax
are really vaccinated?
Do they all lie to their wives?
I didn't lie to her.
She's the liar, looking
for a big divorce settlement.
Hell, she cheated on me.
And that's what
you're gonna tell your audience.
Yeah. And they'll believe me.
Because they want to.
Look, nobody cares anymore
if you lie. They're happy
to believe pure fiction.
Well,
good doctors care, Mr. Miller.
If we didn't, our patients
would die. Including you.
There would be no such thing
as organ transplants.
Blah, blah, blah.
All you doctors want to do
is bully people.
Do you always resort
to personal attacks
when you lose an argument?
You bet I do. Because it works.
Well, I'm not here
to debate you.
I have other patients
to tend to.
I'm just here to let you know
that you cannot
have a transplant at Chastain.
Vaccines are not the only thing
you need to be listed.
You also have to have someone
who's willing to be
your caregiver
for a year after the transplant.
That would have been your wife.
Well, I'll find someone else.
Well, the thing is
it can't be someone you pay.
That's what the rules say.
It has to be someone
who actually cares about you.
You think I don't have that?
You tell me.
You know what?
I am done with you.
I'm gonna get myself
to another hospital.
Yeah. Good luck with that,
Mr. Miller.
Yeah. Mm.
Hey, partner.
I can't tell you how happy I am
to hear those two words.
You must have had some drama.
Any pain?
Not too much.
I must be on some fine drugs.
Well, I made sure of that.
Thank you.
It's good news.
Your neuro exam is pristine,
Dr. Sullivan.
And it makes me very happy
to say that.
It'll be a long recovery,
but you're on your way.
And we have more good news.
More blood, your type,
just arrived downstairs.
Your father's here.
Just flew in from Seattle.
Came straight from the airport.
"Howlin' for You"
by The Black Keys playing...
All right
Yeah
I must admit
I can't explain
Any of these thoughts racin'
Through my brain, it's true
A-baby, I'm howlin' for you.
I am so sorry to do this.
I hate people who jump the line,
but this is an emergency.
Hi.
My name is Dr. Ian Sullivan.
I'm here
to save my daughter's life.
Captioning sponsored by
20th CENTURY FOX TELEVISION
and TOYOTA.
Captioned by Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org