According to this man's
family, he was not a smoker.
But the truth is, he
smoked two packs a day
in his car for 20 years
while his wife
and children slept.
Sometimes, the patient's
shame is the elephant in the room.
They try to hide it from us.
But you can't hide
from a surgeon,
because the body doesn't lie.
The truth is right here,
for everyone to see.
And it doesn't need
to say a single word.
So, uh, DeLuca and I
are basically not talking.
Just like you two.
Only different.
Obviously.
Yeah, I mean, we say "hi,"
but, uh, there's no talking.
I mean, even after
the amazing sex.
Once you've had that,
you would think it would be
easier to have a conversation.
So...
That woman starts today,
the resident from Dillard.
Do you want to talk about that?
'Cause you should.
It doesn't burn
when I pee anymore.
It's your first day.
How... How do you...
It's okay.
You don't have to do that.
Hi.
Can you guys tell me how to
find out whose service I'm on?
I mean, which attending?
You should ask her.
I'm probably not
qualified to answer that.
Just check your e-mail.
Thank you.
As you know, transfer residents
traditionally do
their first rotation
with the Chief of General
Surgery, which is you,
and, as you also know,
our newest transfer,
Penelope Blake,
is starting today.
So, you understand how
this could have happened...
What is "this"?
Dr. Blake is on your service.
However, um, Dr. Webber
has offered to take over.
Or I can. You just say the word.
I'll take Blake.
You don't have to.
I'm Chief of
General. It's the job.
You sure?
Of course. I'll do it.
Uh...
Uh, sir... Sir, you
can't park there.
Oh, no, I'm not parking.
I'm just stopping for a sec.
No, this is for patients only.
Yeah, yeah, I got a
patient. No worries.
All righty.
Well, we're a little
late, but we're here.
You ready for this?
Yeah.
Did this case a year ago.
Looks amazing. And
we're doing something
like this again today? Yeah.
April's bringing in a kid from
Jordan with Ollier's disease.
You can see, these
are the enchondromas.
Cartilaginous tumors.
They grow from the
growth plates, right?
Exactly.
Which is why you're gonna
want to do a wide local excision,
expose the bone so I can get in
there and reconstruct the hand.
Wait, wait, wait, wait. I will?
I'll dissect the tumors?
I thought so.
If you're up for it.
Hell yes, I am.
Are you ready?
They're on their way up.
Uh, why don't you head up
to peds, help him get settled?
Yeah.
Thank you for doing this.
Listen, it's a great case.
And it's just a resection.
He's such a sweet kid.
He's an amazing kid.
He's been through
hell in Jordan,
and he just never gives up.
Since he lost his family,
he's been living at the hospital,
and we just give him all
these odd jobs to do and...
April, you can stop selling
him, okay? It's happening.
We are doing it, so...
Good. Just... I just...
Thanks for putting
our stuff aside, and...
Let's go see him.
Yes.
I am...
I understand I'm on
your service today.
That's right.
Dr. Grey, I just want to say,
I don't want today to be
awkward or uncomfortable.
So don't make it awkward or
uncomfortable like this, right now.
If there's anything that I...
Consult in the
pit. We're walking.
Robert Matthews, 30s, fell
down two flights of stairs.
Possible LOC.
He's been complaining
of abdominal pain.
I can arrange for a
head CT or page neuro.
All I need is an ultrasound.
No! Oh!
Whoa, whoa! Calm down. Okay.
No, I... I have to go!
Okay.
Relax!
I did something bad,
really bad and I...
Where am I?
How'd I get here?
Relax. You fell
down some stairs.
I was trying to get
up to the choir loft.
Choir loft?
I'm the pastor at First
Lutheran, and I had...
There was an accident.
I accidentally...
Oh, God. I have to go!
Hey.
Okay, listen, Robert,
you have to calm down,
or you're gonna
make this worse, okay?
It's not okay!
I sent it to everyone.
Sent what?
The church bulletin.
I went to attach the video of
the youth volleyball game, and...
I've been seeing
someone. A woman.
A nice, but sort of
adventurous woman.
But nice and...
Okay, now you lost me.
I attached the wrong video.
You sent a sex tape?
To my entire congregation.
Oh, good God!
Yeah, can we not talk
about him right now?
I rode on a bus,
a train, a plane,
three cars, and a helicopter.
That's amazing!
Um, Kamal, I want
you to meet Dr. Avery.
He's gonna perform
your operation. Hi.
You are the guy?
"The guy"? Um...
There she is! The machine!
Nathan!
Hey.
Oh, man! Hey!
Thank you, thank you, thank
you for bringing him here.
Hey, come on. Of course.
Nathan and I worked
together on my last tour.
Dr. Riggs, this is Jackson.
Oh. Dr. Avery.
Yeah, Nathan Riggs. Hey.
Hey. Trauma surgeon?
Cardiothoracic, but over there,
it's pretty much all
trauma, you know?
Sure. Sure, yeah.
Dr. Riggs! He is the guy!
What is "the guy"?
The first time we met Kamal,
Keps said, "I know the
guy who can fix your hands."
So ever since, he's been
talking about meeting "the guy."
Well, Kamal, let's
take a look, huh?
Oh.
Okay. Let's get
this guy up here.
All right. Look at this.
Okay.
Uh-huh.
You can fix them?
That's the plan.
You never told me
it was this advanced.
Those tumors are massive.
Okay, maybe I
downplayed it a little.
You downplayed it?
This looks impossible!
I don't understand. You
sent him the scans, right?
Didn't you see the scans?
She told me the scans
were lost in Jordan.
I didn't want him
to see the scans.
Wait. What?
Keps, what the hell?
You lied!
If you had seen the scans,
you might have said no,
and I wanted you
to meet that little boy.
And he's here now.
So how do we help him?
Hey. So, Blake's on
Meredith's service?
Uh, looks like it.
She gonna be all
right? I don't know.
We haven't spoken
since the party.
She feels like I'm
on Meredith's side.
And I am, you know?
But it doesn't mean I'm
not on Penny's side, too.
And now Meredith's not
even talking to me, so win-win!
Oh, God.
Seventy-eight new messages?
They know.
They all know.
What's your assessment?
Well, I think... Not you. Blake.
Ultrasound showed
fluid in Morison's pouch.
We should get an abdominal CT.
And what are we
looking for on the CT?
We need to rule out bleeding
from the liver or the spleen.
We should also evaluate
the retroperitoneal space.
If there's active
bleeding on the CT,
we set him up for an ex-lap.
Are you forgetting anything?
Uh, we cleared his C-spine,
we sent blood out
for a trauma panel,
tox screen, alcohol levels.
And?
And, uh... Order a
type and crossmatch.
Oh. Of course.
Obviously. I... I skipped that.
Okay, well, let's
not skip steps.
We're a Level I Trauma Center.
I need to know what
Dillard taught you.
Let's fill him with fluids
and prep him for a CT.
I didn't lie. I...
You bent the truth a bit.
Until it broke.
It was a good lie.
Okay, it was a bad lie,
but for a good reason.
You know, you haven't been
saying yes to anything lately,
not when it comes from me.
Look at the scans, April.
Okay, these areas are
pure cartilage, right?
They probably destroyed any bone
that was in their path.
Guys, we don't even know
there's anything resembling
hands underneath these things.
Can you even repair the tendons
and the neurovascular bundles?
That's doubtful.
Well, Hopkins and Case
Western did similar cases.
They reconstructed
using bone grafts.
Oh, so have I, and you know
those cases are nothing
compared to Kamal's.
April, he's saying no.
Look, we'll just keep
looking until we find someone.
And they will all say
the exact same thing.
Thanks.
Thanks for taking the time.
Look, I'm not saying no.
I'm saying I will
do some biopsies
so that we can
all get a full picture
of what it is we're
dealing with here.
Thank you.
I heard there was a
bad driver in the house.
Uncle Richard!
Man, you look bald.
And you look old.
"Uncle Richard"?
Yeah, Adele and I knew
Paul and his late wife, Lois,
before we got married.
Bumpy and I go way back.
"Bumpy"? Why "Bumpy"?
Uh... Hey.
Morning, Angela.
Uh...
Tell me about the accident.
How did it happen?
All I know is I
pressed the brake,
but the damn car kept going.
Right into a tree.
Yeah, she's got a severely
displaced clavicular fracture
and a weak pulse
in her right arm.
How about Paul?
I'll be fine. Angela
got the worst of it.
Still, I want to work you
up, too, just to be safe.
So I'll go ahead and
schedule that CTA.
That sound good to you, Bumpy?
That'll be quite enough of that.
Sorry.
Dr. Bumpy.
Tell me what you see.
Retroperitoneal fluid.
Around what? Be specific.
The right kidney.
It's a grade IV injury with
an active extravasation.
We are gonna
need to do an ex-lap.
Should I call upstairs?
What do we have?
Uh, patient came in with
a head lac, GCS of 14,
loss of consciousness
at the scene...
Can you clear the head CT so
we can take him up for an ex-lap?
There's no shift,
contusion, or bleed.
It's a mild concussion.
I'll do a quick exam,
but he's cleared for surgery.
Is this the pastor who
gave his congregation
a, uh, special blessing?
Word travels fast.
All around the hospital.
Yeah, I bet the pews
will be full on Sunday.
Monitor for any neuro deficits.
I will do another
check, post-op.
Blake, get him
ready for transport.
Edwards, show her where it is.
It's not enough to have her
here in the same building.
You invited her on
your service, too?
I am trying to rise above.
And you should, too.
No, you should have
ended it that night.
Forget it.
It was better when
we weren't talking.
As I feared, the biopsy showed
precancerous cells in the tumor.
Both sides.
Okay. Then we need
to get in there ASAP...
April, listen, there is no clear
way to excise all the tumor.
So I have to
recommend amputation.
Of both hands.
No.
It is his best shot before
it progresses to cancer.
No. I brought him to
you to save his hands.
This is how we save his life.
Well, I don't know.
I don't see how he
survives over there
with no hands and no
one to take care of him.
I understand. I'm sorry.
I could have told you sooner
if I had all the information.
You mean you could
have given up sooner.
Yes, you're right, because
there's nothing to be done.
You could try!
You could make an effort
instead of just giving
up and walking away!
And you don't think I want to?
All right, we're not doing this.
Could you leave us
alone for a second, please?
Oh, absolutely, I'm gonna leave,
and I'm gonna take
Kamal with me, all right?
'Cause this isn't
about you two! Okay?
This is about a little boy who
had to see his family murdered,
who saw his home
burned to the ground,
who would've been
taken as a child soldier
if it wasn't for his
deformed hands.
All right, he doesn't
have the time
for you guys to be
working out your crap!
He deserves the
best care he can get,
and I'm gonna
make sure he finds it.
Why'd you even bring him to me?
You saw the scans.
You're a good surgeon.
You knew this was hopeless.
I wasn't hopeless.
I don't know why you are.
Because there's
nothing here to save.
What's the trickiest part
of a partial nephrectomy?
Well, I think it's
essential that...
Not you. Blake.
Mobilizing the colon quickly to get
adequate exposure of the kidney.
By your third year,
you should know this
surgery inside and out.
I do. Okay.
So you are gonna
walk me through this.
Your hands are my hands,
and my hands do not
like making mistakes.
Are you ready?
I am. Yes, I'm ready.
With what? Because I
have nothing in my hands.
Right. Uh, 10 blade.
10 blade.
CTA results showed an injury
to an artery in Angela's chest.
She's on her way to pre-op now.
She doesn't want you
to worry, and neither do I.
You sound just like Bumpy.
You have to tell me why
you call him "Bumpy."
Well, that's 'cause,
back in the day, when
we were in college...
Got your results back.
Oh, you hurt your foot?
No, no, it's fine.
It's pins and needles, is all.
It's... It's, uh... It's
just a little numb.
It'll go away.
I don't think it
will, not by itself.
Your labs show elevated
hemoglobin A1c levels.
And your blood glucose
level is very high.
You're diabetic.
But you already knew that.
Listen, Bumpy, I've been
taking better care of myself.
Angela doesn't know, and...
And I want us to keep it that way.
That pain in your foot?
It's a symptom, Paul.
It's called diabetic nerve pain.
It could be the reason
you crashed your car.
Are you saying I put
my baby in the hospital?
No. It was an accident.
She loves you.
She'll understand.
Just tell her...
Do you have any
children, Richard?
Do you?
No. No, I don't.
So you don't know a damn thing.
You can't possibly understand.
Please, just... Just
take care of my little girl,
and leave me be.
I'll let you know as soon
as Angela's out of surgery.
And now Jackson
wants to amputate.
He won't even try. He
said it was hopeless.
He... He asked me why I
even brought Kamal to him.
What?
Well? Why did you?
I mean, the scans were so bad,
you had to lie about them.
You lied about
a little boy, April.
I'm... What... What
are you saying?
Nothing. I'm sorry.
I'm saying, I
know what it's like
when it feels like
everything's coming apart
and you need something
to pull it together.
I just...
I know.
Are you sure?
Well, maybe you can
show them to Rogers.
Yeah, I'd appreciate it.
All right, call me
back. Thanks, Charlie.
Riggs?
Hunt.
What are you doing here?
April Kepner and
I met in Jordan.
I've been working with the
relief effort in Afghanistan.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
What are you doing here?
We have a patient
with Ollier's disease.
Brought him in to your hand guy.
And then you're leaving.
Yeah, well, maybe
a little sooner than I...
I'm not asking you,
Riggs. I'm telling you.
Nice catching up.
Incise Gerota's fascia.
Now identify and
debride devitalized tissue.
Go on.
Um...
Cauterize cortical bleeders
and establish
hemostasis before closure.
Now close using a
running absorbable suture
to avoid post-op fistulas.
You can even reinforce
using an absorbable mesh.
Well, that's thinking
ahead. I like that.
Dr. Grey. Dr. Blake.
I thought I'd stop in to see
how the first day was going.
Thank you, sir. It's been...
Blake has been dictating
my surgical steps.
Great. How's she
doing? Not too well.
If I had done what
she just suggested,
the patient would have
major renal cortex bleeding.
What did you miss?
I... What?
What did I do that you missed?
Uh, debride,
hemostasis, close...
Come on. Figure it out.
I was watching
you. I didn't see.
DeLuca, can you
fill in the blanks?
Um, Dr. Blake didn't tell
you to clamp the hilum.
Dr. Grey, the hilum is clamped.
It is, sir, because I
clamped it on my own.
I didn't skip a
step, and therefore,
the patient did not
hemorrhage and die.
Blake, hand your
suction to DeLuca.
Dr. Grey, I know this procedure.
You would've killed
the patient, Blake.
If your hands had been
my hands on this patient,
he'd be dead.
It's that simple.
Step away from the table.
What's wrong?
Dr. Grey is what's wrong.
I'm new.
And attendings are
hard on residents.
I know that. It's how we learn.
And she should be hard on
me. She should be grilling me.
And I should be
able to handle it.
But I let her in
my head. I froze.
I knew that surgery
backwards and forwards.
Hey, I can talk to her.
No. Don't.
I'm sorry. I just...
I will figure this out.
It's not your problem.
I sent the biopsies, the
scans to three other guys.
Any luck?
No.
Well, I'd like to
have been wrong.
Hey, look, I'm sorry you
got pulled into this, man.
April can be...
No, look, I know.
She's the machine.
She's the what?
Oh, that's what we call her
over there, "The machine."
It never slows down,
never lets it get to her.
Just makes everyone
else want to work harder.
When she decides on something,
nothing's gonna stop her.
You can't call that one off.
No, that's true.
Thing is, she's usually right.
Go find out what Callie
Torres is doing right now.
Oh. Angela's surgery is over?
How... How'd it go?
Did a primary repair
of the subclavian artery.
It went very well.
You can tell your
friend she's fine.
Maggie, uh, about Paul.
You know, what he said
about my not having children...
Paul knew me with
Adele, my wife...
I know. I know. It's...
It's awkward. Awful.
No, you don't have to
say another word. I get it.
Okay.
I just wanted to make sure...
Don't
say another word.
Are you... No.
No, no. Of course not.
This is, um...
This is allergies.
Allergies?
Can we please pretend
that it's allergies?
Maggie, if I did something...
No, no. God, no.
You... You cheated on your wife.
Why should you admit
that to your friend?
Who would that help?
Not you, not him.
And, you know, you
don't owe me anything.
You and I, we're not...
I don't know what we are.
That's just the thing.
I don't exactly know
how to address you...
Yeah, you don't have to. But...
It's fine.
You have nothing to
be ashamed of. Really.
But...
So, they would just be gone?
Both of them?
We would have to amputate them
right about here, at the wrist.
You see?
On both sides.
Will I still carry things?
Well, let's talk
about that, buddy.
You'll be here when I'm done?
Yes. I promise.
You sure about this?
Nope. Not even a little bit.
We'll have a soda
waiting for you, okay?
Okay.
God.
All right, guys,
how we doing this?
Doing what?
I figure we'll just
debulk the tumor
from the dorsal surface,
and you can show me
what, if any, usable
bone we can find.
There's been a change of plans.
Yeah, judging by the scans,
I'm not sure there's
anything at all. I know.
It just might end up being
the world's slowest amputation,
but can't hurt to try. Mmm-hmm.
But you told Kamal
that he wouldn't...
We lied.
We had to. Didn't want
to get his hopes up again.
He's gonna try? Mmm-hmm.
You lied! To me!
It was a good lie. Come
on. It was a good lie.
Oh, my God.
He's gonna try.
We need to talk.
What's wrong?
I thought you were stepping up,
putting Blake on your service,
but what I saw in that
OR wasn't teaching.
She crapped out on a
basic surgical principle.
You were hazing her.
If she cracks under the
pressure of an emergent surgery,
she does not belong
in this program.
Blake was at the top
of her class at Dillard.
Her references were
impeccable. I checked them myself.
You checked?
So you knew where she was from?
You checked her case record?
Her losses?
Did you know that she...
She was an excellent candidate.
You were the only
reason not to hire her.
And you didn't find
that reason enough?
Your labs are
within normal limits.
That's good news.
I'm on every website.
Got an e-mail from our bishop.
I'm fired.
Someone's threatening
to bring me up
on charges as a sexual predator.
I'm done.
We're supposed
to be a community.
I make one simple mistake,
and they destroyed me.
Put it away.
My mother saw it.
Her friends won't talk to her.
Everybody's trying to
figure out who the woman is,
as if it's any of
their business.
Thank the Lord, she's okay.
At least her life
isn't over, too.
Nothing is over.
It's different for
us, the clergy.
People put their
trust in us, their faith.
We break that
trust, it stays broken.
I can't believe that.
You know who you are.
You can stand up to
them and have faith in that,
have faith in yourself.
I have to believe that.
They say he doesn't give
you more than you can handle.
You say that, actually.
Yes, I do.
Ow.
Are you okay?
My stomach.
Nurse! Coming!
There is a clot in his catheter.
His bladder's about to rupture.
I need a syringe with
some saline and heparin,
and page Dr. Grey, now!
Right away.
You're okay.
Those nerves are
going everywhere.
How do you build
something from that?
Well, for what it's worth,
I think you were
right about him.
He's good.
I know.
He's talking about divorce.
Well, you kind of saw
that coming, though, right?
I mean, he said,
"Don't go." You went.
On some level...
It's not gonna happen.
It's not what I want.
I don't believe
it's what he wants.
I know it's not what
God wants from me.
We're looking at a kid
who's lost his family,
his home.
Might even lose his hands now.
Maybe God has more on his mind
than judging whether
you get a divorce or not.
Don't you think he
has bigger fish to fry?
I've got about 60% of
bone structure over here.
How's it going over there?
I only see free-floating
distal phalanges,
and some of them
are eroded by tumor.
We're approaching the
carpals or what's left of them.
I'm looking for
metacarpals over here.
Do you see any
viable bone at all?
Well... No.
Damn it! JACKSON:
What? What is it? Tell me.
Jackson, I'm sorry. I'm just...
There's nothing here. I...
No, no, no. Wait.
Just wait one second.
Well, no. There's
no bone to work with.
I mean, look at
it. Look right here.
There's fingers, and
then there's nothing.
I don't... Come on. Come on.
Jackson, I think...
Just wait, okay?
I think that you were right.
I don't want to be
right, though. I just...
Let's keep going, please, okay?
Yeah, of course.
Put that down!
We are working here!
We're gonna keep
going until we are sure
that there is nothing left.
Now, do not pick that up
again unless I tell you to.
Jackson? I'm
sorry. I was just...
No, no, no, Jackson,
look right here. Look.
I found something.
I found lunate bone.
This is good lunate bone.
What happened?
I think he clotted his Foley.
I've flushed it five times.
I can't get a new one in.
He's hypotensive.
Get me a 50 cc with
a 14-gauge needle.
You got it. How did this happen?
I was doing a post-op check,
and I saw that there
was blood in his bag.
How long did it take
for you to notice?
I don't... Uh, we
were talking...
You realize if he
goes into renal failure,
this will undo everything
we did in the OR today.
Dr. Grey, I didn't
miss this. I caught it.
It shouldn't have happened!
You froze in the OR, you
screwed up his post-op care!
Is there any part of this job
that you can handle, Blake?
I...
Get out. You're not
touching this patient.
You're off my service.
Get out!
Now!
All right. The
hamate bone's intact.
There's the trapezoid.
And...
There's the scaphoid.
That makes four
good carpal bones.
Which is not much.
And almost no metacarpal.
But we'd have a base
for a proximal phalanx,
so that might regenerate.
He is young, so...
Maybe we could sculpt the bone
and graft the gap in between?
We could wire
them with rib grafts.
I mean, then I could actually
make something out of that.
Yes! Look! Look! That's
a fifth metacarpal head!
Look! Right there!
That's a hand. That
is what we needed.
Under there, that's...
That is a hand!
We got a hand, people!
Whew!
Oh, my God!
I can't friggin' believe it.
I did.
She is going to be fine.
And you should talk to her.
I don't even know if I can
look her in the eye now,
let alone talk to her.
Thirty years ago,
I had an affair.
I cheated on Adele.
And I had a daughter.
I have a daughter.
Adele never told Lois or
anyone about the affair.
She never bashed
me to her family.
She lived with that pain and
embarrassment for years, alone.
She protected me,
and I'm ashamed of that.
It was a mess.
I made a mess.
And for as much pain
as I caused and felt,
I would have never believed
that nything good
would have come of it.
But it did.
She did.
And I am very proud to know her.
You were right. She
doesn't belong here.
She almost killed a patient.
She can't be trusted, not
in the OR, not with patients.
She's just dangerous.
Say it again.
What?
I was right.
I tried to rise above because
it's the right thing to do.
But she has made
mistake after mistake,
and she just is impossible.
I'm sorry. It's the truth.
She is working at a hospital
that is above her skill level.
I have tried to
teach her all day.
I have tried.
Oh, please. You're
being a bully.
And you've gone out of
your way to make her...
You don't teach by shoving
someone else's face in the dirt.
That's not teaching.
That's just being
mean and small.
Leave me alone.
Since when do you pray?
I'm not.
Or talk to God or whatever.
I'm not talking to God.
Well, you talk to tequila.
I'm talking to Derek.
Oh.
Okay, I'll go.
I'm trying.
I've tried to rise, I've
tried to teach her, but I just
don't think I can.
I thought he might know
what I'm supposed
to do with her,
why she's here.
I thought maybe
he could tell me.
So, I'm just gonna sit here and
wait for some divine
intervention or whatever.
They look like hands.
They are.
They're your hands, bud.
- They're real hands!
- Yeah!
I can hold a ball.
Yeah.
Take a little bit of time, a
few more surgeries, but yes.
What did we tell
you? He's the guy.
You are the guy.
Oh! Ah.
He never did tell me
why they call you "Bumpy."
There was a dance called
the bump, before your time,
and I excelled at it.
You didn't tell him it was me.
Well, I feel, if you
want to tell people,
that's your decision, not mine.
I'm sorry. I'm still
trying to figure this out.
Okay.
But for the record,
I'd be fine with it if you did.
Very fine.
Noted.
Yeah.
April.
I, uh... I never said
thanks for bringing Kamal.
I'm so sorry for lying, but...
God, you have no idea
what you did for that little boy.
No, no, no. You did it.
I mean, you brought him.
'Cause I knew you could do it.
Okay.
We did it.
Just, thank you.
Do you want to go... - Hey.
You ready?
Um, Nathan's leaving tomorrow,
so Bailey was gonna
take us out for drinks.
She wanted to hear war stories.
Yeah.
Um, but I could just tell
them that I don't have to go.
Oh, no, no. Come on.
You guys go celebrate.
Well, come with
us. Yeah, come on.
I owe you a drink.
Another time.
Really, you guys have fun.
I didn't want Blake
here. I fought it.
Then why did you hire her?
Because I've been
accused of coddling you,
and I didn't want to do that.
I didn't think you'd want me to.
That was one reason.
I didn't want you here, either.
When you were
accepted to this program,
I didn't know how I was
gonna look at you every day
and be reminded of the best
and worst times of my life.
And you walked in, the
spitting image of your mother.
Talented, smart.
Here, every day.
And I decided that
wasn't fair to you.
I decided to put aside
my personal feelings to...
Rise above.
And I'm glad I did that.
Every day.
He would have
said the same thing.
Derek. He probably
would have even liked her.
Excuse me. I'm
looking for a patient.
Robert Matthews?
Are you his family?
No, I'm... Uh, we work together.
Or worked together.
I'm the choir
director at our church.
Oh. You're the...
Oh. God. You saw it.
Well, I mean, of
course you saw it.
All of America saw it.
Look, he doesn't deserve this.
It's not fair that he's all
of these amazing things,
and this one mistake
is all anybody's even
gonna think about him.
Look, can I see him, please?
I want him to know that,
you know, he's got me, at least.
They say shame controls
every aspect of human behavior.
It's about who
we believe we are.
This was a mistake.
I don't think I can do this.
I don't think that
I want to do this.
I kind of went off
on Grey about you.
Callie, why?
Why are you making this harder?
I did what I should've
done at the party.
Callie, I get it.
They're your friends.
He was...
You're a surgeon.
We make mistakes.
We need to be forgiven.
I will if you will.
And...
I'm here.
If...
If you are.
I'm here, too.
But in the end, you can't hide,
and the body doesn't lie.
The truth is right there
for the world to see.
It's Grey.
She wants me all week. Hmm.
She still wants to work with me?
Or she still wants to ruin you.
Yeah.
Yeah, it's definitely
one of those.
Come on.
Our shame can choke us, kill us.
It can rot us from the inside
if we decide to let it.
Don't let that happen to you.