I'm the man
Come 'round
No-no-nothing can break
You can't break me down
I got gas in the tank
I got money in the bank
I got news for you, baby,
you're looking at the man
Looking at the man
I got skin in the game
I don't feel no pain
I got news for you, baby,
you're looking at the man
Thanks.
Wow, some showy
new wheels.
Not cheap.
What are we talking? 125?
In the neighborhood.
Not one I've ever lived in.
Morning.
Good morning.
Nice looking.
But is she attracted
to you or the car?
I'm gonna go find out.
Catch up to you later.
Hi.
Connor.
Lisette.
That's it.
You got this.
Nice job, little man.
I think you got
a future architect here.
Or a demolitions expert.
Oh, I get a turn.
Thank you.
Owen,
is that good?
You like that?
Told ya.
We'll just have to rebuild
it again now, won't we?
Ow!
What happened?
I have no idea.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Patton.
The Evil Dead.
Usual?
The Dirty Dozen.
Texas Chainsaw Massacre.
Come on, all your favorite
movies can't be slasher films.
Better than
World War II flicks.
They're classics.
What can I get you?
Chai tea latte, almond milk,
no water, no foam, extra hot.
You got it.
Black coffee.
It is mystifying how little
we have in common.
Luckily, opposites attract.
Works for me.
Got a chai tea latte,
no water, no foam,
almond milk,
extra hot.
Thank you.
Really?
Hers comes out first?
He'll pay.
Catch you later.
I need a doctor, please!
What's wrong? Are you hurt?
Not me, a woman,
two blocks over,
she's on the ground,
isn't moving.
Show me.
Excuse me, excuse me.
Hey, can you hear me?
Can you hear me?
Who saw what happened?
She jogged past me,
then she just fell.
I called 911.
God, is she alive?
Barely.
Can't wait on the paramedics.
I need you.
20-something female
went down while jogging.
Barely awake, weak pulse,
hypothermic.
Let's get her on the monitors
and start a line.
Bolus a liter of warm saline
and grab some blankets.
We need to raise
her body temp.
She's pretty bundled up.
How long was she exposed
to the elements?
On the ground.
Two, maybe three minutes.
That's it?
And she's hypothermic?
Yeah.
Oh, God.
There's nothing to her.
Let's get her up.
Okay.
This side.
Hair's brittle and thin,
lanugo covering the skin.
Anorexia.
Stethoscope.
BP 88 over 50,
heart rate 50s.
EKG is sinus brady.
Bilateral crackles.
Her eyes are yellow.
She's jaundiced.
God, I can feel
right through her
to the bed underneath.
Where am I?
Hey, in the hospital.
Can you tell me
your name?
Allison.
Allison, I'm Dr. Choi,
I'm gonna help you, okay?
I'm okay.
I just need to rest.
Let's get a CBC, CMP, LFTs,
a chest X-ray
and a 12-lead EKG.
Yep, on it.
Morning, I'm Dr. Halstead.
Asterid.
It looks like
you're hurting, too.
Need a hit?
Thanks, but let's
get you squared away first.
What happened?
I was running
up the stairs
to the platform
to catch the train.
By the time I got
to the last step,
I was...
I was so exhausted,
I tripped.
Landed on my arm.
Is it broken?
Well, maybe.
We'll get some X-rays.
Lean forward for me.
Ah.
You okay?
I tweaked my back
a few months ago.
Free clinic gave me
some anti-inflammatories.
Said they'd help.
They haven't.
I even crushed them up
and snorted them.
What?
Just kidding.
I'm a stand-up comic,
so when I see an opening
for a joke, I have to take it.
Well, timing was excellent,
I'll give you that.
Where does your back hurt?
Uh, it's a sharp pain
down here.
Mmm-hmm.
More throbbing up here.
The fall made it worse,
didn't it?
Well, I can't say
without a CT,
but no bruising or swelling,
so that's a good sign.
Hang tight.
The techs will be by soon
to take you up to Radiology.
Maggie, which nurse
do you have
covering Asterid
in Treatment Four?
You're looking at her.
Double duty again, huh?
Yep, twice the work for me,
and yet, it's the hospital's
bank account that benefits.
You know,
trickle up economics.
Absolutely.
Nice shiner.
I haven't seen one of those
on you for a while.
This time,
it wasn't my fault.
South Side boy.
Somehow, I don't buy it.
What do you need in Four?
AP lateral of the left elbow
and a CT chest and belly
with contrast.
You got it.
Dr. Reese.
Welcome back.
How are you doing?
Great, great, very eager
to dive back in.
Fantastic.
Just for the record,
easing back in is okay, too,
but thrilled you're here.
How's therapy been going?
Oh, well,
it better be going well.
Daily counseling,
anger management sessions,
meeting with
the hospital attorney.
And remember, not intended
to be a punishment.
Oh, no, of course not.
It's actually a great way
to grow professionally.
Can't hide from it.
It keeps the secrets
in their pockets.
Wonderful.
20-something woman,
agitated and out of control.
PD found her running
around in the middle
of the I-90 express lanes.
What's she on?
Nothing we can tell.
No track marks
or tweaking signs,
but a lot of rambling.
Our insides, holding in...
Airway's clearly intact.
Obviously has no problem
moving four limbs
spontaneously.
I'd say my job is done.
She's all yours.
Thank you.
Dr. Charles, Treatment Three,
can't wait.
But now I see
how everything
is filled with water...
Oh, man.
Um...
Go ahead, I've got Jane Doe.
Do a full assessment,
and we will staff it later.
Thanks.
You good?
I'm good.
Welcome back.
Don't open the box, no.
Open the box, no.
Don't open the box.
Back and forth, on and off.
Allison, how you doing?
We're here...
Take it easy there.
Easy, easy, easy.
Allison, I'm Dr. Charles.
Shrink.
So, um, something tells me
this isn't your first time
in an ED.
Not just saline, is it?
D5?
Well, your blood sugar
was 44,
so you know,
the dextrose...
Treats hypoglycemia and all
that comes with it, I know.
But at
170 calories per liter...
If I can get 80 per mile,
home to lake
and back is four,
that's 320.
So, is your math
working out?
Are you gonna be able
to burn off
those extra calories?
I don't need to be here.
Check my levels, vitamins.
Potassium.
They'll be normal.
What is the go-to trick
these days
for, you know,
gaming those numbers?
You guys still
sucking on lemons
or, I don't know, I heard
that guzzling vitamin water
is kind of coming into vogue.
I mean,
it's none of my business,
but I am curious.
How long has it been
going on for?
Five years?
Ten?
Fifteen? Fifteen years?
At least 15 years.
I want to go home.
Okay.
Allison, you know,
if you can't get out of bed,
you know that I can't...
I can't let you go, right?
And you do know
what that means.
Five hundred.
Five thousand.
One thousand.
Four thousand.
Fifteen hundred.
Three thousand.
Two.
Three.
Fine.
Three thousand calories.
And it has to be
through your nose.
If this goes.
Hmm.
Got yourself a deal.
And following the fingers,
you can count,
the count likes to laugh,
and he's just a puppet,
sometimes I feel
like a puppet,
with someone operating me...
I'm Dr. Reese.
Can you tell me your name?
Not operating on me.
Because surgery belongs in
another part of the hospital.
Each part separated
by a floor, a floor made
of marble or wood.
Can you tell me
how you got here?
Cooking things through
at a slow heat.
The temperature
cooks evenly...
Where do you live?
Through me to the core
of my eyes and my brain,
and none of it will stop.
Watching the whirring,
watching the whirring,
go, go, go, go, go, go, go.
Foot, foot, left, right,
left, right.
Back and forth, on and off,
on and off, on and off.
the switch,
the light switch breaking...
Meds first, talk later?
Please. Uh, let's get her
Risperdal M-TAB
two milligrams,
should calm her down.
All right.
I don't know why
I let you talk me
out of coming
here yesterday.
I'm fine,
it's just a really bad cold.
It's our first
vacation together.
Emergency room's
not on the itinerary.
Temp's 100.4.
See, Hannah,
it's barely a fever.
God forbid he let on
that he's sick.
I've got
a stubborn one also.
Mmm.
Me, too.
Lymph nodes are enlarged.
All right.
I'm gonna have you open
your mouth for me.
He hasn't eaten
in three days.
He can barely sip water.
It hurts that bad.
Throat's pretty raw.
Tonsils are swollen.
Yellow exudate.
What's that?
Pus.
Maybe an infection.
See, we should've
come yesterday.
I'll get a rapid strep test.
And let's get
a CBC and BMP also.
I'm sorry.
I just wanted the trip
to be perfect.
And I just want you
to be healthy.
Well, hopefully we can solve
both of your problems.
I'll be back shortly.
What, you keeping a secret?
Hey.
"Your Toddler and You."
Is this business or pleasure?
Both.
I'm looking for ideas on how
to get Owen to like me.
What makes you think
he doesn't?
Oh, I don't know.
You worry too much.
Hey, Owen's number one
in Natalie's life.
If I can't
make it work with him,
I got no shot with her.
Well, let me break down
toddlers for you.
They eat, sleep,
poop, and play.
Help 'em out with any one of
those things, and you're gold.
Radiologist's report.
Asterid's arm X-ray
and CT scans.
And no fractures?
Mmm-hmm.
Just soft tissue swelling.
Let's wrap her elbow up
and put it in a sling.
Got it.
Whoa.
What is it?
Her CT.
I need Connor and Dr. Neal
in Urology.
I got it.
3,000 calories?
It's all she's willing
to accept.
Why are you negotiating?
Dangerously low albumin,
renal insufficiency.
5'6" and less than 70 pounds.
Dr. Charles, I carried her in,
she was nothing.
She needs high-calorie,
long-term nutrition.
I agree.
Then what are you doing?
Anorexia is actually
the most deadly mental illness
that there is.
Every instinct she has
is telling her to resist this,
and I don't want to push her
any harder than she'll let us.
Then let me push her.
No.
I made a deal,
we have to honor it.
Trust me, it's her best shot.
Listen, we get 3,000,
and you'll go back for more.
Of course.
Dr. Choi,
Allison's parents are here.
Waiting room.
Thanks, Mags.
I'll fill them in
and place the feeding tube.
Is she the worst case
you've ever seen?
Healthy BMI is 18 to 25.
Hers is 11.
If she's going to survive,
we can't afford to make
any mistakes here.
She's killing herself.
So, um, so catch me up
on Jane Doe.
Um, no idea on her.
Maggie is working
with PD to get a name.
Tox screen is clean,
this isn't drug-induced.
And I'm thinking
bipolar mania.
Rapid speech,
psychomotor agitation,
flight of ideas,
plus she hasn't
bathed in days.
So, presumably,
she went manic
and fled wherever
she was living?
Stop this
You started her on Risperdal?
It hasn't made a dent.
I want to double the dose and
add a second mood stabilizer.
You ruled out
all other possibilities?
You know,
schizoaffective disorder,
temporal lobe epilepsy,
delirium,
other mood disorders?
Why?
Mania can be diagnosed
through pattern recognition
just like I've done,
and there's been no clinical
indication to keep digging
for anything else.
Just humor me,
okay, Doctor?
Look, it's your
first day back,
before you add
any other meds,
just check all the boxes,
even if you don't think
it's necessary.
Physical, neural exam,
motor function,
head CT,
all that stuff, okay?
Okay.
Okay, good.
I wish there was
something I could do.
Hi, guys,
Uh, so, Tommy,
you do not have strep.
But your body is
most likely fighting off
a bacterial infection.
So, I'm gonna start you
on clindamycin,
which is an oral antibiotic.
Whatever the bug,
it'll take care of it.
Mmm-hmm.
So we can
get out of here?
Yes, but please,
just try to take it easy
the next few days.
As cliché as it is,
rest is the best medicine.
I won't let him leave
the hotel, promise.
Ow!
Are you okay?
My ankle.
Why don't you
let me take a look?
Whoa,
that's really red.
You didn't feel anything?
Uh-uh.
Hot and fluctuant.
I and D it?
Yeah.
Now, I'm gonna make
a small incision,
so that we can get
a sample, okay?
All right,
and when I ask you to,
I'm gonna have
you take a deep breath,
and exhale for me, okay?
All right, this is gonna hurt
a little bit, all right?
Take a deep breath in.
Good.
And another one.
And again.
Good.
One last time.
Great job.
All right,
here comes the incision.
Oh.
Is that what's in my throat?
How did it get
in his ankle?
Let's just wait
and see what the lab says.
Bad news, though, you guys are
gonna have to hang out here
a little bit longer,
I'm sorry.
All right, you need anything,
I'll be close by.
Bacteria can travel once
it enters the bloodstream,
but for a new infection
to manifest that fast...
Yeah, something's
definitely going on.
See you in the lab, okay?
Yeah.
It's cancer?
Yeah, it's likely
renal cell carcinoma.
The tumor extends
from inside your left kidney,
into the inferior vena cava,
and up
into the right atrium
of your heart.
You never had
a sprained back.
The pain is from
ureteral compression.
You were exhausted
running up the stairs
because the tumor
was blocking blood
from returning
to your heart.
Asterid, you following us?
Yeah, I'm just trying
to find a joke
to cope with all of this.
That's okay.
We'll find the funny
after you've beaten this.
Mmm-hmm.
Seriously, I'm not dying?
No.
No, the cancer is treatable.
The tumor is operable.
Now, to get all of it,
I'm gonna have to involve
other surgeons,
and unfortunately,
we will have to remove
your left kidney.
But you can live
just fine with one.
I know it's a lot
to take all at once.
You don't get it.
I do open mic night.
Those gigs don't come
with health care plans.
And the three jobs
that I do have
barely cover the rent.
So I can't pay for this.
You don't have to.
The tumor invading your heart
is life-threatening,
and that means that Medicaid
will cover the surgery
and the resulting recovery.
It's not gonna
cost me anything?
No.
We're gonna
take care of you.
Allison, I'm gonna put
this tube in your nose.
When you feel it
in your throat,
I need you to swallow.
Allison, you understand?
Okay, here we go.
Swallow.
Allison, swallow.
There you go.
It's going in, nice job.
It's going to work
this time.
We've tried helping her
for years.
Doctors, rehabs.
No matter what we do,
she just keeps withering away.
Sometimes, being out
of options is what it takes
to instill desire
to get better.
X-ray.
Tube's in.
I'm gonna turn on
the pump now.
Allison, Allison.
Look at me, look at me.
Slow breaths.
I can't.
Yes, you can.
You can do this.
You're fine, you're...
No, no, stop.
Just relax,
just relax.
Stop it.
I can't do it.
I need it out!
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
No, no, no, no, no!
We'll try again.
No.
I'm done.
Allison!
I said I'm done.
Why don't we give Dr. Choi
a moment to prepare
another tube?
Maybe we can...
You're not hearing me.
I want my lawyer.
I'm serious.
Get my phone.
I'm calling my lawyer now.
Will, I'll come find you
when we're done.
I'm good.
Kidney free?
Yep, from everything
but the renal vein.
I'm vessel looping
the inferior vena cava
below it now.
I'm curious.
You score a date tonight?
I did.
How's it going on your end?
Opening the right atrium.
I can see the bulb
of the tumor.
There we go.
Your turn.
All right.
Tumor is one long stalk now.
I'm gonna tease it out
as we remove the kidney.
Kidney is detached.
And here we go.
All right.
Got it.
One piece? No stragglers?
It's whole.
Impressive.
Bet your mojo's
gonna last all night long.
Lucky girl.
We will conquer
the evil beast
that live inside,
and I shout them
out, out, out, out.
And the winds blow by, and
carry my breath into the sky.
God's shouting down
and carries my clothes
into your head.
And I will conquer
the evil beast
that live inside...
Thanks, Trudy.
Dr. Reese?
I just got off the phone
with PD.
A woman named Melissa Withers
filed a missing persons report
about her sister, Jamie.
Description matches
your Jane Doe.
Out, out, out,
out, out, out, I pray.
And to follow the pages
as they turn,
thumbing through.
Do you got a phone number
for Melissa?
For Melissa.
Deja vu.
Oh, I had pneumonia,
right after college.
Spent two weeks
in the hospital,
Waukesha, Wisconsin.
Let me guess.
Same vending machines?
It's amazing.
Cafeteria makes
a great smoothie.
No, I want to stay close
to Tommy.
I'll find something.
Hey, so, the clindamycin
is not gonna work.
Bacteria pulled
from his ankle,
gram-positive cocci.
A staph infection.
Yeah.
So, let's switch
to IV Vancomycin.
Staph can be a sticky bug.
We need to be more aggressive.
Okay.
Thank you.
So we clear to try
another feeding tube?
Um, no.
We are not.
Apparently,
Allison was prepared
for this moment.
She's already had
papers drawn up
to prevent forcible feeding.
Hospital lawyers
don't want to fight it.
That's insane.
They'll just let her die?
Well, legally,
they don't have a move.
Precedent's already been set
in the courts.
In each case, the patient's
wishes were upheld.
So we go to the parents.
Don't they have a say?
Allison's an adult, Ethan.
I mean, ultimately,
she decides her own fate.
So, there's nothing
we can do?
Look, after seven years,
anorexia is considered
severe and enduring.
This poor lady
has been struggling
for more than 15.
Her entire being is fixated
on gaining control,
and holding onto it.
Even if it kills her.
So regardless
of the injunction,
or her parents love...
The odds of her
recovery are...
Hey, there.
How you feeling?
All things considered,
fantastic.
I mean...
I'm down a kidney,
but at least it didn't cost me
an arm and a leg.
See, you got your
sense of humor back.
Kind of.
Yeah, that was
pretty awful, huh?
Look, jokes aside, thank you.
Sure.
So, I'm gonna be back
to check on you
in a couple of hours,
but before
we head out,
any questions?
Just one.
My right leg is achy.
Around the shin.
Never felt it before.
Maybe a side effect
from the anesthesia?
Could be.
Let me speak
with the anesthesiologist
and see what he thinks.
Right now,
you just get some rest.
Leg pain? That's not
from the anesthesia.
No, but let's not say it
out loud without an X-ray.
I'll get it going.
Hannah.
Hannah?
Oh, my God. Tommy?
Help. Help!
What's happening?
Temp's up to 104.
He's tachy.
BP's 94 over 62.
Septic shock.
First dose of Vanc
didn't work.
Bolus a liter
of normal saline,
and push IV Tylenol.
Tommy, can you open
your mouth for me?
What are you looking for?
Abscesses that
weren't there earlier.
Nothing dental or oral.
Help me search his skin.
Nothing on this side.
Here either.
Get a cooling blanket.
He should be getting better,
but he's only getting worse.
It's gonna be okay.
It's okay.
Hey.
Hi.
Tommy's latest labs.
He doesn't have
a staph infection.
Vancomycin-Resistant
Enterococcus.
The super bug?
Yeah.
And one that is
not easy to get.
VRE's a nosocomial infection.
It lives in hospitals.
I don't think
I've ever seen it
contracted anywhere else.
Hannah.
She had pneumonia
a decade ago.
Was hospitalized
for two weeks.
Could've picked it up then,
had it ever since.
Asymptomatic carrier.
Intimate relationship,
lots of ways she could've
passed it on.
Okay, let's start Tommy
on IV Linezolid,
swab Hannah's nose
and throat for the bacteria,
confirm she's the source.
Got it.
Thank you.
Oh, Dr. Charles,
our Jane Doe
is Jamie Walker,
an aspiring chef
in culinary school.
Huh.
A month ago, she started
staying up all night,
reading the Bible,
and writing a manifesto.
Last week,
she dropped out of school
and hasn't been seen home
in four days.
Now, my original findings,
combined with her
sudden onset drop,
lack in functioning,
her decreased need
for sleep,
her grandiose thinking
combined with
hyper-religiosity,
it is what I thought,
bipolar mania.
So, exams, lab results
didn't poke any holes?
No, I never got to them.
I filled in the blanks
with the added history.
Wait, so, you got all that,
a detailed,
chronological history,
from a patient
in a manic state?
Uh, well, no,
it came from collateral.
I found and spoke
with her sister, Melissa.
Dr. Reese, I thought
that we were checking
all the boxes.
You know, doing it
by the book?
I... I confirmed my diagnosis.
Does it matter
how I got there?
Yes, when you're
on probation, it does.
It does matter
how you got there.
Um, you're... You're right.
Okay.
So, um...
So what's the next move,
for your patient?
I want to admit her
to the psych ward.
She hasn't responded
to any of her meds.
And what meds would those be?
I doubled the Risperdal
and added Depakote.
Also without filling you in.
Okay.
Well, um, you know,
with bipolar,
all those meds,
should've made
some kind of dent,
so I'd like to take a look.
The cancer metastasized
to her tibia.
Likely months ago.
No discomfort
upon admission?
It was drowned out by
the back pain from her kidney.
Once that was alleviated...
Her body registered
the new problem.
So, did we catch it in time?
Let's start Asterid
on a high dose bolus
of Interleukin-2,
see if she responds.
If she doesn't,
she may be a candidate
for our phase three trial
of Pazopanib,
a chemotherapy agent.
I'm gonna pull Ortho in,
as well.
Excuse me,
Dr. Rhodes, Halstead,
may I speak with you?
I'm canceling
Asterid's move to Oncology.
What?
Instead,
I'm going to find a bed
for her
in a safety net hospital.
Med is a premiere
cancer center.
You're gonna transfer her?
I don't have a choice.
She doesn't have insurance,
and I know the hospital
won't cover the bill
her treatments
are going to generate.
She has emergency coverage
from Medicaid.
Right, but that only
pays for procedures
related to removal
of the tumor.
The bone cancer is new,
and not immediately
life-threatening.
We can't throw Asterid out.
A free clinic misdiagnosed
her renal cell carcinoma
as a back sprain.
If we put her
in the system,
she might fall
through the cracks again.
You have pulled
strings before,
you made the numbers work,
just do it again.
Do you know
what kind of numbers
we're talking about here?
$100,000?
$200,000?
What kind of dream world
are you living in?
Do you want me
to inform the patient?
No, we'll do it.
Sitting in pews...
Hi, I'm Dr. Charles.
Four days ago, we could have
somewhat of a conversation,
and now, I don't know
if she's eaten.
Between her work and school,
I thought Jamie
was just stressed.
I didn't realize she was
having a breakdown.
None of this is on you.
Um, Jamie?
I'd like to examine you now.
Would that be all right?
Free, free, free.
Locked up inside.
Wanted everything for it,
everything.
Everything. So much my arms
can't even hold them all...
Clear,
prominent disinhibition.
Hasn't let up since
my first exam.
Consistent with bipolar mania.
Let me go.
You see this?
In her eyes?
What?
Yellowish-brown circles
around her irises.
I think they're
Kayser-Fleischer rings.
And weeks,
days and weeks
flipping in the calendar,
the bright light
burns the trees,
leaves, falling,
stop falling, too many...
Too many people crowding.
Too many people.
Bright light burns the trees.
Leaves falling.
Too many people.
Um... Your sister
is in culinary school.
Has she ever said anything
to you about... About copper,
using copper pots?
Uh, yeah, I think so.
Something about them being
the best heat conductors.
I don't know anything
about cooking.
Does that mean something
to you?
Dr. Reese?
Wilson's disease.
What's that?
It's a genetic disorder,
um, where com...
Copper accumulates
in the body.
Jamie's use of copper cookware
could've accelerated
the buildup
that led to this
manic episode.
If this is Wilson's disease,
is there a cure?
Um, no, but there is
treatment to manage it,
and she...
She would get better.
Oh, thank God.
Dr. Reese, could I just have
a word outside? Thank you.
And twitching.
Wiggle, wriggle, wiggle...
So, you couldn't even get
close enough to your patient
to examine her eyes?
She was so agitated...
Dr. Reese.
Help!
No pulse. V-fib.
Charge 200.
Charged.
Clear.
Oh, my poor baby.
One milligram epi.
Charge 200 again.
Epi's in. Charged.
Clear.
Asystole.
We can't shock her anymore.
Oh, my God.
What's he doing?
Come on, come on.
She's suffered enough.
Please, stop.
Time of death 18:21.
We're looking
for Dr. Halstead.
Here to transfer
an Asterid Morgan to County.
Right, one sec.
Will?
Yeah?
They're here.
Hey, guys.
Come with me.
I got this from Hannah?
How? I don't have
a sore throat.
No fever, aches, pains,
I'm not sick.
You don't have
an active infection,
but since your pneumonia,
you've been contagious.
For 10 years?
I work in an office,
cross paths with dozens
of people every day,
not to mention
boyfriends before Tommy.
No one else has
ever gotten sick.
We're gonna run some tests
and find out
exactly what it is.
Honey, I am so sorry.
It's not your fault.
You had no idea.
Besides, I'm feeling better.
It means
that these antibiotics
are working, right?
Yes.
Put Hannah on them.
Yeah.
Kill whatever bug
she's been dragging around
for the last 10 years.
I'm afraid
it's not that simple.
You see, as a carrier,
you're colonized
with the bacteria.
Which means
it lives in too many places
in your body
for the antibiotic
to be effective.
You mean,
I've got this forever?
I'm afraid so.
Then I could give it
to Tommy again.
With precautions, the risk
of reinfection can be reduced.
This can't be...
This can't be happening.
We can deal with it.
Yeah.
We'll figure it out.
This sucks.
We do everything right
and still come up short.
All right, let's go.
Screw this.
Stop, she's not
going anywhere.
Sorry, we have
transfer orders.
And I am overriding them.
Dr. Rhodes, what's going on?
It's okay, Asterid.
It's just a miscommunication.
I'm gonna take care of it.
Go ahead and put her back.
Whatever you say.
Sign here, so this doesn't
come down on us.
Connor, what are you doing?
I got this.
Don't worry.
I did my two-week suspension.
I am in therapy.
I am not supposed
to be afraid anymore.
I am a psychiatrist.
Rule number one is to connect
with your patients,
and I could not even
look her in the eye.
Look, the good news is
that you recognize
the problem.
Right?
Sarah, nobody learns
how to master their fears
in two weeks, trust me.
It just doesn't happen.
Not even somebody
as determined as you are.
Okay.
You know what?
Um, when Allison died today,
I saw myself,
because she could not change.
But I have to. I have to.
I just don't know how.
You have to help me,
Dr. Charles.
Of course.
Of course I will.
Okay.
Hey, how's it going?
They haven't taken
their eyes off each other.
Hey, Hannah,
here are some pamphlets
on universal precautions.
I thought they might
be helpful
for you and Tommy.
Yeah, uh, I don't need them.
You don't?
There's only one thing to do.
Will you give this
to Tommy tomorrow?
I couldn't tell him myself.
Hannah...
I love him.
I can't put him at risk.
Dealing with TB,
Tate and I,
the pressure it put
on our relationship...
I get it.
Uh-huh. Same here.
Where are you
gonna put it?
Right there.
Right there?
Oh, that's gonna
be beautiful.
You like it
standing up like that?
Oh, I'll take that as a no.
Oh.
Special delivery.
What did you do?
Hey, little man.
Look what I have for ya.
A car.
A truck!
It is!
Is this because of that?
I'm reading up
on child development.
Emotional modeling,
active engagement.
I thought maybe the best way
to bond might just be a bribe.
Owen, do you like the car?
Yeah.
Yeah?
Want to get in,
try it out?
Take it for a spin?
Oh!
Ah!
I'm so sorry.
Are you okay?
Does he hate me?
What?
No.
Of course not.
Hey, how could he hate you?
I don't know.
Look, you and I are lucky.
A pair of black eyes,
it's nothing.
Let's go get you some ice.
Come on.
Dr. Rhodes.
Excuse me.
A moment.
Asterid's transfer
to County...
I'm sure you can
imagine my surprise
when I learned it was
suddenly unnecessary.
Yeah, it, uh...
It turns out that
the hospital's charitable fund
has enough money
to cover her costs.
It does now.
It seems a six-figure donation
was made a few hours ago
anonymously.
That's good timing, I guess.
Mmm.
Good night.
Dr. Rhodes,
Be careful.
Patients are going
to keep coming.
And as wealthy
as you may be,
your checkbook
won't be able to keep up.
But it did today.
Good night, Ms. Goodwin.