- Previously on
"New Amsterdam."
This may be one
of the last things I do.
- Max!
I am your doctor, Max.
I'm taking you off the chemo
and radiation.
I'm gonna find you
a different regimen
and I'm gonna save your life.
Could you, um, message this
to Dr. Valentina Castro?
- Max's DNA?
- I was actually here
to talk to Max
about extending my leave.
- For how long?
- Like, forever.
- You know I got you, right?
- The placenta previa
ruptured.
I was about to call 911.
- Max, the baby won't survive
another one.
- So we have to get her out.
- Luna.
Your turn.
- It's always my turn.
- Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Come here.
I know, I know, I know.
Yeah.
Hi.
Good morning, Luna.
How you doing?
How are you feeling?
- Oh, not myself just yet.
- It's okay, 'cause
I'm all over baby duty today.
Oh, she wants her mama.
- Hi.
Hi, Luna.
♪ Baby, baby sweet baby
♪ There's something that
I just got to say ♪
- ♪ Baby, baby sweet baby
♪ I didn't mean
to run you away ♪
- Okay, Luna.
Hit it.
- ♪ Baby, baby sweet baby
- Hey, Max.
- How can we help?
- What's the key factor
in how much pain meds
we prescribe to patients?
- How much pain they're in.
Is this a trick question?
- Yes.
- I thought it seemed too easy.
- Well, the key factor
isn't pain.
It's race.
- Ah.
- When white
and black patients present
with identical levels of pain,
doctors tend to prescribe
the white patients
high grade opioids.
- And what do
the black patients get?
- A lecture on how
to tough it out
and a handful of Tylenol.
Wow, so everybody loses.
- Exactly.
That's why I want
New Amsterdam's
patient bill of rights
to guarantee
that each patient's pain
is treated equitably
and responsibly.
- Luna, if you think that's
a good idea,
go ahead and be super cute.
You're good.
- Who's that little Muppet?
Look at me!
Oh, let's see if I can touch
your nose with my nose!
Oh!
- Yeah.
Uh, how--how can I help?
Can you repeat it?
- Yes.
Sorry, Capitan.
Here's the sitch.
All right, come with me.
So, I'll give you one guess
what all those kids
in there have in common.
- They all just heard you do
15 verses of "Baby Shark"?
- Walked right into that one.
- Yeah.
- No, they are all transgender
and they have all been
denied medical care
thanks to these so-called
"conscience laws"
allowing hospitals
to just freely discriminate.
- Hospitals are denying them
transition care?
- No, hospitals are denying
them any care whatsoever.
So I'm proposing that
New Amsterdam starts a fund
to help shoulder the cost.
- A lot of art on these walls.
- Yes, Max, art therapy is
a big part of what we do here,
but I'm gonna need you
to focus up, okay?
- What if we create
an art show annually,
auction your patients' work,
and use that money to,
you know,
build the fund
you're talking about?
- Who's the best
medical director ever?
Who's the best medical
director ever?
Your daddy!
- 30% of doctors are over 63.
- Yeah, just one second.
Marsha, we had a bit
of grunting
after a morning diaper
and there is an extra bottle
in there in case she has
a sudden growth spurt.
Okay, I love you, baby.
You have a good day.
- See you in five minutes.
- Probably.
Uh, so doctors that are old.
What's the, uh, problem?
- Uh, we will soon face
an epidemic when they retire.
- Vijay, you're not trying
to tell me something, are you?
Are you hanging up your spurs?
- Certainly not.
It's not about me.
- Oh, well, then--
But you are over 60, right?
- Legally, I don't have
to answer that.
- Vijay, you look great.
I'm just saying
that if doctors
retire later
than most Americans,
then the problem is not
that they're leaving.
It's that they're sticking
around past their prime.
- What?
No, no.
You're twisting my words.
With age comes wisdom.
- Yeah, and declining
mental acuity.
Look, I--what we should do
is create new programs
for senior physicians
like mentorships, you know?
And--and lower patient loads.
In fact,
that's a really good idea.
Would you look into that?
- Senior physicians?
- The result speak
for themselves.
- I'm rarely at
a loss for words,
but, uh, wow.
- "Wow" works.
I want all my patients
to say wow.
Wow is my preferred reaction.
And I think they will.
With precision-targeted
therapy--
I mean,
you are the proof.
- Thank you, Dr. Castro,
for, um,
saving my life.
Thanks isn't really enough,
is it?
- It is for me.
Look at this.
By targeting your
defective DNA
and not carpet bombing
your entire body with chemo,
your tumor
is finally shrinking.
All three of your blood lines
are in their normal range.
- And I actually gained
a pound or five
but who's counting?
- I mean,
six more months like this
and you'll be cured.
Sorry.
Cured?
- Max, I know you've missed
Dr. Sharpe.
If she were here,
she would say the same thing.
You beat the odds.
You won the cancer lottery.
- Sorry, I gotta--I gotta run.
But, um, thank you,
Dr. Castro.
Thank you.
- Max.
Max.
- Where--where--
where's Georgia?
- Fractured left femur
and possible concussion.
- Give me Bloom's vitals.
- Alright, 110,
BP 150 over 95.
O2 stats at 100%.
- Georgia?
- Max.
- Huh?
Hey, Max.
- What?
- You need to give me Luna.
- No.
- Yes.
She needs to be examined.
- No.
- Yes.
- No, no, no.
No, no, no.
- It's okay, it's okay.
- Why? Why?
- Just give me her.
It's okay.
I'll take her.
She'll be fine,
I promise you.
It's okay.
- Luna?
- It's okay.
It's okay.
Max.
- Are you okay?
- Oh, God.
Thank God.
It's not fair.
Where's Luna?
- She's fine.
- They're examining her.
They'll bring her back
in just a few.
- Max, your head.
- I'm good.
- I want a CT on both of them.
- Is everybody else okay?
- No, where's Sharpe?
Where's Sharpe?
- Max, take a look at this.
- Another case came in.
Alma Pearson.
She's a type 1 diabetic.
This morning she suffered
full-blown ketoacidosis.
It's her third one this year.
- Hey, Alma.
I'm Dr. Goodwin.
You wanna tell me
what happened?
- She's been rationing
her insulin again.
This time she could have died.
- Alma, I'm gonna help you,
but you have to talk to me.
- What's there to say?
When I was first diagnosed,
insulin cost $21 a vial.
Now it's $250.
I'm a substitute teacher
and I can't afford it.
I can't afford to live.
How can you help with that?
- Alma's the eighth diabetic
to come in this week.
One guy was trying
to make insulin on his own
in his garage.
- Hmm.
Who supplies our insulin?
- Uh, Pacentia.
- Pacentia.
Yeah, okay, Alma,
we're--we're on this.
Um, Kenmari,
I'm gonna go ahead
and green light your plan.
- Uh, what's my plan?
- Your plan to terminate
our contract
with Pacentia Pharmaceuticals.
- That's not my plan.
- No?
Maybe it was mine.
- Okay, Max,
how are we gonna buy insulin?
- We're not gonna
buy insulin anymore.
We're gonna make our own.
- Hey, baby.
- Good morning,
beautiful black woman.
- Oh, yeah,
6:00 a.m. with pillow creases
on my face?
- Especially with
pillow creases.
- Oy, keep talking like that,
I might just have
to marry you.
- Oh, that's gonna happen.
But right now I just need you
back from San Francisco.
I can't take it anymore.
- I know.
I know.
Two more weeks and counting.
- Mm-hmm.
- How much time do you have?
- Three minutes.
- You better make
the most of it.
- Mm-hmm.
Yes, please.
Thank you.
- Dr. Reynolds, we could use
your help in the ED.
- I'll be right there.
- Are you sure that
you have some time?
- I'm--I'm positive, all right?
We got 2 1/2 minutes.
- Dr. Reynolds?
- What, Nottingham?
- One of the interns
on our rotation
is always showing up late.
And when he is here,
I can't find him.
- Cut him.
- Seriously?
- Yeah, I don't got time
for dead weight
or interruptions.
- Okay, great.
Oh, hi, Evie.
What are you guys--
- Hey, love.
Just calling to check
on Raffi and Saleem.
Are they, uh--are they
at least trading off
with the barfing now?
- No, they're still
in perfect sync,
like two violently ill
figure skaters.
Now Sameera says she's sick.
- No, no, no, no.
She's faking to stay home
with the boys.
Don't believe that hype.
- Uh, I told her
to get ready for school
but the big headline
is head lice on Harper.
- Again?
Are you kidding me?
That kid's head is like
a cot at Rikers.
I was having trouble
finding someone
to take care of the boys.
Now with Harper,
I'm gonna have
to cancel my patients.
- Ah, I'm so sorry, Martin.
I-I wish I could be there.
- Yeah, just promise
you'll be home by 7:00
to put everyone to bed
so I can start drinking.
Daddy?
- Sameera is not faking.
I-I gotta go.
Oh.
- Hey.
- Interesting.
Tweety Bird?
I always thought of you
as a Yosemite Sam kind of guy.
- Well, that's probably because
of my outlaw vibe.
And I am not seeing
any bathroom breaks on here.
- The residents are all taking
their board exam today
so we're severely understaffed.
I have everyone covering
three different wards.
It's an impossible day.
- No, no, no.
Nothing is impossible, Gladys,
as long as you get me out
of here by 6:00 p.m.
Oh, also can you, um--
can you find me some shoes?
- Shoes, yep.
Got it.
- I see the Mandarin lessons
are paying off.
- They started us with swear
words to get us engaged.
- Typical case?
- Impossible.
I've been working with
this woman for two years.
The worst rheumatoid arthritis
I have ever seen.
No--
- I can take a look.
- Uh, no offense,
Dr. Kapoor,
but she needs
something innovative.
Something I'm not seeing.
- You think as
a senior physician
I can't be innovative?
Hello.
- Ah, the hand off.
I was wondering when
you'd give up on me.
- Ms. Klestadt, it's not--
- It's okay.
I'm used to it.
So, what brilliant cure
do you have?
- I don't.
But I will.
By the end of the day.
- Dr. Kapoor, I've been working
with Ms. Klestadt for two years
and this is my specialty.
- I will help your
rheumatoid arthritis today
or I will retire.
- Uh, yeah,
all this stuff can come out.
Gotta make way for the new lab.
Chairwoman Brantley,
were you riding in the freezer?
- Asphyxiation
in a sub-zero box
would be preferable
to the earful I just received
from the CEO of
Pacentia Pharmaceuticals.
You terminated
our insulin contract?
- I did.
It's this funny thing
where I prefer not to buy
medication from extortionists.
- I and the rest of the country
share your indignation
but you can't just make
homebrew insulin.
It's not kombucha.
- This lab used to grow
thousands of cultures,
process hundreds
of specimens a day.
It's all perfectly safe.
- And that's for--
- Millions of E. coli cultures,
which is way less scary
than it sounds.
- What scares me are lawyers.
Insulin is patented.
- And yet my body is
making it right now for free.
The patent is on
how you make it,
so big pharma keeps changing
how they make it
every couple years
so they can file more patents,
thus keeping competition down
and prices up.
- We both know you can't make
enough insulin
for all of New York,
so cut the kabuki and tell me
what you really want.
- A seat at the table.
A sit-down with the CEO
of Pacentia
to negotiate prices down.
- A stunt like this doesn't
justify dragging New Amsterdam
into a billion dollar lawsuit
with big pharma,
the FDA,
and Department of Justice.
Now tell these people
to stop what they're doing
or so help me,
I will fire them all.
- You're bluffing.
- Try me.
- Okay, sorry, guys.
Change of plans.
Just set that down.
But you know what?
This isn't over.
- Sure it is.
- Kapoor, have you seen Sharpe?
- No, maybe she's here.
- She's not in the ED.
- Then where is she?
- I'll help find her.
- Call the morgue, have them
come collect the body.
- It's one of ours.
Died on impact.
- Sorry.
- I like your necklace.
I like your necklace.
- It belonged to a friend.
- Sorry if I intrude--
- No, it's--it's okay.
It was an accident.
We lost two of our own.
- Three, two, one.
Whoo!
Take a breath.
We did it.
We're done!
I know the dark
is scary, right?
I know,
but guess what?
Fear is a totally healthy
emotion that everyone feels.
- Even you?
- Even me.
Oh, yeah.
Especially me.
I'm scared of so many things.
I got a laundry list
of things I'm afraid of.
I got--I got sharks,
jellyfish, clowns.
In fact, whenever
I'm afraid of anything,
I have a little trick
that I use
to help me get past it.
You guys wanna know what it is?
Okay, visual aid.
Here we go.
Bridge Ignatius
in full effect.
Okay, cool.
Now, what I want you to do
is I want you to imagine
all of your fears floating
beneath me
right under
Bridge Ignatius here,
and then I want you
to imagine climbing over them.
Do you understand?
Can you see that?
Oh, okay.
Uh, yeah.
I said--okay,
I said "imagine," guys.
Imagine, but all right.
This might be a toll bridge.
I may have to charge you, guys.
All right, if this
is working for everybody,
I guess that's cool.
- No time for personal calls.
- No, no, no, just calling
Martin and the kids.
Gotta check in.
- You're already four minutes
late to group therapy.
- I used to go bike riding
with my girls.
I taught them,
running next to them
as they wobbled,
catching them before they fell.
- After the blood tests,
you will be bike riding
in no time.
- Well, the girls
are into rock climbing now.
But still.
- I'd love to be that kind
of mom again
before they don't
need me anymore.
You will.
- Nope.
- What?
That's not possible.
Check it again.
- It's a computer,
not an oven.
- But all of
Ms. Klestadt's symptoms
could be celiac disease
and not rheumatoid arthritis
at all.
- Well, her blood
and my computer disagree.
- Still wanna gamble your
whole medical career on me?
- With my experience,
it's not a gamble.
- Got a five O prolene stitch?
Can you get that for me?
- It's Evie.
- Is there a loving way
to ignore a call?
No?
- Excuse me,
Dr. Reynolds?
- Who is that?
Who are you?
- Michael Duke.
I'm an intern.
- What are you doing here,
Michael Duke?
- Dr. Nottingham dropped me
from the cardiac rotation and--
- Oh, yeah, yeah.
Dr. Nottingham dropped you
at my suggestion.
- Then I'm talking
to the right man,
'cause you made a mistake,
Dr. Reynolds.
- Practicing medicine
is a privilege, Michael Duke.
It's not something you show up
for when you feel like it
or have people come
to find you
while your head's
in the clouds.
- Well, you don't
know me like that.
I mean, you--
you don't know me at all.
'Cause if you did,
you'd know that I consistently
score in the top five
of my class.
That every professor
acknowledges
I've got the hands
for surgery.
And when Nottingham has
to find me,
every time it's with
a book in my hand
because it's easier
to study in quiet here
than in my own neighborhood.
And I'm not--I'm not telling
you all this as an excuse.
I'm just giving you facts.
Like the fact I'm
the best intern up in here.
So good these hands will be
coming for your job one day.
- Clamp.
- These are some of the
hundreds of prescriptions
that New Amsterdam has written
for insulin just this week.
If these same patients
were in Canada,
these same meds would cost
about a fifth as much.
Sadly, hospitals are barred
from importing drugs
from Canada,
but individuals are not.
So, despite all appearances,
New Amsterdam is not going
to Canada
to buy enormous loads
of insulin for the hospital.
We are, however,
going to Canada
to buy enormous loads
of insulin
for thousands of individuals,
and we're gonna keep going
back and forth
until Pacentia understands
that increasing
their profit margin is not
worth the 30 million lives
they are putting at risk,
one of whom is my patient,
Alma Pearson.
Thank you.
Thanks.
- They're going to arrest you.
- Probably, but they say
there's no bad publicity,
right?
- And they would be wrong.
- Would they?
- Thanks, Dr. Goodwin.
- The second those truck
reach the border,
you're gonna have
an international incident
on your hand
and a slate of pharma companies
ready to riot.
- Maybe then they'll give me
a seat at the table.
- That takes favors
and finesse and time,
but you keep throwing tantrums
like a kid with a sugar high.
- That's because my patient,
Alma Pearson,
doesn't have time.
I want a seat at the table
or I'm gonna throw
another tantrum tomorrow.
- Give me a week!
- You got ten hours till
that truck reaches Toronto.
God.
- Wheelchair to Admitting.
Wheelchair to Admitting.
- I just came from the airport.
Sorry it's been so long.
Everyone's just so interested
in your treatment.
That's the great news.
How are you?
- I'm sure Dr. Castro's been
keeping you in the loop.
- She has.
I'm thrilled.
Though I'm surprised
to learn that we're suddenly
in the insulin business.
- I don't know if
we can call it a business.
We're giving it away
for free.
- Max.
How are things at home?
- Good, yeah.
Luna's amazing.
She's, uh, sleeping through
the night now.
Twelve weeks,
so it's great.
- If you ever need to talk,
I'm here.
- Welcome back.
- Do you know your name?
- They've already done
all the questions, Vijay!
Just pop the damn thing
back in, please!
Do it!
Ah, better.
- Hey, where have you been?
We didn't know where you were.
- I was thrown.
There was--
- Page the code team.
We're losing her.
- Who?
- It's Bloom.
- No, no, no, Mark.
This is everyone's win.
Without your research, I--
Thank you.
- Charge nurse to Admitting.
- I appreciate that.
- Okay, talk soon.
So many wins today.
But I bet you get
those days a lot.
- Few and far between,
to be honest.
- Oh, and, uh, a wheel
was broken on your chair.
I had that fixed.
Hope you don't mind.
- Not at all.
I, um--I saw Max.
What you've done
for him is extraordinary.
- Isn't it?
One look at him
and you can't deny
this is the future of oncology.
- That's why I've been
out raising money
using your research.
- Oh.
So maybe you shouldn't
have fired me.
Pot shot, sorry.
Couldn't resist.
- I made a mistake, Valentina.
But now I'd like you
to come back.
- Back?
- To New Amsterdam full-time.
- You damaged my career
when you let me go.
No, I don't need an apology.
It's just that's why
I can't work for you again.
- Okay.
- But maybe we could find
a different arrangement.
- Such as?
- You could make me co-chair
of your department.
Valentina, even with
your success rate,
the financial risk would--
- Half your department.
Or you can find someone else
to administer precision
target therapy.
Max's precision target therapy.
- You're using Max
as a bargaining chip?
- I don't want
to derail Max's progress.
I just can't make my work
vulnerable to you again.
- Done.
- Empty out the contents
of your purse.
- Excuse me?
- Right here.
- Neurologists
are like detectives.
They just need
to know where to look.
- A lot of stuff.
- Here you are.
Here.
What is this?
- Lavender oil.
- Mm-hmm.
For?
- Stress relief.
- Does it work?
- Do I look relieved of stress?
- Okay.
And, uh--hmm.
And what is this?
- Uh, for joint pain.
One of those alternative
medicine things.
- This is why none of
your medications are working.
Come with me.
I love alternative medicine.
Believe me.
But a lot of
these alternative remedies,
especially the ones from China,
they contain heavy metals.
And when heavy metals get
absorbed in your blood stream,
they can block the effect
of your medication.
- Nope, no heavy metals.
- What?
- Okay, it's called
psychotherapeutic reparenting.
- Ricky, since you rolled
your eyes with such finesse,
I'm assuming you'd like
to go first.
Come on, it'll be good.
It'll--it'll give you
a chance to, uh,
you know, feel free
to express your feelings
towards your mother
without fear of abandonment.
Ricky.
Ricky, do you have something
you want to say to me?
Yeah, you look like a dude.
- Okay.
Okay.
Ignore them.
Just say something
honest to me.
Open up.
That's what this is for.
- Okay, "Mama."
When I was a kid,
I wish you looked at me,
seen how messed up I was.
- Why?
- 'Cause all
the bad stuff I did,
I was just trying
to get you to notice me.
To see me,
the real me.
I kept thinking,
"Why didn't you?"
Why couldn't you see me?
Now I think you did see me.
You just didn't care.
So I stopped seeing myself.
You turned me into a ghost,
Mama.
Crap, Dr. Frome,
I didn't mean
to get weird, man.
- No, you did not get weird.
You did not--
you didn't get weird.
I got weird.
You got open and honest
and awesome.
That was the point of all this,
and the only reason I'm crying
is because I'm proud of you.
- Um, should I keep going?
'Cause you look
pretty messed up.
- No, no, no.
Keep going, Ricky.
You're doing great.
- I'm sorry; I know
I shouldn't have hijacked
your surgery like that.
- No, you shouldn't have.
- I've been busting my ass
for five years.
- Just stop.
When I was an intern
on my cardiac rotation,
my attending never bothered
to learn my name.
But if I messed up in rounds
or I was late once,
I would have been dropped,
no questions asked.
All right,
nobody helped me.
No one cared that I
sometimes had to choose
between books and heat.
I had to just figure it out.
I had to figure out how
to be great on my own.
And you know what?
I almost left medicine
because of it.
So...I'm gonna keep
my eye on you.
- Wait, I'm back in?
- No, no, no.
Don't think that I'm gonna be
easy on you, either.
It's gonna be quite
the opposite, all right?
I'm gonna push you
and challenge you
and expect nothing less
than greatness.
And if you rise
to the challenge, maybe,
just maybe you'll be good
enough to come for me.
- Yes, sir.
And thank you, sir.
- You get your seat
at the table?
- No.
Placentia wouldn't budge.
- And the drugs from Canada?
- Customs wouldn't let
medication loads that size
past the border.
- Guess I was crazy to think
we could beat them.
- Yeah.
It was crazy.
But, while we didn't win,
we didn't lose either.
Placentia wasn't so thrilled
about the negative PR,
so, if I stop
embarrassing them,
they've agreed to offer you
some insulin.
- How much?
- Six vials a month.
- But that's--
- A lifetime supply.
- Oh, my God.
Oh, my...
What about everyone else?
Everyone else
who can't afford it...
- Only you're my patient.
And doctors fight
for their patients,
so today I fought for you.
Tomorrow...
It's another story.
- Max...
Max.
One day you're gonna have to
start talking to me again.
- Yeah, not today.
- Sinus rhythm.
- Still no pulse.
- Her heart's
not pumping any blood.
Her neck veins are distended.
- Cardiac tamponade?
- 18 gauge cardiac needle.
20cc syringe, now.
- Told you I got you.
Thank you.
- The ED is all yours now,
doctor.
- Ah, welcome back.
- Come on, everyone wants some.
Get in here, get in there.
- Got a weak and dizzy in 2,
an ortho consult in 11,
and then there's--
- What happened to my posters?
- Oh, yeah, Candelario didn't
think they were professional.
- I like my posters.
- We missed you.
- You still hurting?
- Don't ask stupid questions.
- You taking anything?
- No, I am not taking anything.
- Not even aspirin?
- As long as I keep moving
and stay busy,
it'll keep my mind
off the pain.
Put 'em back up.
- Could be lupus.
Or perhaps
you're a fast metabolizer.
- Dr. Kapoor, maybe it's time
for me to go home.
No, no.
Usually I take more time
with my patients.
Maybe that's
why I'm off my game.
- I didn't really expect you
to help me in one day.
- But I didn't help you at all.
- You came up with
three possible diagnoses
in less than eight hours.
- Were any of them correct?
Lately I've been missing India
quite a lot.
Strangers smiling at you
for no reasons,
the festivals, the fragrances,
all the colors.
If I did retire,
I could go home.
- Here.
- Ugh, I hate flossing.
- Flossing is essential
for healthy teeth and gums.
- You sound
just like my dentist.
I stopped seeing her
because she wouldn't stop with
the lectures.
- What?
What?
- Oh, yeah.
Yeah, that is definitely
an abscessed molar.
- Hmm.
- Why is that good news?
- Because this is the reason
none of your medications
are working.
The abscess in the tooth
created bacteria.
- The bacteria
entered your bloodstream,
which caused your RA symptoms
to escalate.
- And all those medications
you took
went to fight
the bacteria infection,
not rheumatoid arthritis.
- Wait, wait.
All these years,
all the doctors...
All the medicine?
- It was a tooth.
Remove it,
you will feel better.
- Better?
- Yes.
And you may even be able to go
do rock climbing
with your daughters.
- If you retire,
I'll drag you back
from India myself.
- Okay, who'd I miss?
- Uh...
No one.
Covered everybody in here.
Twice.
And you played dentist.
- Guess I'll go get a coffee.
- That's a good idea.
Oh, and, uh, when you get back?
I'ma hit you with
some dance therapy.
I know you can do it!
♪ Doctor Bloom back
in the house, hey ♪
in the house, oh ♪
- Ah, ah, ah.
- Huh?
Oh, yes, thank you.
Thank you very much.
- I don't know how you did it,
but it is 6:00 on the dot.
- Probably has something
to do with
these amazing slippers
you got me here.
I owe you my marriage, Gladys.
And Dr. Frome is
officially off the clock!
- ♪ As it is
- ♪ I wonder how so many
could be in so much pain ♪
- Do you need to talk about it?
- ♪ Feel a thing
♪ I don't feel comfortable
♪ With the way
that my clothes fit ♪
- ♪ I can't get used to
my body's limits ♪
♪ I've got some fancy shoes
♪ To try and kick away
these blues ♪
- ♪ They cost a lot of money
♪ But they aren't
worth a thing ♪
- ♪ I want to free my feet
♪ From the broken glass
and concrete ♪
- I'm here, okay?
- ♪ I need to get
out of this city ♪
- ♪ Lay upon the ground
♪ Stare a hole in the sky
♪ Wondering where I go
when I die ♪
- Hi, hi, I'm here!
Sorry I'm five minutes late!
I just, uh...
No excuses.
Please do not divorce me.
I'll never love again.
Where is everybody?
I'm ready
to shut this place down.
- There is no need.
Hey.
- Hey.
"No need."
Why, did you give
everybody away?
No judgment, just curious.
- Raffi, Saleem, Samera,
and Harper--
they all took care of
each other, the whole day.
They were so cute
and so exhausted.
They were asleep by 7:00.
I also got to FaceTime
with a patient.
She was really escalating
and...
I was able to talk her down.
- Well, look at you.
Look at us.
We helped
a lot of people today.
- I'll drink to that.
- Just makes me feel like
maybe we could, um...
Be helping even more.
- How?
- I think we should adopt
another child.
- What?
- ♪ I know
- Hey.
- Hey, my beautiful black man.
- Did I catch you sleeping?
- No, um, no, I was just--
- 'cause I can--I can
call back later.
- No! No, no, no, no.
This is, uh...
This is what I've been
waiting for all day.
Seeing that beautiful face.
- Then tell me about your day.
- I'd rather not.
- Hmm, okay.
- I mean, do you really want to
hear me talk about work or...
Do you wanna...
Watch me work?
I miss you.
- I miss you, too, baby.
- Long day?
- They're all long days.
- Your turn.
- It's always my turn.
Hey.
Hey, shh.
Hi.
♪ Didn't mean to
run you away ♪
- ♪ Ba ba cha cha
♪ Baby, baby sweet baby
- Max.
Max!
You need to hurry.
Her CT came back.
There was a brain bleed.
Georgia is in surgery
with Hartman.
- ♪ Speak your name
♪ Ooh yeah
- Georgia...
- I did everything
that I could.
♪ Why'd you do it?
Why'd you have to ♪
♪ Since you've been gone
♪ Why'd you do it?
Why'd you have to ♪
♪ Since you've been gone
- ♪ Why'd you do it?
Why'd you have to ♪
♪ Since you've been gone
♪ Why'd you do it?
Why'd you have to ♪
♪ Since you've been gone
♪ If you walk in the door
♪ I can get up off my knees
♪ 'cause I've just
been so blue ♪
♪ Since you've been gone