Another 3-0 Prolene.
Here.
Homestretch, Peter.
Just finishing up
the aortic connection.
Then we'll start you back up.
Talk to the patient
while they're out,
that's a new one.
It's a nice touch.
Actually, not new.
Just the first time
you've noticed.
Thought I'd made more of
an impression on you.
The way you can turn
a compliment into a dig,
it's quite the skill,
Dr. Bekker.
Don't be so sensitive,
Dr. Rhodes.
Okay, donor heart
is fully attached.
All right.
Let's get the pacer leads on.
100 beats per minute, Marty.
We're set.
Okay then, turn it on.
Excellent contractility in
the left and right ventricles.
No distension.
Healthy color.
Take off bypass?
Looks like this one's
going to take, Peter.
There's no better sight,
is there, Dr. Bekker?
Can't argue with that.
No, no, no!
Losing color. It's cyanotic.
Global contractility's
way down.
Left and right ventricles
severely distended.
Hyperacute rejection.
Donor heart's failing.
We need to get it out now.
Damn it.
Okay, back on bypass.
Okay, Peter obviously goes
back on the transplant list,
but for right now,
I only see two options:
ECMO or an artificial heart.
ECMO's quick and easy.
Peter's on bypass, so the
cannulas are already in place.
Downside, he'd be confined to
the ICU and likely intubated.
I'm leaning artificial.
That is a huge surgery.
Peter's already been on
the table for over four hours.
The risk of complications,
especially stroke?
But if all goes well,
he could get out of bed,
walk around,
maybe even go home.
Peter waited a year
for his first donor heart,
two and a half
for the one that just failed.
There's no telling
how long the next will take.
Then I guess you really
only have one option.
It's Peter's wife, Jane.
Not the post-op conversation
I was planning for.
Dr. Rhodes, Dr. Halstead
called from the E.D.
while you were in surgery,
asked that you find him
the moment you're free.
Thank you.
Mmm.
It's Dan Kennet,
my giant-cell
myocarditis patient.
He's back.
Go. I've got this.
All right.
April, this thing tonight,
how big we talking?
It's my little cousin's
15th birthday, okay?
It's gonna be
some of her friends,
a few family members, low-key.
Yeah, right.
You always say that.
Then I get there
and it's Carnaval.
In Brazilian culture,
fifteen's a huge birthday
for a girl.
Baile de Debutante.
Uh, did you Google that?
Yeah.
Okay, that's really cute.
Oh, are you gonna
bring your sister?
I wasn't planning on it.
Come on, you guys
have been talking.
Things are going well, right?
Yeah, but Emily's always
been kind of a wild card.
I don't wanna spend
the whole night worrying
she'll do something
to offend your family.
Plus, she probably
has a poker game.
Lame.
All right,
I'm not gonna push.
I'd really like
to meet her, though.
You will.
One day.
He fainted?
Yeah, getting out
of the shower.
When I pressed for details,
he confessed to being
light-headed all week.
Labs?
Yeah, troponin's
way too high.
Left ventricular
ejection fraction is 10%.
I've been treating Dan
for six months.
Steroids, calcium
channel blockers,
ace inhibitors, beta blockers,
no matter what I try,
he just keeps getting worse.
Where is he
on the transplant list?
Way too low.
Don't let him give up.
Aww.
Hey, Dan. Hey, Sheila.
Hey. We're back too soon.
Listen, Dan,
your heart is failing,
so I'm going to
adjust the meds
that you're already on
and add IV dobutamine.
IV?
Guess I'm not
going home today, am I?
Yeah, we've gotta
get the inflammation
of your heart muscle
under control.
How long in the ICU?
I'm not sure, I'm sorry.
Hey, little B.
Hi.
The hospital has
a daycare center.
I can, uh, call...
No, no.
Having them close keeps me...
Keeps my spirits up.
Good. That's what we want.
I'll see you guys soon,
all right?
All right.
Hey, take it from
the old guy,
ease up or you get
a bunch of these.
What are you grinding on?
My dad asked me
to cosign on a loan.
Huh.
Northwestern offered him
a tenure-track position.
He's gonna buy
a place in Chicago.
Isn't that great news?
Yeah.
I can get through the most
arcane medical jargon,
but legalese? Impossible.
I just wanna know
what I'm signing.
Is that too much to ask?
Not at all.
Cosigning a loan
is a big deal.
Mmm.
If the borrower defaults,
you're on the hook
for the money, right?
Mmm-hmm.
Another little piece of
advice from the old guy.
Finances and family,
they don't always mix.
Oh, no, Dr. Charles,
my dad is good for the money.
He just needs me to cosign
because identity theft messed
up his credit a few years ago.
Huh.
So when did your back
start bothering you?
Oh, it's been killing me
since last night.
Listen, I probably overdid it
in my spin class.
I've been working
on my stamina.
We're off to Italy tonight,
bike trip through Tuscany.
Oh, yeah?
Our 30th anniversary.
Congratulations.
Thanks.
All right, so let me know
if you feel anything tender.
Okay.
Okay?
The spinning, is that a new
activity to prep for the trip?
Um, yeah. And also,
I've been trying to lose
the twenty-ish pounds
I gained over the winter.
Obviously, it's not working.
But muscle weighs more
than fat, isn't that right?
Don't answer that.
Are you on any medications,
Mrs. Davis?
Yeah, I'm on hormone
replacement therapy.
I'm at high risk
for osteoporosis,
so I started the hormones
after menopause.
Okay.
No midline abnormalities.
Is, uh... Do you have
any burning with urination?
Um, no, although lately,
it does seem like I have
to go every ten minutes.
Our granddaughter just
got out of diapers.
I guess I'm on
my way into them.
Well, looks like it's
just a muscle strain.
Really?
Yeah, a ten of Flexeril
and 800 of Ibuprofen.
And, uh, I'll check
back in an hour,
see how you're feeling.
Thanks.
Yeah.
Muscle strain.
Mmm.
Maggie...
Uh-huh?
I need a doctor
in the waiting room.
Got it.
Dr. Choi, we're up.
LaShawn, hold onto this.
Be quiet, please!
Clear out, clear out.
Here, here, here.
Sir, take this chair
and move it,
please, thank you.
She kept falling over
onto the person next to her.
I can't wake her up.
Ma'am. Ma'am,
can you hear me?
She's snoring, so she's
protecting her airway.
Able to breathe, good pulse.
Who is she?
Patient here to be seen?
No idea, she never
checked in with me.
Anyone know who she is?
Mags, see if there's an ID.
Yeah. I got it.
Illinois driver's license.
Her name is Rachel Wexler.
30 years old,
lives in Evanston.
That's not close.
No.
Don't know why she's here,
but she's a patient now.
All right,
get ready to clear out.
Move, people, move, move,
move, move, move, move!
Go, go, go, go,
go, go, go, go!
Doris, Treatment Four.
What do we got?
Fell asleep,
now won't wake up.
OD?
That's my guess.
A drop and dash,
or maybe a last fling
before coming in
to get treatment.
Doris, push 2 of Narcan.
Yep.
Mags, any more info
from her purse?
Wallet, keys, makeup, gum,
birth control pills, and
cigarettes, nothing helpful.
BP, 104 over 68,
heartrate, 72,
pulse ox, 99%,
EKG, normal sinus rhythm.
Not exactly OD vitals,
Dr. Choi.
No response to Narcan.
I told you.
Narcan only counteracts
to opiates. Must be a benzo.
Push.4 of Flumazenil,
and order a CBC, CMP,
ammonia levels,
arterial blood gas, BAC,
and blood and urine
tox screens.
Maggie, she's wearing
a wedding ring.
Can you find a contact
for a spouse?
Would if I could,
but no cell phone,
but a charger, so I'm guessing
she had one at some point.
If she stumbled in here high,
who knows where she lost it.
Flumazenil's not
working either.
Okay, OD's out.
Doris, add an HCG,
a CT chest, spine,
um, abdomen and pelvis
to the test.
Got it.
Dr. Stohl,
you're thinking injury?
All I'm seeing is a scar
on her right cheek,
but it's old, clearly healed.
Just because
there's no bruising
doesn't mean
there's no trauma.
You should know
that, Dr. Choi.
So, I took a second look
at your echo,
and I wanna start you
on dexamethasone.
It's another
anti-inflammatory.
Whatever you think
is best, do it.
How'd it go?
Surgery went well.
Peter's artificial
heart is in.
Let's hope it lasts until a
donor heart becomes available.
Peter's Status One
on the transplant list.
He's got a chance.
My patient, Dan,
he's Status Two.
I am waiting for a call that's
probably never gonna come.
GCM's brutal but not usually
discovered until autopsy.
You're way ahead of it.
I was.
Now I'm just playing catch-up.
23-year-old male.
Went down on his motorcycle
just outside Bloomington.
Wasn't wearing a helmet.
Massive brain hemorrhaging?
Rural hospital's
been working on him,
but he's worse
than they can handle.
GCS, 3,
down six hours already.
Crap scans.
Doubt we can do much better.
You know what they call
a motorcyclist
riding without a helmet,
don't you?
One, two, three.
An organ donor.
Well, she's not catatonic.
Whatever knocked her out,
it's not psychiatric.
What'd her tox screens show?
Yeah, she's clean.
Blood alcohol, arterial gases,
and all other labs too.
Diabetic Ketoacidosis?
Blood sugar's normal.
Liver failure?
Ammonia level's normal.
Tumor?
Chest X-ray and all
the CTs were clean.
The scar on her cheek?
Plate from an old fracture.
No apparent connection
to her unconsciousness.
Just got off the phone
with PD.
Ruzek ran Rachel's name
through the system.
She got busted a few times,
DUI and possession.
And yet a clean tox and BAC.
Hmm, the plot thickens.
Good luck.
Hey.
Hi, Natalie.
Just getting here?
Yeah, remember,
it was my turn
to be volunteer mom
at Owen's daycare class.
Oh, right, yeah.
Three hours and 20 toddlers,
do you have any idea
how many boogers that is?
Ha, I'll bet.
Okay, not my best material,
but not even a courtesy laugh?
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm just tired.
Are you sure?
No, yeah, I'm good.
Dr. Manning, you're up.
You're going to Treatment Two.
Okay. Hey,
I'll catch you later?
Okay.
Sam Covington,
27-year-old male.
Hypotensive and tachypneic.
Long-term care patient
following a TBI.
How long ago did he sustain
the brain injury?
Um, five years.
It was a surfing accident.
He was only 22.
Just graduated from UCSD,
magna cum laude.
Sorry, you don't
need to know all that.
Mom, I take it?
All right, let's transfer him
on my count.
Ready, one, two, three.
Temp, 101.6.
Okay.
Congested on both sides.
Mom, hey, I just got
your message.
Sorry, I was in class.
What happened? Is Sam okay?
Uh, your brother
was breathing fast,
and, um, he...
He looked like he was in pain.
Uh, let's get
a CBC, CMP, ABG,
a UA, and blood cultures,
and begin sepsis protocol.
Excuse me, sorry.
Start him on antibiotics.
That's a lot of tests.
I understand, but since Sam
can't tell us where it hurts,
it's better to err
on the side of caution.
Okay?
Take as much time
with your son as you need.
When you're ready,
someone will come
speak with you
about organ donation.
What happened?
Motorcycle accident.
Never had a chance.
Soon as the immunotyping
results are in, find me.
Yeah, okay.
So, how we feeling?
Ugh, my back is better,
but now I'm feeling
really queasy.
All of a sudden,
it just hit her.
A reaction to the Flexeril?
Yeah, maybe.
Um, can I take a look?
Okay, uh-uh...
Oh, gosh.
Mmm.
April, can I...
Sorry.
Mmm, can I get, um,
four milligrams of Zofran?
Uh, and if you'll
excuse me, I'll...
I'll be right back.
Sorry.
No, yes, it's, um...
It's no, it's no problem.
Sorry.
Oh, I'm so embarrassed.
Oh, he's fine.
First-year resident,
projectile vomit is
a rite of passage.
I'll get you a gown.
Thank you.
Oh, my God.
Are you all right?
Daniel, there you are.
The next round of prospective
transplant candidates.
No rest for the wicked.
Dr. Reese's father, Robert
Haywood, is in this stack.
Class Three heart failure.
I hope he makes a strong
candidate.
You'll keep me in the loop?
Uh, Daniel?
Yes. Yes, of course.
Could you excuse me?
Dan?
Daddy?
Get the crash cart!
Paddles now.
Come here.
Come...
No pulse or breathing.
He's in V-fib.
Get on his chest.
Charge to 200.
Charged.
All right,
hold compressions. Clear!
Charge again. Amp of epi.
Epi's in. Charged.
All right, clear!
He's hurting Daddy!
No, honey.
Charge again. Amp of epi.
He's just trying to help.
Come on, Dan.
Beat, damn it. Come on.
Meds are in.
Charged.
Hold compressions. Clear.
He's back.
Thank you.
So, I'm not getting on
the transplant list?
I didn't say that.
I'm just making you aware
that personality disorders
can be a contraindication
to transplant.
You believe I have Antisocial
Personality Disorder,
but another psychiatrist
might not.
It's... It's a pretty gray
area, wouldn't you say?
Well, actually it isn't.
Uh, take a look at this.
This is a PET scan
of your brain.
Taken...
When Dr. Rhodes was conducting
his thoracic study?
That's right.
And this supports
your diagnosis?
Mmm.
Well...
Since you're bound
by doctor-patient
confidentiality,
I just say we keep
this to ourselves.
I'm afraid
that's not an option.
Um, I am obliged
to report my findings
to the evaluation committee.
I didn't realize you had
such influence on the process,
Dr. Charles.
My heart meds.
Do you have any water?
Of course.
Um, by the way,
contraindication
isn't absolute.
I mean, taking positive steps
to manage your disorder
can go a long way
to mitigating concerns.
Well, I hope you have
some suggestions.
Well, what the committee's
looking for
is self-sufficiency...
Mmm-hmm?
Fiscal responsibility...
Fiscal responsibility?
You wouldn't by any chance
be referring to the loan
I asked Sarah to cosign?
Anything you can do
to establish independence...
Perhaps rescind the request.
Would certainly count
in your favor.
I'm sorry, Bob, you know,
they come up against this
all the time.
There are simply
too many people
waiting for too few organs.
I really appreciate you
giving me this advice.
Hi.
Dr. Manning, this is
my sister, Lizzie.
She just drove down
from Racine.
Nice to meet you.
Uh, how long was I sleeping?
Lizzie, when...
When did you get here?
Just now, Mom.
"Eddie would go"?
Who's Eddie?
Eddie Aikau,
legendary big wave surfer
and lifeguard at Waimea Bay.
He'd charge waves
no one else would dare.
Sam's hero.
So we got the results back
from Sam's labs and X-rays.
Um, I'm afraid
he has pneumonia.
The antibiotics
should knock it out.
Right now, we'd like to
swap out Sam's trach tube
so we can put him on the vent,
you know, give his
respiratory system a rest.
Okay?
No, no, it's okay.
Honey, honey, it's okay.
Just... She'll be gentle.
Okay.
Monique, pass me
the new trach tube.
Hey, that's, um,
Rachel's husband, Jacob.
Where'd you find him?
He found us.
He kept on calling
her voice mail
and finally used
a "find my phone" app,
which led him
to the waiting room.
Her phone was buried
in the chair cushion.
Thanks, Mags.
Yeah.
Mr. Wexler...
Hey.
I'm Dr. Choi. I've been
treating your wife.
What's wrong with her?
Well, we don't know yet.
All her tests
have been negative,
including the tox screen.
But given your wife's
drug history...
You think she overdosed?
She might have taken something
that's beating the test,
possibly a synthetic.
Rachel was in a car accident
a few years ago.
Airbag broke her jaw
and a bone in her cheek.
The injuries healed,
but the pain pills...
After her last arrest,
she promised
that she'd stay clean.
Here we go again.
Meds alone aren't taking
enough pressure
off of Dan's heart,
so I am going to
put him on ECMO.
Full support, so that
his heart doesn't have
to shoulder any load.
When you first
diagnosed the GCM,
you said ECMO was
a final option.
Mmm-hmm.
I told myself...
To make a plan,
to prepare for this moment,
but I couldn't do it.
It felt like giving up.
I promise you...
That's not what's
happening here.
Okay?
How's your TBI patient?
Saw pneumonia on his chart.
Pretty sure he got it
from his trach tube.
It was filthy.
His mom's his caregiver.
Looks like she hasn't been
cleaning or suctioning it.
What, neglect?
No, I don't think so.
All other areas, he was
meticulously well-cared for.
His nails are trimmed,
his teeth are brushed,
skin is moisturized.
So Mom's burnt out.
The first thing to slip
was the tube?
Ever since Sam's injury,
she has devoted
her entire life
to caring for him.
I'm not sure how to tell her
that she may no longer
be up to the task.
You want some backup?
No, I don't want her
to feel ganged up on.
I'll figure it out.
So, the Zofran
hasn't helped at all?
No! And the cramps
are unbearable.
So is her gas.
Hey!
No fever, vitals are normal.
All right, let's hang another
liter of, uh, normal saline,
and order a CBC, CMP,
amylase, and lipase levels.
Okay?
Uh, this might be
a stomach bug,
possibly kidney stones,
okay?
I'm just gonna...
I'm gonna put...
I'm gonna press
on your stomach.
Ah! Wait, I need a bathroom!
Okay.
Oh, okay.
I need a bathroom right now!
All right, come on, honey.
Okay, hold on a second.
We'll get you there.
Oh!
What?
Whoa.
Sorry.
That's okay.
Honey, let's get you
back into bed.
Oh, my God, no...
I still need to go!
Okay, I'm gonna help you.
Really bad!
Come on. Come on, let's go.
Wait, wait, wait, no, no, no.
That's not urine.
Oh, okay. Let's, let's
get you right back into bed.
Come on.
Wait, what...
What's going on?
I don't know
what's happening.
Come on.
What's going on?
Oh! Oh! Ow!
Come on.
Jeez.
What are you doing?
What's going on?
Oh.
Yikes!
What is going on?
Really? Are you...
Whoa!
Oh.
Okay, Mrs. Davis...
Yeah?
You're gonna wanna push,
but don't.
There's no way. No, no, no.
This... This is not possible.
Uh, what is going on?
Your wife is pregnant
and in labor.
No, no, that...
That can't be true.
I'm 55. I've been
through menopause.
I know this might be a shock,
but this is happening.
I am positive. Page OB.
Okay.
I'll be right back, okay?
Uh...
Oh, my God!
Oh, my...
What the hell, Connor?
Not here.
That motorcyclist
is an HLA match
to my patient, Peter,
but suddenly,
your GCM patient is above him
on the transplant list?
How did he come in
this morning at Status Two
and suddenly jump to
the highest priority?
I had to put him on ECMO.
Before other meds?
Milrinone?
Monoclonal antibody therapy?
They're just stop-gaps.
Oh, you sneaky
son of a bitch.
ECMO trumps
an artificial heart,
puts your patient
to the top of the list.
You manipulated the system.
I made an aggressive
treatment decision.
You're taking a heart
that doesn't belong to you!
I am fighting for one
that's available!
This isn't right.
And it isn't over.
The hospital
can connect you
with respite services,
as well as caregiver
support groups.
You do not have
to do this alone.
And we can
help out more, Mom.
Catherine...
No one is blaming you.
You have done
a tremendous job
caring for Sam.
I wasn't trying to hurt him.
No, of course not.
I thought that...
He would go peacefully.
No, I wasn't prepared
to see him in pain.
Mom, what are
you talking about?
Sam doesn't want
this oblivion.
I see it in his eyes
every time he looks at me.
The doctors say there is
no meaning behind it.
That he's not
really looking at me.
I know my son...
And he wants this over.
He was begging me to help him.
Mom, stop talking.
I should never
have called 9-1-1.
I should have just
let him go, like I planned,
like he wanted.
I got scared. I panicked.
Oh, my God, Mom, did you...
Mom, please,
don't say anything else.
Sam, I'm sorry
I let you down.
I am so sorry, honey.
We need to call
a lawyer, now.
First, you're
treating my father,
and now you're
blackmailing him?
What?
You heard me.
Look, I don't know
what he told you...
He said you're jealous
of our relationship,
that you have some twisted
paternal feelings for me,
that you threatened him,
and said if he didn't
stay away from me,
you'd sabotage his chances
of getting on the list.
I threatened him?
Sabotage?
Yes.
I'm a shrink in a sweater
vest, not a secret agent.
Is it true?
I can't disclose
details of our conversation,
but I assure you,
all I did was
lay out the facts
as they pertain
to his condition.
What are you
treating him for?
I can't tell you that, Sarah.
He's my patient.
But he is my father.
Who suddenly reappears
after two decades
of avoiding
parental responsibility
and alienating
everyone in his life,
who now presents himself
as a victim
in order to create
an alliance with you.
Think about
what you know, Sarah.
If he was your patient,
what would be on
your differential?
What was that about?
As you will read
in my evaluation,
her father, Dr. Haywood,
has a particularly
malignant form
of Antisocial
Personality Disorder.
Are you serious?
Is she in danger?
Well, I haven't picked up
any violent tendencies yet,
but he's an extremely
effective manipulator.
Dr. Reese doesn't know?
Well, I think she might be
starting to figure it out
on a clinical level,
but emotionally,
she's not there yet.
Oh! This can't be real!
This can't be real!
Where the hell is the OB?
They said five minutes.
We can't wait.
The baby's crowning.
What?
Tessa...
Yeah?
On three,
really big push, okay?
Okay.
All right, one...
Uh-huh?
Two, three.
Yeah, good, good.
When did we go to
Mark and Patti's cabin?
What?
Was that Fourth of July?
What are you talking about?
I'm just trying to figure out
when this happened.
Oh, God, Greg,
how does that matter now?
Mr. Davis, can you
please help the nurse
hold your wife's leg back?
All right, okay, yeah, yeah.
Thank you. Okay.
Tessa, Tessa, look at me.
Look at me, Tessa.
Okay, Tessa,
one more push, all right?
Okay. Yeah!
You can do it,
you can do it.
Ready?
Yeah!
You're doing great.
You're almost there.
All right, all right.
Yes.
Oh!
Whoa.
Okay, okay...
This is crazy.
It looks okay.
Oh, my...
It's a girl. Congratulations.
Oh!
Oh...
Congratulations
to you both.
Oh, my goodness.
Oh, my gosh.
Natalie, you can't
sit on this.
If I report it,
Catherine will likely be
removed as Sam's guardian.
I wanna pull in
social services.
This goes beyond
family counseling.
It's a criminal matter.
She intentionally
stopped trach care to
cause her son's death.
To end his suffering.
You know, she looked into
moving to a state
where assisted suicide
is legal?
But because Sam
isn't terminally ill
and can't express his wishes,
he didn't qualify.
Exactly, which means
you can't be certain
this is what he wants.
No one knows what Sam wants
more than his mother.
Then she needs to go to court
and make her case,
petition a judge to get
his feeding tube removed.
Look, Natalie,
I'm not arguing she's wrong,
but what she did is illegal.
You have to call the police.
No!
Then I will.
Decerebrate posturing.
Rigid limbs, pointed toes.
She's slipping deeper
into unconsciousness.
Dr. Stohl, Dr. Choi,
we got something.
Right after
we discovered Rachel,
I texted a pic of her license
throughout the hospital.
I just got a call
from my friend from HR.
She said she interviewed
Rachel this morning
for an admin job.
She said she was alert
and engaging.
"Alert and engaging?"
That doesn't sound like
someone about to OD.
All right, but if it's
not drugs, what the hell
knocked her out?
You missed something.
Recheck every test result,
look for anything
that might be
mimicking something else.
Her MRI.
These two spots
of diffusion restriction,
radiology says they're from
movement and mental artifact.
The plate in her cheek.
But what if that's wrong?
This could be damage
from a stroke,
a clot that's knocked out the
Reticular Activating System.
I don't...
Look, RAS controls
wake and sleep patterns.
Easy, Quincy,
that would take a huge clot.
The damage would be
far more extensive than this.
Normally, yes, because
most people have two vessels
that provide blood flow
to the area, but some
only have one.
The Artery of Percheron.
If Rachel has this variant,
a small clot
in just the right area
would take out the RAS.
She's been out for about
four-and-a-half hours.
We missed the window
to use TPA to bust the clot.
Still may be able
to reverse the damage
with local thrombolysis.
Okay, so get on it.
This is not a debate,
Dr. Rhodes.
My patient's HLA is
an ideal match to the donor.
But his antibody levels
are not.
They're too high and suggest
he'll reject the heart.
So it slides to
the next person
on the transplant list,
Dr. Bekker's patient, Peter.
I'm sorry.
Without that heart,
Dan doesn't stand a chance.
Neither does Peter.
No, actually, he does,
because the artificial heart
that you put in
can last months,
possibly even years.
Dan doesn't have
that kind of time.
Peter, he's had
two hearts already,
and with each transplant,
his chances of survival
decrease.
It is not fair
that he gets a third heart
before Dan
even gets his first.
There's no limit
to the number of organs
a person can receive,
and it's impossible
to compare patients in need.
That's why there's a list,
to crunch numbers
and break ties.
You're right.
It's all about the numbers.
Okay.
No, no, right,
uh, I understand.
Okay, bye.
I canceled our trip.
They asked if I wanted
to rebook for a later date.
I said, "Sure,
in about 18 years."
Uh, what's that saying?
"When we plan, God laughs"?
Speaking of planning,
we need diapers
and a crib and a car seat
and bottles and, uh, onesies
and... Did I say diapers?
You did.
I ate sushi.
I had the occasional
glass of wine.
I am happy to report
that you have a completely
healthy baby girl.
Really?
Aw.
Amazing.
Hey, you. Yes!
Hello! God!
Oh.
Oh, holy cow,
you weren't kidding.
No.
This is our son, Martin,
and our daughter-in-law,
Amy, and Haley, come here
and meet your, um... Aunt.
How 'bout that, huh?
We'll give you all some time.
Thanks.
Thanks very much.
Right this way, guys.
It's weird that Will
was so adamant
about calling the cops.
What do you mean?
Well, last week's patient,
Vic Thomas,
he had advanced-stage cancer,
and he was refusing treatment.
Will sent me out of the room
to get a cautery,
and when I came back,
Vic was dead.
I can't be certain,
but I think Will let him die.
What did you do?
Oh, my God.
He's not hooked up.
I need some help here!
Ma'am, I need you to step out.
Right now, ma'am!
I love you, Sam.
Ma'am, please.
No pulse. Bag him.
I need you to step back
from here, please.
Step back, please.
Quick look?
Asystole.
Milligram of epi.
Still no pulse.
Another milligram of epi.
Please, don't hurt him.
Just let him go.
Time of death, 18:16.
It did not have to
get this messy.
I had no choice, Natalie.
When someone commits a crime,
you have to report it.
Except for when it's you?
What are you talking about?
Vic Thomas.
You let him die.
That's why you've been walking
around like a ghost, right?
I don't know
what April told you,
but Vic Thomas explicitly
and repeatedly
expressed his wishes to me,
and there is a monumental
difference between allowing
someone to die naturally
and intentionally
causing their death.
Well, if you did nothing
wrong, then why
keep it a secret?
No, no, no, don't you dare
compare what I did
to what happened here today.
Natalie, they murdered him.
You backed them into a corner
when you called the police.
You forced that family
into a decision!
These are the results
of Dan Kennet's latest
panel reactive antibody test.
His antibody levels
were above 80, but now...
They're within
transplant criteria.
Antibody levels don't
just go down on
their own that quickly.
Uh, you can see for yourself.
I had the lab run it twice.
I'm sorry, Dr. Bekker.
It's not my decision.
Dan Kennet is at
the top of the list.
Assemble the transplant team,
and notify Mr. Kennet
and his family.
Emergency plasmapheresis
and IVIG.
Didn't you?
You made Dan look like
a better candidate
than he really is.
Soon as he's off
the plasmapheresis and IVIG,
his antibody levels
will shoot back up.
Maybe, but the
immunosuppressants
that he's gonna be on
post-transplant
should ensure that his body
doesn't reject the organ.
You got it all covered, huh?
Hey, look, I did what
I had to for my patient.
At the expense of mine!
So do me a favor, okay,
and save your self-righteous
hero speech for someone else.
Will she wake up?
I'm hopeful.
Interventional radiology
was able to locate
the clot and clear it.
But she's so young.
What caused the stroke?
A DVT, deep vein blood clot.
Cigarettes
and birth control pills
were found in Rachel's purse.
Smoking on the pill
can sometimes cause one.
But how'd it get
into her brain?
A PFO, a hole in the heart.
They're not uncommon.
Most people don't even
know they have them.
Jacob?
Oh, thank God, Rachel.
Where am I?
The hospital.
Rachel, I'm Dr. Choi.
Do you know what day it is?
Tuesday.
What's the last thing
you remember?
I sat down...
To wait for my cab.
I had a job interview.
The nurse told me.
That's where you've been going
in the afternoons, isn't it?
Looking for a job?
Why didn't you tell me?
I've messed up
so many times before.
To surprise you, show you
that I really changed.
So, it's really
gonna happen today?
Yes.
You are getting a new heart.
I... My antibody levels,
like, I thought
they were too high.
They were,
but now they're not.
The emergency plasmapheresis
and IVIG you're on now
lowered your levels to
within transplant criteria.
Techs are gonna be by
to prep you for surgery soon.
Thank you, Dr. Rhodes.
Of course.
Thank you.
It's all just
legal mumbo jumbo.
It's pretty boilerplate.
Uh...
Here.
Um, Dad, I'm sorry,
but I can't sign this.
Yeah! Muah.
Yeah!
Just some
friends and family?
You look so good in a suit.
I cannot wait
to tear it off later.
April, this is
my sister, Emily.
Emily, my girlfriend, April.
It's all good.
I am so happy
to finally meet you.
A little.
I spent a year in Rio.
Wow...
Well, hello there.
I am Noah. And you are?
Emily.
Ethan's sister.
Right.
Oh, really?
Really? Well, you know,
how about that?
Yeah? You wanna join me
on the dance floor?
Sure. Think you can keep up?
Oh, yeah?
Oh, it's on. Vamos la.
Aww!
Aww, she seems fun.
I'm so glad you brought her.
With Emily, I always expect
to be disappointed.
Thought I'd give her a chance
to prove me wrong.
But you...
Breathtaking.
Come on, join me
on the dance floor.
No.
Yes!
No!
Hey!
No...
And then faster.