You liked the tile and
the master bedroom suite?
And you like the way the French
doors open out to the deck?
Yes, I love everything so far.
I especially love that I
didn't have to do anything.
Meow.
"Meow." That's right, Zola.
That's what a cat says.
Honestly, when
the house is done,
just bring me out
for the big reveal.
You want a big reveal?
I want a big reveal.
Rawr!
Good, Zola. "Rawr."
That's what a lion says.
Is that a... That's a lion.
We have a phrase
in the operating room,
"Don't pet the lion."
It means, no matter
how nice a tumor looks,
how small it is, how
perfect its margins may be...
Cristina, it's been a week.
At some point, we have to talk.
It's still a tumor,
it's still dangerous,
and it can bite.
It'll be weird at first.
Believe me, you'll
feel like an idiot.
But the words can give
you closure and strength.
So I want you each later to
find a private moment and
just say the words aloud.
"I am a widow."
Gretchen?
It was just so sudden.
Jason was fine,
and then one day,
they said he had some blockages,
minor congestive heart failure,
and then he died, and I...
I'm sorry.
But blockages with
congestive heart failure?
I mean, do you want to
know what that really means?
Your husband's
arteries were clogged.
I mean, he probably was
lucky he lasted as long as he did,
because his heart was working
overtime to pump enough blood
to his brain, let alone
the rest of his body,
which ate away the heart muscle
till the ventricular
wall was paper thin
and barely contracting.
Because just to be clear,
there is no such thing
as minor congestive
heart failure.
A patient with
symptoms that severe?
They're a dead man walking.
A lion? An actual lion?
Looking at me like I was lunch.
Are you sure it wasn't a mountain
lion, or maybe a well-fed cat?
I was staring at Simba.
Grey, you're on my service.
See you. Hey.
I saw a lion today,
walking across the street.
Derek and I were coming
back from the house,
and it was just standing
there in the street.
Cristina's not talking to me.
Okay, how come no one
is concerned about the fact
that I saw a lion
walking around Seattle?
Sorry. I was just...
You can't force
Cristina to open up.
You have to just
let her come to you.
In the meantime, look at this.
Animal Control came.
One dart, and he was down.
It walked across the
road, right in front of us.
I feel like Julia and I
are at a crossroads.
It's been five months.
Maybe it's time to take the
next step and ask her to move in.
Did you hear what I said?
It was a lion.
You like Julia, right?
Dr. Webber.
Don't you have a gallbladder
scheduled for this morning?
Hendricks is doing it.
You heard about
the lion mauling.
Came down here to claim it
before anybody else
could get their hands on it.
I am down here for
those in need, Avery.
I am here to be of
service to human kind.
Yeah, well, you could be
of service to human kind
in OR 3 with that gallbladder.
Try it, son.
Try and challenge me.
Thirty-five-year-old male,
body covered in claw marks
and an arm that
looks like a chew toy.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
My arm. I can't feel my arm.
Don't worry. I'm
gonna take care of you.
So am I.
Naomi. What happened to Naomi?
Did the lion eat my girlfriend?
These wounds are deep,
Avery. Page Sloan and Torres.
Or you can page
Sloan and Torres.
Well, somebody page
Sloan and Torres right now!
Thirty-two-year-old female,
nasty bites to the neck,
and her abdomen's
been eviscerated.
Kirby. Where's Kirby?
Ma'am, my name is Dr. Bailey.
You are at the hospital.
Transferring on one, two, three.
Okay, I need to
look at this neck.
What about Kirby?
All right, let's call for
an OR, and page Hunt.
I need to know if Kirby's
okay. Did he get hurt?
Can you also find out the status
of the gentleman
who came in with her?
No, no. That's Paul.
I want to know
about Kirby, my lion.
So what, it escaped,
like from the zoo?
No, someone's house.
The thing was a pet.
What? Yeah.
I went to a grief group.
You went to a grief group?
Callie! You went to
a grief group. Yay.
That's... No, not "yay."
Bad. Dr. Altman.
I'm ready to get started
on your stem cell project.
See? I mean, who
needs a grief group?
I am doing cutting-edge
stem cell research.
I'm looking toward the future,
not dwelling on the past. Right?
Sorry to interrupt.
It's my last day, and I just
wanted to say good-bye.
Well, it's been great
working with you.
Good luck back east.
Good-bye. Bye.
Is it okay if I give you a hug?
Why wouldn't it be okay?
Yeah, of course it is.
Come here, Colleen.
Give me a hug.
I think he grew.
Doesn't he look longer?
Sure. He's gonna play hoops.
I'm serious. You
should measure him.
He shot up an inch overnight.
I gotta change his dressing.
You changed his
dressing an hour ago.
Please measure him.
I'm using my puppy dog eyes.
He needs a new tape measure.
I need off this case. Put
Kepner on it or something.
This is about
the lion, isn't it?
You want to go see the victims.
I don't blame you.
All right. Go on. Go get a
look and then come back.
And take pictures
while you're there.
This isn't about the lion.
This is about Morgan.
She's into me.
Karev, we work with sick kids
and then we develop close
relationships with their parents.
It's normal. You just
need to deal with it.
And you... You
put up boundaries.
I'm trying, but she acts
like we're, you know...
I can't be this
kid's doctor, okay?
Alex, he smiled.
You gotta come
see. He's smiling.
Okay, you want off my service,
you can be off my service.
But, Alex, you better mean it.
I mean it.
Okay. I mean it.
The patient's belly
is ripped open.
Spleen and
intestines are exposed.
What happened?
She has a lion for a
pet is what happened.
It tried to eat her
and then it got away,
and it probably tried
to eat other people
because it is a lion.
Who has a lion
living in their house?
I'll tell you who has a
lion living in their house.
A crazy person does.
Now because she's crazy
doesn't mean she doesn't
deserve excellent care.
In fact, we're going to
save that crazy lady's life
just so I can tell
her she's crazy.
Got it?
Told you I saw a lion.
I know you know.
Is this about Cristina again?
She walks away every
time I try to talk to her,
so just let her know
how sorry I am.
I wish I could take it back,
if I could. It was just sex.
Just stop. I would love to stop.
I mean, I don't
relish discussing
my own personal
failings with you, but...
We're going to pretend this
conversation never happened.
Okay? No! Meredith...
I mean it.
Damn it. Now I
have to scrub again.
Do you know anything about
Arizona and that nurse Colleen?
Were they a thing
before she met me?
Ortho nurse Colleen?
Yeah. There was a good-bye
hug that lingered too long.
That would explain it.
I been trying to get her
naked for three years.
Anyway, she never said anything,
and I work with
Colleen every day.
Do you think she has other exes
here in the hospital? Probably.
Ugh.
Quit it. Stop thinking
about the hot ortho nurse.
Wait. You... You
think she's hot?
I could see it in those eyes.
Those eyes said, "You are
meat," and in that moment,
I believed him.
What happened then?
Then he lunged,
and I just reacted.
I shoved my arm right into his
mouth. Who the hell who does that?
Who the hell feeds
himself to a lion?
I'm kinda wondering
the same thing.
What do we got? Deep
animal claw laceration
extending down the
left side of the body.
And there's your arm.
Yeah, that's what you
expect when you hear "lion."
I bet it's nice to
know what to expect
instead of showing up at your
girlfriend's house for the first time
and being greeted at the door
by the freakin'
king of the jungle.
She never bothered to
mention she had a pet lion?
Seems like something that
ought to come up on a first date.
Right? She told
me she had a cat.
A big cat, and I'm allergic,
so I took an antihistamine
before I left the house.
Yeah. You should
have brought a bullwhip.
So I dissect out and remove
the animal cadaver hearts.
Then I insert them
with the catheters
and begin injecting
them with the solvent.
Correct. And why do we do that?
To drain the hearts of
their existing cardiac cells
so all that's left is their
extracellular matrix.
Like stripping a house
down to its frame only.
We are scrubbing away
cells of hearts, Cristina,
actual hearts.
We are wiping them
clean till they're blank.
And then in theory,
when we inject
them with stem cells...
They'll live again.
Let's grow ourselves
some new hearts.
Dr. Altman, I traded with
Kepner. I'm on your service today.
Are you up on my patients?
Uh...
Karev? Karev, can you focus?
Yeah. Sorry.
That's the ER. Let's go.
Happy scrubbing.
You immobilize the
aneurysm and place the clip.
Wait. I'm clipping the aneurysm?
What if it ruptures?
I clip proximal and
distal to the aneurysm.
What if you damage
the perforating vessels?
I throw a temporary
clip on the parent artery.
It's okay if you don't
want me to do it.
I know that I really
messed up last week.
Yes, you did.
But you're still a student,
and this is how you learn.
Any other questions?
Are you gonna tell Mark
to move in with Julia?
I mean, what do they
even really talk about?
You know, she sews
eyeballs for a living. It's gross.
I mean, plus, she
has really thin hair,
which can be a sign
of early menopause.
We don't talk
about stuff like this.
I will see you in pre-op.
You're not using the oil.
Alex uses his oil when
Tommy's distressed.
It keeps him from desaturating.
His SATs are really low.
I don't think the oil is...
Just use the oil.
Can we page Dr. Robbins?
No, page Dr. Karev.
Alex... Page Robbins now!
Can you describe the pain?
I don't know. It just...
It's like a...
It's crushing me,
and I can't shake it.
Hand me the EKG.
It looks like anterolateral MI.
We almost didn't come in.
We're only in
town till tomorrow.
We're catching a
cruise for Alaska.
Mr. Carroll, you're
experiencing a heart attack.
We need to take you up to
the cath lab for an angioplasty.
Can you tell me what you were
doing when you felt the chest pain?
We just went out to walk
around our bed and breakfast,
and it was like a piano fell
onto my chest.
So you were walking.
You weren't running
or anything else
that might have
triggered the pain?
Well...
We saw a lion.
Yeah.
Hey.
So that was a little awkward.
Don't you think, that
thing with Colleen?
How she was... She
got so emotional.
Almost seems like
you guys were a thing.
Yeah, she gets
like that. Oh, really?
She gets like that, like
you know how she gets,
like you were a thing? Callie.
What? It's not... What? I'm
just asking. It's not a big deal.
We were. We were a little bit
of a thing a very long time ago.
Seems like something
you would've mentioned.
Well, it didn't
even occur to me.
Have you dated other
people in the hospital
it hasn't occurred to
you to tell me about?
Okay, you know what?
We're not doing this.
No, it's totally fine. I mean,
I'll tell you about my exes.
I know about your exes.
Not all of them. You
don't know about Karev.
Karev. I know about Karev.
Look, just give me
a number. Ballpark.
What, five? Ten? Hundred?
Okay, that's the
NICU. I have to go.
No, no, no, no, no.
You can't just go.
I'm sorry, but the babies,
they need me, so...
Arizona...
I'm sorry. Wait.
Wait. What... "Waah.
"Dr. Robbins, please help us.
Waah." Just give me a number.
Just give me a number.
One or two, okay?
That's... That's it.
One or two.
That's not so bad.
Maybe she should've
gotten a dog.
A dog fetches balls.
Maybe, you know, a rascally dog,
he chews shoes.
But he doesn't
eviscerate your spleen.
Yeah, and don't say it's
because you love lions so much.
If you love lions,
you wouldn't want it
to live in your home.
You would want that lion to roam
freely in the jungle with other lions
where they can eviscerate
the spleens of Gazelles.
That's what lions eat, gazelles?
I think I saw that on a show
where they were
chasing a herd of gazelles.
Have I offended someone?
'Cause it's awfully quiet in here.
Well, don't tell me you own an
exotic pet that I don't know about.
Grey, you living with a monkey?
Please don't tell me
you're living with a monkey.
No. No monkeys.
Hunt?
No. Cristina doesn't
believe in pets.
Cristina doesn't
believe in a lot of things.
Okay, then.
Suction.
I'm sorry. Explain it again.
During the angioplasty,
Mr. Carroll had another heart attack.
We placed a balloon
pump to stabilize him,
but that only buys
us a little time.
They're gonna have
to do surgery, Emma.
But he's going to be okay?
If we can perform a
coronary artery bypass soon,
I'm hopeful that
we've caught it in time.
I am so sorry, Em.
You've been waiting
for this trip 50 years.
This cruise was a gift
from our kids for
our anniversary.
And now I've messed it all up.
You didn't mess anything up.
You wanted to see those
humpback whales so bad.
Forget the whales.
We came
face-to-face with a lion.
Yes, we did.
It's already a
heck of a vacation.
Yes, it is.
Happy anniversary, Martin.
Say that to me tomorrow.
Make sure his
labs are up to date,
and then we'll take
him up to pre-op.
What is wrong with you?
I know... I know
that we don't...
We don't talk about this stuff.
Okay? But I kinda need
to talk about this stuff,
because what if I don't and
then I miss an opportunity
to appeal to my big brother
about, you know, what...
What if Mark is my soul mate?
I am not your best
friend right now, Lexie.
I am not your big brother.
I am your attending,
and what I need is my resident.
You're right.
I'm sorry. I...
I am your resident. Good.
Make sure our
patient is prepped.
You have an aneurysm to clip.
We came to see the hearts.
This blows.
Yang's growing organs,
and I'm stuck
patching up grandpa.
Is that Morgan again? Why
don't you just answer her already?
I've gotta be a
dead fricking mouse.
Cold and dead, okay? I
mean, that's what she needs.
All day, I'm trying to back
off, and all she does is...
See? Hey, you can do this.
All right? You are
good at being a douche,
and that's just, what, one step
away from being cold and dead?
I mean, right, Yang?
See what she's doing?
That's what you need to do.
Do that. Do what she's doing.
Hey, did you guys
hear about a lion lady?
Yeah. Her boyfriend
was the appetizer,
and he wanted mommy for dinner.
I feel bad for her. Okay,
she's just a girl with a pet.
You know, she probably
had some nice friends once,
and maybe even a nice guy, and
then those friends moved away,
the guy started living
with somebody else,
and then her family
probably abandoned her
leaving her alone to rot in an
attic somewhere with her cat,
her big jungle cat,
who was sitting in the
corner, just licking his paws
just wanting to eat
her stupid face off.
Look, this is a scientific
lab, not a lunchroom,
so everyone out right now.
Cold and dead.
Tommy's contrast study shows
that his sepsis is due
to an ileocolic fistula.
So do the surgery.
He has a bleed,
and he's developed
a post-hemorrhagic
hydrocephalus.
He has ROP.
He's at risk for cerebral
palsy, blindness, deafness,
inability to walk or feed
himself, cognitive disabilities...
I don't see how this
surgery changes that.
It doesn't, but it's invasive.
I mean, there's a
chance it won't work,
and he'll need more
surgeries. Yeah, I know that.
I have been here dealing
with this for a while.
I know more about
this stuff than you do.
Where... Where is Alex?
He's on another case.
I think that you need to
consider your other option.
If we don't escalate care...
Have they taught you
what AND means yet?
Allowing natural death.
We're... We're not...
We're not there yet.
Things are
deteriorating significantly.
You think that's
what I should do?
I think that you
need to consider
what kind of life you
want for your son.
Is it okay for him to
be in pain every day?
Is it okay if he
needs a feeding tube
for the rest of his life?
Is it okay if he can't run,
climb, or crawl?
If you want the
surgery, we'll do it.
But if you decide
that enough is enough,
then we'll support
that choice, too.
Hey.
Arizona just taught
me what AND is.
I guess my med school
education's not dead yet.
Imagine.
The power it takes to
cause injuries like these.
A flick of your wrist, and...
Nope. You know
what these injuries are?
This is natural
selection at work.
I mean, the guy was an idiot.
I don't care how
desperate you are for sex,
if a chick tells you she
wants you to meet her cat,
you run fast.
He was blindsided by
someone he trusted.
You never know how you're
gonna react when that happens.
What did you say
to Robbins? Hmm?
Nothing. I just asked
her how many other exes
she has in the hospital.
She said one or two.
I can live with
one or two, right?
What was that? Why did he cough?
Don't say anything.
We're not in this.
Webber, why'd you cough?
Well, it's... It's a little like
when a patient tells you
they have one or
two drinks a week.
We all round that number up
because patients tend to
tell us what we want to hear.
If they'll admit
to two drinks...
They're having so many more.
I got... I got
something sharp here.
Oh...
A lion tooth.
All right.
Hey, hey, hey, don't just
toss that aside just yet.
Boki, keep that safe, will you?
Mrs. Carroll, I'm on my
way up to surgery now.
The grandkids want
pictures of the lion,
but these damn phones make it
so hard to see the damn buttons.
May I?
There. It's sent.
You guys really
did get up close.
Martin faced a lion today.
He faced a lion and
he didn't get eaten.
He's not...
It's not his time, Dr. Altman.
Please don't make me a widow.
I don't want you to worry.
I am very good at my job.
Okay?
Watch the angle. You're
gonna clip the perforators.
No, no, stop.
Lexie, I'm sorry,
but I think I should do this.
Yeah, yeah. It's... It's okay.
Next time.
I'm not gonna tell
Mark what to do.
You're not?
They're gonna move
in together either way.
The man has always
been easy to read.
And the only thing
that could change that
is if he knew he still
had a shot with you.
Really?
He's happy with
the eyeball doctor.
So make sure you want him
back because you want him,
not because he's
with somebody else.
All right. The
grafting is complete.
Let's wean him off bypass.
Dr. Karev, it's yours.
It's from a Morgan.
"Did you get my last
text? Where are you?"
And then it says, "We
need to talk," all caps.
Is that the intern with
the preemie? Yep.
"You're ignoring
me. You're a total..."
Then there's a lot
of strong language.
If you need to step
away, just say so.
I'm fine. Are we warmed?
Yes, we are doctor.
For what it's worth, I think
you're doing the right thing.
She needs to figure out how to
take care of herself and her baby.
She's alone.
There is no time like
the present to embrace it.
Turn it off. Please.
All right. Removing the
aortic cross-clamp now.
I see some bleeding. Damn it.
The ventricle's ruptured.
3-0 prolene. Get in there
with the suction, Karev.
Come on, Martin.
Come on. Damn it.
Meredith...
Hey, just don't
talk to me. Okay?
She knew I would hate you, but
she didn't want me to hate you.
Do you know what that means?
It means she's
planning to forgive you
or she's desperately trying
to find a way to forgive you.
And it doesn't matter
if it was just sex.
She didn't want
me to know, okay?
And now I do, so don't.
All right, give me a
pledget. Here you go.
Shouldn't we go back
on bypass and patch it?
I mean, one slip, and
this guy's as good as dead.
Then I better not slip.
Okay, nobody breathe.
Okay. Cut it. Let's
see if it worked.
I don't see any blood.
Crap. You did it.
I did, didn't I?
All right. Let's finish up.
Just so you know, she's
tweaking about Colleen
and all the others.
Excuse me? I tried
to talk her down,
but it could get ugly,
mauled-by-a-lion ugly.
You talked to your
ex about my exes?
Yeah. I wanted some input.
No. No, no, no. He does not get
to have that input on our love life.
Okay, excuse me.
Colleen was an ortho nurse.
I worked with her
every day for two years,
and I had no idea
that the two of you...
She's seen you naked.
Okay, fine. What do
you want to know?
I want names.
Her.
And her.
And her, over by the
soda machine. Yeah, twice.
Okay, that's Noelle.
She's not even gay.
Well, she was that night.
Also Nancy in
Path, Meg in Dermo,
nurse Tia and her sister,
but, you know, not
at the same time.
Can I get something
for the pain?
You are maxed out
on pain meds, buddy.
Of course I am.
I swear to God, Paul,
you're such a wussy.
No one thinks that. They should.
Naomi does.
Gotta be why she didn't
tell me that Kirby was a lion.
She knew I would've freaked
out. We met on a dating site.
And when I saw her profile,
she seemed so adventurous,
outdoorsy.
Maybe I misrepresented
myself a little bit.
Pretended I was
adventurous and outdoorsy.
When we met, I could
tell she was disappointed.
But she stuck around,
trying to see if
the guy I pretended to be
was in here somewhere.
But when I shoved my
arm into Kirby's mouth
and I felt him chomp down,
I screamed.
I really, really screamed.
She knows the truth.
I am a wussy.
Hang on. Kirby was going for her
and not you,
and you body-blocked a lion?
Son, you are a hero.
You were the knight
on the white horse
who stared into
the dragon's jaws
and shoved his fist straight
down the bastard's throat.
So, I saved her?
I'll tell you one thing,
there's no way I would've
been able to do what you did.
Really?
Yeah. Me... I mean, me either.
Huh...
You want to come
talk to the wife?
You just want an audience
while you do your victory lap.
You bet I do.
You're not even a little interested
in why I know about AND?
It's 'cause I have
to decide today if
I make Robbins operate
on Tommy's fistula
or I just let him die.
I didn't know you
were there already.
Yeah, 'cause you vaporized.
I'm sorry. I was in surgery.
He had such a
good day yesterday.
I actually went online last
night and found a used crib,
and then this
morning, it's like,
"Why can't he just have a
few good days in a row?"
I don't know what to do.
What am I supposed to do?
I think it's time for you to
consider the quality of life
that you want to offer Tommy.
I don't need you to give me
the frigging party line, Alex.
I have Robbins for that.
I need you to tell
me what to do.
It's not my decision.
Hey. Hey. Don't get
all objective on me now.
It's not the time.
No, it is the time.
Look, I'm not his dad,
I'm not your boyfriend,
and you can't rely on me to
help you make this decision.
Wow. Really? Now?
In the worst moment of my life,
you want to make sure I
understand we're not a couple?
Yeah, 'cause you know what?
This isn't the worst
moment of your life.
The worst moment of your life
is gonna be when Tommy dies,
or when he doesn't die and
he's in pain and frustrated
because his body won't
do what he wants it to do,
or his brain doesn't work
like the other kids' brains work,
and you're spending half your
life going to the doctor's office.
So what if he's not perfect?
Why do you all people think
that just because he's blind,
or impaired or not a freaking
doctor, he's not worth something?
The point is, it doesn't
matter what the rest of us think.
At the end of the day, all
that matters is what you think.
So decide... That's
what I'm trying to do.
No, you're not.
Look, you're standing
at the nursery bawling,
looking at all the
healthy babies,
feeling sorry for
yourself. Stop it.
Look, no one's saying that you
didn't get dealt a crappy hand. You did.
But now you've
gotta deal with it.
You. Not me and you. You.
Hey.
I brought you a treat.
Thanks.
Whatcha doing?
Whole organ decellularization.
I wash the hearts
with the solvent
for the next 12 hours, and then
it drains them of their cells so
Teddy and I can reseed them.
So you're making new
hearts from scratch.
Yeah. Kinda.
Cool.
Mrs. Carroll, I just
wanted to tell you
that your husband's
surgery went...
Mrs. Carroll, I'm
sorry to wake you.
Mrs. Carroll? Mrs. Carroll?
Oh, no. Oh, no. I need a gurney.
Hey. We're doing the surgery,
but she doesn't
want you involved.
Yeah. Yeah. Let
me know how it goes.
Hey.
You were a great doctor today.
He's gonna need
a really tough mom.
And if hating you
helps make her tough...
Yeah.
Naomi?
Naomi, I'm here.
Don't try to move.
You have about
a million stitches.
He's gone.
No, I'm right here.
I'm right beside you.
Kirby. He's gone.
He's been my best
friend for 15 years,
and now they're
gonna take him away.
Because of you.
I saved you.
He freaked out because you
were screaming like a little bitch.
I was screaming like a bitch
because he was going for your throat.
Dr. Avery and I are gonna just
let you two have some privacy.
My throat? Are you kidding
me? That's how Kirby plays.
That's how he hunts
because he's a lion
living in a two-bedroom townhome
when he should be
roaming the frigging savanna.
That lion is braver
than any of us.
You'd be dead if it weren't
for me. I'm a knight on a horse.
I slayed a dragon.
I am a hero, and we are so over.
That's disappointing.
But not surprising.
I mean, an idiot
dating an idiot.
I have something I
think you should see.
Come with me.
Maybe. No.
What are you doing?
Trying to figure out how many
dermatology fellows my wife's banged.
For sure her.
Yeah, that one, probably, too.
"Specializes in complete
body rejuvenation."
Yeah, I bet you do, Cheryl.
You gotta get over it.
Everybody's got a past.
Look, I'm fine with
her having a past.
It's just, I didn't know
I was working with it
and operating with it,
seeing it in the cafeteria.
That woman wakes up every day,
sees my face in her
kitchen holding her kid,
the kid that you and I
made together.
Yeah, I guess...
I guess that can't
be easy for her.
Easy? Knowing you've been
with the golden boy of this hospital?
Woman's in hell, Torres.
Okay.
I'm a God. It's killing her.
The nurse said your
surgery was flawless,
that now I have the
heart of a 50-year-old.
Thank you, Dr. Altman.
Martin... Where's Emma?
Did you tell her yet?
When your surgery was finished,
I went to look for your
wife in the waiting room.
I thought that she
had fallen asleep,
so I tried to wake her, but...
Oh, no.
We performed CPR.
I tried to resuscitate
her myself, but she...
She didn't make it.
They pronounced her dead
a few minutes ago in the ER.
I am so sorry.
Oh, no.
Not Emma.
No.
She died?
Yes.
Emma's dead?
She's gone?
Yes, Martin. Emma is dead.
Oh, Emma.
Emma.
Oh, God, Emma.
Oh, no.
No.
No, no. No.
Bailey.
I'm sorry about before.
You didn't need to see that.
I didn't see anything.
We both know that you did.
Now you and I are scheduled
for a whipple tomorrow.
I know that Cristina
is one of your own,
so I understand if you prefer
that I not scrub in with you.
Uh...
I won't pretend to
understand the thing you
and Cristina have going on,
but I do know that affairs
don't happen in a vacuum.
You're human and you
made a human mistake.
You did a terrible thing. It doesn't
mean you're a terrible person.
We've all heard the warnings.
And we've ignored them.
I am...
I am a widow.
I am a...
Lobby?
Lobby.
Parking lot?
Parking lot.
You know what? I forgot that
I have some charting to do,
so have a great night.
We push our luck.
Each and every
one of these items
was removed from a patient.
Christmas lights? Come on.
Where would you...
You don't want to know.
How did you...
Very, very carefully.
Okay.
It's pretty great, right?
Actually,
yeah.
Well, sometimes we
have geniuses on our table
and sometimes we have idiots.
I, for one,
am partial to the idiot.
You don't get a lion's
tooth from a genius.
We roll the dice.
Okay. Hey, here's the thing.
I do know about your exes,
and frankly, sometimes it sucks.
Okay.
And you know, I mean,
I don't like knowing,
and sometimes, you
know, it drives me crazy.
I know. So maybe
there's a reason.
There's a very good
reason that I was...
I wasn't telling
you about my exes.
I was trying to spare you.
Yeah, I understand.
You do? Yeah, I do.
Okay, 'cause I thought
we were fighting.
We totally are.
We play with fire.
Look what Daddy
got you today, Zola.
And now put your
head down. There it is.
Well. Roar.
Don't do that.
Well, you think it's
cute when Zola does it.
What is it?
If you ever cheat
on me, I'll kill you.
Okay. I mean it.
Okay. Say it.
I will never cheat on you.
You want to talk about it? No.
Okay.
It's human nature.
When we're told not
to touch something...
we usually do.
Even if we know better.
Maybe because deep down,
we're just asking for trouble.