Yeah, I said I'm sorry.
I'm just not feeling too hot.
You're sneezing. You could
do that in a movie theater.
Yeah, and I'll be in a nice
soft chair when I collapse.
I'm exhausted, babe.
Oh, come on.
We're gonna be late.
Episode Four never
comes to the big screen.
This is the pre-Lucasized
version, remember?
None of that Greedo
shooting first crap.
Go without me.
What are you talking about?
You love Star Wars.
Don't you?
Ben?
Since when?
Since just before I
started pretending I loved it.
I'm sorry. I was just
trying to be supportive.
Fine. I'll go alone.
Baby, I'm sorry. Me, too.
I'm so woozy I can hardly think.
We'll hang out at home.
No, you should go.
Did you just feel something?
Feel? Like what?
Is there an earthquake?
In New Jersey?
Oh, God. What?
I think I'm, like,
hallucinating.
Call 911.
Twenty-six year old female, gas
main exploded under her building,
she was pulled out of
the rubble after six hours.
Two surgeries for multiple
fractures and burns.
I'm thinking the broken bones
are a response to the
building falling on her head.
And the fever?
She's the only collapse victim
whose body temperature was...
Put her on antipyretics.
Already have. The
fever is holding at 104.
Fluctuating consciousness.
Can't take the case.
I don't have a team.
So hire a team.
What for? I don't have a case.
Have you even
interviewed anybody?
You test-drive a
car before you buy it.
You have sex before
you get married.
I can't hire a team based
on a 10-minute interview.
What if I don't like
having sex with them?
You've spent the last two
weeks doing absolutely nothing.
Concert is over.
In what twisted universe
does mastering Eddie Van Halen's
two-handed arpeggio technique
count as "absolutely nothing"?
Take the case, or you
will spend the next month
helping the collapse
team change bandages.
I diagnose her alone, by the end
of the day, you go away for a week.
Done.
It's not gonna work.
If he solves the
case, we cure the girl.
And prove he
doesn't need a team.
He's not gonna solve
the case. Not that fast.
Why not? Because
he needs a team.
And this will prove to him...
Wanna change his
mind about something?
You need a more convincing
argument than "you promised."
Fever?
Non-responsive to
antibiotics, antipyretics.
Fluctuating consciousness.
Go!
You talking to me?
Yes.
Imagine that the roof
of the storage closet
collapses on your
favorite floor buffer,
which then starts overheating.
Why would I have a
favorite floor buffer?
Okay.
Maybe the electrical
works got banged up in there
from stuff falling on it?
Hmm. Interesting.
Brain damage, leading to
hypothalamic dysregulation.
Nah.
If you're brought in covered in
rubble, it's all about the MRIs.
We'd have seen that. Come
on! Gotta earn that fiver.
Or stuff leaked in the
holes, messing it up.
Lacerations lead to
multiple portals for infection.
Bacterial would have
responded to the antibiotics.
It's too high for viral.
Parasites or fungus is possible.
Or maybe lupus?
My grandma has lupus.
Okay. Auto immune, I'll run a
lupus panel. Infection fits best.
A complete history
would be helpful,
which leads to the
worst part of the job,
dealing with the
floor buffer's family.
We talked every couple of weeks.
But Ben would
know better than I.
No farms, no travel
anywhere weird.
You get that, Dr. Buffer?
No travel, no farm.
The file says she was sick
before the building collapsed.
Yeah, I figured
it was just a cold.
Why, do you think it's related?
Her being sick and
her being sick? Often is.
She was unconscious
when I found her.
We'd been fighting.
I just want to...
Just tell me she's
gonna be okay.
I'm not even sure if
you're gonna be okay.
We're gonna make her all better.
Show off.
You ought to be nicer to people.
Where are we going?
You know how the laughter
of little children is infectious?
Well, parasites and
fungi are even more so.
We're gonna find out which one
is making her brain bubble over.
Where, the building?
EPA's doing that job
for us, they say it's clean.
Which means we're making a
pilgrimage to Castle Blackberry.
Her name's Bradberry. I
should've asked them for keys.
No need, I'm sure we can
find a large rock somewhere.
I'm not breaking into
somebody's house.
I got principles.
I got some loose change
here says you don't.
I'm not doing this
for less than $50.
Where's the restaurant?
What restaurant?
The one you said you
were taking me to for lunch?
Oh! Uh...
This one's homier.
Dibs on the cold pizza!
I'm sure it looked
easier on YouTube.
Oops!
Yeah. You don't need a team.
You can't even get
arrested without company.
You're right. Only one solution,
never replace them, ever.
Do you need help?
Yeah, yeah. Patronize
the poor cripple.
Ow.
Let me get that. I got it.
Will you just let me get it?
I'll check the bedroom.
There's some interesting
mold on the windowsill here.
It's gonna take me a while.
I'll cover the bathroom.
She had a secret diary.
Is there any other kind?
What are you doing?
There's a sale on liquid Tide.
If you're broke,
I could lend you a tiny
bit of the money I owe you.
No, no. I wouldn't put
you in that position.
What does the diary say?
Basically a list of her
sexual encounters,
boys, girls, vibrating
appliances...
If it was, you'd be
quoting, not summarizing.
It's just a parade
of sad banalities.
"I can hardly get out
of bed. Feeling blue."
Then, three months ago, turns
into a parade of happy banalities.
"It's starting to turn the
corner. Job's looking up."
We can stop swabbing. Her
clichés are getting healthier.
Or she's less depressed.
Aren't there pills that do that?
Anti-depressants
don't cause fever.
Not on their own. But the ER didn't
know she was on MAO inhibitors,
so they gave her Demerol,
that's a nasty combo.
So, all you have to
do is convince this kid
that his girlfriend
had a secret doctor,
and a secret stash
and a secret life.
It's been a while since a patient
took a swing at you. Can I watch?
I only have to
convince the mother.
Actually, I don't have
to convince anyone.
This is total crap. If she was
seeing a psychiatrist, I'd know.
If she was on drugs, I'd know.
Mrs. Bradberry, please sign the
forms so we can start the dialysis.
But why anti-depressants?
I don't understand.
Mrs. Bradberry, please sign the
forms so we can start the dialysis.
Stop saying that.
Dr. Buffer, what is going
on? What aren't you telling us?
He's a janitor?
More significantly,
a blabbermouth.
House, shut up.
I am very sorry how Dr. House handled
this. It is completely unforgivable.
Except if he's right.
Dialysis will filter her blood.
There's nothing to filter.
Save her life.
She wasn't depressed.
I'm miserable around Ben.
Not me, I like
Ben. February 12th.
Either she's depressed or
she just thinks you're a jerk.
Neither suggests that
you should be the one
directing her medical treatment.
Does the diary say my
daughter's taking these drugs?
No, but medically...
Did you find drugs
in their home?
She's probably hiding
them in her purse.
I thought it'd be rude to go searching
under a thousand tons of rubble.
This was months
ago. We were in a fight.
It doesn't mean she's depressed
and it doesn't mean
she doesn't love me.
Fine. Maybe the
diary proves nothing.
On the other hand, half the
country's on anti-depressants
and it fits her
symptoms perfectly.
No ring on your daughter's finger
means you make the decisions.
I'm not sure that I know
her well enough anymore.
You really wanna risk her
life on how well he knows her?
Wilson, you idiot.
Listen carefully, and
no one will get hurt.
You must follow
the instructions.
Any attempt to contact the FBI or
other law enforcement agencies,
or Cuddy, will
be met with the...
And a large Coke, no ice.
Give it back. What happened?
Did someone kidnap your guitar,
a $12,000 1967
Flying V or something?
Where'd you hide it?
I'm flattered you would
consider me this bold and brilliant.
Yeah. It takes a...
It takes a criminal mastermind
to pull off a heist from an unlocked,
unguarded room down the hall.
What do you want?
Me? Nothing.
But I'm sure the kidnapper
wants whatever a kidnapper wants.
To see you interview five to seven
well-qualified fellowship candidates.
I don't need a team.
You were bouncing
ideas off a janitor.
And solved the case!
Hi. I'm Dr. Cuddy.
If you can hear what
I'm saying, blink once.
You can't talk right now. You
have a tube down your throat.
And try not to move your head.
You've been in a terrible accident,
but it looks like you will
have no permanent injuries.
You've had a bad
fever, but it's gone now.
I've been here the whole time,
honey. Okay? I'm not leaving.
This is very important.
I need you to blink
one for yes, twice for no.
Were you seeing a psychiatrist?
Were you on MAO
inhibitors, the anti-depressant?
Megan, it's okay. It doesn't
matter, okay? I love you.
Honey? Honey, what's wrong?
Megan, are you all right?
What's happening?
Are we upsetting her?
Heart is beating too fast.
Get the family out of here.
Megan?
Megan! Charging to 200.
Meg. Meg! Megan!
Clear!
We shocked her back into sinus
rhythm, but she's still tachycardic.
Fascinating. Equally
fascinating is, why are you here?
I was gonna leave you
alone if you won the bet.
But you lost.
I explained the fever, which
is all we were talking about.
She confirmed the
anti-depressants.
Go bet with someone else if you
wanna explain the heart problems.
She confirmed them by winking.
Maybe there was a
cute guy across the room.
She got better when I treated
her. Even I'm not that cute.
Two unrelated symptoms.
Just a coincidence?
Or you're grasping at straws
to avoid admitting you
can't do this on your own.
Fine.
What explains the fever
and persistent tachycardia?
It could be anything.
Endocarditis?
No. Fever, no infection.
Um... Keep going,
you're doing great.
You win.
I don't believe you. I'm
not gonna play this game.
Just give me the damn résumés.
And my guitar.
I don't have it.
Although I did hear some plangent
strumming from under that couch earlier.
Wow.
This kidnapper isn't
just bold. He's diabolical.
I guess he realized he probably
shouldn't give it back to you
until after you've
had the interviews.
Huh!
You didn't write anything.
So, what you're saying is, you
didn't find that one big explanation
'cause there isn't one. Clever.
Well, let's just say your anti-depressant
theory does explain the fever.
What about the heart? And
don't say a building fell on her.
Okay.
A structure
collapsed... Shut up.
Come on, it fits. Crushed musculature
releases potassium, causes V-tach.
You'd think she'd get crush
syndrome after she was crushed,
not two days later.
Microvascular occlusions, takes
that long for the blood to reperfuse.
She'd have a baggy
heart. Echo it to confirm.
Is crush syndrome good or bad?
Does it sound good?
I mean, compared to the
other things it could be.
There are no other
things it could be.
Then why are you testing her?
Excellent question.
What? What is it?
The heart's fine.
Why is she sweating?
Her fever's back.
Why would her fever be back?
I can't say.
You don't know?
Well, I know. I just can't
say, 'cause you'll hit me.
Let's discuss this
in front of witnesses.
The DT's?
So, she's an alcoholic now?
Her first fever was from the
medication for her depression.
Or you're wrong.
The second fever was from the
self-medication for depression.
This is insane.
You don't think I would have
noticed her being constantly drunk?
You were practically living with
Sylvia Plath. You didn't notice that.
Tone it down or I will hit you.
Fine. I'll do liver
enzyme tests.
Liver enzymes can also be
elevated from musculoskeletal trauma.
They'd be there whether she
had a drinking problem or not.
They don't know that.
Just pretend to confirm.
What's the treatment?
She's not an alcoholic.
Hair of the dog. IV alcohol.
Taper it off after a few days.
She's sick and
traumatized and half dead,
you wanna make her drunk?
Just do it.
You can't do this. We lived
together. We were gonna have kids.
You barely even know her.
Apparently, neither did you.
Hello?
Hi, can I speak to
Trevor Kaufman?
Yo, yo. This is Trev. What up?
This is Dr. Gregory House. Can
you come in tomorrow to interview?
House? Are you serious? Awesome!
Hey, I got the House interview!
Oh, look at me, I got
the House interview!
Shut up! Would you shut up?
- I'm so cool.
Hey, give me the phone back.
Give the phone
back, seriously, man.
I got a page.
No, you didn't.
They called a code.
No, they didn't.
You got a page, but not from us.
Did you ever see
Raid on Entebbe?
Yeah.
In the end they
release the hostages.
How's that working for you?
The Ugandans played fair.
They didn't move the
hostages on the Israelis.
Once again, I'm in awe of the
kidnapper's tactical brilliance.
What is El Fuego Del Amor,
and why do you need 10 of them?
It's a telenovela.
I'm learning Spanish.
Say adiós.
Are you erasing my TiVo?
House, not the season finale!
I don't negotiate
with terrorists.
I smoke them out
of their hidey-holes.
Do you know what terrorists
do when you don't negotiate?
They terrorize.
Bring it on.
Fever's down. Sweating is
abated. Heart's working fine.
I guess House was right, again.
That's good news, right?
It is good news.
So, what does this
mean, she's an alcoholic?
There's no other explanation?
No, sorry.
It doesn't make any sense.
Dr. Cuddy, she's doing this
thing with her mouth again.
It's been on and off for
the last couple of hours.
Is she trying to talk?
No.
I think she's screaming.
Morning.
Huh!
Where did you come from?
Apes, if you believe
the Democrats.
I heard you were there
when I was proven right.
The alcohol treatment took
away the heart and fever problems.
Yes, I was also there when
you were proven wrong.
She'd been silently
screaming for two hours.
Amylase and lipase are through
the roof. She has pancreatitis.
IV alcohol could
cause pancreatitis.
Okay.
You're not gonna argue with me?
No.
You think I'm right?
Why not? No.
That's not really a
yes or no question.
Which is why I'm
not answering it.
If it's not the IV
alcohol, it's gotta be...
Not interested.
If I'm wrong,
she's gonna die.
Are you sure you're
still Dean of Medicine?
I'm not interested in arguing because
I'm not interested in enabling you.
You need someone to bounce
ideas off of. You need a team.
Don't follow me.
MAO inhibitor caused the fever,
alcohol caused the pancreatitis,
alcohol withdrawal
caused the V-tach.
Your logic is irrefutable.
You're wrong.
Well, who are you gonna
believe? A classic toy,
or a woman who, if she had
any confidence in her ideas,
wouldn't feel the need to
distract you with a water bra?
Are you really just gonna
treat the pancreatitis?
Are you here to enable me?
I don't want her to die
because you're stubborn.
Wow. So, you can enable
and rationalize at the same time.
Guess you are still
Dean of Medicine.
If you're right, then this guy,
who's not an ass, who's not a
workaholic, who's not a sociopath,
has somehow missed both her
depression and severe alcoholism.
Yes. Imagine that, a
couple with secrets!
Why would she lie?
Okay, alcoholism, you
don't wanna advertise, but...
If you're right, there'd be an
abnormality on the pancreas.
At least do an MRI to confirm.
Oh, my God!
This guy means business.
Or guys, could be multiple guys.
Or gal. Who knows?
All I can say is, this
reeks of boldness.
I am not hiring a team.
You ever tighten a guitar
string really, really slowly?
Past the point it can
handle the strain?
It makes this weird sound,
almost like a scream.
I thought this was gonna be fun.
I mess with you, you mess
with me, eventually you give in.
But you've shown a startling lack
of humor, which got me thinking.
Oh, God.
What's the real reason
you won't hire a team?
I told you. I don't need a team.
Then hire three people and
let them sit on their asses.
That wouldn't be right.
Three years ago, you hired
a team. What's changed?
I've become a man of
principle. I've gotten smarter.
What answer will
make Socrates shut up?
What's changed
is, you hired a team.
You connected with a
team, you worked with a team
and you lost a team.
Damn.
There's no abnormalities
in her pancreas.
You fall in love. You get married.
50% chance it'll end in misery.
Hiring employees
can be even tougher,
because you know,
eventually, they're gonna leave.
There's increased T2
signal on her hepatic capsule,
if you know what I mean.
You got hurt. Get over it.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
my patient's about to start
bleeding out of her mouth and anus.
Internal bleeding.
Not anymore. Now
it's all over the place.
Why are you here?
That's my patient down there.
You're here because I'm here.
I am done enabling you.
I know.
The alcohol didn't cause the
pancreatitis, the internal bleeding did.
The question is, what
caused the internal bleeding?
I hate myself.
You do know that the patient
had a building lying on her.
Four days ago.
Bleeding can start at any time.
She's bleeding from
five different sites.
Do you think they
synchronized their watches?
She got Warfarin
after her hip surgery.
It's designed to mess
with bleeding patterns.
Fever, heart and bleeding.
Three problems, three
completely different explanations.
She must be the unluckiest
woman in the world.
I only cling to
this crazy theory
because it's been proven
right every step of the way.
Each treatment worked.
Yes. She looks
perfectly healthy.
This much bleeding is a
symptom of something more.
And you need a team,
because you're wrong
and you're gonna
kill this woman.
If I had a team, this
patient would be dead,
because they'd be
here instead of me
and they wouldn't notice the
size of this woman's uterus.
Hi. How's it going?
Mind if I observe?
Got a big room up top with
a big window just for that.
Stop that.
You wanna look at vaginas,
there are websites for that.
You think I'm made of money?
Can you get him out of here?
Enlarged uterus means that
she was recently pregnant.
She's a good liar, but I doubt she
can hide a baby from her boyfriend.
Scraping in the uterus indicates
that she had an abortion,
and nothing in
her medical history.
Only one reason
to hide an abortion.
Boyfriend wants
babies, she doesn't.
She's bleeding everywhere.
Unless the guy was performing
an abortion with a shotgun...
Stop enabling him.
It's not the abortion,
it's what she did after.
The boyfriend would
have noticed condoms,
he would notice abstinence.
He would not notice the pill,
which means I don't need a team!
Hey, where's your
mother in common law?
Dr. House, this
is Doug McMurtry.
His girlfriend was
working with Megan when...
She's dead?
She passed this morning.
Well, then why
are you still here?
I need the old lady's
consent to do some treatment.
What'd you find out?
I wish I could tell you, but
since you're not legally related...
What the hell did you find out?
Your girlfriend had an abortion.
See why I didn't tell you?
I'd be insane to also tell
you that she's on the pill.
No, she's not.
If they'd known she was on it,
they wouldn't have given her a
blood thinner after her hip surgery.
The combination
caused the bleeding.
It's good news. It's treatable.
Just give her Tamoxifen, which
is normally a breast cancer...
That's not true.
We wanna have kids.
Hmm.
See, I already
did the blood tests.
And either she lied to
you, or her blood lied to us.
Tell Megan I'm glad
she's gonna be okay.
How're you doing?
I got cancer.
You're on an oncology
ward. Everybody's got cancer.
You want sympathy,
you ought to try
the hardly-anything-
wrong-with-me ward.
In fact, why don't I take
you there right now?
How sick are you? Can you walk?
Are you a doctor?
Admitted today. First day
of a five-day chemo course.
Yeah, you can walk.
Come on, let's go.
Does Dr. Wilson
know you're here?
Well, if he didn't, this
would be really stupid.
'Cause then he wouldn't
know where his patient was.
He might think he'd
been kidnapped.
Now the room upstairs
is bigger, it's got cable,
better-looking
sponge bath nurses.
If you feel sick, you call
me directly, not Dr. Wilson.
He's getting his last
set of hormone shots.
You put her on Tamoxifen?
An anticancer drug?
It blocks estrogen receptors.
Does it also block breathing,
and kidney function?
She's crashing.
Doesn't mean I was wrong.
This is Dr. Marvin. We're bringing
this patient over now. Thanks.
Anybody here a doctor?
Kidney failure, spiking
fever, breathing difficulties.
Any theories?
Am I in an M. Night
Shyamalan movie?
You're House, right?
Okay, I assume you know me
because I once insulted you,
your patient, or your relatives.
If that's so, I apologize.
I was drunk that day.
Patient initially presented
with crush injuries.
I know you because
Dr. Cuddy issued a memo.
Telling you to
cooperate fully with me?
No.
Figured that was a long shot.
Anybody here not get that memo?
Fungal infection.
Don't you have a patient?
She shot herself in the
leg while high on meth.
Wouldn't hurt her to be
in pain for a little while.
Fungal infection would
be in her eyes by now.
Haemophilus?
Doesn't explain
the remitting fever.
You've heard that I've
got a job opening, right?
I just care about people.
Acute Respiratory
Distress Syndrome.
ARDS doesn't explain
anything, except the breathing.
If you care about people,
you're not getting the job.
I was lying. Crush syndrome.
Doesn't explain the breathing.
What was the problem with ARDS?
Only explained the breathing.
The crush syndrome?
It didn't explain the breathing.
Are you a fan of symmetry?
Sure. Weird.
'Cause your eyes are lopsided,
and by eyes I mean breasts.
ARDS and crush syndrome,
both reactions to severe trauma.
Why can't she have both?
Because...
Because then, there's
nothing we could do.
Boy, you remind me of someone.
Send me your résumé.
I'll put it on top of the pile
that I'm never gonna look at.
I couldn't leave.
You don't seem like the type of
person who would give up on giving up.
I love her.
You loved somebody.
Somebody who didn't
drink, wanted to have babies
and wasn't miserable.
I know she lied, but...
What are you doing? Why are
you saying these things to him?
The woman you love doesn't
exist. This woman is dying.
She has Acute Respiratory Distress
Syndrome and crush syndrome.
Her body's basically giving up.
We can keep her on supported
dialysis and hope for the best.
Never mind. She
has a lump in her arm.
Does that mean you're wrong?
Well, that'd be good
news for you guys.
We'll know after a biopsy.
Which patient is that?
Megan... House's patient.
Yeah.
Didn't you get my memo? Sure.
Got both memos.
Both.
And the second memo
said to ignore the first memo.
Yeah, seemed odd.
I did an MRI and...
Of course you did.
What'd you find?
It's kind of freaky.
She's got growths
all over the place.
She's got tumors?
Not exactly.
The growths are
eosinophilic granulomas.
They are usually
from allergic reactions,
so I'm putting her on steroids.
Allergy to what? She
doesn't have allergies.
We don't know.
Unfortunately, the only
drug she's had enough of
to have this kind of
reaction is cephalosporin.
And why is that unfortunate?
'Cause she was on
it two months ago.
That's what you mean, right?
She took it for strep throat
so she can't be allergic to it.
It would seem so.
What is this
hospital doing to her?
She has had three
separate medical disasters,
and now she's dying of an
allergy she can't possibly have?
Mr. Lee. I just have to check...
Sam? Are you okay?
What are you doing here?
I was taking a nap.
Where's my patient?
You stole my patient.
You kidnapped my guitar.
Give him back.
Only when you give her back.
It's a she?
It's certainly not a dude.
It's a guitar. You
took a human being!
Now who doesn't
have a sense of humor?
I'm monitoring the guy remotely.
What, are you listening for
the distant sound of screaming?
The nurses know to call me.
They don't know who he is!
His name's right there on the
chart. Now go away. I'm working.
They give him the wrong meds, who
the hell knows what's gonna happen?
House!
Bad things would happen.
He's in Room 318.
What are you giving Megan?
Megan? Nothing.
Nothing? What's going
on? What's wrong with her?
Her? Nothing.
Then why are you
giving her drugs?
Just some amphetamines
to wake her up.
Everything could be
explained by her lying to you.
The anti-depressants,
the drinking, the pill,
until now.
Now she's allergic to something
the chart says she's not allergic to.
That's not her lying, that's the chart
lying, which doesn't make sense.
You know Liz Masters?
No. Yeah, she worked with Megan.
That was her boyfriend
you met outside the morgue.
Mmm.
This is her chart.
She's on MAO inhibitors for
depression. She's on the pill.
She had an abortion a month ago,
and she's allergic
to cephalosporin.
What's going on here? What,
are you saying this isn't Megan?
Yes.
Ben?
Since when?
Since right before I
began pretending I loved it.
She's the same size as Megan,
the same build, the same hair color.
They were both horribly
injured, unrecognizably.
EMT teams do not second-guess
family members' identifications
at accident scenes.
No. Liz died
yesterday. This isn't Liz.
I know Megan.
I know her hair, I know
her hands, I know her smell.
What's your name?
Liz.
Oh, God!
Your girlfriend
never lied to you.
Oh, God.
I did it all by myself, Mommy.
You talking to me?
Go away.
I did it all by myself, Mommy.
How'd you know it was me?
There's a scent given
off by wounded feral cats.
You were wrong.
I got everything right,
just treated the wrong...
They had a good relationship.
He couldn't even identify her.
And you were wrong about
needing a team. She almost died.
So, I almost need a team.
You were content with your
"people are idiots" theory.
But Cameron would
never have accepted
that this guy knew nothing
about the love of his life.
And as soon as you claimed
it was multiple conditions,
Foreman would have done
anything to prove you wrong,
and then Chase would have
done anything to prove you right.
Any one of them would
have solved this days ago.
Hire a team.
I don't care how you do it.
Just do it.
Sometimes I am wrong.
I have a gift for observation.
For reading people and situations,
but sometimes I am wrong.
This will be the longest
job interview of your life.
I will test you in ways
that you will often consider
unfair, demeaning and illegal.
And you'll often be right.
Look to your left.
Now look to your right.
By the end of six weeks,
one of you will be gone,
as will 28 more of you.
Wear a cup.