.
- Your shoe laces.
Those are gang colors.
- What are you, a cop?
- I used to be.
But now I'm a doc.
- Doctor Hammer.
- What brought you back
to Chicago?
- Home, sweet home.
- What made you stay?
- Same.
- And what's up
with you and her?
- Let's go.
- All right, let's get her CT.
- Dr. Cooper?
What happened
with your patient?
Is this due to
the cardiac output monitor?
- I want to come back to Med.
- Dr. Cooper is our biggest
booster of the Vas-COM,
and I suspect it's because
he's getting kickbacks.
- You're saying you want me
to be your spy?
- Are you in...
or out?
- Dr. Halstead.
Thank you.
Glad to catch you
on your way in.
I did some digging
on the Open Payments website.
Turns out, Dr. Cooper
has gotten some very fat perks
since he started boosting
the Vas-COM.
He has also received
more than a few
"consulting fees"
from Vasik Labs
and other companies.
- And you think
they're hidden bribes
for promoting the device.
- Yeah, illegal kickbacks.
We have to establish
that they are bribes
tied to the sale of the device.
Look, I can't report
Dr. Cooper, ruin his career,
unless I know for sure.
- I could stop
by the ICU today,
see what the Critical Care docs
are saying about the Vas-COM
and why they're using it
so frequently.
- See if it's Cooper's doing.
I like that.
Uh, Dr. Halstead.
Be careful.
- Maggie!
- Morning, Dr. Taylor.
- I, um--
I found this in my locker.
Was it you?
- Yeah, I didn't mean to--
- No...thank you.
- Happy birthday.
And don't worry.
No one else knows.
- Good, 'cause I don't like
to make a fuss.
- And of all the days
to come in early.
What are you doing here,
anyway?
You shift doesn't start
for another two hours!
- Decided to start
rounding early.
I want to stay two steps
ahead of my competition.
No, actually,
I want to crush them...
- And win some brownie points
with Dr. Archer.
- Atta girl.
Oh, and I know that you
probably have other plans,
but if you don't,
can I take you out for a drink?
- Okay, I might be down
for a drink.
I'll let you know.
- Okay.
- And that's when I realized
that standing out
was way better
than trying to fit in.
So next time
them little girls
start runnin'
their little mouths
making fun of your height,
you don't throw hands.
You just look at them
and say...
- Don't hate me
'cause you ain't me.
- That's right!
- Thank you, Dr. Scott, really.
- Hey, it's my pleasure.
- Okay, just try to calm down,
please.
- Y'all take care.
- Please, I'm scared. Please.
Oh, my God, are you a doctor?
Please help me, please help me.
I don't want to die, please.
- It's okay, it's all right.
What happened?
- Said she took some pills.
Sleeping pills, I think.
Her name is Krista Valdez.
- Hey, Treatment 4.
- All right, calm down.
- Sorry, I'm so sorry.
- It's all right.
Just slow your breathing.
- Okay.
- Okay?
So you say you took
some sleeping pills.
You gotta tell me how many
and how long ago.
- Uh, I don't know.
12, maybe 14,
about ten minutes ago.
- Grab the activated charcoal.
- Got it.
And I'll grab an NG setup.
.
- Oh, God.
- You got that charcoal ready?
- Right here.
- All right. Okay, Krista,
I need you to drink that down
slow and steady, all right?
It'll help absorb the drugs.
There you go.
Uh-huh.
- Oh, God, I can't.
- All right, come on.
Give it one more try.
You got it.
There you go.
Yup. See?
- NG tube.
- I'm sorry, I can't do it.
- It's all right.
It's all right.
Listen, I'm gonna
take this tube, I'm gonna stick
it down your nose,
and into your stomach,
give you the charcoal that way.
- No, just wait--
Am I gonna die?
Because this was a mistake.
Okay? I swear.
- Listen, you did
the right thing by coming in.
We got you.
Now, hang tight.
You're gonna feel this,
but it won't last a second.
- Okay.
- Page Dr. Charles.
- Mm-hmm.
- Hey, Trish.
Orders for L3.
I was wondering,
is it me,
or does it seem like we've
been seeing the Vas-COM
used a lot more frequently
as of late?
- Oh, yeah.
Dr. Cooper can't stop
talking about it.
- Really?
What's he, uh, saying?
- Heard my name.
You looking for me?
- Matt, hey.
Yeah, actually.
Was, uh,
curious to learn more
of the benefits
with the Vas-COM device.
- It's a pretty remarkable
product, really.
In fact, since we've
started using it,
we've seen an 8% reduction
in mortality.
- Phew.
8%?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, that's impressive.
But, uh, how exactly
do you draw
a correlation to the device?
- Oh, it's pretty simple math,
really.
So when you're monitoring flow,
your patient is,
more often than not,
in the correct fluid balance,
and so that alone
has dramatically reduced
ICU acute kidney injury rates,
which we know is directly
correlated to prognosis.
It's not a perfect science.
But the Vas-COM's the
only new variable
we've introduced, so...
- Pretty straight line.
- Yeah, yeah.
And the other devices
on the market
can't even hold a candle.
Vas-COM is a bit more pricey.
- Oh, yeah?
- Sure, of course.
But, I mean, cost/benefit,
am I right?
Oh, listen.
Sorry, I gotta run.
I can send you more info
if you're interested.
- Yeah, please do!
- Hey, Nancy,
have you seen Dr. Halstead?
- Uh, not for a while, no.
- Okay.
Oh! Dr. Marcel.
- Hey, morning, Ms. Goodwin.
- I've been meaning
to touch base with you
about a new program
the hospital is setting up.
- Uh-huh.
- Totally voluntary,
but attendings can sign up
as advisors to residents.
- Advisors?
- You know, meet regularly,
offer counsel
if they have any questions
or concerns.
Just, you know, see them
through their residency.
- Oh, uh, well, listen.
That sounds like
a great program.
I just, uh--you know,
I wouldn't want to leave
anyone hanging, you know?
- Leave anyone hanging how?
You planning on leaving Med?
- No, no.
Nothing like that.
Just, uh, like to keep
my dance card open, is all.
- Mm.
- But, hey,
let me think about it.
- You know, you're the fifth
"Let me think about it"
this week.
Thank you.
- Hey! Hey, you okay?
- Um, uh, just
a little light-headed.
- Come on, let's sit down.
- You know, I've got this, uh,
this gadget, let's--
- Oh, blood sugar's a bit high.
- Yeah, it's been like that
all week.
Maybe I'll stop
by Endocrinology,
see if Dr. Yang
can squeeze me in.
- Okay, just as a precaution.
You know?
- Yeah, yeah.
- Hey, you gonna be okay?
- I'm gonna be fine, thank you.
Hey.
- I didn't get far.
Cooper caught me off-guard.
Gave me his hard sales pitch.
I gotta say, this guy's good.
- So if he's ever confronted,
he can defend everything
he's doing as legit.
Do you think
he suspected anything?
- No, but if he is
who you say he is,
confession's gonna be tough.
- Incoming!
Who's free?
- Oh, go, go.
And swing by later?
- Yeah.
I'm on it.
- I got this.
- More the merrier, I guess.
- After you.
- What do we got?
- 17 year-old male,
passed out at a skate park.
BP 100/20, heart rate 70.
Blood sugar was 200.
Gave a liter of normal saline
in the ambo.
- What's your name?
- Brandon.
- Brandon, I'm Dr. Hammer.
- I'm Dr. Halstead.
You got a history of diabetes?
- No, uh, no, I don't.
Did someone call my mom?
- Oh, cops called her.
She's en route.
- Brandon, you feel
stable enough
to switch beds yourself?
- Uh yeah, yeah I'm fine.
- Brandon?
Oh, my God.
Are you okay, honey?
- I'm fine, Mom, really.
- What were you doing
at the skate park?
You were supposed
to be studying.
- I know.
- It is not good
to exert yourself like that.
The stress.
He has Addison's disease.
Was this another crisis?
- No, it's his blood sugar.
But is he on steroids
as a part of his regimen?
- Yes, Prednisone.
- Prednisone can cause
high blood sugar
if he's getting too much.
- He's not.
I manage
all of Brandon's medications.
I take care of everything.
What he eats, steps per day.
We're very careful.
Are you sure you're all right?
- Yes, Mom, I'm fine.
- Well, if we're sure
medication isn't the cause,
let's get an A1c test.
That'll give us an idea
of his blood sugar levels
over a period of time.
- It'll help us determine
whether his body's
making insulin.
There's a chance that he
could have developed diabetes.
- Oh, God.
No.
Brandon's supposed to be part
of an Addison clinical trial
for a subcutaneous
medication device.
- Mom, please.
Diabetes is
an exclusionary factor.
- It's okay, Mom.
There's gonna be other trials.
- Let's not jump the gun
just yet.
There may be
another explanation.
- We'll circle back around
as soon as we have something.
We're gonna figure this out.
- So, Krista,
Dr. Scott's telling me
that this is the first time
that you find yourself
in a situation like this.
Is that right?
- Oh, my God.
Yes.
It was such a stupid mistake.
I had been drinking,
so I wasn't in my right mind,
and as soon as I took
the pills, I regretted it.
- When you say that you
weren't in your right mind,
what do you mean by that,
exactly?
- Um...
I got into an argument
with my mom,
and I just sort of... lost it.
I don't even know why I
called her in the first place.
We don't even have
a relationship, so...
- I'm sorry to hear that.
- Yeah, I totally overreacted.
So how much longer
do I need to be here?
I just--I have a work trip
next week.
I'm headed to the Congo,
and I just have so much
to take care of.
- The Congo, wow.
What kind of work do you do?
- I work for UNICEF.
I'm a human rights attorney.
I act as a negotiator,
helping to free child soldiers.
- Wow. That's impressive.
- You know what?
That is truly admirable.
Really.
I imagine, pretty stressful,
too.
- No, I have it--
I have it really easy.
These kids, the things
that they're forced to see,
forced to do--
Some of them are as young
as five years old.
Trust me, we all live
really charmed lives
in comparison.
Just--listen, I would
really like to be discharged
as soon as possible, so...
do you have any more tests
to run or--
how much longer do I
need to be here?
- I want to give you
another liter of fluid,
you know,
make sure you're hydrated.
We'll talk after that.
- You should rest a bit,
and uh, we'll be back.
Nice to meet you, Krista.
- Oof.
Child soldiers?
She's seen
some horrible things.
- Oh, yeah.
No doubt.
I mean, I think we're looking
at a mix of PTSD,
chronic depression,
just general burnout, you know?
- Yeah, she seems
genuinely regretful, though.
You think this is
the wakeup call she needed?
Ending up in the hospital
like this?
- I think she wants
to believe that.
I'm not remotely sold.
Without--without an outlet,
she's very likely
to self-harm again.
- We can't just let her
walk out of here then.
- You know, hopefully
Krista will admit herself
to in-patient psych,
but we gotta get her there.
- A bag of saline
will buy us an hour.
- Stevie.
- Brandon's A1c results?
- Yep.
Blood sugar's been normal.
- So no diabetes.
I guess he could be
hyperthyroid?
- Yeah, I thought about that,
but all of his thyroid labs
are normal.
- What about pancreatitis?
- He's got no pain.
His amylase and lipase
are normal too.
I think the obvious answer
is right in front of us.
- You mean his medicine.
- Yeah.
- You think this is
Munchausen's by proxy.
- Maybe she's giving him
a little extra
to keep him sick.
- I don't know.
Feels like a reach.
- Is it?
You said so yourself.
She's incredibly involved.
A bit too involved,
don't you think?
I mean, 17's a little old
for Mom to be doling out
your pills, no?
- Teens aren't exactly
the most reliable
when it comes
to taking their meds.
- Yeah, but Marie
does fit the profile.
Hovering, overly concerned--
- She cares about her kid!
- Look, if you have
another explanation...
We owe it to Brandon
to get to the bottom of this.
Without a competing theory,
we at least have to explore
the possibility.
- Dr. Archer, Dr. Marcel.
MVC with a motorcycle incoming.
- We're out of beds.
- Hybrid OR.
Taylor, with me.
- Second victim's
right behind us.
- I got this.
- Sean Ritner,
a 26 year-old male,
motorcycle creamed
by a car at the intersection.
Intubated in the field.
GCS 3T, BP 190/60,
heart rate 130.
Significant blood loss
in the field.
Placed a tourniquet and put him
in a cardboard splint,
but his limb's pretty mangled,
and he's shocky.
- Trigger MTP.
On my count.
- We're going to Hybrid OR.
What have we got?
- Oh, my God.
- 38 year-old female.
Unrestrained driver.
Struck a motorcycle
while crossing
the intersection.
Couple scrapes and bruises,
but no focal complaints other
than some minor back pain.
- I didn't see him!
I tried to swerve,
but he came out of nowhere.
- Okay, don't worry.
We're gonna take
good care of you.
John, let me get a bed
in here.
Nice and easy.
Here we go.
Line it up right here.
There it is.
All right, guys, on me.
One, two, three.
- I want you to breathe
for me now.
- Okay.
- Deep breaths.
There you go.
Okay, clear breath sounds
bilaterally.
- Is he gonna be all right?
He's not moving.
- Dr. Archer's gonna take
good care of him.
Let's just focus on you, okay?
- I suffer from anxiety.
I--I need my medication.
- Okay, we're gonna get you
a little something
to help you relax.
Half a milligram of Ativan,
please.
You feeling any pain
anywhere?
Okay.
Chest x-ray, stat.
Look at me.
What's your name?
- Mya.
- Mya, okay.
My name is Dr. Marcel.
I'm gonna take care of you,
okay?
- Okay.
.
- All right, pelvis looks good.
I gotta check his arm.
No active bleeding,
and I don't feel a pulse.
I'll need a CT angiogram
to confirm,
but I'm guessing he needs
a completion amputation.
- Amputation?
- Yeah, that's what I said.
Unless you have
a better idea.
- If the brachial artery
is out, which I suspect it is,
can't we try
to revascularize the arm
with a reverse
saphenous vein graft?
- All right, we do that
and the repair goes down,
then what happens?
The arm dies,
now he's septic,
now he might die.
- Right. Forget it.
Dumb idea.
- No, not a dumb idea.
Good decisions come
from experience,
and experience comes
from bad decisions.
Actually, you might want
to scrub in for this,
if you've got
the stomach for it.
- That'd be incredible.
Thank you, Dr. Archer.
- All right.
I'll come grab you
once the patient's prepped.
- Thank God.
So it isn't diabetes.
Then he can do the trial!
But then...
what's going on?
- Well, we haven't quite
figured that out yet.
But the most obvious answer
is usually the right one,
which brings us back
to Brandon's medication.
- I already told you, though,
I manage his medication,
so I know he's getting
the right dosage.
- Are you giving him
any other supplements?
- No, nothing.
Just his prescriptions.
- All right, well,
we're gonna send over
a social worker
to speak with you.
- A social worker?
Why?
Wait, what's going on?
- We'd like to get a better
picture of Brandon's regimen.
- Do you not believe me?
- No, it's not that.
- It's just that we've ruled
out any other causes.
- I cannot believe this!
You think I'm lying,
that I'm one of those people
that would deliberately
make their kid sick?
I would never hurt my son!
- Mom?
What's going on?
They think I'm messing
with your medication,
giving you too much.
- What? Okay, no.
She's not.
She would never do
something like that.
- Look, we're sorry
that we upset you.
We should go.
- We're only trying to help,
Brandon.
Figure out what
caused the episode.
- But you can't, can you?
That's why you're blaming me,
because of your own ineptitude.
- Mom, please--
- No, that is it.
I have had it.
I want to speak
to your supervisor.
I'm gonna report you both.
- Mom, stop!
It was me, okay?
I did it.
- What?
- It was--it was me.
I've been giving myself
the extra drugs.
- Hey, looks like
this thing's about done.
So do I need to sign
paperwork, or--
- We'll let the nurses know
about that in just a sec.
- Uh, Krista.
What you told us earlier
about your work--
it really spoke to me.
Before I became a doctor,
I was actually a cop
for, like, ten years.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Saw a lot of awful things.
- I bet.
- I had a run at one point,
where, like,
I was racking up
loss after loss,
started to feel like
what I was doing
wasn't even making
a difference.
- One of my superiors--
he encouraged me
to talk to somebody.
I didn't want to do it
at first, but...
once I finally decided
to sit in that seat
and started just letting
it all come out,
it was like a weight
came off my shoulders.
- As gratifying as a career
helping other people is,
there can be
a real emotional cost there.
You know, me?
I see a psychiatrist regularly.
You know?
And those sessions
are a lifeline for me.
I can't imagine doing this work
without them.
- Okay, look.
I do not have time
to indulge in therapy, okay?
These kids--they need someone
to fight for them.
I--no, I don't have time
to sit around
and to lick my wounds.
- You know, you characterize
self-care
as some kind of selfish act.
Right?
But truthfully, Krista, if
you don't address this stuff,
next time you hit a low,
it might not turn out
the way it did today.
- And all those kids that
you've dedicated your life to--
they won't have you around
to fight for them.
- No, but I cannot
let them down!
And it gets really hard.
It's really, really hard
to just keep going.
Look, this wasn't
the first time, okay?
It's not the first time.
- I thought that that
might be the case,
which is why what
I would really like to do
is get you checked into
our in-patient psych clinic,
just for a few days.
Help you get your bearings,
start to talk
about some strategies
to help you out
with this stuff going forward.
What do you say?
Just a few days.
We all need a break sometimes.
You know?
You just--
you can't give
what you don't have.
- Okay.
- So you took the pills
to hike your blood sugar
because you knew diabetes
was an exclusionary factor.
- You don't want
to join the trial.
- Brandon, what were
you thinking?
You could have
seriously hurt yourself.
- I'm sorry, Mom.
It's just that...
I knew you weren't
going to budge on this.
I've spent my whole life
being careful, being monitored.
I have missed out on so much.
And if I start another trial,
I'm not gonna be able
to go to college in London.
- Brandon, I think that
your mom is just concerned
that you'll have
another crisis.
- I--I get that.
But I know my body
better than anybody,
and I know I can handle it
on my own.
- I know you may not
understand this now,
but I am only doing
what is best for you.
I'm sorry, honey.
London's gonna have to wait.
You are doing the trial.
- We'll go get your
discharge paperwork ready.
- Thank you.
- I feel for that kid.
This really should be
his decision.
- Pulling a stunt like that
doesn't instill
a ton of confidence in his
ability to look after himself.
- It's a separate issue.
You heard him.
He felt desperate.
- But this
clinical trial device
could be life-changing
for Brandon.
It'll administer his doses
so that he doesn't
have to monitor himself.
Marie's giving him
more freedom in the long run.
- I think she's trying
to keep him at home.
- Yeah, well,
agree or disagree,
it's not our call, is it?
- Your mom's just signing
your discharge paperwork.
How you doing?
- This is crazy.
I'm gonna be 18
in less than six months.
My mom is--
She just doesn't get it.
- I hear you.
- What can I do?
What can I do?
- There is one thing.
- Hey, Dr. Marcel.
- Hey, Dr. Taylor.
How's it going?
- Uh, it's going.
- Yeah?
Actually, no, it's not.
Listen, you overheard
my conversation with Dr. Archer
in regard to Sean
the motorcyclist's care?
- Ah, yeah.
I caught some stuff, I think.
- I just--I can't shake
this feeling
that we still might be able
to save Sean's arm.
- Huh.
- But Archer is probably right,
right?
- Well, there's an argument
for either side, honestly,
but for my money,
I would have gone
with what you suggested.
- You would have.
- Yeah.
There's nothing dumb
about your idea.
But I have a feeling
you already know that.
We have to go upstairs?
Great.
- I just--look, I didn't
want to ruffle any feathers.
Archer's the chief of E.D.
and I'm, like, barely a doctor.
- No, actually,
you are a doctor,
and a very sharp one at that.
Look, I understand work
politics and power hierarchies,
all of that,
but the next time
you're feeling passionately
about something,
don't be afraid to stand by it.
I learned early on,
sometimes you gotta choose
between being respected
and being liked.
.
- What do you mean
you don't have a bed?
Well, then why does my tablet
say you have two?
You know what?
That's not good enough,
all right?
I just got a patient
to admit herself,
to this hospital,
to my care.
- Scott!
Scott, come here.
Ah, system is showing that
your patient, Krista Valdez,
has been occupying that room
for almost four hours now.
You said you were going
to be transferring her
to in-patient psych?
- We were, but they don't
have any beds.
- Listen, you need to start
looking around
at neighboring hospitals,
and make it snappy, please.
We've got more patients
with more problems, you know.
Can't turn the ED into a
bed and breakfast, now can we?
Ah, there she is.
My prize pupil.
I went over your chartings,
very meticulous work.
You round early today too?
I did, yes.
I wanted to get a head start.
- I tell ya,
my other residents could learn
a thing or two from you.
All right, we're about due
up in the OR.
Ready to head up?
- Uh, Dr. Archer, about that.
- Yeah.
- I'm sorry,
I should have said
something sooner,
but I still think
it's worth trying
a less aggressive approach
first,
if there's any chance
to salvage Sean's arm.
- Well, uh, I appreciate
your honesty,
but the OR's booked,
and Sean's family
has signed off,
so, uh, let's hit it.
But you did only present
one option to his family.
I also consulted Dr. Marcel.
- Did you?
Huh.
You go ahead and present
your option to the family.
Be sure to inform
them of risks,
and if they sign off,
then I'd be happy to pass
the case onto you
and Dr. Marcel,
seeing as you two
have already consulted.
Oh, and you can deliver
any potential outcomes
together as well,
good or bad.
- Everything okay?
- Yeah.
Dr. Marcel advised me
to stand by my opinion
on a case, and he's right,
I should.
I'm just--
I don't know, I'm hoping
things break my way.
- What?
What does he mean?
- Calm down, Mom.
Just let me explain.
- Mrs. Davis, please--
- Don't tell me to calm down.
- Mom.
- You told him to do this,
didn't you?
You have been after me
from the minute I got here.
- Whoa!
What's going on?
- Tell her.
- Brandon has decided to seek
counsel to become emancipated
so he doesn't have
to join the clinical trial.
- What?
- How could you do this?
How could you even
consider this?
- I'm sorry, Mom.
I'm sorry, but...
I can't do the trial.
I didn't know what else to do.
- Excuse us.
I need to talk to you.
- I can't believe you.
You are still just like
you were in med school,
always getting
in other people's business.
- Excuse me?
- Why couldn't you
just leave it alone?
- I'm trying to help
our patient.
- How?
By tearing his family apart?
You planted the idea
in his head, didn't you?
He was distraught.
I told him his options.
- At his mother's expense.
You've been judging Marie
since she walked in here.
- And you've been
defending her.
- Because I don't like seeing
that poor woman being attacked.
- Why are you making
this personal?
- I just think she deserves
someone in her corner.
- Well, news flash, Stevie,
she's not our patient.
Brandon is.
And if he wants my help,
I'm gonna advocate for him,
because that is my job.
Yours too, though you seem
to have forgotten it.
- Not a single bed?
Not even any discharges
scheduled
for the end of the day?
No, I get it.
I appreciate you checking.
Thank you.
- Any luck finding Krista
a transfer?
- I've called every hospital
with a decent psych ward
in a 50-mile radius.
They're all full
to capacity.
System's messed up.
Medical interventions
are given precedence
over psychiatric ones.
- What about relatives?
Is there a world
where we could release her
under family care
for the night,
bring her back in
for an appointment tomorrow?
- Thought about that too,
but her dad's deceased,
and she's estranged
from her mom, you know?
She's pretty damn isolated.
It's just her and her work.
- All right, fellas.
You find another hospital
to transfer Ms. Valdez to?
I need this room free now.
- We're working on it,
we're not there yet, all right?
Every psych ward
in the area is full.
- All right,
well, you know what to do.
All right, arrange for a
transfer to Bachmann Medical.
- The state hospital?
- Whoa, Dean, Dean, Dean--
Patient is extremely fragile.
Bachmann is the wrong
environment, trust me.
- The way they transfer
patients there,
with police, in cuffs--like,
the whole thing is humiliating,
traumatizing.
They treat people like perps
for seeking help.
- I get it, I get it.
I do, but--
- Do you get it?
Do you?
Because you've been
running this joint
like a drive-through car wash
since I got here.
We're supposed
to be helping people.
What the hell are
we doing here any--
Sorry.
I should have kept my cool
back there.
- Don't gotta apologize
to me.
A crappy situation.
- Just when you think you're
making in-roads, you know?
Helping somebody.
Run into red tape
or lack of resources.
It's so damn frustrating.
- You had a fair amount
of experience with bureaucracy
at your old job.
- Grew up in the same
community I was policing.
South Side, hundreds.
Too many times, I felt
like I had to betray
the people I was
supposed to be protecting.
- Hmm. Why you left?
- Part of the reason.
You're not trying
to shrink me?
- No, not trying
to shrink you, man.
- Some years ago,
my partner and I--
we responded to a call.
Stray bullet from a drive-by
hit a 14 year-old boy.
Kid was bleeding out,
shot through the thigh.
By some miracle,
I was able to hold pressure
long enough on the wound
for the paramedics to respond.
- He make it?
- Yeah, he survived.
It's from the slug
that hit him.
Man, it was the most alive,
the most useful
I felt on the force,
you know?
It's what drew me to medicine.
But days like today...
- Don't I know it.
I know it feels like
we failed her.
But the reality is,
it's not safe
for Krista to be alone
right now.
Given where we are, I think
I don't really have a choice.
I gotta call the admitting room
at State.
Now look, some good doctors
there.
I know a couple of them.
I'll call them up,
get her on their radar.
You still got a couple
of buddies on the force?
Maybe we can get them
to handle the transfer?
- Yeah, yeah, I could do that.
- All right.
What do you say we go, uh--
we go make her safe?
- Yeah.
- All right.
.
- Crockett, can I talk
to you for a sec?
- Sure.
We gotta make it quick,
though, sorry.
I'm due in the OR in a sec.
- Yeah, that's actually what
I wanted to talk to you about.
You advised Dr. Taylor to push
back against Archer today
after a treatment plan
had already been put in place.
- Uh, no, not exactly.
Dr. Taylor asked me
for my advice,
and I told her--
- You told her
to stick her neck out
and make an enemy
of the chief of the ED.
You think that
was sound advice?
- Oh, hold on, Maggie.
Dr. Taylor went to Archer
of her own accord.
And I gotta say, I admire her
for advocating for her patient.
Where's this coming from?
- As a person in a position
of influence,
I think you should be
more mindful
of the things that you say.
Your two cents--
it has consequences.
Remember that.
- Mrs. Davis?
Can I join you?
- I swear I only want
what's best for Brandon.
- I know it probably feels
like everyone's judging you
right now, but...
not me.
I see how deeply
you love Brandon,
and I admire that
more than you know.
- Brandon suffered
his first crisis
right after his father died.
My husband was killed
in a head-on collision
by a drunk driver.
- I'm so sorry.
- A few weeks
after the funeral,
Brandon started vomiting
out of nowhere.
He could barely move.
He wasn't making any sense.
We don't have
any family nearby,
I didn't know who to call,
I had just lost my husband,
and I was so scared that--
- You were gonna lose
Brandon, too.
I can see why you're
so determined to protect him.
- It's just--
the thought of him
being so far away.
If anything were
to happen to him,
and I wasn't there--
- Mrs. Davis.
I know that the prospect
of letting him go
must be terrifying.
But you've taken such good care
of Brandon all these years,
I think that you can trust
that you've shown him
how to take care of himself.
- He really is a good kid.
You must have kids of your own.
- No, no kids.
But I was always
the little girl
that wished that she had
a mom like you.
- Okay, repair's done.
Removing the vascular clamp
from the artery.
Hand me the Doppler.
- Not hearing a signal.
Just static.
There's no flow
to the wrist.
All right, we're not sunk yet.
If I can pull out the clot,
there's a chance
we can still restore
blood flow.
Let's open up the repair,
stick down a balloon,
and thrombectomize.
- Putting another quarter
in the machine.
- Wait, what do you mean
you don't have a bed for me?
- I am so sorry that
we can't accommodate you here.
Really, I am.
But we have found a bed
for you at Bachmann.
- Bachmann?
No.
No, no, no.
There's no way.
That is for people
with really serious issues.
That's...
Oh, my God.
That's like lockdown.
No, if I cannot stay here,
then I would like
to go home now, please.
- Krista, I'm really
very worried about you.
So I'm afraid that discharge
is just not an option.
You know, it's my opinion
that you are still
a danger to yourself,
and I really think
you need to be somewhere safe.
- I don't--I don't--
You know what?
You made it seem
like this was my choice.
- And you made the right choice
- No, what you both did
was lie to me.
You were always going
to commit me, weren't you?
- Krista--
- You told me
that I can stay here,
and that we were gonna figure
this out together.
You know what?
Screw you guys.
I'm out of here.
Get this out of me.
- Whoa, Krista--
- No, do not touch me!
- Hold still Krista,
you're gonna hurt yourself.
- Let me go, please!
- Restraints!
- No!
- Whoa, Krista--
- Restraints, please?
- No, please!
No, please!
No I don't want to!
No!
- Calm down.
No, please leave me alone.
- Just let her help you!
- Leave me alone!
Please leave me alone!
- Please, calm down.
- Please.
Liars!
.
- Going to London!
- Good luck at school.
- Thank you!
- Aw, man.
Marie agreed to let
Brandon skip the trial.
She said you spoke to her.
Come on.
What, you're not gonna tell me?
What'd you say?
- There you go,
sticking your nose in again.
Seriously, though, I'm sorry
that I was hard on you today.
You know I can hit
below the belt sometimes.
But it's always followed
by a healthy dose of guilt,
if that's any consolation.
- Oh, it is.
- Dr. Hammer? Your paycheck.
- Thank you.
- Don't spend it all
at one place.
- Yeah, right.
Least I'll be able
to make rent this month.
- Always was your thing.
Always loved to cry broke.
- Well, some of us didn't
get a full ride to med school.
- Well, maybe if you spent
a little less time on your hair
and a little more time
in the books...
- Hey!
How'd it go?
We were able to get a pulse.
- Looks like Sean's
gonna keep his arm.
- Really?
- Yeah, thanks to you.
- This is amazing.
- Well, let's go share
the good news
with the family, yeah?
Um, listen.
I also need to apologize.
You know, when I weighed in
this morning,
I didn't mean to, you know,
throw you into the lion's den.
Maggie said I--
- Wait, Maggie?
- Yeah, she pointed out
that I may have
put you in a bad spot
with Archer.
Maybe I did, but I--
- No, please,
if you hadn't said something,
it would have
haunted me forever.
I am so, so thankful
for your advice.
- Okay.
- As a matter of fact,
they're doing this program
with the residents.
- Yeah, I heard of it.
- Well, they haven't
paired me up with anyone yet.
Any chance you'd want
to be my advisor?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I'd like that.
- Great!
- Come on.
- Okay.
- I really appreciate
your making time
to check me out,
Dr. Yang.
- It's no problem.
I'm actually glad
you checked in when you did.
- I don't like
the sound of that.
What's up?
- Your labs show
your blood sugar
has been climbing
over the last month or so.
- Well, I haven't
changed anything.
I'm still eating healthy,
exercising,
adhering to my insulin regimen.
- Well, as you know,
sometimes the disease
can progress despite
a healthy lifestyle.
But no need to worry.
We'll adjust your meds,
add an oral that will reduce
your resistance to insulin.
Also, stress
can definitely play a part.
Are you dealing with anything
particularly taxing right now?
- Uh, come in?
Just the usual work stuff.
- Sorry to interrupt.
- No, no.
- I was just leaving.
I'll call in a prescription.
- Thank you.
- Everything okay?
- Yeah, yeah.
I'm fine.
- Ms. Goodwin,
I think we've taken
the wrong approach
with Matt Cooper,
coming at him headlong,
hoping eventually
he'll slip up, say something.
- Okay?
- If he's really on the take,
the more devices
the hospital buys,
the bigger his kickbacks,
right?
So he's gonna want as many
departments as he can get
to start using the thing.
- Right.
And he needs docs
not to just use the device,
but to shill for it.
Corruptible docs.
So I make myself
the perfect target.
- And how do you do that?
- Cry broke.
Make him think
I'd do anything for money.
- Let Cooper hook you in.
I knew you were
the right man for this job.
- Okay, gotta go.
- Dr. Taylor.
Hey!
Vanessa.
Are you leaving now?
What about the drink?
- When I confided
in you earlier,
I was silly enough to think
that it was gonna stay
between us.
But you continue to prove
you can't stay in your lane.
- Vanessa, look.
I'm sorry--
- No.
I just want you to treat me
like everyone else.
That's all I want.
- Hey, Willie,
no cuffs, all right?
I know it's protocol,
but do me a solid.
- You got it.
- How long you been doing this?
- 35 years, I don't know.
Something like that.
- How?
- You gotta hang on to those--
those good days.
You know, hang on to the wins.
That's why you got that bullet
around your neck, right?
There you go.
Really important, buddy.
I mean for me, anyway.
Gotta hang on to those wins.