Auggie has a brother
in California.
We can't tell you what
this means to Keshawn.
We can fly out,
so the boys can meet.
A chemical pregnancy?
Does your mom know?
God, no. And please
don't tell her.
He's had surgery.
I realize I shouldn't
have come back so soon.
Why do you think
you did that?
I'm the chief
of the ED. I have
a greater responsibility.
It's often the people
who are the very best,
who feel
the most inadequate.
Wouldn't do that
if I were you.
Dr. Choi.
I'm sorry.
Just had to warn you.
You're leaving
your rook exposed.
I know. I'm attempting
a gambit.
Once he takes my rook...
Knight F six!
Then you've got mate
in three. Well done.
I promise, I don't spend
all day playing games.
Hey, as far as vices go,
online Chess isn't so bad.
Good morning, Dr. Virani.
Hello.
Dr. Choi, a word?
Sure. Excuse us.
You know, you still haven't
sent me your top candidates
for the new ED position.
Right.
After your collapse
last week,
we both agreed
you needed to
lighten your load.
And I'm gonna hire someone.
I just haven't found
the perfect fit yet.
Since you're still searching,
a list of ED docs let go,
through no fault
of their own,
from a nearby
rural hospital.
Gaffney acquired
the institution
when it went bankrupt.
Whoa.
Someone you know?
Yeah, Dean Archer.
He was my senior medical
officer in the Navy.
Outstanding physician.
Taught me most of what I know.
See if you can schedule
an interview today.
And if not Dr. Archer,
I want that position filled
by the end of the week.
Yes, ma'am.
Dad? Dad.
What are you doing here?
Aren't you gonna be late
for your pod?
I've got an Uber
waiting outside.
Can you just sign this
chemistry test for me, please?
Just right there's fine.
Whoa. A "D"?
Plus.
Why are you bringing
this to me?
Isn't it your mom's week?
Dad, you know how she is.
She would take my phone,
or my iPad and just anything
that I say to her,
she'd say it's an excuse.
And what do you have
to say for yourself?
When we talked about this
a few weeks ago,
you really seemed
like you wanted
to step it up.
I know.
It's just with the...
With the pregnancy scare,
and the potential of moving.
I don't even know
if we're staying
or going, so...
Listen, I gotta go.
So, can you just...
Um, I know this has been
a stressful time, okay?
But, at least,
we got the final
custody hearing today,
so, one way or the other,
we are gonna have closure.
No more limbo.
Yep.
Owen! One more video,
and then we're taking Nana
to the airport, okay?
Hello?
Okay!
Ugh. Hey, Mom!
If we don't leave in five,
we're gonna hit traffic.
Mom?
I want you to take two bites
before we leave, okay?
What is it with everyone
in this house today? Mom?
Are you still in the shower?
Hello?
Mom?
Mom! Can you hear me?
Mom, I can't get
my video to play.
Owen, one second!
Mom, can you fix it?
Owen, do not come in here!
Stay in the living room!
Hi, yes, I found my mom
unresponsive on the floor.
I need an ambulance, now.
Mom!
Owen!
Coming through!
Oh.
Sounds like them!
Slow down,
slow down!
Slow down!
Did you spend the whole $10
that I gave you?
At least they got
some healthy options.
That's true.
Let's back this up.
I'll help him.
Okay, then. He's got it.
It's been so great
to spend the week with y'all.
We really appreciate
you making the trip.
Oh, please.
No problem.
It was our pleasure.
Keshawn, why don't you
give your brother
his goodbye present?
A present?
Yeah.
Swamp Tales. Nice.
Can we play right now?
Come on, fellas,
it's your last day together.
You really want to spend it
playing video games?
Yeah.
Have fun, guys.
You like it?
Yeah, thanks!
And I can
show you how to catch...
Dream come true for Keshawn.
He's always wanted
to find his little brother.
Yeah. When we learned
that Auggie was sick,
we just prayed that
he would be okay.
You both have done so much
for him, you saved his life.
We're just happy
he finally got a liver.
Yeah.
We love Auggie to pieces.
That's clear.
Probably why my heart
is going a mile a minute.
What?
Um, look, we don't know
how to put this.
Um. We understand
that your adoption
isn't finalized yet.
You want Auggie.
We were thinking,
wouldn't it be great if the
boys could grow up together?
I know it's an impossible
thing to ask,
but if there's any way
that you could...
No.
Maggie.
There isn't.
No. We're adopting Auggie.
And I can't believe
that you would come here
and suggest this.
No. You're right.
We're sorry.
We're grateful the boys
got a chance to meet.
Yeah. Us, too.
Natalie?
Will.
I heard your mom
was brought in.
Are you okay?
Yeah. Yeah. I'm okay.
They think she had
a heart attack.
Her troponin levels
were a bit elevated,
but they're not sure.
She's in the cath lab now.
Crockett will let me know
something soon.
And Owen? He's...
At the neighbor's house.
Good.
When I found my mom,
I tried to keep him away,
but he saw her...
Come here.
It's okay.
It's gonna be okay.
Crockett, hey.
Hey.
Morning, Will.
Your mom's coronary
arteries are clear.
No evidence of infarction.
There you go, Nat,
that's great news.
But, um,
there is global dyskinesis
and a significantly
depressed ejection fraction.
Her heart's
not pumping properly.
I just don't understand.
What's causing this?
Myocarditis?
That'd be my first guess.
Did you send cultures?
Bacterial and viral, yes.
It could also be
medication induced.
I sent a tox, too.
What about a thyroid panel
and cortisol?
Two steps ahead of you.
Look, I appreciate
the backup, Will, I do.
But I think
I got this covered.
Thank you.
Have you
had anything to eat?
Um, I don't think
I could eat right now.
Still, I think we should
get you something.
You're gonna need
your energy.
Right.
Yeah.
Um. Thanks, Will.
Of course.
Safe travels home tonight.
Thank you.
Can you believe the nerve
of those people?
Their hearts
were in the right place.
Wanting their son
to grow up with his sibling.
So, what are you saying?
You think we should just
let them take Auggie?
No. I'm saying we should
have a conversation about it.
I get that we decided that
we weren't gonna have
any kids, but this...
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
That has nothing to do
with what I'm saying.
No?
'Cause it feels like
you're looking for an out.
That's low, Maggie.
You know, I couldn't
love Auggie more
if he was my own blood.
I'm not gonna do this
with you right now.
Thanks for coming in
on short notice.
Sure.
Driving over here,
I was thinking about
the first time I saw you.
You were just a kid.
And scrawny.
Not anymore.
Missed you the last
couple reunions.
Sorry you weren't there.
I wanted to be,
but, you know, work.
Your qualifications
are excellent, obviously.
This was really
just a formality
more than anything.
Job's yours if you want it.
I appreciate that.
More than you know.
And, uh, I accept.
Matter of fact,
how about if I start today?
Today?
I figured since I'm already
credentialed in the system
and I'm here.
Yeah. Why don't you
shadow me for today?
Just to get the lay
of the land.
It's an ED.
I think I know the lay.
Oh.
But, hey, I welcome
the opportunity
to watch you in action.
Happy to have you
on board, sir.
It's Dean.
Right. Dean.
Gonna take me a minute
to get used to that.
Come on.
My baby needs help!
Someone, please!
Okay, I got it.
Miss, tell me what happened?
I tripped going down
the stairs and I
dropped her. She's...
All right. We're gonna
help your baby, okay?
Okay.
Just follow me right here.
Jim! Meet me in Two.
Why don't you put your baby
down right here, okay?
What's your baby's name?
Sarah.
She's only three months.
I need you to put
Sarah down right here.
Okay?
Maggie. What do we got?
Three-month-old,
fell out of her mother's arms,
won't wake up.
There you go,
there you go.
I got her, I got her.
Okay, okay.
Please tell me
she's gonna be okay.
This is a doll!
What?
Is this some kind of joke?
No, my baby needs help!
You have to help her! Please.
Yeah.
Hey!
We've got a situation
down in the ED.
The nurses tried to page you,
and you haven't responded.
Oh. I'm sorry about that.
I will head down there now.
Daniel, what's wrong?
The judge
just made his ruling.
Susan will be taking
my daughter out to Arizona.
Court decided
it was in her best interest.
What? Why?
I guess with my work hours,
they said that Susan,
technically,
would be home more.
They also noted that
she'd been her primary
caregiver for the majority
of her childhood.
I'm so sorry, Daniel.
Look, I know it's nothing
like her being here,
but with FaceTime and Zoom,
and your visits, you will
be a part of Anna's life.
Oh, yeah.
Definitely. Yep.
Take some time.
I'll get someone else
to see the patient.
No, no. I gotta go to work.
Take my mind off this stuff.
So, we have six
treatment rooms
and two trauma bays,
and over there, is our
state-of-the-art Hybrid OR.
Ah. I always dreamed
of putting an OR in my ED,
never could raise
the funding, though.
April. I want to introduce you
to the newest member
of our team,
Dr. Dean Archer.
This is April Sexton,
one of our star nurses.
Whoa. The famous
Captain Archer, in the flesh.
It's so nice to meet you.
My reputation
precedes me, huh?
It is because of you,
Ethan insists on making
the bed every morning.
Hmm. Why is he
making your bed?
No, he's not...
Uh... We used to...
It's fine, I get it.
If you'll excuse me.
Hold on, April, when you
get a chance, can you
set up for an I&D in 4?
Doris, I&D in 4.
On it.
But we're 2-0 this month.
Next delousing is yours.
Okay.
I hate pus, she hates bugs,
so we switch.
Oh, I see.
I remember when nurses
did both bugs and pus.
Nice of you to let 'em
pick and choose.
I don't want you to worry.
We're gonna take excellent
care of your baby, okay?
I'll be back shortly.
She's definitely
not pretending.
She's convinced
that that is her baby.
And maintains that
they fell down the stairs
earlier today,
while she was holding her.
But I didn't see any signs
of injury or bruising
on Miss Sanders.
Not at all sure that
that actually happened.
What is this,
some kind of delusion, then?
My first guess is something
called delusional companion
syndrome.
The affected believe
that inanimate objects
possess consciousness.
You know, the cause
is usually medical.
Stroke, Alzheimer's.
In this case,
have to be early onset.
Ideally, we'd get a CT,
without tipping her off
to what we're looking for.
Well, we could tell her
that we're gonna check
for injuries
since she said she fell.
Good thinking.
Maggie, can you call
the PICU, tell them
to prepare a crib for Sarah.
Wait, for the doll?
Now, Miss Sanders
believes that that's
her baby and she's hurt.
We challenge her with
reality right now, we risk
shutting her down completely.
Did she mention any family?
Her husband's a truck driver,
but he's on a cross-country
trip right now.
Okay. Maggie, why don't you
give him a call?
And then keep me updated.
All right.
Heart failure?
Uh...
I don't understand. I've never
had any heart issues.
Is this something
that could just pop up?
For some patients,
it's a slow build.
Usually,
due to high blood pressure,
faulty valves.
But, in others,
it can be sudden.
So, then, what? I just
take a bunch of pills?
We're gonna start you
on an intravenous
infusion of medication.
Try to get your heart
to pump more effectively.
Um, but given your
current stage
of heart failure,
the recommended course
of treatment is a left
ventricular assist device.
An LVAD. Mmm-hmm.
LVAD?
That's what,
like Uncle Joe had?
Yeah.
I remember him lugging
around that machine.
So, if I do this,
will it fix my heart?
There's a
small percentage of patients
who fully recover, but...
But it will improve
your quality of life, Mom.
So, then, it won't fix things.
Will?
Hey, Carol.
Sorry to interrupt.
I'm so glad to see you!
It's for you.
My favorite. That is
so sweet of you.
I have missed you so much.
Same.
How're you feeling?
Not great.
These two, they are telling me
that I need a LVAD.
Ah.
You know, Owen talks
about you all the time.
Hey, guys. Why don't we
give Mom some time to rest?
Sure. Carol. Mmm-hmm.
Thank you, Doctor.
I'll stop by later.
Good.
Hey, sorry about that.
Kinda awkward.
I'm assuming Carol
doesn't know?
What's that?
You and Natalie.
That you're, uh,
seeing each other.
Yeah. Guess not.
I'm glad she has
the support right now.
I want Natalie
to be happy.
Yeah, me, too.
Ow!
When did the vomiting start?
Just after 1:00 a.m.
Had my head
in the toilet all...
Oh!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
April? Okay.
Given that the abdominal
pain has been on-and-off
for over a month,
combined with your
alcohol consumption...
I swear I'm gonna
cut back, Doc.
I think we're looking
at pancreatitis.
Pancreatitis?
One of the main things
the pancreas does
is release digestive enzymes
into your small intestine...
But with pancreatitis,
the enzymes become activated
before leaving the pancreas,
causing inflammation
and belly pain.
Couldn't have
said it better myself.
Miss Sanders' head
and c-spine CT readout.
There's no evidence of stroke,
Alzheimer's, anything like...
Oh, but look.
C-3. Evidence
of a fracture pattern.
It's very well healed, though.
So maybe she did fall.
Yeah, but a year ago.
Mom? Hey.
Great news.
Dr. Marcel was able
to pull some strings
and schedule
your LVAD surgery
for later today.
Will remembered
my favorite flower.
It was so nice of him
to come by, wasn't it?
It was.
Sometimes, I think about
that week we all rented
the house on the lake.
How crazy your dad was,
trying to outdo Will.
But Will won him over.
I know you two have had
your ups and downs.
Mom.
Will's a catch.
I know you love Will.
Yeah.
I care about him, too.
But we've both moved on.
Actually, um, I started
seeing someone new.
Yeah. Dr. Marcel.
Oh, God! I put
my foot in my mouth,
didn't I?
It's okay, I should
have given you a heads up.
It's just super early,
so, you know...
Mmm.
You haven't introduced him
to Owen yet, have you?
No, no. Not yet.
Good.
You don't want Owen
to get too attached, just...
Hey. I get it.
Yeah.
All right? I agree.
Anyway, where is
all this coming from?
I want what's best
for you, Natalie.
And now, that I don't know
how much longer I've got...
Mom, stop it.
I wanna see you...
Don't talk like that.
I just love you so much.
I wanna see you happy.
And I will be. Okay?
You're gonna be fine.
Mr. Becker's labs and scans.
Oh. What's the damage?
Elevated lipase and amylase.
Ah. Take a look at his CT.
Big pancreatic abscess
over the body and tail.
Let's start him
on broad spectrum
antibiotics and fluids.
550 milligrams, Imipenem.
No, no. Hold on.
Why not a percutaneous drain?
I prefer starting
with the least
invasive intervention,
and elevate care
as necessary.
Yeah, I understand,
but if it's SIRS,
and not sepsis,
we're gonna be
playing catch-up.
Fair point. But still, given
the chance of perforation,
leak, drain's higher risk.
Not if I do it.
I'm credentialed
in hybrid procedures.
Yeah, okay.
Let's go with the drain.
April, Dr. Archer will
perform the procedure.
Show him up to CT.
Hey.
How're you holding up?
I don't know, Will.
I'm not, really.
I mean, you know
what an LVAD means
for someone my mom's age.
And the chances of her
getting a heart are so slim.
It's a bridge to nowhere.
She'll have two years,
maybe.
I just...
I thought we had
all this time together.
I'm sorry. I shouldn't
unload on you again.
Don't apologize.
Listen, you might have
more time with your mom
than you think.
It's what I came
to talk to you about.
My clinical trial.
I reviewed Carol's charts,
she's an ideal candidate.
I know you've had
promising results,
but it's still experimental.
Nat, our results are
more than promising.
We're actually
seeing patients
reverse heart damage,
without the risk of surgery.
What if she doesn't
get the drug?
After a few months,
everyone gets it.
It may be
too late by then.
Time will have passed,
she'll have gotten worse.
And then she may be
too sick to get an LVAD.
There is a risk
with any treatment,
but if it's time you want,
the trial is the best option.
I don't know.
I think...
I think maybe you should
present it to my mom.
Let's see what
she wants to do.
Dad, I can't leave Chicago!
I just can't.
I know how tough
this must be.
Leaving in the middle
of the school year.
Leaving all your friends.
But you just gotta trust me.
Once you get out there...
Dad, I'm not worried
about losing my friends,
I'm worried about
leaving you.
Oh, honey.
I'm gonna miss you, too.
And we're gonna talk
all the time.
Yeah, but it's not
gonna be the same.
And like, yeah,
I have friends,
but you're the only one
who I know isn't gonna
judge me for anything.
Oh.
It's fine, I know
you have to work.
So I'm gonna go.
Honey, I'm gonna
call you back, okay...
I'm so sorry to interrupt.
But I tracked down
Tally's husband.
Well, ex-husband.
Ex?
Divorce. It sounded recent.
Anyway, he's on
his way here now.
I knew the doll
was a bad idea.
When I first saw it,
I was shocked.
Oh, my God.
Looks just like her.
I guess people see them
as some kind of tribute.
When did you lose
your daughter, if you
don't mind me asking?
About a year ago.
Tally tripped
coming down some stairs.
Sarah slipped out
of her arms.
Docs said the fall
caused, uh, mesenteric...
Ischemia?
Yeah.
Said they could
do some kind of
exploratory surgery,
but probably wouldn't work.
Sarah was so tiny, I just...
I didn't wanna
put her through that.
Did Tally feel the same way?
She couldn't make the call.
She suffered a real bad
neck injury when she fell.
She was out of it for days.
When she came to,
I had to tell her
Sarah was gone.
She thought
I made the wrong decision.
Gave up too soon.
It tore our marriage apart.
I'm so sorry.
You know what I'm thinking,
Mr. Sanders, is that...
Because Tally couldn't
participate in any of
Sarah's end-of-life
decision making,
she couldn't say goodbye.
She hasn't been able
to fully accept her loss.
And that in her despair,
that the doll
might have become
an opportunity for her
to rewrite the past.
That's why she's re-enacting
what happened?
I think she's trying
to change the outcome.
And I have an idea
about how we might be able
to help her begin
to break this delusion.
But we're gonna
need your help.
What happened?
His pressure just plummeted.
Belly's distended.
Hard as a rock.
Maybe it's the drain.
No. I placed it perfectly.
That's not it.
Call general surgery.
Ethan, a word?
All right. Start him on
Levophed and titrate
up to a MAP of 70.
Yeah.
He goes into open surgery
right now, he's a dead man.
Mortality risk is high,
I agree, but at this point,
we don't have a choice.
What if we did a VARD?
Right now, you and me.
It is minimally invasive,
but I'm not trained
in that procedure.
You still want me
to call Surgery, right?
Do you remember
on the Vinson
when we did that
emergency ex-lap with
just a laceration kit?
We got this.
I'll walk you through it.
April, open the Hybrid OR.
We'll need
a laparoscopic setup.
Are you sure about this?
I'm sure.
Hey, Halstead!
Yeah?
So, I finish operating and I
find out that you canceled
Carol's LVAD surgery?
That's right.
She wants to be evaluated
for my clinical trial.
Your clinical trial,
give me a break.
You're unbelievable, man.
Excuse me?
Now, let's be real
with each other, Will.
What are you after?
Hey. You're way out of line.
Am I?
Then why'd you present
the trial to Carol without
my input or approval?
I went to Natalie, 'cause hers
is the only approval I need.
Thought she'd keep you
in the loop,
but apparently not.
Look, I have a lot of history
with Carol and with Natalie.
I understand that makes
you uncomfortable,
but I won't apologize for it.
Wire and dilator in.
Okay. Making the incision.
Thank you.
Go gently, if he starts
to bleed, we won't
be able to stop it. Hmm?
Go, go, go.
All right. There we go.
Phew. Whoo.
That enough pus for you?
Ring forceps.
Mike.
I'm here, Tally.
She slipped through my arms.
I don't know what happened.
I just tripped and then...
Honey, it's okay.
It was an accident.
The doctor needs
to talk to us about Sarah.
Okay.
So, Sarah's fall
caused an injury known
as mesenteric ischemia.
It is an interruption
of the blood supply
to the small intestine.
My God...
Now, I've spoken to our
surgical team, and they can
perform exploratory surgery.
Whatever she needs, do it.
But it is a very
long operation.
And I have to be
honest with you,
it is very unlikely
that Sarah would survive it.
She'd be going through
the operation,
more suffering for nothing?
Mike. What do we do?
You're her mom. You decide.
I mean, if they don't
do the operation,
how long before she...
I'm afraid it would be
a matter of hours.
No!
No.
I'm so sorry.
I don't want her to suffer.
I know.
Don't do the surgery.
Can we be with her
when she...
Of course you can.
Did you know Keshawn
made it all the way to level
100 in Minecraft Dungeons?
I didn't. That's impressive.
Yeah. And he's my brother.
Yes, he is.
Does he really have to
go back tonight?
I'm sorry, sweetie.
I'm sure he's gonna
miss you, too.
Maybe someday soon,
you can go visit him
in California.
Yeah.
I'm sorry. I should
have updated you.
I've just been so overwhelmed.
Yeah, of course.
Look, I understand that.
Thank you.
It's just...
Are you sure
that's the only reason?
I don't know.
It just seems like,
Will, he's been your rock.
Crockett...
I guess I just worry
that your mom's
history with Will,
her affection for him,
it's clouding her judgment.
And possibly yours, too.
I mean, look, Will is someone
I shared a life with
for a very long time and...
Yeah, of course.
But I would never let that
cloud my judgment.
Then why aren't you
objecting to this?
You know the risks of
an experimental drug.
LVAD is proven.
If this were
any other patient...
But it's not
any other patient.
It's my mom!
And if there is a chance
she could recover,
that things could go back
to the way they were.
I know it's
a long shot, but...
As a daughter,
you want to believe.
But, as a doctor,
you have to see this
for what it is.
A gamble.
This could buy you more time
with your mom. Or less.
Look.
I just want you to be
prepared for all the outcomes.
Not just the one
you're betting on.
That was pretty
incredible, huh?
That's one way to put it.
If Archer hadn't suggested
going in with VARDs,
Becker would have died
in the OR.
He saved the man's life.
If Dr. Archer hadn't insisted
on placing a drain,
Mr. Becker never would've gone
downhill in the first place!
We don't know that, April.
Look, I get that
he was your mentor.
Maybe that's why
you trusted his instincts
over your own today.
But, Ethan, he is not
your superior anymore.
I know that.
Does he?
What's going on?
She's, um...
She's finally saying
goodbye to her baby.
Hey.
The Carters.
They want
to adopt Auggie.
Oh.
I can't...
I can't lose another child.
Another? I don't...
I never told you.
I never told anyone, really.
Only Ben.
When I was 16...
...I got pregnant.
By the time I found out,
I was four months along.
I didn't know what to do.
I agreed to put the baby
up for adoption.
After she was born,
I held her.
Then a nurse came in,
and she took her
out of my arms...
When my friends started
having kids, they'd say,
"Mags, you'd make such
a great mom. When are you
gonna get pregnant?"
I couldn't tell them,
but I didn't think
I deserved to be a mother.
Then Auggie
came into my life.
And it felt like
a second chance.
But seeing how he was
with his brother today,
how happy he was...
What do I do, Sharon?
Maggie, you know
I can't answer that.
But what you did
for your baby?
Allowing her to have a life
that you couldn't give her?
That was love.
So, no matter what
decision you make,
it will come from that place.
And I'm sure of that.
Hey.
Listen, if this is about
the judge's ruling...
It's not. I just wanted
to talk to you
because I'm genuinely
worried about Anna.
Why? What's going on?
She came to my house
this morning, so that I could
sign her chemistry exam.
She got a D.
Oh. Of course
she comes to you
'cause you're the good cop,
and I get stuck
being the bad cop.
But I'm not sure
it's quite that simple.
No?
No. Look.
How do I put this?
Anna really responds
when she feels like
she's being heard.
Oh, my God!
Here we go.
And I don't listen
to anything she says, right?
Why else am I
a monster, Dan?
Tell me.
Because I believe
in consequences?
A little discipline?
It's not what I'm saying.
It is.
Look, she's
a teenage girl. Okay?
It's inevitable at some point,
there's gonna be a clash.
You know,
like it's perfectly natural
for her to be pulling away.
She didn't tell me
about one bad grade.
You make it sound like we're
living on different planets.
It's not just
about the grade.
What? What else is there, Dan?
What don't I know about?
Her boyfriend?
I know.
The specifics
aren't important.
Because there
are no specifics.
You just love to play
your little head games.
Su...
No, gotta get packing.
She got pregnant!
What?
It was a chemical pregnancy.
You thought she was pregnant
and you didn't tell me?
No, I didn't,
'cause she begged me
not to. All right?
I'm only telling you now,
'cause you don't wanna
seem to acknowledge
how disconnected you are
from your daughter.
You are a manipulative
son of a bitch!
You wonder why she doesn't
talk to you? It might have
something to do with you.
For instance, the way
you're behaving right now!
Double checking
my handiwork, huh?
Making sure I put the drain
in the right spot?
So, how'd I do?
Drain was placed perfectly.
'Course it was.
But there is one thing
I need to be clear about.
In this ED, I'm in charge.
Yeah, of course. Uh...
To be honest,
I was just eager to make
a good impression, that's all.
This is
gonna be a big adjustment
for the both of us.
Yeah. Hey, "Lead, follow,
or get out of the way."
And it's my turn to follow.
Thanks.
Yeah.
You always have
Auggie's best interest
at heart, I know that.
That's what allowed you
to see what I couldn't.
Auggie should be
with his brother.
You really believe that?
Mmm-hmm.
Growing up
with a sibling to lean on
was everything to me.
If Keshawn is any indication,
Maxine and Antoine are...
They're pretty
great parents.
I was just having
trouble getting past
my own stuff.
What happened when
I was a teenager.
Oh... honey.
I think about her
all the time.
Wonder where she is,
if she's okay, I...
It's okay, baby.
Let's go tell Auggie.
Her surgery went well.
She should be awake
in an hour or so.
Thank you.
Yeah.
I'm gonna
stay here tonight.
Sitter's with Owen.
You want some company?
Yeah, I'd like that.
Okay.
What's going on?
Talk to Mom.
It's clear
that my way of parenting
isn't working anymore.
When Anna was
a baby, we were so close.
And somewhere along
the way, we drifted apart.
Yeah, but that's not
gonna last forever.
You know that, right?
Maybe.
But I feel like
I don't know her anymore.
And I certainly don't know
how to connect to her.
I think that she should
stay in Chicago.
With you.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Su, are you sure?
Look. We can assess at
the end of the school year,
but for now, yes.
Su! No, no, no. Su?