Okay, therafy me.
You're late.
You're fat.
It's unusual.
You know how far the parking
lot is? My leg's been hurting.
Anything been on your mind
lately? Any particular stress?
Nope. Probably just gonna rain.
Hmm.
You like the new Monet
reproduction in the waiting room?
The Water Lilies?
I was late. I wasn't
focusing on the decor,
but it sounds appropriately
bland and calming.
Stress can also make
you absent-minded.
I'm not stressed.
Beyond the stress induced by
you telling me how stressed I am.
Just an ordinary week.
Okay.
Tell me about it.
I had a patient...
House?
Good, I have a case for you.
Beer?
Amnesia.
She was found jogging
in the street, disoriented.
She almost got hit by a truck.
The MRI showed no abnormalities.
No ID on her, just her jogging
clothes and her heart rate monitor.
We know absolutely
nothing about her.
We know she has money.
Blaze Outriggers,
400 bucks a pair.
People who have money
don't just disappear.
Sooner or later, someone is
gonna show up looking for her.
Can I have something to eat?
She just ate 15 minutes ago.
She keeps forgetting.
You don't eat because you
remember it's time to eat,
you eat because you're hungry.
Her metabolism is in high gear.
She is an extreme
long-distance runner who...
Why were you in the ER?
That's your question?
You're a psychotherapist, you're
hearing about a great amnesia case,
and all you're asking
me is geography?
Just curious.
I was avoiding Wilson.
It's not something you couldn't
have seen eight miles away.
Wilson's a processor.
I knew there were some things
that he'd want to process with me.
At length.
Sam's moving in.
If it's before Friday, your
assistant wins the pool.
I was just wondering
what your plans were.
Tonight? In life.
Sam likes you...
But she wants me to move out.
No.
I want you to move out.
I didn't know things with
Sam would happen so quickly.
I didn't... I don't want
to make a mistake here.
I've made a lot of mistakes.
By moving too quickly.
Given your usual
rate of commitment,
I'm surprised you're
not already re-divorced.
I could help you find a place.
What's wrong with my old place?
Nothing. I just thought you
might want to find somewhere new.
Somewhere...
Where I didn't abuse
drugs and hallucinate?
Yes.
I'm fine.
You're fine?
Your best friend is tossing
you out, and you're fine?
Why wouldn't I be?
You're not feeling a
little betrayed and angry?
Wilson bought a
two-bedroom condo
specifically so that you
could move in with him.
It wasn't that long ago.
You don't feel a
little jerked around?
He couldn't foresee Sam
coming back into his life.
That's a very rational
defense of your friend,
and I'm not buying it.
Based on what?
Based on the fact
that you were late,
and you didn't notice the
pictures in the outer office.
Those aren't symptoms.
They are to me.
And here's another one,
you took the case. Hmm.
No negotiating. No bargaining.
No clinic hours changed hands.
Were you looking for
something to distract you
from the fact that your best
friend just threw you out?
The case was interesting.
It's not organic,
it's not mysterious.
Most likely some psychologically
traumatic event occurred
that made the patient's brain
choose to forget everything.
Or not.
Here.
Loss of differentiation
between gray and white matter.
It's subtle.
But it's in the area
that controls memory.
Not likely it's a coincidence.
Bacterial infection?
Do I need to know this?
Fine, I'll give you the
Cliff Notes version.
Chase, MS. Taub,
physical trauma.
I could tell you why
we ruled them out.
Or not.
It's probably a toxin, and we
need to find it before it kills her.
We should search her house.
Good luck with that.
Her heart rate monitor
has a serial number.
The distributor can match the
number to the store that sold it.
She's a serious athlete.
She might have been there
often enough to be remembered.
Brilliant.
Did he really say that?
Subtextually.
Long shot.
Even if the store clerk
does know who she is,
the store's probably
close to where she lives.
Just seeing those surroundings
might spark a memory.
You want us to take her there?
No.
I'll take her.
Really?
It's unusual for you to spend
time with a patient, isn't it?
Patients are boring, as people.
This one, I'm sure,
was no exception,
but her situation
was interesting.
Besides, I was still
avoiding Wilson,
and no better way to avoid
than leaving the hospital.
Maybe. Or were you
avoiding going home?
There's a reason
they tell addicts
to stay away from old geography.
I wasn't avoiding going
home. I'd already gone home,
before I came in
to work that day.
I went straight
there from Wilson's.
Hey! Take it easy.
You're gonna kill me.
God, why don't people knock...
House, it's you! Where
you been? Hold up a second.
Alvie?
Juan Alvarez? You let
him stay at your place?
Not exactly.
I was beginning to wonder if
you were ever gonna show up.
Why are you here?
When I left Mayfield, I went
back to the old neighborhood.
You know, you shouldn't leave
the bathroom window unlocked.
Yeah, thanks for the safety
lesson. Why are you here?
Like I said, when I went
back to the neighborhood,
I found out Immigration
was looking for me.
So I decided to visit
my old buddy House.
And turn his apartment
into a giant prison jumpsuit.
Juan Alvarez is no freeloader.
I do my part, earn my keep.
The first week, I made you
dinner, but you never showed up.
The second week, I
organized your stuff.
My stuff?
But still, you never showed up.
So this week, since I'm a real
good painter, I decided to feng shui...
Coffee table.
Where'd you put it?
In the bedroom?
The paint's not cheap,
House. It's a custom color.
It's a mix of titanium
yellow and ochre.
Ochre. I don't
even like that stuff.
It's like a fruit,
it's got hair on it,
but they say it's a vegetable...
You sold my table to pay
for paint that I don't want?
I had to sell some
other things, too.
Get out.
No, papa, just give
the color a chance.
Look, I'm going to work now.
And when I come
back, the walls will be
a less exciting color,
and you will be gone.
So Wilson threw you out, and you
threw Alvie out. Just another week?
But unlike me,
Alvie didn't leave.
I took my motorcycle
to work that day.
When I went home to get my car,
he was painting
the ceiling magenta.
So I brought him with me
to protect the apartment.
Why?
To protect the apartment.
Whoa, déjà vu.
Tossing him out, or
sending him to the movies,
or locking him in the bathroom
would also minimize
Alvie's destructive force.
But you chose his
company deliberately. Why?
Obviously, because
he's a Wilson substitute.
You can barely tell the
difference between them,
especially when Wilson
raps about the 'hood.
I'm not suggesting
Alvie's a substitute,
but he would make
a great distraction.
From what?
That's what I'm
trying to find out.
Go on.
Maybe the heart rate
monitor was a gift.
That's why no one
recognized her.
Shut up, Alvie.
Anything familiar?
Church? Grocery store?
Sorry.
It's okay, Miss X.
Maybe she's never
been to this town before.
Bought the heart rate
monitor on the store's website.
You know that Puerto
Ricans are US citizens, right?
Instead of working the case,
why don't you contemplate
the inanity of an American with
American immigration issues?
I had a birth
certificate. I lost it.
So get a new one.
I tried that, House.
But the town hall had
burned down when I was a kid,
destroyed the records.
There's only one copy?
They tried to make me fill
out a whole bunch of forms
before they'd give it to me.
I decided it'd be quicker
and easier to do it myself.
How'd that go?
They figured out it was forged,
and now, for some reason,
they don't believe anything I say.
They actually think I'm lying
about being Puerto Rican.
Told me I had to go to a
special hearing to prove it.
What if nothing
ever looks familiar?
Then someone will show
up, a spouse, a friend,
to tell you who you really are
and what you should be feeling.
They always do.
I don't know who
that is, but I miss him.
What did they
say at the hearing?
I didn't go. I lied once.
Your mother's Puerto Rican,
therefore you are Puerto Rican.
All you gotta do is prove
your mom is your mom.
Find some documentation...
People like that don't
listen to people like me.
Donuts. Hey, House,
let's get donuts!
Alvie, the hearing...
Everyone loves donuts.
Glazed, crullers, elephant
ears, even donut holes.
Much better than the
sporting goods store.
I bet Mrs. X went
there all the time.
We're not here...
And then I realized...
You make a good point.
Really? I was making that up.
Dozen glazed,
dozen jelly-filled?
You want the usual, right?
Your old friend, the
fried carbohydrate.
She needed the
calorically dense food
to support the running habit.
Do you know her name?
Sandy or Shelley, I don't know.
The guy she's with
called her that once.
I just work here.
Do you know where they live?
He left a business card
in our free donut jar.
It's up on the Wall of Winners.
Sidney.
God, I was so worried about you.
What happened?
The police said it was
too soon to do anything,
so I started calling
hospitals on my own.
Princeton-Plainsboro
wasn't even on my list.
You really think something around
here could have made her sick?
Here, work, anywhere she
could have been exposed.
Why wasn't
Princeton-Plainsboro on your list?
Well, I mean, it's a long
way to run, even for her.
What is it I do besides run?
You're a lawyer. Civil
rights, class-action suits.
It's a stressful job, running's
the way you deal with it.
That doesn't sound like me.
Do you have any idea
what would sound like you?
Good point.
So what were you
thinking during all this?
That it was a strange
position to be in.
At that moment, she
was more comfortable
with me than with her husband.
And he was picking up on it.
What about you?
What about me how?
There was a sort of artificial
intimacy between you.
She had been dependent on you.
Did you find that
attractive on some level?
Disturbing?
Those are my two choices?
None of the above.
She was just a patient.
She was interesting.
So we're really married.
For four years.
Miss X, you lead
a lemon-fresh life.
I found three different
cleansers under the sink.
Cleaned out the
medicine cabinets, too.
You know, she just won a
settlement for some families
whose housing development
was built on an old methane field.
A toxic exposure to
methane could explain this.
I surf?
You stopped before we met.
You've been too busy.
And we're married?
Yes.
All right, it's
nothing personal.
I bet she didn't think
you were her type
back when you first met either.
We'll take her
back to the hospital,
test her blood and
urine, start treatment.
Are you okay? I'm all right.
What happened?
I don't know. My foot
suddenly went numb.
Her pants are wet.
Urinary incontinence.
She's having complex partial
seizures. This isn't methane.
And you can leave the bucket.
We need to get her...
Seizures?
This is the second
diagnosis you've come up with
that has a personal
resonance for you.
I'm choosing my diagnoses
based on personal issues?
You think she fell down
the stairs and peed her pants
'cause Wilson dumped her, too?
You're choosing to tell me
about this case. So let's look at it.
First, you were fixated on a
harmful toxin from her past,
possibly because you're worried
about a harmful
toxin from your...
Chase had the toxin idea.
Maybe he's obsessed with my past.
And now you're talking
about a seizure disorder...
Which is also not a toxin.
But which is most likely caused
by an old injury to the brain.
Why do you see your
past as such a threat?
Not only am I
unthreatened by it,
I was trying to get it back.
There's a ding mark.
It's a piece of junk. It was
dinged when it came in.
Sure. The cup marks, the scuffs,
and the paint, and
those three chips.
This fourth one is new.
I run a pawn shop, not a storage
company. Do you want it or not?
That should be it.
You said you pawned five
books. There's only four.
That's all there is.
Where's Approach to
the Acute Abdomen?
Sold it.
To? I can't tell you.
It's the law, and it should be.
Crazy bastards like you
try to hunt down their stuff.
How much for the pile?
$500.
You said it was junk.
No, no. It's your
junk, you want it.
$500. Take it or leave it.
Why is it so important
that you get your stuff back?
Unlike the rest of humanity,
who's okay when their
belongings are taken?
Everyone wants their stuff.
That's why it's their stuff.
Everyone doesn't pay
five times what it's worth.
I like my stuff. I hate it
when Wilson moves...
Oh.
This is not about Wilson!
Say it.
I wasn't gonna say anything.
Thirty-one, thirty-one! Hike!
First down!
One more, you get a touchdown.
Whoo!
Hike!
House, you can't
run for the touchdown.
And hike!
Wait, wait, wait. Wait.
You seriously thought you're
gonna tell me that Wilson showed up,
but not tell me what he said?
Because I thought
you were a smart guy
who didn't need the
obvious spelled out to him.
Wilson noticed that I didn't
come to my office all day.
He came to find me.
Wanted to make sure I'm
okay. Boring, boring, boring.
But you thought it was important
to tell me about Nerf football?
Sorry, your story. Continue.
House! House!
Stop! Stop, stop, stop.
You okay?
Yeah.
It was my mother's. She died
when I was four. It's all I have left.
That's very sad, Alvie.
Listen, I set up an
immigration hearing.
No, House. I'm
gonna end up in jail.
Or worse, the Dominican or
someplace, qué sé yo qué. No.
That is interesting.
You present yourself
as not giving a damn
about other people's emotions,
but your actions
indicate otherwise.
You dismiss Alvie's
story about his mother,
but you cared enough
to schedule a hearing.
I cared for eight seconds.
Then I got distracted.
Yeah.
We've kept the patient
up for 12 hours now.
No hint of seizure-like activity.
We should shut this down.
Try a strobe light,
add more stress.
I think there's plenty
of stress in here.
Don't we ever do
anything but work?
You run.
That's just more work!
What about fun? God,
how can we be this boring?
Apparently, without her memory,
the patient's
personality has returned
to what you might
call its natural state.
Seems she had a wake-up
call while she was at college.
Her brother died
in a car accident.
She decided to make her life
mean something, went to law school.
Now that's all gone.
The thing that caused
the change is gone,
so the change itself is gone.
Yeah. I knew the
psychological aspects
of this case would interest you.
Bet you got a theory
already. What is it?
It's not relevant.
What is it?
Why do you care about my theory?
I think he just bores her.
I think she's at an earlier
stage of development,
she's looking at her grownup
future, and it puts her to sleep.
If he just bored her,
she'd hide it to be polite.
Their problem is synchronicity.
Just like you and me, House,
they're not on the same page.
He talks to her like someone
he shares history with.
But from her point of view,
he's a stranger
forcing intimacy on her.
Of course she doesn't
like him. He's not helping.
He can feel he's
losing his wife,
and it makes him
come on stronger.
He almost did lose his wife.
The breathing problem was
caused by fluid overload in the lungs.
Diabetes insipidus.
And the DI came from
damage to the hypothalamus.
Hypothalamus here, that's
the DI and incontinence,
they mingle here, that's
the global amnesia,
and the motor cortex,
that's the foot paralysis.
What do they all have in common?
Okay, now you're just
doing this to mess with me.
What possible relevance does this
differential have to your problems?
It ends with a diagnosis
of Spongiform Encephalitis.
I convinced the team to cut
out part of this woman's brain.
That's not interesting
to you? No.
Not even if it's the amygdala?
She'll lose all her
long-term memories.
Well, this is where you tell me
that being cavalier
with someone else's past
has nothing to do with
avoiding your own past.
The case is irrelevant,
you just found it interesting.
Aren't therapists
supposed to be nurturing?
Nowhere is that in the manual.
Look, you've been
in therapy for a year.
You know when I ask
you to talk about anything,
I mean anything
that affects you.
What upset you, what made
you mad, or relieved, or joyful.
You want me to believe
that this case means nothing?
Then
why should I listen to it?
Are you charging
me for this time?
Yes.
This is ridiculous.
What's that? On
the back of your arm?
It's just a bruise. I fell.
You remember falling?
No. I was drunk.
Hence the balance issues.
It looks like you fell on
the tip of someone's boot.
I said something that
someone objected to.
Well, if you don't
remember, then how...
It's usually the way it is
when someone hits me.
People who kick when
you're down are jerks,
but they're generally
not irrational jerks.
You got drunk enough to get
into a bar fight and not remember,
and you've been insisting
that everything's fine?
Why go out and get blind drunk?
Were you looking for a fight?
I don't know.
What have you screwed up?
What?
You say that when
you've been hit in the past,
it's because you've provoked
it with something that you said.
Which means you're
well aware of the risks.
So, on some level,
you were in that bar
looking for someone to hurt you.
Logically, people punish
themselves for something they did,
or something they didn't do.
So, what did you screw up?
I don't know.
Okay, there may be a problem.
All right.
Let's talk about Wilson.
I told him your book was
contaminated with anthrax spores.
Then I gave him $300.
The address of the buyer.
Maybe I was hasty in
asking you to move out.
Why don't you stay with
me and Sam for a little while?
There's no need to hurry things.
What prompted this?
Look, the whole idea was that after
Mayfield, you wouldn't be on your own.
I can touch base with
you a lot more easily
if you're staying
with me than...
For God's sake, Wilson.
You really span the
chasm from wishy to washy.
If you're gonna be an
ass, be an ass. Stick with it.
Why were you being
so hard on the guy,
when he was being conciliatory?
Come on, Cuddy played on
his guilt. She put him up to this.
How do you know that?
How do you know this
wasn't entirely his own idea?
Two reasons. First,
he wants to create
the perfect environment
to be with Sam.
He's been thinking about
asking me to leave for a while.
Finally, he does it, and immediately
turns around and changes his mind?
No. He talked to somebody.
Maybe it was Sam.
Yeah, that's a possibility.
I want this to be the last
serious relationship I ever have.
I want this to be the one.
Me, too.
Where's House? It's not
as meaningful without him.
Okay, not Sam.
That still doesn't
answer why Cuddy.
Because they've
been talking about me.
She called me to
check on the patient,
which she never
does without a reason.
I asked why, and she said...
She's a barracuda
attorney, House.
These are the kind of
patients we like to keep happy.
Right now, the patient's lucky
if she can spell
"jurisprudence."
Yeah, but when she
gets that memory back,
which we're trying
to make happen,
she'll be able to spell
"lawsuit." I'm just touching base.
"Touching base." Wilson
used exactly the same phrase.
Colluding about me is
their favorite pastime.
Okay, you think they talked.
How do you think that
conversation went?
I'm worried about House.
Me, too. Couldn't
you have waited?
It's way too early for him to be on
his own, back in the old apartment.
What makes you
think he can handle it?
I offered to find
him a new place.
You have to let him
back into your condo.
Sam and I just got
him out of the condo.
You know what House is
like, he's self-destructive.
Without constant supervision,
he's gonna slide
back into drugs.
If you're not watching
him, I've got to.
Yeah.
So they don't trust you.
They assume you'll fail.
Are these their fears or yours?
Let's turn on the lights. Hmm?
In your brain.
Maybe they did talk about you,
but how do you know it
didn't happen like this?
I'm worried about House.
Why?
It's the first time he'll be
on his own since Mayfield.
No, you're being
over-protective.
House doesn't need to
be wrapped in cotton wool.
But you know that, or you wouldn't
have asked him to move out.
Okay. I guess this
is really about me.
It's just I feel like a jerk.
Sure, Sam and I are gonna
wanna be on our own eventually,
but I kind of
sprang this on him.
The right way would've
been to just tell him
to take as long as he needed,
that there's no hurry.
So it's not what you
did, but how you did it?
That matters in a
friendship. I need to fix this.
Why don't you talk to
him about moving back in?
Just touch base.
We're having a consent
issue with the patient.
Wait a minute. Taub's not here.
Yeah, he is.
We're having a consent
issue with the patient.
What's Taub doing in
my imaginary version
of a scene with
Wilson and Cuddy?
Your version needed to
be ended. Because it's crap.
It's all sweetness
and light and faith
that I'm gonna
choose the right path.
Yeah, that sounds like Wilson.
I have as much evidence
for mine as you do for yours.
I know Wilson's your friend,
so he could be wondering
if he did right by you.
And I know he
wouldn't have asked you
to move out in the first place
unless he was convinced you
could handle life on your own.
And I know that he and Cuddy
have gone behind my back before
to strategize about
"the House problem."
So there's truth
in both versions.
But you choose to
focus on the parts
that make you
uncomfortable. So...
Why are you and Wilson friends?
Do you think this friendship
is the best you can do?
Wilson is not a
consolation prize.
There, you're defending him.
And a minute ago, he was
skulking around in the background
like some sort of
manipulative Iago.
He's my friend.
So what do you value in him?
I can say whatever I want
to him, and he'll never leave.
He's sort of leaving.
At least, he won't
be around as much.
Because he's putting Sam first.
For now.
After the divorce, he'll probably
ask me to move in again.
I take the long view.
You say that to Wilson?
Are you kidding?
That's the kind of remark
that leads people to hit you.
Maybe you've been
right from the beginning.
Maybe this isn't about Wilson.
You say that now that
I finally agree with you?
Do you just argue the
opposite of whatever I say?
I don't mean the Wilson
thing doesn't bother you.
But it sounds like
he's the closest
you could come to
a safe relationship.
You'd have to do something
major to screw it up.
What else have you
been involved in this week?
What would you want
to punish yourself for?
I told you I don't know.
Okay, let's approach it
from a different angle.
Have you gotten any other
people angry at you over anything?
Well, yeah. That's why I
called it an ordinary week.
Okay. Tell me about it.
You'd be losing a
part of your brain.
It is my brain. Why is it
not my right to consent?
I'm sorry, but I'll take this to
court, if necessary, all right?
Sidney's in no position to make
decisions about herself right now.
She doesn't even
know who she is.
I read your consent form and I
understood it. I want the surgery.
Why wouldn't she?
Of course she's willing to risk
losing her memories permanently,
she has no idea how
important those memories are.
Does she even
know what "risk" is?
She's never lost anything!
Without the surgery,
she'll lose everything.
The prion infection
will continue to advance
and destroy her whole brain.
There has to be another way.
Please.
I'm speaking for my wife,
the wife I lived
with for four years,
who isn't here and
can't defend herself.
Dr. House, are you listening?
Well, you can stop arguing
'cause it doesn't matter anymore.
Look at the variability
in the heart rate.
The SE's spread
into the brainstem.
Wherever it is, you
can still cut it out.
No. We can't cut the brainstem.
This thing's moving too quickly.
Surgery is no longer an option.
Which, I guess, means
you've won. Congratulations.
Put in a pacer, and start
her on chemo and radiation.
It won't cure her, but
it'll buy a couple weeks,
so she can find out who
she is before she dies.
That was pretty rough.
Do you always break the
news to your patients that way?
Or were you
shorthanding it for me?
Husband was being an idiot.
Well, he was asking for it.
But to punish him, you
had to punish the wife, too.
Why did he make you so angry?
Because he didn't want
to cooperate with you?
He'd rather risk his wife's
life than their marriage.
People's brains stop
working when they think
they're gonna lose
someone they love.
Your leg hurting?
It's all right.
Okay.
Anyone else you pissed off?
Fifty bucks for the book.
Forget it.
You paid $25.
That's 100% return.
That's what I paid.
But it's a rare surgical
text, nearly 100 years old,
plates in mint condition. That
book's worth several thousand dollars.
$2,000. I'll write you a check.
Nice try.
Face it. I had the
wit to recognize
something valuable
when I saw it.
In the great Darwinian race, I get
my just reward, you become roadkill.
Yo, House, you wanna
stop by the library?
'Cause I got a book to return.
Old professor tried to hoard/hog
You can't stop Alvie
with no guard-ass dog
Anyone see you?
Yeah, Prof saw me
walking down the driveway.
He said the roses
need more fertilizer.
I didn't know there was a
section of the brain just for hope.
It's very, very tiny.
We used fluoroscopy to guide
pacemaker placement in the patient's heart.
Hello.
Hello. Rapidly progressive
dilated cardiomyopathy.
This isn't SE,
and whatever it is,
it's not just in her brain,
it's attacking her whole body.
You work for House? I guess
we're teammates. Isn't that cool?
Hello.
Juan Alvarez?
What the hell?
We're taking you into
custody. Deportation order.
I'm a citizen. You're
disrespecting Puerto Rico.
If you're a citizen, why
did you miss your hearing?
You called them?
What's going on?
We're trying to
stabilize her heart.
She's still tachy
and hypotensive.
Brain, heart, and
rapidly progressing.
Endocarditis. Slow-moving
infection in her heart
throws clots to her brain.
I'm not talking to you.
How could you turn me in?
Her extreme exercise
suppresses her immune system,
allows the infection
to smoulder.
Or allows an old
infection to re-activate. TB.
Start her on a
multi-drug regimen.
I don't like you,
House. I hate you.
Even IV antibiotics
will take time to work.
A gentle reminder, the use
of cell phones is prohibited.
Give her the first dose
directly into the lungs in the OR.
Before the less-gentle
arrest for contempt.
Put her in an isolation
room with UV light.
And get yourselves tested.
You've all been exposed.
Docket number 4378.
You are?
I'm Mr. Alvarez's doctor.
Your Honor, DNA evidence proving
the matriarchal
lineage of Juan Alvarez.
My mother's DNA
was still on that cross?
It could be.
You faked it?
It wasn't just me.
You lied to them, too.
But I'm better
at it than you are.
I'm gonna re-paint your
whole apartment now
Make the drapes
match the carpet now
Lungs sound wet.
O2 sats are dropping.
We may need to tube her.
Grab some IV furosemide.
Wait. Wait.
She's crashing.
We need to get her on a vent.
There's something on her ankle.
A tattoo.
"Eddie would go."
It's a surfing phrase.
Must be from her earlier life.
She tried to get it removed.
But they only took off
the top layers of skin.
The ink is still in
the deeper layers.
It set off an allergic reaction.
She was fine until she started
the long-distance running.
The ultra-marathoning
modified her immune system
and set off the
allergic reaction.
We did a full-thickness
skin graft and she'll be okay.
So, you were right in
the end. It was her past.
Did she get her memory back?
Not yet.
Will she?
No way to know.
I think roses are my favorite.
But I guess I told
you that at some point.
I don't remember.
He's treating her as
though they've just met.
He's courting her.
Whose idea was that?
He was doing the opposite
of everything he should,
suddenly he's changed.
Taub thought it might...
That was your idea.
And you asked me what I thought
was going on between them.
It's their relationship
that's on your mind.
That's why you've been
thinking about this case.
Relationships.
Lost one with Wilson,
gained one with Alvie...
Not exactly.
Alvie!
You gonna tell me
what the note said?
Alvie was very grateful that
I'd gotten him out of trouble.
It allowed him to go stay
with his cousin in Phoenix
without worrying about
Immigration looking for him there.
You didn't think he
was gonna stay forever?
No.
What happened next?
Nothing happened next.
That's all I got.
Relationships.
Bergman. What do
you want me to say?
I don't know, you're the
one who set the theme.
Something about relationships
made you go out
and provoke a fight.
Wilson and Sam
have a relationship.
You're not thrilled about it.
They're happy.
Why should I screw that
up? Everyone's happy.
Everyone's moving in together.
Wilson and Sam, Cuddy and
Lucas, even Alvie and his...
Cuddy and Lucas are
moving in together?
You didn't mention that.
They've talked about
moving in together before.
It's not big news.
Cuddy.
Approach to the Acute Abdomen.
Written by Ernest T. Cuddy, M.D.
Any relation to your Cuddy?
Her great-grandfather.
I've had it for years.
Always meant to give it to
her for a special occasion.
Like her housewarming?
It's just a gift.
A woman you care about has
taken one step further away from you
and closer to someone else.
I think I can safely say, yes,
it's significant if
you don't mention it.
You were willing to punish
the husband of your patient
because you identified with him.
He was also losing
someone he loved.
I'm not gonna go out
and get hammered
because a woman I'm not even
with is moving in with someone.
That'd be pathetic.
To hell with this.
When I first came to you,
I told you that I
wanted to be happy.
I followed your advice, and
instead I'm just miserable.
How is this working for me?
It takes time.
For a year, I've done
everything you've asked,
and everybody else is happy.
I run my treadmill, you
just sit there and watch.
You're a faith healer.
You take advantage of
people who want to believe.
But there's nothing
in your bag of tricks.
House!
Whatever the answer
is, you don't have it.