Damn.
Damn right.
Mm.
The sink's clogged again!
Plumber is coming tomorrow!
It's like a crime scene
in here.
Written word not enough, huh?
You want the full
audio experience?
I need an actual human being,
or someone is getting strangled
with a plunger.
We still being sexy?
Look, I've only got
a few weeks left.
It's time to make this
an in-person thing.
So let's do it.
Tonight.
For real, for real?
What about your dad?
Oh, no, no, no, no.
He's... he's doing great.
He's on his meds.
Model roommate.
So it's time for him to see
a sock on the door knob
and get gone.
For real.
Oh, I know that smile.
That's the smile of a man
making plans
for the finest
fishing exposition
in the tristate area.
That's a bunch of old timers
swapping stories
in the back of a bait shop?
Sure.
If you wanna say
the Javits Convention Center
is a bait shop.
Oh, looks great, Dad.
Yeah, tell me about it.
I will not,
'cause you're coming.
Sounds great, Dad.
Good.
We'll go after your work.
Wait, the expo's tonight?
Is that a problem?
Mm.
What did you do that for?
Just making sure you're real.
Only way to know for sure
is to give me a scalp massage.
- Dad's back!
- Hi, everybody.
Hi, guys.
You're darn right, Dad's back.
- Yeah.
- I'm here.
This morning,
my daughter said that
when I'm tired,
I look like a sad racoon.
So do you think I can trade her
for a new car?
A very nice new car.
Good.
Thank you.
Where do you get
your motivation?
Good morning.
I have the clinical
trial prospectus.
Thank you.
Well, Dana, this is Dr. Wilder.
And Dr. Wilder, this is Dana,
my ASL teacher.
Oh, yeah.
No, I got that one.
Crystal clear.
♪ It's a brand new
Please give me
something good.
And this one's
the quarterly budget template.
Another? How many are there?
It's quarterly, so four.
Sandra Fall, I hate forms.
Forms never helped anyone.
Well, this one literally
funds the hospital.
If I'm not looking
into a patient's eyes,
if I'm not looking
into the underlying roots
of their issues, then...
Then you can do your
actual job, sign these forms,
- and end this conversation.
- I had a question.
Is there a form that fires you?
You keep shredding it
against my wishes.
Sign.
The ICU needs
a substitute attending?
Mm-hmm.
Dr. Slavin broke her ankle.
She's out today.
All right. So today I am not
your boss's boss's boss.
I am just simply your boss.
So I'm here for you.
Let's do some actual medicine.
Who's with me?
You look chipper.
Do I?
Well, it is never a bad day
to have a good day,
my enchanting chairwoman.
Charmed and unnerved.
Look, we have a problem outside.
- Okay.
- An unhoused gentleman
who's facing some challenges
has created
an untenable environment.
I don't... I don't follow.
What are you saying?
There's a crazy
homeless guy out front.
He's scaring our patients.
I need him gone.
Well, that was a touching
and heartfelt alternate way
of putting that.
Thank you.
I'm suggesting
you provide him
with appropriate care
and services.
That is far away
from our entrance.
- Thank you, Ignatius.
- You got it.
Do not go inside!
Yes. Yes.
Come out.
Get away from them.
Stop. Stop.
They will kill you!
Hey, there. Hey.
Got a little something here
that might brighten your day.
Evil. Evil people.
Okay. Sure. Sure.
You're one of them.
Actually, I'm just a guy
with some socks.
Yeah, yeah.
Want a pair?
Yeah. Go ahead. Take a pair.
It's cold out here.
Yeah, you're good. Yeah.
I got a whole bag
full of socks here.
I got sweaters.
What you say
you and I take this
wherever you're camping out
and we stash
the whole bag there?
I got a place
just over there.
Oh, over here under
the scaffolding?
Yeah. I've seen people there.
No.
Penthouse.
Penthouse?
Right on.
Oh, that is quite
the decision.
- Tell me about it.
- Right.
So you can either hang out
with a bunch of AARP guys
at a literal fish show,
or you can hook up
with a beautiful, available,
interested woman.
Yeah.
I can see why you're torn.
It's not that easy,
all right?
All I've ever wanted
was my family back.
And now that I have it...
Young woman found
down in Morandi Park.
Unresponsive.
Respirations
and heart rate slow.
Vanessa.
Vanessa?
Pupils are pinpoint, nonreactive.
Narcotics overdose.
I need a second IV.
- O-2 sats are low.
- On it.
Saturation 88%.
I need an intubation tray
with a seven.
Pushing Narcan.
Quick pop quiz.
This is from a 65-year-old man
who is hypertensive
and unconscious.
Do you shock this rhythm?
No.
Yes.
All right.
So you just flip through
these four screens,
and then you pull down
this tab right here.
And, oh, the M key
does not work.
So we just use a little "rn"
right next to each other.
Someone's gotta build
a better system.
Oh.
What if that's someone is you?
When you approach a patient
about hospice,
you don't talk
about end-of-life care.
You just talk about life care.
This is just
the next stage of it.
- It's Duane Roberts.
- All right.
This is it.
You're up.
BP 60 over 49.
Absent breath sounds
on the left.
Left heart's straining EKG.
Tension pneumo.
Need a left-sided chest tube.
VAN runs under the rib.
BP rising.
Sats normalizing.
It worked.
That's good work.
Decision, coordination,
execution, all excellent.
Mika, you okay?
It used to be cleaner.
Oh, no, no.
This is, uh... this is amazing.
Wow.
Look at this place.
Look at that view.
Oh, someone's a gamer, huh?
Uh, coder.
Bit coin.
Cooler.
Do you want one?
Yeah. Yeah. Thank you.
I'll take one of those.
Cheers.
So, hey, just curious.
Why did you start hanging out
in front of New Amsterdam?
I'm warning people.
Warning people about what?
Bad things happen
in that place.
They're evil. They hurt people.
They do experiments
on young children.
They use lightning,
and they rip out their brains.
They tie them down with rubber.
And it's tight.
No! It burns.
And they zap.
They zap and zap and zap.
They...
I'm saving those kids.
Tied down with rubber?
Lightning?
Don't... don't try to deny it.
No, no, I'm not.
That... that is how they
used to do electroshock therapy
40 years ago.
Harlan, when you were a kid,
were you a patient
at New Amsterdam?
Oh...
Hey, how you doing?
How does it freaking look?
It's the Narcan.
You're in withdrawal
from the heroin.
Well, it feels like ants
are crawling out of my body.
So... oh, Jesus.
All right. Okay.
We're gonna get you
through this.
- Stop. Get off.
- What?
- Stop gloating, all right?
- I'm not gloating.
- Please just leave.
- Okay, you really...
Ugh. Jesus.
All right.
You know what, Vanessa?
You tried to kill yourself.
Whether you realize it or not,
that is what you tried to do.
And I'm gonna be here for you, okay?
Yeah. Well, you know what?
Being nice to me now
is not gonna change the fact
that Mom died hating you.
That's not true.
Yes, it is.
Yeah, it is, actually.
Thanks to me, she wrote you
a letter a few years ago,
an apology, you know,
for being
such a terrible mother.
I threw it away.
Why would you do that?
Answer me.
Because you didn't deserve
that, Lauren!
God, she was so vulnerable
when she came to me
with that letter.
She was, like, crying
and asking me
if I thought you'd ever
forgive her.
She thought
you threw it in her face.
So yes, Lauren. Yes.
I'm pretty sure
she died hating you.
You know what?
You really are pathetic,
aren't you?
And there she is. You see,
this is who you really are.
How many times
do I have to tell you?
- I'm done with it!
- Selfish bitch!
- I'm done with being there!
- I can't stand
the condescending bitch
you've become.
Vanessa? Vanessa? Vanessa?
I need help in here!
Okay, okay, okay.
Okay, okay. Okay.
- Chest, it hurts.
- What do you got?
Hypertensive,
diaphoretic, tachy.
Probably narcotic withdrawal.
- My chest.
- Vanessa, I know it hurts,
but we need you to stay still, okay?
Start an Esmolol drip.
- TOX screen?
- The usual polypharmacy.
Oxy, meth, cocaine,
marijuana, you name it.
Was she acting erratically?
She was outta control,
screaming the most hateful...
An adrenergic storm.
From acute cocaine toxicity.
Her coronary artery
is spasming.
I didn't see it. I...
We gotta get her
to a cath lab now.
The clues
were right in front of me,
but why didn't I see it?
With family, we never see it.
Let's go.
Straight. Straight. This way.
Hey.
- Hey.
- You okay?
Uh, yeah,
it was just allergies.
It didn't look
like allergies.
Looked like a panic attack.
Oh, no. Not at all.
I mean, I've been here a month,
and Elliot's code
isn't one of the top ten
most intense things
that have happened all week.
Who's Elliot?
The... the patient.
The code we just ran.
No, Mika.
That was Duane.
Who's Elliot?
Um...
My first patient here.
You never forget your first, right?
No.
Especially if they die.
How did you know that?
'Cause I've stood
where you're standing.
Patients die, Mika,
no matter what you do,
no matter how good you are,
and I've been watching you
on the floor.
You're a really good doctor.
No.
I'm an excellent doctor.
Elliot had a triple A
that ruptured.
That's one of the hardest
procedures we do,
and I ran that code flawlessly.
And then I went home
for the night,
and he died
while I was watching
a reality cooking show
and eating a takeaway salad.
I could have saved him.
He was my patient,
and I left him to die.
They experimented on me
with lightning.
It hurt.
Yeah, I bet.
Yeah, a lot of hospitals
back then used
a very crude version
of electroshock,
and they way overmedicated.
Just so many pills.
You could barely even move.
It's like being in a cage.
A cage you can't see.
You know, Harlan,
we don't do that anymore.
No, we don't.
And I have helped schizophrenics
without pills, without shocks.
None of it.
Really?
Yeah, really.
If you come with me
to my office today,
I will get you
back on your feet.
It doesn't believe you.
The voice?
- Mm...
- Yeah. That's okay.
That's okay. That's okay.
But all you have to do
is let me try,
and you will see
that I can help you.
I mean, Harlan, look
at what you've accomplished.
Look at this.
You were doing really well
for a very long time.
Stop talking.
Look, going to the hospital,
that's new, right?
Shut up!
Did something happen
recently?
- Something...
- Get out.
Get outta here now!
- Get outta here right now.
- Okay.
No hospitals!
No doctors!
No, no, no!
No!
Morandi Park.
I don't...
Vanessa lives
on the Upper West Side.
So do all of her friends.
Yet she OD'd in Morandi Park...
directly across the street
from this hospital.
She knew exactly
where they'd bring her.
She knew that I'd be the one
to see her like this.
She chose this.
That's how much she hates me.
Well, she was coked
out of her mind.
It wasn't the coke.
She meant what she said,
every last word of it.
She meant it.
And why shouldn't she hate me?
I left her.
Lauren...
You wanna know
the worst part?
If she never woke up,
I think a part of me
would be relieved.
Why didn't I help her?
You know why
better than anyone.
An addict has to want help.
I have to try.
I can't... I can't just stand by
and do nothing.
- No, you...
- No, Floyd, I'm not just gonna
walk away
and just watch her die.
This time I'm staying.
Get out.
- Don't you spy on me.
- I'm not.
- Don't you spy.
- 48 floors.
It just... it takes a minute.
Damn thing. Hurry up.
Hurry up.
Hey, the protein shakes,
you like 'em?
They good?
Yeah.
Did you start drinking them
right before
you started warning people
out in front of the hospital?
What?
The M key doesn't work.
Remember?
Gotta just use "rn."
Thanks.
Mika, you left your patient
'cause your shift was over.
Can we not talk about this?
Well, I can't let you
see patients until we do.
Fine.
I could have stayed.
I chose to leave.
When you're not on call,
do you ever sleep here?
We all grab naps sometimes.
That's not what I meant.
How often do you go home?
It depends.
Mika, I'm just asking you,
when was the last time
that you got
a full night's sleep
in your own bed?
The night Elliot died.
That was over a month ago.
Mika, you have to go home.
It's not a request.
I don't think you're allowed
to dictate where I sleep,
and my performance
isn't a problem.
So... thank you for your concern, truly.
But I'm not going anywhere.
You want to take the job.
I have to.
It's too important.
I won't leave you in the lurch.
I'll help with the transition.
I will handle the interviews
for my replacement.
Can we talk alone?
I'll be right outside.
Hey, hey.
I have good news.
You dealt with the homeless...
Unhoused gentleman?
Yes. His name is Harlan,
and I did help him indeed.
It turns out the problem
was protein shakes.
It didn't look like
the problem was protein shakes.
Well, upon further inspection,
they were all he was eating,
which led to a niacin
deficiency, AKA pellagra,
which I then treated
with a multivitamin.
So he wasn't schizophrenic,
he just needed
Flint stone pills?
He is still schizophrenic,
just minus the aggressive
behavior, the irritability,
and the angry voices
in his head.
That was all the pellagra.
As long as sanity has
prevailed at our front door,
- I'm happy.
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Well, you know, about that.
Do you get your vitamins?
There's 13 essential ones.
They're good for your bones,
your immune system.
This will save your life.
I told you to clear
the front door.
No. No, you told me to help.
- Hey, Iggy!
- And I did.
- Hey!
- Hey, doing great.
Excuse me.
Do you get your vitamins?
Vitamins are really good
for you.
You're still here.
Dr. Goodwin.
You gotta go.
Stay, and you're a bad doctor.
Are you asking me
to care less?
No. If anything,
I'm asking you to care more.
The hardest part of caring
is the part you're not doing.
- Letting go.
- Giving up is not caring.
Elliot's gone.
If you worked
1,000 hours straight,
it wouldn't bring him back.
- You can't undo it.
- Stop.
Sometimes people go,
and wanting them to stay,
fighting, clinging,
that's for you.
And you going home,
that's for the person
who needs you next.
Can I walk you out?
Yeah.
Is she...
Vanessa's awake,
and she's asking for you.
You don't have to go.
Don't keep doing this
to yourself.
She's family.
You don't turn your back
on that.
Well, I thought that too.
With my dad when I was trying
to get into his life,
I made so many excuses for him.
I said I wasn't gonna be
the one who turned away,
but my friend told me
that was crap.
It's not the same.
You said that change won't
happen unless you demand it.
But what if it doesn't?
What if she needs me,
and I'm not there?
What if she dies?
I don't know how to help her.
I don't know how...
Yes, you do. Yes, you do.
You've already done it once
when you were 18.
No.
That was selfish.
You know, me leaving her,
that put that needle
in her arm.
Listen.
If you hadn't left,
you'd be in a bed next to her.
All right?
She has someone alive
to help her
because you left, right?
You spent most of your life
wishing you can change things.
But you know what?
It wasn't the worst thing
you ever did.
It was the best.
And I think Vanessa needs you
to do it again.
She's not coming?
No.
But she wanted me
to give you this.
That's where she'll be.
Hey, Pops.
Give me a minute to change,
and we can hit that tri...
What's happening?
I'm moving out.
Okay. If you're...
feeling anxious
about something,
- we can work through it.
- Son, I'm good.
Have a seat.
This may be hard
for you to hear,
but I read all your texts.
- Pops!
- Easy.
It was an accident.
I was checking out vendors
for the expo.
And when I closed the browser,
your message app
was all over the screen.
The thread
with this Gabrielle girl.
I tried not to look,
but those pictures...
Oh, my God.
Calm down. I didn't linger,
but I got enough to know
that you are about to make
the wrong call.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
Pops, look,
you are not in the way.
This isn't pity.
I want to pick you.
I don't know
if I got the right
to give you fatherly advice,
but if I did,
I'd say the most important
thing I've learned
is you go for the girl.
No, Pops. Pops, wait.
Just...
I'm afraid
I won't see you again.
Son, the first time I left,
that was selfish.
This time,
I'm doing it for you.
Hello.
So is anybody in the mood
for a sweeping
romantic gesture?
This Cab is both robust
and impertinent,
much like myself.
Iggy in a bottle.
Hey.
- Hey.
So I know last night
was a lot,
um, but it was wonderful.
Maybe things haven't changed
that much.
Yeah, our good parts
are still good.
But what's it say
about the bad parts?
I don't know.
You know, we'll find out.
Maybe... maybe they're better.
Maybe's not an answer.
We can't just blindly hope
that our problems
have magically solved themselves.
I don't think that, Martin.
I'm not... I'm not waiting
for them to magically
solve themselves.
I'm... I'm working at changing.
I have changed.
You've seen it.
- Mm-hmm.
- And I'm not just talking
about the physical,
the outside.
You know,
I'm talking about inside.
I feel different.
I'm different.
Iggy, so am I.
Martin, I love you.
I'm in love with you.
I love you so much...
But we're not those people anymore.
It's time to finalize
the divorce.
♪ They say
it's a matter of time ♪
♪ A thousand days
and the sun won't shine ♪
♪ Before I come back to you
♪ And I'm happy
♪ Nothing's going to stop me
♪ I'm making my way home
♪ I'm making my way
♪ For your love,
I will go far ♪
♪ I wanna be
wherever you are ♪
♪ I know I'm coming back
for you ♪
♪ I'm happy
♪ Nothing's going to stop me
♪ I'm making my way home
♪ I'm making my way
♪ I go solo
♪ Oh, I go solo
♪ I'm making my way home
♪ I'm making my way
Dr. Helen in her popular
television program.
She stepped out
of the limelight
to pursue oncology research
and to see patients full time.
Dr. Sharpe, tell us about
your latest research.
It also helps reduce pain.
It decreases...
It boosts the immune system.
And the results
are truly astounding.
It's something
we've been practicing
for many years now.
Dr. Helen Sharpe is here
in New York City
representing the NHS's fight
against cancer.
♪ I'll make my way