Are you thinkin'
about taking drugs?
Well, think again, because
drugs are not the answer.
Take it from me, Hank Wiggen.
Oh, don't remember
this ugly mug?
Two years ago, I was a star.
I won n-nine games in a row.
- But by the end of August,
I was gone— - Cut! Cut!
- Not good, huh?
- Well, you caught the ball.
Yeah.
Look, I usually don't, you know,
give line readings, but let me—Try this.
Hollywood ain't
holdin' its breath.
Yeah, well, they're doin'
it wrong. I mean, for Hank.
Tell the director.
I thought I'd give the
marriage a few months
before I go for the
meddling wife thing.
His arm came back the day
after you hooked up. I say meddle.
You okay? Just gas.
Go help your man. Give me
a little room here to work it out.
Take it from me, Hank Wiggen.
Like that? No.
Hey, sweetheart. Hey.
Hi, Bryan. Hey.
Having trouble with the big
speech? Yeah. You got any ideas?
It's your story.
Just be yourself.
Drugs were there,
you took 'em. Simple.
Why'd you get clean?
'Cause I was gonna die.
And, come April,
'cause you're clean,
you're starting Opening
Day against the Yanks.
Try it her way? Yeah.
Okay. Okay.
Let's start with the second part first.
That'll get him in the groove. Okay.
We'll do the
throwing thing first.
Everybody wants to direct.
- Warner all right?
- Yeah, he's good.
You just bring it, babe.
Just tell your story.
Roll cameras.
Rolling. Sound. Speed.
Come on, kid! Show 'em what
you’re gonna give the Yankees!
All right, action!
Oh, God!
You okay? It's gonna be
okay. It's gonna be okay.
He's got osteopenia. His bones
are too thin to fix the arm problem.
No. Price is not a problem
if you have what I need.
Young man? How did you know?
Well, if he's an old man,
osteopenia would just be a fact of life.
You make him comfortable, send him
home, which means you're just boring me.
So he's young, which means
it's most likely caused by cancer.
You're here because you haven't found
it. Have you looked really, really hard?
M.R.I. and PET scan
are both negative.
Well, how old is he? Maybe
the osteopenia is just early onset.
Ah, let's see.
"Born 9/21/77."
It's Hank Wiggen?
And he signed it. Sweet. Yeah.
"To Jimmy Wilson, the
Cy Young of medicine."
Did you ask for that?
Just the "Jimmy" part.
The bone's too thin to support the kind
of surgery that would let him pitch again.
But if we figure out what's
causing the osteopenia,
we can reverse the bone
damage, then do the surgery.
Beat the Yankees
and save the free world.
It was a working dinner.
My work—Company pays.
I don't know. I just feel kind of
weird after what it turned into.
Well, then it
stopped being work.
You know, if it’ll solve
your ethics problem,
you can reimburse me for these.
What are they, $5.57, I believe?
Mmm. Let me know about Friday?
- Yeah.
- Mmm.
None of the usual suspects.
Age isn't right, in apparent
perfect health before this incident,
M.R.I. and PET scan negative for tumors.
Test him again. It's gotta be cancer.
Sorry I'm late. Car broke
down on the interstate.
Don't believe you. CHEM-7
shows a poor kidney function.
- Why would a guy in his 20s
have a poor kidney function?
- Cancer.
It first attacks the bones,
and then the kidneys.
Come on, people. He was
17 and 7. His E.R.A. was 2.1.
You want it to be his
kidneys, because if it's
his kidneys, then maybe
we can treat it, fix it.
And if it’s cancer, then
he'll never pitch again.
If this were a regular
guy who broke his arm
lifting a box, you
would've sent him home.
My God, you're right. I lost my
head. All life is equally sacred.
I promise you. The
next knitting injury that
comes in here, we're
on it like stink on cheese.
- He weighed 1 75 his rookie year.
- Stop.
Now he's 195 after
playing a year in Japan.
Why? He let himself go.
Steroids. The guy was
a drug user. I'm sure he
wouldn't have balked at
pumping up through chemicals.
That'd explain the weight
gain and the kidney problems.
And the bone loss. Go
ask him what he's on.
When he says nothing,
have him pee in a cup.
If your car breaks down, you're
an hour late, not two minutes.
And two minutes isn't late enough to
use a clever excuse like car trouble.
I was coming in early. Huh.
Unprompted lies.
That's a bad sign.
Either a guilty conscience, or
something personal's going on.
See, that's all you had to do—
Just walk in, sit down, do your job.
No. No, I never took 'em.
We're gonna need a urine sample.
Oh, no, you don't trust me.
Baby, I'm worried about
takin' this morphine.
You're in pain.
The doses are
monitored. It's not a slip.
Besides, opiates
weren't your thing.
They should've been. Whoa.
Mr. Wiggen? The urine sample.
I wanna say no, so I am—no.
Trust is a big issue in early recovery.
He really did gain the weight honestly.
If you say so.
You're not gettin' it.
He thinks I'm an idiot.
He sure does.
Should we save a sample?
Dr. Sports Fan can put it in
Lucite and hang it around his neck.
Hey, Friday night,
can you cover for me?
I think so.
Oh, Friday. No, I'm sorry. I have to
go to that oncology thing, the seminar.
Oh. What's goin' on?
Dinner with the drug rep.
Castine Pharmaceuticals.
Arnie? Claims he has 500
lawyer jokes, only tells one?
Uh... new guy.
You need cash?
No, I—I don't have
that much on me.
No, no, it's not a problem.
I'll be over by 6:00. Okay.
5:00 p.m. Dr. House checks out.
It's 4:45. I was rounding up.
Carol Moffatt. Please see
Dr. House in Exam One.
- Whoa, whoa, not so fast, Cathy.
- It's Carol.
Uh— Uh, trouble with the leg?
- When's the wedding?
- This Saturday.
Ooh. Not much time
to fit into that pretty
dress. And no time for
practical shoe shopping.
- You're running two miles a day
further than you should be.
- It hurts right here...
New shoes, less
miles, and ix-nay on the
afternoon Cokes. You're
gonna look beautiful.
- What's wrong with you?
- I can't get my contact lenses out.
Out of what? They're
not in your eyes.
- But they're red.
- That's because you're trying
to remove your corneas.
What's wrong with you? Uh,
lately, my wife has noticed that...
Yeah, yeah. Symptoms. We're
working on a personal best here.
U-Uh, numbness in my feet
and hands, uh, constipation...
And? Maybe he doesn't feel comfortable
talking about his private matters.
Well, neither would I if I was
having trouble controlling my pee-pee.
You're a dentist.
Nitrous oxide poisoning.
Which means you're
either dipping into your own
supply or you got a
bad valve in the office.
Laughing gas rehab's probably
more expensive than the plumber.
Meanwhile, get
yourself some B-12.
Who's left? I can't see.
No, I'm just screwin'
with you. It's a hangover.
My English lit prof told
me he'd fail me next
time if I didn't show
up with a doctor's note.
Well, make friends with the
dentist. He can give you a
note, and maybe a little
nitrous to take the edge off.
Dr. House.
He tested negative for steroids.
Elevated beta-2 proteins though.
Could be cancerous—
Amyloidosis or lymphoma.
Or steroids. You guys
got any money on you?
He tested negative for steroids.
I have a couple 20s
on me. Fifty of 'em?
Foreman? The fat-pad
biopsy and abdominal C.T.
scan were negative
for the cancers, but...
That just leaves
us with steroids.
He tested negative for steroids.
Less money is made by biochemists
working on a cure for cancer...
than by their colleagues struggling
valiantly to find ways to hide steroid use.
But there is one
thing they can't hide.
Hi. I'm Dr. House.
And this is the
coolest day of my life.
See? Steroid use
shrinks the testicles.
I'm clean, man. No
steroids, no nothin'.
Your lips say no,
your prunes say yes.
Hypogonadism. Isn't
that a great word?
Thanks. We don't get to say it nearly
enough. Start him on Lupron right away.
These freaks are willing to defile
themselves for mass entertainment.
For money. I feel
sorry for them.
He drops a clean urine,
denies using steroids.
And you're giving him a
drug for what, steroid abuse?
No, no, it's not.
It's got calcium in it.
It's very good for the bones.
Basically, at a molecular
level, it's just milk.
Dr. Whitman to
Anesthesiology.
Dr. Whitman, Anesthesiology.
How long do you figure
before I get a call from Cuddy?
- You put him on Lupron?
- Uh-huh.
- And you told them it was like milk.
- Yes.
Is there any way in
which that is not a lie?
It's creamy.
- But I had three reasons.
- Good ones?
Well, we'll see in a minute.
I'm just making them up now.
- He lied to me first.
- Your mother did teach you
two wrongs don't make a right.
If he lies to me about
not taking steroids, and I
lie to him about not
treating steroids, he's cured.
Adds up for me. Second reason.
If I told him the truth, he
wouldn't have taken the stuff.
And if he told you the truth,
what would the stuff do to him?
- Severe respiratory problems.
- Third reason?
I wanted to eliminate
the placebo effect.
Excellent.
You and your lawyer
can write a paper.
Which brings me to my fourth reason. I
thought you said there were only three.
- I thought you'd buy one of 'em.
- Seriously?
He's not gonna sue.
Because his lawyer
is a nice guy...
who'll realize it's unfair to blame us
for ruining this kid's $100 million career.
Good guess, but no.
If the Lupron causes respiratory
problems, it means he's not on steroids.
Which means there's
something else wrong with him.
And the choices for
that something else...
are almost universally very bad.
Osteopenia,
messing his bones up.
Hypogonadism, impaired
liver function, kidney function.
And we have managed to find the
only professional athlete in the galaxy...
who is not on steroids.
And it's not cancer.
So what's killing him?
Who shares my suspicions that the
Yankees were somehow involved?
Shrunken testicles indicate his body's
not putting out enough testosterone.
Throw out the lungs.
That was the Lupron— my
fault. Don't worry. I'll
send him a nice note.
What about something
environmental?
Arsenic, mercury. The
symptoms could indicate...
Pretty small environment.
Wife's fine, no one else is sick.
If you throw out the kidneys,
everything else adds up.
The testicles, the bones,
the impaired liver function...
could all be caused by a
breakdown of his adrenal glands.
Addison's disease. I like it.
Mainly, of course,
because the treatment is...
- Steroids.
- Enough irony for all of us.
Treatment would
cause him to retain fluid.
- With the kidneys almost
shut down already, he'll die.
- So we'll get him a new kidney.
Your theory is that Addison's
is causing all the symptoms...
except for the kidney problems.
- What's causing the kidney problems?
- Cameron, if you had to make
an ironic guess right about now...
He tested negative for steroids.
Agreed. He's not
on steroids now.
But if he was on them
at any time in the last five
years, it could have
caused the kidney damage.
You see, kidneys
don't wear watches.
Sure, gall bladders do, but it doesn't
matter, 'cause kidneys can't tell time.
Steroid damage could take years.
No steroids. How many
times does he have to tell you?
I don't know.
How many times did he lie about cocaine
before coming clean with the league?
- That's completely different.
- Oh, that's right, I remember.
You never did come clean. The league was
out to get you. They faked the blood tests.
You had to get yourself
a lawyer and everything.
If Hank says he never
used steroids, that's the truth.
That's too bad, because our theory is
that the kidney damage is caused by "A,"
and everything else
is caused by "B."
The beauty of this theory is
that we can treat "A" and "B."
But if you add the kidney
symptoms back into the mix,
then we are looking at
another letter altogether,
one that is apparently
not in the alphabet.
We can't fix the bones, no
more baseball, no more breathing,
no more brain function.
Get another explanation.
Okay. Yeah, I think I
got one in my other pants.
Hold on.
Five years ago. Bangor, Maine.
My pitching coach had me on
something. I never knew what it was.
And you never tried too
hard to find out either.
I gained twelve pounds of
muscle in, like, four weeks.
I'm sorry, baby.
Huh?
How ya doin', Doc?
Good. Very good, yeah.
You want me to put Hank
Wiggen on the transplant list.
He needs a new kidney. I was thinking
the kidney people might have some.
They like to save them for people who
have— How do I put this? Kidney problems.
He's a professional ball
player. Brings joy to millions.
Do you really want to be known as
the hospital that sent him home to die?
That's a great idea. We could be
the hospital that killed two people...
The guy who deserved the kidney, and
the ball player we bumped up the list...
when we weren't even sure
what was wrong with him.
Everything else is
related to the Addison's.
The test for Addison's
was inconclusive.
is always inconclusive.
Why do we do it at all?
We should just ask you.
You're not putting
him on the list.
Your powers of
deduction are breathtaking.
- You take a perverse pleasure
in turning me down.
- What I live for.
Once in a while, though, try to ruin my
day— ask me something I can say “Yes" to.
Oh, I'm sorry, Doctor. I didn't know
you were busy. Want me to come back?
- Is he on the list?
- No.
- Then I'm giving him one of mine.
- Okay.
You're not gonna tell me
it's a bad idea? Why give
a kidney to someone who
might not be able to use it?
Not my area.
That is, however, my chair.
When do we do it?
Very noble gesture.
My favorite kind. Dramatic,
yet completely empty.
The chances of nonidentical
twins being a match...
You live alone?
You writing a book?
I made it a question just
'cause it's more polite.
You got a big "keep out"
sign stapled on your forehead.
That explains it. I told
'em to put it on my door.
Even if real human contact is something
you don't have or even want or need,
you should at least be
able to see it in other people.
Yeah. Right.
True love—that's just how
we match organs these days.
There's a couple in France— high
school sweethearts— they're trading brains.
We're a match. Run your tests.
Hey. The lab call?
Is she a match?
Haven't heard yet.
You got a text message,
though. "Friday night." Very cryptic.
Gee, thanks for checking.
Can you cover for me?
Oncology seminar. Right.
Friday night the same
thing as the car trouble?
I had car trouble.
House says you were
lying. I believe him.
What's that? You got a little wet
smudge at the end of your nose.
Hey, I like the guy. He says what
he wants, does what he wants.
He won't talk to anyone
unless he can jerk them around.
Or needs a thousand
bucks. What is with that?
I scored.
It's a brave new world, Doc,
and we are the cutting edge.
You are looking at
two all-access passes...
to paradise itself.
How much? True
cost? No man can say.
Could that man's accountant say?
One thousand dollars. Whew.
Friday night. The biggest official monster
truck jam in the history of New Jersey.
Okay, please tell me you
didn't just say Friday night.
Whatever you've got, you cancel.
I can't do it. They only
give these tickets to owners.
Anytime we wanna be in the middle of the
track, we're in the middle of the track.
These tickets are so good,
we have to sign a release.
I mean it. We do
this, we could die.
I've got the
oncology thing. I—I...
The rectal cancer lecture— they booked
me a year ago. I-I-I-I-I can't get out.
There's no way out.
Fine. I'll ask one
of my other friends.
Huh.
What? You're saying
I've only got one friend?
Uh... and wh-who...
Kevin in Bookkeeping.
Okay, well, first of
all, his name's Carl.
I call him Kevin.
It's his secret
friendship club name.
- It's hookers.
- Oh, my God!
Multiple hookers. But House is House. He's
gotta have it his way. Four or five women.
This isn't even funny. What?
You don't think he has sex?
- No, of course he— - He
doesn't have sex, he makes love.
I didn't say that.
It's the lab.
Dr. Foreman.
Respiratory Therapy, call 4702.
Respiratory Therapy,
pick up 4702.
If you have the results,
I'd like you to talk to
both of us. If you don't,
I'm late for a meeting.
Believe me. I'd much
rather be with your better half.
And by better half, I mean the one who
struck out Sammy Sosa on three pitches...
and talks a lot less.
But I thought I would
talk to you first and alone.
I got your results
back from the lab.
You do match.
I—I do?
You're also pregnant.
You can't be a donor.
Not in your current condition.
Um... excuse me.
I have to go talk to my husband.
Heart looks good. We
can schedule the transplant.
No transplant.
Lola's not gonna
have an abortion.
Actually, your wife just told me
that she was making an appointment.
I don't care what she said.
I think you two need
to discuss this further.
We've been trying to get
pregnant almost since we met.
Well, it's your wife's
decision whether or not...
She wants to trade a child
for a kidney. That's murder.
I'm not gonna let her do that.
Foreman says we've got a
problem about the transplant.
If she terminates the pregnancy, he's
not gonna let himself die on principle.
Would you give up a
baby for someone you love?
Please tell me I
don't have to decide.
It depends. How
long would they live?
This is a pragmatic
question for you?
Fifty years, no problem.
Six months, I say let him die.
I've actually given this a
lot of thought. My personal
tipping point is seven years,
eight months and 14 days.
I couldn't do it.
You found religion?
- Do you have to be religious
to believe a fetus is a life?
- There seems to be a correlation.
I'm, uh...
Do you like monster trucks?
- I don't know what they are.
- Right.
I got two tickets. Friday night.
- You asking me to go with you?
- Sure. Sounds good.
Like a date?
Exactly.
Except for the—the date part.
Forget it.
Uh, no, I—I was gonna
go to the oncology dinner.
Of course. You have
to hear Wilson's lecture.
No. I just found out he
canceled, like, two weeks ago.
So... what do I wear?
Still with us, Hank?
Yeah. I'm here.
My chest feels funny.
Tachycardia. Your
heart's beating too fast.
We're sorting it out. But
you stay with us, all right?
- Keep talking to us, Hank!
- Where's Lola?
Ten units of insulin
sub-Q, an I.V. push D-50.
- Why's his potassium up?
- Damned if I know.
Kayexalate too. We
gotta suck that potassium
out of him. We gotta
get his heart rate down.
- We need a crash cart!
- You got it.
- It's definitely not Addison's.
- It's not steroids either.
Set. Help in here, please!
His heart rate is 130 and rising
like a Randy Johnson line drive.
"A" for effort. There's no
point in doing the transplant.
Even if he was stable
enough, it's obvious
that we have no idea
what's wrong with him.
First it's too high.
Now it's too low?
His heart's not
responding to the atropine.
Heart rate's down to
40. I thought it was up.
Now it's down. Last
time he went out at 35.
- What's wrong?
- I have no idea.
Hit him with the atropine
before he gets to 35 again.
We've already given
him three milliliters.
Apparently that's not enough.
We can't stabilize
his heart rate.
What did you do
to him? Kayexalate.
His pulse was through the
roof. So was his potassium.
- It wouldn't do this.
- Something did.
Call me when he's
stable. Or dead.
I remember the first time.
You weren't even supposed
to be pitching that day.
I'd flown all the way to
Tokyo to watch this kid,
and he gets tossed for
arguing a call in the first inning.
Ah, your pitches—perfect.
Ball seemed to go
faster than your arm.
It was like the rules didn't apply,
like physics couldn't slow you down.
Hot damn, it was beautiful.
Hey, Warner.
Hey, kid. How ya feelin'?
I hurt.
My arm, my head, everywhere.
They must've dialed
down the morphine.
That's just wrong,
man. You're in pain.
Hey, I got somethin' for ya.
No.
A doc in St. Louis gave
'em to me for migraine.
I'm an addict. I can't take that. Even
Lola was okay with the morphine.
This stuff's just
a little stronger.
Come on.
I'll just try one, Warner.
Dr. Mulvaney, please
call extension 6 134.
Three more symptoms.
Heart rate up. Heart rate down.
Now he's hallucinating. You
gotta promise not to tell Lola.
Okay, coach? He's
not just dreaming?
No R.E.M. He's actually awake.
Drugs? Not psychedelics.
Not with the heart symptoms.
Well, hallucinations would point to
digitalis. It would also mess up his heart.
But he's not on it.
And why would he take it?
Yeah.
Pithy analysis.
I can see why they asked you
to speak at the cancer dinner.
I'm sorry I'm gonna miss it.
I'm sorry about
the monster trucks.
No, I think it's great.
You're giving back.
Only thing is...
uh, digitalis,
it would only explain
the later symptoms,
not the original ones.
Sure, you know, it's
got a lot of movement.
Problem is, everybody
sees the movement.
You're throwin' your curveball like
you're—you're throwin' a curveball.
Deception. That's the...
Same motion.
Less movement, but it
won't come back at you.
All right, outfielders
move in! Right there!
How'd you get in here?
Spoke Spanish. Told them I was
the new shortstop from the Dominican.
How's Hank doin'? Lousy.
Around your fingernails, that
swelling, it's called clubbing.
Hippocrates noticed that a lot
of his friends who also had that...
tended to frequently
grab their chests and die.
Yeah, I got a heart condition.
What's wrong with Hank?
What do you take
for it? Digitalis.
Got 'em with you?
Huh. Well, that's weird.
I just filled this prescription a couple
days ago. There's another bottle here.
Don't bother.
Hank Wiggen stole your pills.
He tried to kill himself.
So what happened?
He left the bottle open while
he went to get some water?
Next time, just take
the whole bottle.
Hey, man, you got no right.
See, people remember
how many they've got.
Date's right on the label, number of
pills— regular person can do the math.
But a junkie doesn't have
to, because how many
pills he's got left, that's
all he's thinking about.
Big insurance policy?
- This isn't about the money.
- Not for you, no.
Most reputable stores won't
cash your checks after you're dead.
But for Lola, well, girls like
that, they're all about the money.
Don't you say that.
She already saved my life.
I was dead in Japan. She brought me
back. Everything since then, that's gravy.
That's more than I deserve.
You owe her? Everything.
Ah. So the attempted suicide,
the scaring her to death—
What is that? That's gratitude?
Love?
Yeah, I get that.
Well, take out what you
did to yourself yesterday...
We're back to the
kidneys and the bones.
I'm scheduling the transplant.
Never visit a patient.
I want that baby!
Even if I'm gone, that's
a piece of me and Lola...
breathing, walking around town,
goin' to baseball games.
If there's any more transplant
talk from you, Lola, or anybody else,
I won't screw it up this time.
I'll take myself out for good.
I'll start treating the
Addison's, which will
most likely destroy
what's left of your kidneys.
Fine. Start the treatment.
Hey.
What— Hank Wiggen peed on me.
What do you think these
pants are worth on eBay?
I've got some big boy diapers in my
office. The rep hands 'em out like candy.
Is it that bad? No, not if
you like the smell of urine.
Of course, why should I trust someone who
lies about what he's doing Friday night?
Question is, what are you
really doing Friday night?
Or more to the point, what could
possibly be better than monster trucks?
Or are we breaking up?
Stacy's coming into
town this weekend.
We're having dinner.
Just catching up.
I definitely had pants here.
Wait a second. Is
that Stacy the stripper?
I heard she's
playing Atlantic City.
No, Stacy the
constitutional lawyer.
You thought I couldn't
handle this news.
You talk to her a lot?
No, it's been a long time.
- If you don't want me to see her— -
What is this, eighth grade? I'm fine.
It's fine if you're upset.
No, it's...
I have no right to be upset.
You two were friends.
You should see her.
Say hi for me.
So, you're okay?
I'm not the cancer doctor who's
lying about the cancer dinner.
I'm not the one betraying all those
poor little bald-headed dying kids.
I'm gonna go get
some pants. I stink.
You're treating him for Addison's
and you don't think it's gonna work?
He tried to kill
himself. I know.
He's confused. We can have another
baby. I can make him understand that.
I'm having an abortion.
We do the transplant— No.
I can make decisions
about my body.
And he can make decisions about
his. He doesn't want your kidney.
So he'll die?
Probably.
If you keep that appointment,
he'll also probably die.
Keep the baby.
Are you just being polite?
My pants are...
Oh, they're all wet.
You can't smell that?
You think she'll abort
anyway, try to force his hand?
No, she's not gonna
risk losing him.
That's funny?
No, the monster trucks. House
asking you, that's—that's funny.
I was the first person he
ran into. He just asked me.
Yeah, like a date.
Exactly. Except
for the date part.
If the patient decides
to go the dialysis route,
we've got some product
you should check out.
Mmm. Hey, Dr. Foreman.
Courtesy of the generous Sharon and
the good folks at Castine Pharmaceuticals.
I was just telling the guys about
the Bermuda conference in April.
Three days of sun and
scuba, and one hour of lecture.
Oh, God, do we have
to go to the lecture?
So, you're the new Arnie.
Dr. House. It's good to see you.
Would you get me a
coffee? Black, no sugar.
Okay, so who is it?
Come on. She's
sleeping with one of you.
Oh, God, please
tell me it's you.
She buys lunches. She doesn't...
Don't worry. You're not
gay. You're adventurous.
You think she's gonna prostitute herself?
The three of us are that important to her?
I'm afraid not, no.
The groupies sleep with the
roadies in order to get to Mick.
And you're Mick? That was
the metaphor I was making, yes.
Why are you here?
Damn, it's you.
It's not Addison's. New
symptom. Inability to smell.
I was just in Hank's room.
He said it smelled like the men's
room at Veteran's Stadium. He was right.
We rejected environmental
causes because the wife was healthy.
Well, she's not. Last six
months, she can't smell a thing.
If you think of them as one single
patient, you add her symptoms to his...
Cadmium poisoning.
It explains everything. Even why they
had so much trouble getting pregnant.
How could they have gotten
exposed to that much cadmium?
Unless they were eating
steel and batteries for breakfast.
So, where else is cadmium?
Some foods, polluted groundwater.
We should check their home.
I think I know how it happened.
I'm gonna need
another urine sample.
What for? Sure.
Whatever you want.
Why wouldn't you give it to me
before, but now it's no problem?
- I'm dyin', right?
- So you've got nothing to lose this time.
Begs the question, what were
you worried about last time?
The funny thing is, when we tested you
before, we were just looking for steroids.
What should we
look for now, Hank?
Hank, what's the story?
A little weed every now and
then when no one was looking?
I don't believe this.
- We quit.
- You did.
If you'd kept going, you wouldn't
have just lost your sense of smell.
I quit the hard stuff.
- I just needed to relax.
- Based on the symptoms,
you're a lot more than a social user.
So you've been lying to
me all this time? I'm sorry.
There must have been cadmium in
the soil where the marijuana was grown.
Some people get bone loss, kidney
failure, some people's testes shrink,
and some people lose
their sense of smell.
We'll start
treatment right away.
You should be
fine by opening day.
Baseball's in the summer, right?
It didn't hurt the baby,
did it? The cadmium?
- If you've been clean,
the baby should be fine.
- Okay.
Please. I'll stop everything.
I'll—I'll go to meetings every day.
Lola.
Twice a day.
How's the ballplayer doing?
Much better. Too
bad about his career.
What do you mean?
Major League Baseball's
collective bargaining agreement...
requires medical
reports on all treatment.
Given Hank's history, he's
not likely to get much leniency.
Why should they care that
he's being treated for Addison's?
You're not treating him for
Addison's. My report says I am.
You're lying on the report?
Well, everybody
does stupid things.
It shouldn't cost them
everything they want in life.
No, it shouldn't,
but it usually does.
On the other hand, if it means
someone can actually beat the Yankees...
So what about House? Is there
any way we can get him down there?
You really wanna
talk about work?
No. Not at all.
That was amazing!
I'm telling you. Grave
Digger never disappoints.
You ever been married?
Well, now, let's not ruin a lovely
night out by getting personal.
I lived with
someone for a while.
You gonna finish that?
I'll race you to the car.
That's some bad hat, Harry.