Until pretty recently,
doctors would slap a newborn
on the back
immediately after birth.
♪ Trouble, trouble ♪
♪ Trouble,
don't you come my way ♪
♪ Been tryin'
to change my ways ♪
♪ Trouble,
don't you come my way ♪
It's not that they wanted
to make the baby cry.
They needed the baby to cry.
♪ Trouble, trouble ♪
♪ Trouble,
don't you come my way ♪
♪ Oh, Lord,
don't let me stray ♪
♪ Trouble,
don't you come my way ♪
♪ Don't you come my way ♪
♪ Don't come my way ♪
♪ Trouble,
don't you come my way ♪
♪ Oh, no, not today ♪
Thank you.
♪ Trouble,
don't you come my way ♪
♪ Trouble, trouble ♪
Lexie!
♪ Oh, please,
don't tempt my fate ♪
♪ Trouble, don't you come
my way, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
It meant the baby could breathe
on her own.
♪ Oooh, oooh ♪
Thankfully,
we don't do that anymore.
♪ Whoa, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Whoa, oh ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Trouble, trouble ♪
♪ Trouble,
don't you come my way ♪
But we still hold our own
breath until we hear that cry.
♪ Have a little mercy on me ♪
♪ Trouble,
don't you come my way ♪
♪ Don't you come my way ♪
♪ Don't come my way ♪
♪ Trouble,
don't you come my way ♪
♪ Oh, no, not today ♪
♪ Trouble,
don't you come my way ♪
♪ Whoa, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Whoa, oh ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Whoa, oh, oh, oh ♪
And it doesn't matter if you're
the baby's doctor or mother...
♪ Whoa, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Whoa, oh ♪
♪ Don't come my way ♪
...it's the most beautiful
sound in the world.
♪ Whoa, oh ♪
♪ Don't come my way ♪
♪ Oh, no, not today ♪
The first time, anyway.
♪ Don't come my way ♪
♪ Trouble,
don't you come my way ♪
♪ Trouble, trouble,
don't you come my way ♪♪
Lianne La Havas' "Paper Thin"
plays softly...
♪ Paper thin ♪
♪ God only knows
the pain you're in ♪
Boston doesn't need you
as much as I do.
You know I'd stay
if I could.
♪ Love yourself ♪
Morning playlist.
♪ Or else you can't love
no one else ♪
It's better than coffee.
♪ I know your pain is real ♪
♪ But you won't let it heal ♪
♪ Paper thin ♪
♪ If you're trying to lose,
you'll never win ♪
♪ It's your life ♪
Yeah.
♪ But you're not the only one
suffering ♪
♪♪
♪ That's enough, I know... ♪
Marcella Diaz,
62...
...recently admitted to ICU
after sats dropped below 87%.
She was in a lot of discomfort
last night.
Ah, this one worries
too much.
He needs more patients.
Or a hobby.
Well, when are you gonna start
my singing lessons?
Marcella taught music
in high school for 35 years.
Recent chest films?
Opacities
in both lungs.
Veronica...
Of course.
And... And...
Yes, I will call
my mother, too.
Veronica's her daughter.
She's positive, too,
but her symptoms are mild.
Mama!
How are you feeling?
Okay.
It's...
It's just a cough, Mom.
Don't worry.
You focus on you,
alright?
And do everything that
Dr. Pierce says, alright? Okay.
Okay, I love you.
And when did you first start
to feel the pain?
Uh, a few nights ago.
I was watching
these cat videos online when...
For God's sake,
what happened?
The boys are fine.
A little worried.
I told them you'd call.
They called me.
They thought
I might be interested to know
that their aunt left
in an ambulance.
She has a history of acid reflux
and lives with MS.
Right, yes.
She told me.
Irene, are you on any
medications other than steroids?
And those damn teas.
She has an infantile resistance
to Western medicine.
She's had a catastrophic
family experience
with Western medicine.
Okay, it... it... it looks to me
like it's kidney stones,
but I'd like to get a CT
just to...
Then what are you waiting for?
Let's go.
I'm waiting for you to let me
finish a single sentence,
but I'll give up
on that now.
Life of the party, isn't he?
I appreciate everyone
pulling extra shifts.
Bailey does, too.
Uh, she'll be back
in a few days.
Thank you, Dr. Ndugu,
for pitching in where needed.
Boston's hit another surge,
so we need to let him get back.
How's Meredith? Her
vital signs are stable.
Her morning labs
were good.
Oxygen requirements
are decreasing.
Enough to take her off
the vent?
Let's see if the trend
continues.
Well, let's hope it
does, and not just for her sake.
As of 5:00 this morning,
we are down to our last four
available ventilators.
So, until relief arrives, I need
us all to think creatively.
Ventilators
are our last resort.
Put them on BiPAP, the
hyperbaric chamber, uh, proning.
Let's exhaust all options
first.
So, if you extubate
Meredith
and she starts to trend
downward again,
we may not have another one
available.
So let's not make the call
to pull her off
until we are 100% certain.
Captioning provided by
ABC Studios and ABC, Inc.
And brought to you by: Ford,
Built Ford Proud
♪ It's just a matter of time ♪
It's so beautiful.
I love it here.
Me, too.
♪ We'll find a way ♪
Are you gonna stay?
I don't know.
I don't know the rules.
I don't think
there are rules,
which is, um...
well, it takes some
getting used to.
I was big on rules.
I actually, like...
I think I loved rules.
You totally did.
♪ I'm gonna sing
till the sun comes out ♪
Mark!
♪ There's no rain
that's gonna bring me down ♪
You're early, killer.
♪ I'm gonna sing
till the sun comes out ♪
What?
Too early.
♪ Come what may come my way ♪
Your oldest
is Sofia's age?
I promise you,
it's too early.
I don't know
how to get back.
I keep seeing Derek,
and he won't help me get back
or come close enough
to touch.
It's not up to him.
It's up to you.
What do you mean?
The sand isn't real,
Meredith.
I wish everybody would stop
saying that to me.
♪ The sun is gonna shine
after the rain ♪
♪ I'm gonna sing till the sun comes
out ♪ ♪ Rain, rain, go away ♪
out ♪ ♪ Come again another day ♪
So, you two
are together?
♪ I'm gonna sing till the sun comes
out ♪ ♪ Rain, rain, go away ♪
On your beach?
Looks like we are.
♪ Oh, I'm gonna sing ♪
♪ Come what may come my way ♪
♪ The sun is gonna shine
after the rain ♪
Ah!
♪ Come what may come my way ♪
♪ The sun is gonna shine
after the rain ♪
Stop it!
♪ Come what may come my way ♪
Get away! Run away!
Quick, quick! Whoo!
Yes!
I like it here.
♪ The sun is gonna shine
after the rain ♪
♪ Come what may come my way ♪
Alive and well.
Sorry to disappoint.
You heard about
the vents? I did.
So you know if we pull
Grey's tube
too soon,
we don't have...
I heard about
the vents, Tom.
...to Nuclear Medicine.
Dr. Sellers
to Nuclear Medicine.
Hi!
Hey.
Leo threw up on the
way over here. Oh, no!
Do you have a shirt
that I can borrow?
Yeah, come on in.
Thank you.
Okay.
Hey, Leo,
come this way with me.
Here, let me take off
this jacket.
Let me just sit down
for a sec.
Yeah, he gets carsick.
Okay.
He once puked on my op notes
for a glioblastoma.
You know, Ellis really
wants to show you
what she's working on
in the playroom.
Do you want to go see her?
She's right there. Look.
Go say hi.
Okay, bye-bye.
If you had told me
two years ago
that you and I
would be excited
to spend the afternoon together
with six small children...
I know that Owen asked you
to babysit me.
You don't have to
put on a show.
Both things can be true.
I need company.
We can have tea and discuss
life pre-pandemic,
and we don't have to be covered
in puke alone for an afternoon.
It's great.
I just told Liam and Austin
not to worry.
Please tell me
I wasn't lying.
You know it's probably
minor, right?
It's not that.
I mean, it is that,
but...
Irene insisted on moving down
here when the pandemic started,
and we drive
each other mad.
We do.
But I'd be lost
without her.
You're trying
to make me cry.
Don't go getting a big head
in there, now.
Hm.
Kidney stone,
like I thought.
In the right ureter.
It's big, so we should get
urology to weigh in.
Is Catherine Fox
here today?
For a kidney stone?
My boys already lost
their mother.
Irene's her sister and the only
family they have left.
So, yes,
I want the best.
Nurse Hydren to
the OR. Nurse Hydren to the OR.
Well, there he is.
This is happening?
It is definitely
happening.
I hope this wasn't
a bad time.
I abandoned a play date,
and I need a calendar
to remember the last time
I operated.
So,
definitely not a bad time.
How severe is it?
See for yourself.
Crosswalks,
am I right?
Okay, folks,
let's get the OR ready
with the ex-fix set
and the C-arm.
Let's fix this bad boy. Mm.
And, Dr. Webber?
Thank you so much.
Sorry to keep paging you,
Dr. Pierce,
but her breathing is becoming
more labored by the hour.
Let's consider BiPAP if she
continues to decompensate.
But it may be time
to consider next steps.
There's no directive.
Marcella says
that her daughter
will be making all decisions
for her.
Then...
it's time to call her.
Hi. Who's calling?
Jackson?
Maggie, over here.
Rig brought her in
about half an hour ago.
Hey, Dr. Pierce.
Dr. Fox, thank you
for coming in.
I know how busy you must be,
so I appreciate you being here.
I told you not to give me
special treatment.
Did you pull strings?
He pulled
the biggest one.
I sign his checks.
Dr. Wilson?
Irene Davis, 35, nephrolithiasis
with a history of MS.
These are her scans
and a CT. Mm. Mm-hmm.
They say
it's kidney stones.
Which is apparently
my fault.
I did not say that.
She gets some very strong teas
from her acupuncturist
to help manage
her MS pain.
You got to drink a lot of water
to flush those out.
- Which she knows.
- Which she usually does.
So, this stone is apparently
lodged in your ureter.
That's the tube between
your kidney and your bladder.
I'm going to have to perform
a lithotripsy...
That's a procedure
with a tiny, tiny laser
that breaks it down
into smaller pieces.
Broken into pieces?
That's what killed
my sister.
No, this is nothing like
the morcellator, Irene.
If it was, I wouldn't let it
anywhere near you.
So it's safe?
Completely routine.
Takes about 45 minutes,
in typical cases.
I have MS.
Am I still a typical case?
No.
Because you have me
for your doctor.
See you in the OR.
Another screw, please.
Everything okay?
Yes.
Mm-hmm.
I just wanted to enjoy
the moment. Mm-hmm.
Lord knows when
it'll happen again.
After this,
we'll secure the frame.
You'd never know you didn't do
three of these this morning.
Well, I didn't.
But I did change
three diapers.
One was what Amelia has dubbed
the "poo-tastrophe."
That's when the poo
actually kind of explodes
out of the diaper
and hits the wall.
Got it. That is impolite
adult conversation.
Sorry, I rarely get
to talk to adults. Mm.
Wait. What happened?
Heart rate's in the 120s
and his sats are dropping.
He could have thrown a
fat embolism. Oh, come on!
A-Alright, push fluids,
and let's get him packed up
for a CTA.
Did you call
your mom?
I did, and she was
at a grocery store,
which I have asked her
not to go to
at least
a hundred times.
She's stubborn,
like you.
Marcella?
Marcella, Veronica's just been
admitted to the hospital.
No. No.
She was mild.
I know.
But her symptoms became
more pronounced.
Use your time with her,
not me.
Marcella,
you need care, too.
I don't care about me!
Save my baby girl!
Okay. Come on.
But my mom's still alive.
She is,
but she isn't improving.
Veronica, we need to know
whether your mom would want
a machine to breathe for her if
she... No, no. She wants to live.
So instead of scaring
the hell out of me,
can you go
and concentrate on that?
Do whatever you can
to save her.
Maybe now's not
the best time, Maggie.
It may be the only time.
This is my fault.
I'm so sorry.
I'm so, so sorry.
Her sats are in the 80s.
I'm gonna increase the O2.
This is my fault.
All of this.
I-It was her birthday,
and...
and she'd...
She'd been alone
so long,
so I went over to her house
to... to cook for her.
We wore masks
and we ate outside
and w-we... we tried
to stay distanced,
but it was her birthday,
and she's my mom,
so I gave her a hug.
I just gave her one hug.
And I might have killed her.
I killed my mom.
No, no, no, no.
Listen to me.
This is not
your fault, okay?
And I promise you, your mom
will never regret that hug.
Never.
Okay?
And, listen, my daughter's
a doctor here, too.
And she's with your mom
right now,
and she's taking care
of her, okay?
It's okay.
Down that hallway
is PACU.
That's recovery.
This is
a supply closet.
Nice. Here we have
someone's office.
You're an incredible
tour guide.
Well, not much to see
in a pandemic.
Is she here today, or are you
keeping me from her?
She? Who's she?
Come on, Mac.
The boys tell me
everything.
Said you've been talking about
somebody that you work with,
a general surgeon?
I work with several
general surgeons.
Oh, okay.
Do you smile when you talk
about all of them?
I'd like to meet her.
Yeah, well, you can't.
Why?
'Cause she's on a breathing tube
in the ICU.
Mac...
again?
I'll, uh...
check in on you
after the procedure.
Yeah, okay.
Well, he's stable,
but with that large
of an embolism,
he's gonna have to stay
on the vent
for at least
a few days.
This never
should have happened!
I know
I'm a little rusty,
and I probably shouldn't
have been talking
about exploding diapers,
but...
No, I am not angry at you,
Lincoln.
This was
a... a complication.
I mean, there's nothing
you could
or should have done better.
I'm just angry
with this whole situation!
I mean, saving
this young man's life
means we're down
to one available vent!
Which now means I have to close
the doors to our trauma!
Which means people will die
unnecessarily!
Even more people
will die.
We're closing to trauma?
Looks like it.
Okay.
Cristina.
This is nice...
just being able
to talk to you.
What do you mean?
Well, I spend
a fair amount of time
trying to talk
to people.
Sofia, Callie, Arizona.
I try to warn them
sometimes.
Warn them about what?
I can't let go.
When you have
a little kid like that...
hard to let go.
So I hang out,
watch her grow up.
Sometimes I see
something coming.
Like the divorce?
Yep.
I stand beside them.
I yell in their ears, "Wake up!"
"Wake up!
You're missing it!
You're missing the best
part of life!"
When you love someone,
you tell them.
And then w-what do they do
when you yell in their ears?
Well, sometimes they listen.
Sometimes they hear me.
I never
get the credit, though.
They think
it's their own idea.
She looks
so much like you.
Ellis?
Everybody says she looks
like Meredith.
Yeah, she does, but also weirdly
just like you.
You really are sisters.
I'm not gonna ask.
You can. I just...
I don't know anything.
And Richard won't even let me
near the hospital
or any of the charts.
Well, that's because
you need a break,
not because
you did anything wrong.
DeLuca was not
your fault.
We all lost him.
That grief belongs
to all of us,
and it might...
be easier
if you learn to share that.
Is there a recovery program
for people who trash their lives
and can't blame drugs,
so that I can get some of that
sweet program
zen master stuff you have?
You don't have to be
an addict...
It's called therapy.
Hmm.
How many sessions
until Owen feels safe
to leave me alone
with the kids?
I tried therapy.
It makes me uncomfortable.
Mammograms make us
uncomfortable,
but we still get them.
Yeah, the man stared at me
and nodded
and grunted
on every fourth word.
I counted the grunts.
It was an... an expensive
kind of torture.
So, when the first therapist
you tried
was clearly the wrong fit,
did you...
try another one?
You know I was
just being nice
when I said
Ellis looked like you.
Now we're both
right side up.
How'd the mom take it?
How do you think?
Is it just me, or did this job
used to be fun?
Like, not even 10 years ago.
Like, very recently, fun.
This used to be the greatest job
in the world.
Please tell me
Veronica's okay.
Well, I'd hoped with
oxygen therapy and antivirals,
we'd see a better
response, but...
...that hasn't been
the case.
Crap.
I need you to get back in bed.
Take me back. Take me back.
I know, baby. I know.
Ortiz, what the hell?
Sweetheart.
No, no, no, no.
I found her halfway to the
elevator, almost collapsed. No.
Let's get you back in bed.
I need to...
Alright. I need to
see my mom, please.
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
Okay.
Please, I need to
see my mom. Okay.
We want to get you
feeling better first,
then we can talk about
visitation, okay? No, no.
Everyone here is dying,
and you guys have no clue
how to save us,
so at least
let me see my mom.
Let me say goodbye.
Before...
Veronica.
Veronica? Hey!
Blood pressure's tanking.
Veronica?
I've got no pulse.
Alright, get me epi and
a crash cart in here, now!
Okay.
I want to start compressions
right away.
Okay, go, go, go.
Come on, Veronica.
Here we go.
You're doing great,
Marcella.
Stay positive.
If you can make it to Friday
without needing a vent...
you're on your way.
You know, we're, um...
We're almost there,
because it's...
♪ Hump Day ♪
♪ What do you say? ♪
♪ You look at the week
and you say, "Half way!" ♪
♪ Half what? Half way ♪
♪ That's 'cause
it's Hump Day ♪
♪ The next thing you know,
it's gonna be Friday ♪
My mom gives me
that exact same look
every time
I do that rap.
Mnh-mnh.
No, no, that is not rap.
Oh, God.
She's decompensating.
I need a crash cart
in here, now!
And someone page Dr. Pierce!
What? Are you sure you don't
want to wait until the...
No! Her saturation levels
are plummeting and...
Code Blue. Code Blue.
Oxygenate patient.
Uh, prep induction
and paralytic agent.
Uh, ch-check, uh,
pa... patent cuff.
Tube ready?
Code Blue. Code Blue.
You're in.
No. No!
Schmitt, what did you do?
She was desaturating.
I had no choice.
Now, can we please get
a ventilator in here?
Oh, my God.
There isn't one.
Removing the last few
pieces of stone.
Stent?
Stent's gonna stay in place
to ensure proper drainage.
You know, you have
a really good touch, Wilson.
We don't have nearly enough
women in urology.
Have you ever considered
changing specialties?
Change specialties?
That would be just...
No.
I... No.
Uh, n-no. No.
Mm.
Okay, all done here.
Removing the scope.
Oh, my God.
Is that...?
I have never seen
this before,
only read about it
in a textbook.
This is
the patient's ureter.
Her tissues
are so friable,
the scope pulled
the whole damn thing out.
We're gonna have to
open her up.
Prepare an ex lap!
Veronica's X-rays show
worsening consolidations.
I put her on BiPAP.
Her oxygen levels
keep decreasing.
She needs this vent.
She needs to be in ICU.
Marcella is already
intubated.
Schmitt can't bag her
forever.
Well...
Save the daughter.
Protocols say you have to save
the patient
most likely to recover.
We know.
Yeah, we know.
If she wakes up and finds out
we chose her over her mother,
she's not gonna be able
to forgive herself.
Marcella's last words to me
were, "Save my baby girl."
Put Veronica on the vent.
Before somebody else
takes it.
How in the hell does her ureter
come out with a kidney stone?
We will try to reattach it
to her bladder
without having to remove
the kidney.
Irene is everything
to my boys, Wilson.
I mean, everything.
She's always been their aunt,
but now she's their teacher,
their football coach,
their... their therapist,
their best bloody friend.
I-I can't believe this.
I can't. I can't.
I can't.
I cannot do this again.
I cannot look at my boys,
who've already lost everything,
and tell them that
they've lost her, too.
I cannot... I cannot do
that. Okay, okay. Stop. Stop.
This is...
This is not a catastrophe,
this is a complication.
Then what in the hell
are you still doing here?
Get in there and
bloody fix her.
We've reached out to
every hospital in Washington.
I never imagined...
I know.
Schmitt, you did
the right thing.
Another vent will come.
It has to, right?
Have a nice lunch?
I was updating
Dr. Hayes.
You had to take
the kidney?
The remaining piece
of the ureter wasn't long enough
to do a simple
reattachment.
But Irene has MS.
She could have bladder issues
in the future,
which would be much more
complicated
with just one kidney.
Why would she only have
one kidney?
What? I'm putting
it back, Wilson!
You're doing
an auto-transplant?
I am trying to!
It'd be a lot easier if I had
a second pair of hands.
Are you coming or not?
Yes. Yes.
Irrigation.
Child, who throws away
a kidney?
Lord.
Dr. Sikes to Recovery.
Thanks.
If she keeps breathing
over the vent consistently,
we should be able
to take her off it soon.
That's good to hear.
Be a shame if someone like me
got to walk away
while someone like her...
I'll, uh...
I'll get out of your way.
Hey, Tom?
When I got back
from Iraq, I, uh...
I remember thinking,
"Why do I get to
keep working?
Why do I get to
cook dinner?
Swim in a lake?
Fall in love?"
It's a terrible feeling.
I wouldn't wish it
on anyone.
Even me?
Tell me
your favorite thing.
About what?
About life.
Life right now.
There's
a global pandemic.
That
is your favorite thing?
No.
I just meant that I don't...
Oh, okay.
You're saying
that the pandemic...
No, it just feels
very shallow
to talk about
my favorite things
when there's people dying
in record numbers.
Oh, yeah. Okay.
Alright.
Well, that's...
That's stupid.
Excuse me?
You're saying that you're not
allowed to enjoy your life
because people are dying
in record numbers?
That makes
exactly zero sense.
If the having of a life
and a body
isn't cause
for celebration,
then what's the point
of avoiding death?
I mean, just... if you're not
gonna enjoy it,
then you might as well
join them.
Bailey just had a birthday
and I asked him what he wanted,
and he said a whole cake,
all to himself.
He did not want
to share.
So, of course,
I got him the cake.
And so, do you know what he did
as soon as he got that cake?
What?
Faceplant.
Just planted his face
smack in the middle of the cake.
And we laughed and laughed
and laughed.
It was me and Zola
and Ellis
and Maggie and Amelia
and Link.
Zola laughed so hard,
she peed her pants,
so then we had a laugh
at that.
And then
as we were laughing,
Bailey started licking
the frosting off each finger
really slow and making
a whole production out of it.
And I looked at him
watching us laugh,
and I realized that
that was the point.
That was his plan... he wanted
to make us all laugh,
because the baby had been
keeping us up all night
and the pandemic was
all over the news,
and none of us were having
any fun at all,
and nobody was laughing,
and he wanted to make us laugh.
Yeah.
And that's what he wanted
for his birthday.
And when I looked at him and
I saw that light in his eyes,
he looked
just like his dad.
That same sparkle.
That same delight.
That's a pretty good
favorite thing.
If I'd known I was going to
have to choose
whether to vent a mother
or her daughter,
I would have quit
med school.
If I'd seen a tenth of what
I've seen these past few months,
I would have quit, too.
We shouldn't even
be here.
How did we get here?
Let's quit.
Don't go back
to Boston.
We've got each other.
We've got our earbuds.
Let's just live
while we can.
I'll go where you go.
But we both know
you won't let yourself quit.
Take a break, okay?
I'll check on
your patients.
We can share earbuds.
And...?
What if they can share
a vent?
Tell Schmitt
to keep bagging!
The machines
are capable of delivering
much stronger pressure
than any one patient needs.
And we just need
to adapt the vents
to serve
two patients at once
by using a T- or a Y-shaped
splitter on the airflow tube.
And we're using viral filters
to prevent cross-contamination
of particles
between patients.
All of this
was Pierce's idea.
It's not ideal,
but it buys us some time
until we get some
reinforcements.
Yes!
Hey!
Hey, hey!
Uh-huh.
Uh-uh-uh.
Richard, you okay?
I am so good.
I just have to dance
because you all doubled
the amount of vents
we have in the hospital.
I have to dance because we can
now open the doors to trauma,
and you have to dance
because you just got a raise.
Oh, hey!
Oh! I'll dance to that.
Keep an eye on their vitals
and get labs every hour.
Page me for any change,
no matter how small.
Mom...
Come here, mamita.
I know.
It's okay.
It's alright, baby.
I know.
Your vitals look good,
and you are making urine.
One of my party tricks.
You'll be able to go home
in three days
if your pain's under control.
Wilson?
Thank you.
For, um...
Just thank you.
Okay.
She single?
Who... Wilson?
Yeah.
I don't know. Why?
You trying to set me up?
I was hoping
you could set me up.
Mm-hmm.
I mean, she did have my kidney
in her hands.
It doesn't get more intimate
than that.
Uh-huh. Have you
checked on the boys?
Austin's supposed to be reading
"Animal Farm,"
and I'm worried he hasn't
made it past page 50.
Page 50?
We'll be lucky if he's even
opened the book.
Her lungs are clear.
Her ABGs are showing
improved oxygenation,
and she's passed her SBTs.
Her vitals are normalized.
Okay.
Prepare to extubate.
Suction, please.
Okay, here we go.
♪ When your heart's burning
like a forest fire ♪
So, life is pain, right?
Life is pain,
and somehow that's the point?
No.
I lost you both.
I lost George.
I lost my parents, and
even before my parents died...
They caused you
a lot of pain.
So much grief.
So much loss.
So much pain.
Yes.
Yeah, but what's the thing
that caused the pain?
♪ Your thoughts
are getting too deep ♪
I hate this.
♪ And when the summer nights
are getting colder ♪ Hate what?
You knowing things
that I don't.
What's
the thing that caused the pain?
I know it,
I just don't want to say it.
Stubborn
as you ever were.
The depth of grief that you felt
with all the losses...
It's because
of the depth of love.
As long as you're alive,
you get to feel it
and you get to do something
about it.
Everything changes all the time
when you're alive,
and all the time,
you fight the change.
You cling onto what you have
and what you know
like that's how
it should always be.
It's such a waste
of life.
Right?
What's a waste?
Fighting change.
Resisting pain.
♪ Oh, you gotta get up
and just keep on going ♪
I miss you both so much.
That's kind of a waste
of time, too.
Why?
Because
we never left you.
Sometimes we're right next
to you, yelling in your ear.
Don't waste it,
Meredith.
Waste what?
Don't waste
one single minute.
♪ Run, run like a river ♪
♪ Like a river
that runs to the sea ♪
The first minute in a
baby's life is the most terrifying.
In that minute,
a million tiny air sacs
have to perfectly open
and fill with air.
♪ A river that runs to the sea ♪
♪ You gotta run ♪
♪ Run, run, like a river ♪
♪ Run, run, like a river, run ♪
♪ Run, run like a river ♪
♪ Like a river
that runs to the sea ♪
- Whoo!
- ♪ You gotta run to me ♪
Whoo!
It's a pretty traumatizing way
of entering the real world. Yes!
♪ Like a river
that runs to the sea ♪
♪ You gotta run to me ♪
This is the first day in I don't
know how long...
...that I actually
liked my job again.
I felt inspired.
You were inspired.
By you.
Well, by my earbuds.
No, by us.
By these moments of...
Of joy and connection
that we've managed
to carve out.
I would not have had that idea
without you, Winston.
That life-saving idea,
it came from us.
And I know that
Boston needs you,
and I know that
I'm being selfish
when I say how miserable
I'm going to be if you go.
What are you doing?
Um...
I thought...
we could listen to something
before I leave.
I'm trying to tell you
I don't want you to leave.
I know, but I-I think you might
really like this song.
Oh, my God.
♪ Take my voice ♪
Winston.
I still have my loose ends
to tie up back home.
♪ And make it louder ♪
So you have an out,
if you want one.
♪ Make it wilder, set it free
♪ But I hope to God you don't.
I hope you say yes...
♪ And take my words ♪
...because I can't imagine life
without you anymore.
♪ Give me something ♪
♪ To believe in ♪ And
I don't ever want to try.
♪ And if all I can do is sing ♪
Margaret Pierce...
♪ I'm gonna sing louder ♪
...will you marry me?
In that minute,
your whole world stops.
♪ I'm gonna sing louder
♪ Is that a yes?
Yes. It's a yes.
♪ Let it out ♪
Whoo!
It's as if time stands still.
Well, today ended a lot better
than it started.
♪ Oh, but it's not that easy ♪
Your mom is so scary.
What?
Why would you bring up my mom
while we're laying here
naked?
What's wrong with you?
Come here.
And if I'm being honest,
that minute is pure hell.
Ahh! Look what I caught
in the laundry room
when I was scrubbing down.
I caught myself a Leofish!
♪ That all I want
is a little peace ♪
Hey, Zola.
We, um...
We took your mom off
the ventilator today,
and she's breathing
on her own.
Yes! Thank God!
Bailey! Ellis! Scout!
Hope that was alright.
That's fine.
This is amazing.
Oh, my God.
Thank you!
But fortunately,
most of the time,
the crying starts,
the baby's okay...
Don't thank me.
Thank...
Thank Teddy.
She, uh... She's the one
who never gave up.
She stayed with her
night after night.
I just... I just did
what the numbers told me.
...and the rest of us
in the room
can finally breathe again.
♪ Oh, let it out ♪
He lives with his family, six
people.
It's a matter of public health,
just book him a hotel.
On you. You sure?
We got you a hotel
I told the paramedics to save me
first.
Over him, my husband.
Yikes. Well maybe you can blame
that on a brain bleed.
A lot of people panic on their
wedding day, I know I did.
Doctor Hunt knows.
Does this hurt?
Ow. Ya
GET INTO AN ALL NEW GREYS
ANATOMY
THEN STREAM ANYTIME ON THE ALL
NEW CTV.CA AND CTV APP