Good morning.
To what do I owe this?
It's been a great few days.
I kind of wish it
wasn't going to end.
Ah, me neither.
The thought of
getting on that train...
You know, I was thinking...
Maybe I'd stay in
Chicago some nights
when I have to
work the next day.
Stay where?
I don't know, maybe Doug's.
Doug's?
You disapprove?
Well, it's just the thought
of all those pretty girls
padding around
in their underwear.
Yeah. Beats the YMCA.
You have nothing to worry about.
But it was my understanding
that a sub-internship
involved more responsibilities.
What do you want to do, Carter,
Whipples? Trisegmentectomies?
I just I'd be following
my own patients around
instead of assisting on yours.
Uh-huh. What do
we got? This is Ed.
I'm thirsty, doc.
When we're finished,
I'll get you some water.
How about a Scotch
and water? Carter...
Patient experienced
shortness of breath
while sitting on his
stool at Molly's Saloon.
BP, 120/80. Pulse,
112. Respirations, 28.
History of emphysema,
congestive heart failure,
pneumonia.
Upon auscultation, diminished
breath sounds were noted
at the base of the
patient's right lung.
Intrigued, I tested
vocal fremitus
per Bates, second edition,
leading me to a diagnosis
of pleural effusion
confirmed by this radiograph
which shows fluid
in the patient's right...
costophrenic sulcus.
Thank you, Professor Carter.
So what do you want to do?
Tap the fluid. Tap?
How many pleural
taps have you done?
Eight or nine.
Run the procedure.
Prep and drape in the
usual manner, anesthetize...
What's on tap?
Procure a 14-gauge needle...
All right, Carter. Call
me if you need me.
Oh, and, Carter,
consider Ed here your patient.
Uh, Harper,
have you ever
seen a pleural tap?
It's 2B, guys.
Getting tired of life in
the fast lane, Hathaway?
Just of your jokes, Shepherd.
Fifteen more
minutes, I'm recertified.
I won't have to
hear any of them.
Yoo-hoo. Up here.
Those were jokes?
Whoa!
Smells like he's gone already.
I wish!
♪ That hasn't got a ghost... ♪
Been sitting there for weeks
using himself as a toilet.
He hasn't paid his
rent in six months.
I'm losing tenants
because of his smell.
This guy must weigh a ton.
How are we supposed to move him?
I brought a dolly.
Man, his BP's 220/130.
We'd better take him in.
Do I have to?
You don't want to
go to the hospital?
I'd rather stay here
with my rabbits.
All right, well, if he
doesn't want to go...
Oh, no, now you
wait just a minute.
The sheriff said you'd take him.
Hey, hey, lady, we don't run
an eviction service, all right?
You can't just leave him.
He doesn't want to come.
He's not competent
to make that decision.
How do we know that?
Look at him.
♪ I'm a mousetrap
Without a piece of cheese ♪
♪ I'm Vienna Without
the Viennese... ♪
So he's eccentric.
♪ I'm da Vinci Without
the Mona Lees... ♪
Mona Lees?
♪ When I'm without you... ♪
I just cleaned the rig.
Shep...
♪ ...without a hitching post ♪
♪ I'm a network Without
a coast-to-coast... ♪
Raul?
♪ Just a poached egg
That hasn't got a toast ♪
♪ When I'm without you... ♪
Ready?
I'm ready.
One... two... three!
Good morning, Jerry.
Hey, Dr. Lewis.
Hello, little girl.
Yeah.
Hello. How's Chloe?
She's become disenchanted
with computer classes.
She's now going
to find her bliss
at the diesel mechanics academy.
Ah, good school.
How come I'm signed up
for four patients already?
Courtesy of Doc Weaver.
I'm not on for
another 10 minutes.
Eight.
Morning, baby.
Kerry, I appreciate
the vote of confidence,
but I'm used to signing up
for patients one at a time.
Mark and I decided
residents should carry
at least four patients.
There's a memo in your email.
Jerry, are my labs ready?
I'm on a tight deadline,
so the interviews
have to be today.
Harv from Radiology's
coming down at noon
to take your picture.
All right. Morning, Susan.
Yeah, right.
What publication is this?
Nursing newsletter.
The swimsuit issue?
I'm doing a cover story
on our newest Attending,
and I want quotes
from all of you,
so get your thinking caps out.
You're a shameless
self-promoter.
Yeah, yeah.
Nice shirt, Jer.
Consent on Bed 5.
Just leave it.
I need your Juan Hancock.
Hey, Jeanie.
Look, uh, we need to talk.
- 00, same spot.
Any problems,
beep me, all right?
Girlfriend?
♪ I'm a doctor
Without a single pill ♪
♪ I'm a dentist
Without a tooth to fill... ♪
Carotid bruits, papilledema.
Mitchell?
Yes?
Do you have headaches
or loss of consciousness?
Uh, sometimes I-I-I
sort of... Sort of drift off.
Well, it's a good
thing that you're here.
He's at risk
for a cerebral hemorrhage.
Let's start him
with a Nipride drip
and get a CT.
Okay.
Can I borrow a pen? Mm-hmm.
Burning the candle?
Uh. Paramedic
ride-along all night.
♪ I'm Las Vegas
Without a slot machine ♪
♪ I'm a gypsy
Without a tambourine ♪
♪ I'm Napoleon ♪
♪ Without his Josephine... ♪
Hey! How's he doing?
He's clean.
Yeah, that's more than I can say
for my rig.
What's the matter, Mitchell?
What's going to
happen to my rabbits?
Oh, they'll be okay.
How?
Who's gonna feed them?
No.
No. No way.
If nobody feeds them,
they're all gonna die.
Shep?
Okay, what happened?
Mother couldn't wake
him up from his nap.
Okay. Is he breathing?
Barely. His pulse is weak.
Could he have
swallowed something?
No, I don't think so.
Has he been sick? Yes.
Is he on any kind of medication?
Yes.
Bactrim, phenytoin, AZT...
AZT? He's got AIDS?
AIDS? Yes.
We've got Dilantin.
You have him on phenytoin
and Dilantin at the same time?
Yes. Yes.
It's the same thing.
He's OD'd on Dilantin.
He's not breathing.
All right, let's get an
intubation tray, damn it.
I give too much?
Yes, you gave too
much. Way too much.
What do you need, Doug?
CBC, Chem-7. Pull that
thing off. There we go.
Get a Dilantin level
and set up for a
gastric lavage kit.
We're going to have
to pump his stomach.
I'm holding the head.
Okay, here we go.
He's in.
All right, bag him.
Let's get that lavage.
Come on, little guy.
I need Cetacaine.
Grab some Surgilube
and 30 grams of charcoal.
You go in
right over the top
of rib number eight...
at the posterior axillary line,
advancing and
aspirating as you go.
I've got to call home.
Your wife?
Oh, no, not for me.
Why buy the cow
when you get the milk for free?
Take care to avoid
the neurovascular bundle.
I've got to call
Olaf, my roomie.
I left a half a
sandwich in the fridge,
and I don't want
anything to happen to it.
Now is not a good time,
because we're
about to draw fluid.
I'll bet he's over at Molly's.
Who's Molly?
She's a bar. My bar.
Voila.
Ah...
Oh, that's better.
That's better.
Oh...
Ah...
Why'd it stop?
Sometimes you hit an adhesion.
Damn.
Should I get Benton?
No.
Whoops!
What'd you do? What'd you do?
I'm gonna get Benton.
No, he's my patient.
Yeah, yeah. Get
him, get him, get him.
Dilantin level's 40.
Double dose. No surprise.
What's her name?
Ma'am, what's your name?
Mei-Sun.
What's your little boy's name?
Chia-Chia.
Let me tell you what
we're doing, okay?
Now, we've washed
all the medicine out,
and now we're putting charcoal
into Chia-Chia's stomach
to absorb what's left.
Doug? Hmm?
Hey. Hi, buddy.
Don't be scared, all right?
You got a little sick,
and your mom brought
you to the hospital.
She's right here.
Mm-hmm. Come on.
What happened?
I pushed it too far.
Oh, damn it, Carter, you
were supposed to tap his lung,
not biopsy his liver.
Let's get him up
to the O.R., now!
He needs a room. Move!
I don't believe this.
There goes next year's
surgical residency.
Carter!
I've known Mark Greene
since he was a
wet-behind-the-ears med student.
He had the most
beautiful curly blond hair,
and so polite.
All I'd do was ask,
and he would be
cleaning the bedpans
and changing the sheets, and...
he was the best
scut-puppy I ever had.
So would you say that back
then he was sort of green?
No, Wendy, I would
never say that.
Okay, retract
the liver inferiorly
and rotate the right lobe.
Oh, there she blows.
Hit the hepatic vein.
Nice shot, Carter. 5-O proline.
I'm really sorry, Dr. Hicks.
It's just that when I felt
resistance, it felt exactly
like an adhesion I'd
encountered before,
and with the patient's
history of emphysema,
I just figured that...
Oh, one-handed. Peter,
you've been practicing.
I'm really sorry...
Carter, it happens.
It's all right.
My best student once
did a sigmoidoscopy...
Punched through
and saw the appendix.
Sound familiar, Peter?
Metz.
What I'm more
concerned about now
is the condition
of this man's liver.
Feel that.
Hard as a rock,
and shriveled like an old shoe.
Gallon-a-day drinker.
At least.
Look at the size of
those mesenteric veins.
What does that
suggest to you, Carter?
Portal hypertension.
And what are the hallmarks
of portal hypertension?
Caput medusa,
esophageal varices,
hemorrhoids, ascites,
splenomegaly.
Good.
I wouldn't give this
liver three weeks.
NG's returning blood.
Varices are bleeding.
Lucky we're here to
do something about it.
Portal bypass?
We could, but with
a liver this oozy...
Have you ever done
a TIPS procedure?
No, but I'd like to.
I bet.
In fact, it's an excellent
case for teaching.
Sylvia...
round up all surgical residents
who aren't busy.
Tell them we're starting a TIPS.
Standing room only.
What do you know, Carter...
You did this guy a favor.
Mr. Holthouse?
Yes?
I'm Dr. Lewis. What is that?
Tibetan singing bowl.
I get anxious in hospitals.
It helps me to relax.
Oh. I understand you're
feeling dizzy this morning.
Yes, I've had these
spinning sensations
on and off all week.
Headaches?
No, some nausea, though.
Spots before your eyes?
No.
Say, you're under a
lot of stress right now,
aren't you?
Who isn't?
Yes, I can see the
tension in your face.
I could suggest some
relaxation techniques.
Thanks,
but I'm a lot more
relaxed than I look.
Open your mouth.
Hey, big guy.
Love the tie.
Thank you, Malik.
Thank you very much.
What's the occasion?
Well, since you asked,
I've been promoted.
To what?
Supervising
emergency-service coordinator.
Ah, more money, huh?
Uh, unfortunately, no.
Oh.
Better benefits?
No.
More responsibility.
Well, congratulations.
Mark, that big guy,
Mitchell, he's seizing.
All right, make some room.
Bite block.
Point-five Ativan IV push.
Positive Babinski.
Pinpoint pupils.
Does not bode well.
Pressure's up, 250/140.
All right. Jack up the Nipride.
Let's load him up with
Dilantin. How much?
Uh, let's see. He's
about, uh, 400 pounds
divided by 2.2 is, uh...
181 kilograms.
Times 12 milligrams per kilogram
would be, uh...
Uh, 2,730.
I have a facility
for simple math.
All right, we'll
start with a gram,
and we'll titrate up.
Come on, Mitchell, stay with us.
Stay with us, Mitchell. Come on.
Vitals are coming
back to normal.
Let's get him to Pedes ICU, huh?
Hey, there, Chia-Chia,
how you doing?
I'm Doug.
He doesn't like doctors.
I'll bet he sees a lot of us.
Where do you take him?
The pediatric clinic upstairs.
Who's the doctor?
Always a different one.
Yeah, they're
pretty busy up there.
Yes. Very nice, but sometime,
we wait four, five hour.
It's hard for him.
Now, I have to make sure
that this medication problem
doesn't happen again,
so I have to ask you...
Can you read English?
Yes!
I follow direction.
This one from two week ago,
and this one from yesterday.
He gave you two
prescriptions for the same thing.
You did exactly what
they asked you to.
I'm sorry that I
was angry with you.
This is not your fault.
This is the doctors
at the clinic's fault.
Okay. All right.
Next time, you
bring Chia-Chia here.
You give this to
the nurse out front,
and she will bring you
straight back, no waiting.
Okay?
Oh-ho-ho-ho.
I thought he
didn't like doctors.
Chia-Chia, no.
That's okay.
He can hang on
to it for a while.
You can keep that.
Mr. Holthouse?
Over here.
I see you're
feeling much better.
Yeah, but I still have
that spinning feeling,
even upside-down.
Have a seat.
Tony will take you
for a CAT scan.
Doesn't that cause cancer?
Susan, a word, please?
Why are you ordering
a CT for vertigo?
Why are you
questioning my order?
Because it's a $1500 procedure.
I have to rule out
acoustic neuroma.
He's had five bouts
of dizziness in a week.
Well, you wouldn't know
that by looking at his chart.
I haven't had time to
write down my notes yet.
I've had other patients.
So do I, and I manage
to keep track of details.
So have I, on my note cards.
Well, I don't have
access to those, do I?
Here.
Put them on the chart,
and in the future, run
all procedures by me.
Hey, what happened?
Subarachnoid hemorrhage.
He went just like that.
What are you doing with him?
Landlady called animal control.
They were rounding them up.
It was awful.
This guy followed
me down the hall.
Is he clean?
Sure, he's clean,
and he's soft too.
Poor fat guy, he
never hurt anybody,
just sat around with his bunnies
singing that nutty song.
♪ I'm a mousetrap ♪
♪ Without a piece Of cheese ♪
♪ I'm... ♪
What was it?
Vienna.
♪ Without the Viennese ♪
♪ I'm da Vinci ♪
♪ Without the Mona Lees ♪
♪ When I'm without you ♪
Mona Lees?
No, he is a patient of
yours. Chia-Chia Loew.
He's a 4-year-old with AIDS?
Well, try to remember,
because you almost killed him
by giving him a
Dilantin prescription
when one of your cohorts
already had him on phenytoin.
Don't you people
talk to each other?
Making friends again?
Idiots at the Pedes clinic
doubled up a kid's prescription
and almost killed him.
Get her off my back.
Her? Weaver.
She just dressed me
down in the hallway
for ordering a CT.
Ah, we're getting a lot
of pressure from upstairs.
She scours my charts
looking for errors,
she treats me with disdain.
Want me to talk to her?
Yeah. Tell her to
cut me some slack.
See how Peter's
snaking the sheath
through the vena cava
to the right hepatic vein?
I'm in.
Now comes the fun part.
Remove the guide wire.
Rotate the needle
counterclockwise
90 degrees. Pressure's
dropping, 80/60.
Give him pressors
and keep me posted.
Now, puncture
the cirrhotic tissue
and enter the portal vein,
creating a new pathway.
Balloon stent's in.
Expand the balloon...
slowly.
Easy...
We have circulation.
Portal pressure's coming down.
And the liver is reborn.
Hallelujah.
He's getting tachy. 180.
Well, we fixed his liver,
there's not much we
can do for his heart.
Run of five.
Get out of there, Peter.
All right, I'm getting out
He's fibrillating.
Carter, CPR.
Come on, Ed. Come on.
Charge it to 200.
Stand back.
Clear!
Hey, Kerry, how's it going?
Uh, pretty good.
Good.
But there's something
we need to talk about.
Oh?
Susan Lewis.
Oh.
This is a bit awkward.
I mean, I know
you two are friends,
but she seems to
resent my being here,
and it's creating some tension.
You know, I picked up on that.
I assure you, it has
nothing to do with her ability.
She's really quite competent,
but her attitude
is openly hostile.
It's probably a
communication thing.
I mean, you're very
authoritative, which is great,
but your assertiveness,
it might be off-putting to some.
Believe me, I'm aware of that.
That's why I've
bent over backwards
to be sensitive with Susan.
Uh-huh. I'd rather
you not say anything,
but I wanted to make you aware
that this is a potential
problem area.
Right. Thank you.
Uh-huh.
A picture-perfect
procedure, Benton.
Bev, save the tape, would
you? We'll share it at M&M.
Carter, you can present.
It'll be your first time.
I'll tell him.
My first official patient.
Carter, the guy
was a train wreck.
He died of heart failure.
It had nothing to do
with you perfing his liver.
Come on, if the guy hadn't
been on the operating table...
Then his liver
would have failed him in
a month, maybe sooner.
I'll tell the family.
He didn't have any.
Carter...
It's how you learn.
It'll make you a better doctor.
What can I say about Mark
Greene that hasn't already been said?
I think everybody knows
how he overcame adversity
as a child of Quakers,
his years in exile,
his political writings
and limericks,
his mod period
with the turtlenecks,
his blue period,
and, of course his
ruthless march to power,
and the silencing of his rivals.
Dr. Ross?
Hmm?
♪ I'm a doctor
Without a single pill... ♪
Which one do you think?
It's for the nursing newsletter?
Yeah. You think this one?
I'm looking for
the supervising emergency
service coordinator.
You've found him.
Oh, hi. I'm Randi.
I'm the new clerk.
I understand I'll be
working under you.
Uh... Right.
I, uh, I was expecting a
guy, because of the name.
Randi, right. Yeah,
I get that a lot.
Uh, personnel said
that you would have
some immunization
forms for me to fill out.
Right. Um...
you're going to need a rubella
and a Heptovax.
Lab's on the second floor.
And they said I would
need an employee physical,
and that somebody
here could do it.
Jerry, you got any charts
for me, any patients?
Anything?
All right. Well, I'll
be at Pedes ICU.
Carol, you've got to come quick.
What's up?
The 300-pound angel
duster broke out of restraints,
climbed on top of the ambulance.
What is this, crazy-fat-guy day?
Hey, I'm telling you.
This dude is mad.
Call security. Go
find Mark Greene.
The tests show there's
nothing seriously wrong.
I think your dizziness
is caused by labyrinthitis.
What's that?
Inflammation of the inner ear,
Very minor. Nothing serious.
Don't aggravate
it, it'll go away.
You swim?
No. I don't know how.
But I do spend a
lot of time floating
in my sensory deprivation tank.
Not for the next two
weeks, you don't.
Oh.
No standing on
your head, either.
Dr. Lewis?
I'd like for you to have this.
No, thanks.
Please. It's a spare.
It's not necessary, really.
I think it is.
Really.
Oh, God. Not another one.
Look out, Carol.
Relax. Hey, buddy, relax!
Take it easy.
Where's Mara? Mara!
Mara?
Wait, wait, just
back off, there.
What's he on?
PCP.
I got him!
Get away from me!
Don't you touch me!
Are you all right? Are you okay?
Nobody touches me! He's cut.
Stay here. I'm taking
him in. Come on.
Mara!
Where the hell's security?
My God! I can't
see! Let's shoot him.
Let me talk to him.
Make it stop! Make it stop!
Fine.
Okay. Okay.
Hey, what you doing
up there, big guy?
Mara?
Yeah. Why don't
you come down here?
It's much safer, okay?
Mara!
Yes, babe, come on down.
Where's Mara? Mara! Mara!
What are you doing?
Hey, what are you doing?
Hey, hey! No! No!
Oh, my God!
Hey!
Oh, Mark, did you
and you-know-who
have a you-know-what?
You bet.
Good.
And then, these extensions
are for internal use only.
Uh, Dr. Lewis?
Yeah?
Can you do an employee physical?
On? Randi?
Hi.
Hi. Breathe in.
Breathe out.
You're fine. Where's the form?
Uh, do you have my roommate
as a patient?
Uh, Ed Menke?
Yes. Uh, you...
You must be Olaf?
Uh-huh.
Uh, I'm afraid I have some...
Some bad news about... about Ed.
Uh-huh.
He... Well, he had
fluid in his lungs,
and during the course
of trying to remove it,
we... I... accidentally
punctured his liver.
We took him to the O.R.
and successfully
stopped the bleeding,
and did some additional surgery,
but, um, uh, unfortunately
his heart gave out, and, uh...
he died on the table.
I'm very sorry.
Yeah, they told
me that upstairs.
They said you had his property.
Property?
Yeah. He took the
remote-control doohickey.
It's his TV,
and he's kind of
tightfisted about it,
but, uh, I don't think
he's gonna mind now.
Double dose of Haldol.
Well, it's about time.
I can't see! Make it stop!
Look, why don't you
try and, you know...
Right, right, right, right.
Hey! Hey...
Hey, big guy!
Hi!
Hi. So... Are you from Chicago?
Ah, Jeez.
Um...
Come on. Come on.
You can do better
than that, huh?
You weren't even close.
Come on.
Oh, God!
0 and 2, big guy.
Come on. Why don't you just
try to put some mustard on it.
That's it. That's it.
Yeah! Yes!
Bull's-eye.
Nice work.
With a regimen of
ultrasound and TENS,
it's possible
he could regain
the use of his legs...
Jeanie!
You get my message?
Yeah.
All right. 7:00.
Found him on the
floor of his jail cell,
spitting blood.
Swallowed a dozen razor blades.
Suicide try?
Who knows.
Maybe he wanted a field trip.
Set up for endoscopy?
Yeah, get a KUB.
I'll need a rat
tooth on the scope
so I can grab the
blades. Coming through!
Hey, Chloe, what are
you doing up here?
Oh, hi. Just talking to my baby.
Oh, hey, why don't you
listen to her breathing?
Sounds like she's got
pneumonia or something.
She's gurgling.
Oh.
Come here. Yeah.
You picking little Susie up?
What? You picking
little Susie up?
Oh, no. I'm just going to
take her for a little walk.
Big Susie know that you're here?
Uh...
You know, I'm going
to go wait outside.
You okay?
Yes, I'm just a
little tired, that's all.
Well, see you.
No bleeding in the
esophagus or antrum.
H & H back yet?
Normal. Fourteen and 42.
Ah, got one. Razor
blade coming up.
How's his pressure?
120/80.
Won't that slice up his throat?
Nope,
because he taped the blades.
So much for suicide.
What's this about, Curtis?
Not trying to escape, are you?
What's this?
Prisoner swallowed razor blades.
No blood in the gut? No.
You're done. Pull out the scope.
He's already tubed.
I'm not gonna stop now.
I told you, no procedures
without going through me.
Go get Mark.
Dr. Greene!
We need you in Trauma 1.
What's up, guys?
Prisoner swallowed taped razors.
I want to pull them out.
Kerry wants to leave them.
His gut's not bleeding.
It could. Hasn't yet.
I say, let them pass.
It's a judgment call, guys.
Well, if he bleeds, we
go in, we take them out.
For now, pull the scope out.
Excuse me.
Carter, you had a patient
named Menke, right?
Yeah. Why?
Dr. Hicks had pathology
take out his liver
for some cirrhosis study
at the Stendhal clinic.
She said you should
arrange to get it over there.
Ugh. Ugly little
thing, ain't it?
Ay. Qué feo.
An exciting case?
Here's one.
Guy comes in,
hypervolemic shock.
Defibrillated 10, 15 times.
We maxed out on lidocaine,
added bretylium.
Finally, shocked
him back to sinus.
He goes bradycardic.
So I float a transvenous
pacemaker, get capture,
he stops breathing.
I had to climb on
intubate him, cowboy-style,
right there on the table.
Wow.
Yeah.
What happened?
He died.
Please enter
the patient's number
before proceeding.
Jerry...
Dr. Weaver loaded
an audio program
onto the computer.
With her own voice!
Where's Greene?
He and Dr. Ross
went to the gift shop.
Don't forget to log off.
Are you sure you don't mind?
Are you kidding? Mark, anytime.
Yeah? Well, how about tonight?
Now, tonight, I may have company
depending on the
weather patterns
over Greenland.
What?
Dr. Ross? Hi, Neil.
Next time you get the
urge to pick up the phone
and start screaming
at one of my residents,
ask for me instead...
One of your
residents screwed up...
Well, you're not in a position
to make that judgment.
Your job is hanging by a thread,
and I'm the guy with the knife!
You pull this
prima-donna crap again,
and it'll take more
than your friend here
to save you.
Hey, didn't see
much of you today.
Whatever happened to old Ed?
Ed?
Yeah.
They transplanted him?
He died.
From the tap?
No.
Not directly.
So are they taking
away your sub-i?
Are you kidding? Hicks
and Benton were so excited
about getting to do
a TIPS on the guy,
they were glad I screwed up.
Thing is, I didn't
really care, either.
When I put the needle through,
all I thought was
"there goes my surgical career."
So here he is.
What a way to go, huh?
Well, from the looks of things,
he knew how to have a good time.
What do you say we
give him a sendoff?
What?
Get your coat.
Hey...
Quite a day, huh?
I'm telling you.
Head okay?
Yeah.
Knock on wood.
Hey, I'm sorry about that.
Yeah.
Don't worry about it.
Hey, we were...
we were pretty
good out there today.
Not bad, huh?
Uh, we should go out.
Really? Definitely.
Well, right now's not a
really good time for me, but...
I've got your number.
You going to blow
me off just like that?
No.
Look, I'm just getting
over a relationship, so...
Good night.
You know what your
problem is, Hathaway?
You've gone out
with too many doctors.
You've been checking up on me?
I'm... I'm interested, so I ask.
You're shopping
in the wrong part of the store.
What?
You're lost among the Guccis.
And... And where should I be?
Automotive.
Shaw's, Friday night, 8:00?
Okay.
Hey, buddy.
Hey...
What's the matter?
It's my fault.
No, it's not your fault.
I told you. It's the
doctors at the clinic.
No, it's my fault he has AIDS.
I gave it to him.
No, that's nobody's fault.
I gave it to him, and
now he's sick, and I'm not.
It is punishment.
No.
It's okay.
Peter, what are you doing here?
I waited 45 minutes.
Wait, just hold on...
No, no, you hold on.
You couldn't even call me?
I was gonna call. So now
you're even lying to me?
What?
I thought we had enough
respect... enough going on
that we could at least
talk to each other.
I needed time to think.
Time? How much time?
Two weeks? A month?
What was I supposed to do,
get a postcard or something?
Keep your voice down.
No, don't tell me what...
Hi.
It's easy for you, Peter.
I'm the one who's had to
go home to my husband.
You just hand out ultimatums.
You demand answers. I...
I knew your answer... last week.
Peter...
What?
I'm not ready to walk
out on my marriage.
Yeah, right.
You, uh...
you take care of
yourself, all right?
What about
the weather over Greenland?
There's this stewardess
that I've been seeing.
Actually, I met her at work.
A patient?
Sort of. Put a cast on her.
Anyway, with her
flight schedule,
I never know when
she might show up.
Hmm.
Guess the weather was bad.
Well, it's just as well.
Is there a doctor in the house?
Hey...
Oh, hello.
Hulda, that's Mark.
Mark, that's Hulda.
Hello.
You know, the, uh, Finns
are remarkably unselfconscious.
I see that.
I cooked you a lutefisk.
Great.
Set your bag down. Come on.
Yeah.
Now, we are out of here...
Susie! Hey, Susie!
Chloe?
Hey!
Who are you with?
Oh, that's my friend, Ruth.
Hi, Ruth!
Oh, God, you're loaded.
Oh, come on.
Chloe!
Look, hey, everything
is gonna be okay.
What are you on?
I'm going on a trip.
The hell you are.
The flea markets, Susie.
You can make a
fortune selling old stuff.
Just stay there, okay?
I'm gonna come
around, all right?
No, no, Susie, I can't.
We gotta go.
Damn it, Chloe,
You are not
abandoning this baby!
I'll be back.
I just gotta make us some
money, so I can buy us a house.
Chloe, what are you doing?
Don't! Don't do this.
I'm dying inside, Susie.
I gotta go.
No, I know. Chloe, it's fine.
Don't be mad. Please?
It is okay!
I just wanna do
something right, okay?
It's okay. No, I'm not...
I'm not... Chloe, it's okay!
Bye-bye, baby! Mama loves
you. No, Chloe, don't go. It's okay!
Chloe!
Bye-bye!
Chloe.
Chloe!
It's okay.
Bye-bye, baby!
Chloe!
This place is a lot
nicer than I expected.
Yeah, it's not bad.
What's that?
A liver.
What'll it be?
Whatever's on tap.
Cruel. Very cruel.
Two?
Yes, please.
Which stool's Ed's?
Your boyfriend's sitting on it.
You friends of his?
Uh, we knew him.
He's dead, you know.
We know.
To Ed.
♪ I'm a mousetrap Without
a piece of cheese... ♪
Thank you.
For what?
This was a good idea.
♪ I'm Vienna Without
the Viennese ♪
♪ I'm da Vinci ♪
♪ Without the Mona Lees ♪
♪ I'm skies without blue... ♪♪