It can be stressful
planning a wedding.
Had a couple last year
almost come to blows
over the table centerpieces.
We called it
the War of the Roseses.
Uh...
How are things
going for you all?
Will, Natalie?
I think we're coping
just fine.
Don't you think, Nat?
Mmm-hmm.
I mean, we work together
all the time, so that helps.
By that she means we're used
to fighting and stress.
I always tell couples
during Pre-Cana
that it's not the fighting
that undermines a marriage.
It's the not fighting.
Sorry, forgot
to put it on vibrate.
It is impossible to overstate
the importance
of communication
in building and sustaining
a healthy marriage.
Do you need to get that?
No, it's nothing.
I swear,
no more interruptions.
Where were we?
Yes... Uh...
Getting marriage advice
from a celibate man
is kind of hysterical.
Although
I didn't know that
"Don't go to bed angry"
dates back to Saint Paul.
I always thought
it was something from
Dear Abby or someone.
What's that about?
It's just Jay. I got
some errands to run.
How about I catch up
with you later at work?
Why don't I take you?
I've got time.
That's okay,
I can get an Uber.
Don't be silly. I like
running errands.
You know that.
I do.
Just the kind that
a bride-to-be shouldn't
necessarily be aware of.
Okay.
See you.
You need to keep
your phone on.
I told you I had
the Pre-Cana.
What couldn't wait?
Ray Burke.
You got to go see him today.
Yeah, we're
picking up chatter.
He's hosting some
thing tonight. We want
to get ears on it,
so come on. Let's go.
We gotta get you prepped.
Cesar, what do you got?
Forty-nine-year-old male,
high-speed motor vehicle
collision, GCS 9.
Baghdad.
You got a name?
Keith Yates, BP 94/70,
heart rate 122,
sat 93%
on a nasal cannula.
Mr. Yates, I'm Dr. Rhodes.
Can you understand
what I'm saying?
He's not lucid enough
to clear the C-spine.
Board and collar stay on.
Let's get him in there.
All right, on my count.
One, two, three.
All right,
multiple facial lacs,
open fracture
of the right tibia,
muffled breath sounds
on the left. Let's get
a chest X-ray.
Sternum took a lot of impact
here, guys. What happened?
He hit a stanchion
head on.
For some reason,
the airbags didn't deploy.
No seat belt either?
Mmm-mmm
Clear.
X-ray's up.
Big hemothorax on the left.
Let's set up for a chest tube.
Give him five of morphine,
two of midazolam.
Lidocaine.
Scalpel.
Tube.
Oh, glad to see
you're with us, Mr. Yates.
Bolus a liter of saline,
hang two units
of uncrossed blood.
I'm still alive.
Yes, you are.
I'm gonna do
a quick ultrasound
of your belly, okay?
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Okay. Okay. Okay.
Let me go!
I wanna die.
Why won't you let me die!
Have you ever seen
anything so beautiful?
Look.
Has your smile.
Mmm, I don't know.
Yes. Yes. I can tell.
I'm gonna go discharge
room three, okay?
I'm really happy
for you guys.
Thanks, April.
Can't believe how real
this is getting.
Well, I better get back
to the office.
Ethan.
Bernie.
Call me later, okay?
Okay.
Bye.
Bernie said you two
had a nice chat.
Not sure I'd describe it
as a chat per se,
but, yeah,
I heard him out.
God, you know,
I'm kind of blown away,
to be honest.
I mean,
you meet a guy in AA,
you got to be
a little reticent, right?
It's good he came in
with you today.
Thanks for
giving him a chance, Ethan.
Oh!
Hi.
Hey. So, is it
as awkward
as I imagined?
Eh. Father Brady was a doll.
Will, on the other hand...
What'd he do now?
I don't know.
It's like I was supposed
to be there for him,
and yet he was
barely there.
Probably just
pre-wedding jitters.
Unless you think
it's something
more serious?
No.
All right, then.
Okay.
Yeah.
It's bigger
than I thought.
It's small enough.
Trust me, you want it
to have a little heft
'cause it's easier to palm.
We up to speed?
Yeah.
Special Agent Ingrid Lee,
this is my brother, Will.
Hello, Will.
Hello.
You're not
supervising this?
I told you,
it's a joint task force,
so the FBI's gonna be
taking the lead.
The Bureau frowns on CIs
being handled by their own
family members.
It'll be cleaner this way.
All right, so the key
for you, Will,
will be to find a place
to stash the bug
so it's as close as possible
to where Ray likes to sit.
Anywhere
in the vicinity, bam,
open mic night
at the Ray Burke Comedy Club.
How am I supposed to do that
if he's sitting there?
Can't you find a way
to get him out of the room?
Have him go pee
in a cup or something.
You don't think
he's gonna be
suspicious?
Just me calling him
out of the blue,
telling him
I need to make
a house call?
This isn't out of the blue.
It's a pre-existing
heart murmur
you're following up on,
and Ray's the one
who said he prefers
house calls.
He also knows
I'm related to a cop.
You're his doctor.
That's why
this is so perfect.
People inherently
want to trust their doctor.
Yeah, and I'm breaking
that trust.
He thinks I'm coming there
to help him.
I thought you said
he was totally on board.
We are. He is.
My gut was telling me
he was a suicide risk
as soon as I heard
about the air bag.
I should have taken
more precaution.
You're a doctor,
not a clairvoyant.
Don't beat yourself up.
Mr. Yates continues
to dump blood, and
it's not slowing down.
Heart puts 350 cc per hour,
base deficits already at 12.
He needs surgery now.
Can't do that.
He refused consent.
If we operate without
his permission,
it's considered assault.
He also is refusing to
let us hang any more blood.
He would rip that tube
out of his own chest
if he wasn't in restraints.
He's aware he'll die
without intervention?
Pretty sure
that's the point.
So, uh,
no immediate family?
Both parents deceased,
says he never married,
no kids.
He's refusing
any outside visitors.
Huh.
How soon do you think
I might be able
to talk to him?
Uh, I gave him five of Ativan,
so I guess another
half hour or so.
I'm gonna have him
moved upstairs
in case you can get him
to change his mind.
I'll check in
with you guys later.
Okay.
Thanks.
Hey, Ava, you got a second?
I need a signature.
What am I signing?
It is a petition
for a dedicated
bypass machine
for my satellite OR.
The board's never gonna
approve an outlay like that.
But maybe they will give me
the name of the donor
who spearheaded the campaign
in the first place,
and then I can go
hit him or her up
for more money.
I thought the donor wanted
to remain anonymous.
Look, I am sure
whoever it is
will be flattered
when I come
groveling for more.
Ah, thank you.
You are a prince.
Dr. Choi,
48-year-old male, signs of
acute alcohol toxicity.
Is he conscious?
A&O times two and
wouldn't let the medics
take his vitals.
Mags, there isn't a resident
you could fob him off on?
And deprive you
of all the fun?
Sir, I'm Dr. Choi.
I understand you've had
a bit too much to drink.
Can you look at me?
Tell me how many fingers
I'm holding up?
Bernie.
Ethan.
Oh, God, I'm so sorry.
I told the ambulance
not to bring me here.
I need to get out of here.
I don't feel so good.
Oh, God, I'm so sorry.
April, give me hand.
My stomach.
Bernie?
Yeah, Bernie.
Let's clean him up,
get him some fluids,
and order an ultrasound.
Let me know when he sobers up.
I'm telling you she needs
to see a doctor right away.
Dr. Manning, this is
Tonya Griggs, and this is
her daughter Neela.
I don't need to be here.
She needs to be here.
Look at that bruise
on her neck.
She came in last night
and went straight to bed.
Didn't even say good night.
This morning, I found her
crying in her room.
I tried talking with her,
but she won't tell me
what happened.
Okay.
Hi, Neela, I'm Dr. Manning.
Can you tell me
how you got
these bruises?
I was just messing around
with some friends.
It's really not
that big of a deal.
I'm telling you,
she's not acting herself.
Mom, please.
Maybe you should wait outside.
Okay.
Thank you.
Okay, Neela, I'd like to
get you changed into a gown.
Monique here can help you
if you prefer that.
I can do it myself.
Sure.
Thanks.
You said you were feeling
some dizziness last time
I was here.
Not anymore. It went away.
You at all
out of breath lately?
Mmm-mmm.
Any chest pain,
headaches?
Honestly, Doc,
I never felt better.
Yeah, my father's
a freaking bull.
What's going on, Doc?
You seem a little tense.
Just a little
too much coffee, I guess.
Damn it. Sorry.
Wedding jitters.
We're all set here.
Hey, Tommy, you wanna
do me a favor
and push that green button
on the EKG machine,
the green one, and then
I'll tell you again
when to stop it.
This button here?
That's the one.
Is it supposed to be
doing that?
Yep.
The miracles
of modern science, huh?
Right here in your
living room, Pop.
Don't mean to bust your balls,
but we're gonna need
a final head count soon.
What's that?
For the wedding reception.
We need a head count.
Of course,
this week for sure, yeah.
Okay, well,
we're done.
Tom, would you
push it again?
All that for ten seconds?
That's it.
You gonna tell me
what it says?
I gotta confer
with the cardiologist,
and I'll get back to you
soon as I can.
He assured me
he was committed
to his sobriety,
then he falls off the wagon
after seeing an ultrasound.
What happens when there's
an actual mouth to feed?
He's an addict whose life
just got turned upside down.
Yes, he faltered,
but right now what he needs
is understanding and support.
Tomorrow,
you can kick his ass.
Here, the scans.
Let's go check on our patient.
How are you feeling?
Been better.
Any idea when
I can get out of here?
Not right away.
The abdominal CT we took
revealed a mature
pancreatic pseudocyst.
Have you had problems
with your pancreas before?
Twelve years ago.
I had a bout
with pancreatitis.
One of the multitude
of reasons why I decided
to get sober.
I'm keeping you
under observation tonight
to make sure
it doesn't rupture.
I feel so humiliated.
Look, this is not
the impression
I wanted to make
to my future brother-in-law.
I'm such a loser.
Just say it. Just tell
me I'm a loser.
You've had a lot
put on your plate.
We all make mistakes.
Thank you.
Thank you both.
I hate to put you guys
in this position,
but can you not tell Emily
any of this?
You're not gonna tell her?
I'm really sorry.
Oh, my God, Bernie,
how could you slip?
After all this time.
Are you his doctor?
Yes.
He told you about
the pancreatitis, I assume?
His doctors told him he could
never, ever drink again.
Oh, Bernie.
I'm sorry,
who are you exactly?
I'm Ashley Kim,
Bernie's wife,
and this our daughter,
Jamie.
Hey, Dad.
Hi, sweetie.
Stop with the questions.
Can't you just let me
die in peace?
Just answer me this.
You say that
you don't want
any visitors,
but according to your chart
you're pretty much alone
in the world,
so I'm just curious
who is it that
you are hoping not to see?
Freeze, stop it.
Freeze?
What?
You said "freeze."
Please? Did you mean to say
please stop it?
No.
Keith, you've been...
You been having a hard time
mispronouncing words,
repeating words?
No.
You know, you seem
a little agitated.
Why don't we...
Why don't we get
rid of these for now.
No, no, I'm okay.
No. No.
I just wanna give you
a little break.
You got a little spasm.
No, no, freeze, stop it!
Get a little spasmy.
Keith, that's not
a muscle spasm.
That's...
It's chorea.
You have
Huntington's Disease,
don't you?
They say it only gets
worse from here.
Good enough reason
to wanna kill myself?
Monique.
How is she?
Good news is, there are
no signs of concussion.
However, I would like
to discuss with you
the kinds of injuries
I am seeing. The bruises,
they're not consistent
with having fallen down.
Normally we'd find
more abrasions,
and they'd be located
more on her joints,
like her knee or her elbow.
Neela's look like
she was being held down.
Oh, my God.
I haven't been able to do
a complete pelvic exam,
but if I had to guess...
I knew it.
I didn't want to think it,
but it's true, isn't it?
I do suspect some type
of sexual assault,
but like I said,
without a complete exam...
My baby...
Oh, my poor baby.
You were supposed to check in
as soon as you were done.
Sorry. Nothing went the way
you said it would.
And still you made it happen.
The techs tell me
we're getting
clean audio already.
Hey, you did good.
Well, I don't feel good.
I'm not being
a good doctor
to my patient,
and, you know,
I happen to like the guy.
You need reminding
what kind of guy
Ray Burke really is?
You know, I'm also keeping
secrets from my fiancée,
and she's gonna ask
where I was today.
What am I
supposed to tell her?
From what I understand,
she knows you've been
treating Burke, correct?
So, tell her the truth.
You're making a house call.
That's not the truth.
You can't read her
all the way in.
Trust me, it's better for
everyone her not knowing.
Better for you.
How many times
do I have to tell you?
Nothing happened.
It's okay, Neela,
I'm not going
to be angry with you,
but I need you
to tell me the truth.
Why do you think I'm lying?
Because she said I was?
Neela,
please.
Isn't there an exam you do
to determine if an assault
happened?
A rape kit, yes.
We'd start Neela first
with a pelvic exam...
No, I don't want anyone
to touch me.
Neela, you have to
do this exam.
Mom, I said no!
Mrs. Griggs, can I talk to you
outside for a moment?
Just so you know,
I can't administer a rape kit
against Neela's will.
She's 15. I am her mother.
I decide what's best for her.
The exam
is very intrusive,
and if Neela isn't willing
to cooperate,
we would need to
restrain her.
Can't you just
put her to sleep?
I'm sorry,
it's not that simple.
I don't care.
Whoever did this
to my little girl
will pay for what he did.
Oh, Dr. Bekker,
it's just been confirmed
Mr. Yates has
Huntington's Disease.
The poor man.
So given his underlying
condition and his lack of
immediate family,
we've decided not to
surgically intervene
and try to make him
as comfortable as possible.
Of course.
All right.
While I have you here.
Mmm-hmm?
Not sure if you've heard,
but Connor's making
a lot of noise about...
The bypass machine,
I heard.
He is looking to make his case
to the lead donor directly.
It's hospital policy
not to divulge the identity
of any donor who wishes
to be anonymous.
Is that an ironclad thing?
You're worried how
he'll react to you going to
his father for the money.
Yeah, I'd prefer
he not find out.
Dr. Bekker?
I heard you were
treating my father,
Keith Yates.
I'm sorry, how did you say
you were related?
I'm his son, Max.
This is my fiancée, Elodie.
We literally just arrived
from the airport.
You're his son?
Yes.
His neighbor said she heard
something about a car crash.
I been calling hospitals.
They said he was here.
Uh...
I'm sorry, Max, your father
was in an accident.
He's stable now,
but have you been in contact
with your father?
We email,
we talk on the phone.
I haven't seen him
in a couple of years.
I've been away
at culinary school in France.
I need to see him.
I need to see him now.
I'm sorry, Max,
your father's made it clear
he doesn't want any visitors.
Well, I'm his son.
This is insane. I just spoke
with my father yesterday.
He knew we were
flying home today.
I'm sorry, I have to go.
Doctor, please.
You need to help me figure out
what's going on here.
I'll do what I can.
His sats are dropping.
Down to 87 now.
Chest tube must have
clotted off.
Your son is here
in the hospital.
He wants to see you.
No.
That's why you crashed
your car, isn't it?
You wanted to die
before your son
could find out.
Sats at 85.
84.
I can't strip it.
Lidocaine, please.
What are you doing?
I'm placing a second tube.
Patient has a DNR
and a DNI.
That does not mean
do not treat.
Dr. Bekker, for God's sake,
let him go.
Scalpel.
Any idea what might have
led to this?
Are you aware of additional
stress factors in
Bernie's life recently?
Actually, yes.
The new house.
You just bought a house?
Well, we're still
in escrow, but, yeah.
Speaking of, I got to go
meet the contractor
over there.
Some kind of
plumbing emergency.
When it rains, it pours.
Unless you think
this is a bad time?
No, we're just monitoring him.
Okay. Jamie, do you want
to come with me
or do you want stay
with your father?
Go with you.
Okay, come on.
Call me if anything
comes up.
Sure.
Okay.
Ethan, you need to
sign off this case.
Ethan!
Look, before
you say anything...
You have a wife and kid?
No, hear me out.
You don't think that's
something my sister
needed to know?
I swear,
hear me out, okay?
I swear, Ethan. Look,
Ashley and I,
we're on our last legs, okay?
You just bought
a new house together.
Yeah, I know.
That was a bad idea.
I love your sister,
Ethan,
and I'm gonna be
a good father to that baby.
I just need to figure out
how to tell my wife.
I'm gonna kill him.
Do you think
he'll tell Emily?
What do I care?
I'll tell her.
You can't, Ethan. HIPAA.
Why are you
protecting this guy?
I am not protecting him.
I'm protecting you.
Well, sats are back up.
At least he's breathing again.
What the hell
are you thinking?
You wondered who it was Keith
didn't want to come and visit?
It was his son, Max.
Yeah. He's in the surgical
waiting area right now.
He's here?
Yeah. That young man has
a 50/50 chance
of inheriting
a fatal disease,
and he needs to be tested.
We need to convince Keith
to tell him so that
can happen.
Yeah, but what if
we can't convince him?
We can't keep him alive
indefinitely.
Well, then we need to
tell Max ourselves.
We're morally negligent
if we didn't.
Divulging a patient's
confidential medical
information
is a federal offense.
Not long from now
I'm gonna be sitting
across from Max
as he asks me
why his father died,
and all I'm gonna be
able to do is shrug.
You were called in just
to fill out claim forms?
Yeah, I don't know why
I couldn't have
done this earlier.
Leah made it sound
like it was an emergency.
Don't be angry with Leah.
Must be a lot of turnover
recently in Billing.
I'll talk to someone
upstairs about it.
Okay.
Bernie?
Babe, are you okay?
What happened?
What are you doing here?
Ethan, what did you do?
Ethan!
We talked about this.
You have a desire to drink,
you call me or your sponsor
first thing.
Come on, babe,
we had a pact.
We tell each other everything.
I know, baby.
You want to tell her
what's going on, Bernie?
I was just about to ask you
the same question.
I'm sorry, who are you?
Why don't you tell me
who you are,
since you have your hands
all over my husband?
Bernie, tell me this bitch
is as crazy as I think she is.
Oh, my God. Okay.
Bernie.
I...
Say something.
Bernie?
Oh, my gosh.
Ultrasound.
A lot of free fluid here.
The pseudocyst
must have ruptured.
Brittany!
Bolus two liters of LR.
Push 100 micrograms
fentanyl.
Tell the OR
he's coming up.
He's hypotensive.
BP's dropping, 92/66.
Heart rate's up to 130.
Hey, what'd I miss?
Hmm. Way too much
to go over now.
Sorry about
cutting out earlier, I'm...
Errands, right?
What are you gonna do?
Dr. Manning.
Hmm?
What the hell is holding up
the rape kit?
We'll catch up later.
Mrs. Griggs,
I already told you.
I am not gonna authorize it
without Neela's consent.
Then I want her discharged
so I can take her
to someone who will.
Okay, then.
You must think
I'm some kind of monster.
No.
Not at all.
I think you are trying to do
what's best for your daughter
in the midst of
a horrible situation.
I was raped when I was
Neela's age.
I'm so sorry.
I didn't tell anyone
what had happened,
not even my mother.
I was so ashamed.
So I'm guessing
you never told Neela
about this?
Mmm-mmm.
Don't you think she might be
feeling what you felt?
Why she's denying
what happened?
If we are gonna help
your daughter,
you need to
share this with her.
What, so he told you
he loved you?
Who do you think you are,
wrecking this family?
Em.
Em...
Mrs. Kim, due to
the emergent nature
of the procedure,
the surgeons were forced
to open your husband's abdomen
to drain his pancreas.
I expect a lengthy recovery.
Don't waste your breath.
Come on. We're leaving.
Bernie's no longer
my problem.
Your sister can sit with him
and wipe his ass,
if she wants.
Vitner's Triple Cheese,
nice.
Tom. Tim.
Everything okay?
How's your dad doing?
You can ask him yourself.
He's outside.
He sent us in
to get you.
Well, it's not really
a good time for me, guys.
It'll only take
a minute.
I have a patient
I need to see.
You got time
to stuff your face.
Come on.
Sooner you see him,
sooner you're back.
So, where
are we going exactly?
Just up over here.
Wanted to leave the car
running out front.
Douchebag valet
wouldn't let me.
Will, thanks for
seeing me again
on such short notice.
Get in.
So, listen.
I wasn't happy with the way
the exam went earlier.
No?
I didn't want to say anything
in front of the boys,
but when you asked how
I was feeling, I lied to you.
I still got
those dizzy spells,
and it's getting
harder for me
to remember things.
Not sure if it's related
to the murmur or not,
but I just thought that...
Will?
Hey.
You with me?
I always counsel
my patients not to get
ahead of themselves.
Let's review the EKG
and go from there, okay?
So, you think
it might be serious?
Don't worry, Ray,
I'm gonna get
to the bottom of this.
You're a good kid.
Hey.
I heard our suicide
has Huntington's.
That's a tough beat.
Yeah.
So, I just met
with the board.
What'd they say?
No.
Wouldn't give me the names
of the donors either.
Something about
a cloak of anonymity.
Well, you tried.
Oh, trying.
Present tense.
That's why I came
to you, actually.
Figured you could help me
find out who the number one
donor was.
Why would you think that?
Well, I've seen you
at these mixers.
You got most of these guys
wrapped around your finger.
I assure you,
I don't.
Hey, just ask around.
Come on. You can do this
one thing for me.
One thing?
Really?
You don't need a dedicated
bypass machine.
You only want one
'cause you hate it
when you have to
bring patients upstairs to me.
You have everything you need
right in front of you
to make this thing work.
Stop always grasping
for more and appreciate
what you've got.
You're still here?
Well, if you're not gonna
let your son sit vigil,
I'm afraid
you're stuck with me.
Although I really wish
you'd rethink your position.
Keith, Max needs to know
about your condition
so he can be tested.
No.
You know that he has
a right to know.
Max has already been tested.
When I was diagnosed,
I took him in secretly.
My ex-wife never knew.
Max was seven.
I hoped the news
would be good.
And it wasn't?
Max is 25.
I was his age when
I found out I had it.
I lost my purpose in life.
It all seemed so pointless.
I don't want that for my son.
How's he doing?
BP's 80/43.
Ten of morphine.
Listen, Keith, you don't know
how he's gonna react.
He might surprise you,
and medicine is advancing
so rapidly, Keith,
that there could be a cure
by the time he contracts
the disease.
Sir, you can't go in there!
No visitors allowed!
Let me in there...
That's my father.
Dad, it's me, Max. Max.
What's happening?
Sir, you're not supposed
to be in here.
72/30.
Look, do something.
He can't breathe!
He asked not to be
intubated, Max.
Dad, please,
listen to me.
I proposed
to a girl at school,
and she said yes.
Okay? Her name is Elodie.
I know you'll like her.
She's just outside now.
I want you to meet her.
Just please,
let the doctors save you.
Is anyone
gonna do anything?
Bring him back.
Bring him back!
Time of death, 19:13.
So sorry.
Do you need any help
finding a mortuary after
the ME releases his body?
I already contacted one.
I realize it was frustrating
being refused access
like you were.
You know, he also
stipulated that
his medical records be sealed
for the next 50 years.
Fifty years.
What was he so afraid of me
finding out?
I love my dad. I did.
Always felt like he was
hiding something from me,
but I'm not gonna be
that way with my kids.
I don't even know
how my father died.
Are you aware, Max,
that you can ask
the medical examiner
to perform an autopsy?
As the next of kin,
you have that right.
Doesn't he, Dr. Bekker?
Yes, he does.
Yeah.
You never know,
you might get a couple answers
to some of those questions
you have.
Maybe I will.
Thank you.
An autopsy?
That'll tell Max the truth.
He's planning
on having children.
He needs to know the risk.
Despite Keith's
good intentions,
I don't know.
Maybe some secrets
you just don't get to keep.
How you doing, Em?
Can't even imagine
how you must be feeling.
And here I was wondering
if he was marriage material.
Guess we answered
that question.
I wish you didn't have
to find out this way,
but at least now
you can make
plans for your baby
in your life
without Bernie.
I'm not leaving Bernie.
He's the father
of my child, Ethan.
I have to make this work.
But he lied to you.
And so did you.
I'm pretty sure
I didn't need to fill out
all those forms today.
You orchestrated this
huge public confrontation,
humiliating me,
jeopardizing Bernie's health.
No, I was trying
to protect you.
Yeah, I don't know.
Think you're just trying
to rub my nose in it.
Hey, that's not
why he did it.
He's had your back
this whole time, Emily.
You got to know that.
I don't know.
That was all you could do.
Here's the discharge
paperwork.
I told Neela the truth,
and she told me
what really happened.
She went to a party,
and there was this boy.
It's my fault.
No.
No, honey, it's not,
and I won't let you
think it is.
Do you hear me?
This boy attacked you.
He's the only one responsible.
Is it too late to do the exam?
That's for Neela to decide.
It's what I want.
I'll go get things started.
Hey,
there you are.
I was hoping
you hadn't left yet.
Actually, I was...
I was just about to come
looking for you.
I wanted to apologize.
You're right.
A lot of people
have invested
a lot of energy
to make this room a reality,
and all I've done is complain
about how it's not enough.
I have been making it seem
like I settled by deciding
to stay here,
but truth is,
I was looking for an excuse
not to take the job at Mayo
because I didn't wanna
leave you.
Oh?
Yeah.
I'm just putting it
out there on the table.
I felt like...
I felt like
I should come clean.
Anyway, you said you were
looking for me.
Yeah, um...
I wanted to tell you...
We lost Keith.
I heard. Thanks.
Um, well, I have
an M&M tomorrow
I have to prepare for, so...
Yeah, I've got some
protocols to run myself.
Okay.
What are you looking at?
EKG. This patient's
pretty clearly
in Type 2 second-degree
heart block.
Then you should probably
follow up with an echo.
Whose chart is it?
Don't know.
One of the med students
asked me to look at it.
Hey.
You remember how Father Brady
talked about communication
today?
What the hell, Will?
The texts, the errands,
whoever's EKG this is,
and who were those
two guys that you
disappeared with today?
Look, I am excited to spend
the rest of my life with you,
but I don't want you
holding back.
I don't want any secrets.
The EKG is Ray's.
Ray Burke's?
From the reception hall?
I made another
house call today
to check his heart.
Those were his sons,
Tom and Tim.
Ray needed
to talk to me, so...
So, why wouldn't you
just tell me that?
I don't know.
Maybe because I feel guilty
about what
I'm really doing there.
Well, you're making
a house call.
What's there
to feel guilty about?
I'm using him, aren't I,
to get the reception hall?
I guess it makes me feel
a little dirty.
I'm... I'm sorry.
I turned what should have been
nothing into a big deal.
It's okay.
Put your work away.
All right.