Standard urban
immunizations don't apply.
- No ring vaccination works.
- Homeland wants us to consider citywide.
- Take a look at this.
- Ten people died unnecessarily.
- It's debatable.
- I don't want to debate.
- Look at this!
- It's a public-health decision.
We got this from a missionary
hospital 300 miles east of Mbandaka.
Present in the simian
population as well as 18 children.
- When? WOMAN:
Thirty-six hours ago.
Same mutation? - Yes.
Jody...
get me Chicago.
You think we can get
them to move a TV in here?
I think you should
catch up on your reading.
I don't read after midnight.
There.
That's a wolf.
That looks like
a wolf, doesn't it?
A wolf with leprosy maybe.
I don't think that you're
appreciating the degree of difficulty.
Even without this rash.
- What?
- Kidding. Just kidding.
This... This doesn't look good.
Maybe we're
getting early parole.
- You feeling okay?
- What is it?
- We need to evacuate.
- The ER?
The entire hospital.
Everyone but you.
Mr. Harold Drummond was in
his usual state of good health...
until Tuesday evening when he began
to experience pinching in his chest.
The pain seemed to
intensify throughout the day...
as Mr. Drummond
worked in his pet shop.
After an early dinner of pork cutlets,
mashed potatoes and a couple of pints...
he retired to his living room to
do some reading, when the pain...
- We have to guess what
book? MAN 2: Yes, Dr. Corday?
Did you treat Mr. Drummond?
- No.
- Are you certain?
Because I distinctly
heard your voice.
- I'm sorry.
- Indeed.
Why don't we jump ahead
to your presentation...
since you seem unable
to contain yourself?
Uh, I'm... That's
not necessary. No.
Right.
Mr. McKay came into
the ER complaining...
We don't have ER's
in England, Dr. Corday.
Excuse me. He presented
to Casualty complaining of...
Is Mr. McKay the
African bushman?
- I beg your pardon?
- Your patient.
He's the young black
Pygmy, is he? About this high?
He's an accountant
from Manchester.
Specifics, Ms. Corday.
God is in the details.
Mr. McKay is a 63-year-old
Caucasian male who was...
- Man.
- What?
I believe the noun for which
you are searching is "man."
"Male" is an adjective. I
have a male springer spaniel.
His name is Barkley.
Though I love him dearly...
I would never think of
bringing him to a hospital.
But please continue. Most of us
speak a smattering of American.
Where are you taking me?
- Mercy Hospital.
Why?
Because we're
closing this facility.
Damn those HMOs! WEAVER:
How many more can you take?
- We're full.
- Then get it out of here. Call Mercy.
Let them know transport's on the way.
And I need another dozen rigs for OB.
- Is Colin on there?
- No. Only ambulatory patients.
- Where is he?
- I don't think they brought him out yet.
- They said everybody's being evacuated.
- They will be. Be patient.
Lily, can you help
her find her boyfriend?
Do I have to?
MVA, broken pelvis. I thought we
were getting rid of these news helicopters.
They are!
Wait, wait, wait. Stella's
one of the last ones.
- Zadro, you going to Mercy?
- No, no. Lakeshore.
- Got one more.
- Do I put her on my lap?
- Sounds good to me!
- How are you doing out here?
Good. Third and fourth floors are
empty. ICU and O.R. should be cleared...
- in 10 minutes.
- You did a good job today.
Given the situation, it
could have been a disaster.
- Everyone did really well.
- You kicked ass.
- Hold still.
- How come you keep doing that?
- It's the way the vaccine is administered.
- You learned it 10 minutes ago?
- What are you doing?
- No wristband!
- They won't let me go!
- You need to be vaccinated.
- I did.
- No, you didn't.
I'll come back tomorrow for it.
Everyone has to be
vaccinated before they go.
I'm not getting stabbed
by a smallpox needle...
- if it ain't even smallpox!
- It's 15 little pricks.
So shut up, get the
damn shot, and go home!
Tell me what it is,
I'll get a shot for that!
Are you deaf? We don't know!
But this vaccine is
the best we've got.
If you don't want
Dr. Gallant to help you...
I can arrange for the
Army sergeant to come in.
Make sure you don't touch that.
- Where are they taking them?
- Upstairs, respiratory isolation.
And why do we have
to stay in this Petri dish?
"Prolonged exposure,"
whatever that means.
Did you find out for how long?
- The virus is an unknown player.
- You said monkeypox.
A variant of monkeypox.
That's the problem.
How long?
Two weeks.
No. No, no, no. No.
They promised a public-health
nurse on duty around the clock.
Why two weeks? What
aren't they telling us?
I don't know. I think they're
just being extra cautious.
I'm sorry about all this.
Me too.
Thank you.
Could you make any
more noise, Stan?
I can't help it.
At least cover your mouth.
Better knock it off, Stan,
before you cough up a lung.
Agh. It's too late.
Have you ever been
tested for TB, Stan?
- DUI, PCP and HIV, but never TB.
- Great.
Pneumococcal pneumonia can give
you bloody sputum, fever and sweats.
Have you lost any
weight lately, Stan?
I've always been pretty svelte.
But I have had to tighten
my belt a few notches lately.
- Here, put this on.
- No. No, thanks.
- Do it!
- Well, you don't have to be so cranky.
I'm the one with the D.T.'s.
- What are you doing?
- We might have to get him tested.
No, no. Slow down.
They're tripping out enough.
- I don't need double quarantine.
- He may have TB.
And he might not.
Let's take a sputum sample to the
lab, do a Gram's stain and a AFB?
Because we're not
supposed to leave.
- It's not contagious unless we get a rash.
- No.
- What's he still doing here?
- I told you. He can't go by ambulance.
- That's why there's a chopper.
- Why didn't someone tell me?
It landed. We
have to get up top.
Colin, we're gonna take you to the roof
so we can put you on a helicopter, okay?
- I don't like to fly.
- It's a short trip.
You don't understand.
I really don't like to fly.
You don't have a choice.
I'm serious. You take
me up there, I'll freak out!
It's not a plane. It's an
air-rescue helicopter.
That's even worse. A helicopter
can't glide. Just take me back.
I have a bad feeling about this.
Take me back! Please!
Just take me back!
My son doesn't know I'm leaving.
We'll make sure to
tell him. Hold the doors!
Dr. Romano, Saint Rafe says
they can take one critical, not two.
That's too bad,
because I'm sending four.
Dr. Romano needs to send
at least four patients over.
Thank you! NURSE: No...
I've never been in
a Catholic hospital.
Well, you'll like the
nuns. Nice calves.
They said they'll
only accept one.
We're clear. Sign out the
Demerol and morphine.
- To who?
- You, me, my Uncle Bernie. What line?
- Two.
- Get the hell out of here.
- Who's this? WOMAN
1: The admitting nurse.
You like your job? Wanna
keep it? Tell your chief of staff...
- You know who that is?
- Dr. Jones.
Good for you. You tell Jonesy that
Robert Romano is sending over...
- four critical patients...
- Dr. Romano.
To be treated like
his own mother...
without the
inappropriate touching.
Tidal volume's down.
Probably just the morphine.
- Take a deep breath, Colin.
- Hey! Don't even think about it!
- That's my chopper!
- They were sending a chopper...
- for two patients.
- Well, they lied.
I don't want to go
on this helicopter!
- Fine. Fair enough.
- He needs an ICU bed.
- So get him one.
- He has bilateral pulmonary contusions...
and they're blooming.
Marty here's a
70-year-old diabetic...
with Gram-negative
sepsis from cholecystitis.
I'm only 68!
Damn parasites! Hey, get that
news chopper out of our airspace.
- He's gonna lose his airway.
- Intubate him and take him in your Viper.
- He's not safe to transfer.
- Arguing like this isn't helping them.
You're right. I'll tell you what, you
can take the chopper next. Let's go.
- Temp's 101.
- All right.
Give him 10 grams of Tylenol
and piggyback the gentamicin.
A sheet, BP cuff,
anything! Come on!
No vascular clamps, but we have
two Kellys and a needle driver. Oh, God.
- Where's the arm? Do we have the arm?
- I can't see anything.
- Shut this thing down!
- Not with you under it!
He's vomiting.
Twenty-centimeter lac over
the fifth rib, but no sub-Q air.
- Clamp.
- Which one first?
The biggest one.
- Okay, one, two, three.
- Tighter! Tighter.
Get your gurney out!
- I can't see anything.
- No, don't clamp it.
- What?
- Just do it! He's lost half his volume.
- Try for a BP on the good arm.
- Okay, I got it!
- Cold.
- Do we have blood on the rig?
- Six units, type A.
- We need a line. No O-neg?
You asked for type-specific.
Dr. Romano, what
blood type are you?
What blood type are you?
No red snappers?
Mm. Could be an
inadequate sample.
Sputum is loaded with
Gram-positive diplococci.
Pneumococcus. I
told you not to sweat it.
Wait, wait. What are you doing?
It's old-fashioned pneumonia.
I'm hungry. You hungry?
We're quarantined.
Put your mask back on.
You can't eat with a mask
on. Let's raid the cafeteria.
- Put your mask back on.
- Starve a cold, feed a fever.
Pratt? Pratt!
- That's my watch!
- I need the bag.
Cycle the dynamap.
How's he satting?
Nothing on the
monitor. Lungs are wet.
- Damn it.
- We're loading him.
I ain't taking off till I
check out that tail rotor.
- He's looking shock-y.
- He needs an O.R.
I don't know if she flies at
all, much less flies safely!
Call for ground transport.
- No, call another chopper.
- Where you gonna land it?
Luka, he needs to get there
by ambulance. We need ice.
Belly's hard as a
rock. Labored resps.
Okay. Send our guy
downstairs. Radio Dispatch.
Get an orthopedic and a
trauma surgeon up here.
You awake?
Yeah.
Monkeypox sounds
like a video game.
Or voodoo.
Or VD.
Lovely.
Does your back itch?
No.
- You're scratching it.
- It's probably just psychosomatic.
- You want me to take a look?
- No, I'm fine.
Might be a rash.
Turn over.
Do you think someone
did this on purpose?
- Does it matter?
- What do you mean?
I mean, viruses mutate.
That's what they do.
We're more likely to control
bioterrorism than Mother Nature.
Thanks, that makes
me feel a lot better.
No rash.
Nice tattoo, though.
College. I was drunk.
Is that what I think it is?
Yeah, I was going
through a religious phase.
My chest hurts. I can't breathe.
Crank him to 15 liters. Don't
worry, we'll get you down.
- What's wrong with this?
- Tachy at 115.
Where's the helicopter?
- He's first.
- You're next.
- Pressure's dropping...
- on twenty mics of dopamine.
- Over 100?
- Eighty-five.
- Susan, we have to get him down.
Don't hyperventilate.
Assist. Which is dopamine?
On the syringe pump.
Tell Weaver ultrasound was
clear, but he could have a slow leak.
Take everybody to
the ambulance bay.
- Pulse ox is 91.
- Got it. She might need help tubing him.
- Health Department refused reentry.
- Romano authorized it.
Who's Romano?
They coming back?
Uh, don't worry, Mr. Hersch.
I'm right here with you.
I hope they remembered to
call my son. He'll worry about me.
What's his name?
Alan.
His mother wanted
him to become a doctor.
I'm beginning to wish he had.
What's he do?
So how often does
this happen here?
Only since you came along.
Oh, right. The yin and the yang.
Excuse me?
The yin and the yang. You
know, something good happens...
so something bad has to
happen. You are Chinese, right?
Yeah, I'm just trying to
figure out the good part.
Just say the word,
and I'll show it to you.
- Hey, no, no. Pick that up.
- I made it.
It's bad enough that you're
not wearing your mask.
The hospital is abandoned!
Who are we gonna contaminate?
Central line kit. Two liters,
wide open. Where's the O-neg?
- We don't keep it here.
- He's not perfusing. Set up the level one.
- Oh, my God. KOVAC:
I need a lot of blood.
O-neg, packed cells
and platelets. Now.
- Blood bank is closed.
- Open it!
- What happened? KOVAC:
Chen, ice. I need ice. Lots of it.
Mr. Hersch? Mr. Hersch?
Where's the bag?
Uh!
Okay, Mr. Hersch,
I'll be right back.
Somebody! I need help!
Oh, son of a bitch!
Come on.
Damn it.
- You can't open the O.R.
- They're already in there.
Mercy and Lakeshore
are full. That's it.
- Yeah? Maxed out is relative.
- I can't allow anyone else in!
He's our chief of staff.
You're gonna need to stop...
- the replantation team by force.
- Dispatch says to remove...
- the rest to Riverview.
- Where is that?
- Indiana.
- No, no.
- Need a hand here.
- What took you so long?
Elevator doesn't
open on the first floor.
Sats are 89, but not
correlating. Abdomen's tense.
- Hey, over here!
- Colin? Colin, can you hear me?
- Can I ride with him? I'm his fiancée.
- Get her the hell away from me.
Sir, I'm gonna need
you to calm down.
She's not my fiancée.
She's a freaking psycho!
- Gallant.
- We're soul mates!
- She ran me off the road into a bus!
- I was upset! But I'm not now!
I'll... I'll take care of you!
Hey. How bad is he? Romano?
Bad.
Retracting the deltoid.
There's the median nerve.
- Clean cut. That's good, right?
- Where do you want it?
Squeeze in four units
and get a HemoCue.
Bradying down to 50.
One liter of atropine. Break out the
cart. We're gonna have to tube him soon.
- I think I lost the pulse.
- Either you did or you didn't.
- I can't feel it.
- Okay, CPR now.
- Get that blood in. PRATT:
First two units are up.
One milligram epi, IV
push, and FFP to follow.
Is anybody out there? I need
help in here. He's crashing.
Somebody! Ugh.
Somebody!
Come on.
Pick up. Pick up.
Out of the way! Out of the way!
- Donald, get in there.
Kerry Weaver, Dr. Joe Gunn.
- Nice to meet you.
He walked into the tail
rotor? What happened?
- He barely has a pressure.
- Is he in arrest?
- Not yet.
- This way. Wear your mask at all times.
Dr. Weaver. Dispatch
relayed a call from Elevator 4.
Dr. Lewis needs help
with a crashing patient.
Well, who's with her? - No one!
- Normal sinus.
- Good pulse. How many units?
- Fourth almost in.
- Where are we?
Amputation at
the distal humerus.
Dropped his crit to
18 prior to transfusion.
- Arm's on ice.
- Everybody put a mask on!
Hemorrhagic shock resolved
with blood and epi. Pressure's 90.
I need to paralyze and intubate.
- He's coming around.
- What do you think?
- I don't know. Above the elbow's tough.
- Yes or no?
- Maybe.
- Oh, God.
Robert, can you hear me?
Oh, I'm at County.
I don't think I can
take another week.
Uh. Yeah.
All right, up.
Feels like we're the
last people on the planet.
Well, if we were I'd move into
the best suite in the Ritz-Carlton.
- You?
- Um...
- Shopping spree.
- Hm.
How's that look?
- Ooh, hot.
- Really?
- Toe or finger?
- Toe.
- Even the big one?
- Yep.
Arm or leg?
Uh... Leg. You?
- Definitely leg.
- Deaf or blind?
Deaf.
Ha, hah! Six-five.
Okay. Would you rather lose
both your arms or your penis?
- I don't know.
- Could still do it with your equipment.
It would be tough to get
chicks without arms, though.
To tell you the truth, I couldn't
date a chick that was missing pieces.
What if she had a
great personality?
What? And really big tits?
What the hell's going
on in here, Stan?
Hey, nice 'do. Frames
your face better.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
Dr. Weaver.
- How's he doing?
- Could be better.
The ring and long
fingers are a little dusky.
Is it normal post-op erythema?
- It better be.
With the poor perfusion, I'm worried
the antibiotics aren't penetrating.
He's not getting enough
blood to the hand.
Can up his dextran. If
I go back to the O.R...
we decrease meaningful recovery.
- If not, he could lose the whole hand.
- I'm thirsty.
- Does he have a family?
- I don't know.
Has anyone else visited?
No.
You know him.
What would he want?
Robert's aggressive. He'll
want to save the arm at all costs.
So I should operate?
Let him wake up from
the narcotics and ask him.
That could be tomorrow
morning. By then it'll be too late.
Then you wait.
It's his decision, not mine.
Do you think they know?
Pratt's clueless.
Chen knows.
I don't think so.
Oh, no. She knows.
- Did you tell her?
- Where do you think I got the condoms?
And, you know,
you were a little...
loud.
Well, uh...
- You're about a three.
- I always thought I was at least a four.
- That's a nice pustule.
- It's gonna be a big scar. I know it.
You can get another tattoo.
That's true. I could
get "Carter... Yeah.
- Sucks."
- Ehh. Ha-ha.
When I was in Chicago...
I'd often get homesick for London,
think about the things I missed.
- Now you don't have to.
- And now I think about Chicago.
Yes, I heard you had a run-in with
the staff. This time with a cardiologist?
He took one of my
patients hostage.
Wanted to wait for an echo.
That's not unreasonable, is it?
- Ooh, someone groused on me.
- It's a small hospital.
- Small-minded, it's more like.
- And it's not America.
You may have to adjust
your approach somewhat.
My approach is to do what's best
for the patient with a minimum...
- amount of ass-licking.
- Oh, there's my cue.
What? You're not
gonna say hello?
Hello.
I'm really glad you're
back, Elizabeth.
- You're late.
- I'm sorry. I had a bowel resection.
Before lunch? Lovely.
I washed my hands.
Do you think it's possible
to die from boredom?
I don't think so.
What if your mind
wandered off in a daydream...
and you forgot to
eat or drink for days?
Then you'd die of
starvation and dehydration.
- Caused by boredom.
- Hm.
You smell something?
That smells like heaven.
- Where did this come from?
- A friend of mine slipped it...
- through the window.
- It's contraband pizza.
- Yeah. Why? You want some?
- Hell, yes.
Ten bucks a slice.
- Help yourself. STAN: You
didn't get any beer, did you?
I got some sodas.
I take back everything
I said about you, Pratt.
- Really?
- No.
But thanks for the pizza.
No, but seriously, since you
guys make five times what I do...
- all donations are greatly appreciated.
- Hey, I got good news.
Adam's fever broke.
He's out of the woods.
Ah, lovely. How about a toast?
- To young Adam.
- Yes.
- And to us, for surviving the plague.
Unless somebody develops
a rash in the next 48 hours.
Pestis Puerorum.
- What?
- The Black Death.
It started in China.
Infected Italian sailors brought
the disease back to Sicily in 1347.
In the end, 25
million people died.
- How do you know that, Stan?
- Renaissance Philosophy, 1-D-7.
- You studied philosophy?
- Taught it.
- Yeah, right.
- You're a teacher?
Yeah.
What happened?
Things. Things happened.
Things always happen.
Well, you're sober now.
- Not by choice.
You know, you've been
through the hard part.
We can get you into a program,
get you some counseling.
I killed my daughter in a DUI. There's no
counseling for that. Thanks for the pizza.
Oh.
Well, I'm gonna eat this in bed.
- Hm. Sounds good to me.
- Alone.
- Good night.
- So you guys wanna watch some TV?
- No, thanks.
All right. Pizza
will be in the fridge.
Kind of sad, huh?
- What's that?
- The guy was a teacher.
- And he killed his daughter.
- Because of alcohol.
It happens.
- Doesn't have to.
- What are you trying to say?
I just think it's sad.
Tell me what you're
trying to say. Talk to me.
- You want me to talk to you?
- Yeah.
I wanna help you.
But not because I'm a nice guy
or because I'm worried about you.
- But because I wanna be with you.
- You wanna fix me.
- Help you.
- Fix me so I'm good enough.
- No, I want it to work.
- Yeah, well, I'm not broken.
Ms. Corday. I see you
ordered that CT on Mr. McKay.
Yes. After 20 minutes of chatting,
I came to the same conclusion.
CT confirmed dissection.
So you're carrying on
all right then, are you?
- Carrying on?
- Of course.
Well, I suppose you can
still grieve on the inside.
While I'm sure that's
some kind of criticism...
I'm afraid I haven't
got time to decipher it.
You're not in black dress. Matter
of fact, you're not in a dress at all.
Perhaps America has confused
you in more ways than one.
- Interesting.
- Yes.
I thought I might suggest
you reconsider that tie...
as it makes you look like
a boorish, virulent ponce.
But now I realize that's simply
your general disposition...
so it would be out of
place for me to comment.
Out of place indeed.
Tragic, really.
A woman out of place
on two continents.
Congratulations.
- Excuse me?
- They sold your house.
Ten thousand more
than the asking.
If you sign it, I'll
fax it back for you.
Thank you.
I would like to read
it myself, thank you.
What's wrong with your
lunch today, Dr. Romano?
Your body needs
nourishment to heal itself.
That's brilliant. They teach
you that in nursing school?
If you don't eat, I'm
gonna tell Dr. Gunn.
Oh, go ahead, tell
Gunn. I've seen his work.
You might as well have
your prosthetics department...
come fit me for a hook.
I'll see if I can find
you something else.
Whatever.
Kerry, I was wondering when
you were gonna come and visit me.
I was here yesterday
and the day before.
You were a little out of it.
Re-carpeting my office?
How are you feeling?
I've been better.
The surgery went well.
Yeah. So they say.
But you know how surgeons lie.
You were lucky.
Lucky?
Look, your people rallied around
to save you in a deserted hospital.
- If it wasn't for Dr. Kovac...
- I'd still have my arm.
- You do have your arm.
- Do I?
Yes. It was a clean cut above...
I signed the third-quarter
income projections.
We should evacuate the hospital
once a year for the money we're saving.
- Robert...
- Going to sleep now.
Apparently, I need my rest.
Identified the
terminal ileum. Bovie.
We call it
electrocautery, Elizabeth.
Can I help you?
A solo hemicolectomy?
Not by design. Your Professor
Whitehead decided to be tardy.
Yes, I know. He's apparently
saving a motorist on the M1.
Asked me if I'd fill in. But it
seems you've already started.
Transverse incision. Splendid.
- Allows for a more localized approach.
- Yes, and a bloody one. Suction.
The field is clear.
Let's just take
a look, shall we?
- Elizabeth?
- Be my guest.
Well, good separation
around the taut.
The areolar tissue could use better
division, couldn't it? Metzenbaum.
- May I continue now, please?
- The more I see, the better he'll do.
If you merely wish to peer
around this gentleman's anatomy...
why don't you crack
open his skull too?
No, I'm interested in completely excising
this gentleman's cancer, thank you.
- Vascular clips.
- Okay, then, he's all yours.
Retract the cecum medially.
Retraction.
Well, you heard him. Retraction.
Watch the pericolic gutter.
He's had some adhesions...
from an appendectomy.
- Morning, Frank.
- Ah. Welcome back, Dr. Weaver.
- Waxed the floors.
- Nice, huh?
Takes smallpox for them
to finally sanitize the place.
- Wasn't smallpox, Frank.
- Mutated monkey scabs. Whatever.
Other departments online?
ICU and Surgery have
been up since midnight.
Pedes, PICU, Labor and Delivery open
with us. Everybody else starts at noon.
- Dr. Pratt?
- See you.
- Disease Control clear you?
- One hundred percent.
- Probed every which way.
- I don't need to hear details.
Did we get all our
monitors back?
IMEDs, pro-packs and portable vents.
Crash carts are stocked and ready.
Ah. I don't get it. We're
closed for two weeks...
and they make us
come back at 6 a.m.?
It could have been midnight.
- I'll catch you quacks later.
- Oh, I see you're better.
I was never that bad. I
told you guys not to sweat it.
Dr. Pratt, Dr. Gallant called in sick.
I need you to cover for him until 3.
- What?
- Well, you just said you felt good.
- Yeah, I know. But, come on, man...
- Eh.
Kidding, Pratt.
See you next week.
- Can you sign this?
- What is it?
My timecard. Two
straight weeks of overtime.
Do you think I'm kidding?
Dermatologically clear.
- Afebrile.
- Okay, you're free to go.
What, no psych consult?
We try not to inflict
any long-term damage.
- She's borderline.
- Thank you for your understanding...
- and cooperation.
- Hey, can you tell us?
- What?
- If the virus was engineered or natural?
The system worked. Everyone did
their jobs, especially at the local level.
You're not gonna
tell us. See you, Deb.
- Yeah, it was fun, Carter.
- Let's get these beds made up...
so we're not setting up as
we go. Chuny, you triage?
- Yes. On my way.
- Hey, you survived.
Hi. You look tan.
I went to Barbados.
- Sorry.
- Barbados!
I had two weeks. What
else was I supposed to do?
- Frank, what time is it?
- 5:59.
Okay. We're open.
ER.
They just get out, themselves?
He has to leave the trach in for
a few days, but he's off the vent.
They look better, the parents.
Well, maybe they stopped
blaming each other.
- Weird.
- What?
Stuck here two weeks,
I don't wanna go home.
- Wanna get some breakfast?
- No.
You're not thinking of jumping?
No. Not quite that desperate.
- Can I join you?
- It's your hospital.
Yes, it is, isn't it?
So, what's wrong with
the surgical lounge?
Habit, I suppose.
At County, we often go up on the roof
when the place gets too much for us.
I'm glad everything
there isn't perfect.
I was beginning to develop
an inferiority complex.
Far from it.
Homesick then?
Yes, you do.
What?
Have a home.
Can't bring yourself
to sell it, I understand.
I assume Mr. Cummins survived his
hemicolectomy without further incident.
We do seem to manage
here from time to time.
You hadn't developed
vertigo yet as a teen.
Reminds me of your
tree-climbing days.
The headmistress couldn't
get you out of that sycamore.
I had to drive all the way
down to Tunbridge Wells.
A counselor was brought in...
suggested some kind of
rebellion, separation anxiety...
cry for attention, what have you.
Turned out you just liked climbing trees.
I knew that. You were an
unbridled spirit from the womb.
I don't know what to do.
I know, darling. I know.
- Here, let me.
- Thank you.
- This is the right train for Heathrow?
- I hope so.
- Thank you.
- You off on holiday?
No, we're going home.
- Thanks. MAN: Stand
clear of the doors, please.
- The train is about to depart.
- What have you got there?
- The 7:59 train...
from Ealing Broadway and Reading
West is now departing for Heathrow.
- Chaos theory?
- Yeah.
A virus mutates in the Congo,
we evacuate an ER in Chicago...
- Romano gets his arm cut off.
- You lost me.
Seemingly random events,
all part of a larger equation.
- I'm hot.
- You know, a butterfly flaps its wings...
in China and creates a tornado
halfway around the world.
- Are you hot?
- I'm just saying...
that there's an unpredictability
about everything.
Evolution, life,
love, relationships...
So, what am I? The
butterfly or tornado?
- No, you're chaos in general.
- Oh. Thanks.
No, I'm just saying you're chaos to
me. The unknown. I'm chaos to you.
You are hardly chaos, Carter.
I'm saying that there's
a risk in anything you do.
But don't you wanna stack
the odds in your favor?
I mean, I'm drawn to you.
It's kind of that simple. I've
been drawn to you for two years.
But chaos always seems to
rule. And I don't want it to rule.
I wanna know
where it's taking me.
- Know what I mean?
- Nope.
The tornado.
Definitely the tornado.
Are you coming in?