In order to properly
treat a problem,
a surgeon needs as much
information as she can get.
Wasn't this stupid thing
supposed to start already?
So we ask questions.
Questions like...
a central line kit, please.
"When did the pain begin?"
It started about 45 minutes ago.
"Have you experienced
these symptoms before?"
"Do you have a family history?"
"Are you currently
sexually active?"
"Have you recently
undergone surgery?"
If you're unwilling or unable
to answer these
and other questions,
we're forced to rely
on tests for insight.
It's possible that I
may have, by mistake,
said that if she had any
doubts, she should flee.
What?
She was nervous.
How nervous?
How nervous was she, Callie?
Until those test
results come back,
there's nothing
we can do but wait.
Damn it.
What is it?
There's too much bleeding.
Look, even with the scope,
I can't see a damn thing.
Okay. Let's get a
CT. And call the OR.
I want them ready the second
we know what we're dealing with.
Should I call anyone else?
You're going into
surgery. You'll be a while.
Yeah?
Dr. Bailey.
I didn't forget.
I know that. Should
I call your fiance?
Yes, please.
Oh...
What does this mean?
I don't know.
The lawsuit is...
Maybe...
Maybe we'll be fine.
Maybe we can...
Look, just, could we
not talk about that?
Not right now.
Could I have everyone's
attention, please?
My beautiful wife-to-be
has been pulled into
an emergency surgery,
so things are gonna be
delayed for a little while.
Those of you who are
doctors will understand.
And those who aren't...
Well, they're setting up the
buffet, the bar's open in the back.
Drink, eat, and just
as soon as we're able,
we'll have a little wedding.
That poor handsome fool.
Bailey's probably hopped
a boxcar to Mexico by now.
I am the worst
maid of honor ever.
Who made you maid of honor?
I called it.
And then I tanked it.
I'm gonna go to the hospital.
Right now? I'll go.
I'm the general surgeon. Maybe
I can tag her out of surgery.
Put this in water
till I get back.
You really told Bailey to run?
I didn't say she should
run. I said she could run.
And I was joking. I was...
Aw! Funny... Funny me.
No? Okay.
Who needs a drink?
I can stay.
We'll be fine. You should go.
I don't really feel like
going to a wedding
if I'm gonna be
signing divorce papers.
Wow!
I don't know what happened. I
heard a crash, checked my rearview.
Half the club is eating asphalt,
banging around like tenpins.
I mean, it's real, real nasty.
Bowling for bikers?
Maybe you should
stick around. Yeah.
You just gonna stand there
with your junk in your hand,
or you gonna do something, Doc?
Multiple contusions.
Pelvis stabilized in transport.
Coming through. Watch your back.
You know, I used
to ride a donor cycle.
Really? Why'd you stop?
Chest tubes hurt like a bitch.
Stuart Loeb, 35.
Vital signs stable.
Alert before we
pushed 5 of morphine
for a left arm degloving injury.
Ooh! He must have
been thrown out of his car.
He was on one of the bikes.
Seriously, this guy?
I know, right?
Okay. Let's get him in trauma 1.
And start making some calls.
We need more hands in here.
Right away, Doctor.
Hey, look at these.
Macaroni and cheese
in the form of a cupcake.
Might be the cutest
thing I've ever seen.
I just did something.
I got us a room. Just now.
And the guy at the desk
said that it's really nice
and it has a view.
Though, honestly, I only
care that it has a bed.
Are you tired? No.
Oh!
You got us a room.
Yes.
So we could... Yes.
Okay.
Excuse me.
Sorry, but if you knew,
you'd understand.
What is she doing? Wait.
Okay. Hold on. Listen.
We should take
some of that to go.
You know, in case
we work up an appetite.
Right.
Finally.
I'm so sorry.
You're sorry? No, you're not
sorry. You're criminally negligent.
Dr. Webber... My
wife has Alzheimer's,
and you told me my
visits were agitating her.
So instead of
monitoring her myself,
I allowed you to do it.
You want to look at me right
now and tell me you're sorry?
Sir, I understand you're upset.
Though to be clear,
when I said you should
visit less frequently,
I certainly didn't mean
for you to stop altogether.
What did you just say to me?
Dr. Webber, they
need you in OR 2.
Thank you.
Don't thank me. Just go.
Is she in the OR already?
I don't know. I just said that so
you wouldn't punch that guy out.
Is this why she
isn't at the wedding?
Oh, God. The wedding.
I'm gonna go find
her. Are you okay?
Yeah, go. Go.
According to the article,
the doctors discovered
that her hair follicles
had actually been growing
nails instead of hair.
Like fingernails.
Cool story, bro.
Can I get anybody a coffee?
Mmm-mmm. No.
It's like having dinner with
Ripley's Believe It or Not!
So you're starting to regret this
whole "let's bring dates" idea?
No.
No. I love Ripley's
Believe It or Not!
I love easy wedding sex,
which I'm gonna miss out on now
'cause you jerks can't keep
your hands off each other.
You made me bring
sand to the beach,
and it's sand I
can't sleep with.
Since when can you
not sleep with interns?
I'm a homeowner
now. I've grown up.
Besides, they get
all hung up and sad
when you don't want
to be their boyfriend.
It's not worth the hassle.
You are one classy guy, Karev.
I make an effort.
He was just trying to be nice, and
I got him in trouble with his boss.
I can barely look
him in the eye.
Dr. Avery has nice eyes.
Do you think they're
blue or green? Or both?
Don't. Don't you
dare sleep with him.
I'm not. Why not?
'Cause that's the kind
of thing Leah would do.
You want to be like Leah?
Oh! Gross. No.
Besides, he's probably
not even interested.
Of course he's interested.
Interns are like sexual
catnip at this hospital.
Look at me. I was
enjoying a perfectly healthy
teacher-student
relationship with Kepner,
and now she's all over me.
I brought notes so I can keep
the conversation about medicine,
but she keeps asking me
all these personal questions,
and I'm running out of cards.
Did you just get paged?
Both of you? All of us.
Big trauma back at the
ranch. You kids coming?
Yes, indeed. Yeah,
I'm coming, too.
Nope. You don't get
to practice medicine
with booze in your
system, Hobo Jo.
You're Hobo Jo?
Like "rides the rails and
eats beans from a can"?
I don't know. Weird.
Shane, you can ride with me.
A beer for me and
another round for Hobo Jo.
You got it. Let me guess.
Thunderbird or is it just
straight paint thinner?
I told your fiance it
was an emergency.
But not who the patient was?
Should I have? No, no.
He'd just send everybody home.
I am still getting
married today.
What are you doing here?
Oh, tell me he didn't call it off.
No one called anything
off. I'm here to help.
What's the situation?
Well, CT shows an
aortic aneurysm so big,
it's torn into the duodenum.
I've never seen one that big.
Yeah, me neither. Scrub fast.
Chief, where do you need us?
Just a second, Avery.
Guess Dr. Bailey
beat us to the fun.
Dr. Bailey's here?
She and Dr. Grey are working
on Adele Webber in OR 1.
Dr. Webber's wife? Should we...
You have a degloving
injury in trauma 1.
Take care of your patient. Let
Bailey and Grey take care of theirs.
Don't touch me!
Dr. Hunt, a little help, please.
You come at me
with that thing again,
and you will not
like where it ends up.
You two make the rounds.
I want status reports
on all the injured,
and find out what
happened out there.
You two aren't going anywhere
except the waiting room.
And, ma'am, you
need to sit back.
Don't call me "ma'am."
It's Gasoline.
And you don't want to get
in the way of club business.
You screw with one of us,
and we will all screw with you.
Okay.
You want your
guys taken care of?
That's all my guys
are trying to do.
Now I'll let these gentlemen
conduct their investigation
as long as they do not
bother any of my patients.
And you settle down and
let Dr. Brooks here do her job.
Deal.
How's Gasoline?
And The Hammer?
These are people?
Yeah. Those are
their road names.
You get to pick your road
names, and you went with Stuart?
I'm not officially in the club.
They let me hang around,
ride along with them.
It has been the greatest
time of my entire life.
And I ruined it. That
crash was my fault.
My sister was right. I had no
business being on that bike.
I think your arm would agree.
I don't know. I think guys
on motorcycles are hot.
All right, Stuart, your
injuries are extensive,
but I do think it's possible
we can salvage your hand.
We're just gonna get you up
to the OR and debride your arm.
Edwards, you're with me.
Unless you'd rather
I took Dr. Ross.
Are you kidding?
No. Shane's my guy.
Nice. Ooh!
Nice view.
Um...
Open or closed?
Closed.
Lights, on or off?
Um...
Whichever. How about...
That's great.
Um, I'm sorry. I just
suddenly got so nervous.
Me, too. Really?
Okay, hold on. Okay.
I'm sorry. It's okay.
I think I should
take the leg off first.
Of course. Yeah.
I can help if...
No, no, no.
Velcro straps and plastic
sockets aren't exactly sexy,
and I wanted this evening
to be all about sexy,
so I think that I need to
take the leg off myself.
And I need you not to watch.
You want me to
go in the bathroom
until your leg's off and
you're under the covers?
Would you?
Oh.
Okay.
Sure.
Murphy, get your hands in here.
Dr. Bailey.
I need you to put
pressure on the aorta,
there under the diaphragm.
It's just a stopgap until we
can mobilize the duodenum
off the aneurysm.
Grey.
Murphy, I got this.
Go up in the gallery
and sit with him.
Okay.
Have you got a little brown
paper bag you can put that in?
Would you stop?
I had no parents.
I lived in my car.
So, yes, I have trust issues.
Comes with the territory.
You need to stop acting
like you're the only person
who ever had a crappy childhood.
Yeah? How many foster
homes did you get kicked out of
before you moved into your car?
Seventeen.
And I didn't live in
my car. I went to juvie.
Stop making fun of me.
I'm not.
Really?
And you're actually lucky
that your folks abandoned you.
Means you didn't have
to watch your schizo mom
go after your baby
brother with a steak knife.
Fine. Fair.
But you never woke up
in the middle of the night
with junkies banging on
your bedroom windshield,
praying they'd
get tired or bored
before they put a
rock through a window.
No, I didn't, because
the junkie was my dad,
and he didn't break
windows, just fingers.
Well, did you ever
have foster parents
that made you and 19 other kids
sleep on cots in the basement?
Locking the doors at lights out,
so that if you had to pee
in the middle of the night
you had to use buckets
they set up along the wall?
Buckets you couldn't see
because if you turned the lights on,
the bigger kids
would hold you down
and take those buckets and...
No. Never.
Me neither. Saw it
in a movie on cable.
How did you get
cable in your car?
I don't live in my
car anymore, jerk.
Stuart?
He went down first.
Everybody else followed.
Emily Bennett?
The last person
that called me that
is somewhere
choking on a tire iron.
Excuse me.
Gasoline?
I'm Dr. Yang.
Dr. Brooks found that you have
some fluid around your heart.
So I would like to do
a pericardiocentesis
to relieve that pressure.
No, thanks. You've
seen my X-rays.
My body's 85%
metal. I get over stuff.
Well, you just don't get over
this. Untreated, you could die.
Treated, I'm stuck in a
bed. No dice, Dr. Yang.
I can't be out of commission,
not when my boys need
me to take care of business.
Actually, they brought
a guy in with us, Stuart.
Have you seen him? No.
I'll tell you what,
you find him, you
take me to see him,
and then I'll let you
do whatever you want.
Ow! Damn it, kid.
There's no way you're doing that
right. Call the redhead over here.
There's no need to...
No, no, I ain't gonna suffer
just because you're
avoiding your old lady.
My what? I seen the
way she looks at you.
She's not looking
at me. Not now.
Now she's ignoring you,
which means she really digs you.
Ow! Damn it!
What is going on?
This kid's a
menace, that's what.
Okay.
Sir, just calm down.
This is a teaching hospital.
All right? Just...
Allow me to assist Dr. Ross
with his technique, okay?
Yeah.
Okay.
All right, so for a corner stitch
like this, it's usually best to use
a half-buried horizontal
mattress stitch.
So you go in like that...
Okay. I think I got it.
I mean,
it's like this, right?
Yes. Great work.
You're such a quick
study. Keep it up.
Keep it up.
Her aorta is like a rock.
I don't know how we're
gonna sew in this graft.
Where is this
bleeding coming from?
I'm not sure. Hold pressure.
You should be down there
watching what they're doing.
I can see from here.
Primary aortoduodenal fistulas,
they almost never happen.
- My finger.
- Why not?
This usually would present
as a kind of pulsating mass.
Something like that, a patient
wouldn't wait to seek treatment.
The fistula would never develop.
With Alzheimer's, they don't
remember if they told anyone.
Someone should've been there.
Paying attention.
All right. Let's see.
You should be down there.
Sir, respectfully, I am
not going down there.
You should stop asking.
The proximal clamp fractured
the atherosclerotic plaque.
We have to get
above the bleeding.
What are they doing now?
Aneurysms like these
are caused by a buildup
of atherosclerotic plaque.
Their clamp broke off a
chunk of one these plaques.
And that aorta
opened right back up.
They think they'll be able
to move the clamp up higher
and control the bleeding,
but they're already up to
the superior mesenteric artery.
There isn't any place
left for them to go.
I don't understand.
What does that mean?
It means, they've just
about run out of options.
I don't know what else to do.
Just wait. Just... Just
a minute. Just a minute.
Is there anyone I
can call for you?
Shh!
Bailey. Try dividing
the renal vein.
That might get you
above the fractured plaque.
But she's exsanguinating.
I don't think...
Just try it!
Okay. Scalpel.
Here you go, Doctor.
Hey. Hey. Are you...
Hey. Look, I was kidding.
Come on. That wasn't
even the worst thing I said.
Oh, God. Please.
You're not a garbage
eater, okay? I'm sorry.
Look at your face.
I got you. I so got you.
What? Tears, baby.
The number one
tool of the street kid.
Turn on the water works,
you can get out of anything.
Wait, wait. You
can just cry like that?
Got three surgeries
out of you, chump.
Come on. That's not fair.
Chicks can get away with junk like
that. That would never work for me.
You're wrong. A girl
crying is one thing,
but a guy crying
freaks everybody out.
Really?
For sure. Show me how.
Coming up.
Hello. Hey, you're awake.
No, not really.
Oh! Sorry.
I wanted to check your
post-op vitals. How's your BP?
You know who would
know that would be a nurse.
Why don't you call a nurse?
Right. I'll do that.
Why are you whispering?
I'm in a hotel bathroom.
And I'm about to have sex.
For the first time in months.
I'm hanging up now.
Okay. Well, rest up.
Hey.
I decided to take a bath,
which you're gonna appreciate.
'Cause I smell amazing.
I'm sorry, Callie. I'm...
I wanted to be
spontaneous and fun.
But I...
I can't.
And I'm so sorry, Callie.
I'm, I...
I'm not...
I'm not ready.
Please don't be mad.
What are you doing?
Calling room service. We're
gonna need champagne
to go with our mac
and cheese cupcakes.
What?
Sorry. It's just your
technique. It's kind of beautiful.
It's Dr. Sloan's
technique, actually.
But I am pretty good at it.
Here. You try.
Okay.
Hey, just checking
in. What's the story?
Stuart's afraid he's not
gonna be able to ride anymore
because he wiped
out and hit Chicken Bill,
and Chicken Bill hit
Roach Clip, who ended up
taking out Gasoline, The
Hammer, and Blue Corner Pete.
Medically. I meant
what's the story medically?
Well, his limb is still viable.
And we're almost done
with the debridement.
So as soon as he heals up,
I will get him back in
here for a skin graft.
That sounds good.
Thank you.
I think I'll take it from here.
Okay. Definitely.
You need to stop.
You are not gross
and you are not Karev.
Owen.
Oh, Cristina, I'm sorry.
I haven't had two
seconds to think about...
Oh, no, me either.
Actually, I wasn't
looking for you.
Is Avery still in there
with Stuart? Yeah. Why?
Oh, my patient needs
a pericardiocentesis,
and she won't let me touch
her until I take her to see him.
Let me guess. We're
talking about Gasoline?
You know Gasoline?
Oh, we go way back.
A couple of hours ago, she
threatened to have me beaten senseless.
Sounds like her. What a doll.
Wait.
She wants to get
close to Stuart?
Yeah. What?
I need you to page security
and have them meet me in
the ER as soon as possible.
Right away, Doctor. Owen, what?
Where the hell did she go?
Stuart's the reason
they all crashed.
You screw with one of
them, they all screw with you.
We don't keep any tire
irons around, do we?
We need to find her. Now.
They're sewing in the graft now.
Onto the aorta?
Yes.
What's her BP?
100 over 60.
Heart rate?
98.
What's happening, sir?
Dr. Webber?
It's working.
Don't you freakin' touch me!
Move your ass or
he'll move it for you!
Gasoline, this wasn't our deal.
Shove your deal.
You cagers wouldn't
let me see Stuart,
and now my guys find
out he had to have surgery?
I need to see him now!
He is one of us and he's
hurt and he might freakin' die,
and I need to see him!
What did you do
with the room key?
The room key?
Oh, come on!
I gave you the room key
before we left the freakin' room.
No, you didn't. Did you?
You do this all the time.
You did this last week with the
check for Becky's piano lesson.
What is wrong with you?
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
What's the problem?
I lost the key to our room.
Look. I'm sorry.
It's been a very long day.
And obviously we
are both very drunk.
Oh, no. What's your room number?
220.
Jordan Shouse? That's it.
There.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
I think that every food should
be turned into a cupcake.
Mmm.
Lasagna cupcakes.
- Mashed potato cupcakes.
- Mmm!
Callie. Mmm.
Please don't run.
What?
It's all been awful.
And I've been awful.
But I'm just starting to
feel like myself again.
And I know that not everything
can be about my leg all the time.
And I don't want it to be,
but right now, it just...
It is.
But I can't lose you.
So please.
Don't run.
After the car accident,
you never left my side.
Not once.
There's no way
I'm leaving yours.
What would you say to
a good old-fashioned
junior-high make out?
Thank God you were
there. You saved her life.
I almost got her killed,
leaving her in that place.
You did what you
thought was best.
No, I did what I was told.
I never thought it was best.
It won't happen again.
Miranda.
You have to get going.
Go.
Richard.
You came.
You're here.
I'm here, baby.
Stay with me.
Just stay.
I'm not going anywhere.
I'm here.
Hey. Hey.
Promise me you won't put me
in a home if I get Alzheimer's.
You okay?
Yeah. Just promise me.
I promise.
Thank you.
Insert the needle
just below the xiphoid.
Good.
That's good.
Dragging her all over the
hospital wasn't the best idea.
You've met her.
How well do you think
it goes when I say no?
You're gonna need
to explain Stuart.
He's our accountant.
Got us on a group health plan,
helped us set up a
Christmas toy drive.
He wanted to ride, so
we let him hang around.
Thought it was funny.
Now he's like family.
She got him one of these.
Which means he's
one of us for life.
If he was gonna die, she
wanted him to at least see it.
Have you seen his arm?
Doesn't look like he's
gonna get on a bike again.
What do you drive, Doc?
Pickup.
Yeah. Figures.
You're a cager.
Whenever you hit the road,
you're stuck in a metal box.
But the day you
step out of that cage,
say sayonara to your
job, your marriage,
or whatever the hell
else is boxing you in,
you'll never give that up.
Oh, I... I'm... I'm coming.
I have to get my dress.
Okay, take a breath.
Just... I didn't forget.
It was Adele Webber.
I mean, if it was
anybody else...
Well, is she okay?
Stable in the ICU.
We thought she
wasn't gonna make it.
Look, if I'd known
it was her, I...
Hey, we're gonna make it.
I don't know what
they did with my dress.
Look, Miranda.
Miranda, slow down.
Slow down.
Okay, I forgot.
Just for like 20 minutes.
We... We were in
the trauma room,
and she'd lost so much blood,
and we had to rush
up to endoscopy,
and in those 20 minutes,
I forgot
about you and the wedding.
Somebody had to remind me.
Well, was a person dying?
I mean, really
dying, right then?
Well, yeah.
Well, then you're
supposed to forget.
Anyway, you were never so crazy
about the wedding
in the first place.
Yeah, but I...
You were crazy about me, right?
Yeah.
About marrying me?
You were sure about that?
I'm just so scared.
See, I'm scared
that you get it now
only because it
was Adele Webber.
And see, and this is not gonna
be the last time that I forget,
because I have so
many things I want to do,
things I want to be.
See, my ambition, it
killed my last marriage.
I don't want to do that to you.
Miranda, Miranda, you...
You do know that I'm not at home
waiting around with
a roast in the oven?
Yeah. No, I... I'm
in Los Angeles,
becoming a surgeon, too.
I have things I
want to do and be.
And... And... And...
We may only be together
five minutes every two months,
but, hey, when we do,
we will savor every second.
Because we both know how
valuable those five minutes are.
Do you love me?
More than I can
hold in my heart.
You're sure about that?
I am completely sure of that.
Do you want to spend
the rest of your life with me,
even if it is only in
five-minute increments
every two months?
I do.
Then by the power vested in
me by the state of Washington,
I now pronounce
you husband and wife.
All right.
I am so sorry. I didn't mean...
Hey, you cut that
crap out right now.
You didn't do anything.
The Hammer saw the whole thing.
That minivan
drifted into our lane.
Could've made any one of
us wipe out the way you did.
That's right.
That...
Is that mine?
Does this mean that
I get my road name?
We were all thinking
maybe "Road Rash."
God. That's freakin' hard-core.
All right. Give it
up for the little guy.
We missed the whole thing.
Well, maybe she won't notice.
I hope whatever you
were doing was worth it,
'cause you're a
terrible maid of honor.
Easy, easy, easy.
What did I miss? Oh,
pretty much everything.
And Bailey calling
me her maid of honor.
Look at this ring.
Did you see the ring?
And we missed the ceremony.
Oh, shoot.
So...
What do we...
I could take you home.
I can't sleep with you.
That's not what I was...
It wasn't?
You're great, it's just that I
don't... I don't sleep with interns.
I don't... I mean, I... I
don't sleep with my boss.
Yeah, it's messy.
And I've had enough
drama lately, so...
We are entirely
on the same page.
Great.
The lawyer sent over
the divorce papers.
We don't have to
do this right now.
Let's just...
Let's just take a minute and
think about what this means.
I'm done thinking
about it, Cristina.
And?
We should never have
gotten married in the first place.
When we did, we took
something beautiful
and we put it in this box.
And for the last two
years, all we have done
is beat against those walls
and tear each other apart.
Now we sign these papers,
that ends.
We get out of that box.
We don't hurt each
other anymore.
You're gonna want to
remember tonight, Shane.
That is what a great
night in the ER looks like.
We deserve to celebrate.
Let's just get stupid drunk
and dance and...
Dr. Kepner,
I know what you think
is gonna happen,
but it can't.
Look, I worked too hard to
get into this program to start
sleeping with my mentor.
So thank you for the
interest, but, no, thank you.
What makes you think
that I want to sleep with you?
You touched my shoulder
and you brought me wine.
I was being nice.
Oh.
But you feel that you're
being sexually harassed?
No. No, I'm not... No.
Okay, good. Good.
Good. I'm glad
that's all cleared up.
So now we can just have fun.
Cheers.
Where is everybody else?
Oh, Lord.
What? You want
me to put it back on?
Are you kidding? Don't
ever put it back on.
Oh, sorry.
Wait.
This is so soft.
It's like it's made
out of polar bear.
I think this is my room.
What happened to the
mac and cheese cupcakes?
Are you kidding me?
You kept your guests
waiting five hours.
Now I saved a woman's life.
You couldn't save me some food?
You...
Go take care of
your guests, baby.
You look beautiful.
So I'm... I'm glad you
made it. Now how's her BP?
All right.
Where's our bride and groom? Go.
You've been keeping him
waiting long enough tonight. Go.
Everybody's been waiting
a while for this dance.
Ladies and gentlemen, let's
give it up for the newlyweds!
The next time you're
in your doctor's office,
remember,
she's not asking all those
questions for her health.
She's asking them for yours.
You're here?
No.
When?
Tell her everything.
The small details aren't trivial.
They actually make the story.
A little while ago.
What happened?
It was a heart attack.
The surgery fixed the aneurysm,
but it was too
much for her heart.
I shouldn't have...
No.
You did everything right.
Everything.
There's no rush.
Take all the time you need.
Start at the beginning.