Karen!
Uh, K-Kar... Karen... What's the deal?
Did you not see me?
Of course I did,
but I ran because your face says
you want money for something.
Oh, well, yeah, I do.
What is it today?
Therapy dogs for postpartum mothers?
Improv classes for survivors of PTSD?
Uh, no, good idea, both of those,
but I was thinking that, um...
-I want to end systemic racism.
-Oh, for God's sake.
No, just at the hospital.
Start small, right?
Wow, kind of controversial stance,
walking away, siding with racism.
Kind of a Karen move, Karen.
My exasperation with you has no relation
to my thoughts on racism.
-Why today, Max?
-Knew you were going to ask that.
There is no answer.
We should be asking the right question,
which is, why not yesterday?
Why not a year ago?
Why not two years ago
when I first took over?
Systemic racism
should have been the first thing
I addressed when I got to New Amsterdam
and I'm appalled that it wasn't.
-So today it is.
-And you need money for...
A new position,
someone to help us identify
and eliminate systemic marginalization
while correcting inequities
throughout the whole hospital.
You want a chief equity officer?
Yeah, that's perfect. We'll call it that.
Oh and I am not going anywhere
until you give me one.
Well, in that case, go away,
because we already have one.
We do?
-Hey.
-Oh, hi there. Uh...
Are you...
Let's see here. Isabel?
-Yes.
-Great, I'm Max Goodwin, medical director.
How can I help?
I see what you did there.
Um, yeah, I'm here to discuss
some pretty disturbing, uh, statistics.
-Hit me.
-Okay.
Well, according to the latest report
by Health and Human Services,
Latinx women are 40% more likely
to have cervical cancer
and 20% more likely to die from it
than white women.
Indigenous Americans
have twice the HIV infection rate
as that of non-Hispanic whites.
Black women are two to six times
more likely to die from complications
of pregnancy than white women.
Actually, it's 12 times more likely
in New York City.
Your statistics are a bit... generic.
Oh.
-How long have you worked here?
-Three years.
Three... three years?
Well, we have a lot of work to do.
That's exactly what
I say to you in my messages.
Once a week,
I leave word with your office,
hoping to get some time with you.
Sorry, sometimes,
with this hospital, I'm just running
and, uh... Not important. Listen.
-I'm here now, okay?
-Okay.
And we are going to fix this.
So I want innovative proposals
on my desk by tomorrow.
And think big. You know, get creative.
No solution is off the table.
Should we start with acknowledging
New Amsterdam's biggest illustration
of embedded systemic racism?
Yes, yes, of course. What is it?
You.
-Good read?
-Don't get me started.
Actually, do get me started.
I've been made executor
of my brother's will
-and I haven't the foggiest.
-I thought you two weren't close.
Well, we weren't, but now I'm in charge
of his house, his car, his saxophones.
The only thing I'm confident about is
making arrangements for his daughter Mina
to live with her aunt in Dubai...
[chuckles] in an actual palace.
You have a niece.
And a rich second aunt
who doesn't want my brother's boat
because she already has several.
Well, you keep it.
We could spend our vacation at sea.
Sky, the waves, you and me.
It's a rowboat.
Then Bora Bora it is.
So did you like the rest
of Catcher in the Rye?
What about that red hunting hat, man?
I thought that would be
right up your alley.
-Mm, it was fine.
-It was fine.
You, uh... you talked my ear off
about the Ducks last session.
The red hunting hat is way more important.
[grunts softly]
Oh, I'm sorry. What's up with your hand?
I... I fell on it wrong.
Oh, okay. Well, just in case,
let me take a look.
It's fine.
That's a little too much fine
for one session, Ollie. Let me see.
Radiology's slammed,
but they'll fit him in right away.
Okay, thank you. See that, buddy?
VIP treatment for you, right?
What happened?
Uh, he said he fell.
No, Mama, last night, I separated them all
and put them
in your monthly pill organizer, remember?
Yes, of course you can still call me
whenever you want, but...
No, but take the yellow pill now,
the yellow pill while I'm on the phone.
[door bangs open]
Incoming!
A tour bus jumped the curb
in Times Square.
Superman may have a fractured wrist,
but he won't stay put long enough
for me to check.
-Okay, what's his real name?
-ID says Murph Coleman,
but he only responds to Superman.
Kebir Abad,
38-year-old male falafel vendor.
Second-degree hot oil burns
covering both arms.
-[groaning]
-Superman, get back in your chair.
Not till this man's in bay 24!
-Hammond!
-On it.
Skelly, Williams, team three, bed five.
Hey, you got to hold this, okay?
It's important.
Stable vitals? Team one, bed nine.
You okay? You got to keep your eyes open.
-Someone get me Cassian.
-All right.
-Let's do it.
-You going to be okay?
-Got to go.
-I can't...
Come on. Let's not back up triage.
Hammond.
-[sighs] Hammond!
-[grunting]
-Sorry. He really is faster than...
-Do not! Just get him back in his chair.
Wilmer Belasco, male, 42 years old.
Blunt force trauma to the chest.
Heart rate 113, BP 161 over 98.
Possible cracked sternum.
-My boy...
-Don't try to talk. Mr. Belasco.
Hector Belasco,
-13-year-old boy BP 126 over 87.
-That's my son!
Lauren, I got him. I got him.
-[muffled speech]
-Doc, no!
-[Floyd] He's going to be taken care of.
-Hi, Hector, I'm Dr. Shin. It's okay.
-We're going to take good care of you.
-Bilateral compound femur fracture,
-possible hypovolemic shock from injuries.
-Okay, let's take a look.
-[screams]
-[both yelling, screaming]
Trauma one.
-Dad!
-[yelling in Spanish]
Sir.
-In the chair, Superman.
-But I just...
Stay put.
[phone vibrating]
How could you do this to me?
I'm not going to Dubai.
Mina, um, so just give me a second to...
I have friends, a boyfriend,
a whole life here.
If you had bothered to call me
after my father died,
you'd know that.
Do you know how far Dubai is from Tehran?
Mina, I know that it's hard,
but I'm sure your dad would've wanted you
to be with family.
You know nothing about my father.
-Can I talk to you a second?
-Can it wait? I just got...
No, uh, I just made a commitment to ending
the inherent and systemic racism
here at this hospital
and I know what I need to do.
-[clears throat] Max...
-I'm stepping down as medical director.
Who is taking over?
You are.
[breathes heavily]
You want me to be medical director?
-Yeah.
-And you, you'll just...
Quietly recede into a supporting role.
-You've never done anything quietly.
-Yeah, I know. That's exactly the problem.
I tried to force an initiative
on Black barber shops
to get them to turn into
community health ops.
I have called the WHO every single day
for three months, three months,
trying to get racism
coded as a health risk
and now I realize that none of it was ever
actually going to change anything,
because I am part of the problem.
-Says who?
-My chief equity officer.
[chuckles] We have a chief equity officer?
Yeah, Isabel. She's very sweet.
But as women of color,
you are both vastly under... Hi.
...underrepresented in management,
which makes you much less likely
to get a promotion
and therefore not in a position
to then hire other women of color,
so it's a vicious cycle really,
but the thing is it can be changed
if a woman of color is at the top,
which is exactly why
you need to say yes to this job.
-No.
-You could do a lot of good.
Here I thought I was doing good,
being an oncologist.
More good.
Do you not see the irony in asking someone
who's suffering from systemic racism
to also fix it?
Well, does that mean you'll consider it?
Okay, no, Helen, I...
Oh, I don't know where to start!
Just look to your right.
Hey, you are going to be just fine.
I got him down in a wheelchair,
but he got up again.
-Here we go!
-Superman, stay in the chair!
Have Walsh clear Superman's wrist
and escort him out of here, okay?
-Where am I going?
-Hey!
Hey, this has to get to the trauma room.
This is Mr. Abad.
Before his car flipped over,
-he saw the whole accident.
-Hammond, do not let him into trauma one.
Doing the best I can.
Right here.
[grunts] Hey!
Right before his car tipped over,
he saw the whole accident.
Tell Dr. Bloom what you just told me.
It was the craziest thing I've ever seen.
The minute the bus jumped the curb,
everybody started running,
Except for Superman!
[chuckles]
-He just stood there.
-Why?
No idea, but he took the hit like a champ.
I hope someone got video.
-Superman got hit by the bus?
-Hard.
I don't know he's still standing.
-Well, he is the Man of S...
-Don't say it.
Page neurology now.
I've got 52 bones.
Did you hear that Ollie hurt his hand?
Yes.
It's really bad.
I'm a doctor
and I can't even figure out what happened.
I'm not stupid. I know you think I did it.
Did you?
I had to. I had no choice.
Juliet, you were making such progress.
He insulted my brother, my parents.
I was defending their honor.
You were defending their honor?
When I took the vow of the samurai,
I took the vow to the death.
-Is this a joke to you?
-Sure.
Because I didn't do it.
Okay. [clears throat]
Juliet, do you remember the rules
of the game that we've been playing?
Expert level.
I only win
if the loser doesn't think they lost.
If I upset them or hurt them, I lose.
Correct.
So when you smashed Ollie's hand,
you lost.
Except I didn't smash Ollie's hand.
I was joking.
I don't think you're telling the truth.
Right now or before?
Now. I think
you're lying to protect yourself.
-Final answer?
-This is not a game, Juliet.
This is not the game!
Okay.
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have yelled.
It wasn't very professional.
Okay.
Here's what I want.
I want you to tell me one true thing
about Ollie's hand.
One true thing, that's it.
Luisa did it.
Luisa.
[indistinct chattering]
Hi. Can I see you for a second please?
My wrist feels fine.
I'd love to get back downstairs
in case anyone needs my help.
They don't. I need you to hold still.
-What?
-I was just wondering
why he annoys you so much.
Everyone annoys me this much.
Good to know.
The world's a disaster right now.
We all need to pitch in to try to fix it.
Got no patience for someone
dressing up pretending to.
[beeping]
Well, there's no fractures,
or internal damage to his legs or trunk.
It's crazy.
-It's like he's made of steel.
-He's not.
Look.
A brain bleed.
[ringing tone]
Mina.
Don't hang up.
I have nothing to say to you.
You were right. I don't know
the first thing about you,
but, uh, I want to.
I really do.
So, please, can we just try again?
It doesn't matter anyway.
I don't have to move to Dubai anymore.
You...
I don't understand.
I'm moving in with my boyfriend.
We're going to get married.
Really? Um...
Mina, you're 16.
Sixteen, so what?
So marriage is a big decision
and it should really only come
from wanting to spend
the rest of your life with someone.
Is that how you feel about your boyfriend?
No, but it's better than being forced
to live somewhere I hate.
Okay, no, no, okay,
then we'll find you someplace else.
Where?
I don't know, but we can try-
There's no place else!
Marrying Ali's the only way-
What about staying with me?
New York?
[sighs]
[Cassian] Satinsky.
That bus really did a number
on this kid's femur.
Yeah and a splintered femur did a number
on the femoral artery.
Dr. Shin, is this infected?
[Cassian] Nurse, palpate that finger.
Hard and cold. Slow capillary refill.
That's not infected.
The whole finger's clotted off.
Hector's in DIC. Book an OR.
[excited chattering]
The trauma's upset the fibrin
activation balance in his blood.
He could have a heart attack any minute.
No disrespect, but how come
all old-timey doctors were white dudes?
They weren't,
but they were the only ones we hired.
Shall we?
[Run The Jewels' "JU$T"]
♪ Mastered economics ♪
Good, good, racist. Here.
-What's going on here?
-Surgical experimentation.
Sexist.
Racist, racist, racist, racist.
♪ Look at all these slave masters
Posing on your dollar ♪
Forced sterilization.
♪ Slave masters posing on your dollar ♪
♪ Deafening reckoning ♪
And homophobe.
Misogynist.
♪ For you, it's just money ♪
No, Mama,
the shutoff valve stops the water.
Right. No, no, no, wait, wait, wait.
Just let me call a plumber,
so you won't hurt your...
[woman] Oh, dear! Are you all right?
-Oh, Floyd, sorry, buddy.
Just, uh, working on ending racism
and forgot to put out the wet paint sign.
You're ending racism... with paint?
Yeah, well, no. That would be... silly.
This is just a symbol of our commitment
to ending racism.
Okay, uh, and it'll be backed
with real policy change?
-Oh, yeah, absolutely.
-Starting with?
Starting with, uh...
Starting with, uh... Yeah, well, you know,
still analyzing the facts and...
How about the fact that Black doctors
get paid 35% less than white doctors do?
[pager beeps]
-Not here.
-Yeah, here.
-Here?
-Mm-hm.
But... even you?
Even me.
What did they do with my cape?
I'm sure someone bagged it.
Don't worry. It's safe.
[sighs]
So what's it like working in Times Square?
Oh, it's the best. [chuckles]
Ever since I was a kid,
all I ever wanted to be was a hero.
-Always Superman?
-[chuckles] No.
I wanted to be a cop,
maybe a soldier, firefighter.
And why didn't you?
I tried, but I didn't meet
any of the size requirements.
Always been too small
to make a real difference.
But when I put on that cape...
Hey, Murph.
Being a hero's
got nothing to do with size.
So, Luisa, do you have anything at all
that you want to tell me?
About what?
I don't know.
I was thinking about Ollie's hand.
Did you hurt Ollie's hand?
No.
Well, Juliet, she says that you did.
She did?
Yeah, she did.
Then... I did.
No, don't tell me what you think
I want to hear, okay?
You just tell me the truth.
I am.
Luisa. Luisa, can I see your hand please?
It's okay. It's okay. Just...
I just need to take a peek, okay?
[sighs]
Did Juliet do that to you?
No.
She'll never know that you talked to me.
I promise you that.
I just want to make sure that
she never, ever hurts you again.
Do you understand?
Juliet didn't hurt me.
I'm her friend.
Juliet said that?
She told you that you're her friend?
Yes.
Her only friend.
-Right this way. Yeah.
-I have lunch...
I know. We'll be done in a second.
Come on in. Thank you, Dr. Bloom.
Okay, so, uh, guys,
I'm just going to dive right in.
So the reason that
I've asked you all here...
To the fourth floor storage room?
That's right.
...is to exercise a little discretion
and discuss something
that is a little uncomfortable, uh, money.
All of you in this room are the highest
earning doctors at New Amsterdam,
so I'm going to ask all of you,
uh, including myself,
-to renounce 10% of your salaries.
-[murmuring]
-Excuse me?
-What?
-Uh, wait. Is this a joke?
Not a... not a joke, actually.
We're going to take that money
from our collective reductions
and carefully redistribute it
to the physicians of color
who work in this hospital,
despite systemic pay discrimination.
Are you suggesting reparations?
Yeah, kind of. See? Harold gets it.
But we didn't hand out subpar salaries.
HCC did.
No, true, very true.
But, um, uh, well, we benefit from it.
So why don't you just raise the salaries
of the non-white physicians?
Right, yes.
Another very good idea, Harold.
Really kind of on fire today,
but I tried that.
I tried that and HCC could not afford it.
Did you notice that the wage gap
is even wider for women?
-Yeah.
-10% worse, in fact.
So, uh, why are women here?
Right, well, uh, of course, but we're not
discussing gender at the moment.
Oh, okay. So when's that meeting?
That meeting
is going to be scheduled right...
I knew
there was secret white doctor meetings.
Yeah, I'm going to go with you.
Dr. Bloom. Uh, guys,
uh, let me just say one more thing.
Wait, wait. Guys, guys, hold on.
Shut the door. Wait, one second please.
If I could finish. It's not a lot to ask
and it's really going to help
a lot of people,
but, um, thank you so much for listening.
Richardson retractor.
[monitors beeping]
Asystole.
EPI and a ten gauge.
-[Cassian] No response.
-[chattering]
Heart's gone.
[monitors beeping]
I'm not calling it.
-Dr. Reynolds.
-Give him a minute.
-Come on, Hector.
-[chattering]
Initiate cardiac bypass.
At least we can give him a few more hours.
[sighs]
[background chattering]
Heart transplant?
He's just a child.
Yes.
And pediatric heart transplant recipients
have challenging size restrictions.
But being on bypass puts him
at the very top of the donor list.
Don't lose hope for a match.
Dr. Reynolds, I love my boy,
more than anything in the world.
But how can I hope
for another boy's heart?
[sniffles] Hm?
Have you heard
of this term intersectionality?
-Of course. Haven't you?
-Yeah, of course, after I googled it.
Right, well, once you solve racism,
you can put out
a word of the day calendar.
I know you're joking,
but, uh, that's not a bad idea.
Look, I want to apologize.
Uh, it was really unfair of me for trying
to dump that whole thing on you.
-Thank you. I appreciate that.
-Yeah, so I have a better proposition.
Huh, I can't believe it.
Yeah, you could be my, uh... oh.
Be my partner.
Uh, co-medical directors.
And before you say anything,
just think about how... [chuckles]
how great, uh, we'd be together, you know?
I mean, you know the terminology
and I know the system and I just think...
You know, I'm always better when you're
around and... and it's starting...
to be obvious to me that...
Stop. Stop talking.
-Sorry. You're trying to pee...
-No. Just actually...
like, just stop talking.
Have you ever noticed that
you always present your big plans
while you're walking and talking?
[chucklers]
I... I think that it gives you a sense
of momentum that feels encouraging.
But it's actually an illusion,
because this building is a box, Max,
and you're walking in circles.
And while that might
sometimes be enough time
for you to come up with a quick fix,
you're not going to fix this,
because, and I can't believe
I actually have to say this, but...
systemic racism isn't about you.
But you want answers.
Well, then just hold still.
Just be quiet
and just...
Just really listen to the people
that you say you want to help.
It's not revolutionary.
It's not outside of the box and it is
certainly not going to be a quick fix.
And if you can't...
if you can't handle that,
then you're not an ally at all.
You're just another semi-woke liberal
with a white savior complex.
All right, we are here
because I want you to see firsthand
the damage that you've done...
and understand why you've lost the game.
But I didn't lose.
Two kids are hurt because of you.
And I'm afraid that
you can't stay here anymore.
-I didn't lose!
-I'm going to have to call your parents.
I didn't lose the game!
I'm better at the game than you are!
You're the one who lost.
You hurt Luisa
and when Ollie found out,
you hurt him too.
Is that what happened?
That's what happened, right?
-No.
-Don't look at her.
I don't care what she told you.
She is not your friend.
-Yes, I am.
-Juliet, not another word.
[sighs]
I'm sorry. I have to.
-It started when...
-It was Luisa! She just attacked me!
Because he kept grabbing me!
You did this.
He kept trying to hold my hand,
even when I told him to stop.
Why didn't you tell me?
Because Ollie said he wouldn't get in
trouble for just trying to hold my hand,
but I wanted him to stop.
-You're being a baby.
-No, she is not and you are in trouble.
Ollie. Ollie...
-Thank you. Take him to his room.
-Told you.
-Salam.
We broke up.
Ali and me.
-Oh?
-You were right.
I didn't want to marry him.
That was stupid.
But I do want to come to New York.
You changed your mind, didn't you?
It's, um...
It's complicated.
My job is all-consuming.
My apartment is not made for kids
and this city is...
It's big.
But I do care about you, Mina,
and I promise I will check on you
and make sure you have everything you need
with money or with, um,
help with college applications.
So, basically...
you don't have room
in your life for family.
That's not what I said -
No, that's what my father said about you.
I guess he was right.
[hangs up]
I should have known that regular
anesthesia would be no match for...
-The surgery was successful.
-It was.
The burr hole relieved pressure,
but the bleed had already
done too much damage.
He's not going to wake up.
Okay.
-I'm going to look for next of kin.
-Yeah.
[PA announcements in background]
-You sure you got time for this?
-I got all the time in the world.
I started treating patients here the same
time as three other white residents,
but you know how long it took
the department chair to learn my name?
Go ahead. Guess.
Then I'll tell you how long it took
for him to stop calling me sister girl.
I'm not a female surgeon.
I'm not a Puerto Rican surgeon.
I'm a surgeon and I'm one of the best.
Nanny. [scoffs]
Do you see children around me?
I mean, I'm wearing my badge. Hello?
I'm not the translator.
Listen, you don't have to speak Spanish
to me all the time. I speak English.
It was misdiagnosed
because the test didn't account for higher
creatine levels in Black folk.
No matter how many times
I tell 'em, it's sickle cell,
white doctors always have me
take a drug test.
Blamed it on insurance.
I'm like, "For real?"
How does a white male gynecologist
know my pain better than I do?
Four generations, US.
My newborn does not need a TB shot.
I don't have a green card,
but I do have an American passport.
The only border I ever cross
is New Jersey.
I didn't go to school for 12 years
to learn how to smile more.
When Dr. Reynolds made chair, do you
think people asked if his dad was proud?
I see how they look at me
the moment they hear my voice.
He said we can't all be enlightened
as you about gender.
Max, it's not really about
remembering my pronouns.
It's about actually believing me
when I tell you who I am.
I don't know how many of us there are.
-AIDs.
-SIDs.
-Mixed race.
-Multiethnic.
-None of the above.
-Indigenous?
That can be from any part of the world.
I am a Native American.
People call me many things. Bitch.
-Chola.
-Coon. Spook.
-Fragile.
-List goes on and on.
Other.
-Other.
So I owe you a huge apology.
I'm waiting.
[sighs]
I'm sorry.
I'm very sorry that I doubted you.
No, worse. I...
I decided that you were guilty before
you ever even set foot in my office
and I am sorry.
Seems judgmental for a doctor.
I agree.
And I should have had more faith
in your progress, in you, honestly.
Ollie is bad, but I would never lose
the game just to hurt him.
Yeah, I believe you.
So I told Luisa how to do it.
You... You did what?
I told Luisa how to get him alone,
where no one would see,
and I told her to use the door
because it was the best way
for someone her size...
No, no, Juliet, no, you can't do that.
You can't teach kids to hurt other kids.
I taught her how to defend herself.
-That is not your job.
-But she's my friend.
Do you really consider Luisa
to be your friend?
Yes.
Okay.
New rule to the game.
You can't help anyone hurt someone else.
If you do, you lose.
-Starting now?
-Yeah, starting now.
So I'm still winning, right?
Right.
You're still winning.
Heard about your 2021 listening tour.
-I was on the subway this morning.
-Mm-hm.
And there was this toddler, who's
a cute little Black boy around Luna's age,
-and he was just exploring.
-[chuckles]
You know, running around and...
And this random guy starts...
yelling at this kid's mom.
"Control your damn kid."
And... that guy would deny it...
but when Luna runs around like that,
nobody yells at her.
I mean, it's the opposite, you know?
People smile and do funny little voices
and...
Luna gets to grow up
seeing the world as safe,
friendly.
And that kid...
gets screamed at...
and his mom gets to be on high alert
every second of every day,
knowing there's always another guy
who's ready to yell at her kid
or make him feel small, or one day...
or one day kill him.
Do you know what I said
to that racist on the train?
Nothing.
Because I didn't even realize it
until I got off the train.
Look, I'm not going to ask you
to... fix everything.
I just want you to know
that I'm grateful...
that you're here.
It's... It's... It's been hard.
But it's been easier...
knowing that you are here.
I'm here to inform you
that I'm stepping down
as deputy medical director.
I'm sorry that it's poor timing.
The job has meant so much to me.
But I have to focus
on other things right now.
Okay, okay.
Okay.
Thank you... for listening.
[woman]
But your patient's size is limited.
I'll try again in 20 minutes.
I'm sorry about Superman, Lauren.
Nothing about today
feels like it makes sense.
Maybe it does.
He thought he was too small
to really make a difference.
[music: Nina Simone's "New World Coming"]
♪ There's a new world coming ♪
♪ And it's just around the bend ♪
♪ This one's coming to an end ♪
♪ There's a brand-new morning ♪
♪ Rising clear and sweet and free ♪
♪ There's a new day dawning ♪
♪ That belongs to you and me ♪
♪ There's a new world coming ♪
♪ This one's coming to an end ♪
♪ There's a new voice calling ♪
♪ And you can hear it if you try ♪
♪ There's a brand-new morning ♪
♪ Rising clear and sweet and free ♪
♪ There's a new day dawning ♪
♪ That belongs to you and me ♪
[monitors beeping]
♪ Yes, a new world's coming ♪
[breathes heavily]
♪ That belongs to you and me ♪
[exhales sharply]
[phone rings]
Hey, Mama.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I'll be home soon.
Yeah, yeah, you want me to cook that up?
I can cook that up. [chuckles]
Soon as I get there.
I just got to go to the store.
I met with Max today...
to step down as deputy medical director.
Oh, yeah?
Why is that?
'Cause Mina's coming to New York
to live with me.
Mm.
So you changed your mind?
I did.
Having Mina here with me, getting to know
my family, that's what feels right.
Mm.
Well, then I'm very excited.
Um, but if I'm going to do this,
then I have to put my whole self into it.
Everything I have has to go to her.
Of course. I'll help in any way I can.
No, you won't.
'Cause everything I have...
has to go to her.
This is what you want?
♪ There's a brand-new morning ♪
But it's not about me anymore.
♪ Rising clear and sweet and free ♪
♪ There's a new day dawning ♪
♪ That belongs to you and me ♪
[sighs]
♪ Yes, a new world's coming ♪
-So what are you going to do about this?
-I have absolutely no idea.
No idea what to put up that won't offend
someone, or exclude someone else,
or seem too hollow,
or... or too charged. I...
For the first time since I got here...
I have absolutely no idea what to do
for the people in this hospital.
Good.
Good? Uh, why is that good?
You're not supposed
to do things for people.
-That's not sustainable, Max.
-But...
But if you do things with people,
you can start a movement.
What do you need?
Say the word and it's yours.
A new office.
How is that going to end systemic racism
at New Amsterdam?
Because my new office
is going to be right next to yours.