Talking with a patient's family
is a crash course
in grace under pressure.
One clumsy word,
one careless gesture,
can cause irreparable harm.
Okay, hold on. You know what?
I need to get a picture of her
in this cute little hat.
Okay. Um.
Oh, come on. Great.
Camera's full.
You need to delete some pictures.
No, I just need a bigger phone.
- Okay?
- Yeah, okay. Hold on.
Mwah!
- Have a good day.
- Thank you. You, too.
Ideally you're dealing
with a healthy family,
where the main focus is on the
well-being of their loved one.
But that is not often the case.
Hey, what are you doing
with that elephant?
Uh... Uh Leo left it at day care,
and I need to give it back to
Owen before he freaks out.
It's his favorite.
We have three of them.
And that one's Ellis's.
Owen doesn't know I'm pregnant.
And I think I should probably tell him.
Yeah. Probably.
Unless, I mean...
He has his own baby with another person.
I mean, does it really matter?
He will get it, eventually,
when I'm huge and in labor and...
Right. Well, let me know what you decide.
I can't be late.
But a surgeon is required, above all,
to tell the truth.
And the truth is messy.
- Catherine.
- Maggie.
Hi! How is it being back?
- Oh, it's good to be operating again.
- Yeah.
Tell me, how are things
here with the restructuring?
Uh, Tom Koracick is...
a... brilliant surgeon.
Not everybody's cup of tea.
I heard he and Jackson
really got into it.
Oh, yeah, I wouldn't know.
That boy can be so tight-lipped.
He gets it from me.
And I know that's hard
to live with at times.
Have you and Jackson talked much lately?
We should have dinner soon.
The four of us.
- I don't know if that's such a good... Oh.
- Oh, no excuses.
Come on. Family's too important.
- Yeah, okay.
- Mm.
I'm looking forward to it.
Me, too. Yeah.
Richard Webber, are you seriously
just gonna walk on by me like that?
I'm sorry about what happened
in the diner.
- Let me make it up to you.
- I don't think so.
Just coffee... I'll keep my distance.
It's not a good idea.
Well, let's go ahead
and change her pain meds
from I.V. to oral.
- We need to talk.
- I am talking.
To someone else.
Sorry about that.
And check her drain output.
If it's below 20 cc,
we can go ahead and remove it.
Yes, you were saying?
Your mother would like to have dinner.
I know. She texted.
She thinks we're still together.
Oh. Yeah. "Oh."
I take it you didn't say
anything to Richard, then?
W-Well, I never see Richard
because he's, um...
- he's been fired.
- And that's my fault, too?
I-I'm having trouble
- keeping track with you.
- You know what? It's fine.
We can just tell them over dinner.
You should bring Vic.
- That'd be fun.
- I should bring Vic.
- Vic is fun.
- Ohh.
Do you guys laugh a lot
when you talk about her fiancé
who died 10 minutes bef...
I wonder if you can help me.
I'm looking for Richard Webber.
I'm sorry, does that woman look like me?
I dunno. I'd have to see her scowl first.
But he works here. I know it.
Richard Webber.
Can you check with someone?
Take it easy, Sabi.
Don't wear yourself out.
Yeah, I know who he is,
but he doesn't work here anymore.
You need to go to
Pacific Northwest General.
I'm sorry, I couldn't help but overhear.
Are you looking for Richard Webber?
Oh, my God, it's you!
Maggie!
Oh!
I can't believe it.
And who am I now?
Oh, sorry. I-I...
I'm Sabrina.
But everyone calls me Sabi.
Rhymes with "baby."
And this is my dad, Chris.
I-I'm sorry, I'm still confused.
I... I'm Sabrina Webber.
Richard's my uncle.
And he's your biological father.
So...
we're your family!
Synced & corrected by -robtor-
www.addic7ed.com
And I am not a big crier,
but I'm telling to you,
I cried for days.
I mean, that poor little hamster.
Long story short... never buy
a pet on Craigslist.
You wanna see a picture? It's gross.
- You'll love it.
- Oh, oh, no, thank you.
So, Uncle Richard got fired?
What happened?
It's a long story.
Drinking again?
What? No, no.
It was a-a bureaucratic matter.
"Bureaucratic matter"?
So there's a really long story.
So you're, like, a super genius, right?
I mean, well, that's what
all the articles say.
I'm sorry, this is j... It's so weird.
You know so much about me,
and I know almost nothing about you.
Not a surprise. Richard's ashamed of us.
What?
No, that can't be true.
Only you've never talked to us,
never met us, never even heard of us.
Yeah, d-don't mind him.
He's a grump.
Uncle Richard called us a while back,
after your podcast,
explained the whole secret affair thing.
Then I read all about you.
Made sense, too.
Genius is in our blood.
You know I got into Stanford. Uh-huh...
Woulda gone, too, except in-state tuition
- is a whole lot cheaper.
- Yeah, yeah.
I'm sorry, this is just so weird!
I mean, we look the same,
sound the same...
We could be twins!
Well, twins, no...
I mean, we're genetically...
we're more... Oh.
...akin to...
Well, that's... that's weird.
Mary Griggs to L&D.
- Owen.
- Yeah.
A... Amelia. Everything okay?
Fine.
Uh, great, actually. Um...
I just wanted to, uh...
to give this back to Leo.
Oh, well, thanks,
but I don't think this is...
Link and I are having a baby.
Wow. Um... okay.
And you need to know.
Well, I want Leo
to be in the baby's life.
He's already such a good big
brother to Allison, and I...
I'm... realizing in this moment
that we've gone from zero to
three babies in 60 seconds.
So... yay for all the babies!
- Incoming!
- Cassidy Gardner, 25, GCS 14,
blunt trauma to the abdomen, arm lac.
Hemodynamically stable.
Okay, what happened?
I fell down the stairs. I just fell.
Her son called 911.
Henry, Mommy's gonna be fine.
You did real good, buddy.
So someone's gonna sit with you
until we take care of your mom, okay?
I got him.
- I need the practice.
- Thanks.
Okay, let's go.
We need chest and pelvic X-rays now.
Uncle Richard!
Oh! Sabi?
What... What are you...
Maggie? Chris? W-W-What's going on?
They were looking for you at Grey-Sloan.
- It's so good to see you, Uncle Richard!
- Oh, my gosh.
We missed you at Christmas.
And Thanksgiving.
And Easter and birthdays
and family reunions.
I-I-I know. It's, uh,
been a tough year.
Has it been a tough five years?
Anyway, hi!
Hi.
Well... Well, um...
Welcome to Pac North.
Um, you want the tour?
Well, that sounds like fun,
but maybe in a minute.
I'm kinda worn out.
Okay, sweetie, take it easy.
And I need you look at something first...
I don't think he needs
to see a dead hamster.
No.
It's even grosser than that.
Oh, okay.
Why are you showing us a picture
of an insanely large biatrial myxoma?
Because it's mine.
You haven't had any other symptoms?
Some swelling in my legs.
Um, and I lose my breath sometimes
when I walk my dog.
These scans are three weeks old.
Why did you wait so long to come?
My doctor said it could be some time
before it got really bad.
And news like this,
it takes a minute to process.
And Dad wanted to go up to Chicago,
but I wanted to come here.
I'm glad you agreed.
I didn't want her traveling alone.
Okay, Sabrina, this kind of...
- Sabi, please.
- Okay. Sabi.
This kind of tumor is operable,
but it can grow really rapidly,
so we need to get
some new imaging right away.
It was really dumb of me
to wait, wasn't it?
Let's, uh... Let's go get those scans.
Was your dad home when your mom fell?
I don't have a dad.
I came home from school on the bus,
and Mom was in the basement
o-o-on the floor.
She couldn't move.
Is she gonna be okay?
She has got a really great
team of doctors
taking care of her.
Here.
Maybe holding this guy
will make you feel better.
I'm so sorry about this wait.
Do you want to sit down?
No, no. I'm okay now.
Minute you start acting sick,
that's when you really get sick.
So...
what's the tea?
- You know what tea is, right?
- Yeah, no, I do.
I just, uh...
I mostly work.
There's nothing? No scandal?
No love life?!
Uh, my ex-boyfriend rebounded
with a firefighter?
Gay?
Hot chick.
Okay, then. I hate him.
We're family. I've got you.
I hope he wakes up tomorrow,
realizes what a mistake he made,
but it's too late because
you're with Idris Elba.
Oh, girl.
Mm-hmm!
Girl, gimme your phone.
You need my number.
Here.
Mm.
Hey, do you like crossword puzzles?
Love 'em.
Acrostics, Sudoku,
but crosswords are the best.
I only do the ones
on the weekends, though,
- because the other ones are...
- ...too easy.
- Right?! I get so bored!
- I know.
We have so much shared DNA,
I bet we have a ton in common.
- Do you like classical music?
- Love it.
- Can you whistle?
- Yes!
I know that's not necessarily,
like, a genetic thing...
Um they're, uh... they're ready for you.
Okay.
- To be continued... Cuz!
- Yeah.
This thing smells new.
Am I the first person in it?
Close to it.
Hold still now.
I can't imagine how strange
this must be for you.
- I'm sorry I didn't tell you...
- Oh, are you kidding?!
It is fascinating.
And, yes, it's really, really strange.
I've never had a relative
who looked like me before.
And she's just been out there
practically my entire life,
just having different experiences.
I wonder if we've ever been
in the same town
at the same time before today.
I was in Dayton once.
I had a long layover.
I went to the mall.
Has it really been five years
since you saw each other?
Uh... Sabi's not like the others.
My brother and sister
always resented me for leaving,
resented my success.
Accused me of putting on airs
and acting like I was better.
Adele always had a way
of smoothing things over.
I should've tried harder after she died.
And they didn't know about me
until the podcast.
When I called to tell them, they, uh,
said some vicious things,
and I think I just wanted
to protect you from that.
But it's, uh,
it's nice to see the two of you
get along so well.
Oh, God.
The tumor's reaching up through
the tricuspid valve
and into her pulmonary artery now.
I think it's doubled in size.
This might be the biggest
heart tumor I have ever seen.
Is somebody gonna get me out
of this thing or what?
FAST exam shows the free fluid
on the perisplenic space.
Ma'am, did you have any
symptoms before you fell?
I-I was bringing the laundry upstairs,
and I got really dizzy.
Uh-huh. Wait, you see that?
Excess fluid?
That's a heartbeat.
Ma'am...
Ma'am, did you know
that you were pregnant?
Was or am?
We have a strong heartbeat.
Your baby's okay.
Okay?
It didn't work.
What... What didn't?
I can't have another baby.
I can't.
Jeanette Brody to Admitting.
- Hey. Hey.
- Hey.
How's Mom?
She's, um...
Listen, her fall wasn't an accident.
She was trying to terminate a pregnancy.
By throwing herself down the stairs?
I don't know. She's not talking much...
Well, do you want me to try?
She might be more comfortable
talking to another woman.
I can say it's a neuro check.
Sure, might help.
I already paged psych,
but they take forever around here, so...
- How pregnant is she?
- 8, 10 weeks. I'm not sure.
Uh, if you're not up to this,
then I can get someone else, you know.
Why wouldn't I feel up to it?
Because I'm all knocked up?
It's okay, Owen.
I don't need a fainting couch.
I will be fine.
Yeah, okay. Thank you.
- That's the same tumor?
- Yes.
And now it's extending
into your pulmonary artery.
Looks kinda like a baby swan
with that little neck.
Sabi...
this tumor isn't stable.
It could stop your heart's
ability to pump blood.
We need to get you up to surgery.
Today.
- Well, who's gonna do it?
- You're in luck.
This happens to be my specialty.
You? But you don't work here.
They granted me privileges,
so we're good to go.
But we're family.
And we're basically twins.
I mean, What if you see me lying
on that operating table,
and you freak out because
it's you on the table?
That is not a thing I do.
And I'm the best.
Then get second best.
Sabi, she won't even be able
to see your face.
It's covered during surgery.
Okay, that is really creepy.
Do people know that?
I-Isn't there a law
against operating on family?
It isn't a law. It's a guideline.
And since we've only known
each other about two hours,
I'm not really sure how it applies here.
Apple doesn't fall too far from the tree.
- Excuse me?
- You're steamrolling her,
thinking you know what's best.
You're not even listening
to her concerns.
I'm listening. They're just not valid.
Not valid?
We look alike,
we have some things in common,
but we're... we're not family.
Not in the way that matters.
I am the best cardiothoracic
surgeon in the Northwest.
I run my department. I innovate.
You want me in that room.
What makes you think
you know what she wants?
- You don't even know her.
- Which is why I can do this!
Richard? A little support, please?
Um... you know,
I don't trust the cardio surgeon
who's here today.
Thank you.
So I am your only option.
But, um...
there is an on-call surgeon
who's quite good.
I'll, um... I'll make a call.
Thank you.
Took you long enough.
Maggie.
Um, will you, uh, stick around
and brief the surgeon?
Maybe consult?
You want me to consult for
someone who's not as good as me
instead of giving your niece
the best shot she's got?
Maggie, they're family.
So you're just gonna agree with them
because of some bad history
with your brother?
No, that's not what I meant.
Look, they're your family, too.
I know you just met
and it may not feel that way,
but they... look, one day, it could.
And God forbid something
goes wrong in the OR and...
I'll always be the love child
who killed your favorite niece?
Oh, come on, now.
You'll never get a chance to know them.
And I never would've known they existed
if they hadn't come here.
Richard, your niece came here
for help as a doctor.
It's too bad you can't do her
the favor of thinking like one.
Yes, I'll consult.
Text me when he's here.
No sign of concussion.
How's Henry? Is he scared?
Henry is over the moon.
A very sweet nurse showed him
the snack drawer.
Cassidy, the CT shows
that there is some bleeding
in your spleen.
We're gonna have to take you up
to the OR to remove it,
and I can do that laparoscopically.
I-I don't have insurance right now.
Henry just qualified for a state program,
but I'm still waiting to hear.
Emergency departments
don't turn people away,
regardless of their financial situation,
so they will give you the
surgery that you need, okay?
But surgery, uh,
will put the fetus at risk,
so, I have to ask you...
Are you planning on keeping
this pregnancy?
I love Henry.
But it's a lot.
I already work at two restaurants,
and they try to give me
a flexible schedule,
but there's only so much
that they can do.
And another kid...
I mean, that's way more money,
and... and even more time
away from Henry.
I can't... I can't and I don't want to.
So you threw yourself down the stairs?
What?! Oh, my God, no!
No, I tried to go to a clinic
that had financial assistance
three times,
but something always fell through.
Henry got sick
or no one could sub for me.
I-I ran out of favors.
So I looked online, and I found this herb
that was supposed to work.
I-I doubled the recipe
to make sure it would work,
but it made me dizzy.
And then I fell.
I just fell.
I love my son.
And I would never do anything
to try to hurt myself.
I would never do anything
to try to hurt him.
Okay, Cassidy, listen.
You are okay right now.
And Henry is okay.
And if you want an abortion,
Dr. Hunt can get someone from OB
to do that during your surgery
once the bleeding in your
abdomen is under control.
Oh, God, really?
Thank you.
- Thank you so much...
- Um, actually, Cassidy,
I think we want to focus on
the fall injuries first.
Okay?
We can address the pregnancy
once we know that you're all right.
Oh. Okay.
Okay, so, we'll see you up
in the OR shortly.
- What are you doing?
- You really overstepped in there.
I'm a trauma surgeon.
I don't order abortions.
You would have if the fetus
hadn't survived.
But it did.
Owen, she's eight weeks.
She doesn't need a full D&C.
Exactly. It's not emergent,
but her internal injuries are.
So I'm gonna deal with those,
and then she can go see an OB.
She seems pretty clear in her thinking
and committed to her plan.
Why not just give her
the help she's asking for?
Thank you, Amelia, for your consult,
but I'm gonna take it from here, okay?
Hey.
- What are you doing here?
- In the neighborhood.
Lunch break. Having coffee with Alex.
What are you doing in enemy territory?
Wow. That's a beautiful tumor.
Are you taking this out?
I wish, but, no.
I can't do it.
Is it too risky?
Please. I would destroy that thing.
No, I can't do it because
it belongs to Richard's niece.
And she doesn't want me to.
We look so much alike we could be twins,
which is, you know, surreal,
but it's not more than I can handle.
But she thinks it would be like
getting cut into by herself.
I had a dream like that once.
- Not good.
- What are we all doing here?
- Alex.
- Patient.
What patient?
- Sexy.
- Yeah, I know.
I told Owen about the baby.
Oh, that's why you're here.
I thought you were defecting.
I told him about the baby,
and he got weird.
That's understandable.
Is it?
I mean, he's with Teddy, and he's happy.
And just now, he just seemed like
he was angry with me for being pregnant.
But he's gotta get with the program.
This kid is gonna be Leo's
little brother or sister.
So he and Teddy are gonna be...
aunt and uncle, I guess?
Does Leo call Teddy "Mom"?
No, no, he calls her "Weddy"
because he's working on his T's.
Oh, I get the question.
Uh, I'm... Auntie Amelia.
Betty's more like big sister.
So Teddy's... stepmom, I guess?
Damn it.
Sabi's crashing. Here.
Sabi is...?
Her patient. And Richard's niece.
- Oh, damn.
- Yeah.
You know, Owen can be pissed
at me... I don't care...
but he can't take it out on a patient.
Do you want any...?
Everybody's got a patient.
I want a patient.
What happened?
She just stopped talking...
She went into respiratory distress.
I had to intubate.
The tumor is obstructing
blood flow to her lungs.
Let's push fluids and start pressors.
- Where's my sub?
- He's in the parking lot.
But I didn't want him operating.
This is all you.
I'm glad you came to your senses.
Prep an OR! Let's get her ready to move!
Wait. I didn't say you could.
You're not supposed to operate.
I haven't even talked
to the other doctor.
I know you say I always think
I know what's best.
Well, in this case, I do.
I know Margaret Pierce.
And there's not a surgeon in this city
with half of her skill and expertise.
Chris, please.
Don't put your daughter's life
in someone else's hands.
- Thank you.
- I'm sorry. I should've said it sooner.
All right, come on, let's move. Move!
Hey, you look like someone
I used to work with.
Thank you for letting me do this.
Hello, everyone. I'm Maggie Pierce.
I'm Chief of Cardiothoracic
at Grey-Sloan Memorial.
Don't hold that against me.
Who is ready to take on
the biggest biatrial myxoma
- I have ever seen?
- This isn't gonna work
if she doesn't know everyone's listening.
All right! That's better.
Okay, folks, best behavior.
If we impress Pierce, she just might come
and run cardio for us.
You know that's never
gonna happen, right?
You'd be surprised
how many times it's worked.
Hmm.
Shout if you need anything.
Scalpel.
I'm sorry if I raised my voice earlier.
Maggie really is the best there is.
Sabi couldn't be in better hands.
Last time you tried to calm
my nerves in a waiting room,
Mom died.
I was 10 years old, Chris.
No signal here.
I need to call the family.
Dr. Sykes...
Dr. Jennifer Sykes, call Recovery.
Dr. Sykes, call Recovery.
Hey, Richard. What's wrong?
- N-Not now, Gemma, please.
- Oh, we go back too far back
for me to leave you alone
looking like this.
What is it? You need a meeting?
Um...
Maggie's operating on my niece right now.
She came out here
for the first time in years.
Her father, too.
For my help.
I thought they wanted
nothing to do with Maggie.
My brother and sister, yes, but...
Sabi, she's not like them.
She's welcoming
and forgiving
and kind...
and I turned my back on her.
Family's complicated.
I know. I keep saying that.
But I feel like it's just an excuse now.
You made a sincere attempt at amends.
If the other person
doesn't want to hear it,
that's not on you.
They aren't wrong.
I did think I was better.
Or at least knew better.
You know, I never understood
why they were so content
staying in their small, little world.
You know what Chris said to me
when I told him I was an alcoholic?
"That's what you get."
Like ambition was to blame.
Like everything would've been fine
if I hadn't gotten
a big head and left home.
I'm sorry, Richard.
Richard?
Catherine.
Uh, oh, well, this is Gemma.
Uh, she's a friend.
I can see that.
It's so good to meet you, Catherine.
I've heard a-a lot about you, and, um...
- Well, I'll let... I'll let you two be.
- Yeah.
Um...
I wasn't sure you'd come.
Of course I came.
It's family.
Vanessa's making calls.
Starting a prayer chain.
Oh, uh, Catherine, you remember Chris.
Of course.
Chris, you must be worried sick.
Once we go on bypass,
I'll make my incision
into the right atrium.
What's her activated clotting time?
ACT shows 300 seconds and rising.
That's good enough to start.
Let's go on pump.
Clamps off.
Clamp.
And so how is Vanessa?
Is she still in that house?
She'll never leave that house.
I did some work for her.
I added a sunroom in the back.
Oh, that sounds lovely.
And the, uh... the... the hardware store?
- It closed last month.
- Oh.
Everyone orders online now.
It closed?
No one told me that.
You didn't ask.
So, uh, when was the last time
you all came to visit Seattle?
Well, um, Sabi couldn't have
been more than... what... 8?
Hmm.
W-What was that game
she always wanted to play?
Um...
Papa Never Misses!
The little ones would line up
on one side of the yard,
Chris on the other.
And they would throw him a football
as crazy as they could.
I mean, they would fling it,
and flip it, and spin it.
They'd try everything to make him miss,
and he never did.
Not once.
Papa Never Misses.
Sabi came close a few times, though.
Yeah, I remember once
we had a kiddie pool set up,
and Sabi would fill
a little pail of water
and pour it over her cousins' heads,
and they would laugh.
But then, one time, my... my nephew...
W-Was that... Was it Eddie,
Jeffrey, or...?
- It was Eddie.
- Yeah, okay.
Her cousin Eddie poured a pail of water
- over Sabi's head.
- Oh.
Oh, she burst into tears.
She came running to me. She said...
"Uncle Richard,
tell Eddie we don't play like that!"
- Oh, boy.
- That's Sabi.
Adele loved that story.
You got a vending machine around here?
Oh, yeah, down the hall.
Oh, you need some cash?
I can afford a soda, Rich.
Everything I say pisses that man off.
Mm-hmm.
Okay, look, I don't know what
you think you saw, but...
We will talk about that later.
There is nothing to talk about,
Catherine.
Gemma is an accountant here.
A friend from the program.
A while back, she needed a job,
I made some calls.
It was before I even worked here.
I've known her for years.
She was concerned, and that's all.
You're talking an awful lot
for someone who says
there's nothing to talk about.
I need some fresh air.
Doctors made Mommy all better, Bub.
I'm so sorry I scared you.
I love you so much.
And when I'm all better,
we're gonna go to the zoo.
Can we see the baby giraffes?
Yes, anything you want.
Okay? But right now, Mommy's
got to rest a little bit.
All right?
I got so lucky with Henry.
He's such a good kid...
You know, he's so happy, even
with the little I can give him,
and he does not deserve less.
Of course not.
And you don't have to explain
that to anyone.
It is your decision,
even if you didn't have Henry
or money problems.
All right, Cassidy, the doctors
said the labs and imaging
showed an eight-week pregnancy,
so you're all clear.
Okay, so that's it? It's just the pill?
Two pills, actually.
You'll take one medication now
to block the hormones
that keep the pregnancy viable,
then a second pill in 24 hours
to help contract the uterus.
You'll feel nauseated and crampy,
probably emotional... because hormones.
Okay.
And it will be difficult when
you're passing the tissue.
A lot of doctors say
it's like a heavy period,
but it's more than that.
It's completely safe.
I just want you to be prepared.
Thank you.
You'll need to schedule
an appointment with an OB
in about a week or so
to confirm that the medication worked
and that there's no infection.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
I'm so grateful to both of you.
Looks like Dr. Hunt is here
to do some post-op work,
so get some rest, Cassidy.
And you have my card
if you need anything.
Oh, hey.
Any news?
Still in surgery.
- I'll say another prayer.
- Mm.
Richard tells me you're quite gifted.
Pardon?
With numbers.
You work in accounting, right?
- Oh. Yes.
- Mm.
You know, at the Fox Foundation,
we're always looking
for people we can trust
- with our finances.
- Oh.
There's a lot of opportunity.
I'm sure it pays better than this place.
You're too kind.
Any friend of Richard's...
Give him a résumé.
Okay. Maybe I will.
You should.
We have openings all over the country,
though none here in Seattle, I'm afraid.
I should be getting back inside.
Have a good night.
Okay, I've dissected most of the tumor
from the right atrium.
Suction.
MAPs are dropping.
The bypass circuit is clotting off.
Damn it, she's clotting.
Why is she clotting?!
What is her ACT now? 370 seconds.
What?!
You said it was 300 and rising
before we started.
It should be over 480 by now.
We could've given her more heparin.
She's been dosed multiple times
with heparin.
Why didn't you tell me
she had stopped rising?
Our cardio doctor always asks.
It's protocol. You never asked.
Okay, she's heparin-resistant.
Her blood doesn't clot like normal.
Her pressure's gone.
Okay, everyone stop and listen to me!
We have three minutes
before we lose this patient
from lack of blood flow.
We need a new bypass machine and pumps,
ice to keep her body cool,
and start FFP.
Let's move! Clamps!
Come on. Come on.
Stay with me.
Amelia. You crossed a line.
She needed help
that you wouldn't give her.
You don't work here.
Well, from what I've heard,
most of the people who do
lack the skill and sensitivity
that I have,
so you could just say thank you.
Owen, did you really want
to force that poor mom
to bring another human being
onto the planet against her will,
or did you refuse her an abortion
because I wanted to help her have one?
You don't get to come to my place of work
and order me around, okay?
I didn't order you around.
I ordered her an OB
who ordered her some pills!
And you're angry with me for
reasons I can't quite ascertain.
So you said no to her because I said yes.
I said no to her because...
'cause sometimes
people change their minds,
and she was traumatized by a fall.
A fall that she took accidentally
after intentionally trying
to abort the fetus.
You think that the trauma would
change her mind?
Is this about me?!
Is this because I'm pregnant?
So you think that women who say
that they don't want babies
are gonna just wake up one day
and change their minds?
Amelia, that's absurd.
I agree. She was clear.
She knew what she wanted.
She was not gonna change her mind.
And for the record, I did not
change my mind, either.
I... I just got pregnant, and I exercised
my freedom of choice to not
have an abortion.
That's right. So you didn't want
to have kids,
but now you're with
somebody else, and you do.
Y-You're... You're perfectly happy
now that you're having a baby
with another man!
You and I broke up twice.
- Once when we got divorced and then...
- Yeah. Yeah, we got divorced.
You remember why we got divorced?
You remember the pain
that you put me through
when you told me that you
didn't want to ever have kids?
That you didn't want to ever be a mother?
That pain, that "truth," Amelia, it...
It ended our marriage.
And now you're telling me
that it's not because
you didn't want to have kids, you just...
You didn't want to have them with me.
Owen.
Uh, I gotta, um...
Amelia. Amelia, wait. Wait.
Owen.
I'm sorry.
It's my turn to apologize.
I should have thought this through.
I should not have ambushed you
at your place of employment.
I should've known that this was gonna be
a bigger conversation, and I'm sorry.
When I told you
that I didn't want kids...
I didn't.
I didn't when we started seeing
each other and you had Leo.
I didn't when Betty showed up.
If I'm honest,
I didn't even know for sure
when I found out I was pregnant.
But something changed.
What we went through with Leo and Betty
is a big part of that.
I wasn't ready before.
I am now.
And I have you to thank for that.
Like it or not, we're family now.
I like it.
I always liked it.
Mm.
So, okay, how are we gonna do
this whole family thing?
'Cause there's a lot of us.
There's me, Teddy, you, Link,
Leo, Allison, and...
- you got a name yet?
- Uh...
W-We literally have nothing.
And I don't know how this works.
I mean, there should be a book...
Like, "What to Expect
When You're Expecting,
But You Already Sort of Have
an Adopted Kid with Your Ex..."
"...Who Just Had a Baby
with His, uh, Soul Mate."
Sounds like a bestseller.
I was really terrible
with my patient, so I should...
Yeah, you should bring her
an extra Jell-O, for sure.
Maybe one for Henry.
Yeah.
Is this normal?
For it to take this long?
Uh, you don't want to rush
something like this.
I can't imagine
what you're going through.
No, you can't.
Look, what I mean was that...
I've only known Maggie a few years.
But in that time,
I've grown to care about her
more than any person I've ever known.
I worry about her future,
her safety, her happiness.
If I loved her any more...
...I'm not sure I could bear it.
And it's a fraction of what
you must be feeling right now.
I'm sorry.
It's all clotted! Everything has clotted!
Suction! Start the pump!
I'm trying. Still no flow.
We need to get oxygen to her brain!
How long has the circuit been down?
I can get her back! I can.
- How long?
- Seven minutes.
I connected bypass in time.
There's just too many clots.
We need some more ice!
We need to cool her down some more.
Nuce, seven minutes is too long.
We can get her back! We can get her back!
Her entire circulation has clotted off.
There's no way she can recover from that.
- Come on.
- All right? She's gone.
- Come on, come on, come on.
- Okay, everybody stop!
Not yet, Alex. Not yet.
- Maggie...
- No, no!
...she's brain dead. Let her go.
Time of death, 18:58.
- I can't do this.
- I'll be with you.
No, no, no, Alex,
I can't do this. I can't.
I can't. I can't. They... They...
They didn't want me to operate.
They told me not to, and I pushed them.
I bullied them.
I told them I was the best.
You are.
Alex, I-I can't... I can't tell them.
Come on.
You lost your patient.
You tried to do all the right things,
but you lost your patient.
And you're blaming yourself, and...
and I can't make you not feel that.
But you have to tell them.
So just stand here, get it
all out of your system,
and then pull yourself
back together again.
Get it out.
Grace under pressure.
One clumsy word, one careless gesture
can cause irreparable harm.
H-How is she?
Is she okay?
Can I see her?
I'm Alex Karev. I'm the Chief.
Would you, uh, like to sit down?
I'm fine standing.
So, focus on facts.
What happened?
What was the problem,
and what did you do?
Don't make it personal.
During surgery, we discovered
that Sabrina has a resistance to heparin,
- so her blood...
- W-What's that?
W-What's heparin?
Uh, it's a drug to prevent clotting.
Which didn't work for her.
So during surgery,
her blood began to clot,
and that clogged the bypass machine,
which meant we had to
change machines mid-surgery.
I-I don't understand.
So you had to stop?
Is she okay?
Answer questions directly.
This is not your loss.
This is not your pain.
Never make it about you.
Sabrina's condition was critical
before we ever got to the operating room.
I did everything that I could,
but, unfortunately,
I couldn't save her.
She died.
Oh, Maggie...
No.
No, no, no, no. no.
Sabi?
No.
And if there's no silver
lining, don't make one up.
Your job isn't to make
the bad news sound better.
- Chris, let's get you out of here.
- Get your hands off me!
Okay, now.
I didn't even want her to operate!
Sabrina didn't!
You didn't listen!
Even though you're in pain, too...
...even though you don't
feel like a doctor...
Maggie, is... is she cleaned up?
Can we see her?
Come on, Richard. Richard, come on.
Get your brother.
We got to go help him call
the rest of the family.
You're just another person, alone,
falling into the dark.