Am I going to have
to give a speech?
You're the publisher,
can't you do it?
I can warm them up,
but you're gonna have to get
over this fear of public speaking
before the book tour.
Everybody! Can I have
your attention? Thank you.
Tim has a few words to say.
There you go, Tim.
They're warmed up.
Well.
What do you say
at a time like this?
Seriously, what do you say?
You could thank
people for coming.
Thank you, Nick.
Actually, I'm always
thanking Nick.
A man famous not only
for his ruthless editor's pen,
but his patient handholding
of crazy authors.
You'd think that
after three novels,
I'd start to develop a
little confidence, but...
For a book like this, we are
happy to supply the confidence.
Bestseller.
Well, that's not
going to happen.
What?
Come on. Short stories
don't make money.
Short stories weren't
making money back in 1908.
You'd have to be
mathematically illiterate
to think they'd do
as well as a novel.
Okay, Nick, let's step away from the
champagne before somebody gets hurt.
You slaved over this
book right next to me.
Why would Northrop even
publish it if it's only going to tank?
Have you failed to notice
you're our star author?
Obviously, Elaine
wouldn't want to offend you.
Honey...
I'm sorry, I don't... I
don't know why I said that.
He's joking.
Nick knows as well as anyone
what you have done is art.
So is folding paper
into animal shapes,
but you don't expect
to make a living off it.
What the hell is wrong with you?
You really think someone who
goes through 10 assistants a year
and doesn't return her
own children's phone calls
would give a damn about the
state of the American short story?
Please, be quiet.
I think something's wrong.
That title was a mistake, too.
People are going to
compare you to Salinger.
And boy, are you going to
come up short in that one.
Honey?
Call 911. Help! We need help!
Cameron brought
this up from the ER.
Doesn't look like a
friendship bracelet.
It's Phineas Gage.
The most famous case
study in medical history.
You're telling me this
patient got a railroad spike
drilled through
his frontal lobe?
No, no trauma, but he does
have frontal lobe disinhibition.
Just like Gage.
Gage was a different
person after the spike.
Argumentative, impulsive.
Whereas our guy became a
different person after chardonnay.
He was sober when
they brought him in.
There's also the
nosebleed, the collapse.
MRI show anything? Nothing.
Good. What fun would that be?
So the tumor's not in
the cool neighborhood.
It's cool neighborhood adjacent.
A well-placed tumor
in the nasal cavity,
eroding into the brain
could do the damage.
Go stick a scope up Phineas'
nose and see what you find.
Daddy, I'm always going to win if
you keep telling me what your cards are.
Then suppose I tell
you... While I tickle you!
Mr. Greenwald, I'm Dr. Taub
and this is Dr. Kutner.
We're here for another
test. Sorry about that.
You don't look sorry.
Um. No offense.
Although you do
look kind of cheerful.
It's a little creepy. Should I want a
doctor who's excited about how sick I am?
I'm not... We're going
to put this up your nose,
scan for any problems.
I can assure you that we are
completely unexcited about that.
Excuse me, sweetie.
She has an auditory
processing disability.
Marika Balika. You
have to get off the bed.
This might be
slightly uncomfortable.
Honey, do you
mind if I step out?
I have to make sure the final arrangements
are in place for the breast cancer walk.
Yeah. You do that.
I'll pretend to be macho while a guy
stuffs three feet of plastic up my nose.
It's too bad it's not your nose.
Lots more room to maneuver.
I guess the walk
can wait 10 minutes.
Or in a sensible
world, even longer.
Just how does tying up traffic
for six hours stop breast cancer?
You know how it
works, people donate.
Why not spend six hours building
houses for Habitat for Humanity?
Or is it wrong to help two
groups of people at once?
I'll bet there are those who
have breast cancer and no home.
It's my job, Nick.
You walked yourself last year.
To be supportive.
Because I knew you wouldn't
have sex with me if I didn't.
I'm going to make my call.
Make this go away.
God, that honker
really is huge, isn't it?
Wednesday night.
Low-Down-Blue-Meanie
versus the Incinerator.
I can't.
Let me rephrase.
Low-Down-Blue-Meanie...
I understand Monster Truck code.
Do you understand "can't"?
Not when it follows
Low-Down-Blue-Meanie.
Is the world coming to
an end Tuesday night?
Otherwise,
Wednesday... All right.
It's not "can't,"
it's "don't want to."
The fact is, I just don't
like monster trucks.
Yes, you do.
No, I don't.
You've always
liked monster trucks.
No, you've always liked them.
I've tolerated them.
Seriously, I can only watch so
many hyped-up dune buggies
crush so many motor homes without
feeling the urge to go see La Bohème.
And I hate opera, too.
What are you hiding?
I'm not hiding it, I'm
saying it loud and proud.
Death to monster trucks.
No nasal cancer.
And no marriage either,
if our patient keeps saying
everything that comes into his head
without regard for
the consequences.
You always led me to
believe you were one of a kind.
Luckily, jerkiness is a
temporary condition for this guy.
No, it's not.
We may be able to fix his
impulse to say his thoughts out loud,
but he's always gonna be
the guy who thinks them.
But he's also gonna be the
guy who doesn't say them.
If he spent his whole life
constructing a nice-guy persona,
isn't that as much who he
really is as anything else?
You would argue
that. You're all persona.
I agree with Wilson.
This guy's a Harry Potter.
The sorting hat was going to put
Harry in Slytherin, based on his nature.
He refused, so he
ended up in Gryffindor.
Through choice.
There's damage somewhere
in his brain. Go find it.
Are you sure you understand?
No, I'm lying. Except, I can't.
You ask me questions.
While I talk, you look at my brain
activity to see where it's screwed up,
then you're gonna cut the
screwed up part out to test it.
It's depressing, but
it's not rocket science.
I think he understands.
I don't mean to be abrasive.
Especially since you're such
a pleasure to imagine naked.
Again, sorry. It's okay.
Thank you for understanding.
I'd do you, though.
Really, my apologies.
This stuff just comes out.
It's okay. House paged?
Whoa. I would do her in a minute
with fudge and a cherry on top.
Would someone please
explain to this woman?
There's only so
many apologies I can...
He has frontal
lobe disinhibition.
I've already embarrassed
myself with one doctor.
Whom I am at this moment
imagining with you in a king-sized
bed with a mirror on the ceiling.
I am so, so sorry.
But if I couldn't have
both of you together,
you would definitely
be my first choice.
Where's House?
It's like trying not to
think of an elephant.
Not that you're an elephant. Your
breasts, in fact, are all Homo sapiens.
House isn't here.
He wouldn't have paged me
if he couldn't watch
and enjoy the...
Your tush is like the
pistons in a Ferrari.
You're welcome.
That was for my benefit?
You're 40 years
old... Thirty eight.
And the administrator
of a hospital.
Dean of medicine.
People don't get
personal with you.
Except for me, and you dismiss
me as a jerk who's jerking you around.
But that guy can
only tell the truth.
And he prefers your body to
that of a smoking young hottie.
So that was your way of
saying I look good today?
You didn't get the
slightest kick out of that?
Don't be ridiculous, House.
I hope you know your
pistons are second to none.
I'm okay. I'm not jealous
of Cuddy's pistons.
Starting baseline activation.
You sure? You looked upset.
What he was saying
was obnoxious.
You've never been
called attractive?
He didn't call me attractive,
he cast me in his mental porno.
That's what "attractive" means.
It means "I'm attracted
to you sexually."
"Attracted" can also mean, "I'm attracted
to the whole package, to who you are."
Slight elevation
at transaxial 60.
It could.
It never does. It's what women
choose to hear, not what men say.
Actually, it's exactly what men
say, if they have any brains.
All right, we have
enough for a baseline.
What can we ask him that's indiscreet,
but that he won't hate us for knowing?
Nick, do you vote the
same way as your wife?
God, no.
Good. He's spiking at 30.
She believes I voted for
Hillary Clinton in the primary,
and Obama in the general.
You're thinking I'm
secretly Republican, right?
Wrong.
I secretly don't vote ever.
Wait, you're 46 and
you've never voted?
Your voice is no longer attractive
to me with that note of disapproval.
Although I'm
sure that will pass.
Look at that.
There's a spot on the cingulate
gyrus that's not lighting up.
One vote makes a difference?
Not mathematically... Okay,
Nick, we've got what we need.
We can't biopsy that, it's
too close to the brain stem.
Could be neurosarcoidosis.
At least it's treatable.
So we give him
steroids and if we're right,
we should start seeing his
symptoms improve within half a day.
What are you looking at?
I find your strong attachment to a
working democracy to be extremely sexy.
You smooth talker.
Do you think my nose is too big?
Relax. He also implied my
bedside manner was a little off.
You don't agree
with that, right?
No.
No one's ever mentioned
your nose before?
You're a plastic surgeon.
They tell me it suits
my face. It does.
Maybe. Maybe that's
just the social contract.
You tell me I look great,
I tell you you're
a people person.
How can you know the truth?
You could ask for the truth.
What do you think of my
nose? Please tell me the truth.
It's fine, it's a nose.
Just proving a point.
Anyone sitting here?
Just my persona.
You know, it's amazing the
way people cling on to insults.
Or what they think are insults.
So that wasn't an insult?
I'm not suggesting
that like our patient,
you're hiding a
dark, sarcastic core
beneath a candy shell
of compulsive niceness.
I'm not always nice.
I'm not nice to you.
Because you know nice
bores me. Hence, still nice.
No, I'm suggesting
that you have no core.
You're what whoever
you're with needs you to be.
Okay, I guess that
could be insulting.
But the interesting
question is why.
Why do you think the world
will end in chaos and destruction
if you're not there to save it?
Because when my parents put
me in the rocket, and sent me here,
they said, "James, you will grow
to manhood under a yellow sun."
And why did you lie
about monster trucks?
I didn't.
I checked your appointment book.
You've got tomorrow
night marked off,
but you didn't put down
what you were doing.
So you thought someone
might look at the book...
I'm playing racquetball
tomorrow night with Taub.
Why would you hide that?
Because the world
revolves around you.
I devote time to anyone else,
you'd end up stalking
me and harassing them.
You say that as
though it wouldn't be fun.
And maybe I didn't want
to rub your nose in the fact
that we'd be doing something
you can no longer do.
Because I'm nice.
I thought you said the
steroids were gonna help him!
Is it his heart?
EKG says heart's fine.
It's gotta be the kidneys.
We need to get him on dialysis.
Oh, God.
He's on dialysis
and he's stable.
We know it's not
systemic sclerosis.
Hey.
Cyrano de Berkowitz.
Let it go.
Chronic lymphocytic leukemia could
explain brain and kidney problems.
CBC showed normal
white blood cells.
So how long have you been
playing racquetball with Wilson?
Four or five times.
Could be diabetes.
Or a congenital
metabolic disorder.
Congenital disorders generally
don't wait till you're 46 to manifest.
So he's a late bloomer. His
daughter has a neurological condition.
First of all, Wilson played
tennis on his college team,
and you are a Jew.
You're not athletic.
Run to the end of the
hall and back, I'll time you.
Sandy Koufax is Jewish. Greatest
left-handed pitcher of all time.
Sandy Koufax is all you Jews
go on about, Sandy Koufax.
And the Holocaust. It gets old.
There are dozens of congenital
conditions that fit our parameters.
We can't spend time
gene-testing for all of them
especially when we're
only guessing it's congenital.
Is a Z-shot offensive
or defensive?
It's both.
You suspected that
was a trick question.
But I could have said neither.
Diabetes makes more sense.
We can narrow the testing
down to 40 likely candidates.
Test for peripheral
nerve damage.
He's got brain damage,
he's likely to have peripheral nerve
damage no matter what the cause.
Yes, that's why we
should not test him for it.
Test the daughter.
Kutner runs the nerve test.
Taub, you may be
right about the diabetes.
Take supper away from our patient
and run a glucose tolerance test.
Oh, and the nurses have
been working so hard,
you can do the
blood draws yourself.
They have to be done
every couple of hours.
You're punishing me
because you're jealous that I'm
spending time with your best friend.
That would be petty.
I'm punishing you because now you've
joined my best friend in lying to me.
Let me know when you're
ready to confess everything.
These can become
either hot or cold.
As soon as it starts to feel
uncomfortable, I want you to tell me.
But you don't think there's
something wrong with me.
No, baby. They're
testing you to help Daddy.
Yes. What you're
doing is very important.
It's like the better you do,
the better we know your dad is.
It's okay.
I'll start with heat.
I know it's not his fault.
I know what he says
is involuntary, but...
It doesn't help.
Inside he's still the same man.
Yeah, that's the problem.
Apparently he's been
thinking this stuff all along.
Whoever that same man is, it's not
the person I thought I was married to.
You okay?
She should be feeling
something by now.
What does that
mean? Is she sick too?
Marika?
Honey?
You're burned, why didn't
you tell me it started to hurt?
I wanted to help Daddy.
You said the better I do,
the better Daddy has to be.
I'm sorry.
I'm starving.
It's the only way
we can do the test.
Good thing it's you
and not Dr. Hadley.
Could you keep her away from me?
I have a rich imaginative life.
I'd rather not share it.
We all have thoughts.
I know we all have
sexual thoughts.
We have ignoble thoughts.
I just don't want those
to be who I am to people.
Especially not to my wife.
I understand, I don't think it would be
fair to define me by my passing thoughts.
My real choices are my actions.
And I've never done anything
to hurt her, I've never cheated.
You're kidding me,
you've cheated?
What?
No.
Why would you say that?
Because you look guilty as hell.
Are you serious?
Of course you're serious.
Yes, everyone knows.
God, they must
think you're a creep.
They might not know,
they might be idiots.
I just say these things.
Why'd you page me here?
I need you to update me
on the patient's condition.
He seems to be dead.
Why'd you page me here?
I need you to update me
on the patient's condition
while hitting this
against the wall.
This is the only
place we can do both.
I finished the last blood draw.
I expect the people who work
for me to rise to a challenge.
Unless they don't
expect to work for me.
Last blood draw was at 6:00 a.m.
His sugar levels never
rose above 120 all night.
So the glucose was normal.
It means you were
wrong about diabetes.
I still think it's the
endocrine system,
maybe I just got
the wrong gland.
You were going for thyroid
instead of pancreas? It makes sense.
Fine! I'm not playing
racquetball with Wilson!
I was never playing
I have never played
racquetball with Wilson.
I thought it would be helpful if a
department head owed me a favor,
but it's not worth this.
Not bad. You put on a good show.
You studied up, Wilson
actually booked a court.
If you were really
a racquetball player,
you'd know that you're
holding a squash racquet.
Tell Kutner to do a
thyroid reuptake scan,
then go grab a nap in
one of the on-call rooms.
We're taking you to do
a thyroid reuptake scan.
We think your... I'm not going
anywhere until you explain
why my daughter has
a bandage on her hand.
You just said you
wanted to run some test.
If I'd known it would involve
pain, I'd have said, "Hell no."
It's a mild burn.
Since Marika has a
neurological disability, like you,
we needed to make
sure. She has no disability.
Nick, you know about her
problem with auditory processing.
Auditory processing?
That's code, for "I can't stand
thinking my daughter's not perfect."
The therapist said
Marika's test scores...
Were indeterminate.
She doesn't have a
disability. She daydreams.
She gets below average marks in
school because she's below average.
Every parent thinks their
child is above average.
Nick! Do they have any idea
what the word average means?
Somebody has to be under it.
Nick, shut up!
Honey.
I'm not saying you're stupid.
Your mother's not the
sharpest crayon in the box,
and she does great.
See, this is why I told your
mother to keep you at home.
Didn't want you here.
Marika.
Marika, wait.
Get her...
You're burning up.
Your lungs are full of
fluid, we need to get it out.
I need 200 milligrams
of furosemide
and two milligrams
of morphine, stat.
His temperature
is 103. Infection.
The steroids must have
forced it into the open.
What kind of infection?
It could be anything.
Staph aureus,
tuberculosis, strongyloides.
Go back to Phineas
and get a history.
We got a history. He hasn't
been out of the country.
Get a detailed history.
No one at home is sick,
no one at work is sick,
there's no sign of
ticks or mosquitoes.
Get a more detailed history.
Ask him again. And again,
until he remembers something.
Not you. Kutner can do it.
You're going to be busy
with something else.
I'm here to invite you to lunch.
Why?
I've been made. House sent
me back to you as a double agent.
Anything wrong?
Eyes are a little red.
There's a shocker.
I haven't had a good night's
sleep since this thing started.
You should get
some rest yourself.
That's a good idea.
This is going to take some
time, it will be pretty exhaustive.
Are you afraid of what you
might say while I'm here?
Yes.
Are you telling me there's something
worse than what I've already heard?
No, I don't know
what I'm going to say.
I don't know how I'm
going to hurt you next.
I think we should be around each
other as little as possible right now.
This is pathetic.
I know.
Tell Marika I love
her very much.
She understands that.
I don't think she does.
You're just saying that
to make me feel better.
Yeah.
Guy leads a boring life.
They stay home a lot.
No travel, no exotic pets.
No nearby standing water.
You sound pleased about
something. Can we get to that part?
His wife rescues dogs.
Among others, a big Rottweiler,
who's taken over the house.
Our patient hates it.
Was the wife there
to hear this? No.
Too bad. Keep going.
The dog marks its territory
all over the living room.
I asked what the odds were
that he would've put down food
or drink where the dog could reach.
He said he put a glass
of juice on the floor
while he was
fixing the television.
The dog was fixing
the television? Yes.
Patient's eyes red?
Yeah. I'm thinking Weil's.
Bacterial. You lucked out.
Start him on doxycycline. If he
improves, we'll know we were right.
I told Wilson you sent
me to get information.
And now you're telling me.
What does that make
you, a quadruple agent?
He let me print out his e-mails.
Wow. Excellent.
Information he wants us to have.
Did he let you print
out his deleted e-mails?
No.
Go back there... As
long as I was sitting there,
thought I'd print them anyway.
Top one's the one you're looking for.
"I confirm Wednesday
at 7:00 p.m."
It's outgoing to
JGonzalez@NYMercy.net.
There's a Joan Gonzalez
in oncology. It's a consult.
Secret consult at 7:00 p.m.?
Oh, Joan is perky.
You're wrong, there was
a patient file attached.
Where?
It was password protected.
No.
Wilson doesn't password
protect his patient files.
I'm the only one he'd
expect ever to look there,
and he knows there's only
one patient I'd want to check on.
You think Wilson's sick?
If Wilson had cancer,
there'd be no reason for him to
drive three hours to Manhattan.
He knows he could pull strings
here to get the best treatment.
Six articles by Gonzalez.
"Managing suicidal
thoughts in oncology patients."
"Suicidal ideation in
children with leukemia."
I don't want to ask this,
but have you ever had reason
to think he might be depressed?
No. Get out of here.
Your fever's down and
your lungs are clearing.
How long before this
brain thing goes away?
Infection's gone.
The damage the infection
did, you'll have to live with.
You telling me
you can't fix this?
There's got to be a way...
We'd need to remove the damaged
area in your cingulate gyrus,
but it's too close to the
brain stem to risk surgery.
You can't risk it?
But I could shop around,
and maybe some better
doctors at a better hospital...
The brain stem controls the
body's involuntary systems.
The slightest
mistake could kill you.
Even if you survive,
you may never be able to breathe
on your own again, you may never...
I get it.
I know this seems like a
lot to deal with right now,
but people have adapted to living
with all kinds of neurological deficits.
Hey, at least we can promise
you it won't get any worse.
Get the hell out of my room.
Your assistant said that you were
out of the hospital taking a walk.
Is there an emergency?
I don't know, is there?
You never take a walk unless you
got something you need to think about.
Maybe you just don't have a good
statistical sampling of my walks.
The other thing you do when you
need to think is you come to my office.
Apparently, this is something you can only
discuss with Gonzalez at New York Mercy.
Taub. Another graduate of the
House School of Being a Dick.
Private dick.
Look, I'd love to stay for the full
inquisition, but I need some hot coffee.
Of course you need hot
coffee, it's 45 degrees outside
and you left your
coat upstairs. Why?
You're going to tell me
why I forgot my coat?
Once you get outside, the
cold would have reminded you.
Could have gone
back, but you didn't.
You chose to be uncomfortable.
Now why would
someone choose that?
Because they hate themselves?
Has it ever occurred to you that
when I don't share something,
it might not be
meant as a challenge?
It might just mean
that I'd like there to be
one molecule of my life that goes
unexamined by Gregory House.
Nick Greenwald. I hear
you're the guy in charge.
I'm the patient with
the disinhibition.
If you're here to say thanks,
you're welcome. Now go away.
I'm not thankful. I'm pissed.
Oh.
All the more reason to go away.
They're talking about
sending me home.
To what? A life where I'll continually
drive away anyone who might,
for a second, care about me?
Those are the breaks.
You could operate.
You could die.
So I'm either better or
dead? I'm okay with that.
I've always been kind
of an impatient guy.
But I've worked hard
to keep my mouth shut.
I've made my wife happy.
I've made my little girl happy.
I want that back.
Otherwise, it's no life.
I want you to remove
a small problem.
I'm not a neurosurgeon.
Your boss is. You could assist,
I'm sure you'd like to
add to your resume.
It's too near the brain stem.
Nobody's going to touch it.
Your boss would.
He's an egomaniac.
I know 'cause I keep
seeing him at the club.
He just needs a little push.
I'm sure by now you've
kissed his ass sufficiently.
Would you like me to phrase
it as "you're politically gifted"?
I could do that.
You want me to help you?
Tell me why.
Why what?
Why you care?
The puzzle's solved,
the guy's alive.
And the odds of coming out of this surgery
with that same status aren't that great.
My patient has a
quality of life issue.
He says awful things.
Hardly a medical condition.
When he leaves here,
he's going to lose his family.
He's going to alienate
the people he works with.
And if he ever finds a friend
who's willing to put up with his crap,
he'll be lucky.
Until he drives them away, too.
I'll see what I can do.
You've apparently got this
whole coat thing backwards.
I may have overreacted.
You definitely overreacted.
I knew you'd meet me halfway.
But it made me think.
You only snap on one
subject, losing people.
So I went back to the intel.
It's true there's only one doctor
named Gonzalez at New York Mercy,
but there's a Javier Gonzalez
who's a nurse in the psych ward.
Now who could you
lose who'd end up there?
Maybe the reason I don't always
open up to you is because it's redundant.
Daniel Wilson.
Once you've got a name,
it's amazing how much stuff
you can learn on the phone.
I mean, if you're a
doctor and you lie freely.
They found your brother sleeping in the
lobby of an office building in Manhattan.
He got aggressive when
they asked him to leave,
and the cops took him
to the Mercy psych ward.
There've been new anti-psychotics
developed since he ran away.
He's been on them for a
couple of days. And by tonight,
he should be in
shape to talk to me.
But you're not
sure if he wants to.
I'll be in New York in a few
hours, I guess I'll find out.
Why wouldn't you tell me this?
House, you and I,
we don't have the
normal social contract.
I don't expect you to
tell me the lies that...
I'm fully capable
of lying to you.
I've lied plenty of times.
I mean collaborative lies.
Giving someone a hand who maybe
needs to deceive themselves, just a little.
For two days, I've
been thinking about
how Danny's going to
react when he sees me.
If I said that to
anybody else, they'd say,
"Don't worry, it'll
all be all right."
You wouldn't.
Because it might
all go horribly wrong.
Yeah.
Yeah, it might.
In which case, you might
want some company.
Your heart's beating.
First hurdle passed.
Now we need to know if
you can breathe for yourself.
Oh, thank God.
Now, do you know who you are?
Nick Greenwald, former S.O.B.
Thank you.
Now I can go back to my
beautiful life with my beautiful wife.
Maybe she'll stop whining
and cut me some slack
now that I've risked my life.
It doesn't make sense.
We removed the problem.
We removed the damage. Maybe
we were wrong about the problem.
I need to believe we
can get through this.
Temperature's 94.5.
Do you really think I'm stupid?
Honey, you're not stupid,
you're just... Please don't do this.
Could be the
effect of the surgery.
Do you at least
respect me, Nick?
What do you think of
what I do for a living?
I think people who
publicize important things
are people who can't do
important things themselves.
Honey, stop. Don't.
Do you regret marrying me?
94.2.
Sometimes.
Everybody wonders.
Get me a heating blanket.
Do you even love me?
Yes.
I don't know why.
Aud...
Wait. Let me...
V-tach! Get me the paddles.
Clear.
Echo says his heart
is structurally fine,
but his temperature
is still dropping.
He's headed for hypothermia.
I can't reach House. It
just goes to voicemail.
Means we were
wrong about infection.
His temperature's
just going up and down
because something's
playing with his thermostat.
Which means the brain
damage is spreading.
What causes brain
damage and nosebleed,
and involves the lungs,
heart, and kidneys?
Cancer. We could text him.
It's not cancer.
Normal PSA, normal blood
smear, colonoscopy normal.
Do a full body scan.
House hates full body scans.
House isn't here.
House is right.
Everybody's got three or
four meaningless anomalies
that'll come up on a scan. Chasing
each one will take time we don't have.
Feel free to send him an IM.
You told me you saw your
brother once, after he disappeared.
Thirteen years ago.
I used to go to Princeton
whenever I could.
I must have hit every
homeless shelter in town.
Then one day, I'm just sitting
at this deli having a sandwich,
I look out the window
and there he is.
He was gone by
the time I got outside.
That's why you were so eager, when
I told you there was a job in Princeton.
I thought it was just my charm.
That's the team,
shouldn't you answer?
They've already texted me to
say they're doing something stupid.
Small abdominal aneurysm.
Irrelevant. What else you got?
A cyst in the pleura
around the lungs.
Also irrelevant. Couldn't
cause any of the symptoms.
There's a density in the liver,
could be a vascular
malformation.
If he's got multiple AVMs, screwed
up blood flow would explain everything.
We can only spot
them with angiography.
We'll have to do targeted scans with
contrast, and then embolize each one.
Can we do that
before he freezes?
We'll find out.
The spell-correct on Kutner's
phone has got a hair-trigger.
Either that, or the
patient has a "cyclone"
in the "floral" of his lungs.
You took a walk in 45-degree
weather and you left your coat behind.
Go ahead.
I think you were
punishing yourself.
I think you wanted to feel what
it would be like to be homeless
in a New Jersey winter.
That tells me guilt.
That tells me
something happened.
The schizophrenia started
when he was a teenager.
When he was in college,
he was on meds,
but he'd still think a professor was
out to get him because he got a B,
or he would fight with his roommates
because he never showered.
Where were you?
Med school.
He called me every
day, talked for hours.
I didn't have hours.
Interesting.
Later for that. Go on.
I was tired of being the guy
that everybody counted on.
So one night Danny called...
One night Danny called,
crying, upset about something.
I had to study for an
exam. So I hung up.
Took my things, I went to the library where
I wouldn't have to hear the phone ring.
I wonder how that turned out.
My mother called
me the next day,
Danny had run away
and left his meds behind.
Which I knew meant that he would
never be able to choose to come back,
because he'd be so
detached from reality.
So you made your one effort
to live a normal, selfish life,
and the universe immediately
smacked you down.
And because we're wired to find
meaning in semi-random events,
you decided never to
be that careless again.
You don't think
that's a little facile?
Actually, I don't. I think
you did it consciously.
You developed your
people pleasing talents
the way an Olympic
athlete develops his muscles.
Talk about an overreaction
to a single event.
It was a pretty big event.
Hanging up the phone? That's
what you're blaming all this on.
That's the behavior you've
been trying to correct.
As though nothing else went
wrong in your brother's life.
Of course he
overreacted, too, but...
His glucose was normal.
We're not talking about my
brother anymore, are we?
It's House. AVMs don't
explain his glucose.
Since this is a significant
moment in my life and all, I'll...
Yeah.
I think I'll just go in and...
Explain that.
Right.
We'd given him steroids. His
glucose should have been elevated.
That wannabe cyst you
found in the whole body scan,
without the glucose,
it's an irrelevant cyst,
with the glucose,
it's a relevant fibroma.
He has Doege-Potter Syndrome.
His fibroma is secreting
human growth hormone
which acts like insulin,
lowering his glucose.
That doesn't explain the
organ failure, the brain damage.
This whole thing
is an overreaction.
That one small
fibroma, it's benign,
but his body's acting
like it's an invader.
His antibodies went to war
against it and got carried away,
attacked his other systems.
Take out the fibroma,
he'll be a happy
hypocrite again in no time.
Maybe I should call a cab.
Your wife's probably just late.
Yeah.
I'm sorry about,
you know, things I said.
I have a conspicuous nose.
It suits your face.
I'm sorry I'm late.
Traffic.
I have some good news.
I was going to tell you,
and then you got sick,
it didn't seem
like the best time.
I've been offered
a better position.
I'd be coordinating cancer
awareness walks in three cities.
That's great. Congratulations.
I know you've
worked hard for this.
Thank you.
Is Marika okay?
I'm sure she's moved on.
Kids are so resilient.
You okay?
I'll be seeing Danny
again next week.
I'd like you to meet him.
Sure.
Sounds interesting.
Go on.
I thought seeing him again
would change everything.
It'd be wonderful
or terrible. Instead...
We're just strangers.
It's kind of anticlimactic.
Which is better than terrible.
Go on.
Does it bother you that
we have no social contract?
My whole life is
one big compromise.
I tiptoe around everyone
like they're made of china.
I spend all my time analyzing.
"What will the effect
be if I say this?"
And then there's you.
You're a reality junkie.
If I offered you
a comforting lie,
you'd smack me
over the head with it.
Let's not change that.
Okay.
No. See, this...
If you were implementing a
social contract, you'd say that,
but only because it
makes me feel better.
It's kind of fun watching
you torture yourself.
Do you think things will
work out with my brother?
No.
But when it does go
wrong, it won't be your fault.
Thanks, House.
You do actually
like monster trucks?
Absolutely.