What happened?
I guess that's the question.
How could this awful,
senseless thing happen?
I mean, I've-I've seen traumas
from plenty of accidents
since I started my training.
But this was someone I knew.
But you're convinced
it was an accident?
I guess.
Have the police...?
I don't think they've
come to any conclusions.
Either he lost his balance
and fell onto the tracks...
or he jumped.
I understand that you and,
uh, Dr. Gant were friends...
roommates?
Mm-hmm.
Well, we hadn't seen much
of each other for the last...
month.
Um, I had, um...
I was seeing somebody,
and I was staying...
over at her place a lot.
Obviously, the, uh, hospital
is interested in finding out
if anything could have been
done to prevent this tragedy.
You mean if it
were a suicide?
We're both aware of the
complaint about Dr. Benton
Dennis lodged on
the day of his death.
In your judgment,
was this day unique
in Dr. Gant's experience,
or had he frequently felt
he was treated unfairly?
We both complained
about the hours, the residents.
That's what I thought
it was... venting.
I know Dennis had bad days.
We all do.
But what I'm asking is
if anyone or anything
put undue pressure
on Dr. Gant...
A policy, a teaching method...
Anything that seems,
in retrospect, too harsh?
I'll have to think about that.
Dr. Gant's father is
arriving this afternoon
to collect his things and, uh...
bring the body back home to...
Atlanta.
I hope you'll be able
to accompany Mr. Gant
to the apartment.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, my God, John,
I couldn't believe it.
Yeah.
What a shocker.
You think he pulled a Cobain?
Dale...
Well, if they do
rule it a suicide
maybe we'll get some
shorter hours around here.
Dennis said
something at Christmas
about his girlfriend.
But if he were
depressed or whatever
you would have
noticed, wouldn't you?
Yeah, I would've.
That's the ER.
I thought you had
the ER yesterday.
I'm covering Dennis's shift.
I need eight units of
o-neg, the sooner the better.
What's up?
Two GSWs coming
in, both critical.
All sharps and meds
are accounted for.
All right, get ready
for the next guest.
Set up the rapid infuser.
Benton coming down?
I don't know. I
haven't seen him yet.
I was sorry to
hear about Dennis.
Is there any more news?
No, not yet.
We'll take the
chest wound in Two.
We'll handle the
extremity wound right here.
Got it.
Respiratory's alerted.
I'll set up a vent.
I'll spike you up a
couple of liters of saline.
Here's a fresh chest tube tray.
Thank you.
Who's with us, Carol?
I paged Lily. She'll join you.
Connie'll scribe.
Me and Malik are with Carter.
All right, what do we got?
Two GSWs.
You and Carter can
take the chest wound.
Is the room prepped?
Yeah. O-neg's here.
Both rooms are ready.
The chest tube tray is set.
Call Radiology; get a portable.
We did it.
Okay, anybody check the
battery on the laryngoscope?
Done.
Looks like we're
ready to go, folks.
Well, where the hell are they?
I'll check the ETA.
Hey, I was wondering.
Did you get my message
about the memorial service?
Uh, yeah. Yeah, I did.
I was wondering if
you would or could say
a few words. Are you talking
about the memorial? Mm-hmm.
It's 5:00 in the chapel, right?
Man, I still can't believe it.
Me, neither.
Here comes the groom.
Zadro's got the
bride right behind me.
Let's put her in one.
GSW to the chest.
Intubated in the field.
Two liters in.
BP 40 palp, sinus tach at 150.
Two GSWs, left lower extremity.
Arterial bleeding,
no distal pulses.
Why do I see a third gurney?
Best man. Wound to
the abdomen. He's stable.
BP's 120/80, pulse 88.
We only knew about two victims.
Hold him right here.
Carter!
One, two, three.
Evaluate the guy in the hall.
We got a third victim.
I need to steal Malik.
Be my guest.
H & H, cross and type
for six. Portable chest.
Pressure's still 40.
Set up the transfuser.
Large bore IV
with blood tubing.
Let's run it wide open.
Let's go.
Carter, come on.
Coming.
We got to the "Do you take" part
and bam, there's
her ex, blasting away.
Hey, Lily? More
blood for the bride!
Do we have any exam rooms
open for our best man here?
Not yet.
How are Duke and Katria doing?
I'm going to take you
for an abdominal CT.
Whoa. Pressure's dropping.
He's crashing.
Damn it. Take that!
Two units O-neg on board.
My guy just bottomed out.
I need to do a central line.
What do you want me to
do, Carter, hold your hand?
No, there's no room to do him.
Figure it out. Where's
the type specific blood?
It's coming. All
right, let's go.
Start pushing, Malik.
Where are we going?
Trauma two.
Oh, man.
Scoot over. Make room.
To the right. Go.
All right, Malik, let's
get a central line kit
and an intubation tray
and start pushing the o-neg.
How's that pressure?
40 Palp.
Let's get a central
line kit here now.
Trendelenburg.
Whose monitor is that?
Ours. He's arrested.
All right. Thoracotomy
tray. Let's move, come on!
Want to watch your elbows?
Let's go.
Hey.
I missed you last night.
How's your cold?
It's better. Thanks.
Thanks for the roses.
Oh, you liked them?
I loved them.
For you.
Oh, man, you are
spoiling me, you know that?
Something wrong?
Oh, you know,
all this union stuff.
It will be a weird
day for the nurses.
Yeah, so is the sick-out
going to happen?
Yeah, I think so.
Does it bother
you that I told you?
No, no, no. Of course not.
We're still on for
tonight... Movie, dinner?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay. It's a date.
Yeah, it's fractured, all right.
How's that pressure dressing?
Looks like we
stopped the bleeding.
Four units of A-positive.
Next door.
Let's get that Arteriogram.
Oh, finally,
type-specific's here.
All right. It's a little
late now. Statinsky.
Okay, I'm in. Keep
the O-neg going.
Pressure's coming up.
My guy's stable.
You need some help?
Ah, damn it. There's
nothing to clamp.
He's bled out.
Flatline.
All right.
Time of Death... 12:05.
BP's stable, 100/60.
Want to take this guy up?
Yeah. Let's go.
You do the body,
I'll do the room?
Sure.
Malik, I'm a little
shorthanded this afternoon.
A lot of my nurses
are calling in sick.
Is there any way you
can you pull a double?
Sorry.
Carol, can you give
us a hand in here?
Go on. I'll get this.
The, uh, memorial service
is going to be in
the hospital chapel.
You wouldn't need to say much.
Just...
No, forget it, Carter.
I'm no public speaker.
You know, there's
still no official ruling
on the cause of death.
Dr. Anspaugh says the police
are still talking to witnesses,
so maybe they'll
turn up something.
When did you speak to Anspaugh?
This morning.
He called in all the
blue team interns.
Why? Why? To
see how we're doing.
To see what we think
might have happened.
Why? Were there
any blue team interns
on the El platform?
I think he was wondering
about Gant's state of mind
these last couple of weeks
like all of us were.
So did he call you guys in
one at a time or all together?
No. One at a time.
Hasn't Anspaugh
talked to you yet?
Actually I'm supposed
to go talk to him
but I guess he needs
to do a survey first.
GSW to the abdomen.
Who's on call?
Dr. Hicks. Room one.
You know, I don't think
anybody's blaming you.
Why would they?
Carter, did you finish
your rounds this morning?
Not yet.
All right, well, get to it.
I can finish this up by myself.
She'll stay on a 72-hour hold
while we finish her
psychiatric evaluation.
I suggest you steer clear.
You've gotten too entangled.
I'm her doctor.
And her guardian angel
and the guy who let her down.
She pissed?
At you? Yeah, sure.
You told her you wouldn't
sell her into the system
and you did.
But betrayal isn't
anything new to this girl.
Betrayal? She's a
14-year-old on the streets.
You don't have
to explain it to me
And you don't have
to explain it to her.
Another doc could follow
up on her neuro exam.
You knew I'd be back.
She's a kid you went
out of your way to help
who hates your guts.
You want to change that.
Okay, what's
Charlie's prognosis?
Well, she's got a lot of issues,
but I won't recommend
a psychiatric placement.
DCFS will take over from here.
But it wouldn't be a
problem for her if I see her?
Charlie's armor
is in good shape.
How's yours?
So what are you going
to do with the afternoon?
Lydia and I are hitting
the January sales.
Not me, I'm not spending a
penny until our contract is settled.
Oh, it is settled.
Nothing like a
case of the pink flu
to make a point.
I've never been
in a strike before.
I hope you never will be.
This is just a
sick-out. A pink flu.
Close your ears, E. Ray.
Hey, I'm a union man.
One shift without RNs
ought to make them
think twice about
cutting our overtime.
I'm just worried
about the patients.
We all are.
That's why we aren't
going to accept a contract
that compromises patient care.
Or screws us.
That, too.
Chuny, could you help me
with this damn coffee maker?
See. What would they do
without us RNs around here?
Hey, you should be
taking tea and lemon
for that cold of yours.
Oh, boy. I hate to see her fall.
I tried to warn her.
Oh, Dr. Greene's a nice guy.
Dr. Greene's a
doctor on the rebound.
How many nurse/doctor
flings have you known?
Including my own?
And how many of them worked out?
The real problem is, she's
got a grand trine in fire
and his sun is in Pisces.
Labs are back
from curtain three.
They're mine.
Haleh, can you pull a double?
When?
Today. My entire
PM shift called in sick.
I heard something
was going around.
Well, something's
going around, all right.
Can you stay?
I'm sorry, Carol.
I'm coming down with it myself.
Hey, Charlie.
I just want to check
on your concussion.
It will only take a second.
Come here. Sit up.
Come on, let's go.
I need you to sit up.
I want you to
look into the light.
Okay?
Come here.
I want you to follow this
just with your
eyes, not your head.
Hey, look.
That swelling went down.
Okay, follow the light
just with your
eyes, not your head.
How's your head?
Any confusion?
Yeah.
What year is it?
December '95, according
to this hot magazine
you gave me.
Did you know Michael and
Lisa-Marie are splitting up?
Charlie, what was
I supposed to do?
Let you go back
out on the street?
Like I haven't been beaten
worse when I lived at home.
You have any trouble seeing?
No. I get these little blobs.
What kind of blobs?
Open your eye.
Dark spots floating around.
Any flashes of light?
Sometimes, when you
get a blow to the head
there's a danger of
retinal detachment.
We'll have an
ophthalmologist take a look at it.
In the meantime, why don't
you lay back down, okay?
Just when I thought things
couldn't get any more boring.
Yep.
If I go blind
can they still send
me to the nut house?
That's not where you're going.
Oh, good.
Then just to jail?
You're going somewhere
so you'll be safe.
I should have lied...
and said I wasn't raped.
That's why you locked me up.
You're on a hold
for your own good.
Like it was my fault.
I should have just
said it was sex.
It's not like there's
much of a difference.
Like any of it matters.
Don't let them put me in a home.
I won't.
Nobody's going to hurt you.
Please.
Guess.
It's... no more roses.
I mean, I love the roses...
They were beautiful
both times, but...
It's not roses.
It's a beauty.
This thing must have cost you.
Try it on.
You're going to
need it come Spring.
I thought we'd take a week
and head to the Upper Peninsula.
Mark, it's only January.
What makes you think we can't
plan ahead?
My last ten relationships.
Mark, Nurses Admin
is coming to discuss...
What are you rebelling
against, Chuny?
What have you got?
Weaver, without a
chart in curtain three.
Oops. I got distracted.
All his fault.
Does Admin want to discuss
our... situation?
You mean the nurses' sick-out?
Chuny.
That's what it is.
You wouldn't want to stay
and help me out, would you?
Please don't ask.
The nurses have
to stick together.
I'm a nurse.
And a manager.
Don't ask me to break ranks.
It's too hard to say no to you.
She's great.
Yeah.
Heard from Susan?
If you think I'm
just reacting to Susan leaving,
you're completely wrong.
I'm completely wrong.
Picked this guy up
at the airport shuttle
at McCormick Place.
He's diaphoretic,
temp's 103, BP's 70/50.
Vomited three times
en route. Diarrhea, too.
You don't want
to go near my rig.
Find Dr. Greene.
Okay, on my count.
One, two, three.
Let's give him
a liter of saline.
Pulse ox is 98% on five liters.
Temp's 103.6.
Okay, five of Compazine
and Tylenol, ten
grain suppository.
Let's mix a dopamine drip.
What do you got?
This guy was picked
up at an airport shuttle.
Departing or arriving?
Here, let me check.
Cap refill's poor.
Okay, let's get a
CBC, Chem seven
Urine C and S. Chest film.
According to his ticket,
Mr. Hecht just flew in from Paris.
Hang on. His original
point of departure
was Libreville.
Where's that?
Gabon, West Africa.
All right, everybody
get masks on.
I'll mask the patient.
What are you thinking?
I'd like to get a consult
from Infectious Disease
down here right away.
Isn't Gabon one of the places
they've found the Ebola virus?
Let's set up an isolation room.
Keep caregivers
down to a minimum.
I'll stay with Mr. Hecht.
I started the case.
How'd it go?
Best man pull through?
Yeah. Lost his spleen.
I finished my rounds.
Did you want me to take
Dennis's patients, too?
No. I'll do them.
You know, I bumped into
Dr. Morgenstern, and, uh
he told me the police have
ruled Dennis's death an accident.
Is that what you think it was?
I think it's easier for
everyone, for his family.
Yeah. Easier on everyone
but that doesn't mean it's true.
Carter, why do you
care what I think?
Because you and I knew Dennis.
Better than anybody else here.
Look, I'm not
your friend Keaton.
I know if she was
here, she would
hash over this thing with you,
but Carter, you
know, that's not me.
Peter? Ah.
There you are.
When it rains, it pours.
Dissecting aneurysm
coming down from ICU.
Care to join me?
Uh... I'd love to.
Have you finished
your rounds yet?
Yes, I have.
He's covering ER.
Well that shouldn't
stop you from joining us.
If you get paged, you can leave.
Why don't I tell you
how to do your job,
and then we'll see
how you take it?
Is there some way that you can
expedite Charlie's foster placement?
She not going to do well in an
institution. Norm agrees with me.
No, what I said was,
if she gets a chance,
she'll probably ditch
out of a group setting.
That's why my first attempt
is to locate the mother.
Yeah, good luck with that.
She was last seen in
Ohio over a year ago right?
You believe that?
I don't believe Charlie
wants us to find her mom,
that's why she's being
so uncooperative.
She's such a great mom.
Well, even a bad mom
can give parental consent
and that's what you need
for the kind of placement
you're suggesting.
If Charlie would cooperate
in helping find
her other relatives
in Cleveland or elsewhere,
she could be placed with them.
And she understands that?
Yes.
But I'm the enemy.
Okay. All right.
I'll give it a shot
if I'm not stepping
on your toes.
Oh, stomp away.
We all want the same thing.
Jeanie, this is Dr. Fischer
from Infectious Disease.
Hi. How's the patient?
He's defervescing.
Lytes, chest x ray,
urinalysis were all normal.
He's been conscious
off and on, but delirious.
He did confirm that he
was working in Gabon.
Some sort of land survey.
I want a Sed rate and an LP.
Right away.
And as far as the airline goes?
Keep them on alert
but I want to get
some test results
before they contact passengers.
I hear hoofbeats, but I
haven't seen any zebras yet.
Can you draw blood cultures?
The graft is holding, finally.
Let's close.
2-0 Proline on a double-armed.
Carter, suction.
Come on, 2-0 proline.
Let's go. Let's wake up.
The whole
department's off today.
Everyone's still in shock.
Bovie.
I'm sorry I didn't get
to know Dr. Gant better.
How was working with him, Peter?
I don't know. It's
too soon to say.
More 2-O.
He hadn't distinguished
himself yet.
That's surprising,
given his transcripts.
He came to us with the
highest recommendations.
Yeah, well, maybe he was
having adjustment problems.
So you noticed him struggling?
I don't think Gant was prepared
to handle an urban trauma center.
Then why did you give him
a positive progress report?
Sorry?
You heard me. Why
did you praise him
for his "improved
technical skills and initiative"
in his second review?
Perhaps at another time.
No, actually I gave
that review to Gant
before he had some
recent backsliding.
Now, I wasn't even aware
that he received that evaluation.
Oh, he hadn't.
It came today.
You can be sure
that he never received
any encouraging or
supportive word from you.
Candy, take over suctioning.
You're excused, Dr. Carter.
All he got from you
was harping and criticism
and now, he's dead
and you're going
to have to face it.
My apologies, Dr. Hicks.
Whoa! You don't like the roses?
I love the roses.
I'm just telling you
you can slow down.
You don't have to impress me.
Yeah, well, I just
passed a florist shop
and I thought about you.
Yeah, but in my family
if a man sends flowers
two times in one week
the only thing left is
conversion to Catholicism
marriage and seven kids.
So should I be looking
over my shoulder
for your father with a shotgun?
No. My brother
Julio... He packs a .45.
Mark, there you are.
Looks like 100% participation.
We have no nurses
in exactly one hour.
Dr. Greene, this is
Roger Drummond
from labor relations,
and you know Mary Kay.
Well, our attorneys are filing
an injunction against the union.
An organized work stoppage
is illegal under their contract.
No one was actually
stupid enough to admit
to an organized sick-out? Nope.
Hopefully, only this
one shift will be affected.
We can't stay
open without nurses.
Well, I've rounded
up private duty nurses
off the registry and also
some nurse managers
from other departments
who are going to cover.
Oh, boy.
I can come down
myself if you need me.
The extra bodies will help
with non-emergent cases.
The hospital would prefer
not to cave to this kind of tactic.
Well at least, we should stay
closed to trauma.
I agree with Carol.
Me, too.
All right.
We close to trauma, 3:00 sharp.
I'll call the paramedics.
Let them know to divert.
How's she doing?
No signs of retinal detachment.
What about the blobs?
Most people have
floaters, but you've probably
just noticed them more
as you've been recovering.
When's this stuff
going to wear off?
Your vision will be normal
in an hour or so.
Wear these.
Thanks for checking
her out there, Doc.
Any time, Dr. Ross.
You have a very nice daughter.
She's not my daughter.
Who gave you that idea?
It was just a joke.
Cool. It's kind of trippy.
Everything's a blur.
Why'd you tell the doctor that?
That you're my dad? Yep.
You're old enough.
You know, half the
time you clam up
and you don't say anything,
and then the other half,
you're taking back
the lies you just told.
So?
So you're making it tough
for people to help you.
If you cooperate, then
Social Services can find
a relative or get consent
for somebody to take you in.
Like who?
That's what you've got to
help them figure that out.
Stop lying to people.
Like adults don't lie
every chance they get?
Yeah.
Why don't you have any kids?
I get my fill of
them on the job.
So this truth thing's
a one-way street.
I get it.
Okay.
Uh... I haven't gotten
it together long enough
to stay with a woman
let alone family and babies
and long-term commitments.
Well, you wouldn't
have to have a baby
if you had, like, a foster kid.
Anybody in particular?
Well, a teenager
wouldn't be that long
of a commitment.
They're practically
grown up already.
Charlie, if I were ready
you'd be first on my list.
You've used that one
on women, haven't you?
Uh... I have.
There you are.
Hey.
So how are the eyes?
She's doing fine.
Good. Well, I'm sure
her mother will be
relieved to hear that.
You found her, in Cleveland?
No. On South Desplaines Avenue,
just ten blocks away
where she and Charlie live.
My God, Charlie.
I was freaking, I
was so worried.
Look at you.
What did I tell
you would happen?
You're going to end up
with scars from this, you know.
When are you
going to listen to me?
I can't turn my
back for a second.
You're out the door.
Dr. Pomeranz?
Yes.
Dr. Anspaugh said that you might
be available today for counseling
for those of us who
knew Dennis Gant.
That's right.
Um, they've set
up an office for me
on the surgical ward, Room 820,
and I will be there till 6:00.
Oh, I don't know if
I can make it today.
I meant to stop by earlier,
but I got called into a surgery.
Oh, are you an intern?
Yeah. Yeah. John Carter.
Oh, you're John Carter.
Dennis mentioned
you a few times.
You were his friend.
You knew Dennis?
He came to me for counseling
when he first arrived.
But after a few sessions,
he decided to stop.
I see.
I'm really very sorry.
I know how hard
it is to lose a friend.
I hope you'll come by and talk.
Hey, um...
When Dennis quit therapy,
did you think that it was okay?
I mean, did you...
feel it was all right
for him to stop?
I didn't disagree with it,
his stopping at the time.
He seemed to be settling in
developing a support system.
There's a survivor's guilt
that comes with any
unexpected death.
Maybe I feel guilty
because I am.
You should come and see me.
I'll try.
I'll try to remember
all your names,
but please have your ID
tags where they can be seen.
Bye, Lily. Bye, Haleh.
Good-bye, Carol.
Good luck.
Has anyone worked the ER before?
20 years ago; I hated it.
Well, we're closed to trauma,
so that should
ease the workload.
And please, if you
have any questions,
don't hesitate to ask. Later.
Okay, I'll pick you
up at quarter till.
I can meet you there.
I'll pick you up.
Bye, Chuny.
You know if we win this,
it'll be good for nurses.
Yeah, it's not that simple.
County's got to find
the money somewhere.
Well, they can check
my bank account.
It's not in there.
I'll send these up to the lab,
Cell count and
diff, protein, glucose
gram stain, India
ink and culture.
Exactly.
Greg, nice to see
you again. Kerry.
Did we find you
something exotic?
No, we've seen too many movies.
There's no ecchymosis,
bleeding or rash.
It doesn't suggest ebola.
Meet me in the lab.
We'll make the Geimsa stains.
You know we have
techs who will do that.
I'm an old-fashioned lab rat.
I like to do it myself.
Greg's wonderful.
I should have thought of him
for you earlier.
Kerry...
As your doctor.
There's no reason
for you to drive all the way out
to Highland Park anymore.
Greg's very
respected for his work
with HIV patients.
Oh.
He left a successful
private practice
to come to County
after his partner
died of AIDS last summer.
Oh, that's too bad.
Think about it.
Yeah, maybe I will.
Turns out she's
not even a runaway.
Her mom lives ten minutes away.
She sounds like
quite a case herself.
Letting her kid run the streets
all hours of the day and night.
So what do you think...
Chop house for Valentine's day?
Mark, I'd love to, but
you're not my type.
It's not very romantic,
but it's Chuny's favorite.
So are they going to send
Charlie home with her mom?
There's a cooling-off period
where the DCFS
tries to figure out
which end is up.
And I'm on my way to the gym.
Well, sounds like she's
in safe hands for now.
Thank God for Social Services.
Hey, Carter.
Can I get you anything?
Wow. I could get used
to being closed to trauma.
I was actually hoping
for something to do.
Doesn't feel real, does it?
I just keep waiting
for Dennis to come
through that door
and tell everybody
it was a big mistake.
You know you couldn't
have done anything
to change it, right?
I know that.
I just don't believe that.
Help! Somebody
help my friend, please.
He's dying.
Okay, on a count...
Don't lift him up.
His leg is barely hanging on.
What happened to this guy?
Gil was taking a
nap in the alley.
They dropped a dumpster on him.
I had to drag it off of him.
I kept calling for help
but no cars would stop.
I was looking for a
phone. I couldn't find one.
Paramedics wouldn't
have brought you here.
Yeah, we're closed to trauma.
You probably just saved
your friend a ride across town.
What can I do?
Get the doctors.
Get all the doctors.
Nothing. Let's
try the other slide.
Okay.
Thanks.
Want to take a shot?
Sure.
You know what
you're looking for?
They have hoop-shaped
rings, like Saturn.
Exactly.
You like astronomy.
Well, my fifth-grade science
project was on comets,
so I'm pretty much an expert.
You must be excited about
the appearance of Hale-Bopp.
It's a comet that
was just discovered.
Just started to
brighten this month.
Do you have your own telescope?
Careful, you're going to be starting
on a whole new set of useless facts.
I thought about getting
my own telescope once,
but can you see much
with the city lights?
You should join me
for a comet watch.
I set up outside the Adler.
Yeah, I'd love to sometime.
How about tonight?
It's supposed to
be crystal clear.
But bundle up, at 4:00, there can
be a chilly wind coming off the lake.
4:00 a.m.?
It's only visible in
the predawn sky.
Ah. Hey wait, look.
I think I found some.
Take a look.
Am I right?
They have rings...
more than one.
Yeah, that's it.
The asexual form
of the parasite.
It's plain old malaria.
Good news for Mr. Hecht?
Chloroquinine...
ten milligram IV
followed by a 15 milligram drip.
Okay.
Hey, you know, I'm usually awake
at 4:00 a.m. anyway.
I'll bring the coffee.
Great.
O-neg is here, four units.
Thanks. Call Radiology again.
Ask what's taking them so long.
Get it on the rapid infuser.
I got a pumper.
Femoral artery.
4 x 4s for Dr. Greene.
Gauze?
4 x 4s.
Oh, come on, Gil. Come on.
Fight, Gil.
Come on.
Pulse is thready, pressure's 60,
heart rate's 140, pulse ox 90.
How's that lavage coming?
I need some Betadine.
Coming up. Watch out!
I need some help
with this tape.
Okay. I got it.
Who's on the infuser?
I'll get it.
Just a sec.
Oh, yeah. Positive lavage.
We got internal bleeding.
I need a thigh cuff.
Thigh cuff for Dr. Greene.
Upper right drawer.
Right drawer.
Up...
Found it.
He's fibrillating.
I'll start compression.
Let's shock him.
Paddles, Carter. 200.
Everybody off?
No juice.
Uh... uh... Carol?
Hit the sync switch.
Turn it off.
Am I set?
Yeah. Clear!
Come on, Gil.
300.
Clear!
Is he dying?! Is he dying?
Is my buddy dying?!
We're doing the
best we can, sir.
Wait outside.
360. Clear!
He's my friend! I know, I know.
An amp of epi.
I am sorry.
I tried to get him here
as fast as I could...
Shut this guy up!
It's my fault.
I let him down.
Let's shock him
again at 360. Clear.
He's my buddy
and I let him down.
Okay, okay. We got it, okay?
Carter, get him out of here.
I let him down.
No you didn't.
At least, you tried.
Kerry, can you
cover for me?
Yeah. Go on.
Come on. Come on.
Let's try him again at 360.
Clear.
I knew Dennis was
having a hard time.
I knew he was in trouble...
but I was too busy...
and I just didn't want
to get dragged down.
I didn't listen.
You're in the middle
of your first year of residency.
You're working at
an inhuman pace.
Why am I doing it again?
'Cause you are
trying to learn a job
where lives are at stake.
Didn't save Dennis's
life, though, did I?
You don't know
that you could have.
I know that I wasn't
much of a friend.
I'll collect the sharps.
And you can check
off the dispensed meds.
Oh, you don't have to do that.
I can get a temp.
I don't mind chipping in.
#11 Lavage blade
Two needles from
the central line.
Right.
Three epi, 100 of lidocaine.
You know, I wanted
to compliment you
on how you handled
yourself today.
It isn't easy to be a manager
when it's hitting the fan
and your workers
are your friends.
Two IV needles.
Thanks. It's been pretty
awful around here lately.
I still think of myself as
just a nurse, you know,
and I got to wade through
all this management crap.
Two of O-neg, empty, two unused.
Well, you waded through
it very gracefully today.
Ah, isn't there three of O-neg?
Oh, yeah.
Here it is.
No. This one
is marked "A-pos."
What?
Did we order type specific?
It never came down.
Where did this...?
God, this must have
been on the infuser.
There's blood in the Foley bag.
Oh, my God, I gave him
the wrong blood.
This unit of A-positive
must have been
left on the infuser.
And when I started it up,
I'm pretty sure there
was a bag on there.
I just, I thought
someone had hung it,
and I didn't check the label.
Have you sent an EDTA-treated
sample to be recross-matched?
Yeah. It showed
massive intravascular hemolysis.
I gave type-A blood
to a type-O patient.
I killed him.
He was bleeding out anyway.
Possibly bleeding out.
We've saved worse.
It was an honest mistake.
You were the only
RN in the trauma.
We were all filling in roles
we weren't accustomed to.
That still doesn't take
away the basic error.
I did not check the label.
Carol, I think we're saying
that if you determined
an incident report
was unnecessary
we wouldn't pursue it.
Am I speaking out of turn?
No. If you'd been
alone cleaning up
you could have thrown the
empty bag in the hazardous waste
and been done with it.
That's true.
But I'd still have
to look at myself
in the mirror every day.
Thank you for making the
arrangements, Dr. Carter.
And the sentiments you expressed
set just the right tone.
I want to apologize, Dr. Hicks,
about what happened
earlier in surgery.
You already did.
Did I miss it?
Yeah.
Mr. Gant, this is Dr. Benton,
who you were asking about.
Dr. Benton, this
is Dennis Gant, Sr.
He was hoping to meet you.
My sympathies are
with you and your family.
Thank you, doctor.
I'm sorry I missed the service.
Dennis's e-mail gave me a sense
of how demanding
your schedules are.
In fact, I had to
admonish my son
for taking time to
write home at all.
I didn't want him to
neglect his workload.
I know that Dennis
greatly respected your work
and looked up to you.
Well, I'm afraid I was, uh...
I was a bit tough on your son.
Maybe Dr. Carter filled you in.
No, I haven't.
You have to be tough. Life is.
I wasn't entirely
convinced that my boy
should have chosen such
an ambitious specialty.
But I didn't raise a quitter.
I hope he didn't disappoint you.
No. Your son worked very hard
and I think he...
would have made
an excellent surgeon.
Oh, I am so late.
What a day, huh?
You know, you and
Dr. Fischer make a good team.
Well, we're getting
together later.
He's an astronomy buff.
You have a date
with Greg Fischer?
Well, no, not a date.
In some ways, it's perfect
for me that he's gay.
Jeanie, what makes you think
Greg Fischer is gay?
Well, you said...
He isn't gay.
But you said that his
partner died of AIDS.
No. His partner in
his medical practice
not his lover.
Oh, my God, Greg
Fischer is one of the most
eligible heterosexuals
in Chicago.
So he thinks this is a date.
It is a date.
I can't go.
Oh, don't be silly.
No. I didn't tell him about
my being HIV-positive.
Look, it's just a date.
Get to know him.
You're entitled to a date.
Really. Go. Have fun.
I expect to hear all
about it tomorrow.
Have you seen E. Ray?
I think he's helping
one of the temp nurses.
What?
Not with a patient.
He's helping her with
her astrological chart.
Is Dr. Fischer in?
I see. Is he on
pager, by chance?
No? No? Okay, thanks.
Carol.
Good news.
The union blinked first.
The nurses will be back
on the morning shift.
Well, you saved me
a trip from upstairs.
I needed to give you this.
During a trauma
that came in privately
I inadvertently gave the patient
the wrong blood, and he died.
Oh, my God.
The patient's family
aware of the error?
He was a transient.
His friend said he had
no family members.
Well, that's fortunate.
What?
I'll look over
the report, Carol,
but don't beat yourself up here.
Did the sick-out contribute to
this man's demise?
No. It was my error.
I didn't check the label.
I'm going to have
to write this up
of course
but I think
in view of the
circumstances of the day
we may be able to
forego an investigation.
I don't want any
special favors here.
I stayed on today because,
as a manager, I'm required to.
I understand.
So the mom admits
that there have been
fights in the house.
She claims she can't
keep Charlie in at night.
Sounds more like the
mom's not in at night herself.
She confirmed the abuse
by one if not two of her
boyfriends in the past.
Why'd you page me?
Charlie's making some claims.
Against me?
No, not accusations
but Norm and I
felt it would be best
if we hash this
thing out together.
I appreciate you coming.
Mm-hmm.
What's up?
Thank you so much for
taking care of her, doctor.
It's my job.
Yeah, but there are
so many who don't care
or just don't take the time.
I was out of my
mind. When I heard...
I thought she was
baby-sitting at Gloria's.
I was updating Dr. Ross about
what we've been discussing,
about the problems at home.
Yeah. I won't say I
don't have a temper
and I've made a lot of mistakes
but I love Charlie like crazy.
I just want her
to find something.
You know?
She can't go out
on her own yet, but...
So I told them what you told me
about how my mom
could give consent.
Adelle would be the one who
would know more about that.
Charlie means parental
consent for her to live with you.
She believes you agreed to that.
Like we said
I'm almost grown up.
I wouldn't be around
all the time. I mean,
I'd be in school...
Charlie, I'm...
And I can see you're a
good man and a doctor
and it's not like I'm
giving up my daughter.
She needs a good influence.
Charlie, that isn't
what we talked about.
In fact, that's just the exact
opposite of what we talked about.
So Charlie was mistaken.
Yes. We could do it.
They'd let us.
So, what, you
were flat-out lying?
You see what it's like with her?
You make me nuts.
All right. I can't do this.
Why not? I'd do
whatever you said.
These people can help
you. Adelle can help you
Dr. Middleton can help you...
Screw Adelle and
Dr. Middleton and screw Mom!
It's all a bunch of crap
and I'll run away for good.
You know it, and it'll be
your fault! Settle down.
I hate you! I hate you!
Maybe you should go.
Yeah, yeah.
Go! Go on! Get out of my face!
Oh, God, I'm frozen.
The snow was supposed to stop.
Sorry, you didn't even
get a glimpse of the comet.
That's okay, we'll have to
try again like in June or July.
Two hot chocolates.
You want something to eat?
Yeah, maybe.
I'm afraid I'm not hardy
enough for astronomy.
Or crazy enough.
Come to think of
it, I've never been
all that interested in
the stars themselves.
It's always been the
stories behind them.
They have some great
myths. Have a favorite?
I like the gruesome
ones, like Cassiopeia.
Turned to stone by
the head of Medusa.
Are you sure she didn't
freeze to death stargazing?
Actually, she's sitting there
waiting for the
man of her dreams.
Remember? She's searching
for a nice, upstanding guy.
He could even be a bit of a nerd
as long as he's not completely
lacking in spontaneity.
I'm sorry.
No, I'm sorry.
No, it's my fault.
I, uh...
I just didn't expect that.
But did you like it?
Yes, I did.
But, Greg...
Hmm.
I'm HIV-positive.
Oh.
I'm sorry. I should've told
you before we got here,
but I didn't think it
was a date at first.
That's okay. You didn't need to.
No, I should've
but I was having fun.
So...
Here you go.
Did you want to order anything?
No.
No, thanks. I'm fine.
I know I was hard on Gant.
But I thought that
was the best way
for him to learn.
And I don't blame you.
No more than I blame myself.
I just feel like I have
been walking around
with this secret
and you're the only
person who knows it
and you won't admit to it.
You know, a few years ago
I went to my high
school reunion.
North Lawndale.
Jackie got it in her head.
Now, there wasn't
much of a turnout
'cause half the class
had dropped out.
I didn't know the others.
You know, my parents tried to
keep me away from bad influences.
But here I am with
them, you know,
and, uh, a third of
the guys are in prison
and I bet another
third are dead.
You know, you hear about this
one and that one over the years.
But this night
I'm just struck by
the sheer numbers.
I don't know what to
think of Gant's death.
But, Carter, I don't need
you to tell me how I feel.
You want to go
through this alone?
You want to make this
into something that, um...
I don't know about.
I guess you can.
We'll both keep our distance.
We'll both do our work.
Pretend like nothing happened.
We're good at that.
Look what that
did for Dennis Gant.