You'll be back Soon you'll see
You'll remember You belong to me
And when push comes to shove
I will send a fully
armed battalion...
Oh!
I see how it is. Yeah,
it's called strategy.
Yeah, where I'm from,
it's called cheating.
You all right, Willow?
I swear, if they wrote a
Broadway musical about me,
it'd be called The
Sound of Mucus.
Mine would be called
Mamma Mastectomy.
More like Thoroughly
Mortal Millie.
That's a good one. The
Phantom of the Operation.
Willow, uh, how long
have you had that cough?
Mine'd be Liver Let Die.
Liver-less.
Of course, that's a Bond
film, not a Broadway musical,
but unlike you, I'm cool
with cheating. She's right.
Well, actually, I was thinking
of the Guns N' Roses song.
So, Max, what's
your cancer musical?
Forever and ever...
What's the matter,
Max? No jokes today?
Where's your sense of tumor?
Thank you, Andre.
That was so brave.
Nice connecting.
Lauren, how about you?
I know that you're
still getting acclimated
but we would love
to hear from you.
Your friend just visited?
Maybe you want to talk
about how that made you feel.
No.
But, um, thank you.
Maybe at evening group.
Have a beautiful
morning, everyone.
Thanks for sharing, Andre.
- Good session.
Way to go.
Yeah, hi. Come in. It's Martin.
No, babe. I hear what
you're saying loud and clear,
but she needs to try
new things, all right?
And plus, literally,
there's nothing cooler
that a kid could do.
Yes, or an adult. You got
me, okay? But she is going.
Yes, I'll call you
later. Love you.
Husbands, am I right?
Anyway, sorry about the mess.
Me and Sameera are
going for a sleepover
at the Museum of
Natural History later
and I am so excited.
I visited Lauren in rehab.
Okay.
Well, that happened.
I shouldn't have done that.
Yeah.
How was she?
I don't know. She wouldn't
even look at me, man. Just...
Then she just told me to leave.
Well, you invaded her privacy.
Yeah, but come
on. I'm her friend.
Yeah, but you may remind her
of an environment that's toxic.
Understand? Toxic?
The hospital. This place. All
the stress that it caused her.
Oh, yeah.
Besides, the first few days
in rehab are a huge transition.
You shouldn't have...
I thought you were
supposed to be a good listener.
Do... Ugh.
You know what? If you
want me to stand here
and make you feel better
about doing something
that I strongly advised
you not to, I'm not going to.
Because the person that I'm concerned
about right now is Lauren. Not you.
What? Really?
The old saved-by-the-page,
huh? That old chestnut?
Ten-year-old boy, status
post heart transplant,
now with respiratory arrest during
the Pope's procession down Fifth.
Trauma one. 126, 150/92 and 22.
O2 sat 92 on 100%
non-rebreather.
Jimmy, your parents are
right behind you, okay?
And I'm here. Ah, good. Jump in.
Jimmy, we're right here.
He's 10 years old.
Recent heart transplant.
O2 sats still in low 90s.
Push another 10
milligrams of Lasix.
Jimmy, everything's gonna be
okay. Just keep breathing, okay?
His lungs are filled with fluid.
Heart failure?
Most likely secondary
acute rejection,
which we need a left
ventricular biopsy to confirm.
Why is he rejecting
the transplant?
God only knows.
Good morning,
Mr. Brandt. Oh, okay.
Ahem!
Sorry.
You know how young women are
sex positive and everything nowadays.
Yes.
I understand you're
under a protocol at Baptist.
Yeah, for colon
cancer. Stage three.
Worst 18 months of my life.
Of course, until I met
this gorgeous woman.
So what would you
like me to do for you?
Well, it's pretty simple.
I want this thing removed.
Well, that thing is
how they administer
your chemotherapy
drugs for your colon cancer.
I'm not interested
in that either.
He wants to stop the chemo.
Have you discussed that with your
oncologist over at Baptist because...
Look, look. Can you take
the catheter out or not?
But the treatment is
prolonging your life.
It... It might be,
but I'm certain
as hell not living.
Tethered to a hospital,
dragged down by drugs.
I'd rather spend some time
traveling with this young woman.
Well, all my patients would rather be
doing something besides chemotherapy,
but it's vital in order
to treat the disease.
Haven't you ever been in love?
What wouldn't you give
for just a little bit more of it?
Meeting with Brennan
from HCC at 9:00.
Maintenance review
panel at 10:00.
Morbidity and Mortality
conference at 11:00.
I have a sense of humor, right?
I don't find you funny
but that's mainly because most
of your decisions ruin my life.
Ah.
You owe a call to the head of
the board about year-end budgets,
and you're meeting Georgia
for birthing class at 1:30.
Can you push it? Yeah, okay.
That was funny. What?
No, it wasn't a joke.
I just... I'm not really in
the push-push mood today.
Yeah, because birthing
class is all about your mood.
It's the... You know, I
don't know. It's like...
Something about joking about
death that's just not to me very funny.
You know, as much as I'd
love to keep talking to you
about your sense of humor,
do you remember speaking to the
Secret Service a few weeks ago?
Maybe, but if I told
you, I'd have to kill you.
Don't give up your day job.
Come on, that was funny.
They're in your office.
Hmm.
Uh... Max Goodwin, Medical
Director. Welcome to New Amsterdam.
Thank you. I am
Cardinal Mancini.
Hi. This is Agent Hayes
and Agent Larson...
How you doing? From
the Secret Service.
Cool. You know why we're here?
Uh... Yeah, no.
The Pope is addressing
the UN this afternoon.
Right, the Pope is addressing
the... Right. Yeah, I remember.
Ah, yes. And as
papal security liaison,
it falls to me to secure
your presidential bay
in case of an
emergency, God forbid.
Sure. Great. Well, I'm happy to
help. You need the presidential bay?
Yes, sir. And
surrounding floors.
Ah, yes. And the
Well, I don't love the
sound of surrounding floors.
This is a working hospital.
It's a precaution.
And merely a formality.
You'll hardly tell we're here.
Please make room. - Excuse us.
All the way to the
end of the hall, please.
Behind you.
Let's go, let's go.
Keep moving, please.
Hate to say this, but I
can kinda tell you're here.
Quincey.
Good hound, good
hound, good hound.
I'm not seeing any significant
scarring. It would be a very mild surgery.
Let her rip.
Before we let her rip I need to make
sure that you're absolutely certain
that you wanna end
your chemotherapy.
Never more sure of anything.
Okay. Well, while we wait for your
records to be sent over from Baptist,
we can schedule the procedure,
and then we'll take it from...
Dr. Sharpe. Lila,
I'm with a patient.
I'm sorry. I tried to tell them.
Tell who? Yeah, she's the one.
Ma'am, I'm gonna have
to ask you a few questions.
I haven't done anything.
Don't you touch her!
Sheila! Come on, let's go.
Sorry. Excuse me.
What's going on, please?
Hi. I'm Carl Jimenez. I'm
Mr. Brandt's legal guardian.
That woman kidnapped him.
Gentlemen.
We have received a
credible death threat
against the Pope
from within this hospital.
Security will need
to be heightened.
Uh... Sorry. Wait. Who here
would threaten the Pope?
As it turns out,
one of your doctors.
Dr. Vijay Kapoor.
It's not as simple as whether I
did or did not try to kill the Pope.
How could it possibly
not be that simple?
Dr. Kapoor coated the bed in the
presidential bay with a known poison.
Sorry. Poison? It
was oleander petals!
Which are poisonous.
But it was a gift.
It represents heart chakra.
Pope has a big heart.
Yeah, Vijay, couldn't you just
have given the Pope a normal gift?
I would have, but what do you give
someone who lives in the Vatican?
Pope is a man of peace.
He supports women's
rights and gay people.
In fact, I heard a rumor that
he sneaks out of the Vatican,
disguised, to help to
feed the poor people.
As you can see, Dr. Kapoor
made an innocent mistake.
He loves the Pope.
I love the Pope. Loves him.
Your background
check came back clear.
So he can go, right?
I'll check. Great. Thank you.
I mean, if I actually
wanted to kill the Pope,
I would have used
white snakeroot petals.
Excuse me? Yeah, it's
faster and untraceable.
That's exactly what killed
Abraham Lincoln's mother, you know.
Take a seat, please, Dr. Kapoor.
What? You're on your own, pal.
Please take a seat.
So, Jimmy's heart biopsy results
show signs of acute rejection
and that's why your son collapsed.
Well, is he gonna be all right?
Well, I've increased
his immunosuppressants
and that should
treat this episode,
but we need to find out why
it happened in the first place.
Now, were there any changes in his
diet? Any rashes, colds or upset stomach?
Hmm.
Well, can you think of anything different?
Like, anything out of the ordinary?
Mrs. Corrigan?
Our insurance paid
for the transplant,
but they didn't pay for any
of the post-op medications.
Doesn't make any sense.
The pills, they cost
over $9,000 a month.
Our church held a fundraiser,
but it wasn't enough.
Okay. And?
We started
spreading out the pills.
Like, just giving him
one every other day.
We were trying
to make them last.
Um...
That's what made Jimmy sick.
We did this.
Well, I mean... It's real
easy to blame yourselves.
That's not gonna make
Jimmy better, okay?
We just need to make sure
that it never happens again.
All right? But it will.
We can't afford the pills.
What are we supposed to do?
I'm just doing my job.
Walter's living will
specifically states
any and all known medical
treatments should be explored.
Okay. But Sheila?
You can't honestly think that
that sweet lady's a kidnapper.
She removed him from his
residence and ran away with him.
They're in love.
Look, I'm just trying to protect
Walter from the story I see all the time.
An older man, alone, vulnerable,
meets a younger woman...
She's 75.
Twenty-five or 75, she wants
him to stop his cancer treatment.
Now, I've been granted his
healthcare decisions because frankly,
his healthcare proxy
was asleep at the wheel.
So here I am,
doing the best I can.
I can appreciate that.
So, tell me.
Is stopping treatment in
Walter's best interests?
Medically, no.
But I have to respect
the patient's wishes.
Well, legally, you have
to respect my wishes.
And even though Walt's a pain in
the ass, I'm just trying to keep him alive.
He's trying to kill me.
If it were left up to Carl, I would
be alone, rotting in my apartment,
having the life
drained out of me.
He's doing what
he thinks is best.
He thinks Sheila pushed me.
The whole thing was my idea.
Unfortunately, the law
may not see it that way.
I don't have a lot of
time left on this Earth.
And the law won't let
me live the way I want to.
That ain't right.
Maybe there is
something that we can do.
Get the law on our side.
Max. How can I help?
Change the fundamental
idiocracy of American healthcare?
I'm working on it.
I've got this kid, just
had a heart transplant,
family can't afford
the post-op meds.
What's their financial profile?
Married, stable.
Dad's a security guard who
pulls in about 45K a year.
Too much to
qualify for Medicaid.
Or the Community Care Fund.
Well, we can help them in the short
term but they need a long-term solution.
Working class, just
caught in the middle.
Maybe not.
Um...
You could get a divorce.
Is this a joke?
Look, if Patricia is a
single mom with no income,
she and Jimmy could
qualify for Medicaid.
And Medicaid would cover
the cost of Jimmy's medication.
But we love each other.
Well, no one's questioning that.
And as Catholics, we don't
even believe in divorce.
You can't ask us to break
something that's
unbreakable. I can't even...
I'm sorry. It's just
this system is flawed.
And so is this solution, but
I can't think of a better one.
Get divorced, save your son.
What happened?
I don't know. I
just got the page.
Heart rate 140. BP 90 over
palp. Respiratory rate 22.
She collapsed at work.
EMS just dropped off.
Any history of
infection? No, none.
She's tachy, hypotensive,
warm to the touch.
Sepsis?
She has a hot, red, macular
rash around her J-tube.
Cellulitis. Looks like it.
That's preventable.
Helen, your people let her walk
out with an infection? Who's next?
Max, I paged you here as
her friend, not as her doctor.
Let's get her to Trauma One!
I've got this under control.
Do you?
I'm gonna give you a minute to
think about what you just said.
Max. Birthing class?
Hmm. I'll be there.
Okay.
How is she?
She's stable, but
not out of the woods.
Yeah. She was coughing this
morning but there was no indication...
Setbacks happen. You're
calling sepsis a setback?
Is this your way of apologizing?
She was laughing
at her symptoms.
This morning in chemo.
Everyone was laughing, and
I could have done something.
I could have gotten someone.
She was laughing
at her symptoms.
She was laughing because
of her symptoms, Max.
There's a difference.
One, two, three, four, five.
No.
Five, four, three, two, one?
Can you think of any
other five-digit password?
As soon as I scan your
email, you're free to go.
I want to help you
but I rarely use email.
Honestly, I thought it
was a passing trend.
What do you use?
A cup of tea and a conversation.
Is it your back
that's bothering you?
Maybe I can help.
You wanna help?
Remember your password.
Hello, John Wilkes Booth.
I warned you not
to do it, didn't I? Ah.
You did?
Yeah. Hell yeah, I did,
because it was idiotic.
You mean you knew about this little
stunt and you decided not to report it?
Yeah. No.
No, wait. What?
Take a seat, please.
No, no, no, I gotta...
That's a joke, right?
You're kidding?
I'm not known for
my sense of humor.
Do you know my password?
The ICU is a secured area, sir.
Sure it is, and you're
doing a hell of a job,
but I'm late for a birthing
class and this way's faster,
so I'm just gonna go
ahead and... Okay.
That's my ICU, right?
And I'm really late
so I'm just gonna go ahead
and walk through it right now.
So you can just step aside.
Go ahead and just step...
Yeah. Did I mention
I have cancer?
When you find out
that you have cancer,
it's the worst moment.
Everything is chaos and...
And fear.
When adult protection services
petitioned to have Mr. Brandt
become a ward of the state,
he had just got his
cancer diagnosis.
He was unraveling.
But then Walter met Sheila.
And since he's been with Sheila,
he's happy and taken care of.
Will love cure Walter? No.
But it will heal
him in other ways.
Mr. Jimenez, do
you have a response?
I do, Your Honor.
The decision to deem
Mr. Brandt an incapacitated person
was not made lightly.
Now... Oh, come on.
Mr. Brandt, this
is for your benefit.
You're petitioning to
get your rights back.
Please let Mr. Jimenez finish.
I'm sorry.
Look, I didn't want to go there,
but of the five speeding
tickets Walter got last year,
one of them was near a school.
His hoarding caused a
small fire in his apartment.
And then Walter got aggressive
with his healthcare attendant
when she tried to
help him clean up.
That's why the state stepped in.
You believe he's a danger
to himself and to others?
I do, Your Honor.
Hey, there.
Can we talk for a minute?
I just wanted to check in. I
know we hit you with a crazy idea.
We were just trying to help
you duck some red tape.
Our marriage isn't red tape.
I realize that.
When Neil and I got
married, we made a promise
to our friends,
our family, to God.
It was a divine pact to each
other. That's a... It's a real promise.
Marriage is forever.
I can't even imagine.
Neil is our rock.
Look, Mrs. Corrigan...
I won't abandon my family.
It'd just be on paper. "Render
unto Caesar," that sort of thing.
There has to be another way.
We'd lose our community.
We wouldn't be able
to receive the Eucharist.
I understand,
but is that worth more
than your son's life?
Hey, maybe we
could get remarried.
You know, when Jimmy's
off his medications.
Unfortunately, Jimmy will be
on meds for the rest of his life.
This is forever?
I don't see any
other way around it.
Then we'll do it.
Inhale.
And exhale.
Okay, moms. Put all your
weight on your partner.
Inhale.
And sway.
Good. Doesn't that feel good?
Are you okay? Hmm?
If this is too
much, we can stop.
No, yeah, I'm good. I'm swaying.
Sorry. All right.
Okay, now guide
mom down to her pillow.
And, moms, this
is the best part.
Foot massage.
This is great if you
have a headache.
And who remembers the
one place not to massage?
Ankles.
Everyone, this is Max,
the Medical Director.
Yeah, I got a follow-up question.
Why are we giving foot massages
when we should be discussing
postpartum hemorrhaging,
which is the number one
cause of maternal mortality?
Not a joke.
Max... What?
Rest assured that
hemorrhaging is very rare, okay?
Yeah, rare, but 5% of births
and double that for Cesareans
and I mean, if mom
does have a headache,
that could be preeclampsia
or any number of...
Max, stop it. Sorry, sorry.
Just there's a lot that could
go wrong.
Sorry.
So you have your
settlement agreement.
We'll take it to the
judge for questioning.
It'll take a while before
your divorce becomes official,
so when you go home, we'll
make sure that we send you
with enough meds to cover
Jimmy until the Medicaid kicks in.
As long as Jimmy's okay.
That's what's important.
Where is he?
Jimmy couldn't have gone far.
Sepsis in oncology,
missing patients...
This isn't supposed to happen
here at New Amsterdam.
Well, it's still a hospital, Max.
People get sick, scared or...
Don't say it. Die.
Dude, I just said,
"Don't say it."
Why... I literally... Oh,
my God. Seriously?
Agents, have you
seen a 10-year-old boy,
straight brown hair,
in the last 30 minutes?
I have not. Hmm. Right.
Of course you haven't.
Can I just ask,
what have you seen?
Four orderlies, 12 patients,
nine doctors, 17 nurses,
a janitor and two pregnant couples
looking for building D. Three couples.
Wow.
Yeah, since the Pope
probably isn't coming today...
How about you and a few of your
guys help us out in another way?
Scent.
Good dog.
Can we go now, please?
My supervisor wants you to stay
put until the Pope leaves the city.
Till...
Come on, come on! Till
the Pope leaves the city?
Do we look like Pope
assassins to you?
He doesn't even know where his
glasses are and they're on top of his head.
Right? I'm a pacifist.
I can't even swat a fly.
We should all have
a nice cup of tea.
Tea? Martin and Sameera
are on their way here right now.
We're gonna miss the sleepover
at the Natural History Museum
and you're talking
to me about tea?
It's cinnamon spice.
I do love cinnamon spice.
The Museum of Natural History
must be so creepy at night.
Yeah, well, you must
be so creepy at night.
You know, with those all
dead animals with their eyes.
My Rohan never liked
to go there as a child.
It's creepy. No, it's not.
It's magical, it's wonderful
and it's educational.
The trifecta.
You're not listening.
No, you guys are having
a different conversation
- than I am, clearly.
- Jesus!
What's the matter? Scalding hot.
No, actually, it's kinda
the perfect temperature.
My leg's on fire.
Have you been experiencing
strange sensation in your leg?
Tingling.
On and off.
Is it better after work hours?
How do you know?
You have meralgia paresthetica.
It's caused by your gun.
My gun?
Yeah, it's pressing on your
lateral femoral cutaneous nerve.
If you switch to a shoulder holster,
your symptoms should go away.
Thank you.
So let me ask you
something. In your line of work,
do a lot of assassins stop to diagnose
strangers with nerve disorders?
Dr. Sharpe, like you,
I do believe in love.
But love doesn't change the law.
The law grants Mr. Jimenez
the right to determine
the medical decisions
for Mr. Brandt.
Unless you have
anything else to present.
I don't, Your Honor.
Then I'm afraid
to say we're done.
Legal guardianship
remains with Mr. Jimenez.
Thank you, Your Honor.
Walt.
Let's get you home.
What are you doing?
Hiding.
If I thought I could get
back up, I would join you.
You got a family?
I'm mad at them.
Yeah.
Authority figures.
I'm mad at them, too.
I wish I was old.
I wish I was young.
Found him.
Honey, we were so
worried about you.
Are you gonna live
in different houses?
No.
Will you still love each other?
Of course.
But you're gonna go to hell.
Jimmy.
It's not that simple.
Divorce is a sin. Sister Frances
said so. She said sinning isn't cool.
Is she wrong?
No, she's right.
Sinning isn't cool.
So you'll go to hell and I'll go to
heaven and not be with you forever.
Hi. Hi.
It's an ambush. I see that.
So are we kicked out
of foot massage class?
No, but there
were a lot of people
googling preeclampsia
and hyperventilating.
Well, hyperventilating
is kinda like Lamaze,
so good practice, right?
Sorry.
Not funny.
Kind of off my game today.
What is going on, babe?
It's nothing.
I should get back to work. Max.
Okay, it's just that... I
mean, foot massages?
And standing squats,
and changing doll diapers. The
focus of that class is just way off.
Babe, the focus of that
class is managing labor.
The focus of that class
is situations that you could
handle with an epidural
when what you need to
focus on is getting ready.
I mean, you need to get...
You need to get ready.
Just in case.
In case of what?
In case I'm not there.
I might not be able
to carry your weight,
or help you change positions
or bring you ice chips.
I might not be in there at all.
You understand?
That is what you
need to think about.
need to get ready for.
I know. And I do.
Every day.
Yeah, but you
don't... I don't what?
I don't have public outbursts?
I don't rail about
maternal death rates?
No, I don't.
Then how do you...
I look around.
At everything that I have.
And I focus on that.
Hmm.
And if it goes?
Then it goes.
But it's not gone yet.
You hear me?
You're not gone yet.
Mmm-hmm.
There's no improvement
yet but she is a tough cookie.
Not that cancer cares.
Why was she laughing?
You should hear
some of their jokes.
I mean, they used
to name their tumors.
I believe Willow's
was Arnold, as in,
"It's not a tumor."
That's pretty good.
But it is a tumor.
Grace comes in many forms.
You would have been
proud of me today.
Yeah? Yeah, I pulled a Max.
How? Had multiple panic
attacks in the hospital,
frightened pregnant
women, encouraged sin?
No. Mmm.
No, I...
I got way more involved with
a patient than I should have.
Feels good, doesn't it?
Not when it doesn't work out.
Yeah.
Sorry to interrupt.
Dr. Sharpe, can we talk
about Walter's next steps?
Yeah.
First thing we have to do is
get Walter back to Mt. Zion.
Baptist. What?
No, no. He's at...
Oh.
Baptist. Yeah,
you're right. Sorry.
How many are you taking care of?
Wards of the state? Ten?
Seems rather a lot.
Well, it is, but I wish
I could take on more.
There are so many
seniors out there alone.
No husband or wife, no children.
And the ones like Walter, they
require even more time and attention.
And even more care.
You mean like that?
Yeah, like that.
I have an idea.
Well, this is one for the books.
You want me to
terminate his guardianship?
Yes, Your Honor.
The ruling that I just
confirmed in your favor?
Yes, Your Honor. Can I ask why?
Actually, it was
Dr. Sharpe's idea.
But there is one condition.
One condition?
If Mr. Jimenez is not going to be
Mr. Brandt's guardian, who will?
His wife.
I didn't realize you
were married, Mr. Brandt.
That's the one condition.
All I want is for someone
to look out for Walter.
Someone with his
best interests at heart.
And I accept.
Me, too.
Dr. Goodwin, grazie.
I apologize for
any inconvenience.
It's no inconvenience at all.
Actually, that's not true. It
was a lot of inconvenience.
Ah.
If there is any way I
can express my gratitude,
just let me know.
Mmm.
Actually...
There is.
Dr. Reynolds? Oh. Just in time.
Hey, guys. Jimmy, I'd
like you to meet someone.
This is Cardinal Mancini,
the Pope's right-hand man.
The Pope?
Mmm-hmm.
It's a great honor,
Cardinal, sir.
We're big fans.
I talked to His Holiness
about your predicament.
The Pope says it's cool.
You guys will not believe
what I just went through.
Iggy. All right,
so if we're gonna make the flashlight
tour of the museum, we gotta get going.
Put that away. Hang on a second.
What? What is it?
She doesn't want to go.
What are you talking about?
Of course, she wants to go.
That's what we talked about.
We're going, right?
Put that stuff away.
Iggy, Iggy. Stop
talking and listen.
Okay.
Wanna tell him what you told me?
Okay, come on. Come on, bug.
You gotta tell me what's
going on. What's wrong?
The museum is scary.
The museum is not
scary. It's a museum.
And you told me that
you wanted to go, right?
'Cause you wanted to go.
I just, um...
You know, I just...
I wanna share all the things
that I loved the most with you
because that's my favorite
part about being your dad.
But maybe sometimes
I'm not the best listener.
Even though that
is technically my job.
Maybe sometimes at home
you don't get the best of me.
I'm sorry. I always want
you to have the best of me.
Okay?
What do you think? Hug?
You're in? Come
here. Meet me halfway.
Get up here. Oh, my
gosh. You're getting so big.
Can I get in on that? Of course.
Does anyone else wanna speak?
All right, then. I'll see you
guys tomorrow morning.
I messed up.
Uh...
I was in trouble,
and instead of asking for help,
I just pushed everyone away.
I didn't think I had
any friends left.
I thought, well,
I ruin all my relationships.
And I was wondering...
Why even bother
recovering, you know?
Why not let myself sink
deeper down the hole?
Didn't think I
had anything left.
I have nothing to go back to.
But then,
the other night,
a friend of mine came to visit,
and I'm just really
grateful that he did.
Thank you.
I wish I was the moon tonight
"Out of the night that covers me
"Black as the pit
from pole to pole
"I thank whatever gods may be
"For my unconquerable soul"
God bless me I'm a free man
With no place free to go
Paralyzed and collared-tight
No pills for what I fear
This is crazy
I wish I was the moon tonight
Chimney falls as lovers blaze
Thought that I was young
Now I've freezing hands
And bloodless veins
No! What have you
done with my daughter?
Numb as I've
become, I'm so tired
And I wish I was the moon
I'm so tired
Tonight
Jeez. Feels like I walked into
the final scene of Miss Saigon.
We were worried about you,
hon. Yeah, you scared us.
Yeah, we... For a minute there,
we thought you were "Croaklahoma."
Oh, my...
- That's twisted, man.
- I love it.
You know, you also could
have gone with Oaklymphoma.
See, that's good. That's better.
Or A Little Night Mucus.
Fiddler on the Puke?
Does that work?
Ew. It's good. Why is it
"Ew"? Why is that "Ew"?
- Catch Me If You Cancer.
- Mmm. Strong.
The King and Eye Cancer.
Very specific.
Good one, Mike.
An actual musical.
Anything Ghosts is a pretty good one.
- "Anything Ghosts"!
Gurney Boys.
It's a good one.
That's a good one.
How about this?