After our honeymoon,
we'd like to start
treating people.
Are you
giving me notice?
Yes, ma'am.
Come on, Dean.
What's going on?
Is there anything
I can do?
You can keep it to yourself.
Justin Lieu.
I spent a decade doing
search and rescue before
deciding on med school.
I'm Liliana.
I clean your office.
Would you like
to have some coffee
with me?
How about now?
Are you having
an affair?
No. Never.
He thinks that
we need time apart.
And thanks
to Mr. Dayton's
generosity,
Chicago Med
is able to provide
a whole new level
of surgical intervention.
I know the tech.
I promise you,
it won't let you down.
You know tech,
but you don't
know surgery.
Jack Dayton has bought
controlling interest
in the Gaffney Medical Group.
So I guess
he's in charge now.
Man, I've been seeing
these 2.0 ads everywhere.
Kind of makes me wish
I needed surgery.
Yeah. These are
a lot of signs.
I guess there are worse things
than having Jack Dayton's
PR machine
in our corner,
though, right?
Hey, look.
As long as he
keeps us ahead
of the supply shortages,
I am not complaining.
You know what?
Come to think of it,
I saw a whole new shipment
of PPE came in.
Let me catch up
with you later.
Hey, Maggie.
Oh, hey, Sharon.
How you doing?
I'm okay.
You know,
Ben used to make me
breakfast every morning.
You two still
aren't talking, huh?
Uh-uh.
Well, I know
it must be hard
not having him around,
so I'm here if you ever
need to talk.
I know. Thank you.
Liliana.
Good morning, Daniel.
What a pleasant way
to start the day.
Thank you, though
I just finished my shift.
I am on my way out.
You know what
I've been thinking?
We've had a couple
of very pleasant
coffees together.
How about we,
I don't know,
advance to dinner?
Okay, sure.
You want to pick
the restaurant? Should I?
Better idea. Let me cook.
I'll make zrazy.
Zrazy. Fantastic.
What is that?
It's Polish dish.
It's my grandmother's recipe.
Okay.
So my apartment, 8:00?
Great.
I'll text you
my address.
I will see you there.
What have we got?
Martha Kittle,
75 years old.
Took a bad spill
in her kitchen.
Let's get you checked out,
Martha. I need an X-ray
in treatment five.
Grandma!
I hear you,
Alexander.
I'm coming, Grandma.
Where are they taking her?
Just into her room to
check her out. You can
go in with her if you want.
What's that?
That's an
X-ray machine.
Will it hurt her?
No, no.
That's just so
the doctor can help
your grandmother.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
His name's Alexander.
Looks to me like
he could be on
the autism spectrum.
He's having trouble
making sense of what's going
on with his grandmother.
Leave her alone!
Get away from her!
She's just trying
to get an X-ray.
Yeah, Alexander. It's okay.
I'm not going
to let you hurt her.
Alexander, how about
we get you a little space?
Would that be good?
Let's get you some space.
Thank you, Nancy.
Let's go home, Grandma.
Alexander, please stop.
Let's go home.
I need to be here.
And I need you
to calm down, please.
These are nice people.
They're trying
to help me.
I'm sorry.
I...
Aw, again?
Yeah.
Is Jack Dayton gonna have
fresh donuts for us every day?
I suppose these
aren't allowed
on your renal diet.
I'm sorry.
Don't be.
You're the one missing out
on my cranberry juice.
Woah, brand-new
espresso machine?
Yeah, a generous gift
bestowed upon us
by Jack Dayton.
Well, hopefully,
these upgrades extend
to patient care too.
Yeah, you keep telling
yourself that, pal.
Dean won't be swayed
by Dayton's new shiny
toys and sweets.
Don't tell me you don't
remember the story of
"Hansel and Gretel," right?
The witch
fattening them up?
You think Jack Dayton
wants to eat us?
Guy seems to have
a big appetite.
Dr. Lieu,
you're with me today.
Sure thing, Dr. Archer.
Dr. Archer, we've got
one coming down
from the helicopter pad.
Use Baghdad.
What do we got?
Brandon Thompson,
34-year-old male.
Restrained driver in MVC.
Intubated en route.
Five hundred
milliliters of fluid
in the field.
HR 120. BP stable,
130 over 82.
What happened?
Drove his car off road.
Barreled through the woods
until smashing into a tree.
All right,
on my count. Ready?
One, two, three.
All right.
Lungs are clear.
Bilateral breath sounds.
Okay.
Pupils are equal
and reactive.
Fast him.
No free fluid.
Put in an A-line
and blood gas.
Doris, I'm gonna need
a chest and pelvis X-ray
as well as a EKG
and a PanScan.
Got it.
Must have lost control
of the car. Wonder why.
Let's hope he can wake up
and tell us.
I'm sorry, we didn't get
a chance to introduce
ourselves before.
This is Dr. Cuevas.
I'm Dr. Charles.
Is now a good time?
Of course.
Go ahead, Alexander.
What do you say?
I'm sorry.
I was wrong.
I didn't know
what was happening.
Alexander, you know what?
This can be a very
confusing place.
You have absolutely nothing
to worry about, okay?
Are you gonna
fix Grandma?
We're gonna do
our very best.
Martha, I would like to go
over your X-rays with you.
Um...
Alexander, maybe you
could go get a snack?
There's some vending
machines in
the waiting room.
I can take you.
There's some money
in my purse.
Thanks for not sharing
anything in front
of Alexander.
It's hard for him knowing
I'm in pain.
Ms. Kittle, when you fell,
you suffered
an intertrochanteric fracture.
You broke your hip.
Perhaps more concerning,
you've got lytic lesions
on your bones
that are causing areas
of weakness.
That's probably
because of the cancer.
Stage 4 lymphoma.
It's metastasized
to my bones.
Very sorry to hear that.
It is what it is.
I've decided
not to treat it,
though I do take medication
for the pain.
The doctors say I might have
only a few more months.
Does Alexander know?
I'm struggling to find
the right way to tell him.
I understand.
Um...
Listen, Martha, you are
gonna need some surgery, okay?
But I want you to know that
we're gonna do everything
we can to make this workable
for Alexander.
Surgery?
You're gonna need
to have your hip pinned.
What's the recovery time
for that?
At least a month,
but likely longer.
An orthopedic surgeon
can give you a more
accurate estimate.
I'll page the ortho resident
on call to come down.
Don't, please. I can't go
through a surgery like that.
Who will take care
of Alexander?
There isn't another
family member who
might be able to help?
No, not since he was a baby.
It's always just been
the two of us.
Right. No friend
that he feels
comfortable with or...
You saw how he was earlier.
Blowups like that happen
at least once a day.
No one I know
would want to
take that on.
Then what we're gonna do
is we're gonna appoint
a short-term guardianship.
Alexander won't listen
to anyone but me. I'm the only
one who can calm him down.
So no surgery.
Grandma?
Look.
Can I have it?
Yes, but not before lunch.
Hi, Sophia.
I'm Dr. Halstead.
Are you her mom?
Her swim coach, Cindy.
Her dad should be
here soon. He lives
a few hours away.
Sophia goes
to St. Joseph Prep
here in the city.
The boarding school, right?
Mmm-hmm.
Okay. So what's
going on, Sophia?
I don't know honestly.
It was the weirdest thing.
Sophia and her teammates
were practicing their
individual medley races,
and right after Sophia
made her last flip turn,
she fell behind
all the others.
Then she stopped
swimming altogether.
I think I felt something
in my chest,
but then I passed out.
Okay if I give
a quick listen?
Oh,
it was terrifying.
I mean, she was just
floating there, face down.
One of the other
coaches helped me get
her out of the pool.
And she was unconscious
at first.
And then after a few seconds,
she came to, thank goodness.
Anything like this
ever happened before?
No, never.
Sophia is
a fantastic swimmer.
I broke the state record
for the 200-meter
breaststroke last year.
Wow, impressive.
All right, let's get
a chest X-ray, CBC,
CMP, EKG, and cardiac labs.
And why don't we get
Sophia a gown?
Hey, is this the hospital
Jack Dayton bought?
It is.
Any chance
I'll get to see him?
You're 16 and you keep up
with Jack Dayton?
When Jack Dayton was 16,
he'd already created the beta
version of what would become
SapphireCash.com.
You know
a lot about him?
Of course.
I'm a dev.
Dev?
Developer.
It's hard not to
look up to somebody
like Jack Dayton.
Unfortunately, I doubt
Jack will make
an appearance today.
He's a pretty
busy guy. Sorry.
But we'll get
these tests and figure out
what's going on.
Sound good?
Mmm-hmm.
Yeah.
I swear,
I would never wish
Crohn's disease
on my worst enemy.
The gastric tube
is definitely clogged.
You called it, Roy.
That's the fourth time
in the last three months.
Yeah. You flushing it out?
I've used warm water,
seltzer, soda,
everything short of Drano.
Okay, well, let's upsize
the tube a little bit.
Come on, Dr. Marcel.
It's a temporary solution.
There's got to be
something better than this
game of musical tubes.
Yeah, look, I get
that you're frustrated, Roy,
but we got to get you
nutrition somehow.
You don't understand.
I can't take this.
I need to eat something.
Look, sadly, that's not
possible anymore
because of your
esophageal strictures.
You won't be able
to get the food down.
What about
my surgical options?
I read online you can remove
and replace my esophagus.
Can we do something
like that?
Well, if I do that,
I'll need to replace it
by reconstructing
a new esophagus
from a part
of your stomach
or intestine.
But it's
a complicated procedure,
especially for you.
Look, you've had a lot
of surgeries over the years,
and all of that
resulting scar tissue
makes it very difficult
to find a piece
of intestine
that can work.
But you could try, right?
Too much can go wrong.
How much worse
can it be than this?
You worried
you might kill me?
I can't stand the idea
of having to keep
living like this.
I'm serious.
I don't know
how much longer
I could go on.
I hear you, Roy.
All right, well...
let me have a think
on it, okay?
Dr. Dupre, morning.
Can you input that for me?
Dr. Marcel, I couldn't
help but overhear
you discussing
what sounded to be
like an Ivor Lewis
operation
on a Crohn's patient
with a hostile abdomen.
Eavesdropping much?
Not intentionally.
Look, I would love
to offer 2.0 services
for the operation.
Thanks, but I told him
we're not gonna go
the surgical route.
Roy's Crohn's disease
and adhesions
from prior surgeries
make him a very high risk
and poor surgical candidate.
I think this is the perfect
case to take advantage
of 2.0's imaging.
If 2.0 is gonna
revolutionize surgery,
this is exactly
the kind of case
it should be used on.
You know, Roy's situation
is very precarious.
I'm not convinced
2.0 can make a difference.
I understand
your reservations,
but don't you think
it's worth exploring?
You must be Sophia's dad.
Glen Eastman.
I'm sorry I'm late.
I live out in Rochelle.
Got here as soon as I could.
I'm glad you made it.
I'm Dr. Halstead.
I have your lab results.
I'll step outside.
No, Coach, please stay.
You're basically
family, Cindy.
She's been a wonderful
influence in Sophia's life
over the past few years,
especially since I live
so far away.
Okay.
Well, the good news is
your labs and EKG
came back normal.
Any idea what did
cause this then?
Not yet, but I'd like to test
Sophia for something called
Brugada syndrome.
It's a very rare disorder
that causes arrhythmias
or irregular heartbeats,
especially if someone
who has it
overexerts themselves
like you did swimming today.
That sounds serious.
In the very worst cases,
it can cause the heart
to stop altogether.
But there are treatments
that will prevent that
from happening.
That's why I'd like
to do another EKG.
But this time, I'd like
to administer a medication
called procainamide
that will trigger
an irregular EKG result
if Sophia does in fact
have Brugada syndrome.
We've got to do it, right?
So we know either way.
All right, I'll have a nurse
get you set up right away.
Brandon's CT.
He's got a grade two
splenic crack
with no blush.
All right. What's your
recommendation?
Track his hemoglobins
over the next 24 hours.
As long as it
remains stable,
I don't see any need
for surgical intervention.
He also passed
a spontaneous
breathing test.
Good. Let's extubate.
Here you go.
Brandon, we're gonna
remove your endotracheal
tube now, okay?
All right, Brandon,
I'm just gonna loosen
the strap.
There you go.
Nice and easy.
Breathe.
Good job.
Is Tiffany okay?
Tiffany?
My wife. Did they bring
her here?
I don't understand.
Was she in the car?
Yes.
She's pregnant.
In labor.
Where is she?
Just spoke to the
local fire department
on the scene.
I'm afraid they didn't
find anyone else there.
What?
No, What are you saying?
Brandon, are you sure
you're not misremembering
what happened?
I'm not making this up.
She was sitting
right next to me.
I can prove it. Just...
Where's my phone?
Okay.
Look, this dot on the map
is her cell phone.
That's right by
Interstate 55.
That's where
I crashed, right?
Okay, I'll go back there
myself if I have to.
Brandon, you're in no shape
to leave the hospital.
We're gonna
get on top of this.
You just sit tight.
Please.
This is what
she looks like.
We'll do everything
we can to find her.
Doris, call the Illinois State
Police and the local
sheriff department.
Tell them we've pinned
a possible location.
I should go out there
to help them.
I have experience
in search and rescue.
Yeah, but there are
other people for that.
Look, back in Colorado,
hikers would go missing
all the time.
We would have a designated
incident commander
and experienced
hasty teams
at the ready
with helicopters and trucks
and commtech.
I'm not sure the local sheriff
has those kind of resources.
Maybe I can make up
for some of that.
Yeah, you're not
a helicopter.
But I do have 63 rescues
under my belt.
For Tiffany and her baby
to have the best chance
of survival,
I need to be out there.
I can bring
the hospital to her.
Dr. Asher.
Hmm?
What's up?
There's a pregnant woman
missing out in the woods
and Dr. Lieu here seems
to be convinced
that he needs to join
the search and rescue.
I want you to go with him.
She's reportedly
in labor, okay?
Sixty-three rescues, huh?
Make Tiffany number 64.
The stomach is just
too fibrotic and scarred
to manipulate
into an esophagus.
How about a colonic
interpositioning?
Can you use his colon?
There's too many strictures
throughout the bowel,
not to mention the extensive
adhesions we can't see
on the scans.
Look, I want this
to work. I do.
I hate that Roy
has to suffer this much,
but I'm not gonna open him up
and risk further damage
to his intestine
without a plan
in place, okay?
Perhaps a better angle
can help.
2.0, show us the digital twin
for patient Roy Tooley.
Loading.
Based on Roy's
charts and scans,
2.0 has created
this twin that is
anatomically identical.
Feel free to poke around
in there.
What do you mean?
I've enabled a function
with 2.0
that allows you to manipulate
the hologram using
the sensory gloves.
Here, try it.
Okay.
Here we go.
Area of bowel has previous
intestinal anastomosis.
Neat trick.
But it's just a hologram.
There's no telling how
Roy's body would respond
to any of this
in real life.
2.0 can simulate
the real-life responses
based on an extensive
database of previous
surgical input
while continuously
recalibrating
to incorporate Roy's
personal data as well.
Hmm.
Look, if you're worried
about that little hiccup
where 2.0 questioned
your suturing technique,
it won't happen again.
2.0 is here to assist,
not hinder.
Well, I guess there's no harm
in running a simulation.
Okay, we ready?
Okay, it all looks normal
so far, just like
the first time.
Push the procainamide.
So see the slope
that gradually descends
after each heartbeat?
I don't feel
any different.
You're not supposed to.
The medication
only changes
the EKG reading
if you have
Brugada syndrome.
So does this mean
Sophia has it?
I'm afraid so.
Yeah. A cardiologist will walk
you through it, but, Sophia,
you're going to need
an implantable cardioverter
defibrillator, an ICD.
What's that?
It's a device
that monitors
your heartbeats.
And if you were
to ever have another
heart-stopping arrhythmia,
it will deliver a very
small shock to your heart
to restore
regular rhythm.
It's a procedure
typically done
in a cath lab OR,
but after four to six weeks,
Sophia should be able
to resume
all normal activities,
including swimming.
Wait, you mean
I can't swim
at all until then?
You will need
to take a break.
Um, that's gonna be
a problem for regionals.
If Sophia doesn't compete
in the upcoming meet
in two weeks,
she'll be ineligible
for future events.
That means I won't be able
to compete at state.
Can't we put
this surgery off until later?
That makes me
a little nervous.
I agree. It's best to
take care of this right away.
Okay, we'll do it.
Dad.
Dr. Halstead is saying
your heart could stop beating.
You don't understand, Dad.
You're not around,
and you hardly come
to my meets.
If I don't compete at state,
that screws up my chances
of going out for the Olympics
a year from now.
I'm sorry, honey.
It's just too risky.
There'll be plenty more
opportunities for you
to compete in the future.
Yeah, I will have someone
from cardiology
come speak with you.
Well, thank you very much.
You've been really helpful.
Huh.
So that's the mayor's office
for people with disabilities
with a very
promising referral
for a short-term guardian
who has extensive experience
working with adults
with special needs.
Well, that's good.
Yeah.
Hopefully, Martha
will sign off on it.
We need some help in here.
Alexander!
Help him!
What's going on?
Okay, he's unresponsive,
and he's not breathing.
Oh, God.
His lips
are turning blue.
Pinpoint pupils.
Did he take something?
It looks like
he's overdosed.
Do something, please.
Narcan.
Alexander, are you
all right? You okay?
What happened?
You're okay, baby.
You're okay.
I don't feel good.
You're going to be fine.
Don't worry.
The car crashed
through this fence here.
The car then careened
into the woods
until an oak tree brought it
to a halt right about here.
There was no sign
of a passenger, so we went
ahead and had it towed.
Sheriff, I found these
about 100 yards due east.
Those are Tiffany's.
Brandon had the same picture
on his phone.
Deputy Russell,
this is Dr. Lieu
and Dr. Asher.
They treated the driver
at Chicago Med.
Bring over Brix.
Has Brix helped you out
on other search
and rescues before?
No, but he once found
12 kilos of blow buried
in a local trailer park.
Hopefully,
he'll be able to find
a pregnant woman in the woods.
Sheriff Parker, we'd like to
head out with the first team.
We can provided immediate
medical support.
Works for me.
First team, let's head out.
Let's go.
Let's grab our supplies.
Here?
Vascular pedicle
is too short.
This looks promising.
Left colon just past
the splenic flexure.
Tissue is extremely friable.
Many adhesions. Easy to tear.
Well, it seems 2.0 has already
assessed all my options.
So why don't we
just skip to the part
where it tells me what segment
of the bowel to pull up?
2.0, your recommendation?
Abort esophageal
reconstruction.
You're kidding me.
Place gastric tube
and commit to
liquid enteral nutrition.
Well, Roy's already
been doing all of that,
so what was the point
of any of this?
Hold on.
2.0, what is the prognosis
of an esophageal
reconstruction
with this patient?
48% chance of success.
Forty-eight percent?
Those are decent odds.
Why would 2.0
insist this will fail?
Well, 2.0
has a default setting.
Not to support
any surgical procedure
that has less than
a 50% chance of success.
But I am going to lower
that threshold.
You are good to go.
Okay.
Here we go.
Starting from square one, 2.0.
The left colon
has the best odds
of viability.
Yeah, I see it.
Looks pretty good.
Oh.
Yeah, that section
looks long enough.
Seems like it has adequate
blood flow.
I think this
could actually work.
Yeah.
Okay, well, let's do
a couple of practice rounds,
and then we can bring in
the real Roy.
Okay, from the top.
Let's go.
Alexander,
how are you doing?
Can I see Grandma now?
Very soon.
We want to keep you
on IV fluids,
that tube that's in your arm,
just a little while longer.
Make sure you feel better.
In the meantime,
we're hoping you
can help us
figure out exactly
what happened.
I think I fainted.
Any idea why that might
have happened?
Can you remember eating
anything different
than you normally do,
like anything at all?
No.
Think real hard,
Alexander.
We're here to help you.
I know.
Alexander, are you...
Are you a candy person?
Do you like candy?
Yes.
I'm just wondering
if there's any chance
you could have looked
in your grandma's purse
and seen red and blue pills
and thought that they
were candy maybe?
I don't eat anything
unless Grandma lets me.
I have to ask.
Like the soda this morning
from the vending machine?
Uh-huh.
She said I could.
She opened it for me.
I guess
it doesn't matter
what I think.
We're very sorry,
Mr. Eastman.
What's going on?
Sophia's refusing to stop
swimming competitively.
She's petitioned a judge
to issue a stay
on her ICD implantation.
Well, how is that possible?
Her father signed off,
and she's a minor.
She's filing
for emancipation.
What? She's gonna need
her father's consent, right?
Well, in most cases, yes.
But she's been living
independently
at her boarding school
these last few years
on a swimming scholarship,
so the court may grant her
emancipation regardless
of what her father wants.
She has a heart disorder,
and you're telling me
a judge is, what,
gonna let her ignore it?
It's out
of our hands now.
We're sorry.
Great. Yeah, okay.
As long
as we have
an automated external
defibrillator on standby,
you are okay
to compete.
That another doctor
you were talking to there?
A friend who's in contact
with the state's
competitive committee.
Sophia, you do realize
the more you exert yourself,
the higher the chances
this happens again?
Which is why we're looking
into precautionary measures
that don't
require surgery.
There aren't any.
I've trained
my whole life
for this,
and I'm not about to throw it
all away just because
I passed out once.
Sophia, if another
arrhythmia occurs,
you may not get the chance
to go to the Olympics.
Dr. Halstead.
You could die.
May I have a word?
Ms. Goodwin,
she's taking medical advice
from a swim coach.
You need to give
this girl some space.
I don't like it any more
than you do,
but it's time to step away.
Is Alexander okay?
He's gonna be.
But, you know,
Martha, there was, um,
a pretty significant amount
of opiates in his bloodstream.
And, you know,
it occurred to me
that given your stage 4
cancer pain,
it would be completely
understandable if you were
carrying around, you know,
just a lot of very strong
medicine with you
all the time, right?
And at first,
I thought that maybe...
I don't know,
maybe Alexander
was looking in your purse,
and I don't know,
he mistook the medicine
for candy
or something.
But then he told me pretty
explicitly that he never puts
anything in his mouth
without your permission.
So, Martha,
I have to ask you,
did you...
Did you put a bunch of pills
in his soda this morning?
I didn't know
what else to do.
When I got my diagnosis,
I thought if I could just
hold on a little longer,
maybe when he got
a bit older,
he could manage by himself.
But then I realized
that was never gonna happen.
You know, there are other
options, though.
Martha...
I've tried them.
I put Alexander
in different
group homes,
but he wouldn't eat,
wouldn't sleep.
He'd sob and bang
the ground with his fists
until they bled.
Every time,
it was a disaster.
So you thought
that he would...
He would be
better off dead?
I love Alexander more
than I've loved anybody.
But after I fell
this morning, I couldn't
stop thinking,
if I can't be there
for him, who will?
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
It looks like Brix
wants to cross.
Let's split up.
You guys cross.
Dr. Asher and I
will stay on this side,
move downstream.
Cover more
ground that way.
You got it.
So what was that about?
Brix has been trained
to detect drugs
and contraband.
It's not the same skillset
as searching for
a missing person.
I'm just not sure
it makes sense
for Tiffany to cross
the stream in her state.
All right,
see this twig here?
Yeah.
How it's broken
about waist level?
You think
Tiffany did that?
It's high off the ground.
Some human did.
Check this out.
Huh.
Looks like fresh
blood to me.
Could be Tiffany's.
Sheriff, this is
Dr. Lieu.
We've got blood droplets
just off the creek
in grid D5 on the map.
We're marking
it off now.
SHERIFF PARKER ON RADIO:
Copy that.
She's close.
Come on.
Okay, gonna take
the left colon just up to
the middle colic artery.
Tissue appears viable.
Adequate blood supply.
Okay, good.
I'm gonna resect.
GIA stapler.
Thank you.
Is something wrong?
Colon looks okay,
but the small bowel
looks much better.
It's got a good
vascular pedicle.
Appears more
freely mobile.
Might be better
for the reconstruction.
Small bowel interposition
is not recommended.
Why is that?
There's no dataset
to guide you.
I don't need a data set.
I just need a viable bowel.
Okay, but first,
let's remove
the esophagus.
Once you take
the esophagus out,
there's no turning back.
Scalpel, please.
Mr. Dayton, hi.
I'm Will Halstead,
one of the ED docs.
Sorry. Mr. Dayton's
on a very tight schedule.
I understand, but I have
a patient, a teenager,
who has a heart condition.
She needs a procedure,
and she's refusing
because it'll get in the way
of her competitive swimming.
But I think
you might be able
to change her mind.
Why would she listen to me?
She's into computers.
She idolizes you.
I wouldn't be
asking otherwise.
Mr. Dayton, you have to
be in San Francisco
by 8:00 p.m.
I've got a very
important meeting.
It can't be rescheduled.
All I'm asking for
is a few minutes.
Convincing Sophia
to get this procedure,
it could save her life.
I appreciate your concern
for your patient,
but I really do have
a plane to catch.
Why did you even buy
a hospital if you don't care
about the patients in it?
Excuse me?
You know, when you
took over Med,
I hoped it might have
something to do with
a desire to help people,
but clearly, that was
naive on my part.
We're nothing to you.
Just another
toy to play with.
Have a safe flight.
There.
Tiffany.
Hey, Tiffany.
We're doctors.
We're here to help you.
What's happening?
You were in
a car accident.
She's cold to the touch.
We're gonna put a tarp
under you, okay?
Here we go.
Lift up just a little.
Great job.
Okay, I'm gonna
remove your jacket
so we can put a warming
blanket on you.
Sheriff,
this is Dr. Lieu.
We've located Tiffany
in grid C7.
Track the orange markers,
and you'll find us.
SHERIFF PARKER ON RADIO:
Copy. On our way.
Tiffany, I'm gonna
examine you, okay?
Am I bleeding?
You're in labor.
She's disoriented.
Could be from the head lash
or from hypothermia.
Abdomen's hard
as a rock.
Most likely
placenta abruption.
Baby's not getting enough
blood or oxygen.
Heart rate 110,
BP 90 over 42.
Hand me
the fetal doppler.
Help me.
It's gonna be okay, Tiffany.
We're trying, okay?
Just hang on in there.
Baby's heart rate
is down to 80.
She's completely dilated.
All right.
Hang in there, Tiffany.
Tiffany, we're gonna
need to deliver
your baby right now.
So when I tell you,
you're gonna push as hard
as you can, okay?
Okay.
May we interrupt?
You okay, Grandma?
I will be.
How about you?
I feel...
I'm feeling better now.
When can we go home?
Alexander...
I can't go home.
You have to.
You live there.
I know,
but I'm very sick.
I'll help you
get better.
Oh, baby,
I wish you could,
but I'm the kind
of sick that never
gets better.
Then I'll stay here
with you.
You can't.
Why? Did I do
something wrong?
No. No, you didn't do
anything wrong.
This wasn't
your fault at all.
But I'm not able to care
for you anymore.
Alexander, we're gonna
help you find somebody
who can, okay?
You stay out of this.
Alexander, no.
Listen to me, please.
You need to trust
Dr. Charles.
He can help you
in ways that I can't.
But I want you,
Grandma.
Alexander,
you are so special
and deserve the very best
this world has to offer.
I just can't give that
to you anymore.
Someone else can.
And I'm going to need you
to let them.
Can you do that for me?
I love you, Grandma.
Baby, I love you so much.
I love you
with all my heart.
Okay, Tiffany,
we're gonna go again.
You ready? Push.
You got it.
You're doing
great, Tiffany.
Keep pushing.
You're doing great.
Come on.
I can't. I can't.
Yes, you can.
You're almost there.
I promise.
Here we go again.
Push.
Yes.
It's a girl.
You got
a little girl.
Well, Sophia,
your discharge
paperwork is complete.
You're free to go.
Sorry.
Hope this is
the right room.
You're Jack Dayton.
You must be Sophia.
Dr. Halstead here tells me
you're quite the swimmer.
She is.
She is also
a fan of yours.
Well, that's very kind
of you.
You know, one of the perks
of owning my own hospital
is getting to know
the patients.
So I thought I'd come by
and say hello.
Hi.
Now you love swimming,
but I also hear
that you have an interest
in computers, right?
Tell me about that.
Well, I'll leave you
all to talk.
What are you developing?
All right.
We'll take it from here.
Thank you.
Nice work out there.
Looks like Alexander
and his guardian are off
to a good start.
Yeah, well,
thank God
for that anyway.
Yeah.
I really do appreciate
you stepping in,
Mr. Dayton.
She's a smart girl,
Sophia.
Glad she changed her mind
about having the procedure.
Yeah, curious.
What did you say
to get through to her?
Oh.
Well, it turns out
we have a lot in common.
I told her how I used to be
a bit of an athlete myself.
Basketball was my thing.
But I also loved computers.
So when I messed up
my back, couldn't play
for a little bit,
I still had this
other passion. And, well,
it worked out well for me.
I think it gave her
a whole new perspective.
Okay, look, about
what I said earlier...
No one ever talks
to me like that.
I'd like to apologize.
Save it.
I can respect
a straight shooter,
especially one
so committed
to his patients.
Glad to know I have you
on my team, Dr. Halstead.
Now if you'll excuse me,
I have a plane to catch.
You know, if this week's
contrast study goes well
and shows
there are no leaks,
Roy will get to taste
food for the first time
in three months.
Man, he is gonna
be thrilled.
He has you to thank
for that.
No.
I had already given up
on this surgery.
If it hadn't been
for you insisting on 2.0,
I don't think
we'd be here
right now.
The AI is not perfect yet,
but it's evolving.
I hope I am too.
That's a beautiful family.
Yeah.
They're so lucky
they found their way
back to each other.
Maggie.
I mean,
first Vanessa left.
Now Ben is gone.
Oh, boy.
That zrazy is spectacular.
Granny knew
what the heck
she was doing.
She did.
I'm so glad
you enjoyed it.
Listen, Liliana,
I just want to apologize
if I've been
a little bit
glum tonight.
I had a brutal day,
and I happened...
You help people
with their problems
all day long.
Once in a while,
one or two of these
problems will follow
you home.
Yeah.
Ah, you are my guest.
You sit.
Okay. Thank you.