Q-101 time is 8:30
under partly cloudy skies.
We'll be back with the news on the
hour after this 30-minute music mix.
You realize you've been
in there for 20 minutes?
You miss me or
am I wasting water?
Both.
How much longer
are you gonna be?
Your shift doesn't
start for two hours.
Yeah. There's an
8:00 meeting near here.
You gonna go?
I was thinking about it.
Hello?
Something wrong?
Carter? What are you doing?
We really can't help
you anymore, sir.
I'm not a junkie. The stuff
just finds me, you know?
How convenient.
I need another
room for Mr. Hudlin.
He says Exam 3
is full of ectoplasm.
- Did you cut yourself shaving?
- What?
Ooh. Never mind. Lipstick.
- Dr. Carter...
- Mrs. Breeland, you need to stay in bed.
Otherwise, we might be
tempted to put somebody else in it.
Okay, I think
we're getting there.
Hardly. Board number two
is for the patients in the halls.
We have heat exhaustion...
barbecue-smoke inhalation,
and boils. All up for grabs.
- I love my job.
- No, you don't.
Why are you dressed like that
if you can't prescribe nothing?
Ah, the smell of fresh med
students in the morning.
God, what is it about
them? They all seem so...
- Gullible? Immature? Vapid?
- I was going to say sweet.
Bee sting in 1
is asking for you.
Have them start the orientation
manuals. I'll be with them soon.
- Carter, MVA, two minutes.
- But not to hold their breath.
Dr. Carter, so there's
a trauma coming in.
Yeah. Why don't you take the bee
sting in 1, the wrist fracture in 4...
and the burning rash in
2? Care to give me a hand?
- Help me!
- Why not?
- Hey! That's just been mopped, damn it!
You don't talk if you're
having a real seizure.
Remember that for next time.
- Ah, come on, man!
- Think it's always this crazy here?
- Probably.
They need to bring you
back to the VA hospital, sir.
- I don't understand.
- Your driver will explain.
You guys suck, you know that?
- Don't bother. We don't have any beds.
- So, what else is new?
- No, I'm serious. Try Mercy.
- They're refusing patients too.
- Then try Rush. We're filled.
- I've been bounced all over town...
with this guy. I'm out
of gas and so is he.
If I don't get him into a bed
his UTI's turning into urosepsis.
I got to make water!
Yo, doc!
- You are one sadistic bitch.
- Now give me your middle finger.
I would if I could. Any emergency
meetings get scheduled?
Just one, about this spate
of ER closures in the area.
I've advised the board that
preliminary figures show an increase...
in our patient
load by 34 percent.
- Who'd you take to La Scala's?
- Sorry?
Which board member's
ass are you kissing?
- Now the ring finger.
- Robert, I simply compiled a report.
- Nerve regeneration's a millimeter a week.
- I'm not kissing ass.
It's not my dominant hand.
In fact, I only agreed to take on
your responsibilities out of necessity.
I'll be in my office
in two weeks...
- and back in the OR in two months.
- I hope you are.
Thought about
upping your Vicodin?
Ibuprofen. I want
to stay clear-headed.
- That's enough for today.
- No, keep going.
Sorry, have another patient.
Don't get comfortable, Kerry.
- Is there anything else?
- Just your continued support.
Lizzy.
- Elizabeth, how are you doing?
- Fine.
Good. Well, uh, we'll
catch up downstairs.
- I heard rumors.
- All true, I'm afraid.
The one face I missed
seeing in Recovery.
I'm so sorry, Robert.
What, about my arm or
about not being there?
- How are you healing?
- Hurts like a son of a bitch.
You?
Any sensory function yet?
Nope.
It's a motorcycle accident.
I have to go. I'm sorry.
- Dr. Corday. How was London?
- Good.
Timed your trip right.
Missed the pox scare we had.
- So I hear.
- How's Ella?
- Fine.
- Is it nice to be back?
I'm off to the ER.
I'll let you know.
Okay. Well, good luck.
Bite me, panty smellers!
Ma'am, you need to calm down!
Die, you sucking pervert!
Dr. Corday, hi. We
need some Haldol here!
- You think that's necessary?
- Yes!
Doctor C, looking good.
Thanks, Malik. So, what's the
GCS on this motorcycle trauma?
- Sorry, I didn't do the ride.
- Oh. Well, have the X-ray tech...
come down for portables.
- You got it.
Hold the CT till we eyeball the patient.
- Hey, welcome back.
Thanks. So do you
know any of the specifics?
Sixteen-year-old girl, motorcycle
versus utility pole, no helmet.
Carter's bringing her in.
- What's a chick doing on a motorcycle?
- What's anyone doing on a motorcycle?
Have the rapid infuser primed
and ready, draw her up 100 of fent...
four of Ativan. Make sure the
airway drugs are out of the box.
- It's like you never left.
- Yeah.
Vital sign.
- We need some O-neg.
- She got a rhythm?
- P.E.A. to agonal before arrival.
- Decreased breath sounds.
Intubated for agonal resps.
Didn't know you were back.
When did she lose her pulse?
- Never had one.
- Everybody. On my count. One...
- Hold transfer and compressions!
- Asystole!
- Abdomen's distended. Pelvic instability.
Uh, suction on high.
I need a Yankauer.
That's easily two liters.
All right, amp of epi.
Don't bother.
Obvious C-spine fracture.
She's not even a
good organ donor now.
- Is her family here?
- Trying to locate them.
- We can talk to them...
- It's fine.
Just let me know
when they arrive.
If it'd be easier for you.
I could pull the trigger right now if I
wanted to. Because it's all right here.
Welcome back, Elizabeth.
Do you have time for a consult?
As it turns out, yes.
What's he have? Belly pain?
Only because he swallowed
a handful of nitroglycerin.
No sudden moves unless
you want me to blow!
Milo has right upper quadrant
tenderness with rebound.
I'm a human time bomb.
He needs to be cleared
before we move him upstairs.
- I could go off.
- He could get hypotensive.
Are you scared? I'd be scared.
No! Give him two
liters of saline...
- and monitor him for a few hours.
- Thank you.
Gallant hasn't turfed a
case to Psych all day.
- You wanted the consult.
- Dr. Lewis.
- Yeah?
- We're to capacity?
Every bed, every day since
Mission Hospital closed.
I thought it was
just St. Paul's.
No. It doesn't help
Weaver's been gone so much.
- She's gunning for Romano's job.
- It keeps her very busy.
- Dr. Lewis.
- Mr. Sprooner. Guess you're still itchy?
Yeah. But there's...
You need to give drugs a
chance to work and quit scratching.
I think the guy next to
me stopped breathing.
- Great!
- Got a gang shootout here.
Couple DOA's at the scene.
Another rig's coming behind me.
- Where was she hit?
- In the neck.
- BP's 100/76, pulse stable at 100.
- Through and through?
Saw one hole but it wasn't leaking air.
- You need a hand?
- Possible SCI.
- Where is he? Ricky?
- What's her name?
- Alma.
Hang in there, Alma. We're
gonna try to find him for you.
Set up a cross-table lateral of the neck.
- Carter.
Still got med students waiting.
Want me to jump on that?
Better idea. You talk to them.
So. Newbies, huh?
You don't wanna work here.
- Haleh, get that dead body out of here.
- And take it where?
- Someplace else.
- How much O2?
- Five liters by nasal cannula.
- You hurt anywhere else?
They shot him! Oh, please,
God, don't let him be hurt!
We're gonna find out for
you, but you gotta help us.
- Do you have pain anywhere else?
- I don't know. I can't tell.
- How about your legs?
- No. I can't feel them.
Gallant, need a hand here.
We're talking smithereens here!
Have you ever seen smithereens?
I'm on Psych rotation. I
really shouldn't be helping you.
- Haleh, this is a dead body.
- You ought to go to med school.
Can't take her to the morgue
yet. We're waiting on family.
Why am I not exploding?
No movement below the umbilicus.
What's wrong with me?
Why can't I feel anything?
You might have bruising
to your spinal cord.
I need 30 mgs per kilo of
methylprednisolone, IV bolus.
- Where the hell's X-ray?
- Behind you. Start with the chest.
- Please. I need Ricky.
- Stay with us, Alma.
Entry wound, left mid-sternocleidomastoid
with a large hematoma.
There's blood
behind the ear as well.
Be nice to hear
about that ultrasound.
Morrison's is dry. The
pericolic gutters look good.
- Bladder is...
- Shooting.
Wait! Wait. She's pregnant.
- What?
- Looks like about 11 weeks.
Fetal heart rate is 140. Baby
appears healthy and intact.
I need Ricky.
It's my arm, man.
It hurts like a...
Do something already!
BP's steady at 120. But he's
been like this the whole time.
Ricky, you need to calm down.
- Did you give him anything?
- Wouldn't hold still long enough.
Good breath sounds. Full
trauma panel, chest and AP pelvis.
He's a regular customer.
Through and through to the
right triceps. You were lucky.
Yeah? You should
see the other guys.
No fracture or deformity.
So, what? Just
go back and forth...
shooting each other
till all of you are dead?
- An eye for an eye, man.
- Yeah. Meanwhile his girl gets shot.
- They got Alma too?
- She was hit in the neck...
and it's pretty serious.
- Where you going, dog?
- Let me go!
- Calm down!
- I'm gonna kill those bitches!
You already did!
Repeat hemogram
and update tetanus.
Keep your hand there and don't
take it off until you get upstairs.
- Dr. Corday, when you have a chance?
- Be right there.
Make sure the blood bank sends
type-specific straight to the OR.
Have the anesthesiologist
call me with any questions.
- Are you the one...?
- A neurosurgeon will perform it.
He'll talk with you shortly.
- I'm sorry?
- Don't let me die.
You're one cold-hearted
bitch, you know that?
I don't have any damn
pity for you, whore!
I'm talking to you, pissface!
Don't you dare turn your back on
me, you stuck-up little ass-shaker!
Where the hell do
you think you're going?!
Pardon me. Coming through.
Watch your back, sweetie. Excuse me.
- Doc, I'm gonna miss the season...
- Keep your cup on.
I should have been off two
hours ago. You still here?
Can't leave till my patient
gets a bed. Them's the rules.
- Don't sound upset about it.
- Up to level 12.
Turn that off,
disturbs the patients.
- Frank, what'd I miss?
- County HHS needs to talk to you.
- Ditto, Human Resources.
- Anything from Dr. Romano?
He called half an hour
ago, an hour before that.
Somebody from Dr. Rydell's office
called to confirm your appointment...
Frank, 2 needs a janitor.
What the hell is this? Why is
Stella Willits still on the board?
I called to have her
admitted to Psych hours ago.
- I haven't evaluated her yet.
- Save yourself the trouble. She's nuts.
She's a frequent flyer with a
history of bogus medical complaints.
With all due respect, I'd
like to determine that myself.
The ER doesn't have time or
manpower to deal with hypochondriacs.
That's what you're for.
Get her off my board.
- It's part...
- I said, get rid of her.
Stubborn. Gotta give you that.
How are those medical
students coming?
Fine. I gave them
three volumes of Rosen.
ER. Carter, Urology on two.
Think you can come up with
something a bit more interactive?
Yeah. Sam Polivy's back with
a ureteral stone. P-O-L-I-V-Y.
Abby? Those labs
back on Melinda Harrell?
- Let me check.
- Hi, I'm Erin Harkins.
- I'm on the phone.
- You're busy. We get it.
Can we get an approximate
time orientation will begin? Doctor?
Don't tell me you're keeping
med students waiting.
- Check with Pratt.
- I'm checking with you.
Intractable pain
and hydronephrosis.
Dr. Carter?
I cannot admit him to Eight
West. There are no beds.
I'm Dr. Weaver, Chief of Emergency
Medicine. I will give you a brief tour...
of the ambulance bay, after which our
Chief Resident will give you his attention.
Because, as you'll learn, it's his
primary responsibility. Come on.
- Sorry. What was that?
- Demolition-site accident downtown.
- At least a dozen injuries.
- ETA?
- Now.
- I gotta call you back.
Paramedics can transport
using standing field protocols...
- We've got multiples.
- Wait here.
- Who's on first?
- Sick one. Frank Chambers.
Forty years old, severe chest
trauma when a walkway fell.
Wrecking-ball crane collapsed.
BP, 80 systolic, but headed the
wrong way. Tachy 120, denies LOC.
Crepitus on right
side. Page Surgery.
- Mr. Chambers, can you talk?
- Hurts too much.
He thought his ribs were broken.
- You are?
- His secretary.
Sustained a facial lac and
chest pain but refused treatment.
- You need to be examined.
- After.
He's decreased on the left.
Let's hear it.
I've heard it since
Michigan Avenue.
Ken Ambrose, 34, tib-fib
fracture with dislocation.
F.D. had to lift a
flower shop off his leg.
Not a shop. It's a kiosk!
Abdomen's soft, non-tender.
Vitals normal, tachy
at 120 with a liter in.
- Gave him ten of MS.
- Don't touch! It hurts!
Okay, uh, bear with us.
We'll give you something.
- Oh, God! I see a light.
- You're not dying. It's just your ankle.
Oh, God!
You're supposed to help me!
- Watch where you're going!
- You ran into me!
- Haleh? Where's the trauma?
Throw a rock, honey.
Blunt chest in 2.
You look wonderful, by the way.
- Eighty-five pounds and counting.
- Good for you.
- You cut your hair?
- Mm-hm.
- BP's falling, 70 systolic.
- Keep squeezing that bag.
- Where are we? CARTER:
Flail and crepitus. Needs a tube.
- Who has an angio cath?
- Right here. How can I help?
Given there's only one,
I don't see how you can.
- What is that? What are you doing?
- It's a tube to help him breathe.
He has a collapsed
lung, this will re-inflate it.
I need a thoracostomy tray.
All right, let's see how
much air he's got in here.
Oh, God!
That any better, Mr. Chambers?
Sats 88.
He's not talking anymore.
Why is he not talking?
Because he can't. Let's Betadine
the whole chest just in case.
- You need any help?
- Yes. With his wife. She's bleeding.
- I'm not his wife. CORDAY:
Then you shouldn't be here.
Where's the rapid infuser?
- Got it.
We need that blood.
Let's get her on a monitor. She refused
treatment for chest pain at the scene.
I'm Dr. Kovac. Come with me.
- No. Somebody needs to be with him.
- Okay, I'm in.
- Hook me up.
- Let us take care of him...
and Dr. Kovac will
take care of you.
Please.
What are you doing down there?
Lewis, what are you doing up
there? This guy's got no DP pulse.
It's called a trauma assessment.
Lungs clear, chest tones normal.
- Got the Doppler.
- Give it to me.
- Sweet Jesus!
- Explains no pulse.
Okay, let's get a CBC, chem seven,
dip a urine, chest and pelvis x-rays.
Chen, give me your hands.
- What are you doing?
- Hold tight.
Ken! Have you ever
been to Hawaii before?
- Uh-uh.
- Well, pretend that you're there now.
Pratt, wait!
I can't believe you!
I feel better. I
feel totally better!
I feel totally sick.
Why would you reduce an
ankle with no pain meds?
No pulse is no
blood is dead tissue.
In other words, I
just saved your foot.
Thank you. You're wonderful.
- Subclavian's in. Is that the film?
- Five hundred cc's are out the chest tube.
- He's holding his pressure.
- No pneumothorax.
Looks like a widened mediastinum
and loss of the AP window.
Hard to tell. The pulmonary
contusion is impressive.
One of us should
go with him to CT.
Not unless you're
ready to crack the chest.
Flail chest, pulmonary
contusions, and labile hypotension.
Could also be from
a splenic fracture.
Carter, I'd like an
aortagram. Better yet, a TEE.
The fact he's still alive
argues against aortic injury.
Page me with the result, okay?
- Elizabeth, I think
there's more to discuss.
Kerry, I'm a trauma surgeon. The last
time I checked, you weren't chief of staff.
Keep me apprised
of his condition.
- Okay, the last one.
- Can I go see him now?
No. We have to make sure you didn't
bruise your heart or damage your lungs.
They're not doing anything.
Probably just waiting
to go up to surgery.
I'm sure he's stable.
I told Mr. Chambers
we were 10 minutes late.
It's a trick I use to get
him to meetings on time.
- You don't call him by his first name?
- He's kind of formal.
How long have you
been working for him?
Two years. Six days a
week, 10 hours a day.
Probably spend more time
with him than his wife does.
They're really happy, though. I
mean, she's lucky to have him.
- He's a good man.
- Luka...
no fragments in the
x-ray. Ready to irrigate?
Yeah. Uh, put Polysporin on the wound.
- Mm-hm.
Where'd you get that one?
A lowlife stuck me in the
back with a switchblade.
An inch to the left and you
would have lost a kidney.
Guy that did it to me got
snuffed with a sawed-off.
Dude was bite-size.
That's funny?
- Whatever, bitch.
- Hey, watch your mouth.
Are you almost done, man?
Why? You in a
hurry to go to jail?
We can check on Alma. She's
probably in Recovery by now.
- That means she's okay, then?
- No. She could wind up paralyzed.
- Like, all over or just her legs?
- They're not sure yet.
Well, better if they just
killed her, you know?
An hour ago you
were ready for revenge.
Yeah, that was personal. It
was about my name, honor.
- But paralyzed? That blows.
- Just dress the wound with Adaptic.
- Hey, Luka.
- Huh?
- Piece of work, huh?
- Yeah.
And she's pregnant.
- Who?
- The girl. Says it's his baby.
You want to tell him?
No. Do you?
Not really.
Hi. I'm Michael
Gallant from Psychiatry.
Stella Willits from
Ohio. Nice shiner.
I understand you have quite
a few medical complaints.
- I'll need to ask you a few questions.
- Knock yourself out, hon.
Had any recent weight gain?
I've been thinking
about going on the Zone.
- How about dry skin?
- Like the Sahara. Here. Give me this.
"Intolerance to cold." Yes.
"Arthritis, sore muscles,
constipation." Yes, yes, and yes.
"Fatigue." Well, I have been
kind of low-energy lately.
You have some delayed relaxation
from the deep-tendon reflexes.
What about depression?
- Me?
- Yeah.
No, I'm glass-half-full, I'm
silver-lining girl. I'm an optimist.
Listen, I'll be back to finish.
Um...
I guess I do get a
little blue sometimes.
Get this gurney out of the way.
If you haven't talked to anyone, you
need to go back to the nurse in Triage.
Your food poisoning in Exam
4's been here for 11 hours...
- Waiting on a consult.
- From the Naked Chef? He ate bad shrimp.
- Can I get something for my skin?
- Yeah, sun block.
Can I talk about Stella Willits?
- If you're admitting her to Psych.
- She may have a reason...
Just got word on
Mr. Chambers. Aortic dissection.
I'm taking him up
to Surgery now...
- unless you have objections.
- Uh, no.
Would it be possible for
us to speak in private first?
- Of course.
- Dr. Weaver?
- Later.
- Yeah, but I need...
I wanted to talk to you
about what happened earlier.
Oh, for God's sake! Who
left a cadaver in here?
Sasha's a bit of a bad penny.
She keeps being moved while
they try to locate her family.
I don't mind if you don't mind.
I'm concerned that you might
be taking on too much too soon...
particularly in the
area of trauma.
Based on?
What I saw earlier. A pronounced
inability to work with others.
A lack of professional respect.
You're joking, right?
Look, it's stressful,
no question.
Copping an attitude
with me and my staff...
is not gonna make a
trauma go any easier.
Kerry, I saw a dissected aorta.
In fact, it only adds to the intense
pressure that we're all feeling.
Given my position, I didn't think it
necessary to seek your approval.
We all have our sensitivities.
Quite frankly, if anyone
has an attitude here, it's you.
- But we can't let them interfere...
- No!
It's you, with your insistence on being
kowtowed to at every bloody opportunity!
Oh, my God!
Excuse me.
I want some milk, I'm thirsty.
His landlord found him in his
apartment crying, hyperventilating.
- Apparently, his girlfriend left him.
- The term would be "mommy."
- What?
- Mommy.
Well, he appears to be an Aby.
You know, an adult baby?
It's a fetish in which the
baby is taken care of...
in every way by a
"mommy" or a "daddy."
You're familiar
with this condition?
It's not really a condition. It's
more like a form of relaxation.
- Are you kidding me?
- No, it says right here:
"Abies like to relinquish control,
get away from their stressful lives."
- Mr. Dwyer, what do you do for a living?
- Shoe sales.
A foot fetish too. This is an issue
for the Psych Department. No offense.
I am not so sure about that.
Mr. Dwyer, when's the last
time someone changed you?
This morning.
More than likely, he suffers from a
diaper rash, which is a medical ailment...
to be treated by the ER.
- When are you done with this rotation?
- Next week.
Remind me to give you
some serious scut work.
"To Dr. Pratt, thanks from a
grateful patient. Ken, the kiosk man."
Amazing.
Too bad this guy didn't
run a hot-dog stand.
I'm here for allergies. These
things are pushing me over the edge.
Can you get rid of them?
Or give them to someone
a little more deserving.
Hey, hey. Who saved
flower boy's foot...
and moved more patients
than anybody today?
Me, that's who. You're gonna
miss me too, because I'm out of here.
- Banker's hours, Pratt?
- Only if they work doubles.
Hey, Carter. What's
up with your boss?
Is it true she was,
uh, crying earlier?
- Weaver?
- Yeah. Bad breakup or something?
- Been pretty moody lately.
- Lately?
I'm sorry! I think this man
needs immediate attention!
- You gotta help my pops!
- What happened?
They came in the
ambulance entrance.
- I saw he was diaphoretic.
- Not asking you.
We were playing ball.
He grabbed his chest.
- When did the pain start?
- An hour ago.
- Thought it would go away!
- You have pain anywhere else?
- Scale of 1-10, how's your pain?
- Forty.
- How you feel?
- Talk to the elephant on my chest.
- It could...
- Excuse me. You mind?
- What are your names?
- I'm Pete and he's Derek.
Can you take Pete and Derek
to the TV room. One, Pratt!
Okay, here. Come on.
Is there any way that we can
wait in the doctors' lounge?
As soon as you're a doctor.
- Tombstones in two, three and F.
- Better with the spray under your tongue?
No. What do you
mean by "tombstones?"
It's a non-medical way of describing
the line tracings on an EKG.
It's not good news, Mr. Royston. It
looks like you're having a heart attack.
- Aspirin?
- Already gave him 80.
Push five of Metoprolol, titrate
morphine, start heparin and nitro drips.
- Call Cards and cath lab.
- What's going on? What's he gonna do?
There's a blocked vessel.
We open it with a
balloon to stop your attack.
We need your permission.
It's called angioplasty.
- Sign for me.
- Cath lab will be ready in 30 minutes.
- He's a hot MI.
- They're finishing a pacer.
While they're messing
around, he's killing heart cells.
It'll give us time to medicate.
- V-tach.
Like I said. CARTER:
Charge paddles to 200.
- No pulse. Starting compressions.
- Abby, open an intubation tray.
Let's get Cardiology
in here! And, clear.
The doctors there
will give you antibiotics.
Make sure to get that
wound checked in two days.
- Right.
- So he's good to go?
- Later, I guess.
- She's pregnant.
- Who?
- Your girlfriend.
I told you, man,
she's not my girlfriend!
Well, whoever she is to
you, she's carrying your baby.
- Why don't you care?
- Why do you?
Three-sixty again. Clear.
- Still fib.
- Resuming compressions.
- Is this my consult?
- Acute inferior MI.
Refractory V-fib despite
lidocaine and procainamide.
Want to go TNK?
Isn't gonna make
it to the cath lab.
I've been pounding on him.
He'll bleed out with thrombolytics.
- Who's talking?
- Pratt, first-year Resident.
Then shut up.
CPR as a contra-indication
to thrombolytics...
has been debunked. It's a myth.
- Forty of Tenecteplase, IV push.
- Charging to 360, and clear.
A boatload from Lake Michigan
just came with alcohol poisoning.
- Kids?
- Worse. Parents.
The 10-year-old was the
only one sober enough to dock.
Do you think it's too late
to go into Dermatology?
- Excuse me, doctor?
- Yes?
I had a message that said my
daughter was in a motorcycle accident.
Her name is Sasha,
Sasha Huffner.
Uh, yeah. Yeah. I'll
check on her for you.
- Thanks.
- Wait right there.
Susan, did you order
a urine tox screen...?
Check my orders.
Elizabeth?
This guy with the
ringworm, he's...
Can you hang on a
second? Elizabeth.
And an abdominal CT with
contrast and two grams of cefotetan.
- Can we talk?
- I'm on my way to the OR...
with a bowel
obstruction, if it can wait.
Sasha Huffner's father's here.
- Your first patient, the DOA.
- Right, right.
Look, if you want, I
can tell him for you.
Why would I want that?
You're on your way to surgery.
- It's depressing.
- What's his name?
- Paul. He's standing over...
- I'll find him.
Hold compressions.
- Fine V-fib. PRATT:
Resuming compressions.
How long has it been?
Forty-two minutes.
Okay, that's it. Call
it. You can stop now.
Time of death is 7:11.
- Wife here?
- She's on her way.
- You should still wait.
- Can't lie to them now.
Want to turn off that monitor?
- Whoa! He's in V-tach.
- What?
I can shock that.
They pronounced him.
Yeah, well, now he's got a
good rhythm. Two hundred. Clear.
Yeah. Still V-tach.
That's enough, Pratt.
- Bag him. Do it!
- No! He's dead!
Three hundred. Clear.
Oh, my God.
Sinus tach. I said, bag him.
We did everything that we could.
We had three doctors
working on him for over an hour.
We gave him medicine and we shocked
his heart, but it didn't do any good.
- Why not?
- Because his heart was very, very sick.
And it was too sick to save.
I shouldn't have
made him play ball.
- I mean, he said he was tired.
- No, no. It's not your fault.
It's not your fault. Your dad had
a problem nobody knew about.
Not you, not your
mom, and not even him.
You gave him the best possible chance
he had by getting him to the hospital.
He can't be dead.
I'm sorry, Pete, he is dead.
And it's very sad. And
it's very unexpected.
And it's okay to cry. It's just a sign
of how much you loved your dad.
Do you guys want to see him?
You can say goodbye?
Yeah.
Okay.
You need to know your dad's gonna
have a lot of tubes attached to him.
And it might be a little scary.
- It's okay.
- Ready?
Keep the lidocaine at
two milligrams per minute...
and page the CCU team.
- What are you doing?
- I got him back.
What the hell's going on?
BP's 90 palp. He's back.
- He's alive?
- He's not dead.
Daddy's alive!
- Mr. Huffner?
- Yes.
I'm Dr. Corday. I'm a
surgeon here at County...
and I was your daughter's
physician this morning.
Did you operate on
her? Is she all right?
I mean, where is she?
Can I see her?
I'm afraid your daughter
died this morning.
She came in essentially DOA
with massive internal injuries...
from a motorcycle accident.
My God.
Someone can take
you to see the body.
We've kept it in the
department for your benefit.
And afterwards you can make
arrangements with the morgue.
A nurse can give you
information about grief counseling.
She's my little
baby. Is she gone?
I'm sorry.
Nobody walks out of a
hospital after 40 minutes of CPR.
There was improvement.
From V-fib to V-tach.
He's either dead
or should be dead.
Which means your Resident
is cruel, stupid, or both!
He saw a shockable rhythm
in the setting of thrombolytics.
It could take 30 minutes for
TNK to open the coronary artery.
- Are you defending this?
- He made a split-second decision.
He was acting in the
interest of his patient.
Well, he was wrong. And now we have
a vegetable with a pulse on our hands.
Well, our names are
on the chart, not yours.
Dr. Pratt and I will take full
responsibility for any negative outcome.
Oh, you bet your ass you will.
Hey, I just want to say thanks
for backing me up like that.
A Chief Resident...
and a cardiologist with more
than 25 years of experience...
pronounce a man dead.
And you decide to resurrect him.
- Yes. But just like you said...
- Think I defended you because I like you?
Or I approve of the way
you practice medicine?
You are my responsibility.
You are my job.
And I'm doing mine.
If you wanted to shock,
you could have paged me.
I could have been here in a second
and we could have discussed it.
Instead, you go off!
Without regard for authority or
the best interest of your patient.
Now, that's not true.
The guy's got kids. He's got a
wife. I was trying to save him...
You brought the man back,
Pratt, because you felt like it!
Because you wanted
to see if you could.
Why's he still sleeping?
He didn't get enough
oxygen to the brain.
So we have to wait
and see if he wakes up.
You know, there's a
chance he might not.
Why's that?
He's just taking a nap is all.
Pete, your dad's
still pretty sick.
Yeah.
But you saved his life.
Hey, you guys hungry?
Come on. Let's go down to the cafeteria.
I'll get you something to eat. All right?
I'll take you where
the doctors eat.
My daddy doesn't like
doctors, but I bet he'd like you.
You tired?
There's gotta be a better word
for it. Enervated, asthenic, atonic?
- Pooped?
- Bingo.
Does that mean you
want to stay home tonight?
Not necessarily.
Anything particular
come to mind?
You keep working that spot,
I'll do whatever you want.
You know, I do need my
sock drawer organized.
Can you help me? They told
me my husband was back here.
He had a heart attack.
Mrs. Royston?
Even though we got
his heart beating again...
the neurologic tests showed that
there's a lack of basic brain function.
- What that means is that...
- I know what it means.
How long can he last like this?
Indefinitely.
Did your husband
leave any instructions?
Did he ever
express his wishes...
about what should be
done in a situation like this?
He's 42 years old.
Then I need to ask you, if
his heart stops beating again...
do you want heroic measures
taken to save his life?
Or do you want to sign a
Do Not Resuscitate order?
Is that the right thing to do?
I can't make that
decision for you.
Is it the right thing to do?
Yes.
I want to thank
you, Dr. Gallant.
There's no need,
Mrs. Teasley. No need.
I just get, I don't know,
panicky in public places.
You know, that's why you need
to keep taking your Klonopin.
- Well, I hope I wasn't too much trouble.
- Oh, not at all. Not at all.
Gallant.
You want to explain
why Stella's still here?
- I'm waiting on some lab work.
- Who said you could order labs?
- No one. I thought...
- You're here...
to assess psychiatric problems,
not do a medical workup.
I realize that. I think
she is really sick.
You looking for these? - What?
- Her TSH level is over a hundred.
- Stella?
Well, she's hypothyroid, which explains
all of her symptoms. Depression, fatigue...
But not the fact that she's a
con artist and a hypochondriac.
Until your rotation is over, you
are not a member of this ER.
Stop doing our work, start doing
the work of your current department.
- Yes, ma'am.
- But good catch. You off soon?
In a few minutes, yeah.
Do me a favor. Discharge Stella before you
leave. I feel like crap. I'm going home.
Yeah. We sent the
labs out this morning.
- She's been here for 24 hours...
- Something's wrong with my dad!
Hey, Pratt! Can you get in here?
Mama, what's wrong?
Mrs. Royston, did
you sign the DNR?
You gotta help my dad.
He's in arrest.
Mrs. Royston, did
you sign the DNR?
What's a DNR?
It means that your dad is too
sick for us to try to help him.
- Why can't she?
- Because he's already gone, baby.
No, he's not! No, he's
not. He saved him.
- He said he was gonna be okay.
- Derek, we tried.
- Why are you letting him die?
- Baby, please...
You gotta help. Mama, tell
them to do something, please.
Why are you doing this?
Asystole.
Why?
Daddy?
Rominger's not an appy.
Twenty-five, male, periumbilical to the
lower right quadrant. He's a poster boy.
You can bring him
back in 12 hours.
Oh, Dr. Lewis asked that you
take a look at the cholecystitis.
Page the next shift.
- Do you want to take a call from Neuro?
- If it's urgent.
- You forgot to sign off.
- Oh.
So, uh, how are you feeling?
It's about the GSW you
handled earlier. Alma Salazar.
I'm fine.
- You wanted to know her status.
- What is it? You gonna tell me?
She's a quad.
Hey.
Hi.
Oh. You're not
gonna wake him up?
- No.
- Didn't you two come in together?
Yeah. I'm sure he can find
his way home without me.
- You need a lift then?
- No, thanks.
Have a good night.
Oh, man.
Oh, man! I don't know.
This is the craziest movie!
Hey, yo. What's all this?
Pay-per-view. Want some pizza?
Yo, Biz. Let me talk to you for a minute.
- Yo, I'm watching a movie, man.
If I gotta come there, I'm
gonna smack fire at you.
Come here, man! Let
me talk to you for a minute.
Come on, man! Hurry
up! Come here, man.
What's your problem?
I thought I told you, man,
don't come here again!
Stay away from him!
You understand that?
- Yo, I'm saying, now you his mama, yo?
- What?
Yo, man, chill out!
- You hear what I'm saying?
- Why you tripping?
Don't play with me, man.
All right, that's it! The
party's over! Everybody out!
Come on, man, get up!
You too, get up! All y'all!
Get up and get out!
Yo, my man, are you stupid?
- Come on. Come on.
- What you doing, G?
Get out. Close the
door behind you.
What's wrong, G? Yo,
I'll holler at y'all later?
All right.
- Those are my friends, G!
- Yeah? Well, this is my house.
It's mine too.
Oh, yeah? Oh, what? You pay
rent? Come on. Watch out, man.
No. Does that mean I
can't have no friends?
Just be quiet. I'm tired.
Yeah. You tired, all
right. Grouchy too.
Yo.
You know those guys are
just using you, right? Hm?
Yo, dog.
How they blow up a whole town
like that without killing anybody?
They don't.
And if you shot the gun that close,
he'd blow his eardrums out too.
Yo, G. It's just a movie, man.
You ain't got to take it so seriously.
Yeah, whatever.
But she's hot, though.
Most definitely. You right about
that, G. Yo, you still want some pizza?
Uh.
Hey, Sleeping Beauty.
- How long have I been in there?
- Since before my shift started.
Is Abby here?
Nope. But she
left you a Post-it.
And you still have a med
student waiting for you.
Hey.
Look, I'm sorry. The day
just kind of got away from me.
- Why don't we try again tomorrow?
- No. No, I don't think so. No.
I have been here for 16
hours. I have been ignored...
and yelled at, and called "honey,"
and "sweetie," and "bitch" twice.
I don't smell good. And all I've had
to eat is gummi bears and Diet Coke.
I'm not leaving until
I get what I came for.
This is the Admit area.
This is the center of the ER universe,
where you pick up your patients' charts...
order labs, spend the bulk of
your life for the next three months.
- How do you know who's next?
- You check that chart rack.
We see people in
the order they arrive...
unless the nurse feels
they're of high acuity.
- Then they're moved ahead.
- Do you get to suture?
If you're supervised
by an Attending...