Oh, my God!
Shaun!
You're masturbating.
I thought you left.
I could catch the next bus
if you would like
to have sex now.
No... No, thank you.
But you were...
I'm good, and it's late.
Okay.
Oh, my God.
Mariel Torres, 31, fever,
BP 124 over 83.
Fainted coming
off a plane at SFO.
Fiance said she's had
a persistent cough,
pain in her chest
and abdomen.
How long has she had
these symptoms?
Months, on and off.
I kept telling her
to go to a doctor.
Soft and non-tender,
no distention
or guarding present.
Uh...Isaac, what's...
what's happening?
Ms. Torres, I'm Dr. Lim.
You're at
St. Bonaventure Hospital.
You collapsed
at the airport.
I'm... I'm not covered.
My insurance lapsed.
We can fast-track
your access
to St. Bonaventure's
uninsured program.
Any recent stressors?
I've been traveling a lot
for work.
Deep breath, please.
She's a photographer.
She documents immigrant
communities across California.
I tagged along
this last trip.
He keeps me sane.
Rales and rhonchi, decreased
breath sounds bilaterally.
We need a chest X-ray.
Hey.
We got this.
You and me.
What do you do for work?
Uh, I am one
of the research professors
of the Jane Austen project
at Stanford.
I imagine you sit a lot?
Well, it would be unethical
to read a first edition
of Sense and Sensibility
standing up.
That explains why you're
in so much pain.
You have
severe hemorrhoids.
Well... Can you give me
a salve or something?
This is...beyond salve.
They seem like
a cool couple.
They seem fine.
Torres imaging
come through yet?
Not yet.
Supportive,
fun, loving,
but not in a gross,
performative way.
You picked up a lot
in two minutes.
Sounds like someone
wants a boyfriend.
I have been considering
venturing out of Hookuptown
for something more serious,
which requires finding
someone to get serious about.
That does tend to be
the hard part.
Well, that's why I've decided
to raise the bar,
only date guys
that check all the boxes.
So, your plan
is to be more open
by being more closed?
The images are in.
I want to be
more intentional about it,
find someone who gets me,
but also challenges me.
Instead of getting diverted
by whoever has
the hottest profile pic.
Two nodules
in the left lung,
one in the upper lobe,
one lower.
That doesn't look like
pneumonia.
That looks like cancer.
Hi.
So, about this morning,
when you came home
and caught me, you know...
Boosting my own morale...
I used to boost my own morale
a lot before we got together.
But I don't anymore
because we usually have
very satisfying sex.
Yes, we do.
Absolutely, we do.
Did you need a boost
because we haven't had sex
in nine days?
I didn't know
we were counting.
Our average
is every 2.3 days.
It has been
a stressful few months.
If you wanted
a morale boost,
why didn't you want me
to do it for you?
No, it's... it's not that.
I-I just... I don't know.
I woke up
and had a few minutes
and wanted
to take the edge off.
Is it...the same
as when we're together?
No.
It's...different.
It's definitely not as good,
but it is...faster.
Oh, I can go faster.
No, Shaun.
Boosting my own morale
is not a substitute
for being with you, ever.
And I did try
to get things going
a couple times
last week,
but you were busy.
You didn't ring
the cowbell.
It wasn't
cowbell worthy.
We agreed
if we were off course,
we'd ring the cowbell.
We are not off course.
We're having a dry spell,
and it will blow over.
That is a lot
of weather terms.
I'm not sure they apply.
Yeah.
Anorectal ailments are one
of the oldest recorded
medical conditions.
One early remedy
was to burn them off
with hot coals.
We can remove
yours surgically,
but we need to
do it right away.
Isn't there some way we could
schedule it for next week?
Your hemorrhoids
have already ruptured.
You're at risk
of serious complications.
Oh.
The surgery is now routine
and effective.
No hot coals.
But the recovery
can be quite painful.
You'll need a special diet
and sitz baths.
No exercise or exertion,
including sex,
for six to eight weeks
post-op.
No sex? Why?
The wounds need time
to heal.
We can get you on the schedule
for later today.
The X-rays show two nodules
in your left lung,
possibly cancerous.
We'll know more
after the biopsy.
It's a simple procedure.
Um, the... the biopsy...
Is covered
under the uninsured program?
It all is.
And we'll run a few labs
and get you started on fluids.
Is this arm okay for the IV?
Mm-hmm.
Listen, Mari,
I was on the phone
with your insurance.
What? W-Why?
To save you the hassle.
Sorry,
I need you to hold still.Oh. Sorry.
You... You shouldn't
have called them.
Why not?
We need to get this
sorted out.
Mari, whatever is going on,
you can tell me.
Um...
My insurance didn't lapse.
I, uh...I lost it.
Because, um...
I'm undocumented.
Brenna?
W-Where is our patient?
She's not in the bathroom,
and her clothes and personal
belongings are all gone.
Code green.
We have a runner.
I checked the whole
second floor. No Brenna.
She's not in the cafeteria
or the lobby or the gift shop.
We should check
all the exits.
Lea and I haven't had sex
for nine days.
Lenore,
the gift-shop cashier,
she recommended
light bondage.
Dr. Park suggested
a romantic bubble bath,
but Lea and I don't agree
on water temperature.
You both are busy.
Have you tried
scheduling it?
Reliability is sexy.
I think we found her.
All right,
time for your biopsy.
I'll have her back
in about an hour or so.
I should drop the bags off
at the apartment.
Isaac, can we please
talk about this
before I go
into my procedure?
We've been together
two years.
I was gonna tell you.
When?
The wedding?
I promised myself that
if marriage
were ever on the table
for real,
that I'd tell you,
but when you proposed,
my DACA renewal
had just been rejected.
And it really
freaked me out.
It was, uh...
It was all because of a stupid
marijuana DUI on my record.
Another thing
you've been hiding.
It was years ago.
Cops pulled me over
for a tail light.
They searched
and they found edibles,
and they arrested me
for driving high,
which I wasn't.
Okay, let's get her
some humidified oxygen.
I was...
I was trying
to get it expunged.
Breathe into this.
I'm gonna go.
I can get rid of that
for you.
There's blood in her sputum.
You're bleeding
from your lungs and airway.
Let's get to the O.R.,
stat.
I'm sorry I ran.
I know I need surgery.
You're scared.
I understand.
No, it's not just that.
I have this date
that I've been waiting
a really long time for.
And a rain check
poses a problem?
I am...
A virgin.
I am 45 years old
and I have never had sex.
Because of your religion?
Honestly, I don't know.
I mean,
freshman year in college,
I-I made
this really detailed list
of what I wanted
in a boyfriend,
and then I fell madly in love
with my work.
For a while, I thought
I wasn't having sex
because I was obsessed
with Jane Austen.
It's commonly believed
that she was a virgin
when she died.
She was obsessed
with her work, too.
I n--
I never stopped looking.
But every year
that I waited,
it just got harder
to imagine telling someone
I'd met a couple times
over coffee or drinks
that I...
had never had sex.
I just...
I just felt so ashamed.
You have nothing
to be ashamed of.
Well, okay.
Tell me about this date.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
Okay. Um...
His name is Viktor.
He's an old friend
from college.
Glaciologist.
Oh.Yeah.
And he's usually in Antarctica
or the Arctic Circle,
but he's visiting San Jose
for two days.
I was so scared to ask.
I thought
he would laugh at me.
But he just said
he would be honored.
You've waited a long time.
I have.
And if I don't do it now,
then w-what if I never...
I'm not having the surgery
until I have sex with Viktor.
Lea and I haven't had sex
in nine days.
Okay.
Um...
nine days isn't a thing.
It is something.
You said you and Debbie
had a very good sex life.
I would like to know
all your secrets.
I said that?
Okay. Okay.
Okay. Uh...
I got to test drive
a Testarossa once,
a Ferrari, an '86.
Oh, my God.
Beautiful car.
Got my friend to get us
a track at Thunderhill.
I get into the car...
Leather interior,
stunning detail.
I mean,
this car is ready.
And I kick it into gear,
and it stalls.
I kick it into gear again,
and it stalls again.
It's jerking back and forth.
I'm destroying
this $200,000 machine.
Why? Because the pedals
are too close together.
I'm...
I'm stepping on the brake
and the accelerator
at the same time.
Are you saying
that a Ferrari
will not cure my dry spell
with Lea?
No.
I'm trying to explain
this sex book
that Debbie gave me
called Come As You Are.
See, uh,
according to the book,
people think of it
as a sex drive, you know,
and that's too simple.
There's also a brake
and an accelerator.
Dr. Glassman? The new
nursing schedule is a mess.
Hawks and I have some ideas
to make it better,
if you have time today?Okay, I think...
I think
Dr. Andrews is your guy.
If I could get time
on his calendar, I'd ask him.
Fine. Um, if he doesn't get
back to you in a week,
then come back to me.
Uh...
Accelerating is
all the things that rev...
...the engine.
Oh.
All right. Listening,
chocolates,
listening a lot.
And braking is everything
that... that gets
in the way of good...
You know, sex.
Stress and work
and insecurities
and jealousy and stress.
Yes?
Sorry to interrupt, but we are
having major crackage problems
with the BioGlass pipettes.
Isn't that
a President thing?
I have had issues
talking to him after
the last couple months.
I'll send you an e-mail,
fill you in on all the issues.
I look forward to that.
Car.
Do you do
regular maintenance?
Are you, you know, talking
and communicating and...
Oh, talking, texting.
But mostly about work.
Okay.
So, maybe
a little bit less braking,
a little bit
more accelerating.
You know,
when you get home tonight,
leave your work
at the door.
Go inside,
put on some music,
light some candles,
not too many.
You don't want to make
an announcement.
How many?
Nine.
And no weather channel.
Okay.
I...will try.
I have to get back
to work.
Okay.
Got a minute?
There's the bleeder.
Cauterizing.
This nodule's
caused a lot of damage.
It's too bad she didn't feel
safe coming to a hospital.
Mm. One of my aunts
was undocumented.
She never let
her guard down.
With anyone.
Inserting mini-forceps
into the tract.
But hiding it
from your fiance?
Doesn't exactly bode well.
Ah, you're really ready
to judge this relationship,
aren't you?
First, they're "supportive,
fun, and loving,"
now it's built on betrayal.
There's the nodule.
Advance a little further.
Then we can take the sample.
Which suggests that you
might be lacking experience
with long-term
relationships.
The one thing they never are
is simple.
The capsule's tough
for a pulmonary nodule.
The inside's friable,
crumbly.
That's not cancer.
It's fungus.
And we just released it
into her bloodstream.
What if we just let her
go home to see Viktor?
It's one night.
Dr. Allen,
she has grade four
internal
and external hemorrhoids,
which have
already ruptured.
If it happens again
while she's home,
she's at risk
for severe blood loss.
I should tell her
about my first time.
I vowed
that under no circumstances,
I would be a virgin
when I went to college.
Senior prom,
my high school boyfriend and I
finally decided to take
that last big step past...
"Heavy petting."
Afterwards,
all I could think was,
"I preferred the petting."
Mm, no second time
without a first time.
Let's bring Viktor here.
Afterwards,
we'll do the surgery,
and if she has a rupture,
there's no safer place to be
than in a hospital.
The hospital has rules
against alcohol,
illegal drugs,
patients running in socks,
but there is nothing
about consensual sex.
It's an illness
commonly known
as Valley Fever.
It's endemic to soil
in the Southwest.
Our immediate concern is,
the fungus is now
in your bloodstream.
If an infection takes root
in your brain or spine,
that could be fatal.
We're gonna treat you
with an anti-fungal
called amphotericin B.
It can be pretty intense.
The side effects
include nausea,
violent chills,
high fever, convulsions.
Has Isaac been back?
Um, we haven't seen him.
We'll do what we can to
alleviate any discomfort.
Get the infusion ready.
Yeah?
You're appointment only
now?
It's fine.
I had to establish
boundaries,
at least until the hospital's
on firmer financial ground.
Huh.
There's a whole lot
of broken glass in the lab.
Is that a metaphor?
Yeah, and there's a whole lot
of broken glass in the lab.
It's a supplier issue.
Apparently news to you?
My assistant also
filters requests
before they hit my desk.
Allows me to focus
on the bigger
post-Ethicure adjustments.
Huh.Now, is there a reason
for this...delightful,
if unscheduled visit,
because...
St. Bon's
needs a softball team.
There's a hospital league.
$650 covers a roster of 16.
The team
covers bats and gloves.
It'll be good for morale.
You know,
I heard something
about you playing softball
in Montana.
What was your average?
.394 and trending up.
Hm.
Fine. The hospital can cover
registration fee and uniforms.
Gloves and bats
are on you.
Next time,
make an appointment.
Dr. Wolke?
Sorry to interrupt.
I'm just swiping left again.
Please, interrupt.
I saw Ms. Torres
is going on ampho-B.
Can we get her fiance back
so she has
some emotional support?
Uh, we tried.
He's not responding.
Pretty lousy time
to ghost.
Maybe, but I get it.
You "get" taking off
when someone needs you?
She lied to him for years.
She hid things,
for pretty clear reasons.
It's still
a violation of trust.
That can take a while
to get over.
Give him some time.Great empathy for him.
Meanwhile, your patient
is about to be
in a lot of pain,
and you're judging her.
I'm treating her.
It is not my place to do
couples therapy. Or yours.
If you don't have compassion
for her, Dr. Wolke,
then maybe someone else
should handle her care.
And you can go back to
polishing your Tinder profile.
I have to hang her meds.
You went all out.
Mm-hmm.
You didn't have
to bring those.
I stole them
from the chapel.
Oh.God works
in mysterious ways.
Are you in any pain?
No.
Lying here, I'm totally fine.
It only hurts
when I walk around,
but what about tomorrow,
when Viktor's...here?
I got you covered.
Tylenol,
a little Lidocaine cream.
Should do the trick.
You know, my mom had
the sex talk with me
when I was
in the fifth grade.
She showed me
The Joy of Sex,
you know, that book
from the '70s.
Lots of...hair.
And, uh, when I asked her
to explain the pictures,
she got really awkward
and then started to cry.
That's not
very sex-positive.
Well, she said she was upset
because I was so young
and I was asking
all these questions.
I just ended up
rubbing her back
and making her a cup of tea.
Oh.
After wanting this for so many
years, why am I so scared?
Being intimate with someone
feels vulnerable,
no matter how many times
you've done it.
That's why it's special.
It will be an adventure...
Your adventure,
on your terms.
Have fun,
tell him what you want,
and lube is your friend.
Oh, my God.
It's all about
setting the mood.
♪♪ Close your eyes,
Little Queenie
♪♪ Go to sleep soon
♪♪ I'll be dreaming
in a hurry ♪♪
Tonight, there will be
no brakes.
Oh.
Only accelerators.
Including wine.
Oh, my God.
And...
A relaxing massage.
I've researched
the best massages on YouTube
and have been practicing...
On a pillow.
Okay.
Yes.
♪♪ Any time you're scared ♪♪
Mmm...
♪♪ There ain't nothin' wrong ♪♪
Mm,
you havebeen practicing.
You are much better
than a pillow.
Mm.
How's your back now?
Much better.
Would you like
a chocolate?
Mm. Mm-hmm.
♪♪ I love you
♪♪ My Baby Blue
♪♪ My Suzie Q ♪♪
♪♪ I love you
♪♪ My Baby Blue
♪♪ My Suzie Q
♪♪ I love you ♪♪
You took these?
Mm. On my last trip,
Imperial Valley.
They're beautiful.
So...relaxed.
Just a bunch of friends
hanging out.
Yeah.
There are so many images
out there of the, uh, plight
of the undocumented,
like we're just
some sad story.
I wanted to show
how we really are...
Cracking jokes,
laughing,
a bunch of badasses.
Oh, not that I feel that way
at the moment.
Oh!
I can call Isaac again.
Don't bother.
If he doesn't see
how scary this all is,
if he can't support me,
then I don't want him here.
When I was in high school,
I had a chavrusa...
A study partner.
I totally fell for him.
His close textual readings
were super sexy.
We grew up Hasidic.
Micah was the first person
I told about being gay...
And my first kiss.
He said he was gay, too.
That according
to two verses in Samuel,
so were
King David and Jonathan.
Like I said,
close textual readings.
Next level.
Micah said
we should be open.
We should
tell our families.
I was scared, but I did,
And my dad...
...lost it.
Our home
just...imploded.
But Micah backed out.
He said
he couldn't do it.
I lost my family
and never spoke
to Micah again.
He cut you off?
I cut himoff.
He reached out to me,
but I... I was so angry.
He betrayed me and...
Broke my heart.
And then I realized
how terrified
he must have been, too.
And how...
Alone he must feel now.
I miss him.
O2 falling.
Is this from the ampho-B?
No.
EKG steady.It's not her heart.
The area around
the nodule ruptured.
Your lung has collapsed.
We need to get her to the O.R.
Completing
final muscular suture.
Lung is
reinflating nicely.
Let's finish
closing her up.
Dr. Lim? Who's talking to me?
This is Nurse Martel.
Her renal panel
just came back.
How bad?
B.U.N. 30, creatinine 4.
Thanks
for letting us know.
It's impacting
both her kidneys.
We need to get that nodule
out of there.
Now?No.
There's still too much fungus
circulating in her blood.
She needs around round
of ampho-B
to clear as much fungus
as we can.
Then we can do
the kidney surgery.
Are you Viktor?
Brenna showed me
your picture.
I'm Dr. Allen.Pleased to meet you.
Perhaps you could point me
toward the gift shop?
I wanted to get something
for Brenna.
What kind of a date
shows up empty-handed?
Most of them.
I am Dr. Shaun Murphy.
Give her these.
Chocolate contains tryptophan
and Phenylethylamine,
which will help to elevate
your moods.
Oh, they are very good.
Okay, please get started.
As soon as you are done,
we can do the procedure.
Oh, uh, I owe it to Brenna
not to rush.
Definitely worth the wait.
You're here.
Uh, bearing
slightly used chocolates.
Uh, Dr. Murphy says they...
they will improve our mood,
w-which
I hope won't be necessary.
Always the gentleman.
Are you sure
this isn't too strange?
Uh, well, making love
in a hospital is strange.
And surprising
and... and completely unique.
Exciting.
I'll be outside,
guarding the door.
Try not to be too loud.
Yo.
See you on the field.
I gave you your team.
My involvement ends there.
You're a baller, right?
You played in college.
Yeah, I also ate instant ramen
for breakfast.
I need a shortstop,
a field general,
a boss of the infield.
You're perfect.
I'm busy being
the actual boss.
You're busy
being a bad boss.
You isolate yourself
from your own staff.
They don't like you.
Especially since
this business with Salen.
I've got bridges to build.
I'll get there eventually.
I'm offering you a bridge
to build right now.
Show them
you're on their team.
Maybe they'll help you
right the ship.
I know.
Mixed metaphor.
And by the way,
maybe they'll stop
bothering me
with their problems
every five minutes.
Let's have sex.
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Shaun! Oh, my God!
I'm so sorry!
Okay.
Are you okay?
Spontaneity
is not the solution.
No.
Sorry.
Okay.
Maybe we could try
more of a...
planned surprise next time.
That is a good idea.
We should have
a sex schedule.
Jordan recommended it.
Did you mention
my morale boosting?
N-No.
Lea,
that is very personal.
Yeah. Yeah, it is.
The...
The sex schedule... sorry...
It just feels like
the ultimate buzzkill.
Okay.
Lou the janitor mentioned
something called a sex swing,
but the installation
sounds very cumbersome.
Even allowing for foreplay,
Viktor should be finished.
Uh...
God.
This feels worse
than the last time.
The nausea, the pain...
We have to clear
as much fungus from your blood
as possible
before surgery.
I got your message.
Thanks for coming back.
You lied to me.
I don't know
what's going on anymore.
Or what to trust.
Of course you don't.
I didn't give you
a chance.
I didn't trust you,
and I should have.
You don't have
to forgive me,
but I-I hope you...
You understand...
...why I hid from you.
Seriously, I thought
they'd be done by now.
This is
Dr. Shaun Murphy.
Help.
Mm.
Um...
What happened?
Well, um, we finished...
Both of us.
Yay.
Um, but we...
Um...he's...I-I-I seem to be stuck.
Oh, you must have
vaginismus.
What?
Your pelvic floor
is having a muscle spasm,
and it's holding...Oh!
Shaun.
It's very rare in humans,
but it is common
in mammals who need
to ensure fertilization.
Once your pelvic walls
relax,
everything should go
back to normal.
Oh, my God.
I am so sorry.
You came to do me a favor,
and now we're literally stuck.No, stop, stop,
stop, stop, stop.
This is a beautiful choice
you made.
And now that I know that
we're gonna be okay, uh...
It's actually quite nice.
Yes, it is.
That was...
Lovely.
Mm.
I owe you an apology.
It's okay.
The ice packs
are really helping.
Not that.
I'm sorry
for brushing you off.
You've been trying to get us
out of this dry spell,
and I've done nothing.
About the sex schedule...
My parents used
to have one.
They used to mark
our kitchen calendar
with "S.T."
They claimed it was
for "Steak Tonight,"
but we didn't have steak
that often.
We finally realized it stood
for... "Sexy Time."
Oh.
I-I don't want my sex life
to be like my parents'.
But they have been married
for 42 years.
Yeah, they have.
They seem happy.
I think it is nice that they
still want
to touch each other.
I need to go remove
some hemorrhoids.
We removed the nodule,
and your kidney function
is improving.
A few rounds of ampho-B
to go, but we think
you're in the clear.
Thank you, Dr. Park.
We'll get through this.
All of it.
And I won't freak out again.
I'll step up.
I'm sorry.
Sorry it took me so long.
You and me?
Yeah. You and me.
How did I do?
The surgery was a success.
And as long as you follow
the recovery protocols,
you should have
no further problems.
Look who I found
in the gift shop.
I wanted to see
how you were doing,
and, uh, give you these.
Aww.
And ask
if you might be open
to another visit next month.
There's a polar microbes
conference in San Francisco
that I, uh,
was considering attending.
I'd love that.
Cafeteria closed
while you were in the O.R.,
so I sat a couple
of meal trays aside.
Oh, my God.
I'm starving.
Thank you.
And...
Thanks for the push.
We've got grilled salmon.
Can be a little dry,
although Ms. Shenoy in 314
seems to like it.
Mm.Penne pesto.
Sounds promising, I know,
but lower your expectations.
Oh.And finally,
the humble-but-classic
grilled chicken.
Mm.
Even my 5-year-old niece
loves it,
and she's got the palate
of a 5-year-old.
I would have gone
with the pesto.
I could tell.
I'm sold.
Hit me
with that chicken.
You got it.
Unless we head over
to Tres Reyes,
upgrade
to insanely good tamales.
Are you...asking me out?
In, like, a date-y way?
Looks like it.
Wait.
You're gay?
Nothing gets by you, huh?
An upgrade to insanely good
tamales sounds perfect.
All right, Reznick!
Way to battle.Aw!
Park, you're up!
Allen on deck.
I got some intel.
First up is a fastball,
followed by a change-up.
Yeah, that's
because he doesn't
have anything else, man.
His curve ball's a disaster.Good to know.
All right. You got this.Dilallo, in the hole.
Oh. It's 7:45.Yeah.
Sorry. Gotta go.
What do you mean,
you gotta go?
You're... You're
the cleanup hitter.
We are on a schedule.
Go, Park!
Oh!
Strike!Ah!
Oh, that's a ball!
That was high!
0-1!
Nice turn on
that double play last inning.
Thanks.
If only you could handle
our schedule
with the same skill.
1 and 1.
You got some ideas?
Actually, yeah.
I'm listening.
Oh!
Go, Park! Yeah!
Good job, man!
Park!
It just feels
a little weird.
Like we're on the clock,
you know?
I would offer you a chocolate
to help you relax,
but I gave them away
to Viktor.
Who's Viktor?
A very nice Arctic explorer
who came to the hospital
to have sex
with my patient.
Oh.
How full service.
It was remarkable.
His penis got stuck
in my patient's vagina.
No, it didn't.
Oh, yes, it did.
No.
It did.
Come here.
Oh.