Oh, boy. Hold on one second.
I got lost here yesterday.
I love puzzles.
Since I was a kid.
Nope, your present
hasn't come yet.
What is this present?
You keep saying I'll
know it when I see it.
When am I gonna see it?
Yes, Mom, I am still at work.
I've got all the last guy's
caseload, plus the new patients.
There's almost no
time for research.
Yes, I've made friends.
"What are their names," Mom?
My record for the Friday
New York Times crossword
is 11 minutes, when I was 13.
I'm still trying to beat that.
Why do I need to make friends?
I'm here to run a department.
Okay, that sounds braggy.
I just mean once
I pick a puzzle up,
I can't put it down
until it's solved.
No, I haven't talked to her yet.
I don't think I'm going to.
I've gotten by just
fine without a sister.
I don't need one now.
At least not this one.
I was curious. I
picked up the rock.
I saw what was underneath
it. I'm gonna put the rock back.
It was stupid to have
picked it up in the first place.
No, I'm just saying I don't need
answers about my birth mom.
I have a family. I have the
best family I could ask for.
I have you guys.
Dad. Dad, stop crying.
I'm not coming home.
Mom. Tell him I'm
not coming home.
Guys, I love you. I got to go.
I think puzzles are why
I went into medicine.
That's most of what medicine is.
Gather all available
information...
How long has she been
down? Less than a minute.
She brady'd, and then
she went into asystole.
We started CPR.
Assess the problem...
That's not gonna do it. Let me.
You focus your attention...
Shoot, I'm gonna break her ribs.
Sorry, Marjorie. Hold on.
V-fib. Paddles,
please. Charge to 100.
Charged. Clear.
Charge to 200.
Charging. Clear.
And you solve the puzzle.
Thank you. Thank you.
People are a harder puzzle.
There's never one right answer.
Oh. No, thanks. I'm going down.
Me, too.
And you never have
all of the information.
I mean down the stairs.
You know, heart health.
You both work here. You
can't keep avoiding her.
I came here to work.
That's what I'm gonna do.
When I have to work
with Dr. Grey, I will.
I don't think that's
all you came here for.
Look, can we go back to
before I opened my mouth
about my personal problems?
And we can just
be work colleagues.
Can we do that, please?
Number 32 down is "cornpone."
Took me forever.
When are you gonna
talk to Lebackes?
Not till I'm sure I have
my old job back. Dr. Willis?
I thought this board
appointment was a done deal.
But now that I have to
compete for it... Dr. Willis.
I think Lebackes
will understand.
I just have to find
the right moment.
Dr. Willis.
I think she's talking to you.
Oh. Hi!
I think you're with me
today. You ready for rounds?
Yes. Sorry, but it's
Wilson, not Willis.
Oh, God. I'm so sorry.
That's okay.
Wilson. What's first?
Jo. Josephine.
Not your name.
What patient is first?
Right. Uh, Dr. Bailey
needs a consult.
Dr. Bailey.
This is Robbie McCutcheon, 22,
no medical history
or cardiac risk factors.
Robbie is currently
trying to pass
a pretty impressive
kidney stone.
Hi, Robbie. I'm Dr. Pierce.
You hang in there, Robbie.
He's scheduled for a
percutaneous nephrolithotomy
to remove the stone. Too
big to pass on his own?
I had a child once.
I'd rather have four more
than do what he's trying to do.
Hang in there, Robbie.
Robbie's been having fairly
sustained runs of V-tach.
Dr. Bailey ordered a
cardiac panel and a stat EKG.
Robbie, is the pain
just in your stomach,
or does your chest hurt, too?
Chest.
Get me 80 milligrams IV
Sotalol and 6 of morphine.
Robbie, I'm going to need
you to take some deep breaths.
It hurts. I know.
Bundle branch block
re-entrant V-tach.
He's at risk for
sudden cardiac death?
Breathe, Robbie.
Just relax.
Good.
Okay, you got a
normal sinus rhythm.
He's at risk for
even minor surgery.
You'll have to postpone
until I can do a full work-up.
He'll need an echo. Who's next?
Rita, Eric.
All settled in?
Getting there.
Hit it, Milton.
Wilson.
God. I'm Sorry.
Rita Choudry, 35,
33 weeks pregnant,
admitted for low
sats and bed rest.
Forever.
Really? I have to be here
until this baby comes out?
Yes, you do. Tell me why.
Rita suffers from
Ebstein's malformation.
Which is?
A congenital malformation
of the tricuspid valve.
Excuse me, Dr. Pierce. Do
you mind if we play through?
Absolutely. You have
a patient here, too.
Baby Girl Choudry,
EDD six weeks.
She suffers from
double inlet left ventricle,
which will require immediate
heart surgery when she's born
and fetal monitoring until then,
which is why we've
admitted her mom.
And also because...
I know. I know.
Because the strain
of childbirth might
cause my crappy
heart to poop out.
I just need to be sure
you know the risks.
And the risks are having
this baby could kill me.
Please stop saying it.
I've heard it, and I refuse
to believe it, right, hon?
Yep.
Well, get settled, relax.
You'll be seeing
way too much of us.
Her chances are that bad?
There's a good possibility
she'll die trying to have this baby.
She was strongly
advised against it.
Then why take the case?
Because she decided
to have it anyway.
And I like my chances
better than hers.
That sounds braggy.
No, it sounds badass.
What's next?
Marjorie Reed, 88, stage IV
small cell cancer of the lung
with mets to the liver.
Marjorie, how you doing now?
She says her stomach hurts,
but I think she's doing
better, thanks to you.
Thank you again.
Mom! I'm gonna go get some tea!
I'll be right back, okay?
You gave us a big
scare this morning.
No more of that, okay?
That happens
again, I want to die.
Oh, please, please, let me die.
Marjorie, do you
know where you are?
Do you know... You think...
You ask me if I'm
out of my mind?
I wouldn't say...
Yes.
I've lived 88 years, 65
of them with my husband.
More with him than without.
We taught English
in Japan for a while.
Looks like here, Japan.
So green.
We taught English.
Did I say that?
Yes, you did. Oh.
Now I live in this ugly room
with these ugly machines, alone.
But hurting constantly.
Those drugs you give
me made me forget.
I'm forgetting my life.
It was beautiful, my life.
I earned a better end than this.
There are forms you can sign.
Oh.
Jeannie won't let me.
She'd never forgive herself if
she didn't do everything she could.
Bless her heart,
but she's scared.
Always has been.
Where she gets
it, I have no idea.
And am I out of my mind? No.
When it's my time, I should
get to die remembering my life.
Shouldn't I?
I don't understand. Can't
we override the daughter?
She has power of attorney,
and the mother won't do it.
And unless she has a signed DNR,
we are legally required to do...
To do everything
we can to save her.
Even though I almost killed
her this morning trying to do it.
Then talk to the daughter.
It's trickier than that.
She's better, right?
She seems better.
Jeannie, I'm afraid she's not.
Your mother's
cancer has progressed
beyond what we can
hope to treat or cure.
But she survived
this morning and...
She is in incredible pain,
and the process of
resuscitation is so hard on her.
If it happens again...
What? What is she saying?
I'm afraid it's only a matter of time
now, and your mother deserves...
Is she saying I
should let her die?
No! You're her doctor.
You do whatever you
have to do to keep her alive,
to save her, right?
You're her doctors, right?
Of course.
You don't speak to a
patient unless I tell you to,
is that understood?
I was just trying to help...
You don't counsel a patient's
family on patient care, understood?
I got it. Now you've
made that woman think
that we are pushing
for her mother to die.
I got it. I'm sorry.
Okay.
I just had to bring the thunder.
Bring the thunder?
When you seem really
nice or young or pretty,
sometimes people
don't take you seriously.
You have to help them
understand who they're dealing with.
You have to bring the thunder.
If you don't do
this, you should.
You're really
pretty. What's next?
Robbie McCutcheon's
cardiac echo came back.
Well, that sucks. What sucks?
Robbie has dilated
cardiomyopathy.
Should get cardiac anesthesia
involved before you operate.
Oh, hang in there.
We're gonna have
to before that boy
tries to push a pencil
eraser through his pin hole.
If you don't mind, I'd like to send
out for Robbie's full exome panel.
Just out of curiosity.
You want to know if his
cardiomyopathy is genetic?
It's a little project
I'm working on.
I can run it for you.
You have a genome lab here?
We did. The board just voted...
We do, and I still
have a set of keys.
And if the board has
a problem with that,
you have them come talk to me,
and I'll tell them what hole
they can push that through!
Was she bringing the thunder
or did we just piss her off?
Dr. Bailey doesn't
need to bring anything.
She is the thunder. Oh.
The board just voted to
shut down her genome lab,
then they promised
her a seat on the board,
but she's probably gonna
lose it to another surgeon.
Wow. Rightfully pissed.
Well, there's two
sides to every...
What's next?
Uh, Rita Choudry's
complaining of back pain.
Who is Dr. Karev?
Why?
He's paging me for a consult.
Oh. That's the guy that's
gonna take Bailey's board seat.
You saw me talking
to him this morning.
He's in private practice,
but he's gonna be
appointed to the board,
so he'll be coming back.
Okay. First Rita,
then Dr. Karev.
I don't know. I've had
a lot of lower back pain
throughout this whole
pregnancy, but this is different.
It's high in the
center and it burns.
All right, Rita. Dr...
Wilson.
Sorry. It's weird.
I'm really good with names.
Really?
Dr. Wilson is gonna
take you for a CT.
Okay? Is there something wrong?
Not necessarily.
Back pain can
mean a lot of things.
Could just mean you're pregnant.
This kid's had persistent
hypoxia and occasional PVCs.
Could you check
his cardiac function?
We'll just take a look.
Who are you?
How is it you and
I haven't met yet?
I've been here
less than a month.
Maggie Pierce,
new head of cardio.
Well, don't be afraid
to dance, Maggie.
Oh, I'm not afraid.
I'm just not going to.
People are great here,
really fun. Right, Karev?
Karev worked here. I know.
And I hear congratulations
are in order. The board?
What's that? - Nothing.
I said I hear
congratulations are in order!
No. OLIVER: For what?
I hear you've been
appointed to our board.
Well, that's not
really... It's...
Stop the music.
Something you want to tell me?
Was that...
I was gonna talk to
you at the right time.
Are you quitting my practice?
No, I've just been offered a...
I might be.
I chose you!
I selected you to have the keys
to the premier imperforate-anus
practice in the nation,
and you take another
job behind my back?
I was gonna talk... You
are not quitting my practice.
I am firing you
from my practice.
I'm not seeing any
cardiac abnormalities, so...
And I am gonna tell your tale of
disloyalty far and wide, my friend.
I will make sure that
everybody knows
that you're as deceitful
as you are stupid.
I'm just gonna go.
Watson.
That is not my name.
You were indiscrete and
stupid, and you are off my service.
Wait, what?
Karev's your boyfriend, right?
I've been...
Yeah, he is. I could tell.
But you just met me and
apparently felt it appropriate
to casually share
confidential information
about your boyfriend's career
and then fail to tell
me it was confidential,
so I just used it
to make small talk.
And now I don't ever
need to learn your name
because you are off my service.
Is this you bringing
more thunder?
No, no. No, this
is me being pissed.
Because I can't trust you.
Go swap with a
resident I can trust.
And you just got
your boyfriend fired.
Dr. Pierce, did
you ask for all of
Dr. Yang's chart on
the McNeil family?
Yes. I did link McNeil's
transplant the day Yang left.
I know. I just wondered
why you needed access
to the rest of the family's.
I mean, three kids in one
family with cardiomyopathy?
It just bugged me why
no one found out why.
It bugged us, too.
Dr. Yang ran every imaginable
test, including a full exome panel.
Now, you really think you could
find something that she didn't?
Do you think that's impossible?
I think in most cases,
this disease is idiopathic,
and its cause remains a mystery.
I think the McNeils have
been through a year of hell.
Unless you have
something new to tell them,
they're gonna build up
their hopes for nothing.
I think we should leave
them alone to heal.
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
Hi.
Hello. Hello.
- Who are you?
- Zola, sweetie.
Zola, sweetie.
Come on over here.
Come and sit down right here.
Dr. Pierce, right?
Dr. Shepherd. Nice to meet you.
Hi. You've met Dr. Grey.
Yes. Hi. We've met.
Who is this?
This is our daughter, Zola.
Oh. Hi, Zola. I'm Maggie.
Oh.
I hear you're going
to run the new
brain-mapping
initiative at the NIH.
That's very exciting.
Uh... I'm not.
I'm sorry. I was misinformed.
I'm really killing it today.
We have two children.
Their lives are here.
Being away from my family
is... It's untenable for me.
I totally understand.
My family's back in Boston.
It's very hard being away.
Isn't that gonna get cold?
Would you like to join us?
I'm gonna... I have
to talk to Dr. Webber.
Nice to meet you both.
This big secret is
why you ended up
at a meeting in the first place.
Look, I...
May I join you?
Um...
Amelia Shepherd, do you
know Dr. Maggie Pierce?
Weird, you're the second
Dr. Shepherd I've met today.
Derek is my brother.
I'm sorry. Is everyone in
this room somehow related?
I'm gonna leave you two
alone. Nice meeting you.
Meredith Grey has
an adopted daughter.
Uh... I know this.
Well, I didn't.
Zola came to them as a patient
through the African exchange program.
Spina bifida. And
they adopted her.
Oh, my God, just stop.
I'm sorry?
It's easier when she's
just a rude bitchy person
I don't care to know,
but she keeps getting...
She adopted a beautiful,
surgically needy African orphan.
It's annoying.
Should I talk to her? What
do you think? Honestly.
I think she's more
than you bargained for.
But I think when the world gives
you more than you bargain for,
you usually end
up glad you got it.
You're staring.
Isn't it funny?
She adopts a kid, her
mother gives one up.
You have no idea what
the story was there?
I never knew anything about it.
I do know this.
Based on what I
know about Ellis,
leaving you would have been
the most difficult decision of her life.
How well did you know her?
Dr. Pierce, bad news.
You're off my service.
I know. Just look, though.
Oh, God. Let me find
Dr. Robbins. I'll go talk to them.
Okay.
The fellowship committee
wants an answer tonight?
Sorry, Dr. Robbins?
One minute, okay?
Listen, I'm surprised that
you're surprised by this.
I mean, it's a natural
extension of what I already do.
I'm surprised because
it came out of the blue.
No, I thought about it for a while.
I mean, I need something new.
We're having another
kid. That's not new?
This is different. It has
nothing to do with that.
It does, though.
I have research.
With you at work and
then the fellowship,
how do we have time
for a new baby? How?
You know what? I
haven't said yes yet.
But you're going to.
Listen to me. I haven't
made up my mind.
Oh. See, I thought you had. I
thought we were having a kid.
I'm sorry.
About what? I wasn't listening.
You're nice and full of crap.
How's it going? Not good.
You're having an
aortic dissection.
There's a tear in the
inner wall of your aorta
that causes blood to
force the vessel apart.
Oh, God, I knew it.
What about the baby? ARIZONA:
The baby needs to come out.
An OB will do an
emergency C-section,
and then Dr. Pierce
will repair the dissection.
But isn't she too little?
Can she handle the surgery?
We don't have a choice.
If I don't operate, you'll die.
Just make sure
that my baby is...
Rita, please! Please stop
talking about the baby!
I told you not to do this! Eric!
I knew something
like this would happen!
Step outside. Please.
I'm gonna call up and let
them know we're coming.
Okay?
Edwards, Whitton,
get her ready to move.
I know this is scary,
but it's happening.
And the only thing she needs
right now is your support.
I can't do it anymore. I can't
support her killing herself!
She doesn't want
to lose a child.
We already lost our child.
Five years ago.
Madeleine. She was two.
They were walking
down the sidewalk.
Maddie wanted to run.
Rita let go of her
hand so she could run.
Maddie tripped, she hit
her head, and she was gone.
Four feet away from her mother.
Just a freak thing, you know?
But Rita will always believe it's
because she let go of her hand.
I'm sorry.
And then when Rita
got her diagnosis,
we never thought
we'd have another child.
We knew, with her heart,
what it would do to her.
And when she got
pregnant, it was an accident.
And I begged.
I begged her not to have
the baby, but she just...
She wouldn't let it go.
Yeah, now I'm
gonna lose them both.
Eric, nobody wants it
this way, least of all Rita.
She made a hard choice
for the sake of the baby.
We just need to have
the faith that she has.
Okay, they're ready for us.
We're gonna do our
best for her, okay?
How do you feel?
I wish she could have
cooked it a little longer.
How do you feel?
I wish I was anywhere else.
Good luck. You too.
How's that baby doing?
Baby's cyanotic and
apneic. Dr. Robbins?
Let's get to work on Rita.
We need to get the
baby's airway cleared.
Let's get her breathing
and get her to the OR.
You ready? Mmm-hmm.
I think she's breathing.
She's ready to move.
Robbins, keep me posted.
I will.
Scalpel.
Dacron graft and
4-0 Prolene, please.
Damn it. Damn
it. It's tearing more.
Pledget.
When we're done here, I'd like
you to remember that you are...
Off your service. I know.
You want me to leave
now, I'll leave now.
Another pledget.
All right. Let's see
if this heart will start.
Internal paddles, please.
Any update from
Robbins? How's the baby?
Dr. Robbins can't talk.
That can't be good.
Okay, charge to 10, please.
All right, everybody,
cross your fingers, pray,
do whatever you do.
And clear.
Again? Wait.
We have sinus.
Thanks, everybody.
I got to go check on
that baby. Can you close?
Can I close? You're
a third-year resident.
Can you close a
midline sternotomy?
Can I trust you to do that?
Yes. Yes, absolutely I can.
She's flatline. Suction. I
can't even see the field.
Come on. Come on.
What happened?
I'm losing her.
There's a solution. We'll
find it. Talk me through it.
I was banding the
pulmonary artery together
when it perfed
through her vessels.
Okay, can you try a systemic
to pulmonary artery shunt?
It won't help. They're
both too small...
To take the pulmonary pressure.
It's not in her vessels.
It's something else.
It's the ventricle. I
can do a septation.
Separate her one
good ventricle...
Into two ventricles.
Septation has a pretty
high mortality rate.
She currently has
zero chance of survival.
So this is better.
This is better.
Let's start bypass.
Push heparin and
get me my loops.
Nurses' station.
How's Rita Choudry?
Good. Easy closure.
She's in post-op.
You can check my work.
How's the baby?
It got complicated.
I'm going to the
ER for a consult.
I'll come with you.
You can go home.
You're off my service.
See, I wanted to
talk to you about that.
Hey, it's Dr. Blabbermouth.
Dr. Karev, I am sorry...
Next time, maybe don't speak up
till you know what
you're talking about.
Look, it's my fault. I sent
her in there with half the story.
It's me you should be pissed at.
Okay, now I'm pissed at you.
Sorry. I didn't know she
was gonna say anything.
Why did you even tell
her in the first place?
Alex, I said...
Now I got no job.
Dr. Shepherd, I was
called for a cardio consult.
Was that you or the
other Dr. Shepherd?
I love you.
Thank you.
I'm sorry. No one
has ever called
my brother, "The
other Dr. Shepherd."
It's beautiful. I
called you. Over here.
This is Tracey, early 20s,
possible minor ischemic stroke.
A stroke? I gave her a stroke?
After sexual activity.
Tracey, could you
squeeze my fingers?
Really hard.
It's okay. I've got
you. Just relax.
Any more history? We
don't have a last name.
We just met, like, an
hour ago at the gym.
We went to my place.
What? We hit it off.
Like gangbusters.
Sorry, but was this sexual
activity pretty vigorous?
It was really good. At
one point, we were...
That's all I need.
And then it was over,
and she went all
wonky like this.
Do people get strokes from sex?
Almost never.
So, was it just me?
What answer are you hoping for?
Did she say if she
was on the pill?
We used a condom.
I'm not stupid.
I'm looking for possible
risk factors for stroke.
Birth-control pills can
increase the risk of blood clots.
There was no ID?
I couldn't find her purse.
Tracey, can you tell
us your last name?
Regger? Roger?
Yeah, I did this for
10 minutes, guys.
She was at the gym. Did
she have headphones?
Uh, yeah. This is hers.
She'd have to register
that thing to put music on it.
Get a serial number, call the
company, get a name, and get a history.
On it. Nice one, Sherlock.
I'll get an echo and
some chest films.
Okay, meantime,
let's get a head CT
and a bilateral
carotid artery Doppler.
What the hell is she doing?
Marjorie got hypotensive.
Grey was here.
She decided to put in a
central line to give her pressors.
Dr. Pierce, Dr. Bailey told me
you ordered an exome
panel for her patient.
They caught me, and I threw
you under the bus. Sorry.
Yeah, Dr. Bailey's
genome-research program
has been discontinued.
You know, I heard that. And I
have to say, I think it's stupid.
Genome mapping is like getting
the answers in the back of the book.
It is the key to so
many medical solutions.
Closing that program makes your
board look like a
bunch of morons.
Have you met Dr. Avery?
Yeah, Plastics, right?
Dr. Avery is also a voting
member on the board.
Of course you are.
Yeah, I like her.
You put a central line in my
patient without notifying me first.
There wasn't time.
There was time to
ask a nurse to tell me.
Doesn't work like
that here, Pierce.
I don't need your permission
to keep her from dying.
She's right, Dr. Pierce.
Damn it.
Listen, I get that I'm new.
I get that you don't know me,
but I'm gonna demand
that you listen to me.
Like it or not, I am the chief
of cardiothoracic surgery.
You can't even look at
me when I'm talking to you.
Dr. Margaret Pierce?
♪ We're so proud,
we'll shout it loud
♪ 'Cause we've no
doubt that you'll be
♪ Doing great as chief
of cardiothoracic surgery
♪ Maggie, we are so impressed
♪ You're our favorite surgeon
♪ We send you our
best wishes from ♪
It's a gift.
♪ This giant singing sturgeon ♪
From my parents.
♪ We love you, Maggie ♪
It was... No, it was hilarious.
Everyone thought
it was hilarious.
The timing could
have been better.
It was incredibly
cheesy, and I loved it.
It was perfect. Thank you.
Nothing, I'm just...
I just miss you guys.
No, nothing
happened, Mom. I just...
I think it might have
been a mistake,
coming here.
I don't feel like
I can be myself.
Dad, don't start crying.
I got to go.
So, Tracey's coming around.
She was lucky. Minor stroke.
Nerve responses
returning, no signs of deficits,
but we still don't know...
What caused it, right?
Uh-huh.
No signs of cardiovascular
disease, no signs of carotid disease.
So I thought...
Are you listening?
Sorry.
I was thinking I
have had good sex,
but I've never had
put-you-in-the-hospital sex.
I feel like I'm missing out.
So, I was thinking, could the
clot be coming from some...
I mean, I don't want a
stroke, but I'd like to get close.
The clot could have
come from someplace else.
Guess that's what you call
one mind-blowing orgasm.
Are you done? I have one more.
He nearly screwed
her brains out. I'm done.
And I found one in her leg.
I have not had
sex in a long time.
You're preaching
to the choir, sister.
The clot in her left leg meant
there must be a hole in her heart.
Through which
the clot in her leg,
with help from pressure
changes during very good sex,
traveled from the right to
the left chamber of her heart,
on up to her brain.
Now I just have to
plug the hole like this.
Nice catch, Doctor.
Or should I say...
♪ Chief of
cardiothoracic surgery ♪
Oh, dear God. You heard.
Your parents sound
like very sweet people.
They are. They're very
sweet and very funny,
and nothing at all like me.
No understanding of what
I do or why I like doing it.
Oh, I know that feeling.
I always felt like
the odd man out.
I have three sisters
and a brother.
They are all very put together,
and I, kind of a mess.
It wasn't until I met Meredith
I had a sister I could relate to.
Really? Not at first. You know?
She's hard to get to know,
but she's worth knowing.
Really.
Dr. Pierce. Dr. Bailey...
You are not on...
On your service. Yes.
Dr. Bailey asked to see
you when you're finished.
I apprehended the culprit.
RAF-One mutation right there.
That little orange bastard
caused Robbie's cardiomyopathy.
RAF-One. Since when?
It was just isolated a month
ago by a doctor in Australia,
and the screening panel
was updated last week.
So, until a week ago...
We didn't know it
caused cardiomyopathy.
Is this what you wanted?
Yes!
Genetic profiling is a
rapidly growing science.
New findings crop
up every single day.
For example, three months ago,
there were only 33 known
genetic causes for cardiomyopathy.
Today, there are 34.
This right here, this
is the genetic mutation
that gave your kids
cardiomyopathy.
That's what made our kids sick?
Yes.
There's...
So it isn't our house.
It isn't the water. It isn't
anything, uh, we did.
It wasn't me.
No, Sabine, it
wasn't you. Sabine.
Everything that
you have done has
made your kids
healthier and safer.
You did everything you could.
Dr. Yang did
everything she could.
No one could have
known about this.
Okay.
Why... Why did you keep looking?
I just...
When I find a puzzle,
it's very hard for
me to put it down.
Son of a bitch. I'm
sorry. I got to go.
Thank you. WOMAN:
Thank you so much.
I need that crash cart in here!
Wait. Wait. Wait, wait.
Wait for what? Get off.
I got it! I got her!
You got to go harder
than that, Pierce.
She's my patient. I
know what she can take.
Okay, let me in. I
have to shock her.
I have this.
Pierce, you're not helping her!
Dr. Grey, she can't
take the defibrillation.
I got this.
Marjorie. You're all
right. You're okay.
I'm here with you. It's okay.
Pierce, you're letting her die.
Pierce.
You're okay.
Pierce! It's okay.
Time of death?
Time of death, Dr. Grey?
Nurse, what is the time?
20:42.
Time of death, 20:42.
Pierce.
Pierce. Pierce, hold up.
Chief.
I just wanted to say thank you
for what you did for the McNeils.
You gave them some peace.
And I'm... I'm glad
you're here, so thank you.
You and Yang did
all the hard work.
I just got to bring it
over the finish line.
Chief.
I think you should know that
Dr. Pierce just slow-coded a patient
right in front of me.
What? Grey, that is a...
I watched it happen.
She deliberately withheld
care from a coding patient.
Her CPR was totally ineffectual
and she would not let
me defibrillate. Slow down.
Dr. Grey. You let
that woman die.
Grey, slow down! Pierce?
Dr. Grey has been
doubting my effectiveness
and undermining my authority
since the minute I got here.
Maybe I'm being judged too
harshly against my predecessor
or maybe she just
doesn't like me,
but I can only say to her what
I will say to my patient's family.
I did everything in my power
as a physician to help her,
but I am sorry to
say she's gone.
Are we finished, Chief?
For now.
Grey, wait.
If you want to get me
fired, go ahead. I don't care.
If you want to tell that
woman what I did, fine.
But tell her the whole truth.
Her mother begged
me, in no uncertain terms,
to end her suffering naturally.
She would have signed
papers to that effect,
but her daughter
wouldn't allow her to.
Her daughter was
too scared to realize
that she was keeping
her alive and in agony.
I did what my patient and I
decided was in her best interest.
You look me in the
eye and tell me you
wouldn't have
done the same thing.
Is she all right, my mother?
I went for dinner and some
errands, but when I came...
Jeannie. I'm sorry.
Your mother's heart
stopped again, and I...
I... Dr. Pierce did
everything in her power.
Despite all our
efforts and capabilities,
we were unable to
save your mother.
I am very sorry for your loss.
I'm saying that I
think you're right.
You know, maybe this is
something that I can give up
so that we can have,
you know... Hey!
How's she doing?
Oh, um, no signs of cyanosis
or congestive heart failure.
So far, so good.
Nice work. You, too.
You should go see her.
Thank you, Doctor.
So?
So, I'm gonna pass
on the fellowship.
No, you're not. You can't. What?
Look, I was wrong this morning.
This isn't a sacrifice that
you should have to make.
We can figure this out.
If it makes you happy,
that will benefit our kid,
kids, more than anything.
So, you think I should do it?
I think you have to.
Thank you.
Goodnight,
Dr. Robbins, Dr. Torres.
Where's the baby? Is the baby...
The baby's fine.
She's beautiful.
Thanks to you, she's fine.
I'll let you know as soon
as you can go see her.
Looks like a full recovery, and
we found her parents, Sherlock.
They're on their
way in from Arizona.
Can I ask you guys something?
We just hooked up the one time,
but I wanted to ask her out
because she was really cool,
you know, before
she went all derp.
Should I hang out
till she wakes up or
does that make
me look, like, clingy?
Um, that's sweet.
Well, I was once the girl
who went home with the
guy she met an hour ago.
If this had been me,
you would be the last
person I'd want to see.
Oh. Okay.
Yeah, maybe run
into her at the gym.
Maybe learn her last name.
Maybe invite her to dinner.
Yeah.
Can I have your number?
Go.
Most puzzles come down to
one last missing
piece of information.
Whether it's the answer
to a medical mystery...
Pierce figured out what happened
to the McNeil kids? JO: Mmm-hmm.
That's surprising.
- She solved it.
She did what Yang couldn't
do, and she hates me.
Hi.
I finished your
post-ops. Anything else?
You don't take no for an answer.
So you're insubordinate,
as well as everything else.
No. No?
No. I am not insubordinate
or untrustworthy.
I think we got
off to a bad start.
I made a mistake. I should
have told you the whole story.
But I came here to learn,
and I learned a
crap-ton from you today,
so I decided I deserved
a second chance,
and you weren't gonna give
me one, so I gave myself one.
Or to the question of who
you are, where you fit...
Is this your thunder?
Yeah.
All right, Wilson.
I'll see you in the morning.
You called me by my name.
I did.
You keep checking your watch.
Did you write my name
on your wrist? I did.
Hmm. I appreciate the effort.
It all comes down
to that last piece.
Grey, wait. Can I talk to you?
Tomorrow. I'm heading home.
There's something
I should tell you.
You know what?
I've heard enough.
It's fine. We're
fine. You're fine.
My mother was Ellis Grey.
That's why the final
piece of a jigsaw puzzle
is so satisfying to place.
I know. I'm sorry.
We... This isn't fair to you.
And we got off to a bad
start, but I'm here to work.
And if I'm gonna be
here, I got to be who I am.
So I need you to
know the whole story.
I was put up for
adoption in Boston.
In Boston? Yes.
And I was adopted
by a very nice couple,
an amazing couple.
They are my parents,
but my mother...
My mother, I found
out a year ago,
my mother was your
mother, Ellis Grey.
Unless, of course, the
piece doesn't quite fit.
What do you want?
What?
What are you after here?
I know it sounds like...
You're five years
younger than me.
If my mother were
pregnant, I would have known.
You're wrong.
Just... Or you're lying.
What? What? Just listen.
Stay away from me.
That can make you
wish you'd never opened
the puzzle in the first place.