Taxi!
Carpe diem.
That was hell.
Actual physical hell.
I think I went a tad overboard.
How annoying is carpe diem?
A lot overboard.
They took something from me.
Yeah, that wasn't an exam.
That was an interrogation.
Like, way, way overboard.
The mind games. Trick questions.
It felt like al-Qaeda in there.
How are you supposed to
plan a life, a career, a family,
if you're always
carpe-ing the diem?
Next test is June.
June's not bad.
2013.
Oh.
What's done is done. Let's just
not even talk about it anymore.
If we all seized every
moment of every day,
there wouldn't be doctors.
Who would sit
through med school?
Anyone know how Alex did?
Anyone know if Alex made it?
Made it?
What do you mean, "Made it"?
We'd all be too busy
living in the now.
Whatever that means.
Hey.
You okay?
I'm not sure.
I hope you're not
worried about last night.
I'm not worried
about last night.
I'm worried because I
checked with some of my friends
on the committee,
and one of your Seattle
Grace doctors didn't pass.
Any idea who?
They weren't sure.
But if it's Jackson,
he'll blame me forever.
Welcome to the
American Medical Board
of Surgery Certifying
Examination.
We'll give you four
separate scenarios
in three 30-minute sessions,
10-minute breaks in between.
To pass the test, you must
pass two of the three sessions.
Now, you can fail a
session and still pass.
Still pass. But examiners
are not permitted to indicate
whether you passed
or failed each session.
You'll be rated on your ability
to diagnose, manage treatment,
handle the unexpected,
basically, the strength of
your constitution in crisis.
And when we move
on to the next scenario,
there's no doubling
back, meaning,
once a question is asked...
You can't go back.
Understood, sir.
Are you in a hurry, Dr. Yang?
No, sir. Just ready
when you are.
Mm-hmm.
So then, a 65-year-old woman
is being seen by her
primary care physician
for a workup of osteoporosis
when she is found to
have elevated calcium.
Her PTH level was
well above normal.
Her doctor sends her to you.
Elevated calcium and
PTH would indicate
primary hyperparathyroidism.
I would offer the
patient a para...
thyroidectomy.
And first, I would
explore the right side.
If that gland is large...
I would biopsy it.
After doing the
biopsy, I would...
Hang on. What did the
pathologist's report say?
Path comes back with
parathyroid hyperplasia.
Uh, oh...
And how large was the gland?
How much longer are we
gonna give this Dr. Karev?
Fifteen?
Next, I would resect it and
explore the other glands.
Aggressive choice.
Well, I suppose I could wait for
the IPM before taking further actions.
Mm-hmm.
Are you sure you're
okay with that?
Yes, I'm okay with that.
If the IPM
showed PTH levels
in the normal range...
Dr. Grey?
I would feel comfortable
concluding the procedure.
Dude, there's no other way?
Helicopter. Magic carpet.
That lane is open.
That's the bus lane. I
don't see any buses.
I'll get a ticket.
Come on, man. I'll give
you double any ticket.
What about my insurance?
Come on, man. Just
take the bus lane.
Nah. How far are we?
Twenty blocks, give or take.
Catch the game last night?
Come on, come on. Move.
I heard it went 11 innings.
Move! Move! Look out! Move!
Come one, come on! Almost
there. Move, it's a hurry.
Okay, who wants more pancakes?
You haven't had any. Sit down.
I can't sit still. He's
taking his test right now.
It's cute, you being
nervous for Jackson.
You want some more
juice? It's paternal.
You're a natural father.
Are you sure you don't want
anything? I could make some bacon...
We should have a baby.
Don't freak out. I
mean, I like this.
I like you, I like your kid,
and I like your
kid's moms. And I...
You know, you don't have
to say anything right now.
Just go back to
worrying about Jackson,
and we can talk
about this later.
I would say no
rush, but, you know,
actually, my FSH
levels would suggest that
rushing a little might not be
the worst thing in the world.
Julia wants to have
a baby with Mark.
I can't even deal
with that right now.
Wow.
I should've picked him up myself.
I mean, what's wrong with me?
Okay, I thought he was your
brother's best friend, not yours.
We were all super close, and
he was my rock when Tim died.
I just... Oh, God. I
let my rock take a cab.
So you let him take a cab.
Well, I mean, listen,
he just flew in from Tibet
and he has cancer.
I mean, the least I
could do is pick him up at
the baggage claim.
Hey, hey, hey. Okay,
you need to chill out.
Look, I know that you're
worried, but as far as cancers go,
I mean, his is
very slow-growing.
He told you he found
out, what, six months ago?
I mean, he could be fine.
Yeah. Yeah.
Well, with you in the
OR, I'm not worried.
You're gonna love him,
and he's gonna love you.
Well, I'm taking his tumor
out. It's the least he could do.
Phoenix.
Nick!
Hey. It's good to see you.
Oh! Wait. What's with the cane?
Tumor, man. It hurts to walk.
Already? But you were only
diagnosed six months ago.
Did I say months?
I meant years. So...
You must be the wife. Yeah.
Good to meet you.
Good to meet you, too.
Julia went all FSH
on me this morning.
Is that a sexual term?
Wait. You know what?
I don't want to know.
She wants a baby.
She wants my baby.
What did you say?
Nothing. It's crazy.
Until you think about it and
realize it's kind of genius.
I love Julia. I want Sofia to
have some siblings
to grow up with.
Why wouldn't I do it?
Are you asking me if
you should have a baby?
What, you think I shouldn't?
Have a baby or ask me if
you should have a baby?
So you think I should do it?
Well, do you want Julia
to be in your life forever?
You think I shouldn't do it?
Do you have to
answer that right now?
Hey. Answer what?
We were just talking
about the cranioplasty.
Oh, it's exciting, right?
Mm. Yeah.
Charlie Connor, 37. He fell
off the roof six months ago.
He presents for repair
of a skull bone defect
that occurred secondary
to surgical removal
of part of his skull.
We waited several
months for the swelling
to subside before...
What were you doing anyway?
Being an idiot.
You gonna fix it next time?
No, I want the roofers
to fix it next time,
like they had
to do it this time,
because Humpty Dumpty
almost killed himself.
You want to pay for it?
Okay, we have
mirrored the healthy skull
and created a
custom titanium plate
that we will secure to the bone.
Titanium. Like The Terminator.
And I'll take fat from the
belly and fill in the gaps,
pull your face into shape.
So, Doc, what are you using to
fasten the new skull into place?
Hexagonal screws? Yes.
You know your stuff.
Yeah, we could do this in my
garage. Save me a few grand.
You got a 2-millimeter bit?
Do I have a 2-millimeter bit?
Please! Don't encourage him.
What? No.
I am counting on you to treat
these candidates extremely well.
Show them whatever they
want to see. Really woo them.
"Woo"? Yeah, woo. You know.
What about me says "woo"?
After the boards,
we might be losing
some very good doctors
to other programs.
Now, if that happens,
we need to be sure
that we have some
fresh talent ready
and willing to take their place,
so I am asking you,
as Chief, please
woo their socks off.
For you. Just this
once, I will woo.
Their socks off?
Don't push it.
Hi.
Hey.
Hey, um, so,
do you have any word on what
Cristina's plans are for next year?
No. No, not yet.
Okay. Will you keep me posted?
I will.
Good. Thanks.
The first session was so easy.
I want to punch your face.
Hey.
Hi. I am so, so
sorry to interrupt.
I'm Dr. Karev.
I was stuck in Seattle
with a patient, and...
Well, I don't want to bore you
with a bunch of travel crap...
Your time was set
for 9:00 this morning.
We were here. We
called your name.
Yeah, I was with a
patient. You get that.
We all have patients,
Dr. Karev. Yet, here we were.
So what? I just fail?
The first of three
sessions, yes.
Which means you need perfect
scores in the next two sessions.
How are you everywhere?
How'd it go for you in there?
Look, baby, I know
you were shocked.
Shocked?
Shocked at the sight
of my mother half-naked
with a senior attending
at my hospital?
No, far from it. Okay?
I mean, it's kind of par for
the course for you, right, Mom?
But every door that I open,
every corner that I turn,
there you are.
I know I'm your mother,
but I'm also a woman.
I have needs.
If you don't want
to talk about this
like an adult,
don't bring it up.
Wait a second. Did I
bring it up? Did I bring it up?
Don't play games.
Just talk to me.
Just leave me alone! I'm in
the middle of my freakin' boards.
Are you following me, Mom?
I'm the examiner in the
room right next to yours.
Of course, you are.
After that, I might
mobilize the small intestine
to create a Roux limb,
and open up the pancreatic duct
longitudinally from
the tail to the neck?
The patient has died.
Moving on to the next scenario.
Can we go back
just for a second?
We're moving on, Dr. Kepner.
A 38-year-old
male with a history...
But if we could go back for
one second so that I can clarify.
You have a 40-year-old man
who complains of rectal pain
and burning with defecation,
and occasionally some
blood in the bowel movement.
I would do a rigid sigmoidoscopy
to make sure there were
no lesions in the rectum.
Squeamish,
Dr. Grey? No, not at all.
Good, then let's pick up
the answers, shall we?
Of course. If there were
lesions in the rectum,
I would do an incisional biopsy
and begin to fulgurate...
I would cover the
bowel with omentum
and close the fascia primarily.
The sutures tear right
through the fascia.
In that case, I would use
1-0 nylon retention sutures
through the full thickness
of the abdominal wall.
Moving on.
Because I would
make sure the area
was adequately
drained and closed.
Dr. Kepner...
Because if it leaked,
and if the leak was early,
I would re-explore the
patient and repair the leak,
making sure that if...
Once the question is finished...
Finished. Yes, I
know. I'm sorry.
I just really need
you to understand
that if the leak was late, I
would obtain an abdominal CT.
Just to make sure, and also, if it
wasn't, if it wasn't drained... God.
Can you hang on
just for a second?
It's just so
incredibly hot in here.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Uh...
Can we move on, Dr. Kepner?
Would you allow
us that courtesy?
Yes.
Great. Thank you.
Now a 38-year-old male
with a history of diabetes...
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm
sorry. Just, just, just...
Just one last thing going
back to the beginning,
'cause you heard what I said about
finding the pancreatic duct, right?
Because I really want
to make sure you know
that I would drain
the anastomosis...
That patient should
be stable! They just...
Why won't you tell
me? Just tell me!
How am I supposed to answer this
question without
the full information?
Please...
Look, I'm a really good doctor.
I am. I just... I need
all the information.
I'm...
I'm a really good doctor.
Um... No free air.
The spleen looks fine.
There is some
perihepatic fluid...
I'm sorry. Are you guys
hearing this noise next door?
It's very distracting. If we could
just ask them to keep it down.
If you get
distracted this easily,
I think it calls to
question your ability
to function in a high-volume OR.
Certainly calls
it into question.
It is not that at all.
Okay? It's just my...
Um...
Never mind. Let's wait
for traffic to die down.
We wouldn't want to throw
you off your game, Dr. Avery.
I'm fine. Let's just... Shhh!
I would stop the patient's continuous
bleeding with a portacaval shunt.
Your patient is now in a coma.
That's highly unlikely,
but, in that case,
I would suspect a
hepatic encephalopathy
and check an ammonia
level to confirm.
I'll save you the trouble.
It's confirmed.
I'd check the
patient's medication...
Medication...
Okay, then I'd start on
lactulose and neomycin.
The patient... Still
not getting better?
Then I would do a shunt
revision with a stent graft.
Stent graft? Yes, a stent graft.
Hmm.
Well...
Risky move, Dr. Yang.
Moving on.
Did you have something
to add, Dr. Yang?
Nope. All good.
Does that hurt? Nope.
What about...
Yeah. That's what happens when
you wait six years to get treated.
So she's not shy.
Yeah, I know. I
never went for shy.
Yeah.
I've been working
with a naturopath.
I figured I'd try the
nontraditional route.
It helped.
It did.
But then the pain started to
kick up, so I saw a real doctor.
He was gonna send me
to an orthopedic surgeon,
but then I was like, "Hold up.
"Yuma Robbins just
married one of those."
Not that it was a real wedding.
Excuse me?
Oh, uh... She
thinks you're serious.
I am serious. Tucson's
already married.
To him.
She loves me. We were 10.
It was in my tree house, and
we had rings made of crabgrass.
You're probably the
last guy I ever kissed.
It was a beautiful ceremony.
Tim officiated, her brother.
He made me swear to stop
pulling the streamers off of her bike.
It was an issue for a while.
Yeah, I'm a little concerned
about how much pain you're in.
So I am going to order some
new scans. These are how old?
Nine, you know, maybe 12
months. I had to finish up a project
on the guys who carry
all the tourists' crap up K2.
With a cane?
I stayed at base camp.
Play through the pain, right?
No. Anybody?
Is she always like
that, or am I dying?
No, you are going to be fine,
because she is a
genius with a scalpel.
She'll be in and out, and
you won't even know it.
And they're not even
gonna use drugs.
Nope, nope, just chamomile tea.
You are so damn cute.
How does she get through
a work day with you around?
I don't know.
I forgot how much I missed you.
Me, too.
And our surgical
rotations often allow
flexibility to set aside
consecutive days
for research projects and
field work, if necessary.
Any questions?
Would I have to share an office?
We don't...
I'll have to check on that.
Are parking spaces
assigned for attendings,
or do we have to,
like, find our own?
I'll have to check on that.
All right, we just need
to screw this down
and then adjust it to fit.
Well, Mark said that
I get to graft the fat.
How cool is that?
Yeah, that's cool.
I'm gonna be your big
brother for 30 seconds.
Okay.
Julia wants to have
a baby with Mark.
She what? What did she say?
Well, I don't know. What do
you mean, you don't know?
What did he say?
How did it go down?
My 30 seconds of
brotherly advice is over.
I got to go check on a patient.
No... Does he want to do it?
I mean, did it seem like
he was excited about it,
or does he seem like,
"That's an insane idea"?
Because it is. Yeah,
you know what?
I hope you told him
that it's an insane idea.
Are all your questions gross?
Gross? What do you mean, gross?
They keep asking me about
bowels and bloody stools.
It's general surgery.
What do you expect?
You're not helping, at all.
My guy is a freakin' fossil.
The last time he was in
the OR, it was lit by candles.
Maybe I'll just live in
here, in this stall, in my filth
till I die.
Sick woman in here. Go away.
I really need to get in there.
Sorry. Closed for maintenance.
Please let me in.
Come back later!
Hey, the applicants keep
asking to see the gym.
Should I show it to them?
'Cause I don't want the cobwebs
and sweaty menthol
stench to scare them...
When did I become
the advice columnist?
Touchy, touchy. Well, I'm sorry.
It's just, no one can seem to
make up their own mind today.
People do make
up their own minds,
they just need a little
help getting there.
What do you mean?
Okay, if someone comes
to me with a problem...
Yeah. I give them a metaphor.
A metaphor?
A figure of speech, which...
Yes, I know what a
metaphor is. Fantastic.
Now, the next time someone
comes to you with a problem,
you just give them a metaphor.
Any kind of metaphor?
See? That's the beauty of it.
They'll draw some
meaning from it,
and it'll help them
to make the decision
they were gonna
make in the first place.
I'll stick with being
honest, thank you.
Suit yourself, but when
they take your advice
and it doesn't work out,
honesty can bite you in the ass.
If you don't mind,
it is a men's room.
What? What? You're
supposed to be doctors.
I've seen your things.
You've seen mine.
It's all just flesh and
cartilage. Get over it!
April, what...
Hey, Jackson. How's it going?
Not so good. You?
I am dying in there.
I am actually failing.
You, too? 'Cause
mine is a total fiasco.
They think I'm insane!
They're toying with me.
I am self-destructing
into a puddle of sweat.
I don't know what's
wrong with me.
I know exactly what is wrong
with me and I still can't reel it in.
I broke my promise to Jesus,
and now I can't even
talk to him and I need him.
He's the only one
who can calm me down!
Why the hell did you
do it? Why'd you let me?
I don't know! You
said it was okay.
I know! I knew you'd regret it!
Stop yelling! Why
are you yelling at me?
Because I'm all
messed up now, too.
I mean, what am I?
I'm now the guy that made you
break your promise to Jesus?
I am not that guy! All right?
That guy is gross, okay?
It's all very unbecoming,
especially for an Avery.
What?
Are you honestly comparing
breaking my promise to Jesus
with putting a tiny dent
in your family crest?
You're right.
You're right, and I'm sorry.
My mom is the examiner in
the room right next to mine.
It's throwing me.
Oh, God.
I know. I'm worried about my mom
and what she's
gonna think if I fail.
It's pathetic.
Right?
No. God, no, Jackson.
It's not pathetic.
That's the most important
relationship in your life.
The problem isn't
that I broke my promise.
That's not the problem.
The problem is...
That it felt good.
It felt good.
I shouldn't have
taken advantage.
Taken advantage? What?
We should go.
Taken advantage?
I kissed you, remember?
Yeah, but I kissed you back.
Yeah, but then I
unbuttoned your shirt.
Yeah, and then I
pulled up that skirt.
Yeah, but then I
kissed your neck.
Yeah. And then I
took off your shirt.
And I...
But then I unbuckled your belt.
And then I slipped
my hand up your back.
And I wrapped my
arms around your neck.
And then I...
Then you...
Then I...
No. He's not gonna...
Yes, he is.
No!
- Oh, my God.
- I told you.
Disgusting.
Dr. Bailey, where
are the candidates?
Over there
destroying my appetite.
You know, I never
thought I would've said this,
but we need to keep
our people, people.
Right?
We haven't put
in all this training
and put up with
all their nonsense
to go groveling at the
feet of bread sniffers.
Kepner's already gotten job
offers at four different programs.
Well, Grey's not going anywhere.
Not without Yang, anyway.
Cristina has options.
My contact in Boston
may have mentioned
that Meredith said their
program's her first choice.
You're building a house.
Harvard has an excellent
neurosurgery department.
And they have plenty
of really nice houses.
Don't be all cryptic
and then just walk away.
Meredith?
I lied to you.
About what?
I'm not okay.
I might be dying. I think
our daughter tried to kill me
with her flu for
being a bad mother.
Why didn't you tell me before?
I'm failing, Derek, and I don't
think I can go back in there.
I just can't. I mean...
Will you still
love me if I fail?
You want me to yell at you
or tell you to come home?
I want you to tell
me what to do.
The test is a mirror.
What are you talking about?
The test. It's a mirror.
Reflecting my
sickly incompetence?
Are you saying I won't like
myself if I give up right now?
That I won't be able to look
myself in the mirror if I quit?
Whatever you decide,
I will still love you.
No, you won't.
Nobody loves a quitter.
Good luck, Meredith.
Huh.
You find out the
patient has advanced
metastatic disease
and is terminal.
What do you do?
Honestly?
I'd pray for them.
I know that's not the right
answer, but it's what I'd do first.
Or at least if you asked me
yesterday, that's what I'd do.
Now I'm not so
sure if he's listening.
Dr. Kepner, this is
highly inappropriate.
Yeah, well, so is having
premarital sex in the men's room
with a really good friend,
but that just happened, so...
You know, I have been surrounded
by scientists for a decade now,
holding back my feelings
about my relationship with God,
'cause I was afraid
of being laughed at,
or judged, or considered
less of a doctor.
I was hiding.
Ashamed to admit
that I love Him.
That His is the one
relationship I count on.
And now I'm not sure
if I just screwed that up
or freed myself
from its limitations.
The one thing I
know for sure, though,
is I think I'm done hiding.
Dr. Kepner, we
asked you a question.
Yes, I would do a palliative
endoscopic stenting.
If that failed and the patient
was still alive and having pain,
I would do a biliary-enteric
bypass. After that, I might...
A 30-year-old female comes
in with third-degree burns.
You've checked her airway
and started fluid resuscitation
with D5NS fluids.
Actually, I would use
LR for fluid resuscitation,
not NS.
Saline has too much chloride,
and that could cause
acidosis in my patient.
Okay.
So you've started your
patient on a liter of LR.
Thanks for assisting, Bailey.
You know, Nick did a big spread
in National Geographic once
on this school for
orphan girls in Calcutta,
and he sent them
a bunch of cameras.
I think that it was Polaroids,
so they wouldn't have to pay
for the film to get processed.
But, anyways, you know,
a couple of those girls
actually became photographers.
Like professionals.
Isn't that amazing?
We're not going
to kill your friend.
What? I know. I'm just saying...
Hey, does he save puppies, too?
Less sarcasm. A
little more focus.
Oh, shoot.
We were supposed
to bring snack today
to the day care
for all the kids.
Today? Yeah.
That mom from Psych asked
if we would switch with her,
and I said we would,
and then I forgot.
You need to write this
stuff down. I know. I know.
I'm so sorry. Sorry.
I... Sorry!
You didn't forget
snack, did you?
No, I'm seeing mets in
the vessels. Look at this.
Damn. And if they're here...
They're gonna be everywhere.
The temporalis
muscle is atrophied.
Any idea why, Dr. Grey?
Lack of use?
It had nowhere to attach
since the bone was gone.
That's right. It's too
late for this muscle.
It's missed its
chance to attach.
Why are we talking
about the temporalis?
Teachable moment,
Dr. Sloan. Stay out of it.
Once you inject the fat into
Charlie's temple, the muscle will...
Again with the muscle?
Yeah, the once healthy muscle
will slowly wither to nothing all alone,
surrounded by a
thick layer of fat.
Mmm. Very crafty, Dr. Shepherd.
Message received,
loud and clear.
They had snack.
And now I have two pounds
of strawberries for no reason.
Why is Teddy here?
Honey,
we did a PET scan,
and Nick has intradural mets.
They've spread
into his lymph nodes,
they've even
gone into his heart.
He has a cardiac tumor,
which looks like it might have
invaded into the right ventricle.
At this point, there's
very little that we can do.
I would be concerned
about Crohn's disease,
but differential
diagnosis could be PUD,
ulcerative colitis,
or appendicitis.
Dr. Grey?
I'm sorry. I can't...
I'd locate the fistula
endoscopically, then inject fibrin glue.
What about an abscess?
What about it?
Well, apparently,
you have ruled it out.
It just feels a bit
cavalier, doesn't it?
If you say so.
I'm having a hard
time understanding
why I would open her up when
I could treat it endoscopically.
Precisely my question, Dr. Yang.
I've treated this
condition a dozen times.
And I, 1,000 times.
If you would rather I open her
up and do a tube duodenostomy,
that's fine, too.
It's more invasive, but fine.
Mm-hmm.
Dr. Grey.
Dr. Grey, we're
gonna have to call this.
You can take the
exam again next year.
And we won't count this
as a failure, so, please...
Okay, you're doctors. You
can't handle a little vomit?
Dr. Grey, it's really okay...
I would repair it with
an abdominal approach,
reduce the size of
the hernia contents,
excise the sac,
close the hiatus,
and perform a floppy Nissen
for anti-reflux and gastropexy.
But ask me something else,
because I've known that answer
since I was, like, 12 years old.
My mother practically
invented the floppy Nissen.
So keep them coming,
but don't go easy on me.
All right. A 40-year-old man
presents with a suspicious lesion
on his left temporal,
sent in by his...
Ooh!
Pigmented lesion?
You seem awfully
sure of yourself.
I'm sorry. Is that a question?
Do you feel threatened?
Have we moved on to psychology?
I find your hostility curious.
And I'm curious as to
why you think me hostile.
You know, if you don't
agree with my approach,
I wish you would
voice your issues.
I don't disagree.
I don't believe you.
Are you calling me a liar, sir?
Fine. You know what?
Earlier, when I said I was
okay with that open procedure,
I wasn't.
That might have
been okay when, like,
Hawkeye and BJ did it on MASH,
but this being the
new century and all,
I would have, as I said
earlier, treated it endoscopically.
Then you lied earlier.
You know what? Oh, God. I
can answer these questions
any way you want using
medical techniques from any era.
So how about we just, you know,
pick a decade you're comfortable
with and go from there?
Well, then...
It's been a pleasure being
witness to such genius.
I can now finally retire
knowing that such
advanced and creative minds
are at work in
the surgical field.
That's it?
I think we've had enough of
an education today, Dr. Yang.
But there's still 20 minutes.
No need.
Oh.
Best of luck.
I'd do a biopsy.
Path shows LCIS. What's your
best mastectomy approach?
I'd make a periareolar incision
to preserve the
inframammary fold.
But wait. Did you say LCIS?
Yes, lobular carcinoma in situ.
You wouldn't do a mastectomy.
You'd observe and repeat mammos.
You already did a
skin-sparing mastectomy.
That was a trick question.
You had all the facts to answer.
Yeah, but my answer was wrong.
I'm gonna fail because
of a trick question?
The questions are designed
to get your response...
You got to be kidding me?
You missed your first session.
You're lucky to be
even getting this chance.
Yeah, I missed my first session
for the best freakin' reason.
I was with a patient.
For months with this kid
who doesn't have a chance.
Not a chance.
And we give them a
chance and we try everything,
and then when there's
nothing left to do,
I'm supposed to just walk
away from his mother?
I had to be there. I had to.
And what did I miss here, a few
more hypothetical
trick questions?
What are you staring at?
You guys are doctors.
You're supposed to decide
if I'm gonna be a doctor,
and you can't understand that?
Thank you,
Dr. Karev. It's Karev.
Can you at least
tell me if I passed?
Thank you. Thank you.
Taxi.
Well, you don't want
to miss your flight.
No, I don't want to miss
my flight. I better go.
Richard, I don't
regret last night one bit.
Neither do I.
It's just bad timing.
You know, we live
in different cities.
It's too complicated right now.
Yeah, bad timing.
Bye, Richard.
Bye, Catherine. Safe flight.
Call me if you hear
anymore about the boards.
I will. And call me
when you get home,
let me know you got there okay.
I will.
Are you going to the trauma and
critical care conference in May?
In New Orleans?
I'm speaking at it.
Me, too.
I'm at the Soniat House.
Where are they putting you up?
Uh...
Windsor Court.
No. Soniat House is much better.
The breakfast biscuits will
make you jump up and down.
When do you fly in?
I think it's Thursday.
I fly in Thursday, too.
I can't believe it.
My whole Charlie is back.
You people are miracle workers.
So how long till I'm
back on the ladder?
I just got a tile saw and I'm
gonna mosaic the stucco.
You can't... Dr. Shepherd,
talk some sense into him.
It's really not my place.
But if you want to say
something to your husband,
please, by all means,
you should do it.
I know how much you
love to work on the house,
but listen to me,
you are clumsy.
And I can't stand the thought
of almost losing you again.
So would you just take a second,
and what's left of your brain,
and think about how I felt about it?
How scared I was
to lose you forever?
You're right. I'm sorry, babe.
I'll find a new hobby.
Right? Something we can
do together, like, bowling.
No, I hate bowling.
But you never even tried it.
Well, you can hate
something without trying it.
Hey.
Thanks for today.
For letting me...
You did a good job in there.
Thanks.
You okay?
I love you.
Oh, my God. That just came
flying out of my face,
like it was some kind of...
I love you. I just... God.
Did it again.
I love you. I do. I
just... I love you.
And I have been
trying not to say it.
I have been trying so
hard to just mash it down
and ignore it and not say it.
And Jackson is a great guy.
He is, and he's gorgeous,
and he's younger than you,
and he doesn't
have any grandkids
or babies with his lesbian BFFs,
and he's an Avery, and
he liked me, you know?
He really liked me.
But it was never gonna work out,
because I love you.
I am so in love with you.
And you're in me.
It's like you're a disease.
It's like I am infected
by Mark Sloan.
And I just can't...
I can't think about
anything or anybody,
and I can't sleep.
I can't breathe.
I can't eat.
And I love you. I just...
I love you all the time.
Every minute of every day.
And I...
I...
Love you.
God, that feels
good, just to say that.
I feel so much better.
Just... I love you.
Mark?
Hey, Lexie.
I thought you said
the lobby. You ready?
Hey there, sunshine.
You feeling okay?
Yeah. You know, just groggy.
You guys got good
drugs in this place.
Good. What the hell
were you thinking?
Dude. You're an idiot.
You should have called me.
I mean, why didn't you
call me? I'm a doctor.
What do you think
I do all day long?
Instead, you go to
some quack in Tibet.
I mean, you should've
freakin' called me!
Naturopathy
works, too, Flagstaff.
Whoa. It's not Flagstaff!
And it's not Phoenix
and it's not Tempe!
It's Arizona Robbins, MD.
Do you know what that means?
How do you spell
it? It's not funny, Nick.
Nothing is funny. You're dying!
And you know what
hell it was when Tim died
because you were there,
and you and I barely
made it through that.
So to do nothing for six years
and then to come
when it's too late,
I...
Why do you think I didn't
come to you sooner?
As if after Tim died, I could...
You think I don't know
how this must feel for you?
You're an idiot!
I couldn't have helped Tim,
but I could've helped you!
I'll admit, the
Romans had a point.
You got to live life.
Got to pee. Got
to pee. Got to pee.
What time you got?
12:04.
It's supposed to come
online at midnight.
I mean, it's four minutes
late. Come on, people.
Crazy doctors, they
crashed the system.
I already know I failed,
so I don't know why I keep
hitting the refresh button.
And living means that every
morning, when you wake up,
you have to choose...
Okay, if anyone failed, it was me,
because my guy had a vendetta.
Please. I've got
the odds on failure.
Are any of you on
call? I've got a trauma.
No!
Wait. Wait. Wait.
I passed. I passed.
I passed! I passed!
I passed! Yes!
Oh, my God! Yeah!
Between seizing what
life offers in the moment,
and forging ahead,
no matter the weather...
Alex? It's not coming up.
Here, here. Use mine.
Wait. Wait. Where is April?
Or closing the curtains...
and shutting out the day.