Previously on "ER".
Be good, son.
We typically only do amnio
when you're over 35
unless you have genetic
disorders in your family.
No.
No, Reggie.
I'm seeing someone else.
Dr. Carter, can I hang around
and see how this goes?
Absolutely.
Thank you, but I'm taking
the Trauma Fellowship, okay?
Fine. Whatever, Peter.
I'd consider you
for cardiothoracic.
I thought that
belonged to Peter.
Ritalin is for
hyperactive children. You're 24.
And my doctor still
prescribes it.
So I'm not doing
anything wrong.
Did I do something wrong,
officer?
I'm just trying
to get your attention.
Which has not been
that easy to do of late.
I've been busy working.
And seeing someone else.
I have to get to work.
‐ I'll give you a lift.
‐ It's two blocks away.
You don't want to be resisting
an officer here, do you?
Oh, what are you gonna do,
arrest me?
I'm a cop. It's what I do.
Okay, you win.
Oh, whoa. Oh.
Uh‐oh.
Let's pick up the doggy.
Can you say doggy, Reese?
'Doggy. Arf'
'Doggy.'
I don't think
he's got that one yet.
He will soon.
He's doing great.
He's responding
to vocalizations
repeating back more.
I just wish we had more time.
In about a month,
I'll be able to add
a couple more sessions a week.
Cutting back
on your schedule?
Well, this Trauma Fellowship
that I'm going to be doing
will give me more free time.
That's great.
On top of the three sessions
we're doing now
Reese is going to make
real progress.
Three? Is Carla coming
twice a week now?
No, just once.
But her fiance's doing a session
once a week now, too.
Roger's working with Reese here?
I assumed you knew.
No, no, no, I mean..
...it's not a problem, you know.
The more we work
with him the better, right?
'Right.'
'See you next time.'
‐ Excuse me. Is that your son?
‐ What?
No, he's not mine.
Where'd he come from?
‐ Are you with this child?
‐ No.
Hey.
Hi, there.
Where's your mommy, huh?
Where's your mommy?
Is he okay?
No.
Something's not right with him.
Do you feel okay?
What's your name, honey?
Honey, can you
tell me your name?
Huh?
Okay. Alright, alright.
Yeah, we're going
to take good care of you.
Don't worry.
You're going to be okay.
Jerry, why can't I get
an outside line?
Because you have to
punch in the code first.
‐ Code?
‐ Yes.
A Rocket Romano
innovation.
What for?
Uh, make things
more difficult
is the only reason
I can imagine.
Jerry, have you seen
Dr. Greene?
Yeah, he's on rounds
with his high holiness.
Have you heard
about this new code?
Unbelievable.
Listen, if you see Mark, I need
to speak with him.
Sure.
Hey, hey, Carla.
Um, it's me.
Listen, I...we need to talk.
No, no, no, no, no.
Reese is fine.
Yeah, but, uh, we need to talk
about some other stuff, okay?
Yeah, I know, I‐I just, uh..
...well, can you get away
for lunch?
Great. Cool.
I'll meet you there. Bye.
You just found him?
He was wandering around
about a block from here.
Resps 11.
'Pupils still pinpoint
and nonreactive.'
Lacerations on the feet.
Look infected.
Okay, Haleh, let's get
an O2 mask on him.
CBC, lytes, tox screen,
EKG and bag a urine.
‐ So you think he was just lost?
‐ Lost or neglected.
With the decreased resps
and contracted pupils..
...looks like he might have
been given opiates.
Okay, we need to give him
Narcan .1 milligram.
'Stand by
with an intubation tray.'
He's dehydrated.
I can't get a line.
Blew the hand
and the antecubital on the arm.
Can't use the feet,
they're infected.
Page surgery.
We need to get IV access.
'Resps are down to eight.
You want to intubate?'
'No, uh, give me
Narcan in a syringe.'
Hold the mouth open.
I'm gonna inject sublingually
into the vascular bed.
I paged Dr. Corday.
You're not going to intubate?
Not if this works.
'Come on, little guy.'
'Let's hear something.
Come on.'
Second EKG was normal
so we'll hold for another hour
and then release.
'Thank you, Dr. Carter.
Ms. Knight.'
Would that be you catching
your breath from running
to get here because
you're 20 minutes late?
Sorry.
Let's proceed..
...with presenting
Mr. David Chameides.
Complains of back pain.
Yep, uh..
...this is a 68‐year‐old man.
He complains, um,
he presents with back pain
and he said it started
two days ago
when he was helping his daughter
move into her new apartment.
He was lifting heavy boxes
and she was living in Dubuque,
but she got a divorce
so she had to move
back here to Chicago.
Did I mention that
the pain was constant?
‐ Not yet.
‐ 'Well, it is.'
Um, and upon
physical examination‐‐
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
What about pertinent negatives?
Uh, no fever,
no, um, trauma
no abdominal pain,
no, um..
No, uh..
'No..'
...uh, he's a heavy smoker.
And, um,
the BP is 1...sorry.
BP is 170/95, um..
...no, no, no, his, um..
...his BP is, um, 175/100.
Pulse 95.
‐ Neuro exam normal?
‐ Yes.
'And could you appreciate
a pulsatile abdominal mass?'
No.
But the ultrasound revealed
an abdominal aortic aneurysm.
‐ How'd you know that?
‐ Dr. Carter.
Patient has
all the risk factors.
Ms. Knight,
presenting a case
is like telling
good stories.
Succinct, focused
and to the point.
Frankly, you lost me somewhere
around Dubuque.
Dr. Carter, Ms. Knight is a
student of yours, is that right?
Yes.
Work harder.
Thank God I've got
a small bowel obstruction
waiting for me upstairs.
Gentlemen. Ms. Knight.
I think we can all thank God
for that small bowel.
If you're going to be late,
at least be prepared.
Any idea as to the source
of the fever?
No, probably cellulitis.
‐ Kerry, Reggie's still here.
‐ Good.
We're gonna need a photo.
We've got a camera
by the desk.
Carol, as soon as the IV's in
let's get him some juice
and something to eat, okay?
Sure.
‐ Could I have a Kelly?
‐ Yep.
What sort of parents would
just abandon their child?
Well, we're not sure that's
what really happened.
You know, if there are drugs
in his system
parents could be
drug addicts.
Not even know
he's missing.
Okay. That's lovely.
I've exposed the saphenous vein,
18 angio.
Is this baby John Doe?
Yeah. Two year old.
Kerry found him.
Mm‐hmm. Looks good.
Jerry said you needed
to talk to me?
Oh, no, I mean,
it's nothing important.
‐ I'll find you.
‐ Okay.
Oh, uh, well, I remembered
to bring my tuxedo
'but I left the tickets
at home.'
So can we stop by
on the way?
‐ Sure. Sounds fine.
‐ Okay. Catch you later.
Mm‐hmm.
Okay, IV's in.
Let's start hydrating him
with a bolus of 100 CCs
normal saline
250 milligrams IV Oxacillin
and put him on a Narcan drip.
Tuxedo?
Yes, just some, um, fundraiser
thing we agreed to go to.
Uh‐huh.
Dr. Weaver, I've still
not found that camera.
‐ I know it's here somewhere.
‐ Just find it, Jerry.
Jerry, have you seen
my palmtop computer?
What, is everything missing now?
No, I haven't.
That's why you're so
scattered this morning?
You lost
your electronic cheat sheet?
Hey, Jerry, when did
Antoine Bell come in?
Oh, yeah, uh,
he asked for you. I'm sorry.
‐ I put him in trauma one.
‐ Just give me a break, alright.
I didn't get much sleep.
I was late and I got
my cards all messed up.
I've done 100 presentations
without notes, without computers
and definitely without sleep.
So why don't you get
yourself a cup of coffee
and pull yourself together?
I am together.
‐ I went off the Ritalin.
‐ When?
‐ Two days ago.
‐ That's great.
Look, I got a patient.
Maybe we can talk
more later.
Sure.
Antoine..
...expected to see you today.
Just not like this.
Antoine does not associate
with any of those gangs.
He knows that, mom.
This is one of those bad
boys from the neighborhood.
And I hate that you've go
to school with them too.
Can we just let Dr. Carter
do his job?
‐ Dr. Carter?
‐ 'Mm‐hmm.'
I am so happy to meet you.
'Antoine has so enjoyed
all you've been teaching him.'
And thank you for setting up
this interview for him to go to.
Oh, yeah. That's, um,
that's this afternoon, right?
Summer science lab.
‐ Maybe I won't go now.
‐ Of course you're going.
Looking like this?
What are they gonna think?
Hey, let's worry
about that later, huh?
Why don't you tell me
what happened?
Got mugged. Took my wallet.
Follow my finger
with your eyes.
You want an orbital series?
Uh..
...yeah.
Let's check
for a rim fracture.
‐ Does that hurt?
‐ No
No septal hematoma
and you didn't break your nose.
But you might have
an orbital fracture.
‐ What do we do about that?
‐ Just apply ice.
Keep his head elevated
when he sleeps.
We'll wait on the X‐ray
to see if you need antibiotics.
‐ Can he go to the interview?
‐ 'Mom!'
Oh, come on, Antoine.
It's not that bad.
You've worked hard for this.
We've worked hard for this.
I think your mom's right.
Hey, you'll be the candidate
they'll remember.
There was a man waiting down
in the ultrasound place.
I think he's gonna be
parting with his gall bladder
later today.
Really tall guy?
Red hair?
Yeah, that's the one.
You're right. They took him
out to surgery.
‐ How did you know?
‐ Oh, what a sweet little face.
‐ 'He's not going to be crying.'
‐ Oh, no, don't worry.
Uh, I think he'll be
pretty quiet.
No, that's what I mean
he's not gonna be
doing any crying.
This is Celinda Randlett,
in for a rule‐out appy.
‐ She's medically empathetic.
‐ Sorry?
Mm. I can tell
what's going on with people.
‐ Inside them.
‐ 'Kind of like a psychic.'
'No, I don't predict things.'
'I just feel what's happening
in the present.'
It started when I was a girl,
been with me ever since.
But she can't tell
about herself
'maybe appendicitis,
maybe not.'
It's not like I can treat
anybody for anything.
‐ By the way, when are you due?
‐ Excuse me?
Uh, you know,
I mean when's your due date?
Oh, right, that. Um, well, we'll
be expecting in early November.
Lydia, you want to
help me with this IV?
'Sure.'
Have you called psych yet?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Uh‐huh.
Hi, there, huh?
How are you doing?
You know, he's doing pretty
good. He's settling in.
Great. You got a stuffed cow.
That's pretty neat.
Jerry finally found
the camera.
Carol, can you, uh,
prop his head up a little bit?
‐ 'Yeah.'
‐ There you go.
Come on, little guy,
let's sit you up.
‐ He's been through quite a lot.
‐ 'Oh, yeah.'
'Wandering around by himself
about a block from here, lost.'
No, he doesn't look lost.
He looks found.
Alright, let me
just get one more.
Hey, where's
the roach coach?
Ah, let's go over
to Doc Magoo's.
So you wanted to talk
about something?
Yeah, about tonight,
actually.
I've never been
to this fundraiser before
but it's a dinner cruise
around the lake, swing band,
How bad can it be?
No, sounds wonderful. I'm really
looking forward to it.
It's just we've never
actually talked, you know.
Oh! Elizabeth!
‐ You alright?
‐ Yeah.
You okay in there?
You alright?
It's okay. It's alright.
We're gonna help you.
My dad.
Please help my dad.
Okay. It's okay. It's alright.
We need a couple of gurneys
out here!
He's had four of Ativan.
Alright, give him another two.
Good breath sounds.
BP's 125/75, pulse 100.
No signs of abdominal trauma.
Let's get the ultrasound on him
and see if there's any bleeding.
The pupils are equal
and reactive.
Here we go.
That's more like it.
Okay, Malik, load him
with a gram of Dilantin.
He'll need a C‐spine
and a head CT.
You got it.
No evidence of
intra‐abdominal bleeding.
Alright.
Well, that's a good sign.
I'm gonna go
talk to his daughter.
Hi.
I'm Dr. Greene.
‐ How are you doing?
‐ Okay.
Your dad's doing okay, too.
Ms. Knight,
why don't you fill me in?
Uh, this is Sarah..
‐ Uh, sorry. Sarah..
‐ Bengossi.
Bengossi and she is ten.
Uh, she has facial lacerations,
bruise to her forehead.
Normal cranial nerve exam,
no loss of consciousness.
She was in a car accident
right outside the ER.
She was driving.
I know about that part,
don't I?
So did you ask her
what happened?
Car accident.
And she said she hit
the el or something.
Call me crazy...but you're
too young to drive, aren't you?
Yeah.
Not that you're not
a good driver.
I mean, that el stanchion
just jumped right out
in the middle there,
didn't it?
So did something happen
to your dad?
Well, he has epilepsy.
'He hasn't had a seizure
in two years.'
When that happens
I know what to do.
He and mom taught us.
This time he was driving,
so you had to grab the wheel.
Well, it was kind of hard
to reach the pedals.
But you thought fast enough
to get him to the ER.
Yeah, well, we brought
my brother here last week.
He fell out of his bunk bed
and broke his collar bone.
Well, you did
a great job, Sarah.
And you know,
when I tell my 10 year old
that you got to drive,
she is gonna be so jealous.
Yosh, why don't you
get that cut cleaned up
and get her in
to see her dad.
‐ 'Sure, no problem.'
‐ 'Lucy, come with me.'
I was going to ask her
what happened.
I just didn't get a chance to,
and then you walked in‐‐
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Hold up!
Hold up, hold up!
Okay, hold up! Okay?
What's going on?
‐ Are you okay?
‐ I'm fine. I'm definitely fine.
You didn't seem definitely fine
this morning
when you were presenting
that patient to Dr. Romano.
I've seen you handle kids much
better than you did just now.
Dr. Greene, I didn't get
much sleep last night, alright?
You're gonna get even less
when you're a resident.
You gotta learn
to deal with it.
Jeanie. I was
looking for you.
Hey, did they
find anything?
No kids reported missing
in the past week.
‐ What about the neighborhood?
‐ Nothing's turned up yet.
But I'll let you know
if I hear anything else.
‐ Alright, I'll fill Kerry in.
‐ Okay.
‐ You gotta get back to work?
‐ Yeah.
They called in all
the PO's in this district.
Some lunatic is standing
on top of a van
down on Madison
waving a .45.
Shooting at people?
No, threatening
to kill himself.
‐ Catch you later.
‐ Okay.
Hey, uh, thanks
for the ride this morning.
My pleasure.
'So we have to use
this code first?'
‐ All calls get charged to it?
‐ Right.
So if I use the code
for my phone at home‐‐
‐ Yeah, good luck.
‐ I could use some help here.
Hello, ER.
Nope, she's not here.
Okay. McLucas has to cancel.
Call to reschedule.
Okay, I'll tell her.
‐ Anyone seen Carol?
‐ She's in curtain three.
Her doctor's appointment
was canceled.
‐ She needs to call McLucas.
‐ Oh, yeah, I know her.
She was, uh, Connie's OB
when she had her baby.
‐ Did you say baby?
‐ You don't think sh‐‐
Pop‐Tart in the toaster?
That empathetic woman
did ask about her due date.
That what woman?
Yosh, did you hear anything
about Carol being pregnant?
By Doug Ross?
Yeah, I'm sure
it would be Doug.
You know, McLucas
is also a GYN.
Maybe Carol's just
going in for a checkup
or a yeast infection?
‐ What is it, Jerry?
‐ They think Carol's knocked up.
‐ Wow. She happy about it?
‐ She hasn't told anyone.
She must have told someone.
What?
‐ How's he doing?
‐ He's doing great.
But I still can't get him
to tell me his name.
Definitely not a talker.
The police haven't
come up with anything yet.
How can you not know
where your child is
unless you abandoned him?
Labs came back.
He tested positive for opiates.
Great.
Drugs lying around the house.
'I mean, if he was crying a lot'
maybe they gave him something
to quiet him down.
I don't know.
I'll look in
on him later, okay?
Okay.
Hey.
He's alright now.
Although there's still
something inside of him.
I...just don't know
what it is.
Well, he has an infection.
Cellulitis.
No, that's not it.
So anyway, have you started
thinking about names?
'That's the hard part, you know.
Everybody's got an opinion.'
You are in the family way,
aren't you
'as my grandmother
used to say.'
How could you tell?
Like I said, I'm sensitive
to what's going on with people.
Like that gentleman over there,
I'm sad to say...has leukemia.
You could have looked
at his chart.
That's right.
I could have.
The odd thing is,
I can't tell
if you're having
a boy or a girl.
Oh, well, I'm just beginning
my second trimester, so..
No. I can usually tell
long before that.
So you've had this gift
your whole life?
Well, it doesn't seem
like much of a gift
when I see a gentleman
like that.
What?
Nothing.
Hey, Carla, uh, look,
I'm sorry I'm late.
It's okay.
I'm glad you called.
I needed to talk to you.
Yeah. I, uh..
Look, um,
I know I haven't..
...I haven't spoken to you
about Roger working
with Reese on language
and Martha called
and told me about
this morning.
Yeah, look.
I was angry at first,
but, uh, Carla, I know
you know, the more anybody
works with him
the quicker he's gonna learn,
so it's okay.
Peter..
...Roger and I got
married last weekend.
Wow.
There's a lot you haven't
told me yet.
His company is transferring
him to Germany, Hamburg.
I'm gonna sell the restaurant
and we're going..
...and I'm taking
Reese with us.
Carla, what are you..
We're, we're not gonna
even have this conversation.
‐ Peter.
‐ You know what?
There's no way in hell
am I gonna let that happen.
Look, he's gonna
have to be
with one of us
and I'm his mother.
'This will happen.'
Oh, Mark,
do you have a minute?
Uh, yeah. You want to talk
about something?
Yeah. I've moved
Mr. Bengossi
and his daughter, Sarah,
to the Exam Four.
That's what you
wanted to talk about?
Uh..
No time
like the present.
Alright.
I want to talk about, uh..
...you know,
what's been going on between us
over the past few weeks.
Something been going on?
Come on, we'll talk in here.
Look, Mark, it's no big deal
or anything.
It's‐it's just that..
Carol.
Ah, damn, I thought
I locked that door.
What are you doing?
‐ An ultrasound.
‐ On yourself?
Yes, Mark. My, uh, my doctor's
appointment canceled
and no one was using
the equipment.
'Well, why don't you
let us do it? Okay?'
If you must.
Let me get it.
You think it's too early to tell
if it's a girl or a boy?
It's never too early
to be inaccurate.
There's the heartbeat.
Any turtle sign?
I'm looking.
Okay.
There's the, uh..
‐ Mark?
‐ Uh‐huh.
What? Mark? What?
Heartbeat.
Yes, Mark. Elizabeth
already said that. What?
And what he means is
there's another heartbeat.
Twins?
Jerry, what's up
with Malik?
He's got a big grin
on his face.
He knows nothing.
I mean, uh, he's just
a naturally happy person.
‐ Yeah, that's Malik.
‐ Downright inspiring.
And infectious.
I'm happy, too.
Excuse me. Could somebody
please tell me
what the hell's going on
with these phones?
Dr. Romano has instituted
a code system
'so that people don't make
so many personal calls.'
‐ 'A code system?'
‐ 'Yes, sir.'
Poor kid ditched school
only to ride his bike
into the side of a bus.
Life is not fair. Lucy.
Um, X‐ray definitely shows
a fracture in the ankle.
‐ What kind?
‐ Comminuted.
Trimalleolar.
Which needs?
Open reduction
and internal fixation.
Mark, we got a double trauma
coming in.
Two GSWs. Police officer
and the man who shot him.
Wh‐what happened?
Some guy was waving a .45
around. Police got him.
Alright, find Carter or Weaver
and let's get set up.
Carol, did you..
Did you notice this before?
'Here.'
Looks like a small scar
from surgery.
Hey, it's okay.
We're just looking you over.
Yes. Alright.
Let's just look you over.
He's got a shunt.
From the ventricles
in his brain..
...to his peritoneum.
He was probably born
with hydrocephalus.
What's a shunt?
It's like a small tube
that runs through the body.
It drains excess fluid.
That must be what I've been
feeling inside him then.
Carol, please.
‐ I'm sorry.
‐ No problem. Mystery solved.
He could have
a shunt infection.
‐ We need to do a tap.
‐ Go bye‐bye?
Yeah, you wanna go bye‐bye,
don't you, huh?
‐ Where's the officer?
‐ What?
The cop.
He shot a cop.
Oh, another unit took him
to Mercy.
Approximately 40 years old.
GSW x 2 to the left chest.
Full arrest.
Two lines in.
Weak pulse in the field
and then he lost it.
Agonal rhythm on the scope.
This is Jeanie Boulet at County.
I need to check on an officer..
'Lucy, over here, I'll show you
how to put in an atrial line.'
‐ Thoracotomy tray.
‐ Hey, sorry to barge in.
Lucy, I got a call
from Psych.
Were you supposed to see
some kid like 20 minutes ago?
‐ Seth Willows. Yeah.
‐ 'Well, you better go.'
They said Mercy.
Could you check again, please?
‐ Asystole on the monitor.
‐ I'll take over bagging.
Alright, squeeze in that O‐neg
as fast as you can.
‐ Rib spreader.
‐ Well, I need suction.
'Whoa!'
Lap pad.
Left ventricle's shredded.
Give me a sponge stick.
Second shot transected
the ascending aorta.
Two units in.
Still asystole.
Okay, that's it.
There's nothing
we can do here.
I'm calling it.
Time of death, 15:09.
‐ Reggie.
‐ He didn't make it?
Not even close.
We heard that
an officer was shot.
Bullet grazed his shoulder.
He'll be okay.
Well, could have been
much worse.
Carter, let's go talk
about your student.
So it was you
who shot him?
Hey, Seth.
I'm so sorry
I'm late.
Um, a trauma came in
to the ER.
And I got delayed.
Okay, that's not true.
I forgot.
And I'm really sorry.
Seth?
‐ Seth?
‐ What?
What? What? What?
Please.
Can we just talk
about this?
I don't feel like
talking right now.
I know you're angry
and you have every right to be.
You know, I do need to get
on there at some point.
In a minute, Jerry.
Jerry, don't we have a
lost‐and‐now‐it's‐ours box
around here somewhere?
‐ Yeah, right here.
‐ Oh, thanks.
So the police find out
anything about that little boy?
‐ I hear he has a shunt.
‐ Nothing yet.
I'm e‐mailing all his info
and a scanned photo
to all the board‐certified
neurosurgeons.
All of them?
There's only 380
that specialize in pediatrics.
Hopefully, someone
will recognize him.
So we know where he belongs.
Three hundred and eighty?
And which one are you on?
Elizabeth, are you about ready
to take a break?
I wish. I've got a vegetectomy
and a valvuloplasty with Romano.
‐ How are you taking the news?
‐ I'm‐I'm in denial.
But thanks for asking.
Mark, what are you doing?
Uh, I have a woman
who has arthritis
and so I had to cut
her wedding ring off
and so I thought
I'd glue it back together
and hang it on a chain, so she
could wear it around her neck.
‐ That's very sweet of you.
‐ Yeah, I thought she'd like it.
‐ I'll catch you later.
‐ Uh‐huh.
Mark, what's that movie called
where, um, where all the people
turn into some kind of a pod?
What?
His life was
in his own hands, not yours.
There must have been
20 other cops out there.
I don't know.
My patrol car was closest.
It was just random, I guess.
Yeah. I don't think I believe
in random anymore.
You know, Reggie,
when I told you
that I was seeing
someone else..
...that wasn't
the complete truth.
I'd just found out that
I have hepatitis C.
I'm responding to medication.
It's under control.
You didn't think I could
handle that kind of news?
I couldn't handle
that kind of news.
I just kept thinking,
why me?
Why this on top of
everything else?
But after a while, I came
to see that I wasn't sick.
I was healed.
I don't think
I'm getting this.
I think that God kept
throwing things at me
until finally I realized
that it's not about
what happens to us
it's about how we deal with
what happens to us.
We have choices.
Our lives are in our own hands.
So you think what happened today
was some kind of message for me.
Maybe, what happened today
didn't happen to you.
Maybe it happened for you.
Yeah, I understand
what you're saying.
I'm not sure it makes me feel
all that much better.
Sitting here feels
pretty good.
Yeah, it does.
You're awfully quiet, Peter.
Bad mood?
Just working.
Ah, the nimble fingers
of a surgeon toiling away.
Suction, please. Let's give him
a nice, clean field.
I know you didn't expect
to be assisting today.
‐ But I hope you don't mind.
‐ Of course not.
This might very well be
Dr. Benton's last
cardiothoracic surgery..
Cleaned up the vegetation.
6‐0 Prolene.
'It's a shame you're not
gonna be able to use'
all that hard‐earned knowledge
while you're doing trauma scut.
Lizzie, I think
you've actually been spared.
Peter was chosen fairly.
I've made my peace with it.
An excellent attitude,
which is why I think
we should be trying keep you
on here at County.
'Whether it's with a
Cardiothoracic Fellowship'
or something else,
but I know that's something
you're still thinking about
and you should.
After all...it's what
any good candidate would do.
Dr. Weaver, someone's calling
about that little boy.
Thanks, Jerry. Chuny, can
you stay with him for a moment?
Hey, Carter, you busy? I need
you to look at that patient.
‐ Yeah, okay.
‐ Thank you
Antoine? That same kid
jump you again?
No.
Was it somebody
else from school?
No, it was the same dude.
I jumped him.
What?
The kid from this morning?
‐ You went after him?
‐ He took my wallet, man.
I can't be letting
that go down.
Why not? What'd you lose?
Ten‐fifteen bucks?
‐ He sounds like my mom.
‐ BP's 128/74. Pulse 96.
You got any pain
in your belly?
Did you get kicked
or punched in the stomach?
No, he only got me
in the face.
Looks like a Colles'
with dorsal angulation.
It's gonna need
a closed reduction.
‐ What's that?
‐ You broke your left wrist.
Can you feel this?
Ah, yeah.
What kind of sutures
do you want?
5‐0 Vicryl, 6‐0 Nylon.
I gotta have stitches?
Fifth metacarpal fracture
with rotational deformity.
You broke both your hands.
Let's get an orbital series.
Left hand, right wrist.
Call Ortho. That one's gonna
have to be pinned in the OR.
‐ I gotta have an operation?
‐ That's right.
Well, you wanted to blow
off your interview.
Maybe I can go
in a couple of days.
You're not getting into any
summer science lab. Not now.
You have to go to surgery
and have a pin
put into your right hand.
Then you get a cast
that goes from your elbow
all the way down
to your fingers.
But I can still
go to class.
It's a hands‐on program,
Antoine.
You're not gonna have
use of your hands.
You're not gonna be able
to dress yourself.
You're not gonna be able to
tie your own shoe.
And you're not gonna be able
to blow your own nose
for the next six weeks.
‐ It's not your problem.
‐ No?
I'm the one that's been
spending time with you
and showing you around here
for the last month.
Just trying to teach you
something, you know?
So you can go and screw it up
by having to go
beat down some punk
in the neighborhood.
‐ Carter.
‐ You don't know about it.
I know that it just
dragged you away
from the best opportunity
that you've ever been given.
No one gave me anything.
I earned that chance myself.
You just blew it,
all by yourself.
‐ Dr. Carter.
‐ Yes, Chuny?
Don't forget
to call Ortho.
Hey, Jerry, any word
on the kid yet?
Uh, just one call
for Dr. Weaver.
Yeah, it was the grocer
I met this morning.
He called to see
what had happened.
Labs came back.
Shunt's not causing
the infection.
Maybe it's the cellulitis.
Do you think his parents
abandoned him
because of the shunt?
What?
I mean, you know, because..
...he wasn't born normal.
Something was wrong with him.
Well, I'd hate to think so,
but anything's possible.
I'm going to go
check on him.
Okay, Seth,
we'll see you next week.
‐ Is your mom here?
‐ She's my foster mom.
‐ Okay. See you.
‐ Bye, Seth.
I'm sorry I had
to call you in.
Don't be. I'm glad you recognize
you were in over your head.
A lot of students don't
want to admit that.
I really blew it.
Kid like Seth, alcoholic father,
been bounced around a lot.
You can expect
a lot of setbacks.
They'll happen
again and again.
Well, I caused
this setback.
I was 20 minutes late
for our meeting today.
Well, that is something
that cannot happen again.
It won't.
I won't let it.
Now, from the sublime
to the utterly mundane
but then the appendectomy is
our bread and butter, isn't it?
Maybe not
if I do cardiothoracic.
Yeah, so...what do you think?
I think
you're an utter bastard
for mentioning it to me
in front of Peter.
‐ He's a big boy.
‐ It was mean.
Oh, well, he was mean
to me first.
He led me on to think that
he wanted the cardiothoracic
and then he took trauma.
Nevertheless, it was bad form
to speak to one colleague
in front of another
about a sensitive matter.
Geez, talk about
being sensitive.
‐ Robert.
‐ 'Donald!'
'How was your Whipple,
you lucky dog?'
A long six hours,
that's how.
Which is why I wasn't able
to find you earlier.
You initiated this, uh, code
phone system down in the ER?
‐ 'Yes, sir.'
‐ For what purpose?
Patients' families
can't sneak in calls
to their relatives
in Hoboken.
Which I believe
is not a big problem.
No, no, but you wanna know what
is? Employee personal calls.
'This allows us to track all
the outgoing calls internally.'
That way we don't have to wait
for the phone bills to arrive.
‐ So to speak.
‐ Uh, I see.
Big‐brother‐is‐watching
kind of thing.
No, monitoring might be
a better word.
Have you so little respect
for the people who work here
sometimes very long hours
and not a great deal of pay?
‐ I don't see it that way.
‐ Well, I do.
'So if you'd be so kind
as to take your..'
...code phone system
and put it where the sun‐‐
Got it.
Good.
Point taken.
That's really exciting.
Yeah, a new little voice
in the world.
Uh, but Carol actually
hasn't told anyone yet
so we're pretending
like we don't know.
Okay, I won't
say anything.
‐ Oop! Sorry!
‐ Aw, man!
‐ Uh, Carter..
‐ Look!
I'm sorry. I wanted to talk
to you about this..
I think it's great that
you went off the Ritalin.
I really do. I think
it's the right decision.
But I can't be holding
your hand through this.
I wouldn't be so stupid
as to ask you to.
‐ I know you're not capable.
‐ What does that mean?
You haven't liked me
from the get‐go.
I've never been quite
up to your standards.
I just want you to be
a better student.
‐ I want you to succeed.
‐ I know that's what you think.
But I think that you're
the one who wants to succeed
as a teacher, and..
...in order for that to happen
I would have to be
the perfect reflection of you
and that's not who I am.
I have a patient.
I'm dropping these off
for Dr. Weintraub.
Hey, Peter, I just want to
tell you I think Rocket
was a complete ass for doing
what he did in the OR today.
He can do whatever
he wants.
Yeah, well,
not entirely, but‐‐
It doesn't matter, Elizabeth.
Cardiothoracic, trauma.
I don't think I care
about any of it anymore.
Hang on.
What do you mean?
Carla came to see me today.
She married Roger.
She wants to take Reese
and, uh, move to Germany.
Something about
Roger's job.
Well, she can't.
I mean, legally,
she can't do that, can she?
Yeah, well, she won't
get the chance to.
Hey, Carol, this fax
just came in for you.
Thanks, Jerry.
‐ By the way, I know you know.
‐ Know what?
I know nothing. I'm a complete
walking lack of information.
‐ Oh, man.
‐ Carol, it's for you.
This is Carol Hathaway.
Yeah, you're doing
so much better, huh?
It's kind of a big day.
You want some juice?
I got some
apple juice here.
My name is Kerry.
Can you tell me your name?
Jack.
Jack Toberen.
So that's your name,
little guy Jack.
Wow. What a great name,
Jack, huh?
So you got a response?
Pediatric neurosurgeon
on the north side.
'He recognized the photo.
He put the shunt in.'
He saw Jack about two months ago
for a follow‐up.
‐ He called the parents.
‐ They're coming in?
Oh, yeah, in a big hurry.
I just spoke to the mother
on the phone.
Jack was kidnapped
three weeks ago.
‐ What?
‐ Unreal, huh?
By the nanny
and the drugged‐out boyfriend.
They must've been
the ones who abandoned him.
‐ 'I guess so.'
‐ 'There you go. Oop.'
I called the police.
They're on their way in.
So now we know
who you are, Jack. Yeah.
Your mom and dad are coming in
and you get to go home.
Yeah.
Alright.
‐ Hey, Peter.
‐ Hey, Lizette.
Carla won't be home
until 7:30.
Yeah, I know. Actually,
it might even be later.
Uh, maybe not till 10:00.
Hey, man.
She didn't tell me
she'd be late.
I told her I'd tell you
when I got here.
You know, I don't
have to take Reese.
It's just that Carla
was pretty sure
you would have
some plans tonight.
Oh, I was planning
to go to the Quartz Lounge.
Um, I‐I kind of have been
seeing this trumpet player.
‐ Oh, a musician, huh?
‐ Yeah.
Yeah, well, you better
watch yourself.
Say bye, Reese.
‐ Bye‐bye, Reese.
‐ Say bye.
Bye‐bye.
Bye.
So is your mom more
or less pissed off
than I imagine she is?
That'd be more
or less than you?
That's fair.
She's acting like I'll never
play the violin again.
It's pretty funny.
I heard it
in a stupid TV movie.
What are you doing watching
TV when you got homework?
Oh, man, you are my mom.
I don't know about that.
See, I think I want
the best for you..
...but I suspect that
she's...does a better job
of appreciating you
for who you are.
As long as I grow up
to be just like her.
I know that routine.
My family wanted me to grow up
to be a rich, white guy.
Damn, they must be dancing.
You don't make that kind of
money in emergency medicine.
I think they figure they'd
settle on two out of three.
I wish I hadn't blown
that summer thing, Dr. Carter.
You'll get another chance.
I mean now I'll be spending
my time bagging groceries.
Actually, I'm not even sure
you're gonna be doing that.
'I'll be right here
when you get out.'
‐ We'll still make it.
‐ Doesn't matter.
This is worth staying for.
Carol!
Wow, you two look great.
I'll walk out with you.
You know what,
I have to check on a chart.
Oh, return a phone call.
Okay.
Goodnight.
Surprise!
‐ Oh, man.
‐ 'We got you.'
‐ She got us.
‐ What are you doing?
We know you haven't officially
told us about the baby‐‐
But we couldn't sit on it
another darn minute.
'We just wanted you to know
how happy we are.'
And we're gonna get you
something better‐‐
But for now..
Oh, man! God!
Guys..
Hey, Carol,
need a Lamaze coach?
‐ You're it, Malik.
‐ Alright.
Yeah.
Oh, this is amazing. I, uh..
I've just been overwhelmed
with this news myself.
And, uh, today I found out
I'm‐I'm having twins.
‐ Wow.
‐ Hey!
So, um, I didn't know
when or how to tell people
and I'm, I'm really glad that
I can share this with you now.
‐ So thank you.
‐ Congratulations.
'Hi, you've reached Peter.'
'If you wanna leave a message,
please do so after the tone.'
'Peter, are you there?'
'Is Reese there with you?'
'Peter.'
'Peter, what are you doing?'
'You know darn well Reese
is supposed to be here tonight.'
'Peter, if you're there,
please pick up.'
So we missed the boat.
Oh, well, cruises
are overrated anyway.
Shall we?
So about
what's been going on.
See, the thing is
I'm not exactly sure
what has been going on.
What do you mean?
Look, Peter and I jumped
into something rather quickly
and when it wasn't working,
we both jumped out.
‐ Is it still unresolved?
‐ No, no, no, it is.
Uh..
...the thing is you
and I have been seeing
a lot of each other
and it's, uh..
It's been great.
But, uh, it's not anything
that I was looking for
and it's caught me
off balance, rather
which I'm not used to.
It makes me
rather nervous.
Elizabeth, I don't..
...I don't know
what's going to happen..
...but I do know
how I feel.
And I feel like..
...I've found something..
...amazing.
And I wanna be here.
I wanna get to know you..
...and not be scared.
I would hate to miss
another boat.
Mmm.