- Previously, on "The Resident"...
- I saw Yorn.
Did he say why
he hasn't hired a CEO?
- They're selling the hospital.
- Oh.
I need to show Yorn
that Chastain
is worth a hell of a lot more
than he thinks it is.
My father, when he died,
I didn't even get
to say goodbye.
What I would do for just
one more day with my dad.
Sorry. Losing someone
is never easy.
I'll get someone
to cover for you.
No.
I'm okay.
I just need a minute.
It's official.
A baby?
What is this?
Uh, breakfast in bed.
- Where did you even get this?
- Ah...
Pancakes?
Your favorite.
- Blue wildflowers.
- Aw...
Nic's favorite berries. Ah!
Get in there,
get in there.
All right.
Mmm. Mmm.
Whose dad do we want
to call first, yours or mine?
I think we should wait
a little longer.
Well, sure,
there's no rush to tell anyone.
I mean, right?
Your pregnancy
is already further along
than it was last time.
This time is gonna be different,
and it's...
it's gonna be okay.
You know that, right?
But we can't.
I had a miscarriage,
and it was awful.
And if it happens again,
I don't want
to have to tell everyone,
so I just...
just want to wait
a little longer, okay?
Of course.
Whatever you want.
Thank you.
I'm coming.
All right!
Did I park in someone's spot
or something?
Okay!
Mom. What are you...
- what are you doing here?
- Surprise.
I thought I'd
finally come visit my s...
What happened to you?
Oh, my God.
Were you in a car accident?
I knew something was wrong.
I knew it.
A mother always knows.
Mom, I'm fine.
We had an ER patient
with psychosis,
and... someone should have
restrained him immediately,
but we missed it,
and then he was...
swinging at a nurse, and I...
uh, went in to help.
Yeah, in retrospect, I should
have just left it to the...
security.
You are a hero.
My poor boy.
But where are your pajamas, huh?
And, uh...
what is that smell?
You know, just wait right here.
I just got to... I'll wash up.
Hey, don't worry.
I-I'm going to take care
of everything.
The way you drive
like a hellion,
I was sure
you'd beat me here.
Normally, I would beat you here,
because you drive like a nun,
but today... I stopped for this.
- Doughnuts.
- Mm.
Maple. I believe
they're your favorite.
And I believe you mentioned
a fondness
for breakfast burritos.
Oh, I do not hate
this part of being
in a relationship.
Oh, such high praise.
Tell me, what can I do to make
sure you stay this effusive?
There is one thing.
Uh, you can...
Marry me.
*The Resident*
Season 04  Episode 04
Title: "Moving on and Mother Hens"
Aired on: February 02, 2021
My 0-1 visa is expiring.
I knew it was coming,
so I applied way in advance.
Yesterday I found out
it was denied.
Mina, you should have
told me this yesterday.
I was gonna tell you
when I came over last night,
but you had made
such a nice dinner,
and I didn't want to ruin it,
so... I said nothing.
And then we got occupied
with other things.
I don't understand
why the government
would deny your renewal,
as many American lives
as you've saved.
Since February of 2020,
Nigerians are no longer able
to obtain... visas to immigrate
to the U.S. permanently.
If I want to stay,
I have to find a way
to renew my current visa
or marry an American citizen.
- You are terrible at this.
- I applied months in advance.
No, no, I mean this.
You know, Mina,
proposals usually come...
with a ring.
And a carefully crafted speech
About commitment and love,
full of compliments.
Flowers wouldn't hurt, either.
Okay, so will you do it?
You didn't even buy me
a nice dinner first.
I got you doughnuts.
True. And they're maple.
Hey. Come here.
Mm...
Breathe.
It's gonna be okay, Mina.
We can make this work.
All right?
Love.
Honor.
Obey.
Ooh, I love the way that sounds.
- Don't you?
- Okay, uh,
maybe we are rushing this.
Oh, no,
we're definitely rushing this.
What's that about?
Good morning.
Good question.
How's the other guy look?
Funny.
I couldn't sleep,
so I went out for a bike ride
in the middle of the night.
And it was pitch black,
and I was tired.
Yeah, I know.
- It was stupid.
- Mm.
I, uh, hit a curb
and I wiped out.
Oh, and then my mother showed up
this morning unannounced and,
uh, I lied to her about it,
because I didn't want her
to worry.
Anything else you want to know?
Well, your father
passed away, and...
It's been months.
- I'm fine.
- You're not fine.
You're grieving. You don't need
to put a timeline on it.
Getting through it takes
as long as it takes.
- Let's just talk about how you're feeling.
- Okay.
I said fine.
You don't need to ask me again.
Excuse me? Excuse me?
Can we get some help?
Okay, what's going on?
My daughter Trinity needs
medical attention.
No, I don't.
What's happening, Trinity?
Show them.
It looks worse than it is.
My mom is making this
a big thing.
Your hand looks like
a sea monster.
It's a big thing.
Whatever.
I tripped on the stairs.
You, too?
Um, bike accident.
I don't need sedation.
Just pop my fingers
back into place.
Trust me,
I have a high pain tolerance.
Look how well she tolerated
the existential pain
of being stuck at home
with her mom during lockdown.
I was supposed to speak
at my graduation.
Then I didn't go to college
in the fall
'cause it's all
distance learning.
Apologies for our family drama.
It's been a year.
Well, we're ready
to fix your fingers
if you really want to do it
that way.
- Positive?
- Yep.
Okay.
Trinity, look at your mom.
Let's remember the good parts
of lockdown.
The tap shoes.
The quail.- -
- Quail?
- We incubated eggs
and raised them
o adulthood.
- Kept the only girl.
- Sidney Vicious.
Ah, Sidney Vicious.
I love that name.
She's coming with me
when I get my own apartment,
which I'm supposed
to look at today.
Finally.
You're all done.
You should be good
to apartment hunt now.
Actually,
there's something else.
- This wasn't Trinity's first fall.
- Mom, stop.
- You said we didn't have to...
- She's been off lately.
Something
with her balance, maybe.
We can take a look at
that.
I said no.
I just want to go and get my...
If you want a cosigner
for that apartment,
you will stay in that bed
and let the doctors work.
It will be quick.
We'll get X-rays on your hand
just to be safe.
And then we'll be back
for a full physical.
I'll let imaging know.
Procurement
coordinator to the ICU.
Quail.
Maybe Nic and I need
to bring some variety
to our chicken coop, huh?
Well, it sounds like Trinity...
wants independence
more than any bird.
I hear the mother-daughter thing
can be tough sometimes.
Yeah, the mother-son thing is
no walk in the park, either.
My mom wants to know
where I keep the disinfectant,
the trash bags,
the good toilet paper.
This is the
last thing I need right now.
I don't know. Maybe
you can set some boundaries
with her or something?
I'm not really looking
for advice here.
I'm doing my job,
I'm not making any mistakes.
Anything beyond that
is not your business.
It's my business that my friend
is upset and grieving.
Can you stop trying
to doctor this?
Okay? I need a minute.
Can you handle the exam?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
So the good news is
that the PR coming in
from my show's segment
on the patient helped.
And Yorn thinks that Chastain
might still be valuable enough
to take selling the hospital
off the table.
The bad news is,
they're talking about filling
the empty CEO seat with me.
I thought you weren't keen
on the job anymore,
- you were focusing on surgery.
- Trust me, I don't want it.
Even if I said yes,
Red Rock could
still dump Chastain
if we don't rebound
financially.
And we'd be under the thumb
of some other conglomerate.
And there are companies
out there
that are way worse
than Red Rock.
Well, here's something
to cheer you up.
There's a rather attractive
young woman over there
who can't take her eyes off you.
Do you know her?
No.
- No.
- Oh.
Here she comes.
I'm so sorry to interrupt,
but can I?
Interrupt, I mean?
I love your show.
- Ah.
- That segment on scurvy.
I-I don't have scurvy,
but you made me feel like I did.
Well, that's high praise.
That's...
that's very kind of you.
- What's your name?
- Fiona.
Well, it's lovely
to meet you, Fiona.
Thank-thank you
for watching the show.
You're... so nice.
Could I?
Yeah. Of course. Of course.
This is my lucky day.
- Thank you.
- You bet.
You are so happy right now.
No comments from you.
All right.
I've got some good news
for you, Trinity.
- Nothing's broken.
- Great.
I don't need any more tests?
Let's get out of here.
No. Get back in that bed.
Trinity?
Walk toward me.
Your steps are uneven.
Did you feel a little
off-balance when you fell?
I mean, I wasn't
totally awake yet.
I was tired.
I feel like I've been tired
the whole...
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
My heart's a little fluttery,
that's all.
Heather.
Need to get her on the monitor.
Let's see what's going on.
I'm fine.
I'm f...
I knew it.
What's wrong with her?
Easy, easy, easy.
She just fainted.
What happened?
You just bought yourself some
more time in the hospital.
Got a call I have a visitor.
Hi again.
Um...
Fiona? Right?
I'm sorry to drop in
unannounced. I'll be quick.
I'm actually curious
about employment at Chastain.
Uh, well...
I admire the gusto.
Um, hiring is sort of...
- It's outside my purview.
- I know, it's just I'm...
I'm trying to switch paths,
so I'm looking
for something entry-level.
And after seeing
the way that you
talk about Chastain
on your show, and then...
when I met you in person,
I got all inspired.
It felt like fate.
Well, HR is on two, east wing.
And you can tell them
Dr. Bell sent you.
Thank you so much.
- You're amazing.
- Okay.
Yes!
Hey. So...
I assume you've spoken to Mina.
I talk to Mina all the time.
So you know about the proposal?
No.
No, you-you did not
propose.
You've been dating
for, like, five seconds.
Why would you jump the gun like
that? - Mina Okafor proposed to me.
Yeah, she needs a green card
so she doesn't get deported.
- What?
- Yeah.
How can I help?
Well...
You can help plan a wedding.
It has to happen quick,
so it can't be elaborate.
You know, small guest list,
tasteful, intimate.
Wait, so this is a real wedding?
Well, under normal
circumstances,
it'd be way too early.
- Way.
- But...
we will rise to the occasion.
And just figure out
if you want to be married
while being married.
Well, that's what
most people do anyway, right?
They're just not honest
about it.
All right. Oh.
Duty calls.
You are a doll.
Nic?
You okay?
Yeah.
Are you okay?
Yeah. Well, it turns out biking
at night is not a good idea,
which is why I was
looking for you.
Uh, I need a small favor.
- Okay.
- So, I can't sleep.
And I am exhausted.
So I was taking meds to help,
but my doctor's out of town,
so he can't refill the script.
- Mm-hmm?
- So I just need
something to sleep,
just enough for a couple days.
I mean, Devon, we're friends.
We don't have
a clinical relationship.
I know, but if-if I don't sleep,
I'm not gonna be able to focus.
And I'm not gonna ask Conrad,
'cause he's gonna worry
for nothing.
My next day off,
I'll go straight to the doctor.
- Are you on any other medication?
- No.
And this is just to
get you over the hump?
Yes, this one time.
All right, I'm sending this
to the pharmacy.
Zolpidem, five milligrams.
I'm only giving you three pills.
If you need more,
you go to your doctor.
For sure.
Thank you.
Hey, are you sure you're okay?
Yeah.
Good.
Trinity's arrhythmia broke
on its own.
Her heart is
structurally normal.
So why are these cardiac events
happening?
This is a 19-year-old female
with sporadic runs
of non-sustained V tach
that are symptomatic.
Echo is not impressive.
Interesting.
That is a wide-open box.
- Any other history?
- Her mother reports
difficulty with coordination.
Otherwise healthy.
All right, well,
keep her on telemetry.
And grab me another EKG
now that she's in sinus.
Will do.
Come in.
Sorry again.
I left my résumé
with the lady in HR.
Is there something else?
I thought
you'd want to see it.
Okay.
Thank you.
This is not a résumé.
- Let's call it my headshot.
- Oh, no, no.
This is... No, no.
This is not your head.
And-and this,
this is not appropriate.
You know, I'm gonna ask you...
to leave.
- Don't pretend this isn't real.
- Just...
- stand back. Kit.
- I know you want me.
Kit. Dr. Voss. Could you
come in here for just...
- just a moment?
- Yes, Randolph.
I know you.
- You're the girl from this morning.
- Fiona.
She's acting psychotic.
And security's been notified.
You called security?
- Well...
- because
we are gonna get you some...
We're gonna get you some help.
Stop her! Stop her!
- Fiona. Fiona. Fiona.
- I need five of Haldol for IM.
Look at me. Look at me.
We're gonna get you some help.
We'll take a little trip
down to the ER.
I'll be there with you
the whole time.
There you go.
There you go, darling.
Just give it a minute.
You'll be okay.
Nice work.
Hey, Mom.
Can you pick up laundry
detergent on your way home?
- I had plenty.
- Now you have none,
but you have clean clothes
and linens.
You didn't have to do that.
Your home is lonely.
You are lonely.
You need a partner.
No. No, I don't.
No, don't-don't do that.
Check your phone.
Don't forget the detergent.
Love you.
Are you getting deported?
I will kill AJ Austin.
You can't marry a corpse, Mina.
Why didn't you tell me?
Uh, because saying it
makes it real.
Not saying it
doesn't change that.
I didn't want you to get upset.
All right?
It's not an ideal situation,
but AJ and I are handling it.
We'll do it quickly.
And I'll be safe
from deportation.
"Quickly"?
He wants a wedding.
This is real to him.
Of course it's real.
Sort of real.
It's also business.
A real marriage
and a business arrangement
are two separate things.
- I mean, it can't be both.
- Why not?
By definition, a marriage is
a business arrangement.
You are linking your finances,
your housing arrangement,
your professional
and biological plans
to someone else.
It makes sense.
It makes sense
if you're in love.
Are you in love with him?
Okay.
The reason I didn't want you
to get upset
is because I think
you also have a secret.
Yesterday, you took a power nap
in the nurses' lounge.
You have developed
the superpower
to smell doughnuts a hall away.
Your hair is extra lustrous.
And some might say
you're glowing.
- Okay, it's early.
- Mm-hmm.
- I'm not ready to talk about it.
- Okay.
I will keep your secret.
Please keep mine.
For now.
And congratulations.
Your girl here is
a missing person.
I called her house
and talked to her roommate.
Two days ago, she left for
groceries and never came home.
Pravesh said
her head CT came back normal.
No drugs in her system.
Did the roommate say anything
about a history
- of mental illness?
- I asked.
None that she knew of.
She's trying to get in touch
with her family
on the West Coast.
Then maybe this is
a new diagnosis.
- It might be her first psychotic break.
- Mm.
She's in the right age range.
Can't treat her
till we find out what it is.
Well, Dr. Pravesh is on his way
to do a full exam.
- I'll keep you posted.
- Okay. Thank you.
Lots of people faint.
True.
But you fainted
because your heart
was beating abnormally.
We need to find out why.
We ordered a few more lab tests,
okay, Trinity?
Mmm. Your coffee smells
like heaven.
- Is that hazelnut?
- Yeah.
- I'm gonna go get us some, Trin.
- That's weird.
I can't smell it.
What do you mean
you can't smell it?
What about this?
My perfume?
She can't have COVID, can she?
Let's all just take a breath.
Loss of smell can be a symptom
of multiple things.
- No, no, no, no.
- We were so careful.
We-we-we got
all our groceries delivered.
- We didn't see friends. We...
- It could be allergies or a cold.
Even when we joined a pod
and we tested positive,
we-we-we were lucky because
we didn't have any symptoms.
Okay. Good, good.
The danger's supposed
to be over.
It's supposed to be... safe.
- Whoa.
- Mom.
- Whoa. Gotcha, gotcha.
- Mom!
Mom...
- are you okay?
- Your mom's stable.
They're just taking a look at
her heart with an ultrasound.
Akinesis
of the postero-basal wall.
Circumflex infarct.
That explains
the non-diagnostic EKG.
Is that bad?
It sounds bad.
Your mom collapsed
because she's
actually having
a heart attack right now.
Oh, my God.
How is that possible?
Her EKG shows evidence
of another heart attack
in the past.
Has your mom ever had chest pain
or shortness of breath before?
The protests.
When George Floyd was murdered.
We made our signs
and we went out there.
It was supposed to be peaceful,
but it didn't matter.
They tear gassed us all.
That must've been awful.
I recovered pretty quickly,
but Mom said
she felt like an elephant
was sitting on her chest.
I wanted to take her
to the hospital,
but she was afraid we were
gonna catch COVID again.
Back then, we didn't know
if that was possible.
She was afraid.
Okay, that could be it.
Tear gas can cause stress
on the heart
and aggravate cardiac issues.
Your mom has
a good chance of recovery.
We need to get her
to a cath lab now.
We'll put a stent in to open up
the clogged arteries
- in her heart.
- Don't worry.
It's a routine procedure, okay?
Mom?
I love you.
I love you, too, baby girl.
I'll be right back to cosign
for that apartment.
Okay.
Okay, you got to
get it closer to the vessel wall
before you deploy.
I'm trying to rotate it,
but I can't get the stent
- into position.
- Well, see, it's a tight spot.
No blood flow.
She's in V tach!
Charge the defib to 200.
Any sign of trauma?
Not yet.
There's no bruising,
no breaks in the skin at all.
It looks like Fiona works
as a paralegal
while in law school.
No edema. No rashes.
She posts pictures of her food
and her feet in sandals.
No clues there.
Uh, hold on.
There's bruising
on her lower flank.
Grey Turner's sign?
Wait, wait. Feel this.
You're right.
There's a mass.
Let's take a look.
It's right there.
It's a tumor
right above her kidney.
Extending deep
towards her spine.
How long has she been walking
around with that in her?
If this is an adrenal tumor
secreting hormones,
it could be causing
her psychosis.
Certainly could explain her
interest in the famous Dr. Bell.
Zoom in.
There... active extravasation.
She's got
a retroperitoneal bleed.
Could've happened when she
was fighting with security.
Well, if we don't
get it out soon,
she's just gonna bleed out.
I'll get an OR ready.
I gave the lab a heads-up
about putting a rush
on Trinity's bloodwork.
Nope. It's not my business.
- You do you.
- It's not a dating app.
It's my mom.
It's the tenth eligible woman
she's sent me today.
You getting enough sleep?
Oh, you're talking to Nic?
No, but... if she
noticed you look tired,
it's because you do.
Yeah, I'm tired.
But I'm handling it.
I get it. I've been there.
So much of what we fight against
is preventable.
It's like...
why am I drowning in debt
for this?
It's exhausting.
I don't know
how many different ways
- I can tell you that I'm fine.
- You don't have
to talk to me... I'll give you
a name, someone good.
But I'm not looking
to talk to anyone.
Drop it.
- Hi.
- How's my mom?
Is she okay?
Dr. Austin and Dr. Okafor
are still with her
in the cath lab.
While we're waiting,
we want to run
a couple other tests on you.
I bet your mom would feel better
if we had some answers
when she came out.
Put your hands up like this.
Okay.
This is my fault, isn't it?
I pushed back about everything.
I argued with her all last year.
I'm why she was so stressed.
No. No, you didn't do this.
This past year was stressful
for everyone.
You can't blame yourself
for circumstances
that are out of your control.
That was a near miss
with that stent deployment.
Fine job back there.
We do make a good team.
That we do.
I have bad news.
I spoke
to an immigration lawyer.
If we get married,
it could raise red flags.
Why?
We've known each other
for years.
It's easy to prove we have
a basis for a real marriage.
But this version of us is new.
We don't have photos or records
of vacations together.
The government
will ask "Why now?"
They can ask
all the questions they want.
We got nothing to hide.
The lawyer said
the presumption will be
that our marriage
is not bona fide.
If there is an investigation
and it goes badly,
I'll get deported and not
allowed back in the country.
Not allowed back in the country?
You could face
felony charges for perjury.
Not if I don't perjure myself.
Mina, if we end up in court,
I will tell them the truth.
The marriage is real.
Unless you're saying
you don't think it'll be real.
Okay, AJ,
you're not hearing me.
If we get married
right after my visa denial,
no matter what we say or do,
I can still get deported.
It's putting us both at risk
and I refuse to do that.
- So you're saying the wedding is off.
- I am.
We've got to deal
with this bigger problem first.
You can't marry or even date
someone who isn't here.
Ah.
Murgh makhani, Bharta,
Coconut barfi,
all of your favorites.
Mom, the hospital
has a cafeteria.
Well, now you don't
have to go there.
Or come home to filth.
Your room was
particularly a disaster.
- I discarded these things.
- Okay, stop.
Okay?
Did you like any of the pictures
that I sent you?
Hmm?
Listen, I am not there
right now.
Dating is not exactly
on my radar, okay?
Let-Let's go.
I thought we could eat together.
God, you cannot
just show up at my job
and expect me to drop everything
and go eat barfi with you.
You need to listen.
I-I eat cafeteria food,
I have women over
who might not be Indian,
and that is my choice.
I don't want any of this.
I don't need it.
You should have asked
before coming here.
We both miss your father.
I thought we could
help each other.
Well, you should have
called first.
My calls go
straight to voice mail.
And when you do answer,
it's always,
"I only have a minute,"
or "I have to get back."
I didn't ask if I could visit
because I knew you'd say no.
Two minutes in the microwave.
Well, the famous Sidney Vicious
won't be lonely tonight.
We should be able
to get you out of here soon.
You have a rare genetic
disease called Refsum syndrome.
- Does my mom have it, too?
- No.
She's a carrier of the mutation,
but to get the disease,
you have to have
two genetic defects.
Basically, y-your body
isn't able to process
a certain type of fat.
Over time, that causes toxicity
to multiple organs.
That's why you were falling.
And it's why your heart
was giving you trouble.
Here's the good news:
It's totally manageable.
We caught it early,
which is fantastic.
And my buddy Dr. Pravesh and I,
we think changes
in your diet are gonna
do the trick.
So we'll hook you up
with a nutritionist,
and we'll schedule
regular appointments
to keep an eye on everything.
I acted like everything was fine
because I wanted it to be.
You wanted life to be normal.
We all do.
Yeah, but Mom knew something
was wrong with me.
Yeah, well,
sometimes our parents
see things that we don't see
in ourselves.
I stomped around like
the world was happening to me.
While she was the one who
actually had something wrong.
Eh, don't take that on.
You and your mom,
you got through the impossible.
Cut yourself a break.
Celebrate it.
I've been so annoyed with my mom
this whole time,
but now it's like...
I just want her to be okay.
I need her.
I'm pretty sure
she needs you, too.
It's Nic.
Go.
Oh, wow.
Doesn't matter how many times
I've seen one of these.
It's different when it's ours.
It's magical.
Oh, look. That's the heartbeat.
- Ah. Looks like a fighter.
- I agree.
Growing just like it should be.
That is a perfect baby.
This is good.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Want to know
what you're having?
Uh...
Mom?
I'm right here, Mama.
Hi, baby.
The doctors fixed your heart.
We managed to place a stent
in your blocked artery.
You get to go home
in a couple of days.
Well, we didn't make it
to your apartment.
It's okay.
I'm not moving out
anymore.
I'm gonna stay home with you.
The hell you are.
You think I helped those wings
grow strong just to clip them?
You're ready to fly.
But what if you need me?
Then I'll call you.
Pickups to me.
These buggers are everywhere.
Well, we're
making good progress.
Last time with one of these
tumors, it took hours to ligate
all vessels.
I think we're lucky she's young,
and we caught this
while it was still small.
Metz?
I see why you
don't want to be CEO.
You're a wizard in the OR.
Still, Chastain needs you.
It's about quality of life, Kit.
That's why
you should do it.
As CEO,
you can hire anyone you want.
Remind me, Randolph.
What are the
"Cs of medical cash flow"?
- I'm not doing that.
- I'll start.
Chemo, cataracts, colonoscopies.
Come on, give me one.
Cancer.
Already covered when
I said "chemo." Try again.
Cosmetic surgery.
There you go.
You could gain financial ground
by hiring a rock star
plastic surgeon.
Like your stepson Jake.
- Cauterize.
- I am.
Trust me, the kid doesn't want
to be anywhere near me,
much less work under me.
Maybe you could sweeten the deal
if you took Yorn's offer.
Did I...
did I give you a picture?
Don't worry. It went straight
in the shredder.
Never mind. I don't want
to remember anything else.
No, it's not your fault.
You had a very rare type
of tumor
that secreted hormones,
and it caused your behavior
to change.
- What happens now?
- We have to wait
for pathology results
to stage it appropriately,
but we have some
of the finest oncologists
here who will help
with the next steps.
And we can already see
your mental status is improving.
Try not to be embarrassed.
If you hadn't followed
Dr. Bell here,
who knows when
you would've been diagnosed.
- Okay. But still, Dr. Bell.
- Mm.
You're like four decades
too old for me.
I don't think four is right.
You're like my grandpa.
Or father.
It's fortunate we caught it
when we did. Get some rest.
Let's go, Gramps.
Thanks.
Hey, Nic.
- Hey.
- Um...
I'm giving these
back to you.
And, um, I shouldn't have
put you in that weird position.
I'm sorry.
It did...
feel strange giving them to you.
Um, but are you okay?
Everyone keeps asking me that.
I guess I need
to figure it out.
Yeah, figuring it out
will help.
And you know I'm here
if you need anything, right?
Yeah.
- Thanks again.
- Mm.
What's all that about?
Well, I was just
texting everybody.
Check your phone.
I was with Nic
when she sent that text.
She didn't say why.
- Do you know why we're here?
- We'll find out soon enough.
I'm guessing a baby.
They just got married.
- It's got to be a baby.
- Shh. Don't jinx it.
We wanted you
to be the first to know.
- You're having a baby?
- Don't jinx it.
- - Guess it was obvious.
- Oh!
- Fantastic news.
- Yeah, I'll have that now.
Here you go. Here you go.
- You want to do the honors?
- Thank you.
It's a girl.
You didn't waste any time there.
Yay! Congrats!
Cheers. Cheers.
All right.
♪ Reason. ♪
Hey, Mom.
I wanted to see for myself
that you are okay.
And now that I have,
I will be on a plane tomorrow.
No.
Mom, I'm...
I'm sorry I lied to you.
I didn't get this
from an ER patient.
I told my friends at work that
I got in a bike accident,
and that was a lie, too.
Last night, I went to a bar,
and there was this guy,
six foot five, huge arms,
minding his own business.
I just got in a fight with him.
Oh, Devon.
Mom, that's not even
the first dumb thing I've done.
I just...
keep thinking about Dad,
you know, and...
what I could have done
different.
You know?
You cannot blame yourself.
If I...
just moved him
to a different hospital,
or spoke
to his doctors more often...
If I had made him
stop driving that taxi.
No, Mom.
That was his choice.
And then,
the system failed him.
And it failed us.
Listen, that isn't your fault.
Well, it's not yours, either.
No, his death was out
of our control.
Yeah.
We need each other.
Okay?
Please stay.
I will. I will.
Mm.
Someone has to help you eat
all of this food.
You could always make
a nice dinner
for one of the lovely women in
the pictures that I sent you.
Oh, my... You don't quit.
AJ?
Well, if you came here
to wish me good luck,
I'm offended.
I can do an inguinal
hernia repair in my sleep.
I'm not here
for luck.
I need to tell you something.
I'm listening.
I don't often apologize,
because I rarely
make mistakes,
but today,
I made one.
I shouldn't have
proposed to you like that
without doing
the proper research.
You had every right
to be upset.
You were in a tough spot.
You still are.
I asked you the impossible and
you agreed without hesitation.
I'm grateful for that.
Okay.
Nic asked me
if I'm in love with you.
I didn't know
what to say then, but...
now I do.
It's yes.
I am...
in love with you.
So the end of today's
roller coaster ride is here.
And what a beautiful ending
it is.
Except, I may still
be deported.
No. No, no,
that's not gonna happen.
We are not gonna
let that happen, guaranteed.
You know I love you, too,
right?
I suspected so.
What'd I tell you? Huh?
Magnificent lobby.
I think it would fall right
n line with what... - Jacob.
Your, uh, office
was my next stop
after I finished this tour.
Well, uh,
pardon the interruption.
Do you mind if I just steal him
for just a moment?
I've decided to accept
Red Rock's generous offer.
I'm confident, as CEO,
I can turn
our financial situation around.
And I have
some initial thoughts about...
Since last we spoke,
Red Rock has had
to make
some very difficult decisions.
So that CEO spot...
No longer open.
Who are you filling it with?
No one. We sold Chastain.
Well, um, I'll be happy to work
with the new conglomerate
- in any way...
- Look around. Look around.
We are standing on
a prime piece of real estate.
These buyers are developers.
Yeah.
They're turning Chastain
into luxury condos.
My apologies.
Why don't we walk over
to the elevators here.
I want you guys to get that
magnificent view from up top.
Captioning sponsored by
20th CENTURY FOX TELEVISION
and TOYOTA.
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
Sync corrections by srjanapala