Touching down at Med
in eight minutes.
Sounds good.
Hey, Daniel.
What's up?
How was your weekend?
I actually went out on a date.
Nice!
Mmm.
With that guy you met
at the jazz club? At Andy's?
Nope, I met him online.
Online?
I thought
I'd give it a shot.
Wow.
I don't know, man.
Placing the deepest core
of my innermost self
in the hands
of an algorithm?
Not sure
I'm there yet.
Well, where else am I
gonna meet anybody?
Are you gonna go out
with him again?
Nah, but I'm gonna
keep trying.
NICU wants to know
how he's looking.
Uh...
He's tolerating the ECMO
and his vitals are good.
All right, we'll be there
in about two minutes.
What's going on?
Power's gone.
What do you mean
the power's gone?
We lost an engine.
We're gonna have to land.
Brace yourself.
Hold on tight!
Are you guys okay?
Yeah. Uh...
Cody's foot is jammed,
and I think I dislocated
my shoulder.
You?
My leg's stuck,
but I'm okay.
You guys just sit tight.
I'm gonna call for help.
Okay. Ow.
This is November Hotel
6-3-2-0-1.
We've made
an emergency landing
in Townsend Quarry.
Looks like we've got
a bent airframe.
We're gonna need assistance
evacuating the aircraft.
His sats are down to 94.
His oxygenator's not working.
He won't make it
to the hospital.
Call Med, we need to get
a new oxygenator
out here fast.
This is November Hotel...
Vicki and I just hung around
the apartment, nothing big.
You okay?
Yeah.
I've been crashing
on my brother's couch.
It's like a pile of rocks.
You're still not back
with Nat? What's going on?
She kicked me out.
You got to ask her.
Dr. Manning's helicopter
just went down hard
outside of the city.
Is Natalie hurt?
Nothing serious,
dislocated shoulder.
The patient's okay,
but they're stuck.
The oxygenator on
the ECMO is damaged.
We need to get a new one
out to her, now.
Okay, Dr. Choi,
grab an ambulance.
No, I'll go.
No.
I just put a patient in Five.
Let Choi do it.
No way, I'm going.
And I'll cover for him.
Thanks.
Suit yourself.
Mr. Green? Hi, I'm Dr. Choi.
Yeah, it's Bruce.
This is Carol and Jesse.
Nice to meet you.
So, what seems to be
the problem?
My belly
is killing me, man.
He's been throwing up a lot.
It's getting worse.
My mouth is dry.
Hey, Jesse, could you grab
my water bottle?
Thanks, bud.
What happened to you?
Broke my arm.
That's a bummer.
I think Monique might have
some cool stickers to
put on your cast.
Want to go take a look?
Sure.
Nice.
I'll run some tests,
but everything I'm seeing
points to liver failure.
Any history of hepatitis?
No.
How about alcohol abuse?
Couple of drinks
here and there.
How many drinks is a couple?
I don't know, two or three
while I'm watching the game.
Honey...
Carol, we...
I'd like to take some blood
and get a CT,
then go from there.
We can discuss this more
once I have the results.
Okay.
Dr. Choi?
He drinks more
than he says he does.
It's a problem.
Look, we'll do everything
we can for him,
but he won't get any better
unless he stops drinking.
I tried. Nothing works.
Let me have one of
our psychiatrists talk to him.
He might be able to help.
Thank you.
Sure.
What, no coffee today?
All that vanilla syrup's
going to go to waste.
What are you going to do?
Connor, what's going on?
Nothing.
It's not nothing. You've been
distant and aloof for weeks.
Can you please tell me
what's going on?
There's nothing to tell.
I'm fine.
Dr. Rhodes, Dr. Bekker,
your patient's here.
We're in Trauma Two.
Thank you.
I've got Barbara Duncan,
Down syndrome,
21 weeks pregnant,
passed out, and is stable now
on five liters O2.
This is her mother, Kathy.
Hi.
Hey, Barbara,
I'm Dr. Rhodes,
I'm gonna take
good care of you, okay?
Okay.
Good.
All right, let's transfer
on my count.
One, two, three!
There we go.
So, what happened?
I got dizzy.
She fainted in art class.
This is the second time
this week.
I have a baby in me.
Congratulations.
I'm gonna be a great mom,
just like my mom.
I am certain
that you will.
So, I spoke
with Barbara's cardiologist.
He said that she has
a congenital heart defect?
Tetralogy of Fallot.
It wasn't that severe,
so they decided
not to repair it.
It's possible
the extra load
from the pregnancy
is starting to cause
too much strain.
Well, her lungs are wet.
So, Barbara,
we would like to run
some tests to figure out
what's wrong.
Is that okay?
Sure.
Good deal.
We will check
on you soon.
Doctor, is she gonna
need surgery?
It's possible, but we need
to wait and see her
test results first.
Fine, just let me know
as soon as you can
in case I have
to make arrangements,
or bring in special equipment
to the house.
Look, I know that
this is all a lot,
so is there
anybody else
that we can call?
Maybe the baby's father?
He took off. It's just
the two of us.
Excuse me.
Ethan, I just talked
to the Greens.
Any luck?
He doesn't seem
to think he has a problem.
I think the wife's been trying
to get through, but...
Yeah, but what can she do?
She's a victim in this, too.
Yeah, family dynamics
can be crucial when it
comes to recovery.
You just don't tend to get
results by maintaining
the status quo.
In my experience,
something pretty drastic
has to happen
to get the drinker
to realize
they hit rock bottom
and start looking
for a solution.
Dr. Charles, he's got
portal hypertension,
esophageal varices,
and LFTs through the roof.
This is rock bottom.
You'd think.
Hey, guys, I need to get
this oxygenator down there.
It's gonna be a minute.
We gotta get our extrication
equipment down first.
Natalie's got a dislocated
shoulder and her patient's
in trouble.
All right, we'll send it
down in the basket.
No, I'm going, too.
Doc, come on.
We don't even have
our guys down there yet.
I have to get to Natalie.
Send me down now.
You okay?
I'm fine.
How's the boy?
Sats are down to 82.
What about your shoulder?
It's all right. I'm fine.
Got it?
Yeah.
Wait, stop. Let me see
if I can pry open
another window.
I told you I'm fine.
Natalie, just hold on.
You don't have to be a hero.
Ow.
Come on. What, do you want
to damage the nerve?
I don't need your
medical advice, Will.
Mr. Flores, can you tell me
how long you've been in pain?
Just since last night.
Usually, her cooking wears off
by the morning.
Okay. Have you ever
had pain like this before?
No.
Any history of abdominal
conditions or surgeries?
No.
Okay, based on your
positive McBurney's sign
and rebound tenderness,
I suspect
you have a routine
case of appendicitis.
Do you have any allergies?
Not that I know of.
Then we're going
to order some tests
and call Surgery.
Surgery?
Mmm-hmm. Yes.
If necessary,
an appendectomy is
a very simple procedure.
You'd most likely be out
of the hospital by tomorrow.
Okay.
Here you go.
Oh, thank you.
Yeah.
I like to keep notes
on all my cases.
Tell radiology we need a CT
with contrast, stat.
Nah, keep it.
Turns out people don't hire
a flooring company
'cause you give 'em
free pens.
Who knew?
Yeah, that does
seem unlikely.
And for the pain?
I think it's time
to think about
ibuprofen 600.
Okay.
Would you excuse me
for a second?
Of course.
Oh, yeah, snack time.
Yeah.
I would stay away from those
apple slices. They don't
change them out that much.
Okay, thanks.
Ooh, I got you. I got you.
That's an excellent cast.
What did you do to your arm?
I broke it.
What, bear attack?
Motorcycle?
It was nothing. I just...
You know, I fell.
From my treehouse.
Oh.
Excellent choice.
So, what happened?
What, rainy day?
Rotten plank?
Oh, I... You know,
I was just playing around.
I got to get back
to my mom and dad.
So, Barbara,
your tests are showing
that you are in heart failure,
and we have every reason
to expect
that it will get worse
as the pregnancy progresses.
How much worse?
It's impossible to say,
but the odds of you having
a life-threatening event
are quite high.
So, she needs
the surgery.
That would be
my recommendation, yes,
but you should know,
the surgery is long
and difficult
and it could pose a risk
to the baby.
It's gonna hurt my baby?
It's possible.
And, unfortunately,
if it does,
your baby is too small
to survive on its own.
He'll die?
He may.
No, I don't want the surgery.
Barbie, I don't think they're
saying that we have a choice.
Yes, we do.
Honey...
You don't want to take care
of this baby.
Barbara...
You think it's going
to be a problem like me.
I know this is difficult
and painful,
but you have to let me
handle this.
No, this is my decision!
You're not capable
of making this decision!
Look, why don't you two
take some time?
You can think about it,
and we will come back
in just a bit.
Excuse me.
I have Barbara's
medical power
of attorney.
Do the surgery.
Ms. Duncan, I really think
that the two of you
should discuss this.
If she doesn't have
the surgery,
she could die.
Do the surgery.
I'll go put her
on the schedule.
No, you won't.
You heard her mother,
she has power of attorney.
I heard my patient
and she doesn't want it.
Got it.
Are you okay?
Yeah, thanks.
Hey, Cruz.
Yeah.
Help me try
and get this kid out.
On my way.
How's Cody doing?
His sats are improving,
but the battery
is running low on the ECMO.
Looks like they should
have him out soon.
Let me reduce your shoulder.
No, we'll do it
when we get back.
We still have to get him
out of here, back
to the ambulance,
and all the way to Med.
You're gonna need your arm.
Fine.
No, I think
you're a little too
high on the forearm.
Natalie, I've done
this before.
I know, but this is
the arm that...
You broke in college
when Lisa Gates ran into you
with her bike.
I know.
All right,
you're gonna feel this.
Just be still.
Okay, but I still think
you're too...
Ow.
There, try it out.
It's good. Thank you.
I'm gonna go check on Cody.
Dr. Choi?
Is my dad gonna die?
We're doing everything we can
to help him get better.
So, he might?
Give us a chance.
We still have
some things we can try.
Doc, that thing for me?
Once we drain the fluid
from your abdomen,
it'll be easier to breathe.
And then what happens?
We'll start you
on a diuretic.
Then have you evaluated
for an intrahepatic
portosystemic shunt.
That sounds serious.
It is, but here's
the thing...
If you keep drinking,
none of it will work.
Come on, Doc, I told you...
You'll lose
your mental status first.
Confusion, memory loss.
That's when your kidneys
start to fail.
Your lungs fill
with fluid.
Then it's either
heart failure,
infection, or coma.
Probably two,
three months tops.
Okay, I get it,
it's your job to scare me.
My job is to try
to keep you alive,
and, from what I can tell,
you have a lot to live for.
But it's up to you whether you
want to do that or not.
Let me know when
the drainage stops.
Bruce.
Okay, you're right.
Clearly, I drink too much.
She's always telling me that.
That's it.
I'm done.
Quitting doesn't mean
just saying it.
It means going
through detox, A.A.
Doc, I got a boy
I love, my wife.
I am telling you,
I have taken my last drink.
Okay, let's get
you stabilized.
Then I'll have a social worker
come down to go over
the next steps.
Thank you.
A code in radiology?
Let's go.
Did he get contrast?
Just a minute ago.
Okay, it's an
allergic reaction.
His throat's swelling.
.3 milligrams of epi IM.
Okay, Pete, just relax.
Try and take a deep breath.
Epi's in.
I need to intubate.
Laryngoscope and ET tube.
He said he didn't
have any allergies.
Well, you don't
always know
until they happen.
Tube's in. Start bagging.
He's in v-fib.
Grab the paddles.
Curry, run the code.
What? No, I...
Curry!
Okay, um, charge to 200.
Clear?
Still in v-fib.
Giving an amp of epi.
Again.
Charging to 200.
Clear!
Charge it again.
April, 200.
It's over.
What?
Call it.
Time of death, 13:06.
And this young woman
with Down syndrome is 25?
Yes, she is an adult and
does not want the surgery.
Barbara has a life-threatening
condition. She needs
this procedure.
And what happens
if she doesn't get it?
We will put her on medication.
We'll have her
get weekly checkups
from her cardiologist.
And she'll likely still die
from heart failure.
Barbara's mother has spent
her entire life caring
for her daughter.
Everything she's done,
she has done for her.
We need to trust her judgment.
We need to let people
make their own decisions,
not have them made
against their will.
I understand your concerns,
Dr. Rhodes,
but the patient's mother
does have legal
decision-making power.
I don't see any choice
but to authorize the surgery.
Thank you.
Okay.
We should give Barbara
some credit for knowing
what she wants.
What is going on with you?
I want to honor
my patient's wishes.
No, we've had professional
disagreements before.
This is different.
This feels personal.
All right.
My father told me
his version
of how he came to donate
money for the Hybrid OR.
Yeah, he said I slept
with him. He's lying.
He said that you were
the instigator,
that you seduced him.
It sounded like
he was telling the truth.
Patient is out
and we're on the move.
Copy that, Squad 3.
We'll notify Chicago Med.
I know you didn't want to go,
but how's therapy going?
Only gone once,
but Dr. Moore seems fine.
Good. Well, I mean,
I'm glad you like her.
She spent a lot of time
waiting for me
to say something,
but I didn't know what
I was supposed to talk about.
What happened, happened.
Dr. Manning!
His sats and heart rate
are tanking!
No breath sounds
on the left.
The bag must've
blown out the lung.
We need a chest tube.
No, he's too anticoagulated.
A chest tube might cause
a major bleed.
I'm doing a needle.
Wait, a needle is only
temporary. He's still gonna
need a tube.
We can deal with that
when we get there.
He needs decompression now.
Natalie...
You know what? You're right.
Let's do a needle.
Sats are back in the 80s.
Breath sounds are better.
Let's get him out of here.
Barbara, I'm very sorry,
but we do have to take you
up to surgery now.
No, I don't want to go.
Everything is only getting
worse. I'm afraid
we don't have a choice.
But my baby!
We're going to do everything
that we can to make sure that
your baby is safe.
You said you can't!
You said my baby might die!
Mom, make them stop!
Sweetie, it's going
to be okay.
Dr. Rhodes?
We're taking her
up to surgery now.
They're gonna kill my baby!
Everything's gonna be okay.
It's my baby, Mom!
No, I don't wanna go! No!
No, no!
You still haven't told her
about her husband.
Uh...
No, I was just about to.
Is this the first patient
you've lost?
Yeah.
You want to go over
what you should say?
No, no, I'm fine.
We had a lecture on this
in second year.
Why don't I come with you?
Okay.
I got worried.
It was taking so long.
Mrs. Flores, I'm afraid
there was a complication.
"Complication"?
Your husband had
an allergic reaction
and stopped breathing.
We tried to save him,
but his heart went into
an arrhythmia and he died.
What?
Ventricular fibrillation.
He died.
That doesn't make any sense.
You said that it was just
his appendix, and it was
a simple procedure!
Yes, but this was a contrast
reaction, which had
nothing to do with...
He can't be dead!
I'm afraid he is.
His heart went into
a fatal arrhythmia.
That's not true!
He's not dead!
Mrs. Flores.
Mrs. Flores, it is true.
We did everything
that we could,
but your husband is gone.
I am so sorry.
No.
No!
So sorry.
Oh, God.
No.
Help! We need help!
He's been throwing up.
Go to the MTP
and get me an AGG.
He's bleeding! Please!
He has enlarged vessels
in his esophagus.
They must've torn
from the vomiting.
All right, Bruce,
this is gonna
be uncomfortable,
but I need you
to swallow for me, okay?
Hang on, Mr. Green.
This'll only take a second.
Have you been drinking?
Have you been drinking
this whole time?
Call GI. We gotta send him
upstairs for ligation.
How could you?
You're killing yourself!
Bruce, we can't stop
the bleeding.
We have to send you upstairs
for a procedure. Let's go!
This is what you get!
The procedure could
take a while.
I'll bring you to a room
where you can wait.
It's fine. Bastard.
Where's Jesse?
Jesse? Where is he?
Jesse!
Hank, have you seen her son?
Broken arm?
I didn't see him.
Where did he go?
Let's check the waiting room.
You seen a kid with a cast?
Yeah, he was going
towards the elevators.
Call security right now.
Stay there.
Ooh.
It's cold out here.
Leave me alone.
Jesse, I want you
to know that I really...
I really understand
how hard this all
is for you.
You've been
put in a really
tough situation.
I know it sucks.
You know I got this hunch...
Maybe, you didn't fall
out of your treehouse.
That maybe you jumped
because you just
wanted all the pain
to go away.
You didn't want to feel
all those helpless
feelings anymore.
I get that.
I think that
probably your dad
feels that way
when he wants to drink.
You might think
that your dad
acts the way he does 'cause
he doesn't care about you.
Nothing could be
further from the truth.
Your dad drinks
'cause he's trying
to get away
from the
difficult feelings,
and not wanting
to feel those feelings,
I mean, it's the most
normal thing in the world.
Yeah.
Thing is, it turns out
that the only way
to make them go away,
is to talk about them.
Yeah, talking about them,
it can make bad feelings
go away
and it also helps
you understand them better
if they come back.
You know, so
if you're up for it,
I'd be really interested
to talk about that stuff
with you, if you want.
I mean, think about it.
In the meantime,
what I really want to do,
I want to get you back inside,
so your mom and dad
know that you're safe.
They're really
worried about you.
You know why?
It's just they love you
so much.
So, what do you say?
Do you wanna go back inside?
Ms. Duncan?
Sharon Goodwin,
Director of Patient Services.
I wanted to return
your legal documents.
Have you heard anything?
Is Barbara okay?
I'm sorry. I don't have
any news yet,
but could I get someone
to bring something for you
from the cafeteria?
A sandwich or some coffee?
I'm not hungry. Thank you.
Yeah, I'm sure
this isn't easy.
If the baby dies,
I don't think Barbara
will ever forgive me.
Do you have children,
Miss Goodwin?
I do, three.
But they're all grown.
With Barbara,
it's like having
a child who never grows up.
Don't get me wrong.
I wouldn't trade it
for the world.
It's just the possibility
of having another one...
It's a lot.
The baby doesn't have
Down syndrome, it's not that.
It's just...
I'm not 30 anymore, and...
You don't feel up to it.
So, I keep asking myself,
when I pushed so hard
for this surgery...
Did you do it
for your daughter,
or yourself?
Now, come.
Scalpel and DeBakeys?
Scalpel and DeBakeys.
Marty?
Fetal heart rate
is down to 115.
Can you get it back up?
Transfusing her.
We're down to 109.
103.
We're going to lose the fetus.
Where are we at on the bypass?
4 liters.
Crank it up to six.
Wait, what are you doing?
The fetus needs more blood.
Connor, our priority
is to save the patient,
not the fetus.
We can save both.
If you flood too much blood
to Barbara's brain,
she could have permanent
neurological damage.
It could put her into a coma.
Fetal heart rate's
down to 86.
Connor, it's too dangerous.
Dr. Rhodes?
It's what Barbara wants.
Turn the bypass up to six.
Curry, write some
admissions orders
for Mr. Banes in Six.
Okay.
I'm so sorry, Will...
For the way things
got between us.
Yeah.
You went through
something terrible,
and I never even asked you
what it was like
to have your life
in danger.
I can't even imagine.
You know, when I was
in that room, afraid
I was going to die,
all I could think was...
I'd never see you again.
I can't believe it.
My baby...
My baby tried
to kill himself.
We're going to keep Jesse
here for a few days,
if that's all right.
You know, see how he does,
come up with a treatment plan
for him.
But then what?
After we get home,
I already missed this once.
The signs aren't always
so apparent. You got to
take it easy on yourself.
It's not like you haven't
had other stuff going on.
Oh, God.
How do I help him?
You wanna communicate
with him.
Talk to him, listen,
have honest conversations
about what's going on
in your family.
I think for Jesse,
just knowing
that you're there,
it'll go a very long way.
You ready?
Yeah.
Jesse...
Hey, Mom.
We're gonna
get through this.
I promise.
Mrs. Green, we heard
your husband's procedure
went well.
I'm leaving him.
We're gonna go stay
with my sister.
Okay.
Bruce says he'll go to rehab,
that he'll stop drinking,
but I cannot risk Jesse's life
on the chance that he doesn't.
And if he can stay sober
for three months,
I'll go back to him.
It takes a lot of courage
to make a sacrifice like that.
Yeah.
Maybe now,
that'll finally get
his attention.
Let's hope so.
Dr. Rhodes,
she's waking up.
Barbie, it's me, Mom.
Barbie?
Mom?
Barbara, do you know
where you are?
Hospital?
Mmm-hmm.
How is my baby?
Why don't we find out?
Can you help me out there?
All right.
Good, and...
there he is.
Look at him.
Look at his little hand.
Mom, isn't he cute?
He's beautiful. We're going
to have a beautiful baby.
Looks like the fever's
starting to break.
He should be
off ECMO soon.
Good.
Have a good night.
Will?
I want you
to come back home.
To me.
You do?
The thing is, you have
to get rid of your gun.
I'm sorry, but that's just
how it has to be.
Okay.
I'll take it to
the police station tonight,
and turn it in.
April.
Have a good night.
April... April.
We should talk
about that kiss.
I'm sorry that happened.
I know you're with Vicki now.
There's nothing for us
to talk about.
I cannot believe that
you are even considering
taking your father's word
over mine.
Ava, every step of the way,
you have lied to me.
About going to my dad, about
knowing that he cut the check.
How am I supposed to believe
anything that you have to say?
Because I care about you,
and he doesn't!
He never has.
Your whole life, he's tried
to keep you under his thumb.
He's attempted to undermine
everything you do.
He's trying to drive a wedge
between us.
He said that
he liked your perfume.
That it smelled
like lilacs. It does.
So, what? I was standing
over him.
I was showing him
the prospectus.
That doesn't mean anything.
"The ends justify the means."
Those were your words.
Connor,
I did not sleep
with your father.
I wish I could believe you.
Daniel, it's late.
You still doing notes?
Yeah, just cleaning
a couple of things up.
What are you doing?
Nothing. What are you doing?
Let me see.
A dating profile? Really?
I thought you didn't
trust algorithms.
I don't.
You're just scared.
I am.
So, what changed?
I don't know.
I witnessed this real act
of courage today,
love even.
Maybe it made me
a little braver.
What can I say?
Hope springs eternal.
"Tell us about yourself."
What am I supposed to say?
"Jazz, walks on the beach"?
You don't like jazz.
You like hip-hop.
I like everything.
Come on.
I got all night.
Let's do this.
Oh, man.