Every disease
has its unique course
it takes in the body
when left untreated.
The process begins with
exposure to a root cause
that sends a ripple effect
throughout the body.
Simone, I didn't know,
okay? - No, sorry.
I-I-I can't do
the "I don't know"
story anymore.
You knew exactly
what was happening.
You chose not to see it.
Yeah, I guess moving to
Seattle hasn't changed
how quick you are
to point a finger.
Excuse me?
Well, you constantly assume
that I'm trying to hurt you...
No, you saw me come home from work
every night in tears. Okay. Mm-hmm.
You saw me almost throw
in the towel on my career.
You were too scared of tarnishing
your sterling reputation
to speak up for me!
I was an intern.
The
disease then progresses,
ultimately resolving in one
of three possible outcomes...
You get better, you
stay chronically ill,
They
kicked me out, Trey!
Oh, they've been
fighting nonstop
since he arrived last night.
Yeah, I heard.
I almost fell asleep
during rounds.
Well, maybe we should cancel.
Uh, we have an empty house.
We are having a party.
I don't care if he's her
ex-fiancé or whatever.
Trey is the competition.
If they're fighting, it
means you're still in this.
Team Skywalker.
You two were half a second
away from boning last night.
The sexual tension was,
frankly, oppressive.
Yeah, well, what am I
supposed to about it?
Mm, stop sulking and
tell her how you feel
so I don't have to look at
your sad, sad face all night.
Surgeons swoop in once
a diagnosis is made
and the patient
needs reinforcements.
We take decisive action
in order to give them
a fighting chance.
Ohh. I spent the
first half of the day
fending off requests for
comment...
on the death of Jermaine Talbott
and the other half
trying to get a grasp
on our budget deficits,
which are substantial,
by the way.
Well, they always are.
Oh, I am kicking myself
for inviting Bailey and
Warren to dinner tonight.
Makes two of us
especially because Allison
bit Pru again. What?
I was told when I picked
her up from daycare.
Why didn't you tell me?
I am. This is me telling you.
Wait. So, what... Is
this becoming a thing?
I mean, should we cancel
dinner? You know what?
Don't... Don't answer that.
I knew I should have
picked up more wine.
I think Tuck is
building a fort with Pru,
so we're set...
unless you want to cancel
and just go to bed early.
We will do no such thing.
Yeah.
What's that?
Well, we can't show
up empty-handed.
Yeah, but what if it
sends the wrong message?
What message?
That we like pie?
Their daughter has now
bitten our daughter.
Twice.
It's a problem.
Do you remember the last time
that you and I had a
civilized, adult dinner
without children present?
Let's get out of here while we
still can. Mm-hmm.
Mr. Simms needs
neurochecks q two hours,
and Natalia Asaki was
just admitted for pre-op,
so coordinate with
Webber and Pierce.
Are you going to the party
tonight?
You look nice.
In an appropriate,
respectful way.
Just
try not to kill anyone.
So... I guess we're the
only ones stuck here
while everyone else gets drunk
and makes poor decisions.
I hate the ICU.
Oh, there's nothing to it.
Just try not to kill anyone.
Everyone has to
stop saying that.
Well, have fun.
While you're running codes,
I'll be on Pierce's service,
scrubbing in on her
Ivor Lewis procedure
in the morning.
Natalia Asaki?
I hate you.
Don't hate the player,
hate the game.
Okay, now I hate both.
Ew.
Uh, you know, I
haven't had a chance
to congratulate you on your
partial heart transplant.
Now, there's some
groundbreaking stuff.
We worked hard on
it. Thank you. Yeah.
Well, you keep this
up, you'll be in line
for a Catherine Fox Award.
And you and Winston sure do
make a great team.
Dr. Pierce...
I just wanted to say thank you
for allowing me to
scrub in tomorrow...
Uh, Dr. Pierce, Dr. Webber,
I have studied the Ivor
Lewis procedure extensively.
I know that the
major complications
are respiratory and
atrial arrhythmias,
which can be controlled
by amiodarone.
Well, this is an 8-hour surgery,
so if you're not too tired
after your overnight in the ICU,
you may also scrub in.
Who's a player now?
Natalia, Elliot.
Welcome to Seattle.
- Thank you.
I hope your trip
from Coeur d'Alene
wasn't too bad.
I slept through most
of it, thanks to him.
And I'm highly
caffeinated right now.
Well, we're glad you made it.
Dr. Kwan?
Natalia Asaki, 32, stage
II esophageal cancer,
status post neoadjuvant
therapy, admitted for pre-op
for an Ivor Lewis procedure
first thing in the morning.
Which is? Uh,
resecting the esophagus
through an abdominal incision
and a right thoracotomy,
then pulling the
stomach into the chest
to replace the esophagus.
I'm sorry.
Amor, my painting sold.
The landscape from
our camping trip.
I love that one. Yeah.
How much?
$500.
She's an art teacher at
an after-school program,
but she sells her own
pieces on the side.
I'm sorry, but the
past couple of months
of chemo and radiation were...
not the most fun I've ever had.
We're ready to put
this chapter behind us.
Well, let's get a move on.
Okay, Kwan, Millin,
let's start Natalia's
pre-op work-up...
Bloodwork, EKG, chest X-ray.
Um, I definitely need all
that before the surgery?
You do. We will
be back in a bit.
Babe, don't worry.
We'll figure out a
way to pay for it.
It's okay.
Oh, it's my fault?!
Look, I hate that
they kicked you out.
Alright? I really hate it.
I promise you, I hate it more.
Oh, still so competitive.
Ah.
Hey.
Come here.
Trey, I was broken.
I-I felt... broken.
But I am sorry that
I disappeared on you.
I'm sorry. I should
have chased after you.
I wanted to. I should have.
I mean, you kinda
did. You're here.
I feel like I waited too long.
Did I wait too long?
Can we just go to the
party and try to have fun?
I missed you.
Ben, Bailey. Enter at your
own risk.
Ooh, come on in. Oooh, look
at that. Mm-hmm. Apple pie.
My mother's recipe.
Maybe you can think of
it when you are approving
budget requests for the clinic.
Thank you. You shouldn't have.
Hey, I heard there were some
fires down in south Seattle.
You been on those?
Uh, no, no, no.
Uh, we have a little girl now,
so I sit the crazy stuff out.
That
never stopped Owen.
Ah, please excuse her.
She's exhausted after
one day of the job
that you and I did for years.
Wine?
Uh, by wine, can
you mean bourbon?
Good idea.
Yeah.
Cheese and crackers are
on the coffee table.
- Oh.
- Oh, fantastic.
I'd love a bite.
Chest X-ray is normal.
Coags, CBC, CMP all look good.
Oh, great. Let's start
her on her bowel prep...
Help!
I was just
finishing her EKG,
and she started seizing.
Okay, well, let's
get her on her side.
Blood glucose was normal,
so it can't be that.
And her sats are 92 on room air.
I checked her airway.
There's no vomit.
Let's get some suction
in here, anyway.
Elliot, does she have a history
of epilepsy or alcohol abuse?
No, never. What's going on?
We don't know, but we
are going to find out.
Let's load her up with
Keppra and lorazepam.
A-And, Kwan, take Elliot
out and page neuro.
- Let's hurry.
- I love you, Natalia.
It's okay.
Yeah, my place is definitely
a work in progress,
so you have to promise not to
judge me when you get here.
Okay, is there a door?
There is.
Alright. A bed?
Uh-huh. No duvet
cover, though.
No! Well, that's
it. I'm canceling.
Okay, uh, crap.
I got to go.
I'll see you tomorrow. Okay.
Oh, hey.
You are still here. Awesome.
Uh, would you take
Scout for a bit?
I was on my way home with him,
and I just got paged for a
consult on a grand mal seizure.
Well, I was on my way home,
and I got egged by a
couple of angry Tank fans.
Seriously?
Based on how tonight's going,
I could, uh, use some
time with my only fan.
Okay. It
should not take long.
You have fun with Daddy, okay?
Mwah! Bye.
Can anyone help me?! Gahhhh!
Uh... Please, I need help.
I-I-I'm a surgeon.
At least for now.
Here. Here. Here.
My stupid wife promised
she'd be back from trial
before I went into
labor.
I take it that didn't happen?
Aah! Oh, okay. Alright.
Just... Just breathe.
Uh, I'll... I'll page OB.
It... Oh, thank God.
Hi. So sorry.
Hi. You must be Whitney.
Okay, let's get you upstairs.
Thank you, Dr. Lincoln.
I can take it from here.
Okay. I can't let
go. I can't let go.
I'm sorry, but my anxiety
hovers around an 8
when I'm not in labor.
You mind if I bring a plus-one?
It... It's fine by me.
Sure. Yeah.
Okay, okay. Gahhhhh!
Okay.
Okay, let's do this.
♪ I go to Mars in my head ♪
[ Cheers and laughter ]
Levi.
Push one of... Levi!
One of epi and atropine. Hey!
Oh, sorry.
You need to get laid.
Like, badly.
And you cannot get laid
if you're the guy
sleeping at the party.
I just worked a 16-hour shift,
and alcohol is a
depressant.
You want to know what time
I got up this morning?
Noon.
I shouldn't even be here.
Like it or not, I
am a manager now,
and boundaries are important.
You're where fun goes to die.
♪ So I'm gonna make
him proud in the end ♪
Hey. You came.
Nice house.
Yeah, Levi and I
live in a studio.
This place has rooms.
A few weeks ago, I
was living in a van,
and I thought that
was nice.
Dr. Schmitt. Yasuda.
Good booze is over here.
Find someone to talk to.
Oh. Anyone.
♪ And I start reverting back ♪
H...
♪ I start reverting
back now, honey ♪
♪ Swap my happiness
for checks ♪
It's good out here.
Yeah, actually, it is.
You mind getting us some drinks?
Uh, your usual? Yeah.
Coming right up.
Hey.
♪ Forget ♪
Okay.
Can we talk?
I don't know if, uh,
now is the best time.
Look, I-I am sorry
about last night.
Trey showing up
was... unexpected.
Does he know about you and I?
No, of course not.
A whiskey
ginger.
You remember last
New Year's Eve?
Might have went a
little hard on the whiskey gingers.
Might not have made
it to midnight.
Rookie move.
Yeah, she kept giving the finger
to every stranger walking by,
saying, "Let's send
last year to hell."
At least I
had the right holiday.
♪ Is going to die ♪
So, new-onset grand mal
seizure? - Yep.
Stage II adenocarcinoma
of the esophagus,
had chemoradiation
two months ago,
scheduled for surgery tomorrow.
Kwan, what are the possible
causes of new-onset seizures?
Meningitis, encephalitis,
alcohol withdrawal,
stroke, hyponatremia, or...
Mm.
Natalia's esophageal cancer
metastasized to her brain.
Most likely a localized met
in the right temporal lobe.
And it's bleeding.
Damn it.
What happened?
Am I okay?
Natalia, your CT scan shows
a possible metastasis
in your brain.
We'll need to excise
it immediately.
What about the surgery
we came here for?
I am so sorry that this is
not the news that you wanted,
but we have to do this
surgery as soon as possible.
I can't
believe this is happening.
Could you just give us a minute?
Of course.
We'll be back with
consent forms.
You know... you might as well
go home and get some rest.
I have no place better to be.
You sure? Yeah, yeah.
Give Catherine my best.
Okay, Whitney, you are
6 centimeters dilated.
You are having this baby.
No one really tells you
how much this hurts.
Mother... Oh, sorry.
I'll try not to... Holy crap!
He's heard worse. Trust me.
Do you have any idea
how lucky you are
that you didn't push your
son's watermelon body
out of your teeny tiny vagina?!
I-I don't have a
teeny tiny vagina.
But if it
makes you feel any better,
I am so hated by the city
of Seattle right now,
I can't walk outside without
getting literal egg on my face.
No. Yes, I'm
officially in hiding.
That actually does make
me feel a little better.
Gahhhhh. Okay,
Whitney. Just breathe.
Yeah.
What?
Well, when I first
heard you were living
with a bunch of interns in
a house with fire damage,
I was kinda scared for you.
Oh, hard same.
They seem cool.
Even though they're
not quite your caliber.
No. Don't judge my people.
Oh, they're your people now?
I mean... yeah.
They kinda are.
Come on.
Now, you were the
top of your class
in every class
you've ever been in.
And you're top tier.
I'm sorry, but these?
These are not your people.
Trey, I swear to God, we just...
No, no, no, you're only mad
because you know it's true.
Grey-Sloan isn't the
program it used to be,
and you don't belong here.
You belong with me, at the top.
And if you present your
case and you come back...
Present my case? and you
stay calm and collected...
Oh, wow. Look, we could
have it all back, Simone.
We could have us back. We
could have our future back.
These are not your people.
Baby, I'm your people.
I'm walking away, Trey.
And I promise if
you walk after me,
I won't remain
calm and collected.
- Come on.
- No!
Simone. No!
Sorry.
♪ I've been dreaming ♪
You think this is hard?
Tuck spent 45 minutes in the
bathroom the other morning. Mm.
45, alright?
You know what he was doing?
Do we want to know?
He was shaving.
Sorry. Sorry.
Manscaping.
His chest.
He's going out
for the swim team.
Ah.
I mean, Pru might
be a threenager,
but at least she doesn't
hog the bathroom.
She's been angling for a dog.
Aww.
Oh, that's all we need, right?
You know,
little puppy teeth
nipping at her fingers and toes.
Mm.
You know, here we are,
kid-free, finally,
and we're still talking
about kids.
Right, who wants to
talk about adult stuff?
I do. Okay.
Uh, Bailey, how's the clinic?
Mm, busy.
We can hardly keep
up with the demand.
Uh, how's the...
medical license?
Still suspended, but,
you know, getting there.
Is it?
Do you want to help
me in the kitchen?
I can't. No license, so...
I can help
you with something. Ah.
No, no, no, no,
no. Don't be silly.
Teddy's got it, right?
Right. Mm.
So, uh...
should we go back to
talking about kids?
It'll be okay. Babe.
It'll be okay.
I'll start driving on the
rideshare app. Babe.
And if you need another
surgery after that,
I'll take on more guitar
students or... Amor.
Stop!
Uh, Natalia, Elliot.
This is the consent form
identifying the risks
of the procedure.
They say I could die, right?
If I die...
How deep in the hole are you?
During the pandemic, they
made us both part-time.
We just got the only health
insurance we could afford,
and we thought we
were gonna be fine,
but now we're buried in
debt, and I'm gonna die
and leave the love of my
life poor and homeless.
You two should get a divorce.
That's not funny.
No, and it wasn't meant to be.
Dr. Kwan, please step outside. No,
medical divorce is a real thing.
It could help Elliot not get
saddled by Natalia's debt.
It could help Natalia to qualify
for more insurance or aid,
since they won't
have a joint income.
And if they have assets,
it could protect them.
Wait.
That's brilliant.
What? Babe.
No, you're my wife.
Dr. Kwan, I'd like a
word. Outside, please.
Now. I'm not divorcing
the woman I love.
I said do not follow me!
Are you okay?
Do I look okay?
Um, well, you
look...
Well, you look perfect.
What? To me, you kinda
always look perfect.
And maybe my timing isn't great,
but I need to say that
even when you're upset,
you are... pretty
damn perfect.
Lucas... You're so smart.
And when you get
mad, you get smarter.
Like, when you get mad 'cause
you can't figure out a case...
that's when you figure it out.
So, right now... Now
you look like a person
who's about to...
solve a big mystery.
Like a person who's gonna...
figure everything out.
♪ I believe I've
seen a ghost ♪
♪ And I don't know who it is ♪
♪ It just follows me around ♪
♪ Pretending to exist ♪
♪ I've never related more ♪
♪ To anything or
anyone before ♪
♪ I can't explain it ♪
Simone, can
I come in? No.
Baby, baby, I'm... I'm
sorry for what I said, okay?
I-I love you. I-I'm sorry.
I just... I'm trying
to get this right,
and I keep getting it wrong.
Baby. Baby, please.
Trey, can you just
give me a minute, okay?
Can we talk later? No.
I-I've never loved anyone
the way that I love you.
Look, I can't see my
life with anyone else.
I-I know I'm a snob.
I know I'm an ass.
But I'll... I'll be better.
'Cause you make me better.
Trey, I'm...
I'm tired. I just
need a few minutes.
Okay.
I'll come find you.
I love you.
♪ To anything or
anyone before ♪
Okay.
We were engaged. We
had a whole life.
He knows my family.
My dad loves him. My
grandmother loves him.
He's... Do you love him?
♪ Politely, I asked,
"Are you real?" ♪
Yeah, 'cause if you
love him, you should...
Yeah, you should go talk to him.
♪ It said, "Here,
let me prove it" ♪
Are you serious? Yeah, no.
If you love him, you should...
you
should fight for him.
Now you're...
pushing me toward him?
Hey, I'm not pushing you.
♪ "Don't kill the
messenger," it begged ♪
I'm saying, do you love him?
♪ "You're alive" ♪
Yeah, okay. I'm gonna go.
♪ "Quit acting
like you're dead" ♪
I'm... I'm so... I'm
so... Hey, hey, hey.
Don't say you're sorry.
♪ Like a mirror... ♪
We're good.
♪ ...it spoke so clear ♪
♪ "Don't you recognize..." ♪
Lucas, wait.
♪ "...the reason
why you're here?" ♪
Can y... Before
you open the door,
can I just make sure
he's not out there?
♪ "To be enchanted" ♪
Yeah, okay. Now you
can say you're sorry.
♪ "To be enchanted" ♪
What happened in there? Do you have any
idea how crushing medical debt can be
for people who
aren't millionaires?
Of course I do.
But before you cross
a line with a patient,
you have to talk to
an attending first.
I could have called
financial services
or a social worker or
a pastor or a therapist
or someone who is trained to
have that kind of conversation.
Her brain is bleeding.
They don't have that kind
of time to go through...
You had time to talk to me.
Now her brain is bleeding and
she's fighting with her husband.
And that is not an improvement,
and it has not
saved us any time.
She is my patient.
You are here at my invitation.
Is that understood?
Okay, Dr. Kwan.
The invitation is rescinded.
And let's hope she
signs that consent form
that'll allow us
to save her life.
Alright, what
is that one, again?
I don't know. Let's see.
Bourbon. With...
Bourbon. Bourbon.
Uh, I might have
drank from that.
Don't care.
- Hey.
♪ Maybe this will be the song I
hear, when it all goes wrong ♪
This is Taryn.
She was a surgeon,
but followed sanity
and became a bartender.
And this is Trey.
He might like crabs.
- He's from Baltimore.
- Yeah.
Um, I'm visiting Simone.
So, uh, how'd you two meet?
Uh, med school.
Physiology class.
I'd sit on the opposite
side of the lecture hall
Yeah.
I hooked up with a girl in
my physiology class, too.
Oh, cool.
Not my story. Not my story.
Oh, you're not
getting off that easy.
Uh, I was home sick one day.
Didn't show up to class.
Trey spent the entire day
cooking his mom's famous soup,
brought it to my apartment
with notes from class,
told me he liked my smile.
I told him I'm not
really a soup person,
but clutch on the notes.
And just like that,
I was in love.
Wow, Griffith. You
missed a class?
You want to get some
air? Yeah, sure.
♪ I'm not living, I'm
just killing time, time ♪
Do you want to go see the
hole in the roof? Yes.
Yeah? Yeah.
- Okay, come on.
- Okay.
♪ Suffocating on
my own supply ♪
♪ Caught up in the tangle
of your lives, lives ♪
♪ Suffocating on
my own supply ♪
Party that bad?
No, I'm just, uh,
bad at... at this.
At parties? Yes.
And people.
I'm not even that drunk,
so I'm also bad at alcohol?
I'm Carlos. Traveling nurse.
Uh, I'm only here
for a couple months,
but here's the thing...
Levi. Here's the thing, Levi.
If you leave, you won't
get to hang out with me.
You... You brought
your own drinks.
Oh, I work way too hard
to drink whatever surgical
interns can afford.
♪ Get my mind in line ♪
♪ Submissive till the
day I die ♪
♪ I'll detach... ♪
Um, Altman, did you have a
chance to look at those résumés?
Oh. Um, no. Not yet.
Which résumés?
Uh, for chief of trauma.
There are some excellent
candidates in there.
Oh, um, I think you mean
"interim" chief of trauma.
No, she doesn't.
You literally just promised
me my job back yesterday.
I... didn't know that. Mm. Mm.
But it turns out hiring a
decent interim chief of trauma
is harder than hiring
a permanent one.
Seriously? Oh.
Look, if I have to
wait for your license,
I-I need to consider my options.
Okay, so
when were you gonna tell me?
This is me telling you. Mm.
Y... Now that I think about it,
the candidates weren't
that great, just...
You know what, Owen?
Maybe if you had asked
me how my day was,
this would've come up earlier.
Been there.
I don't think they were
asking our opinion.
You know, like it or
not, you can barely
practice medicine
right now, anyway.
Do you know who practices the
least amount of medicine, Teddy?
The chief of surgery.
This is a business decision.
Just grow up and deal with it.
My wife wants a divorce.
We said... "'til
death do us part."
I'm so sorry.
I can only imagine how
you're feeling right now.
Everything's been always so...
easy with her.
I still think the
biggest fight we ever had
was over refilling
the water pitcher.
Most of us can only dream
of having a love like that.
I'm just saying that,
if you trusted her
enough to marry her,
why not trust her
enough to un-marry her?
Don't make it mean
something it doesn't.
She loves you and she
wants to protect you.
So maybe just... let her.
I didn't
know what kind of flowers
to get for our divorce,
but turns out,
you can't have them in the ICU,
so fake ones it is.
This is Aaron, uh,
one of the hospital lawyers
who's nice enough
to help us pro bono.
Fortunately, the
divorce petition's
rather simple for you two.
No kids, no owned property,
no assets.
Once you sign, I
will file a copy
with the court in
Idaho immediately.
I just need you
both to sign there.
It feels like we're
getting married again.
Amor, I promise to love
you until my dying breath.
Whether
it's in a few minutes,
days, or years.
I promise that my love for you
will only grow in divorce
like it has in marriage.
And I promise you to keep trying
to refill the water pitcher.
I am the luckiest
girl in the world
to be divorcing you.
Natalia, as your ex-husband...
I promise to be there for you
in good times and in bad.
In sickness and in health.
I promise to treat
each day as a gift.
And
I promise to love you
for every moment of every day
for the rest of
our lives together.
I've
witnessed several weddings
in hospital rooms,
but this is definitely
the first divorce.
Okay.
Um, I'm ready.
It's okay.
Mnh. Unh-unh.
I changed my mind.
I can't do it.
Yes, you can, Whitney.
You are doing great.
I have a brother who's not well,
ruined my parents' lives.
So sorry to hear that.
I told my wife that
I was scared our kid
would get my brother's genes.
You know what she said?
"We don't have that
in our family."
And I just accepted that?!
You know what, Whitney?
Hey, you're right. Alright?
The world is a terrifying,
mostly awful place,
and you can't choose your kids.
Tell me something to
make me feel better.
When I look at my son
drooling in the corner,
he gives me hope.
Pure, blind, probably
irrational hope.
He gives me a reason
to put my fears aside
and believe that
everything might be okay.
So, traveling doesn't
get old for you?
No way. Uh, I'm a Sagittarius.
I'm, um...
Jewish.
Ah, smart, funny, and a doctor.
Mm.
The dying wish of
Hilda Narvaez Garcia.
My mother.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Oh, no, she's still alive.
She's just very dramatic
about my love life.
Does she
cut out magazine articles
and comment on
your sock choices?
Yes! Yes!
Plus, a whole lot more
which I will not tell you
because I want you to
pick up my call one day.
That was me asking
for your number.
I... Oh, I...
Maybe we can go someplace
where they bring drinks to you.
Like, um, I know this
place downtown...
Yes.
You know, when I was chief,
at least I paid my co-workers
the respect of
full transparency.
Oh, please. When
you were chief,
the hospital almost went under.
Oh, wait. It kinda did.
That was not my fault.
When you're chief,
everything is your fault.
That's why I can't
have a chief of trauma
with a suspended
medical license!
Oh, just say it again, Teddy.
We having fun yet?
You wanna know why
Allison is biting kids?
Because her dad is a man-child
who can't control his tantrums!
Yeah, well, she's not
old enough to drink,
so she can't take after her mom!
Okay, enough! Ugh,
this won't work.
Altman, you are the
chief now, officially.
And this is just
poor leadership.
Okay, whatever happened
between the two of you
needs to be fixed
because, yes, now your child
is biting other people.
You said biting happens.
It does.
But you two constantly
biting each other
with your sharp
words and nasty looks
and rage at all
times isn't helping.
Pretty soon, that rage of yours
is going to infect
the entire hospital
and we'll all be
biting at each other
like zombies or cannibals!
So for all of our
sakes, get some help.
Ben, get the pie.
Okay.
Oh, maybe we should have
people over more often.
Bite me.
Dr. Newton.
Dr. Erica Newton to trauma two.
Dr. Newton to trauma two.
Thanks for pissing off Pierce.
I've never scrubbed in on
a craniotomy. Have fun.
She gave me like a week's worth
of progress notes to review.
Just apologize.
Tell her you screwed up.
I don't apologize
unless I'm wrong.
Now, can you go scrub
in on the surgery
that you basically
stole so I can focus?
Okay,
Whitney, it's time to push.
One, two, three.
Gahhhhhhh!
♪ You said some things
you didn't mean ♪
♪ I lost my nerve
in the disbelief ♪
♪ I'm gonna take my heart
out and wipe it clean ♪
♪ I hope it saves me ♪
♪ My hope is weak ♪
♪ And I have run
towards the cliff ♪
♪ I've fallen into the blue ♪
♪ But don't try to stop me ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm in recovery ♪
♪ Light me a fire,
I'll step too close ♪
♪ I'll learn to
let go of you ♪
Okay, Whitney, one last push.
One, two, three.
Gahhhh!
♪ And I
have run towards the cliff ♪
♪ I've fallen into the blue ♪
♪ But don't try to stop me ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm in recovery ♪
Hi, stranger.
Oh! Oh!
♪ You're losing grip ♪
♪ I feel release ♪
Simone, look, I
meant what I said...
I'll come here if
that's what it takes.
Your family would
never forgive you.
Maybe not. They're snobs.
They're such snobs.
I'll tell you what, though.
They get that I don't
want to lose you.
I have to fight for you.
Whatever it takes.
Our program treated
me like human garbage.
And tonight you suggested
that if I had just
stayed calm and collected
and continued to suck it
up, that I might have...
- No, I didn't say that.
- I-I didn't.
I hate the way they treated you.
I just miss you, okay?
I miss you.
I hate sleeping without you.
Nothing's fun without you.
♪ Oh, baby, I
miss you so much ♪
When I left, I was a mess,
and it was easier for me
to leave the whole
chapter behind me.
But I spent so many nights...
♪ And I'll begin,
don't touch me now ♪
wishing you'd show
up on my doorstep.
What changed?
♪ And this is springtime ♪
Nothing.
Nothing's changed.
Trey.
Simone Audrey Griffith,
I've loved you
since the day I met you and...
And every single day since.
♪ I've fallen into the blue ♪
You're
my favorite person.
You're my North Star.
Alright, you're my past
and you're my future.
Baby, put your ring
back on and marry me.
Marry
me for real this time.
♪ I'll learn to
let go of you ♪
♪ But don't try to stop me ♪
Yeah? Yeah.
Yeah? Yes, yes, yes.
♪ Don't try to stop me ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm in recovery ♪
Your pie was the best thing
that happened tonight, hands down.
In fairness,
the bar was very low.
You gonna tell me
what this is about,
or are you gonna make
me drag it out of you?
The resentment.
I've been sensing it on
you for a while now and...
I can smell it
on you like cheap cologne.
Yeah, well, my cologne is
cheap, so maybe it's just that.
I do not want to end up
like Hunt and Altman.
Before you went to work,
we were doing so well.
Wait... I
know you're not saying
you resent me
going back to work.
I do.
I don't know what I expected,
but it wasn't that.
Look, I am aware that
I sound like an ass.
I'm working on it.
And I hate myself
for even saying it,
but I-I've never done
this before, Miranda.
I've never parented
a little girl.
A-And Pru's lost so
much in her life.
I just... I worry, you know,
that... that I'm
not doing it right.
And I... I miss you.
Okay, I know starting
up this clinic
has been a big undertaking,
but I am prioritizing
our family...
I mean, I'm limiting
my hours in the OR,
I'm barely taking weekend calls,
I'm... I'm delegating
to Wilson...
But now you're saying
that isn't enough?
Can we please just go home now?
God, yes.
This is sad.
I can fix it.
I got the feels
for ya ♪
That's how I know it's real ♪
Why?
Real love ♪
Just get up!
♪ Yeah, I got the
feels for ya, woo ♪
♪ That's how I know
it's real love ♪
Real love ♪
Hey!
I got the feels for ya ♪
Come on.
♪ That's how I know
it's real love ♪
Real love ♪
I got the feels for ya ♪
Yeah ♪
♪ That's how I know
it's real, real love ♪
♪ Yeah, I got the
feels for ya, woo ♪
♪ That's how I know
it's real love ♪
Real love ♪
I got the feels ♪
Feels, feels, feels ♪
Do you feel the love? ♪
Ooh, yeaaah ♪
Dr. Cohen to Radiology.
Dr. Harlene Cohen
to Radiology.
Brought you these.
It's kinda a weird
breakfast, but, uh...
Here.
Thank you.
For, um...
everything.
Kwan?
Kwan.
I explicitly took you
off of Natalia's case.
Okay, look.
You want me to pretend that
medical bills don't exist?
That the system
doesn't force people
to choose between
bankruptcy and death?
Dr. Kwan, that... If my
mom could've divorced me,
she would've done
it in a heartbeat,
but I opened up credit
cards to pay for her care,
and every time I get a bill,
it feels like a
noose around my neck.
Forgive me for not wanting
to put someone
else through that.
Dr. Kwan, I...
Um...
How'd it go last night?
Is everything okay?
Nothing is okay.
Everyone is in pain.
Maggie, what's going on?
When you and Catherine were
going through your rough patch
where you couldn't, um,
speak to each other
without fighting,
how did you know that it
was just a rough patch
and it wasn't something more...
malignant?
Well, I think with...
With Catherine, uh,
we always still had the
love underneath it all.
When that dries up,
then it's time to reevaluate.
Surgical intervention
doesn't always work.
Look, Maggie,
whatever's going on,
you and Winston have so
much love between you
that whatever it is,
you'll work through it.
I know you will.
Thank you. Thank you.
♪ Like trying to find
a missing person ♪
Sometimes, despite
our schooling and centuries
of medical advancement,
the disease wins.
♪ From the inside out ♪
Well, looks like Whitney
and her wife made up.
Well, babies don't give you
much room to hold a grudge.
♪ Like trying to
dive into a river ♪
You cut your hair.
I discovered I have a lot
of free time during the day
when all my patients
cancel on me.
Looks nice.
♪ Like holding candles with
no matches ♪ [ Chuckles ]
Oh! I can't believe you
two are still here. Ugh.
Yeah, Scout and I
got board-certified
in OB-GYN last night and
delivered a baby. Mm.
Nope, not joking.
How was your surgery?
It was fine. It was
just a long night.
Yeah.
I'm gonna slip out the back
and try to get home
this time. Mm-hmm.
- Bye.
- Okay.
He just... held a laboring
mom's hand for hours
and took care of her
like it was his job,
all while in the midst of
a major personal crisis.
He's perfect.
How do you just let
someone like that go?
I've also had a long night.
He wasn't perfect for me.
But maybe he's perfect for you?
It takes over our
cells one by one,
until the damage can no longer
be reversed.
I didn't wake you, did I?
No, I was just...
resting my eyes.
Yeah.
I just had the longest,
strangest, saddest night
and wanted to see your face.
Well, here it is.
Will you fly here real quick
and hit the button
on the coffee maker?
When that happens,
all you can do is take
the loss and move on.
♪ I keep searching ♪
♪ For something ♪
I'm so sorry. I-I didn't know.
Forget it.
But when you can change the
course of someone's disease,
you can change the
course of their life.
You missed a helluva
party last night, Millin.
Griffith's got some big news.
Wow! Congratulations.
You all are late for rounds
and being hungover is no excuse.
I need clothes
off and scrubs on.
Get up!
Oh, go fall on a lightsaber.
♪ All the broken
puzzle pieces ♪
It's enough to make you want
to come back the next day
and do it all over again.
♪ That used
to fit together somehow ♪