- Okay, so basically you want
Bobbi to stay up for you?
She could at least try.
- Just for a few
good night kisses.
- Right.
- And then go to sleep
super easy
with no bouncing, white noise,
or tiptoeing required.
Very realistic plan.
- I have been using
the five Ss by the way.
Thank you for that.
- Yeah.
- Really knocks Luna out.
Lifesaver.
- The real lifesaver is
you can take Luna to work.
Sadly, Bobbi's not into
the whole music scene.
- Not what she told me.
Is everything okay?
Yeah, I got
impossible-to-get tickets
for me and a friend to
see Carol Churchill's play.
- Oh, I'm dying to see that.
- And my friend just bailed.
- Oh.
- You should come.
- Um, yeah--no, uh...
- If you want, I mean.
No pressure.
- No, I mean if you want.
I don't wanna...
- If you don't,
that's cool.
- I'm into it.
Yes.
- Okay.
- Okay, so--
- Great.
- Yeah.
I'm sorry.
Sorry!
Sorry, I'm late.
I hate being the last one
here--uh, Sergeant Todd.
- Sir.
- Uh, are we very early
or very late?
- There's no meeting,
Dr. Goodwin.
- No meeting?
Why do I suddenly get the
feeling I'm being ambushed?
- No, no.
If this were an ambush
I would've placed myself
against that wall,
allowing the open door
to obscure me
as you entered the room.
I'm here to deliver a message
from the board
that they were
too afraid to deliver.
- Which is?
- You have to cut $2 million
from the budget
by the end of tomorrow.
And may I send a specifically
worded message back with you?
- As soon as we've picked
what goes.
Now, it appears in your tenure
at New Amsterdam,
you have created more than
200 very successful programs.
- Thank you, Todd.
- That have
absolutely no funding.
Most never did.
This one here, CF56Z,
costs exactly 2 million.
We could get this done
right now.
- Great, CF56Z,
that would be...hmm.
"Postnatal Care for
Undocumented Mothers."
- That's unfortunate.
- It is, Todd.
- I'm not here to argue
which of these programs
deserves to stay.
I'm here to make sure that
2 million dollars'
worth of them goes.
- And if I refuse?
- Then New Amsterdam
will not make payroll.
And tomorrow
every one of your employees
will be sent home
without a dime.
- Notice anything
different about me?
And don't say my hair
because I chopped it off last
year, and I will punch you.
- Good morning.
- What?
That's what people say
when they first interact
for in day.
- Yeah, well, it was implied.
Hey now--
- All I'm saying is that every
time I'm in the hallway
people are jumping out at me
mid-conversation.
It's rude.
There is always time
for manners.
- Outside of nuclear
submarines,
this is literally the place
with the least amount of time
for manners.
Now, you know what?
I'm just gonna tell you.
It's my leg.
I'm finally better.
No more braces,
no more crutches...
- Lauren.
- Oh, we really need
to work on your manners.
- Hey, we need help!
- Yes, sir?
- Yes, please, please.
Somebody help my wife!
- You don't have to shout.
- Just please tell me
what happened.
- She fell, hit her head--
- No, no.
- She was unconscious.
- I bumped my head.
It's not a big deal.
- Yes, it is a big deal!
I just slipped for a second.
- This is serious.
- Please, don't make
a drama out of it.
- Hi, I'm Dr. Bloom.
- Hi.
- We're gonna figure out just
how big a deal this is, okay?
- I promise you,
it looks worse than it is.
- Let's go to bay 27.
- I slipped on our way to Shul,
in front everyone we know.
- Okay, Dr. Walsh!
Please, can you come
stitch up a lac--
And let's get, um...
- Steph Goldman.
- Mrs. Goldman a CT scan.
- But it's the Sabbath.
No electricity.
- It's not a big deal.
- If mom hit her head,
it could be dangerous.
HaShem makes exceptions
to save a life.
- Uh, if you could just go
with Casey,
and I'm gonna bring
your mom right back, okay?
- Mom.
Mom, wait.
- Can I stay with her?
- Ah...
How did I get so lucky?
Is it okay if she stays?
- Uh, sure.
Yeah.
- Thank you.
Come here, sweetheart.
I am fine.
It looks worse than it is.
Your mother's a klutz.
- It's just a little blood.
Right?
- Oh, you must be
my new mentee, Dawn.
- Uh--
- Today must be
very exciting for you.
I still remember my first day
working in a hospital.
Oh.
Thank you, but I'm--
I'm actually--
- Now, before you join me
on my rounds,
I've compiled these books
you must read to give you
a proper framework on Neurology
at New Amsterdam.
- Dr. Kapoor.
I'm not Dawn.
I'm Dr. Gibbs,
the lead programmer.
- Programmer?
Yes.
This is D.A.W.N.
The Diagnostic Assessment
Wellness Network.
I don't understand.
You want me to mentor an iPad?
- Dawn is a prototype
for what we hope will become
the most advanced
Artificial Intelligence program
in medical diagnosing.
- But, wh--I'm--
no, no, no, no--
- You'll take D.A.W.N.
with you on rounds,
so it can improve
its algorithms,
and these textbooks,
I'll just upload them.
Upload?
It took me years
to read those books.
- Well, D.A.W.N.'s connected to
the hospital's medical network.
So you'll have instant access
to patient files,
radiology scans,
MRIs, lab data.
With your help, D.A.W.N. will
become the future of medicine.
- Nice to meet you,
Dr. Kay-poor.
- Mm.
- It's Kapoor!
- I refuse.
- Okay, Todd, here's the deal.
Since we are not gonna
cut anything major
from this budget,
we're gonna make a lot of
small cuts to each department.
- My commanding officer would
call that the Fabian Strategy.
- That's the one.
- You have no idea
what that is, do you?
- No, I do not.
- Max, you got a sec?
- Yeah.
- It's about my future.
- Great, I wanna talk to you
about your future as well.
- You do?
- Yeah.
You have, uh, seven
dual-chamber
pacemaker surgeries
on the books for tomorrow?
- That's right.
- Yeah, so those pacemakers
are made in Mexico,
but the American inventors
charge three times as much,
so we're gonna
cancel the order,
place it directly with the
manufacturer in Mexico city.
It's gonna save us 50,000,
but it's gonna, uh, have
to push your surgeries.
Why not save money on shipping
and just have me do
the surgeries in Mexico?
- No, that--
that was sarcasm.
- That was genius.
Mexico's opening tons
of new clinics
in response to our
skyrocketing medical costs.
We could pay for you and your
patients to fly to Mexico,
it's gonna save them in
co-pays, and us, like, 50--
$100,000.
- So my patients are supposed
to just go to Mexico tomorrow?
- Yeah.
Only if they're content with
getting the same surgery,
with the same surgeon
for less money
and a better view.
100,000 down.
You happy?
- Sure.
Why wouldn't I be happy about
outsourcing American jobs?
- That also--
- Sarcasm.
- Yeah.
- I don't know what Ralph
and Piggy thought
when they found it,
I think both the conch shell
and the boar's head symbolize
power, just different types.
- Knock knock.
I hate to interrupt
the creative process,
but I have the results
of your biopsy.
The mass in your stomach
turned out to be a Primitive
Neuroectodermal Tumor.
- Tumor?
- The good news is,
it's benign.
Surgeons should be able
to remove it,
and Cephas will make
a full recovery.
- What caused it?
- Tumors are very sensitive
to hormone levels
inside the body,
and in Cephas' case,
he had an excessive amount
of cortisol,
which is one of the body's
main stress hormones.
How does a 13-year-old
get a tumor from stress?
- That's what
I'd like to find out.
- Dr. Sharpe didn't
say anything
about the tumor
being in my brain.
- No, no, no, no.
Um...
that's a little misleading.
Psych is not just about what's
going on in your head.
Because what is going on
up there
can affect
your entire body, right?
In your case, excessive
cortisol levels caused a tumor,
but cortisol is triggered by
PTSD, stress, anxiety--
- But, I don't have
any of those things.
PTSD?
My life was pretty boring
until I came here.
- Okay.
Do you have any stressors
in your life?
- I'm good.
Home's good.
School's good.
My biggest stressor
is the school librarian.
- The librarian?
All right.
What's happening there?
Tell me about that.
- She refuses to let me
check out some books
because they're reserved
for gifted students--
even though I've been
reading them for years.
That's it.
- But that upset you.
- Yeah.
But they're just books.
Who cares?
- Well, yeah, but they're
not just books, are they?
And I think that you care.
I think you care
very much.
Tell me why.
- Because I'm smart too.
- Yeah.
Does anyone else in your life
make you feel that way?
Less than?
Diminished?
- I'm 13,
so, like...everybody.
- You know what?
Let's, uh, let's try something
different here.
Yes.
All right, Cephas, I'm going
to read a few remarks,
and you simply have to reply
one through ten.
One meaning almost never,
ten meaning almost always.
Okay?
Piece of cake.
Here we go.
What you think doesn't count
very much.
- Ten.
- Ten?
Really?
- Yeah, ten.
Ten it is.
You feel excluded, isolated.
- Ten.
- The rich get richer
while the poor get poorer.
- Absolutely ten.
- When I walk into a store,
I am followed
or closely watched.
- Ten.
These questions are easy.
- You feel threatened,
harassed,
even if you can't
articulate why.
- Ten.
- Make yourself comfortable,
there's a couch over there.
- Hey.
Is he okay?
- Yeah, yeah, he's, um--
he's okay.
I had Cephas answer some
questions from a Harvard test
known as "Unrest."
It is designed to, um,
measure someone's level
of social resistance.
- Social resistance?
- When people like us oppose
the values and policies
of the dominant culture.
- That's right.
- And what does that
have to do with--
- Your son, he feels threatened
on a daily basis.
Like everything he's earned can
just be taken away.
He's disenfranchised.
But because his life is
seemingly free from all this,
because he can't name it,
he's internalizing it.
- Name what?
- Racism.
I think your son's tumor
was caused by racism.
- Good to see you,
Mrs. Holland.
- Dr. Reynolds, this place...
no offence, but it's so much
nicer than New Amsterdam.
- I'm glad you approve.
I'll see you in there.
Wow, this is quite
the operation.
We're pretty proud of it.
For people who can't afford
American healthcare
or a nice safe alternative.
- And you only do
pacemakers here?
- Focusing one procedure
makes us hyper efficient.
- How efficient?
- Well, we can usually
knock out about 11 a day.
Ah--that's pretty efficient.
It may not be as fancy
as your cardio wing, but--
- It definitely is.
It's nice!
- How long have
you been Chair?
- Uh, for about a year,
but I'm leaving.
- Oh, I hear you.
Public hospitals are what
sent me packing for Mexico.
- Oh, I actually love
New Amsterdam.
- Then why?
- I love my fiancée more.
- Max!
Max, I need to talk to you.
- Yeah, what's up?
- She keeps coming back.
- Should I be made aware
of any suspicious activity?
- Just stand down, Todd.
- She wants to teach a computer
to replace me.
After all the personal
sacrifices I've made,
just to have an iPad
steal my knowledge--
it is not
"artificial" intelligence,
it is my intelligence.
- Max we're due in dermatology.
- I know.
Vijay, since I have no idea
what you're talking about,
I'm gonna trust you
to make the right decision.
- Thank you.
I won't do it.
No matter how much her company
is paying the hospital.
- Come again?
- How much are they
paying the hospital?
- They are--
- $160,000.
- Really?
That's, uh--Vijay,
my friend, I think
that you and the iPad
might've gotten off
on the wrong foot.
- My body's been sore, and my
girl saw this crazy rash.
- I have a couple of theories.
The first one I think--
- Diagnosis confirmed.
Lyme disease.
An email is being sent
to your account
with detailed
treatment information.
- Yes,
something to do with your--
- I'm sorry,
but let me see--I--I...
- What happens next?
- We wait for the results
from your CT scan.
Unfortunately, it can take
a couple hours to arrive
from, uh, Radiology
because--
- CT scan results
have arrived.
- Diagnosis ACA aneurysm.
- What?
- What? Where?
- What, what?
- Aneurysm is located
on the anterior clinoid
segment--
- Nobody likes a show-off,
so just shut up, okay?
- I-I have to go.
I need that back please.
Okay.
You keep it.
Every day, 9:30-9:45--
Sandra Fall from billing!
Hi.
How goes it?
- It doesn't go good because
you can't code for racism.
- And yet, I did, so...
- No, you hand-wrote
a non-option in the margin
like a Bern Bro during
the 2016 General Election.
- Yes, I did, because
there isn't a code
for my actual diagnosis.
- Okay, then change
your diagnosis
to an approved ICD-10 code
because that's how we bill
insurance companies.
- No.
No, I'm sorry,
I'm not gonna change
my diagnosis,
Sandra Fall from billing--
not this time.
Many, many times I've played it
fast and loose
with insurance codes
to help patients.
- Please, don't tell me that!
- Many times.
But this time it will
actually hurt patients.
Like, specifically
the 13-year-old boy
who is lying in our OR
with a tumor.
He's proof that racism
can cause life-threatening
medical issues,
and no one is doing
anything about it
because no one is tracking
the data to prove it.
And do you know why no one is
tracking the data to prove it?
- Because the ICD-10 doesn't
have a diagnostic code for it?
- Exactly.
- Dr. Frome,
go ahead, change the world,
but not until
you change the ICD codes.
That's--
- Clamp.
- Cephas' tumor's
nestled up against
the inferior mesenteric.
- I can definitely
get in there.
Forceps.
- NR BP 55.
- Dr. Ayton,
look at this.
Right next to the duodenum.
- Another tumor.
- Patient is hemodynamically
stable.
- And looks like another two
right at the celiac junction.
- Four total?
- Surgery's gonna take
a bit longer.
- I'll go tell his mother.
- Helen, from what I can tell,
these tumors are just going
to keep recurring.
And next time they might not
be benign.
- Stand by with
pylorus clamp.
- Okay, give it to me straight,
Todd.
- 100,000 from cardiothoracic--
- Yep.
- 160k from neurology--
- 45,000 from dermatology.
- Come on, admit it.
This skimming thing
is kind of working, right?
- So long as everyone
does their part
and sacrifices
for the greater good.
- Exactly.
- Like Communism.
- Max!
- Yeah?
- Notice anything different
about me?
- Actually,
I have been noticing
a lot of your patients
are being admitted
before they need to be.
Uh, ACS, pre-crisis diabetics--
The thing is, if they don't
actually end up in crisis,
then we can't bill for it.
- It's my leg.
Um, finally better.
No biggie.
- That's great.
So, it would save this hospital
a lot of money
if you could keep
these patients in the ED
for observation until a crisis
diagnosis can be confirmed.
- If you don't mind hiring
20 more nurses,
a dozen more orderlies,
and increasing
the number of residents,
and adding, like,
30 beds, then sure.
Excuse me!
This area is off limits!
You can't just keep coming back
here like this!
Who the hell
do you think you are?
Uh...
- So ultimately,
I don't think it's going to
save you any money.
- She seems fun.
- Yeah, I'll figure out
whatever, uh, that was,
but right now
I need a new strategy.
- We could always
revisit cutting CF56Z.
- You mean "Postnatal Care
for Undocumented Mothers."
- I mean to save this hospital.
From your own good intentions.
- I need some help here!
Grab me an orderly
and a non-rebreather mask!
- Hey, what happened?
- She just started walking
and collapsed.
- Okay, well, let's get her
back on her feet.
- I-I can't feel my legs.
- Where?
What part?
- All over.
Everywhere.
- What do her CTs say?
- Nothing.
They were all clear.
- Do we need a collar?
- Please, I--
I can't--I can't feel my legs.
- Mom?
Are you okay?
- I can't feel my legs.
What's going on?
Please!
- She didn't hit her head.
She just fell down.
- Sir.
- Hi there.
- Ma'am.
- Um, thank you for agreeing
to meet us here.
- We thought neutral territory
would be best
for what Dr. Goodwin
has to say.
- Yeah.
- Max, I think
I can save New Amsterdam
and the city of New York
hundreds of millions
of dollars.
- Oh, then you should
definitely go first.
- There's a 13-year-old boy
in surgery right now
having multiple tumors removed
caused by racism.
I know--I know how that sounds,
trust me, I do,
but yesterday, I treated
two patients with PTSD
from the exact same thing.
Our ED,
at least three times a week,
treats victims of hate crimes.
The city is spending hundreds
of millions of dollars
managing medical repercussions
of racism,
and it doesn't even know it
because the ICD-10
does not have a code for it.
- This is not
gonna save us money.
- How can I help?
- A campaign
to make the ICD-10
add racism
to their diagnostic index.
All I need
is a little bit of money
for a small team of
researchers and lobbyists--
No.
- What?
Say that again?
- No.
- That's--I've never heard you
say that word before.
- In order to balance
the budget,
Max has no choice
but to cut personnel.
- How awful.
- Did you guys have
anyone in mind?
- Back away slowly.
Go, go, slower.
Okay, break.
Break--break for it.
- Four tumors,
all being removed--
it's just going to take
a little bit more time.
- Why is this happening
to my son?
- Uh...
Cephas let me read his essay
on "Lord of the Flies,
and it's clear
just how open he is.
to the world.
And while that openness lets in
a lot of beauty,
it also lets in darker things.
- God, I really thought
that I shielded him from...
everything that
I have to deal with.
I jumped through hoops to get
him into a progressive school
with a uniform policy.
I got him into group sports
with diverse coaches.
His friends are amazing.
I--
I thought I was doing
a good job, I really--
- You--you are doing more
than a good job.
That boy is extraordinary
because of you.
Even here,
in this progressive hospital,
I deal with microaggressions
every day.
From people who mean well.
From people
who should know better.
That's the world
that we live in.
- So, then what can I do
to keep my son from ending up
here next year?
Next month?
- Have you been out of country
recently?
- No.
- Been bitten by an animal
or a rodent?
- Uh, just the occasional
mosquito bite.
- Started any new diets?
- We keep kosher.
Nothing trendy.
- Swam in any natural
bodies of water?
- No.
Do you have any idea
what's happening to me?
- Will you excuse us
for a second?
Okay.
Any theories?
- Guillain-Barre syndrome
and Zika
are both known
to cause leg paralysis,
but her tests
came back normal.
- And her CT came back negative
except for some swelling
around the spine.
- The only viable option right
now is to treat her symptoms,
push steroids to reduce
her spinal swelling,
unless D.A.W.N. has a different
diagnosis to humiliate me.
D.A.W.N.-ji?
This is bad.
This is my favorite achievement
since coming here.
Free daycare for all employees.
- I don't see how getting rid
of a few daycare employees
is gonna put a dent
in the budget.
- Well, we contract out
the daycare service.
It's a luxury,
I mean, it's not essential,
and if we close it,
we might break even.
- You're closing the daycare?
- Now, Mariana,
I wouldn't even consider this
unless I absolutely had to.
I mean, I need the daycare too.
- So do a lot of the nurses
and residents.
- I hear you, but--
- I don't think you do.
- Do you know how expensive
regular daycare is?
Not to mention,
they're only open ten hours,
and most of us work
12-hour shifts.
Are you gonna cut our hours
and pay us more too?
- I need to cut costs
just to make payroll.
- Well,
you can keep my paycheck
because if we have to pay
for daycare,
a lot of us will need new jobs.
- We're not gonna cut
daycare, are we?
- At the aortic arch.
- Anterior wall
of the left atrium
looks prime for placement
of the first lead.
- All right, advancing now.
- Just as good
as at New Amsterdam?
I'm not gonna lie to you,
I'm pretty proud
of what we accomplished.
I mean, that's what makes
leaving so hard, you know?
Whoa.
Is that from a lung?
Did I hit something?
- No, it's from her stomach.
Massive hematemesis.
- Maybe it's a bleeding ulcer
or a Mallory Weiss Tear.
- It looks like
variceal bleeding.
- Her cirrhotic liver
decompensated.
The blood is backing up
behind it.
We need to make a new pathway
so the blood
can bypass the liver.
- Heart rate's up to 130.
- All right, transfuse 2
units of packed red cells.
- We don't have a blood bank.
We're not a hospital.
I'm calling an ambulance.
- Her blood pressure's
dropping.
We don't have time.
We're working on her now.
- I told you,
we're only equipped
for cardiac emergencies.
- Then we have to treat
Grace's liver like a heart.
- She's never there anymore.
She's only about her trial
these days.
- Uh, can I run
something by you?
- Sure,
but where's your bodyguard?
- Oh, I gave him the slip.
- Really?
- No, that's impossible.
He's at lunch.
- I'm having a bit
of a budget crisis,
and I finally figured out
a way to, uh, close the gap.
You ready?
- As ready as I'll ever be.
- Okay, I want to eliminate
all over-testing.
- That's a great idea.
- Really?
- Oh, my God,
you're the first person who has
not wanted to strangle me,
or you know,
slam the door in my face.
What test did you have in mind?
- I wanna cut
yearly mammograms.
- Sorry?
- I know how that sounds,
okay, but
the US Preventative Task Force
says they're unnecessary
for women under 50
unless of course they fall
into a high-risk group.
- Yeah, the American Cancer
Society says 45.
A woman's individual doctor
might say 40.
These tests aren't one-size
fits all.
- I'm not saying they are.
All I am saying
is women under 50
are more likely
to get false positive
and therefore
be over-diagnosed
and over-treated
for something
that may ultimately be
benign.
- Someone may want
that peace of mind.
- Well, but should New
Amsterdam be paying for it?
- Fine, cut yearly mammograms.
- Really?
- Sure.
- Thank you.
- Except those mammograms
are actually money-makers
for this hospital.
- I walked right into this,
didn't I?
- If you cut mammograms paid
for by insurance,
I'm fairly certain
it's gonna make your budget
shortfall even worse.
- What about mammograms not
covered by insurance?
- So you're suggesting
two standards of care,
one for women with insurance
and one for women without?
- No, because that would be--
- Draconian.
- Yeah.
And I would be ashamed to even
be having this conversation.
- Don't be,
because I'm sure Castro
will cut whatever you want.
- Mm.
- Glad I was at lunch
for that one.
- These cardiac stents
are too small.
They're made to open
a tiny artery,
not make a large conduit
for bypassing the liver.
- If I can just get
this last stent in place,
the portal vein and the
hepatic vein will flow as one.
- Switch ultrasound
to Doppler mode.
- I don't see anything.
There's no flow.
- You missed the connection.
We must have gone too distal.
- BP's dropping again.
- Hang a bag of Dobutamine.
Titrate to 3 micrograms.
- I'm gonna try
to pass the wire.
See if you can grab it,
all right?
That'll help us
make the connection.
Little further.
A little further.
Now.
- Got it.
- Muy bien.
- Looks like flow.
I can't believe it.
- Gauze.
- Forgot how much
I missed real medicine.
- My baby.
- Okay, but the W.H.O.
needs a sponsor,
and I can't--I can't get
a sponsor until the W.H.O.--
Right exactly.
Yes.
- Iggy!
- Yes, I'll be there.
Thank you very much.
- Iggy, where have you been?
- Every day patients come in
with so many stressors
that I have no idea
what the problem is.
With Cephas, I know exactly
what the problem is,
but I can't to do
anything about it,
which is just crazy-maker,
you know?
So I just managed
to get a meeting
with a member the World Health
Organization so I can lobby--
- Okay, Iggy, I love you,
and I mean this
in the best possible way--
- Uh-oh.
- Forget about trying
to save the world
and focus on trying
to save our patient,
'cause no one else is going to.
- Help.
Help, please, help.
- Okay, deep breaths for me,
Steph, okay?
Deep breaths.
- Now I can't move my arms.
- Okay, let's get her on 100%
non-rebreather and a stat EKG.
- Squeeze my hands.
Come on, as hard as you can.
- I can't.
Steph!
- Okay, let's get her
on 2 milligrams of Ativan.
2 milligrams of Ativan!
Oh, Mommy...
I need that Ativan!
- Mommy, please stop.
- Ascending paralysis.
Soon she won't be able
to breathe.
- It could be
Neuro-Bechet's Disease.
- Diagnostic accuracy
below 1%.
- A tumor can cause
paraneoplastic syndrome.
- Diagnostic accuracy
less than 1%.
- D.A.W.N. if you do not
have any actual ideas,
please shut up.
- Advise patient be placed
in phenobarbital coma
until diagnosis
can be reached.
- Tell me we're not
doing that.
- If we do not reach
diagnosis today...
We'll have to.
I really thought
we could do it.
- We knew this
would be painful.
Why do you think
Brantley sent me?
- I could chip away at it,
but every cut
just makes this hospital worse.
- Which is why
I still think you should pick
one big ticket item.
Will it make
the hospital worse?
Unfortunately, yes.
But will it compromise every
single one of your departments?
No.
- Yeah.
You know,
we were the first hospital
in the country
to cover postnatal care
for undocumented mothers.
We were trying
to be pioneers.
Now I can make payroll.
- Max.
You did the right thing.
- Well, it looks like
Klinger's missed
11 games this year,
and he's been battling
this injury all season.
- Oh, missed the second
free throw.
Miller with the rebound.
- Are we winning?
- He's got seven assists...
- Oh, I'm sorry.
Please, please,
don't tell my dad.
- Ah, the Sabbath.
No electricity.
- It's just a really big game.
- Your secret is safe
with me.
Nets fans have suffered
enough.
- May I?
You must miss many games
because of the Sabbath.
- Well, I kind of make
an exception for the Nets.
We haven't won a championship
game in my whole life,
but we're doing
really well this year.
- Hm.
- Mm-hmm.
- So do you break
any other Sabbath rules?
- No way.
Never.
- Shirley...
this is question is a matter
of life and death.
I believe you have
kept the Sabbath, but...
have you kept kosher?
- Vijay, you paged?
- Hot dog!
- What are we talking about?
- Shirley secretly ate
a street vendor's hot dog.
- Shirley got a tapeworm?
- And passed
its eggs unknowingly
to her mother with a kiss.
- Neurocysticercosis.
Did D.A.W.N. confirm?
- I turned D.A.W.N. off.
Two tablets each,
and they will be cleared up.
- I...
I don't understand.
Did I hurt my mom?
- No, Shirley.
You saved her life.
- Hey, there, kiddo.
How you doing?
- Better.
- Better is good.
Very good.
So listen, I have...
I have one question that was
not on my list from earlier.
You feel up to answering it?
Why wouldn't the librarian
let you take out those books?
- I don't know.
- Well, I think you do know.
I think you know it so well
that it is
eating you up inside,
and it is causing you
to be sick.
Why wouldn't the librarian
let you take out those books?
- Because of the color
of my skin.
But she's not racist.
- Yeah, I don't doubt that
for a second.
But, you know,
racism is so deeply ingrained
in our society that people,
myself included,
we often don't realize
that we're perpetuating it.
- So, like...
when people give me
nicknames I don't want
'cause my name is different?
- Yes,
that is a microaggression
because of the color
of your skin.
- What about when adults tell
me I speak really good English?
- It's because of the color
of your skin.
- Or when people assume
I only got into my school
'cause I'm diverse?
- Yes.
- When the teacher tells me
to lower my voice,
even though I'm not
the only one talking?
Or she makes me answer
all the Latino questions
'cause I'm the only one
in the room?
- Yes.
- I just thought...
I didn't deserve to be there.
I wasn't good enough.
I was a mistake.
- No, Cephas, listen to me.
All of this,
everything you're talking about
has nothing to do with you,
and everything to do
with the world around you.
You walking around with all
of this shame and confusion
and stress inside your body,
I can see that you don't
want to feel this right now.
But I'm telling you, your body
is definitely feeling it,
and that is what
is making you sick.
- So...
How are you
gonna fix the world?
- I'm not.
I can't.
But I can help you process.
Because if we can name it,
we can treat it.
- You win.
What do you want, Mom?
- Dinner.
- May, how long
has Fatima been like this?
- All day.
- You should've paged me.
- She's listed
as Castro's patient.
- Fatima, sweetheart,
can I help you get back?
- I'm fine.
Fine, fine, fine.
- Okay.
Have you seen Dr. Castro?
- Dr. Castro said
my numbers are good.
I'm good.
Better than good.
She said her trial's helping.
- Yeah.
- Max, I got some bad news.
- I'm already there,
so just hit me.
- Mexico is not the answer
to your budget crisis.
You know, we shouldn't be
sending our patients
2,000 miles away.
It erodes our hospital.
And American hospitals
are eroded enough.
And, Max, the other thing
I gotta tell you,
it can't wait anymore,
all right?
- Floyd, you're the best.
I gotta go.
Hey, wait!
Excuse me.
Todd.
Wait, buddy, hold up.
Hey.
Listen,
I found a way to make payroll,
save $2 million,
and not cut a single program.
- How?
Add a program.
- Todd, there are two ways
to meet the budget, right?
We were trying to cut costs,
but what if we tried
to add revenue?
Okay, what we need
isn't less programs,
it's more patients.
- I think you've got all
the sick people you can handle.
- Exactly.
And so does
every other hospital.
New Amsterdam has every
specialist under the sun.
Right? But other hospitals
can't even afford
to keep one specialist
on staff full time.
America is full of people
who have specific medical needs
that their local hospitals
can't meet,
but we can.
So instead of outsourcing
our patients,
we're gonna outsource
our doctors.
Okay, yeah, I'm gonna call it
something better,
but I have commitments already
from Bridgeport Medical
in Alabama,
Mount Ida Memorial in Arkansas,
Townsend Hospital Center
in Delaware.
Look, we can fill America's
healthcare gaps,
we can get fairly compensated,
and most importantly,
we can...
we can balance the budget.
What?
Am I too late?
The budget's already in?
- I threw it away.
- You what?
- Your budget.
Threw it away.
- Threw it away?
Why?
- I knew
you'd come up with something.
- Huh.
Hi.
You look really nice.
- So do you.
- Thanks.
- Here you go.
- Right.
Yeah.
Um...
I'm sorry.
I don't think I can do this.
Thank God.
Me, neither.
- Really?
- Yeah, I feel incredibly
guilty just being here.
And I know I shouldn't,
but I--
- Yeah, no, it just
sneaks up on you, right?
- My husband was a musician.
He took his own life.
- Sorry.
- I don't talk
about that much.
- Yeah, no--
- Ever.
But the moment
I start to feel happiness,
a wave of panic just...
- Yeah.
- Is that crazy
to be triggered by happiness?
- No.
- Sorry I ruined the evening.
- No, I mean...
you--you didn't.
You didn't ruin anything.
Um...
- ♪ It's hard
to put it into words ♪
♪ When I tried,
I felt absurd ♪
♪ You light the rooms
of my soul ♪
♪ I tell myself
not to lose control ♪
♪ I'll take it slow,
but it's hard to do ♪
Yeah, this is Max.
- Sorry, I thought
I'd get your voicemail.
- No, that's okay.
Who is this?
- My name's Nolene George,
and I heard there was
an opening at New Amsterdam.
I'd love to be considered
for the position.
- Sorry, what position?
- Chair
of cardiothoracic surgery.
Since Dr. Reynolds is leaving.
- ♪ Damn