Renegades. Rule breakers.
Gangsters with scalpels.
This is the way we like
to think of ourselves.
It makes us feel bad-ass. Sexy.
- Can you wash this,
too?
- Jackson...
Shh.
Is there anywhere
you don't do it?
- We should go upstairs.
- Yeah.
Yeah...
Problem is, it's
not exactly true.
At heart, we're rule
followers. Sheep.
We don't break protocol.
We follow it to a T.
Why is there a trailer
in my parking spot?
Is one of these yours? My bad.
You're living here? In a
trailer in the parking lot?
I'm in the race for chief
resident, you know?
I get to the surgeries first,
I'm here when the chief arrives.
Just get the thing out of
my spot, and move my car.
Because if we don't follow
protocol, our patients die.
And then we're no longer
bad-ass. We're just bad.
When are the two of you
finally getting married?
Um, Meredith and Derek already
got married, honey. Remember?
I know that! They wrote on a
Post-it. I meant a real wedding,
in a church with a white dress.
This isn't Alzheimer's, Richard.
Adele, the tests
we ran last month
showed findings consistent
with early-onset Alzheimer's.
I was a nurse for 30 years, Derek.
I know what Alzheimer's looks like.
I also know that 20 percent of
the people that are diagnosed with it
turn out to have something else.
I don't have Alzheimer's. I don't!
So, a lot of patients need time to
come to terms with their diagnosis.
- The same thing
happened to my mother.
- We don't have time.
Derek, we need to get
Adele in on your trial right now.
We need her consent
to even consider her.
I'll take care of
that, don't worry.
We don't even know if she fits
the criteria, and the trial is full.
- Even the waiting list is full.
- I know all of that.
I also know that you'll do whatever
you need to do to help my wife.
Everything looks fine. Right
on track for 23 and a half weeks.
- How's his size?
- Oh, Mark.
It's OK. I'm used to that
trick. Its size is within the norm.
Come on, we're here.
You know you want to know.
No, no, no, you want to know.
We prefer an element of surprise.
- Callie?
- Mark, we voted, two to one.
- We're waiting.
- Uh, your BP is borderline
high.
- Are you feeling OK?
- Oh, yeah, no. That's the
nerves about the baby shower.
Yeah, it's like, um, it's
like Christmas morning.
You are way too
excited about this.
Hey, I have bought
expensive gifts
and played stupid games for
every knocked up nurse in this place.
Now, it's my turn.
You're coming, right?
Arizona, you invite the OB. The
fate of my vagina is in her hands.
Yeah, um...
- 1:00 pm, fourth floor
doctor's lounge.
- I'll see if I can make it.
I'll make it.
Hee.
- What's that about?
- Chief's in the bathroom.
- With an audience?
- His trial funding
came through this morning,
and they all want on it.
Door's opening!
- My specialty!
- I'm the best one qualified.
Wait, quiet! I haven't
made my decision yet!
Get out of the way!
Stalking a man while
he's in the restroom?
I'd clean the restroom if
he'd let me on this trial.
- I'd live in it.
- You are surgeons.
If you want to impress the
chief, impress him surgically.
- Avery, you're with me.
- OK...
So you've been all
buddy-buddy with Webber lately.
I'm staying out of it. But
you... you're very beautiful.
Oh, screw
beautiful! I'm brilliant!
You wanna appease
me, compliment my brain!
OK.
- Ah, Sonya! You ready for the big day?
- You bet.
Try to shave as little
of my head as possible.
It's hard enough dating with
Alzheimer's. I can't be bald, too.
I promise. You must be Tarik.
Congratulations on the
marathon, by the way.
- You didn't.
- - He's not like other doctors.
He's actually
interested in his patients.
I heard you just moved
back from London?
I came as soon as you accepted us
into the trial. I can't thank you enough.
I'm glad you're here. Thank you.
I'm gonna let Dr. Grey
get on with her work,
and I'll see
you in a little bit.
OK, Mrs. Amin, I'm going
to say three words to you
and ask you to repeat them back
to me later. Truck, cabin, spoon.
Truck, cabin, spoon.
OK. What did you do for
Thanksgiving last year?
Oh, I was in
London visiting Tarik.
What? Why, is that wrong?
Last year you were at
the Simmons', remember?
No, I was with you
and Gavin in London.
I have that picture
outside the palace.
That was three years ago,
Mom, before we broke up.
- You really should call him.
- He broke up with me.
We're not getting back together. Sorry.
Out of all the things she can't remember
- she still remembers the ex.
- OK.
Starting at 100, count
backwards by seven.
One hundred, 93...
- Good morning, Clara.
- Good's kinda pushing it.
Yeah, I hear you. Dr. Avery?
Clara Green, 42, Type 1 diabetic. Eight
weeks post-op from a tumor resection.
You know what? No. I'm sorry.
I can't listen to the kid today.
- I would like to hear
from the grown-up doctor.
- Sean!
I don't want to hear from the
stupid kid anymore, I want answers!
Sean, um, I know it's
incredibly frustrating...
You don't know. My kids are
in Iowa, living with my parents.
I barely survived that house,
now I'm inflicting it on my kids?
Diabetes is a
bear of an illness.
Now, the tumor removal was
successful, but we knew it could be tough
getting the insulin levels on
track, and, yeah, it has been tough.
Well, that's not good
enough anymore.
- We are doing everything...
- Sean?
She's doing better
than any of us expected.
Remember when we talked about how
she might not make it through the surgery?
Dr. Bailey said she was
prepared to roll the dice,
but surgery was a
gamble. And Clara rocked it.
And if she can do that,
she can do anything.
You need any help today? Robbins
has her baby shower so I'm free.
- I still don't like you, Karev.
- Dude.
Goodbye.
I just finished recasting
the O'Connor girl.
Did you still need me to
change Jason Cook's drain?
Nope. All done. You can handle
the rest of the patients, right?
I think we got a
thoracentesis in there.
- Really? Thank you!
- Yeah.
We're on for tonight,
seven o'clock reservation.
- Oh, you know it!
- All right.
You're gonna screw your
way to the top. I'm impressed.
- I am not screwing Stark.
- - "I am not screwing Stark."
- We're not even dating.
- "We're not even dating."
I'm serious, we're not. Maybe
I thought we were at first,
but it's not like that now.
We're just... hanging out.
- Friends.
- Yeah. Naked friends.
- What do you have?
- Jogger found unconscious
on the street. No ID.
Dr. Yang's running the code.
- He's in V-fib!
- OK.
Clear!
You had chest pain so
you decided to go for a jog?
- Ow! Oh.
- Sorry.
- How much morphine
did you give him?
- Ten.
He shouldn't be in this
much pain. Give him more.
So, what is this, a heart attack?
'Cause it sure feels like one.
I don't know. We're gonna
have to run some tests to find out.
Ah.
A jog?
Hey, it's not like I went
out for a cheeseburger.
Her name is Clara Green.
I know it's premature,
but I was thinking she could
be a candidate for your trial.
I still don't have approval
from the FDA, Bailey.
Sir, these people are desperate. If
we could make them first on the list
to give them something
to look forward to...
Why not just do
the surgery today?
Avery, just because the patient
called you a stupid kid doesn't
mean you should act like one.
She can't even take immunosuppressants
without risking her tumor coming back.
She's deteriorating by the hour. Why
not apply for an emergency waiver?
Because if something
goes wrong during surgery,
then it would kill the chief's
chance for getting approval.
- Sir, her kids
are stuck in Iowa...
- Dr. Avery!
With their grandparents
who are mean, sir.
Chief, Dr. Altman's paging you.
I'll call the FDA, see
if we can get a waiver
and get the patient on board.
What? I...
Where do you want this?
- What's that for?
- Scrapbook station.
Put it next to that box
with the glitter pens.
No, don't put it anywhere. We're
not having a scrapbook station.
You heard Callie this morning.
She wants us to go all out.
- Move the table.
- - No, don't move the table.
Mark, this isn't a scrapbook
station kind of shower.
You're wrong. Yang, tell her.
Torres wants all the girly stuff.
Games, onesie decorating...
- I have a patient.
- Grey?
I can't get over the fact that you
know what onesie decorating is.
I've been boning up. That's what
you do for the people you love.
- Bite me, Mark.
- Oh. What's going on?
Are you guys fighting again?
Did you want a
scrapbook station?
Oh, yeah, of course.
It's not a real shower
if you don't get to take
home a scrapbook.
Ooh! We should
have glitter pens!
No, you can't. Because
if you quit and move here,
you'll get depressed
and start to hate me.
Look, I have to go. Just...
please, stop calling. Goodbye.
We're ready, can
you bring the chart?
- Sure.
- Sorry. The boyfriend thing's
a little more complicated
than she can handle.
- So you two are
still together or...?
- No. Why?
Well, we require the caretaker to be a
full-time resident of the State of Washington.
- I know that.
- OK. I mean,
it's a big commitment.
And it may not feel like it
now, but six months from now,
a year down the road,
it can get overwhelming.
And if you think you might
move back to London,
if there's even the slightest
chance, you need to let us know.
Look, when I came out to my
family, my mother stood by me.
She loved me. And I know that
may not seem like a big deal to you,
but in my family, where we come
from, being gay isn't something
people just come to accept
after a while. It's a crime.
And people die because of it.
My father refused to
deal with it, so he left.
He got a new wife and
my mom lost everything.
This is, this is the
least I can do for her.
- I'm committed to this trial,
Dr. Grey.
- OK.
Now, islet cells
produce insulin.
We would put the cells
in a device in your body,
and it will act like a
brand-new pancreas.
We're contacting the FDA to
get their approval right now.
Say yes. I yelled at him this
morning, I acted like an ass.
What are the risks? They
have to be pretty serious, right?
Otherwise, the FDA
would've already approved it.
Dr. Bailey?
Yeah, there are risks,
of course. I was just
about to get there. Um...
there's heavy bleeding,
uh, low platelet counts,
um, and stress on the liver.
But in Clara's condition,
especially since we've
done everything else,
um, this really
is the best option.
Can we have some
more time? Is that OK?
Of course. Take all
the time you need.
Eli?
Go do something else.
- What was that?
- What was what?
I was getting to those
risks. You interrupted,
made it seem like I
was hiding something.
In my experience,
doctors do hide things.
I just asked a question they
didn't know to ask, that's all.
- No, that's not your job.
- I think it is.
To undermine surgeons
and alarm patients?
To care for patients.
That's my job.
Making sure they understand
what highly experimental procedures
they're signing up for
seems a part of that.
Oh. I thought that was my job,
especially considering that I'm the one
who specializes in said
highly experimental procedures.
Oh. OK, I get it. You're the doctor,
I'm the nurse. I should know my place.
OK, enough. Um...
There is a doctor-nurse protocol
in this hospital for a reason.
You know it, I know it.
Let's just agree to follow it.
Not if it hurts the patient.
Wha...
- Hey, you paged.
- Yeah.
I don't think I'm gonna be able
to make it to dinner by seven.
These post-ops are taking
me longer than I thought.
OK. Skip dinner. Hey, you know,
From Here to Eternity's on cable.
We could just grab dinner at my place.
OK, sounds fun. Um, I still
don't know what time I'll finish.
Karev, could you help
Dr. Kepner with her patients?
- Now you need my help?
- Don't push me, dude.
OK, so if you take these,
then I can do the rest.
What?
The only way you'll
be watching that movie
is if it's playing on
his bedroom ceiling.
His EKG and cardiac
enzymes were normal
so a heart attack
seems unlikely.
We're doing a CT angio to
rule out dissection or aneurysm.
Dr. Altman, are you
OK to stay on the case?
Considering your
personal relationship...
Richard, we've been over this. It's a
business arrangement, nothing more.
- How're you feeling?
- Great.
Great, great,
great, great, great.
- Painkillers finally kicked in,
huh?
- Mm-hmm.
Well, enjoy the ride.
I've been thinking lately,
and I think I've figured it out.
- And... Why all your dates go so bad.
- Mm.
So, so bad. Laughably
bad. And it's not your fault.
It's mine. 'Cause I'm... I'm
not the guy on them with you.
- We're ready to start.
- Teddy, wait, wait.
You're my wife.
- You're my hot wife.
- Henry, um...
I'm your husband.
Let's do it. Let's be together.
I mean, look at you.
Look at your eyes.
You're not looking at your eyes.
I could look into your
eyes my whole life.
- Business arrangement?
- He's hopped up on painkillers.
Which just means his
inhibitions are down.
Come on, Richard. Even if he meant what
he said, I don't feel that way. I don't!
And scans are up.
Damn it. He's got a mass.
It's close to his heart. I'm gonna
have to take it out right away.
You? I'm not sure I
should allow you in that OR,
let alone allow you
to operate on him.
- Chief, with all due respect...
- I can do it.
It's an extremely
delicate surgery.
I soloed on a similar
surgery last month. I nailed it...
- is what you said.
- Problem solved.
- Yang'll do the surgery, you'll supervise.
- - Chief.
I've made my decision,
Dr. Altman. Now, if you'll excuse me.
He was gonna kick
you out of the OR.
At least, this way you
get to stay in. It's win-win.
- Yay!
- Whoo!
Don't feel bad. I've
known Torres a long time.
She's a traditional
girl. Catholic.
This whole baby out of wedlock
thing, the three parents, it's a lot
for her to swallow. That's why I
figured the bigger shower the better.
- Oh, shut up.
- Excuse me?
You're not the Callie Whisperer.
And I'm not a monster for
finding baby showers annoying.
Every woman who's ever had
a pregnant friend hates them.
It's like a wedding, the bridesmaids
always want to strangle the bride.
It's practically a rule. The only
one who's not normal here is you
for acting like
you're enjoying this.
OK, Arizona's turn!
Um, I'm fine, I'm fine
over here. But thanks.
Oh, just 'cause I'm the pregnant
one doesn't mean you don't get to play.
Come on, it'll be fun!
- It's what the bride wants.
- Oh.
Hey!
Yay!
I'm going.
Hey. I'm glad you came.
I know it's awkward.
No, you know...
It's... It's not. It's...
I'm... I'm happy for you.
And, uh, plus, I'm seeing
somebody else, so it's...
- Really?
- Yeah.
That's, uh... Good for you.
Do I know him?
I should go.
I know they're not paying you
well, but this seems a little extreme.
I just moved into my own
place. I don't have time to shop.
Pass me those cookies.
All these people in here,
and you came to talk
to me? You like me.
No, I'm talking to you because I want
something to eat and you're in the way.
Admit it, you find me charming.
- Are those pigs in a blanket?
- Hot.
- Dirty hot.
- It was good talking to you,
Dr. Karev.
I say he's totally gay.
Well, if he were gay, then
why would he ask April out?
No straight guy waits a whole
month before making a move.
- Maybe he has herpes.
- That wouldn't stop a guy
either. I vote gay.
I just wish he was into me. Then I
could be in all his cool surgeries, too.
He's not gay, he
doesn't have herpes
and I'm not using him
to get cool surgeries.
We have a lot to talk about, OK? He's
really interesting once you get to know him.
- Which is why she's taking her pants off for him tonight.
- - What?
She's going to his place. From
Here to Eternity's playing on cable.
Oh, yeah, pants are
definitely coming off.
- Nobody's pants are coming off.
- A movie at his place?
That's the definition
of pants coming off.
- Virgin's a goner.
- With an older man, too.
- It's very impressive.
- I'm not taking off my pants
for Stark!
- Oh, my God, that is so ugly.
- Are you still blind?
- I like it. It's abstract.
- Check it out. Scrubs.
Yes, I will do a consult now.
You're not fooling anyone!
- Chief.
- Uh, Derek, I need a favor.
- Mm-hmm.
- I'm applying for an emergency
waiver
with the FDA. I need you to
call your guy that helped you
through your trial over there, see
if he can push my request through.
I'll see what I can do, but
you're the chief of surgery.
I'm not sure how much
more pull I'm gonna have.
There's always ways to work the
system, Derek, we both know that.
I can't put Adele on my trial,
Richard. I've looked at it all day.
- Well, go over it again.
- You're not hearing me.
I love Adele, but I can't pull
a patient off the waiting list.
It could compromise the whole trial.
It could get us blacklisted by the FDA.
- Adele has no future without this!
- - Chief?
It... It's Clara Green,
you need to come now.
What happened?
Sugar bottomed out
again. No response.
- Why won't she wake up?
- Uh, she's in a hypoglycemic
coma.
Her sugar dropped
too fast so her brain
doesn't have enough to feed on.
Sats are dropping and she's got
rales. I'm gonna set up to intubate.
- What? Wait, what's going on?
- Mr. Green, there's no time to
wait.
If we're gonna try this islet cell
transplant, we need to do it now.
We just need your consent.
Yeah, of course. You do
whatever you need to do.
All right. Let's book an OR.
Sir, the FDA hasn't
given us the waiver.
- I know that.
- But...
This woman will die
without this surgery.
Now book an OR. Now!
I don't understand, why does
Dr. Yang have to do the surgery?
You and I are
technically married,
and the hospital
doesn't allow doctors
- to treat family members.
- Mm-hmm.
Right, because how can you stay objective
when your feelings get in the way?
Is it wrong that I'm a little flattered
that, uh, you won't operate on me?
Dr. Yang is excellent and
I will be there to supervise.
I'll see you in surgery.
- She's into me, right?
- Can I have your arm, please?
So this Karev guy, you're
actually friends with him?
- That's real?
- Yeah. Why?
Uh, it surprises me is all. You don't
seem like the type of girl to put up
with his whole Neanderthal thing.
So... tell me, what am I missing?
You're missing a lot.
He had a girl go crazy on
him. His wife almost died,
and then she walked out on
him. And then he was shot,
and almost bled to death in an
elevator. He's been through a lot.
So the Neanderthal
thing is just... It is an act.
A well-executed one.
We are through the peritoneum
and ready for the implant.
- Anything from the FDA?
- Nothing, chief.
- Damn it.
- Sir, I think we should wait.
The longer we wait,
the worse she gets.
I know, but...
Are you sure we're doing
this for the right reason?
That you're not trying to prove
a point, to Shepherd maybe?
I'm thinking of my patient
here, Bailey, that's all.
Hybrid device.
Implanting it in the omentum,
near the large intestine loops.
I left my phone when
I went to the cafeteria.
She saw Gavin's name so she picked
up. Please, you can't let her do this.
We'll talk to her, don't worry.
- What's going on, Sonya?
- I'm not doing
the trial.
- I'm sorry if I've wasted
your time.
- Mom, just listen to him.
I don't have to. I'm going home,
and you're going to London. It's done.
Sonya, you were chosen
from hundreds of applicants.
And this surgery, I can't
guarantee anything, but it could help.
There won't be another
opportunity like this.
I'm sorry, I've made up my mind.
- Please, take me off your list.
- She's not lucid, Dr. Shepherd.
This is just the Alzheimer's.
She's already consented.
My name is Sonya Lela Amin.
I was born Sonya Beshari. My parents
were Ahmed and Saleemah Beshari.
I live at 3105 River Road.
I spent last Thanksgiving with the
Simmons, but three years before,
I was in London with Gavin.
Who did not break up with you.
You broke up with him last
week, when I got on the trial.
You did that for me, and
that makes me very proud.
I raised a good son.
You are a good son.
Go back to London.
Be with Gavin.
Ready to resect
the tumor. Bovie.
Slow and steady.
Any disturbance to his heart,
and he could go into
hypertensive crisis.
- He's pre-medicated,
I'm all over it.
- Steady, Yang.
- I got it.
- Good. Good.
Now, just irrigate and explore.
- BP's shooting up.
- - What did you do, Cristina?
I don't know. Suction.
- Damn it, Cristina!
- I got it. Don't worry.
All right, check
for residual tumor.
I am. You know, I need
more light. Pickups!
Hurry up! Come on! Did
you find anything? Cristina.
Cristina, I need you need
to talk to me, right now.
- Do you need me to do this?!
- I need you to shut up
and stop acting
like a scared wife!
There, I got it. I...
I got it.
- I'm sorry, I didn't mean to...
- No. No, it's OK. It's just...
Thank you.
- Hey, Richard.
- I just did
my first trial surgery
without FDA approval.
Maybe they'll take my license,
maybe they'll blacklist me.
You know what? I don't care.
- I saved a life.
- Yes... Richard.
- Yeah?
- Someone just
dropped out of my trial.
That's why you dragged me
back in here? For another test?
It's just a few questions to see
if you meet the criteria, honey.
And then what? I let Derek
drill into my brain for no reason?
I just did a surgery that
I wasn't approved to do.
I did it because I knew I
didn't have any time to wait.
The patient would've
died. It's the same for you.
You have Alzheimer's,
honey. You do.
There's no time
to wait to treat it.
Please, take the test, baby.
Do it for me.
Fine. I'll take the test.
- Thank you.
- But I'm going to pass.
That way, you'll
see I'm fine. Healthy.
We're going to grow old
together, just like we always said.
We're going to
grow old together.
What is that, a
tumbleweed? A hurricane?
- What's your problem?
- Someone threw out
the gift list.
Now, we don't know who got what
and people are gonna think of us
as the type of people who write
vague and impersonal thank-you notes.
I'm not sure that's
actually a type of people.
- What's going on?
- Arizona lost the gift list.
Yes, Mark, I lost the
list. I... I suck at this.
Congratulations, you're
a better woman than I am.
Hey, it's OK, it's
OK. It's not a big deal.
Mark, can you give us a minute?
- She lost the gift list,
not me.
- Mark.
So, there is one
more gift left to open.
Oh, I... I didn't
get you anything.
You got me a shower.
Open it.
It's a B&B a few hours away.
We leave in the morning.
But I have patients.
You have patients.
Look, I'm extending
an olive branch here.
Because I know how annoying
I must be to you right now.
But since I was four and I got that
doll that craps its pants for Christmas,
I wanted a kid because other
than cracking bones, this...
this baby is my dream.
And I get to be insanely out of
my mind happy for my dream.
But I'm not discounting your
need to vomit over my insanity.
So just let me take you to a stupid
B&B for the weekend. Thank you.
What did you do for
Thanksgiving last year?
Hmm... Nothing.
Uh, Richard and I stayed home,
ordered in Chinese,
and it was lovely.
OK. Starting at 100,
count backwards by seven.
One hundred, 93, 86...
The Rodriguez boy had an
incarcerated incisional hernia,
but we did conscious sedation
and were able to reduce it.
This is all while I was in
surgery. I am impressed.
Dr. Karev did
most of it, actually.
Oh, Dr. Karev? OK,
it's good to know.
I'll check to make
sure it was done right.
Robert, just say thank you.
Thank you, Dr. Karev.
Now, go away.
Oh, my God, I'm so sorry. I
didn't mean to call you that.
There's no need to
apologize, Dr. Kepner.
No, it was completely
unprofessional.
- I promise I won't...
- Hey, April,
I'm saying I liked it.
- I... I can't make it tonight.
- To...? What?
Um... The new chief
resident is getting picked soon,
and everyone is
stepping up their game.
So I should probably just
stay late here. Work. I'm sorry.
I understand. We
got the age difference,
we work together...
not to mention you
are very beautiful.
But still, you know, I'd hoped you
wouldn't feel the need to use work
as an excuse to get out
of spending time with me.
No, no, no, I wasn't...
I enjoy spending time
with you, so much.
It's just... I guess I just
think of you more as a friend.
Friends. You know,
we're... we're friends.
Yeah. Well...
But that's the thing, you know?
I never wanted to
be just your friend.
Good night, Dr. Kepner.
You needed to
score a 26 or below
to meet the
criteria of the trial.
You were above that.
- What is it?
- It's not important.
Derek...
- It's 27.
- One point?
You're going to deny her
this because of one point?
- I'm so sorry.
- Sorry? No. It's good.
It means I passed. I...
I'm not sick. I
told you, Richard.
That's not what it means.
You have Alzheimer's.
It just hasn't progressed
enough to get into the trial.
But Derek said I
passed. I passed.
Meredith, I'm OK, right?
When I asked you to repeat
the three words back to me,
you said "pool"
instead of "spoon."
I asked you to identify
my stethoscope,
it took you a while
to find the word.
And I asked you where
you took your honeymoon.
And you said Hawaii,
but you were here
because the chief
was a medical student
and he had to work.
You're just a resident,
what do you know?
What the hell do any of you
know?! You work in a hospital all day
around sick people and disease.
You're obsessed. That's what this is.
So I got a few answers wrong.
That's all? It's normal.
To forget things at my age...
You can never remember where you parked
the car whenever we go to the movies,
and they're not
saying that you have...
It's not fair.
I finally... It's...
We're finally happy, you and me.
Loving each other the way we
should have all these years, and now...
It's not fair!
Don't look at me like that,
like I'm damaged goods.
I'm still me, I'm still here!
I'm still me. I...
Maybe, maybe I won't
be here much longer,
but I'm right here,
baby. I'm right here.
I can't do... I'm so scared.
Richard, help me, please.
I'm so scared.
You can help me.
Please. Please.
I'm here. I'm not
going anywhere.
I'm here.
Clara Green's extubated,
her sats are 100 percent
and her glucose levels are
stable. No organ damage.
- It's working, chief. It's working!
- Good.
'Cause I just talked to the
FDA. They gave us a waiver.
I just heard the waiver
came through. We did it, right?
You know, a good
chief resident would be...
You need to pick a
chief resident already.
Alex Karev is living in a
trailer in the hospital parking lot,
residents are waiting for
you outside bathrooms.
Karev's living in
the parking lot?
Your trial is up and running,
and you've got things
to deal with at home.
You don't need to be picking
a new chief resident, too.
Let somebody else
handle that. Delegate.
OK. I'd like you to.
No. I raised those babies.
Um, what I mean is, delegate
to someone else. Who is not me.
- Good night, Dr. Bailey.
- Good night.
And sir? Congratulations
on the surgery.
It was a clean excision,
and we got clean margins.
- You're gonna be OK.
- So, what I said before,
about your eyes, it
wasn't just the painkillers.
Henry, you've got to stop. You
gotta stop talking to me about my eyes,
and flirting with me in
front of other doctors.
- You're right. I'm sorry.
- OK.
OK, I'm not sorry.
I meant what I said.
All of it.
If not more.
I get it. It's a great story.
We get married
to save your life.
Then we fall in love. I
mean, how romantic is that?
Not to mention
that you are smart
and funny and not at
all hard on the eyes.
And I'd be lying to say that
it's never crossed my mind.
But I don't feel it. It's...
It's not real. It's
just a good story.
What's so wrong
with a good story?
I'm sorry.
Did you hear back from the
patient on the waiting list?
I haven't called yet.
Maybe Richard's
right. It's just one point.
But it's a point that could
ruin the trial for everyone else
- that we're trying to save.
- Hmm.
Call them.
Well, I heard the good
news. Our patient's doing well.
- Sorry, your patient, doctor.
- Eli, I'm tired.
Good. Then just admit I was
right so we can kiss and make up.
Not that tired.
Miranda Bailey, we are
not inside the hospital!
Inside the hospital, you're
the man. That's the protocol.
But outside, I'm the
man. I am the man. Me.
Now you can call me
Cro-Magnon or old-fashioned,
but that is not gonna stop me from
taking you home to my bed tonight
and showing you
what kind a man I am.
Now how's that? Does
that protocol suit you?
- Yeah.
- Good.
Mmm. Be at my place in 15.
Hey!
- This is your new place?
- You hungry?
I got crab cakes,
cucumber sandwiches.
You ate all the pigs
in a blanket, so...
I'll take a beer.
So this was your plan? Wait for me
on the stoop of your trailer you squat in?
- What?
- You were waiting for me.
'Cause you find me charming.
- Hot.
- What? No, I...
And now, you're stuttering
because I intimidate you.
Whatever.
Which explains it really, why you
haven't made a move this whole time.
- That's complete bull...
- And now...
you're forcing me to do it.
Ah. So was I right?
- OK.
- Do you mind?
Nope. Although if it were me and
I had someone to make out with,
I might want to do it in
private. Like in a room.
Where there's a door that locks.
OK. Let's go upstairs.
It's every doctor's dilemma.
Do you play it safe
and follow protocol?
Yep. Actual, real dinner in honor
of me rocking my surgery today.
If Webber doesn't pick me
for chief resident, he's an idiot.
Or take a risk and
invent a new one?
- Cristina.
- Yes, darling.
Richard just asked me to
take over picking chief resident.
Oh, my God, this is
awesome! You can...
Oh, my God, this sucks!
This sucks! You can't pick me.
Everyone's gonna say it's
because you're my husband. This...
No! No! What?
No! This is... What?!
Oh, God, how can you eat?!
This is not fair, wait, wait, wait!
No, no, no! This... No!
There can be reward in risk.
There can also be fallout.
We've been gone
all of ten minutes,
what could Mark possibly want?
I don't know.
Ooh... Oh... yeah.
OK, this is bad. He found out
Lexie's with Avery. He's freaking.
Oh!
- Just let go!
- What the hell?!
What, this, this is time
for us. It's just for us.
The first thing you
wanna do is talk to Mark.
You just said it was
OK! OK, you know what?
- Screw it. I'm gonna talk to him!
- What are you doing?
Don't you dare call him! I...
This is jealousy, Arizona.
You're jealous of Mark. Get over it.
Do you blame me?
He gets most of you.
The straight you, the Catholic
you, the girl who loves baby showers.
I just get the gay you, which is
really only about 20 minutes a night,
and not even, since you feel too
fat to even let me touch you lately.
Look, I am doing my best here,
to make sure that you are happy
and that Mark's happy and the tiny
person growing inside me is happy!
I don't know what else I can
do, to be honest! Please, tell me.
'Cause I'll do it. Whatever
will make you happy, I will do it.
Still, you need to buck the
system every once in awhile.
Bet big.
Marry me.
- What?
- I mean it.
I love you more than anything.
But I want more. I want
commitments. I want rings.
So...
marry me.
And when you get
the results you want,
there's no better
feeling in the world.
But when you don't...