Visualizing?
All right. You're up, tiger.
You feel all right?
You look a little pale.
I'm fine. Does
your neck still hurt?
It'll be fine. Maybe you should
do the two-and-a-half instead.
I'm gonna do the three. Well, it's
better to nail the two-and-a-half than...
I'm gonna nail the three.
All right.
Well, let's show these senior citizens what
a well-coached 12-year-old can do, huh?
Next diver, two-time National
Junior champion, Mary Carroll.
Damn it.
You can do this. Come
on, just... see it. See it.
Big jump. Pike out. Rip it.
Call 911. We need an ambulance.
- I saw the light on.
- It's daytime.
It's a figure of speech.
Always so literal.
- Got a new cane.
- Yeah.
Guy in the store
said it was slimming.
Vertical stripe.
- Why are you here?
- Vogler is dead.
What? What happened?
Again with the literal
translation. Vogler, the idea.
Mr. Destructo, Mr. Moneybags.
"Bow down before me."
He is gone from the hospital.
So things can go back
to the way they were.
The way they were
was kind of weird.
Hmm. Weird works for me.
What are you saying? Literally.
- I want you to come back.
- Why?
Please unclench.
You're not on the clock, and when you
do that, I clench and it's a whole thing.
Could you look at your pager?
It's no big deal. Some sort
of epidemic. Not my area.
- You should go. It's important.
- What I'm doing now is important.
- Why do you want me back?
- 'Cause you're a good doctor.
- That's it?
- That's not enough?
Not for me.
Go deal with your plague.
You are in a quarantined area.
Please remain calm and stay in
line. A doctor will see you shortly.
When you see a doctor, you
will receive a blue or yellow form.
Patients with blue forms must
immediately exit to the parking lot.
Dr. House. Need you here.
Sorry. Lot of sick people.
I might catch something.
A judge at the campus
pool center collapsed.
L.P. revealed a virulent
form of bacterial meningitis.
Great. You got it diagnosed.
You don't need me.
2,500 people at the
pool center were exposed.
They're being bused to all
the neighboring hospitals.
That's a problem with
resources, not diagnostics.
I—I'd be completely lost,
get in everyone's way.
Joe. Dr. House
doesn't have a blue slip.
No one leaves the quarantine
area without a blue slip.
You are a doctor at
this hospital. Act like one.
And...
take these.
102.
You win a trip to
the second floor.
Next.
All right. No fever. No rash.
You're fine. Take
these two pills.
And show this blue slip to
Security on your way out.
Next.
Take these. Go home.
Talk to your daughter. What?
Your pants, your
blouse, your scarf are all
freshly dry cleaned.
Everything except your jacket.
It's got a smudge on it.
Probably two days old.
Which means you didn't
know the jacket had been worn.
So either your husband
is a cross-dresser,
or your daughter's been borrowing
your clothes without telling you.
She probably wants to
look older to get into bars.
I don't have a daughter.
Next.
So I have it? Take the
yellow form to the second floor.
You're gonna be
fine. I'm gonna die.
It's treatable— As long as
you go to the second floor.
Next.
Yow.
Fever? Does that mean I have it?
Do you have a rash?
Come on.
It's from my new bathing
suit. I've had it a week.
Yeah.
Does your neck hurt? If
it does, you hit the trifecta.
It's nothing. I pulled it trying
to do a three-and-a-half tuck.
Where are your parents?
We live in Chicago.
I'm here with my coach.
I wanted to see
what you were writing.
Go like this.
Ow.
Take these pills.
Blue slip will get
you out of here.
Next.
You're coming with me.
Proceed to the second
floor for further examination.
You're gonna need a
C.T. scan. Second floor.
Take the elevators,
follow the parade.
Next.
- Maybe it's something systemic.
- Or maybe it's meningitis.
She's had the rash a week. If it was
this meningitis she'd be dead by now.
You guys figure we're
done down there?
The 800 people milling around
are just waiting for the bathroom?
Twelve-year-old female. Fever,
rash, neck pains. Not meningitis.
It's the definition
of meningitis.
Sure. Pus in the spinal canal makes it
hurt to move your head up and down,
but her neck only hurts
moving side to side.
- Oh, side to side.
- Doesn't fit.
The three of you, lobby, now.
Those little pills you're
passing out so efficiently...
aren't gonna do
Miss Louganis squat.
You just don't want to
deal with the epidemic.
That's right. I'm
subjecting a 12-year-old...
to a battery of dangerous and
invasive tests to avoid being bored.
Okay, maybe I would
do that. But I'm not.
If it turns out she's
got meningitis,
you're right, you win; but if we
go back downstairs and she dies...
your face will be so red.
You have one hour.
Get a lumbar puncture.
Some brain infections
can be pretty clever
at hide-and-seek.
I'll get on her blood
work. No, you won't.
You, sir, will research all the
causes in the universe of neck pain.
- The list is, like, two miles long.
- Start with the letter "A."
And put her on rifampin. Rifampin
is for meningitis. You just said—
In case I'm wrong.
It has happened.
Brenda, I need a
C.B.C. Chem 7 in 2046.
Hold on. Excuse me. Excuse me.
Hey, there's a line here.
That's why I said excuse me.
Brenda, I need a bed
and a— We all need stuff.
Push me again.
Brenda, I need a bed and a
nurse for a lumbar puncture.
No beds, no nurses for at least
four hours. I've only got one.
Your patient only has an hour to live
unless she gets a lumbar puncture?
Cuddy only gave us an
hour to work on the patient.
Back of the line.
Do not leave the quarantine
area until you have
been seen by a doctor.
When you see a doctor, you
will receive a blue or yellow form—
This novocaine will numb
you for the lumbar puncture.
Sorry this has to
be so public, Mary.
Normally I'm in a bathing suit
with 5,000 people staring at my butt.
I can block this out.
These kids are all very mature. Travel
around the country from event to event.
Okay, I want you to hold
your knees and tuck your head.
- Like a dive?
- Exactly.
Good. Great. Don't
forget to breathe.
All right.
Sorry.
Geez. Coach, help me out here.
Play a little defense before
I poke the wrong thing.
Okay, here we go.
- Ow. I feel it. Ow. I feel it. I fee—Ow.
- Try to relax, Mary. Try to relax.
Relax.
What letter are you up to? "A."
Torture combing through
all that stuff, ain't it?
- Real dull. Awful.
- It's no problem.
Well, thank goodness.
A lot of people would
resent having to do this.
If you receive a blue
form, please exit the area.
If you receive a yellow form,
please proceed to the second floor.
Where's the 12-year-old
girl that was here?
Needed the gurney. She
just had a lumbar puncture.
She's not supposed to be moved.
Sorry. We needed the gurney.
Hey.
- Hey.
- You okay? How's your head feeling?
She's got a headache
and she's dizzy.
She shouldn't have been moved
after the procedure. I'm sorry.
I'm fine. What
did the test show?
No meningitis and
no other infections.
But you're not carrying a blue
form. I have something else, don't I?
Something's causing your symptoms.
We're gonna keep you here overnight.
I know it's a little crazy in here,
but hopefully it'll settle down...
and we'll be able
to get you a room.
I'm sorry. I'm not usually
all emotional like this. I just—
You're doing great. Your
folks land in a few hours.
I just— I haven't
slept. I'm so tired.
Oh, my God. My eye's bleeding.
What is it? What's happening?
Oh, don't worry.
The antibiotic we gave you in case you
had meningitis can turn your tears reddish.
That's not blood.
But that...
That's blood.
That's going into my stomach?
The lavage showed
blood in your G.I. tract.
We need to find
where it's coming from.
You won't feel it.
I'm gonna numb the
back of your throat, and
Dr. Foreman is gonna
give you a sedative. Open.
- Ugh.
- Swallow.
Now lay on your side for me.
And... here we go.
- Yell fire or something.
- People, this area is highly contagious.
Please step back.
Highly contagious.
All right. Try to relax, Mary.
This shouldn't take too long.
I don't see any
tears or lesions.
All right. I'm in the stomach.
It's not bleeding.
There was more than a tablespoon of
blood in the mouth, so it's gotta be there.
Maybe her small intestine.
Thirty feet of digestive tract,
it could be anywhere in there.
We're not gonna
see it with this.
Believe it or not,
this is a camera.
You swallow it, and it goes all
the way through your system.
The antennae pick up
the signal from the pill.
Then we look at the
video of your intestines,
see where the blood is
coming from, and fix it.
All right? Water?
Down the hatch.
Think I've seen this movie.
The ending's kind of dark.
You want one?
How come you did the endoscopy?
- He asked for help.
- Her blood pressure was high.
Foreman is not your boss.
When I tell you to do something—
Whoa. Hold it there.
Back it up a couple of frames.
Oh, yeah. That's
your money shot.
I don't see anything.
Really? "Ginormous"
thing on the right side
of her intestine. That
doesn't intrigue you?
Does "ginormous" mean
really big, or really, really small?
- 'Cause I don't see anything.
- There? The Dieulafoy?
Well, we can burn off
the swollen blood vessel,
but it still doesn't account
for her other symptoms.
No, but it does
tell us something.
Though I have no idea what.
Could be a precursor to
intestinal intussusception.
Precursor isn't causing all
her other symptoms. What else?
You, in the lobby now.
I hurt my leg. I have a note. You
had your hour— three, actually.
Dr. Chase, I told you to
tell us when our time was up.
She has intestinal
bleeding. She'll wait.
Two more buses just arrived.
We need you downstairs.
No, you need more nurses, but
you cut back on the nursing staff,
so now you've got doctors doing
what nurses should be doing.
That's true.
I wonder if that has anything to
do with you costing us $100 million.
Attention. If you do
not have a blue form,
you will not be allowed to
leave the quarantine area.
Go. Be free.
If it's not the intussusception,
what about stomach cancer?
Does she have any
abdominal pain? No.
Then it's not stomach cancer.
Have you ruled out sepsis?
The L.P. and blood
smears showed no signs of
infection. Here. Take these
two pills and you can go.
Well, the lab's working at double their
capacity. Maybe someone screwed up.
No fever, no neck pain.
Take the elevator to the third floor—
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Wrong form.
- No fever, no neck pain. She's fine.
- Smell her hair. No chlorine.
Which means she wasn't at the pool, which
means she's come to a quarantined area...
because she's an
idiot or she's insane.
No one is that stupid. East
wing, psych ward. Bye-bye.
Neck pain could be a
symptom for bone cancer.
You up to the B's? Well done.
That would account for all her
meningeal symptoms—rash, fever.
You're fine. Take
these two pills.
Get a sample of her bone marrow.
From here? Break time.
- I need more than 15 minutes.
- Use Chase's break too.
Go.
You should just fire Chase.
What, and miss out on all this fun?
So you're gonna torture him
for a while and then fire him?
That's cold. You don't
think he has it coming?
Hey, I said fire
him. That's cold.
All he did was
save his job. What?
He completely screwed you over.
Right rudder.
Bank, bank, bank.
Good coffee? The rest of this
hospital is busting its tail and you're...
- What are you doing?
- Trying to think of anything except
the produce department at Whole Foods.
I am working. It got hot. Stop
acting like a 13-year-old. Sorry.
You just don't usually see breasts
like that on deans of medicine.
Oh, women can't be heads of
hospitals? Or just ugly ones?
No, they can be babes. It's just
you don't usually see their fun bags.
Your 3:00 interview for
Dr. Cameron's position is in your office.
Not interviewing today.
I don't know if you've
heard, but there's
this big-time epidemic.
Many sick people. Puking in the
hallways. It's crazy. We can reschedule.
No, you won't. You will
interview this person.
And if he can put two sentences
together, you will send him to the lobby...
where he will do his job.
Unlike the two of you.
Come on. You know I can't do a
bone marrow aspiration in the hallway.
And I can't give you
a procedure room.
I just need something at least
close to a sterile environment.
I need ten more nurses.
Brenda, listen.
Listen. She'll die.
At least she'll have a bed
then. Put that over there.
Are there dead people
in those cabinets?
I hope that's who's in there.
Just be calm. Relax.
Ow. Ow, ow, ow, ow.
Hang on.
You know, I really admire
the way you don't care what
anyone thinks. You just do
what you want, the way you want.
So you went to Hopkins for
both undergrad and med school?
- That's right.
- He's in a band.
- You're into music?
- Totally.
What kind of music do you play?
Mostly blues, you know,
James Cotton, some original stuff.
- Oh, dude, you are so hired.
- Really?
- Not a chance.
- Why?
Tattoo.
Wow. I thought you'd be the last person
to have a problem with nonconformity.
Nonconformity. Right.
I can't remember the last
time I saw a 20-something
kid with a tattoo of an
Asian letter on his wrist.
You are one wicked freethinker.
You want to be a
rebel? Stop being cool.
Wear a pocket protector
like he does, and get a haircut,
like the Asian kids who don't leave
the library for 20-hour stretches.
They're the ones who
don't care what you think.
Sayonara.
So, should I go through all the
résumés looking for Asian names?
Actually, the Asian kids
are probably just responding
to parental pressure,
but my point is still valid.
So when do they think
you're getting out of here?
They don't know.
You don't look sick.
Better hope you're not.
- This equipment looks
like it's 100 years old.
- Just got it out of storage.
It is the previous generation,
but it works just fine.
Could you, uh— Could
you guys give us a second?
If it's good news,
you can tell them.
Okay. We're, uh, we're
pretty sure it's not cancer.
- Hey, that's great.
- I'll call your parents.
Well, we still can't
release her. We still
don't know yet exactly
what's causing the...
Mary?
What's wrong?
She's having an absence
seizure. Mary? You okay?
She looks fine. I need some help over
here. Push two milligrams Ativan, stat.
Are you sure it was
an absence seizure?
Absolutely. She was
totally unresponsive...
and unaware of what
was going on around her.
Do you mind?
We're trying to work.
We should get back out there.
Cuddy's gonna be looking for us.
Looking, but not finding.
Did you do an E.E.G.?
Seizure frequency's
increasing. They—They're
almost constant now.
Five in the last half hour.
Which tells us— It's
definitely in her brain.
- And it's getting worse.
- And?
Good Lord. Are you having
a bowl movement or a baby?
- Could be barbiturate withdrawal.
- No, it can't be drugs.
She's tested at every
meet she competes at.
A bleed in the brain
could cause seizures.
Rat poison? Could
also cause the neck pain.
You think she's eating off
the floor of her folks' garage?
Doesn't have to be.
Who would poison a 12-year-old?
Well, let's see now.
There's the 18-year-old
has-been that she beat
out to make the Nationals,
the has-been's parents, jealous
siblings, sociopathic swim fan,
and then there's just your plain
old garden variety whack job.
Hey.
- You know what a hemorrhoid is?
- No.
Well, Google it. And try some
raisin bran instead of the doughnuts.
Do a C.T. scan. Check
for intracranial bleeding.
Not a chance. Radiology's
totally swamped.
If our patient's bleeding into her brain,
she's gonna be dead in eight hours.
She could be, but a meningitis
patient will be without a C.T. scan.
- When I was in med
school, I had this old
professor— - Who touched
you in the naughty place?
Before the C.T. scan was introduced,
he specialized in transcranial ultrasound.
Hmm.
Ancient, but if there's
enough bleeding it might work.
Okay, do what the guy who
didn't specialize in neurology said.
It was my idea.
Nyah, nyah, nyah. You've
still gotta cover "Q" to "Z."
Sorry I'm late. I
was taking a dump.
I'm guessing I'm better off
interviewing right after than right before.
Dr. Petra Gilmar,
Dr. Gregory House.
You actually speak four
languages, or are you just
banking on never being
interviewed by anyone who does?
It's true, and I can
swear in two more.
Why are you leaving Dr. Hazel?
Did you fall for him and can't handle
it, or was it the other way around?
- Yes, well, pretty much
every fellowship ends that way.
- No, it was nothing like that.
- You Jewish?
- Yes.
Is it true what they say
about Jewish foreplay?
- Two hours of begging?
- I heard four.
Well, actually, I'm
only half Jewish.
Look, I know you like to
play games with people.
I know you like to say outrageous
things and study how they react.
What you should know about me
is that I grew up with four brothers.
Keep your hands to yourself, I'm okay
with anything that comes out of your mouth.
Uh, well, that's, uh, great.
I think that's all we need.
Thank you for
coming by. Thank you.
- That's our Hitler!
- No way.
Are you kidding? Her
background's perfect.
She's smart, she can obviously
deal with your insanity...
You see her shoes? Her shoes?
What, did your horoscope in Vogue tell
you to avoid women wearing green shoes?
The eyes can
mislead, a smile can lie,
but the shoes
always tell the truth.
They were Prada.
Means she has good taste.
They were not Prada.
You wouldn't know Prada if
one stepped on your scrotum.
Okay. Well, they were
nice. Pointy. Exactly.
They were stylish,
and very painful to wear.
Only an incredibly
shallow, insecure woman...
would rather be in pain all daylong than
wear a decent-looking, comfortable shoe,
and that's exactly the type
I don't need around here.
No. Someone who can
handle a lot of pain...
is exactly the type you do need.
Excuse me.
What are you doing?
I'm "ultrasounding" your head.
You're still having seizures. This
should help us figure out what's going on.
Blue form to the security guard.
You're not gonna be happy with anyone.
So what, your advice is...
hire someone I'm not
happy with and be happy?
No, my advice is much more
subtle. Stop being an ass.
You always find some tiny
little flaw to push people away.
Oh, now it's people. I thought we
were talking about fellowship applicants.
You have a history of this.
Well, when I do decide...
to push you away, I hope
there's a small person kneeling
behind you, so you fall
down and hurt your head.
Take these. There's water over
there. Blue form to the guard.
And you're done.
You had the perfect
person, and you blew it.
You saw the shoes.
I'm not talking about her.
You're talking about Cameron.
I'm talking about every woman
you've ever given a damn about.
Cameron is so not perfect.
Well, nobody's perfect.
Mother Teresa? Dead.
Angelina Jolie?
No medical degree.
Now who's being picky?
You're gonna wind
up alone, House.
You were right. There's a
significant bleed in her temporal lobe.
But no poisons.
Did tox screens on her blood, urine,
and hair. Nothing. Did them twice.
He's a little dehydrated. Put him on a
saline drip and give him some orange juice.
I need an operating
room and a neurosurgeon.
Given the current crisis,
I'm tempted to say no,
but since you've been
so sweet to me today—
Our little mermaid is
bleeding into her temporal lobe.
- How fast can you have her prepped?
- Twenty minutes.
You'll have a surgeon
in the room in ten.
Mr. and Mrs. Carroll?
Are you Dr. House?
- This is Dr. Foreman.
- Is Mary all right?
The operation went well.
The intracranial pressure's been relieved,
and the swelling's already going down.
Oh, thank God.
Well, what happened?
I mean, did she bang her
head at a meet, or did she...
No, nothing like that.
Then why is she bleeding?
Is she gonna be all right?
I'm sorry. We still don't know.
No toxins, no tumor,
no bone cancer.
Renal failure could cause the
rash, fever, and muscle pain.
Maybe it's some sort of genetic
kidney disorder. No family history.
- And no blood in her urine or uremia.
- Not yet.
You want to do a differential based
on symptoms that might happen?
- You got a better idea?
- Stop it.
Stop looking for things we don't
know and focus on what we do know.
What do we actually know,
besides what's up there?
Come on. How hard can it be to
tell me what you already know?
- She's 12.
- She spends a lot of time in pools—
exposure to chemicals.
- She travels a lot.
- But never out of the country.
What else?
Come on!
We're gonna put you right here.
We're missing something.
What? Well, if I knew
that, it wouldn't be missing.
Maybe she's adopted and
we've got the wrong history.
No. She's got her mom's eyes
and a red patch of hair just like Dad.
What about an allergic reaction?
That could explain the
rash and muscle pain,
but probably not the
bleeding or seizures.
That's a lot of balloons.
- You think she's allergic to polyester?
- Not unless she's been competing
in the nude all these years.
Then what are you thinking?
What do the balloons mean?
What if the rash isn't a rash?
What are you talking about?
Who gave her the balloons?
Some of the girls from her team.
They've been visiting
her pretty regularly,
but none of them are
sick. What about the guys?
- None of them are sick either.
- Which guys visited her?
Uh...
Actually, none.
She's cute. She's nice.
She's a kick-ass diver.
You'd think the guys would be falling
all over themselves to get close to her.
She's 12. The youngest
guy on her team is 16.
- Okay, so maybe they're just not
interested, or— - They're avoiding her.
There any cell fragments
in her blood smears?
No. Red blood cells were intact.
Check 'em again.
Blood looks like it's been
put through the blender now.
You done yet? You were right.
The rash wasn't a rash. She's
bleeding into her skin. It's purpura.
Thrombotic
thrombocytopenic purpura?
Starts with "T."
You were so close.
What could have set it off?
She had no traces of
E. coli in her cultures.
She's obviously not
menopausal, so no estrogen.
There is one other
possible cause.
Oh, God.
Pregnancy causes...
all kinds of chemical
and biological changes...
in a woman's body...
Or a girl's body,
as the case may be.
In extremely rare cases, everything
goes haywire. It's called T.T.P.
Blood starts clotting like crazy and clogs
the vessels in your brain and kidneys.
Red blood cells end up getting
shredded as they squeeze past the clot,
like a fat guy in a crowded bar.
I'm sure you know
what that's like.
I mean, you're only 12, but
you're all grown up, right?
Travel on your own,
hang out in hotel rooms...
getting room service
with your teammates.
Maybe someone sneaks in a couple of
beers. You start playing spin the bottle.
Next thing you know you're waking
up with nothing on but your socks.
It wasn't like that.
Of course not.
- You wanted it.
- Yeah. I did.
He turned out
to be a jerk, but...
Actually, under New
Jersey law, the term is felon.
I knew what I was doing.
We're gonna have to do
something called plasmapheresis.
Cleans the antibodies
from your blood.
We're also gonna have
to terminate the pregnancy.
You gonna tell my parents?
Someone should.
Rock, paper, scissors?
They don't need to know.
I'll be all right.
Of course you will.
I mean, if you're old enough
to bleed out of your vagina,
then obviously you’re
mature enough...
to handle a simple thing like an
abortion without Mommy and Daddy's help.
You gonna tell my parents?
Under New Jersey
law, you're the boss.
Your daughter has T.T.P.
Don't worry. It's
curable. She'll be fine.
Well, wait. I mean, what
does T.T.P. stand for?
Some really big words that
you've never heard before...
and, when we're done,
will never hear again.
Have a nice day.
- Well, when can we take her home?
- Uh, in a few days.
She needs some minor surgery
to remove the underlying cause...
before we can do the...
another really big word.
What's the underlying cause?
- She has an abnormal growth
in her abdomen.
- What kind of surgery?
It's— It's very simple.
We do it here all the time.
- Could you be a little more specific?
- Actually, no.
I'm sorry.
We're almost done.
Hang in there.
You're doing good.
Feeling okay?
Yeah. You should be.
- Your platelets count's up.
- How's your neck?
Looks good. Anything
else we can get you?
No, thanks.
Okay.
Yeah.
Can I see my mom and dad?
Plasmapheresis is
working. She's gonna be fine.
I know.
Hi. I've got these.
I can't even tell you
how much I appreciate...
the opportunity
to meet with you.
- The moment I
heard you had another
fellowship opening, I—
- There is no opening.
House.
- You have to hire someone.
- I know.
Position's been filled.
- Why am I interviewing for a position
that's already been filled?
- Exactly.
I called to confirm the
interview this morning.
You figure if you keep
arguing, I'm gonna cave,
admit it's all a
lie and hire you?
Do you need your
parking validated?
I don't wanna
interview anyone else.
You're interviewing?
I thought you'd just have them
send a head shot along with their C.V.
Ha.
That's good, and why
I need you around...
To keep me in my place.
I can't come back.
I told you that.
- Wasn't listening.
- Right.
You want me to listen to
you more? I can do that.
Right.
I already accepted a
position somewhere else.
- With who?
- Yeuell—atJefferson.
- Unaccept it.
- Why?
Because Yeuell is boring.
He's pedantic and preachy.
Because he's short.
Because I want you to come back.
Not good enough.
Want more money?
A car allowance?
Better parking space?
Dinner.
And not just a meal
between two colleagues.
A date.
You'll come back to work...
if I go out on a date with you?
Yes.
Okay.
It's a deal.
See you tomorrow morning.
Don't be late.
I won't.
That's some bad hat, Harry.