Previously on
The Good Doctor...
I omitted some of
the patient reviews.
That's why your
scores went up.
I am truly so sorry.
Your apology is
not accepted.
Page Dr. Lim to the OR
for an emergency C-section.
The baby's in distress.
We need to open the duct
and oxygenate her blood.
Call the pharmacy
for PGE, stat.
Oh.
What?
It's expired.
Pulse not palpable.
Restarting
compressions.
Push 0.2.
Dr. Murphy,
the baby is flatlining.
No.
There's nothing
more we can do.
No, I can save her!
Shaun.
We just lost a baby
because this hospital
wasn't prepared.
The medication
we needed was expired.
Salen made cuts.
We're... We're
behind on inventory.
Expired.
Shaun, stop,
stop, stop!
They're all... No!
It wasn't your fault!
There's...
You lied to me!
I can't marry you.
Okay.
I'm right here.
I got you.
♪ My body is a cage
♪ That keeps me from dancing
With the one I love
♪ But my mind holds the key
♪ I'm standing on a stage
♪ Of fear and self-doubt
♪ It's a hollow play
♪ But they'll clap anyway
♪ My body is a cage
♪ That keeps me from dancing
With the one I love
♪ But my mind holds the key
♪ My mind holds the key
♪ I'm living in an age
♪ Whose name I don't know
♪ Though the fear
Keeps me moving
♪ Still my heart beats so slow
♪ My body is a cage
♪ That keeps me from dancing
With the one I love
♪ But my mind holds the key
♪ My mind holds the key ♪
I am so sorry for what
you all must be going through.
I can assure you
I've begun an extensive review
of pharmacy
inventory policy,
and I will do everything
in my power to make sure
that nothing like this
ever happens again.
If there's anything
that you need...
Counseling,
paid time off,
just someone to talk to...
I'm available.
Thank you.
As I'm sure you know,
a lawsuit is a possibility.
We need to use the utmost
professional discretion
in our communication
with the baby's mother.
We're all very aware
of our professional
responsibilities.
I just felt
a reminder never hurts.
Whatever you're thinking
of doing, don't.
She's gonna lecture us
on professional
responsibility?
A baby's dead because
of her narcissistic need
to be a "disrupter"
instead of an administrator.
You're furious,
I get it.
Take a day off.
Take a personal day.
Let her make
the first move.
She is who she is.
Which is the owner
of this hospital
and your employer.
And she has
more experience
in corporate and legal
matters than you,
and if you go up
against her
in a fit of rage,
you're gonna suffer
the consequences.
I'm taking her down.
I was surprised
you were gone when I woke up.
I'd hoped
we could've talked before work.
I don't want
to talk.
You said you didn't
want to marry me.
You can't drop a bomb
like that and expect me
to just accept it.
I know you're hurting,
and... And I want
to be there for you.
I don't need your help.
Shaun,
stop it, please.
I made a mistake.
But that can't just
erase everything
we've been through.
You can't have
totally changed
how you feel about me
over just one incident.
Mmm.
It wasn't just one.
It was three.
You lied about
your trip to Montana,
falsified
my performance rating,
and refused to
make things right
by correcting my scores
or telling Salen
what you'd done.
I can't marry you.
That doesn't
make any sense.
We love each other.
We can figure out a way
to work this out.
I'm going to help
Dr. Park in the ER.
Male, 32,
single car M.V.A.
I'm so sorry.
Please tell me
I didn't hurt anyone.
For the tenth time,
all you messed up
was yourself,
your car, and a tree.
He has an open comminuted
tib/fib fracture.
And by the smell,
I'm guessing
an off-the-chart B.A.C.
I thought
she really liked me.
But she just wanted
to be friends,
like all the rest.
I'm such an idiot.
Just a fat,
disgusting loser.
Decent pulses.
He'll need IV
antibiotics and surgery
to I and D the wound
and repair the fracture.
The leg can wait.
GCS is 13.
Need head and trauma
CT pan scans
to rule out
closed-head injury.
Let's get him
to imaging.
He's right.
He's an idiot.
A very lucky one.
Go ahead
and take a seat.
Actually, I can't.
Uh... I... I had surgery
a couple weeks ago
in Brazil.
They call it
a Brazilian Butt Lift.
I know,
it's totally vain,
but my whole life,
I've been unhappy
with my shape.
Um, I've tried everything.
Diet, exercise,
waist trainers.
But I'm 33-years-old,
and every time
I look in the mirror,
I can still hear the kids
in school calling me...
Tater Tot
or SpongeBob.
You don't have to justify
your decision to me
or any other doctor.
I'm here to help you.
She has severe
surgical site infections
with multiple abscesses.
Gluteal fat grafting's not
as easy as it looks.
Not something you
want to try to save
a few bucks on.
She didn't go to Brazil
to save money.
She went to prevent
being mocked
and judged by
her own friends.
She didn't need
to go at all.
There's nothing wrong
with her belly
or her butt.
Well, there's
nothing "wrong"
with your hair,
either,
but you spend oodles
of time and money on it.
You're hilarious
and spend just as much
on your skincare
and manscaping.
This is fun. I wish
I had some popcorn.
As it is,
it's a waste of time
our patient
doesn't have.
Get CTs
with contrast
to gauge
the size and depth
of the abscesses,
then schedule her for surgery
to incise and drain.
On it.
My skin looks good,
though, right?
Could you do
me a favor?
I need all the
documents related to
Ethicure's takeover.
I'm doing some work
on regulatory responses
and need info
from the contracts.
Not exactly my area.
But I'm sure
Salen has copies
of all that stuff.
I don't want
to bother her.
She's pretty
swamped today.
I'm pretty sure
it's backed up
on the server.
Okay.
Thanks.
I'll print them out
for you.
You can just e-mail them.
Mmm, better if I don't.
Whatever your
real reason is
for wanting them,
I'm sure you don't want
Salen to know.
Paper copies
will be harder
for her to trace.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Hi, Alma.
I'm Salen Morrison,
the CEO of Ethicure.
I just wanted
to personally
offer my condolences.
I don't have children.
I can't even begin
to comprehend
the depth of your grief.
I probably
shouldn't be doing this.
My head of legal
is gonna freak,
but I don't care.
You deserve to know.
Dr. Lim and Dr. Murphy
were both truly heroic
in their attempts
to save your baby's life.
But there was an error
made by one
of our pharmacists,
which caused Dr. Murphy
to briefly administer
an expired medication.
He quickly realized and
corrected the mistake,
and it's unlikely
it had any effect,
but it was a mistake,
which we take
full responsibility for.
The pharmacist
feels horrible.
He's already resigned.
Oh, my God.
Ethicure will cover
all of your
medical expenses,
provide counseling
for you or for anyone
in your family
who needs it.
And I've authorized
an immediate
payment of $200,000
for your
pain and suffering.
I'm... I'm not sure
what to say.
It's the least
we can do.
I just need you to sign
a short consent form.
So our accounting
department can
issue the payment.
If anybody should
be fired here,
it should be you.
I warned you.
I told you that something
like this would happen
if you went ahead
with the changes.
Hmm.
That's not how
I remember it.
You do realize
that I have notes
from every meeting
we ever had,
copies of every e-mail?
What I realize is
you've never
sued anyone before,
while I've sued
and been sued by
my co-founders, banks,
billionaires, and the guy
who used to prune
my rose bushes.
Which is why I have
multiple lawyers
on retainer.
So if I were you,
I'd stop threatening
and start negotiating.
I want my job.
I deserve it.
No, you don't.
Because you
killed a baby.
So you're gonna
take your severance
and agree to a legally
enforceable promise
to go away
and keep
your mouth shut.
No sign of any
intracranial bleed
or injury to
chest or abdomen.
We should brief Lim
and get him to the OR
for the surgery
on his leg.
That silence
mean you agree?
Mmm?
Oh.
I was distracted.
You're right.
We'll need to do
two surgeries...
A prophylactic fasciotomy
and then stabilize
the tib/fib fractures.
Whatever you think
is best.
You want to talk?
Mmm, I already said...
I mean about what happened
last night in the pharmacy.
No.
Talking about it
won't change anything.
You know, I've never
seen him like this before.
It's like I'm suddenly
a totally different
person to him.
Yeah, give him
some time.
Have you
talked to him?
Yeah.
And what did
he say?
I don't know.
He... He's Shaun,
you know?
What's he gonna say?
Sometimes men
need more time
to get over stuff.
Okay, that is
both sexist
and wrong.
He's totally
cut me out.
He refuses to
talk to me at all.
Well,
he's stressed.
You know,
he's retreating
into medicine.
You're using that
as a metaphor,
but he literally
ran away from me
in the cafeteria
this morning.
Okay, I'll talk to him.
Thank you.
Excuse me?
You're Phil Hall's
doctors, right?
Yes.
Apparently
only family
can see him,
but the nurses said that
if I talked to you,
that maybe...
Are you the woman
who told him she just
wanted to be friends?
He told you that?
Yes.
That's why he got so
drunk and crashed
his car into a tree.
Oh, my God.
Could you at least
tell him that I'm here
and that I care about
him and that I hope
he's gonna be okay?
We can tell him.
But it won't make him
feel any better.
We'll tell him.
The abscesses are huge.
And multiloculated.
The surgeon probably
tried to inject
too much fat.
There doesn't
appear to be any
intra-abdominal
or pelvic
involvement yet.
She should've hid
from her friends
in Beverly Hills,
not Brazil.
Or just learned to love
the body God gave her.
You two really have such
strong beliefs about
aesthetic surgery
or do you just get off
on arguing with each other?
He doesn't believe
strongly in anything.
Just likes
to provoke me.
I just want to get
you to open your
mind a little.
You know, not be
so judgmental.
I'm the judgmental one?
Mr. "I never date a guy
who drives a sports car,
"can't dance, or who
doesn't like
'The Golden Girls'"?
I get the car and the dancing,
but "The Golden Girls"?
I'm not gonna date
a total moron.
My chest
is starting to hurt.
It feels like something's
squeezing my...
Petechial rash
on the neck and...
Oh!
BP's crashing.
She's hypoxic and agitated.
We need high-flow oxygen.
Muscle injuries
are actually not
as severe
as I expected.
The fact
he was so drunk
probably helped him.
Kept the arteries
from thrombosing.
Need more saline
in the pulse lavage.
I'm not surprised
he got friend-zoned.
You see the woman
in the waiting area?
That's who he was
drowning his
sorrows over?
Mm, bit out
of his league.
Yeah.
You don't think
a woman like her
could ever fall in love
with a guy like him?
Eh, it's possible,
if he was rich
or a rock star.
So you think all women
are greedy and shallow?
Humans are
greedy and shallow,
and it's silly
to pretend we're not
just because it's nicer
to talk about
the world that way.
Saline's clear.
No bleeding,
no sign of
muscle necrosis.
Good job.
Dr. Lim, you got a page
from Lea Dilallo.
Tell her
I'm on my way.
Place the ex-fix
to stabilize
the fractures for now.
We can do
a more extensive
reconstruction
after the swelling's
gone down.
Murphy can take
lead on that.
Murphy, you hear me?
Yes.
That was fast.
It was actually
incredibly slow.
I had to route
the downloads
through a proxy
and print at different
nurses' stations to
stay untraceable.
Thank you.
Hold on.
These too.
You said
you wanted everything.
It came out to over
4,000 pages.
Damn it.
What exactly
are you looking for?
I'm not sure.
Looks complicated.
He has a severe
comminuted fracture
with significant
bone loss.
The standard ex-fix
puts him at high risk
for deformity
and malunion.
Hey, Shaun, I...
I know you know
that I'm on your side,
no matter what.
But for whatever
it's worth,
I think you and Lea
make a very
good couple.
No, I don't want to
talk about Lea.
Why?
Dr. Park says
women are shallow.
He said that about Lea?
She's never dated anyone
like me before.
Okay, Shaun,
Lea might be flaky
and impulsive,
but, my God,
she's not shallow.
She made a mistake,
Shaun.
Give her a break.
I have to go.
Some of
the injected fat got
into your bloodstream
and embolized
to your lungs.
We can treat them
with medication.
But blood thinners
will make the surgery
on the abscesses
too risky.
We need to delay repairing
the aesthetic surgery
until after we fix
the clots in your lungs.
How long
will that take?
At least a few days.
And even with
broad spectrum
antibiotics,
the infection could
spread and damage
your glute muscles.
Possibly even cause
necrosis.
You mean
like dying flesh?
We'll do everything
we can to...
No way. I...
I don't care
how risky it is.
I want my butt
fixed first.
If we don't reduce
the clot burden to
your lungs immediately,
the complications
could be life-threatening.
You said you could
do them both.
You want to risk your
life to avoid an injury
to your butt?
Yes.
I already took
a huge risk.
I traveled halfway
around the world to fix
the way I look,
and there is no way
I'm gonna go
backwards now.
But what Dr. Reznick
is recommending
isn't going backward.
It's making the best
out of an awful situation.
You said you wouldn't
judge me.
I told you
what I want.
Are you gonna
help me or not?
Yes.
Aspirate
the superficial
collection,
start blood thinners,
and schedule her
for a surgery
first thing
in the morning.
Your friend's
first surgery went well,
but he needs to stay
under observation
until we finish
stabilizing
his leg fractures.
Can I see him?
No. But Dr. Park told him
what you'd said.
Thank you.
I'll come back tomorrow.
Why could you never
be more than just
friends with him?
Um...
Phil is
a really great guy.
I do love him.
I even tried
for a while.
I thought I could get
past it, that I was
being shallow.
But it's how
I feel.
I shouldn't
just settle.
This is...
She doesn't
own the place.
At least not yet.
By law, the State
Attorney General
has to approve the
change from non-profit
to for-profit status.
That hasn't happened,
which means the
deal's not closed.
That doesn't make
any sense.
She's been
running the place
for months.
These
acquisitions
take time.
The buyer
has to take control
before the regulatory
requirements are finalized.
And one requirement is,
"For-profit status
"cannot adversely affect
the obligation
"to serve
the community interest."
And there's no
way the A.G.'s
gonna agree
that killing babies
"serves the
community interest."
Okay, but why are
you telling me?
Because while I know
what she did, I don't
have written proof.
Well, I'm sorry.
I, um...
I took the severance.
Agreed to a non-disclosure.
Then give it
back and...
And tear it up.
She fired you for
something she forced
you to do,
made you the scapegoat
for everything she's done
and will continue to do
if you don't stop her.
If we don't stop her.
I have a wife
and two kids.
I... I need to know
that I can get another job.
And what about
sleeping at night?
Don't act like
you've never made
a compromise,
done something at work
that you thought was wrong.
We all make compromises.
But I know you believe
this is a lot
more than that
because you're
a decent man,
a father trying
to do right
by his kids.
But what happens
when they ask you why
you changed jobs?
Will you tell
the truth,
or will you look your kids
in the eye and lie?
Okay.
What do you need?
You think
Morgan's right?
That we constantly argue
because we like it?
No. It's part
of the job.
We have to kick
the tires
on every idea.
But we don't have to
kick each other.
We?
You're the one who said
my skin looked like
the Crypt Keeper's.
I was obviously joking.
You were obviously
annoyed because
I expressed an opinion.
My problem is not you
expressing your opinion.
It's that you attribute
all of mine
to a personal flaw.
Maybe growing up
where you did,
you weren't exposed to
a lot of strong women.
And maybe growing
up where you did,
it's common to insult
people's mothers.
I didn't say anything
about your mother.
Have you ever even met
a Hasidic woman?
Is there a problem?
No.
Then why are you
still in here
and not in the OR
getting our patient
positioned for surgery?
Sorry.
On it.
I can't stop
thinking about
what Monica said.
Who's Monica?
Lea thinks I'm not
good enough
to be her husband.
Is that the issue?
Because that's ridiculous.
No, it's not ridiculous.
She told me before
that we could never be
more than just friends
because of my ASD.
And now she knows
she was wrong, right?
No.
She saw me save a patient
from a collapsed building,
which shouldn't
have made her
realize anything
because she already
knew I was a good doctor
who could save patients.
Shaun...
And she wanted
you to come back
from Montana
so she wouldn't be
burdened with me
on her own,
and she changed my
client satisfaction scores
because she thinks
I can't succeed by myself.
That's not quite true.
Yes, it is.
Okay.
I don't want
to be married
to someone who is just
settling for me,
especially because
all her other boyfriends
were just drummers
and jerks and...
Okay, stop, stop,
stop, stop, stop!
Sit down.
Shaun, sit down.
Okay.
Lea is not settling.
You're... You're
hardworking and honest
and loyal and brilliant,
and she's lucky
to have you,
and she damn well
knows it.
Shaun, sometimes
when people
love us, they...
They want to help,
and they help
at the wrong time
and for the wrong reasons
in the wrong way.
But Lea loves you.
She loves you.
Okay.
I have to go.
Okay, for your
surgery, we'll be
inserting screws
and a series of
circular rings with
connecting rods...
Is Monica still here?
No, she went home
last night.
Connecting
rods between...
She waited all day,
obviously cares
about you.
That's just pity.
Which makes me feel like
an even bigger loser.
Stop it.
You did something
irresponsible,
but you're not a loser.
You wouldn't understand.
You're good-looking,
muscular.
I'm sure you were always
a great athlete.
If she's that superficial,
would you have
fallen for her?
Maybe she's afraid
of committing.
If you back off,
let things develop,
maybe she'll change
her mind.
You really think so?
It can't hurt to try.
She won't change
her mind.
And you don't think
she ever will.
He said there's no
way a woman who
looked like her
would ever love a guy
who looked like you.
Connecting rods
between each
circular ring.
What the hell
are you doing?
You... You were
lying to him.
No, I was trying to
cheer him up,
which is not only
nice but medically
beneficial.
Look, I understand
you're going
through some stuff,
but if you're not
able to get
your head straight
and focus on the job,
you need to let
someone else
do this surgery.
I can focus fine.
I did it.
Found exactly
what we need
to get rid of her.
You found $52 million?
We don't need
to buy her out,
because she hasn't
bought us.
Not yet.
And once the A.G. gets
the information
I convinced Fremes
to turn over,
she never will.
Fremes the pharmacist?
He signed an N.D.A.
He... He took a check.
Which he regrets.
He's willing to pass
up the money
and come forward.
Well, that's very
heroic of him,
but it's irrelevant.
The A.G. isn't
gonna blow up
this deal.
We have proof
that she was
warned her policies
would endanger patients,
but she forced them
through anyway.
Let me get this straight.
You're gonna rely on
someone who's already
signed an N.D.A.,
who's taken money,
not to mention that Salen
has top-dollar lawyers
and lobbyists who
are gonna argue
that the baby didn't die
from expired meds
but from a car crash
and premature delivery
and a pre-existing
cardiac condition.
Look, I... I...
I agree with you that
Salen should not be
running a hospital.
But there isn't an
A.G. in America who
would take this on.
Unless it comes
from you.
Fine.
We'll go in
on our own.
Bleeding's
not as bad as I'd feared.
We need
great hemostasis
so there's no unsightly
fluid collections.
Definitely don't
want that.
No, we definitely don't.
This isn't the first
time you let your
personal feelings
about aesthetic surgery
impact patient care.
Patients have
a right to make
their own decisions,
but they also deserve
my honest opinion
of the risks and benefits.
Honest and professional.
Which means based on
the medicine,
not your personal bias.
Patients deserve to benefit
from their surgeon's
life experience.
And clearly felt
comfortable enough to
make her own decision.
He's right.
They make a good team.
She's hemodynamically
unstable. End-tidal
CO2 plummeting.
Did we cause
a venous air embolism?
No, it's not air.
She's thrown more
pulmonary clots.
We need mechanical
thrombectomy, STAT.
Adding an additional
Schanz screw.
Dr. Park,
can you add
more traction
to facilitate
fracture reduction?
How's that?
Perfect.
Dr. Lim,
you've got a call.
I'm a little busy.
It's Dr. Fremes.
He says it's urgent.
The meeting's
already set.
No, I... I understand
that she's worried,
but your kids need a father
they can look up to,
someone they can
be proud of.
No. No, no.
It can't just be my word.
I need your...
Spineless prick.
Her pressure's dropping.
Increase vasopressors
and limit fluid
overloading.
These damn fat clots
are harder to aspirate
than a blood clot.
Can you use
a stent retriever?
No, it's better to just
go with a larger bore
aspiration catheter.
Should we stop
what we're...
No, keep going.
No reason
to back up now.
Got it.
Come on.
Hold on.
Got you,
you little bastard.
She's crashing!
Gotta be more
in her heart.
Let's run an echo,
optimize pressers
for her cardiac
parameters,
and prep her femoral
for cerebral angio.
The surgery
was a success.
Dr. Lim let Dr. Park
and I do it almost
all on our own.
You want to go out and
have a drink tonight?
Do you really think Lea
realized she was wrong
about my ASD?
Were you just lying
to cheer me up?
Have I ever lied before?
Oh, yes.
Okay. I'm not lying.
Mmm.
Okay. I used to let
Robin Johnson
copy off my test.
She'd tell me
how cute I was.
But Michelle Plasse
told me Robin would
make fun of me
behind my back.
Both seemed nice
but one of them
was lying.
Shaun, you're not
a kid anymore.
But I'm still weird.
Yes, you're weird.
I'm weird.
Everyone's weird.
Everyone feels weird
at some point.
Everyone feels ugly
or stupid or old
or whatever it is.
That doesn't
help at all.
I know.
What's wrong?
If you can still speak
and see us... Nothing.
You had us
very worried.
We had to remove
multiple clots
from your heart
and brain
during surgery.
But now...
We were able to
debride the gluteal
abscesses.
We won't know for
sure until we see
how you heal, but...
Doesn't look like
there'll be
any visible scarring
or deformity.
Thank you.
I don't understand.
You told my associates
that you and Dr. Fremes
had actual evidence.
And now not only
do you not have
any documents,
you don't have
Dr. Fremes.
Because he was
intimidated into silence
by Salen Morrison.
Into silence?
Or into taking
responsibility
for his own actions?
I don't understand
how a mistake
made in an OR
or a hospital pharmacy
could possibly
be the fault
of your parent
company's CEO.
She sidelined our president
and began inserting herself
into medical decisions.
She consistently reduced
the quality of care
to boost
Ethicure's profits.
Dr. Lim, I get that
these takeovers
may involve policy changes
that you don't approve of...
If she started her own
for-profit hospital,
she'd have every
right to run it
however she saw fit.
But she didn't do that.
She bought ours...
Aa non-profit.
Which means
she's legally obligated
to serve the community,
the whole community,
not just patients
with premium insurance.
And you have
a responsibility
to make sure that
means something.
That it's not
just fine print
in a contract
no one will ever read.
I agree.
But do you
have any actual
evidence of fraud
or criminal activity
done by Salen Morrison?
I have a dead baby.
And that is Salen
Morrison's fault.
And I guarantee
this is gonna happen
again and again
if you don't step in
and do what only
you can do to stop it.
Let me think,
and I'll get back to you.
Thank you.
Dr. Murphy
did a great job.
You've a long
road ahead
and probably
a few more surgeries,
but it looks
very good.
You have no nerve
injuries and both
bones in your shin
have been stabilized
with good alignment.
Did Monica come back?
No.
Good.
I don't need her pity.
And you were right.
She obviously
wasn't gonna
change her mind.
Maybe you should
change yours.
I get the feeling
that you also
care a bit too much
about how your
dates look,
how they make you look
to other people
instead of how they make
you feel about yourself.
Is that your way of
telling me that because
I'm fat and ugly
I should only
date women
who are the same?
I don't think
you're fat or ugly.
But if you want
to find someone
who loves you more
than just a friend,
you need to start
loving yourself.
Just get out
and leave me alone.
Let the nurse know
if you need more
meds for the pain.
What're you looking at?
I just... I told you,
just... Just get out.
Dr. Park is right.
You should listen
to him.
I can't
believe it.
We actually saved
her lungs, her brain,
and her ass.
That's a triple play.
She's lucky she didn't
end up with major
organ damage.
She was lucky
to have us.
The way we fight
all the time at work?
That's how it is with me
and my oldest brother.
He drives me insane.
But I love him.
He also thinks a beard
makes him look taller.
That was unkind
and uncalled for.
Or the truth.
Hello?
This is she.
Thank you. I...
I really appreciate
your taking the time.
No, actually,
I don't understand.
Good night.
How was your meeting?
What meeting?
Your meeting
with the A.G.
I've always been
open with you, Audrey.
Tried to help
you understand
what it is
I'm trying to
accomplish here.
And you went behind
my back and tried
to destroy it all.
I'm never gonna
forget it.
I don't want
to cancel
our wedding.
We love each other
and are good
for each other.
And I forgive you for
lying about your
trip to Montana
and changing my scores.
I know you were just
trying to help me.
Thank you.
Did you want
Dr. Glassman
to come back
so you wouldn't have
to take care of me
on your own?
I wanted him to come
back because
he cares about you.
And I know
that you care
about him, too.
I don't need you to
take care of me.
I know. And I don't
mean to smother you.
I... I just want
to help you
and be there for you.
Do you believe I'm not
good enough for you?
That you're not
good enough?
What're you even
talking about?
You told me once
that you could
never be
in a relationship with me
because of my ASD.
Is that what you think?
It's what you said.
Yeah, a long time ago.
Are you seriously
telling me
that you don't see
a difference in how
I feel about you?
That I haven't
grown at all?
Our relationship
hasn't grown?
Shaun, all I was trying
to do is help someone
that I love,
to be there for you
like you've been
there for me.
But you just can't seem
to see it that way,
no matter how many
times I've tried.
I mean, is every mistake
I make going
to be something
that you hold against
me forever?
No, I...
I am forgiving you.
No, I don't need you
to forgive me.
And I'm done.
I'm... I'm done
apologizing
for helping you
and caring about you
and whatever
else I'm doing
that you seem to find
so unbearable.
Yes. No... No,
that's not what I said.
No. What you're saying
is that I'm not good
enough for you.
That's actually
not true...
And if that's what
you feel, then fine.
Maybe we shouldn't
get married.
Mmm-hmm.
And you know what?
Maybe we shouldn't even be
living together,
so I'm gonna get
out of your way. Totally.
And you can sleep
in your own bed tonight,
and first thing tomorrow,
I'll start looking
for a new place to live.