So, you got a Green Beret, a Navy
SEAL and a sister from Brooklyn.
The general hands each
of them a gun and says,
"Your spouse is seated
next door in a room in a chair.
"In order to pass this test, you
must go inside and kill them."
Immediately the
Green Beret says,
"No, sir, I could never kill
my wife. I just can't do it."
The General looks at him
and says, "You know what?
"You ain't got what it takes.
Take your wife and go on home."
Navy Seal then heads in.
Five minutes later, comes
out, tears strolling down his face.
"I tried, I tried, I
tried, I just can't do it,
"she looked so beautiful
in the chair, I can't do it."
General looks at him and
says, "You know what?
"You ain't got what it takes."
Finally, sister from Brooklyn
strolls in with a swagger.
Shots rang out,
there's banging, there's
screaming, it's going crazy!
Suddenly,
everything goes silent.
The General says, "Well,
what the hell happened inside?"
The sister from
Brooklyn screams back,
"The damn gun had blanks in it,
"so I had to beat him
to death with my bare..."
What the hell?
A little bit of warning
would have been nice!
The sound of a saw
cutting a hole in the wall
wasn't warning enough?
Bite me.
What, are you kidding me? Tub of
Goo there's gotta be over six bills.
You ain't gonna lift him
with a couple of blankets.
You got a better idea, Einstein?
Yeah, just roll him off.
What? He's already dead,
it ain't like he's gonna feel it.
How the hell's a
guy get that big?
You roll him off from this high,
he's likely to go right through
the floor and take us with him.
Are you ready? All
right, one, two, lift!
Come on, man!
Me? You're the kielbasa king.
It wasn't me.
Whoa, it wasn't me, either.
Don't look at me.
Please tell me
dead guys can fart.
Of course. Dead bodies
are full of all sorts of gases.
But a dead body can't
tighten a sphincter.
You need a tight
sphincter to make a fart.
No, you need a loose
sphincter. A tight sphincter...
You check his femoral?
No. He peed all over himself!
Look, I've heard dead
bodies moan, groan, hiss,
hell, I've even seen them
sit straight up on a gurney.
Trust me, his skin's cold, pupils are
fixed and dilated, he's not breathing.
He's got a pulse! No way.
All right, give me an Ambu bag
and an EKG. It's thready, but it's there.
Let's get him in
a basket. Ready?
One, two, lift!
Forty-six-year-old
guy in a coma.
Doesn't appear to be
anything wrong with him
except for the fact that he
weighs over 600 pounds.
What time does
he usually get in?
Any time between 8:00 and 10:00.
Did you say 600? At least.
Biggest scale we got
only goes up to 350
but this guy's waistline
is over seven feet.
Which means he's a diabetic with
blood thicker than pancake batter.
No mystery there,
not much we can do.
Blood sugar's normal.
Cholesterol's lower than mine, tox
screen's clean, no sign of trauma.
Sure there wasn't
a mix-up at the lab?
Three times?
It's almost 11:00,
where is House?
Hello!
It's 11:00.
Which means my friend is ready for
his sponge bath and I shouldn't be here!
Hey, Gomer Pyle! I
know you can hear me.
I think you mean Barney Fife.
So many great idiot
icons to choose from.
You need time to
think of some more?
Either arraign me or let me go.
No problem. Which do you prefer?
What took you so long?
Sorry. I didn't have 15
grand in my loose change jar.
What the hell did
you do? Nothing.
Your motorcycle was impounded,
that explains the speeding, DUI,
and driving without a license.
The fact that you're you explains
the illegal possession of narcotics
and resisting arrest.
Where's your car?
What happened?
Some idiot cop with
crotch rot obviously thought
that I didn't treat him with the
deference due to a man of his stature.
He trumped up a traffic stop,
next thing I know
I'm sharing a cage
with a guy who
thinks that showers
are the way the
devil gets inside you.
Does Cuddy know?
Everything she needs to.
I'm innocent.
Till proven guilty.
Guy wanted to punish
me, he did it. It's over.
Gotta get yourself a lawyer.
Already got one.
You know what they say about the
lawyer who has himself as a client?
Same thing they say about
the doctor who lends 15 grand
to a friend he knows
can't pay him back.
Relax, you'll get it. Where
am I gonna take off to?
Does Salma Hayek
live in Mexico or Spain?
There's nothing abnormal in
the EEG or the neurological exam.
I'm guessing it's food-related.
Improperly prepared puffer fish
can have toxins that
could cause a coma
and might not show
up on the tox screen.
Where do you think he is?
He's probably at the track.
If he's at the track he'd tell us
so we don't have to page him,
and if it was a puffer fish, he'd
be dead in six to eight hours, tops.
He's been in a coma at least 24.
And the guy didn't get to 600
pounds eating a load of sushi.
What if he was in a
motorcycle accident?
Explains the coma. But
how'd he get back in bed?
Oh, Cameron's
talking about House!
You ever see how he drives?
No, we haven't.
But I have seen how many
pills he's been popping lately,
I wouldn't be surprised if he's
in a coma somewhere himself.
If I am, this is one
lame hallucination.
What happened to you?
If you ever end up in a bar with the
Cambridge Women's Heavyweight Eight,
do not accept an offer of an
upside-down kamikaze shot.
We have a case. Fat
guy in a coma, I know.
Cuddy found you? Nope.
But the wall between
Wilson's office
and this one is
thinner than you'd think.
Which means we
need to stop talking
about what a
pathetic loser he is.
Start treating Jabba for
pickwickian syndrome.
His 96 double-Zs are probably putting
pressure on his chest, suffocating him.
CO2 and oxygen sats are normal.
For you and me. What's
normal for a hippopotamus?
And get a detailed
medical history.
From who? He was
brought in alone.
And I doubt a guy who weighs 600
pounds bothers with annual physicals.
Talk to the neighbors
and search the house.
Let's see what else Shamu's
been up to besides eating.
This conversation is over
because I've officially run out
of clever things to call the guy.
It's hard to believe
you can even attach this
much flesh to a human skeleton.
I wouldn't exactly
call this attached.
This is ridiculous.
A person shouldn't be able
to eat themselves into oblivion
and then just expect everyone to
pull out the stops to fix everything.
What are we supposed to do? Refuse
treatment to anyone who's obese?
Come on, give me a
break. This guy's not obese.
He's not even morbidly
obese. He's suicidal.
People who attempt
suicide get treated.
Plenty of noncompliant
diabetics don't.
We don't give
drug addicts dialysis
or alcoholics liver transplants.
What is your problem?
You get beat up
by a gang of fat kids
when you were in grade
school or something?
Yeah. I'm the one
with the problem.
So, I think his
bedroom's through there,
and the kitchen's to the left.
Have you seen any
changes in his personality?
Any trouble with
memory or balance?
No, but I really don't
see him that often.
He's not unfriendly or anything,
I guess he just likes
to keep to himself.
I think he only gave me a spare
set of keys 'cause I gave him mine.
What?
Nothing. Just reminds me of
someone I know. Who is unfriendly.
Does George have a job?
He has a headhunting
business he runs from home.
Occasionally he'll
interview people here,
but he does most
of it over the phone.
Wow!
Yeah, he loves to cook.
And eat, obviously.
Four-course gourmet
meals almost every night,
sometimes for lunch, too.
Do you know if he ever uses any
unpasteurized cheese or wild game?
I'm not sure.
He gets all his groceries delivered
from that market down on Alden.
They'd probably know.
He have any friends? No.
I mean, sometimes
women do come by.
Young, attractive, never the same
one twice, if you know what I mean.
I see.
There can't be many women
who'd wanna be with a guy like him.
It's usually worst
in the morning.
Especially if I've
slept on my arm.
If I sleep on my back or with
my arms out, I'm usually okay.
So your arm only hurts after
you lie on top of it all night.
Yeah.
Well, have you thought about,
I don't know, not doing that?
Yeah. But it's how I sleep,
it's how I've always slept.
Well, there's always surgery.
To do what? Like, clean out
some cartilage or something?
You're not sleeping on some
cartilage, you're sleeping on your arm.
You wanna remove my arm?
Well, it is your left. You
know, a guy's gotta sleep.
Are you insane?
I see spending a night in
jail hasn't humbled you a bit.
While following my
every move is flattering,
a single rose on my doorstep each
morning would be more enticing.
Just bringing your
boss up to speed,
which I guess you
didn't feel was necessary.
You gonna add that
to my list of charges?
People who are innocent tend
not to try to hide their arrest.
Is that based on your years of
experience arresting innocent people?
The way you're
going at that gum,
it's obviously not
having the desired effect.
You're the addict. You're gonna
be back on the butts in a month.
You're just taking out your frustration
on me 'cause my meds actually work.
Why don't you quit
while you're ahead.
Before you end up
as a security guard
working the night
shift at some strip mall.
I think working around
a bunch of nurses
has given you a false sense
of your ability to intimidate.
Who was that?
Apparently Cuddy's widened
her sperm donor search
to include Neanderthals.
Cuddy's looking
for a sperm donor?
It was a joke. Like Cuddy
would ever want a kid.
Or a kid would ever want Cuddy.
Hello, that's why it's funny!
Why are you guys here?
It's not pickwick's.
Intubation and steroids
have had no effect.
Except maybe to cause
whatever it is to get worse.
He's got a fever now.
What'd you find out?
That you and George have the same
taste in home furnishings and women.
Danish Modern and
Russian gymnasts?
Pianos and prostitutes.
We should do an LP
and look for neurosyphilis.
It's not syphilis.
How do you know?
Because you get STDs
from people you trust,
people you don't feel the
need to protect yourself from.
Whatever he has is connected
to his gut, not what's below it.
MRI his brain, look for clots.
Weight limit on the MRI
machine is 450 pounds.
So do a CT.
Limit's 350.
Then just start treatment.
If we give him blood thinners
and the coma's caused
by a bleed instead of
a clot, we could kill him.
Either start treatment or
start building a stronger MRI.
Whatever you do, do it fast.
The longer he stays in the coma,
the less likely it is
he'll ever wake up.
There's no way.
His head's the only part that
we have to get in the machine.
If we can just get
him on the table...
We get him on the
table, we break the table.
We break the table,
hospital's out a million dollars
and we're out of our jobs.
The weight limit's
obviously just an estimation.
It's not like if it can
hold 450 pounds fine,
it'll instantly
collapse under 451.
He's not one pound over,
he's 150 pounds over.
I don't care!
He still deserves the same
standard of care as anyone else.
Then you believe the
machine will stand on principle.
You guys gonna help or not?
How much does this guy weigh?
440.
Looks like a lot more than that.
It's 'cause he's lying down.
You guys ready? One, two, three.
Here. What's this?
I made some calls for you.
The guy's the best criminal
attorney in Princeton.
Thanks, but I don't need it.
I assume you told
Inspector Clouseau
that I have a valid
prescription for the Vicodin.
Yeah, and I assume you did
as well. Did it make a difference?
The guy's pissed!
And with the DEA now treating
pain doctors like Colombian...
I'm not a pain doctor,
I'm a pain patient.
Tell it to your lawyer.
No midline shifts, no
bleeds, clots, infarcts.
I don't see any edema, either.
So what do we do now?
An LP.
Even if it's not an STD, a fever
points toward some sort of infection.
I'm not sure we can do
an LP on a guy his size.
What?
You have to be able to palpate
the spine to know where to go.
We could use
fluoroscopy to guide us.
He still wouldn't be able to bring
his knees up and bend forward
in order to open
the space between...
George, it's all right,
you're in a hospital!
Calm down, man, calm down!
Get him out already! I'm trying!
Come on!
We're gonna get you out!
We still have no idea why he
was in the coma to begin with.
Or why he woke up.
It was probably just
some sort of head trauma
and we missed the swelling
because, well, his
head's already swollen.
Bump on the noggin
doesn't explain the fever.
An infection made worse by the
steroids we gave him for pickwick's does.
He's not worse, he's better.
We just replaced the
last MRI you broke.
Referring to the fund-raising
funbags by the royal "we" now?
Let me explain cause
and effect to you.
I specifically told them to
skip the boring testing part
and jump right to the
dangerous treatment.
You blow stuff up,
makes my life miserable,
makes me need to
make your life miserable.
He's telling the truth.
Kids these days, got no respect
for other people's property.
Repairmen cost
less than lawyers.
Morbid obesity is a
legally defined disability,
which means if we'd
denied access to the MRI,
he could have sued us for
discrimination as well as malpractice.
This was your idea?
Yeah.
Looks like Cameron's gonna be
having a lot more ideas in future.
Who knew that being bloated and
bitchy could actually come in handy?
Shut up. What if it is hormones?
It's not hormones.
I'm talking about George.
Acute adrenal insufficiency
could cause a temporary coma.
A glandular problem would cause
his temperature to be low, not high.
Maybe the fever's not related.
If it's not related, there's
nothing to talk about.
We should do an
ACTH stimulation test
and check his skin for
acanthosis nigricans.
Or the fever is related
and so are the prostitutes.
We should do a full STD panel
and check his genitals for chancres.
We should do nothing.
Just keep him a couple
of days for observation.
If he doesn't get any worse,
it was probably just a hematoma
that dissipated on its own.
Or we do all of the above.
You check his belly for patches.
You check underneath for sores.
And you just sit on your ass.
Acanthosis nigricans is a
hyperpigmentation of the skin,
usually indicates some
sort of hormonal imbalance.
There's nothing wrong
with my hormones.
It's the first thing every doctor
I've ever gone to has checked.
Then it's the blood pressure,
then it's gotta be diabetes.
They all figure there's gotta
be something wrong with me.
You having any
problems with your vision?
No, I have nystagmus. I've
had it since birth, I'm fine.
You're not fine. You were
in a coma for two days.
There's something
wrong with you.
Was something wrong with me,
now I'm better, now I'd like to go home.
A coma's not like
a stomach ache.
You can't just shrug it off and
hope it's not anything serious.
My company places a
lot of insurance executives.
There are over 300,000 deaths
caused each year by medical mistakes
and hospital-associated
infections. I'll come in for tests.
There are over 400,000 deaths
caused by obesity-related illnesses.
The CDC says those figures
are a gross overestimation.
George, you ever notice you
don't see a lot of obese old men?
If I'm gonna have
a heart attack,
I would rather it be caused by a
perfect pan-roasted ris de veau
than running 26 miles for no reason
other than to brag that I can do it.
Or to have an MRI machine
break in the middle of a procedure!
We're sorry about that.
It was the only way to rule out
a stroke or brain hemorrhage.
And now that you
have, when can I go?
It's probably her mom.
I bet she's huge.
She's from the Midwest.
Since when do you eat beets?
Since I was five.
And who are we talking about?
You know, just in case you need me
to chime in and tell you
you're a lunatic at some point?
Cameron. She's lying,
destroying hospital equipment,
telling Cuddy off.
I gotta find out where she
got the Fat Scratch Fever.
Yeah, you definitely better
get to the bottom of that.
I heard Cuddy gave
you the name of a lawyer.
Or it could just be pity. She feels
guilty about being born beautiful.
So she overcompensates
by being nice to ugly people.
Would explain why she
gets along so well with you.
From what I hear, the patient
reminds her of you, not me.
Call the lawyer.
Cameron sees a clump
of dirt and she thinks of me.
Or a lump of something else.
You're a lunatic. Call the lawyer.
Very mature. You started it.
Skin exam and ACTH
stimulation test were both normal.
He has nystagmus
but it's congenital.
No way it's related to the coma.
You say, "No way," I
say... Yeah, no way.
Blood and urine were negative
for chlamydia, herpes, and syphilis.
Looks like we got
ourselves a mystery.
Not for long. He
wants to be discharged.
Oh, sure. Places
to go, people to eat.
He insists his chance of dying
from a hospital-acquired
infection
is greater than him dying
from whatever caused his coma.
Did you tell him that statistics
also say that he's a big, fat idiot?
Yeah, I did. He's
not backing down.
He says if we don't
discharge him, he'll leave AMA.
Selectively rational,
stubborn, uncooperative,
maybe you ought
to check his leg.
Do you see what he did
there? The patient's like me.
The patient's three mes.
If I were him...
Maybe it's not such
a mystery after all.
Enjoying your Salisbury steak?
Putting chopped
parsley in a hamburger
does not a Salisbury steak make.
You must be Dr. House.
And you must be full
of baloney. A lot of it.
Right. Fat joke. Always fun.
The only people you
can still make fun of.
And Christians. Oh,
and black people.
No one in their right
mind comes out of a coma
and immediately asks to go
home with an unknown condition,
which means that either
you're not in your right mind
or it's not an
unknown condition.
So, what is it? You
tried to off yourself?
You figure I'm fat,
therefore I hate myself.
Yeah, that's a
huge leap of logic.
I don't wanna die. I
just don't wanna be here.
Then it's a condition you've
already had diagnosed,
or it's something you
know you've inherited.
Let's see, your stomach
has deep-seated feelings
of abandonment
written all over it,
which points
toward sexual abuse.
While a fear of hospitals, that points
to a more specific traumatic event.
So I'm gonna say, your mom
in the hospital with a candlestick.
And by candlestick, of course, I
mean inherited OTC deficiency.
My parents are both alive and
well and living in Boca Raton.
Thyrotoxic periodic paralysis?
I have no idea what that is.
Leukoencephalopathy.
Will you stop!
If I knew what was
wrong, I would tell you.
I'm not an imbecile,
and I'm not miserable.
I'm just overweight.
What?
When?
To be continued.
What are you doing here?
Executing a search
of the premises.
When you... When
you got bailed out
before we could get a
judge to approve this,
I almost didn't bother.
I thought for sure you'd come
straight home and throw everything out.
Rookie mistake. Never
underestimate the stupidity of an addict.
There's gotta be over
600 Vicodin in here.
Which most DAs would
say proves intent to traffic.
Even if all you really intended
was to simply be wasted 24/7
while practicing medicine.
In case you hadn't noticed,
those are prescription bottles.
I'm not an expert
on linguistics per se,
but I think that means
they were prescribed.
All these were
legally prescribed
to a man who's in constant pain
but never misses a day of work?
Has it ever occurred to you
that's why I don't miss a day?
Yeah. Yeah, crossed my
mind. Among other things.
Like what an unprofessional,
unethical, arrogant ass you are.
Because if you're
unprofessional in one area,
it only makes sense.
Now maybe just a few of these
are in someone else's name.
Forged prescription,
or just, um, swiped from the
pharmacy when nobody's looking.
No, but, well, you
wouldn't do that. Right?
Send him home.
Why? You think he's healthy?
Either I'm right,
he knows what's wrong, he's
just too stubborn to admit it,
or I was right
and it's pickwick's.
The treatment just
had a delayed effect.
You don't have delayed
effects to oxygen.
And Pickwick's doesn't
explain the fever.
Being engulfed in an
electric blanket of blubber
could explain the fever.
Yesterday you insisted we keep
him here because of the fever.
We have no idea what's
wrong with the guy.
For all we know he
could be dead in 12 hours.
He does not want our help.
Which means he
doesn't want your help.
He's obviously just
rationalizing. And so are you!
You would never
give up this easy
if you weren't so busy dealing
with your own personal problems.
Send him home.
What did you tell that cop?
Nothing.
Nothing as in nothing?
Or as in nothing that
could cause him to think
I have a stash in my apartment?
He called to see if I prescribed
the pills, I said yes. That's all.
Obviously not. What happened?
He searched my house,
found a buttload of pills.
Guy's gotta be
prepared for a rainy day.
Last I checked pharmacies
were still open when it rained.
And because I never know when
you're gonna be in one of your moods
and cut me off.
Oh, it's my fault.
I'm not the one who
talked to the cop.
Well, I'm not the one who put
a thermometer in his rectum.
So stop yelling at me and
start talking to your lawyer.
Is there someone
who can check on you?
Oh, don't worry.
There's gonna be a whole
crew of carpenters in my bedroom
for the next week at least.
You know, there's an Overeaters
Anonymous meeting here at the hospital.
If I wanted to jump out of
airplanes or climb Mount Everest,
would you be telling me to
go to Daredevils Anonymous?
I would be worried about
you just like I am now.
Don't be.
I enjoy food.
I like cooking it, I like
looking at it, I like smelling it,
and I especially like eating it.
Listen, whatever
happens is gonna happen.
Ultimately it's all out
of our control anyway.
Why doesn't that
philosophy apply
to medical mistakes and
hospital-acquired infections as well?
I'm a complicated
man, Dr. Cameron.
But don't worry, I plan on
staying that way for a long time.
Wait, wait, let us take
you all the way outside.
I'm fine.
It doesn't matter,
it's hospital rules.
Oh, screw the rules. I've
been on my back for four days.
I need the exercise, right?
George, come on, let us
just take you to the taxi.
Don't worry, I may not be able to
climb Everest, but I can walk, okay?
George... Now enough already.
George, are you all right?
George? You all right? George?
Disorientation
and loss of balance
could mean a neurofibromatosis.
Where's Chase? Don't know.
Haven't seen him since you told
him to sit on his ass yesterday.
Interesting.
NF2 is also inherited,
which means I was right.
You kept saying
it was pickwick's.
Between the first pickwick's and the
second pickwick's, I said it was inherited.
Whatever. NF2
doesn't explain fever.
I think we should focus
on the coma and the fever.
Why? The disorientation and
loss of balance are more recent.
The coma was the
most severe symptom.
But he's not in the coma
anymore and he is disoriented.
No, he's not.
We have a rather large piece of
tempered glass that begs to differ.
I just mean it's not connected.
You don't know that.
Yeah, I do.
How could you possibly know...
Because I did it!
I didn't think he
should be discharged,
so I gave him three
grams of phenytoin.
I wasn't gonna
just let him leave.
But you were okay with him
crashing through a glass wall?
I tried to keep him in the
wheelchair, but he's tough to stop.
Nice audible, Peyton.
So, what do we do now?
Discharge report says
he didn't eat his breakfast.
Humpty Dumpty didn't get to
be the size of all the king's horses
by skipping the most
important meal of the day.
What causes coma,
fever, and loss of appetite?
It can't be Chagas', he's
never been outside the country.
But his stomach has.
The food we eat no longer
comes from America's heartland.
It comes from South
America's deforested jungle land
where lettuce now grows
and lettuce pickers now poop.
Get a sample of his CSF
before the little bugs that are now
feasting on his brain move on to dessert.
How are we gonna do that?
He's too big to do an LP.
So go straight to the source.
You wanna drill a
hole in my head?
It's the only way.
It's gotta be something
other than a parasite.
I buy my produce at the best
market in town and I always wash it.
Leafy vegetables can
suck contaminated water
through their roots
right into the plant.
You could have
washed them in chlorine
and it still wouldn't
have mattered.
Then other people
would be sick as well.
The parasites could have
been on only a few items,
or maybe they just didn't
eat as much as you did.
It's always about
my weight, isn't it?
Why can't you people
come up with one theory...
This one fits, George.
It explains your coma, your
fever, your loss of appetite...
And the disorientation?
It's all explained.
And if we don't treat it while
it's still in the acute stage,
it'll be too late.
It could go on to infect your
heart, intestines, esophagus...
This is what I get
for eating salad.
- Suction.
Aspirator.
Your turn.
Irrigation.
Sponge.
What did you do?
Nothing. Why, what's wrong?
I can't see.
Vision's blurry
or you've lost...
I didn't lose it, you
took it from me!
George, calm down. I can't see!
Give me some lorazepam!
What did you do
to me? Hold still!
George! George! What's going on?
No. No. Calm down!
What did you do to me?
There's no inflammation in the
optic nerve and his retina's intact.
The blindness has to have been
caused by something in his brain.
And not surprisingly there
was no sign of Chagas'
or any other
parasites in his CSF.
So we've ruled out his parents,
prostitutes, the
arugula. Means either...
I took the sample
from the prefrontal.
I was never anywhere
near his visual cortex.
Or you missed a
tumor on the MRI.
Not a chance, the MRI was clean.
You mind? Where are you going?
To get a $400 butt plug.
What about George?
He's gonna have to
get his own. Come on.
Let's see if we can
get this thing figured out
by the time we
get to the elevator.
It could be MS.
Would explain the
coma, the blindness,
loss of balance, and the fever.
Could also explain his lack
of concern for his health.
MS can cause
excessive cheerfulness.
Yeah, he's a delight.
You don't get to MS with
coma as the first symptom.
Blindness plus coma
says diabetes. Just in time.
No. Blood sugar, urine dip stick
and hemoglobin A1c are normal.
Were normal when you tested.
He's been in and out of a coma,
whatever's going on
is waxing and waning,
unlike his pants size,
which only waxes.
Which also points to
diabetes. Test him again.
And this time add a glucose
tolerance test and an HEC.
We already have a CSF sample,
we might as well check it
for proteins to rule out MS first.
Agreed. Except for the
part about doing it first.
Where are you going?
The butt plug was my way of
saying, "Mind your own business."
Apparently too subtle.
George, all it is is
sugar water, I promise.
Just because I'm overweight
doesn't make me diabetic!
You tested me,
everybody's tested me.
Sometimes the blood
sugar levels can fluctuate,
make it difficult to diagnose.
You stuck a needle in my brain
and 10 seconds later I was blind!
How is that difficult
to diagnose?
Who the hell knows what
else you guys done to me?
I should have never come
here! You didn't come here,
you were brought here because
you were in a coma and barely alive.
We didn't do that to you, you
need to let us figure out what did.
For someone who insists he
enjoys life as much as you do,
you certainly don't seem
willing to do much to prolong it.
Yeah,
because I don't agree with the
brilliant doctors, suddenly I'm suicidal!
Refusing to cooperate with us does not
make you suicidal, it makes you an idiot.
You think we want to see
you blind or in a coma?
I've been fat all my life.
I've only been sick
for the past few days.
You look for a disease that
has nothing to do with my size,
and I will help you.
Otherwise, leave me alone.
Speeding, DUI, reckless driving,
resisting arrest, possession
of a class three narcotic.
And now it looks
like they've added
another possession with
intent to traffic charge as well.
They found some
pills at your house.
All of which I had
a prescription for.
That's a lot of pills.
I'm in a lot of pain.
This is all because some
cop came into the clinic,
I was rude to him, this is
his way of getting back at me.
You've made it pretty easy.
His insane reaction to a simple
rectal thermometer reading
probably says a lot more about
his mother than it says about me.
I'm inclined to think
your particular charm
may not be immediately
appreciated by a jury.
I'm not interested
in a plea bargain.
It's your best bet to
make this go away.
There is no this. There's a him.
The only thing I'm guilty
of is humiliating a bully.
I wasn't speeding, I wasn't
impaired, I didn't resist,
and I certainly was
not distributing narcotics
to anyone but myself,
because I need those narcotics.
Five grand retainer.
If we end up going to trial, there'll
be another 30 due before the first day.
My hourly is 450.
That work for you?
What'd your lawyer say?
I looked up butt plug in a
legal dictionary. What'd he say?
That a smile like
mine can't lose.
What did the tests say?
You were right about MS. No
myelin basic proteins in his CSF.
What about diabetes? Don't know.
He says we only
think it's diabetes
because of his weight,
won't let us test him.
So, you would rather be a
blind invalid than admit the fact
that maybe you might have a
little problem with overeating.
By a little problem, of course,
I mean you've eaten
yourself half to death.
And you would rather let
me die than consider the fact
that whatever is wrong with me
has nothing to do with my weight.
I go where the
symptoms tell me to go.
And right now they're
asking why this stuff
is the first thing you've
ever refused to swallow.
I am not diabetic.
Grocery stores giving away medical
degrees with the free turkeys now?
The sooner you drink this,
the sooner I get to go waste
my time with something else.
Get the hell off of me!
No dessert till you've
finished your dinner!
George, just drink it!
Nurse!
Get this jackass off of me!
What the hell is going on?
Just trying to
force a horse to...
Let go!
What's going on?
Get X-rays of his hands. Then
bronc him, do a sputum cytology
and check his CSF
for anti-hu antibodies.
How are we gonna
get him to do all that,
we can't even get him to
drink a bottle of sugar water?
Tell him that lung cancer is in
no way connected to obesity.
You don't think he'll
realize we're lying?
You're not. Lung cancer's
got nothing to do with obesity.
I meant about him
having lung cancer.
You didn't notice his fingers?
I noticed they were fat.
You should have pissed him off,
he would have grabbed you.
Then you would
have felt the bones,
they're not just
fat, they're clubbed.
George,
it's me.
Your tests were positive.
You have a small
cell lung carcinoma.
It caused a paraneoplastic
neurologic syndrome,
which in turn caused
your blindness and coma.
The cancer's metastasized
to your lymph nodes.
It's inoperable,
but there are radiation
treatments available.
They might give you
a few more months.
I never smoked.
C'est la vie.
You were right.
So was he.
He said, "C'est la vie."
He's a complicated man.
What about you?
What are you gonna
do about your problem?
Nothing. Just got a
call from my lawyer.
He gave the DA copies
of my prescriptions.
Soon as they confirm
they're bona fides,
they're gonna drop the
possession, DUI and resisting arrest.
Soon as I pay my
$85 speeding ticket
and the impound
fine, I get my bike back.
I guess that's good.
You guess? No, it's good.
You get to keep going
like you always have.
All right, I give
up. Who was it?
Who in your family
had the weight problem?
You think I can only
care about a patient
if I know someone else who's
been through the same thing?
You care for everybody.
You only lie and stand
up to Cuddy for a few.
You lie for everybody
and only care about a few.
You're avoiding the question.
I like damaged people, remember?
It explains everything I do.
Almost everything.
It wasn't you, was it?
Does it matter?
Nope, but it'd be interesting.
Sorry to disappoint you,
but sometimes the answers
just aren't that simple.
I know he can be a real ass,
and he has no problem
lying when it serves him,
but he's not lying
about the pain.
He needs the medication,
which is why I prescribed it.
All of it.
Well, I see a lot of cases
where people who have real
injuries end up getting addicted.
And then, well, things
kind of spiral out of control.
And lives get ruined,
and not just their own.
I don't know what
else to tell you.
What about these?
This is getting...
If it's got my name
on it, it's a legit scrip.
You sure? Yeah.
Because the signatures on these
look a little different than
the signatures on those.
You look surprised.
No, I'm just...
I hadn't thought about it. I do sign
my name differently sometimes.
Are you sure? Yeah.
I just, I guess get bored
signing it the same way.
You know what they say
about doctors' handwriting.
I'm gonna give you a moment
to reconsider that answer.
Because if you are, for
some reason, mistaken,
we will find out, and that
will not be good for you.
Or Dr. House.
I am sure. Absolutely.
All right.
I guess that's it, then.
Thank you for your help.
Okay, no problem.