Previously on
The Good Doctor...
Nira is half-blind
because of you.
You think I control Salen?
How about taking a stand?
You could've worked with me
to make things right.
Instead, you had to
burn the building down.
She lit the match.
If you're gonna
go through with this deal,
you're gonna
have to destroy me.
♪♪
Good luck.
'Cause now this is all
your problem.
♪♪
♪ I woke up
to the morning sky first
♪ Baby blue
Just like we rehearsed
♪ When I get up
off this ground
♪ I shake leaves back down to
the brown, brown, brown, brown
♪ Till I'm clean
♪♪
♪ Then I walk where
I'd be shaded by the trees
♪ By a meadow of green
♪ For about a mile
♪ I'm headed
to town, town, town in style
♪♪
♪ With all my favorite colors
Yes, sir
♪ All my favorite colors
Right on
♪ My sisters and my brothers
♪ See 'em like no other
♪ All my favorite colors ♪
♪♪
Your
"Unsave-the-date" card.
You're...uninviting us
to your wedding?
We decided
there will be no wedding
for the
foreseeable future.
We've canceled
everything.
The way
you're smiling,
I feel like I should be
congratulating you.
We're happy. We just want
to enjoy being happy.
We've had enough stress
in our lives.
We're living
in the moment.
Mm-hmm.
Good morning, everyone.
Thanks for coming.
As the new President,
I'd like to acknowledge
we've been through
a challenging time,
but St. Bon's has never
been about a logo
or a fancy
coffee selection.
We've always been about
the people in this room
and how we can help the people
who come through these doors.
So we're gonna get
back to what we've
always done the best,
and that's
putting patients first.
You know what a world-class
surgical center needs?
It needs a world-class
Chief of Surgery.
And that's why
I am reinstating
Dr. Audrey Lim.
♪♪
I'll also be hiring
three new oncology nurses,
so if you know
some good people,
let me know, okay?
You okay
with all this?
No more board meetings.
Are you kidding?
Plus, I get a lot more time
with the clinic.
Doctors Reznick,
Glassman, can I have
a word with you two?
We lost
a clinic contract.
Our biggest.
Thanks to your confession
of borderline malpractice
to the person who runs
their health plan.
Nira had the right
to know the truth.
You're lucky it was
an experimental procedure.
She's not pursuing
a lawsuit.
But I'm closing
the clinic.
I'm sorry.
I just can't
justify the expense
of keeping it open.
People need a way
to get healthcare
they otherwise
can't afford.
How's this
for justification...
We can,
and so we should.
Exactly.
I've arranged
for Bay Area Medical
to take over their care.
Can I talk to you
for one second?
If I can just
take a look at the budget,
I can figure out a way
to keep this clinic open.
I'm afraid you're gonna be
busy in the O.R.
Aaron, you're
a gifted surgeon.
This hospital
needs those skills.
Wow. Okay.
Uh, let's talk trade.
I'll give you
20 hours a week,
and we figure out a way
to keep this clinic open.
So you can keep freezing
plantar warts?
See? Someone must need
a really good neurosurgeon.
♪♪
Family of three
in a head-on collision.
Another ambulance
is behind us
with the occupant
of the other vehicle.
Park, you're with me.
Bryan Liu.
40 years old.
Hypotensive in the field.
GCS ten.
Abdominal bruising,
some distention,
internal bleeding.
How's that leg look?
♪♪
We might be able
to save his arm.
I need a vascular clamp.
Elaine hit her head
on the dash.
GCS 15.
Vomited twice.
Elaine, I'm Dr. Glassman.
How bad
was your headache?
Really bad.
Is my daughter okay?
She was wearing her seatbelt.
She has pain and bruising
in her chest.
I'm right here, honey.
Spleen's ruptured.
He's got about two liters
of blood in his abdomen.
What's going on
with my dad?
Please don't talk.
Those doctors
are taking care of him.
She has decreased
left-sided breath sounds.
We need
to insert a chest tube.
W-Why?
What's wrong?
A broken rib
punctured her lung.
♪♪
Left pupil's dilated.
Subdural?
Elaine, you may
have some bleeding
around your brain.
We're gonna have to
take you to the O.R.
Mommy?
I-I'm okay, sweetie.
We're all gonna be
just fine.
You just need to...
Oh!
His BP's tanking.
We have to get him
to the O.R. now.
♪♪
Mommy.
Daddy.
♪♪
Splenic hilum
is clamped.
His pressure's holding.
Below-knee
amputation is complete.
The stump is covered
and healthy.
Start working on
his arm.
I'm not
getting any circulation
to his hand.
We could use
Andrews' vascular
reconstruction skills.
Try reducing the fracture
to restore blood flow.
It's not helping.
I've got too much
bleeding to help.
Try fasciotomies
to relieve pressure.
There's too much
upstream damage.
Page Andrews.
She has an SSS tear.
We'll have to
open up her skull
to find a fix,
which I do not
want to do.
I can stop the leak
with a dural flap,
wait till
the swelling goes down,
find a better fix.
Pressure's still dropping.
I got a tight seal.
No leaks.
Maybe we're looking
in the wrong place.
I hear an
early-diastolic murmur.
It's her heart.
Get me an echo.
Contact social work.
Make sure the daughter's
not alone today.
She may be losing
both her parents.
How bad are they?
We won't know
anything for sure
until your parents
get out of surgery.
The chest tube
was successful.
That doctor said my mom
was bleeding in her brain.
Did he stop it?
They're trying.
She has one of the best
neurosurgeons in the state.
Did they fix
my dad's leg?
I don't know yet.
And I understand how scary
and confusing it must be
not to have
all the answers.
I just want to know
what's happening.
Your dad's leg
is likely unsalvageable.
He also had
a severe splenic injury
that caused catastrophic
internal bleeding
and hypovolemic shock.
Removing his spleen
may stop the bleeding,
but if not, they may need
to remove his kidney, as well.
He may also lose
his lower arm.
Dr. Murphy, maybe Isla and I
should chat alone
for a few minutes.
It's okay. You can stay.
You can go.
Thank you
for talking to me.
Are you sure?
Okay.
I'll check in later.
You can always
have a nurse page me.
Could my parents...die?
It is too soon to say
if either of them
will survive their injuries.
♪♪
I'll round
on Asher's patients,
and the night nurse
said Mr. Jones
is ready for discharge.
Um, my bowel obstruction
in 4C, did he pass gas?
Why do you think the nurses
want him discharged?
I'm hungry.
The nurse gave me a sandwich,
but it has pickles.
They're gross.
They are.
I'd like
something else, please.
I gotta discharge
your windbag in 4C.
Nurse.
Will you find
this patient
something to eat
without pickles?
Sure.
She isn't just hungry.
She's scared.
She wants
to spend time with you
so she doesn't feel
all alone.
Doctors need to maintain
professional boundaries.
Convenient,
since you don't want
to get close to patients.
I think it's
the most rewarding
part of our job.
Oh, no.
Minimally invasive
microvascular surgery
is the most rewarding part.
I already treated
her pneumothorax.
She's fine.
♪♪
Subclavian artery's
also damaged.
Yeah,
brachial plexus nerves, too.
Thought you'd be
a little more excited
about being Chief again.
Hard to get too jubilant
about being given a job
I never should have lost
in the first place.
One you were happy
to step into.
BP's stabilizing.
This arm's a mess.
There's no
distal blood supply,
nerves shot,
hand showing signs
of ischemia.
I think
I can save it.
I need
to open up his chest,
get access to proximal vessel
for graft bypass.
That's a big,
lengthy surgery
with a catastrophic
risk of bleeding.
Yeah, which may
save his arm.
He's already lost
too much blood
from his other injuries.
We have to amputate.
Sorry to interrupt.
Dr. Lim, there's major damage
to Elaine's heart valve.
We need
a trauma surgeon.
Go. Dr. Park
can close up
the abdomen.
Put a wound vac
on the arm stump
and run antibiotics
post-op.
♪♪
What are you doing?
Practicing mindfulness.
I...don't know
what that means.
It helps you let go,
not be self-obsessed,
stressed out,
utterly career-driven.
I still don't understand.
You're being mindful
right now.
By letting go
of your wedding plan.
Being "in the moment"
with Lea.
Oh.
N-No, Lea and I are still
getting married.
We're only
"enjoying the moment" for now.
Good for you.
I suck
at "the moment."
I like making a plan,
having a plan...
Following a plan.
Do you want my apple?
You're acting
very strangely.
Isla's hemoglobin
dropped to nine,
and there's blood
in her chest tube.
Oh. That's not good.
We'll take a few
pictures to find out
where the problem is.
Won't hurt at all.
Then you can
stop the bleeding?
Probably.
But it will likely
require something
that does hurt.
You need to remove that
before the M.R. Angiogram.
No. I can't.
It's a gum wrapper.
My dad gave it to me.
I wanted my birthstone,
sapphire.
But we couldn't afford it.
So my dad made me this.
He called it
a placeholder.
That's really sweet.
An MRI
is a powerful magnet.
It will destroy
your gum-wrapper ring,
and it could
burn your finger.
♪♪
Promise you won't
lose it?
I promise.
♪♪
Okay.
She damaged
her aortic valve.
We'll need
to open her up.
CP bypass is generally
not a good chaser
to a brain bleed.
She needs
a functional valve.
You'll need
to figure out a way
to give her one
without turning her
into a vegetable.
I brought you here
for your expertise.
Or would you rather I try
to figure it out for you?
Throwing up your hands
and making someone else
solve the problem
is not leadership.
I'm gonna guess
we're not talking
about a heart valve.
When Ethicure took over,
you just walked out,
headed for Paradise.
I know you were
going through
a rough patch,
but we were going
through it here, too.
And you didn't bother
to step up
until it became
a problem for Shaun.
You want me to apologize
for my commitment to Shaun?
That's not gonna happen.
I would never
ask you to do that.
I just didn't realize
how little the rest of us
matter to you.
♪♪
I can insert an aortic pump
to support her heart.
That should buy me
some time to fix her valve.
♪♪
The chest trauma
damaged a branch
of her pulmonary artery.
The bleeding has stopped,
but her artery could
re-bleed at any time.
How do we get to it?
It's surrounded
by vital organs.
Thoracotomy, dissect from
proximal to distal hilum,
isolate the vessel,
and reconstruct the vessel.
That's a big surgery
for a small injury.
It's almost as risky
as a re-rupture.
We need a safer plan.
♪♪
I don't have one.
I need time
to figure it out.
I'll need to monitor her
around the clock
in case she bleeds again.
Looks like Isla's
getting some QT
with Dr. Murphy
after all.
♪♪
Are we done?
I'm bored.
♪♪
Who's your friend?
She's not my friend.
She's my patient.
Isla Liu,
10-year-old female
with a pseudo-aneurysm
of a segmental branch
of the left
pulmonary artery.
I need to monitor her
closely
to make sure she
does not bleed out.
This is my fiancee, Lea.
She's Head of
the I.T. Department.
I need you
to talk to her
while I figure out
how to fix her.
She talks a lot.
I do.
Where's your ring?
He said you were his fiancee.
I proposed to him,
and it was
a spur of the moment
kinda thing, so no ring.
Very modern.
Mm.
I asked out my last boyfriend,
but it didn't work out.
When's your wedding?
We don't have a date.
Did you pick a cake?
My aunt had red velvet.
It was really good.
And her gown was super long.
They call it a train.
Do you have
one of those?
Trains can lead to tripping
and orthopedic injuries.
I don't want a dress
with a train.
You have no cake, no ring,
no dress, and no date?
We have a cake.
Then how are you
his fiancee?
Isn't it just, like,
boyfriend and girlfriend?
♪♪
What's I.T.?
Well, I.T. stands for
"information technology,"
so I work with
a lot of computers.
Increase the flow to P-eight
and get a CT of her heart.
We need exact
valve measurements.
Got some good news.
I restored blood flow
to Bryan's arm.
You were supposed
to amputate.
I didn't open his chest.
I rebuilt his vessels
from under the clavicle.
Still got
a large tissue defect,
but I can cover that
with a tissue flap.
I know a great neurosurgeon
for the nerve repairs.
More surgery?
He could bleed again.
I can handle that.
And what about
the potential
for post-transfusion
clotting issues?
Removing his arm
is the only way
to guarantee
we save his life.
Losing two limbs
would be devastating.
It's such a high cost to avoid
a relatively small risk.
But it's not small
to that little girl,
whom you could orphan
to serve your own ego.
Pretty harsh assessment,
especially considering
I just rescued you
and our colleagues
from your suicide mission.
You want a medal for finding
your moral compass
at the last
possible moment?
I was there
when it counted.
♪♪
You did her bidding,
even after the baby died,
and then leveraged
the situation
so you came out in charge.
I am in charge.
I'm saving
this man's arm.
♪♪
Hmm.
Are you stealing
from children now?
This stuff's been in here
since my first year
of residency.
Aren't you supposed
to be in peer review?
I'm tied up
on this trauma case.
I thought you might want
to sit in on it for me.
Dr. Farber's leading it.
Chair of the Executive Ops
Committee.
If you want to run
a hospital one day...
Gotta go.
But thanks for
thinking of me.
How can I resect
a pseudo-aneurysm
without cutting off blood flow
to the upper lobe?
What about
arterial bypass?
Isla's 10 years old.
The bypassed artery
wouldn't grow with her lungs.
Do you think Lea and I
are just boyfriend
and girlfriend?
No?
Me neither.
But if we're not
planning a wedding,
then what are we doing?
Are we
moving backwards?
Shaun, a wedding
is just a symbol.
A very nice,
very expensive one,
but real stability
comes from committing
to each other every day.
What should I do?
Uh, you and Lea will need
to figure that out.
The older I get,
the less everyone
seems to know.
That's probably true.
Oh, have you considered
an endovascular embolization
for Isla's pseudo-aneurysm?
Your medical advice
is much better
than your personal advice.
♪♪
Self-retaining retractor.
Stay out of
my nerve field,
please.
I need
better vessel exposure.
This muscle needs a nerve.
I feel bad about
closing the clinic,
but we can't help anyone
if we can't keep
the lights on.
It's not about
helping anyone.
It's about making sure
you can put your feet up
on the biggest desk
in the building.
You look down on me
'cause I want the big job,
but it was your
apathy towards it
that made us vulnerable
to Ethicure
in the first place.
Nerves are attached.
Reconstructed vessel's
blown.
You want me to...
No, I got it.
♪♪
The embolization
will be short.
It should prevent further
bleeding in your chest.
Dr. Park thinks
you're wrong.
Lea is still my fiancee
and a wedding
is just a symbol.
Symbols are
a super big deal.
They remind us
what's important.
That's what my mom said
when I wanted
to return
my confirmation cross
and use the money
to get my ears pierced.
Lie down.
I need to inject
the anesthetic.
I hate needles.
I still make my mom
hold my hand
when I get shots.
You can squeeze my hand
as hard as you want.
I practiced when Lea
was pregnant.
You two have a baby?
♪♪
No.
Why not?
There was a clot
in the umbilical cord.
The baby died.
♪♪
I'm injecting
the anesthetic.
♪♪
You can let go
of my hand now.
That hardly hurt
at all.
You're very good
at your job.
♪♪
Isla, the doctors are still
taking care of your mom,
but your dad's
out of surgery.
He lost his leg,
but he's gonna
be okay.
You can see him as soon
as you're done.
♪♪
I don't want
to see him.
♪♪
Fluid's backed up
in Elaine's brain.
75 mannitol.
Hopefully, that'll
take the pressure off.
Elaine needs a shunt.
Can her heart take it?
Not with just a pump
keeping her alive,
but she's got
another problem.
She's got a big tear
in her trachea
and she could lose
her airway any minute.
Know of any experts
in tracheal reconstruction?
Time to call
the President.
♪♪
This is Donald Adler.
He's had chest pain
for the past few weeks.
I'm fine.
My son's taking me
to the doctor.
The one who's postponed
three times already?
I tried to contact his GP.
No luck.
We need to rule out
coronary artery disease.
Is he your patient?
She's my chess partner
at the home.
I beat her
three times in a row.
Impressive.
She always kicks my ass.
He's much better
than you are.
How long
is this gonna take?
We're having
arts and crafts
tonight.
She's teaching us
how to decoupage.
Let's, uh,
get you a cardiac CT.
Help Mr. Adler
into a gown.
♪♪
You look a lot like
my girlfriend,
but she doesn't
decoupage.
She mocks people
who decoupage.
Well, she sounds like
a real piece of work.
♪♪
Hey. I got this for Isla.
How is she?
Hello.
I'm waiting on labs to see
if the embolization
repaired the artery
in her chest.
I meant emotionally.
She's refusing
to see her father.
We don't know why.
Well, shouldn't
you find out?
I am waiting on labs.
Jordan is talking to her.
I think we should
pick a date
for when we're going
to start planning
our wedding again.
June 8th?
What happened to
enjoying the moment?
I'm not enjoying it.
Okay.
We had a plan.
Now, we don't have a plan,
and you're okay with that,
but I'm not.
We will figure it out,
Shaunie.
How?
I don't know yet.
No one has
good advice anymore.
Isla's not talking to me.
We should page
the social worker.
She's not going to open up
to the social worker, Shaun.
♪♪
Isla trusts you.
I can use
a transcervical approach
to reconstruct
the airway.
If you use a retractor
in her neck,
I'll lose drainage
from her brain.
I need to start her
on heparin
so I can get working
on her heart.
You can't use heparin
until I've placed the shunt.
Not while
I'm working on her neck.
One wrong move,
she'll need
a lifelong trach.
If she bleeds again
from her sagittal sinus,
she'll be brain dead.
If she has
catastrophic heart failure,
she'll be dead-dead.
Okay.
Airway's priority one.
Once it's secure,
you can fix the valve.
You're overruling
my judgment again?
Overruling? We...
Elaine's pump failed.
She's in total heart failure.
I'm prepping an O.R.
♪♪
Mm.
That is a very accurate
drawing of a horse.
It's my dog, Abigail.
Oh.
She must
look like a horse.
Is my dad
in a lot of pain?
No.
He is on
very strong narcotics.
Why don't you
want to see him?
His residual limb
is heavily bandaged,
so you won't be able
to see any...
Blood or tissue
or bones.
I'm not afraid of that.
Okay.
I was kicking
the back of the seat.
The driver's seat,
which my dad hates.
He missed my choir concert,
which made me mad,
so I kicked his seat.
And he told me to stop,
but I kept kicking
and kicking,
and then he turned around,
told me to cut it out,
and then I heard
Mom scream,
and there were sirens,
and then we were here.
He's going to hate me
because I'm selfish and stupid
and it was all my fault.
It was...
My fault
my brother Steve died.
♪♪
But it was
Steve's fault, too.
It was his idea to hide
on the roof of the train.
♪♪
He fell.
He broke his neck.
♪♪
Your dad took his eyes
off the road,
and a car ran a red light
and the airbags didn't deploy.
Those things
are not your fault.
And even if it were...
Your parents would
probably still love you,
because of your shared
experience in combination
with the parental
bonding hormone oxytocin.
Although, in my case,
it wasn't enough.
My parents
didn't like me.
I'm sorry
about your brother.
And your parents.
And your baby.
You've had
a lot of bad things
happen to you.
♪♪
I've had
a lot of good things
happen, too.
♪♪
Okay.
I want to go see my dad.
Aah.
Isla?
♪♪
I need a rapid response team,
stat.
She's bleeding
in her chest!
♪♪
BP is 65 over palp.
Give another
unit of blood.
We have to
open her up, Shaun.
We could
injure her bronchi
and cause
chronic respiratory failure
or rupture her
pulmonary artery.
She could bleed out.
If we don't operate now,
she's gonna die.
Prep an O.R.
for stat thoracotomy,
and page Dr. Lim.
♪♪
The old fart
needs angioplasty and a stent.
You may have just saved
this guy's life.
I'm gonna be late
for arts and crafts.
Does this have anything
to do with Nira?
Hey, you made one bad call.
You're not a bad person.
Uh, that is not what
you said last week.
I may have overreacted.
I've woken up
every morning
my whole life
wanting to conquer the world,
and then I hurt someone,
and I almost lost...
I almost lost everything.
So now,
I am going to cultivate
virtuous intentions
and...generally
not be so awful.
If you want to meditate
and volunteer
and save random old guys,
go ahead.
But don't become
a totally different person.
I would miss you.
The world needs people
who wake up every morning
wanting to conquer it.
Those kinds of people
land on the moon
and cure cancer and...
Drag grumpy, old men
into the E.R.
And trample innocent souls
along the way.
Yeah, don't do that part.
I'll be around
to remind you.
♪♪
I'll prep a suite
for Old Fart.
♪♪
Take much longer and she'll
have a cardiac arrest.
Trach is secure.
Go ahead.
Advancing the catheter
to the ascending aorta.
Bring down her CO2.
Retract the neck muscles
so there's...
Yeah, no, I got it.
The death of that baby
kept me up at night.
It still does.
I should have
taken a stand then,
but Salen told me
it kept her up at night, too.
She promised
to make changes
to ensure that
it never would
happen again,
and I believed her
because I cared for her.
A lot.
But my eyes were closed,
and I should have
stepped up sooner.
Because this place
is my home,
and you pains-in-the-ass
are my family.
Together, we can fix
this woman's heart,
her brain, and neck.
We can do great things
for all our patients...
If we don't
kill each other first.
♪♪
Shunt's through.
You can go ahead
with the trach repair.
She's crashing.
♪♪
Dr. Cain will be here
in 20 minutes.
We don't have
20 minutes.
♪♪
I have to
open her chest now.
Get an attending
out of surgery.
♪♪
She has
critical bradycardia,
but the valve
is well-positioned.
Drain two cc's of CSF
every minute.
That should buy me
ten minutes.
I'll remove
the delivery valve.
I'll put in
a temporary pacer.
But I still don't know
what's tanking her heart rate.
I do.
The tracheal injury
compressed her carotid.
It's lowering
her heart rate.
Try removing
the retractor.
Push atropine.
♪♪
No good.
Heart rate's in the 30s.
She's gonna arrest.
Gonna try to decompress
the carotid bulb.
Shaun needs one of you
in O.R. three.
Isla's
pulmonary vessel ruptured.
He's cracking her chest.
♪♪
I need ten minutes.
Tell Shaun to use every
bit of his Shaun-ness
to keep her alive
till I get there.
♪♪
Andrews can be here
in ten minutes.
I've located
the bleeding vessel.
♪♪
If I clamp too close
to the pulmonary artery,
I'll extend the injury
and she will bleed out.
If I get too close
to the hilum,
I could cause
a pulmonary infarct.
She'd need a ventilator
for the rest of her life.
I need Andrews' help.
She's going into shock.
You can do this, Shaun.
♪♪
I need Metz, stay sutures,
and a needle driver.
♪♪
BP's climbing.
Well done, Dr. Murphy.
Want me to take over?
Yes.
♪♪
We're all going to be okay.
Except for
the severe chest pain
you will both experience
for several weeks.
And there is a 1% chance of
a recurrent pseudo-aneurysm.
But yes, you will
most likely be okay.
Thank you, Dr. Murphy.
We'll give you all
some time.
I didn't lose it.
♪♪
Thank you, Dr. Murphy.
Personal connections
aren't so bad, are they?
Mm. No.
They are not so bad.
But I do not
want to do it again.
I have to go home.
♪♪
I think I can
save the clinic.
Dr. Reznick,
it's been a long day.
I talk fast.
Old people.
They need care the most
and they have
the least access.
Telemedicine services
for nursing homes.
I just brought in a patient
who needed a $100,000 angio,
entirely paid for
by Medicare.
That alone would
cover the cost
of three uninsured
clinic patients.
It's a good idea, but ideas
aren't your problem.
I know.
I made a mistake...
And followed it up
with another.
You've bungled
your opportunity
from every direction.
I know.
Which is why
Dr. Glassman should
be in charge of the clinic.
I'm not ready,
but I will be.
Someday.
And you're gonna need
people like me
if you're gonna
save this place.
And you know I'm right,
because you wake up
every morning
wanting to
conquer the world, too.
♪♪
♪ Ooh
♪ Ooh ooh ooh ooh
♪ I'm torn between the past
that I wanna keep...
What is all of this?
I got you something.
♪♪
♪ Try to hold myself together
while I risk it all...
I made it myself.
♪ And I'm holding onto you
Waiting for the fall
♪ I want you by my side
along the way...
Lea Dilallo...
♪♪
...will you
make a bond
of shared experience
and oxytocin...
...and love with me
for the rest of our lives?
Of course.
♪ Ooh ooh ooh ooh
♪ They say the feeling's
just a feeling
and you won't survive
♪ And love is just a light
that will fade in time...
It's a placeholder.
It's perfect.
♪ Ooh
♪ Ooh ooh ooh ooh
♪ You will always have
this part of me
♪ Ooh
♪ Ooh ooh ooh ooh
♪ You will always have
this part of me ♪
♪♪
I left a bottle of Scotch
around here somewhere
after the first time
you stole my job.
Did you drink
all my fizzy water?
There's a cucumber one
left in the back.
They're disgusting.
It's refreshing
and delicious.
Agree to disagree.
Yep.
Found it.
♪♪
Why not?