♪♪
You have a couch, right?
Mm-hmm.
Thank you.
Hey, good morning.
♪♪
Salen didn't tell you?
She made me
Chief of Surgery.
♪♪
Dr. Park, this is Joe.
He was helping his son, Cody,
into his wheelchair
when they had a spill.
I'm too big for Dad.
No, you're not, buddy.
Cody has Kabuki Syndrome.
You got banged up,
too, huh?
I-I'm okay.
Just help Dad.
You know about Kabuki?
Genetic disorder characterized
by low muscle tone,
heart defects,
intellectual impairment...
And in Cody's case,
chronic hypoglycemia.
And Joe has a group three
clavicle fracture
and shoulder dislocation.
Ah, it looks worse
than it feels.
You're not in pain?
Is that a bad thing?
Might be a sign
of nerve damage.
We'll use some plate
and screws
to stabilize
your collarbone.
While we're in there,
we'll figure out why
you're not hurting.
Are you gonna be okay?
Yeah. I'll be
right back, Code.
Last few years,
it's just been the two of us.
But we're a team.
Best team ever.
♪♪
Bye, Dad.
See you in a bit, buddy.
Sorry if
I'm a bit nervous.
I'm a huge fan.
So I still have one?
I was 16 when I first saw
the Dunn Sisters live,
and I saw your sister's tour
last year at the Rose Bowl.
Then you've seen her
more than I have.
She's made it even without
my accompaniment.
Hey.
Your bloodwork confirms
good compatibility
with the donor tissue,
so, Nelly,
if you're up for it...
I have been
for five years.
All right.
Let's begin prep
on all asp...
Oh. There's a thrill
in her left carotid.
Could be
arterial obstruction.
Without an
adequate blood supply
to the donor trachea,
we can't do the surgery.
It's a concern,
but not sure it's a problem.
Let's do a CTA.
You'll be fine.
♪♪
Uh, don't, uh...
Don't bother.
I'm fired?
No.
But I expect
you'll be moving on.
Dr. Novick
at San Jose General
is looking for
a new Head of Trauma.
It'll be more money
and a chance
for a fresh start.
♪♪
He's expecting your call.
That's one way
to deal with dissent.
And by dissent,
I mean attempting
to hold you accountable
for your negligence.
I'm sorry you couldn't get
on board with my approach.
We could have crushed it.
I'll text you his number.
♪♪
Giants fan?
Churros.
Most people call 'em
the San Jose Giants,
but fans call them
the Churros.
How many stitches
am I gonna get?
Looks like six.
You've had them before,
though, right?
Yep, when I was a baby
and they fixed my heart.
How many is
my dad gonna need?
A few more than six.
But we've got our two
best doctors working on him.
You know, besides me.
How long is Dad's surgery
gonna take?
He should be out
in about two hours.
He was a high school principal
in charge of 844 kids.
Mm, very cool.
But he had to quit
to look after me.
Will he still be able
to lift me?
Once his arm's all better?
Absolutely.
You two will be out there
catching foul balls
before you know it.
You promise?
Mm-hmm.
All done.
♪♪
What does Lea like
for breakfast?
Huevos Rancheros
con salsa verde.
Muy bien,
but I'm asking
because she's sleeping
on my couch.
Nelly's internal carotids
look good.
Hmm, yes. They do look
better than they felt.
Check the external
carotids.
So you're not
getting married?
Yes.
Because of something she said
over two years ago?
Shaun, stop being
a relationship archeologist.
You're digging up stuff
that isn't relevant.
Archeologists dig up stuff
that is very relevant.
And Lea
still believes it.
She changed
my client satisfa...
She apologized, Shaun.
You're attributing
an expired motive
to her current actions.
How do I know
it's expired?
Because you trust her,
and you love her
for who she is,
a flawed, messy,
and totally wonderful
human being.
♪♪
Hmm, the left external carotid
is stenotic.
I was right.
We can't do the surgery.
You have to do
the surgery.
Poor flow from the carotid
could lead to graft necrosis,
sepsis, and possible death.
It's been a minute.
You look awful.
You look fake.
Because of
the blood flow issues,
the transplant will be riskier
than we thought,
but I don't believe
prohibitively so.
It's still a viable option
if you feel
it's worth the risks.
It isn't, okay?
Your electrolarynx
works fine,
and a normal voice
is not worth dying for.
You don't sing,
do you?
N-No, but even if
the transplant is successful,
your new voice
may be very different
from your original
singing voice.
I know.
I just want a voice.
People don't listen
to robots.
Nelly, we're talking
about your life.
See?
You didn't hear me.
I want the surgery.
Okay.
♪♪
Nerve signaling
is disrupted.
That's why Joe
wasn't feeling any pain.
Evaluating
the brachial plexus.
Just a heads-up,
you may be getting a call
for a reference.
You're leaving St. Bon's?
More like fleeing
Salen Morrison.
Demoting you
is an insult to all of us.
I found the culprit.
Bone splinter
compressing the plexus.
Well, thanks for that.
I'm sure Andrews
will do a fine job.
If he's not Salen's puppet.
Good news is,
no nerve laceration.
I have an interview to run
trauma over at SJ General.
That was fast.
They need any surgical
residents?
Or anesthesiologists?
Nerve signaling
isn't improving.
It's an ossified ligament
compressing the cervical cord.
His arm's
permanently paralyzed.
♪♪
The ossified ligament has
probably developed over years.
It's why you weren't
feeling any pain.
Your fall drove it
into your cervical cord.
Can't you remove it?
It's adhered to the dura
encasing your spinal cord.
The surgery to remove it
could leave you paralyzed
in multiple limbs.
♪♪
I can't take care of Cody
with one arm.
You know, if I don't have
this surgery,
there's a 100% chance
that my son will be
institutionalized.
I'm sorry.
But I strongly recommend
against it.
♪♪
I agree with Dr. Park.
But only you know
what's best for your family.
♪♪
I need to do this.
We're starting you
on immunosuppressive therapy.
You may feel
some headaches
or nausea.
Dr. Allen is
a bit of a fangirl.
Hey, backstage passes
if you can talk some sense
into my sister.
Dr. Andrews is the best.
If he says
he can make it work,
it'll work.
Dr. Murphy
doesn't think so.
Dr. Andrews is
the Chief of Surgery.
I'm your big sister.
If I had listened to you,
I would have ended
my career in fishnets.
If you'd listened to me,
you'd still have a career.
Yes.
I should have been
wearing my seatbelt,
especially with
you driving.
♪♪
I demonstrated
lousy judgment.
It's kind of like
this whole transplant thing.
Ooh, clever new spin.
If only your songs
were that smart.
♪♪
Okay.
You've been
at St. Bonaventure
for 17 years,
went from resident
to Chief.
Makes for
a pretty boring resume.
It shows dedication
and a loyal following.
But it does beg
the question,
why now?
Um...
St. Bon's
has changed a lot.
Well, Salen and Ethicure
will do that.
But still, man,
it's tough to leave home.
Yeah.
St. Bon's made me
the doctor I am, but...
I don't know
if it's home anymore.
Hmm.
Well, it's their loss.
You'd be overseeing
the busiest Level 1
trauma center
in the Bay Area.
The wall is too stiff.
Too stiff.
I can't maintain
lumen patency.
And that's why
we're practicing.
You practice because
something is difficult,
not because
it's impossible.
Ugh, okay, obstruct it again
for the eighth time.
We should not attempt this.
This is an innovative
surgery, Shaun.
The exact kind of case
that usually makes you
very excited.
Instead, it's made you
very...contrary.
That might be because
there's a certain someone
crashing on my couch.
Hmm.
Oh, she means Lea.
Oh, I know.
This is not
about Lea, okay?
This is about
a bad surgery.
It's a risky surgery,
Shaun,
but one that can
drastically improve
the quality
of this young woman's life,
and not just physically,
but emotionally
and psychologically.
We need to be aware
of how our own
personal dynamics
might impact
our decisions.
Oh, you're talking
about me and Lea.
Again.
Yes, I am.
You and Salen are dating.
Is that dynamic impacting
your decision to...
Why did you
just kick me?
I'm very aware
of my "dynamic,"
and, no, it's not affecting
my medical decisions.
Ninth time's the charm.
It's perfusing.
♪♪
This is possible,
and it's going to work.
Looking good.
What's his name?
Sebastian.
Ooh.
First time
I swiped right in...
Three months.
Mm.
Looks like you got
your night planned.
Yeah, I thought...
We could talk.
Tomorrow.
My problems are not
going anywhere.
♪♪
Give me a beer.
No. Go.
I-I'll be fine.
Mm-mmm, I already broke
Sebastian's heart.
Beer.
♪♪
Mm-hmm.
I never did like
the big office.
Always made me feel guilty
for not reading enough books.
A Dr. Novick called me
from San Jose General
asking me
if he could poach you.
Six months ago,
I would have been pissed.
this was a great
place to work.
Yeah, well,
we had a good run.
Must be hard not to say
"I told you so."
Excruciating.
You did
what you had to do.
Now you gotta go.
Should I?
Get out while you can.
♪♪
And let Salen ruin
this place?
This is my home.
I'm gonna fight for it.
♪♪
Hey.
Lexi?
You want to
see your sister?
Yes.
I don't know.
You... You should see her.
It may be your last chance.
I thought I'd lost her
in the car accident.
Prayed to just
keep her alive,
but I really did lose her
that night.
She was pissed that
I'd go on without her,
but I-I had to.
It was my life.
I'm glad you did.
Without her music,
it's not the same.
She's the genius,
and without her...
You miss her.
♪♪
What really hurts
is that she thinks
this is what I've always
wanted, to be the star.
Did she tell you that?
She doesn't have to.
♪♪
You should tell her
how you feel
and trust her to tell you
the truth about how she feels.
Nelly's crashing.
♪♪
We need epi
and a central line, STAT.
She's having a reaction to
the immunosuppressive therapy.
We have to call off
the transplant.
No, we don't.
We find a fix
to this problem,
and if she still wants
the surgery, we'll do it.
♪♪
Dr. Andrews still wants
to do the trachea transplant,
but I think
that's a very bad idea,
so I'd rather not help him
figure out how to do it.
Dr. Andrews thinks
I only feel that way
because I am upset
about Lea.
Well, you are upset.
Emotions have a way of leaking
everywhere sometimes.
Okay, how do I know
if that's happening?
I don't know, Shaun.
You just have to focus on,
you know, work, I guess.
Look,
Dr. Andrews is smart,
he's experienced,
the Chief of the Department.
He also happens
to be your boss.
You're just a resident,
so guess what.
Tell him what you think
and, bang, boss wins.
Okay.
Okay, I will help him.
But our patient
will probably die.
♪♪
Pedicle screws.
I'm guessing
you aced the interview?
Yes.
And turned the job down.
Cervicothoracic rod.
Remember
The Magnificent Seven?
Which version?
The metaphor works
for either one,
or Seven Samurai.
Our village is under siege,
and I've decided
to recruit a ragtag group
of freedom fighters
willing to stand up
to the bad guy.
I'm in.
If she finds out,
she will slaughter us.
I'm in.
♪♪
I have four months left
of my residency.
I get it.
I've been keeping
my head down.
That's smart.
That's what
I told myself.
Then she killed a baby.
I'm in.
Yippee-ki-yay.
Ossified ligament
is isolated.
Elevating.
It's eroded through
the dura.
Evoked potentials
are dropping.
Yeah, it's fused to
the spinal cord itself.
♪♪
Dad? Dad?
Cody, what's up?
Dad shoulda been done
with his surgery by now.
I said his doctors
are good, not fast.
They're major slowpokes.
I need to see Dad.
Hey, Cody,
everything is okay.
I'm a doctor.
I know all about this stuff.
That's what they said!
Who?
The doctors!
When Mom died!
You have to keep calm,
Cody.
Just nice,
gentle breaths.
Now?
Please?
Now!
Please!
I need oxygen
and a crash cart!
♪♪
I can't feel my legs.
The ligament was adhered
to your spinal cord.
There was no way
to decompress it
without damage.
Am I a paraplegic?
♪♪
Yes.
There's nothing else?
Not at this time, Joe.
Where's Cody?
In the ICU.
He had a panic attack
that led to a ruptured
aortic aneurysm
at the site of his childhood
heart surgery.
He's recovering now.
♪♪
You took a big, brave risk
for your family.
Can I see my son now?
♪♪
Monoclonal antibodies
could block cytokine signals.
Nelly's reaction to
the immunosuppressants
suggests she'll have
an even worse reaction
to the antibodies.
What if we tried a different
grafting technique like...
No, no, there is too much
scar tissue from the...
I...
Oh, relax.
I'm just an attending now.
With a favor to ask.
Park already asked me.
I really respect you,
but I worked my ass off
to get into
this residency program.
I can't risk it.
I know you think
things were better
before Salen took over.
Definitely.
So, you're in?
Definitely not.
I have too many emotions, and
they may already be leaking.
I can't even tell.
Oh. Oh.
Bone marrow.
♪♪
Oh, that was odd.
I'm pretty sure
she just had an idea.
Hmm.
You may want to
go with her.
I have to go.
♪♪
By infusing the donor's bone
marrow stem cells into Nelly,
we trick her body
into thinking
the donor trachea
is hers.
Nice.
Although, it does increase
the risk of infection,
which I assume
you're about to point out.
No, not now
that you've said it.
I may be cranky about Lea,
but you are
definitely my boss,
and the boss wins.
Run it past Nelly.
Hey, Codeman.
Dad.
What... Why are you
in a wheelchair?
When they tried
to fix my arm,
it kind of messed up
my legs.
Now I get to ride around
in this hotrod all day.
How you feeling?
Tired.
When can we go home?
Real soon, buddy.
♪♪
But you're gonna
have a new home.
What? Where are we going?
I...
I can't come with you.
Y-You'd live
somewhere else?
With both of us
in the chairs,
it's just...
I don't know
how we'd manage.
There's a great place
in San Francisco.
Dad, no...
No, you'll be way closer
to the Giants.
And I'll come see you
and take you to a game.
But we're a team.
Always will be, buddy.
♪♪
Cody?
Are you seeing double?
It happens sometimes.
♪♪
We need to get him an MRI.
This could actually be
a good thing.
♪♪
Trick my body
any way you want.
You forget something?
I remembered something.
♪♪
Christmas, 1999.
We had two...
Big presents
under the tree.
You opened yours first.
♪ I never wanna
cause you harm...
A Baby Taylor
acoustic guitar.
I was hoping
for a keyboard.
But you got
a makeup set
because you were
the pretty one.
♪ Never brought it up
at all...
Because I was
the talentless one.
♪ Hear me calling...
I still f-feel like that.
You sell out arenas.
You write
like Joni Mitchell.
♪ Will you catch me?
♪ Will you hold out
your arms...
It would be nice
to do it together.
♪ Will you catch me?
♪ Do you think
that you're strong enough?
She misses her, too.
♪♪
♪ Do you think
that you're strong enough?
♪ Hold out your arms
and catch me ♪
♪♪
In fourth grade,
I always got picked on
and beat up
in the locker room
before gym class.
My gym teacher,
Mr. Carl,
tried to get
the other kids to stop.
That just made it worse.
So he told me if I stopped
coming to gym class,
he'd give me a B anyway.
So I stopped.
Okay...
I still got bullied,
just not
in the locker room.
All Mr. Carl did was make me
feel weak and useless.
The same way you felt
when I changed your scores.
♪♪
You are a flawed, messy,
and totally wonderful
human being.
You're definitely
good enough for me.
So are you, Shaun.
I promise.
I trust you.
Thank you.
But at some point,
you'll feel worried
and insecure,
or I'll feel messy,
and we will fight agai...
I don't want to.
Neither do I, Shaun.
Jordan's couch
is not comfortable.
But my point is...
Next time I feel insecure,
I'll ring the cowbell.
I think we're gonna need
more than the cowbell.
We're gonna need
a lot of hard work.
♪♪
I like hard work.
Me, too.
He was sweaty, pale,
had visual issues.
A pituitary tumor
may be causing
some of the symptoms
we thought were due to
his Kabuki Syndrome.
This is a fishing expedition.
You feel guilty.
You gave Joe permission
to risk it all,
and it didn't work.
Now you're desperate to do
anything to help this family.
And that's a problem?
Getting these
people's hopes up
for a miracle?
His pituitary's clear.
Let's look at
his other endocrine organs.
I heard you joined
Lim's posse.
I live by the credo,
people who kill babies
shouldn't run hospitals.
Adrenals are clear.
That's reductive.
There was a mistake,
a big one.
No one's denying that.
But systemic changes rarely
happen without a hitch,
and hopefully,
in the long run,
this will become
a better place.
Pancreas.
Right diagnosis,
wrong organ.
♪♪
Dissecting
the distal trachea.
There's extensive
lumen scarring.
But we can resect
all but the posterior third
of the cricoid cartilage
to address it.
That's right.
You seem more agreeable.
Lea and I made up.
That's great news.
Tonight's
Sebastian's lucky night.
Shall I place the new
endotracheal tube?
Yes, please, Dr. Murphy.
Okay.
♪♪
Let us know when you're
ready for O2 flow, Dr. Murphy.
Have you thought
about it?
Call Novick back.
Take the job.
Aaron, please,
we need you.
This hospital needs you.
♪♪
It's a small tumor
on his pancreas,
and it's been causing
his low blood sugar,
chronic fatigue,
and muscle weakness.
He might be able to walk
if we remove it.
His doctor said those symptoms
were tied to his Kabuki.
Well, sometimes, doctors
only see the disability.
Dr. Reznick
saw beyond that.
What if we don't
remove it?
Nothing new.
It's benign,
slow-growing.
♪♪
No.
I took the big swing.
I can't do that to Cody.
If this works,
you could make it
together, as a team.
♪♪
Almost there.
Release the clamps.
♪♪
Superior aspect
looks well-perfused.
Inferior's still
pretty dusky.
Bleed. TCT artery.
No.
Blood pressure's
crashing.
Push fluids, pressors.
Give me four units
of B-Neg, STAT.
We need
a substitute artery.
BP's 70 over 40.
She's bleeding out
from our suture sites.
40 over 28.
Epinephrine.
I told you
this was a bad surgery.
You didn't listen.
You convinced me
I was upset about Lea,
but you were wrong.
Sponges.
Innovation doesn't matter.
What Salen wants
doesn't matter.
Our patient is dying
because of you.
You were wrong.
Where's my B-Neg?
Crash cart!
♪♪
Come on. Come on.
Dr. Andrews.
♪♪
Bleeding's stopped.
The tracheal perfusion's
improved.
BP's 100 over 76.
She's...fine.
♪♪
What just happened?
I don't know.
Let's finish this up.
♪♪
Blood glucose is perfect.
And?
The surgery worked.
Can I walk now?
♪♪
Let's give it a shot.
Yeah.
I'll stand right here,
just in case.
♪♪
How do you feel,
Codeman?
Tall.
♪♪
Ahh, got it.
The best team ever.
Yeah.
Thank you.
♪♪
You had a bleed
that would have
killed most patients.
Turns out,
you have incredible
clotting factors.
Thank you for that.
I don't think
you're gonna be
needing that.
Try. It won't hurt it.
♪♪
My...
...name is Nelly.
♪♪
Holy crap.
Thank you.
Our pleasure.
♪♪
♪ Down here in the rain fields
♪ Outside of the glow...
So, you... You patched
things up with Lea.
And the surgery worked out.
That's... That's good.
It was a failure.
Well, the patient survived,
and... And she's talking now.
That's... That's...
That's a good thing.
She only lived because
of her clotting factors.
It had nothing
to do with us.
So, you caught a break.
That's okay.
♪ Where do they go?
No.
No, it isn't.
♪ Count me...
I knew it was
a bad surgery,
but everyone wanted me
to think I was wrong.
But you were wrong,
and s-so was Dr. Andrews.
And it is Salen's fault.
She's ruining everything.
Shaun, there is...
There are some things
that are o-out
of your control.
This isn't one of them.
♪♪
♪ Ooh...
I've gotten
five press inquiries
about Nelly dying.
You saved
the voice of the once
and future Queen of Pop.
I got lucky.
♪♪
"Being deeply learned
and skilled,
"being well-trained
and using well-spoken words,
"this is good luck."
Gautama Buddha.
A wise man making
a rationalization.
♪♪
♪ Ohh, no...
That surgery
was bad medicine.
Dr. Andrews used to be
a good doctor,
but you made him
a bad one.
I need to leave before
you make me a bad doctor.
I quit.
♪♪
Shaun.
♪ Ooh
♪ We're falling down
♪ Alone ♪
♪♪
I'm in.
Let's run her bandit ass
outta town.
♪♪