- Previously on
"New Amsterdam"...
- You tell Mama
about your child out of wedlock
and wanting to start
something with your father,
you'll send her
to an early grave.
- It's the first installment
of my loan repayment.
- Something I love
is hurting me.
I'm just not really sure
how to let it out.
- How can I help?
- You call off this raid
and I will walk
out of this building,
and you will never,
ever hear from me again.
- That's not enough.
This is fraud.
Our shareholders--
- Someone called them off.
- So what are we
supposed to do now?
- You can start by
getting out of my office.
♪
- Dr. Sherman to Radiology.
Dr. Sherman to Radiology.
♪
- Hello, everyone!
And welcome
to Orientation Day--
well, actually, I should say
Re-Orientation Day.
There are so many lovely
familiar faces here.
Uh, look, new cards.
So, Ms. Miller, here you go.
And Dr. Kao.
Ms. Fall.
Nurse Acosta.
The lovely Dr. Bloom.
And last but not least,
Max Goodwin.
So please let this serve
as your official "welcome back"
to New Amsterdam.
Now, your old positions
might not be available
because somebody
else has taken them,
but do not worry.
We will find you a new spot.
It might not have
the same stature
as your former position,
but I'm sure,
like me, you're
just happy to be working.
- Happy?
- Yes.
Thank you so much for coming.
And let's get back to work.
- You're literally
forcing us to work here.
- No, I'm not.
- Well, with our non-compete
clause in our contract,
we can't work anywhere else
for the next three years.
- Of course you can.
You can work anywhere you like.
You just can't
practice medicine.
But it's good
to have you back, Dr. Bloom.
- Mm.
Uh, Max, can I speak to you
for a moment?
Um...
I went back and forth
for a really long time
about presenting you
with that badge,
because...
I--I just--
I don't know what you want.
- Do you mean would I rather
give up on Helen
to stay here
and keep being a doctor
or go back to London,
where now, thanks to you,
I can't practice medicine?
- Yeah, sure.
- You win.
You get to keep running
this hospital, okay?
Let's not make it personal.
- Personal?
My God, you tried to take
my medical license.
You tried to have me indicted
for a fraud
that I did not commit.
What,
that was just professional?
Because the threat of prison
felt pretty damn personal
to me.
I didn't make this personal,
Max.
You did.
That's on you.
So you just let me know
what you decide.
Okay?
♪
- Dr. Goodwin, in the house!
Well, the hospital.
Good to see you, man.
- You too.
- Hey, remember that cruise
my wife and I were
supposed to take
right before COVID?
- Mm-hmm.
- Well, after being postponed,
canceled, and rebooked
about 14 times,
we're finally set
to shove off on Saturday.
Only problem is,
I woke up with this rash.
Can you--
- Yeah, I'm sorry, Jerry.
I-I can't help.
♪
- Oh, my gosh.
Look at what
the cat dragged in.
- You know I hate
that expression.
- You know
that's why I used it.
- Back in Duluth,
we had a tabby
who'd bring in mangled robins.
They'd die right there
on my mom's carpet.
- Look at you, you're back
for five minutes and already
sharing folksy anecdotes
about your sociopathic cats.
It's almost like
you never even left.
- No rush.
Your 8:30's not here yet.
- Uh, no, no, no, no.
It's a virtual patient.
The poor guy hasn't left
his apartment in three years.
- Okay, I'll make a note
he's telehealth only.
What's the patient's name?
- Uh, LazerFox404.
- Is that his given name?
- No.
That would be cool,
but I doubt it.
Uh, our sessions take place
in a video game.
- Ah, the fox sits and talks
to the doctor?
- No.
The fox and the doc talk
while running around
killing globbets.
Yeah, they're like these, um...
I don't know,
bat people, I guess.
Uh, also, he doesn't know
that I'm a doctor.
He's refused therapy,
so I'm disguised as a samurai.
A rodent samurai.
- It all sounds
very nontraditional.
- Yeah, in Japan,
they're called hikikomori.
And the best treatment
they've found--
this is no joke--
is using attractive women
to lure the male patients
back into the world.
These people have become so
stricken with anxiety and shame
that they've completely
given up on their real lives.
So unfortunately,
bending the laws of therapy
is the only way
to get them out.
Excuse me.
- I'm sure you know
what you're doing.
- Whoa, LazerFox!
Globbets on your six!
- Well, well, well.
Life is funny, isn't it?
- Congratulations
on being made Chair, Dr. Walsh.
- Thank you, Bloom.
So things work a little
differently around here now.
We--
- Pile up on the FDR.
I got a man, 40s, broken
femur and multiple lacerations.
- Um, aren't you gonna--
- Ooh.
Whoop. Whoop, whoop.
- Let's take him to bay 28.
- Thank you.
What's that?
No racing across the ED?
Descending on a patient
like a bat out of hell?
No barking out orders
for who to take who where?
No, no.
I stayed right here
and allowed my system to work.
"What system?" you ask.
The Walsh White Board.
- My man went to Staples.
- Each doctor has a color,
and when your color's up,
that's your patient.
Stunningly simple,
yet brilliant, don't you think?
- I do.
- Uh, so before I
officially welcome you back,
let me ask you, are you
on board with the board?
- You're the boss.
♪
- Okay, um...
So I've assigned you tan.
- Great.
- Better colors were available.
I'm happy with tan.
♪
- I know. She's different.
Oh, you guys are up.
- Gary Burgess, 52,
complaining of stomach pains.
He collapsed
walking down 2nd Ave.
Doorman called 911.
- Okay, Mr. Burgess.
Is the pain dull,
sharp, or throbbing?
- I'm fine, I just overdid it
at dinner last night.
- Definitely sharp.
- Trauma One.
- What time is it?
It's important.
- Not more important
than a middle-aged man
with epigastric pain.
- Where you supposed to be?
- My daughter Emma and I
are here to tour NYU
this afternoon.
She's so excited.
Can't you just give me
an antacid or something?
- I'm gonna run
some more tests.
- Is Emma here?
- No, she's back at the hotel.
She thinks I'm still
out for my walk.
- I can give her a call.
- No way.
I'm not ruining her big day
with a terrifying call
about acid reflux.
- Mr. Burgess...
you're having a heart attack.
- Hi! Babe.
- Come on.
Don't keep me in suspense.
Did she cry?
Oh, God, I hope she cried.
- Easy there, Judge Dredd.
She's still here.
But, uh, yeah, I've got her
right where I want her.
- I bet you do.
I'm so proud of you, my love.
- Yeah.
Maybe, uh...
maybe save that praise
till after it's over.
- No, we have to
acknowledge it all.
You are saving that hospital
from abject ruin.
Everyone who works there
should be
singing your praises,
especially those
who depend on New Amsterdam
for their very survival.
So you take the flowers.
- Mm-hmm.
All right. Well, I should,
uh, should get back to it.
You know, gotta be consistent
with your vanquishing.
But I love you.
Love you more.
Bye.
♪
- This rash is now at my elbow.
- Yeah, mine
is also covering my hands.
- That's nasty, bro.
Where'd you get that?
- I don't know.
- Uh, sorry to eavesdrop,
but did you both say
you have a rash?
- Yeah.
- You seen anything like it
before, Doc?
♪
- I froze these eggs years ago.
I was worried they'd gone bad.
I know that's not how it works,
but...
everything's been
so much harder than I thought.
Now there are two surgeons
in my room.
- Well, Inez,
your twins look well-developed
at 18 weeks gestation.
- However, they have tumors
in their respective lungs
that's threatening
their development.
- Both of them?
- Yes, identical twins
have the same DNA.
- But we can treat it.
- Now, they're too young
to be delivered,
but what we can do is remove
each baby from the uterus,
excise the tumors,
and then put them back in.
- They will be connected
to the umbilical cord
the whole time.
♪
- Is that their only chance?
- Yes.
♪
- Please save my babies.
- Please help him!
- Don't just stand there.
Do something!
- He's dying!
- I'm very sorry.
- What the hell is going on?
- The boy has no
brain function, Dr. Sharpe.
Hasn't in weeks.
Restarting his heart
won't change the fact
that he's already gone.
- That's not true.
We were with him this morning.
- You can't just
let our son die.
This is a hospital!
- Please save him.
- Do you have a court order
to withhold life support?
- Dr. Sharpe--
- Do you?
- No, but--
- Then move.
Okay. Clear!
♪
- Dr. Sharpe--
- Going again.
Clear!
♪
- Oh...
- Oh, thank you.
- You didn't save him,
you know.
You just made it
that much harder
for his parents to say goodbye.
♪
- Unbelievable. You know,
when I was medical director,
this supplier would always
try to sell me
on these third-rate products.
But cheaper is never better,
it is most certainly not safer,
and I'm willing to bet
that my successor--
- Didn't care.
- Who cares about janitors,
right?
- Well, I do.
This steroid cream, and, uh...
never touching
those gloves again
should take care of that rash.
- Come on.
- So are these things
also giving
my sudden migraines?
- Migraines?
- What about intense cramping?
- No, no, gloves should--
- My asthma
has been kicking up.
- My lungs are messed up too.
♪
- Mr. Burgess,
how are you feeling?
- Ah, like a piano
has been lifted off my chest.
- Oh, then the morphine's
doing its job.
Have you had this pressure
in your chest for a long time?
- Is 17 years a long time?
You have kids?
- I don't.
- Wait until you do.
It's everything.
- I'm gonna be right back.
Hey, hey.
I know this is a job
even first years hate,
but these patients'
blood work showed
potassium levels
that were irregular by .1%.
They need to be notified,
by phone.
- On it.
- I know what you're
trying to do.
You're playing
mind games with me,
pretending to be okay
with me being the boss,
but really trying
to get under my skin.
- Nope.
I gotta go make these calls,
okay, boss?
♪
- Follow me
if you want to live.
- Oh! Look out!
Look out!
The turrets,
deploy the turrets!
- Turrets and rodent-leap
on three...
both: Two, one.
- Pow!
Oh, shoot! Yeah!
- That was sick.
- Whoo!
- We just did
our deluxe turbo moves
simultaneously to the second.
- I love it! That was awesome.
It's like you're in my head.
Wow!
Is it like that for you
with everybody,
like instant connection?
♪
- Nah.
Man, not so much.
Yeah, me neither.
Uh...
So, uh, hey, you hear
about this Manhattanhenge?
- The sunset thing?
- Yeah.
- Yeah. It's nuts.
I was, uh,
thinking about going.
You want to come with?
♪
- I don't get out much.
- Okay. Why not?
- Whatever.
Forget it.
I'm a freak.
- No, no, no, no, no.
I get it, man.
I'm--you know, I'm the same.
I haven't been out of my
apartment in so long
it's like I've
gotten used to it.
- Yeah.
- But I'm, uh,
I'm trying to change.
I'm getting out there,
I'm doing more.
Hence, Manhattanhenge.
So if you want to come
with me, that's cool.
We'll meet up.
If not,
I completely understand.
♪
- I feel like you're
the only person
in the whole world
who understands me.
I trust you.
You're the only person
I trust.
I'll meet you there.
♪
- Give me a clamp.
- Hysterotomy is hemostatic.
No leaks.
- Clamp.
- Give me a little more
traction.
- My baby's stable.
- So is mine.
It's Inez.
- Uh, BP's dropping.
- Uh, the uterus
is contracting.
♪
- It's gonna rupture.
- Stay with the babies.
Give me all the suction
you got.
Retractor.
There's got to be a pumper
in here somewhere.
♪
More traction.
I can't find it.
♪
- You have to resect.
- What if I hit the placenta?
- Don't.
- Scalpel.
- Adding back now.
- Can I get another
10 milligrams, please?
♪
- How are the babies?
- Stable.
♪
- Resecting...
- Suture.
♪
Piece.
- Lowering suction.
- There we go.
Surgical field's drying up.
Suture.
- Dropping.
Okay. Cut it.
- 96 now.
♪
- Clamp.
- We did it.
- Appears to be--one second.
- It's smaller now.
♪
- Both fetuses
won't fit back inside.
♪
- We wish to resume
Ollie's stem cell treatments
as soon as possible.
- This morning was a setback,
that's all.
- The treatment
that Ollie has been receiving
is still considered
experimental--
- We're not giving up
on our son.
- No, of course not.
But Ollie has a rare
neurodegenerative disease
that's left him
in a semi-vegetative state.
The odds of a full recovery
lie somewhere around...
one in a billion.
- So why did you save him?
I mean, you brought him back.
You must have thought
he had a chance.
I can feel him, Dr. Sharpe.
Our boy is still here.
- We know the odds.
All we want
is the chance to try.
- I understand.
- Apologies.
NHS Hampstead
has received an order
from the family division
of the UK High Court.
- To do what?
At 10:00 a.m. tomorrow,
we are ordered by law
to remove this child
from his life support--
- Over my dead body.
- I am truly sorry,
but the 1989 Children's Act
gives the government
the power to weigh in, and they
are exercising that right.
- That's impossible.
Please, Dr. Sharpe!
- He's right.
♪
It's the law.
- 16 years, it's a long time.
- And I've liked sanitation.
It's predictable, you know?
But this asthma kicking up...
Getting worse, and...
- And you don't smoke?
- Smoke? No.
- What about a wood-burning
fireplace in your home?
- Yeah, my studio in Queens
has got all that.
A waterfall
with a spiral staircase too.
- Sounds nice.
Um, can you think
of anything in your life,
in your daily routine
that might have changed?
- We recently
stopped recycling here.
- What do you do now?
- We incinerate everything.
- When lunch was 30 minutes,
I could go grab a salad.
Now I'm lucky if I can
get to the vending machine.
- Double shifts twice a week.
But with extended childcare,
barely breaking even.
- Cuts or guys out sick.
We're down
a dozen plumbers every day.
- The more shifts I cover,
the more exposure
to infected patients.
- And when the network crashes,
guess whose pay gets docked.
- Then my lower back went out
because they told me
I had to help
transfer patients.
- How do they add more rooms
to my shift
without adding more pay?
- Why cut my hours?
We're sure not
cutting the number
of patient medical records.
- And now my meds
is out of pocket because
somehow my PPO
got switched to an HMO.
Who treats their employees
this way?
- Well, I think I have a guess.
♪
- Oh, uh, boss.
- Stop calling me that.
- I was just wondering
if I could take five,
for a personal errand.
- What you can do
is drop the long con,
'cause I'm not buying it.
- Huh?
- Enough with this
respectful and nice garbage.
Where's the real Bloom, huh?
Did you kill her?
- No!
Look, Mia's been
helping me with cupping
and acupuncture
and all that crap, and...
I don't know, I think
it might actually be working.
♪
- So you're okay
with me being your boss.
- I think I might actually
be relieved by it.
I mean, as I'm sure
you're aware by now,
it's, like, a lot
to have hanging over your head.
♪
- Okay, yeah. Go, go.
Take care
of your personal thing.
- Okay, thanks.
♪
- You look like a man
who has seen
the bad side of some globbets.
LazerFox404 slip off your hook?
- No, worse.
He bit.
Yeah, I'm meeting him
in person tonight.
- Isn't that good news?
- Yeah, that's good news.
You know, it all went exactly
as the protocol
for hikikomori prescribes.
I built trust,
we opened a door for a huge
therapeutic breakthrough,
and now I feel...
weird about it.
Not good. Why?
- I don't like to question
your methods.
But...
this morning,
you were using phrases
like "bending the laws
of therapy," and...
- Yeah.
- I think if we're
being honest,
what you mean is,
you're lying to him.
- Well...
- And you feel bad,
because now you're gonna
have to do it to his face.
- Mm.
- And I think
you should feel bad.
Okay, thank you.
Uh...
All right, what...
what if this is truly
the only way to help this guy?
What if that's the case?
Shouldn't that matter more
than how I feel morally
about it?
I mean, do you know
how hard it would be for him
if I canceled on him now?
- Better than if you met him
and he found out
you were manipulating him.
- Hey, we don't have
much time.
We need to put one
of these babies back inside.
- No, what we have to do
is think.
- We cannot make
her uterus bigger.
- Well, we also can't
just terminate one of them.
I don't know
how to make that call, do you?
- Whichever one
has developed less.
- What if...
No, no. Forget it.
- No, say it.
- Well, we could zipper
one into the uterus
and leave the other one outside
in the abdominal cavity.
It'd still be attached
to the placenta
where it can get oxygen
and other nutrients from Inez.
♪
- We'd essentially be creating
an ectopic pregnancy.
- Yes.
- Well, it's not impossible.
- No.
But it could also kill
the mother and both fetuses.
- Or it could save them all.
♪
- So are you gonna appeal
the court's decision?
- I'd have to go
on record saying
I believe
keeping Ollie alive
is the best course of action,
medically speaking.
- But you know
his condition won't improve,
even with treatment.
- Yeah, the doctor in me
knows that.
But I'm also a parent now.
How can I support a system
that blocks a parent's right
to try absolutely everything
to save their child?
If it were Luna, I would never
accept that it was impossible.
- Well, I guess
that's why the UK system
has a committee of doctors
to make that decision
so you don't have to.
♪
- Ollie is gone, but I can
still help his parents.
- You can't give them the legal
right they don't have.
- No, but I can move them
somewhere they do.
I'm transferring Ollie
to New Amsterdam.
♪
- BP's down to 80,
systolic and dropping.
- Back off the nitro drip.
It's causing the drop.
- BP is rising again.
- Good.
Let's continue
to make sure that--
- Ah! My chest.
What's happening?
- Should I re-up the nitro?
- Yes.
- Oh, God!
- No, no! No.
- Oh, God.
- Dr. Walsh?
- Get--get Dr. Bloom.
- Hey, what's happening?
- Patient is in
excruciating chest pain,
but if I increase his IV nitro,
his BP crashes,
which is against protocol.
- That's a tough call.
- Yes, I know that.
- How can I help?
- Stop being supportive.
Be Bloom and tell me what to do
to keep this man alive.
- I'd break protocol.
- You'd up the nitro?
- Yeah.
I mean, the pain will go away,
and you can manage
the pressure.
♪
- Up the nitro drip.
- Good call, Dr. Walsh.
♪
- Outfoxed.
That's, like,
such a bad catchphrase,
it's like ironically good,
right?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Are you stressed
about Manhattanhenge?
Going out?
- Yeah, you could say that.
- I've been so alone
for so long.
But with you,
it'll be different.
We got each other's backs.
Like in the game--
- My name's Iggy.
- Hi, Iggy.
- Is that short for--
- Dr. Ignatius Frome, actually.
I work here
at New Amsterdam Hospital.
- What's going on right now?
- I volunteer for a group
that helps people
who have withdrawn
from society.
And I hate that I lied to you.
I hate it. I hate it so much.
But it was the only way
that I could reach you.
And the truth doesn't change
how huge a deal it is
for you to even consider
leaving your apartment.
♪
- Closing incisions
on the uterus.
Ooh.
Get that little foot in there.
All right.
Okay, here we go.
- Switching out canisters.
- We're steady.
- Hold it sideways.
There you go.
Move the uterus over.
Easy, easy.
Gonna be there...
- Clamping.
- Closing abdominal wall
over fetus two.
- Hang tight in there,
my friend.
♪
- Hey, Max! Max, Max, Max.
- Hey.
- Thank you.
- That's great.
Steroid cream works fast.
- No, no. I'm not just
talking about the cream, Doc.
You heard me,
and you helped me.
Now, that's who you are.
You care.
You might be the only guy
at the top who does.
- Yeah,
I'm not at the top anymore.
- But you're gonna be, right?
You're gonna fix this place.
Take out Veronica.
Boom. Back on top.
- I tried.
Jerry, I tried
everything I could.
I asked everyone I could
for help,
and I couldn't fix it.
I can't even
be a doctor anymore.
- You're giving up?
♪
- I'm going home.
- This will take you
to the airport
where a plane is waiting.
Once you land at JFK,
there'll be an ambulance there
waiting to transport Ollie
directly to New Amsterdam.
- Thank you, Dr. Sharpe,
for everything.
- Just call me when you land.
- We will.
Dr. Sharpe?
- Stay back.
Move. Now.
- This child is not permitted
to leave the hospital, ma'am.
- Excuse me?
- And anyone helping
to push him across
the threshold
will be violating the law.
- Let me be clear:
under my medical advice,
the Gardams have transferred
their son's care
out of the country.
- They can't do that.
Ollie Gardam
is a British citizen
whose welfare
is protected by the court.
And the court has determined,
in accordance
with the National Institute
of Health and Care Excellence's
guidelines, that artificially
prolonging his life
would be unkind and inhumane.
Their decision stands.
By 10:00 a.m. tomorrow,
life support must be withdrawn.
- Listen, this child's life
has got nothing to do
with the government!
- Officers.
- No. Stop! No, no.
- Step aside, ma'am, or I'll
be forced to arrest you.
- No! No!
- Take him.
- Please stop!
- We just want to help him!
Get off him! Get off him!
- Stop!
♪
- You can see one little guy
there in your uterus,
as you might expect.
And here is your other son.
He'll be there
until you deliver.
- Oh, my God. Is he safe?
- He will continue
to be nourished
through his umbilical cord.
And we're gonna monitor
his development.
So far, he's doing great.
Already doing things
his own way, huh?
- Yeah.
- Thank you both.
For everything.
- It was my honor.
I'm actually gonna
be a father myself.
- I didn't know.
- Yeah, I gotta get used
to saying that out loud.
♪
- You did the right thing.
- Maybe.
- Ethics aside,
you're an awful liar.
You would have given it away
two minutes after he met you.
- Thanks, Gladys.
- Are you ready
for your next patient?
Or should we reschedule?
- Uh, no, no, that's okay.
Send him in. Thank you.
Hi. Sorry to keep you waiting.
Um, how can I help?
- You could tell me
if the Sword of Ra...
Is in the Zombie Castle.
- It is...
but it's being guarded
by the Globbet King.
A very fearsome foe.
♪
- Then I guess
I'll need your help.
♪
- Grab a seat.
- You thought you had to worry
about me coming to New York.
- I'm so sorry I didn't call.
- How'd you know
upping the nitro would work?
- I didn't.
And if it had gone wrong,
I would have had to accept
that I was the one
who made that call.
- Hmm. You know, I...
I thought I wanted
to make those decisions.
But honestly, I'm...
I'm not sure I do.
- Yeah, takes some time
to get used to it.
- Yeah.
Or maybe I don't want
to be the boss.
- Walsh--
- No, it's actually freeing
to consider--I mean...
You know, what I--
what I do know is
I don't want
to do it right now.
Will you take back the ED?
- Okay, but...
if you decide that you do want
to do it one day,
you're gonna be amazing at it.
Now go check on bay 11.
- Was that a pep talk?
- I don't know
what's wrong with me.
- I'm not sure.
It might need a little salt.
- Mmm-mmm-mmm.
Woman, you can burn.
This short rib sauce almost
has me speaking in tongues.
Sha-na-na-na-na-na!
Mmm! Hallelujah!
- Hi, Mama. Uh...
I didn't realize
you had company.
- Oh, Floyd.
Now, I know I raised you
better than that.
- Deacon Earnest.
- Floyd.
- I was hoping
I could talk to you.
- Uh, I think you need rolls--
- You just stay put.
Floyd can speak freely.
We don't keep secrets
in this household.
- Ma, I--I...
want you to help me
find my father.
♪
- You know,
it feels a little light.
You wouldn't be ripping me off,
would you?
- Just when I thought you
were out of money-drop bits.
- Never.
Makes this less weird.
- I won't need
to borrow money anymore.
I don't need a lawyer because
I don't have a winnable case.
- What? What happened?
- I don't have a stable address
which shows lack of,
well, stability,
which I do lack.
I just got ahead of myself.
I need time to either--
- Put down my address.
- It's not just a place
to receive paperwork.
My case worker said
that there would be interviews
and then random visits--
- Well then, move back in.
For real.
- What about your sobriety?
Your health.
You said I trigger you.
- You did.
But...I've changed.
I'm not who I was.
I can do this, okay?
♪
- Thank you.
- I'm sorry, babe. That's...
Those parents.
I can't imagine.
- I wish you were here.
I could do with some
of the old Max optimism.
- I could use some of it too.
I lied to you.
- A-about what?
- Veronica.
I didn't vanquish anything.
She beat me at almost every
turn, and now looks like...
She's won the war.
- But the federal case?
- It's gone.
Slipped under the rug.
all: Hey-hey, ho-ho!
- Listen, um...
I was thinking...
Hang on a second.
all: Hey-hey, ho-ho,
Dr. Fuentes has to go!
Hey-hey, ho-ho,
Hey-hey!
♪
- Uh, who was supposed
to prep the OR?
- Don't look at me.
♪
- Hey, hello?
- Hello?
- I need a hand.
I'm, uh, out of TP over here.
- Ah. Okay, hang on. I gotcha.
- Shoot--hold on.
Okay.
♪
- Doctor, can you look at this?
- Where are the orderlies?
- Don't know.
- We've got
a tumor resection in OR 2.
- I can't attend.
- Why not?
- We're out of clean scrubs.
♪
all: Hey-hey, ho-ho,
Dr. Fuentes has to go!
Hey-hey, ho-ho,
- What in God's name
could be so wrong
that we would cancel
all surgeries?
That doesn't make any sense.
- Maintenance
is completely M.I.A.
Hang on.
So?
- So the ED's
going on diversion.
- You're telling me
that New Amsterdam
is shutting down
because of janitors?
- And orderlies, technicians,
mechanics, groundskeepers,
plumbers, carpenters,
security, electricians.
It really is quite the list,
you know,
in terms
of keeping a hospital running.
- Karen, not now.
I'm very busy.
- Oh, I've heard.
And after the fourth member
of the board phoned me,
I decided I better swing by
and see it for myself.
And I must say, wow,
was it worth the trip.
- Okay, well,
gloat if you must,
but can you please do it
away from my office?
Because I need to fix this.
- Fix this?
You lost your
entire support staff!
- Because of a stunt.
Another impetuous stunt!
- No, to the largest
single day walkout
in this country's history
of public health.
And one that you're
presiding over.
The board is scrambling,
HCC is doing damage control,
but the fact remains:
until these employees
come back,
this hospital can't operate.
You're shut down
from top to bottom.
And that has
never happened before.
Maybe that's why they call them
"essential workers."
- What do you want me to do?
all: Hey-hey, ho-ho,
Dr. Fuentes has to go!
Hey-hey, ho-ho,
Hey-hey, ho-ho...
- I pretty sure
the people are telling you
exactly what to do.
all: Hey-hey, ho-ho,
Dr. Fuentes has to go!
Hey-hey, ho-ho,
- Dr. Goodwin!
- Gary...
um, how did this happen?
- You spent a lot of time
helping us.
Time for us to help you.
all: Dr. Fuentes has to go!
Hey-hey, ho-ho,
Dr. Fuentes has to go!
Hey-hey!
♪
- Oh, my God!
- Yes!
- We did it, buddy!
We actually did it, man.
To our fearless leader!
To Max!
- To Maximus!
- This wasn't me.
This was everyone.
This was...
♪
This was New Amsterdam.
Whoo-hoo!
- Hey.
We got our hospital back.
- Do we?
- Yeah. What do you mean?
- This revolution
wasn't successful
because people hate Veronica.
It was successful
because they love you.
We don't have our hospital back
unless we have you too.
Do we?
♪