Previously on ER:
I need to loosen up a bit. I have
a tendency to micro-manage...
Yeah, Cate mentioned that.
I don't wanna be
here. I don't like it here.
I know how it is to come
back from war and feel adrift.
Saying it fancy doesn't make
you seem smarter, Andrew.
It makes you seem insecure.
Could you get me
a death kit please?
It's your job to decide what needs to
be considered and when to speak up.
If you're submissive when someone's
life is on the line, you're not ready...
I try to speak up
and nobody listens!
You can't be a great doctor
until you've killed a patient.
- So that Brenner guy?
- Mm-hm?
Kind of seems like a dick.
"Because of the ongoing chaos...
there has been a depletion
of resources including water...
which continues
to divide the area.
- What are you doing?
- Water resources are at such a low...
scholars are projecting
that by 2025...
- Okay, put that down.
- Syria, Oman, Libya...
and Ethiopia will also be
struggling for a larger supply."
That's my thesis. It's rough.
That is not rough.
That is scholarly.
I haven't even
rewritten that page.
You misspelled irrigation.
- No, I didn't.
- Yeah, you did. It's "i-g" not "a-g."
Look, I can't type.
"Well, one of the most efficient
resources is drip irrigation..."
You're torturing me. Stop.
But as more countries
gain the use...
of this technology...
the areas will become... Better.
When was Kennedy assassinated?
- No.
- John or Robert?
- I haven't heard a thing.
- I was hoping you had.
- Do I look fat?
- No, sit down. When was Bobby killed?
- 1978. '73?
Does your son have any
friends that may have called?
- '65?
- '68, Alex. You gotta learn these.
- Six, six, '68.
- I knew that one.
You don't even know
how to choose clothes.
- I'm changing.
- No, you look great. Sit down.
No, I hear you. I'll call you if I
know anything, Mrs. Gonzalez.
- Thank you.
- No news?
Maybe this guy
wants to be homeless.
- Nobody wants to be homeless, Sarah.
- You know everyone in the world?
No, smart-Alex, do you know every
one of those flashcards? Let me see.
When was the War of 1812?
- Look at him. He's thinking.
- No, I got you.
- It's over his breakfast.
- He thought about it.
Hi, yeah, this is him. Quiet.
Shh, shh. It's the shelter on Third.
Hi, yes.
You haven't heard
from him. Okay.
No, thank you. I appreciate
you calling me back. Bye.
I was thinking of staying put.
I was gonna go back home but
the airfare is so bloody expensive.
What about you?
What are your plans?
Oh, that's great, Ray.
Where's she from?
Oh, I've heard that
Georgia is beautiful.
Well, that should be fun.
Well, I guess I'll talk to
you when you get back.
Yeah, you too.
- You don't have to do that.
- I don't work Tuesday, it's no big deal.
Don't worry about it. My
brother's friends will help me move.
Neela, this is Leanne.
Leanne, Neela.
Moving. I hate moving.
Hard to concentrate on my dissertation
when my roommate's screwing.
- What's your focus?
- Middle Eastern politics.
Speaking of which,
Samuir Khalaf's...
giving a lecture in
an hour, I've gotta go.
Okay, I'll see you tonight.
She seems impressive.
Full scholarship to
University of Chicago...
and she speaks five languages.
Does she twirl around in
phone booths and fight crime?
She doesn't seem like your type.
- Why's that?
- I don't know.
I figured you with
someone less intellectual.
Now, that is rude. No,
you've got me all wrong.
In fact, it's evolving
into quite a thing.
- How about you? You seeing anyone?
- No, riding solo.
I can set you up
with a rugby mate.
Yeah, I'd rather be boiled
and laid in a bed of cat litter.
- I can arrange that too.
- Bug off.
Beth, 46, fell down a flight of
stairs trying to escape a house fire.
I'm Dr. Brenner, do you
know where you are?
- Hospital.
- Shallow resps, tachy to 125...
BP's 100/58.
- My leg.
- Closed deformity on the left...
looks like a tib-fib.
- How is she?
- You were to obey...
- the traffic lights.
- She's my wife.
Pulled her from the fire. I
tried to have him looked over.
- How you feeling?
- I'm fine.
- Trauma room, let's go.
- Bolus 5000 units heparin.
Then 900 an hour.
- Hey, do you have a second?
- What's up? I'm late for a diverticulum.
I wanted to talk
about Mendenhall.
Let's all try to move
on from that, shall we?
Pull into the slow lane during
an accident you'll have a problem.
I was thinking of a way to
ensure that never happens.
Really? I hope you
plan to patent that idea.
If you have the ability to control the
future, you might be onto something.
- Lucien, I'm not joking.
- Let's just use this...
as an opportunity to assess
your management style.
My style is not the problem.
How am I to delegate work
to an intern I can't trust?
Make him into one you can.
I wish I didn't have
to supervise anyone.
- I'd be better off.
- That's really how you feel?
- Yeah, it is.
- Fine then. Permission granted.
You are free of having to
supervise. No more interns for you.
He's not capable, not competent.
I can't have him killing another.
I'm moving him. He's gone.
You made a decision, stick by it.
- They have me in surgical clinic.
- You'll have to do it anyway.
I was planning on the end
of the year when I was tired.
- You'll be fine.
- What if Dr. Rasgotra...
cockblocks me in the department?
- She's not.
- Andrew thinks everyone...
is thinking about him.
Do not entertain him.
She told Dubenko she doesn't
want me to work with her.
Give her a few
weeks, she'll get over it.
And if she doesn't?
You'll look at ass ditzels
on old women forever.
Hey, just because
Banfield's on vacation...
doesn't mean you
guys can slack off.
Tracy, Grady, Brenner
just got a trauma.
And Daria, Gates is doing
a central line in Curtains.
And Andrew, you shouldn't
even be down here.
You see? Even the
nurses don't want me here.
- I am gonna strangle you.
- Is he like this at home?
- Uh-huh. All the time.
- All right, you need some love.
Hands in. Intern power.
Break.
Thank God I'm a resident.
Maybe I should call the VA
hospital or Voices for Veterans.
You've done enough.
I could also check the
alleys around the hospital.
Sorry, I got stuck
splinting a 3-year-old.
Ten of lido.
Hey, sir, you're gonna feel a little
stick, this is the numbing medicine.
Ceftriaxone's ready.
What's the name of that
shelter on Michigan near the El?
St. Mary's.
My neighbor volunteers there.
All right. Angle
that up a little bit.
- How many rounds of epi?
- Three.
- He's been out 20 minutes.
- Lily? What's going on?
Homeless man found down.
You guys got this, right?
Line is primed.
- Only 80 systolic.
- I can't thread the guidewire.
Don't pull back. Try
rotating the bevel.
- Maybe that's not him.
- That's his duffle.
It's not going. SAM: He
needs volume and pressors.
All right. Get me
gloves. Open a new tray.
That's it.
Superficial burns
to the right arm.
- What labs do you want?
- CBC, trauma panel, type and cross.
Why won't they leave us alone?
- Chest is stable.
- It's okay, honey. We'll move.
- Right-upper quadrant's tender.
- Not going anywhere.
This is our home.
Talk later. Let's
just get you well first.
IV's in.
Your interns do know
how to hold a scalpel?
- Excuse me? NEELA:
Why was surgery called...
for a buttock abscess?
I was late because I was doing
an I&D that an ER intern could do.
A surgical intern.
Your underlings?
That's really not the
point. What have you got?
Beth Lotery. Blunt trauma to
the belly and legs, minor burns.
- How's the ultrasound?
- We're getting to that.
- Sat's 86.
- What's happening?
Mrs. Lotery, open your eyes.
- She's not breathing.
- Intubating.
- Tracy, you up for this?
- Totally. Mac two and seven-oh.
Morris, can you sew this
and check the chest x-ray?
Let your intern do it.
- Five hundred cc's in.
- He's still hypotensive.
Two liters and start levophed.
He's septic, help me
get his pressure up.
- What are you doing?
- I have to take care of something.
- Dr. Gates.
- Hey, Sully. How are you?
I need more colored condoms.
- I gave you a bunch.
- What are you, jealous?
I'm scared. I'll
hook you up later.
Tony, I'm sorry.
It's not him.
It's not Max.
Pericardium looks good.
Systolic's only 79.
Could be the anesthesia.
Okay. Hang another liter of
NS. Do we have a repeat crit?
Running it now.
- You guys need any help?
- We're fine, Andrew.
Clinic's not for another
hour. I thought...
More gel please, thank you.
What was that about?
This is the patient's brother.
Hey, Beth. It's
Richie. I'm right here.
- She's been sedated.
- Helping her breathe while her body heals.
I told you something
was gonna happen.
I didn't burn down the house. I wasn't
the one who threw rocks at our car.
But this is because of you.
My sister shouldn't
have to live like this.
- What do you think that is? MORRIS:
Maybe a subcapsular hematoma.
- Crit's down to 31.
- Let's get her to CT.
- She might need surgery.
- Wait a minute, surgery?
She's got to have surgery?
Possibly the fall may have
caused injury to her liver.
- You son of a bitch.
- Whoa, whoa.
No, I told her to
leave you a year ago.
Settle down. RICHIE:
You're a freak and a pervert.
Twelve years old. Twelve
years old, Hank, that kid was.
I didn't do it, Richie.
I didn't touch that girl.
How do you think that
guy got Max's bag?
Probably ripped it off
at a homeless shelter.
Pretty lame.
Oh, look at this.
Is that Max?
Yeah, it says a couple
years ago, up in Tal Afar.
- You'd hardly recognize him.
- You know what?
I'll put this up at fire houses.
- Maybe it'll make someone give a damn.
- Well, that's a good idea.
And after that, you're
going to let it go?
I'm gonna try.
Daria, did you look at the
x-ray for my pneumonia guy?
Yeah, line's in the
near the atrium.
Start him on antibiotics and
move him upstairs, okay?
- All right. Now show me the look.
- Okay. It was like this:
"We're fine, Andrew."
She's probably having a bad day.
Daria, did you see the
stink eye? Look again.
"We're fine, Andrew."
Dude, you're cool. I promise.
The stink eye, Daria...
- Hello, Dr. Rasgotra.
- Hi, there.
Hey.
Okay, I take it
back. You're dead.
Whoa, Little Miss
Sunshine's mad.
I'm sick of interns.
- This about that old lady last week?
- It is.
- It was a mistake.
- A mistake that cost someone their life.
You need vacation. What
you doing for holidays?
I was thinking to visit Ray but
he's going away with his girlfriend.
His girlfriend?
Morris, that storage
locker in Indiana called.
They said if you don't pay
up they'll sell your dad's stuff.
Dead, my dad's driving me
crazy. Ray has a girlfriend?
- He just met her at the gym.
- Are you okay?
I'm happy for him.
This is wonderful.
- Are you Neela Rasgotra?
- Yeah, how can I help you?
You've been served.
Is that a subpoena?
Yeah, it's a medical
malpractice suit.
Going for a CAT scan of
her abdomen and pelvis.
Could give her cancer.
We have to have it to
see if she needs surgery.
- You coming up, Dr. Brenner?
- Yeah. Did you bring O-neg?
- Right here.
- How long does this take?
Not very long.
Can you check his oxygen
levels while we go upstairs?
- I wanna stay.
- Should listen to your lungs.
- You can't be with her.
- I'll let you know her results.
I'm okay. Really.
You're short of breath,
let me check you out.
Okay.
Bye, sweetie.
Why don't you come with us?
This way.
It's not true what
he's saying about me.
- None of my business.
- I mean, I teach music.
How am I supposed to show
a kid how to play clarinet...
without touching
their arm, their back?
What school are you at?
- Oak Hill Elementary.
- Lily, can you give me a hand?
No problem.
One of my students came
forward about a year ago.
I thought it would all be
settled by a quick conversation...
with her and her parents...
but then next thing I know...
I'm suspended without
pay, facing a lawsuit.
Her word against yours?
Then the whole neighborhood...
went on a witch-hunt.
Everyone we knew.
They just turned against us.
Can you open your
mouth for me please?
- Say "Ah."
- Ah.
She said I did stuff.
Made her do stuff.
I have a daughter.
I would never hurt a kid.
I thought it would be all over
when they found me not guilty...
but they just kept harassing us.
Now they tried to
burn down our house.
I'm sure the cops will
find out who did this.
The cops don't care.
To them, I'm guilty.
I've got eight clinic patients
waiting, so this better be...
- Is that your hand?
- Can you forget that.
I was hoping you could
do a quick skin biopsy.
- Do something.
- Send him...
- to Derm clinic?
- Don't have an opening until February.
How long have you had this?
Don't know, for a while? I'm
getting married in a month.
My body can't look like this.
- Have a minute?
- Asymmetric, irregular burns.
He can't wait three
months for a biopsy.
Yeah. Give me a sec.
- Get one of these?
- No, what is it?
Bertha's family is suing.
You're kidding. They
said they wouldn't do that.
- You talked to them?
- I had to tell them the truth.
You told them?
- My brother's very ethical...
- I can handle it.
- I'm just saying that...
- Daria, I can handle it.
It was my mistake, I
needed to own up to it.
This is not just about you.
What about the department?
You're an intern. You'll be protected.
It's the rest of us who are gonna fry.
Hey, Dr. Rasgotra?
Dr. Rasgotra, please.
Dr. Rasgotra.
- How'd my diverticulitis guy do?
- Sepsis resolved.
- Was there peritonitis?
- Just a walled-off abscess.
Mr. Lotery's wheezing cleared.
No carbon monoxide on his ABG.
That's too bad.
Okay, thanks. You're
wife's still in Radiology.
- It was a rush CT.
- They're backed up.
Still in the hallway.
Go sit back down...
- I get an update, I'll let you know.
- Thank you.
I had a rough night. My friend, Mary
Ann, read my blog and went ballistic.
- What did you write?
- I said how a certain tall boy...
in gym class who
she thought liked her...
really doesn't like
her, in fact likes Jean.
I see.
And then when I woke
up my head was killing me.
Then you took the acetaminophen?
When I went into the
bathroom I saw the bottle open.
How many did you take?
Six?
You did the right thing bringing her
in. We'll be able to give you antidote.
- Thank you.
- It's not gonna hurt, is it?
- You'll be fine.
- Deep breath.
GI consult, LFTs and
four-hour Tylenol level?
Start mucomyst. We can't be
sure until we get the labs back.
How long? I just need
to go call my job...
- tell them.
- Phone's at the desk...
- or you can use your cell outside.
- I'll be right back.
So tell me more about this blog.
Why would Andrew do that?
All the research says
when you're honest...
about your mistakes,
they are less likely to sue.
Look, I'll speak to Anspaugh.
I bet it'll get tossed out.
Better or else I'll be doing
a ho stroll down the street.
- A what?
- Forget it.
- Doctors.
- Oh, hey.
I've been here a month
and I have an enemy.
I don't get enemies.
- Jeff Davis, you stepped on his frog.
- It jumped under my shoe, remember?
Hey, what's up, guys?
- Hey.
- We're having a pity party.
More Attending problems?
Andrew told the family he made
a mistake and now they're suing.
Do you think what you did was right?
- I'd do it again.
Then man up, go
in there and kick ass.
- Yeah?
- The more you rock it...
- the less likely they are to remember.
- She's got a point.
Right I do. Because if you
keep acting all soft and wimpy...
we're gonna throw
you out of the crew.
We have a crew?
I can't find your mom...
and we need to draw
your blood level now.
Sure, just get it over with.
- Ow.
- Relax, I haven't done anything yet.
I hate needles.
Can't you wait until
the mom comes back?
Blood has to be drawn
four hours after ingestion.
She took the pills at
9 so now is the time.
- I'll go find your mom.
- No, please, just stay here. I can do it.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. You're okay.
- What school do you go to?
- Claflin Elementary, over on Lincoln.
Thank you.
I'm friends with your principal.
He's really nice.
He's a great guy. We used
to be in a band together.
Would you do me a favor?
Tell him the next time you see
him that Henry Lotery says hello?
Sir, what are you
doing? Step back.
Are you crazy?
- It's not what you think.
- No, you need to move.
You piece of crap.
You twisted
bastard. I'll kill you.
He was helping me.
Security!
Okay, okay, that's
enough. That's enough.
All right. All right. I'm good.
I didn't do anything.
I need some help here.
I didn't do it.
Scalp bleeder. I
need a Raney clip.
- No one wants to believe me.
- Epistaxis. Some pressure on your nose.
What's the point
of their system?
- Tachy at 120.
- You need help in here?
- We're fine.
- I'll give you a hand with the access.
- Hey! I don't want him working on me.
- Go.
Cops are done with the brother-in-law,
they may need to talk to you too.
Dr. Brenner. Dr. Brenner,
I've got a complex lip laceration.
Align the vermilion
border with 6-oh.
- I haven't done it.
- You should.
Simon, I could use your help.
Just get Dr. Gates to help you.
Looks like a flail chest with
diminished breath sounds.
- This the chopper run?
- Tasha Overbrook, auto vs. pedestrian.
- Pulse, weak and thready.
- She needs bilateral chest tubes ASAP.
I was on my way to my first date
with this guy I met on Facebook.
Open an intubation tray.
A car came out of
nowhere and hit me.
Trauma panel, get two of O-neg.
- I die the day I'm to meet my husband...
- One, two, three.
You know when the last
time I got kissed was?
Let's concentrate
on getting you better.
We need you in here.
Possible orbital blowout.
It's gonna have to wait.
Check an intraocular pressure.
Could be worse.
Maybe a surgical eye.
I was there. He was awake.
This lady's more critical. Did
you try Dubenko or Crenshaw?
- They're both in the O.R. Your intern?
- One percent with lido, 32 French.
Neela, I need a hand.
10 blade.
- Neela.
- Call Andrew. Tell him I need him now.
Mitch Kellems twisted his ankle getting
into a fight outside of a supermarket.
- I'm Dr. Gates.
- I was passing out my coupons...
and some vegans
started talking smack.
- Can you wiggle your toes?
- I can...
but my giblets kind of hurt.
Neurovascular intact.
- Curtain 4's open.
- Give him 10 of morphine...
and a knee series
with a sunrise view.
I saw that picture you
had posted in the station.
- Max Gonzalez?
- I might've seen him...
couple nights ago in
front of Benny's Liquor.
Passed out, when we got
there he didn't want to come in.
All he kept yapping about was
how he lost his bag or something.
Still don't have
a BP on this girl.
Two units are up.
- What are you doing?
- I'm hooking up my central line.
What, you don't want
blood from the infuser?
Right.
- You all right?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
You wanted me in here?
Yeah, go in next door and
see if he needs the O.R.
- Me?
- Yes, you.
Sure, no problem.
Get T-POD, it's a
bad pelvic fracture.
Large hematoma behind the eye.
- I can't see a thing. Going blind.
- Your optic nerve is getting compressed.
The anterior packing's not
helping. He lost a couple units.
Vision loss from a
retrobulbar hematoma...
- bleeding from posterior epistaxis.
- Blood's going down my throat.
Frazier-tip suction.
Okay, Gottschalk the nose
and do a lateral canthotomy.
- Uh. You sure you don't want to switch?
- Come on, somebody do something.
Systolic's down to 60.
You're going to have to do it.
- Heart rate's 42.
- Amp of atropine.
Okay, let's get her to
Angio before she arrests.
Ugh. Please don't make
me drink more of that stuff.
Well, hopefully
you won't have to.
If your acetaminophen level is low
enough, you'll be able to go home.
Is that man okay?
- They're working on him. Don't worry.
- When are those results gonna be back?
Soon. I'm gonna go call the lab.
- Where are you going?
- To find his mind. Clearly, he's lost it.
Zadro saw Max on Halstead.
- Are you kidding?
- No, you want to come?
Tony, I'm working
and so are you.
- It'll take a half hour.
- What are you doing?
You didn't chase diabetic
patient who left last week...
or the AIDS patient
who went this morning.
- This is different.
- Why, because he's military?
- You don't understand.
- No, because you won't let me in.
You toss and turn. Every morning
you're calling Veteran advocacy groups...
homeless shelters. Not
like you served with him...
Sam, either you're going
with me or you're not.
T-POD's tightened
as far as it goes.
Okay, ask the blood
bank to stay ahead 8 units.
- Passed the Gottschalk. Now?
- I can't breathe.
Pulse ox 97.
Inflate the posterior
balloon at 8 cc's of water.
Ten-cc syringe.
- Chest tube bandage is loose.
- Oh, God.
- We're getting an air leak.
- Keep a hand on it.
I'll go and get some elastoplast.
- Okay.
- It's going in.
- Then 20 cc's anterior. Slowly.
Okay, both balloons are up.
Oropharynx looks
dry. I think you got it.
I need to get
this girl to Angio.
I could use some help
with the canthotomy.
- Lost the pulse.
- I'll bag.
- Starting compressions.
- Thoracotomy tray.
- Can we wait for Neela to assist?
- No, you can do it.
- Come on, help me.
- We're looking at permanent blindness.
Lido's ready.
Sir, I need to numb
up the side of your eye.
- Yankauer.
- Two units, type specific.
Major hematemesis. You
think it's just swallowed blood?
It's a good possibility.
- Maybe increased intraocular pressure.
- Or exsanguinating from GI bleed.
One way to tell. Hemostat and iris
scissors. I'm gonna open the eye socket.
- Hey.
- Lotto just closed.
Have you seen this guy?
No, can't say I have.
I heard he was asleep
out on your sidewalk...
and you called the paramedics.
You know where he is?
I don't follow them with GPS.
I just try to keep them
away from the front door.
Yeah?
How about this guy?
Look familiar?
That the same guy?
I wish I could help you.
He's numb. TRACY: And
he's out with four of Versed.
Then crimp the skin
at the lateral corner.
You're prepped and ready.
- You feeling okay?
- Yeah, I'm good.
- We can get someone to cover for you.
- I'm fine.
What's next?
Okay. Iris scissors.
Two centimeter cut.
- 10 blade's ready.
- Hold on, I've got a femoral pulse.
It feels pretty strong.
We got ahead of the
bleeding. Try for a BP.
Incision's done. The eye
pressure's still way up.
Cut the inferior crux of
the lateral canthus tendon.
- You're gonna have to dissect down a bit.
- Great.
Neela, we could
use your help in here.
I can't. Keep the blood pouring
in with platelets and Factor 7-A.
Let's get her to Angio and
bring a thoracotomy tray.
I may have to open her up.
Retract the inferior lid downward.
- Got it.
That's either a
tendon or the arteriole.
You better be
sure it's a tendon.
Well, should I?
I'm cutting.
- Did he bag the artery?
- Bleeding stops, we're out of the woods.
Hematoma's drained. We did it, Neela!
- Congratulations.
Get him to CT,
we're off to Angio.
- I've got the infuser.
- You stay here. We've got it.
Hey!
You want a ride?
I'm doing my show, laying
my normal knowledge.
This guy calls in and
says, "The economy's fine."
I say, "The
economy is not fine."
Then he breaks into
this long monologue...
about how we're
screwing up and I said:
"Dude, have you been living under
a rock for the last eight years...?"
- God. My left arm's hurting again.
- Just take a deep breath.
I can't stay long. I gotta
tape some commercials.
I need to check some labs.
This whole political season's
been way too stressful.
Well, thank goodness it's over.
It's not over. I'm
on five days a week.
You might need a break.
That is unless you wanna be
doing a radio show up there.
You have a recording
studio upstairs?
What? You mean I could die?
Well, we're all dying. Stress
just gets you there faster.
Let me get a nurse
to draw your blood.
- Hey.
You all right?
They moved Henry's
wife out of recovery.
- That's good.
- Into the ICU.
- She needed another two units.
- Okay.
I gotta finish up with a patient
but we can talk in a minute.
- About what?
- You're kidding me?
It's not my fault. The
street sign says no parking.
What does she think, I
made the sign? It's my job.
Gary Jones, punched in
the face during an altercation.
Swollen over the zygoma.
Once I start the ticket, I
can't stop it. It's in the system.
Why don't we take him to
Curtain 2, we'll do a facial series.
I'm pregnant and this jerk
won't let me get my vitamins.
She got into it with the parking
guy. Fell with a knee abrasion.
Let's move her to Exam 3.
Does he want me to
park around the corner?
I don't make the rules!
What man writes parking
tickets anyway, you wuss?
Get a real job!
- I'll catch up with you later.
- Yeah.
If my kid grows up to be like
him, I'm dropping him off in Omaha.
I will disown him!
- What are you starting?
- Abdominal aortic aneurysm.
- With an endovascular stent?
- That's the plan.
Well, if you need an
extra set of hands, I'm free.
I'll be fine. I should be in
and out in an hour or so.
So rumor has it that Andrew
did a lateral canthotomy.
- He did.
- By himself?
Well, actually I
walked him through it.
Oh, you taught him? I thought
Mighty Mouse worked alone.
I was with an unstable
patient. No way I could do it.
- I assisted him through the other room.
- So he was receptive to your knowledge?
He was a little nervous...
but he was able to incise the canthus
tendon and relieve the pressure.
- I'm surprised the patient isn't blind.
- What?
Well, yeah. An inexperienced
surgeon can rupture the globe.
Okay. You've made your point.
I'm sorry, I probably
didn't react very well earlier.
Good, because I was beginning
to wonder why I'd wasted my time...
- teaching you.
- I was never like that.
Right. I seem to remember a
blown triple-A you almost sent home.
Then the phrenic nerve I
stopped you from cutting.
Lucien...
And when you
cross-clamped the esophagus.
- What, are you keeping score? I get it.
- Who do you think you are?
Dr. Dubenko, uh, we're ready.
They call this a
teaching hospital...
because this is where
doctors give back.
If you're only interested in
becoming a rock star, Dr. Rasgotra...
I suggest you look elsewhere.
We don't need you here.
- We're driving around in circles.
- Make a right up here.
Tony, it's getting absurd.
- If you didn't wanna help, why come?
- Because I'm worried about you.
Don't worry about
me. Just drive me.
I'm sorry, Sam.
I'm sorry.
I told you about Keith, right?
Sarah's dad?
Yeah. We got back from the
Gulf, we were so messed up.
Nobody cared about
us. Nobody gave a damn.
We had no plans, we had no
goals. So we just... We cut loose.
We got high all the
time, drank like crazy.
Yeah, you were
young, it happens.
No. Keith started having
these nightmares, you know?
Alcohol wouldn't make them go
away. He'd get aggressive and angry.
And then one night,
he just snapped.
He punched Meg so hard in the
face, she flew across the room.
Was Sarah there?
Yeah. She saw everything.
Instead of asking
him what's wrong...
or finding out if I could help
him, I said "Get the hell out...
you're not my problem anymore."
And although I was trying
to protect Meg and Sarah...
You know, I turned my
back on my best friend.
And then two days later he OD'd.
So I'd really like to
try to find this guy.
Okay.
Well, we got good
news. No brain bleed.
And the eye surgery took all
the pressure off the optic nerve.
- My vision's better.
- Good. That's what I like to hear.
How's my wife?
Repaired injuries to
the liver and spleen.
- She's doing well in recovery.
- Good, that's good.
That doctor had
no right to touch me.
I was helping that girl.
I'll speak to him.
Are you gonna speak to the
jerks who hurt my wife too?
You know, you
guys got lucky today.
It could have been far worse.
And it might be next time.
I'd leave here in a minute...
move someplace else...
but my wife grew
up in that house.
Her parents are in a
nursing home 3 miles away.
- I understand...
- She has a card shop around the corner.
She's not gonna go.
Umbrella girl tolerated fluids,
going home with follow-up.
Great. I didn't
think she'd make it.
What happened to you in there?
- I'm just having a bad day.
- I'm the one getting served.
- You want to talk about it?
- No, it's okay.
Oh, and Crohn's CT
is negative for abscess.
Yeah, well, pulse with steroids
and have GI see him next week.
I'll talk to you later.
Is he acting strange?
Kind of. I don't know
what's up with him.
- You kicked ass in there.
- I rocked it.
- Yeah, Neela can't say jack now.
- Excuse me, Dr. Martin?
Oh, Dr. Rasgotra.
We were about to go get drinks
to celebrate the team's victory.
And we were
hoping you'd join us.
I'll pass. Andrew, you have a second?
- Yeah.
Thank you for trusting me.
- Doctor.
- For guiding me and teaching me.
- That's what I'm supposed to do.
And about last week, I thought
I was doing the right thing.
I didn't realize what's right
for me isn't for the team.
Look, I admire your
empathy for Bertha's family.
Your emotional
impulse was correct.
Next time talk to me or Dubenko
before you approach the family.
- That's why we're here.
- Got it.
Now go have yourself a drink.
- You did kind of rock it today.
- Thank you.
Hey, I was looking for you.
What was up with you today?
You know, that guy
could throw a lawsuit at us.
You Americans sure love to sue.
You think this is funny?
He was proven innocent.
So what does that mean?
He has the right to get treatment
without getting roughed-up by doctors.
What if he goes to Anspaugh?
Or the board? What then?
You don't know what
you're dealing with.
- What are you talking about?
- That guy's guilty.
- Hey, we don't know that.
- I know what he is.
What? What do you...?
What do you know...?
Did something happen to you?
I was 10 the first time.
My mother was wild, you know?
The type everyone wants to be around.
And she'd throw these parties...
that started on the Friday
and they'd last till the Sunday.
There was this one guy.
Bobby.
Older.
He has a grey mustache.
He'd always buy my
mom this cheap wine...
and he'd give me those little
candies that were stuck on the paper.
And when the parties were going on,
he'd sometimes hang out in my room.
Did you tell anybody about this?
My dad was long gone
and my... My mom...
She was unconscious
half the time, so...
They appear to be nice, Archie.
That's what they do.
Hi. I just wanted to make
sure you were all right.
That's very sweet
of you. How are you?
- Good, how are you?
- I've been better.
They buddy up to you.
I hear you have a blog. - Yeah.
- What's it called?
- "Meredith's Memories.com."
I'm gonna e-mail you
soon as I get home.
Cool.
They act interested in
everything you've got to say.
- Do you like movies?
- I like animation movies.
- I love all the Shreks.
- I love the Shreks too.
And then you let your guard
down just for one second...
And that's when
they make their move.
Come here. Let
me give you a hug.
But it feels... It
feels normal...
It feels normal at first.
Like your secret and his.
We'll be special friends.
- Let's not tell anyone, okay?
- Okay.
You better get back to your
mom, she's gonna be worried.
- Okay. Bye.
- Bye.
But then it fes... It festers in
you because you know it's wrong.
Like it's your fault. Like
you've actually brought this on.
You feel... You feel guilty.
I mean, I could've screamed.
I could've screamed.
My mom was in the next room.
Simon.
Simon, you... You need to
talk to somebody about this.
It does... It doesn't
just go away.
I need to go back to work.
It's still affecting you.
You have to deal with it.
I am dealing with
it. In my own way.