Callie! Callie! Callie!
The brain is the human
body's most mysterious organ.
It learns...
it changes...
it adapts.
It tells us what we see...
what we hear.
It lets us feel love.
I think it holds our soul.
Callie!
- Help! Help! Somebody call 911!
- Oh, no!
Help me! Help!
But no matter how
much research we do,
no one can really
say how all that
delicate grey matter
inside our skull works.
And when it's hurt, when the
human brain is traumatized...
well...
that's when it gets
even more mysterious.
♪ Nobody knows
where we might end up ♪
♪ Nobody knows ♪
Dr. Sloan, are you
almost done here?
I'm good in two
seconds. What's up?
Um, I... I'll wait.
I rocked this mandibular repair.
You'd never know this guy's
jaw was broken in five places.
I'm somewhat of an artist.
Not Picasso, because then
his jaw would be on his forehead.
More like Chagall.
Michelangelo.
I'm Michelangelo. There.
Done. What've you got?
- What the hell happened?
- Car versus truck,
that's all we know.
And her injuries?
What...? The baby?
- We don't know yet.
- Why the hell don't you know?
- Someone get me a trauma gown.
- Mark, you need
to sit this one out.
I'm not sitting this one out.
That's Callie. That's my kid!
Which is why you can't. I'm sorry,
you can't be a doctor on this one.
- Screw you.
- Sloan...
Screw all of you!
Look at me, Sloan. Look at me.
Look, maybe I don't understand
what you two have, how you have it,
but I understand this:
She is your family.
Callie Torres and that
baby are your family.
And the best way that you can
help your family is to step back
and let the rest of us do
what you can't rationally do:
Save their lives.
OK?
Mark.
- I'm in the room, you hear me?
- OK.
- I'm in the room!
Hunt, you're in charge.
All right, everybody.
Multiple blunt trauma protocol.
- Let's go.
- Tachycardic
and hypotensive en route.
Obvious head and chest injuries.
Callie?
Callie, we've got
you, you hear me?
- Everything is gonna be OK.
- She's hemorrhaging.
Wait, wait, hold on. Is that
blood coming from her chest?
Is it blood?
Calliope means... means music.
Honey, we're gonna fix you
up just fine. Don't you worry.
She went through the windshield.
- No seatbelt? Airbags?
- She took it off.
- ♪ We'll do it all ♪
- We need
to make sure...
How are her vital signs?
♪ Everything ♪
Callie! Blink for me.
♪ On our own ♪
- Set up a chest tray.
- I'm on it!
Let's get the fetal
monitor set up.
- ♪ We don't need ♪
-  Let's go, come on!
- Out of the way!
- ♪ Anything ♪
♪ Or anyone ♪
- What the hell happened?
- It came out of nowhere. I...
I asked her to marry me, and
a truck came out of nowhere.
♪ If I lay here ♪ -
Out of the way! Move!
- ♪ If I just lay here ♪
-  Get out of the way!
♪ Would you lie with me ♪
- ♪ And just forget the world?
- ♪ - Torres, stay with me.
You got that? You stay with me.
♪ I don't quite know ♪
♪ How to say ♪
♪ How I feel ♪
One, two, three.
Get those IVs up.
Make sure her lines are patent.
Depressed skull fracture
with a probable bleed.
Tell CT to get ready for her.
No obvious spinal deformities.
Hang two bags of O neg.
But she's A positive!
Scratch that. Type
specific A positive.
Is there a fetal heartbeat?
No breath sounds on the
right. Set up a chest tube.
- I'm on it!
- Lucy, is there a fetal heartbeat?
- Lucy!
- Give me a minute!
You two need to back up.
I want an answer!
Against the wall and silent.
- ♪ If I lay here ♪
- You hear me?
♪ If I just lay here ♪
- OK, reflexes intact.
- I need those drapes to prep
her chest.
- ♪ Would you lie with me ♪
-  Sterile drapes and Betadine.
- Check Morison's pouch.
- ♪ And just forget the world? ♪
I need a 36 French tube.
Keep giving warm fluids so
she doesn't get hypothermic.
Should we start mannitol?
We'll hold off for now.
♪ Forget what we're told ♪
♪ Before we get too old ♪
There's blood in
the right quadrant!
Push that LR in faster!
Bailey, where are you?
- Rapid infuser!
- - She needs a central line.
- I'll do a subclavian.
- ♪ Bursting into life ♪
- Come on!
- Call upstairs,
and tell them to prep an OR.
And where's that blood?
♪ Let's waste time ♪
♪ Chasing cars ♪
♪ Around our heads ♪
♪ I need your grace ♪
♪ To remind me ♪
♪ To find my own ♪
♪ If I lay here ♪
♪ If I just lay here ♪
♪ Would you lie with me ♪
- ♪ And just forget the world?
- ♪ - This monitor's not picking up.
- Doppler's here.
- OK, let's switch.
-  Derek, please.
- ♪ Forget what we're told ♪
- Pushing in chest tube.
- How we doing with the heartbeat, Lucy?
- Systolic's down to 72.
- ♪ Before we get too old ♪
If I'm gonna find a heartbeat, I need
everybody to shut up for a second.
Everyone, quiet. Right now!
♪ Show me a garden
that's bursting into life ♪
There it is! Fetal heartbeat.
- V-fib!
- She's crashing!
- Start bagging her!
- - Come on, get her on her back!
- ♪ All that I am ♪
- Watch her C-spine.
- Starting CPR!
- Get me an intubation tray!
- Intubate!
- ♪ All that I ever was ♪
- Hold inline stabilization.
- - I've got cricoid pressure for you.
♪ Is here in your perfect eyes ♪
♪ They're all I can see
♪ - Charging to 120! Clear!
- Still in v-fib.
- ♪ I don't know where ♪
Charge the paddles to 200!
- ♪ Confused about
how as well... ♪
- Charged to 200. Clear!
♪ Just know that these
things will never... ♪
- Sinus tach.
- She's back.
- Get the Ambu on.
- Let's move!
Everybody ready?
Grab that, grab that!
Go, go, go! Move!
♪ If I lay here ♪
♪ If I just lay here ♪
♪ Would you lie with me ♪
- ♪ And just forget the world? ♪
- Too many people! Get out!
I asked her to marry me, and
a truck came out of nowhere.
CT shows a large
epidural and subdural.
- I need to get in there. Is she under?
- We're ready for you.
All right, I'm going in. I need
a 10-blade... to Dr. Grey.
Bovie.
Wait, wait, stop. Her
anesthesia's too light.
- I can fix that.
- Oh, my God!
- We're on the run here!
- People!
Take a breath. Everybody, I
mean it. Stop what you're doing,
and every one of you take
a breath and center yourself.
There's no room for rushing
here. We rush, we make a mistake.
So, everybody, take a breath.
OK.
Just breathe. Callie,
relax. We've got this.
It's under control.
Just breathe.
♪ Two AM and she calls
me 'cause I'm still awake ♪
♪ "Can you help me
unravel my latest mistake? ♪
♪ I don't love him. Winter
just wasn't my season" ♪
Someone needs to
keep an eye on Mark.
Little Grey.
Eyes on Sloan.
♪ Yeah, we walk through the
doors So accusing, their eyes ♪
♪ Like they have any
right at all to criticize ♪
♪ Hypocrites, you're all here
for the very same reason ♪
Did Dr. Sloan come by here?
♪ 'Cause you can't
jump the track ♪
- ♪ We're like cars on a cable ♪
-  We need more lap pads - in here.
- More, please, more.
- - There's your subdural.
All right. Let's zip the dura,
get her decompressed. Hurry!
- Give me some bone wax.
- I've got bleeders everywhere!
Let's get control of this
before she gets unstable.
Body temp's dropped
to 32 degrees.
She's getting hypothermic.
- She's contracting.
- More lap pads!
♪ And breathe ♪
♪ Just breathe ♪
♪ Oh, breathe ♪
I need a retractor in here.
Her pressure's dropping.
If you're not needed,
get out of the way!
She can't take much
more. We need to get out.
She's not clotting well.
- You need me?
- Contractions have stopped. Go.
♪ You'll just make them again ♪
♪ If you'd only try
turning around... ♪
She needs time to recuperate.
We don't pack her and get out now,
she's gonna bleed to death. So get set
up for a temporary abdominal closure.
- So, what happens now?
- We get her up to the ICU,
and see if she lives
for the next 24 hours.
- If she makes it,
we go in again.
- I want a doctor with Torres
at all times. Dr. Fields,
what's your plan here?
- My plan?
- Yes, plan.
What if Torres starts contracting
again? What if she has preterm labor?
What if, God forbid, you
have to deliver this baby?
I may be a little out
of my depth here, sir.
♪ But you can't jump the track
We're like cars on a cable ♪
♪ Life's like an hourglass
glued to the table ♪
♪ No one can find ♪
♪ The rewind button now ♪
♪ Sing it if you understand ♪
You don't have to do
this. I know you hate me.
I don't hate you.
♪ And breathe ♪
♪ Just breathe... ♪
What do you need?
I can stitch up that nasty
cut you got going there.
I'm OK. I'm...
I'm fine.
♪ Just breathe ♪
♪ Oh, breathe ♪
She's my best friend.
This is humiliating! He's
benching me! I've been benched!
She's the best there is! He
wants the best for Torres!
It makes me look like a complete
moron in front of my colleagues.
They're not thinking about you!
They're thinking about Torres!
I'm sorry, but suck it up!
- What's her status?
- She's in SVT.
I gave her adenosine
and some diltiazem, but...
Go. Take a break. I got it.
Dr. Montgomery, there's a
chance the baby could survive
if we deliver by C-section
while Callie is stable.
No, there's not, because not only
did you fail to stop her contractions,
you didn't give steroids to the
baby to help mature her lungs.
So you can go, too.
Go!
Oh, sweetie...
I'm so sorry.
But don't you worry. We got this.
The attendings, we're all gonna meet,
and we are gonna
come up with a plan.
I promise you, we're
gonna make a plan,
and we're gonna figure out
what to do. It's gonna be all right.
You're gonna be OK.
She has got a hole in her heart. Needs
bypass to fix it, and she needs it now!
- Bypass would mean
a lot of heparin.
- It is a setup for a rebleed.
- The hypothermia
would kill the baby.
- Traumatic VSDs
- can close on their own.
- - Which is why we should wait
- to repair the heart.
- She's not stable enough
to wait.
- Damage control...
- This is Callie...
The risk of a
rebleed is too great.
Yelling at each other...
♪ Calm down ♪
♪ And get straight ♪
♪ It's in our eyes
It's how we operate ♪
♪ You're true ♪
♪ You are ♪
♪ I'd apologize, but
it won't go very far ♪
♪ Please come here ♪
♪ Come right on over... ♪
Yesterday we were at
her stupid baby shower.
I take it back. You can be
Callie's baby's godmother.
If there's a baby to godmother.
The only way to save
the baby is to save Callie,
and the only way to save Callie
might end up killing the baby.
- You've got
a hickey on your neck.
- What?
Oh. Oh! Oh, Karev
is turning all red.
Are you in love?
- Oh, you love her?
- Shut up.
- Love her?
- Shut up!
Lucy's the first girl
that he's really liked,
- since...
- Big deal. She works here
at Seattle Grace Mercy Death,
so I'm sure she's pretty much
gonna go crazy or get cancer
or shot by a gunman or hit by a
truck. So don't get your hopes up
for Karev's Big
Happily Ever After.
- Seattle Grace Mercy Death.
- Yeah, he's got a point.
♪ Turn me inside out ♪
♪ And upside down ♪
So you think that she'd have
a better chance if we took
the baby out now. Electively?
Callie's cardiovascular status
could possibly be greatly
improved. But we just need to know...
- What we want to do.
- No, what Callie
would want us to do.
The baby's barely viable.
Why are we talking
about the baby?
- Did... Did you just say that?
- No, I'm saying we give Callie
- the best shot she can get.
- Callie wants a baby.
- Callie wants to live!
- We all want her to live!
But what's her life gonna be like if
she wakes up and her child is gone?
What's her life gonna
be like if she's dead?
- God, it's not that simple.
- - It is.
- ♪ Wait ♪ - I don't
like it, but - it is simple.
♪ Wait for the dawn, my dear ♪
Gonna screw my girlfriend again?
For God's sakes,
we screwed, big deal.
♪ Wait till the sun gets here ♪
It is, Mark! It is a big deal!
If that's what it takes
to make another child,
-  my child, we'll screw again.
- ♪ And you will wait too long ♪
- ♪ He will be gone ♪
- No, you won't!
- Yes, we will!
- You are out of your mind!
Just because you're too much of a
man-whore to make any relationship work
it doesn't mean you
get to make a life...
♪ Wait ♪
♪ Wait till the sun
shines through ♪
♪ Wait till the sky is blue ♪
♪ And you will wait too long ♪
♪ He will be gone ♪
This is my family. I'm
the father. I'm the father!
♪ He will be gone ♪
♪ Ooh ooh ooh ♪
They have a plan?
Torres goes back
to the OR tomorrow.
Now, the big question is whether
or not to deliver the baby first.
They're waiting for
Robbins and Sloan to decide.
How's...? How are they doing?
You mean Sloan?
I think he's OK.
You want to go home
tonight or sleep here?
I don't know, I might need to...
- I...
- I get it.
It's Mark's kid.
♪ He will be gone ♪
♪ Ooh ooh ooh ♪
♪ He will be gone... ♪
Derek?
She's suffered
massive head trauma.
I fixed all the
bleeders I saw, but...
She could have permanent
neurological damage.
She may not come back.
Even if they manage to save her
body, her brain may not come back.
Mark was standing there...
- You have to tell him.
- I can't do that. I'm not... I can't...
OK. Come on. You need to sleep.
♪ Ooh ooh ooh ♪
♪ He will be gone... ♪
A baby born at 23 weeks
risks encephalopathy, ROP,
- cerebral palsy,
developmental...
- I know the risks!
No, do you? Because you're acting
like you don't care about the baby!
I'm thinking about Callie!
You don't think I care?!
- This is my baby!
- You're not being rational.
Oh! You never wanted
this. You never asked for it.
Why the hell are you giving
some opinion on what you...?
No, no! You know what I didn't
ask for? I didn't ask for you, Mark!
Because you know what you
are? You're basically a sperm donor.
This is me and this is Callie,
and we're together. So I say...
No! You don't get a say!
This is my family!
I'm the father.
I'm the father! You're not
anything! You're nothing!
♪ Wait till you doubt no more ♪
♪ Wait till you
know you're sure ♪
♪ And you will wait too long ♪
♪ He will be gone ♪
Wait.
Oh, this is bad. Mark just found out
Lexie's with Jackson. He's freaking.
I thought we were getting
away from Mark for the weekend.
There. He's gone.
You know what? Just get it,
'cause he's not gonna stop.
All right.
- You're gonna
ask me to marry you.
- What? No, I'm not.
In a few seconds, you're
gonna ask me to marry you
and then we're
gonna run into a truck.
Well, then you better
put on your seat belt.
I didn't answer you
because I don't know.
- Put on your seat belt.
- I mean, is this what love
is supposed to feel like? Is this
what love feels like for other people?
I don't really care about
other people right now.
Other people can do it. Meredith
and Derek, Cristina and Owen,
Bailey's got Eli,
Karev's with Lucy,
even Teddy's got that
tumor patient husband.
- Put your seat belt on.
- I want that.
I want us to be like that.
Because I love you.
- I do!
- Put on your seat belt!
♪ Girl, you got me
trippin' on sunshine ♪
♪ God knows you
just made my day ♪
♪ Since you came around
No, I just can't slow down, no ♪
- ♪ I want to see you
walkin' my way ♪
-  All right.
♪ Girl, you got me
thinkin' 'bout diamonds ♪
♪ And gettin' down on
one knee Maybe two ♪
♪ Oh, Lord People
may stop and stare ♪
♪ But I don't even care, no ♪
♪ Just as long
as I am with you ♪
♪ You got me
runnin' on sunshine ♪
♪ Ain't no clouds
gettin' in my way ♪
♪ I must be runnin'
on sunshine ♪
♪ Ain't no rain
gettin' in my way ♪
♪ Girl, you've got
me actin' real crazy ♪
♪ Chasin' tail like
some old dog ♪
♪ Ooh, I got this rocket ♪
♪ In my front left pocket ♪
♪ Ready to explode like a bomb ♪
♪ Somethin' tells me
your name is Lucy ♪
♪ 'Cause everything
keeps shakin' around ♪
♪ We can cop a room ♪
♪ Make these walls go boom ♪
♪ We can do this right
here and now, now, now ♪
♪ Runnin' on sunshine ♪
♪ Ain't no clouds
gettin' in my way ♪
♪ I must be runnin'
on sunshine ♪
♪ Ain't no rain
gettin' in my way ♪
♪ Hey, just get over yourself ♪
♪ This ain't too
good for your health ♪
♪ Hey, just get over yourself ♪
♪ This ain't too
good for your health ♪
♪ Hey, just get over
yourself self, self, self ♪
- OK.
- ♪ You got me runnin'
on sunshine ♪
♪ Ain't no clouds
gettin' in my way ♪
♪ I must be runnin'
on sunshine ♪
♪ Ain't no rain
gettin' in my way ♪
♪ No doubt ♪
♪ No doubt about it ♪
♪ And there ain't no
clouds in my sky ♪
Paralytics are off.
♪ No doubt ♪
♪ No doubt about it ♪
♪ And there ain't no
clouds in my sky ♪
Callie.
I know it hurts, but we're
gonna lower your sedation
and check on
your neuro function.
Don't fight the intubation.
This won't take long.
Can you follow
me with your eyes?
With your eyes, OK?
Can you squeeze my hand?
What about one finger?
Can you move one finger?
I'm gonna put her under.
- It's too soon
to tell anything.
- She didn't respond?
She opened her eyes, and...
- Look, it's just
too soon to tell.
- Derek, she follow commands?
Anything else?
No. Nothing else.
These are Dr. Burke's ex-patients.
Both stab wounds to the chest.
Both presented after their
initial surgeries with DOE.
He fixed both of them percutaneously,
which drastically reduces the amount
of heparin needed, so we
could avoid the brain rebleeding,
and we don't need hypothermia so
the baby would have a better chance...
Callie has a cardiac contusion, not
penetrating trauma. This is different.
But I read cases where
it worked in blunt trauma.
Well, I have seen every cardiac
structure sheered off by the wire
- in the loop in that procedure.
- Dr. Burke uses a technique
that doesn't require
the formation of a loop.
By placing an extra stiff wire
deep into the pulmonary artery,
- we avoided that complication.
- Even if that's the case,
- there's embolization
and hemolysis...
- Which all could be avoided
with a meticulous delivery
technique. It's genius!
No.
- What?
- I'm saying no.
It's too risky in this case.
The chances that we
could puncture her heart
- are too high.
- I did the surgery with Burke!
He taught me. If you're
unfamiliar with the technique,
I can show you
operative reports.
This discussion is over.
- Owen?
- I am head of Cardio,
- not your husband.
- I am not asking my husband.
I'm asking the person in
charge of Callie's case. Dr. Hunt?
I'm sorry, but... If Dr. Altman
says that it's too risky...
Cristina!
Mark's kind of right, you know?
I'm... nothing.
I mean, legally, I'm... no one.
Which is kinda crazy,
'cause I feel like your wife.
I feel like our baby's mom.
Can you just...?
Can you live?
Can you live for me?
Please live for me.
♪ You know there's
no need to hide away ♪
♪ You know I tell the truth ♪
♪ We are just the same ♪
♪ I can feel in
everything you do ♪
♪ Hear everything you say ♪
♪ Even when you're miles away ♪
♪ 'Cause I am me,
the universe and you ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh ooh ooh ooh-ooh ♪
♪ Yeah-ah ♪
♪ Oh yeah ♪
♪ When you're on your own ♪
♪ I'll send you a sign ♪
♪ Just so you know ♪
♪ That I am me, the
universe and you ♪
♪ The universe and you ♪
♪ I am the universe ♪
♪ And you ♪
You should go in there and
make peace. You both love Callie.
There's nothing left to say.
- What happened?
- - Pressure's bottoming out.
- Belly's tight as a drum.
- Flash pulmonary edema.
- Her lungs are full of fluid.
- Abdominal compartment
syndrome.
She's bleeding out.
Alert an OR that
we're on our way down.
♪ I'm on my knees ♪
♪ Only memories ♪
♪ Are left for me to hold ♪
♪ Don't know how ♪
♪ But I'll get by ♪
♪ Slowly pull myself ♪
♪ Together ♪
♪ I'll get through this ♪
♪ There's no escape ♪
♪ So keep me safe ♪
♪ This feels so unreal ♪
♪ Nothing comes easily ♪
♪ Fill this empty space ♪
♪ Nothing is like it seems ♪
♪ Turn my grief to grace ♪
♪ I feel the cold ♪
♪ Loneliness unfold ♪
♪ Like from another world ♪
♪ Come what may ♪
♪ I won't fade away ♪
♪ But I know I might change ♪
♪ Nothing comes easily ♪
♪ Fill this empty space ♪
♪ Nothing is like it was ♪
♪ Turn my grief to grace ♪
♪ Nothing comes easily ♪
♪ Where do I begin? ♪
♪ Nothing can bring me peace ♪
♪ I've lost everything ♪
♪ I just wanna
feel your embrace ♪
We should say a prayer.
She'd want us to pray.
I haven't stopped
praying since yesterday.
Definitely got
some new bleeding.
Remove the abdominal packs
carefully. They may be stuck. Irrigation.
- Starting to cannulate.
- Slowly push the heparin.
- We've got blood!
- Damn it.
- We gotta go back in.
- It's the heparin.
Dr. Altman, we can still
do the percutaneous repair.
- It'll work, I know it will.
- Dr. Yang, the decision's been
made.
Get me more lap pads, I got
a lot of bleeding down here.
- Baby's having decels.
- This is not working.
Yang is right. We need to reverse the
heparin and try the percutaneous repair.
- What? No. I can do this.
- Get me a percutaneous catheter
kit
and flip on the echo. I'm
going up through the groin.
- No, I said I've got this!
- Avery, can you assist?
Dr. Altman, stabilize
the heart and step back.
No, I can do this. I
just need to... Damn it.
Dr. Altman.
Dr. Altman! Step away.
You can do this.
One step at a time.
♪ Step one: You
say we need to talk ♪
♪ He walks You say
sit down, it's just a talk ♪
♪ He smiles politely back
at you You stare politely ♪
- ♪ Right on through ♪
- Removing needle
over the guide wire.
- Catheter.
- Forceps. Suction to Dr. Grey.
♪ Some sort of window to your right
as he goes left and you stay right ♪
♪ Between the lines of
fear and blame you begin ♪
- ♪ To wonder why you came ♪ -
It's going in easy. Get the TEE ready.
♪ Where did I go
wrong? I lost a friend ♪
♪ Somewhere along in the
bitterness And I would have stayed up ♪
♪ With you all night ♪
♪ Had I known ♪
♪ How to save a life ♪
Still got active bleeding
coming from somewhere.
- Let's recheck the
retroperitoneum.
- I've got access.
♪ Let him know
that you know best ♪
♪ 'Cause, after all,
you do know best... ♪
- Forceps. Get me some suction.
- Clamp.
- Give me a tie, please.
- - Brain is decompressing.
Balloon is advanced.
Extra-stiff guide wire, please.
Brain bleed has been controlled.
♪ Lay down a list ♪
- ♪ Of what is wrong ♪
- Occluder's in.
- Turn on the Doppler.
- ♪ The things you've
told him all along ♪
♪ And pray to God
he hears you... ♪
Got minimal residual VSD flow.
Good. Then we're
done here. Pulling out.
I got a lumbar vein avulsed in
the vena cava. Two Allis clamps!
- Ventricular rhythm.
- ♪ Where did I go wrong? ♪
Damn it, she's bradying down.
Pressure's down, 55 systolic!
- Pulse is down to 40, and dropping!
- - One of atropine!
CVP and arterial
pressures shot up.
It might be an air embolus.
- Pull back on the PA catheter.
- - Hang more FFP
- and Factor VII.
- We're losing her.
We've already replaced...
Starting cardiac massage.
- Push one of epi!
- Find whatever's bleeding
- and shut it down.
- How about an amp of bicarb?
♪ As he begins to
raise his voice... ♪
Push three of epi and
another of atropine!
Richard, you have one minute to get
her heart back or I'm taking the baby out.
♪ Drive until you lose the
road Or break with the ones... ♪
Come on, come on!
♪ He will do one of two things ♪
♪ He will admit to everything ♪
♪ Or he'll say he's
just not the same ♪
♪ And you'll begin to
wonder why you came ♪
♪ Where did I go wrong? ♪
- Is she breathing?
- Her color's bad.
Stimulate and suction
and get some access.
♪ And I would have
stayed up with you all night ♪
♪ Had I known
how to save a life ♪
- ♪ Where did I go wrong? ♪ -
Not getting a heartbeat. Dr. Karev?
- I could use a hand.
- Go.
Get those monitors on.
Ventilate. Apgar still zero.
- Come on, baby.
- There it is.
- Torres is coming back.
- Systolic's 70 and rising.
I'm getting no chest
rise with the bagging.
- We should intubate.
- OK, do it.
Tube's in. Starting ventilation.
♪ How to save a life ♪
Move.
Continue compression
suction through the tube.
Got it. Bleeding's controlled.
- ICP's stable.
- Push nine cc's of LR,
.05 cc's of epi
and .5 of bicarb.
Give me another 2-0
vicryl. I'm almost done.
♪ How to save a life... ♪
I have a heartbeat.
- Mom's heart is strong.
- ♪ How to save a life ♪
We've done everything we can. Now
we just have to wait for her to wake up.
And the fact that
she barely responded
when you weaned her
off the paralytics before?
It could mean she
wasn't ready to wake up.
- Or?
- Or it could mean
her brain has been
compromised, and...
she's not going to wake up.
You're not nothing.
We have a kid together.
You're a mom.
I'm a dad.
I'm sorry.
She's gonna wake up.
She has to wake up.
Yesterday, at
that baby shower...
I was jealous of Callie
because she got pregnant...
without trying.
And we try.
I get shots, I take
my temperature,
I put my legs in
the air and nothing.
The universe says, "Screw you,
Meredith," and gives Callie a kid...
and then puts Callie
through a windshield.
I mean, what the
hell is going on?
What's the point?
I mean, is there
a reason for this?
Because if you can think of
a reason, any reason at all,
why the universe
is so screwed up...
and random and mean, now would
be an amazingly good time to tell me
- because I really
need some answers!
- I know. I know. I know.
I know. Listen.
I will make sure we have
a baby. I promise you.
One way or another.
You and I will be
parents. I promise you.
OK?
She's... She's really small.
But she's strong.
She's one pound,
one ounce of strong,
fighting against all
the complications.
She's got beautiful black
hair, Calliope. Beautiful hair.
She's... She's beautiful.
She can't open her eyes yet.
But I can tell, she's
looking for you.
OK? She's asking for you.
- You sleeping at home tonight?
- Look.
I am not the kind of guy
that waits around for the girl
who's still in love with
someone else. I'm just not.
Jackson.
Let's go home.
And let's put her on a low
dose of dopamine. Dr. Altman.
Um, is there...?
Did you have anything
you wanted to add?
- I can't teach you anymore.
- What?
If you refuse to learn,
if you won't listen,
- I can't teach you.
- I'm sorry...
Find someone else to learn from.
Yes...
Oh, my God. Oh, my God! Callie?
- Yes.
- Callie?
- What? What?
I'll marry you.
Yes. Yes.