This job
was hard enough before.
Now, it's a nightmare.
Well, you're the chief, right?
That's your job.
Are you okay, Crockett?
Every time I see kids
with leukemia, I think
about my little girl.
Dr. Halstead?
Sabeena Virani.
We're running a trial at Med.
Dr. Ramsey recommended you.
Thanks. Another time,
I might be interested.
I got a lot
going on right now.
You said drug addicts
can replace drugs
with romance.
You think that's maybe
what happened here?
I can't be the reason
you stay sober.
Well, a little more leeway
would've been nice.
All my stuff's packed up
and ready to go.
Fine. Just let me know.
But don't go cashing
that deposit check.
That apartment I had lined up?
Mmm-hmm?
It's infested with bed bugs.
Ew.
Can't you stay at Hannah's
for a few more nights?
No. She let her lease go.
She's headed
for the West Coast
when she gets out of rehab.
Well, if you need a place
to stay, there's always room
at Club Med.
There's no one in my life
I have to quarantine from.
It's just me. And my stuff.
Here I am,
another failed relationship
and no place to live.
I'm no further along
than when I was
a first-year resident.
I wouldn't go that far.
With Lanik quitting,
you could be named Chief.
Me?
No attending's been
in the ED longer than you.
You're a zealot
for your patients.
Why not you?
I honestly hadn't even
thought about it.
Well, maybe
you should start.
You might get that office.
Then you'll have
somewhere to put
all that stuff of yours.
Incoming. It's got
your name on it.
What happened?
Jerome Kirk, 56 years old.
Lost control of his car,
hit a lamp post.
Rapid tested negative
for COVID en route.
GCS 14, BP low at 90/60.
No breath sounds on the right.
I need an X-ray!
One, two, three.
Yep. Can't hear
anything, either.
I took the wrong turn.
Easy, Mr. Kirk. Let's get
this X-ray, and then you can
tell me all about it.
Clear!
Right-sided pneumothorax,
but there's air in the
mediastinum between the lungs.
That's strange.
Mr. Kirk, your right lung
has collapsed,
I'm gonna place a tube
to help it reinflate.
Okay, now what were you
saying before, something
about a wrong turn?
What did I say?
I think you were trying
to tell me how it happened.
The accident.
I was in a car accident?
Maybe you hit your head
in the process?
No?
Right after this, let's send
Mr. Kirk for a panscan.
I wanna make sure
nothing else is bothering him.
My heart's doing great, Mama.
Is that true, April?
We're on top of it.
We've established
a baseline echo, we have her
on continuous monitoring.
And because of COVID, we're
paying extra close attention.
I found an article
on the Internet about what
patients with cardiomyopathy
need to know
about the coronavirus.
I'll send it to the doctors.
You don't need to do that...
Go ahead, Alejandra.
No harm in sharing an article.
I should go.
My shift starts soon.
Mama, you said
you'd stop working
at the hotel.
I have to work, Yesenia.
Talk to you
later, Alejandra.
Okay.
She's so stubborn. I know
she takes off her mask
when it bothers her.
What if she gets sick?
Who'll take care of her
while I'm in here?
Hey.
Then we just have
to get you better,
so you can go home. Okay?
Hey. Come on.
Goodwin is making
an announcement.
As you all know, Dr. Lanik
has stepped down
as interim Chief of the ED.
And after
careful consideration,
the board and I
have come to a decision
on his replacement.
So, I am proud to announce
your new Chief
is Dr. Ethan Choi.
Nice work, yeah.
Congrats, man.
You okay?
Yeah.
Twenty-four-year-old female,
pregnant, complaining
of severe nausea and fatigue.
Started vomiting
this morning.
Records show
she's at 37 weeks.
Where'd they
bring her in from?
Cook County Jail.
Name's Aisha Barnes.
Okay. Thanks.
Hey. Uh, are those
cuffs necessary?
We can remove them
at your request.
But we prefer to keep them on
when dealing
with violent offenders.
Oh. Okay. Um...
I'll let
you know, then. Thanks.
Good morning, Aisha.
I'm Dr. Manning.
How are you feeling?
Like I'm gonna explode.
Thirty-seven weeks?
Not much longer, now.
So it says here, you started
feeling sick this morning?
It didn't start this morning.
I've been feeling sick
for over a week.
The nausea?
Yeah, and I get these
insane headaches,
like, on and off.
I kept telling them
in the infirmary,
but they wouldn't listen,
until I threw up
in the mess today.
Hmm.
BP 162/110.
Okay.
162/110 is a little higher
than we'd like to see.
Do you have any history
of hypertension?
I don't think so.
Doesn't it say in there?
Uh, no. No, it doesn't.
You're gonna get them
to take these cuffs off?
Um...
It's all right,
I can work around 'em.
Yeah. You know,
I heard them out there,
calling me a violent offender.
Just like the cop at my trial.
Told everybody I was
resisting arrest,
but all I did was push him
'cause he was harassing
my cousin.
And I served my time.
I'm sorry.
Let's warm up
the ultrasound.
The only reason
I'm back in jail is
'cause of a busted taillight.
Damn probation officer
called it a violation
of my parole.
I can't even get a court date,
so a judge can weigh in.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Yeah, I can tell.
Uh...
Why don't we see
how your baby's doing, okay?
With your free hand, would you
mind lifting up your shirt
over your stomach for me?
lifting up your shirt
over your stomach?
You a licensed OB?
I specialize
in Emergency Medicine
and Pediatrics.
I wanna see someone
who knows what they're doing.
I am more than qualified
to perform a preliminary exam.
I wanna see
a licensed OB.
And you can't do anything else
until I see one.
Okay. Um, I will send
someone down from OB.
All right.
That's subdural air,
a pneumocephalus.
A what?
So, there's a pocket of air
trapped in the front
of your head, Mr. Kirk.
Is that bad?
Very.
For that much air,
it's just hard to believe
there's not any bruising
indicating blunt head trauma
from the car accident.
It could be something else
causing it.
Previous surgeries,
tumors, infections.
However the air got there,
we have to get it out.
Right. What's the best way?
Burr a hole in his head.
My head?
Anything less invasive?
I suppose we could
put it on hold for now.
Put him on high flow oxygen,
raise his bed 45 degrees,
see if venous
drainage helps.
Thanks, Sam.
Ah.
Here he comes. The new Chief.
Couldn't happen
to a nicer guy.
That's Sam.
But, seriously,
congratulations, man.
Well deserved.
Thanks, Will.
Appreciate that.
Hey, how's your case going?
A bit of a mystery,
but I'll crack it eventually.
Maybe I can help.
Um... Right now I'm good,
but thanks.
Actually, Will, as Chief,
I'd like to take a more
hands-on approach.
Help out where I can.
Great. I'm sending it
to you now.
Thanks.
So, Mr. Kirk crashed his car
into a lamp post.
He had a pneumothorax
I treated with a chest tube.
But the CT shows air
in his mediastinum
and his head.
He had a pneumothorax
from the crash.
Big blunt hit like that,
the air could go
all kinds of places.
Or maybe the air was there
before the car accident,
creating
intracranial pressure.
If the air wasn't there
from the crash,
then how'd it get there?
Jerome's medical records show
he had a cardiac ablation
in East Mercy
three weeks ago.
If the surgeon
was overzealous
with the RF probe,
he could have burned
a microscopic hole
in his esophagus
that's been leaking air
ever since.
Interesting theory.
I'm sending him
for an esophageal scope.
See if we can find the hole
before having surgery
scheduled to repair it.
Go for it.
Keep me posted?
Yeah.
Thanks.
Dr. Marcel.
Yeah?
Just the man
I was looking for.
Oh.
This about that directive
from Goodwin?
The, uh, shrink session?
It's just a check-in.
You know,
see how you guys
are all doing,
given everything
that's going on.
Right.
Everybody in your department
I have on the books,
except for you.
If I didn't know any better,
I'd say you were trying
to avoid me.
Yeah, well,
that's 'cause I am.
Ha-ha.
Look, uh...
I appreciate the invite,
but I respectfully
RSVP "No."
Oh. So, you decline?
No offense, Daniel,
but talking about myself's
not really my thing.
Buddy, we can
talk about whatever you want.
Sports, movies. Look...
Thanksgiving's coming up.
I need a new stuffing recipe.
I'm serious.
You got some fantastic
ancient Cajun family recipe
you care to share with me?
How soon can I
get this over with?
Dr. Manning?
You needed a consult.
Ah! Are you
the new OBG-YN?
Angela Douglas.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you. Thanks for
coming.
We've got
a young woman in
from Cook County Jail.
I didn't draw any labs
'cause she requested
a consult,
but I suspect
she's pre-eclamptic.
How's the baby doing?
She wouldn't
let me do an ultrasound,
but looks fine
on the fetal monitor.
Okay. I'll take a look.
Thanks.
Dr. Manning!
She's having a seizure!
Magnesium.
Ten grams IM.
Damn it! Why is this woman
still shackled?
I was told she was
a violent offender.
Officer! Start an IV.
I need a CBC, CMP,
uric acid, LDH,
and a magnesium drip
of two milligrams an hour.
You're right.
She's eclamptic.
I'm gonna have to
deliver this baby.
I'll take it from here.
Let me know
if there's anything
I can do to help.
Transport! Hurry!
Yesenia, talk to me.
Too hard to breathe?
Dr. Stanton, I need you.
What's going on, April?
Yesenia's working
too hard to breathe.
We should intubate her now,
before it's too late.
She's not hypoxic.
Her arterial blood gas
pH is normal.
So is her pCO2
and her SaO2.
No, she's using
accessory muscles
to breathe.
She's gonna tire out.
I've seen this before.
No. The numbers
don't support intubating her
at this time. Sorry.
Go get another doctor.
Excuse me?
Get another doctor
who's willing
to give Yesenia
the treatment she needs.
You can't talk
to me like that.
I know what I'm doing.
No, you don't.
I swear to God,
you get another doctor,
or I will come out there
and get one myself.
Help me suit up.
Yes, Doctor.
Don't think this is over.
I've been cooking for myself
every meal for about a month.
And all of a sudden,
it dawns on me,
I'm a terrible cook.
It relaxes me, though.
I sleep better.
You sleeping okay?
Oh, man. Like a baby.
Good.
Yeah.
Does that mean
we're done here?
You really don't like talking
about yourself, do you?
I mean, come on. Do you?
I don't know.
In certain circumstances,
yeah.
I guess I consider myself
more of a stoic.
Interesting.
Big on hiding emotion.
Never let 'em see you sweat,
no matter how much pain
and suffering you're in.
That you?
Nope.
No, I didn't think so.
But, uh, you did just
describe yourself that way.
You're reading way too much
into a simple word.
I meant it
more like, uh, laconic.
You sure you don't
need to get that?
I'm sorry.
It's my daughter.
She's saying
it's an emergency.
You mind if we cut this
a little short?
Oh, man. Long as
it satisfies Goodwin.
Just remember, you ever
need to talk to anybody,
about anything, I'm here.
Thank you, man.
So, Ethan's the new chief.
Yep.
Hey, I feel for him.
All that administrative work,
who wants the headache?
You must be disappointed.
Would've been nice
to have been asked.
But it's all good.
Ethan will do great.
Big of you, Will.
Because if I were
in your shoes,
guy comes in
underneath me,
then leapfrogs me
to be my boss,
I'd wanna kill somebody.
Any word on Jerome Kirk's
scope results?
Not yet.
But Ethan's been
asking, too.
You let me know
as soon as they get in.
Dr. Virani.
Good to see you.
Thanks again
for that offer.
I'm sorry you didn't
take it, Dr. Halstead.
How's the
clinical trial going?
Fine.
I'm about to meet a colleague
of yours, Dr. Lyall.
To be Co-PI?
He came
highly recommended,
and we had a good talk
over the phone.
Did a med school rotation
in cardiology,
so he's an excellent candidate
to study a heart failure
medication.
Yeah. Ted's a good doctor.
Smart.
Hey, Will.
Uh, excuse me.
I just talked to GI.
Mr. Kirk's esophageal
scope was negative.
I forwarded it
to you.
Hmm. I see.
The hole could be
more proximal,
higher up
on the esophagus.
That's where the scope
would miss it.
We need to do
a contrast study.
A heart ablation
accidentally burned
a hole in the esophagus?
It's kind of a stretch.
He came in
with a collapsed lung.
If there is a hole,
it's gotta be related
to that.
I say send him
for a bronchoscopy.
Why overthink it?
Where is she, honey?
She's in here.
Daniel?
Oh, for God's sakes,
Anna, really?
Mom, you've been in pain
since last night.
You need a doctor.
You should have asked me
before you called him.
You'd have said no.
I can't believe this.
You did the right
thing, sweetie.
Daniel, no.
So, it's your stomach?
I'm just constipated.
Mom, it's not just that.
Honey, I told you if I didn't
feel better tomorrow,
I'd go to the doctor.
Well. look, I'm here, now.
Why don't you just let me
take a quick look?
No.
Mom! Seriously?
Maybe we should go
to the hospital.
Come on. We can be in Med
in 10 minutes.
Guys, look.
I've been managing it fine
with Ibuprofen.
It doesn't really
seem that way.
You are both making
way too much out of this.
Ooh.
Oh, I'm gonna
be sick.
Mom, you're scaring me.
Can we please just do
what Dad said?
Okay. Go get
your Mom's coat. Honey?
Honey, we'll take you
to the hospital.
Get you fixed up, okay?
Okay.
Stanton's a resident, April.
You have to respect that.
Yesenia was falling apart.
I've watched it
countless times.
COVID comes on so fast,
we can't get ahead of it.
I understand.
But you set him off.
Now he's saying
he won't work
with you anymore.
Good. He shouldn't be
in here anyway.
Get him out
of the COVID wing.
Okay.
I'll move him
somewhere else.
Thank you, Ethan.
But no more chewing out
the residents.
I know your heart's
in this COVID battle,
but you can't go in alone.
Understood.
Have to admit,
it's nice having you
as the Chief.
Funny enough, I was gonna
ask you to keep me in line.
You know I can be
a bit of a...
Hard-ass?
I was thinking more along
the line of perfectionist.
But, yeah, I guess
that's what I meant.
I'll speak up if need be.
You've made that clear.
Hi. Looks like
everything went well.
Yeah. Mom gorked out a little
on the Valium we gave her
for the seizures,
but other than that,
no complications.
Good.
Aisha delivered a beautiful
and healthy baby girl.
Is this your first?
She is.
Mine, too.
You picked out
a name yet?
Mmm-mmm.
You got plenty of time
to think about it.
About 24 more hours
of magnesium to prevent
any more seizures,
and you should have
a speedy recovery.
Aisha?
What's the matter?
When they send me back,
they're gonna take her
away from me.
Look, you still have
a couple more days
while you recover
from the cesarean.
Okay?
Wait. You really need to put
those shackles back on her?
Uh, standard protocol.
She just had
emergency surgery.
Don't tell us
how to do our jobs.
She's still
breastfeeding in there.
If that baby ends up
malnourished because you were
just following protocol,
you might not have a job
to worry about any longer.
We can wait
until she's done.
Thank you.
All these protocols
and not one of them
prioritizes the health
of the people in their care.
Aisha said her complaints
were ignored back at the jail.
Oh, I don't doubt it.
And now, she has a baby
they can't accommodate.
I assume Family Services
will care for the baby
until she's released?
Sure. But Aisha and the baby
will miss out on weeks,
maybe months, of bonding.
Yeah.
All this in the name
of public safety.
Yeah, right.
I've been down
this road before.
I have another call
with the ACLU next week.
What more
can be done for Aisha?
Outside of dismantling
the entire penal system?
Mr. Kirk's bronchoscopy
results just came in.
Send them to me.
Uh-huh.
No hole in his airway.
I knew it.
Send him up to IR right now
for a contrast study
of his esophagus.
Mmm-hmm.
No. Mr. Kirk?
Can you hear me?
He's unresponsive.
Sats down in the 60s.
Heart rate's dropping,
too, 54, 48, 42.
We're intubating.
Twenty of etomidate,
100 of sux. Damn it.
I'm in. Bag him.
It's the pneumocephalus.
We have to get that air
out of his head.
Get Abrams down here now.
Should I call Ethan, too?
Ethan's not his doctor! I am!
What's this?
The air in his head
was compressing his brain,
causing him to rapidly
deteriorate. It needed
immediate evacuation.
By sticking
a needle in his eye?
Easy access.
He was already sedated,
and we would've wasted time
moving to the OR.
All right.
I'm almost done.
But I'm just treating
a symptom here.
If you don't figure out
where that air is coming from,
next time, I'm gonna have to
burr that hole in his skull.
That won't be
an issue.
He's going straight upstairs
for a CT surgeon
to locate
and plug directly.
You good?
Can I talk to you?
Yeah.
Just wait for the surgeons
to figure it out?
That's the plan?
Will, you said so yourself,
he was always gonna
need surgery to fix this.
Yeah, but if you'd let me
do my job, we might know
where the problem is.
You never let me finish
working up the esophagus.
I'm sorry,
but he's too sick now.
There's no time.
But there was time
for your bronchoscopy?
He came in
with lung trauma.
It felt necessary
to scope his airway
instead of going on
a wild goose chase
through the esophagus.
What's this
really about, man?
You meddling with
my patient's treatment.
You sure?
It's not about the fact
that I made Chief over you?
Oh, please. The only thing
that matters to me right now,
is Mr. Kirk's well-being.
Then, you agree.
The only option right now,
is to send him to surgery
so he doesn't die.
Dad, what are
they doing?
Sweetie, we gotta
try and give Mom her privacy
right now, okay?
Yeah. But what's
that long tube thing
they're getting?
It's called an endoscope.
And they are gonna use it
to find out what's going on
in your mom's tummy.
Dad, can we
go in, please?
Sweetie, I'm pretty sure
that she doesn't wanna
see me right now.
Dad, I am freaking out
right now, okay?
Can we please go in?
Dr. Marcel?
Yeah.
I don't know if they told you,
but the patient is my ex-wife.
Yeah.
And this is
our daughter, Anna.
Hi, Anna.
So, you guys doing
a little endoscopy, huh?
Yeah. The X-rays
weren't conclusive,
so, we're trying
to figure out
what's going on.
What are you
doing here, Daniel?
He cares
about you, Mom.
That's a change.
Mom!
It's okay, sweetie. It's just
the anesthesia talking.
Um, why don't we
let them do their thing?
Thank you, Crockett,
we'll leave you to it.
Sure thing.
I...
Dad, how long
is this gonna take?
Well, that depends on
what Dr. Marcel finds.
Well, it could be
really serious,
don't you think?
You know what, honey,
I think it's gonna be okay.
Let's get
a little lunch.
Come on.
Mi cielito needs a machine
to breathe?
This can't be happening.
Her lungs aren't
working properly, Alejandra.
She's in
respiratory failure.
But I assure you, this is
the best option for now.
My baby.
Please, April.
Please help me.
Aisha's broken taillight
was deemed a violation
of her parole.
I don't get how
a probation officer
can have that much control
over whether or not
she gets to see her baby.
Maybe someone
can talk to him?
Well, you could try,
but it won't do any good.
Her fate is in the hands
of the court now.
Her court date
keeps getting pushed
because of COVID.
There is an argument
to be made here,
about trying to get Aisha
a compassionate release.
Compassion's not really
the name of the game
in the justice system.
Cops are promoted
for the number
of arrests they make.
Prosecutors for the number
of defendants they convict.
Look, I'm not sure anyone
will listen, but let me
make a couple of phone calls.
Come in.
Hi. So, she has an ulcer.
I'm waiting for the biopsy
to detect H. pylori,
but I suspect the cause
might be an overuse
of NSAIDs.
Yeah. She did mention
she'd been taking them.
Yeah, it's perforated
her duodenal wall.
I'm gonna have
to take her up
for an emergency lap.
I'm sorry.
What does that mean?
Mom just needs
a little surgery, honey.
Surgery? Oh, my God.
I've done this
hundreds of times.
Your mom'll be sore,
but before long,
she'll be as good as new.
How long a convalescence?
Uh, she shouldn't stray
too far from home
for about eight weeks.
Okay. Thank you, buddy.
Mmm-hmm.
Gonna be fine. Right?
She'll be fine.
Hey.
Did you check your iPad?
I sent you
Yesenia Cruz's chart.
She's still
on the vent, but I don't think
she's gonna make it.
Sorry to hear that.
She's really close
with her mom.
It's just the two of them.
We should allow
her mom in here
to sit vigil.
You know there are
strict protocols in place.
Yes. And the only two reasons
that we would make
an exception to them ever,
are if the patient is a minor
or facing imminent death.
Yesenia is both.
Let her mom have
this one last moment.
April, she's testing positive
for COVID as recently
as this morning.
That negates everything.
Ethan, she needs
her mom.
I'm sorry. I really am.
But if the mother's exposed...
It's a risk
she's willing to take.
That's not a decision
she's allowed to make.
Ethan...
I'm sorry.
You wanted to know
when you're being
a hard-ass?
This is it.
ASA Lake, we want
to thank you for taking
the time to talk to us.
Not a problem.
I'm on call to
the State's Attorney's office
this week anyway,
and my boss asked me
to look into this directly.
It's about
Aisha Barnes.
She was transferred
from Cook County today.
Dr. Douglas
delivered her baby.
I'm familiar with
Miss Barnes' situation.
She had a girl,
by the way.
So, you're aware that
Miss Barnes is in jail
on a parole violation?
I am.
We understand
how much the pandemic
must be clogging up
the legal docket,
so, I'm sure her case
is just an oversight,
but in looking
at House Bill 1464,
it seems like Miss Barnes
is a good candidate
to be offered
a compassionate release.
That amendment
to the criminal code
only applies
to nonviolent offenders.
Miss Barnes was
convicted of assault.
She put her hands
on a peace officer.
It's our understanding
that she was defending
her cousin,
and all she did
was push an officer.
That's not how
the cop described it.
Oh, and the cops
never lie, right?
Dr. Douglas,
she was convicted by a jury.
Sir, we're not asking
to re-litigate the past.
We're simply asking
for your assistance
in getting her hearing
moved up on the docket.
Listen, I know the most
politic answer
I can give you,
is that I'll promise
to look into it.
But the reality is,
we've got somewhere
north of a thousand cases
waiting to clear
because of this
COVID bottleneck,
and pretty much every one
of them takes preference
to this.
I'm sorry, that's just
where we are.
How's it going in there?
We found the hole.
Repairing it now.
In case you're wondering,
it was in the esophagus.
I guess it wasn't
a wild goose chase
after all.
You were right, Will.
Good job.
Look, I hope you understand,
I feel I have to make
some changes around here.
Last week, when Miss Goodwin
and I discussed my new role...
Last week?
Yeah. And we both agreed,
the ED has not been running
as effectively as it could be.
I think that's
because of a lack
of leadership.
And I believe a good leader
takes responsibility
for everything
that happens on his watch.
That's true.
A good leader also doesn't
micro-manage.
A good leader trusts
that those under him
know what they're doing.
Maybe even more
than he does.
Your turn, honey.
Mmm?
You could
come over next week
and cook dinner for us.
Mom has always
loved your lasagna.
Why don't we, uh,
wait and see
how Mom feels?
She doesn't act like it,
but she actually really
needs you, Dad.
Sweetie,
Mom is gonna be fine.
I really don't
want you to worry.
Don't you wanna
be there for her?
I'm just a phone call away.
If Mom needs me, she'll call.
Dad, she's moving us
to Arizona.
What?
Yeah.
Move?
Why? What...
Did she say why?
She was
acting weird one day,
so I got into
her computer and...
You broke
into her computer?
No, no, no. I know.
But I found
all of these emails
from this realtor in Phoenix,
and he's been
sending her listings.
Dad, I don't wanna
go to Phoenix!
Okay, sweetie. Look.
It hasn't happened yet.
We're gonna
figure it out. Okay?
Walkie.
Hey, April?
You still think
it's a good idea
to bring in the mother?
Yeah, I do.
All right,
tell her it's okay.
Really?
As long as she's
dressed in full PPE.
I'll make sure of it.
I promise.
Hang in there, okay?
We'll get your mom.
Pick up.
Hey, Mama.
Hey.
How are
you two doing?
I decided
on a name. Nuru.
Aw.
It means
"born in daylight."
Isn't that pretty?
Yeah, it is.
Yeah, that's your name.
Nuru...
My Nuru...
We're gonna have to
return this child back
to the nursery temporarily.
Why?
My partner just
ended his shift,
so I'm on my own
until I can get
a replacement to sub in.
So?
So, when there's
just one of us,
protocol dictates that
the inmate remain shackled
at all times.
Okay, cuff me
if you have to,
but leave my baby.
It also states
that there are
no visitors allowed.
Are you kidding?
You don't have to do this.
I'm just following orders.
Do it.
No!
Dr. Manning?
Wait outside.
I really don't want
to have to do this
myself, ma'am.
Then, don't.
I'm gonna need you
to step out of the way.
This baby is not
going anywhere.
I don't have time for this.
No.
Natalie?
The thing is,
we're done, right?
Okay? It's not
gonna happen again.
And I appreciate you guys
understanding this. We good?
Yeah.
Thank you.
You got it.
I always say, negotiations
are like temperature checks,
cooler heads prevail.
Sorry, Dr. Manning.
It's okay, Earl.
They're not
pressing charges?
I didn't have to do
much saber-rattling.
Sheriff's department
really didn't want
to make this an issue.
Let's not do this
again, okay, killer?
You okay?
Seems so.
I convinced
a lawyer at the ACLU
to look into Aisha's case.
That's great news.
Yeah. That's what
I was coming to tell you
before you went Wonder Woman
on that guard.
We both
assault an officer.
She gets separated
from her baby, I get
a slap on the wrist.
I wonder
what the difference is.
You think it would've
been different
if you pushed him?
I don't know.
I'm a doctor.
I may get some leeway.
Maybe I'll do the shoving
next time and we'll see.
Hopefully, someday,
our kids won't have
to deal with this.
Yeah. Well...
We're nothing
without hope.
April, help me
with this intake.
Alejandra Cruz, 50 years old,
collapsed at the hotel
where she works.
Just tested positive
for COVID upon arrival.
April.
Maybe I wasn't
so careful after all.
Easy, Alejandra.
Save your energy, okay?
Please don't tell Yesenia.
I don't want her to worry.
Yes. How can I help you,
Dr. Halstead?
Would you be willing to talk
about how you and the board
decided on Ethan as Chief?
Uh...
Sure.
As we went through
our list of names,
the one thing we kept
coming back to was Dr. Choi's
military experience.
His familiarity with that sort
of structured system,
especially when you're filling
a managerial position,
we thought it put him
over the top.
Makes total sense.
But as a doctor,
all due respect, Miss Goodwin,
I have more experience,
I'm a better diagnostician.
You have a real talent,
Dr. Halstead. No question.
Wish I would've been
considered more seriously.
I've been here longer
than almost anyone.
There are a lot
of other factors
that come into play
when you're making
a hire like this.
But the job should've been
mine to lose. So, why?
Is it because of Dr. Asher?
Because I fell in love
with someone
struggling with drugs?
Well...
Since you bring it up,
that didn't help.
You know, sometimes,
you make very poor decisions.
I admit, I have made
some mistakes in the past.
It's not what you've done,
it's how you've done it,
Dr. Halstead.
You're impulsive,
you break the rules,
you trust your gut
over everything
and everyone else.
And hey,
sometimes, it works.
But it's just not
the way to run an ED.
The truth is,
I didn't even consider you
for this job.
I understand.
Thank you for your candor.
Dr. Virani!
Dr. Virani, hold up.
How are you feeling?
Okay.
Extra ice chips?
Oh, thank you.
Well...
You must have been
popping a whole lot
of NSAIDs.
I know.
I've been getting
migraines lately.
I remember
when you used to
get those from stress.
Mmm-hmm.
Like the time
we moved to Hyde Park.
Oh.
Yeah.
Yeah,
moving can be stressful.
Especially, uh,
long distances
to, say, some place
like Arizona.
How did you know?
Anna saw
some of your emails.
She's been snooping
in my computer?
When were you
gonna tell me?
Look, they've been talking
about transferring me
to Phoenix.
It's a great opportunity.
I suppose you'd be wanting
to take Anna with you?
You know,
if it happens, yes.
Do you think this was
an easy decision for me?
I knew this was
gonna go like this.
What do you expect?
You're taking my daughter
to Ari-freaking-zona!
Dan, please, can we...
Mind if I interrupt?
No.
Nope, that's perfect.
I was just leaving.
Yeah. Well, take care
of yourself.
Okay.
All right.
We'll talk some more.
Okay.
Hey, Daniel,
I'm sorry, man.
I didn't mean to get
in the middle of that.
Middle of what?
Well, I know what it's like,
I got an ex myself.
Oh.
Yeah.
Congratulations.
So, if you ever
need someone to talk to,
I'm available.
I appreciate that.
Hey, I mean that.
No, really, I do.
Okay. All right.
Hey.
Just came
from the COVID wing.
Saw Alejandra Cruz
was admitted across
the hall from Yesenia.
It isn't fair.
We just...
We have to keep doing
everything we can.
It's never enough.