Mom!
I'm thirsty.
I just gave you water.
I want juice.
It's bedtime.
Close your eyes and go to sleep.
Mom!
What do you want, Clance?
Oh. Hi, Dad.
Go to bed.
Can I turn the TV on?
TV's only for the
daytime. That was the deal.
I'll keep the volume
down. I just like the light.
Go to bed.
Dad, what if...
What if they come
to get me again?
Nobody is coming to get
you, okay? Go to bed now.
Come on, Clancy.
It's time to get up.
If you plan to be out at the
shore today, you are in for a treat.
We're looking at mostly sunny
skies up and down the Jersey coast...
I guess he's already up.
That's a first.
Well, I'll see if he
needs breakfast.
Hey, Clance, you hungry?
Hon, he's not down here.
You sure?
Clancy?
Clancy? Where are you?
Sweetie, are you hiding? Clancy?
Where is he?
Clancy!
You're gonna be in big
trouble when I find you.
Honey, come out right now,
wherever you are. This is not funny.
Clance?
Clancy?
Where's the sweat and the BO?
You've taken such pride in
bathing us all in your musk.
I showered at home.
And yet you're
earlier than usual.
Is this an intervention?
It's a little late, since I'm
not using drugs anymore.
I am, however, still
hooked on phonics.
If you did your morning
run and showered at home,
you'd be later than usual.
Thought of you in the shower.
How's your leg? You seem
to be favoring your left side.
I was hanging down my
right pant leg yesterday,
makes all the
difference in the world.
You've taken the
stairs every day.
Do I need a restraining order?
You slack on your rehab,
the muscle will weaken,
and your leg will hurt again.
Looks like the ketamine
treatment might not stick.
Or maybe we've made him
depressed because we're lying to him,
telling him he got
that case wrong.
We didn't hurt
him. The pain isn't...
He gets depressed,
he stops exercising.
He stops exercising,
the muscle atrophies.
The muscle atrophies,
the pain returns.
Maybe he stopped exercising because
the giant hole in his leg actually hurts.
The ketamine
could work perfectly,
and he would still be back on
his cane, popping Vicodin again.
You can't tell him. He got
lucky. There was no medical...
He was right.
We tell him he was right,
and we're feeding his addiction.
Without Vicodin, he's
only got one to focus on.
Well, he's not gonna
OD on puzzles.
No, it's not gonna hurt him,
but he could just as easily
have killed that patient.
We have a tiny window of time here where
House may be healthy enough to change,
and based on that limp,
the window's closing fast.
Kid is a product of an in
vitro fertilization pregnancy,
had all his vaccinations,
fractured his right ulna at age three,
chicken pox at age five...
He ever get his feelings hurt?
I'll need to know that, too.
You are "0" for one since you came
back. We just wanna make sure that...
Rectal bleeding plus
alien-abduction fantasies.
Most likely sexual abuse.
Penetration causes the bleed.
Trauma causes the fantasy.
ER ran a rape kit, found no evidence
of tearing, semen or pubic hairs.
I think we should
talk to the kid.
Why? In case he's
telling the truth?
You're a believer, aren't you?
Well, I'm just not
arrogant enough to think
that of the 50 billion galaxies,
100 billion stars per galaxy
and 10 million billion
planets in the universe,
that we're the
only ones with life.
No, but I'm guessing we're the
only ones who like shoving things
through our back doors. There
is new research indicating a link
between neurological
problems and bleeding disorders.
Perfect, especially if there
were neurological problems.
What part of hallucinating an
alien abduction isn't neurological?
It wasn't a hallucination.
What? You think the kid...
He's having nightmares.
Nightmares aren't a symptom of anything
other than wanting to sleep with Mommy,
which just leaves us with one
symptom, the bloody tuchus,
which can easily explained by a
GI problem or bleeding disorder.
Check his coags with a
PT, PTT and bleeding time,
and prep him for endoscopies
from above and below.
I'm gonna make a tiny
nick in your forearm, okay?
Then I'm gonna time how long
it takes for you to stop bleeding.
Now, this is gonna sting a little, so
you might wanna look the other way.
Are those windows locked?
Those windows don't even open.
They're just here to let sunshine in.
Good, 'cause they know I'm here.
Clancy, don't bother
the doctor with this stuff.
No, it's okay. How do
they know you're here?
They put a chip in my neck
so they can keep track of me.
I can feel it back there.
Clancy, you know there
is nothing back there.
There is.
Let me see. Lean forwards.
And they have this other thing, and
they put it in between these two ribs,
always on this side, and then
they move it around my insides.
It hurts.
You know what, Clancy?
I think I might have
found the chip back there,
and I think I might be
able to get it out. Really?
Mmm-hmm.
Okay, lean forwards.
Now hold very still, okay?
Got it.
I'm seven, not three. All
you did was pinch my neck.
Sorry.
His alien-abduction
story, the level of detail is...
Well, I don't know
where he gets it from.
The parents say he doesn't watch
sci-fi. He doesn't read comic books...
Great. You do any of that
medical stuff we talked about?
Upper and lower
endoscopies were clean.
So it's a simple
bleeding disorder.
No, blood tests are all normal,
and he clotted in six minutes.
So it's a simple bleeding disorder,
and you screwed up the test.
I didn't screw up the test.
So it's a UFO.
Unidentified Flowing Orifice.
Either you screwed up the test, or I
screwed up my analysis of this case.
If you screwed up, I don't
have to cry myself to sleep.
It's a simple bleeding
disorder. Foreman, redo the test.
How could I screw up a
simple bleeding-time test?
Maybe you were
abducted, lost time.
Kid's got a bleeding disorder.
Sure?
I had to stop the bleeding
myself after 25 minutes.
So you're saying
Chase did screw up.
Or Foreman screwed up.
Big hand points to minutes.
Maybe you got it mixed up.
Oh, snap. Foreman's
playing the dozens.
You're at a huge cultural
disadvantage here, Chase.
Take a couple of minutes
to think of a witty retort.
So we have contradicting
bleeding-time tests.
If we run labs to check his clotting
factors, we can confirm which one's right.
Yeah, testing. Nice idea.
Way better than trying to guess
which doctor's incompetent.
Looks better in
the paperwork, too.
Hey, Foreman, your mama's
so fat, when her beeper goes off,
people think she's backing up.
Where's Clancy?
He's asleep. He's...
House, Clancy's gone missing.
Oh, no! You take Alpha Centauri,
Foreman can look on Tatooine,
and Cameron can set up
an intergalactic checkpoint.
Let's pray he hasn't gone into
hyperdrive. We'll never catch him.
Clancy?
I had to go where there are no windows
so I could get the chip out like you said.
God.
I can feel it. I
just can't grab it.
Clancy, stop. There is no chip.
We're gonna clean you up, and
we're gonna go back to your room.
You can't do things
like this. Your parents...
Results came back. The
lab cannot identify the metal.
Said it might not
even be terrestrial.
Really?
No, you idiot, it's titanium,
like from a surgical pin,
like the kind the kid had inserted
into his broken arm four years ago.
Nice medical history.
That pin was
removed six months...
So a little piece broke
off during removal.
Titanium is used to build nuclear
subs. Pieces don't just break off.
Tell that to the
guys on the Kursk.
And how exactly did it get from
his arm to the back of his neck?
Body attacks any foreign object.
Inflammatory reaction could erode it
into a vein. Fragment gets a free ride.
To his lungs
maybe, not his neck.
Yeah, an alien chip
makes more sense.
The real mystery is that
you didn't actually screw up.
You okay?
Fine. Tripped.
Kid carved a hole in
the back of his neck.
Apparently didn't bleed
to death. Now that's weird.
He clotted on his own?
Sure did.
So first there was no bleeding disorder.
Then there was. Now there's not again.
Which is impossible.
Or Foreman screwed up.
Two out of three tests
agree with my findings.
Lucky for us, the fourth
test will be the charm.
So you're just gonna keep
cutting him? Until what?
This test is different.
We'll draw some blood, and see if
any clotting factors are low or missing.
But why haven't the other
tests... We've got three results.
They haven't been consistent.
One of them must be wrong.
Or two of them.
Is it possible the problem isn't
his blood? It's just psychological?
I mean, he almost
killed himself.
He wasn't trying
to hurt himself.
No, he was just looking
for an alien tracking device.
I have time for one more.
Can't blame you for
spending extra time down here.
I heard the Artist Formerly
Known as Gimp is back upstairs.
Oh, Dr. Cuddy wants that one.
She's busy. I'll take it.
Oh, my God! You're...
You're okay!
Have we met?
I was one of your doctors.
You were in a vegetative state
when you left here last week.
Addison's disease.
All I needed was cortisol, and
my brain turned on like a switch.
This is amazing!
Surprised you didn't know.
How would I know?
Not quite my old self yet.
Baby steps, the
doctors tell me. Now...
With rehab, you'll do great.
What hospital did you go to?
How would I... I wanna
have sex with my wife,
and I was hoping
that maybe you could...
Viagra? You're here for Viagra?
A bucketful would be nice.
Dr. Cuddy.
Hi.
It's completely unethical.
He was reckless with a patient.
He was right. But
he didn't know that.
He needs at least
some glimmer of humility.
Why does he need that?
Because other people have that? Why
does he need to be like other people?
He needs to be less reckless.
Well, you did it.
He's dismissing symptoms, looking
for easy solutions. He's in pain.
How much pain? Why?
You know this is
affecting him, don't you?
Telling him that he got his last case
right won't do anything to help him.
It'll make him less depressed.
Which might not help his leg.
But you don't know.
Just let me run a PET scan
on his parietal thalamic
area to see if it's sensing pain.
If it is, the ketamine isn't working
anymore, and he's headed for a huge crash.
If it's not, the leg pain is my
fault, and I will tell him the truth.
Too tight?
My parents think I'm crazy.
No, they don't.
They're just worried
about you. That's all.
I'm not weird.
It's just that weird things
keep happening to me.
Slight pinch.
If you make me better, do you
think the aliens will leave me alone?
I don't think they're gonna be
bothering you for much longer.
Are you lying again?
No.
We figure this out,
everything's gonna be okay.
Still with us?
Let's go.
Pulmonary edema,
stage-two hypertensive crisis.
What is happening? Wait outside.
Get him oxygen, and start him on
an IV drip of sodium nitroprusside.
Get them outside!
He's in ICU, systolic
is hovering around 170.
I left instructions to lower it slowly so
we don't risk hypoperfusing his organs.
Trade-off being that leaving his
blood pressure that high risks stroke,
MI and blindness.
I'm open to suggestions.
Solve the case. Kidneys could
explain... Kidneys are clean.
Tell me he's a
mutant-human hybrid.
It is a bleeding disorder.
Clancy tested positive
for Von Willebrand's.
I didn't screw up.
How could he clot on his
own two out of three times?
Maybe he cheated. CHASE: Right.
Kids always cheat on
their bleeding-time tests.
She was being metaphorical.
She's trying to sound like me.
I have no idea what you meant, but I
could smell what The Rock was cooking.
I meant, he's clotting right now,
and he's in hypertensive crisis.
Maybe the two are related.
What if he was hypertensive
the other two times that he clotted?
Hypertensive crisis can
activate clotting factors.
Even someone low on Von
Willebrand's could theoretically clot.
And the first time Clancy
clotted, he was all worked up
recounting his alien abduction. He
could've easily been hypertensive.
I know I get worked up when I cut
microchip tracking implants out of my neck.
Sounds like a cheat to me.
Yeah, we get it.
Okay, what's the differential
for a seven-year-old boy
suffering multiple
hypertensive crises?
We think the problem
is in your son's heart.
We need to do a procedure
called a transesophageal echo.
Okay, and that
will fix his heart?
That will tell us where the problem
is, hopefully. Then we can fix him.
Listen, this isn't
really part of my job,
but he's worried that
you think he's crazy.
Well, isn't he?
There are still plenty of other
explanations for what's going on.
It's important he knows you
believe in him, even if you don't.
It's clean. His heart
isn't the problem.
Why don't I have a high-def in
my office? I'm a department head.
There are no structural
defects. Valves are intact.
Tissue characterization is impossible
when the pixels are the size of Legos.
See, this is what
I'm talking about.
Foreman, you gotta
steal this thing for me.
Let me ring up
one of the homies.
The clearer the
image, the clearer it is
that there are no
masses, no clots, no tears.
The problem's gotta
be somewhere else.
We're gonna need a bigger boat.
You're wrong, House.
Think he'll make us break into
the IMAX before he admits it?
There. Where?
Right there. Left
side, no movement.
Well, don't freeze it.
Something's not moving.
How do you see something
not move if nothing's moving?
I need a laser pointer.
We don't have a laser
pointer. Well, why not?
Who's gonna take us seriously
if we don't have a laser pointer?
Right here.
A few thousand myocytes
not beating with the rest.
So you've found an arrhythmia?
That's not an arrhythmia.
That's a no-rhtyhmia.
Myocytes contract.
These aren't moving at all.
Go get me those myocytes. I
wanna talk to them in my office.
How's the kid doing?
Heart nearly exploded.
Still beating, though.
Most of it, anyway.
Why do they bother putting
age restrictions on these things
when all you have to do
is click, "Yes, I am 18?"
Even a 17-year-old
can figure that out.
What's going on with the leg?
First, tell me what's
going on with the boobs.
If you're feeling
pain... They're firmer.
It's called an underwire.
I wanna get a PET
scan of your brain.
I think it's hormones.
As long as there's no increased
activity in the thalamus...
Looks to me like those puppies
are going into the dairy business.
Then the pain can be good. It
could be muscle regenerating.
After you workout, you get sore.
Pain doesn't mean the ketamine failed.
Guess I should be saying, "Mazel
tov." Who gets to pass out the cigars?
I'm not pregnant. I need to
get a PET scan of your brain.
Boy or girl? You got a name
picked out? I'm not pregnant.
My leg doesn't
hurt. You're in denial.
No, I'm not!
Oh, you got me.
If I thought that my
leg was deteriorating,
don't you think I'd want to
take steps to prevent that?
Okay.
Gotta go.
Here's Clancy's DNA.
And here's the DNA from that
piece of his heart we just biopsied.
That is impossible.
Run it again.
We already did and
once more after that.
The genes from Clancy's
myocytes don't match the genes
from the rest of his body.
Alien DNA.
Anybody watch any X-Files
that inspired an explanation?
There are ways DNA can become
mutated. Extreme UV radiation.
That much sun, he'd be dying
with a healthy bronze glow.
Nitrous acid or
ethidium-bromide exposure.
First, Daddy was a
rapist. Now he's a chemist.
Various species of fungus
have been proven mutagenic.
Not unless the kid's been eating barrels
of celery or living in Indonesia or both.
Is your leg hurting? Is
that question helping?
You're leaning. You're sitting.
You're evading.
My head's hurting.
Please, someone, give me a
plausible, terrestrial explanation
for this kid's alien DNA.
We could search his home
for toxins, fungals and radiation.
Who cares what caused
it? A kid comes in with strep,
we don't conduct a search to see
which classmate he got it from. We cure it.
We know he's got the stuff inside
him. Let's get a scalpel and cut it out.
Where do we cut? Chances
are, it's not just in his heart.
Well, we got lucky with
the heart. Myocytes contract.
We could see that
these weren't working.
I don't know how the hell we're
gonna find it anywhere else.
What if we take the heart cells
with the bad DNA, and we tag them?
Can you phrase that in
the form of a metaphor?
It's the same way
we search for cancer.
The bad DNA creates a unique protein
on the surface of the affected cells.
We create an antibody that
recognizes only that protein,
we flush it throughout his
system, and the similar cells light up
like light bulbs.
Okay, let's do that.
You have to tell him.
He said he wasn't in any pain.
He's lying. Of
course he's lying.
We need another plan.
Don't talk about it that way.
What way?
"Plan."
It sounds like we're conspiring
against him. I'm gonna tell him.
No, you're not. Then come
up with a cunning plan and fast.
She's not nearly as
delightful as she thinks she is.
What's this machine do?
Makes a lot of noise,
and it's gonna help us figure
out what's wrong with you.
You think House has lost a step?
He's fine.
There. Clump of affected cells
in the bone marrow of the femur.
Explains the
intermittent-bleeding disorder.
'Cause I don't need to subject myself
to House's torture if there's no upside.
I'm telling you, he's fine.
We missed some
affected cells in his heart.
Explains the continuing
hypertensive issues.
You said the last case really
threw him, and now suddenly...
I was wrong.
So you changed your mind. Why?
His brilliant ideas on this
case have all been yours.
There's the reason for
him needing glasses.
Apparently, it's a symptom. It
means the condition predates...
You don't change your mind without
a reason. Now, what do you know?
House didn't blow the last case.
Cuddy cured the guy
using House's idea.
Cuddy and Wilson are trying
to teach him some humility.
Scan is complete. Three hot
spots, but nothing in his brain.
House's original theory was
right. It is not neurological.
Is he going to be able to walk?
His leg should be
functional after some rehab.
"Functional"? What
does that mean?
He'll be able to walk, but
not run? He'll have a limp?
If everything goes
well, he'll walk. He'll run.
He'll probably be even
stronger than he is now.
When we close him up, we'll
move over to his other leg,
snake a catheter up through the
femoral artery and into his heart.
Once the affected
areas are removed,
his normal tissue will
step back in, do its job.
He should have no more
problems with his blood pressure.
After confirming those areas are
clear, we'll start the final procedure.
We're gonna insert a
needle through the pupil
and get rid of the
abnormal cells in the retina.
Close your right eye.
Can you see my face?
Yeah, it's clear.
You can throw away
your glasses. We got it all.
Get some sleep. You're
going home tomorrow.
Thank you.
Do you wanna go for a run?
What do you want?
I want you to run.
When did you become an enabler?
I'm enabling you to exercise.
Vicodin blocks the pain,
you get through your rehab,
muscle strength increases,
and pain decreases.
I'd rather not become dependent
on pain pills to get through my day.
You're just like
any other patient,
running away from knowledge
that won't make you happy.
I'm as happy as a pig in poop.
You're scared the ketamine
treatment's wearing off,
that it was just a torturous
window to the good life.
What part of "poop"
didn't you understand?
How can you be so sure
it isn't just a sore muscle?
It's my leg. We've known
each other a long time.
You're not always right,
House. You've proven that lately.
What's happening to him?
He's seizing. I need clonazepam.
I thought you got it all. Yeah,
yell at me. That'll fix your kid.
Obviously, we missed some foreign
tissue. There's something still in him.
The hallucinations and seizures
indicate problems in the temporal lobe.
Sorry, House, it is neurological.
Looks like you're wrong again.
We didn't miss anything. Brain
scan was completely clean.
Our tag must not have
penetrated the blood-brain barrier.
Don't use an IV this time.
Get it right into the brain.
No cells are lighting up. His
brain is clean. It is not neurological.
His symptoms are neurological.
His condition has to be neurological.
His scan was clean
twice. It's not there.
What if it is there, but
didn't show up on the scan?
What if the tag just
doesn't work in his brain?
Brain cells are structurally
different, express a different protein.
So how do we find it?
Where are we going?
I am going to think.
Send the kid home.
What do you mean?
Make sure his blood pressure's
stabilized, and send him home.
What, like nothing
ever happened?
We cured his bleeding disorder,
removed all the damaged
cells we could find.
We don't know that we fixed
anything. It's only been a day.
Maybe these symptoms come
and go like the blood disorder.
It's more probable that
his remaining symptoms are
just a nightmare.
He had a convulsion.
May be epilepsy. May be
psychological. May be nothing.
If the kid gets sick again,
it'll give us another clue.
We can start searching again.
If he doesn't, doesn't matter.
Send him home.
House.
You're just giving
up on this kid?
You gotta know when to stop.
You don't stop. You never stop.
You just keep on going until you
come up with something so insane
that it's usually right.
Except on my last case.
Don't be pathetic. Just
forget the last case.
This kid obviously has
something wrong with him.
When did you develop such
strong opinions about my patients?
Last week, you were
convinced my patient wasn't sick.
Now you're
convinced this one is.
This one is a young boy.
His parents are desperate.
Just get together with your
team, spend a few extra hours...
Well, I guess we could amputate his
left leg. That's where we found most of it.
Maybe we should just remove
his affected eye completely.
If you have reason to
believe that that might help...
I'm not gonna start
lopping off body parts,
but it's interesting that
you give me the green light.
I just want you to do something.
You've been overly
supportive this entire week.
Either you're hormonal,
or you're guilt-ridden,
and it's too early in the
pregnancy for this to be hormonal.
I'm not pregnant. Then
what did you do wrong?
He had Addison's. Your
last patient. You were right.
I gave him one shot of cortisol
and he woke up like Rip van Winkle.
Oh, your mommy is in such
trouble. She's such a liar.
That's why you don't have a
daddy. That's why she had to...
How does one person end up
with two different sets of DNA?
We've been through this.
Our assumptions are faulty.
We've confirmed two different sets
of DNA. We re-ran the sequence.
I didn't say the lab work was faulty.
I said our assumptions were faulty.
We assumed he's a person.
Of course. The aliens didn't
just visit him. They replaced him.
You're being silly. What if he's not
a person? What if he's two persons?
I'm not getting the
metaphor. No metaphor.
Chase, you said the mom
used in vitro fertilization, right?
Yeah, they had
trouble conceiving.
Kid was right all along.
He was implanted with something,
back when he was young.
I mean really young,
like 12-cells young.
In vitro increases the
likelihood of twinning.
But he doesn't have a twin.
Not walking around.
But in vitro fertilization
costs around 25 grand a pop,
so doctors implant two to six embryos
to make sure you get your money's worth.
Problem is, there's not always
enough bedrooms for all the kiddies.
Two brothers get stuck
sharing. There's no bunk beds,
so they cuddle up to keep
warm, and they never untangle.
He's two people in one.
It's called chimerism.
Unfortunately, his brother's
like a bad doubles partner.
The guy just takes up
space, gets in the way.
Clancy's body thinks that he's
gonna put away the easy winners.
His brother just keeps
swatting balls into the net.
We gotta get him off the court.
So does that mean that you can
find the bad cells in his brain or not?
Sure, abandon
the metaphor. Fine.
Clancy thinks differently than
his brother because he thinks.
If we induce an
alien abduction...
Wait. What the hell
are you talking about?
The foreign DNA has got to be
in a portion of your son's brain
that makes him believe
that he's being abducted.
If we stimulate those
neurons with an electric probe,
we can trick your son's
brain into hallucinating.
Your son's neurons will light up,
and his brother's cells will remain dark.
Those are the ones we cut out.
You're talking
about brain surgery.
I'm talking about really cool brain
surgery. One of your sons will die,
but the taller one won't
be so annoying anymore.
So I have a twin?
Not really. What's on the card?
A light bulb.
Start us out at 10.
I'm not doing that.
That was all me, kid. Sorry.
You're in motor function.
Try two centimeters back.
He lives inside me?
Sort of.
That tickles. Stop
tickling my feet.
You're in sensory.
You're getting closer.
What do you see on this one?
Moon and stars.
So I am kind of weird?
We're all kind of weird.
No!
Clancy? We got something.
What do you see? The light.
Here they come, I think.
Brain waves indicate a mild
hallucination. Neurons are lighting up.
Any dark spots?
Area's too fuzzy.
Hallucination isn't
strong enough.
Turn up the juice.
His blood pressure's already
160 over 110. Any higher...
Riding the short bus is better
than not breathing. Take us to 100.
Area's still too fuzzy to
make any kind of distinction.
Crank it up higher.
You've already exceeded
the preset maximum.
Next step's brain damage.
They're gonna get you.
They're coming through the walls.
They're gonna take you, torture you.
You'll never see your parents again.
Clancy? Can you hear me?
Clancy?
You got them.
Yep.
We got them all.
Close him up.
Everything's gonna
be normal again.
You believe what
Cuddy tried to pull?
What now?
She lied to me.
She cured my patient with my
diagnosis, then lied to me about it.
That doesn't sound like her.
You're right.
Does sound like you, though.
What exactly did Cuddy tell you?
Nothing that your body
language isn't telling me right now.
So what was the plan?
I'd feel so humbled by missing a
case that I'd reevaluate my entire life,
question the nature of truth and
goodness and become Cameron?
Something like that. More
that if we told you the truth,
that you solved a case based
on absolutely no medical proof,
you'd think you were God.
And I was worried
your wings would melt.
God doesn't limp.