Previously on "ER."
This is Carla.
Carla, this is Dr. Corday.
Doug has difficulty
dealing with strong women.
I don't know about that.
‐ We work as a team.
‐ Oh, come on, what team?
Every contractor in Chicago
will hear that I have AIDS.
Do you mind walking me
up to the platform?
I just, get kinda
scared out here at night.
‐ What's the story?
‐ Motorcycle accident.
Left upper quadrant contusion.
It's okay, I can handle it.
But if my mother gets
another bill from this hospital
maybe I'm gonna kick some ass.
Maybe I'll start with yours.
There could be
some kind of counseling
for teenage mothers,
abuse victims, you know.
‐ Doug?
‐ 'Listening.'
I think a clinic's a good way
to keep track of people
who fall
through the cracks.
Okay, here we go.
I got it.
No, it's...it's a good idea.
I just don't know
that Kerry Weaver's
looking for new ways
to spend money.
It would be on
a volunteer basis.
Well...worth a try.
Right, you ready?
Yeah, I'm ready
if you are.
If I am?
This was your idea. Hang on.
Doug, I was kidding.
I didn't think you'd actually
go out and rent equipment.
'Now, now, you talked about
this fantasy years ago.'
I did not.
‐ Did I?
‐ Yeah.
Uh, actually, I think
you accused me
of taping myself with
various 20‐year‐olds.
‐ Oh, that was harsh.
‐ Yeah.
Was I right?
Uh...no.
You see all this stuff..
...I did it because
I wanna make you happy.
‐ Really?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
You did all
this for me?
I'd do anything for you.
Come on, Reese,
daddy's workin'.
Reese, I've got to study
for a proctocolectomy.
Come on, man,
give me a break, please?
Please, Reese,
please, please.
Okay, okay, okay.
Come on, come on, okay.
Alright, alright, alright.
I know, I know, I know.
Oh, boy.
Okay, hey,
you gonna wake up mommy.
You gonna wake up mommy.
Do you wanna wake up mommy?
Huh? Do you wanna
wake up mommy?
If you wake up mommy,
she's not gonna be happy.
She's not gonna be happy!
Okay, okay, okay.
Come here, come here.
It's just me and you.
Okay? It's just me and you.
Come on. Hey, hey!
Hey, hey, hey.
Hey, you wanna get funky
with your old man, huh?
You want to get funky with your
old man? Come on, come on, say.
♪ Papa don't take no mess
hey hey hey ♪
♪ Papa don't papa don't
papa don't ♪
Come on, Reese.
Come on, give me
a break, please?
What do I have to do
to make you stop crying, huh?
Okay, okay, shh.
Shh, I know, I know, I know.
Come here. Come here.
What do I have to do to
get you to stop crying, huh?
Talk to me,
talk to me, okay.
Alright, man,
come here.
Okay, hey, you wanna study
with your old man?
You wanna study
How's that, huh?
Come here.
Come on and study.
Come on.
Come on, come on, come on.
I know, I know.
Listen.
"After performing the colectomy,
take the distal ileum
"and measure seven inches
from the transected distal end
proximally."
Seven inches.
"Fold that distal end upward
to form a J‐pouch."
You like that?
You like that, Reese, huh?
You like forming a J‐pouch?
Do you know how to form
a J‐pouch? Okay, here we go.
"And begin stapling together
the two limbs of the small bowel
with the GIA 55."
Hey, man, you like that, huh?
Thank you very much.
And in seconds,
we will chop these onions.
'Hi. We're not here.'
'Please leave a message
at the tone.'
'Lisa, whose voice
is that on the machine?'
'Lisa, pick up the phone.'
'Lisa, who you there with?'
'Pick up, I know you home.'
'Sorry ass bitch.'
'Why you got to..'
'Pick up the damn phone now,
Lisa! You know I‐‐'
Hey, wrong number.
'Who the hell are you?'
'Put Lisa on the phone!'
Look, pay attention, dumb ass.
There's nobody here named Lisa.
You got the wrong number.
Goodbye.
‐ Hey, Mark.
‐ Peter.
Thought you didn't
drink caffeine.
Yeah, well, I do now.
Listen, you had your kid when
you were in med school, right?
Yeah, sure did.
What a mistake that was.
See you around, Peter.
We got Ernesto Ruiz
in curtain two.
18 years old,
through and through GSW
to the right shoulder.
You know, this
same knucklehead was in here
a couple of months ago,
shot in the chest?
He must walk around
wearing a bull's eye.
I gave him a gram of Ancef
and called surgery.
Three is a 40‐year‐old gentleman
with urinary retention
and Jeanie's working up
a 65‐year‐old woman in exam two
with abdominal pain.
Alright. We'll do
rounds about 8.
And I'll drum up
some more business.
Hey, Mark, take a look
at a patient for me?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Female, 65.
Recurrent right upper quadrant
pain over the past six months
becoming increasingly
worse today.
Temp's 101,
white count's 15,000
and she's vomiting
bilious material.
Sounds like cholecystitis.
Yeah, I think she
might need surgery.
Let's take a look.
Hi, Pablo.
No, Haleh's not here.
Is, uh, Haleh here?
No. She called
in sick today.
Oh, but today's Thursday.
I know, but she'll
be back tomorrow, okay?
Yeah, she be
back later on.
She'll be back tomorrow.
Why don't you come then?
She'll be glad to see you.
‐ Yeah, okay.
‐ Okay?
Hey, Anna, you got
any procedures?
Can't wait for the next one
to come through the door, huh?
Nah, it's for Fu's benefit.
I swear to you,
I'm going to turn that kid
into a functioning med student.
How many times has
he puked in trauma?
Twice, but the second time
was really dry heaves.
‐ Uh‐huh.
‐ How's yours doing?
Uh, he's not the sharpest
knife in the drawer
but he's a hard worker.
He hasn't puked yet.
Ha! So, you got
anything we can do?
You can cath the guy
in curtain three.
Perfect. Thank you.
Tell me if this hurts.
You're a good‐looking fellow.
Ah, Thank you.
Does this hurt?
Oh!
Last night, it was so bad,
I couldn't sleep.
‐ What about here?
‐ Not really.
Here?
No. Higher.
Can I have my hand back?
Ma'am...give me
my hand back.
Wait...handsome.
‐ You can handle this.
‐ Uh, Mark.
I think she's got
a hot gallbladder.
We should get an ultrasound
and surgical consult.
‐ Good. Do it.
‐ Yeah, but, Mark‐‐
I don't have time
for this today.
For the average
male penis you'll use
a 16 French
Foley catheter.
Those French,
they think of everything.
It refers
to the circumference.
One French is a third
of a millimeter diameter.
You wanna check
the Foley balloon for leaks
by injecting some saline.
You lube up the tip
with lidocaine jelly.
Now you are ready to insert
applying gentle,
constant pressure.
Isn't this a nurse's job?
Um, You need to know how, Ivan.
So...grab that penis
and show it who's boss.
Yo.
‐ When can I go home?
‐ Who's your doctor?
Some chick.
I don't know her name.
Uh‐huh. Well,
why don't you go back
to your own bed
and wait for her?
Hey, what are you
doing to that dude?
Hey, come on, let's go.
back to your bed. Please.
Uh‐uh, sometimes
it's a little tricky
'to get it past
the, uh, prostate.'
You all did this
to me last time.
Yeah, I wish I knew
who it was, too.
Am I gonna have
to call security here?
Come on, let's go.
Back to your own room.
'It's in, Dr. Carter.'
'Balloon's inflated.'
Okay, hey, hook it up
to the bag, Ivan!
Hi. Who peed in
your cornflakes?
What?
You're in a bad mood.
Just caught up
in this lawsuit.
Have to give a deposition
this afternoon.
Lawsuit? Over what?
Family of a gunshot victim
who died last spring.
It's a shakedown and they're
just looking for money.
Wow. Well, I'm pretty good
at giving back rubs.
It might help you relax.
Thanks. I'll take
a rain check on that.
Okay. Sure.
Um...I hope
that wasn't inappropriate
to say in the workplace.
Don't worry,
I won't sue.
‐ 'Hey, Mark.'
‐ Hey.
So, where's that going?
‐ What do you mean?
‐ You and the desk clerk.
There is no
me and the desk clerk.
Girl like that, you do
get into something
you better be thinking ahead
how you gonna get out.
A girl like what?
Pretty needy.
A, you don't know
anything about her
and B, if I was interested
in her or anybody else
I don't need your advice.
Brett Nicholson, 20.
Complains
of shortness of breath.
No fever, just
a little tachy at 100.
‐ Okay, I'm Dr. Del Amico.
‐ Hi.
Tell me
what happened.
Uh, I was just running.
I'm on the lakefront.
Got so out of breath,
I had to stop and sit down.
Have you ever had
shortness of breath before?
No, just the last few weeks
but it's getting
worse and worse, you know.
Any history of asthma?
‐ No.
‐ Okay.
Let's listen
to your chest.
Alright.
‐ So, you're an athlete?
‐ Yeah, I'm a runner at De Paul.
'Take deep breaths, please.'
‐ What's your event?
‐ 400 meters.
‐ Again.
‐ Best time?
46 flat.
Man, that's good.
Deep breaths.
You listening, James?
That's why I'm freaking out
a little bit.
Not being able
to run to me, that's like
not being able to walk,
you know what I mean.
Shh. Hold on.
What do you hear?
Scattered rales, bilaterally.
I agree.
What do you wanna do?
Get a chest film and order CBC
to check the white count.
White count doesn't
change your management.
What do you guys
think it is?
Uh, we'll have to wait
for your x‐ray.
Call radiology,
and next time
make sure the nurse
gets them into a gown.
Kerry, you got a minute?
Half a minute.
‐ Can I bounce an idea off you?
‐ Sure.
I see a need for some kind of
patient follow up in the ER.
You know, services like
psych counseling.
We patch these people up,
throw them back out there
without any hope
of staying well.
So I was thinking about a
women's and children's clinic.
Entirely volunteer staffed.
A women's and children's clinic.
We could designate an exam room,
two or three days a week.
Yeah, it's a‐a‐an
interesting idea.
Hey, I'd volunteer. I'm sure
lots of docs and nurses would.
I'll add it to the long list
of interesting ideas
we could implement
if we had the money.
Stony Island's ER
got a $100,000
from the department of public
health for a wound check clinic.
‐ Now, if they can do‐‐
‐ Carol.
I'm going to a budget meeting,
trying to see to it
we don't compromise
basic patient care.
I'm not looking to take on
any new side projects.
But my door is always open.
Going someplace, Ernesto?
Yeah, I'm leaving.
Where's my shirt?
Surgery's been by to see you.
For what? Bullet
went straight through.
A surgeon has to
explore the wound.
Nothing's wrong
with me, I'm fine.
‐ You need a wound explored?
‐ Oh, hold on a sec.
So, you're now,
now you're a big tough guy?
Last time you were yelling
for your mama.
‐ I can help you out.
‐ You're not a surgeon.
I've done it 50 times.
What are you doing?
Bye‐bye, chica.
You don't think I could
debride a gunshot wound?
Put some pressure on that so you
don't bleed all over the place.
‐ Maggie‐‐
‐ See you next time!
You know, I could
help you out there.
I called surgery.
Who was supposed
to be covering the ER?
You‐you're not gonna
be sick, are you?
Start with the
colectomy at the secum
and proceed distally.
His bowel's
very friable.
Metz.
How do you make a W‐pouch,
Dr. Benton?
Measure seven inches
from the transected distal end
fold it upward
and begin stapling‐‐
That's a J‐pouch.
I said W‐pouch.
Well, I assumed
we were doing a‐‐
Dr. Corday?
A W‐pouch?
'It's just the same
as the J‐pouch'
'but with two
extra loops.'
You take the distal
ileum and fold it
back on itself three times
instead of just once.
Quite right. Didn't get that far
in your reading, Dr. Benton?
I understand, that you've fallen
behind in your operative reports
and discharge summaries as well.
I plan to get caught up
this week, sir.
Perhaps your day would be
better spent in medical records.
Dr. Anspaugh,
I'm prepared for this.
Would you step out, Dr. Benton?
Catch up on your dictations.
Don't worry about
the patient.
I'd say that he's in
quite capable hands.
'Whoa, what are those things?'
Cannonball infiltrates,
probably testicular cancer.
Testicular?
It metastasizes through
lungs like this.
‐ Who's the unlucky soul?
‐ Twenty‐year‐old male.
Presented, uh, with
shortness of breath.
Sweet guy, college athlete.
He won't know what hit him.
Did he do the
testicular exam?
That's next, yeah.
If you think it'd be better,
I can do it.
Why would I think
that's better?
Because he might feel more
comfortable with a male doctor.
If it were a young woman
needing a pelvic exam
would you hand it off to me?
‐ I was just offering.
‐ Thanks. I can handle it.
Okay. Fine.
Great.
'Cynthia?'
How long has Pablo
been sitting out there?
‐ That guy?
‐ Yeah.
Ten minutes.
Will you tell him
Haleh is not coming in.
Try back tomorrow.
‐ Okay.
‐ Thanks.
Somebody call
for a surgeon?
Yeah, three hours ago.
I called, Dale.
Something about
a gangrenous toe?
Joseph Kupchak,
49 year old diabetic male
noticed an infection on his
left baby toe two weeks ago.
He put off coming in.
Oh, this is why
you quit surgery.
So, how's the
internship going?
It's going great.
'Mr. Kupchak?'
I'm Dr. Edson. I'm a surgeon.
Here to take care
of this toe for you.
Oh, Carter..
...this looks like something
you could have handled.
I want you to tell me
if you feel this.
No.
Alright, I don't believe
that they don't trust
a first year to clip a toe.
I think I clipped a couple of
toes when I was a student.
‐ Feel that?
‐ No.
How's Benton treating you?
Oh, piece of cake.
I got him handled.
‐ Hey, you know, Rocket's back.
‐ Dr. Romano?
Oh, yeah, I heard that.
He's letting me
scrub in tomorrow.
'Lab collie with a laser.'
Hey, did you work
with him before
you washed out of surgery?
I didn't wash out, Dale.
That's your story and
you're sticking to it, huh?
‐ What you got?
‐ Head lac, MVA.
‐ Excuse me.
‐ Head lac?
Gosh golly.
Feel that?
Uh, September 5, '52.
Hi. I'm Dr. Carter.
‐ Tom Angevine.
‐ What happened, Mr. Angevine?
Uh, going to
a lunch appointment.
Then I get this sudden,
blinding headache
and bam, straight
into a tree.
'Pressure's 210 over 160.'
Do you have a history
of hypertension?
Yeah, I'm taking
vasotec and lasix.
Okay, let's bring
that pressure down.
Let's start nitroprusside,
0.3 mics per kilo per minute.
'Get an EKG And keep
monitoring his pressure.'
And call for an abdominal CT.
‐ Abdominal CT?
‐ Right.
For hypertensive emergency‐‐
Just do it, please,
Connie, okay?
Okay.
‐ Hey.
‐ Hey, Brett.
You guys
find out what's wrong?
Uh, we have an idea but
we're going to have to do
a further physical
examination.
I need to examine
your testicles.
I'm, uh, I'm short of breath.
How'd my testicles get into it?
I have to check
for abnormalities.
Uh, my student can leave
the room if you like.
Uh...no, he can stay.
I don't care.
Alright.
Okay, could you take down your
pants and underwear, please?
Alrighty.
It's a good thing
I put on clean drawers, huh?
Thanks.
Whoa.
Oh.
Oh, man.
Hey, I'm, uh,
sorry about that.
It's alright.
It's a normal male reaction.
Oh, God, I'm sorry, doctor.
I‐I'm sorry, I can't do this.
There's nothing to be
embarrassed about, Brett.
‐ Uh, Brett‐‐
‐ Okay, just wait, just wait.
It's really not a problem.
Okay. Okay.
I'm sorry, It's really important
that we finish the physical‐‐
Just give me a minute. Okay?
Alright?
Geez.
Carter, tell me
about your hypertensive
crisis Mr. Angevine.
Presented as a minor trauma
case, head lac from an MVA.
Upon exam, he was
tachycardic, diaphoretic.
BP was 210 over 160.
We got his pressure down.
Why'd you do
an abdominal CT?
History of intermittent
flushing and palpitations.
Classic findings for a pheo.
That's going fishing with
some pretty expensive bait.
‐ What did the CT Show?
‐ It hasn't come back yet.
I know for you it's tempting
to reach for a surgical cause
but in the ER, we can't run
expensive tests
based on hunches.
Just check with me
in the future.
‐ Carol.
‐ Yeah.
I didn't mean to be
short with you earlier.
I do think an ER clinic is an
interesting idea and you might
be able to get some state
and federal funds for it.
‐ I might?
‐ Yeah.
Here's the place to start.
What are these?
Grant application manuals.
And this is a really good book
on fundraising strategies.
Oh, no, Kerry.
‐ I didn't mean me.
‐ I don't have the time.
What am I supposed
to do with these?
Carol, the only way
a good idea comes to life
is if somebody chooses
to see it through.
If you need help deciphering
these, we can talk later.
Kerry, I've got a problem
with this case.
Hey, you know what,
could you tell Mark? I've‐‐
Mark is the problem.
I worked up this LOL with a hot
gallbladder and Mark walked out
in the middle of the physical
exam and refused to finish.
‐ Why?
‐ The woman's a little flaky.
She put Mark's hand
on her breast
but that doesn't mean
she's not sick.
The ultrasound
confirms cholangitis.
Let me see.
Maybe he's got
other things on his mind.
You know, how
Mark's been lately.
She's a Medicare patient?
Yeah. I was reluctant
to bring this to you.
I don't care if somebody
is in a bad mood‐‐
‐ I'll talk to Mark.
‐ When it affects‐‐
I'll talk to him.
Uh, Brett, you have a mass
on your left testicle.
The chest x‐ray shows
spots on your lungs
which is why you've been
short of breath.
Spots? What..
The growth on your testicle
may have spread to your lungs.
What, cancer?
Before we can determine,
I need to draw up some blood
and, uh, you need
a CAT scan on your abdomen.
Could I have a,
uh, pen and paper?
I just want to write
this down real quick.
Sure.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Okay, so...so‐so
what happens now?
What, you draw some blood?
Right, um, then I'll send you
back to radiology
for the CAT scan.
And then I'll call
an oncologist down to see you.
Okay.
So, how bad...how
bad is the cancer?
We're not certain that
it is cancer.
Yeah, but you think so.
So what happens if it is?
You know what,
these are things
you should really discuss
with an oncologist.
Look, I don't wanna wait
for somebody else to tell me
if you could tell me now.
Okay.
If it is, uh, cancer
treatment is removal
of the testicle
'plus chemotherapy,
probably radiation as well.'
What, you gonna cut
one of my nuts off?
With successful treatment,
there's a 70% survival rate.
Oh, my god.
Dr. Greene?
Mark?
What?
Hi, Alan.
You didn't get my page?
Oh, yeah, no, I‐I got it.
I just, uh, I was just
on my way up.
If you're gonna lie to an
attorney Dr. Greene, try harder.
Listen, I know you don't feel
the need for final preparation
for this, but I do.
We're not prepared enough?
For deposition,
there's no such thing.
Alright, any question
they ask, you answer what?
Yes, no, or I don't recall.
That's right,
and nothing else.
Why the hell haven't we
settled this thing already?
Well, these people won't come
down from eight figures.
They say they're entitled
to compensation
for what Kenny Law
might have earned
if he'd made it
to the NBA.
And the jury could
go for that.
Listen, their lawyer,
she's gonna try to rattle you.
Can't rattle me.
I did everything I could
to save the boy's life.
I'll page you when they come.
Answer it this time.
Primary surgeon,
Dr. Peter Benton.
Attending, Angela Hicks.
Oh, boy. Boy, boy...
♪ Hey papa don't
hey hey hey ♪
♪ Hey hey ♪
♪ Hey papa don't ♪
Alright, come on, do this.
Clinical narrative.
"This patient presented
to the emergency department
"with a gunshot wound
to the right upper quadrant
and a systolic
blood pressure of.."
Hey, how you doing?
Dr. Peter Benton.
‐ Vinay Radhakrishnan.
‐ Ah, yeah.
Hey, you know, that's
the way to do it
instead of letting
them stack up on you.
It's like falling
off a freight train.
Do you have kids?
Yes. Three boys, two girls.
Well, uh, how do you
balance it with work?
I mean, if you
don't mind me asking.
My wife handles everything
with the children.
Pardon me, please.
"This is Dr. Vinay Radhakrishnan
dictating a discharge summary
"on patient Stella Kline
medical record
number 84‐98‐29."
I didn't know what to say.
You know, he was stooped
over with an erection
and I needed to
finish the exam.
Don't beat yourself up over it.
You like these
spicy string beans?
Yeah, all of it's good.
‐ How much was it?
‐ No, my treat.
‐ No, how much do I owe you?
‐ Why can't it be my treat?
Thirty dollars?
Where is this place?
On Wacker.
Keep spending like
that you're, uh..
you're gonna be in big trouble.
Back at chop, I got
way in over my head
maxed out
on my credit cards‐‐
Mr. Angevine's CT.
You're right. It's a pheo.
‐ Yeah?
‐ Good pickup, Dr. Carter.
‐ Whoa.
‐ There it is.
DC the nipride and
start him on phentolamine
five milligrams IV.
I'll call down a surgeon.
‐ Way to go, Dr. Carter.
‐ Uh‐huh.
Here, I owe you
a buck fifty.
I, uh, gotta go check
on my track star.
‐ Ding dongs?
‐ Uh‐huh. Want a bite?
No, no. I'll just
watch you eat it.
These are
my all time favorites.
When I was in Virginia
they didn't call
them ding dongs.
They called them king dons
only on the package.
All I'm saying, why weren't they
called ding dongs in Virginia?
I mean, look, what law
does that violate, right?
What I can't figure out
maybe you can help me
with this...ding dongs,
ho hos, same food
just different shape.
How did they get
away with that?
That's right.
Why are they pretending that
they're two different things?
Ding dong, ho ho, conspiracy.
Mark, can I see you
for a minute?
Yeah. Sure.
What's up?
You saw a patient
this morning Marian Rice.
Ah, horny old lady?
Medicare won't
reimburse 100%
unless an attending
has examined the patient
and written out
a note in detail.
You walked out in the
middle of the exam.
Ah, who told you that? Jeanie?
We can no longer write
seen and agree notes
on Medicare patients.
You didn't read the memo
I sent out last month?
Which memo was that?
Alright. What do I have to do
so that we can get paid?
You need to examine this patient
and chart your
findings in detail.
If I have to examine
every Medicare patient
that comes in here,
why do we have PAs?
‐ This is not about the PAs.
‐ Alright, alright.
No problem.
Jeanie, football.
‐ What?
‐ Bears play tonight.
Hey, you wanna get some
squares for Al?
No. We're not gonna
play this week.
Three weeks in a row?
What's up?
Y'all quit rooting
for the Bears?
We're still rooting,
we're just not betting.
Okay, well, you know
where you can find the brother.
What's all this stuff?
Grant applications.
Weaver gave them to me.
Might be a good idea
to start a clinic in the ER.
Like Stony Island?
That's where the gangsters go
to get their old
bullet wounds looked at.
Hey, they got a $100,000
state grant.
So, Weaver's got you
panhandling for her now?
No, it was my idea.
You know, it was a nurse who
started that Wun Zhai clinic.
‐ Really?
‐ Yep. ER charge nurse.
Mr. Angevine's in shock!
‐ His BP crashed!
‐ My pheo?
He's flossing multiple PVCs
and he's desaturating.
Okay. Get four units of O‐neg
going and pre‐op labs.
And find out why a surgeon
is not down here?
‐ What happened?
‐ He's in v‐fib.
‐ Tumor maybe infarcted.
‐ Where's surgery?
‐ Charging, 200.
‐ Clear.
‐ Go again.
‐ Charging, 300.
Clear.
'Let's get ready to move
him into surgery.'
Is this the pheo?
We shocked him out of v‐fib.
You're Dr. Romano?
Call me Rocket.
We'll take it from here.
'Dr. Carter made
the diagnosis.'
Great. Come on,
don't wait for me. Let's go.
You ever do one of
these, Dr. Edson?
No. Are you gonna use a scope?
No, we'll do it
the old‐fashioned way.
I'll walk you through it.
They're fun.
‐ Look out.
‐ Alright.
Nice work, Carter.
Thank you.
'Come on, let's go.'
I brought you some tea.
Oh. Thanks.
This'll be me
in a month's time.
Then you can
return the favor.
Oh, man.
How did the
proctocolectomy go?
Ooh, my ileo‐anal pouch
drew rave reviews.
Listen, you've not worked
with Dr. Romano, have you?
Rocket Romano?
No, he's never here.
Ten months out of the year,
he's in Europe.
Well, he's performing
an operation tomorrow
with an extraordinary
device, the Aesop 2000.
Are you interested in robotics?
No.
I can get you in
on the team.
The Aesop's a robotic
arm with a camera.
Rocket will be directing it
with a microphone headset.
Like Madonna, or whoever.
Hmm, fascinating.
Uh, how could you
get me on the team?
Oh, Rocket's
sponsoring my BTA.
‐ BTA?
‐ Been to America.
In order to come here,
I needed a sponsor.
And now you wanna broaden
my surgical horizons, huh?
You really should
get to know him, Peter.
No, no, I, um..
My plate's full.
‐ Thank you.
‐ 'Alright.'
I'll let you get back
to your beauty sleep then.
Angevine. A‐N‐G‐E‐V‐I‐N‐E.
Anybody see a black,
male patient
twenty years old,
about six foot three?
‐ No.
‐ You lose somebody?
He might have had on a gray
sweat suit. Nobody saw him?
This is Dr. Carter in the ER.
Yeah. I'm trying to find out
about a patient named Angevine.
"Emergency excision
of a pheochromocytoma."
Dr. Romano took him up?
Romano.
What's wrong?
My testicular
cancer guy ran away.
The oncologist never saw him.
You want me to
help you find him?
No. I'll try
this number he gave.
I think he lives on campus.
Oh, use this phone.
I'm not getting
anywhere with surgery.
‐ Thanks.
‐ Dr. Carter.
I can't find a vein
on the patient in four.
Really?
Well, you see,
he's blown them all.
Well, if you'll all excuse me
I'm going to put my years
of education and training
to the test.
By drawing blood
from a heroin addict.
‐ Come on, Ivan.
‐ Is Haleh here?
No. She's sick, remember?
No, because, see,
today's Thursday.
Oh, I know, Pablo.
Haleh's not here today,
come back tomorrow.
Yeah, okay.
I come back later, huh?
No, no, no. Manana.
Friday, okay?
Manana.
I told you. You won't
find nothing there.
How long have you been
an IV drug user, Mr. Hayes?
Since 1977.
Wow.
There's always a vein somewhere.
Summer of '77.
Never will forget it.
I was over at
Charlie Wilson's house.
Old Charlie boy!
Down in the basement, banging.
Like we just invented something.
Told you you wouldn't find
nothing over there.
Hmm.
Warm compresses
or a dab of nitro paste
'can dilate a hidden vein,
but before we do that'
let's see if we can find one
in a lower extremity
like the saphenous
vein in the leg.
‐ How about the femoral vein?
‐ Nope.
Dorsal venous plexus
of the foot?
Give it here. I'll find you one.
Thank you. Cotton.
Yeah.
‐ Uh..
‐ Oh.
Wow.
Wow! Don't you ever,
ever try this.
I screwed up.
With my testicular
cancer patient. He ran away.
Ran away?
I sent my student out
to look for him.
The guy likes to run
along the lakefront.
He's not running anywhere
with those mets in his lungs.
Yeah.
I left a message at his dorm.
He'll show up,
you know, but, uh..
...the thing is,
when we do find him
it would be good
if he could talk to a man
about the orchiectomy.
If you could explain to him
that his life's not over
just because
he's losing a testicle.
Alright, well. Let me
know when you find him.
We got a wild one!
Alright. Give it to me.
ALOC, heavy ETOH Odor.
Unrousable at scene.
BP 130 over 80.
‐ Let me go!
‐ Sinus rhythm 72.
O2 by mask, ten liters.
Go to trauma one.
Cynthia, call security.
We started an IV,
gave d‐50 and
two milligrams of narcan.
No effect.
No signs of trauma on scene,
but he awoke en route
kicked out
the window of the rig.
He's got a nasty lac here!
Tough as hell
throwing him into restraints.
Hard leathers!
You can't tie me up like this!
We'll need as many
as we can to transfer.
‐ Hold his head down.
‐ Are we ready to move him?
‐ What's his name?
‐ McNamara.
Mr. McNamara, you gotta stop
thrashing around.
Who are you to tell me?
‐ I was kidnapped from my house.
‐ Listen to me.
Ow! Damn you people!
'Hold him down.'
Son of a bitch!
She bit down on her tongue.
You have no right
to tie me up like this!
That's enough!
Listen up, you understand!
Don't move!
‐ 'Ow!'
‐ 'Don't move!'
‐ 'Mark!'
‐ Shut up and don't move.
Mark!
Go check on Chuny.
'Alright, everybody,
we're gonna move him'
'on the count of three.'
'Hold him down.'
'One...two...three.'
I'm sorry I embarrassed
you, Dr. Carter.
You didn't.
Well, I embarrassed myself.
You know, you get
used to this stuff, Ivan.
How?
Eventually,
it doesn't faze you.
What if I can't cut it?
Well, you need to see more.
Get a few more traumas
under your belt.
What if my whole life
is a wrong decision?
Yeah.
Ah, Dr. Anspaugh.
How are those dictations coming?
Almost finished,
I wanted to thank you
for giving me time
to get caught up
and to also apologize
for this morning
for not being prepared.
It'll never happen again.
I should hope not.
You know, when your, uh..
when your son was in the NICU
everyone gladly bent
over backwards
to accommodate you because
we all felt sympathy
'for your situation.'
'But now, your baby's
out of the hospital.'
And as you've probably noted
Dr. Corday has raised
the bar considerably
'for surgical residents.'
Yes. She's talented.
If we don't stay on our toes
she could end up
making all of us look bad.
Oh man, these
grant applications
are making my
eyes glaze over.
What's the nurse's
name at Stony Island
who started up
their clinic?
Um, Ellen Buckley?
Maybe she could
show me the ropes.
Oh, I can tell you
how she got her grant.
‐ Really?
‐ No big mystery.
Her dad's a state senator.
Dr. Del Amico?
Your patient?
Oh, yeah.
That's him, thanks.
Hey, Cynthia, can you find
Dr. Ross for me, please?
'Yeah. Right away.'
‐ Hey, Brett.
‐ Hey.
Where'd you go?
Just walking around.
Listen, I know
this great doctor.
He's a pediatrician,
but he'd be
a good person to
talk to about all this.
'Any questions
you might have.'
What? You don't wanna
answer any more of my questions?
No, I thought you might
be more comfortable
with a male doctor.
Is he gonna tell me that
my left nut's got to go?
If that's the diagnosis, yes.
I don't care if‐if
it's you or whoever.
I just..
I just needed to walk
around a little bit.
Get this all straight
in my mind, you know?
Okay.
So, what do you want me to do?
You want me to go
talk to that oncologist?
Yeah. I'll, uh, I'll
take you up there now.
Uh, do you have
any family in the area?
Uh, yeah. Milwaukee.
You should call them.
Hey. Can I bum one?
Yeah.
You know, that was so great
the way you handled
that drunken jerk.
Uh, I don't know
about that.
Hey, nobody else
could get him under control.
You did,
I was watching.
Yeah, well.
Can I tell you something, Mark?
Mm‐hmm.
I understated before
when I said that
I give good back rubs.
I give really great back rubs.
It's one of
the things I'm best at.
Want me to show you?
Here?
Turn around.
‐ Oh.
‐ Oh, man, you are so tight.
I knew you'd have a really
strong back, though.
That feels great.
It's Alan McConagha.
‐ Huh?
‐ The hospital lawyer.
I'd better get going.
Can I walk with you?
Sure.
I could never do this.
What was I thinking?
What'd you say?
Nothing.
Still thinking
about a clinic, huh?
You could spend half your life
trying to get this money.
Yeah, if you go
to the government.
You should look into
private foundations.
‐ Private?
‐ Yeah. Yeah?
No, no, no, I just wanna
know if Thomas Angevine
is out of surgery or not.
I was just on hold.
Private foundations?
Yeah. They exist pretty
much to give money away.
It's that or pay taxes.
Do you think a
private foundation
would consider this clinic?
You should hear some of the
nutty ideas that get pitched
to my grandmother.
I.. wait a second. Yeah.
What do you mean,
nobody knows?
Just go down the hall!
Wait, wait, no, no, no.
Just tell me what OR they're in.
Okay. Thank you.
Your grandmother's involved
in a foundation?
Yeah, yeah.
I gotta go to surgery.
Wait, Carter. Do you think
your grandmother would consider
this clinic idea?
If you put something
down on paper
she'd probably look at it, yeah.
Have there been previous
lawsuits alleging
malpractice by you, Dr. Greene?
Yes. One.
Isn't it true that
in the spring of 1995
a Mrs. Jodi O'Brian,
a healthy 29‐year‐old woman
pregnant with her first child
died as a result
of your misdiagnosis?
No. Her medical course was‐‐
Mark..
You answered the question.
'Following the death
of Mrs. O'Brian'
did you express feelings
of guilt to co‐workers?
Not that I recall.
'Did you, in fact,
feel guilty?'
Guilty? No.
'What word would describe your'
'state of mind
regarding her death?'
‐ Regret.
‐ Huh.
Is it fair to say that
this regretful feeling
'reflected an awareness
of the quality'
'of care you provided?'
No. It happens here
all the time.
People die,
we feel horrible.
Did you feel horrible
after the death of Kenny Law?
Hell, no.
Mr. Law, you're
here as a courtesy.
Look, we can cut
this short right now.
Please refrain
from commenting.
I put a question
to you, Dr. Greene.
Ask it again.
Did you feel horrible
after Kenny Law died
after being treated
by you in this hospital?
I felt regret, yes.
Had you applied the same
standard of care
to Kenny Law as
to the white teenager
'brought into the emergency
room five minutes before?'
‐ Yes.
‐ That's a damn lie!
Oh, Miss Davis, do something
about your client please.
‐ Chris, will you be quiet.
‐ He knows it's a lie.
You be quiet!
You're in no position to accuse
me of anything!
You, of all people.
Dr. Greene, do you hold
the life of a young black man
to be of lesser value than
the life of a white person?
What kind of question is that?
Will you answer it?
People die. I'm human.
I'm fallible.
So, you'd characterize
yourself are fallible.
Don't twist my words around.
'Let me ask you about
this fallibility.'
When this young black man
was brought into the ER‐‐
You want me to say
that I'm a racist, is that it?
I'm a racist, alright?
Does that makes you feel better
about almost beating me
to death?
'Mark, sit down and shut up.'
Is that gonna bring
your son back?
Hey, don't point at my mother!
That's it!
We're taking a break.
We're stopping this right now.
Talking about regret.
Regret.
You never expressed
any regrets to my mother.
You belong in jail.
I wish it was me who kicked
your white ass!
Dr. Carter,
coming back to surgery?
I just came to pay a visit.
Oh. We miss you up here.
Did you work on this
pheo with Dr. Romano?
Yes. Dr. Edson
did the procedure.
‐ He did?
‐ Are you looking for him?
I think he's
in the waiting room.
Okay. Thanks.
Honey, settle.
Thank him, sweetie.
This is the doctor
that saved your daddy's life.
‐ Thank you, doctor.
‐ Hey.
I heard Dr. Romano
let you do the procedure.
That's right. I was just saying,
it was a total success.
So when can I see Tom?
He's just been
moved down to ICU.
I can take you down there,
if you'd like.
Uh‐huh. Great.
Hi. I'm Dr. Carter.
Oh, were you part
of the surgical team?
Uh, no, I wasn't.
I‐I actually saw
your husband when he came
into the emergency room.
Oh.
Well, I'm glad
everything went alright.
‐ Thanks.
‐ ICU is this way.
Oh, thanks so much, Dr. Edson.
Come on, sweetie.
I'll be leaving on time,
so what? I'll meet you there.
‐ Last call for football.
‐ Okay, see you soon.
‐ Hi there, Pablo.
‐ Is Haleh here?
No. I'm gonna do you this time.
‐ Haleh not here.
‐ No. You got Carol today.
‐ Oh, Carol.
‐ Mm‐hmm.
Oh, okay.
Mark. Hey. How'd it go
with the lawyer?
‐ I don't know.
‐ You leaving?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Hang on ten minutes.
I'll go with you.
See you tomorrow, Doug.
You know what, Liz?
I'm thinking I'm gonna want you
handling the laser tomorrow.
While you control
the Aesop 2000?
Terrific.
Don't act too surprised.
Ah. Peter. That's fantastic.
Now I get to introduce you.
Peter Benton,
Rocket Romano.
Dr. Benton. Hey!
‐ Lizzy's talked about you.
‐ It's a pleasure.
Tell me something.
You think Chris Rock is funny?
‐ Excuse me?
‐ The comedian, Chris Rock?
Did that HBO special.
Must have used the "N" word..
...fifty times.
"N" word this, "N" word that.
They're calling him a genius.
If I went around
saying the "N" word
you'd probably wanna
smack the hell
out of me, am I right?
I think Chris Rock is hilarious.
‐ Good to meet you.
‐ Have a good night.
You're right.
I like him.
Feeling better now, Pablo?
Yeah, I'm feeling better now.
All nice and clean?
Yeah.
Now Haleh listens
to my chest.
Why?
So my pneumonia
doesn't come back.
You had pneumonia?
Yeah, twice.
Okay.
I want you to take
a nice, deep breath
for me, alright?
And again.
‐ Sounds good.
‐ Uh‐huh.
Pablo?
If there was a clinic
in the emergency room
where you could get checkups
and medicine if you needed it.
‐ Uh‐huh.
‐ Do you think you'd come?
‐ Free clinic?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Would Haleh be there?
‐ I bet she would.
I'd like it. Yeah,
I would come. Uh‐huh.
Okay, Pablo.
‐ Hey, Carter.
‐ Hi.
Anything new and exciting
happening in the ER?
Oh, I diagnosed
a pheochromocytoma.
‐ You serious?
‐ Patient crashed.
They took him up to surgery.
Dale did the procedure,
but I hear he did pretty good.
Ah, Dale's a weasel.
Excuse me?
Carter, you're twice
the surgeon Dale will ever be.
Thanks.
Busy day for you?
Yeah. Anspaugh
got on my case
about some
delinquent charts.
Bummer.
So, you enjoying fatherhood?
Yeah. Yeah, I am.
Goodnight, Carter.
Goodnight.
Congratulations, my man.
Yeah, my luck's changing.
Send over two ginger ales.
'You got it.'
I thought it was
gonna be no gambling.
Well, it's just a ball pool.
You're not gonna complain now.
It's 200 bucks.
We just have to be
careful with our money.
Don't‐don't spoil
this for me, okay?
Billy Nelson just came in.
‐ Give me a cold one.
‐ 'Sure.'
Thanks.
You talked to him
since the accident?
About what?
The drugs he has to take
over the next six months
'in the off chance
I gave him HIV?'
‐ 'I haven't talked to him.'
‐ He's staring at us.
I'm gonna go say something.
Just drink your‐your
ginger ale, okay?
But he's your friend, Al.
That's how I know.
If I was in his place..
'Hey, Al, how'd you get it?'
Hey, Al, how'd you get it?
In the arm? Huh?
You get it through the vein
or you get it through the booty?
'I wanna know!'
Huh?
Bill, just come over
here and let's talk.
Sit down, bitch!
I ain't talking to you.
What? Who the hell do you
think you're talking to, man?
That's my wife!
You're gonna try
and be a man, now?
Yes, that's right.
You shut your mouth!
...got AIDS,
and gave it to your wife!
You tried to give it to me!
Hey! Not in here, fellas.
Not in here!
Al, please, take me home.
That's right,
get the hell out of here
before I do
what I feel like doing.
‐ Move away. Al, please.
‐ What you wanna do?
What?
That's what I thought.
Faggot!
Wait!
‐ Okay, now, come on!
‐ Come on!
Don't, Al!
Stop it!
'Stop it, Al!'
'Stop it.
Al, stop it!'
Stop it, Al.
Stop it.