Previously on Grey's Anatomy:
I have an 18-year-old daughter.
I'm having a baby and I don't
have anywhere else to go.
Dr. Bailey, have
you seen the chief?
There's something wrong with
his emergency chole patient.
You may have accidentally
clipped the common bile duct.
That's one of the most serious
mistakes a general surgeon can make.
Have you told anyone what
you saw? Have you told Derek?
No.
I have loved you forever.
I'm in love with Cristina.
We assume the really
serious changes in our lives
happen slowly, over time.
But it's not true.
The big stuff
happens in an instant.
- You're up early.
- Yeah. I want to
get some stuff done
so I can meet the
chief this afternoon.
He's gonna show me
another old surgery tape.
Again? It's every night this week. I
thought last night was the last one.
He got held up.
He couldn't make it.
I went by his office on my way out.
He was sound asleep on his couch.
Aah... Which is why
he couldn't make it.
I think maybe he just
doesn't sleep well at home,
with Adele gone.
Mmm.
I need something from you.
- That, too.
- Mmm.
I need you to give Sloan
an ultrasound today.
- It's been almost three weeks.
- Can't someone from OB do it?
Yeah, but...
she likes you.
All the Sloans do.
Hey, do we have
any more...? Oh! Ew!
- Sloan!
- Whoa!
Becoming an adult.
Becoming a parent.
Becoming a doctor.
One minute you're
not, and the next...
- Sloan?
- you are.
- Sorry about that.
- Whatever. There's no more cereal.
Why are you sorry?
She's the one who didn't
knock before she came in.
I'll get some cereal
this afternoon.
How about some juice?
Lexie's gonna give
you an ultrasound today.
Why don't you pick up
some breakfast at the hospital.
It's gonna be more.
- You need some for lunch, too?
- Yeah.
- I'm gonna shower.
- Can you hold on a minute?
I'm probably gonna
have to hurl this.
Sloan Sloan monopolizing
your bathroom again?
- Yeah. Yours?
- Owen's in mine.
Oh, God!
- They're in there.
- You should knock first.
I'm late. My hair is dirty.
And he just gave her 80 bucks
for a muffin and a sandwich.
- That's quite a sandwich.
- She's gonna spend it on jeans
that show off her butt crack, and
then ask me for half my pasta salad.
- You sound like my mother.
- Knock much?
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
There's no more hot water.
Ask any doctor, and
they can point to the
one moment they
became a physician.
It usually isn't med
school graduation day.
Yang, you're going solo today.
- Been there.
- Cardio solo.
- Whatever it is...
- Valve replacement.
- nobody forgets it.
- Porcine or...?
Mechanical.
I can try out the
sub-annular stitches?
I didn't teach it to you
so you could crochet.
OK. Thank you!
Oh, my God!
- What? What?
- Altman's letting her go solo
- on a valve.
- Wow!
- Feel ready?
- She's ready.
- She just needs to breathe.
- I am breathing.
I am a living, breathing
cardiothoracic
surgeon, as of right now.
I have to go prep.
Sometimes, you don't even
know anything's changed.
You think you're still you
and your life is still your life...
but you wake up one
day and look around,
and you don't
recognize anything.
Not anything at all.
Hey, do you have any cash? I
lost the headset to my phone.
How about you hold
the phone up to your ear?
You were the one bitching at
me for being on the phone so late.
Maybe if I had a headset, I
wouldn't have to talk so loud.
Maybe if you had your
own apartment, you could
talk whenever you want, but
we're all making compromises.
OK. Here's the head.
- It looks like an alien.
- It's gonna be a cute alien.
Boy alien or girl?
Dude, does it
have a thing or not?
I'm not looking at
the sex, I'm... I don't...
Yeah. I'm new at
this. I'm not very good.
So why don't we go upstairs.
There's a better machine. We'll
have someone else take a look.
Adamson with me, Meredith
with Bailey, Karev with Torres.
- Tom Kates's in this ambulance.
- The quarterback?
- Yeah.
- See photographers,
call security.
Tell your interns no
autographs, no pictures.
I see anyone pull out a camera
phone, it's going in the toilet.
- The three of us
on one patient?
- Come on.
He's a high-profile patient,
he gets a lot of attention.
I thought we agreed
to stop meeting like this.
What can I say, man, I
missed your smiling face.
- Good to see you.
- Head trauma, but GCS 15
since regaining consciousness.
He got high-lowed by a couple
of linebackers,
dropped like a rock.
Get X-ray in here
for a trauma series.
Tenderness in the
left upper quadrant.
- I'm gonna need a CT.
- Got it.
There's pain and
crepitance in the knee.
Get an X-ray of the left
knee with the trauma series.
I saw that hit.
That was a bad hit.
I knew it the minute I saw it.
I knew before you even hit
the ground. That was bad.
Hey. Hi, sweetheart.
And that's my boy!
- He's very cute.
- Dr. Shepherd?
He's gonna be
fine. He'll be fine.
I can't have you in
here with the baby.
Littlest high five in the world.
We'll come and find you
the second we
know what's going on.
I love you, babe.
Don't give him too much
morphine. It makes him goofy.
- How great is that kid?
- He's pretty great.
- You tell Sloan to move out?
- No.
- Not that it's a bad idea.
- You're making her
feel like crap.
She said you wouldn't even
be alone in a room with her.
- No...
- Why do I have to chaperone
- the ultrasound?
- There's something wrong
with the baby.
See, right there,
on the left thigh?
Yeah. On his other ankle, too.
- Wait, it's a boy?
- I hadn't gotten that far.
Sorry. Congratulations.
There's a lot of swelling on the
right foot. It's very constricted.
What the hell are
you talking about?
The baby's got strands of amniotic
tissue wrapped around his legs.
They're called amniotic bands.
There's a danger of them
compromising one of his limbs.
So, what, one of his
legs is gonna, like, fall off?
- That's worst-case scenario.
- He's gonna have stumps?
We don't know what
we're dealing with yet,
and whatever it is, we're
gonna take care of it.
I can't have a stumpy
baby. Can't you fix it?
- Um, I don't know.
- I have an idea.
How about we don't
answer any patient questions
with the phrase,
"Um, I don't know."
We're gonna fix it.
Let's get a fetal MRI.
- I'm not sure...
- I wasn't talking to you. You're done.
I'll be right back.
Get me Addison Montgomery.
I adore you.
I was in the
middle of breakfast.
She had an MRI.
Right's worse than the left.
- I just need to say it once.
- Go ahead.
Grandpa.
- Grandpa, grandpa, grandpa.
- OK, that was four times.
- Is it out of your system?
- I don't know.
Look at that, he thinks he's got
an opening behind Martin, then...
- Back that up again.
- I'd never ask for
an autograph.
But if he signed a consent form
and there's a copy lying around...
- Torres!
- What?
- Look who's here!
- You get lost on the freeway?
- What are you doing here?
- Sloan's got a little something
- going on with the baby.
- She OK?
- We'll figure it out.
- I'm gonna go see
if they're ready.
You know how long
I've been waiting?
You pull his blood
out with leeches?
Ooh...
- She's perkier than usual.
- Divorce'll do that to you.
- Sad.
- She'll move on and be happy.
She needs somebody
to move on to.
That can't be so hard.
Hey, wait. What about you?
Can't you find her someone?
That guy from Oncology,
the cute one. Isn't he still here?
- That's not my area.
- He used to play
basketball with him.
- Dave.
- Torres should do it. They're friends.
- She thinks I'm loopy.
- You are loopy.
Come on. It's
Bailey. She's lonely.
Hey. He needs a transfusion.
That splenic lac is
bleeding more than I thought.
Take a look at his CTs and
come up with a game plan.
All set.
- Ah.
- I'm coming with you.
You know Dave from
Oncology? He's single.
You wouldn't be starting
a conversation about
- my personal life, would you?
- Bad idea? He's handsome.
- Bad idea!
- OK.
I tried.
Hi, Ruthie. This is Dr. Yang.
She'll be performing
your surgery today.
She's the best of the
best. You're gonna like her.
- Good! I'm so glad to meet you!
- Hi.
I have a couple things
I want to discuss.
- Of course, of course.
- I have allergies.
I know they write
them in the chart,
but I find if you
don't tell everyone,
it kind of gets
lost in the shuffle.
- Yeah.
- Aspirin, ibuprofen,
bananas, zucchini,
all forms of squash.
Pumpkin is a squash.
People forget that.
Latex, dust mites.
I asked the nurse
with the red hair
for a new pillow.
I would also love
to get a new nurse,
because I think the redhead
brought back the old pillow
with a new case and
it's making me sneezy.
I was supposed to
get a mechanical valve,
but I've been thinking about
the clicking noise they say
the mechanical valve makes...
That would be irritating. Don't
you think that might make you nuts?
I'm sorry, but a different valve
is a whole different procedure.
Yes, but I think the pig is
a better idea, the pig valve.
It's organic. They
say they're very clean.
All that business about, "You're
such a pig," that's just bad marketing.
And this blanket,
this has a smell.
Yeah. Like... I'm not
saying it's not clean.
It's like a chemical of some
kind. It's chafing and causing...
Can you see my rash?
As the legs continue to grow,
the bands'll cut off his circulation.
If we wait, we risk severe
damage to the left leg,
possible loss of
the right entirely.
But if we operate, 22
weeks, it's... still risky.
If you don't operate, you're
not gonna kill the baby.
We can rehabilitate the
remaining part of his leg
after he's born, and we
can fit him with a prosthesis.
It's possible that he'll walk.
- Oh, my God!
- Honey, we've got options here.
If we operate, Dr. Montgomery can
remove the bands. He'll be just fine.
Or we can wait a few weeks
till he's bigger and stronger
and we know the
surgery's less risky.
Which one of you
did he sleep with?
Oh, not me.
- You told her?
- She's my kid. We were bonding.
That's not how you
bond with children!
I'm still getting
the hang of it.
You're sure he didn't, like,
knock you up and leave you
with a child to raise on
your own or something?
You're not really pissed
and trying to get revenge?
No! No.
It was a long time ago, OK?
The fact is, Mark,
your father, is a good guy.
And I think you're a good kid.
I'm gonna do everything I
can to help you with your baby.
OK. Well, let's get these
things off his legs right now.
I'll book an OR.
Stupid quarterback
only has a concussion.
- Tragic.
- I know.
I'm on his ortho stuff.
There's bound to be a surgery.
- You wanna share?
- Why would I do that?
- 'Cause you like me.
- Not that much.
Sure you do. Come on.
Let me scrub in
and I'll take you out for
drinks afterwards and...
You know.
Really?
OK.
- What?
- "Let me take you
out for drinks
and you know."
What's "you know"?
- Whatever.
- It's sex.
Charlie, get over it.
You're trading sex for
surgery. That's prostitution.
Is that the part I'm
supposed to get over?
- Are you calling me a whore?
- Explain what "you know" means.
I'm messing with him.
Karev knows it, and I know it.
- He's gonna want to collect.
- Charlie,
go find something
else to worry about.
Dr. Bailey, this is
Dr. Stanton from Radiology.
Rob, Miranda.
Rob was looking over Tom's
CT, I thought he should talk to you.
- OK.
- Rob's new here.
I thought you might give
him a tour of the hospital
while you discuss the CT.
Excuse me. What are you doing?
You spent Christmas
with me and Meredith.
- That can't be what you want.
- True, but I do have a patient
that I have to do a
follow-up on right now.
- I don't have time to...
- I can do it. Have fun. Take care.
Have a good tour.
- You want to show me the scan?
- How about we look at it
over lunch?
I'm in the middle of a divorce.
People call me The Nazi, and it's
not because of my ice-blue eyes.
I spend 12 hours a day
carving people up and I like it.
I have a child.
And I have no room
for casual anything.
I'm angry all the time
and deeply confused,
because a lot of people in my
life have let me down recently,
and one of them was me. It's
devastating, but not completely
because it turns out I like
sleeping crosswise in the bed
and not having to shave my legs.
My three year old
used to be potty trained,
and now he isn't because his
father no longer lives with us
and his world no
longer makes sense
and the only thing he thinks
he can control is his bladder,
so he urinates in a lot of places
you wish he wouldn't urinate.
You want lunch or you
wanna show me the scan?
Mr. Morris, I'm Dr. Shepherd.
I'll be filling in for
Dr. Bailey today.
- You're here for a follow-up?
- Yeah.
I had my gallbladder
out a couple months ago.
Months? You're still
getting follow-ups?
- I am. Once a week.
- Once a week?
Yeah. Dr. B says she
just wants to make sure
- I'm in tiptop shape.
- Dr. Webber did your surgery?
Yeah, chief of
surgery. Fancy, huh?
You guys are the best.
People say a lot of crap about
health care, but
they've never been here.
- You take care of people.
- We certainly do.
Dr. B was all worried 'cause I turned
yellow after my first surgery. See?
But it went away. I'm fine now.
You want to look at my scar
or wait till after I pee in the cup?
Dr. Altman. The patient's no longer
interested in the mechanical valve.
I couldn't give you a total
unadulterated dream case.
- People would talk.
- I just spent hours prepping
for the mechanical. A pig
valve is a whole different surgery!
Two for the price of one. Think
about how much you're learning.
You want me to get someone else?
No.
It's a concussion, no worse
than you've seen before.
Nothing we need
to go in and fix.
Initially, we thought the injury
to your spleen'd resolve itself,
but it's bleeding too much.
Dr. Bailey needs to remove
it as soon as possible.
The surgery is gonna have
you out for a couple weeks.
But you'll be back in
the game for next season.
- Tom?
- I can't... I can't breathe!
- Get some oxygen!
- I can't breathe!
Get a crash cart! Tom...
Let's get an EKG just in case.
Tom, have you had
a panic attack before?
I'm fine.
It's just, uh...
- It's nothing.
- There's Daddy!
- How's my guy?
- He's fine.
How's my guy?
- He was...
- Brain's OK.
But they gotta
cut my belly open.
- I can't play till next season.
- Honey...
Don't worry, next season
will be here before you know it.
- What's the deal
with you and Reed?
- Nothing.
You're not trading
her surgery for sex?
- Give me a break.
- Because if you are,
it's gross.
If I sleep with her,
it's 'cause I want to.
You look me in
the eye and tell me
Derek never threw a
craniotomy your way
after the two of you spent an
hour in the on-call room? Please.
I know it may not feel like
it, but you are still married.
And Izzie...
You know what? I'm
done worrying about Izzie.
She sure as hell
ain't worried about me.
This is the old Alex.
Sleeping with some random
person because you're angry and hurt.
- That's what you always did.
- Then we grew up and
got married.
Turns out your stupid Post-it
is ten times the marriage
my church wedding ever
got me. I'm moving on.
Hey. Tom Kates is
having panic attacks?
Yeah, I don't know
why. He's not talking.
I took care of your
chole patient. It's all good.
- Thanks.
- He's getting high-class care.
Six visits with a surgeon? A
nurse practitioner can do this.
I like to do after-care myself.
He wasn't even your patient. He
was the chief's. There was an error.
- He's fine.
- So why all the...?
I have a thing for him, OK?
- Sheldon Morris?
- He caught my eye.
Sheldon has a quality
that I'm... drawn to. I...
I can't put my finger
on what it is exactly.
Sure. Sure. Want
to keep his picture?
Do you know what my sister
had for lunch today? Pork chops.
I watched her eat. I
didn't feel any kinship.
With the pig.
I think the pig valve
may be the wrong choice.
You feel more kinship with cows?
- I don't know.
- Mrs. Carlin,
we've prepared the
porcine valve replacement.
A bovine replacement is
a whole different surgery.
Like the mechanical valve
was a whole different surgery.
Do you think it's possible I could
see the valves? The pig and the cow?
Maybe then I could
recognize one as more familiar.
We don't do that. We don't
march the parts around the hospital.
Maybe we should call
this off. Can I do that?
- If you're not comfortable...
- No, no, no.
I mean, I can get the valves.
And I'll bring them here. OK?
Oh... You're so wonderful!
- You really are.
- Great.
- She's so wonderful.
- She is.
Richard, Tom Kates
needs a splenectomy.
Any chance I can get
you to do the procedure?
Well, I asked Bailey
to take over my service.
With the merger and all...
It's a high-profile patient.
I thought you could
make an exception.
Sure.
- You must have
extras lying around.
- We don't.
You never drop one?
Open up the box and see that
the pig has a cholesterol problem?
- Let me check in the back.
- OK.
She thinks maybe one
of them will speak to her.
- It's ringing.
- I'm prepping
for three different
surgeries in one day,
chasing animal parts
all over the hospital.
Teddy thinks it's hysterical,
but this may actually kill me.
Maybe one of them'll speak to
her. There're pros and cons for each.
At the end of the day,
it's a gut thing. Pig or cow.
It's not a gut thing. It's a
decision based on fact and reason.
- Hey! Where are my parts?
- Izzie, it's me.
I know you want space,
but you can't have space,
because Alex might be moving on.
Come back and work in the clinic!
You're throwing your career away!
- Cristina...
- She got fired from surgery,
- not all medicine.
- Ignore her. Just call me back.
OK. Bye.
There. That wasn't
so difficult, was it?
OK.
Got the first band.
Let's move down so I can
take a look at the second.
- Like that?
- Good.
Why... can't I grab his leg?
- Problem?
- No, it's just that
one of the bands
is holding the leg in place.
It's a little difficult
to get around.
Can you move the
ultrasound up here?
- Oh, come on.
- What's the matter?
Her uterine arteries are
engorged. But the only way in
is in between them.
OK, I'm gonna need
another trocar. Hold this?
You sure you have enough
room? Those arteries are huge.
That's why I'm gonna be
very, very careful. Scalpel.
What happens if you nick them?
Dr. Grey?
She could bleed
out. They both could.
I don't like it. It's
too dangerous.
Mark, I've assessed
the risk factors.
I'm 95 percent confident I
can get around the arteries.
I'm choosing to
continue my surgery.
I don't like the
other five percent.
You hit any one of those, she
bleeds out right on this table.
Look, you're
nervous, I get that.
I'm a surgeon, and I'm looking at a
time bomb in a uterus. Shut it down!
Now, Addison!
Let's close her up.
- Good to go?
- Yeah.
You baby-sitting?
'Cause I'm new at this.
- Where's the chief?
- I don't know. Check his office.
He said he was
gonna do this surgery.
Then he told me
he didn't have time
and asked if I would do it,
which I was planning
on in the first place.
- So I said yes.
- He said something about
a budget meeting. I
think he's pretty swamped.
If he's got time to watch old surgical
films with you, he's not swamped.
What the hell is going on?
The chole patient,
your boyfriend,
it was the chief's mistake. He
hasn't touched a patient since then.
- He's been busy
with the merger.
- I've heard that story before.
What is going on?
It is not my job to get
involved in his personal life.
Just like it's not your job
to get involved in mine.
Ten blade.
I made a judgment call,
you didn't like it, I'm sorry.
You threw me on a plane in
the middle of my morning coffee
- because you
wanted my judgment.
- It was risky.
That's not your call
to make in my OR!
You acted like a father.
Why do you think they
don't let parents in the room
- during an operation?
- I'm not her father, Addison.
Biologically, yes,
but... I just met the
kid. I'm helping out.
You reacted like a parent.
Now, I don't know
when, I don't know how,
but at some point, you
became a dad to that little urchin,
because you just
lost it in my OR,
and Mark Sloan never
loses it in the OR, not ever.
Yes, it was risky. And
yes, most surgeons
would've jumped ship at the
sight of the engorged arteries.
But I am not most surgeons.
And neither are you.
We can try this again.
With you in the waiting room.
It's too risky.
She's just a kid.
Well, have Morrison monitor
the bands as the baby grows.
It might be OK.
I gotta go. I have
patients at home.
Congratulations.
You're a parent.
- Neither one is speaking to me.
- For God's...
- Are they speaking to you?
- They aren't.
If I put your own valve in front of
you, it wouldn't speak to you either.
I have a cousin. His wife is a
cardiologist. I should call her.
No, no, no! No more calls.
This is about you
and your heart.
You need to use your instinct
and make a decision. Right now.
- Pig or cow.
- But I...
Pig or cow. Pig or cow!
Don't think! Just...
pig or cow! Go! Now!
Pig! No.
Cow!
Pig! Pig! Pig. Pig.
Pig.
Procedure went well.
You're gonna be back
on your feet in no time.
Great.
You're scared to play.
You thought you were done.
And when I said you'd be
back in the game next season,
you panicked.
Um... I used to be able
to block out the fear,
but ever since Des was
born, I'm on the field,
my heart starts racing.
I can't catch my breath.
I look at the guys who
played their whole careers,
hit so many times they can
barely remember their own names.
I'm scared he's gonna
grow up without a dad.
- I'm scared all the time.
- It's a natural reaction.
You're a father.
- Why don't you retire?
- Come on.
Two years into a
pro career? I can't.
I know I'm not a soldier
in Iraq or a rocket scientist
or any kind of real hero.
I know I'm just
some big, dumb jock.
But I'm a big, dumb jock
the entire city roots for.
Kids. Guys on the street.
I can't let them down.
This is the tradeoff.
- I get hit.
- Mmm...
Some guys can't even feed
their families, you know?
Some guys are soldiers in Iraq.
They get shot at.
So I'm not complaining.
I'm just... I'm
scared of the hits.
I wanna be able to
remember who my kid is.
OK. No more bubbles.
OK. Pressures are
good. Let's come off.
Decannulating.
I told Torres she had to let
you scrub in if she was cutting.
- Cool!
- Book an on-call room.
What...? What
happened to drinks first?
It's kind of a waste of
time, right? Cut to the chase.
Hey, Reed.
- Do you know Izzie Stevens?
- Grey.
Yes. I met her
before she got fired.
You know she's Alex's wife.
And she's not here right now,
- but they're still married.
- Meredith, shut up!
No. Some people think
you're divorced, and you're not.
How about you shut up long enough
to watch your friend tank her valve.
- How...? What?
- She's tachycardic.
Suction. Take this.
Laps, I need more laps.
Someone get me a sponge stick.
Um...
I'm having difficulty
locating the bleeder.
- Dr. Altman?
- Keep looking.
BP's dropping!
How come Altman's
not doing anything?
Suction! More suction.
Knee looks like crap, but
that's been true for a long time.
He should be able to
play through the pain.
What if he can't? What
about a knee replacement?
Right now.
He needs to stop. How about
we make it so it's not his idea?
- Systolic's down to 80!
- I could suture directly
or clamp.
- I don't know which to do.
- I don't know either.
My guess is if you
came and looked at it,
- you'd have a better idea.
- I'm sure that's true,
- but I'm not the one operating.
- This's a lot of blood.
- She's crashing!
- You're over-thinking it.
- Dr. Yang?
- Look at the aorta.
- What does it tell you?
- I have two options.
- I don't know which one to do!
- This is crazy.
- Why isn't she helping her?
- How's it going?
Yang's killing her patient and
Altman's reading The Atlantic Monthly.
If I suture, it might not hold.
If I clamp, it could rupture.
- BP's tanking.
- What the hell are you doing?
- I'm teaching. She's learning.
- She needs help.
She may be too proud to say it, but
how about we don't let this patient die
- and give her a hand anyhow?
- She asked, she's not
that proud.
And I said no. This
patient is not going to die.
- She's going to
save the patient.
- Pig or cow.
If you sit on your hands
because you're angry...
- Get over yourself.
- That patient...
Dr. Hunt, you are blowing my
concentration! Get out of my OR!
Pig or cow, pig or
cow, pig or cow...
Pig! Clamp.
Three-oh wool pledget.
Dr. Torres and I think
your knee needs replacing.
That's been true since college.
There's too much degeneration.
The joint is completely shot.
You need a unicondylar repair
or you may lose
the ability to walk.
Knee replacement'll take
me out of the game. Forever.
Exactly.
OK, it's coming up.
Look, right there!
Look at that.
That's the minute we knew
your mother was different.
That other hand
holding the retractor?
That's Garber. He was the
chief of surgery back then.
No one could believe it.
She walked in that
room a resident,
and walked out a legend.
Derek was worried
when you didn't show up
for the Tom Kates surgery.
Derek worries. It makes him
a good guy. Look, look, look.
If Dr. Montgomery had
hit it during the procedure...
It's dangerous.
What about that band
that's squeezing his thigh?
- He's not gonna have a knee?
- Sloan, you could have died.
- I can't have a gimpy kid.
- I know I haven't been
your father for long, but if
you say "gimp" one more time,
- I'm gonna smack you.
- You don't get it.
He needs legs! OK?
He doesn't have a dad!
He's got a stupid, slutty mom!
Don't you see?
I've already hurt him enough
by giving him me as a mother.
- He needs feet!
- Sloan...
I don't know how to
take care of any baby.
OK? I can't have one
that's hurt. I can't handle it.
My mom doesn't even talk to me.
I'm doing this alone.
Please.
Listen. You're not stupid.
And you're not slutty.
The Sloans...
are a... passionate people.
You dragged yourself across
the country so you could get help
taking care of this baby.
That's not being stupid.
That's being a mom.
I'm not gonna let
anything happen to you.
Or the baby.
Go to LA.
Addison said 95 percent.
That's not that bad.
Let her do the surgery.
Looks like we're going to LA.
You're not gonna do this alone.
Hey.
Stay. After the baby's born.
Live with me and Lexie.
Raise the baby with us.
I don't know anything
about being a dad,
you don't know
about being a mom.
Maybe we could...
figure it all out together.
- Really?
- Yeah.
OK!
Drill, please.
Are you sure there's
nothing I can do to help?
Uh, no.
So I'm not gonna get to
do anything in this surgery?
Not worth what you paid for it?
- Shut up.
- You guys are
worked up about how none
of you get to operate anymore,
but you know
what? At some point,
you'll log enough
hours with a scalpel.
At some point,
you'll be surgeons.
And one day, you'll
look up and realize
there's more in the
world than cutting.
Tom Kates' career is ending.
That is what's
happening in this room.
So could you, for one second,
think about something other
than yourselves? Bone saw.
I can't believe I'm taking out the
best quarterback Seattle's ever seen.
You're not. He was out of
the game a long time ago.
I would have stepped in.
I would not have let
that patient get hurt.
- I know that.
- She needs to be pushed.
She's like a racehorse.
You need to push her.
- Otherwise,
she's gonna lose her mind.
- I know, Teddy.
So nothing else was
going on in that room?
Owen...
You ready to pay up?
That was the lamest
assist in history.
- Hardly worth...
- Oh... Oh... A deal's a deal.
Look, there might have
been a little misunderstanding
about what "you know" means.
I don't trade surgery for sex.
If you want sex, ask for it.
If you want surgery, go kiss
an attending's ass, not mine.
Hey, hey, hey! Whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa!
Hey, this is illegal and immoral
and... you two should be
ashamed of yourselves.
Charlie, go to hell!
How am I the bad guy here?
I should have asked you first,
but I was so excited,
and I was so sure
it was the right thing.
And you know why? 'Cause of you.
Since you, I know, for
the first time in my life,
- what the right thing is.
- I'm happy for you.
I really am.
Something happened
today. You became a dad.
A real one. And
Sloan, against all odds,
became a mom.
But I didn't.
I was barely ready
to move in with you,
never mind your
daughter and a grandbaby.
I just... I don't want this.
You wanted to give
your liver to your dad.
This is what you
do for family, right?
I understand why
you're doing it.
I just don't understand
why I'm doing it.
I think you're doing it for me.
Don't make me out
to be the selfish one.
You don't get to
unilaterally decide
to let a teenager and her
infant move into our house.
We'll get a bigger
place. She needs us.
Lexie, I thought I missed this.
This is a chance for me.
Don't make me choose
between you and her.
Why?
'Cause you'll choose her?
Yeah.
I'll choose her.
I think our
relationship just ended.
Something's going on with
the chief, I can't figure it out.
I think he's scared to
operate. Is that possible?
You don't know or
you're not gonna tell me?
Did you see that?
I'm holding the heart,
I feel it almost starting
to fibrillate in my hand!
I mean, piss-poor aortic
tissue, possibly irreparable,
and then bam!
Sutures hold, and it comes back!
I mean, please, I don't
wanna see the face.
I don't want to hear what
you have to say. I was fine!
I was on fire! I was learning!
I felt alive for the first time in
I don't know how long, Owen.
- Like I had air in my lungs.
- She's leaving Seattle.
It's just not gonna
work for her.
When I lost my nerve
the chief helped me.
It's... nothing.
If it's nothing, find a
way to look me in the eye.
- What are you doing in here?
- Moving in.
No, no, no. I'm sick of
living in a damn trailer.
- Go live in Izzie's old room.
- You go, she's your wife.
I thought you were shacking
up with what's-his-face.
I'm not.
The Post-it didn't say
anything about lying.
- I didn't think it needed it.
- I'm not lying.
You don't need to know
every thought in my head.
I have relationships
that don't...
What are you doing?
I'm too young to
be a grandmother.
I'm just supposed to
be working like a dog
and then come home
and do stupid things
like Bungee jumping.
Or Jell-O shots.
I don't even know what
people my own age do anymore.
I know something
stupid you can do.
Hmm...
You never forget the
moment you become a doctor.
I don't know why I...
I keep telling myself
there's no problem.
But if there's no problem,
why can't I just say it?
A switch flips.
Suddenly, you're not
playing dress-up anymore.
You own the white coat.
Dr. Altman, wait. Wait.
What do you want? More money?
- I'll talk to the chief.
- No.
They can set up a new
cardio unit with a research lab
- or you can work with vets.
- It isn't about that.
Wait, wait, wait. No one's
ever believed in me like this.
You believe in me more
than I do. And I need that.
I'm gonna die here without that.
Cristina, it's complicated.
- Tell me what you want...
- I want Owen!
Take him!
What you may not notice
is the moment that
being a doctor...
changes you.
He's drinking again.