I will turn myself in.
I'm looking for Dr. Asher.
She hasn't come in yet.
My phone crashed on me,
and I had to get it fixed.
And I caught a flat.
You expect me to believe that?
You didn't seem to have
a problem last night.
Your patient and her baby
almost died today,
while you were off somewhere
getting high.
You think whatever
you want to.
Yeah, what do you need?
A favor.
That was a mistake thinking
you'd turn yourself in.
Hey, how's your
hormone therapy going?
It feels like my skin
is crawling with ants.
How lucky am I to
have found you?
You give me hope, Ben.
All right, Maggie,
the radiologist should read
your scans sometime today,
so that just leaves
your labs.
Come back at 6:00 p.m.
for a blood draw.
Okay, yeah.
Thanks. Ooh, Dr. Singh?
The results, how soon?
I'll ask the lab
to put a rush on it.
Yeah...
The wait is hell,
I know.
Yeah.
But I got a good feeling.
I'm not worried.
Hey. I gotta get to work.
See you at 6:00.
Okay.
Wait. Your bowling
semi-finals are tonight.
You should go.
I can handle this alone.
Nah, I'm gonna skip.
I wanna be there.
Are you kidding?
Your team needs you.
Go.
Baby, don't sweat it.
They'll call in an alternate.
I said I'll be fine.
Okay? Just...
What's up?
Why are you boxing me out
all of a sudden?
I'm not boxing you out.
You are.
Just...
Just, don't miss
your game, okay?
I'll be there
as soon as I can
after my appointment.
I gotta get back
to the ED.
Word is, Doc Crock's
fooling around with
Lena Maynor. CT Tech.
Funny, I heard
he was hooking up with
Camille in the pharmacy.
What?
Don't you all
have anything
better to do?
Morning, Sexton.
Mags, I think I left
my badge in the car.
I'll be right back.
All right.
Make it snappy.
You okay?
Yeah. Why do I care
who he sees?
Don't forget, appointment
with Dr. Patchefsky tonight.
See how many
eggs fertilized.
You mean
if any eggs fertilized.
After, I was thinking
we can grab dinner
at Galit,
celebrate.
The eternal optimist.
All right, I'm in.
Dr. Manning!
You'd probably
call this ill fortune,
but I'd call it fate.
Your shift started
an hour ago.
What, did you have
one too many bourbons
last night?
Didn't know you were
punching my time card,
but no, actually.
Not this time.
Left my badge
in the car. Again.
Should probably
super glue it to my forehead.
Stapler would work, too.
Help! Help, please!
Whoa, what's going on?
My wife, she's in labor.
She's bleeding real bad!
Okay.
Were you
in an accident?
Yeah. Yeah.
Did she have problems
with her pregnancy
before today?
Not sure.
Gimme your phones,
and get in.
What?
Hey, you don't
need to do this.
Gimme your damn phone.
Okay, listen.
I'm the surgeon, okay?
I can help him.
You let her go, okay?
I said get in!
Okay, okay, okay.
Listen.
Now! Get in!
Sit down.
Okay. Easy.
Easy.
That's a nasty laceration.
Want to tell me what happened?
Watch it.
You're gonna kill him!
He nicked his femoral vein.
Belt's not gonna
stop the bleeding.
Hand me that paintbrush.
Okay.
I need you to lift
your leg for me, okay?
That's too tight,
damn it!
Any looser, and you'll
bleed out in minutes.
Look, if he
doesn't get surgery,
he's gonna lose his leg.
We need to get him
to the hospital now.
No hospital!
Figure something out!
What?
Maybe you take us to get
supplies, okay?
There's a pharmacy
right down the road.
No, security's
too tight there.
Is there still
that gas station
up on Cermak, Jimmy?
Yeah.
Go!
Easy, man.
All right. All right.
Hey, Will Halstead,
here to see Dr. Hannah Asher.
Let's see. Asher.
Looks like she was admitted
yesterday morning.
Yeah.
We typically don't
recommend visitors
for the first 48 hours.
Yeah, she's expecting me.
You know, I don't wanna
leave her hanging.
Room 2268.
Make it brief.
Thank you.
Hey! Excuse me?
What dose of methadone
is Dr. Asher on?
She's sick as a dog.
She's being tapered
way too fast.
This facility doesn't
permit the use
of opioid agonists
like methadone
for medical staff.
Most peer-run
centers don't.
Wait, wait.
So, you're telling me
she's gotta go cold-turkey?
No methadone?
Because she's a doctor?
It's the protocol.
Dr. Choi, Treatment 3.
Oh, no. Jasmine.
You know her?
She's been in and out of ED
for end-stage liver disease.
Hey.
April.
That's her friend, Lauren.
Hey, Lauren.
April, oh, my God.
Hey, boys.
Momma's not feeling
so well.
I'm so sorry to hear that.
What's going on?
Jasmine was making
the boys' breakfast,
and she just
started throwing up,
and then she passed out.
Is she gonna be okay?
We're gonna take
good care of her, okay?
I promise. Come on.
Why don't you take them
to the day care center, okay?
Okay.
I'll keep you posted.
All right. Thanks.
Right through there.
Hey, Jasmine.
April! April,
where are my babies?
Lauren just took them...
Easy.
...to the day care center.
Don't worry. Just lie back.
Okay.
No nodes,
but eyes are icteric.
Jasmine, I'm gonna
push on your belly, okay?
Okay.
Severe ascites.
Let's get a CBC, CMP,
UA and chest X-ray.
Jasmine, says here
you're scheduled
for a living donor
transplant next week,
but I'm thinking
they may move it up to today.
They found you a donor?
That's great.
Last time you were here,
you were still waiting
on the list.
I found my own, actually.
My biological mom, Annette.
I didn't know
you were adopted.
Petitioned the courts
to disclose her information.
Thank God she was
willing to donate.
She's my last shot.
That's some good luck.
Yeah.
More like a miracle.
All right, I see
Annette's info here.
Is it okay if I contact her?
Uh-huh.
Please do. Thank you.
Okay.
Baghdad!
Has anyone seen Dr. Marcel?
He left for his car ages ago.
I paged him twice.
Because methadone
and suboxone
are technically opiates,
the concern is they're gonna
cause impairment on the job.
But doctors can
take depression meds
and sleeping pills?
And residents can
work 30-hour shifts?
Where's the concern there?
I hear ya. You know,
it's complicated.
No, you know what?
It's inhumane.
They're punishing addicts
because of the stigma.
Look, Will,
it must have been
an agonizing decision,
you know, turning in Hannah?
I can only imagine.
But for what it's worth,
I think you did
the right thing.
Yeah.
Will, patient in 4.
College kid, passed out
on campus.
Suffering from dizziness
and a headache.
Dr. Charles, turns out
she's an old patient
of yours. Krista Butler.
Oh, Krista.
Early-onset schizophrenia
presented when she was
about 15.
All right.
Good to know.
Krista.
Dr. Charles.
How ya doing?
They didn't...
They didn't call
my mom, did they?
'Cause I'm 18 now.
She has not been contacted.
Everything okay
with you two?
Since I started college,
she's just...
She's gone all psycho
helicopter mom on me.
I just...
I've had to stay
at my boyfriend's place
the past couple nights,
just to catch a break.
Hmm.
Mothers and daughters.
Krista, this is Dr. Halstead.
I have brought him
up to date
on your history.
Okay.
Hi there.
So, other than
the dizziness and headache,
anything else
bothering you?
Stomach doesn't
feel so great.
Heart rate's
a bit elevated.
I'm thinking
you're dehydrated.
Any chance you had
a few drinks last night?
Maybe a couple.
But nothing crazy.
Look, you're in college,
you wanna try new things,
I completely get it,
but you know,
you gotta be really
careful mixing alcohol
and antipsychotics, right?
What are you taking
right now?
Nothing.
I'm not taking
risperidone anymore.
I haven't taken it
for months, actually.
Krista, it's really important
you remain compliant
with your meds...
It makes me feel numb.
Less creative.
What, so, you're just
symptom free?
Yeah, totally.
Never felt better.
Okay. I wanna talk about
this more a little later.
But in the meantime,
let's get you feeling better.
Yeah, CBC, BMP,
hang a normal liter
of saline,
and two milligrams
of metoclopramide
for the nausea.
Krista, I'll be back
to check on you soon.
So, just out of curiosity,
when's the last time
you checked in
with your mom?
Fine. You can call her.
Okay. I'll be back
in a bit.
All right. Make sure
you keep his leg elevated
until I get back.
Okay.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
She comes with me,
you stay here.
Listen, I'm the surgeon.
I know what to get.
Cuff him. Catch.
Come on, do it!
Okay.
Let's go!
I'm sorry.
No, no. Hands above
his head. That bar.
Okay.
It's all right.
All right, all right.
Cover your hands.
Come on.
Move.
That your boy on your arm?
Just...
You just keep...
How old is he?
Get back!
Get in there, come on!
Move!
What the hell
did you do to him?
Nothing!
He just passed out.
What the hell you doing?
See? He's alive, okay?
Bro?
His calf is rock solid.
We need to move.
I need my hands
to work, man.
Come on.
Pull around the corner.
Over there.
Okay. Okay.
Hey, Miss Hill.
I'm Dr. Choi.
How's my daughter?
Is she doing okay?
I told Jasmine
that I would watch the boys,
so she could rest up
till the transplant,
but that girl,
she thinks
she's superwoman,
I swear.
So, they're getting
her ready for surgery?
Yeah, the transplant team
is just
running some tests to ensure
everything goes smoothly.
Oh, it's gonna go smoothly.
Been praying on it
since I got the call.
I like your attitude.
And while they finish up
with Jasmine,
I just need to check your BP,
if you don't mind.
Not at all.
I heard your story.
Pretty incredible
being reunited
with your daughter
under the circumstances.
God works in mysterious ways,
and I've learned not
to question Him.
Your hard work paid off.
BP's improved.
Amen!
Miss Hill, your chart
says you had an episode
of malignant hyperthermia?
When I got foot surgery
a few years back.
That drug...
I forget the name...
Succinylcholine.
I had a real
bad reaction to it.
But they said I could still
donate to Jasmine...
I just have to use
a different anesthesia, right?
That's correct.
Just double checking.
Excuse me.
I have been calling
and texting you nonstop!
You're supposed to
come home every night,
no exceptions...
Mom, chill!
I was busy studying.
I was about to
call the police.
You see what
I'm talking about?
How about we let
Krista rest a bit?
I'm gonna go get you
some food.
Okay.
I bet you've been living
on vending machine crap.
Don't you know...
I will be right back.
You know me so well.
Joanne? Look,
I don't wanna overstep,
but sometimes,
when we loosen
the reigns a bit...
Loosen the reigns,
like what?
Let her drink?
Krista's no longer
a minor. I'm not
at liberty to discuss...
Don't give me that.
She is a week over 18.
Dr. Charles.
Some help in here.
Honey? Oh, my God!
Two of Ativan.
What's wrong with her?
Having a seizure.
Has she ever had one before?
No, never.
Okay, so,
give me a BMP, a CBC,
a head CT,
EKG and a urine tox.
Copy that.
Mmm-hmm.
Also, an EEG.
Shh.
Wait, you don't think
Annette is Jasmine's
biological mother?
Malignant hypothermia
is a genetic disorder.
If Annette can't tolerate
succinylcholine,
Jasmine shouldn't
be able to, either.
But I checked Jasmine's chart,
they used it in her
previous surgeries.
Yeah, but look,
the transplant team
didn't flag it.
Are we really gonna
jeopardize Jasmine's life
over a possibility?
If it were me on that gurney,
I'd at least wanna know.
Look, Ethan, wait.
If Annette
changes her mind,
that is it for Jasmine.
She doesn't have
any time left.
Think of her boys.
Please, you don't
have to do this.
Krista's EEG is normal.
No epileptiform activity.
She didn't have a seizure.
So, we're looking
at what, dyskinesia?
Right. CT was normal
as well.
No previous signs
of strokes.
Yeah, it can
also be caused by
a drug interaction.
Urine tox is clean.
It's not dyskinesia.
Unless,
you gave her
metoclopramide
for the nausea, right?
Yeah.
How much?
Two milligrams, why?
I'm gonna order
a couple more labs.
Hey, Doris? I got
a peds patient
in Treatment 2.
Grab Dr. Lanik for me?
Peds? Where's Dr. Manning?
I mean, first Crockett
goes AWOL,
and now, Nat's late
with no call-in.
It's not like her.
Dr. Manning's car
is in the lot.
I just passed it.
That's strange.
She's not picking up
her phone.
Can you track
her location
on "Drop A Pin"?
Yeah.
That's weird.
It says that she's been
just outside of the hospital
for the last hour.
Kristi, grab the brick.
This thing says
she should be
right here.
I'm gonna
call her again.
Come on, Nat.
It's coming from in here.
Oh, my God.
Wait. There's
another phone here.
Be careful.
There could be prints.
That's Crockett's phone.
Okay. Uncuff him.
All right, come on,
let's go!
Come on, do it!
All right,
easy with that trigger.
Come on, let's do it.
Okay.
Sterilize him.
This is gonna hurt.
Easy.
Just be quick.
Yeah. Yeah. No, the alley
near the back end
of the south parking lot.
Any luck?
No. There's a blind spot.
Thank you.
Two of my doctors
are missing.
Possibly,
in grave danger.
What do you have?
Okay, so, the prints were
smeared, but techs were
able to lift two partials.
And they're a match
for an escaped convict's
brother, Jim Clemons.
And the blood?
It's a DNA match
for Tyler Clemons,
convicted murderer.
So, what now?
Now? We don't stop
'til we find them.
I got a BOLO out,
and an investigative alert.
I have officers across
the city sitting on their
known associates,
and their family members.
So far, no hits.
Meantime, no one else
can know about this.
If the news catches wind
of the kidnapping,
the abductors might
try to cut their losses...
Understood. But please,
keep us posted?
Will do.
Yeah.
I'm going to run Tyler
and Jim Clemons
through our system,
see if any medical
records come up.
What do you mean
Krista didn't have a seizure?
I saw it with my own eyes.
So, the involuntary
movements you saw
were caused by something
called dyskinesia.
Is that due
to her schizophrenia?
No.
It can be caused
by an adverse
drug interaction.
In this case,
between the drug
we gave Krista for her nausea,
metoclopramide,
and her antipsychotic
medication, risperidone.
But here's the thing,
Krista told us that
she had stopped
taking her risperidone,
and yet, the labs showed
a low level of the drug
in her system.
Do you have any idea
why that might be?
I don't know.
What does it matter?
At least, she's taking
her medicine again.
I think we can all
agree that that's
a good thing. Right?
So, based on the half-life
of risperidone,
we know that Krista
hasn't taken the drug
in roughly 48 hours.
The amount of time
she's been crashing
at her boyfriend's,
away from home.
Joanne, have you been
giving Krista risperidone
without her knowledge?
She had been doing
so well, I just...
When she told me
she was stopping,
I had to do something.
Dr. Charles, please,
you remember
her hallucinations,
how bad it got.
You can't say anything.
I'm only trying
to protect her.
I am begging you. Please.
Joanne, dosing her
without her knowledge
it's just,
it's extraordinarily
dangerous.
It's also
a direct violation
of her autonomy.
Now the best thing would be
for you to tell her,
but if you're
not up for that,
I'm sorry,
but it is my duty
to let her know.
Please don't.
Hurry up, God damn it!
We gotta get back on the road!
With the tourniquet
turned down,
I can only move so fast.
I gotta deal with
these bleeders
individually.
We don't have time.
You want it
to go fast? Move.
There.
The bleeding's stopped.
Easy, easy.
You crazy bitch.
All right,
easy. Easy.
Let's go.
Oh! Whoa!
Hey! We did our part,
you let us go.
You're not going anywhere.
Come on.
Jasmine did great.
The transplant
couldn't have
gone any better.
Thank you.
She's really lucky
to have a friend like you.
Will you excuse me?
I should probably go tell
the boys the good news.
Yeah, of course.
Lauren! Hey!
Hey, April.
Was that Lauren Knight?
Do you know her?
Yeah. From when
I worked at Children
and Family Services.
Wait. Lauren used
to work at DCFS?
Mmm-hmm.
Do you know
if she still works there?
Pretty sure, yeah. Why?
No, I just thought she said
she worked at a bank.
Doesn't DCFS keep
adoption records?
Mmm-hmm.
Excuse me, Arlene.
I need to make a call.
Thank you so much for calling.
Okay.
Sharon!
Yeah.
A clerk from
a local gas station in
the West Loop just called,
said he found
Natalie's badge.
Please tell me
he laid eyes on her?
He did. She was okay.
Okay, I'll call
Detective Halstead,
hopefully, they'll have
security cameras there.
Yeah. Oh, Sharon.
Yeah?
Where are we
with the medical records?
I'm still working on it.
Okay.
How's my mom?
Any side effects
from the anesthesia?
None. She started asking
about you the moment
she woke up. Sweet lady.
Yeah, she is.
Jasmine, how could you?
Both of you?
April, what are you
talking about?
They conned Annette.
She posed as her daughter.
They catfished her
for an organ.
That's not true.
Jasmine, yeah,
you were adopted,
your biological parents
are Derrick and Janine,
both deceased.
You accessed
adoption records
to set up Annette?
Of course not.
That's ridiculous.
Jasmine?
Say something!
Jasmine, don't answer him.
Annette put her life
on the line for you!
I know.
I know she did.
And I didn't set out
to hurt her, I promise.
It's just, when I found out
that my biological parents
were dead,
I had no other option.
My boys.
I couldn't leave my boys,
I couldn't.
What you did is illegal.
Annette could press charges.
What was the plan?
Were you gonna ditch her
while she's recovering?
God, no.
Never.
Annette may not be
my biological mom,
but she's become family
to me and the boys.
We love her.
We'd never abandon her.
This isn't Jasmine's fault.
Listen, this whole thing
was my idea.
Okay, please.
I cannot believe
you would do this.
April.
Where are you taking us?
Just be quiet, go.
Come on, man.
We done with them?
No, no, no. I need them,
they're my insurance policy.
But you... You go
and I will see you soon,
okay? I love you, man.
Don't even think
about it, girl.
Please, I have a son...
Come on. Just go,
just go in the house.
Let's go.
All right.
Easy, man. Easy!
Go. Just keep quiet.
Go. Move.
Come on, inside.
I can't believe
you're really here.
But...
Go now, Ma.
I just need you
to go. Go.
In the living room.
Go.
He's ill.
Maybe we can help him.
Nah. You can't.
Just grab these chairs.
Put 'em back to back.
And sit down.
But we can help.
Just do it, please.
Okay.
Close the door. I may have
something to help
with your investigation.
Bobby Clemons,
Tyler's son's
medical records.
How'd you get those?
We can't unseal
medical records.
All that matters
is I got them.
Bobby was
treated for stage four
brain cancer at East Mercy.
He's terminal.
His grandmother
signed him out,
took him home
for hospice.
His grandmother?
We couldn't track her down,
her last known was demolished.
3768 South Parnell Ave.
Everybody, listen up,
this is Halstead.
I need you to meet at Sox lot
for a pre-raid brief.
I got a solid location
on our target.
Copy that.
I was hoping you were
Jasmine and my grandbabies.
Annette, that's
what we came
to talk to you about.
I'm so sorry,
but we have to tell you,
Jasmine is not actually
your daughter.
Miss Hill?
I already knew.
What?
My daughter, Zora,
died 12 years ago,
in a shelter.
At least,
that's what the folks in
the neighborhood tell me.
But, if you knew Jasmine
wasn't yours, why didn't
you say something?
I was just a baby myself
when I got pregnant.
I made some bad choices
trying to provide
for my little girl,
and I ended up doing time.
That's how I lost her.
But I never stopped
thinking about her.
So, when Jasmine called?
I knew it was God
giving me another chance
to do some good.
To make it up
to Zora, somehow.
So, I played along.
I didn't tell Jasmine
that someone must've
made a clerical error,
and I wasn't really
her mother.
Annette, it wasn't
a clerical error.
Jasmine knew
you were not her mother.
She conned you.
I don't care.
Miss Hill,
what they did was wrong.
For the first time
in my life,
I have a family.
And I don't
wanna lose her
or those boys.
Um...
Our obligation
was to inform you.
How you deal with it
is up to you.
Thank you.
So, can you ask them,
my family, to come see me?
She'd rather
live in a lie.
Guess sometimes,
the truth is more painful.
Help!
Somebody, help!
No! No.
Stop it!
No!
Krista, don't. Ow!
They're under my skin.
I have to get
them out! Please!
Two of Haldol IV.
Need help.
Let's go, let's go.
No, please, no!
No, no! No, no! No, please!
You're poisoning me!
Mom! No, you have
to listen, it's poison! Stop!
I'm sorry,
but you're a danger
to yourself, we have to
give you medication.
Please!
Meds are in.
Joanne, are you all right?
Let's take a look
at your face.
Are you okay?
If you hadn't told her.
If you'd just let me continue
helping her. Now what?
If she continues to exhibit
self-harming behavior,
we'll put her
on a psych hold.
And what if
she doesn't take
her medicine?
In that case,
the next step would be
to seek a court order
to get her committed
so that she can receive
the necessary treatment.
But let's not get ahead
of ourselves...
Institutionalize her?
She's gonna have to
drop out of college.
I had this under control.
You've ruined her life.
I'm sorry, son.
I'm so sorry
I wasn't there.
This is Detective
Jay Halstead with
Chicago Police Department.
Tyler,
we have you surrounded.
I don't want you
or your family to get hurt.
I want you to come out
the front door, with your
hands where we can see them.
No one's going to shoot.
I know you're
with Natalie Manning
and Crockett Marcel.
As an act of good faith,
have them come out first.
If you do not comply...
Here. Uncuff her.
...we'll be forced
to breach the house.
Okay, you can go.
Go ahead. Go. You go.
No, I...
It's okay.
Do as he says. It's okay, go.
It's okay. It's okay.
Shut the door behind you.
Shut the door.
Hold, stand down.
Friendly coming out.
Hold the door. Hold your fire.
Hostage coming out.
Shields. Go, go.
Go! Go, go, now! Get her out.
I got you. Hey.
Get her out of there.
Move! Move!
I'm sorry about your son.
Go ahead.
Hey, no! No!
Come on, come on, man!
Don't do that!
Crockett!
Breach! Breach! Breach!
No!
Crockett!
Wait!
Natalie!
Come here.
Are you okay?
Are you hurt?
Yes. I'm fine. I'm fine.
But Crockett...
Where is he?
I don't know.
He was in the house,
and there was a gunshot,
and all the officers
swarmed in.
But they won't let me in.
They won't tell me anything.
Crockett!
I was so scared.
I'm okay. I'm okay.
You all right?
Yeah.
All right.
Get him to the ED,
make sure you
get him two units
of uncrossed blood, stat.
That man owes you his life.
For what it's worth,
I completely understand
why you did what you did.
Oh, I wish I could
just shake her.
I wanna make her see
she's just throwing
her future away.
I mean,
it's our most basic,
primal instinct as parents,
is protect our kids,
often from themselves, right?
Which is when it gets
really tricky.
If you can resist
that instinct,
if you can just...
Just try and let Krista
figure things out on her own.
You mean, let her
lose everything.
If that's what
it takes, yeah.
I mean, if you can tolerate
watching her experience
the consequences
of her own decisions,
there's a really
good chance that eventually,
she will see the benefits
of staying compliant.
And Joanne,
that's the only
real shot she has,
at learning how
to manage her illness.
What are you doing here?
So, I brought you something.
What's that?
It's suboxone.
I'll bring you more tomorrow.
You should not have
to suffer like this.
First, you snitch on me.
Then, you come in here,
and you jeopardize
my recovery.
They catch me,
I will never be able
to practice again.
Hannah, I was
just trying to...
Go.
Go and don't come back again.
Go! Go! Go!
Get out! Get out!
Get out, now!
Hannah, is everything okay?
Ben.
Now, look here.
I know you're used
to running things
in the hospital,
but I am my own man.
You do not make decisions
for me, okay?
You still waiting
for your results?
I'm sorry, babe.
I just can't.
What if it's bad news?
What if the hormone therapy
isn't working?
Then we'll figure
something else out.
I'm gonna be with you
every step of the way.
I know you will.
And that's what scares me.
What's that mean?
Ben, no!
Maggie!
You were by my side
at my lowest.
And now,
you're in remission.
You should be out there,
having fun.
Not stuck in
the hospital with me.
And there you go again.
Telling me what to do.
You don't get it, do you?
You are my life.
Sorry to interrupt.
I come bearing
very good news.
What?
Do you want to step
into my office?
No.
Please, tell me now.
The radiologist
read your scans.
No sign of a mass.
And your blood work,
it was remarkable, really.
No detectable
tumor markers.
So, does that mean...
You're officially
in remission.
After inseminating the eggs,
unfortunately, we found
that none of them fertilized.
I know this is not
the news you wanted,
but it doesn't
have to be
the end of the road.
You can start another cycle
in as little as six weeks.
We'll talk about it,
and let you know.
No. I'll do it.
All right.
So, what do you wanna
do to celebrate?
Spa treatment? Dinner?
You name it, I got you.
Just being with you,
that's enough.
Oh, come on! Come on,
come on, come on.
Weren't you just
lecturing me about
having fun?
Yeah!
Go big or go home.
If you had
one wish right now,
anything in the world,
what would it be?
Honestly?
Mmm-hmm.
If... The only thing
I would wish is...
To spend the rest
of my life with you.
Are you serious?
You better not be
playing with me,
because I'd marry
you tomorrow.
I'm not playing.
Oh, baby.