Previously on "ER."
Son of a bitch!
I can be a competent surgeon.
I can learn the techniques,
the mechanics..
...but I'll never
be a great surgeon.
Mark, I'm not gonna write
you that prescription
for the Percodan. I think
you've gotta get some help.
I'm fine.
Your baby was deprived
of oxygen in the womb.
'So there's always
the possibility'
'that there could
be brain damage.'
Back off!
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
‐ 'Can we get this tonight?'
‐ 'We have to.'
'Change out the batteries
in those lavaliers.'
'He's getting
more nine‐volts.'
‐ 'It's got the smell, huh?'
‐ 'Rob, white‐balance that.'
'Tony already did it.
He laid down bars and tones.'
'How come hospitals
have this smell?'
'Pork buns?
Who went for food?'
‐ 'I brought it myself.'
‐ 'Thanks a hell of a lot.'
'Camera mount in the trauma
room's key‐stoning.'
‐ 'Hasn't been leveled yet.'
‐ 'Alright, guys.'
'Let's get ready to shoot.
Everybody on the same page?'
‐ 'You worried about that?'
‐ 'No, it's working fine.'
'Hey, hey!
Those tapes are numbered!'
'Stuart and I will stick
with the doctor.'
'Luis and Rob,
follow our lead.'
'This is still breaking up.'
'Remember our deadline. We don't
get a second chance here.'
‐ 'I hate hospitals.'
‐ 'Is Dr. Greene here yet?'
‐ 'I haven't seen him.'
‐ 'We'll catch up.'
‐ 'Are you set in the lounge?'
‐ 'Just need tapes.'
'Where do we put
the battery charger?'
'It's plugged in
in the x‐ray room.'
'Trim RF six,
it's too hot.'
'What is that?'
'Oh, you know,
it's back‐up footage.'
'Workplace stuff.'
Cubbies still losing?
I don't know.
I haven't been watching.
We put up stationary cameras,
one at your main desk
one in that yellow
operating room.
‐ Trauma one?
‐ Yeah, high‐traffic areas.
Get some wide angles to cut with
what the hand‐held guys shoot
for pace, variety, you know.
Right.
And we just leave them running.
Get what we get.
It's on?
By the end of the day
you'll forget we're here.
See you.
Excuse me.
Oh!
...in 1983 and again in 1986.
Philadelphia in '83,
the New York Mets in '86.
We'll see another
one right here.
'I thought we were gonna start
with him coming on shift.'
Too late.
He's already in trauma.
Careful!
He's the one
with the little glasses.
'I remember.'
Open fracture,
distal tibia.
We gave four milligrams of
morphine in the field.
How bad did
the goalpost look?
Hey, I scored.
Nurse Marquez,
let's order pre‐op labs
CBC, type and screen, and
left lower extremity films.
Ancef?
One gram IV piggyback
and 100 of gentamicin.
I really broke it, huh?
You won't be playing
varsity this fall.
Varsity?
I'm 24 years old.
‐ Twenty‐four?
‐ Guess, I don't need you.
Man, you are going
to get carded until you're 40.
‐ Can you stay for a moment?
‐ You need me?
Yeah, I want to get Dr. Greene
discussing the orders.
‐ You need the back of my head?
‐ Yeah. That will be great.
Uh, Dr. Greene,
how's that pulse?
Distal pulses are
two plus and equal.
No arterial injury.
'Good evening.'
Dr. Carter,
you're early.
Open fracture?
‐ Yup.
‐ Need me?
Yes, uh, actually I'm sick of
assisting Dr. Welby here.
Listen, why don't you
finish the history?
Do you have pain anywhere
besides your leg, Mr. Chang?
Justin.
I kind of jammed my stomach.
Have you got
any allergies?
Just hay fever.
‐ Anything for me?
‐ Oh, this is today?
'Please don't look
into the lens.'
‐ Yeah, right.
‐ Possible surgical‐‐
‐ You're still here?
‐ Yep. 36 hours.
We're short a surgeon.
Alright,
Belly's benign. Call ortho.
How's it going?
Is he pissed off
about losing you?
We haven't talked.
When was your
last meal?
I ate lunch around one.
‐ Cimetidine, 300 milligrams IV.
‐ You got it.
That will cut down on the
acidity in your stomach.
If you vomit in the OR,
you could aspirate your stomach
contents into your lungs
and develop pneumonia.
That's probably more
than Mr. Chang needed to hear.
Whoa, whoa.
We've got a problem.
‐ What.
‐ Sorry to interrupt.
One of the docs says she wasn't
informed about our shoot.
Alright. I'll be right there.
Stuart, are you okay?
'Dr. Carter, uh, our mic will
pick you up at normal volume'
'you can relax and
speak naturally.'
Okay, Carter wasn't acting.
He's really like that.
They're focusing on Dr. Greene
but their goal is to get a sense
of what all of us do
in the emergency department
and portray it
in a positive light.
It says nothing there
about a "Positive light."
'It only talks
about their rights'
'to use my name and
image in perpetuity.'
Why not take this
in the lounge?
You know, doctors Anspaugh
and Morgenstern
think this documentary will
increase public awareness
of the health care
issues we face.
Okay, I understand.
That's fine.
I'm sorry,
what's your name?
‐ 'Luis.'
‐ Luis. No offence, Luis.
I'm not saying you're
ambush us or do any expose
but there's nothing on
this form to stop them
and if I don't sign this
you're wasting film right now.
'It's tape.
It's cheap.'
Hi. I'm Agi Orton. My husband
and I are the directors.
Hi.
Anna Del Amico.
'Do you have
some questions?'
If we could speak in the lounge,
it will all straighten out.
Okay, sure.
I'll catch you later.
You know, Dr. Del Amico
is new here..
It's fine if she doesn't wanna
sign, we can shoot around her.
Luis, if you're
finished setting up
Stuart needs you.
Hey, miss, is this
gonna be on TV?
Uh, pre‐sold to PBS.
PBS? Not Network?
No. Luis.
That's not the point,
it's something Mark agreed
and he's excited about it.
‐ 'You think he's up to it?'
‐ Yeah, sure. Why not?
Cameras all over the place.
It makes me uptight.
I know. We'll all be hiding out
here by the end of the night.
I don't know Mark the way you do
but he seems a little shaky.
Oh, he's going
to be fine.
Yeah, I'd be shaky, too if I had
the crap beaten out of me.
'Mark wanted to do this.
I think that's a good sign.'
‐ 'Maybe he's back on his game.'
‐ Maybe.
In any case, they're here,
they're shooting.
There's nothing we can do about
it except stick up for Mark
which is what I'm doing.
Buddy, you look like
a star out there.
Well, I'm enjoying
all the attention.
Don't get too used to everybody
taking orders from you.
Yeah, I was hoping
for a sequel.
Yeah, well some of us
are working stiffs.
I've got measles
in four.
Later.
Oh!
Phew!
Mr. Schoenberger
is in sinus rhythm.
BP's 110/70,
pulse is 72, reps are 16..
...resps, uh, sorry.
Should I start over?
'Sure.'
Next time you can
just keep going.
Oh, well, Mr. Schoenberger's
cardiogram is normal.
His shortness of
breath was resolved
with two liters
of oxygen.
And he may have had slight
indigestion a couple hours ago.
Today was
all‐you‐can‐eat burritos
at my favorite
Mexican place.
Do you have any family
history of heart disease?
No. My relatives
generally prefer cancer.
‐ Do you smoke?
‐ Not cigarettes.
Mr. Schoenberger
recently took up cigars.
I don't inhale.
I started a cardiac work‐up
ordered a CBC, chem seven.
Cardiac enzymes,
serum myoglobin.
Whoa, Jeanie,
that's a little gung‐ho
for a guy who ate
too many burritos.
Well, he was concerned enough to
come in, and he has insurance.
That's no reason
to order a million tests.
You can lie back now.
You know where I can get
a hold of any Havana's?
Whoa! My tastes are
a little more pedestrian.
I'm happy puffing
on one of these.
No wonder you're
short of breath.
Seriously? You think
it's the cigars?
Those aren't fit
to be called cigars.
You should lay off
the cheapos for a few days
and I think
you're gonna feel fine.
Give up the stogies?
At least treat yourself
to something decent.
Hey, you think
this'll be in the movie?
I just dropped by
to thank you again, Mark
and to see how
things are going.
Y‐you don't
have to film this.
Everything
under control?
Yeah. Yeah, it is.
Seems like a pretty
busy night.
Not that too busy...for
a weeknight.
Right.
It's pretty slow
for a weeknight.
I'm sure it'll
pick up later.
Yeah. Later.
It should pick up.
You'll get good stuff.
I just wanted to make sure
things were copasetic
and thank you again
for taking this on.
Sure.
Stuart,
come grab this.
Excuse me, who do
I give this to?
Oh, you
decided to sign?
Yeah, just keep my face
off hard copy, okay?
The nurses are cooking,
they're mic'd to channel three.
The best one was the guy
with the transistor radio.
‐ Remember?
‐ Right.
He said he was
getting out of the shower
he slipped and he
sat down on it.
‐ Ouch.
‐ While it was still playing?
Whoop, there it is.
So I asked Mark,
Dr. Greene..
...if he was going to
extract the foreign body
and he said, "No, but I'll
tune it to the ball game!"
Head lac for Carter,
has anybody seen him?
'Is there's a camaraderie
between doctors and nurses?'
‐ 'What about dating?'
‐ Who, Mark?
'You tell me.'
Oh...um..
Oh, I'm sorry..
'Let me get that,
I got that.'
Actually, we do socialize
but more as a group.
And Dr. Greene comes...but he,
well, he used to come‐‐
Well, he's been taking
it kind of slow.
Yeah, since he got beat
down I mean, beat up.
You know about
that, right?
Mm.
Well, you know what,
actually, it's a myth
about doctors and
nurses dating so much.
I mean, I know more nurses who
date cops, firemen, paramedics.
Now, that cliche is true.
Oh, especially cops.
Especially young cops.
'Getting back to Dr. Greene,
he does seem a little..'
I need a nurse in three.
'Oh, okay, everybody,
that was great.'
'Lucy, you got
some explaining to do.'
'What?'
'What's all this
about cops and firemen?'
Stay with them.
They're mic'd.
'Jealous?'
'Jealous.'
I don't know what
you're doing for them
you're not doing for me.
I'll tell you later
if you bring the cuffs.
I thought I was gonna
get some sleep tonight.
Oh, don't count on that.
Look at that.
He wishes he
could read lips.
Hi, there, dumb ass.
Doug, he's waving.
You got a mic on?
Oh, my God! Do you think
he could he hear me?
Turn it off.
But that's the thing
about the ER, you know
You got to stay on your toes.
‐ Hey, Lily's looking for you.
‐ I'm on my way.
You're also more on
your own down here.
When I was up in surgery
there was always someone
looking over my shoulder
critiquing every move.
Here the residents
are responsible‐‐
Carter! Help me.
Get me a basin,
I can't get him rolled.
I think I'm
gonna puke again!
'I know..'
‐ I feel much better.
‐ 'Oh, good. Good.'
Oh, yeah.
I'm going to change.
Compazine for
our friend, please.
Twenty‐five milligrams PR.
Excuse me.
'What's that mean, "PR"?'
"Per rectum."
'Do you have
to clean this up?'
Oh, no.
Housekeeping
to suture room.
I don't know exactly
what you're looking for.
We're just gonna keep it
really conversational.
Everybody, come and go
as you normally would.
Don't be afraid
to interrupt.
Just talk right to me.
I'll be next to the camera.
'First, explain how long
you've been here'
'what an attending does.'
My name's Mark Greene.
And I've been working here
at County General
since I finished med school
six years ago.
I got the GI bleed in curtain
two admitted to medicine.
Okay, great.
Thanks, Kerry.
'Describe how an emergency
room serves the public.'
Oh, well for a lot of people
we're the only access‐‐
Mark, paramedics are pulling
in a 37‐year‐old male
under respiratory distress.
Neighbor called, he says
he's got cancer.
Alright, prep trauma
one and find Carter.
Oh, Mark, sorry, labs are
back on Schoenberger.
‐ You'd better take a look.
‐ The cigar smoker?
CKMBs are pretty high.
I'll say.
Did he go home?
He's getting
ready to go.
‐ Dr. Del Amico?
‐ Yeah.
Stick around, we have a
respiratory distress pulling up.
I'm on it.
Mr. Schoenberger,
we got your tests back
with a result we didn't expect,
indicating a possible problem.
What do you mean?
You ought to stick around
for one more test.
Troponin‐t.
It's just for clarification.
We can do it on the blood
we've already drawn.
Better safe
than sorry.
Exactly. And while
you're waiting
we're gonna stick you
back on a monitor.
An elevated CKMB
indicates heart
muscle damage.
‐ 'A heart attack?'
‐ That's right.
‐ I'll get another EKG.
‐ 'Can it mean something else?'
It's probably an MI. But the
other test will confirm it.
'And then what?'
Actually, regardless
of the other results
an elevated CKMB,
means he's had an MI.
So, I'm actually just
giving him a little time
to adjust to that possibility.
And, of course,
since I missed it
I'm buying some time
to cover my ass.
37‐year‐old man
in respiratory distress.
Neighbor here says
he was diagnosed
with esophageal cancer
six months ago.
I was watching him
while Krista went to the store.
He hasn't been
breathing that good‐‐
‐ Out of the way!
‐ He started, like, choking..
He's tachy at 120.
Pressure's 130/100.
Resps are increased at 30.
He's got a lot of secretions.
Alright, let's get him
on high‐flow O‐2
and prep
an intubation tray.
On my count,
one, two, three.
Help him, he can't breathe.
Hang in there, Boz.
Chuny, suction
these secretions.
Hang two liters of saline,
this guy is bone dry.
‐ Pulse ox is 89.
‐ Should I intubate?
With the mass in his throat,
we'd have to crike him.
But I don't want to use
extraordinary measures
if he has a DNR.
Do you know anything about
your best friend's wishes?
He's the best bass
player I ever met.
Yo, man, you can't light
that thing up in here.
Keep suctioning.
Anna, grab a blood gas.
Pulse ox down to 87.
Alright, prep a crike tray.
Give him 600 of clindamycin IV..
‐ Carol, get the slate.
‐ Excuse me.
‐ What's his name?
‐ Boz.
Boz, can you hear me?
I know you're having
trouble breathing.
Do you want us
to help you out?
‐ Antibiotics are up.
‐ I got to get in here.
Sir, I'm gonna hold up this
slate, and you can write on it.
Boz, do you want a
crichothyroidectomy?
I can cut a hole in your
neck to help you breathe.
Do you want that?
If you can't write your answer
I'll have to put the tube in.
Do you want
to be criked?
Come on, don't let him die!
Give him the crike thing!
Damn. I can't get this.
‐ Okay, crike tray.
‐ Yeah, do it. Do it!
No, no, no!
You do not want to know.
'I wouldn't ask
if I didn't want to know.'
I have done this
too long not to know.
This job, people don't
want to hear about it.
'Why? Because of what
you clean up?'
This is nothing.
Believe me, this here
is just a little...picnic.
You ought to see
what some of them do.
A body is only so big, but..
...you can hardly believe
all that comes out of it.
You get used to it though,
like every mama and daddy
get used to changing
a baby's diaper.
But the blood and the gore..
You know what
the gore is, right?
That's the part
you don't talk about
when you go home and they
ask you how your day was.
No, no.
It doesn't bother me.
You see, I'm a religious person
and I believe human beings
were created in God's image.
So, whatever I'm cleaning up
must be just fine.
Do you believe?
'I don't know.'
'You mean,
believe in God.'
Uh‐huh.
You couldn't do my job
if you didn't.
You could maybe be a doctor
or a nurse or make a movie.
Not my job.
Hey, I'll tell you
something else, too.
Luis, we need you
in the trauma room.
‐ A guy stopped breathing.
‐ I'm on my way.
'I'll catch you later.'
Sure, you will.
Most of the ones I can remember
are from my first year.
After a while,
you get protective
and you don't let
them get to you.
'What does it take these days to
break through your armor?'
It doesn't happen.
But there was this one
girl my first year.
I guess I'd gotten used to
this being a County facility.
I'd treated a lot
of homeless people
a lot of people
from the projects.
One day, this girl came in,
traffic accident
in a coma, brain dead,
and I realized I knew her.
She was the kid sister of a guy
I'd gone to med school with.
One night, she'd tried to show
me how to slam dance
you know, just fooling around.
That's when I realized
that trauma isn't something
that happens to other people.
'It could happen
to you.'
That's right.
'Does it change things
when it is you?'
What do you mean?
'When you yourself
are traumatized..'
'...as a doctor.'
'I see you have a splint
on your wrist.'
'I heard you had an incident
recently here at the hospital.'
Is that what
you're doing here?
‐ I don't wanna talk about that.
‐ 'I'm sorry.'
But safety is something
everybody worries about.
Is that why you picked me?
To get into all that?
Dr. Green, we're not here to
make you uncomfortable.
'You don't have to talk about
something if you don't want to.'
‐ Good, because I'm not.
‐ 'But we are here.'
And we are committed
to making this film.
'And we want you
to have an opportunity'
'to say what's
on your mind.'
Yeah, well I have
nothing to say.
I agreed to let
you follow me around
you can do that, but no more
comments, no interview.
Dr. Greene,
we are professionals.
We're not here
to attack you.
'Agi?'
Damn.
‐ 'Is that his daughter?'
‐ 'No, it's his wife.'
'Esophageal cancer,
it's a horrible death.'
Dr. Greene criked him.
He's running
into surgical options
and none of them are going
to buy him much time.
Are you sure you want
to speak to the wife?
She looks like
she's a teenager.
It may be difficult to get her
to understand the situation.
No, I'd like to try.
Normally, we wouldn't
have an intern take on
something like this,
but Carter's been around.
And technically, I'm not an
intern. I'm second year.
‐ Uh, no, you're an intern.
‐ I am?
You can't switch your specialty
here without starting over.
‐ I've already done a year.
‐ In surgery.
This is emergency medicine.
I thought you understood that.
Uh..
You know, let's, we'll
discuss this later
when we're not in the
middle of all this.
‐ 'Where do you start?'
‐ Huh?
'When you have
to counsel family'
'about something
like this.'
Oh, yeah, well,
it's tricky, you know.
People are upset,
and they're hearing
a lot of complex information.
An emergency resident..
...or intern, has to establish
an instant rapport with the‐‐
‐ Excuse me, doctor.
‐ No, not at all.
I was just coming in
to see you.
Um, your husband
is going to be admitted.
Yeah, well, you'd
better call transport.
They can take forever.
Okay. Well, we should talk about
your husband's condition.
Excuse me
for one second.
Chuny, can I see that
chart for a second? Thanks.
'If I go too fast for you or
if you have any questions'
'just please stop me.'
'Now I know your husband's
had some laser treatments.'
'That's a procedure to enlarge
the opening of the esophagus.'
'Yeah, for all
the good it did.'
'Well, a feeding tube can be
inserted through that opening.'
Cancer eats right through it.
Right. Well, there's
an option called the j‐tube.
We're not screwing
around with that.
The sucker's on his aorta,
he's a dead man.
If you feel that way,
you might want to consider
having your husband
sign a DNR.
That's a do‐not‐resuscitate
order, which‐‐
Yeah, got it.
There was one by his bed,
too but Rog sort of freaked.
I'm sorry.
We tried to ask him.
I was just out buying garlic
and herbs...
Boz' food.
But all he can do now
is smell it anyways.
I hold it under his nose,
and he smells.
Want to hear
about our sex life?
If there's anything
that I can answer
or if there's anything
that you need..
Yeah.
I'm on Librium.
Can you write me
a refill?
The mother wants
to call animal control.
Well, this
ought to be fun.
I've had Jojo
for nine years.
‐ He's a vicious dog.
‐ He only sounds that way.
He's never bitten
anyone before.
He hadn't been
around children.
Can you give it a
rest over there!
You see who's laying here
behaving herself?
‐ Did you call animal control?
‐ Please, take a breath.
This is our daughter who was
bitten! I can't believe you!
You're supposed to call
animal control with bites.
‐ Isn't that the law?
‐ Yes, it is.
Anna, can you pull that
light over here?
Hang on, sweetheart.
Hang on.
Did you see how
the bite happened?
My son did.
I'd run out
to get the phone
and apparently the dog
just went for her.
How bad does it look?
Uh, it's deep. She's going to
need intravenous antibiotics.
‐ Intravenous?
‐ Yeah.
‐ That's not a canine bite.
‐ What?
That's a bite from an
immature homo‐sapien
that's one who still
has primary incisors.
Todd?
‐ Did you bite your sister?
‐ It's okay.
Why would you do
such a thing?
‐ You know you love your sister.
‐ He gets a hug for this?
Okay, why don't you
guys wait here?
If you and I can speak
out in the hallway?
'How'd you get these burns on
your hands and your lip?'
I already told her.
She was making popcorn
when it exploded.
Her resting pulse is 120,
and she's tremulous.
You should lay
off the crack.
‐ I don't do that stuff.
‐ Uh‐huh.
You want me
to get a tox screen?
You want to stop
doing crack?
Go away, man.
I don't think the taxpayers
are interested
in buying Doris
a tox screen.
So, let's update her tetanus,
dress the burns
and have her checked in
the surgical clinic in two days.
She also complained
of an upset stomach.
‐ What have you eaten today?
‐ Nothing.
Nothing?
Not even popcorn?
You got to eat right
and stop the drugs.
‐ None of your business!
‐ See you next time.
'You didn't see any reason
to confirm her drug use?'
That's right.
‐ 'Dr. Greene's a busy man.'
‐ Yes, he is.
He has a lot of responsibility,
a lot of pressure.
Dr. Del Amica,
that's the chart.
‐ Okay. Thanks.
‐ How's he handle it?
Ah, you're going to have
to ask him that.
Sir, we have a
bed for you now.
No, I know, I know, we'll get
you in as soon as possible.
Nurse, did you see my doctor?
Where's the doctor?
It's okay, dear.
The doctor will see you soon.
I need a doctor!
Peter.
Hey, Peter!
Peter, wake up!
We've got a double
trauma coming in.
Teenager, a victim
of a gang beating
and a bystander who tried
to stop the attack.
They're both critical.
Have you seen Mark?
No, I'll meet him
in trauma two.
So, how'd
they find out?
I don't know.
Police report, gossip.
It doesn't matter.
‐ I'm not talking about it.
‐ That's good policy, man.
‐ Hey, how you doing?
‐ Hey, what's the score?
It's 8‐1, Cubs behind,
bottom of the seventh.
Listen, what you can't do is you
can't get mad at them on camera.
'Cause they go for
that stuff like sharks.
They're not sharks.
They just want to
make a tearjerker
with me as the poor pathetic
victimized doctor.
I don't know.
That's not what I mean.
I was watching
that director.
‐ She was looking at you.
‐ Agi?
Yeah, she was watching.
She's trying to get
personal and stuff.
You go for that, too, the
intense, kind of brainy type.
Doug, she's married
to the guy behind the camera.
‐ The old guy?
‐ Yeah, they're a pair.
May‐Decembers
never hold up.
Are you guys talking
about the filmmakers?
‐ Yep.
‐ We don't trust them.
Yeah, they're bloodsuckers.
You think you should be doing
that in front of their camera?
Is that on?
Doug, Mark, we've got
a double trauma.
Help my brother.
14‐year‐old with blunt
trauma from baseball bats.
Bats?
Pulse 130,
BP 100/60.
We tubed him
to protect his airway.
We got a 30‐year‐old victim
of a 15‐foot fall.
He got pushed over a railing
onto a concrete surface.
Brief loss of consciousness
at scene, cleared en route.
Now alert and oriented.
Occipital hematoma.
'BP 60 palp,
pulse 120.'
'Flaccid paralysis in
all four extremities'
'with loss
of sensation.'
Call neurology
and get x‐ray down here.
On my count,
one, two, three.
CBC, type and cross,
four units.
Lateral c‐spine,
chest and pelvis. Let's move!
Can you feel anything
anywhere?
No, not a bit.
Is that okay?
He's got good breath sounds
but diminished tidal volume.
BP's 60 palp.
I need a path
here, guys.
Could be spinal shock.
Alright, let's rule out
intra‐abdominal bleed.
Let's set up.
Let's get a lap.
Let's go. Move.
What else should we
order, Dr. Del Amico?
‐ 'High‐dose steroids.'
‐ And why?
To improve motor
function and sensation
after a spinal cord injury.
Spinal cord?
Would somebody
shut that guy up!
We're just trying to
assess your injuries, sir.
How much do you weigh?
Um, call me Theo,
alright? Uh, 165.
'It's negative. I'm going
to go check on the kid.'
Alright. Start dopamine
at ten mics.
We're out of the woods.
Listen, Theo, we need to check
your motor response.
Okay, Dr. Del Amico?
Sir, can you squeeze
my hand?
What's wrong with me, huh?
Mr. Williams, can you shrug
your shoulders, please?
Hey, we just want
to talk to him.
That's it, see if he's okay.
You have to sit in chairs.
These guys tailgated me
all the way here.
Where's Chico, huh?
No, no, no, no, no!
I'll go see
if your friend's okay.
Just wait here, okay?
Elle sigue, por favor.
Por favor?
‐ 'Is my brother gonna be okay?'
‐ Mannitol, 75 grams.
Blown left pupil.
Let's hyperventilate him.
Intracranial hemorrhage.
Call for a stat head CT.
Decorticate posturing
GCS, eight.
Randi's got a situation
at the desk.
She's got security,
but don't bring
that kid down to CT
right now.
‐ Why not?
‐ His homeys are out there.
They came here?
Those bastards.
You stay away
from him, okay?
Come on, you guys,
take it outside!
Stay away!
You know what?
Your brother's a ranker.
You almost killed him!
What more do you want!
You call the cops!
Shut up, bitch!
It wasn't us!
You pushed that guy
right over the rail!
You didn't even
know that man!
Hey, who are
you, huh?
He was just trying to help,
and you pushed him over!
At the moment, the gentleman's
C‐4 nerve, that's the nerve
between the fourth
and fifth cervical vertebrae
is still functioning.
It means he can move
the diaphragm
and shrug his shoulders
but if the swelling continues
and he becomes a C‐3
he will lose the ability
to breathe on his own.
So how's the shooting
going so far?
Are you getting
everything you need?
'Yeah, I think so.'
‐ 'It's been good.'
‐ Good.
Yeah, one of the
things I noticed
that you might be missing is
the importance of women..
'Excuse me.'
Women working in the ER's.
That's changed dramatically
over the last few years.
All kinds of diversity
among medical workers.
It's crucial
to the understanding
of how emergency medicine
has evolved.
'Yeah, I'll mention that
to Agi and Stuart.'
'Um, what was that
you were pointing to?'
‐ Uh, here?
‐ 'Yeah.'
This is a fracture of the fourth
and fifth cervical vertebrae.
'What does that mean?'
It means that Mr. Williams,
who tried to be a Good Samaritan
and stop a young man
he didn't even know
from being beaten to death
is now paralyzed
from the neck down.
‐ 'Kerry.'
‐ David.
‐ May I interrupt?
‐ Come on in. Come in.
‐ No, I'd rather talk out‐‐
‐ This is, uh, Dr. Morgenstern.
Our too‐modest chief
of emergency services.
If you heard about our little
altercation it's all settled.
‐ The police subdued the perp‐‐
‐ Police?
I thought..
David,
you're diaphoretic.
‐ 'Is something wrong?'
‐ Chest pain.
Radiating?
To the jaw.
Started 20 minutes ago.
Oh, my God.
Lie down.
Lie down. Let's get you on a
monitor. Here you go. Gently.
You get out.
Out!
Get out! Out!
Lydia!
Lydia! Grab me some atropine,
nitro and a 12‐lead EKG.
Oh, my God.
Pulse ox monitor
and start a line.
There you go, David.
We're going to take
good care of you.
'How about there?'
'No, nothing.'
Anything at all?
No, ma'am.
The feeling will
come back, won't it?
That's what the doctors
are trying to find out.
Ouch!
Oh, I felt that.
Good.
Good. Mark it.
Sir, we're going to
watch you very closely.
If the swelling in your
spinal cord continues
we may have to put you on a
ventilator to help you breathe.
I got a hold of a baby‐sitter
at your house, Mr. Williams.
She said your wife
was at school.
Oh, that's right,
it's, um, it's Thursday.
She won't get in
until midnight.
Okay, we'll get
a message to her.
Get that baby‐sitter
on the phone, now.
Okay.
Malik.
Malik, hold on!
Damn it!
‐ I'll bring it back.
‐ 'I need it now!'
‐ Kerry, I was about to do‐‐
‐ Jeanie it's Morgenstern.
Oh, my God.
'What you got, Carter?'
The kid who got
beat up earlier.
He crashed before
we could get a CT.
Lavage was positive.
It may be his spleen.
Is it the kid with
the head trauma?
Yeah, you've to get in line.
I need a CT.
No time, you'll have to drill
the burr holes up in OR.
Let's move.
Carter, where are you going?
Up. I'm bagging him.
Not anymore. Go move.
‐ Dr. Benton.
‐ Thank you.
Somebody's disappointed
I left surgery, isn't he?
Excuse me, I'm Ms. Corday.
Could you point me
towards casualty?
Sorry, trauma.
I mean trauma.
‐ Trauma is that way.
‐ Do you need any help?
No, I'll call out
if I get lost.
You okay?
Kid was trying
to get out of a gang.
You're in the
ER, Carter.
Get them on the elevator alive,
you've done your job.
How do you think
he's gonna do?
He's got a blown
left pupil
probably means
a chronic vegetative state
if he doesn't
bleed to death first.
How bad does he look?
His STs are sky high
in two, three, and F.
His father had an MI at 40.
Yeah, I'll hold.
Hey, Dr. Weaver, I wonder
if we could talk now..
‐ Later.
‐ He's throwing PVC's.
‐ Should we give him lidocaine?
‐ Yes. Great.
Cath lab's ready for us.
Let's get him up.
Dr. Greene, I wonder if you're
aware of my situation..
'I got the baby‐sitter.'
Later, Carter.
Excuse me.
Is this
the Williams' sitter?
Hello, this is Dr. Greene
from the emergency room
at County General Hospital.
Do you understand me?
How far away are you from where
Mrs. Williams goes to school?
Good, get a neighbor
to watch the baby
and run there as fast
as you can and get her.
Tell her it's an emergency
and that every minute counts.
Put her in a cab.
We're about
a ten‐minute ride away.
You got all that?
Any questions?
Good. Go.
'Is he losing his
ability to breathe?'
At the rate his
pulse ox is falling
I'll be forced
to intubate him soon.
'So, you need the wife here to
sign a consent or something?'
Mr. Williams is paralyzed
probably for the rest
of his life.
Right now,
he can still speak.
It would be nice
if he and his wife
could talk to each other for a
few minutes while he still can.
Theo, can you take
a deep breath for me?
Good.
I'll see if Dr. Greene
can join us.
Good idea.
Excuse me, nurse.
I'm Ms. Corday.
I was beeped down
for a consult.
You're a doctor?
Oh, don't mind them.
These gentlemen are
making a movie.
Yes, I'm a surgical lecturer
in orthopedics and trauma.
They said there was
an adolescent who decompensated.
Oh, Dr. Benton took him up.
Ah, Dr. Benton.
You call your
surgeons "Doctor."
Well, I suppose "Ms. Corday"
won't get me very
far around here.
Just to the waiting room.
‐ I'm Carol Hathaway.
‐ 'Pleasure meeting you.'
'So, how did the
patient look?'
'The boy with the
positive lavage?'
Not good,
blown pupil, deep coma.
‐ This the kid I saved?
‐ Yeah.
We're keeping
our fingers crossed.
David, are you still
experiencing
the same amount
of pain? Okay.
On a scale of one to ten how
would you rate that pain?
'Uh, ei‐eight.'
‐ Pardon? Eight.
‐ Eight.
Okay, let's get him
on very gently
and they're all
set up for us.
'They know we're coming.'
‐ 'Here we go.'
‐ What the hell..?
Hey, what are you doing?
No. No. I asked
you not to.
‐ 'You going to the cath lab?'
‐ Yes. Turn it off.
'Isn't there an another patient
who's been waiting for hours?'
What? What do you mean?
'Do some patients get
preferential treatment'
'in the ER?'
Look at me.
I'm talking to you.
‐ Is this recording?
‐ 'Yes.'
Good, because I want to know.
Are you a doctor?
Do you have experience
with myocardial infarctions?
‐ 'No.'
‐ How's he doing?
Sinus rhythm 60,
pulse ox 96.
Look at me, then
how can you make
an accusation about
patient treatment?
Just because your camera sees
a picture of one man going
to the cath lab, you assume
preferential treatment!
Do you know what acute
ST elevations are?
Is there another patient in the
ER who had a run of V‐tach?
'I don't know.'
‐ How's the ectopy?
‐ 'Under five per minute.'
So, what do you want
to know?
‐ What can we tell you?
‐ 'I'm sorry.'
'I got carried away.'
You did.
What have you got?
82‐year‐old male
found down
at his nursing home.
Went in fib en route,
shocked twice without success.
‐ 'Shall I defibrillate?'
‐ 'Be my guest.'
‐ Charge to 360.
‐ 'You got it.'
‐ Has he had EPI?
‐ Yup. Three minutes ago.
‐ 'Go ahead.'
‐ Lube it up.
‐ Three‐sixty? Clear.
‐ Yeah.
'Agi, I need a battery.'
'Another 50 of lidocaine.
Do it again, 360.'
'Agi, my camera
battery's dying!'
'Keep shooting, Stuart.
‐ 'Got a rhythm.'
‐ Pulse?
'Faint, but it's there.'
Alright, everybody,
we got him back!
‐ Good work.
‐ 'I'm losing power.'
'How's that feel, doctor?'
To bring somebody back?
Oh, that's the, uh,
that's the, um..
‐ Dr. Benton?
‐ Yeah?
Elizabeth Corday.
Visiting surgical lecturer
and your savior.
Excuse me.
You've been on call forever.
You're free to go.
‐ I'm on now.
‐ Oh, I'm sorry.
Excuse me,
are you the doctor
who was taking care
of my brother?
Yeah.
You're still down here?
Yeah, I had to talk
to the cops.
‐ Oh.
‐ Oh, sorry.
How is he?
Well, they removed his spleen
to stop the bleeding
and the neurosurgeons
are still working on him.
Does he have brain damage?
Let's call upstairs and see
if there's any news, okay?
‐ Here we go.
‐ I thought I was a goner.
Yeah? Me, too.
You'll be getting
a lot of "Thank‐you's"
from the female population
over at Riverview.
I don't want to brag
too much, but‐‐
Yeah. You a pretty popular
guy over there?
Well, I seem to be.
I never was much of
a Casanova in my day.
I didn't go in for all the wild
positions and so forth.
But the ladies need that,
you know, all the positions.
So I've heard.
And the sweet talk.
I never was much
for that either.
You know, I was mostly
meat and potatoes.
But now, I'm 82,
I'm a man, I'm breathing
the odds are 12‐1
in my favor.
I'm getting it
anytime I want.
Not too bad, old age.
I'm glad to hear it.
Tell you, it feels good
to save the life of a man
who's performing
such a service to society.
Stud service.
Get that in.
He was found down outside
the Stones concert.
He looked like he fell through
a sheet of plate
glass or something.
‐ Easy. Easy.
‐ No, no, no, no.
Leave me alone.
Stop. Stop. Stop.
‐ Get away! Don't touch me!
‐ Call security.
Security!
Alright, alright, alright.
Everything's okay.
It's alright.
Just relax.
No, stay away.
Stay away!
I‐m‐I'm sick.
Okay. Just stay away from me.
‐ Okay. It's okay.
‐ No, it's not okay.
‐ It's alright.
‐ I'm sick.
I'm HIV‐positive, okay.
I've got aids.
Stay away from me.
‐ Please. No, no.
‐ Stop.
Shh.
It's okay.
Alright? Just lay back.
Let us help you.
‐ Don't..
‐ It's okay.
‐ It itches.
‐ I know it itches.
Just take it away.
I'll take it away, okay?
Lay back. It's okay.
Shh. Come on.
We'll make it better, okay.
‐ Help me.
‐ I'll do what I can.
'So when did you decide
to become a surgeon?'
Oh, well, uh, that gets
into pleasing my father
rattling my mother and all sorts
of boring family secrets.
But the short answer is
my father is a surgeon
as was his father
and my father had no sons.
'Are you a resident
in the UK?'
Well, I'm afraid it's a
different system altogether.
Um, I'm an FRCS which is
a Fellow of the Royal College
of Surgeons and a lecturer.
That's roughly the equivalent of
your senior surgical residents
but not really,
because I have six..
I'm sorry. You can't possibly
be interested in this.
Dr. Benton?
Please rescue me from
these well‐intentioned people.
'We're just talking about
the surgical service.'
Listen, have you seen that young
lady I was talking to earlier?
The sister of the
boy up in surgery?
Yeah, I got some news
and I can't find her.
‐ I'll keep my eyes open.
‐ Alright, thank you.
Paralyzed?
For good?
It's too early to say
if your husband's
going to have any
recovery of function.
What did he think
he was doing?
He was trying to
save a boy's life.
I know.
Your husband is very
eager to talk to you.
I'm afraid it'll
have to be brief.
I wouldn't want to
be in those shoes.
Whose shoes,
Mark's or the wife's?
Neither.
Sometimes I hesitate with a
family before I give the news.
I know I'm going
to say something
that will change
their lives forever.
You just think that
if you don't say it
it'll be okay for
a little while longer.
I told this one mother
that her son had been killed
and she said, "Is it broken?"
I'm looking at her and I didn't
know what she was saying.
So she said,
"His arm, is it broken?
'cause he's
pitching tomorrow."
Then she just walked away.
'Did you just let
her leave like that?'
No, no, I called Carol,
I had her take care of it.
That's a true story.
At least...at least we..
...shot those videos of us
on the playground,
me and him, huh?
‐ Theo..
‐ It's a good thing.
I mean, TJ will be
able to see
what his daddy...look like,
used to be like.
You're gonna be that way again.
You hear me, Theo?
We are not giving
up that easy.
His blood gas showed PO‐2,
65 and PCO‐2 50.
We're standing by
with Versed.
Dr. Greene, look,
Dr. Carter needs you now!
I'll be there in a minute.
I'm afraid we have
to interrupt.
Just another minute,
please?
Can you get somebody to
drive her home, please?
Theo, stop bossing me around.
I'm staying right here.
Pulse ox is down to 89.
He's getting dusky.
Two of Versed.
We can't wait any longer.
Once this sedative takes effect,
I'll intubate your husband.
Theo, when you wake up
you're gonna have a tube
helping you to breathe.
Mark, you mind
if we interrupt?
Ms. Cruz wanted to let you know
her brother came out of surgery.
The head CT showed no
bleeding in the brain.
That is really good news.
Thank you.
The boy's gonna be okay?
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
You saved my
brother's life.
That's good.
Can you feel that, honey?
‐ Oh, yeah.
‐ Okay.
'I'm in.'
Is he breathing?
'We're breathing
for him now.'
'Dr. Greene, look,
you need to come now!'
'Excuse me.'
‐ What happened?
‐ He went into fib. Clear!
I've shocked him five times.
He went into asystole.
I've given high dose
EPI and atropine.
Charge it again,
Malik to 360!
‐ 'Why didn't you call me?'
‐ I did.
‐ 'Yeah, two minutes ago.'
‐ Clear!
Charge it again, Malik.
I was following
the ACLS algorithms.
I thought I could handle it.
‐ Charge it again, Malik!
‐ Go ahead and call it.
Clear!
‐ Call it, Dr. Carter!
‐ Charge it again.
No rhythm.
Time of death is 9:56.
Call an attending when
there's a full arrest.
You get help.
You don't try and play the hero.
‐ I've run them before.
‐ That was up in surgery.
You work here now.
Did I miss anything?
Not that I can see.
I'm sorry, I didn't think
I was gonna lose him.
I'll sign the code sheet.
I'll do it.
'Do you want that interview?'
‐ 'Yes.'
‐ 'Do you?'
'You willing to answer
our questions?'
As long as you don't use
what you just shot.
'The walk‐away?'
The whole thing,
him losing the patient
me chewing him out.
It wasn't bad,
you know‐‐
‐ Do you want the interview?
‐ Yes.
Okay.
Look, I need a death
kit in here.
Probably the best
part of my job
is that sometimes,
working here
you can repair
some of the violence.
Some of the bad things
that happen to people.
Not always.
We couldn't do much for
that guy who was paralyzed
probably on a vent
for the rest of his life.
I guess we did save the kid
that he was trying to help.
So, his sacrifice
wasn't for nothing.
And, yes...
I was attacked myself
right here in this hospital.
They haven't been able
to catch the guy who did it
or at least they haven't been
able to charge anyone.
The worst thing about it
isn't what it did to me.
The worst thing is
that it meant that some
of the world's violence
has leaked into our own ER.
This is meant to be a safe
place for fixing people.
Now it's vulnerable.
And as an ER doctor,
that's hard to accept.
'Sounds frightening.'
'Are you scared?'
Sure.
Of, uh, losing control.
'Control of what's outside?'
And what's in me.
Is that enough?
'Yes.'
Then turn it off.