Previously on "ER.."
You don't need me
to tell you this
but it's okay for
you to miss him.
Hell, I miss him.
It's possible that
he may need surgery.
Do you know what
happened to Mobalage?
He was tortured
in Nigeria, right?
Turns out Mr. Ikabo came into
the country on a forged visa.
‐ He's an illegal.
‐ Send him back to Nigeria?
The INS will start
a deportation hearing.
You'll need the dough
if you accept
the cardiothoracic
fellowship next year.
Making the decision to tracking
down your birth parents
is not something
you should do lightly.
You're what?
I'm pregnant.
'Carol?'
'Doug?'
‐ Mom.
‐ Oh, you're still here.
Huh?
I knocked before
I used my key.
I thought
you had left.
What? I was just resting.
What time is it?
Um, 8:30.
Oh, man, I'm late.
Where's Doug?
He left.
I thought you
went in together.
No. Not anymore.
I had extra holubtsi
from Evonne's shower.
'I know he likes it.'
Are you..
Are you alright?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I'm fine.
I don't know
how you stay healthy
working in that place.
Have you eaten?
I'm not hungry.
Call in sick.
I'll make you breakfast.
Ma, I've got to go.
'Lock up when you
leave, alright?'
‐ Carol?
‐ Yeah.
Are you sure you're okay?
I'm fine.
We'll talk later, alright?
I'll call you.
Why was it rescheduled anyway?
Oh, come on.
You're kidding. Reese.
Uh‐uh. Here. Here you go.
'No. I have an appointment
with the new school for Reese.'
The only have open house
once a month
and I've already
missed it twice.
Tell Romano you called
and I wasn't home.
Yeah. No. Hey.. Hello.
No, no, no. I don't want..
Dr. Romano.
No. Listen.
Uh, I'm off this morning.
The earliest I
can get there is noon.
Yeah, I know, but I can't..
Hold on. Hold on.
Reese, no! No, Reese!
This is no. No!
No!
That's no.
Hey, hey, here.
Take that.
Play with that.
Yeah. I'm sorry.
I have an important
appointment, okay?
I can't..
Yeah. Yeah.
Alright. I'll be there
in half an hour.
Jerk.
Reese!
No, Reese.
Not your hearing aid!
No, no, no!
Damn!
No, no, no.
Mr. Deluz, time for your meds.
'Need some help here.'
‐ Just a minute.
‐ No, now. I need O2.
We don't provide that here.
Well, then I‐I need some pillows
to help prop up her head
to help her breathe.
Of course.
She's really altered.
Is that her baseline?
No. Mrs. Brennan was
agitated this morning.
I've got a PRN
order for Haldol.
She's hypoxic. Have you
listened to her lungs?
That's not what
we do here.
We're strictly board and care.
You should have
called somebody.
Her lungs are wet,
and she's got pitting edema.
Dr. Davis increased her Lasix
from 40 to 80 milligrams.
And he hasn't
seen her since?
‐ No.
‐ We've got to push IV meds.
Look, I'm a LVN.
If you want I can arrange for
an RN to come out tomorrow.
Tomorrow? She's in
congestive heart failure.
You call 911.
‐ She's DNR.
‐ Call 911 now!
‐ You're not her doctor.
‐ No, I'm her daughter.
Group therapy
in your first week?
That's what my intern said.
God, all I did was observed
the my first two weeks
of psych rotation.
I believe he used
the words sink or swim.
I think, he's just
trying to scare you.
I'm not scared, I'm actually
really good at this stuff.
What's that?
Mental illness?
Shut up.
‐ Sorry I'm late.
‐ That's okay.
Now that you're
out of management
you can slack off
with the rest of us.
‐ Hey, Carol.
‐ Hi.
So, Carter,
where do you want me?
Oh, I don't know.
Let's see
why don't you
take the hematuria.
After your work‐up,
we'll discuss your plan.
Okey‐dokey.
Did I miss something?
Yeah, Carter is
senior for the day.
Part of your chief resident
application?
Yeah, something like that.
For the next eight hours
if you have a problem,
go to him.
‐ Peachy.
‐ Good luck.
Yeah, you, too.
Jerry, where are all the pens?
I don't know. Some idiot's idea
of an April fool's joke.
Well, listen, go down to supply
and steal a couple, would you?
I got you.
‐ 1.5 volts is pretty cool.
‐ Real mature.
Oh, come on, it's April fool's.
Jerry, I'd watch my back
if I were you.
I've got an anxious
hemorrhoids in four
and a kid with a high
fever in triage.
‐ Talk to Dr. Carter.
‐ 'Dr. Greene?'
‐ How did it go?
‐ We got a problem.
‐ Did you get my affidavit?
‐ Yeah, that's fine.
But I can only get
the continuance
for physical disability
if Mobalage remains
hospitalized.
Shouldn't be a problem.
Urology still has him
on the surgical service.
INS confirmed he was being
discharged this morning.
Where did you get that?
Uh, "Elizabeth Corday."
I thought you had an open house
or something?
Yeah, well, Weinstein
pushed up a lung resection.
Weinstein
the cardiothoracic guru?
Yeah, he got tickets to some
college baseball game
so Reese has to stay in day care
for another month.
Yeah. No, it was only in
there for a few seconds.
Uh, I just wanted to make sure
the water didn't damage it.
Reese's hearing aid.
‐ How much?
‐ Don't ask.
Okay, well, yeah.. I know, but
is there any way to test it?
Come on, Peter,
Weinstein's ready for us.
Yeah, hold on.
I know I can't‐‐
‐ Hey!
‐ I said, let's go.
‐ Don't ever do that.
‐ Are you deaf? I said let's go.
I heard you. I'm trying to fix
my son's hearing aid, okay?
One word, Peter.
Nanny.
I can think of a word
of my own.
Get out now, Elizabeth.
What do you mean?
In a few months,
you'll have your license
and your pick
of fifth‐year residencies.
Oh, it's alright,
I think I found a way
to limit my Romano exposure.
Oh, yeah. What's that?
Garlic?
Trauma surgery.
A fellowship run
out of the ER.
It would start in July.
I didn't know there
was a trauma fellowship.
Well, there wasn't.
Trauma is the reason
why I came
to the States
in the first place.
And the hours are better
and I'd have some
semblance of a normal life.
Uh, yeah, yeah,
we got disconnected.
I'm the one
with the hearing aid..
Elizabeth?
Oh, Mark, I need
to speak to you.
Uh, the INS called
about Mobalage.
I know. Did you discharge him?
I didn't volunteer
any information
but I couldn't lie.
He was afebrile.
His wound was dry,
clean and intact.
‐ Did you discharge him?
‐ Yes.
When did he leave?
I don't know if transport's
taken him down yet.
Why? Is there a problem?
We're trying to get a physical
disability continuance.
On a pudendal
artery bypass?
As long as he
was hospitalized
we could avoid
a deportation hearing.
Now, he'll have to see
the judge.
Yeah, but one look at the scars
and the judge
will grant him asylum.
It doesn't work that way.
Mobalage has to testify,
describe the torture.
Isn't it obvious?
Apparently not
to the government.
They need a record,
a sworn statement.
What? And Mobalage
refuses to give it?
I don't think he can.
After his nap, he
was a little upset.
I thought it
was a nightmare.
But he wouldn't
stop crying.
Temp's 101.
Now I can't
wake him up.
‐ Is he on any medications?
‐ No.
‐ Has he ever been hospitalized?
‐ Never. He's a healthy kid.
‐ He could be septic.
‐ What does that mean?
Well, we need to treat him
with antibiotics right away
'and then perform some tests'
'to find out the source
of the infection.'
Jerry, is trauma one open?
Yeah. You're in early.
Ah, be right back.
Hey, who's this?
Critical patient.
Pulmonary edema.
I need a monitored bed.
BP's borderline at 95
after her fifth
nitro spray.
You guys are only supposed
to give three.
I gave it to her.
Oh, you doing a ride‐along?
Set up a nitro drip, hurry!
I don't want to intubate.
No extraordinary measures.
Board and care says
she's a DNR.
Set up BiPAP,
we'll go from there.
How's your
breathing, ma'am?
I'm, uh..
She's altered, Carter.
On my count,
one, two, three.
Gently.
Call upstairs,
see if we have a ICU bed.
Let's get some
admit labs.
Chest film,
EKG, blood gas.
BP's 100/75, resps 20.
Tachy at 130.
She's pretty gorked out.
‐ I can take it from here.
‐ Put in a Foley.
Where's my 12‐lead?
Yes, I'll take it
from here, Dr. Weaver.
This one's mine, Carter.
I'm senior for the day,
remember?
I'm running the big board.
So, go run it.
Okay.
Carol, where's the nitro?
Hold on. I just got to
clear an air bubble.
Okay, then give her another
sublingual spray, now.
Dr. Sadowinski is an expert
in these kind of cases, okay?
I just want you
to meet him.
But I've already talked
to your psychiatrist.
Yeah. But, talk to this one.
Mobalage, they will
send you back.
He's not been
through enough?
Kubby.
I don't understand
it either.
I'm not an
immigration expert.
But I do know that
you telling your story
is the only way
that you can stay.
Let me just get you a little
time to think about it.
I'll take you
down to the ER.
You're feverish,
pulse is tachy.
If anybody asks you
you're experiencing
belly pain.
‐ Go.
‐ Okay.
'I never imagined frozen sperm
would be a good investment.'
'It's tricky.
You've got to buy the best.'
Good of you
to join us, Peter.
Sorry, I had to
rearrange my schedule.
Oh, that's alright,
in another ten years
you get to
set the schedule.
So you only inseminate Arabians
or what?
No, thoroughbreds too.
Remind me,
I'll get you a brochure.
You like horses, Peter?
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, neither did I.
But they got a big upside
once you know what you're doing.
You ought to
keep that in mind.
‐ Thanks.
‐ 'Dr. Weinstein.'
Your office is on the phone
a sales rep from
Symatac is waiting.
Oh, damn, I forgot.
This guy's going to comp me
a new thoracoscope.
Okay if we push this
back to 1:00?
Yeah, sure, no sweat.
Okay, I'll see
you then.
‐ End of shift?
‐ Oh, no, just started.
‐ You?
‐ Post call.
Six hours to go.
Feels like this internship's
never going to end.
It always feels
like that.
That looks really good.
I'm famished.
I just can't eat
anything, you know?
I'm trying to keep
something down, but..
Here.
Thanks.
Morning sickness?
Yeah..
And I'm really,
really tired.
Have you seen your OB?
You've not made
a decision.
You know, three months ago,
I was worried
that I couldn't
even get pregnant
and now, here I am,
all alone.
I wanted to have
a baby with Doug.
I don't want to be
a single mother.
Well, do you have to be?
I mean, have you
spoken with Doug?
I see all these pregnant women
parading through here
lost, frightened,
not knowing what to do.
Okay, and what do
you tell them?
I always say,
go with your gut
'cause most of the time
it's right.
So, what does yours tell you?
I don't know.
'I need somebody
from surgery on board.'
You discharged Mobalage
so according to bounce‐back
rules, he's yours.
I know, but there's
nothing wrong with him.
Mmm, the incision looks
a little erythematous
around the sutures.
‐ Could be a wound infection.
‐ Mark..
I don't need you
to take him upstairs right away.
Just sign the readmit orders
and we'll observe him
down here in the ER.
You want me to
falsify his chart.
Just trying
to buy him some time.
His lawyer's already
on his way to see the judge
to tell him
he's being readmitted.
You're asking me to lie,
to sign my name to a lie.
I'm asking you
to help him.
Give it to me.
Thank you.
Hey, Mark, think I can get you
to see a couple patients?
In a second, Carter.
Jerry, did you steal
my stethoscope?
Nope. Haven't
seen it.
What makes you think
somebody gonna pick that one
out of all those pens?
'Cause it's shiny.
Malik, I need
postural vital signs
on bed three and..
You can discharge
Mr. Dudley.
Come on, Jerry, I need it.
What makes you think
I took it?
‐ Aw, come on, man.
‐ Stealing stuff?
Where's the creativity
in that?
There has to be
a contact person
for the board and care.
No. Her fees are paid
for out of her pension.
Thank God you
found her.
She was totally
abandoned.
Sh‐she was going
to die there, alone.
I know, sometimes they're
gone before we find them.
Can you do a more
extensive search?
Find out where she's from,
any other children, maybe..
Maybe find my father?
Sure, I'll check it out.
Page me if you need anything.
Thanks.
Is that you, Claire?
No, my name is Kerry.
You were
having trouble breathing
so we had to bring you
to the hospital.
Hospital?
Now, don't worry.
We're gonna take very good
care of you, I promise.
Oh.
Ativan's on board, but
he's still tachycardiac.
Okay, let's add a blood
and urine tox screen.
Could he have
ingested anything?
Uh, something
from the medicine cabinet maybe?
No. I don't think so.
I thought it was an infection.
Pupils is dilated
you don't usually
get that with meningitis.
BP's up to 170/90.
'Anything, um..'
Cold medicine,
nicotine, bug spray?
All that stuff's put away.
Your house is childproofed?
No.
I‐I only have him
every so often.
He sleeps in my room.
Oh, my God.
‐ What?
‐ No. T‐the drawer was closed.
What was in it?
Sir, there are
different treatments
for different toxins.
If I don't know what he ingested
he could die.
It was only, like,
half a gram.
Half a gram of what?
Cocaine?
Get Dr. Greene.
NG tube, activated charcoal.
Start IV Esmolol
'50 mics per kilo
per minute.'
'Sir, you might want
to wait outside.'
No, I want to
be with him.
This is going
to be messy.
That's alright.
‐ Haleh.
‐ Out.. Now.
♪ This old man
came rolling home ♪
♪ This old man ♪
♪ He played two ♪
♪ He played knick‐knack
on my shoe ♪
♪ With a knick‐knack
paddy‐whack ♪
♪ Give a dog a bone ♪
♪ This old man
came rolling home ♪
♪ This old man ♪
♪ He played three ♪
♪ He played knick‐knack
on my knee ♪
♪ With a knick‐knack
paddy‐whack ♪
♪ Give a dog a bone ♪
♪ This old man
came rolling home ♪
♪ This old man ♪
♪ He played four.. ♪
No. I need an ICU bed, yeah.
Yeah, she needs
aggressive diuresis.
I thought a beta blockade
would do it.
She is not stable enough
for telemetry.
It was a good
pickup, though.
Hey, Dr. Weaver,
did you hear about this one?
Guy leaves his cocaine
where his 3‐year‐old
can find it.
Did you call DCFS?
Oh! What the hell?
‐ Jerry.
Dr. Greene..
Mobalage is asking
for you.
Is Dr. Sadowinski here?
Yes, but Mobalage
wants you there.
He trusts you.
Red‐blanket baby on the way.
Some schizophrenic delivered
in the street.
Carter, you got it?
Uh, sure, yeah.
Give me a hand?
'I don't know.'
'There was a hood over my face.'
Were you frightened?
I thought I was
about to die.
Then what?
They took you to a cell.
Yes.
What kind of cell?
It was cold.
What did it look like?
I don't know, sir.
They kept the hood
on your head?
Yes.
'Then what?'
'They came and got you?'
'How long
before they came back?'
'Mobalage, what happened next?'
I cannot tell you.
'Why?'
'Cause I do not remember.
My baby.
Where's my baby?
She's in the middle of the
street holding the newborn baby.
It was still wet
with amniotic fluid.
BP's 140/90.
How much blood loss?
Uh, about a pad
since we found her.
Start an IV, call OB.
Okay, good breath sounds.
No. No. Where‐where's my..
How did she cut
her forehead?
She must have fallen
on the sidewalk.
Did they find
the placenta?
She said a dog ate it.
Okay. Irrigate
this scalp lac.
Get me a speculum
I'll do a pelvic.
Oh, hey, please,
please, please
Where is my
baby? Where?
I'll go check on him
right now, alright?
Okay?
Let's give her
five of Haldol IM.
I'll be right back.
How's the mother?
She needs her head sutured
and I'm giving her Haldol.
'How's it going?'
Mottled and lethargic
initially
but we're warming him up.
Good color. Good tone.
Pulse 140.
'Looks full term.'
'What is that?'
'Is that a garbage tie?'
At least she knew
to clamp it off.
Give me an umbilical clamp
and some betadine.
You gonna do
a heel stick?
Yeah. Where are
the 22‐butterflies?
Try the pedes room.
Okay, let's get a newborn
screen and a cap gas.
She stole my baby.
Give him back to me.
Honey, you have to go
back in and lie down.
‐ No.
‐ Haleh, call security.
You can't have him.
He's mine.
Yeah, we're just
taking care of him.
‐ Can I hold him?
‐ Not right now.
We're going back
in the other room.
We're going to stitch up
that cut on your forehead
and then you can come
back in and see him
‐ I promise, alright?
‐ I love my baby.
‐ I know.
It's okay.
No!
Give him back to me!
Give him to me!
Coco, you have
to let go now.
No, can't have him.
He's mine!
‐ Let go, Coco..
‐ No. No.
Help!
No! No! He's my baby!
‐ Out. Get her out.
‐ Come on. Come on.
No! He's my baby!
You.. No!
You cannot have him!
'He's mine!'
‐ Take it easy.
‐ No!
No!
Any signs of trauma?
No. He seems okay.
'Are you okay?'
Yeah.
Okay, sweetie.
Hey, Kerry,
you got a minute?
If you want
to walk with me.
Hey, listen I was wondering,
what are we going to do
with our sternal
saw study?
Well, as soon as I finish
compiling the data
I'll pass it on to you.
You know, I was thinking
maybe we should
write a paper together.
Oh, I assumed
you'd want to write
yours separately.
Why would you think that?
Different specialties,
different journals.
Come on. It was a joint study.
It should be a joint paper.
I think it's better
suited
for an emergency medicine
journal anyway.
Sure. Peter,
that would be great.
Okay, I'll call you.
Hey, Kerry, you know,
I heard that there might be
a surgical trauma fellowship
run out of the ER.
Did Romano tell you that?
No. Why?
Uh, confidentially
we're trying to
go around him.
Oh. Yeah, well,
that makes sense.
So, is it an open
application process?
Anspaugh's taking it
to the board next week.
Are you interested?
Um, I don't..
I might be, yeah.
Okay, I'll let you know.
Thanks.
'You said he had
to stay admitted.'
‐ I had him readmitted.
‐ I know.
But the judge suspects
we're stalling.
‐ Which we are.
‐ I'll talk to the judge.
It wouldn't matter.
Government prosecutors
are coming tomorrow
to take a deposition.
Off that, the court
will review
and make its decision.
He won't be able
to tell them anything.
If he wants to stay in the
country, he'll have to.
‐ He doesn't remember.
‐ Anything?
The abduction,
not the torture.
They must have seen
post‐traumatic stress before.
People claim it
all the time.
That's the problem.
We have physical evidence.
Look, I'm not arguing
their position.
I'm simply telling you
what the reality is.
Without a sworn statement
specific to the torture,
it can go either way.
How's the baby doin'?
Blood glucose is good
up to 68.
He's in the nursery
eating like a champ.
Good. How we
doing in here?
She's throwing PVCs.
Don't worry.
She's gorked out.
‐ How long?
‐ What?
Has she been
throwing PVCs?
I don't know.
I just took it down.
Well, you should have
called me.
She's DNR.
I'm working on an
ICU bed for her.
Did her family change
their mind?
No. There isn't any family.
Oh, well, that makes it easier.
Less complicated.
Jerry, why is that frequent
flyer still in four?
Uh, he's waiting on a cab.
For 55 minutes?
Come on, I need the bed.
Carter, Dr. Greene told
me to talk to you.
Make it fast.
Time clock's broken.
I can't punch in.
Call administration.
I did. But they said I can't
start working until they fix it.
Note the time
on the back of the card.
They won't let us do that.
They think we gonna cheat.
Just clock in
upstairs then.
I can't.
A different system.
Uh‐huh! Nice try.
April fool's?
‐ You blew it.
‐ Sorry. He was getting mad.
Chuny, I thought
better of you.
Malik put me up to it.
I swear.
Yeah, blame the brother.
‐ Here, have a pen.
‐ Thanks.
‐ You wanted to see me?
‐ What's the deal with CT?
I got three patients upstairs
in a holding pattern.
Crashed on us.
Computer guy's working on it.
‐ How long?
‐ Four hours.
Four hours?
You serious?
Have you known me
not to be serious?
Okay, Jerry, that's it.
We're closed
to neuro trauma.
Uh, I'll call Weaver.
No, don't call Weaver.
I'm senior for the day.
CT's down, closed to neuro.
Whatever you say, boss.
We got another one.
Four‐month‐old female,
high fever, cough.
Okay, I'll be right there.
Sam, don't go anywhere.
I may need a wet read
on a chest film.
What are you doing?
We need to massage
your uterus
to help shrink it.
It closes off
all the blood vessels?
That's right.
I read that.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean
to attack you.
I‐I get crazy
without my meds.
I understand.
How's my baby?
He's doing great.
He's in the nursery
and they're taking
good care of him.
But he's healthy, right?
There's nothing wrong with him?
No, no, no. He's perfect.
I went.. I went off the drugs
for the pregnancy.
I know.
I didn't want them
to hurt him.
I know.
I thought about it.
I knew what I was doing.
I knew I was taking a risk.
That I couldn't get out
of control
end up on the street,
but it worked.
I made it.
You got lucky,
but it's not over.
I can go back home.
I'll stay on the medication.
I know that I have to.
Not for me, for him.
Coco, we're
not talking
about a month
or six months or a year.
You can't ever stop.
I won't. I love him already.
I loved just the idea of him.
That's all that really
matters, right?
They'll let me keep him,
won't they?
‐ We'll see.
‐ No, no!
They can't take him
away from me.
‐ Please, please.
‐ You need to rest.
Hi, my name is Lucy Knight.
I'm a student doctor.
How are you feeling?
Michael, stop it.
Be still.
You want a fourth tube.
Might as well.
Fluid looks
pretty clear, though.
‐ That's good?
‐ Yes.
If it's a really
bad infection
the fluid can be
kind of cloudy.
We'll still need to send
these tubes to the lab though.
Michael!
You got a second?
Yeah. Be with you
in one minute.
Hold him still.
Okay, I'll be right back.
Gram stain and culture in one.
Glucose and protein in two
and cell count in three.
‐ What do we got?
‐ You tell me.
What's wrong
with this picture?
Uh.. Those rib fractures?
Four. One, two,
three, four.
Any signs of abuse?
I didn't see
any ecchymosis.
Bruises heal on infants
pretty quickly.
Huh.
‐ Chuny?
‐ 'Yeah.'
Can you get DCFS
on the phone
and call security
to curtain two?
I want a full bone survey
skull series, long
bones, the works.
Let's take them now
before the inquisition.
Mrs. Leason, there's
a little problem
with the chest X‐ray.
‐ What kind of problem?
‐ Nothing to be alarmed about.
Just a little fuzzy.
She might have been moving.
But we need
to try again.
Can I go with her?
It's actually better
if you stay here.
I said stop it!
Your sister is sick!
Mrs. Leason, take it easy.
I'm fine.
What's this?
We discovered
some old fractures
that looked like they may be
the result of some trauma.
What?
By law, I'm required
to report them.
I thought you said
the X‐ray was fuzzy.
We need to document
a complete set.
Document what?
How did Michael break his arm?
He fell off the bed.
A representative
of the department of child
and family services
is going to come
and talk to you.
The hell they will.
‐ I'm leaving.
‐ Not with your children.
I brought my baby to you
because she is sick.
And now you want
to take my children?
She doesn't leave
with this one.
Make sure she doesn't
go near radiology.
I'll call the police.
You go ahead,
you call the police!
'Cause you don't know
what you're talking about!
You cannot do this!
‐ Yes, I can.
‐ No, you can't.
'They let Mobalage live'
'for people to
see him broken.'
To set an example.
Why? What did he do?
He wrote a short story.
They saw it as
a call for revolution.
Was it?
I didn't know
he was a writer.
He's an engineer, but
he was a romantic to me.
Not as you see him today.
He was warm and funny.
Energetic.
Kubby, I need to know things
about the torture.
Anything that could help
spark his memory.
We don't speak of it.
You must know the sort of things
that they did.
You can see the sort
of things they did.
I was thinking more of where?
How long? When? Details.
I cannot give you details.
I wish I could.
When will we have to go?
Your visa's valid.
It's only Mobalage.
When will we have to go?
I don't know.
Thank you.
For what?
You've been very kind.
I want to help him.
So do I.
‐ Hey, Kerry.
‐ Hey.
I was checking vitals
on Mrs. Brennan.
Chart says you pushed
some lidocaine.
That's right.
Did her DNR
status change?
Do Not Resuscitate
does not mean,
Do Not Treat.
You treated
an arrhythmia.
Yeah, that's
not resuscitation.
So you won't intubate?
Carol, she's my patient
and I'll make a judgment call
if it comes to that.
Excuse me.
A judgment call?
Isn't that a little
hypocritical?
What?
Doug made judgment calls
what he thought was best
for his patients.
Carol, Doug created
his own problems.
You didn't help much.
Is that what you think?
Is that what you think,
that I drove him out of here?
No. But I know you
wanted him out.
Oh.. I am not gonna have
this conversation with you.
At least, he never
went against his patient.
‐ No, this is different.
‐ How, Kerry?
‐ How is this different?
‐ She is my mother.
Mrs. Brennan..
Mrs. Brennan is my mother.
Why didn't
you tell me?
I don't know.
I was adopted.
And I hired..
I hired this private detective
to find her.
I never imagined
it would happen like this.
I..
I didn't expect
to find an old woman.
I always thought
that she was probably
some scared teenager
who couldn't keep me.
I..
I thought that I
would have more time
have some kind of meaningful
conversation, ask her questions.
But the minute I find her,
she's dying.
Kerry, I'm so sorry.
It's not your problem.
She's Hemoccult positive.
Crit's down.
I'm going to call
for a GI consult
Type and cross‐match
two units, okay?
You know your way around
a resection, Peter.
But do a little more
homework next time.
Ah, we keep him pretty busy.
Want to get coffee?
No, thanks. If I leave now,
I can make the third inning.
Always a pleasure,
gentlemen.
You bet. Take care.
See you later. You jerk.
Don't worry about that.
I didn't even know
the answer to that question.
No.. I should be
more prepared.
Ah, go home.
See your munchkin.
His name is Reese.
Oh, like Reese's
pieces, cute.
‐ Hey.
How'd it go?
Oh, fine, I guess.
Not exciting
enough for you?
No, it was...interesting.
So why did you feel the need
to poach my meager ambitions?
What?
I spoke with Kerry Weaver
about the status
of the trauma fellowship.
She told me there might
be a selection committee.
That there was
other interest.
Was that you?
I mentioned something.
Peter, I told you
in confidence.
I wouldn't have said anything
if I thought for a second
you'd try and
steal it from me.
It's already yours?
It was my idea.
I brought it to
Greene and Weaver.
Okay, well, I'm sorry,
you didn't tell me that.
Peter.
Look, I didn't say I wanted it.
I was just asking.
Oh, well, then.
Let me know when
you decide.
I'll go ahead and
plan my life.
Elizabeth,
it's not like that.
You know, it's just that..
I don't know, you know, things
aren't working out right now.
I don't like cardiothoracic.
Oh, what?
So trauma's a backup?
No. I just thought that this
might make sense, you know?
I can't spend the
next five years
being some kind of
indentured servant.
I‐I need time for Reese.
‐ Oh, now that's low.
‐ What?
Well, I know you
love your son
but don't use him as
an excuse to screw me over.
You know what? Take it.
I don't want it.
I'll find somethin' else.
No! I don't want you
to forfeit it to me!
If you want it, by all means,
you go for it.
I'll still get it.
How are those
films coming?
Come in. You're gonna
want to see this.
Whose is this?
I don't know.
It's been here all day.
I've been looking
everywhere for this.
28 different
fractures total.
Not all calcified.
Bilateral humerus,
left femur..
Right tib‐fib, linear
involvement of the skull.
Geez, what did she
do to this kid?
We should get a head CT.
There's some pleural
scarring.
Possibly a spontaneously
healed pneumothorax.
Wait a minute. What is this?
Non‐displaced fracture
of the eighth rib.
I thought, uh..
There were only
four rib fractures.
There's five here.
You sure this is hers?
‐ Yeah, I took a whole new set.
‐ Where's the old one?
‐ Same technique?
‐ Yeah.
So where's the fifth fracture?
There isn't one.
What, it happened in the ER?
Did you press on her chest?
I held her down
to do the LP.
Could be osteogenesis
imperfecta.
Uh.. I did it?
Their bones break
like glass.
Oh, man..
Oh, man.. I went
right to abuse.
I didn't even..
I didn't even think about OI.
Did you already call
social services?
Yeah, cops are down there
talking to the mother right now.
Well.. Honest mistake.
Better to be safe, right?
Yeah, how do I go from
sorry I accused you
to your daughter's got
a terrible disease?
'You should put
on a jacket.'
It's still a little
nippy out here.
Yeah. I'm ready for spring.
I got your page
in the car
I figured I'd just
swing by, how is she?
Uh.. She's dying.
I got some preliminary
info for you. Wanna hear?
Cathy Brennan, she was a
stewardess back in the day
they called them
stewardesses.
Uh, married late, two
years after having you.
Not to your father.
I'm still working on that.
Divorced six years later.
One child, a daughter, Claire.
Died in a car accident
in her mid‐twenties.
Are you okay?
Did you know that
her blood type was O positive?
We don't usually get
that kind of information.
Yeah, I had to type
her blood
because I was going
to put her in the ICU.
She.. She didn't want that.
But somehow I thought
I had the right.
That's a natural reaction.
I'm AB.
it's impossible for
that woman to be my mother.
‐ Are you sure?
‐ It's basic hematology.
A plus B equals AB.
There's no O in the equation.
I'll call my guy in the
County Clerk's Office.
He, uh, stole a peek
at the file.
He must have rushed,
read it wrong.
You should be more careful.
The information is there,
I can get it.
You're not going
to quit, are you?
It's my fault.
You shouldn't let it
undermine your resolve.
You're fired.
‐ 'Hey, Carter.'
‐ Hi.
How many patients
do you have?
One. I finally got
a good case.
A paranoid schizophrenic
had a baby.
Yeah, I know.
I was there.
Oh, great.
How's senior for a day?
Not over yet.
‐ Lucy.
‐ Yeah?
Have you called your
resident about Coco yet?
Uh, no, I have
to complete
a comprehensive
mental status exam.
I'm presenting her
at chief rounds.
Well, you need to call
your resident, now!
Why? Is something wrong?
Look, Coco's had
over 12 admissions.
She's dealt with a lot of
different psychiatrists.
I bet.
She feels you're
too inexperienced.
A schizophrenic thinks
I'm not qualified?
Well, she's asked
for someone else.
Can she do that?
She's got a lot at stake,
Lucy, you know?
She's worried.
Just call your resident.
Hey, Dr. Greene.
Can I ask you somethin'?
Sure, Jerry.
What does it mean if
your piss turns blue?
Just out of curiosity?
My piss is blue.
Dark blue.
Somebody got you.
Oh, man.
How could they change
my bodily fluids?
Have you eaten anything that
you didn't make yourself today?
Brownies in the lounge.
Mmm.
Oh, man,
it's not toxic, is it?
It's probably methylene blue.
Let me know
if it starts burning.
Burning?
I'm just kidding, Jerry.
You'll be fine.
Well, how long am I
going to pee like this?
Mmm, day or two.
Eh, someone's going to pay.
Told you to watch your back.
You're here.
You came back.
That's right.
Claire?
Yes.
I love you.
I love you, too, mom.
It's okay.
It's a bathroom.
Yeah, it's just
a bathroom.
Three stalls..
Urinals..
Couple of sinks.
But for a long time..
I had trouble
even coming in here.
I used to dream about it.
It was my nightmare.
I was standing right
here at the sink.
Someone had just left.
I was washing my face.
Suddenly, I feel a pain
shooting through my skull
and I realize
that my head has
hit the porcelain
as I'm crashing
into the mirror.
My mind is one step behind.
Someone's attacking me.
I end up on
the ground here..
...and he's gone.
So I crawl out..
...and I try to stand up
and he's on me again
and he's kicking and punching
and kicking
and this sharp pain
shoots through my hand
as he stomps on it.
I can still feel it.
I'm lying there
in the middle of the floor..
I can't stand..
I can't talk..
I just keep thinkin'..
...why didn't I do anything?
'Why didn't I fight back?'
You cannot fight back.
You cannot move.
There's no window there.
Only a bright light
in that corner.
Someone lies over there.
You know him.
A friend.
He's dead.
There are voices..
A scream from over there.
A chain..
You hang from a chain
right here.
Right here.
There is laughter.
A fire over there.
They heat the long blade.
Oh..
Hold it to you,
it burns.
You cannot breathe.
It comes again, harder.
Longer.
'You smell it.'
You smell your
own flesh burning.
Death.
I wish for death.
But my wife..
...my family.
My family..
‐ Hi.
‐ Hi. Can I help you?
Yeah, I was hoping
to catch Dr. McLucas.
She left for the day.
We are closing up.
Are you a patient?
Yes. Carol Hathaway.
Is it an emergency?
No, um.. I just need
to see her.
Uh, can I make an appointment?
'Sure. What's it for?'
I'm going to have a baby.