Previously, on Grey's Anatomy...
Look at that hand.
This is assault.
A pediatric surgeon
walking around this hospital...
Do you realize what happens
if you're convicted of a felony?
Mer, the trial's tomorrow. It could be
our last chance for like eight, ten years.
Jo Wilson isn't my real name.
That's why I couldn't marry you.
It might all come
out in court tomorrow.
You picked the bad guy. The guy
who hurts you or hurts other people.
Karev, what are you about to do?
I'm going to the district
attorney's tonight,
and I'm gonna take the plea.
It's just us, now.
There were five of us,
and it can't be just me.
Mr. Karev? He'll see you now.
Back in the day,
physicians made house calls.
- We can still turn around.
- Bailey, no, we can't.
So, if you chopped off your finger,
or woke up with a touch of cholera...
We've all had a long day.
I have to see this patient
and this was the window
of time we were offered.
Wilson? Are you
sure you're good?
You could order up a
doctor, like delivery pizza.
Ew.
Um... You know, I don't
want to talk about it.
A respected member of the
community, at your service.
The ultimate personal touch.
I mean, with everything
that's happening with Karev.
There's nothing
that I can do about it.
Whatever happens at
the trial tomorrow happens,
so I just... I want
to do this tonight.
God, this is so gross!
Okay.
Well...
Wilson's right.
Tonight's gonna be hard
enough already. Let's focus on this.
Look.
Oh, now, that's...
A crime against God.
Oh, my... This one has feet.
Wilson.
What? It's not a baby.
It's a mass of skin
and cells, like a tumor.
Wilson, stop talking about
symptoms and start talking patient.
Kristen Rochester,
16, 31 weeks pregnant,
preliminary ultrasound
shows likely TRAPS Syndrome.
Yeah, hard to say for sure, since
their ultrasound machine is junk.
- It's outdated, is all.
- It's junk.
Well, you know what's not junk?
Our portable ultrasound, which
we have. It's in the bag, right?
Mm-hmm, along with
the fetal ablation machine.
Easier to handle in
our not-junky hospital.
Well, it's not possible for us to
transport this patient, and you...
And you know it.
Doesn't mean I have to like it.
You have somewhere to be?
I don't wanna spend more
time here than we have to.
We do this fast,
then get the hell out.
She's just another patient.
No, she's not.
- No, she's not. God, can you imagine?
- No.
I mean, but really,
to be pregnant and...
- I cannot imagine.
- Bailey...
I would never put myself
in a position to be in here.
Nobody intends to be here.
I'm just saying. You get
hungry and desperate
or broke and desperate,
and stuff happens.
Stuff does not
just happen to you.
You happen to stuff.
It's gonna be fine.
Hi. How you doing tonight?
- Name.
- Dr. Robbins. This is...
Inmate name.
Oh. Kristen Rochester.
Bag.
- Yeah, this is all
medical equipment.
- Stand back against the wall.
Now what?
In Orange, they strip-search.
I am not getting
strip-searched. Arizona...
Bailey, you are not
getting strip-searched.
- Sir, can I...
- Against the wall.
Sorry. Sorry. Thanks for coming.
Amanda Joseph,
Kristen's attorney.
Let's go get popped through.
"Popped through"?
I represent inmate
Kristen Rochester
and I'm accompanying
these doctors
to deliver court-ordered
medical care. Let us through.
Now.
Personal effects, cell
phones, keys, weapons.
- Who brings weapons to a prison?
- So many people.
Arms out.
Um... I have a prosthetic leg.
- I'm gonna raise your pants leg.
- Come on, is that
really necess...
ary.
Visitors pass. Keep
them on you at all times.
You will not be able
to exit without them.
- What?
- Hold the badge up to your face,
look at that camera.
Four visitors
clear for Eldredge.
We should get immediate access
to Kristen, but you never know.
- Badges up.
- "Never know"? Why?
Dr. Eldredge is already
pissed you're here.
You're doing fancy,
expensive surgery.
Special treatment
gets the others riled up.
Eldredge pushes
you, you push back.
Not literal pushing, correct?
I got this. I can
handle a pushing.
No-one is pushing.
What, you think someone's
gonna swipe that thing?
Hey, someone could.
Then, all of a sudden,
she's walking around outside.
They're locked in cells.
And I'd be trapped
on the inside.
No-one knows me,
no-one trusts me.
My record says that I'm in for theft
or worse, so who's gonna listen to me
when I'm yelling that there's
been some horrible mix-up?
Nobody. Nobody listens.
I never get my hair
done. My teeth go bad.
I die in here.
- That can't happen, right?
- Just don't lose your badge.
Badges.
This way.
- Ms. Joseph.
- Dr. Eldredge.
Doctors Robbins, Bailey and
Wilson are here for Kristen Rochester.
I hope they brought a book.
I don't have time to wait
around. I've got 12 cases today.
I have 26 inmates, and Rochester
isn't number one on my list.
If you insist on creating
an unreasonable delay
and obstructing my
client's legal rights,
- you know I have no recourse
but to report you.
- Fine.
Rochester for the
win. Follow me.
I have ground rules.
Walking.
Totally normal. Don't engage.
Rochester's a wild one, and I
don't have time to stitch you up
if she goes off on you.
Hey! I've been sitting
here for an hour!
You should stop banging
your head against the wall.
You suck!
Rochester isn't allowed
to initiate contact.
So, we can touch her
but she can't touch us?
Yeah. And don't be a hero and
tell her anything about her condition.
Tell me. Bad news sets her off.
"Sets her off"?
If she goes into labor today...
Well, we're hoping
that's not gonna happen.
If she goes into labor today, she
gets 24 hours with the baby, max.
Then she goes back into gen pop.
Twenty-four hours? That's it?
But she's the baby's mother.
She's a violent felon
with a sentence to serve,
and I can't spare the bed.
- I don't make the rules.
- At least nod so I know
you all heard me.
- Okay.
- Yes.
- Let me out!
- Here we are.
Um, what's K-10?
K-10 is for especially
dangerous inmates,
murderers, validated
gang members.
Which is she?
That's confidential.
She's a minor.
It means she can't circulate freely
with other inmates. For their safety.
What about our safety?
She behaves for me. We're fine.
Rochester. Company.
See? Look at her.
She's just another patient.
You know how it goes. No
touching, no sudden moves.
Hi. Hi, Kristen. I'm Dr. Robbins.
How are you feeling today?
The baby's really hungry.
Could I have something to eat?
You had your pregnancy
snack an hour ago.
No seconds. You know that.
- I'll need written proof
of that.
- Of course you do.
Please? I'm so hungry.
We really can't give
her another snack?
There are no extras to give.
Really? You're starving
a pregnant mom?
- That's okay with you?
- You'll live.
You're gonna be like that?
I am.
Okay, then.
Kristen, we're gonna take a look
at your baby. How's that sound?
Inmate, away from the door.
Hi, Kristen. Good to see you.
We can get you
access to supplies.
Backup in cell
seven! Inmate, get...
Oh, my God!
Hey! No excessive force!
I told her I was hungry!
That's a write-up
and a white card.
It's totally worth it.
Now are you gonna
get me something to eat?
"Just another patient"?
Listen to me. Kristen
doesn't scare you.
She sure does.
No, she doesn't.
She can smell fear. If you
treat her like an animal in a cage,
she will act like one.
She and Eldredge
have a rocky history.
You have a clean slate,
with me on your side.
Use it.
- What are they doing? Is that even legal?
- Hey!
Get off!
You can't shackle a woman
in late-term pregnancy!
- It's policy.
- It's illegal.
She hurts me, she gets 24
hours in four-point restraints again.
Do something!
I can't allow this.
I can't allow putting civilians
at risk with a violent inmate
unless she's fully restrained.
She's trying to starve me!
Spare me the dramatics. You ate.
You guys are just
gonna stand there?
Let her treat a
pregnant girl like this?
She's fully restrained.
I need you to get the
sheriff on the phone
to discuss this
violation immediately.
Sure. He always returns my
calls in a hurry. I'll be outside.
Go! Get out of my face! Get out!
I'm gonna go check
her finger. It's injured.
Kristen, we've talked about
the yelling. How it doesn't help?
Yes, ma'am.
Are you going to let these
doctors help you and your baby?
Yes, ma'am.
You could use a
second set of hands.
You spook easy.
It's dislocated.
Could be broken.
We should get an
x-ray to make sure.
Okay!
Uh... Can I help?
You got a splint?
I don't wanna waste
one. Just buddy-tape it.
Buddy-tape it?
Tape the broken finger
to the uninjured finger.
I know what it is,
and it isn't sufficient.
Are you trying to act tough,
here? Is that what this is?
Because you and I are
on the same side, here.
I'm just trying to help.
Your help has already
buried me in paperwork
and broken my finger.
You know what? You should
probably get back to your VIP patient.
I'll tape it myself.
Do you need me
to hold your hand?
I don't bite.
I mean, I have.
But... can't right now.
Okay.
We're all set.
Okay, Mama, you ready
to take a look at this baby?
Does she always talk like that?
- Yep.
- Like what?
Like unicorns and rainbows
are about to shoot out of your ass.
Okay.
- All right, let's...
- Hey, hey, hey!
- No sudden moves!
- That wasn't a sudden move.
You can't just put hands on me
like that! How about a little heads-up?
Got it.
Okay. The next thing
you'll feel is some cool gel.
Heads up.
And then this
wand on your belly.
I don't think she likes your
thing. She keeps kicking.
She's definitely on the move.
There's her fingers and toes.
Oh. Good. I don't
want her to be a freak.
And there's our problem.
I don't even want to see that.
I can't believe that monster
thing is in there with my baby.
It's like a...
Acardiac twin.
Yeah, I know.
I made a guard Google
it and show it to me.
The way it's sucking my baby's
blood just reminds me of, like, a...
A vampire?
Yeah.
Yeah, it's so gross.
So, do you have any questions?
Yeah. How soon can we start?
As soon as we get the baby
into position, we're good to go.
Then let's get going.
As soon as I go into labor,
I get my mom here. Right?
Yes, when you go into labor.
Yeah. I know. Just call her now,
'cause as soon as you
guys give me the medicine
or whatever to start labor,
she should already be here.
Kristen, that's not
what's happening.
It's the law! I get my
mom when I'm in labor!
To hold my hand and crap!
Right?
Yes, that is the rule, but I... I thought
Dr. Eldredge explained this to you.
Dr. Evil? Is that a joke?
The baby's not coming today.
What?
Today, we're just gonna cut the
connection between the mass and the baby
so that your baby's heart doesn't
have to work double-time anymore.
But, Dr. Evil said
it wasn't surgery.
Yeah, it's a procedure. You'll
be awake the whole time.
Well, that doesn't
make any sense.
We use a probe to go into
your belly through a tiny incision.
You want to poke my belly
with a gigantic probe thing?
No! No, no, no, no, no. I want
my baby. I want to deliver my baby.
Why didn't you tell me this?
Kristen, I'm not a doctor. I told you
everything I knew. Nothing has changed.
This is the safest, best
way for us to get to our goal.
- But I...
- Kristen. What is our goal?
To have a healthy baby so
that my mom can adopt her
and I can see her all
the time when they visit.
You're sure. No baby today.
There... There's
still a chance, right?
Very slim chance.
Hey.
You know, I saw this movie, once, where
this girl got to keep her baby in prison.
They gave her a crib and diapers
and everything, all in her cell.
And her mom just dropped the
baby off every morning, like daycare.
What?
Oh, nothing.
It's just a movie.
Yeah, obviously, I know that.
- Do you think I'm stupid?
- Nobody thinks you're stupid.
She does! Don't you?
Speak!
I think that's a movie.
And you're in a
maximum-security prison.
I know that! I live
here! Don't you get that?
- Inmate, settle down!
- She's okay. Right, Kristen?
Yeah. I'm fine.
You know, things don't always
happen the way they do in movies.
I know that.
Ms. Joseph? We
have a call for you.
I'll be right back.
I still get to be her mom.
Even if I don't see
her all the time.
And she'll know I'm her mom
because there's this, like, touch thing
and this smell thing
when she's born.
That's what they say.
She'll know I'm her mom forever.
No matter what.
Doctors?
- Okay, so, I have to go.
- What?
- Why?
- Just downstairs.
A little emergency with another
client needs my attention.
How about focusing your
attention on keeping your K-10 client
- from killing us?
- She's not gonna kill us.
She'll just break our fingers.
One of my clients pulled a
knife on a doctor in the ER, okay?
I have to go now. I'll
be right downstairs.
- But...
- You'll be fine.
Hey, that lawyer is the one
person that girl listens to.
She's the K-10 whisperer.
Baby's position's blocking our
access to the acardiac twin's vessels.
And now she's just abandoned us.
So, Wilson, what do we do?
We externally rotate the baby.
- Yep.
- Wait, you wanna lay hands
on the violent criminal?
Push her around and just cross our
fingers that she doesn't push back? No!
- We have to.
- She's calmer, now.
Because the lawyer calmed
her, and now the lawyer is gone!
She seems so hopeful.
Sure, about turning her
prison cell into a nursery.
But there are prison nursery programs
where they teach you parenting,
let you spend time with your
baby... Maybe she could get into one.
She is shackled to
her bed, right now,
because she attacks
people who bother her.
You think a crying baby
isn't gonna bother her?
- Who are you?
- What?
I mean, how did I not
know that you felt this way?
I mean, what did
prison ever do to you?
Okay, we're gonna push on
your belly to move the baby around
so we can get access
to the acardiac twin.
Will it hurt?
A little. I'm sorry. You'll...
Not me, Stupid.
Will it hurt the baby?
No. No, she won't feel a thing.
Okay, Wilson, take the wand.
You're gonna feel my hands on
your belly, and then a lot of pressure.
Okay? Here we go.
Ow, ow, ow, ow!
Can you show me
the umbilical cord?
It's still covered.
This baby does not want to move.
All right. More pressure, okay?
Ow. Ow. Stop. Stop it!
Okay. Okay.
Can... Can you at least
take these cuffs off?
I'm so sorry, that's...
It's not up to me.
I went to court to get you here.
And you are freaking useless!
Let's try it again.
God! What the hell?
So what's your adoption
plan? With your mom?
I'm not gonna talk to you
about that. I don't have to...
More pressure. More pressure.
All right. So, then, how about
I tell you something about me?
My daughter lives across the
country, so she's not always with me.
Is she making that up?
No. It's true.
You ready for more?
Robbins. They
want you downstairs.
I'm kind of in the middle
of something. Is it urgent?
- I don't know. Ask her yourself.
- Ask who? Amanda?
I don't take messages.
Such a bitch.
All right, Wilson, continue
with the cephalic version?
Yes. Absolutely.
Thank you, Dr. Robbins.
"Thank you, Dr. Robbins."
You have to kiss her ass, huh?
Hey! Are you a doctor?
I need help.
Yes, you! Help!
Well, hell.
What seems to be the problem?
It's been oozing for days.
And then there was this smell.
Is that normal?
No. That's
definitely not normal.
I'm Lee.
But everybody calls me Needles.
Okay, then.
Oh...
You know, I once helped a guy
I liked rob a convenience store.
You're a doctor.
Yeah, now. But before...
I had a... bunch of
crappy foster parents.
"Stars, they're just like us."
What?
You're trying to act like we're the
same, you and me, but... we're not.
Hmm.
I also used to live in my car.
Which was stolen.
I get how life can screw
you over, sometimes.
No. You don't get it. At all.
I grew up on Bainbridge Island
with a mom who bakes casseroles.
I went to an all-girls
private school.
What was that like?
Too many blazers,
not enough boys.
Okay, more pressure.
Well, the casserole
part doesn't sound bad.
Mm.
First place at the block
party, three years running.
Fanciest swing set on the
block, huge room with a TV.
It was a good setup.
Yeah.
It was a really good swing set.
And in the summer,
my mom would take me
to this soft-serve
place on the beach.
We'd do cartwheels
until it was dark
and we were freezing and sandy.
'Cause in front of the other
prep-school moms, she wore pearls, but...
at the beach, she didn't
even wear makeup.
That was my favorite.
Anyway, my baby will
get the casseroles...
the swing set, the big room...
the cartwheels on
the beach, all of it.
Sounds really nice.
Do you wanna know
what I'm gonna name her?
Sure.
Ellie.
Ellie? I love that.
If you tell anyone I said
all that crap, I'll kill you.
Hey, I just IND'd an abscess
without packing it or using antibiotics.
Good. You're treating
my patients at random.
I know this place looks
like a shanty town to you,
but we do actually keep
records here, charts.
Hey, you know what you
don't keep? Basic gauze!
See, if you put a little aside
each day, you'd build a surplus.
Maybe stay in your
own lane, Dr. Bailey.
That's Chief Bailey. And I've
been asked to drive in yours, today.
And you're used to driving a
luxury vehicle with cruise control.
A little trickier when you're at the wheel
of an '86 Datsun with the engine on fire.
You know what?
If I were you, I'd take a look at
how I allocate my resources, is all.
Come here. You'll love this.
Two inmates just beat
the hell out of each other.
I've got one eyelid lac and
a human bite to the hand.
What do you need?
Lidocaine.
Lidocaine. Great.
I have 14 vials for
these two inmates.
Oh, and I also have to do a
digital block, a wound closure,
and drain an abscess,
so who gets the lidocaine?
- I...
- Here's another fun one.
Seven protein shakes
for eight pregnant inmates.
That's almost enough for every
woman to get one every other day.
How's that possible?
A dozen women
need sanitary napkins.
Good news. I got 35
for the whole week.
So, who gets and who
doesn't? Go ahead. Choose.
I see.
Seriously, make
a decision, Chief.
I understand. I get it.
I don't allocate my
resources. The state does.
And when the state
decides between
cutting the school
budgets or the prisons,
guess which one they pick.
So then I get to
pick. From this.
In here.
Hi. I'm Dr. Robbins.
You're the doctor.
I'm Emily Rochester.
Yeah, you're Kristen's
mom. Kristen's doing fine.
We're prepping her for the
procedure, which means...
- You haven't started yet.
- No. You're just in time.
Is... Is there anything
you want me to tell her?
No.
You can't tell
her that I'm here.
I'm sure that she'd be
happy to know her mom...
No.
I'm here for the baby.
I don't understand.
The mother is never gonna
bring the baby to visit?
Can she even do that?
If she's legally adopting her after the
baby's born and she signs the papers,
she can do whatever she wants.
I hate people.
Okay, so, do we tell
Kristen? 'Cause it'll kill her.
We have to.
No. We do not.
It's not our place, and
it's not our business.
So she's just gonna
give birth to that baby
and then never see her again?
We don't tell.
If my mother was abandoning me,
I would want to know
what was happening.
She's in agony as it is. Telling
her is only gonna make it worse.
We do not hurt her
more, not right now.
That's the probe?
Yeah. Maybe you
look the other way.
Once we start, you
have to stay very still.
No moving. You got it?
Okay, you're gonna
feel a little bit of pressure.
And we are in the
amniotic cavity.
Okay, now we're in the
abdomen of the acardiac twin.
And coagulating
intra-abdominal vessels.
What happens to
the tumor baby thing?
You just suck it
out or something?
Wilson?
Uh, the mass is harmless,
so it actually stays in
the belly until delivery.
Nasty!
The baby's tired from
pumping blood for two.
She'll feel much better soon.
I don't think I'm gonna tell
her about her vampire sister.
I mean, not until she's older.
You know, my mom never
told me anything juicy.
I hated being kept in the dark.
What's wrong?
What? Nothing.
No, it's not nothing.
You made a face.
Did you mess her up?
Okay, whoa, whoa.
Remember? We're not moving.
No, don't talk down to
me with that "we" crap!
There is nothing to
be upset about, Kristen.
Yes, there is. I can tell.
You're lying to me.
Is she lying to me?
No, Kristen. Your
baby's totally fine.
Rochester, calm down.
They're trying to help you.
Now you're lying to me?
No, I'm not. There,
there! I got it!
Get this stuff out of me!
Okay, we're done.
Probe is almost out.
Ow, ow, ow, ow! What did you do?
Nothing. Please,
just stay still.
I'm bleeding. I'm
bleeding. I can feel it.
I can feel it. I'm
bleeding all over.
It's not blood.
What?
Okay, all right. Hold pressure.
All right, I'm gonna
examine you now, okay?
Okay, we need a little privacy.
That's strictly
against protocol.
Can we at least shut the door?
No.
I am about to examine
her with her legs open.
The least you could
do is back the hell up.
Thanks.
All right, deep breath. Okay.
All right, you're
gonna feel my hands.
All right, I see pooling, so
it's definitely amniotic fluid.
And she's having
some contractions.
Okay, I need oxygen, suction,
and an infant warmer, Eldredge.
Did you hurt my baby?
- No, no, no.
- What's going on?
Everything is okay.
Nothing is wrong.
Your water broke, and
you're in pre-term labor.
She's in labor already?
Isn't it too early?
Well, she's 31 weeks,
which isn't completely to term,
but it's... it's far enough
along for survival.
I don't even have a crib yet.
Kristen's allowed to have you in
the room with her, for the labor.
Did you tell her that I'm here?
No. But she's
been asking for you.
And if you could just
come with me to see her...
I'm fine where I am.
She needs her mom.
She's having a baby.
I said that I'm fine where I am.
She's your daughter.
Do you have a daughter?
I do.
Well, keep an eye on her.
Pay attention.
I don't know what for,
because Kristen was...
perfect. She was beautiful.
I never could have imagined.
Just pay attention.
She's someone that I
don't even recognize now.
The baby is better off never
knowing her in the first place.
God!
They're five minutes apart.
I hate this! It hurts!
I know. I know. I know. But you
know what? You're doing great.
No, it's not that!
It's the cuffs!
Did Amanda call my mom?
Is she on her way?
I'm not aware of that.
You are keeping her from me!
No, I'm not.
I have the right.
She has the right to be here.
Call Amanda. I want Amanda!
Ms. Joseph is unavailable.
Why are you letting her do this?
No one ever tells me anything!
Her pulse is skyrocketing.
Okay, you need to
calm down, okay, honey?
Don't call me stupid
freaking pet names!
I know you know.
Where is my mom?
Tell me!
Rochester. Settle down.
Okay, listen, we need to get
your pulse rate down, okay?
So just take a couple of deep
breaths with me, okay, Kristen?
Take a deep breath.
Why won't you just tell me?
She's downstairs.
- Wilson!
- Wilson.
Sorry. She doesn't
want to be lied to, right?
What?
I'm so sorry, Kristen.
Your mom's here,
but she won't see you.
I want to know why.
I don't know the
answer. I wish I did.
Well, tell, tell me again,
what did she say exactly?
I've told you
everything that I know.
Liar.
You're all liars.
Bring me my mom!
I wish we were lying, but
we're not. She won't come.
No. No. Liar.
Nobody's mom doesn't come
when they're having a baby.
I need her here.
I want my mom.
Mommy!
Okay. Kristen, Kristen, I'm
sorry, but it's time to push again.
No. I'm not gonna
do this, I won't.
Honey, it's gonna happen
whether you want it to or not.
No, I can't.
I can't do it alone.
You're not.
Get off!
Shush, shush, shush, I'm holding
your hand. You're not alone.
Now...
push.
Okay, great. Good, good, good,
good. Great job. Great job, Kristen.
Good, good, good, good, good.
I want my mommy!
Shush, I know, I know, I know.
Just tell her... just tell
her... Tell her I'm sorry.
Tell her I'm so sorry.
Tell her... tell her I
wish I could take it back.
Tell her that, and...
and maybe she'll come.
Please?
We're here with you.
Yeah, we got you.
We're here, Kristen.
I hate this. I hate you!
Get away from me!
Squeeze all you want.
You're pissed off.
You're hurt. You're tired.
You deserve to
be. Put it all on me.
Good, good,
good... Just like that.
Here we go. Another push. I need
a big push, Kristen. Push, push!
All right, keep your
head in the game.
We're here with you,
Kristen. We got you. Come on.
Keep on pushing, keep on
pushing, keep on pushing!
Yes! Yes, yes! Good job.
You got this, all right? Okay,
good. Okay, take a breath.
Great. That was perfect.
Can we undo two
of these restraints?
It's too risky.
They're cutting off
her blood supply.
She still has good blood
flow. They're not cyanotic.
She's having a baby! Do you think
that she needs this to hurt more?
If this was illegal before, it has to be 10
times more illegal now that she's in labor.
Rochester's K-10. She's
combative, unpredictable.
Well, can't we call someone?
I tried the sheriff.
There has to be someone else.
Me. I'm someone else.
So, it's up to you?
Come on, Dr. Eldredge!
You get to say yes here!
Say yes!
Hall, unhook them.
After what she did this morning?
You'll stay close by.
Unhook her restraints.
Hall, get them off
of her right now!
Okay, good job.
Here, here.
Good.
We are so close,
Kristen! We are so close!
You're doing so well.
Baby's head is out! Suction!
Okay, you're almost there.
One more push.
No, I can't. I can't.
Give us one more push,
and it'll all be over. Okay.
Okay!
Yes!
Just tell me she's okay.
Just... Just tell me I
didn't mess her up. Please.
No, she's perfect.
You should be so
proud of yourself.
Good job, Kristen.
I am.
Take her away. I
don't want to see her.
No, Kristen, that's
not what you want.
Yes, it is.
I'm not her mom.
I don't get to be
her mom at all.
I'm no one.
Just take her away.
No, Kristen, she's so beautiful.
Just look, just for a moment.
No.
I want to hold her.
Okay.
I want you to be good.
Okay?
Listen to your grandma.
Don't be like me.
I love you, Ellie.
Be good.
Please.
I'm your mama.
Remember me.
Okay?
Okay. I'm ready.
You sure?
Yes. Please take her.
Come here.
She'll be okay.
She'll play on
your nice swing set,
in your big room.
She'll grow up doing
cartwheels on the beach.
She's gonna miss you every day.
But she'll be okay.
What happens to Kristen now?
She'll recover here a few
days, then go back into gen pop.
For how long?
The rest of her
sentence. 20 years to life.
That's longer than
she's been alive.
You want to know what
she did to end up in here?
No. I really don't.
We're keeping Ellie for...
Hannah. Her name is
Hannah. Please call her Hannah.
The baby will be kept
in the hospital's NICU
for observation for
as long as she needs.
And then she can come home?
And then she can go with you.
Uh, any other questions?
No.
Was there something else?
If this one makes a mistake,
will you leave her, too?
Excuse me?
If you're ever looking for a new
job, please come see me first.
Yeah, well, same goes for you.
Maybe it won't be so bad.
Maybe she'll be okay.
Yeah, maybe.
No. She won't...
be okay.
There's a reason doctors prefer
to see a patient in
person, face-to-face.
You were right.
Stuff does happen to people.
I don't want to be right.
Karev. He came
to see me last night.
He told me...
I don't want to be right.
It's the laying on of hands.
Human touch, that
spark of connection.
Just listen to me. Karev...
I don't want to be right.
Wilson...
For God's sake, I
don't want to be right!
I want there to be
something good.
I want the world to be good.
For once, I want to
see sun and happy.
For once, I want to be
wrong. So just stop talking.
We lay hands on each other
so we feel like we're
all in this together.
Say it.
Alex went to the D.A.
and took a plea bargain.
He's going to prison.
What? When?
Last night, before we left.
We connect with each
other, because if we didn't...
Stop the car.
Stop the car. I'm gonna be sick.
Let's go.
You okay?
Drive the car.
Drive the damn car!
We would all feel so, so alone.