In 1967,
surgeons in South Africa
performed the first successfl
heart transplant.
The following year,
there were 100 heart
transplants worldwide.
Problem was,
the patients kept dying.
I told you I didn't want
to have a party.
♪ I can already tell ♪
- ♪ I'm under your spell ♪
- So the following year, transplants
fell to 18.
♪ And that spells trouble,
trouble for me ♪
Kinda seems like people werea
little too eager to celebrat.
- ♪ I can't get it off my mind ♪
- Wow, I think that
you have found
every egg roll in Seattle.
Well, Mom said nothing
too fancy.
- Damn it.
- What?
I was just trying to get this
thing to stand up straight.
Oh. Just, um, pour some
of the wax down into the bottom.
- ♪ La la la la la la ♪
- and then stick the candle in.
- Right.
- ♪ La la la la la la ♪
- This place looks amazing.
Your mother
is going to love this.
She'd better love it.
God knows she gave me
enough stipulations.
No more than 40 people,
no foundation people...
no photographers.
"Only the doctors
that saved my life
and a few friends,
child."
Got it!
Oh, my.
- Wow.
- ♪ Oh, you look so good ♪
- ♪ I bet you feel good, too ♪
- You know...
people aren't really gonna
be here for a while.
So, I don't see
why we can't...
Uh, there are people
working here.
They'll know.
Well, let them know.
♪ You got that oooh la la la
la la la ♪
You're coming with me.
♪ You got that oooh la la la
la la la ♪
Bye.
♪ And it's just the kinda trouble ♪
♪ I've been lookin' for ♪
Captioning provided by
ABC Studios and ABC, Inc.
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 15  Episode 15
Episode Title: "We Didn't Start the Fire"
Sync corrections  by  srjanapala
Diagnostics, please.
Oh, good.
You are still here.
Let's go.
T... Oh.
Do you need a ride
to your own party?
It's Jackson's party.
And, no,
I don't need a ride.
What I need is a drink
to help calm my nerves...
...before I have
to go and pretend to like it.
A friend would help.
What?
Okay, I have been
sternly warned,
by more than one person,
not to aid and abet in any way,
should you try to ditch.
Well, I was offering you
a ride in my limousine,
that has a fully
stocked bar.
But enjoy going
in your own car,
that you have to drive
yourself.
You should have led
with limo.
So, I'm not sure
where it's going,
um
if it's even going anywhere.
But seeing how half of my
co-workers will be at the party
and see us together,
I am doing the responsible thing
and letting you know that
Andrew DeLuca and I are dating.
Well?
Are you telling me this
as the chief
or as your friend?
I don't know.
Both. Why?
Because I want to know
if I need to explain hospital rules
or just laugh at you.
When is Bailey
getting her job back?
Oh, why?
Would you rather tell her?
Can I watch?
You know,
you married a resident,
and I didn't say anything.
Yes, you did.
You were mean to her
for like two years.
And by the time I married her,
she was a fellow.
Well, you put my
resident
- in the hospital.
- Okay, we can stop.
But as chief,
I need to tell you
to report your relationship
to HR.
As your friend,
I hope he makes you happy.
Thank you.
Dr. Lawrence to the NICU.
Chief, Mrs. Karev
wants to see you.
All right, tell her
I'll see her at the party.
And it's Dr. Karev, Helm.
Oh. Right. Sorry.
He said he'll meet you
at the party.
Oh.
Dr. Millicent, call Radiolog.
Dr. Millicent, call Radiology.
That's it.
Easy.
It's only been two weeks.
I can get this.
Or you could not.
I could stay.
Betty, you can do this.
How?
I'm a drug addict with a baby
and a dead boyfriend.
I have nothing in common
with anyone my age,
and they're all gonna look at me
like I'm some sort of freak.
Because that's what I am.
I ruined my life.
That was the drugs.
And they tried to ruin
your life, but they failed.
Because you are here.
And I am here,
and I am here for you
no matter where you live.
And you are gonna call me
anytime you need to.
Day or night.
You are not in this alone.
It is gonna get better,
Betty.
I promise you
it gets so much better.
Can't we just stay another
night, John?
And get stuck
in morning traffic.
Yeah. But... But it's
4 1/2 hours'
difference... The difference
that's gonna make.
I mean, it's... it's crazy.
Well...
Uh, uh...
Sorry, sorry. Uh, just...
Babies are a lot more work
than I remember.
Well, uh...
God, you're so weird.
Well, uh,
thank you both.
So much.
For everything.
She didn't say goodbye.
I'm gonna go get ready.
You're going
to the party?
Yeah, I, uh, can't be
in this house tonight.
Hey, hey.
Oh. You know the party's
catered, right?
Well, it's rude not
to bring anything.
Hey!
I rest my case.
Hey, Pierce!
Hi... Uh, nothing.
Hi, I mean.
- Did you see it?
- What?
What? That lady you hated
wrote an article about you.
I'll text it to all of you.
- Oh, what lady?
- Kiki?
- What kind of article?
- Uh, who is this person?
"How Bravery and Self-Advocacy
Saved My Life."
Oh, that sounds nice.
That bitch.
Why? What'd she say?
Shh, shh, shh.
I'm reading.
I thought you gave
all your money away.
I could fit my whole loft
inside your fireplace.
That's not how it works.
Um, I created
a restricted endowment
invested
in a diverse portfolio
for my mom's foundation
to handle all the payouts.
Oh, you have ping-pong.
So, you got the whole place
to yourself, huh?
Yes. No sisters, no kids.
First time
in recent memory.
Do we have to go
to this party?
Yes.
But we don't
have to stay long.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
- Okay, good to go.
- Okay.
There is an MRI pending
for Mr. Evans in ICU 4.
And can you check all the labs
for the 11:00 p.m. draw
and get back to me if there's
anything I should know?
Mrs. Karev.
It's Doctor.
Wait. What?
Hi. Mrs. Karev. Hi.
You're in Seattle.
Jo. Hi.
- Surprise!
- Um, is everything okay?
- Does Alex know that you're here?
- Oh, yeah.
But he told me to
meet him at a party?
Oh. Uh... okay. Um...
Uh, we must have got
our wires crossed.
Um... great.
I-I can give you
a ride there.
Wonderful.
You've reached
Chief Alex Karev.
Leave a message.
Hey, Alex.
It's me again.
And your mom.
On our way to Jackson's.
See you soon.
Did you fly here, or...
Oh, a bus and a train
and another bus.
I-I thought flying might
be a little overwhelming.
Yes. It can be.
You know, I, uh...
I read this book recently,
uh, about the Lewis and Clark expedition.
- Mm-hmm.
And they encountered
so many hardships
making almost the same journey
that I just did.
So I thought, if they
could do that on horseback,
fighting disease,
then why couldn't I?
- Oh! Hey.
- Oh.
- Hey.
- Hey!
Sorry you had to see that,
Hunt.
But she's
just so damn happy.
She can't
keep her hands off me.
- What? Why?
- Oh, h... he surprised me.
Yeah, with a trip
to Palm Springs.
A little fun in the sun
before baby makes three.
Or, uh, four.
What? You're going on a trip?
I mean, you're seven months pregnant.
Yeah, I'm aware of how
pregnant I am, Owen. Yeah.
It's perfectly safe
for me to travel.
Yeah. First class.
She'll be in good hands.
Mm. My hands.
Mm. Shall we?
- Hey!
- Hi!
- Come on in!
- Good to see you.
- Good to see you. All right.
- Hey.
- Welcome, guys. Welcome.
- Thanks. - Hi.
Wow.
Come on in.
All right, you guys, uh,
make yourselves at home.
M'lady, let me, uh, get you
a club soda and cran. Oh.
You've had enough vodka tonight.
Thank you.
Nothing for me,
thanks.
Yes, and...
and brush your teeth
when Tanya tells you to,
and no extra books, okay?
I love you, too,
Elle-Belle.
Bye.
- You ready for another?
- Yes.
- Hey.
Who has the kids?
Bailey and Zola
are at a sleepover,
and Ellis
is with the babysitter.
Wow, empty house?
Maybe I should, uh,
go home with you.
- I actually wanted to tell you...
- I have no idea
what is going on
with Owen and me.
And why we are even sleeping
in the same bed.
I mean, it's not like
we're having any sex.
We went from ex-sex
to bickering married couple
in, like, 60 seconds.
And now... now
Betty and Leo are gone,
and we're just
both stuck in this,
you know,
giant sinkhole of sadness.
We've just been so focused
on the kids,
we didn't take time
to assess the damage
that we were doing to us.
This sucks.
I mean, I say, "us,"
but is there really an "us"
with no sex and no family?
Can I get you another glass
of wine there?
Or anything but that?
She's got, like,
a kajillion likes.
Listen to this...
"I had to find the courage
to find the answers
I could not find."
It's clearly way too many
"finds" in one sentence.
No, I barely get
a mention...
It's all about the bravery
and humility it took
to beg me to do a radical,
pioneering surgery...
These egg rolls are going
like hotcakes.
Oh, are you talking
about that article?
Mnh-mnh.
Oh, that was something!
You know, really...
really moving.
You come off very well.
It's like
she healed herself
with the magical power of her own narcissism.
I need more wine.
Yeah.
Babe, I just off...
Have you seen my mom?
Oh.
I could get used to this.
Yes, you can.
What's to stop you?
Hmm. Well, you have
money now, right?
With that butt-blazer?
T-Trail-Blazer.
It's a golden...
Butt-cork.
And you should
spend some of it.
No... I have!
No, I-I paid off my car,
this year's
property taxes.
Oh, yeah, and Ben and I did,
uh, replace the garage door.
That's just taking care
of business.
What have you done
for you?
W...
We need to talk.
Uh...
Oh, thanks.
No, no. This one.
You hate this party,
don't you?
No. No,
I-I don't hate this party.
No, I feel bad.
I mean, it's great.
It's... It's in my honor,
"For I'm a jolly good fellow"
and all that,
but, uh, for you, it's like
a gauntlet of awkwardness.
Baby-daddy is really
not happy about our trip.
Yeah, not his best moment.
But, in fairness,
I mean, he and Amelia had to say
goodbye to both their kids.
We can go, if you want.
I will feign diarrhea.
No, you won't. No,
for you, I will get diarrhea.
- No, stop it. Stop it!
- I will. I will...
Why?
- Oh. Hey.
- Hey.
Have you seen my mom?
Not your mom.
Uh, I-is Alex here?
Do you mind grabbing him
for me?
Can I grab...
Um, yeah.
Yeah, sure.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
Um, I'm going to update
an intern
on a patient
just real quick.
Mom?
What's wrong?
Hey, Jo, what's wrong?
Nothing's wrong.
W... You didn't tell her
to meet you here?
Uh, no.
No, it was...
It was the other doctor.
- Not Alex.
- Uh, wait, w-what doctor?
What... What doctor are you
talking... Jo, what's she...
I don't know.
- She didn't give me her name.
- All right.
Mom, could you, um, could you
give us a sec, please?
She was in the lobby.
- Of the hospital?
- Yeah, to surprise you.
You didn't say for her
to meet you here?
No.
Do you think the
other doctor's in her head?
- Why didn't you call me?
- You didn't pick up your phone!
I was playing ping-pong.
Catherine's party
has ping-pong?
How did she seem?
Did she seem hyper?
Um, you know,
seeing things?
She was, um... She was
talking a lot for her.
Or, at least, I think.
I...
About what?
Lewis and Clark.
Huh?
All right. Look, um...
I'm... I'm just gonna get her
back to our place, all right?
Perfect.
- Uh, Mom?
- No.
- Mom?
- No!
Hey. Hey!
How many ways are there
out of here?
- Why?
- Look, just... Are... Is there, like,
panic rooms or any place
somewhere someone could hide?
Very funny, Karev.
The place is not that big.
Just tell me!
Front door.
Or the fire exit upstairs.
Right. All right.
I don't have
a panic room!
Not smart
to announce that.
Mom?
Hey.
We're at a party.
Yep.
And you're standing out here
by yourself on the deck.
You okay?
That looks really good
right now.
You want to leave?
Uh, go to a meeting? Or...
No, I'm saying...
Should I not
be drinking, or...
No, t-t-that's not...
- I mean, I'm at a party...
- Owen, that is not what I'm saying.
I'm... I'm saying
I'm sad, too.
I'm saying sometimes I wish
I could drink
like a normal person.
And... It's not a big deal.
Just finish your stupid drink.
Did I do something to you?
Are we fighting
and I missed it?
Is that a yes?
Really?
We're fighting?
That's what you want to do
the night that we said goodbye
to Betty and Leo?
She didn't say goodbye.
Look, I don't want to fight.
I just want to talk.
We have not talked
in weeks.
Okay, let's talk.
Okay.
Let's talk.
Where do we start?
- How about "piss poor life choices"?
- Wow.
Or how you refuse to accept
that addiction is a disease?
- I never said that.
- You may as well have.
Why do you do that?
You always throw things
in my face that I said months ago.
- I hate it.
- And I hate... I hate
that... you have not asked me how
I have been through any of this.
- I've be in pain, Amelia.
- Yeah, and when
you're in pain,
you go silent.
You... You keep it
all inside.
You act like you are all alone in it,
and you are not.
Yeah, because I-I-I-I
haven't been able to fix it.
- So I just...
- So... So we should just never
- talk about it?
- We don't never talk about it.
I hate
how you generalize.
You know, "You always do this,
and you always do that."
Okay, you literally
just did that to me.
You said I "always"
throw things in your face.
Are we trying to talk,
or are you just trying to win?
Well, I wanted to talk,
but it's kind of hard
when you have been staring
at Teddy the entire time.
How about you?
Thank you.
- Hey!
- Hey.
Mm. Nice article.
Really? Teddy? Was it?
Or was it just some puff piece
on a website
that may as well
be called "OMG! BOYS!"
Well, I mean, I thought it was really...
- No.
You know, they should
really read my piece
that I just submitted to the Journal
of Cardiothoracic Advancement,
where I actually outline
the procedure!
All right, well, I'll do that when...
- No, you won't.
Because they probably
won't even publish it now,
because it's just
the same story, only boring.
'Cause who needs science
when there's pluckiness
and spunk?
Helen?
I do hate this party.
Hey. You're leaving?
Hi. I, um...
Tanya called, and Ellis
is really scared, so...
Oh, oh,
I can pick her up.
No. It's a party
in your honor.
- You can't leave.
- It's not really an honor
when you didn't
get 100% margins.
And on top of that, I think Owen
still has feelings for Teddy.
You should have seen
how he reacted
when he found out that she was
going on vacation with Koracick.
Teddy is always going
to be in Owen's life.
Baby or no baby.
It was this way
for Cristina.
It's been this way
your whole marriage.
And your divorce.
It's not gonna change.
Just make peace with it.
I'm not in a love triangle.
This is a circle.
And it just keeps going
around and around.
I'm definitely staying
at your place tonight.
Historians believe
that Meriwether Lewis
had bipolar disorder,
but in
the early 19th century,
they called it,
um, "melancholy."
Mm. So you're
a psychologist?
- Librarian.
- Oh.
H-How do you
know Catherine?
- Who?
- Mom.
What?
Look, uh, DeLuca, thanks.
Yeah.
He's very nice.
Oh, thank God.
Oh, I worried you.
Yeah, you had us worried.
I am doing well.
I feel sturdy.
How about I give you
both a minute?
I made something for you.
Oh.
When you were a little boy,
green was your favorite color,
but it could have changed by now,
so you can just pick.
Yeah, it's, uh... it's not
much of a wedding gift.
Uh, y-you don't
have to take one.
- That's okay.
- No, no, no. Green is good.
It's... It's... It's great.
It's... It's lovely.
Okay, what about Jo?
Blue.
Okay.
Oh, Dr. Grey.
Excuse me, Bokhee, Jae.
Mm.
Bokhee.
Uh, I got your text.
Yeah.
- Is everything okay?
- No. Amelia's in a state.
Oh.
So I think
I'm on duty tonight.
In the guest room?
Hey.
What?
I'm just trying to burn this
image in my head forever.
Okay, but you do realize
nothing is happening
in the guest room of
Jackson Avery's house, right,
with all of our co-workers
downstairs?
Okay.
Speaking Italian...
I... Look,
I don't know how long
the Trail-Blazer's success
will run.
It's like, what if
somebody else comes along
with something better?
All my checks... poof.
Bailey,
that's how money works.
I mean, my grandfather
made a fortune
when he opened
a candy store in 1921.
- And what happened in 1927?
- Mnh. Poof?
My father didn't have shoes
that fit for over a month.
Oh. I'm just trying to tell you
that money comes,
money goes.
And what's the point
if you lose it
before you get to
enjoy it a little?
So, you want me to buy
myself a few hospitals?
How many to start, three?
Start slow, honey. Okay.
What is the one thing that
you haven't let yourself get?
Come on.
There's got to be something.
The C7500 TurboMix in red.
Uh, soups, smoothies, dips,
dressings, desserts...
You can make
Christmas dinner with it.
And... it cleans itself.
Act of God.
What is it?
A blender.
Oh, Lord.
- What?
- Well, you should just
buy the damn thing.
Look at that price.
Bailey, think about when
you walk into your kitchen,
and it's gleaming at you
from the counter
with its five
programmable speeds.
The price is nothing
compared to that joy...
I bought it!
All right!
We got
something to celebrate.
Come on.
N-No, it's almost 8:00.
We need to get to the party.
Oh, please,
I'm not going to that.
Mmm.
Well, this is the last
of the duck sauce.
Avery, thanks for everything,
but I gotta... I'm heading out.
What? No, no, no.
- Come on.
- Listen, I'm sorry. I just...
God, I hate that guy.
Who... Koracick?
Oh, well, yeah.
He's a creep.
- What? You think so, too?
- I know so.
He took advantage of April
during a pretty vulnerable time.
You're kidding.
He's been after Catherine
since the minute
he got into town.
What is she...
What is she doing with him?
I can't say I'd be thrilled
if I were you.
On the other hand,
he did save my mom's life,
so I don't know.
But it's a party for you!
It's for Shepherd
and Koracick.
Because they saved
your life.
They did.
They performed
an astonishing feat,
and for that,
I am forever grateful.
But Miranda, if I walk
into that party right now,
people are gonna come up to me
and say things like,
"Oh, congratulations,."
"You did it"...
Like it's all over,
like I'm cancer-free.
Yes, my tumor hasn't gotten
any bigger, but it could.
It could.
And so I have to live in dread
from one scan to the next.
For every scan.
I'm never gonna be out of
the woods with this thing,
and it's not something
I feel like celebrating.
Hypocrite.
Excuse me?
You're all easy come, easy go
when it comes to money,
but you're afraid
to spend joy.
What... you think
you're gonna run out of it?
That dread between scans
is scary.
But it's life.
And it's not perfect,
but it's the one you get now.
W-What I get.
I-I have a heart that
I no longer trust.
I live day by day trying to
get it to not blow up again
and hoping that the fix
they gave me stays a fix.
And you?
You have
a piece of tumor
on your spine,
and it could get bigger
or it could not.
And you know what?
An earthquake could take us
all out tomorrow.
Or a meteor.
Or robots.
We don't get to know that.
Banners' "Got It In You
" plays...
But just right now,
we're alive...
We are still here.
And people love us, so,
that's cause to celebrate.
♪ Holding back the flood
in this skyscraper town ♪
Hey, excuse me.
Can we talk?
What else is there
to talk about?
Listen, I wasn't
looking at Teddy.
I was looking at Koracick.
Okay?
I don't like that guy.
I don't like that
he's dating Teddy.
Because you're jealous.
No, because he's like a dog
marking his territory.
And because who hits on a woman
who's seven months pregnant?
That's Tom.
He's available. Always.
He was available for me
after the tumor.
- Wait. What?
- Why does it matter?
If you're not interested
in Teddy, what does it matter?
If he's with her, then he's
gonna be in my daughter's life,
and I don't want that.
This has got nothing
to do with Teddy.
How many times do I have
to choose you, Amelia,
for you to stop feeling
insecure?
Insecure?
This is not about some fling
from your past.
She is pregnant
with your child right now
because you got on a plane
to profess your love to her
seven months ago.
Not... Not seven years.
Seven months.
So forgive me for worrying
that maybe your feelings
might still be lingering,
and that maybe
when you see your baby,
you are gonna realize how deeply
you are in love with her.
You and I fell back in love
over children that we adored
and that
we no longer have.
Okay? Do you
really think that,
when you see your daughter
lying in Teddy's arms,
that you are not gonna think
that maybe this is
where you belong?
Because I do.
And maybe you're right.
Maybe that is insecurity.
Or maybe it is wisdom.
Whatever you want to call it,
it is what I believe.
And I cannot talk my way
out of it.
I can't.
And I'm starting
to think maybe I...
♪ Maybe you don't see it ♪
♪ But you're quicker than ♪
I'm starting to think
♪ the world can spin ♪
I shouldn't try.
- What are you saying?
- I'm saying I'm dizzy.
Owen, I'm...
I'm dizzy.
I need to step out
of the circle.
What?
I'm saying this
is an impossible situation.
And... you are in it
no matter what
because there is a child
involved.
But I'm not.
I'm not in it, no matter what.
I'm saying...
♪ When the lights go out ♪
I'm saying I'm not in it
anymore.
♪ And leave you standing
in the dark ♪
♪ No one ever told you
this would be so hard ♪
Hey, uh, Dr. Lummis,
this is Alex Karev,
uh, Helen Karev's son.
If you could, uh,
give me a call back
as soon as you can...
It's pretty urgent.
Please.
They're two hours ahead.
Y-You're not gonna hear
from them until tomorrow.
Right. I should
probably text, too.
Hey. Here. Come here.
Come sit down.
- ♪ You got it in you ♪
- Come here.
♪ When the lights go out ♪
She seems okay.
♪ And leave you standing in the
dark ♪ - The doctor will call.
And then we will find out
what's going on.
My mom comes for a visit,
and I have to worry
if it's a sign she's gonna
split from reality.
Isn't that how
it's always been?
Well, yeah.
Growing up.
But then, you could tell
when things were getting bad.
I knew the signs.
I mean, now that
she's doing fine,
I d... I don't know
what a split looks like.
I want to trust it.
I want to trust it so much
that she's fine.
- I really do. I swear, Jo.
- I know.
These are really nice.
She shouldn't have needles.
♪ You got it in you ♪
Okay, we...
We should stop now.
Why?
Because I'm going to
change my mind.
Sounds good.
Ohh.
Just answer it.
I don't care who it is.
But someone might
hear it ringing.
It's Carina.
Oh. Our sisters are really
getting in the way tonight.
Yeah, they really are.
Oh. Uh...
Um...
This is
not the restroom.
No, that's, uh...
That's down the hall.
We're not...
I...
Alex knows.
W-Wonderful.
Uh, don't let me keep you.
Hmm.
Oh, my...
I told you!
It's not funny!
Hey. I can do this.
Thanks.
What are you doing?
Oh, I'm being normal.
Huh. Will you put these
in the oven for me?
I don't think
this counts as normal.
Jackson hired people
to do this.
- Just do it.
- Okay, you're flustered.
Yes,
I'm getting flustered.
Richard just
walked in on us.
Yeah, kissing.
At a work party.
So now I feel like
everybody's staring at us.
No one is staring at us.
Because we're
acting normal.
And after going to many doctors,
this woman found Maggie.
She was
a med school acquaintance,
and after that,
they...
Excuse us.
Just one second.
Uh, excuse me for a second.
Please stop telling people
- about that article, please?
- Why? It's very nice.
No, it's not.
And she is not.
That was my story to tell,
for doctors,
in a way that mattered,
and she stole it.
She is a bully who made me
feel small and insignificant,
and she is still managing,
even from a thousand miles away,
to make me feel small
and insignificant!
Maggie Pierce. You are not small and insig...
- No, no!
Please, please, don't...
Don't say anything kind
or comforting or consoling.
I'm pissed.
I want to stay pissed.
I want
to burn something down!
Did you know that I was the only
black resident in my class?
So I was bullied, too.
Residents would take my number
off the pager service...
- Oh, my God.
- So I'd miss traumas.
Some of the attendings would
call the other residents "Dr."
But I only got "Webber."
And I was plenty pissed.
But I found out that
it's no good to be pissed
if you don't use it.
You know, the difference
between a great surgeon
and a celebration
surgeon...
is a little bit
of what Kiki has.
A little flair
for promotion.
You could use
a little of that.
If someone takes your story,
you take it back,
and you tell it louder.
Stop publication of that piece,
and rewrite it,
from your point of view.
Start that fire,
Maggie Pierce.
Hi. You want something
to eat?
I'm happy to see you.
It's just, uh,
it threw me.
I mean, uh...
I mean, it really means a lot
for Jo and me both.
Tires. No.
Tennis shoes.
- Melting tennis shoes.
- What?
- Don't you smell that?
- No.
All right, t-take it easy.
Take it easy.
The... The shoes...
The shoes you had in
high school, the red ones.
Remember?
They were on sale.
But they're
burning.
The shoe...
Alex,
we are really high up.
Honestly, everybody needs
to get out of here right now.
But, Mom,
there is no fire.
Yes, there is!
There is!
Mom, come on. Just stop.
Just calm down.
Come on. Sit down.
Come on. Please?
It's gonna be all right.
I am a little hungry.
What if you go into
labor when you're out of town?
They have hospitals
in California...
But I wouldn't be there.
Well, a flight
is not even three hours.
I wanna be there.
I understand that,
but I'm taking this trip.
And what is this about,
Teddy?
You want that dirtbag
in the delivery room?
- Whoa.
- I mean,
do you want him around
our daughter?
He is not a good guy.
I think he's a great guy.
And he saved Amelia's life,
and he's...
Hey.
Uh, pickles,
uh, seven almonds,
pasteurized cheese.
- But one of the almonds is for me.
- Thank you.
Okay.
Uh, do you mind?
Uh, we're in the middle
of something.
I do mind.
But thanks for asking.
- Mom. Hey. You made it.
- Oh.
- Yeah. Mm.
- Finally.
She's your problem now.
All right. Everyone!
Our guest of honor is here.
- There's nothing fun about any of this.
- Alex, we have to get out of here.
All right,
w-we're gonna go.
- We're gonna leave.
- No, uh...
Karev. Can you just stay
till after the toast?
Do you hear him, Teddy?
Do you hear these words...
Mom, come on over.
All right, folks, over here. Oh.
You're starting to upset her.
And embarrass yourself.
Hey. She's seven
months pregnant, Tom,
so why don't you just do the right thing?
So, what... what,
we're on a first-name basis now?
Because I barely know you.
Wait. What was it again? It was Oliver? Ollie?
- No, no, I know you.
Because any man
who would prey on
- a vulnerable pregnant woman.
- Okay, over here.
Okay, okay,
this was a blast,
but I shouldn't keep
my public waiting.
And I will tell you another
thing, Tom.
If you think you're gonna
be around my kid,
then you have
another thing coming.
'Cause you may be
many things,
- but a father isn't one of them!
- Owen!
- Oh, wow!
- What the hell?!
- Oh!
- Okay. I'm done.
- Owen!
- Owen, he is a father!
All right,
if you're gonna punch him,
you're gonna have to go through
a pregnant woman.
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I...
- Oh, don't be. All right.
Million dollar hand.
Sorry, Avery, proceed.
Yeah. Um, anyway,
as you can see,
I am so happy to be standing
here with...
Fire!
- What's that?
- It's a fire.
It's a real fire!
Uh, all right,
well, okay...
There appears to be
a small situation here.
Just carefully... if you all
could make your way...
Be safe.
Oh, no!
Come on, everybody.
It's a real fire!
Come on, Mom.
I told you I didn't want
to have a party.
If I could get
everyone's attention, please,
the building is cleared
for re-entry.
Everyone except
the penthouse level.
The fumes are still
pretty bad up there,
and it should really air out
for a few days.
- Ben.
- Plastic in the oven.
See it all the time.
Bad smoke but no fire.
Who put plastic
in the oven?
Sometimes the trays
look like metal.
Think it might've been
egg rolls.
You've got access?
We don't know that
that was us.
We're pretty sure it was.
- Mer!
- Yeah?
Meredith Grey... I want you
to meet my mother, Helen.
Helen.
It's so nice to meet you.
Meredith...
you're Alex's best friend.
I am. And he's mine.
That smoke is messing
with my eyes.
Let's go.
Come on. Come on.
Good night.
Oh.
Amelia doesn't need to
stay at my house now.
Oh.
But maybe we should
go to your house
just in case she changes
her mind again.
Yeah.
Okay.
I didn't mean
to be ungrateful.
But you know how hard
this is for me, baby.
It's hard for everyone.
I know I wasn't the one that
was sick, but it was hell.
You're not the only one who gets
to have feelings, you know?
Unfortunate way
to meet the neighbors.
Hey, we still have
the limo.
We could all go
somewhere together.
And celebrate.
Uh, you're going to see
a very expensive blender
on our next credit-card
statement.
Because I deserve it.
And I need a ride home.
There's plenty of room
in the aid car.
Oh.
Um, and you can wear
this uniform home
anytime you feel like it.
Well, I think I'm gonna need to,
'cause, uh, you are fire.
Ooh!
This Kiki person sounds
like a real piece of work.
She is.
That's all right.
I'm gonna tell my story louder.
I'm gonna start
my own fire.
Mnh-mnh.
Let's come up with
a new metaphor, huh, babe?
Am I just drunk,
or is this burger amazing?
Everything tastes better
in the back of a limousine.
And you may also be drunk.
Okay. From here on out...
From here on out,
every scan that I get,
good news or bad,
this is how I want
to celebrate.
In the back of my limousine,
eating trashy food,
drinking expensive champagne
and sparkling apple cider.
With the people that I love most
in this world.
- Mwah!
Cheers to that.
Ah!
Surgeons are reluctant
to celebrate.
Even in success,
we obsess about
what could have been better.
Whoa. What are you...
Owen,
they brought Leo back.
Why would they...
♪ I'm walking
on a thin line ♪
♪ I try not to look down ♪
Can we talk?
♪ Can't stop my hands
from shaking ♪
I mean, we fought her on it
at first.
It just felt
so crazy for us to...
Giving up our grandchild,
but...
We're gonna have our hands
so full with Britney,
you know,
just helping her to adjust,
to just stay sober and...
Sure. A-And we've
seen you with him and...
You and Dr. Shepherd.
And don't get me wrong, that
self-reflection is important.
You brought
our Britney back to us.
We're so grateful.
And she always
just talks about
you and Amelia
as being his parents.
And she's right.
♪ Wind upon the water ♪
We're...
We're Britney's parents, but...
♪ Storm under the sea ♪
You're Leo's.
♪ 'Cause I know the moon's
watching over me ♪
We only get better when
we admit our shortcomings,
acknowledge our limits.
- ♪ What has been will not always be ♪
- Yes, sweetheart.
Are you sure
this is what you want?
♪ Steady now ♪
- ♪ Eyes on the horizon ♪
- Yeah.
I want to be a kid.
♪ This will pass ♪
I-I want to be able
to make mistakes...
You know, not, like,
overdose mistakes,
but, like...
Breaking curfew.
Or, um,
- crashing my dad's car into the fence.
- ♪ Steady now ♪
♪ Steady now ♪
- Thank you.
For everything.
So, um, you have our info.
We do.
Oh.
Take care.
And... keep in touch.
But there are so many moments
along the way to celebrate.
Bye.
♪ Steady now ♪
♪ Eyes on the horizon ♪
♪ This will pass ♪
- ♪ And the world will keep ♪
- Some of those moments
- ♪ Spinning on ♪
- are bigger than others.
- Good night.
- Yes.
♪ And on ♪
♪ Steady now ♪
And you really don't want
to miss those moments.
So, yeah, I feel like
we missed some, um...
Serious time together?
- Yeah.
This is it.
Let me just, um, get my... out...
Hey, do you mind?
Why you didn't
answer the phone?
What? Wha...
Why...
What are you doing back?
Conversing in Italian...
Because believe me
when I say...
Andrea.
I tried to warn you.
Ciao!
Uh. Uh...
Ciao. Ciao.
Ciao.
Um... M-Meredith,
this is, um, my dad.
- Oh. Buona sera.
- Sera.
The bad times are gonna
find you all on their own.
Sync corrections by srjanapala