We've all heard the saying.
It's one of those things we learn
in seventh grade science class.
Adapt or die.
- I don't understand.
- It's two words:
- "No sex."
- I'm sure there should
be more words.
If you're gonna choose a chief
resident, you have to be impartial.
- Come on, this, now?
- Sex with me,
however hot and excellent,
could cloud your judgment.
- This is blackmail,
is what it is.
- No, it is not.
Final interviews are today, and
coincidentally, I am on your service.
- Coincidentally.
- Since Teddy's shutting me out
of cardio, where I can show
my stuff, I'm gonna show it to you.
So today you'll see me, not as
your naked and desirable wife,
but as a focused, organized,
efficient and deserving candidate.
Who's getting in the shower.
I'll come with you.
No, no, no. No clouding.
Owen, this hurts me
more than it hurts you.
- No, it doesn't.
- I know.
Adapting isn't easy, though.
You have to fight your
competition, fend off their attacks.
And sometimes, you have to kill.
Good morning.
You're meeting with
Owen this morning, right?
Yeah.
You're not gonna say anything
about me or the trial, right?
You know, I thought you were
gonna say something like, "Good luck."
But I guess it's every
freaking man for himself, huh?
You do what you
need to do to survive.
Tell him that you were instrumental
in getting the chief's trial approved
for phase one human
testing. From mice to humans.
- I'm not doing that.
- Yeah, OK.
I know, you don't like
bragging about yourself.
But you don't even have to brag.
Your diabetes trial does it for you.
It's gonna win every
award. Seriously.
- Just make sure
that he knows that...
- I got it.
- That you've been
instrumental...
- Got it!
He don't got it.
I got it.
I got the job at Baylor,
over 50 applicants.
- I... I got it.
- That's awesome.
Well, I don't know. I
mean, it's in Texas.
There are a lot of
factors to consider, right?
Yeah, but that's what you
wanted. It's a great program.
Well, I mean, I was thinking of
sticking around here for another year.
Crap. I gotta go. I gotta
prep for my meeting with Hunt.
Besides, if I'm here when you win
chief resident, you'll still have a friend.
Look, we all get it's not
personal. I mean, it's a competition.
Sometimes you gotta be a
shark. Congratulations on Baylor.
Hm? You see?
- Sorry I'm late. I was cramming.
- What, for Hunt?
- You've got it in the bag.
- No, I'm more worried about
the interview with
the social worker.
Don't laugh at me, Derek. Nothing
in my life has prepared me for this.
My mother was about as
nurturing as a steak knife.
I don't know anything about making
lunches or Halloween costumes.
Good moms make
Halloween costumes.
- You can sew.
- I sew skin.
Yeah. Z's gonna be fine.
It's just instinct, right?
You go with her. There
you go. There you go.
Baby...
OK...
She looks good! Her weight's up
and her previous incisions have healed,
the labs are within normal limits and
she's super-duper cute! Aren't you?
So it's an uncomplicated hernia, so you don't
have to use any artificial closures, right?
Yeah, no. No, it
should be simple.
I'll do a short incision
in her suprapubic crease
to do a traditional exposure,
and then I'll...
finish with... Chupo!
I'm sorry. That's what
Callie calls a pacifier.
Zola hasn't eaten because of the
surgery. She's probably really hungry.
You might wanna try and
soothe her with a pacifier.
Come here, baby.
Come here, little lady.
Oh, yes, there you go.
- Chupo.
- Wow.
All right. I'll call you when
we're ready to come take her up.
See? We'll figure it out.
Are you excited? It's been a
month, Abena, you ready to go home?
I snagged some
extra hydroxyurea.
Wait, wait, wait.
You forgot something.
You need to take that at home,
OK, along with your antibiotics.
It's gonna help with the sickle cell
symptoms and the attacks will be
- less severe when they happen.
- Thank you.
I'll make sure she takes it.
Now, you have sickle cell, Lebo, so
you need to make sure you take some, too.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Promise me.
Yes, Dr. Alex.
And don't forget, you both have to
have your blood counts monitored
- at the clinic,
even if you feel fine.
- I will. Just as you told me.
I promise. Thank you. Thank you for
helping my sister. Thank you so much.
- Are you in pain, Lebo?
- No, no. I'm fine.
- We have to go.
- Dr. Bailey.
Maybe we should check you out.
She'll miss the plane.
It's no trouble, I'm fine.
OK, wait. Hold...
Gurney!
OK, OK.
- How about her?
- She's smiling.
- Who smiles when
they go for a run?
- Happy people.
Happiness is overrated.
What about you?
Shouldn't what's his name be
off to save the world pretty soon?
What's his name is taking
a break from world-saving.
He was offered a permanent
position at Landstuhl.
- On your left.
- Watch out.
It's a U.S. military
hospital in Germany.
- And he leaves in a week.
- That's great.
He asked me to go with him.
- Wow.
- You OK?
Yeah.
I mean, I really... I like him.
I feel like things
could be good with us.
That's just crazy, right? Besides,
I have too many obligations here.
I'm in the middle of my
contract, I have residents to teach,
- I have you.
- You just listed me
as an obligation.
- No. That's not what I meant...
- No, I get it. Like I'm dead weight.
- I'm an anchor
dragging you down.
- No, stop. No!
If I move, it might cause
you insurance headaches.
I'm just saying that
we would sort of...
- We would just
have to sort it out.
- OK.
OK.
What about her?
Yeah, if a unibrow was
my thing, I'd be all over that.
You're hopeless.
What do you got?
Seventeen-year-old pregnant female
with syncopal episode outside the ER.
She's got blood in
her left lower quadrant.
Could be a splenic
rupture, but it's hard to tell.
- Abena?
- Abena's fine.
Don't worry about her right now.
You need to worry
about yourself.
- You need to have surgery.
- Lebo, why didn't you tell us
- you were pregnant?
- You would have said
I cannot fly.
I had to be here for my sister. Is
something wrong with my baby?
I see a strong heartbeat, but there's
not much fluid surrounding the baby,
- and he's very small
for 32 weeks.
- She's eight months along?
Yeah, I'm gonna need
to monitor this baby.
We need to take her
to CT first to see where
the abdominal
bleeding's coming from.
OK, I'll meet you in surgery.
She's barely breathing.
I'll get an ambu.
I've got blood hanging
and her BP's still dropping.
- No time for a CT.
- Call up and get an OR ready.
It's based on a
protocol used in aviation.
A simple checklist has led to
a huge drop in plane crashes.
- Because it cuts down
on human error.
- Exactly.
And I thought, instead of... thanks...
telling you about it in an interview,
I'd walk you through it.
So the checklist is the first
page on every patient clipboard.
So you can see, at a glance, that
Mr. Aranda has been checked in
for coughing up blood, has been seen
by a physician, has had a chest X-ray,
and those results have come back.
So now we just need to get a consent
- for bronchoscopy
to rule out cancer.
- Cancer?
- He might have cancer?
- Like Grandpa had?
- He died.
- What are you talking about?
I'm sorry. I said
"rule out" cancer.
There's a spot on your X-ray that
we just need to take a closer look at,
so that we can be sure that your
dad's just fine. Just to be sure. OK?
OK, so that's
"update the patient."
Dr. Hunt, bed seven is admitted for
observation, bed five is discharged,
I put in a drain in bed nine and
I'm reporting for further instruction.
- You are organized.
- And focused and efficient.
Well, Mr. Aranda here needs
to go up to bronchoscopy.
- Well, I'll take him.
- Actually, no, proper protocol
is to page Dr. Altman, she
will schedule the bronchoscopy.
See? It's right here on
the checklist. Protocol.
OK, so the next step
is the OR checklist.
Mr. Aranda, let's get
you up to bronchoscopy.
There's a lot of bleeding
here. More suction?
- Where's the source?
- Well, so far,
the spleen looks good.
Just keep exploring.
Just a little more retraction.
There. Please.
- What's he doing there?
- Nobody move! Gown me. I'm going in.
How did her baby get
tangled up in her intestines?
Right over here.
The baby survived a full
term outside of the uterus?
Yeah, it's extremely rare.
Her tubes are scarred,
so the fertilized egg found a place to
implant where it could continue to grow.
Dr. Bailey, grab
his foot while I
- free him from these adhesions.
- Why didn't it show up
- on the ultrasound?
- Believe it or not
it's missed about 50 percent
of the time. Keep suctioning.
OK, he's coming out.
Clamps to Dr. Robbins, please.
Dr. Karev, cut the cord and
take him to get checked out.
OK, the blood in her abdomen
is from her placenta ripping apart.
We need to remove as much
as possible. Be prepared for
torrential hemorrhage.
Check the...
Pressure's dropping.
Damn it! Clamps! Zero Vicryl!
We've got to stop this
bleeding or we're gonna lose her.
Cross-match six more units of
RBCs, and get them up here stat!
- Alex, I don't hear that baby!
- Come on, buddy, give it up.
And I've been doing
some research on diabetes,
and I heard you're
starting a clinical trial.
I'd like to see if
I could get on it.
The trial has very
specific criteria.
The subjects have
to remain impartial.
The fact that you're married
to one of my attendings...
Look, I know you've never been wild
about the fact that Teddy married me,
but the truth is,
I really like her.
And not just for her insurance.
But she still sees me as a patient.
As an insurance sponge. I
need to get my own insurance.
So in order to do that, I need
a job. And in order to get a job,
it would be helpful if I wasn't going
into diabetic shock every five minutes.
- Hey. What's this?
- Just a med change.
Hunt, my knee replacement got
canceled and I need to break some bones.
- Aren't you supposed to mend
them?
- Well, it's my first day back.
And I left my baby for the
first time since we got home.
I need to remember why I
love being a surgeon so much,
or I'm afraid I will walk out
of here and never come back.
It doesn't have to be
big. Just a sprained ankle,
a hairline fracture. Anything.
- OK.
- Oh, my God,
anytime I hear a baby cry,
it makes me think of Sofia.
They all sound like her. Wait,
that really sounds like her.
- What! What are you doing here?
- It's Bring Your Daughter
to Work Day.
- No, it's not.
- I bathed her, changed her,
I fed her,
I napped her, we read a book,
played with that little
hanging jingling thing.
And it was still only 11:30. I
needed some adult contact.
Mm-hm.
Please take this
baby away from me.
- Sure.
- I'm serious, take her, Mark.
Oh, my God! Oh, my
God! This baby's crack.
- She's a crack baby.
- You shouldn't call her that.
Torres, you're in luck.
Motorcycle crash, 20 minutes out.
Yes. OK. Oh, I love you,
but Mommy's gotta go to work.
- Take her, Mark.
- Give me the baby.
- Physically lift her
from my arms.
- OK.
- Oh, hi... No!
- No, it's not
that big of a deal.
- OK, I'll be right... OK.
- Back.
Lebo's bowel looks clean.
We got all the adhesions.
- How's the baby?
- Good. APGAR scores nine and
ten. How's she doing?
We got the bleeding under control and
removed the placenta. We're about to close.
- She's gonna be just fine.
- For now.
She's gonna go back there, she won't
get the follow-up care that she needs.
Once she and her sister run out of
the sickle cell meds we gave them,
- then what are they gonna do?
- The best they can.
What about the kid? He's
probably a sickler, too.
- Who's gonna give him
his vaccination?
- How about you, Karev?
- What?
- You.
Go there. Go back with them.
The job at Namboze
Clinic has never been filled.
They're looking for
someone who's single,
unattached, with minimum
three years residency.
There's a med school loan
forgiveness grant attached to it.
They've been coordinating with you,
they know you. You're kind of perfect.
Well, it's pretty far to
go for a follow-up exam.
You'd be great. I could
take care of it with one call.
You just think about it.
Sir.
Avery, that chart over there,
Henry Burton, needs to be screened.
If he meets the criteria,
put him in line for phase one.
Chief, I... I'm sorry. I need
to step away from the trial.
- You what?
- I appreciate the opportunity. I do.
I don't want to inconvenience
you going forward.
I'm not worried about me. You're a
big part of getting this thing where it is.
I don't know why
you want to give it up.
That's very nice
of you to say, sir,
but I feel like I need to
focus on surgery right now.
- You're sure about this?
- Respectfully, yes.
I am.
Thank you, sir.
Excellent work, Dr. Karev.
- Grey, just give me two
seconds.
- OK.
No. I didn't say anything.
But maybe you should if
you're so worried about it,
- before somebody finds out.
- No one is going to.
- Grey? Ready?
- Yeah.
OK, there it is.
Doesn't look like a
tumor. It looks like...
Wait... What is that?
I'm gonna come at it from a
different angle. There, that's better.
I just need to
get a little closer.
Oh, my God! Wait, is that...?
- Is that...?
- Is it?
Yes.
- Should we call Dr. Altman?
- No.
No.
Merry Christmas.
You don't have a tumor,
you have a tree
growing in your lung.
- My husband has a what?
- A tree.
You could have inhaled a
seedling, and somehow it took root
- and started growing in there.
- We were, um,
trimming our trees
a couple of months ago, and
stuff was flying around, but...
Whoa. How can it grow?
There's no light, there's no soil.
It happens. Somehow,
it just adapted.
- So my dad doesn't have cancer?
- No. He doesn't.
But he'll need a little
surgery, and then he'll be fine.
Dr. Yang, can I please
see you in the hall?
- My dad doesn't have cancer.
- That's great!
To be clear, I never
said he had cancer.
- You were wrong! You're a bad doctor!
- Shh. Hey...
Dr. Yang? One minute, please?
I'll be back.
- You falsified his checklist!
- I streamlined it.
- And I found a tree
in his lung.
- You never paged Dr. Altman.
- You just hijacked this
patient.
- A tree, April. A conifer.
That's...
- Well, that's...
- Mm-hm.
Well, did you... Did
you tell Dr. Altman?
No. I found it, he's my patient.
And I'm gonna take it out myself.
- You're what?
- It's a biopsy.
- A glorified lung biopsy.
- Otherwise known
as a thoracotomy,
which is a procedure
that needs to be
- supervised by an attending.
- One little breach in protocol
won't...
So you do admit it was
a breach of protocol!
April, if you do this with me, I will
put in a good word for you with Owen.
- Why would you do that?
- 'Cause it's a tree
in a man's lung.
I got your CT and
bloodwork, reviewed your files.
- Yes, and...?
- And, it looks like, medically,
you're a candidate. But, uh, I
still have some reservations.
- Dr. Webber.
- Andrew Perkins?
This is a surprise. Hope
you're not here on business.
Actually, I have a lunch
date with Dr. Altman.
Hey.
- Hey.
Andrew, this is my friend,
who I told you about.
- Oh, the VHL guy with diabetes.
- Among other things, yes. Henry Burton.
- Sorry. I didn't mean...
- No, it's fine. I am Teddy's friend.
The VHL guy with diabetes.
But hopefully not for long.
Henry's gonna be on my clinical trial.
That's great. You
didn't tell me that.
Well, I don't
like to brag, so...
- So should we get to lunch?
- Yeah, sure.
- Congratulations.
- Thanks.
I'm in? What about
your reservations?
You're going against
Andrew Perkins.
Let's just say... I have
a thing for the underdog.
- He is a handsome man.
- He's also one of the world's
foremost trauma counselors.
If there was an
earthquake, a plane crash,
any kind of catastrophe,
he swoops in and helps.
So you're saying he's a
professional knight in shining armor?
I'm saying you need
all the help you can get.
Thanks.
How long of a commitment
would you need?
OK. No, I understand.
Yeah, I just wanted a few days.
Yeah. I will. You, too.
- How's she doing?
- Was that...?
Were you just talking
to the Namboze Clinic?
Yeah, yeah. I just wanted
to get some more specifics.
- So you're gonna go?
- I don't know.
I mean, I'd get to do incredible
surgeries right there in the trenches.
Plus, I'd be the boss. After
bringing all these kids over here,
I can't imagine going back
to just being a resident.
Being chief resident could be cool. I
mean, that would be a reason to stay,
but, I mean, who knows? If I don't
get it, where does that leave me?
I'm left here with nothing.
What do you think? Stay or go?
At this point, I really don't
think it matters what I think.
Hey. What are you doing?
Getting ready to remove
a tree from a guy's lung.
No time for mommy prep.
OK, what if the social worker wants
to ask me about the time I spent
- sleeping around Europe?
- That's easy.
You were absorbing
other cultures.
OK, and what about the fact that my
mother had early on-set Alzheimer's,
and may have passed
the gene on to me?
Makes you more
appreciative of the gift of life.
OK, I put my hand on a bomb in
a body. She could think that was...
- Suicidal? No, it was brave.
- I told a shooter to shoot me.
Change the subject.
- Chicks suck.
- What's your problem?
- Like you'd care.
- I don't.
But I've got four floors to
kill, and I'm on a hot streak.
Arizona offered me this
job at her old clinic in Africa.
When I told Lucy I was thinking about
it, she got all pissed and stormed off.
Well, did you ask her to come
with you? Tell her you'd miss her?
- Look deeply into her eyes?
- No.
Well, obviously, she's got
feelings for you. You're dead inside.
You have no feelings.
By the way, you should
take that job in Africa.
It'd be totally amazing.
You just want me out of
the running for chief resident.
Just trying to help!
- Can I ask you a question?
- Bring it.
OK. What is it about guys with
babies that makes women go crazy?
I mean, it's like when you're at the
park and you see a guy with a puppy.
Normally, you wouldn't
even notice the guy.
But then he's laughing and
the puppy's crawling all over him,
and then he's tickling the puppy's
little puppy belly, and you're thinking,
"I wouldn't mind spending the rest
of my life with that guy." What is that?
Everybody's looking at the
baby, and no one's looking at Mark.
Except you.
- Oh, Kepner!
- Cristina.
- Did you book the OR?
- I did.
Yes! Kepner, you know what? I
think I figured out something about you.
I have not had sex
for, like, three days.
And I think it's giving
me superpowers.
Everything is bright and clear,
I am solving problems. No
wonder you're so organized,
- you have virgin superpowers.
- I don't think...
Seriously, thank you. I've been
shut out of cardio for months.
And today is like the first
day I've felt like myself.
Thank you, I really needed this.
- Oh, my God.
- What?
- You're just, like,
treating me like a friend.
- Yeah. So?
I'll go in and excise the tree with
minimal invasion to your lungs.
- Dr. Yang.
- Join us, please.
Sorry. I needed this, too.
I don't understand, why isn't
Dr. Yang doing the surgery?
She's certainly capable, but
Dr. Altman is our chief of cardio.
I have experience with
complex cases like yours.
OK, see, I saw three doctors for
this cough before I came here today.
They all said the same
thing: It'll go away, be patient.
Then I wake up this morning
and I'm coughing up blood.
And then this one over
here tells me it's cancer.
Come on, that
is not what I said!
Then, finally, I
meet Dr. Yang here,
and she says it's not a cough and
it's not cancer, but a tree in my lung!
And, just like that,
I'm not gonna die.
I'm gonna be fine.
So if she can do the surgery,
I'd like to stick with her.
All right. Here is a scenario
for you: You're chief resident.
One of your colleagues comes to
you and says that he's dropping out
of a clinical trial.
What do you say?
- Dr. Hunt...
- What do you tell him?
I'd urge him to think
it through carefully.
But I would
respect his decision.
My opinion is that
you have a history
of quitting when things get tough, of
walking away when you are challenged.
Now, maybe it's because you're
not used to working hard for things,
or maybe because you have a
fear of success, but I'm telling you,
you're making a
big mistake here.
I hear you.
I just disagree. Anything else?
- No.
- Thank you.
You're actually
considering this?
Look, just answer the question.
- Can she perform the surgery?
- Yes. She can.
- She is capable.
- In my defense,
I was simply streamlining the
process, and took the initiative...
Cut the crap! You went
behind my back to spite me.
- Well, you gave me no choice.
- OK, enough!
You obviously
have axes to grind,
and I'm not gonna stand
here while you sort it out.
In the meantime, this
patient needs surgery,
he's more comfortable
with Yang doing it.
She should be suspended
for insubordination,
but you're gonna
reward her instead?
I'll decide disciplinary
actions, Dr. Altman,
and I will take them out on Dr. Yang,
not on the patient. You will observe.
Yes, sir.
- Kepner, you'll assist.
- Sir, under the
circumstances...
The decision's been made.
I'll make sure Dr. Hunt considers
this in his evaluation for chief resident.
Let's get him prepped.
If it's a sliding hernia,
she could ligate her ovary.
Look, she's freeing the hernia sac
to make sure that doesn't happen.
Is she preparing to
do a Goldstein test?
Is she thinking about
exploring the other side?
Arizona is just being thorough.
Don't worry, everything's gonna be fine.
I wish you would stop saying
that. You don't know that.
- Saying what?
- Everything's gonna be fine.
She's got a hernia,
hydrocephalus, spina bifida.
Anything could happen. Her bowel
could rupture, her BP could drop out...
Robbins is not
gonna let that happen.
What if they find
better parents for her?
- Oh, come on.
- What if they realize
that we rushed into this without
really knowing what we're doing?
Or that maybe a resident
who works 80 hours a week
isn't the best
candidate for a mom?
So just please stop saying
everything's gonna be OK.
Because you don't know that.
OK.
Everything... is gonna go...
- the way it goes.
- Thank you.
Mm-hm.
Please don't.
This is the only
place she'll fall asleep.
Turns out she's as bored
with radiology as we are.
- I'll get out of your way.
- No, no, no, you stay.
Besides, I... haven't
really seen her up close yet.
She's so much bigger
than the last time I saw her.
Eats like a champ.
- You wanna hold her?
- Oh, no, no, it's OK.
Come on, look at that
face. You know you want to.
No, it's OK. Yeah, I'll just wake
her and she'll cry and you'll hate me.
Besides, she doesn't look
like she really wants to move.
I should go.
I...
I am really happy for you.
- You seem happy.
- I am.
I have everything
I always wanted.
Almost.
I have it. I have it.
Can I get some more
suction down here, please?
- Look at that.
- I can't believe it lived in there.
It managed to thrive in
a hostile environment.
- I'm gonna keep it.
- What? No.
No, no, it has to go to
Path and then get destroyed.
It's not cancer. It's
a Christmas tree.
It a pathology
specimen. Protocol...
Protocol doesn't account
for trees in people!
Protocol accounts for
whatever comes up!
That's why we have protocol!
So there are rules and
steps that we can depend on.
Look, I know the rules seem fussy
and annoying, and people hate them,
and the people who enforce
them are fussy and annoying, too.
- But they're there
for a reason...
- Fine!
- Take it to Path.
- Thank you. I think you'll...
It's not gonna be you, April.
I don't care how
many boxes you check,
you're not gonna
be chief resident.
Three-O Vicryl.
I... gave Lebo platelets.
And the baby's stable. A
little smushed, but stable.
It's hard to believe he spent the
last eight months sleeping on a colon.
Nice work.
So you gonna do it? Africa?
Honestly, I'm not sure.
It's a big decision
to make in a day.
Are you in love
with Lucy Fields?
Lucy and I... It's new.
Why?
Because I don't want the person
that I recommend to pull a me
and go running back to
the girl they left behind.
So just... make sure you
know what you're doing.
Or else you'll have
me to answer to.
Admit it.
You saw how good this baby looked on
me so you had to go get one of your own.
Everything's a competition.
- How'd her surgery go?
- Robbins said she's fine.
- She's feeding again.
- Good.
Because Sofia can't wait to have
a new friend. Isn't that right, Sofia?
You and Zola are gonna be
best friends, isn't that right?
Oh, you just wait. This crap will
be coming out of your mouth, too.
Well, let's hope so.
We're dealing with the
international adoption treaties.
And the waiver we
need, they just don't...
usually give those things out.
You're both surgeons.
You'd make good parents.
They're gonna see that.
We'd be naive to get
ahead of ourselves.
You're Derek Shepherd. There's a reason
I've been jealous of you my whole life,
and it's not your hair.
You're gonna be OK.
Even Sofia knows that. Right,
Sofia? Say hi to Uncle Derek.
That's Zola's daddy.
Yes, he is. Right?
Ohh.
- I'm gonna go feed her.
- Mm.
So I see here that your mother
was a surgeon. What was that like?
Well, being raised by a surgeon,
you definitely get to
be very independent.
And... not that I would raise Zola
the way that my mother raised me.
She didn't bake.
She wasn't a bake-sale mom,
and I... plan on baking all the time.
How about you
tell me about Zola?
Well, Zola had already had a
shunt and spina bifida surgery,
and then we realized
she had this hernia.
And today in her surgery, it
looked like she might go into SVT.
And just as the anesthesiologist
was about to push the adenosine,
it's like she knew to stop,
and her heart just slowed down
all by itself and she went into sinus.
I... I'm sorry. That's not
what you asked me, right?
You want me talk about
how cute and sweet she is.
And she is very cute and sweet.
And... I'm not doing
very well, am I?
I don't have an
agenda here, Dr. Grey.
I'm just trying to get a
sense of who you are.
I'm a surgeon.
And I'm a good surgeon.
And I want to be a good mother.
Honestly, I don't know much about it.
But I am ready to learn.
And I'm a fast learner,
and I will do whatever it
takes to be a good mom.
You know what good moms do?
They brag about their babies,
and that's what I heard today.
As it turns out, Zola's day didn't
involve playgroup or baby gym class.
It involved surgery. And you
knew where she was every second.
I appreciate you
sharing that with me.
I was showing initiative!
That doesn't mean you get to
pretend that you're an attending!
I wasn't pretending, I just
didn't need an attending.
- Oh, my God!
- Teddy is doing
a disservice to me,
and to the education
that I deserve.
I had no choice but to take
my learning into my own hands.
So I took the initiative
and treated a patient
and followed through
to a successful outcome.
If that doesn't show the qualities of a
chief resident, I don't know what does.
You're not gonna
be the chief resident.
It's not gonna
be you. I'm sorry.
Is this from the
chief, or from Teddy?
No, it's from me.
You real... You know
how important this is.
Chief resident can make your career.
You have your pick of fellowships...
You never had
the qualifications.
- Based on what?!
- Chief resident is more
than just a resume boost. It's
managing schedules, overseeing interns,
pushing papers, working
within the system. That isn't you.
- It's never been you.
- I'm protesting this!
- You are screwing
with my career.
- And it will kill you!
You're a surgeon.
Anything that keeps you from
being a surgeon will hurt you,
and it will make you
crazy. We saw it today.
You're not built for this job.
You will hate it and
you will resent it,
you will fight against it until
you fail. So just be a surgeon.
You know, it's what you are.
Just be excellent
at what you are.
- Are you done?
- Yes.
Thank you for your time.
I'm not going to Africa.
- Right. Let me just say this...
- No. It's the right thing.
I can finish my residency and then
maybe we can both go to Africa together...
- Alex, I just... Just listen to me.
- You were right this morning.
You said there were other factors
to consider. And you are a factor.
I'm sorry I didn't
say that sooner.
When Robbins said they were
looking for someone single...
I mean, that's how I think of myself.
Because whenever I think of a future
with someone I always get kicked in
the teeth. So I stopped even looking.
- But now, with you...
- Alex, stop! OK, just stop.
You were right, this morning.
Career comes first.
It's how it should be.
And so I... I took the job.
- So call them. Call Baylor...
- At Namboze.
I took the job at
Namboze Clinic.
You what? My job?
You took my job?
Like you said,
it's not personal.
Sometimes you
have to be a shark.
My job in Africa? The bitch
stole it out from under me.
- Who?
- Lucy. I told her I'd stay.
You open yourself up to someone
- for one freaking second...
- Mm-hmm.
Callaghan, I'll take
a double whiskey.
I freakin' better
get chief resident.
Here you go.
Scotch, please.
You know, the rules
are there for a reason.
- Oh, boy.
- I killed a woman
when I first started
here. I got fired for it.
Because I missed a little
step. One simple step.
We follow the protocols,
we don't skip steps.
People live, simple as that.
You know, you're right, I
probably won't be chief resident,
but the checklists work.
You can't tell me they don't.
Dropping out of the chief's trial
was a real bonehead move, Avery.
- Sir...
- Such a bonehead move,
that I started thinking,
maybe the chief's
trial is flawed.
So I looked into it myself.
The methodology is flawless.
In fact, it's kind of the
stuff that wins awards.
Big awards. Like
the Harper Avery.
You dropped out of the chief's
trial because you knew that
if your name was on it, it
would ruin the chief's chances.
I respect that you don't want
to succeed on your name,
but don't you ever
let it hold you back.
There you are.
- Hey. Everything OK?
- Completely.
I wanted you to be the first to
hear just how OK everything is.
- I got my old job back.
- You're kidding.
Mm-mm. I told them about Webber's
trial, that I'm getting a new pancreas.
I've never used a
pancreas as a selling point
in a job interview
before, but it did the trick.
Which means that I'm gonna have
my own insurance in a couple of months.
- That's really good news.
- I'm glad you think so.
Because I've been thinking about us and
our situation and where we go from here,
- and I wanted to ask you...
- Teddy!
Yeah, I will be
right there, Andrew.
Lunch and dinner. The
man's getting serious.
Dinner's to celebrate
what we decided at lunch.
I'm going to Germany with him.
Oh.
Well, that's... That's
really good news, too.
It is.
- Right?
- Yeah.
Because, like I said,
I'm gonna be fine.
Which brings me back to the
question that I wanted to ask you.
What's that?
May I please have a divorce?
Oh.
Yeah, I guess. Sure.
I mean...
you don't need
me anymore, right?
Right.
- I gotta go.
- Yeah.
Yeah. OK.
Adapt or die.
As many times as we've heard
it, the lesson doesn't get easier.
I fed her, I changed her diaper.
Prettiest poop you ever saw.
- Hi, baby girl.
- Oh! I've missed you.
Yes, Mommy got to be
a surgeon again today.
I got to fix two dislocated shoulders,
and save a leg from amputation.
Problem is... we're human.
We want more
than just to survive.
- Were you staring
at Sloan again?
- Oh!
The... The baby.
Did you see her?
- How did the interview go?
- I'm out.
- What? What happened?
- It's a long story. It's fine.
Seriously, I'm OK with it.
I have you, what else do I need?
We want love.
Hey.
Hi.
Hi, Zola.
I'm Meredith.
I'm hoping to be your mama.
We want success.
You know it's
gonna be Mer, right?
It doesn't mean that you're a
bad surgeon or a bad doctor.
Some people just
don't fit the bill.
They're better at other things. Like
you and those kids, you're good at that.
But between you and
Mer? She's organized.
People like her, people
trust her, she's a natural.
- People trust her.
- I'm just saying,
go steal your job
back. Go to Africa.
That's what you're good at.
Go do what you're good at.
We want to be the
best that we can be.
OK, I know you're mad, but you
can't just sit here and drink all night.
So I'm gonna take you home...
I... I was not expecting that.
You told me to be excellent.
So I'm gonna be.
I'm gonna be an
excellent surgeon.
And I'm gonna be
excellent in bed tonight.
So we fight like hell
to get those things.
All right, Karev?
Meredith messed with
the Alzheimer's trial.
Anything else feels...
like death.