The first 24 hours
after surgery are critical.
Every breath you take,
every fluid you make
is meticulously
recorded and analyzed,
celebrated or mourned.
But what about
the next 24 hours?
So you and Cristina are going
fishing? Whose idea was that?
Owen's concerned about
leaving Cristina alone,
so when I told him I
was going fishing...
Right. But you haven't
actually spoken to Cristina?
- Actually, I have.
- You spoke to her? When?
I called her last night.
She must've been drunk or something
because she doesn't do the wilderness.
I mean, there aren't even any
bathrooms in the wilderness.
Look, I know you're concerned
about her, but I also know that there's
nothing else we
can do right now.
- But you can?
- Mm.
Because if fishing is your big
plan to get her back to work...
We're not trying to get her back to
work. We want to make sure she's OK.
Well, she's not OK and she's not going
to be OK until she gets back to work.
- I know Cristina. She needs to work.
- Meredith...
Well, I mean, she's
not gonna show today.
I mean, she may have
agreed to it last night,
but in the cold hard light
of day, there's no way...
What happens when
that first day turns to two,
- and weeks turn into months?
- You wanna do it? Real quick?
Nothing says good
morning like shower sex.
I hope you don't take this the wrong way
because the sex with you has been great,
but... it just... It just
makes me miss Arizona.
Sex with you just makes me sad.
- Oh, no, that
came out wrong. Sorry.
- No, I get it.
- Yeah?
- Last night,
when we were doing it,
I was thinking about Lexie...
You were thinking about Lexie?
I'm gonna need some
more consonants.
When we were having sex,
you were thinking about Lexie?
- OK, now, that's just rude!
- You just said
having sex with me
- makes you sad.
- 'Cause I'm amazing!
I know! That's why I
suggested the wake up call.
Get out. Seriously, get out!
- Now, I'm missing
Lexie even more.
- What was that?
- Nothing.
- I am amazing!
- Um, let me
give you a hand with that.
- Thanks.
- Hey.
- Bye.
Thank you.
What happens when the
immediate danger has passed?
When the machines
are disconnected
and the teams of doctors
and nurses are gone?
- Well, I should go.
- Cristina!
There are no bathrooms...
out there, you know.
I know.
Surgery is when you get saved,
but post-op, after surgery, -
is when you heal.
But what if you don't?
You're removing a gallbladder
from someone's mouth. I mean,
no incision, no scar, it's
like you were never there.
- Sorry, I'll stop talking.
- You want to do one of these?
- Is that a trick question?
- The trick is
how bad do you want it?
Um... When I was
little, I wanted a pony.
Like, really, really
wanted a pony.
This feels a
little bit like that.
Good. 'Cause I'm
having a contest.
Grabbing the gallbladder.
Each of you is researching
a different protocol aimed
at trying to eliminate fistulas.
But it's taking too long,
so this is the incentive:
The person whose
protocol leads to the fewest
number of post-operative
complication,
gets to pull a gallbladder
out of a mouth.
There she is. Beautiful.
- All righty.
- May I be excused?
I am checking on my patients
every two hours and it's time.
Go ahead.
- Uh, may I be excused, please?
- Uh, me, too.
Go.
Mm.
- You're a mad genius.
- If I was a genius,
I'd have rid the world
of fistulas by now.
- Morning.
- How's Cristina?
- She's fine.
- She's fishing.
- She's fishing?
- Why?
- Ask him.
- Have you got any better ideas?
- No.
No. See ya.
How do I look?
I'm about to propose to my
girlfriend. So besides the gown
and the IV and
the ghostly pallor
from being in the
hospital for the past week,
what do you think?
Do I have a shot?
She'd be a fool to say no.
Good luck!
Hey, can either of you use me
today? I was supposed to be with Stark,
but he wants to work
with someone else.
- Ouch.
- Guy's an ass.
- Maybe heartlessness
is a Peds thing.
- No offense,
but your girlfriend leaving
town really screwed me.
I'm happy for
children of Malawi...
No, you should be
worried for them.
She's making them
fall in love with her.
"Oh, I'll uncleft your palate,
I'll unherniate your hernia.
I'm here for you, I'm yours."
Then someplace better will come along,
Peru or India, and suddenly she's all,
"I know I was helping you
and I made you all kinds
- of promises..."
- "But I gotta go."
"Have fun with Stark."
- Hi.
- I miss you.
- Mark.
What, are you saying
you don't miss me?
Pretty much what I'm saying.
- You seeing someone?
- Yes.
His name is Andrew Rabb.
He had a tumor removed from
his pancreas three days ago
and I'm trying to make sure
he doesn't develop a fistula.
Go. Cure fistulas. Or fistulae?
Fistulas.
I miss you!
Two minutes out.
So, uh... you ever
go fishing with Derek?
I'm a surgical resident. When
would I have time for that?
- You get a day off
now and then.
- I spend my days off here,
- where she should be.
- Meredith...
What are your plans for her tomorrow?
Bowling with Bailey? Cooking class?
Not sure. But...
bowling with Bailey,
that sounds fun.
Trina Paiz, 27, stable. Only
complaint is a lacerated ear.
Pretty amazing considering she
fell a hundred feet into a ravine.
Apparently, her
husband broke her fall.
Jason Paiz, 27.
- Jason! Is he OK?
- Grey,
take her to Trauma Two.
Please be OK. Please be OK.
OK, Trina, do you
know where you are?
A hospital in Seattle. I...
I don't know the name, I'm not from
here. I'm here on my honeymoon.
- Oh, my God, my husband!
- Dr. Hunt is excellent,
so he's in good hands. Do
you remember what happened?
We were hiking up this
mountain and we wanted a picture,
so we handed our camera
to some guy and we posed,
we kissed. No, we were kissing.
And then the next thing I
know I'm looking up at the sky,
and then we're on the ground,
or Jason's on the ground
and I'm on top of him and...
Please tell me he's not
gonna die. He can't die.
- His wife is stable. Nervous, but...
- She should be.
His abdomen is distended and
he has a lot of internal bleeding.
Systolic's 60, Dr. Hunt.
Pressure's dropping.
- Let's get him to an OR now. Quickly!
- Watch that line.
Grey, no time to scrub.
Come on. Gown me.
On three. One, two, three.
See if his type and
cross is back yet.
In the meantime, get me some
FFP and Factor VII up here!
Drape him.
Good.
- OK. Let's go. Ten blade.
- Ten blade.
- I hope no one is wearing new shoes.
- - More laps.
Laps! Laps!
- Grey, I can't see anything.
- - I'm suctioning.
Suction's too slow, use
your hands. Another suction.
- How's his pressure?
- Seventy-nine over 40.
Ugh! He's like a
bucket full of holes.
I'm gonna occlude
the aorta at the hiatus,
see if we can get his pressure back
up. How many units has he gotten?
Three units of O neg, one
unit A positive type specific
- and one unit of FFP.
- Let's get some
more packs in there.
Try and isolate this bleeder until
we figure out what we're dealing with.
Laps. More. Keep
'em coming. More.
More. Quickly! Faster! I don't
wanna have to keep asking!
- Can I make a suggestion?
- - Yeah.
If you mount the rod-holders
midship, we can both reach the rods
from either end of the boat.
After you called last
night, I did some research.
I didn't want to be anything
less than seaworthy.
- It's a lake.
- Still.
Uh, actually, it's,
uh... it's a great idea.
You may need clip-on
mounts to clear the gunwales.
Are you gonna
be like this all day?
I can't help it.
I've tried to avoid getting a new
hip because I just didn't want to deal
- with the recovery, but...
- There's no cartilage left,
- bone spurs...
- Our daughter's an orthodontist
- in Sarasota.
- Hm!
- Sheila.
- What?
They should know that we
have medical people in the family.
- We're not nobodies
off the street.
- Mr. Cherkovsky,
clearly you need a new hip.
Now, I've had a lot of success
with a new minimally
invasive technique. Dr. Karev?
Well, she would use computer
guidance to avoid any excess radiation
and she'd make a small
incision along the muscle
so we would avoid
damaging the hip muscle.
Now, I can fit you in this afternoon at
2pm and have you walking out of here
- by the end of the week.
- Why does she have an opening?
- Why isn't she busier?
- What my wife wants to know...
I heard her. I'm... I'm
standing right here.
Um, actually, I'm just
coming off of some leave,
and so my schedule is flexible.
But, uh, I'm the only
surgeon in the Northwest
doing minimally invasive
hip replacements.
Ask her why no one else
is doing it if it's so great.
Because they can't and she can.
Tell them you want
a second opinion.
- Sheila.
- No, no, no. You know what?
Actually, your wife's right. It's always
a good idea to get another opinion.
Call Dan Miller and see if he
can squeeze them in right now.
Maybe I should mention that
their daughter's an orthodontist.
They're gonna meet with Miller,
hear about his six-week recovery period
and come running back.
Keep my 2pm slot open.
We're gonna be
replacing Ron's hip.
- Hey! Morning, Eli.
- Hey.
Um, did you send Mr. Rabb's
sample of pancreatic fluid to the lab yet?
- Not yet.
- Uh, I asked
for it over an hour ago.
Yeah, I was letting him rest.
He didn't sleep much last night.
Dr. Grey. Check out Mrs. Kay.
Day three post-op, no fistula.
Already walking right
away, eating right away.
- Isn't that right, Mrs. Kay?
- Can I go back to bed now? I'm tired.
One more lap.
- April.
- OK, there's no
evidence that shows
that getting patients up faster
makes any difference at all.
How's it going with your
protocol? Looks like you... Oh! Hey.
Added just another medicine
to your drug regimen there, huh?
Yeah, I mean, if you call
octreotide just another medicine.
So you're still, uh,
sticking with the little list?
Yeah. Standard post-op protocol
with a checklist I've
developed for accountability.
Oh, my gosh! So, you know what?
When I was little, I wanted a pony, too.
And you know what happened?
I, uh... I worked really
hard, and I got one.
Mr. Rabb probably can't sleep
at night because you're letting him
sleep during the day.
Get the fluid sample now.
Hey. How'd it go?
- Hey, uh, not so well.
- Oh.
- I'm sorry.
- No, I don't blame her.
I was proposing for
all the wrong reasons.
I mean, I liked her and all,
but what I liked most
about her was her PPO.
- You don't have insurance?
- Capped out about
three operations ago.
I've been charging
it on my credit cards.
- You mind if I look
at your chart?
- No, go ahead.
I'm warning you, though, it's
pretty scary stuff. Just saying.
Wow. Um...
You have Von
Hippel-Lindau disease.
And you have been hospitalized
for over 200 days in the last...
- three years.
- Lotta good memories.
Dr. Webber's your surgeon?
Not for long. They're
discharging me today.
You have a pretty dangerous
tumor on your adrenal gland.
They're not gonna just
throw you out on the street.
Let me see what I can do.
I don't know how
much your fee is, uh,
but I know I can't afford it.
I heard you just got married.
How'd you meet your husband?
Uh, we worked together. There
was a no-dating policy at our firm.
- Oh, my God.
- You're doing great. Keep talking.
He kept asking me out,
and he's just like that.
You tell him he can't do something,
it just makes him want to do it more.
- Sounds like my kinda guy.
- And then there was this
work bowling party, and...
we were both waiting in
line to return our shoes,
and he just kissed me.
And then I was like, OK,
I need to find a new job,
because he was a
really good kisser.
Is.
He is a really good kisser.
His BP is still 70.
With all these lap pads it
should be better by now.
His pelvis and his spleen
look clean. It has to be his liver.
Try a Pringle maneuver, and
see if you can stop this bleeding.
- OK.
Damn it. That's what I was
afraid of. His vena cava is torn.
You can let go.
Dr. Hunt, what are we doing?
- This is a lethal injury.
- He's on his honeymoon!
Pressure's still
dropping, 60 over 40.
Dr. Hunt? What do we do?
Dr. Hunt.
Dr. Hunt, what's your plan?!
You have to have a plan! We
can't stand here and do nothing
while this guy bleeds out!
If you don't have a plan...
OK, ten blade. It's a long
shot, but if we crack his chest,
put in a shunt, bypass the blood
flow trying to get to the heart...
will give us time
to make the repair.
You don't get to talk to
me like that in my OR.
If you can't keep your problems, our
problems outside, then you should go.
Bone saw.
What is this?
Wait, don't tell me.
Crankbait, best
used in muddy water.
I know. Quiz me.
Is this a... spinnerbait?
You know, the fish can hear you.
Did you read about
that in your research?
Fishing is supposed to be quiet.
Is this a spinnerbait?
I'm not quizzing
you. I'm fishing.
You're no fun.
Maybe we should move the boat
over to the other side of the lake.
No.
This is a good spot.
For tanning maybe.
Is this typical? I mean, to
go for hours without a bite?
The only thing predictable about
fishing is that it's unpredictable.
Wow. That's deep.
Yeah, why don't you
ponder that for a while.
Quietly.
OK, I pondered it,
but the thing is, I don't
agree with the basic premise.
Assuming a lake has fish
in it, which this lake does,
and assuming that you're using the
right baits and lures, which we are,
you should be able to predict
getting more bites than, um,
- like, none an hour.
- You know...
Which leads me to believe
that the fish are elsewhere, like...
Like over there or
over there or over there.
And if we were over there,
you would scare them away
with your incessant chatter.
Fishing is supposed to be quiet.
And it's supposed to involve
catching fish, which we could do
if we moved the boat to where
the fish are... are sleeping...
Just stop! Stop talking,
stop worrying,
stop thinking. Stop.
Can we... Can we just...?
Can we just try it my way?
No!
I can't stop.
I can't turn my mind off.
Yes, you can.
- But...
- But you can.
Just fish.
- Do it pro bono.
- Henry needs long-term medical care
and the hospital just
can't afford to take that on.
- So we do nothing?
- No, we treat him with drugs
and we schedule regular
follow-ups at the clinic.
- You might as well do nothing.
- Look, I wish
I could treat him.
- I really do. But my hands are tied.
- That is a load of crap.
I have seen you bend the rules
around here. If I was Bailey or Shepherd,
I'm sure that your
hands wouldn't be so tied.
- Dr. Altman, that's enough.
- I'm sorry.
Cristina Yang is fishing today.
She is one of the most talented
surgical residents I have ever seen,
and she is fishing instead of
operating, and that is partly my fault.
I just want to do
something good today.
Make it up, pay it forward,
whatever you want to call it.
I... I just need
to do some good.
I'll set up a meeting
with the review board.
Thank you.
Look, they met with
Dr. Miller three hours ago.
- Give it time.
- They're not gonna call
- 'cause they're idiots.
- Hey, where are you going?
Going up to Miller's office to
tell him what idiots they are.
No, they're gonna call.
Now, you're just being stubborn.
Yes, I am being stubborn.
I'm stubbornly choosing to believe that
sometimes people make sane decisions
like having minimally invasive
surgery when it's available.
I am stubbornly choosing to believe
that not all people are evil and bad
and leave me in airports.
Hm!
Told ya.
Good, shunt is in.
Secure it inferiorly.
- Umbilical tape.
- Here you go, doctor.
Now, we're gonna fix the IVC.
I'm gonna lift the liver only enough
for you to gain access to the tear.
- You're gonna let me sew?
- Are you questioning
my judgment
- or are you saying thank you?
- No, I just...
- Thank you.
- Good.
So, one stitch at a time.
Slow and steady. Ready?
OK. 3-0 Prolene.
Mm... Anybody want my soup?
It's reminding me of pancreatic fluid.
- Mm-hm. Then I
definitely want it.
- Sparkle.
That was the name of my pony.
Dr. Kepner? Your patient, Mrs.
Hathaway, just came into the ER.
She's in septic shock.
CT showed a fistula.
- Dr. Bailey wants you in OR 2.
- Mrs. Hathaway?
We just discharged her
three days ago, she was fine!
And then there were two.
Um...
Eli, I need another
sample of Mr. Rabb's fluid.
Uh, that's gonna be
tough. I took the drain out.
- You what?
- With the drain in,
he can't turn over,
which means he has to sleep on his
back, which means he isn't sleeping.
OK, just call Radiology.
We have to put it back in.
I need to be able to see the
fluid to tell if there's an infection.
I can tell by looking at
it that it's not infected.
- Call Radiology.
- If Dr. Bailey
wants it put back in,
- then I will...
- No, she's in surgery.
- Well, then it'll have to wait.
- Fine, I'll do it myself.
- You're not
touching that patient.
- Excuse me?
You have your list, but I have 12
years of experience that tells me
that putting that drain back in
could actually put him at more risk
for infection. Twelve years
I've been here. Twelve years.
You residents come and go, but
this is my home and you are my guest.
And right now, you
are no longer welcome.
- What's the emergency?
- Oh, uh, I need a favor.
A nurse hates me.
You're a resident. I'm
sure all the nurses hate you.
- Yes, well, they love you.
- I think you love me.
Fine. OK. Whatever. Can
you please just talk to him?
Smooth things over so that when I
go to take my patient back to Radiology
and get his drain put back
in, he doesn't make a scene.
Fine. I'll talk to him.
But you gotta meet me
at Joe's tonight for a drink.
- You are unbelievable!
- That's why you love me.
- 'Cause I'm unbelievable.
- You and I, we don't work.
- OK? We've been through this.
- One drink.
Fine. One drink.
Oh! OK, there he is.
- Eli?
- Uh...
Two drinks.
- Fine!
- Fine. Stay here.
- Eli! You got a second?
- Yeah.
Listen, I don't know what's going
on here, but I know better than
to mess with you on your
turf, so do me a solid, nod
and act as if we're
having a big debate here,
'cause Dr. Grey over there,
she agreed to go out
with me if I talk to you.
- She's bossy.
- I know. I dig it.
Hm. What's in it for me?
Seahawks, Sunday, box seats.
- Parking? Mm-hm.
- Of course.
OK. Unless Dr. Bailey herself
orders that drain put back in...
Now mention how
highly I think of her.
I don't care if you think Dr. Grey is
the best resident you've ever seen
- come through this program.
- I understand,
and I respect that.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
I did what I could. What
time do you get off?
What? That's it? You
didn't do anything!
See you at 9:00.
- You're going out
with Sloan tonight?
- One drink.
And then you are gonna interrupt us
and tell me there's a medical emergency.
There might be a
medical emergency
if you don't get that drain
back in your guy. I'm just saying.
I guess you can observe when
I'm taking out that gallbladder
through a dude's mouth.
Dr. Hunt, I updated Mrs.
Paiz and checked your calls.
Dr. Marshall from NYU called
about speaking at their conference,
and the lab called with
results for your kidney patient.
- That it? Nothing from my wife?
- No. That's it.
You ready? Lifting the liver.
Dr. Miller can't fit
Ron in for three weeks,
and we called our daughter in Sarasota
and she said maybe we should wait,
but Ron wants it and I
just want what Ron wants.
So, um, tell her Ron, tell
her we want this 2:00 slot.
Oh, yeah. I wish I could,
but I'm already booked.
- No, you're not.
- Yeah, I am. Yeah.
That, um... fused knee thing.
- Right, the guy with the knee.
- Yeah.
Let me see if I can, uh,
switch some things around.
I'd really appreciate it.
Oh. What if I push
that down to later?
You're getting that award
tonight, you can't miss that.
Oh! That's right. Shoot.
OK, you know what? I'll do Ron
and I'll just be late for the dinner.
I am so sick of those awards
dinners anyway. It's like...
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Eli.
- Dr. Bailey.
Have I told you lately
how much I like your eyes?
I am not in the mood. Why
did you remove the drain?
Because it was
ready to be removed.
Now, I have to put
the drain back in.
And write you up.
- You said you were
gonna write him up.
- Let me handle this, Grey.
OK, Mr. Rabb is not
sleeping. That's a problem...
I feel for him, but this
protocol isn't just about him.
I don't do protocols.
I treat patients.
Eli, save your high and
mighty routine for someone else.
Now, I'm sick of all these
post-op complications.
I hate post-op complications
more than you do, Dr. Bailey. I do.
They're time-consuming and messy
and make it difficult for me to check up
on my fantasy football
team as often as I'd like.
So I make sure that my
patients don't get them.
You know you're
happy when I'm working,
and it's not just because of my pretty
face, it's 'cause I'm good at what I do.
Think about it, when's the last
time you had a post-op complication
with one of my patients? Hm?
Good work.
I think I can get
another stitch in.
We can't risk it. There's
too much pull on the liver.
- I'm lowering it.
- I want to try it.
- No.
- There's not
as much blood in the field
as before. He can
handle another stitch.
- Remove your hand, Dr. Grey.
- Just another second.
- Don't!
- Done. I got it. Lower the liver.
- Get out of my OR.
- What? I did it.
- See, he's fine.
- I'm not gonna say it again!
No, I just got
kicked out of the OR.
Because I'm just so sick of all
this. I'm sick of her not talking to me.
I'm sick of you two
pretending to be friends.
- So put her on the phone.
- Well, thank you, Dr. Keller.
I think you did the right thing coiling
the aneurysm rather than clipping it.
Thank you for the update
and I will check in with you later.
- Was that Meredith?
- No.
Yes.
Oh, my God! Oh, my
God! I think I have a bite!
I think I got a bite! What do I
do? What do I do?! Oh, my God!
Stay calm. Sit down. Sit down.
- OK, I'm sitting down.
- All right, good.
I didn't read the part... what
to do when you catch a fish!
- Let it run.
- What does that mean?
- Just stay right there.
- OK, OK.
Let it go. Let the
fish run a little bit.
- OK, go! Go, go, go, go!
- Give it some... There it is.
- OK. Now what?
- Give it some line,
let it go. Easy.
- Let her tire herself out.
- OK.
- Reel it in.
- Reeling it in.
- OK, good, good.
- Oh, my God!
Oh, my God! I'm
fishing! I'm fishing!
- You're fishing!
- I'm fishing!
OK.
- You're good.
- - Yeah, tell that to Stark.
Stark? Please, you don't
need Stark. You know why?
In a year, everyone's
gonna want this surgery,
except there's only one of me,
unless I create another me.
That could be you.
The guy me.
Not as pretty, not
as good, but close.
I could teach you, if you want.
Screw Stark.
Stark's loss is my gain.
OK, Ron, here
comes your new hip.
Can I talk to you for a second?
- Uh, guys, give us the room.
- Yes, doctor.
I knew what I was doing. I
knew I could do that second stitch.
And you knew I could
do that second stitch.
And if it were anyone else,
you would have let them do it.
But because I questioned
how you handled Cristina,
you chose to slap me down and
let everybody know who's boss.
You want to know what I
think? I think you're reckless.
I think you're reckless
with your own life
and today you were
reckless with a patient's life.
I don't care who you are,
I don't want that in my OR,
and I do not want
that around my wife,
who is struggling
just to hold on.
Your wife is struggling
just to hold on
because you married her
and let it be OK for her
to completely fall apart.
What is Cristina gonna do when she
gets back from her fishing trip tonight?
Tomorrow, next week,
next month, next year?
Because we'll all be here
working, and Cristina will be...
- Where?
- I don't know.
I don't know. But she has
the right to figure that out.
You don't know. Well, I know.
Because I know Cristina Yang.
And she needs to work.
Because surgery is who we are.
You told a guy with a gun to
shoot you. That is who you are.
- What the hell
does that have to do...?
- You are fearless.
And I don't mean
that in a good way.
Most people don't tell the
guy with the gun to shoot them.
Most people are like Cristina!
Most people are afraid.
So, what she needs
isn't what you need.
She isn't you, Meredith.
Well, he's right. His patient
records for the past three months
show a post-op complication
rate way lower than the norm.
Twelve percent compared
to 42 percent? Wow.
OK, can you two stop being
impressed by him? It's a fluke.
- He's mean.
- Hand me those charts.
I think he's kind of hot. Can
you say that about a nurse?
- No.
- Day three.
Day... three.
- Day three!
- Yeah?
- Day three.
- Oh, oh, oh!
OK, deep, deep breaths.
Deep breaths. Ooh!
- Dr. Bailey?
- OK. OK.
OK. Should we be following her?
A medic alert bracelet?
That's your solution?
If the patient has a
hypertensive crisis...
When. When he has
a hypertensive crisis.
The paramedics will
bring Mr. Burton here,
we'll treat his
emergent condition.
That'll be too
late. He'll be dead.
So you're sending him home
to die, but you're OK with it
because you're giving him a
bracelet with his name on it.
Hey! Um, if we remove the drain
on day three instead of day five,
we can reduce the formation
of fistulas by 30 percent.
See, Eli took out a drain
when he wasn't supposed to,
and I was gonna write him up
because he can't do that but he did.
Ah! I'm going to leave
these files for you to look at.
Oh! I'm sorry.
I'm Miranda Bailey, the
doctor who cured fistula.
That's right, I said it.
Uh, Jonas Salk, he cured polio,
Miranda Bailey is
going to cure fistula.
Three! Day three!
Twenty-eight pounds!
That's one of the biggest
we've had this year.
- Look at that!
- Do you want a picture?
Oh! Definitely!
Definitely! Come on!
All right. You pick it
up, I'll get the camera.
How am I supposed to pick it up?
Just pick it up
with your gloves.
It's very slippery. Be careful.
- Oh, my God! Oh, my God! Yes!
- All ready, ready?
- Oh, my God,
it's totally heavy!
- Ready?
- Your friend's first time out?
- Yeah, first time.
- She really is something.
- Yeah, she is. She really is.
OK, smile now.
It's OK. We don't
need the picture.
Take it.
- Wait till she's...
- Take it now.
We're gonna want
to remember this.
Oh, my God!
Jason, honey.
We were able to repair the damage,
but the next 24 hours are crucial.
But he can recover, right?
If everything goes OK,
- he can fully recover?
- We're just focusing
on getting Jason
through the night.
I know it's hard,
but try not to think
too far into the future.
I'm afraid to touch him.
I know right now all you
can see are the machines
and the damage,
but he's still there.
Hey! There's my star resident.
- Come on,
we're drinking, I'm buying.
- Oh. Dude, sorry. I can't.
- Why not?
- Stark ended up hating the guy
who assisted him today
even more than he hates me.
- Oh, God...
- Anyway, there's a midgut volvulus
and I'm gonna assist.
- You're going back to Stark?
- The guy's a douche,
- and hips are cool, you know.
- Just go.
I'm still awesome.
I've prescribed alpha blockers
and set you up
in our free clinic.
You need anything
at all, call me.
- We're gonna
see you through this.
- Thank you.
Hey. Um...
- I tried. I'm sorry. I...
- I'll be OK.
Dr. Webber slipped me some free
samples, so I'm good for a while.
Good, good.
Well, good luck.
I have great medical insurance.
Way to kick a guy
when he's down.
I'm saying, I'm...
I'm saying that I'll marry you.
Uh...
That's a really generous
offer, but I can't.
I'm a doctor. I took an oath.
And I can't leave you now
any more than I could leave you
bleeding out in the street.
This is absurd.
You're aware of that?
And you're gonna regret
it deeply in the morning.
You're dying.
Henry, you're dying.
And you don't have
to, 'cause I can help.
I mean it.
I'll marry you.
I want all post-op drains
removed on day three from now on
unless I tell you otherwise.
Do you know what this
means? What you did?
- What? What?
- Uh...
I was wondering if you wanted to
go out with me sometime, Dr. Bailey?
Even that shocked, "Oh, my
God, a nurse just asked me out,
how the hell do I get out of it?"
expression you got on right now
is pretty cute.
Fine. Because you
gave me day three.
- And because I'm very handsome.
- Yeah.
I know I agreed to
have a drink with you,
but as I walked here I
realized how unfair that was.
It's unfair to you,
it's unfair to me,
because, really, nothing
has changed. I mean...
You're still in a very
different place in your life
than I am and
you want different...
The goal of any
surgery is total recovery.
To come out better
than you were before.
Some patients heal quickly
and feel immediate relief.
Lexie? I just got a page.
Bailey wants us back in the ICU.
Can you deal with it, please?
- Hey.
- Hey!
I have 21 pounds of trout.
How was it?
It was good.
For others, the healing
happens gradually,
and it's not until months
or even years later
that you realize you
don't hurt anymore.
Do you think Cristina's
gonna be OK?
Mm. Yeah. I do.
Do you think she's
gonna be a surgeon?
Honestly?
I don't know.
So the challenge after
any surgery is to be patient.
Mark, did you forget your keys?
OK, so picture this: I'm in
Africa, everything's great.
The people are so nice, and the
clinic is amazing and I'm doing work
that actually feels important,
like I can actually see
that I'm making a difference.
But I'm crying, like, constantly.
And then this guy that I work with at
the clinic finally asks me what's wrong
and I say that I miss my
girlfriend. Like, I really miss her.
So then he asks me if I want to
go back, if they could replace me,
and then I opened my mouth to say
no, but what comes out weirdly instead
is yes.
And so they did.
And then I came back.
And you look really pretty.
But if you can make it through
the first weeks and months,
if you believe that
healing is possible...
then you can get your life back.
But that's a big if.