Hang on, Hannah.
I love you.
Dr. Halstead.
Doris.
Any symptoms? Headache?
Dry cough?
No.
98.5, good.
Let's get you tested.
I was just tested
this morning.
You went home.
Nobody goes back in the ED
without getting tested.
Come on. Open up.
Jim, a word?
Let's take it inside.
I need a break.
Hey. This is April's third
straight week
in the COVID Ward.
We're short-staffed.
April volunteered.
Protocol is one week on
and one week off.
She's putting herself at risk.
I don't know
what to tell you.
April feels
this is her mission.
Jim, you're
the Chief of the ED.
You've gotta
protect your staff.
She knows what she's doing.
And what's it to you?
I thought you guys broke up.
That has nothing
to do with it.
Ethan, I need her, okay?
Check your iPad.
You got five patients.
You know the drill,
monitor them
from outside the room.
Leave it
to the nurses inside
to treat them.
Dr. Halstead?
COVID test was negative.
You're good to go.
Hannah's sats dropped
and we couldn't recover,
so, we intubated.
Figured you'd have to.
Now it looks like she has
a chemical pneumonitis,
aspirated some vomit.
So, I put an OG tube down
to decompress
her stomach, okay?
Hey, Will.
She's gonna be okay.
Yeah, thanks.
Crockett, I'm glad
you're taking care of her.
You got it.
Hey. I just got a text.
Hannah was brought in?
Yeah.
She's in here,
so, it can't be COVID.
Um... I found her unconscious
in her bathroom,
syringe in her arm.
She OD'd.
Hey. How you feeling?
Good. Fine.
Got your energy back?
Sharon, I am ready
to go back to work. Trust me.
Good. You've been missed.
How you been doing?
The board still doesn't
want me coming back
because of my diabetes.
So, all of my meetings
are virtual.
Like Zooming with ten people,
all in their little box.
It's driving me crazy.
I can't read the room.
I don't know if people
are actually paying attention,
or just looking down
at their phones.
There's already
a name for that,
they're calling it
"Zoom Fatigue."
I've already read
three psych papers on it.
And speaking of psych,
I need you to carve out time
for the staff.
There's just been no let-up
with the workload
and so many fatalities.
And then you add to that,
all the social trauma
they've been dealing with.
I'm sending out a memo, now.
Great, good.
And is Anna with you?
Yeah.
Yeah, we decided that
it was safe for her
to come back.
Say hi for me, okay?
Will do. Okay.
Take care of yourself.
Take care.
Morning.
Sharon Goodwin says hi.
So, I am going to work.
Uh...
You're pretty much
gonna stay put?
Dad, I'm not gonna go out.
That's good, because...
I mean, it's...
I know.
Okay. I'll see you later.
Bye.
Whoa!
Sorry!
Manning. Eyes on the road.
Sorry, Crockett.
Oh, hey.
Yeah?
Heard you moved into Club Med.
The Pavilion? Yes, I am.
Oh.
Watch yourself.
I hear it gets pretty rowdy
in there.
A lot
of questionable behavior.
Okay.
Nat?
Yes.
Check your iPad.
You're going to Treatment 4.
Got it.
See you, Crockett.
All right.
Mr. Lieu?
Hi, I'm Dr. Manning.
And you must be Kellie.
Hi.
I see Kellie's been dealing
with myelogenous leukemia.
For a couple years.
She's immunocompromised,
so, I didn't wanna bring her
into the hospital
if I didn't need to.
She was in remission,
but her leukemia came back.
So, we had to do chemo
all over.
Just finished the last round
eight weeks ago.
Just hope she won't
have to do it again.
Let's see.
You're having difficulty
breathing, aren't you?
It's okay, I'm used to it.
We're gonna help you
feel better, okay?
Let's get a CBC, a BMP, ECG,
an echo and a BNP, okay?
You got it.
You mind if I talk to your dad
for a moment?
So, I am hearing
an "S" three gallop
in her heart,
which means
it's struggling.
Also, her neck veins
are distended.
And I am seeing
some swelling in her legs
and ankles.
Those are symptoms
of heart failure, aren't they?
Her oncologist
warned us about that.
It's likely a result
of the chemo medication.
Unfortunately,
some are cardiotoxic.
They can damage
the heart muscle.
The good news is,
I think we can reverse it
if we change her medication.
So let's get
the test results back,
and then I will loop in
your oncologist, okay?
Okay. Thank you.
All right. Mmm-hmm.
Clear.
Mr. Booker?
I'm afraid your X-ray
looks wet.
That means
that you still have
fluid in your lungs.
The proning hasn't helped.
So, what now?
I suggest we intubate
and put you on a ventilator.
A ventilator?
You'll be sedated.
But I don't feel that bad.
I know, but the thing
that makes people feel bad,
a rise in CO2,
doesn't happen with COVID.
But you're still not getting
enough oxygen.
If we put you on a ventilator,
it'll allow you to rest.
Please. Can't you
wait a little longer,
make sure
I really need it?
If we wait and you go
into cardiac arrest,
we can't resuscitate you.
I know it's terrible,
but we can't run a code
in here.
Chest compressions release
so much virus.
Please, Alvin,
let us help you.
Okay.
Twenty of etomidate,
a hundred of roc?
Start a propofol infusion.
I need to suit up.
I gotta go and intubate.
Dr. Marcel, look alive.
Incoming GSW.
Twenty-year-old male,
COVID negative,
gunshot wound
to the upper right thigh,
GCS 15. BP 100/77.
It hurts...
Gonna take care of that, bud.
Fifty of Fentanyl.
X-rays, meet us inside.
Gunshot wound?
Second one today.
COVID or no COVID,
some things never change.
How're we ever gonna heal
this city?
I know what you're gonna say.
"I told you so."
Why would I say that?
You said drug addicts can
replace drugs with romance.
Ring a bell?
Well, I mean, it happens.
Well, not with us.
We love each other. Okay?
Yeah, uh, sure, there's stress
because of the pandemic,
but everybody's feeling that.
And maybe
'cause of the quarantine,
we moved in sooner
than we would've.
Totally understandable.
Trust me, you are not
the only ones.
But we're making it work.
What happened last night
was a lapse. That's all.
Will, look. I'm not here
to confront you, buddy.
I mean, these sessions
are about one thing
and one thing only,
and that is
lowering your stress levels
in a time when practicing
emergency medicine
can be overwhelming.
You know, that's it.
Is that okay?
I'm sorry,
I haven't even asked
how you're doing.
I understand you had
a pretty bad time of it.
Yeah, this COVID thing
ain't no joke,
but, you know what,
I'm fine.
And, look,
I really appreciate
your asking,
but I really
wanna use this time,
if it's okay,
to talk about you,
you know,
and how you're doing.
I'm managing, I guess.
I mean, we finally have
enough PPE.
The safety protocols
seem to be working.
Okay, good.
I just...
What?
I thought we'd be over it
by now.
Three weeks straight?
Don't start, Ethan.
You're putting yourself
at risk.
Look around.
So many of these patients...
I see the people
I grew up with,
they're dying
at twice the rate.
I know. I know.
They've been discriminated
against their entire lives,
poverty,
terrible health care...
Now, they're hit with this.
Yeah.
April.
I'm just worried about you.
The two men I'm treating?
They are sick,
they are frightened,
and they are alone.
I'm not abandoning them.
Miss Palmer,
hi, I'm Dr. Halstead.
Hi. Call me Anita.
Okay.
This is her husband, Brad.
Hey, Brad,
sorry you can't be here.
We're limiting visitors
for safety.
No, I understand.
Thank you.
Is it true redheads
like spicy food?
Uh...
Haven't heard that one.
So, Anita,
you had a fall today, huh?
Yeah. In the kitchen
after breakfast.
Okay. You hurt your arm.
Mmm-hmm.
Did you lose consciousness?
No.
Oh! What happened here?
Oh.
That was a couple days ago.
She's actually fallen
three times
in the last week.
Any history
of low blood pressure,
fainting, or seizures?
Mmm-mmm.
On any new medications?
No. I don't take anything.
I think this country's
over-medicated.
I see you're
an air traffic controller?
Mmm-hmm.
Pretty stressful work.
No, I've been doing it
for five years.
I know where all those
little planes are going.
Impressive. Brad, can you
think of anything else?
She hasn't gone to the gym
since the pandemic,
and she stopped her paleo diet
a few weeks ago.
And I'm not seeing anything
that concerns me.
But we will get an EKG, labs,
and an X-ray of your arm,
see if we can't find out why
you've been unsteady lately.
Okey-dokey.
Hang in there.
She seem
a little high to you?
Yeah, maybe.
You know, some people get
a little loopy in the ED.
Add a tox screen
to her blood work.
Yeah. Blood alcohol?
Yeah. Okay.
Any change?
Not yet.
Dr. Halstead?
Sabeena Virani.
Uh...
I'm sorry, Dr. Virani.
We were supposed to meet
in the cardiology clinic.
If this isn't a good time...
No, it's just...
Someone I know.
I'm sorry. I'll catch you
another time.
Wait. You said you work
for Kender Pharma?
R&D.
We're running a trial at Med
for an oral
heart failure medication.
Dr. Ramsey
is principal investigator.
He thought
it'd be good to have
an ED doc as co-PI.
Recommended you.
Thanks. Another time,
I might be interested.
I just got a lot
going on right now.
I understand.
Hope everything works out.
Dina? Status on Mr. Booker?
Sats are stable.
Keep me posted.
Ethan.
Coming to you.
Mr. MacNeal,
his sats are 85.
I think you better
talk to his wife.
Mrs. MacNeal?
Hi, I'm Dr. Choi. I've been
treating your husband today.
Please. How is he?
I'm sorry to say,
he's not doing well.
His oxygen saturation level
is still only 85,
a good ten points
under what it should be.
Oh, my God.
We've done everything we can
with the ventilator,
inhaled nitrous oxide,
100% oxygen,
and, unfortunately,
nothing's worked.
So, if the ventilator
hasn't helped,
what else can we...
There is one more thing
we could try.
It's called ECMO.
It's a life support system
that takes the place
of the lungs.
Life support?
That sounds so...
It is.
It is, ma'am.
I don't wanna minimize
the seriousness
of your husband's condition.
At this point, I believe
ECMO is his only option.
Do we have
your permission?
Yes. Of course.
Please, save my Freddie.
I'll do my best, ma'am.
Oh, hey.
Hi, sweetie!
Hey, how's the arm?
The X-ray's negative.
Her arm is not broken.
Yay! It's not broken.
But there is one thing.
So, your labs show you have
a blood alcohol level of 0.14.
A what?
It indicates that you had
alcohol today.
No, I didn't.
No. No way.
So, I'm just wondering
maybe if that's the reason
you've been falling lately.
No, no. I haven't had
any alcohol today.
What about last night?
No. I don't drink.
I don't like the taste.
Yuck!
Tell you what,
why don't we get some more
fluids in your system
and we'll be back
to check on you
in a bit. Okay?
Okay.
She's drunk.
Well, something's going on.
I think he has
a serious problem.
Hey, it might be
a one-time event,
set off by some stressor.
The woman's fallen
three times
in the last week.
Wouldn't you call that
a pattern?
Her husband said
she doesn't drink.
She doesn't drink.
So, let's monitor her BAC
and when she comes down,
we'll chat with her.
Wh...
Hey. Kellie Lieu,
my peds patient
with leukemia?
Yeah. The labs and history
just came in.
Oh, perfect.
Not good, huh?
No.
I need a surgical consult.
All right. I'll ask Crockett.
You know what? Wait.
Don't page Crockett.
Just page whoever's on call.
Hello?
Make sure he gets that.
Why not Crockett?
It's nothing.
I just need a consult,
and so, I was gonna page
the call person.
Why do that? I'm free.
Okay.
Uh, the patient
is Kellie Lieu. She's 12.
She's been battling leukemia.
She presented today
with chemo-induced
heart failure.
Is that why you didn't want
to bring me in?
Kid with leukemia?
'Cause I lost my little girl?
I just thought maybe
it was a little too close
to home.
Thank you.
Tell me about the patient.
BNP's 2500,
ejection fraction 15%.
Bad numbers.
And it just gets worse.
Her latest blood smear shows
an increase in elevated cells
in her bone marrow.
So, the cancer's
coming back.
Yeah.
Okay, send me the chart.
And what you just did?
That's why I don't tell people
about my past.
The leukemia's
gonna come back?
Yes, it seems like it is.
I'm so sorry, Mr. Lieu.
So, we have to start
chemo again?
Eventually, yes.
But right now,
Kellie's heart's too damaged
for more chemo.
Getting her heart in shape
has to be our first priority.
Yes, okay,
how do we do that?
Well, there are
two options.
The first, we talked about,
replace Kellie's
current regimen
with one that's less toxic,
but in addition,
we add Milrinone to ease
the strain on her heart.
But we don't know how long
that would take to work,
and if the cancer comes back
before her heart
is healthy for chemo,
we'd have no way
to fight it.
You said there's
a second option?
Surgery. Implant an LVAD.
An assist device
that would take the pressure
off Kellie's heart
so it can recover faster.
Surgery?
That would be
my recommendation.
But you have to know
it comes with risks, okay?
Kellie is immunocompromised,
that increases the chance
of post-op infection.
And with COVID,
the danger is even greater.
So, you don't advise surgery?
Well, we've learned
how to mitigate those risks.
Still, LVADs are rarely used
in pediatric cases
because they are tailored
to fit adults.
That's because there aren't
many kids with Kellie's level
of heart disease.
If you two don't agree,
how can I make
this decision?
Mr. Lieu, I know how...
We know how difficult this is,
but I would...
I don't think you do!
I lost my wife two years ago.
She's not here to help me.
The world is upside-down.
Yesterday, a woman
in the parking lot
pointed at us and screamed,
"You brought COVID here!
It's your fault!
"Go back where you're from!"
I have to worry about
my daughter's leukemia,
the pandemic,
and now,
that we could get attacked?
Who do I trust?
I'm sorry
this is happening to you.
All I wanna do is
what's best for Kellie.
The safest thing.
And that doesn't
sound like surgery.
We'll try the medication.
All right.
I'll call your oncologist
and we'll get started.
Thank you.
Hey.
Yeah?
What's going on with you?
When did you get
so hyper conservative?
I thought he should have
all the facts.
Let me tell you something,
you talked that man
out of an operation
his little girl needs.
Thank you.
What are you doing?
Dr. Lanik canceled
Mr. MacNeal's ECMO.
Why did you cancel it?
He shouldn't have ordered it
in the first place.
Excuse me.
He's my patient.
And I'm Chief of the ED.
I have to allocate resources.
We only have four ECMOs
for the entire ward. Four.
Three are already in use.
Which leaves one
for Mr. MacNeal.
April, I can't tie up
my last circuit on him.
Especially when we know
Mr. Booker,
who still has a chance,
is gonna need it.
You don't know
he's going to need it
for sure,
and ECMO's the only thing
that could possibly save
Mr. MacNeal's life.
The man is gonna go
into multi-organ failure.
Over the last six months,
how many times
have we seen this?
ECMO is not gonna
change the outcome.
You can't say that for sure.
You're just gonna give up?
We've done
everything we could.
You want to make me
the bad guy? Get in line.
Crockett?
Yeah.
Oh, yeah. She's doing fine.
Aced her spontaneous
breathing trial.
I just extubated her.
You can head in.
All right.
Hey.
I'm so sorry.
It's all right, Hannah.
It's all right.
No.
No, you trusted me.
And I let you down.
Hey, the most important thing
is you're okay.
And you will come back
from this.
When they were taking me
out of the ambulance,
as messed up as I was,
I could still hear you.
You said, "I love you."
I do.
I swear I will
make this up to you.
When I get out of here,
I will go straight into rehab.
I'm gonna be so good.
Dr. Halstead.
They need you.
You rest.
I don't want it!
Okay.
Sweetie,
these are electrolytes.
No!
You need them.
No. Let me alone,
I wanna go home!
Hey.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Anita, I'm sorry.
Get security in here.
I can't let you leave
in this condition.
What condition?
There's no condition.
You're intoxicated.
I am not!
Okay.
Earl...
Let go!
Fifty of Benadryl.
I got it. Earl,
come up here, please.
No.
Thank you.
No! You can't!
Okay, hold on, sweetie.
I wanna go home!
Okay.
All right.
You were right.
When am I gonna learn?
Dr. Halstead.
Miss Goodwin
I have a patient,
an air traffic controller
who has a drinking problem.
Both she and her husband
refuse to admit it,
so, I am going
to inform the FAA.
I wanted to make you aware.
And you're certain
about this?
Yes. Uh, I didn't want
to believe it at first.
She's very convincing.
But it has been going on
for some time,
and clearly,
both she and her husband
are in denial.
I see.
Well, she's your patient.
It's your call.
I heard about Dr. Asher.
I'm sorry. How's she doing?
Yeah, better.
Thanks for asking.
But you know
I have no choice
but to report Dr. Asher.
I know.
And as to your patient,
I would encourage you
to make sure
there are no extenuating
circumstances
that you're not aware of.
Because once you make
the call to FAA,
this woman's career
is very likely over.
Mrs. MacNeal?
Um...
This is bad, isn't it?
The doctors have reconsidered
your husband's treatment.
They don't feel ECMO
will change
the course of his illness.
Does that mean...
I'm afraid, yes.
You have to prepare yourself.
Can I be with him?
Hold his hand?
No. It would put you
at too much risk.
We've been married
for 40 years.
And now, he's going to die
without me by his side.
I wish I could change that,
but I can't.
But he won't die alone.
I will be there.
I promise you.
I want you
to give him something.
I just found this.
It was our first date.
I'll make sure he gets this.
Help! Somebody help.
She can't breathe.
Kellie? Kellie?
Hey, sweetheart. Look at me.
Look at me. I know
you're scared, all right?
I just need you to take slow,
deep breaths, okay?
Okay? There you go.
"S" Gallop is worse.
Let's get another echo
and chest X-ray.
What? What's happening?
Kellie's heart failure
is getting worse.
If we don't act now,
she may not be around
to fight the leukemia.
Oh, God. It's that bad?
You wanna operate?
Put in that LVAD?
That's right.
Dr. Manning,
you were against it before.
I have to agree
with Dr. Marcel now.
It's what's best for Kellie.
All right.
Do the surgery.
All right. Let's get
this girl upstairs.
Trini, page Dr. Latham
and tell him to meet me
in the OR.
Yeah.
You got a minute?
Yeah, sure.
Have a seat.
I wasn't being honest earlier.
Things haven't been good
with Hannah.
In fact, they've been
kind of a hell.
These last months,
if she was having a hard day
or we had a fight,
I was always afraid
she'd start using again.
I was just constantly
on eggshells,
and, uh, she could tell.
She blamed me
for not trusting her.
And I see now,
that I blamed her
for being an addict.
Blame, resentment...
Tricky stuff, you know,
hard to let go of.
You were right, what you said
about addicts and romance,
that if the romance
goes south,
they'll likely turn to drugs.
You think that's maybe
what happened here?
Hannah and I got into
a huge fight yesterday.
I stormed out of the condo.
And next thing I know,
she's, uh, OD'd.
Oh, buddy, I'm sorry.
Yeah, that's not
the worst of it.
See,
I think I've been waiting
for it to happen.
Where are we at?
She's sobering up.
You wanna talk to her?
Not yet. This case
got too personal for me.
I need to do some research
and look into this more.
Hey.
I just heard Kellie Lieu's
surgery went well.
Congratulations.
Yeah.
I was being
overly cautious.
I should've agreed
with the LVAD way sooner.
Well, not necessarily.
It was a risky procedure.
Could've easily gone
the other way.
You know, yesterday,
I moved out of my house.
I said goodbye to my son.
I have been thinking
about him all day,
wondering if I did
the right thing,
if he'll be okay.
I think those feelings
clouded my judgment today.
You weren't wrong about me
and kids with leukemia.
Every time I see one,
I think of my little girl.
You know,
we try to protect them
as much as we can...
...until that last moment,
when we, uh, can't.
Uh, all I'm saying is
you're doing the right thing.
Yeah.
Owen will be okay.
See you tomorrow.
Now, what?
I did some research
and ordered one last test.
I owe you an apology.
We now know
you have not been drinking.
Finally.
I gotta be honest with you,
this is a first for me.
You have a condition
called auto-brewery syndrome.
And because of it,
the yeast in your gut
turns certain carbohydrates
into alcohol.
You never even
have to take a drink.
Really?
Yes.
Why would this happen
all of a sudden?
So, you said Anita
was on a paleo diet,
very low carbs,
but she stopped.
Yeah. I was hungry
all the time.
We're not sure why
some people react this way,
but that's probably
what triggered it.
And if you cut out
simple carbs
from your diet,
you should be fine.
Maggie's gonna discharge you,
so you can get out of here.
Okay.
Again, I'm sorry.
Hey.
Look, um...
You know, I've been thinking,
when I get out of rehab,
I wanna go somewhere.
Away from here,
get a fresh start.
You wanna leave Med?
Here, I'm just
the addict doctor.
I always will be.
I was thinking LA.
Decent weather for a change.
I want you to come with me.
Hannah,
I'm not gonna do that.
You don't have to decide
right away, so...
No, I'm not coming with you.
I was afraid
you'd say that.
See, the thing is, Will,
without you...
...I'm worried that, uh...
I'm worried that
I'll start using again.
I love you.
But I can't be the reason
you stay sober.
It's not good for you
and, uh, it's not good for me.
Who's gonna cut your hair?
Who knows?
Maybe in a year or so,
you'll wanna
come visit Disneyland.
Yeah. Maybe I will.
What?
Hey, I picked up
a little Thai.
You, uh, hungry?
I hadn't been
out of the house
in months.
I was going crazy.
I just wanted
to see some friends.
None of them were sick.
Honey, I get it.
I totally understand.
Jennifer had no idea
that she had it.
She felt completely fine.
You know, sweetie,
it's okay to feel bad.
It's okay. I'm really glad
that we're...
Dad, of course I feel bad!
I gave you COVID!
That's why you're mad at me!
I'm not mad at you.
Yes, you are!
You've been walking
around the house
acting like everything's fine,
using that phony, calm voice,
but clearly, it's not fine.
Why aren't you yelling at me
right now?
Why would I yell at you?
Because I screwed up!
I could've killed you.
I'm so sorry.
Can you forgive me?
Oh, sweetie, of course,
I forgive you.
Of course, I do.
And you know what?
I mean, I think you're right.
I think I have been angry.
And you know what?
Maybe I should
have told you,
but I know you didn't do it
on purpose.
I didn't want
to make you feel
any worse.
Here's the thing
about your dad.
I can be pretty good
with other people's emotions,
but sometimes, not so much
when dealing with my own.
Which is why
I need you around.
Keep me honest.
The pad thai's
probably getting
cold by now.
So you know
I'm not coming home
tonight, right?
Yeah, I know.
You're helping people.
But I miss you
and I love you very much.
I love you, too.
Nana and I
are making cookies.
Oh, yeah?
What kind of cookies?
Chocolate chip.
Mmm.
So, you're having fun
with Nana?
Yeah.
Good.
I'm glad to hear that.
I'm gonna go, now.
Oh, okay.
Bye, Mom.
Bye, sweetheart.
BP 55/38. Sats at 60.
Maxed on pressors.
He's in
multi-organ failure.
We've exhausted
our options, April.
Turn up his morphine?
Yeah. And contact his wife.
April?
Hi. Um...
I'm afraid it's his time.
Let me see him.
Fred?
Freddie?
I love you, honey.
And I'll miss you every day,
for the rest of my life.
But then I'll see you again.
And we'll be together...
...forever.
I'm so sorry.
No.
Another week.
We remember those gone.
Let's share their names.
Helen-Mae Samuels, 85.
Her kids say
she was a great cook.
Malcolm Grazer, 44.
Coached his son's
little league team.
Maria Lopez, 58,
dedicated life-long
schoolteacher.
Frederick MacNeal.
Sixty-two,
avid stamp collector,
scout master,
and beloved husband
of Beverly
for 40 years.