Have you seen my coat?
It's right here.
PARROT: Don't touch that.
Get away.
He's really taken to you.
(SCOFFS) Funny.
No, he really has.
It's because I'm
the one with the food.
That's why I took to you.
Really?
That mean if I
feed you some seeds,
you'll forget about
teaching this course?
And miss two months
in Bethesda?
It's the vacation capital
of Montgomery County.
PARROT: Get away, get away.
(VICKI CHUCKLES)
(SQUAWKS)
Don't touch that. Get away.
(VICKI LAUGHS)
ETHAN: Hush.
(VICKI SIGHS)
They charge you twice
for your cable again?
No. I got offered a job.
Yeah? That's great.
I guess.
It's in California.
Oh.
But I mean,
that's okay, right?
It's nice out there.
Yeah. Definitely.
It's just... Just far.
Have you heard
from Rush yet?
Northwestern?
Still waiting.
Of course,
there's always a chance
things could work out here.
A very slim chance.
Hey, you two.
Patients incoming.
You're going to treatment six.
April, you got this?
Yeah.
Thank you.
Right here.
WILL: What do we got?
COURTNEY: Chuck Gleason,
42-year-old male,
found at the bottom
of some stairs
on Lower Wacker with
a fractured left tibia.
Okay, on my count.
One, two, three.
(GROANS)
He looks dehydrated.
Let's call ortho
and get some fluids.
NURSE: On it. Start a line.
Let's get him set up.
Let's pull the board out.
(CHUCK GROANS)
You got a drink, April?
Could really use a drink.
You guys friends?
Frequent flyer.
Alcohol. And everything
that goes with it.
How about you, buddy?
You got a drink?
Unfortunately, this is
a hospital, not a bar.
When did this happen?
Yesterday. (GROANS)
Dr. Manning.
101.
All right, let's get
a chest x-ray and a UA.
Okay.
Mr. Gleason, you
broke your leg pretty bad.
We're gonna have
to evaluate this...
NATALIE: He's seizing.
Mr. Gleason?
All right.
Milligram of Ativan.
APRIL: On it.
It's a grand mal seizure.
He ever had this before?
Not that I've seen.
Milligram of Ativan.
He's withdrawing.
Going into delirium tremens.
Here you go.
Never seen him
get DTs before.
It's gonna be bad, isn't it?
Is it ever good?
EARL: (CHUCKLES) Hey.
Thanks for the bird.
Kids are gonna love it.
ETHAN: Definitely.
Glad it'll have a nice home.
Anything I need to know?
No. Just enjoy.
All right,
you're a good man, doc.
(LAUGHS)
Cirrhosis, hepatitis,
cardiomyopathy, renal failure.
WILL: Reads like the index
of Harrison's Guide
to Internal Medicine.
(GROANS)
(YELLING)
Mr. Gleason,
when was your last drink?
Two nights ago.
Which is why I need
to get the hell out of here.
Afraid I can't do that.
Talk to this guy,
will you, please?
I'm sorry, Chuck,
the doctor's in charge.
No, I'm in charge, okay?
I'm in charge.
I know my rights.
I don't have to stay here
if I don't wanna stay here.
That's very true.
But you're not gonna
get far on that leg
without ortho
taking care of it.
Okay, fine, man. It's cool.
What are we talking
about here? Two hours?
Mr. Gleason, you're going
through delirium tremens.
Your body is so used
to the presence of alcohol
that it's reacting
violently to its absence.
Blah! Blah! Blah!
We need to keep
you here a day or so,
till you get through it.
That ain't gonna
happen, man.
Okay? I've seen what
happens with the DTs.
I can't go
through that, please!
We can't stop them,
but we have given you
a sedative to make it easier.
I'm sorry, but at this point,
it's no longer safe for
you to leave.
(GAGGING)
(RETCHES)
APRIL: Okay.
Okay.
Hey, Maggie,
can you call ortho
and see what's taking so long?
Sure can.
Hey.
Where's your wedding ring?
I don't know. Um,
I had it on when I got here.
You didn't put
it in your locker?
No. I never take it off.
Well, where else
have you been?
Retrace your steps.
I've been in and out of
five rooms, washing my hands.
I mean, who knows how many
gloves I've taken on and off.
Maggie. (SIGHS)
All right, all right.
I got this.
Everyone, listen up.
We're missing
a gold wedding band.
So take a room and
search every inch of it.
From now on,
nothing leaves the ED.
Every sheet, every gown,
every piece of trash
gets bagged and
stored until I search it.
Got that?
WOMAN: Got it, Maggie.
Hey.
We're gonna find it, okay?
I'm gonna check in the lounge.
Okay.
Thank you.
So this is Rose Wechsler, 83.
Arrived from her
nursing facility
confused and agitated.
Ms. Wechsler, good morning.
ROSE: Baloney.
Are you here for the sink?
You know I'm not.
But it would help
me out a great deal
if you could tell
me what year it was.
Check your damn calendar.
No wonder you people
never show up on time.
That's completely my fault.
Do you mind if I
just shine...
What are you,
some kind of a maniac?
Get the hell out of here!
Thank you.
Out!
Lovely to meet you.
What do you think?
(SIGHS)
Nursing home delirium.
Acute cognitive
dysfunction from some
combination of dehydration,
stasis,
overmedication,
and a lack of
human engagement.
Could be.
She's neurologically intact,
but her mucous membranes
are dry.
If you're right,
fluids will perk her up.
Hmm, yeah. For now.
What?
Uh, I'm sorry.
It's just that her records
indicate she led
a remarkable life.
Was one of the first
female test pilots.
Trained at NASA.
Even if fluids work,
it's sad seeing
someone like that
wind up like this.
Well...
MAGGIE: Incoming!
Dr. Choi, we're going
to Baghdad.
WOMAN ON PA:
All attending physicians
to the ED, stat.
On it.
MAGGIE: Talk to me.
CESAR: Frank McCormick.
Here's his EKG.
42. Lost his
rhythm again in the van.
Shocked from
V-fib in the field.
Hang in there, Frank.
It's gonna be okay.
Excuse us, ma'am.
Let's rotate.
All right. Let's transfer him
on my count.
One, two, three. Transfer.
Dr. Choi, what do you got?
STEMI. A big one.
NURSE 1: Hang a volume
expander and get Lactater
Ringer's going.
NURSE 2: I got it.
(EKG FLATLINING)
He flipped back into V-fib.
On it.
Sats are dropping.
Frank.
Paddles to Dr. Choi.
Ma'am, is this your husband?
JUDY: Yes.
He had a heart attack.
Please step outside.
Oh, my God.
Please come with me
and stand right there.
ETHAN: Charge to 200.
DORIS: Charging.
(GRUNTING)
Clear.
NURSES: Clear.
(ZAPS)
Charging.
(GRUNTING)
Clear.
(ZAPS)
(EKG BEEPING)
Heart rate's back to 65.
Pressure's 115 over 60.
All right, let's get
him up to the cath lab.
Based on his EKG,
he's gonna need a bypass.
DORIS: Okay, let's go.
Watch the lines.
Wait. Did you say
he needs a bypass?
Yes, ma'am.
We got your
husband's rhythm back,
but he's still not
out of the woods.
We need to find the blockage
that caused his heart attack.
Then most likely,
we'll graft new
vessels on around it.
But that means going on
a heart-lung machine, right?
Yes, it does.
Then I'll have to refuse.
Refuse? What?
My husband can't
have any surgery
that involves
the administration of blood.
We're Jehovah's Witnesses.
CHUCK: Stop! Stop it!
Get it off of me!
They're inside
of this thing now!
Chuck, you're
hallucinating again.
It's part of the DTs.
I'm gonna
increase your sedatives.
(WHIMPERING)
I don't want sedatives.
How many times I
gotta tell you that?
I don't need a sedative.
I need a drink.
You know I can't do that.
Then get the hell
out of here!
Hey, how long
have I known you? Years.
Every time you come in here,
you are sicker.
One of these times,
you're gonna be
too far gone.
Chuck, listen to me.
You're never gonna beat
this if you give in now.
(SOBBING)
I'm never gonna beat this.
I ain't beating nothing.
Please, honey.
Make it stop. Please.
Please make it stop.
I'm trying to help you.
(RETCHES)
(GASPING)
I told you.
I told you how to help me.
But you don't listen.
I'm gonna
increase your sedatives.
I'm gonna get you
a clean blanket.
I don't need
I need a drink.
Because you're killing
me with all your help!
Frank, we respect
your beliefs. We do.
But the fact is,
you're going to have
another heart attack.
The only question is when.
You paged me?
This is Dr. Downey, our top
cardio-thoracic surgeon.
I was just explaining
to the McCormicks
that, unfortunately,
surgery is the only
option that we have left.
And I was explaining
that we need an alternative
that doesn't involve
the administration of blood.
It is his own blood.
It's recirculated.
Blood contains
the gift of life.
Once it leaves the body,
it's contaminated forever.
I know you think
we're being difficult.
But this isn't
just about the danger
that Frank's body
is in right now.
It's about he and I
being able to spend
eternity together.
We understand, but...
What about bloodless surgery?
What's that?
It's where we
do it off-pump.
Operate on the heart
while it's still beating.
You can do that?
Yes.
Though it comes
with significant risks.
For the McCormicks,
the heart-lung
machine is a risk.
Stopping the heart,
removing the blood
to oxygenate it,
and putting it back
violates their faith.
So let's do it
without the machine.
Excuse us for a moment.
He's got bad
three-vessel disease.
He is a terrible candidate.
It's too high of a risk.
Higher than not
doing anything at all?
Let's at least
give them some time
to see if they wanna
choose the safer option.
We don't wanna wait.
We wanna do
the bloodless surgery.
Okay.
I'll inform the OR.
Please.
This is a lot of... Please.
You need to up his benzos.
I already did. Twice.
Then give him
a milligram of Haldol, too.
I'll tell you,
when I was a clinical nurse,
I used to dread DT patients.
I know. Such misery.
And most of the time,
they're back
in two months to do
it all over again.
MAGGIE: Mmm-hmm.
I lost my
wedding ring recently.
Didn't find it for three days.
What did Bert say?
You know, he didn't
say anything, which was weird
because he's
usually so observant.
Excuse me. Daniel.
What are you doing tonight?
Working. Why?
Well, an old friend
of Bert's and mine
has moved to town,
and I thought we
could all go to dinner.
You know,
sounds like a blast,
but I really am slammed.
Oh, come on, Daniel.
Bert's been so grumpy lately,
and he always cheers up
when he talks to you.
What's going on?
It's a long story,
but you'd really
be helping me out.
Besides, Maribel loves
scotch and ballroom dancing.
You haven't been
out in a while.
You know,
there's a reason for that.
There's this new study out.
Says dating can
lead to marriage.
It's just a friendly dinner.
Yeah. And I'm still paying
two and a half alimonies.
So these friendly
dinners can get expensive.
Ms. Reese, any word
on that nursing home patient?
Actually, there is.
Daniel.
I gotta go. Thank you
so much for the invite.
Best to Bert.
We'll do it next time.
So the good news is,
Ms. Wechsler's
doing much better
after some fluids.
She's awake and alert.
That is good news.
Yes.
Though she does
still have a fever
and is reporting
lower abdominal pain.
Fluids and scans?
All negative.
Except for a slightly
elevated white count,
but I'm already doing
an infectious workup now.
Sounds like a great plan.
What's the bad news?
This is Wanda Stern.
In from the same
nursing home.
She has a 101 fever
and feels Nixon is
just what this country
needs to run out the commies.
Fluids and labs?
Fluids and labs.
Hey.
I'm sorry about your ring.
So stupid.
I can't believe I lost it.
No, no, no. Come on.
These things, they happen.
No. Illnesses happen.
Bad weather happens.
This is on me.
Look, I'm on
all your patients.
So don't worry, okay?
Just try to take it easy.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
I feel so terrible.
Like I betrayed Jeff.
Like I didn't care enough.
Hey, April.
April.
What's in the bag?
Nothing. It's
a personal item.
Is that a bottle of booze?
(SIGHS)
You were gonna give
that to Mr. Gleason?
My nursing supervisor
did it all the time.
April, it's against protocol.
Since when do you
care about that?
I care about getting
our patient through this.
Does he look like he's
getting through this?
He needs a drink.
I didn't say
it would be easy.
But that?
That's just a Band-Aid.
I come in here
every day and I put
Band-Aids on patients,
and most of them
thank me for it.
And he may thank you.
But you're not helping him.
And you are?
Standing around while
he dies in front of us?
This man has
a chance to get past
his problem and
make a new start.
He's telling us that
he doesn't want that.
It's up to us to listen.
No, no, no, no.
It's not my job to listen.
I'm a doctor.
It's my job to decide
what is best for him.
That is exactly
why I'm a nurse.
Hey. Uh, Frank McCormick
is going into surgery.
I need you to load his
angio into the system.
You Dr. Rhodes?
Uh, yep.
Should be up now.
Yeah, thanks.
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
No luck yet, huh?
Not yet.
But we haven't even
gone through the trash.
Are you okay?
Yeah. Uh...
(CLEARS THROAT)
My head is spinning.
I feel like I'm
gonna throw up.
Oh, Maggie.
Natalie, I'm gonna
find your ring.
But in the meantime,
I want you to go in there,
have a drink of
water and lie down.
Okay? All right.
Mmm-hmm.
(GROANS)
Natalie.
I don't know why you guys
are ordering all these tests.
I'm anemic.
It was nothing.
Well, that's not
what the EKG's saying.
I'm seeing
elevated ST segments
in the anterior
and lateral leads.
Where?
Tell echo we're
bringing her upstairs.
Echo? I have
no cardiac history,
no risk factors.
You guys are just being
overly cautious
because it's me.
Nat, darn right
that's what we're doing.
Stop being stubborn
and listen to the man.
Please?
Let's go.
Ugh!
On Wednesdays,
I go downstairs
to the beauty shop.
And my neighbor,
she always does my hair.
Okay.
How about the card room?
I play a lot of canasta.
In the south lobby?
No, darling. In the north.
Oh.
How we doing, ladies?
Any luck?
Wanda here is lovely.
And though I
appreciate your theory
that our conditions
may arise from
the same source,
I'm afraid the only thing
we have in common
is Sinai Gardens.
Ah.
Ms. Reese, could I
talk to you for a moment?
Keep at it.
(SIGHS)
Their labs are all negative.
They both are febrile
with leukocytosis.
And infections in
the elderly can present
quite differently than normal.
I think we need to
start looking for zebras.
Rickettsia.
Leptospirosis.
Ms. Stern has a
redness in her left eye.
Did you notice that?
Probably from
the chlorine in the pool.
She likes to do
water aerobics.
But consider the symptoms.
Acute delirium,
severe dehydration,
lower abdominal pain,
one itchy red eye.
Like I said,
in an 85-year-old,
it could be anything.
If these women were
closer to you in age,
what might you suspect?
(GASPS)
No.
No, no, no. No.
Why not?
No, because
they're old ladies.
They can't have gonorrhea.
Are you trying to tell me
that because they're old,
they can no longer
be sexually active?
Oh, come on,
they barely have the energy
to play canasta,
whatever that is.
I say we keep digging.
(CLEARS THROAT)
There's a gentleman
from the retirement
home out there
inquiring about the status
of your two patients.
Says his name is Clyde.
(INAUDIBLE)
Hmm.
Maybe they, uh, have
something in common
after all.
We're gonna need
some swabs.
(CHUCKLES)
Dr. Halstead!
WILL: What happened?
He just started
vomiting blood.
Must have ruptured
an esophageal varix.
Prep a Minnesota
tube and call for MTP.
I need to intubate.
This is from years of
alcoholic cirrhosis.
Vessels get
dilated and tortured.
But why is this all
happening right now?
Must have ruptured
from all the vomiting.
All right. Tube.
Got an airway. Bag him.
Good breath
sounds bilaterally.
We need to stop
this bleeding.
Minnesota tube.
DORIS: Yes, doctor.
What do you need?
Start a groin line,
get a rapid transfuser,
and give him
two of blood stat.
I need more suction.
APRIL: I got it.
DORIS: Send a runner
to central for the infuser
and call the blood bank.
APRIL: I'm on it.
I can't see a damn thing.
I'm gonna have to
go in blind.
Line's in.
Start the MTP.
Pressure's down
to 80 over 40.
He's bleeding out.
Come on. Come on, come on.
Got it.
Blood's going.
Good.
Ready to inflate
the internal balloons.
Syringe.
Want an x-ray for placement?
No time.
As soon as the balloons
are inflated,
we'll know
whether the pressure
they're placing
on the vessels is enough
to staunch the bleeding.
Bleeding stopped.
For now.
Call GI to
cauterize the vessels.
Okay.
I'm doing
everything I can.
MAGGIE: Dr. Halstead.
Dr. Manning's
results from echo.
Knock, knock.
Hey. (EXHALES)
You got my echo results?
Yeah.
Good news.
You definitely did
not have a heart attack.
You see, that's what
I've been saying.
But you did have
a cardiac event.
Takotsubo cardiomyopathy.
Let me see that.
Spasm on your
coronary artery
would explain the
shortness of breath
and chest pain.
Scary for sure,
but completely
reversible.
We should have you
out of here in a day or two.
Losing my wedding ring.
That's what triggered this.
It's not always
easy to pinpoint
the cause of the stress.
You just can't know.
Will, no, you don't
have to sugarcoat it.
I know the colloquial
term for this.
Broken-heart syndrome.
This is about, uh...
This is about Jeff.
Chance of another episode
is incredibly low.
You will get past this.
I promise.
Yeah.
I came as soon as
Maggie called me.
How is she?
Hi. Uh, she's
gonna be okay.
(SIGHS)
Hi.
DOWNEY: And LAD is finished.
CONNOR: Raising
the heart ventrally
to get at the RCA.
Uh-huh.
We're two-thirds
of the way there.
This is the big one.
Right there.
CONNOR: Scalpel and Gerald.
BETH: Scalpel.
(ALARM BEEPING)
MARTY: Blood pressure
bottomed out. You gotta
lower the heart back down.
CONNOR: Okay.
Okay.
(EKG FLATLINING)
Marty?
It's not coming back.
He's in V-fib.
We gotta put him on the pump.
DOWNEY: No.
We defibrillate him.
Continue as planned.
CONNOR: And then what?
This is gonna happen again.
DOWNEY: Clear.
BETH: Clear.
(ZAPS)
Still V-fib.
We have to put
him on the pump.
We don't have a choice.
Charge to 50.
BETH: Charging.
DOWNEY: Clear.
(ZAPS)
CONNOR: This isn't working.
We need to get
the perfusionist
and the bypass
team in here now.
That's not an option,
Dr. Rhodes.
Then we will get
his wife in here,
and we'll get her consent.
It's his ball game.
I don't understand.
Is Frank okay?
Please. Put this on.
MARTY: We're not getting
the pressure back.
Frank. Oh, my God.
Your husband is dying.
I'm pumping his heart
with my hands.
ETHAN: Mrs. McCormick.
(JUDY SOBBING)
If you don't authorize
this right now,
you'll never see
him alive again.
Is there really
no other way?
No.
Do what you have to.
Forgive me, Jehovah.
Why don't you
come with me outside?
CONNOR: All right, let's
hook him up and get to work.
This is the right
thing to do.
Thank you. Yeah.
That was Julia.
She needs me to relieve her.
I could bring Owen
back here a little later.
Maybe later tonight.
Okay. All right.
Well, you just...
You just call me
and let me know what
you'd like, all right?
Oh, Helen, actually,
I'm sorry. One last thing.
Mmm-hmm.
Do you know where
Jeff got my ring?
Well, not right offhand,
but I can look that up.
Please.
You're not thinking about
replacing the ring, are you?
Yes, I am.
Do you really think
that's a good idea?
Why wouldn't it be?
Natalie.
I know you love Jeff,
Jeff loved you,
but maybe losing
the ring is a sign.
A sign?
Natalie.
What do they call this?
Broken-heart syndrome.
Your grieving is so great
that it has put you
in a hospital bed,
and it's keeping
you from coming home
to see your son.
So maybe you just...
You need to let
go a little bit.
How could you say that?
I will never let go of Jeff.
I don't mean let go of him.
Just
move forward.
(SOBBING)
You just...
You call me
and let me know if you
need anything from home.
The clap?
Yikes.
Have Rose and Wanda
been told?
How did they take it?
You'd have to ask them.
Mr. Glickman,
partner notification
is an important part
of gonorrhea treatment.
And while,
we really don't
wanna be intrusive...
A gentleman never tells.
But if there are others,
they should be informed.
There's Cookie.
Beautiful blue eyes.
Cookie?
Sylvia. Marvelous
sense of humor.
So you're sleeping
with four different women?
Ms. Reese.
You make it sound tawdry.
It's not like that.
At our age,
there are very few men left.
And people
need companionship.
I make them happy.
They make me happy.
And I love them.
All of them.
I think of it as
assisted loving.
We'll get you
a shot of Ceftriaxone
and Azithromycin.
The nurse will be
with you shortly.
PARROT: Don't touch that.
Get away.
MAGGIE: Hey, Dr. Choi.
Earl said to give
this back to you.
What do you mean?
Made such a racket,
wouldn't let him
get any sleep.
Said he's gonna
get a gerbil.
PARROT: Don't touch that.
Get away. Get away.
Sorry, Maggie, I gotta go.
Hey, what am I
supposed to do with it?
I don't know. Put him
in the Doctors' Lounge.
(SIGHS) Come on.
Get away. Get away.
(JUDY SIGHS IN RELIEF)
(CHUCKLES)
(KISSES)
Oh, Frank,
I was so scared.
Told you it'd be all right.
Jehovah lit the path.
It was his will.
These doctors.
Maybe you should do
every surgery this way.
(CHUCKLES)
Mr. McCormick.
You should know
that there were
complications
with the surgery.
What kind of complications?
We had to use
the bypass machine after all.
I thought we made
our wishes clear.
Did they tell you
they were doing this?
They did.
And you gave them
your permission?
How can you do this to me?
I did it for you. For us.
You weren't going to
survive the surgery.
Now how am I supposed
to survive eternity?
Frank, I'm sorry.
Get out.
(SOBBING) Please.
You had no right.
That is why we don't
disregard patients' wishes.
Have you read
the fine print of
what they believe in?
They can accept all
the fractions of blood,
but they can't accept
them all together.
Does that make
any sense to you?
It doesn't have to
make sense to us.
If he believed he
would live longer
if his wounds were
dressed in green bandages,
then we give him
green bandages.
Not if the green bandages
are going to kill him.
Yeah! Even if it
kills him.
David.
Do you really believe that?
Or is this just
because this is the day
that your liver is
going to be ablated?
I saw your name
on the board in IR.
The mass on my liver
isn't shrinking.
We're gonna try
and reduce it again.
In fact, I should
mosey down there.
You're a good surgeon,
Dr. Rhodes.
But saving a life
isn't always the answer.
And you will never
be a great surgeon
until you understand that.
Hey, hey, hey.
Look what I found.
Where did you find it?
In a linen bag,
stuck to the hem
of a fitted sheet.
That's why you
quadruple check, right?
Thank you, Maggie.
I thought it was
gone for good.
Well, now it's back.
CLYDE: We're gonna beat
them to the finish line.
Here it comes.
Hold on tight. Up we go.
And thank you very much.
Thank you again
for all your help.
Ms. Wechsler,
can I ask you something?
Sure.
(EXHALES)
You're a strong,
successful woman.
You flew jets.
Aren't you angry with him?
I tell you, Ms. Reese,
some men spend
their whole lives
with women
but never bother to learn
what pleases them.
Clyde learned.
Let's go, Rosebud.
Before this thing
turns back into a pumpkin.
Thank you very much.
We're going flying.
He seems like
a nice enough guy,
but no one is worth lying,
cheating or disease.
Where you getting
lying and cheating?
You heard what he said.
Didn't hear that.
This looks like
more of an open
relationship to me.
Well, you would
think by their age,
they'd be past that.
Past wanting
physical intimacy?
If my boyfriend
ever suggested
an open relationship,
I'd kill him.
Huh.
You might be
surprised how things
you once thought
were so important
become less so
when you get older.
My life has
definitely become
bigger, messier,
far more interesting than
I ever thought it could,
when I was younger.
And you know what?
It hasn't always
been such a bad thing.
Well, I'm not that young.
I'm almost 26.
So, you know,
I was thinking, if you guys,
you know, your friend,
are still going
out to dinner,
I wouldn't be opposed.
Great.
You changed your mind.
Yeah. Got hungry.
Well, not too hungry, I hope.
My friend's a vegan.
A vegan? And you're
telling me now?
That's curious.
The important thing is,
it'll make Bert happy.
You know I live to serve.
Pair of jeans.
I paid for it.
How much?
(LAUGHING)
Mr. Gleason seems
much improved.
Yeah.
When did his
tremors subside?
Uh, about 20 minutes ago.
And no more hallucinations?
DORIS: Mmm-mmm.
Did we up his benzos?
No. Why?
Nurse Sexton.
Pretty miraculous turnaround
for our frequent flyer,
don't you think?
It looks like he'll
pull through, yeah.
Did you give him a drink?
No.
Well, someone did,
so who was it?
Goodwin?
I guess, once a nurse,
always a nurse.
Excuse me. A word please.
Sure.
You gave Mr. Gleason
a drink?
He was likely going
to die without one.
I've seen it happen.
So it doesn't matter
if that was against
hospital policy?
Because I'm pretty
sure if that were me,
I'd be raked over the coals
right now by you.
Damned if you do
and damned if you don't.
I admit it's a bit
of a double standard.
What can I say?
This patient...
He had a chance to
kick his addiction.
Now it's gone.
Dr. Halstead,
an addict doesn't
just kick a habit.
He's gotta want to quit.
And right now, he doesn't.
Listen, you can't
force a person to move on
from something
if they're not ready.
You know, they found
Dr. Manning's ring.
You wanna come up
with me to see her?
I'll be up a little later.
ETHAN: Any shortness
of breath?
Mr. McCormick.
I am sorry.
We were just trying to deal
with the circumstances...
The best you could. I know.
Do you even think
about God's will
or just your own?
You familiar with
Peter 5:2?
"Be a shepherd to the flock
that is under your care,
watch over them.
"Not for what
you'll get out of it
"but because you are
eager to serve God."
You entrusted me to
watch over not just
your body but your soul.
You're alive.
Because I couldn't
imagine life without you.
I misplaced my faith.
Today, I didn't serve God.
But I have to believe
that a God of love
is also a God
of forgiveness.
(DOWNEY CHUCKLING)
(DIALING)
(SQUAWKING)