- Previously on The Resident...
- I think I need to get back
to Minnesota 'cause my
MS could be progressing.
Whatever you need,
you just say the word.
- They think I'm crazy.
- You'll see a psychiatrist.
And we'll move you
to a better place,
one that specializes in
postpartum depression.
I was hoping for some
kind of reprieve,
but the governor
didn't budge, so, yes,
we will be closing
the ER to trauma.
That's awful. I
mean, can't we make
an emergency appeal
to the state assembly?
Our funding was always from the
governor's discretionary fund,
so we're completely
at his mercy.
I believe you and I joined
the same club today.
We were too good for 'em.
I don't love how we
got here, but I am
so happy that we are here.
I know. Me, too.
Resync By M_I_S
www.opensubtitles.org
♪ Well, well ♪
♪ If this is love ♪
♪ I'm back on board ♪
♪ Though I've ridden
this bus before ♪
Hey.
Last night was amazing.
It was.
♪ Maybe it's more,
maybe it's not ♪
And so are you.
♪ Oh, I'll know when
we meet the wall... ♪
And we should do it again.
And again. And again.
♪ All I got is
love and time... ♪
Feels weird to say it.
But this...
us... feels so...
Feels right.
That was fun.
Who knew there were pros
to getting dumped at work?
It was lovely.
You are lovely.
But I have a shift
in the ER, so...
♪ All I got is love and time ♪
♪ I'm just living... ♪
Hey, uh, why don't
I ride in with you?
- Uh, your car's right outside.
- Yeah, well,
it gives me a perfect excuse
to have to ride back here
with you after work then.
- Whoa, tiger.
- Ooh.
I know. I promise
I won't get clingy.
Neither will I.
♪ Ooh. ♪
I wish you'd been there.
I'm so proud of you for
protecting this place.
You know, taking Chastain
apart piece by piece, it just,
you know, it felt like
the beginning of the end.
And victory for Betz.
Still, at this rate
we're on the fast track
to a total shutdown by spring.
Not just the trauma center...
The entire hospital is at risk.
There is a parachute somewhere.
We'll find it.
God knows we need all
the help we can get.
Which is another reason
I'm glad you're home.
We need you back in the OR.
You haven't said much
about the clinic.
How was your new treatment?
Oh, the muscle weakening has
lessened, so that's a win.
And, um, no tremors lately.
I'm your wife, Randolph.
I know when you're not
telling me something.
Oh, I just
think I should, uh,
you know, I should
take a beat before...
jumping back into surgery.
The treatment. It didn't work.
No, it did, it just...
Just a little less than before.
But we knew from the start
there'd be diminishing
returns, so...
Just need to make a new plan.
It's Dr. Feldman.
"Turn on the TV."
We currently
have field reporters
on scene in Midtown.
Heavy rain and winds
are said to be the cause
of a devastating
helicopter crash
at 13th and Piedmont.
13th and Piedmont. That's a
couple blocks from Chastain.
Again, we are getting
unconfirmed reports
that one of the passengers on
board was Governor Mark Betz.
- The governor's condition...
- You can't be serious.
If it's that close, he'll
be taken to Chastain.
Copter crashed into the
café where she was working.
Her vitals?
Stable, GCS 14.
Okay. Mass casualty protocol.
Looks like a concussion
and second-degree burns.
Let's get her to Bay Two.
Hey, glad you're here. We
need all the help we can get.
Betz was in a helicopter crash.
- The governor?
- Yeah.
It's like musical
chairs around here.
How many so far?
Three ambo, two walk-ins.
Let's get the next one.
Thea Dwyer... the pilot. Blunt
trauma to chest and abdomen.
Prolonged extraction
time. Some lacerations.
Okay. Trauma Room 11.
Is he okay? Is
the governor okay?
All right, I'll go with
her, you get the next?
All right.
She put that bird down
in zero visibility.
Somehow avoided a school.
And the governor? Do we
know about his condition?
Not sure. He's in
the next ambulance.
Should be here any second.
Obvious tenderness
and bruising on her abdomen.
- Put me to work.
- Another 18-gauge IV.
One of hers just blew.
One immaculate IV,
coming right up.
How you feeling, Thea?
Like... I should've done more.
That's Betz, for sure.
Hey. You guys got this?
- Yeah.
- Go.
Listen. You did the best you
could in terrible weather.
And you know what? You
saved lives in the process.
Wait, wait, that...
This isn't Atlanta General!
Get me out of this place!
We're gonna take
good care of you.
Let's get a burn cart.
Governor, you
shouldn't be alone.
Is there anyone we can call?
Uh, just my office.
My daughter's at college.
My wife... my ex-wife
is in New Zealand.
One, two, three.
Oh, I bet you're loving this.
I most certainly am not.
Well, the sooner I'm
out of here, the better.
Rest assured my doctors will
give you the very best care.
Oh, come on. Who
are you kidding?
It's no secret how
you all feel about me.
I'm not about to give
you the chance to kill me
and call it complications.
We are professionals
with one goal:
caring for all our patients.
But we will do our best
to get you transferred
as soon as possible.
We'll try to get him
stable enough to move.
Can't happen fast enough.
Look, I don't want
any tests... Ow! Ow!
Possible broken clavicle.
EMTs say that he was briefly
unconscious at the scene.
Well, we'll have
to scan him when we can.
Chastain. It's some
kind of a joke.
Look, I-I told them
not to bring me here.
Somebody call my office!
Or-or bring me a phone!
Hey, hey, hey.
Can we finish assessing
your injuries first?
We're gonna get you
stable, give you some pain meds.
And then we will talk
about that transfer.
Any chest pain?
Just when I breathe in deep.
Sounds like pleuritic pain
from the rib fracture.
- Maybe this was an overcall.
- No, definitely not.
Needs to be checked out.
Oh, thank God! Thea!
Mom. Dad. I-I'm okay. I'm okay.
What the hell were you doing
flying in this weather?
Why would the governor
risk your life?
I'm her dad Quentin Dwyer,
this is my wife Jane.
What do you know?
Well, actually, Dr. Sullivan
is the ER doctor,
and can explain.
Your daughter has
sustained some injuries,
but we're still
assessing the extent.
I couldn't climb. Must've
been that crosswind.
Her heart sounds good, but I'd
like a few more tests before...
- What kind of tests?
- This laceration's gonna need stitches at some point.
What's wrong with her heart?
Likely nothing. We just
want to be thorough.
I don't believe this.
You should have
never taken that job.
There was a crosswind.
I couldn't climb.
She just said that.
Thea, you just said that.
Is he here? The governor?
Because I'd like to give
him a piece of my mind.
I just don't like
how he treats you.
I-I couldn't climb...
What's happening?
- Thea?
- Grabbing an intubation kit.
Page Dr. Sutton
and clear the CT!
Hold the elevator.
I've got this.
Okay, uh, page if
you need me, okay?
Hey, is she
from the heli crash?
Yeah, she's the pilot.
Her EKG was
intermittently arrhythmic.
I think it's related
to the head trauma.
She was oriented but
repeating herself,
then became unconscious.
We needed to intubate.
CT should give answers.
Hey, uh, you believe
Governor Betz is here?
Oh, my guess is, he's
not too happy about it.
So, I hear, uh, you and
Billie called it quits.
Well, she called it.
You okay?
Uh, yeah, I-I'm good.
You know, I-I think, uh...
everybody ended up right
where they ought to be.
You're gonna need an
X-ray on that clavicle,
but of course you can get
that done at another facility
if you feel more comfortable.
Oh, so I can go?
No.
We need a CT so we can
rule out anything serious
from your head trauma.
You were unconscious
at the scene.
Well, sooner the better.
Well, unfortunately,
CT is all backed up.
Due to budget cuts, we're
a bit short-staffed.
Do you think I'm stupid?
I know what's happening here!
You're-you're trying
to teach me a lesson!
Well, I don't have
to put up with it!
Now get me out of here now!
Get me my...
Ow.
ST elevation. He's
having a heart attack.
All right, let's go.
Activate the cath lab.
It's hard to believe
anyone walked away from it.
She landed that helicopter
at the intersection
of 13th and Piedmont.
Can you imagine?
Oh, no.
Multiple contusions.
Sulcal and cisternal effacement.
Swelling is severe already.
I'll book an OR. And you...
I know. Slam her with
diuretics, hyperosmolar therapy.
I'll bring her up.
Thanks, Billie.
Of course.
Hey, Marko.
Whoa, you actually
answered this time.
I was not expecting that.
I'm sorry,
work has been nuts,
- and I've had some personal stuff to deal with.
- Pravesh, please.
I've been around long enough
to know when I'm being ghosted.
All right?
Just be straight with me.
You've lost interest in my
longevity aspirations, right?
Listen, I've reviewed
the materials.
And I just don't feel like
it aligns with my interests.
Y-You think it's bogus crap
and you're not a bogus doctor?
I'm not the right guy.
And you deserve someone
who's passionate,
and that isn't me.
Look, sorry I have to go.
But listen, good luck.
I am positive that you're gonna
find the right
collaborator, okay?
Check it out.
- You made those?
- Mm-hmm.
Oh, they're adorable.
When did you get so
good at knitting?
They have a class
here. As therapy.
It's really, really relaxing.
Hey, will you give those to AJ?
To give to the boys from me?
Of course.
I really miss them.
Of course you do.
You'll see them soon.
AJ must regret this so
much, having babies with me.
Look, it has not
been easy, okay?
For either of you.
But if there's one
thing I know, it's that
AJ doesn't regret a thing.
Arjun and Elijah are the two
gifts he never even saw coming.
I hope when the boys are older,
they are for each other
what you are for me.
Everything.
His blood pressure is still
soft, despite the pressor.
I'm worried he's going
into cardiogenic shock.
Once we find the
lesion and open it up,
he should rebound.
Oh, wow, look at that.
Two prior stents.
Yeah, this isn't his
first heart attack.
None of this was on
his medical record.
I can't believe our
governor is not smart enough
to give us an honest
medical history.
Well, fake tough guys
like Betz are always afraid
that health problems
will make them look weak.
His pressure's still
dropping. Are we close?
I think I found it.
The culprit lesion.
Bingo. Obtuse marginal
branch in the circumflex.
That's a tiny vessel.
Opening something that small
won't improve his cardiac
function that much.
He'll still be
dependent on pressors.
Agreed. This man's heart was
in bad shape before the accident.
Yeah, he's lucky he
didn't arrest during the crash.
All right, well, let's
open the vessel up
and see what else we can do.
We will have
an official statement
a little bit later in
the day, but for now
the cause of the accident
- is still under investigation, but we will be releasing...
- Dr. Sullivan.
- Hey.
- You're back.
Yeah.
How was, uh, your
trek across España?
Great, yeah, really something.
I've always wanted to do that.
I'd love to pick your brain
when you've recovered
from the jet lag.
- Sure, a-anytime.
- Yeah.
- Good to see you, Dr. Feldman.
- Likewise.
Considering
what he went through,
it's nothing less
than a miracle.
But the doctors expect him
to make a full recovery.
However, he will be transferred
to a top-tier hospital for
the remainder of his care.
I can...
She's selling
scrapes and bruises
when I just heard from
Raptor that the man
was a cardiac time bomb
even before the accident.
And if they're not honest
about his prior heart issues,
they may spin it
to make it look like we
withheld appropriate care.
We have got to get
him transferred.
But so far everyone is full.
And what we discovered
is that you've had two stents
and two prior heart attacks.
None of which appears
in your medical records.
Look, let me...
Let me make something clear.
Neither you nor anyone
else in this hospital
are authorized to speak publicly
about my medical condition,
past or present.
Now, can you please check with
Dr. Voss about my transfer?
Yeah, that's not
going to be so easy, Governor.
We opened what we
could in the cath lab,
but your cardiac function
must've been bad from the start.
And right now your heart is
working only at ten percent.
Governor, your only hope for
survival is a heart transplant.
Your heart was
weak to begin with.
And now you're in heart failure.
The meds you're getting from
that big IV in your chest
are the only reason your heart
is beating strong enough
to keep you alive.
The only way you get on
the other side of this
is with a new heart.
We'll get you listed with UNOS,
the organ-sharing network,
but that's just the
start of the process.
Unfortunately you're sick
enough to need a new heart
but not sick enough to be
at the top of the list.
You're gonna have to wait.
How long?
Months, maybe longer.
What do I do all that
time? Wither away?
Well,
there are options.
We can get you out
of here with a VAD.
- Now, a VAD is...
- Yeah, yeah, I know what a VAD is.
My dad had one.
Plugging it into a
wall socket at night.
Barely able to shower.
It is an adjustment.
Yeah, but-but it
is not happening.
I am getting a new heart
and I'm not waiting.
I'm the governor,
for God's sake!
If you won't get me to the
top of the transplant list,
another hospital will.
- Hey.
Welcome back. We missed you.
Yeah, thanks, good to be missed.
- You got a minute?
- Yeah.
How's your immunotherapy
work progressing?
If you mean the MS trial...
- Yeah.
- The phase one results
weren't conclusive but
promising enough where I'm still
a believer that targeting
the EBV-infected cells
is gonna have good results.
But how about phase two?
Clinically, we're ready to
launch, but as you know,
we don't have the money yet.
We're barely 50% funded.
You know, I'm working on it.
Okay, then.
Well, how are you holding up?
Uh, yesterday wasn't bad.
Today's good.
Tomorrow, I don't...
I'm...
I'm just trying to make
some smart choices about
my treatment moving forward.
But-but I feel...
I-I feel good today.
So... And I'm glad to be back.
Thanks for the assist.
No problem.
Those parents seem wrecked.
Can't imagine.
The primary issue is
doing the craniotomy
and trying to
reduce the swelling.
But after the kind
of accident she had,
there could be surprises.
Of course.
To be honest, based on the CT,
this surgery is a Hail
Mary. But we have to try.
Okay.
Removing the skull cap.
This should
relieve the pressure.
All right, brain
looks good. Pulsatile.
Wouldn't it be cool
to fly a helicopter?
Choppers terrify me.
But if this goes well, maybe
Thea will give you a lesson.
She's hypertensive
and bradycardic.
Pressure must be building again.
Her brain is herniating
out of her skull.
Could be a seizure.
Or fluid overload.
Let's give her more
mannitol, stat.
Re-dose furosemide and get
the head of the bed up higher.
Oh, she's getting worse.
What am I not seeing?
It's something we can't see.
- A bleed?
- On the other side of the brain.
I couldn't see it in CT
because of the swelling.
When the brain
was decompressed,
the bleed had room to expand.
We have to open up the
skull on the other side.
Let's get her turned over.
Hey. You're here.
Yeah.
- It's good to have you back.
- Thanks.
It's a little weird.
I'm sure.
Just take it slow.
Have you, um...
Have you seen Dr. Voss yet?
No. I may be stalling.
I have some explaining to do.
Got to come clean.
Well, that's brave.
And hard, I'm sure.
A part of me would
just like to resign.
Keep everything a secret,
go work somewhere else.
The minute I tell Voss, the...
stigma of addiction
is on me forever.
Could end my career.
I'm sure people will understand.
Hmm.
I did.
And that means so much to me.
So...?
Will you tell her?
I will. I need to.
Okay.
- Hey.
How was Padma?
It's hard to say.
She's doing better, for
sure, I'm just worried
about how it'll be
when she returns.
Right, well, we'll just
take it one day at a time.
I assisted Billie
with the pilot.
It's not looking good.
If she dies and the
governor lives...
When he made her
fly in bad weather.
That is so unfair.
It's just a rough day.
You know, we've just had
so many of those lately.
Why? What happened?
So, I was talking to
Bell about his MS.
And I think that he was hoping
I was gonna get him a spot
in the second phase
of the MS trial.
But there is no phase two yet.
Right.
Hey, what about
that gazillionaire
who wanted to live forever?
I thought he was willing
to underwrite it, right?
Yeah, but I became a
doctor to help sick people,
not rich people who can't
accept that they're mortal.
If you help Marko,
you might help Bell
and thousands of other
people suffering from MS.
And pretend to be
passionate about something
that I don't even care about?
Sure, why not?
If it's for the greater good.
You always make complicated
things seem simple.
You always make simple
things complicated.
That's why we're a perfect fit.
Thank you.
How is she?
Was the surgery successful?
Mr. and Mrs. Dwyer,
this is Dr. Sutton.
She's the neurosurgeon who's
been operating on Thea.
She's one of our best.
Your daughter had a significant
injury to her brain.
We were able to repair a bleed
and relieve the pressure.
The swelling has gone down and
she's out of immediate danger.
My poor baby.
She'll recover, though, right?
We won't really know
that for some time.
Of course we will do
absolutely everything we can.
You mean she could die?
I'm afraid it's possible.
She's our only child.
Our everything.
She flew Apaches in Afghanistan.
Two tours without a scratch.
We'd almost stopped
worrying about her.
All she ever wanted
was to serve, you know?
To fly and serve.
She seems like
an amazing young woman.
She is.
Don't give up hope.
We won't either.
Come here.
So, I hear they were
unable to transfer you
due to lack of beds.
You know, all the ICUs
around town are full
because of the patients
we have to transfer
due to budget cuts?
That's correct.
But I have... a solution...
that solves both our problems
and keeps me here.
Okay, let's hear it.
I am willing to
save this hospital.
Restore the money
that's been cut.
From my discretionary fund.
Out of gratitude.
Gratitude.
My personal physician says...
that there are things
that you can do...
to move me to the
top of the UNOS list.
But in exchange you are
offering to save Chastain?
Correct.
So what'll it take...
to lift me higher?
An intra-aortic balloon pump.
We take a catheter and we insert
a small balloon in your aorta.
And it helps your
heart function.
Okay.
Are there risks?
Of course there are risks.
The balloon could rupture,
causing damage to your aorta.
Your platelet count might fall,
which means you could bleed out.
But you've done this?
Plenty of times when it
was called for medically.
And afterwards?
I'll be high on the list?
And could get a heart soon?
I can't believe
you're entertaining this.
Is he the person you want to
compromise your ethics for?
No, it's not about him, Hawkins.
But I-I think
about all the lives
we can save if we save Chastain.
Think about it. Every
hospital in Atlanta
will be strained to
the point of overwhelm
if Chastain cannot provide
the care that we do.
You do realize bumping
Betz up the list
- knocks somebody else down.
- Yeah.
Yet I'm willing
to live with that.
You think it's worth it.
For the greater good? Yes.
And what happens when he doesn't
keep his end of the bargain?
We have leverage.
The secrets he's been keeping.
The multiple heart attacks.
The stents he's had
implanted out of state,
hidden from his own doctors.
Oh, so you just want to
throw blackmail into the mix?
Pretend we break HIPAA.
He goes back on his word,
there will be no pretending.
Look, I don't like any of it.
But we have a chance to
do a whole lot of good
by doing just a little
bit of bad, right?
Come on, think about the Hawkins
who used to break all the rules.
Tell me what that guy would say.
He'd say go for it.
Um, thanks for agreeing
to meet me, Marko.
Well, I was a little surprised
after the way you blew me off.
Yeah.
Well, after we spoke, um,
I wondered if I was
being inflexible.
So I took another look at
the data that you gave me,
see if I missed anything.
- And did you?
- Yes.
Um, I came across a paper
that sort of blew my mind.
It's from the Academy of
Health and Lifespan Research.
- Excellent resource.
- Yes.
And their work on gene therapy
made me wonder if aging...
could actually be a
reversible disease.
And wouldn't
that be something?
I mean, I would
love to be around
to meet my great-great-
grandchildren someday.
Who wouldn't?
Right?
So, if you are still willing
to fund the second phase
of my clinical trial,
studying the relationship
between Epstein-Barr and MS...
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Pravesh,
I already told you
I'm completely on board.
You're the one who, uh,
couldn't stomach a
little bit of compromise
to make this happen.
But I like this new side of you.
I know you're still
on the fence, okay?
But I need you and you need me.
And there is nothing
wrong with that.
Dr. Sullivan. Ian.
Oh, I'm so sorry to
have kept you waiting.
- Yeah.
- It's been quite a day here.
Our three-ring circus has
added a few extra rings.
We squeaked by without you,
but I am so glad you're back.
Not quite back yet.
I hope Texas Children's
hasn't made a play for you.
No, no,
nothing like that.
But I do feel an
obligation to tell you...
um... I have a...
I have a personal issue...
that I-I need to take care of.
And I...
can't do that working the
way that... I used to work.
Oh, it's nothing
serious, I hope.
Do you want to work part-time?
No.
I think I...
It's best I resign.
Is this because we can't fund
the intrauterine surgery center?
No, it's not, n-nothing
to do with that.
I-I, I love it here. I-I
love being near my daughter.
The culture you've created,
it-it can't be beat.
But this private
issue, I-I don't...
I just don't see any
other way around it.
- I'm sorry.
- Oh.
Well, is there anything
I can do to help?
I wish that there was. I do.
We've loved having you
here, Dr. Sullivan.
Thank you.
Likewise.
Advancing the balloon
catheter over the guide wire.
And there we are, in
the descending thoracic aorta.
Just distal
to the subclavian.
Great positioning.
As high as possible above
the femoral bifurcation
and renal arteries, without
compromising blood flow.
Removing
the guide wire.
Uh, just a question.
Uh, from the numbers,
I would have thought
he'd be a VAD candidate, no?
Well, you're
not wrong, but a VAD...
Was not the best
option in this case.
Well, because it wasn't the
right thing to do medically?
Or 'cause it wouldn't have
boosted him up on
the transplant list?
Believe me, we are conflicted.
This wasn't just about Betz.
Actually,
you know what?
Uh, I don't want to know.
Attaching the pump console.
Initiate pumping.
All good. For now.
I'll notify UNOS
where Betz stands.
Conrad, I need your help.
It's Thea, the pilot.
I thought the surgery went
well, but I'm having trouble
keeping her O2 sats up.
If she dies of hypoxia,
then nothing I did in
surgery is gonna matter.
All right, well,
we'll figure this out.
It's the ICU.
I can't get her sats above 85
and her peak
pressures are rising.
Bilateral breath sounds? She
did have the rib fractures.
Pneumothorax was my
first thought too,
but she has lung sliding
on her ultrasound.
Okay, so no pneumo. Let's
get a portable chest X-ray.
I called them twice,
they're short-staffed.
But her chest imaging
post-intubation was clear.
- She has no history of asthma.
- And her resistance isn't high.
But her plateau is.
This is ARDS.
Damn, you're right.
Maybe she had an aspiration
event on her way to CT?
Leading to
inflammation and ARDS.
So we start low tidal
volume ventilation.
And we go up on the PEEP now.
But, Billie, this means...
I know. Deep sedation
and paralytics.
We will not be able to
monitor her neuro status.
If we can't get her sats up,
there'll be no neuro
status to monitor.
Let's do it.
I just got off
the phone with UNOS.
Governor Betz has been
moved to the top of the list
for a heart transplant.
I'd like an explanation.
Well, we performed a balloon
pump procedure on the governor
to assist with his
cardiac functioning.
A procedure he did
not actually need
but conveniently
moved him up the list.
Yeah, well, we don't
make the rules.
I agree with the decision.
And the procedure
was successful.
Do you know what this means?
The pilot who may
be about to die
because Betz made her
fly in unsafe conditions,
could end up giving
him her heart.
Thea is still hanging
on in the ICU.
We're not giving up on her.
And the procedure
on the governor
was part of a compromise
that will benefit us all.
And how would that be?
Betz agreed to unlock the
money we need to save Chastain.
He's going to restore the money
from his discretionary fund?
If he gets a heart.
And survives the transplant.
You'd better move heaven and
earth to keep Thea alive.
You're still here?
Yeah. Didn't want to leave yet.
Me, too.
Any sign?
No.
How are they doing?
What you'd expect.
They're strong.
You were good today.
Thanks.
Lost a lot of patients
the last few...
I was starting to feel like I
couldn't help anyone anymore.
Not sure why I pinned
my hopes on Thea.
It's hard to predict which
patients we'll get attached to.
But, you know, a lady chopper
pilot is pretty badass.
Says the resident badass.
Dr. Sullivan, Dr. Sutton.
Her eyes opened. Come quick!
You didn't have to wait for me.
I wanted to.
What's wrong?
I met with Marko.
And I signed on to
participate in his research.
And secured funding for
phase two of my trial.
What? That's incredible.
Congratulations.
But you're not happy?
I just, you know...
I feel like a con man.
Faking enthusiasm for something
I really don't even care about.
- Did you make promises you can't deliver?
- No.
Then you're not a con man.
Did you tell Bell?
- Yeah.
- Was he happy?
Thrilled.
Well, I call that a win.
You know...
I don't know how I ever
managed without you.
I'm serious.
You came here all
those years ago, and...
you changed my life.
I love you, Leela Devi.
I love you, too, Devon Pravesh.
Hey. What happened?
You're leaving?
I couldn't tell Kit the truth.
I'm sorry, Cade, but it would
mean giving up my career.
And I can only take
so much at one time.
I understand. I'm sorry.
I'm heartbroken.
I've loved being here with you.
And I hope that w-we can...
Anyhow, for what it's worth,
I think some time off may
be what I need anyway.
But I'm gonna make it up to you.
Everything I've done,
every way I've hurt you.
Look, that's in the past.
I'm proud of you.
Not near as proud
as I am of you.
I'll call you tomorrow.
Yes, and the day after.
Hey.
It's so exciting. For
Devon and for you.
When will phase two start?
Is he sure you qualify?
He says I meet all the
criteria for the trial
and says he's ready to go.
It's incredible news.
Wow, that was fast.
What's that?
There's been a motorcycle
accident outside of Macon.
UNOS may have a heart
for the governor.
I just can't believe,
after everything that jerk
put us through, we're
gonna save his life.
Well, he still has to
survive the surgery.
But, yes, it's what we
do. And I'm proud of that.
Well, I just hope we don't come
to regret this deal we've made.
You and me both, Randolph.
- So Thea's going to make it?
- Yeah.
That's incredible.
I know. I can't
quite believe it.
Bye, Ms. Jordan! Bye, Max!
Ah! Come here, you.
Daddy, are we
going to start decorating
for my birthday
when we get home?
Yup. Right after dinner.
You know, now that you're
going to be such a big girl,
pretty soon you're gonna have
to leave the kindergarten here
and go to first grade.
I want to go to first grade.
But first my birthday party.
Okay, birthday girl.
And Sammie. When
does she get here?
Hmm. Sammie and her dads, hey,
they're on a plane
right this minute.
I'm so excited!
Honey, you okay?
My tummy. It's hurting.
A lot.
She has a fever.
Maybe the flu, right?