Failure is an inevitability.
Dr. Cristina Yang.
Thank you, Dr. Hunt.
The, uh...
The procedure is
so relatively untried
that the associated
risks are unusually high.
Still, that shouldn't
be a reason
not to try.
Every scientist was told no,
over and over.
You okay? CRISTINA: Yeah.
Fortunately, the patient is
responding very well for now.
His vitals remain
stable, and it is our hope
that this will continue.
And if it does, I am
cautiously optimistic
that we can call this
procedure a success...
Uh,
"Homerun" is a better word.
Dr. Yang hit a homerun.
Thanks to her, baby Nathan
is thriving this morning.
The ones we remember.
The ones who changed our lives.
The Curies, the
Salks, the Barnards.
We'll print another portal vein.
We'll perform tests
on that and look
for material that
will hold up better.
So we go back to
the drawing board?
They're the ones who
wouldn't take no for an answer.
Yes, ma'am.
Morning.
Is that your name I see on
the OR board this afternoon?
Well, it's just a cholie.
Getting my feet wet.
You're gonna miss
Kepner's wedding?
Well, I scheduled my first surgery
when everyone will be gone.
I didn't want to
make a big fuss.
You got a tumor debulking.
You gonna be done in
time? I will be done on time.
All right.
You're operating, too, huh?
The medication's helping?
Mmm.
I'm proud of you, Bailey.
I don't want to make a big fuss.
I thought that went pretty well.
You're off my service. And
you've got to be over your hours.
You should go home
and take a day off.
What? What for?
You don't know when
to keep your mouth shut.
They needed to hear it
was an extraordinary...
I am not comfortable
with you speaking for me,
especially about this case.
Ross actually said
what needed to be said.
And you were not comfortable
at all. You were tanking in there.
I'm only at 68 hours
for the week. See?
JAMA wants an interview.
It should be short.
Conference room C.
I'm worried about you.
You've been
going too fast lately.
And I'm not the only
one who noticed. Who?
It doesn't matter who.
Have I screwed up?
Is my work not up to...
No. Your work is great.
It's just, you're becoming...
You're going to
burn yourself out.
I think I know what this is.
You just need to
work off some tension.
We're not doing that anymore.
If you're worried I think
it's more than it is, I don't.
It's just to relax you.
It's you who needs to relax.
I'm fine.
I'm sorry. Don't shut me out.
Ross, go home.
Okay, so first we determine
the receptive field of
all the sensors, right?
Yeah. Okay.
Derek, the guys from Kleiss
Neuroscience will be here in 20.
I can't. Once I'm done here,
I have to get Bailey
to a music class.
Um, what's this?
They want to talk to me
about a research thing.
It's not just a thing.
It is the presidential
initiative on brain mapping.
It is the thing.
Okay. No.
We're starting phase two.
Okay? He's my brain now.
Meredith can have
the rest. I get his brain.
I'll get rid of them.
No, you won't.
You will say yes to them.
And you're both gonna be
at Kepner's wedding, yes?
Mmm-hmm. Uh-huh.
I'm not going. Bailey's
doing surgery, finally.
And I'd rather do that
than watch Arizona
stand up there looking gorgeous,
while I'm some pathetic,
shriveled, leftover, discarded thing
she scraped off her shoe.
Ew! No, don't do that.
No! I know you think
this is just what I do.
Oh, hey, hey! You're all
going to the wedding, right?
Yes. Is it mandatory?
This is exactly what you
do. Exactly what you do.
I know what I do,
and this is not that.
She was important.
We were something.
Maybe they were something.
No. No.
How's your dad?
He's told all the nurses you're
his kid. He's proud. How is he?
Don't know. Don't really care.
Help! You gotta help my
boy! He's been run over!
Sir, do not move!
Don't move him!
No, no, no. Stop!
Stop! The gurney!
Keep him still.
Backboard and C-spine!
He was driving the tractor.
He hit a bump and fell off.
He went under the wheel
and the chaser bin, too.
Has he moved at all since?
Yeah, yeah, he
was trying to get up.
Okay, let's get him
straight to the lodox.
All right, let's go!
What's his name?
Cody. His name's Cody.
Cody, I'm Dr. Robbins.
Can you hear me?
You didn't call an ambulance?
I called 911. But
then he passed out,
and I was so
scared, I couldn't wait.
So I brought him here myself.
You say he was moving before?
Yeah. That's good, right?
Sir, I'm gonna need
you to step back.
We're going to do
everything we can.
Uh, excuse me, Grey?
Uh, the press would
like some photos
of the printer. Is
this a good time?
Oh, sure. Where do you want us?
Oh, well, it's actually...
It's for the Nathan
Glazier case. So...
But it's printing my work.
Yeah, that's fine. I
mean, no one would know.
We can come back.
Okay, right by the printer.
Oh, Dr. Yang, that's perfect.
It's a burst fracture at C6.
Page Torres. His belly's full of
blood. He's going to the OR now.
He should've waited
for the ambulance.
I think this guy paralyzed his own
kid by bringing him here himself.
We don't know that
yet, Alex. I got this.
Why don't you go
be with your dad?
That's all right. What?
You must have
questions. Long-lost father?
I mean, I'd have a billion.
Help me get him to the OR,
and then I'll call you
if I need you, okay?
Let's go.
Is he gonna be okay?
He has a lot of
internal bleeding,
so we need to
operate right away.
Also, his neck is
broken. Oh, my God.
He can move, right?
He was moving. That
was before he was...
We'll know more
in a bit. We're doing
everything that
we can. So sit tight.
Ohh! Ugh!
Wow, you look... Nope! No.
Don't say I look nice.
Like a train wreck.
But I can see where it's going.
Um, what are you doing here?
I'm hunting bridesmaids.
Now is that a farm tradition?
Are you gonna be there?
All right. I totally
understand if you're not.
I just... Do you
want me to be there?
Yes! Of course.
Then I'll be there.
Thank you.
All right. Okay.
Wait. You know what?
Watch it. The hair is...
Elliot Hooks, 20, here
for repeat debulking
of bronchial tumors.
This will be his...
Wait, that can't be right.
It's right.
Three-hundred twelve surgeries.
I started treatments
when I was four.
His growths recur,
build up and threaten
his larynx and lungs.
We have to laser them out.
Every seven to 10 days.
Three-hundred
twelve? That's rough.
I'm used to it.
My folks bought a
house a few blocks away.
Kind of the way you move
close to the good school.
No, we're not doing this.
Sorry? MIRANDA: Elliot...
What if I can culture
your tumor cells in a lab
and custom design a drug
that can stop the growth,
find exactly the
medicine to stop them?
And no surgery?
No surgeries ever again.
Oh, my God.
Right? Oh, my God.
You don't think this young
man's had enough surgery?
Yes, ma'am. I'm sorry.
Damn right, you're sorry.
Now let's go open up my lab.
No!
I haven't had enough surgery.
I have waited and waited
for you to get back in the OR,
and damn it, enough is enough.
I'm here to study surgery,
and I'm being left behind.
And I deserve better than this.
So I...
I'm just tired.
Let's go.
We need to do Elliot's
procedure once more
to get the samples I need.
And you will perform
it, beginning to end.
Prep the man.
Thank you.
Watch yourself in there.
His breath in incredibly nasty.
It's fine. It's not.
It's rank.
I can smell what
he ate last Tuesday.
That is Zenker's diverticulum.
Now these muscles here
should be working together
to push food down the esophagus.
But unfortunately, Dalton's
are working against each other.
So the wall forms
a sack, and that's
where the food's getting caught.
I always feel like I have
something caught in my throat.
He got pneumonia once
from getting food in his lungs.
He's a mess. I'm a mess.
Well, I'll be cutting
into the lower muscle,
so that'll allow the food
to pass right through.
And the walls will
tighten up on their own.
Anything we should worry about?
Well, of course, with all
surgeries there are certain risks,
worst case being
stroke or even death.
But these are all very
minimal in this case.
There is a small risk of damage
to the vocal cord
nerves, though.
What, like, I won't
be able to talk?
That's the worst case.
It's very unlikely.
You have a cute butt.
Dalton!
You heard the man. I
might not speak again.
And I don't want to
leave anything unsaid.
You have a sweet caboose.
Also, I never
liked your brother.
What?
I also could have
kept that one to myself.
But it felt good to say it.
You're an idiot. How soon
can you put him under?
Ugh!
There you are.
Yeah, she is the
magical healer of children.
But you're done now, right?
You're done? Can we go?
Can we get one more?
Please come with me.
Why are you here?
Are you bailing on
your wedding? What?
No! I'm not bail... Why
would you say that?
No, I need you. Come with me.
Gentlemen, as you
know, the President himself
has issued a mandate
for our community
to devise a full and complete
map of the human brain.
Kleiss Neuroscience
wants to lead
the pack towards that goal.
We've got a huge
NIH grant to do it with.
The first steps will be
developing the technology.
The sensors you
developed for your BCI work
are the most
responsive we've seen.
I'm flattered. Thank you.
Wait till you see
what we're doing.
I'm afraid that Dr. Torres
and my BCI work
is all-consuming.
I don't have the time.
This will be the compensation
that you'll receive
just for consulting
long-distance.
Okay, see, I'm not even
gonna turn that over.
It's not about the compensation.
Turn over the
paper. I don't want to.
Just turn it over. It's
not about the money.
It's a lot of money.
I don't care how much
it is. It's not about that.
Will you just watch our movie?
Yes. Yes, he will.
Just listen to what
they have to say.
Absolutely.
Mapping the way to tomorrow.
You want to watch
the movie? Here we go.
Once more. Up.
I'm too tired.
Sorry, darling.
Could you, uh, give us a sec?
I got a question.
I recognized you the
first time I saw you.
How do you forget a
wife and three kids?
How do you do that?
I made such a
mess of everything.
The more time went
by, the more drugs I did,
the more I let
myself forget 'cause
I couldn't stand
myself, you know?
I remember you, though.
I remember you used
to laugh in your sleep.
Well, that's when I
was, like, four, right?
You were just a happy kid.
I guess I fixed that, huh?
Yeah, I remember you
took me to the fair once.
It was one of
those traveling ones
where all the rides are
crappy and you might die.
But, uh, we rode
every ride twice.
It was a good night.
I remember that.
Your mom was having a meltdown.
She was tearing the
wallpaper off the walls,
saying someone
was hiding in there.
That woman was
such a damn mess...
What about this other family?
I mean, how'd you
leave it with them?
Better.
I could maybe try and go back.
Naomi's tough, but
she's not your mother.
She's not bug-eyed crazy.
All right, this has
got to stop now.
Mom was not the problem.
I'm not trying to
bad-talk your mother,
but you can't know what a strain
it is being with someone like that.
Who do you think
took care of her?
Kept track of her?
Got her committed so
she wouldn't hurt herself?
Who do you think
took care of your kids?
I did the best I could.
Oh, well, if that's your best
then you should just hang it up!
Your best is worthless!
I was the dad!
I was a kid, but I was the dad!
You were nothing!
You were gone!
You're worthless!
Okay! Okay, okay.
Walk away.
Okay, I can fuse C5 and
6, but I have to work fast
if we even want a shot
at avoiding paralysis.
Oh, thank you. You're
a genius. 10 blade.
I am, actually, well,
sort of a genius.
Derek and I start
phase two today,
tactile pressure feedback.
Awesome! Good for you.
Well, it's good for you, too.
The goal is a prosthetic leg
as sensitive and as responsive
as the one that you lost.
Get you back to where you were.
Okay, um, prep the
neck. I'm gonna scrub.
Hey, I told you I'd
call you if I need you.
How's your dad?
Where do you want me?
Grab a clamp. Help
me find the bleeders.
Meredith!
April, what are you doing?
Oh, God. Are you
making a break for it?
Don't worry. I know
what to do. Really?
Why does everybody
think I'm running?
I'm not running. Come with me.
But I... No.
You bailed on every
single one of your
fittings for your
bridesmaid's dress, so,
I brought the seamstress to you.
You will look pretty
for my wedding.
Hello. No clothes, please.
You guys are supposed
to be doing this stuff for me.
I saw your, uh,
press conference.
What happened to you up there?
I was supposed to tell them
what I did, but I'm not totally sure.
What do you mean?
I'm not sure why
the kid is still alive.
The conduit? You
thought it would fail?
It did fail. We adjusted, but
I don't know what I did, Mer.
It's like slapping
the side of a TV.
I fixed it, but
I'm not sure how.
I feel like a complete fraud.
So you just went ahead anyway?
I mean, you didn't
mention that to anyone?
To who, Mer? You weren't
talking to me, Alex was against me.
I had no one. I had no
choice. It was his best shot.
Wow. You were right.
We are in two completely
different places.
Mer, please. No, I
mean, I may overreach,
and I may have
something to prove, but...
I will never be as
arrogant as you are.
You know what, Meredith?
Go to hell.
I have listened to your
crap for weeks now,
and I'm not gonna stand
here and take it anymore.
You stand here.
And that's why at
Kleiss Neuroscience
tomorrow is today.
Well? Very impressive.
Like I said, I'm overextended.
Derek, they're just
asking for a consult.
This is not a relocation, right?
No, no, no, no, no.
Just, it'd be a couple of
visits every couple of months.
Once again, I'm flattered, but
I... I just don't have the time.
Just guide us in
what we're doing.
Not if this is
what you're doing.
Wait, you think that there's
something wrong with our approach?
Our method is the
bleeding edge of...
Your method couldn't
map the human sphincter.
Derek.
I'm sorry, but they made me.
You're looking at a planet.
I'm saying step back
and look at the universe.
You don't kiss someone
by puckering your lips.
You see someone and you
remember why you desire them.
Your sympathetic nervous
system quickens your pulse,
your frontal lobe
lowers your inhibitions,
and you need to kiss them.
It happens all at once.
We're impulsive and compulsive.
That's how the brain works.
Stop looking at what we do.
Look at why we do it.
Is he saying change
the sensor placement?
No, you don't get it, Tim.
- I want to.
He's saying change everything.
He is saying... Where are you...
That this diffuser/tensor
imaging is old news.
He's saying that
cortical firing...
They're starting to get it.
Deeper cuts and faster
pictures of the whole brain.
Oh, you know that dress,
the purple one with the stripes?
Yeah.
It does make you look fat.
What?
You said it was pretty. I lied.
But I want my last
words to be honest ones.
You are gorgeous.
But in that dress...
Bastard. you look
like a parade float.
I wore that dress
to three weddings.
It's our song. Last chance, hon.
Guys, the risk of damage to
your vocal chords are so minimal...
Cut them. Cut
the chords, please.
Uh, this is your
last stop, Karen.
Hey.
Come here.
I'll see you after.
Move it more laterally.
There.
Got it.
I owe you an apology.
I shouldn't have
spoken to you that way.
Why? You got what you wanted.
And you were right.
Part of my job is to teach you.
I haven't been doing that.
I wasn't sure if I was
being rewarded or punished.
Part of my mystique.
Oh, get that one.
Never be afraid to
stand up for yourself.
Just be sure you're
right when you do.
That's so true.
I have to stand up
for what I deserve.
That is so incredibly true...
I know, I said it.
You missed that one.
You tell me how
you can give 100%
to your family and
100% to your job.
It's categorically impossible...
Because you keep
screwing with my research.
Oh, God, Mer.
My borrowing your printer had
nothing to do with your dead sheep.
Did you ever think maybe your
research is failing all on its own?
Right, because I'm a terrible
doctor. We've established that.
No, I never said that.
You said that...
I never said that!
But you said I was
a terrible person,
over and over,
because I don't agree with you.
Because I'm
committed to my work.
Because I don't want a baby?
When did I become
such a monster to you?
- Can I talk to you?
- Ugh.
Shane, go away.
I thought they should
hear what you did,
and you downplayed it.
Shane, I said get out! Go home!
And I was right.
What?
An e-mail from the Harper Avery
Foundation
requesting a case study
and patient status. What?
You're in consideration
for this year's award.
Now you take off,
and you take off.
Are you gonna wear
your high-heel leg?
'Cause it looks amazing. But you
always get so sore after a while.
Also, it's on a farm,
so it might be muddy.
I'll be fine.
Okay.
Were you able to
decompress the cord?
Is he paralyzed?
Uh! It's too soon to tell.
You gonna tell the dad?
- Tell the dad what?
The spinal injury was likely
caused by the father
transporting him.
Oh, God. You wait
for an ambulance.
Well, he didn't know.
Yeah, well, and now
maybe his kid might not walk?
I mean, he would
have been better off
if he had just
kept his hands off.
Callie, stop it.
His kid was hurt, and
he was trying to fix it.
Sometimes we try
to make things better
and we have no idea that
we're actually causing more pain.
Of course we don't tell him.
No.
I can't get in there to staple.
There's too many strictures.
All right. I'm gonna
go in through his neck.
Okay. Yeah.
There you go.
What do you think
he said to her?
No idea.
Though, I don't
think there's much
they wouldn't say to each other.
Right? How do you
get to that point?
There's nothing I wouldn't
say to you. Oh, I doubt that.
We are nowhere near that point.
You shed.
You shed hair. You shed bras.
That is untrue and unkind.
You stay over my
place for the weekend,
and there's hair all
over every pillow,
and a bra on every door knob.
You got a bra in my
silverware drawer.
Which one? Was it blue?
How do you have so many bras?
Well, you have angry face.
I have angry face?
Yeah, when you are
thinking or solving a problem
or just counting change,
people think you're pissed off.
Well, I'm not pissed off.
Well, I know.
It's just your face.
I'm getting pissed off.
Then you should smile more.
You have a beautiful smile.
I think he said he loved her.
Maybe.
Say it loud and go from there.
What?
No, it's something Mark
Sloan said to me once.
He's ready, Doctors.
He said, "If you love somebody,
"you tell 'em, even if you're
scared it'll cause problems
"or burn your
life to the ground.
"Say it loud and go from there."
That's nice.
Oh, my God!
What are you doing here?
I'm working. On our wedding day?
I have to earn enough to take
time off after our wedding day.
You saw me. Barely.
I didn't see your dress.
I didn't see your hair.
Do you have a really big hat on?
This is such bad
luck! Such bad luck!
No, no, no, no, no. No.
It's good. It's good, 'cause...
If the first time
I saw you today
was in the dress with the hair,
looking that beautiful,
I would just be reminded of
how much I don't deserve you,
and I'd probably pass out.
And we'd wind up back
here. We wouldn't be married.
They'd have to cut off my
suit, and I'm still paying for it.
I'm glad I saw you like this,
'cause I'm gonna see
you like this a lot more
than I'll see you like that
for the rest of our lives.
And I love you like this.
I love you, too.
I can't wait.
Oh! Hey, don't
forget black socks.
Matthew?
It's possible the lack of
nerve response is due to
uh, trauma and swelling
to the spinal cord.
It could recede with time.
And if it doesn't?
We're looking at paralysis,
likely quadriplegia.
We'll have to wait and see.
It's my fault, isn't it?
He was moving when it happened.
Then I brought him here.
I did this.
I did this to him.
You were trying to help him.
Whatever happens,
it's not your fault.
Look, you were just trying
to do your best for your kid.
Okay?
Well, unfortunately, I wasn't
able to access the diverticulum
with the scope, so
we went in surgically.
But it went seamlessly and he
is gonna have very fresh breath.
Thank you. He's waking up.
All right.
Hi, honey.
What's wrong with him?
Page Shepherd right away.
Dalton?
Excuse me.
I can compete as a
mother and as a surgeon.
You just don't think I
can compete against you.
You can't, because,
Mer, this is all I do.
This is all I want to do.
So don't whine to me because you
made a decision you regret now.
You think I regret my family?
I think you feel left behind
and that sucks for you,
but no one forced
you out of the game.
I am not out of the game!
I just won't sabotage
my friends to win it!
Oh. Oh, is that what I do?
That's what sharks do.
You called it our first day.
Well, as I recall, I
was talking about you.
How long have you
been sleeping with Shane?
He blushes at an exposed ankle.
He saw you in your
underwear and didn't bat an eye.
That is none of your business!
You don't have
to justify it to me.
He's just hooking up
with the best teacher
to make sure he can
get everything he can.
It's what you did all through med
school and all through intern year.
Congratulations.
You've become the
thing you worship.
And you became the
thing we laughed at.
Hey.
I'm sorry. I... You
don't have to be sorry.
I mean, it's like you said.
You did your best, and...
I turned out all right, so...
Thanks.
I just want my family
again. We're not family.
All right, I turned out
all right because you left.
Aaron and Amber and Mom,
they're okay now because you left.
If you'd stayed, I'd probably
be selling beer or something.
Or maybe I would've followed in
your footsteps and ODed by now.
But you left us, thank God. So
you can stop beating yourself up.
Maybe you can fix it
with your kid in Florida.
Good luck with that.
Bye, Jimmy.
He had a massive stroke.
It could've
dislodged a blood clot
in the carotid
during the surgery.
It's a rare outcome for any
surgery, but it does happen.
We will pursue every avenue for
rehabilitation, but
I'm afraid that...
You can't fix it?
I'm sorry.
So he's awake, but...
He can't speak?
Not at this point, no.
But we will do everything
that we can for him, Karen.
I am so sorry.
Dalton.
Honey?
Can he hear me?
We're not sure.
Was it something we did?
No.
It was totally
unforeseen. It's...
I...
What? What's that?
Nothing. Mmm, nothing.
Hey. You're not going
to the wedding, right?
Can you cover my patients?
No, I am going,
because when you stand up
for what you deserve, you get it.
And I deserve her.
I am not gonna be thrown aside.
I am going to that wedding,
and I am going to stand
up in front of everyone,
and I'm gonna tell
Arizona how I feel,
and she's gonna be
forced to deal with it.
And I sound crazy.
And this is the thing,
the thing that I do!
Yeah, it is!
Thank you! Thank you
for not letting me do that.
I got your patients.
Thank you.
Oh, crap! What?
I just told Jo that
I would cover her,
and I'm already at my
80 hours for the week.
Oh, I can fix that.
Put in your password.
Just go to "Menu."
Down here is "Manual input."
Let's put you at 60.
You do this?
I can't believe you don't.
When do you sleep?
Oh, Hunt, Avery's stroke
patient is in my care.
You're gonna go to
the wedding, right?
'Cause you've been yelling
at people all day today.
Yeah, I'm gonna change and
get Emma. Derek, the Kleiss guys?
It wasn't enough just
to turn them down?
You had to tear down
everything that they're doing?
Do you think I don't want
to help them? It's bad timing.
And you need me to
keep my focus here.
I know. I do, but...
To turn this place
into an innovation hub.
It is a call to serve, Derek.
It is a presidential initiative.
The President asks you to serve?
You serve. You do
what is asked of you.
Well, your service was
a calling and a sacrifice.
But this is about guys just trying
to score some government money
and stacking the
deck with my name.
I appreciate how you
feel. I do. But this?
This isn't that.
ARIZONA: Oh!
So pretty.
Hey, um, after this is over, I
want to have a toast to celebrate.
Oh. There'll be
plenty of toasts.
No, no, no. For phase two.
Ah.
Your research.
Well, our research.
It's yours, too.
You inspired it.
I wouldn't be
doing it without you.
Okay.
Are you crying?
Yeah. You know...
Weddings.
Yeah. Come on.
At their engagement party,
I mean, I kind of knew...
Oh!
"Mint to be." Cute!
What is in these?
Oh, we're supposed to
open those when they kiss.
Nice.
You just ruined
Kepner's wedding.
Huh? Come on.
So I spent all day in the lab.
It'll take a few weeks, but
I think I can cure this kid.
Medically. You
know, once and for all.
What's going on
with you, Miranda?
You're handing surgeries
over to residents.
You're back in your
lab, where you hid
when you first
got that infection.
Hey, what are you saying?
Well, I'm worried
you're quitting surgery.
I see.
Okay.
While we're on the
subject of quitting surgery,
maybe it's time we talked about,
uh, why the hell you
up and quit surgery.
Look, I told you, I want
my family. I need to be here.
Hell, look at you.
Do you think we'd
have gotten this
under control if I
hadn't been here?
Did it ever occur to you
that my symptoms got worse
when you showed up
having quit your job?
Okay.
So, that's what
we're saying, is it?
Thing's about to start. Mmm-hmm.
Mr. Evans?
He's having an MI, get
an EKG and a crash cart.
You look so beautiful.
Aw! That's really sweet.
But, uh, you're gonna be
all puffy if you keep that up.
Are you gonna get it together?
Yeah.
No, I'm sorry.
Callie's trying so hard to
forgive me and to take care of me,
and it's driving me crazy.
I thought you wanted...
I do! I do.
I love her and I want her back.
And I broke us.
And I want to fix it.
But she wants to fix me.
The reason that I
cheated that night...
Someone was attracted to me.
And she never knew me before.
She only knew me after.
And I was enough for her.
And Callie she knew me
before and she loved me before.
And now sometimes
I feel like I'm not...
I'm not... You're not?
It's not fair.
It's not fair. It's
not her fault.
It's not her fault that I
hate feeling this way.
And Callie's just... She's
trying to fix everything.
And I'm finally feeling
okay the way that I am now!
And I'm not sure that Callie
will ever make me feel that way.
I'm so sorry that you're
going through all this.
Today.
I'm here.
Oh, thank God!
Acute MR. He might
have a chordal rupture.
We won't know
until we open him up.
I paged you to get
Yang. Yang is his doctor.
Yang's at the wedding. I'm here.
Besides, I treated him. I did a
pericardial window by myself.
I know what I'm doing.
Then find Russell or
page the on-call doctor.
Ruth, clear an OR right now
and prep him for a sternotomy.
Dr. Ross, I don't think so. We
should wait for an attending.
You want to wait? We'll wait.
Then you can explain
to the attending
how this man died because
you wouldn't let me help him.
Is that what you want to do?
Yang forgot.
I knew one of you would forget.
No.
Ah! Thank you!
I knew you'd make it.
Okay, so when we get out there,
Arizona's gonna take my bouquet.
So if you and Meredith can
be on either side of my train...
How dare you say
I haven't changed.
I don't have to justify my
choices to you, not one.
How dare you say I am the
same person I was when I got here,
before I knew Burke
and Owen and you.
Your life looks different
because it's filled with
houses and husbands and kids.
And my mine looks
the same, but I'm not.
I've changed. I'm
doing this alone.
And that's...
That's just as hard
as what you're doing.
But I thought I would
at least have you.
I'm so jealous of you, I
want to set things on fire.
You did what I tried
to do, and I couldn't.
And you don't even
know how you did it.
You have nothing
but time and focus.
You're not who we
were when we got here.
You are who we
both set out to be.
And you've become something
we never saw coming.
You are as good a mother
as you are a surgeon.
And I'm happy for you.
But we are growing
apart. I know.
And I don't want to
compete with you, but I do,
because we're supposed
to push each other
and make each
other better forever.
Since the day we met, right?
Right.
Okay. So then...
God, I know. I'm
so glad because...
Oh! Shut up!
Today is not the day.
You two, super neat that
you're working your crap out,
but not today.
And you! You know what?
Stop talking about
adultery on my wedding day,
because it is my wedding day!
I should be feeling
very special right now.
I should be flounced and
fluffed up and checked over
and handed tissues and
told not to cry with joy.
So just... You know what?
Stop thinking about you,
and you make me feel special.
Would you like a tissue?
I'm gonna... You looked good.
You know what? The veil
turned out to be so pretty.
And you...
The pericardium's open!
I cannot believe
we're doing this.
All this blood. Where
is it? Where is it?
Ah. There. Ventricular perf.
Got it. I got my finger on it.
Okay. We put him on bypass,
right? And put a patch on.
No. The perf's widening already.
I'll throw a stitch in.
I've seen Yang do it.
2-0 silk. Doctor? Bypass...
I have it! 2-0 silk!
Oh, God. No, no, no.
It's tearing. It's all tearing.
Shane, wait.
I can fix this. I can fix it!
Call for help.
Who? Anyone.
Shane, his heart
wall is disintegrating.
We can just hold
pressure and call for help.
I got it. I got it. I'll do
it. Just shut up! Shut up!
Shane, get back.
Get your hand out of his chest
and get away from the table.
Don't touch her!
I got her!
I got her.
Okay, we ready?
Yeah. Okay.
Oh! You made it!
I made it. Oh, great! Come here.
Chief!
You came! Of course.
The whole hospital's
practically here.
Really? Yeah.
You're very well liked.
Okay, well, now you have to
go, 'cause I'm gonna start crying.
Because if it weren't for you, none
of this would be happening to me.
You deserve it, all of it.
And you look beautiful.
Thank you.
Congratulations.
Hey.
And how are the kids?
Zola cried 'cause she couldn't
come with me, but they're fine now.
Oh, she's spoiled from having
you around so much now.
You look spectacular. Thank you.
Hey? What?
Um, listen, I just
want to thank you
because this
research is gonna take
so much more
time than I expected.
And I couldn't do it without
the time you're giving me.
And I know you're turning
down a lot of stuff, so thank you.
It's my pleasure.
Hey. You made it.
Wow. Hi.
We're the only
family we need, right?
And we'll be together
forever, right? You and me.
And if we have
kids, we'll be great.
I'll be a great dad,
and you'll be great,
and it'll be just us.
We won't need
anybody else, okay?
Yes. Absolutely.
Dr. Webber, help!
You have to come!
Wow.
Go get re-scrubbed.
Ross?
What do we got here, son?
I did this.
Well, let's just see, okay?
So I hear there's a
tear in the right ventricle.
It's my fault.
All I know is, they
need Webber here
and Shepherd
wants you to get him.
Apparently, he went to
deal with the generator.
Well, you did well, son.
We're okay here. I did this.
You didn't do anything.
This is not your fault.
This just happened.
I think we need
some bypass, though.
Well, what do you think, Ross?
You did good.
We're all done here.
Why don't you go get some rest?
No!
When I come
back, she'll be dead.
It's my fault. I sent
her to the basement.
Ross, look at me.
Look at me.
I got her.
She's gonna be fine.
Go get some rest.
Failure is inevitable.
Unavoidable.
Laps! More laps! Suction.
Murphy, get in here!
Let's get him on bypass.
And let's take someone
from cardio now!
On it.
But failure should
never get the last word.
There is no greater
example of God's power
than the love we
share between us.
April and Matthew are here today
to commit that
love to each other
before God and
before all of you.
So let's pray.
Heavenly father,
watch over April and Matthew
as they take the first steps
on a journey that will last them
the rest of their
lives on earth.
Yes, it's Dr. Shepherd.
Sir, we have a call for
you. It seems very urgent.
Okay. Hold please.
I'll put it through. Thank you.
You have to hold
on to what you want.
Dr. Derek Shepherd? DEREK: Yes.
Please hold for the
President of the United States.
What?
Please hold for the
President of the United States.
And give them the strength to
commit their love to one another.
Unshakable through any storm,
unbreakable in the
face of any stress.
A promise we simply
refuse to break.
You have to not
take no for an answer,
and take what's coming to you.
Never give in.
Starting heart massage.
Never give up.
Come on.
And you, April and Matthew's
closest friends and family,
are here today to bear
witness to their union.
Will you promise to love
and support their marriage
in all the days to come?
If so, please
respond, "We will."
We will. We will.
Now...
I, uh... I've known
the two of you...
What? For quite some time...
I'm sorry.
Stand up.
And I'm happy to be here
today to be able to do this for you.
I...
April and Matthew, I
have known the two of you
for quite some time, and
I'm happy to be here today...
I love you, April.
I always have.
I love everything about you.
Even the things I don't like,
I love.
And I want you with me.
I love you, and I think
that you love me, too.
Do you?
Stand up and take it.