Your body contains
approximately
35 trillion cells,
and every one of them
is constantly being pulled down
to Earth by gravity.
Look at these losers.
Looks like they're eating
each other's faces.
♪ I backed my car into
a cop car the other day ♪
I once made out
through a tornado.
Really?
Went for gum later,
♪ Well, he just drove off, sometimes
life's okay ♪ - and the 7-Eleven was gone.
♪ I ran my mouth off ♪
- ♪ A bit too much ♪
- And a guitar?
- Probably on their way to an open mic.
- ♪ Ah, what did I say? ♪
I play guitar.
That's different.
When you're lying down,
gravitational forces
are spread between
the thorax, abdomen, and legs.
Get a dorm,
face-eaters!
Don't they know that
all love sucks eventually?
Too bad there's no
sappy love songs about
the part where
your husband leaves you,
you cry every time
you see his toothbrush,
so you're living on
your best friend's couch.
Well, stay as
long as you want.
It's been perfect, hanging out
and watching bad movies,
trying every dinner special
at Kung Pao's.
It's been nice
to think about anything
other than Amelia.
Hear she's back at work,
by the way.
Yeah, I heard
that, too.
Stand up too fast,
and blood rushes downward,
away from the brain.
It causes dizziness
or even fainting.
So, he moved there, and he's not
coming back to say goodbye?
I don't want
to talk about it.
- How's Jo?
- ♪ Good news will work its way ... ♪
She's staying with
Link for a few days.
Other than that, she doesn't
want to talk about it.
Oof. This is massive.
This is a sea change.
How are you?
♪ Well, we'll float on,
good news is on the way ♪
I don't really want
to talk about it.
Ah, right.
You're probably not one
to judge someone
for leaving town
with no goodbye
or return date.
It's a minor miracle
our cells get anything
done at all.
How's Link?
Have you spoken to him?
♪ Already we'll all float on ♪
If Link can't love me for me,
no matter who the father is,
then we don't have anything
to talk about.
Because the human body
has to perform even
the simplest of tasks...
I'm guessing you don't want to
talk about that, either.
...under unimaginable
pressure.
Well, my mom e-mailed
some venue suggestions... 13.
Planning this wedding
is gonna be a part-time job.
Or a full-time job.
That's why they call it
a wedding planner.
We could hire one.
'Cause you don't want
to plan the wedding?
No, of course...
of course I do.
I'm just a little anxious
to check in
on one of my patients,
and this elevator just
doesn't seem to want to...
Oh.
You coming or...?
Yep.
Dr. Hunt. Dr. Altman.
Kiddos.
You're looking like... kids.
We...
There's a VIP guest today,
uh, Hunt.
Uh, Griffin Ford.
Tech billionaire...
blew up a rocket
over a gas station.
Oh, yeah, thanks
for the heads up.
Oh, oh, you betcha.
Will you be visiting
the cardio floor?
Depends on how bored
he is.
Oh, mm, two more
wedding venues from my mom.
I'll forward them
to you.
Maybe it'll help you figure out
what it is you want.
Great. Thanks.
It's important
to know what you want.
It's...
Let me know
what you think, okay?
Okay, yeah.
Love you. Okay.
- You got the kids?
- Yeah.
Okay. Oh! Sorry.
Oh! Hello.
- Sorry.
Okay.
Hey, do you have
a minute to discuss
Mr. Paxton's pacemaker?
I do.
Uh, do you want to go
get his chart?
Um, sure.
- Great.
- Mm-hmm.
You're acting weird.
I'm being nice.
Which for you,
with Owen, is weird.
My pillow still smells
like your hair.
I'm supposed to be mean
to the guy, too?
Well, he's gonna
know something is up.
Something is up.
I mean, as much as
I... as I enjoyed
the... the up-ness of it
and hope it continues,
I think we should take a minute
to discuss what it means.
It doesn't mean anything.
I'm sorry, but I acted
impulsively because
I'm afraid of... something,
which might not even be true.
That wasn't much
of an apology.
Tom, you're a good man.
I try to be, but you
haven't been helping.
Hi.
- Okay.
- Mm-hmm.
Uh, so, Mr. Paxton...
his, uh, last X-ray showed a...
Something is happening.
Well, he did have
an arrhythmia.
Yeah, I'm not talking
about Mr. Paxton.
You asked me
if you were crazy.
I said you weren't.
Then I share an elevator ride
with you, and I feel
the need to take a shower.
Okay, fine.
I slept with Tom.
What?!
No, no, no, no, no!
Don't tell me that!
I thought you were
saying that...
I was speculating!
God, talk about
a telltale heart.
I know! I know!
I feel awful.
I- I panicked,
and he was there,
or I went there...
Oh, God, I want to die!
Okay, Mr. Paxton?
I'll cover it.
Great. Thank you.
Oh, no, no, no.
I got it. I got it.
I got this.
That is a donation from
the Victoria Hughes
apology fund.
I was gonna
bake you something.
But...
"Sorry I sorta kinda
moved into your place
without telling you,"
doesn't really fit on
a cupcake,
and I wasn't sure
you wanted to see me.
I just wanted communication.
That's it.
If you need to crash
at my place
'cause you're
looking for an apartment,
of course you can.
Just maybe ask first.
Yeah. Yeah, well, thanks
for the offer.
But I already
found the perfect spot, so...
Well, good. Yeah.
That's good news.
What part of town?
Lake Union.
Dean's place.
Dean? Really?
Okay, so, he's moved out
of that houseboat?
No, no, no.
We're boatmates, I guess.
Or, he just had a kid
so technically,
I have two boatmates.
But it's great news,
right?
It's, uh... It's news.
That is certainly news.
Um, well, I'm gonna
go see Rigo
and give his wife
some coffee.
- Okay.
- Alright.
It's really good news,
Jackson.
It's all good.
No worries.
Who... Who sent you?
Look, I-I want a name.
Was it Catherine?
You know, I want to see
that invoice there.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa! - What?
What? Uh, uh,
let's just... I'm sorry.
I'm Chief Bailey.
Can I help you?
He's the one
who needs help.
Someone sent back my office
furniture from Pac-North,
and I told these guys
that I didn't send for it,
I don't want it,
and they can take it back!
- Whoa, wait, wait!
- Hey.
A- All of it?
Are you planning on
sitting on the floor?
You know what?
I don't have time for this.
I have a skills lab
to teach.
Dr. Rager to Peds.
Dr. Sara Rager to Peds.
So, we're
taking it all back?
Noelle Webb, 43,
complains of abdominal pain
and dizziness
after falling off
a ladder.
- Hi, Noelle. I'm Dr. Grey.
- Hi.
Did you just
lose your balance?
Do you have
any other symptoms?
I- I was painting this house,
and I just got woozy for a sec.
Fumes got to me.
I need my phone.
I think it's still at the site.
Okay.
Noelle, we'll get
your phone for you.
Ohh.
Do you have any other
health issues
that I need to know about?
Oh, I-I'm a type-1 diabetic,
but I take care of it.
You know, I-I-I'm good
about what I eat.
- Oh! Oh!
- When's the last time
you checked
your blood sugar?
Recently... ish.
Ohh,
my Giggle Days rating
is gonna go
in the toilet from this.
- Ooh!
- What's Giggle Days?
It's an app
for small jobs.
Gig economy.
They think they're cute.
Connects you to people
who need help
or their Internet hooked up
or their couch moved,
or, in my case,
a house painted.
But it's so un-cute
if my rating goes down.
I see some
free fluid there.
What's that?
Is that bad?
Well, we just need to run
some more tests to make sure.
Dr. Schmitt, let's admit
her for observation.
Get a full set of labs
and order a CT trauma series.
And my phone!
We will ask the paramedics
if they have found your phone.
I'll see you
soon, Noelle.
Dr. Daniel to Pediatrics.
Heads up.
She may seem nice,
but she just wants
a condo on Mars.
Oh, no. No, no,
I'll take the kindness,
even if it's insincere.
Most of the people in this
city think I'm a monster.
Well, big company,
big accident,
classic clickbait.
The firefighter, Rigo Vasquez,
is here recovering.
I know he's eager
to thank you for covering his,
uh, medical expenses.
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
Listen, before we, uh...
before we get to that...
This thing is,
uh, catastrophic.
My investors are spooked.
"Woke" Twitter is
eating me alive.
Well, th... there were
no fatalities.
"Billionaire explodes
rocket over Seattle"
is the only thing
anyone cares about.
And now there are rumors
of a criminal investigation.
People got hurt on my watch,
by my hand.
I made mistakes, Tom.
Mistakes that
are... beneath me.
Now, I may fail sometimes.
I was a crap husband,
and I suck at golf.
But my critical thinking,
my calculations,
my understanding of physics...
that's never failed me.
Now, I don't know
if it's a brain tumor,
some neurological disease,
if it's cancer,
but I need you to find
whatever it is and fix it
before this nightmare wipes out
all the good I've done.
Well, you've come
to the right place.
Why don't you text her,
see if she wants to talk?
About what?
The baby that might
be Owen's
or the relationship
she just ended?
Or the weather?
I'll pass.
If she wants to talk to me,
she can find me.
I'm done chasing her.
Okay.
Brad Spencer, 22.
Found unresponsive with burns
on three extremities.
GCS of 6T.
We got him back after
multiple rounds of CPR.
He jumped onto a train track
and got electrocuted.
He didn't jump. He fell.
We were kissing.
We were saying goodbye,
and we thought that
the train
was still behind us.
Then he turned around
too fast, and he just fell.
Oh, my God! Link!
It's the face-eaters
from this morning!
Alright, okay,
we got to go!
Trauma one!
Go, go, go!
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 16  Episode 17
Episode Title: "Life on Mars?"
Aired on: March 12, 2020
Third-degree burns
on this arm.
- Head trauma?
- I paged Koracick.
And he's busy.
What happened?
Brad fell on his guitar,
which fell on the train tracks.
He was making out
with his girlfriend.
I don't have a pulse
in either wrist,
and this arm is cold
and tight.
- This one, too.
- Okay, right leg's okay,
but I'm not getting
anything in the left foot.
- Compartment syndrome.
- Compartment syndrome, okay.
- Okay.
- Scalpels and sterile gloves!
Simms, you ever done
a fasciotomy?
Does a cadaver count?
You and Jo take the arms.
I'll take the leg.
Pupils are equal
and reactive,
but I can't rule out
a head injury.
He needs a CT ASAP.
After we
save his limbs.
Okay, fasciotomies
on my count.
One, two...
Wait, wait! Is that her?
She should
not see this.
Alright,
one, two, three.
Do you care if I stand?
Stand, sit,
whatever you need.
I don't need to stand.
I just p-prefer to,
I guess.
Okay, whatever's
more comfortable.
You don't think
that's possible?
To be comfortable here?
I think that
when your bosses tell you
that you can't operate
until a counselor signs off,
it sort of casts a mood.
Okay, what kind of mood?
Look, our patients were
at extreme risk, alright?
And I keep coming back
to the fact that
if I'd behaved differently,
they'd be dead.
Mm-hmm.
And that's all it was...
just passion for the work.
Trying to save lives.
It's not some manic,
uh, whatever.
I didn't say "manic."
Are you experiencing
symptoms of mania?
No.
Agitation,
inflated confidence,
rambling,
increased sex drive?
N- No.
No, none of that.
I just... I've... had
a very stressful couple weeks.
That's all.
Okay.
"Painter left job unfinished,
spilled paint on porch.
Do not hire this person.
Shrug emoji, poop emoji,
thumbs-down emoji.
Zero stars."
I'm sure you can have
that removed
if you contact
customer service.
You sound like someone
who's never tried to do that.
Schmitt, she should've
had a CT by now.
And what's the status
on her room?
Apparently there's an issue
with admissions.
A lot of people
got moved around.
Some VIP thing.
Do I get some kind of
discount for the wait?
I do have
her lab results, though.
Oh.
Whoa. Noelle, these
numbers are kinda high.
Are you taking your
insulin regularly?
I'm pretty good
about it.
"Pretty good"...
what does that mean?
We're not gonna judge you.
I just need to know so these
numbers make sense.
Are you taking
your insulin?
Okay, the deal is
I just moved my folks
into assisted living,
and that's not cheap.
I've been working all these apps
trying to make ends meet.
But there isn't always
enough left over for me.
So, um, I've been
rationing my insulin
until my situation's
more stable.
Unfortunately, that's
not how this works.
I'm... I'm sure that's why
you got dizzy and fell.
Dr. Grey,
Chief Koracick needs you.
Well, tell him to wait.
He says
it's an emergency.
Okay, let's get her a CT,
check on the status of her room,
page me as soon
as she gets in.
- Okay.
- Okay?
Dr. Grey.
Thank you for coming.
Why's this floor empty?
You said this was
an emergency.
Oh, it is.
Emergent, uh, consult.
Griffin Ford
is here today.
The billionaire
rocket guy?
Yeah, maybe don't
call him that.
Wait a second.
Please don't tell me
you let him buy out
this entire floor.
No, of course not.
He got it for free.
He's a great friend to
the Catherine Fox Foundation.
The emergency room is
overflowing!
Patients need rooms.
My patient needs a room.
Well, all... all the more reason
to get this taken care of
and get him on his...
on his way.
Th-This guy is about
a lot more than,
uh, spaceships, Grey.
He's working to fight
climate change, uh, end poverty.
And... And I'm pretty sure,
uh, he's... he's single.
Okay, not interested.
Okay, you don't have to be
nice, but be a pro.
Yes.
Yes. Good girl, Emmie.
Dr. Mochrie to OR 3.
Hey.
Dr. Julia Mochrie to OR 3.
Teddy, what...
what was that?
Oh, I...
Well, I just, uh...
I just wanted to
take the stairs.
Teddy, what's wrong?
I know you too well.
Something has happened.
Just tell me.
Amelia's baby
might be yours.
I mean
Might be,
as in might not.
I just...
I don't... I don't
think she knows yet.
Jo.
What does Jo have to do
with anything?
She mentioned
something in surgery.
She said, "What would
you do if..."
How do you even know this?
Did Amelia tell you or...
- No.
- Then who?
It doesn't matter.
Te... You just told me
that I-I might have another
baby with another woman.
Amelia, your ex-wife.
I need to make sure
that you didn't hear
some rumor
and run with it.
Run with it?
I want to make sure
that it's real.
It's real, Owen!
It's a real baby,
and you might
really be the father!
If you have a baby
with Amelia,
what does that mean
for us?
I...
Wow.
Teddy.
I enjoyed your article.
Which one?
Uh, "The List."
Exposing all those problems
with the healthcare system.
I bet that ruffled
some feathers around here.
We survived.
Reasonable people adapt
themselves to the world...
unreasonable people persist
in adapting the world
to themselves.
Therefore, all progress depends
on unreasonable people.
- Huh. Profound.
- Hmm.
The future should ruffle
feathers. Don't you think?
Sometimes your vision demands
that you light the spark,
you... storm the palace.
- I've been there.
- Hmm.
You don't agree?
I just find it ironic
that someone who has
a whole hospital floor
to themselves
is talking about
storming palaces.
I didn't ask for
an entire floor.
You didn't have to.
You just asked
Catherine Fox for a favor,
and, boom, here you are.
Grey, time to
check his thyroid.
Excuse me.
Ooh! Look at that.
My patient's in CT.
Your patient's right here.
He's someone else's
patient now.
Mr. Ford,
may I introduce you to
- Dr. Jackson Avery?
- Grey.
We're rolling out
the red carpet for Mr. Ford,
and it doesn't get any redder
than Dr. Avery.
Wh... What's going on?
Your mom, your mess.
Brad's electrocution
injury
affected the tissue
in his limbs.
We had to cut through
both of his arms and his leg
to preserve
the circulation.
Still,
the damage was extensive.
His head CT shows a small
epidural bleed in his brain,
which I'll evacuate
in the OR.
It could have been
a lot worse.
We think that
the neck of his guitar
took most of the impact.
It probably
saved his life.
Wow.
One second, he was there,
and then he just disappeared
like he fell through a trapdoor.
You didn't hear
the train leaving?
We... We just graduated
from U-Dub,
and Brad got this internship
at a music studio here.
But I won a Rhodes Scholarship,
and he's been so sweet,
singing me these
corny love songs.
But it's been torture
just knowing that
we were gonna be apart.
And I was on my way to
the airport today,
and he just got this look
on his face
and... and he said, "Screw it.
Let's go to England together."
And then he kissed me,
and it was like...
everything was solved.
Not even the "ding-ding"
of the doors closing?
The annoying loudspeaker?
Okay, uh, we are gonna
take Brad to the OR
and then move him
to the ICU.
We will let you know
if we have any updates.
Okay.
What are you doing here?
I wasn't sure
if you could leave,
so I paged everyone.
There's a guy up there with
the entire floor to himself.
Meanwhile, this woman
is rationing her insulin
just to stay alive.
It's infuriating.
Oh. Scans are up.
Big retroperitoneal
bleed.
Kidney's shattered.
She needs an ex-lap.
Let's book the OR.
And if any billionaire
tries to get in your way,
push them aside.
Are you okay?
Huh? Uh...
Have you
talked to Amelia?
About...?
Help! I need help!
BP's dropping.
Abdomen's more distended.
Let's get
an intubation tray.
Book the OR.
Hey, I got your page.
What's wrong?
Let's talk
in your office.
Ta-da!
What the hell
did you do?
What? I had the movers
bring up your old furniture
from the basement and arrange
it like it was before.
Look, I-I know
you're still feeling down
about Catherine
and everything else.
So o-of course you didn't
want that Pac-North stuff.
You think you know what
I want and what I don't want?
I never wanted
this furniture moved in here
in the first place!
And it came anyway!
And if I had wanted
this old junk back,
I would have
asked for it!
Look, I want
an empty room!
Why is that so hard
to understand?!
You know,
you're just like her.
You presume
to know what's best!
Okay! Okay.
It's an easy fix.
Ri... I d...
I'll just call
building services and right...
Ah.
Okay, apparently,
Tom Koracick has decided to
wreak havoc on the hospital.
Look, I-I'll come back,
and I'll fix it.
Don't bother!
I'll do it myself!
Hey, I texted.
You didn't reply.
Uh, yeah, I got stuck helping
babysit a billionaire.
It screwed up
my entire schedule.
You should go enjoy
your day off, though.
You know, I can swing by
the boat later.
Maybe I can bring a housewarming
present for you and Dean.
Jackson.
Jackson, hey.
What's up?
I move in, you're mad,
and I move out,
and you're still mad.
So, what... If you have
a problem, just tell me.
- Please.
- Okay.
Look, I know you
and Dean are friends.
- Okay, I get that.
- Mm-hmm.
I also think he has
a thing for you, so...
What? No, he doesn't.
He doesn't have a...
He also hit on Maggie
when we were together,
so I kind of
question his whole...
Oh, you don't need
to question anything.
He didn't know
she had a boyfriend,
and when he did,
he backed off.
And then he invited you
to live with him.
No, no, he did not...
He did not invite me.
I asked.
Which somehow makes
it worse,
- It...
- okay? Not...
You live with him now.
You're raising a baby
together, alright?
You haven't
even met my child.
You haven't invited me
to meet her.
'Cause we're not
there yet!
Then where are we?!
Because it sounds like
we're in the place
where you freak out
when I get too close
and when I live my life.
So pick a lane.
Look, I don't want to
fight with you.
- Well, I do!
- I'm at work.
I have a VIP patient
to deal with.
So I'd like us...
...to be able to talk about this
completely later.
You know, I'm sorry.
If you can't answer
the simple question
of where we are,
I'm not sure we have
that much left
- to talk about.
- Oh, you know what? Come on, okay?
You don't get to suddenly
dictate the timeline.
You made choices that
I was not involved in.
Give me a second
to process.
Process what?
That I have friends?
Okay, alright, yeah.
You have your process.
Let me know
how it goes.
We'll
need to page Avery post-op
to take a look at these wounds
for closure later.
Hematoma drained.
He's lucky that guitar
didn't jam
straight into his brain.
It was a cheap guitar.
So much
for dumb love songs.
What is wrong
with making out in public
and singing to each other
un-ironically, saying,
"Screw it...
let's go have an adventure"?
Isn't that what being 22
and in love is for?
Yeah, until the part where
you get cooked on a train track.
Word.
Hmm. I'm done here.
Do you two need help
dressing those wounds?
No, I think
we got it from here.
Yeah, and we're good
to update the girlfriend
if you have somewhere
you need to be.
"Word"? Really?
I know.
I'll be right with
you guys, okay?
Hey, Chief! Uh, I think
I got the overflow handled.
So...
DeLuca, telling me
you're doing your job
isn't a part of
doing your job.
Right, but I just thought now
that that's taken care of,
I could maybe start
treating some of the patients
- that I've been moving?
- Oh, that isn't our deal.
Look, I've been seeing
the counselor, alright?
I did that.
And now with Dr. Webber
handing off his entire service,
I just thought I could help.
Webber handed off
his entire service?
- Why?
- You know what?
I don't really know because
gossip isn't a part of my job.
I'm a surgeon.
Please, Chief, let me work.
This... This...
Chief?
Is that a yes?
It is not.
I can't find the bleeding.
She's in DIC.
Can we control it
with a REBOA?
She's lost too much blood.
She couldn't
afford her insulin.
She was healthy.
She was doing everything
she needed to do.
She was taking care
of her parents.
She had her whole life
ahead of her.
This shouldn't
have happened!
Dr. Crone to Peds ICU.
Dr. Alexandria Crone
to Peds ICU.
Hey.
I told Owen.
Okay, did he...
Should someone warn Tom?
No, not about that.
About the baby,
about Amelia's baby.
I told him
because she wouldn't
and he deserves to know,
and I deserve answers,
and Link deserves answers,
and, I mean,
who does this?
Who gets this far
into the pregnancy
and just toys
with people's feelings,
with...
with their lives?
I was just starting
to really like her.
And I was just starting
to really like you.
I mean, who does this?
Who cheats on her fiancé
with a man who is clearly
desperately in love with her?
And before you go
judging Amelia,
let's just take a second
to remember how long you waited
before you told Owen
that you were pregnant.
You're right.
I'm... I'm sorry.
Yeah.
That's my sister
you're talking about.
Yeah, aside from
low Vitamin D levels
and some ligament wear and tear
in your C-spine,
you're the picture of health.
When we have bad outcomes,
we tend to blame the conditions,
but sometimes,
it's just human error.
And we need to take the hit
and move on.
You know, ironically,
I'm getting that,
"You are the picture
of health,"
is not the news
you were hoping to hear.
You don't think there's
a chance
that one of your team
made an error?
More specifically,
um, that you made an error?
I've read
about rare conditions...
a tiny bubble in an artery,
a blip that
most doctors would miss.
I mean, if you were to find
something like that,
it would explain
everything.
The world
is falling apart, Tom,
and people act like, "Well,
somebody's gonna save us."
But I don't see
that person.
And I sure as hell
can't be that person
from a jail cell.
Just think
of all the good you could do
with my resources,
my cash.
You could research
anything you wanted.
You'd be a legend.
And if anyone ever
caught you, you'd just say,
"Uh, oops,
I misread his scan.
Human error."
Take another look
at the scans,
just in case there's
something you missed.
Okay, Tom,
my patient just died.
So if your billionaire
needs a lollipop
or a foot massage,
please go to someone else.
If you had
his kind of money,
what would you do
with it?
Wh...
I don't know.
I'd triple the size
of the clinic.
I'd make half our cases
pro bono.
I could develop
a research lab
and come up
with our own medicine
so we could cut out
big pharma completely.
Public healthcare
initiatives.
We could put a stop
to food deserts.
We could get healthcare
and nutrition to the homeless.
The point is you'd do good,
lots of it,
because this world
never runs out of people
who need help.
How do you decide
which rules to break?
How do I decide?
We're surgeons. We live by
rules, precedents, protocols.
I mean, annoying as they are,
they reproduce success,
so, Meredith Grey,
award-winning rule breaker,
how do you decide
which rules to break?
I- I just go with my gut.
And I hope that
whatever I'm doing
improves this mess of a world
just a little bit.
We believe he's out
of immediate danger,
but there's no question
he's gonna have a long recovery.
Does he have
family nearby?
Yeah, um, I called.
They're on the way.
He'll also need
additional surgeries
to treat the burns
and close the wounds
on his arms and leg.
Right.
So...
England...
Um
whoever takes care of Brad
needs to be prepared to spend
a lot of time in hospitals
for a while.
I can't... I can't do that.
I can't stay.
You don't have to make
that decision right now.
No, but I already decided.
And... And he decided
to come with me,
but I was always gonna go,
with or without him.
What does it mean if
he would leave his dream for me,
but I... I won't
stay for him?
Wow.
That went from forever to over
in less than a day.
You called it, Jo.
All love
sucks eventually.
No.
It doesn't suck.
I've spent all week
trying to hate Alex,
and nothing works.
Because every time
I get into my car,
I see
this little trash bag
that he put
in my side pocket
so that I had somewhere to put
my gum wrappers and tissues.
And I felt...
I felt so loved
that he did that.
And now he put me
in the trash
with the gum wrappers
and the tissues.
I'm so mad.
I'm so hurt.
But I also know
that he is the reason
that I will
get up again.
I will climb out
of the trash,
and I will rise.
I'll rise so high
that I'll make him a fool
for ever having left me,
and I'll do it
because of how well
he loved me.
I am changed
because of him.
He helped me
feel worthy of love,
and even though
it's over,
that is mine to keep.
Link, don't blow it
with Amelia.
I didn't do anything.
She pushed me away.
She ended it.
She didn't push you away.
She gave you a choice.
♪ Wildly ♪
I never had that.
♪ Burns the flame ♪
♪ Moves closer ♪
♪ To be tamed ♪
Why did Andrew DeLuca
tell me you'd handed over
- your entire service?
- ♪ We can feel the clock tick down ♪
♪ On us tonight ♪
Well, lately, um,
the smallest thing sets me off.
And when that happens...
- ♪ You burn up so fast ♪
- ..I-I see red.
♪ When you burn so bright ♪
I'm sorry.
I know you were
just trying to be kind,
and I was wrong to
- treat you that way.
- ♪ Stars fade out ♪
- ♪ And we will, too ♪
- That doesn't answer my question.
This isn't something
I arrived at easily.
♪ Stars fade out ♪
I've decided to step away
from surgery.
- Indefinitely.
- ♪ And we will, too ♪
I don't care how
you arrived at it.
It's the wrong
destination. No!
M- My mind is made up,
Bailey.
- ♪ Reveries lie and wait ♪
- I want to focus on
my PATH Pen
and other innovations.
You can do that
while you operate.
You know,
a little while ago,
you asked
how you could help me.
- Well, this is how.
- ♪ To rise from dust ♪
Support me on
my next adventure.
♪ Of beds we made ♪
This room reminds me
of another time.
Another me.
- ♪ We can feel the clock tick down ♪
- It clutters my mind.
♪ On us tonight ♪
- I want to look ahead.
- Richard...
..this place needs you.
♪ You burn up so fast
when you burn so bright ♪
And that's how I want
to step away.
At the top of my game.
- ♪ Stars fade out ♪
- We've both seen people
cling to their scalpels
longer than they should have.
♪ And we will, too ♪
Mr. Ford.
Can I have a minute?
I took another look
at your scans.
You have an aneurysm
in your anterior
cerebral artery.
I, uh... I missed it,
uh, initially
because it's...
it's minor.
It's barely detectable.
There's no doubt that it could
influence your judgment.
It's the sort of thing that,
uh, could resolve on its own,
but you may need
surgery down the road.
Um, when...
when will we know?
Hmm.
Well, when we see
the size of the check.
- ♪ A marble of fate ♪
- Thanks for waiting.
It was a hell of a day.
- Yeah.
- I had it all pictured.
I was gonna buy you coffee,
and then I was gonna
tell you about the houseboat,
and you were gonna be
really happy for me,
and it was gonna be
so nice.
This doesn't
feel right, Vic.
And I'm saying that to you
because I have been through
a, um... when...
when something's not right...
- Mm-hmm.
- ..and you hold on too long.
You know, it's like
two people carrying one stone,
- never...
- Okay, stop talking like a fortune cookie
and just say it,
Jackson.
You don't want
to see me anymore.
I am past the time
in my life
where I can just
go with things...
move in and out on a whim,
move in with a friend who
you tried to set up with my ex,
who has a kid now,
but, hey, it's all good.
Nah, it's not all good.
We're not teenagers.
Okay, but sleeping together
with no commitment...
that's good?
Or friends with benefits?
What... that's... that's
state of the freakin' art,
Jackson.
What an adult!
Vic.
- We moved really fast.
- Mm-hmm.
I'm just saying we could
take a little time
to get to know
each other better,
be... be friends
for a little while.
- ♪ In a silent way ♪
- I have friends.
Bye, Jackson.
♪ You're waiting to save me ♪
You too, huh?
God.
You know,
on days like this,
Alex would be the one
who would make me laugh.
Dark, gallows humor,
but he made me laugh.
My first day
of residency,
when the chief gave us
that speech...
you know, "The seven years
you spend here"...
I stood in that room
dreaming of being
the last one left
of my class,
of being the kind of surgeon
that I have become,
of winning.
Then one by one,
they dropped off
till Torres and I were
the only ones left.
Then she left.
♪ Ooh, ♪
- At some point, it stops feeling like
- ♪ Ooh, so opaque ♪
victory
and... just feels lonely.
- ♪ I've been waiting to say ♪
- I just don't know if I know
how to do this
without him.
Or if I want to.
I'm not talking
about Alex.
Richard Webber is
stepping down from surgery.
What? Why?
I don't... I don't want
to talk about it.
♪ You don't have to ♪
♪ You're waiting to save me ♪
Hey.
You're right.
You deserve a way better apology
than I managed this morning,
- which wasn't even...
- ♪ You're waiting to save me ♪
I'm sorry.
I'm... I'm sorry
that I used you.
I'm sorry
that I hurt you.
I mean, everything was fine.
I was happy.
Owen and I finally
found our way back to each other
after years
of bad timing.
We finally worked.
You know, I-I really
don't think I'm in the mood
to hear how you and Hunt
are working.
And then I felt... I...
I feel that he might
choose another woman again,
and I have been through...
with my whole body,
I'm remembering
unimaginable loss
and unbearable pain,
and you...
You make me laugh.
You make me feel good.
You make me feel like
my life isn't completely
spinning out of control.
And... And I-I hate
that that hurts you
because you're such
a good guy.
Stop. St...
Stop saying that.
I'm really not
a good guy, Teddy.
I don't think
that's true.
It is true.
♪ I've never had a kiss
like yours ♪
Hey, you look like
you could use one of these, huh?
- Cheers.
- ♪ 'Cause it ain't never felt like this, ♪
♪ I swear, I ain't fooling ♪
So, Alex. Crazy, right?
Sorry about that.
But on the plus side,
we are both free now.
So we could, uh, make the best
out of a bad situation,
take away
each other's pain.
I mean, come on,
you're beautiful.
You're brilliant.
And where is he?
Nowhere.
He doesn't respect you.
Do you think Meredith
respects me? Please.
I think he's
a complete idiot if you ask...
You're not okay. You're not yourself.
Listen to people
when they tell you that.
Get help before
it's too late.
You would
think weightlessness
is a good thing,
but it's not.
Because people weren't
meant to float.
Hey.
The kids are down,
and I thought you'd be starving,
so I roasted a chicken,
and, yes,
I put a whole stick of butter
into the potatoes.
My favorite.
I know.
Owen, this is, um...
Wait, wait.
Me first.
You didn't do anything
wrong, okay?
All you did was
tell me the truth.
I was shocked,
and I froze.
But for our future, Teddy,
I need you to know you are not
a replacement for anyone.
And if you need
to tell me anything,
my answer will be,
"I love you."
I love you, and we're
gonna figure it out.
And that's
my answer now.
- ♪ You're on my mind ♪
- That's my answer tomorrow.
♪ But you can't hear your name ♪
That's my answer always.
♪ I scream out loud, ♪
- ♪ But it won't cut through ♪
- And I'm sorry.
Without gravity,
we lose blood volume,
- bone density, muscle.
- ♪ I'd give it all ♪
♪ To tell you face to face ♪
Without it, we're untethered.
♪ It's not the way
we had it planned ♪
♪ I'm afraid of goodbyes,
yeah, I don't like it ♪
♪ Tell you a thousand times ♪
♪ I'm afraid of goodbyes,
yeah, I don't like it ♪
♪ Hold you a thousand times ♪
♪ Now and forever,
will you remember... ♪
- Oh, hey.
- What are you doing?
- ♪ ...me when you close your eyes? ♪
- I wanted to write you a song,
but I can't write songs,
uh, as fast as I needed
to come here
and, um, tell you...
I don't
want to live without you.
You seemed pretty clear
about how you felt
- if the baby isn't yours.
- ♪ If I think of you and you think of me ♪
I was hurting.
I was in pain.
But that doesn't mean
I don't love you,
- Amelia, because I do.
- ♪ Will that bring me right back to you? ♪
Doesn't mean
I don't want you.
- ♪ We ran so fast ♪
- Because I do... I want you.
- ♪ But time caught up with us ♪
- You're the only person
that makes me feel
all the things
that I thought I was too smart
or too damaged to feel.
You make me want to write
love songs in the rain!
♪ I'm afraid of goodbyes,
yeah, I don't like it ♪
You make me
want to be a parent.
And I don't... I don't
give a crap whose baby it is.
I don't want to feel
this sad and this lonely,
not if I don't have to.
- ♪ Now and forever ♪
- I fell in love with you, Amelia,
and I fell in love
with this baby,
and that is what
matters to me.
♪ Will you remember me when you close
your eyes? ♪ - So when you feel yourself
being pulled toward something,
it's not necessarily
a bad thing.
So, you want to do this?
♪ Now and forever,
will you remember... ♪
Even if he isn't yours?
I do.
♪ ...me when the tears
all dry? ♪
I really needed
to hear that.
Because
I got the results.
♪ Now and forever ♪
And he is yours.
It may keep you centered.
- But you still got to write me that song.
- It may keep you safe.
♪ Now and forever ♪