Collins working on
King here, top of the key—
Dribbling around him, coming
around the corner there, he's up!
Two points! Beautiful play.
Now, that's a great play.
If you testify, no
one can protect you,
especially the feds.
- We'll keep you safe, Joey.
- Right. In Witness Protection.
This great new
life he's giving you?
You're sackin' groceries at
some goat-town Stop and Shop,
when one of Vitale's guys comes
and puts two in the back of your skull.
Counselor, are you
advising a witness to
withhold evidence from
a federal grand jury?
He came forward. He volunteered.
I'm advising him not to testify until
I'm satisfied you can protect him.
Hey, you guys mind?
I got money on this.
What do you want? We gave
you everything you asked for.
- I asked for pasta.
- You got steak. Enjoy it.
- What are you doin'?
- What?
Where's your quit candy? I just
gave you a pack. Yeah, sorry.
I forgot.
Joey, whatever they give us,
what they tell you, you get popped,
what am I gonna do, sue them?
That's not what this is about.
You're gonna miss me.
- I'm your lawyer, Joey.
- You're my brother.
And I do this—you know, I
go into Witness Protection...
We're never gonna
see each other again.
- That doesn't bother you?
- It kills me.
There he goes. Nice pick.
I gotta take a leak.
You all right?
Yeah, yeah. Just,
uh, a little dizzy.
Get some air. Hot.
- Joey.
- What'd you say to him?
Yeah, nice try. Come
on! Let go of me!
- Let go of me! Can't you see he's sick?
- Joey!
Let me go! Something's
wrong with him!
You're not getting out
of this that easy. Joey.
Either you’re dead
or you’re testifying.
Don't have it.
Budget? Nope.
Revenue statement.
List of expenses.
House has been very busy.
Saving New Jersey
from leprosy. Yes, I know.
Getting me his
numbers, that's your job.
- We're in a meeting.
- I need the lawyer.
Who'd you kill? Nobody.
But it's not even lunch.
I got served with a federal court
order. Some witness went into a coma.
They want me to
take a look at him.
What?
They want you to
examine a sick person?
This is a public
relations nightmare.
Folk think our staff do that
kind of thing around here,
this place will be
crawling with sick people.
I'm a doctor. I'm not a lapdog
for the feds. I don't play fetch.
Nobody tells you what to
do. Am I right, Dr. Cuddy?
You have three choices.
Hire a lawyer to fight the
order, treat the guy or
go to jail for contempt.
Up to you.
Jail. You'd like that. No
more naughty schoolgirl.
Conjugal visit—that's
her new fantasy.
We're not leaving until
he's gone, or you show me...
one good reason for keeping him.
He's really out of it, huh?
Causes of coma— metabolic,
structural— He had his stomach pumped.
Why would they do
that? Rule out poisoning.
Huh. Not the
typical first guess.
Nope, first guess was
faking it. The patient's
a federal witness—
Reluctant, I'm assuming.
He's also an eight on
the Glasgow Coma Scale.
He's barely alive.
Pretty tough to fake.
Any recent history of head
trauma? Bad car accident? Fall?
They tell me no, but
do an M.R.I. to be sure.
Metabolic causes—
Liver, kidney, diabetes—
Check for everything.
Feds are paying.
We're gonna turn a
profit on this one, boys.
Dr. House, Bill
Arnello. I'm a lawyer.
I represent Mr. Smith.
What's wrong with him?
Do I come to you
with my problems?
He's also my brother.
What? You changed your name?
Smith wasn't good
enough for you?
His name's Joey. He's my only
brother. He's important to you.
Got it. So, no placebos for
him. We'll use the real medicine.
This was fun. Let's
do it again soon.
Brother in the Mafia?
So, just Joey?
I was hoping for a nickname.
Joey Mango. Joey the Wrench.
People know where I am.
I want you to do your job.
Diagnose him, fix
him and keep him here.
We're a bit of a specialized
hospital. We generally
only deal with patients
while they're actually sick.
If you release my
brother to the government,
and he does what they want,
even if you fix him, he's dead.
I need time to
convince him of that.
Good news is, if you screw up,
you don't have to worry
about a malpractice suit.
Instead, one by one,
I'll take away the things you
love till there's nothing left.
So, on the Mafia thing,
that's a yes.
Did House seem weird to you?
Were you expecting
him to be weird?
We spoke...
about how we felt.
You told him you liked
him? No, of course not.
Wh-What are you talking about
then? I asked him if he liked me.
Why would you
do that? Because...
I like him.
You like him like him?
Doesn't matter.
He doesn't like me.
Hey, he doesn't like anybody.
And nobody likes him.
M.R.I. showed a
subdural hematoma.
Bleeding around his brain caused pressure
inside his head, which caused the coma.
These look like
pseudo-membranes.
Those take time to form.
If it's an old injury, it
wouldn't cause the coma.
Patient history indicates he
was hit with a tire iron in 1996.
Brother says he was
changing a tire and it slipped.
An old hematoma placed where this
one is could have caused his coma.
- What about his liver?
- L.F.T.'s are slightly elevated.
Key word is "slightly," as in not
high enough to cause the coma.
It's the subdural. I say we evacuate
the cavity, see if he wakes up.
The neurologist thinks
it's his brain and wants
to open up his head?
Frankly, I'm shocked.
And you get to use the "big boy"
drill in Daddy's big red toolbox.
No drilling.
- Hi.
- Mr. Smith.
Call me Joe. Can
you not do that?
So, we're clear
about the no drilling?
He's okay now. He can leave.
I'm not releasing him. 'Cause
the brother doesn't want you to?
Or because he had an unexplained
coma. Which sounds better?
The hematoma caused the coma. That's a
catchy diagnosis. You could dance to that.
I think Chase is right.
It still should be evacuated,
but it's not an immediate threat.
Cameron's my girl.
I'd release him.
- Are you disagreeing
with me because— - I'm
disagreeing because
that's my medical opinion.
Of course it is.
But unless I've been named as
the fourth part of the "axis of evil,"
invaded and occupied,
this is still not a democracy.
He's staying. Send for hepatitis
serologies and an autoimmune panel.
Hey, I'm with you.
Old enough to drink, old
enough to do something
really stupid and
make yourself a baby.
He's my brother. I'm watching him
while our parents are in Barbados.
He's having trouble breathing,
and there's a lot of wheezing.
Whistling, technically.
Upper airways. Nose.
If he's got the croup, that— that could
become meningitis, right? Absolutely.
I—I was just studying, and all of a sudden
I hear him crying and sounding all weird.
Oh— M-My parents
are gonna kill me.
I doubt it. You don't know them.
No, I doubt you were studying
while your parents were away.
Hello, Officer.
You might wanna rinse this off
before you let him play with it again.
What happened? Where is he?
Vogler called Admitting. Admitting called
Justice. Justice came and took him away.
And who called Vogler?
He loses money.
So does Ophthalmology.
Who cares? This is a hospital.
- You can't just cut a department.
- You can't control him.
I am the only one
that can control him.
♪ D-D-Dr. House in the house ♪
Impeccable timing as always.
You had no authority
to release my patient.
My colleague has just informed
me she has a singular talent.
You are just in time
for a demonstration.
Dr. House, from
what I understand,
your patient— From what you
understand— He's not your patient.
How the hell do you
understand anything? It's sad.
- You're not even a doctor.
- John Smith is here
only because of a court order.
I had the records faxed to the
judge. She rescinded the order.
- Why bother? Just to piss me off?
- Keeping the government off our ass.
Hmm. Yeah.
- That makes no sense
for a public institution.
- Okay.
- Okay, what?
- Okay, sir.
Carry on.
He really cares
about his patients.
Yeah, and he just walked out of
here with nothin'. Something's up.
Just started vomiting
and passed out.
More lidocaine. 590, with epi.
Thirty-five-year-old
male. Vital signs
are stable now. Gave
him two liters en route.
He was just released
from here two hours ago.
You said he was good to go.
Watch that line. He's
still not responding.
So, the junior G-man
badge isn't looking so good.
- His liver's worse.
- Comatose?
No. Completely different
symptoms than the first time.
His serology tests came
back positive for hepatitis "C."
Hep "C" is a chronic condition. You
don't think this is an acute situation?
Coma, vomiting, abdominal
pain. Hep "C" explains everything.
- Except for the suddenness of the onset.
- What's wrong with the timing?
You get home one night, your
wife hits you with a baseball bat.
Likely causes: The fact that you haven't
thanked her for dinner in eight years...
or the receipt for fur handcuffs
that she found in your pants?
Sudden onset equals
approximate cause.
He also has high
estrogen levels in his blood.
That's indicative of a
chronic condition, not acute.
One test. What do his
other liver tests tell us?
Normal albumen levels
point toward acute.
Oh, okay, and, uh, why is
her test better than mine?
Because she's cuter,
though it's close.
Do a liver biopsy. When the results come
back, we'll know what we're looking at.
Why wait to treat the hep "C"? If I'm
right, Joey gets better that much faster.
Right. Then he gets to testify.
And you get a gold star from Cuddy.
And what's the downside?
Or is that the downside?
Do I have a reason for not
wanting you to get any stars?
Fine. Start the treatment.
It's all your idea. Don't
even mention my name.
There's nothing wrong
with your theory. Go.
But in the "humor me" department,
get a biopsy while you're at it.
Foreman, we need to talk.
- You're off the case.
- What?
- Why?
- Somebody told Vogler that I lied
to the transplant committee.
- You think I did?
- You're too careful.
You wouldn't jump ship
unless you knew what
was in the water. Stop.
You're embarrassing me.
But I want Vogler to
think I think it's you.
And I want Cameron and Chase,
Cuddy and Wilson, the nursing staff...
and the cashier in the
parking lot to think that too.
Right.
The blood tests show
you have hepatitis "C."
It's a virus that
infects the liver.
No way. It's not all bad news.
It can often be cured. And
even if not, it's manageable.
How'd my brother get
this? It usually involves
the exchange of
bodily fluids. Either...
Bodily fluids? What
are you talkin' about?
There are many ways the
virus can be transmitted...
Sharing needles,
blood transfusions...
Hey! Nobody talks to
my brother like this, okay?
Fine. No idea how he got it.
But he has hepatitis "C."
We're gonna start him on...
He doesn't have it. Don't mention
it again. Don't treat him for it.
House has some
directed donations,
foundation support...
It's around here.
He makes you miserable.
Eight years he's worked here—
Never made a dime for you.
Never listened to you.
He can change. He's...
He hasn't changed
in eight years.
Either he can't change,
or you can't change him.
You have no idea how many times
he's lied to you, undercut your authority,
made you look like
crap to other doctors.
Yes, I hate him, and here I am
desperately trying to protect his job.
- What does that tell you?
- That you don't hate him.
I do not protect people I like.
I protect people who
are assets to this hospital.
No. That's me.
You...
- You're softer.
- Right.
There are three female
chiefs of medicine...
at major hospitals
in this country,
and we all got there
using our feminine wiles.
- It's human nature to want to
protect people we like.
- I don't like him.
To think if we just
form the right team, we'll
all get along and be
able to pull the boat—
- I don't get along with him!
- This is not a team.
It's not a boat. It's
not a machine that has
a lot of parts that
have to work together.
The metaphors are all crap.
This is a business. That's all it is.
You like him. That's
bad for business.
Oh, this is all my fault.
Took another homework
break with Betty Lou?
No, last week I showed
him a magic trick.
You pulled a quarter out
of his nose. It's a classic.
Yeah, and now he won't
stop shovin' stuff up there.
- Dr. House.
- Got a crisis here.
It's okay.
Stop!
That's a neat trick.
They have to believe
you'll actually hurt them.
Ah.
Your people insulted my brother.
What, they put Romano in the
Parmesan cheese shaker again?
Said he was a crackhead
or a homo or somethin'.
Those idiots.
How many times am I gonna have
to send them for sensitivity training?
Nobody's saying he's a homo.
That would be really, really bad.
So let's put a nice,
friendly spin on it.
Let's go with, "He
got raped in prison."
I saw the jailhouse tats.
Put it together
with the blood tests.
There were rumors, but Joey
never said anything about it.
If people find out he's
bein' treated for hep "C"...
Feds get that chart, someone says
somethin' to somebody, word will get out.
And then Joey's manhood,
his rep— He's destroyed.
You're worried about how his coworkers
will react at the Wal-Mart in Des Moines.
He's not going into Witness
Protection. I'm not gonna let that happen.
Listen, I don't know
if you know about this,
but mob businesses sometimes
keep two sets of books.
- One legit, one not.
- Exactly.
You jerkin' my chain?
Doctors are busy. Sometimes they forget
to write things down. Happens all the time.
Thanks.
Oh, and, uh,
whatever you're not giving him
for whatever he doesn't have,
is that gonna fix him?
I doubt it.
On your way to
polish Vogler's car?
Gone are the days of
the grumpy old doc...
seeing patients in the basement of
his house, getting paid a few chickens.
- How will I eat?
- You know what Cuddy's been
locked away with Vogler about...
all day today and yesterday?
Floor polish costs
through the roof?
You. Her secretary's been at the
photocopier all day with your records.
That's all they're looking at
in there. My car's been stolen.
Or rein-car-nated.
Pink slip.
A gift from the
Arnello brothers.
You know, they're
gangsters, sure,
but they're thoughtful too.
You can't keep
it. It's... graft.
No, no, no, no. Uh-uh.
Graft is if I tell him I'll only make him
better if he slips me a couple bucks.
Or a payoff for something
I'm not supposed to do.
If I'd asked for the
payoff, which I didn't,
I would've done the
bad thing anyway.
So there's nothing
wrong with this.
Right. Damn.
Sixty-five.
Perfectly restored.
What do you think a guy like Joey
would do if someone turned down a gift?
That's kind of
an insult, isn't it?
He might hurt you.
It's definitely possible.
I'm screwed. Gotta take the car.
Did you see House's new car?
From Joey. He
obviously can't keep it.
You don't mind the hospital
taking money from Vogler?
That's different.
Vogler's legit.
That's worse. Vogler's
money came with strings.
Vogler doesn't set me up to
have a mobster take a swing at me.
- I'm sure House didn't know—
- Joey's pressure dropped.
Pushed I.V. fluids, now he's
holding a hundred systolic.
Septic? No, it looks like
he's bleeding into his liver.
Varices. See it with
chronic hep "C" all the time.
Biopsy's back.
Two findings. Number one,
lymphocytic infiltrate
and no bridging fibrosis.
Whatever's killing him's
not hep "C." It's acute.
Who said that? I forget.
What are you doing here? I
told you you were off the case.
Right. Your diabolic plan to convince
the evil genius he's in the clear,
so he'll let his guard down
and make a fatal mistake.
Sure. Well, it's clearly
not gonna work now.
What evil genius?
If we knew that, we wouldn't
need a diabolic plan, would we?
- House thinks someone
ratted him out to Vogler.
- What, one of us?
No, you guys love me too much.
Look, if it's not the
hep "C," then what's
the problem? What's
causing the liver failure?
Finding number two, toxins.
No. He's only 30 years
old, and his job doesn't
expose him to heavy
metals or environmental...
He's a 30-year-old mobster.
He doesn't have a job that results
in accidental exposure to toxins.
He has a job that results in
intentional exposure to toxins.
Someone's poisoned him.
Whatever this toxin is,
it's doing the job and fast.
How long till we have the
next round of test results?
- About four hours.
- Too bad his liver's only
gonna last another two.
- We're gonna have to get him a new one.
- What, in two hours?
There is another way.
Relax. It's kosher.
This is so bizarre.
Not really. We just take
Joey's blood out of his body...
and run it through a pig.
The pig's liver does what
Joey's can't. It cleans the blood.
Which we send right back to him.
And the pig makes him better?
Nope. Just buys us some time to
figure out what's poisoning your brother.
Like nothin'. Like you
do this all the time.
Oh, we've basically got
a barn in the basement.
Cross off hemlock.
You thought he was being
poisoned by hemlock?
Dr. Euripides tell
you to check for that?
It grows wild by the
highways out here.
So, how much do you like House?
- Chase has a big mouth.
- Yeah. He's probably the one
who ratted to Vogler.
- I don't think that he would— -
Does it hurt when you're with House?
Little pain in the tummy,
but it sort of feels good too?
- I don't have the right to show
interest in someone?
- You absolutely do.
And I absolutely have the
right to humiliate you for it.
Anything?
White blood count's
low, probably a result of
the illness. Nothing
to connect to the liver.
- Is he a smoker?
- Let me check.
Early signs of emphysema. He's
been smoking at least a dozen years.
Eighteen. You got that
from the white count?
Nope. Got that
from the chest X-ray.
White count just
tells me he's quitting.
Two weeks ago.
How's your tummy?
Flat and taut.
I've been on the
job for 12 years.
You put $3,000 in your
wife's checking account
this morning. I wanna
know where it came from.
I got a perfect record.
Where did you get the money?
Cancel the thumbscrews.
I've got our culprit.
Who? Not who, "Hu."
- Huh?
- Thanks for playing along.
Chai Hu. Chinese herb in
his "quit smoking" candy.
Reduces cravings. Also
reduces his white blood count.
Oh, yeah, he also took enough
of them to poison himself.
We'll keep him on the pig for a few more
hours, and then take him off the candy.
He'll be fine.
Pig won't be. Oh, no.
Hey.
Hey, feelin' better?
I'm famished.
I think they got fish
sticks on the menu.
Ah, yeah. Makes me miss prison.
So, the mobster's good to go?
I'll keep him overnight,
then let the feds know...
he's good to rat out
whoever he wants.
- Brother won't be happy.
- Maybe I have to give back the car.
You should let Vogler
tell the feds. Why?
Because it matters to him.
Because you humiliated him
the first time Joey was released.
- You think you should still
be in third there, ace?
- He humiliated himself.
And because your job
depends on the kind of mood
Vogler's in at the end of
his marathon with Cuddy.
Seriously, man, have
you ever actually driven an
automobile before? There
are four gears, you know?
The '66 came with
a "shut up" button.
I have a problem with the tests.
I need to know...
It is my medical opinion that the
patient is healthy and can be released.
Thanks for letting us know.
Get me the U.S.
Attorney's office.
I see you found out what we're
meeting about. You're having a meeting?
Well, whatever the reason,
the coat looks good on you.
Chai Hu lozenges cause this
kind of liver failure? No way.
Not by themselves. But in combination with
the interferon it's like gas to a flame.
- What interferon?
- For the hep "C."
- What hep "C"?
- Oops.
Is hiding a mobster's
hep "C" that important?
Is letting the feds know
everything that important?
You are a piece of work.
Even now, knowing— Ed...
Edward.
Joey's back in a coma.
He's stable, but comatose.
Worse than before.
He's on a ventilator.
Question is, why?
It's not his brain.
It's not a toxin.
Our friend Babe
helped with that one.
- So, what else?
- Hep "C."
We never really treated
it. We stopped the
interferon when it
started poisoning his liver.
Am I gonna have to write a song
about it? His chronic hep "C"...
was not bad enough to
produce these symptoms.
- The estrogen level indicates it is.
- It indicates something else entirely.
We can't give him
interferon now. There are
still traces of the
lozenges in his system.
It’ll just poison him
again. Genetics.
We don't treat the
virus, we change it.
A nonnucleoside
allosteric inhibitor.
It's never been tried on a
human being. It could kill him.
What's the difference?
He's dead without it.
They're running a trial...
on dogs at St. Sebastian's
out in Philadelphia.
I'll make the call.
What else could cause his
estrogen level to be that high?
Nothing.
We're gonna put
the medicine in here.
Don't want it to burn
his veins when it goes in.
And you have
no idea if it’ll work.
It's shown promise in testing.
Ma-Maybe there's nothing up
there. I watched him like a hawk.
Pretty sure you didn't.
I—I didn't let him play
with any more little toys.
Thus forcing him to
shove a big one up there.
Stop, or I snap your nose off!
He— He's not too smart.
Genetics is a powerful force.
On the other hand, maybe
he's smarter than you think.
What's goin' on?
Just give me a second.
Always wanted to
use one of these.
Tilt his head back.
I—I don't know. I do...
Just tilt his head back.
Nice grasp of concepts.
Relationships. Very smart.
Very cool.
First the policeman, the
fireman, then the fire truck.
Your brother was sending
in teams to save the cat.
Wow.
Sometimes the simplest answer...
What types of comas
do you just snap out of?
He's not snapping out of
this one. He's not improving.
You've crossed out estrogen.
You got an explanation?
Yes, I have, a very simple one.
And?
It's private.
You think I'm the
one— Running to Vogler.
You're currently
top of the list.
Toxic comas—
Person's away from the cause
long enough, they recover.
The feds checked for poisons.
We checked for poisons. I didn't do it.
It's not a poison
then. An allergy.
- Did you hear me?
- What about a food sensitivity?
All his food is strictly
controlled. There's no
correlation between his
meals and his condition.
He had steak and potatoes
before the first coma,
and the hospital served fish
sticks before the second one.
You can trust me.
Problem is, if I
can't trust you,
I can't trust your statement
that I can trust you.
But thanks anyway.
You've been a big help.
So, where did you
get the money? What?
Someone paid you off.
What are you talkin' about?
He wasn't poisoned.
You told us that...
Who's talking about poison?
I'm talking about payoffs, graft.
Leave him alone.
You paid the marshal off.
I didn't pay him to
poison my brother.
No. It just worked out that way.
I gave the guy some money
to bring in some decent food.
Better than fish sticks?
I'm thinking steak.
We asked for pasta, but those
stupid feds could care less...
He had steak before both comas.
Your brother has ornithine
transcarbamylase deficiency.
Want me to write it down?
Good, 'cause it takes a while. It's
genetic, can present at any time.
If the patient eats
a large amount of
protein, especially
if he's not used to it...
What, that's it? He just stays off
the red meat, and he's gonna be fine?
Yes. If I'm right and we stop the
current treatment, he gets better.
If we stop the current
treatment and I'm wrong, he dies.
- Why would you be wrong?
- His estrogen level.
O.T.D. doesn't explain
his estrogen level.
But I have a theory.
There is one chemical
that, if ingested,
can cause a person's estrogen
level to increase dramatically.
- What is it?
- It's called estrogen.
Joey's taking estrogen?
What, he wants a sex change?
No, nothing like that.
It's called "Male Flame."
It's probably more consumer-friendly
in the original Chinese.
It's an herbal aphrodisiac
marketed to gay men.
- Ah, here we go.
- And it's sold on the same Web site
that sells his Chai Hu lozenges.
Guess what's in it?
It starts with an "E."
You wanna get hit too?
That would be quite a trick. He slapped
me so hard, his brother turned straight.
Joey's a big-time mobster. Guys
like that don't get raped in prison.
They get gifts. They get
food, drugs, cigarettes.
Cable TV.
Joey is not gay.
Maybe not gay, but
certainly delightful.
You, on the other hand, hitting a
doctor, even if it was only Chase,
and asking another one to keep
Joey's chart fresh and homo-free...
That's a bit of an
overreaction, wouldn't you say?
It's almost like you're scared
that it might be true. You're wrong.
Okay. Then don't
stop the treatment.
But if you're wrong, he dies.
Okay.
He never said anything
to me about it, not once.
That's what I love about you
mob guys, so tolerant of others.
So accepting.
Only way he was coming
out was way, way out.
Lose the tattoos, change his
name, move to another town.
How's a guy like
him gonna do that?
Witness Protection.
It's not just for
witnesses anymore.
You can go in now,
sit with him if you want.
- How much longer?
- It's only been three hours.
- If it's the O.T.D.— - If it's the
O.T.D.? What if House is wrong, huh?
That severe a reaction,
it'll take some time...
- He makes these assumptions about people,
talks you into things— - Mr. Arnello...
He's awake. He wants to see you.
You look like crap.
That's a joke. See? I'm
sick. I said you look like crap.
You have no idea what I
just went through out there.
You kept gettin' worse.
And Dr. House kept
sayin' all this crap.
You know, if—if I think you're normal, then
he's gonna keep giving you the medicine.
- If you weren't—
- Weren't what?
Normal?
Yeah.
He said you were a fag.
Witness Protection— That's
your big chance to be one.
- You believed him?
- I don't know what to believe.
You were sick.
I had to make a decision. I
thought you were gonna die.
You believed him.
He stopped the medicine.
Here I am.
- I wanted to talk to you about this.
- There's nothin' to talk about.
You, uh,
ordered some Chinese
Internet health crap,
and they sent the wrong
pills, and you took 'em.
Yeah, yeah. That, uh...
That must be it.
You wanna testify?
Go ahead.
I told the doc.
He said it's okay.
- I don't expect you to understand.
- I don't.
All I need to know is
you're my brother, Joey.
If you think this...
thing, whatever, is
gonna make you happy,
then I think you should do it.
You should.
Vogler wants to fire you.
Lose the whole department.
Good thing you fought
for me though, right?
Dress was a nice move,
but you gotta follow it up.
Nasty weekend in Vegas.
Something that shows off
your real administrative skills.
He threatened to fire me.
I'm sorry.
So, how long do I have? I've got
a lot of personal stuff to pack up.
And I assume you're
gonna want to throw a party.
I told him I know where
the bodies are buried.
The stuff he needs to know that's not
in the books. I told him he can't ditch me.
He's only keeping you on because
you know the secret handshakes.
He's a quick study. Six months, he'll have
the moves down. He won't need you anymore.
- I'll deal with that then.
- So I stay.
Yes.
But some things
are going to change.
Profits. New world order.
Everything's about profits.
Yeah, that's real new.
You could rent out the Corvette every
once in a while or lend it to a friend.
That would be easy,
and it would be wrong.
But Cuddy stood up for you.
To a point.
To what point?
I gotta do six more clinic hours
a month. So do two of them.
Why only two?
'Cause one of them's gone.
I gotta fire somebody.
Good morning.
That's some bad hat, Harry.