You have to work out
whatever feelings you're
having about Dr. Marcel.
Fast.
Get me a Narcan inhaler.
You overdosed.
But you're gonna be all right.
You let this get
way too personal, Will.
Never a good idea.
For God's sakes,
isn't it personal?
You lost a brother to drugs.
Enough!
I met you this morning.
I'm gonna try to
turn things around.
Good.
Hey.
Hi.
I love you.
Easy.
Oh, God.
Sorry.
Only me.
I wasn't expecting that.
Hey, I know
work's not the place
for ambush affection,
but I couldn't help myself.
I won't hold it against you.
What's up?
I haven't seen
a smile this big
since Navy beat Army.
Just thinking about
being a dad.
Birthday parties,
coaching teams.
That's a decade down the road.
We are three weeks into IVF.
You know what they say,
you blink
and the kids are grown.
Hey.
What up?
Pelicans covered
the spread.
How many rings
do the Pelicans have?
Go Bulls.
Yeah, we'll see.
I'm a horrible person,
aren't I?
No, you're human.
What can I do to help?
You got a time machine?
Hey, you.
Hey.
Date last night, spill it.
It was nice.
He was polite,
handsome, smart, but...
I don't think so.
Oh. Well, polite, smart
and handsome. Sounds awful.
All right, the real reason,
he's a psych professor.
The way he looked at me,
I just couldn't shake
the feeling that
I was being analyzed.
This is the fourth
first date
without even
considering a second.
Well, I'm glad
you're counting, Mom.
Look, it doesn't matter,
because none of those guys
were gonna work out anyways.
Wow. ESP.
Say, do you know
when the Saints
are gonna win
another Super Bowl?
All right, well, let me know
if you get another vision.
All I'm saying is the right
second date is out there,
and I'll know it
when I meet him.
Help! Please, my son!
Oh, my...
I got him.
Where am I going?
Trauma One.
Help
my husband and son!
Help!
Help, help, help, help!
Help him, I...
I didn't know what to do.
Okay, bruising on his neck.
Protect it and bag him.
Hold C-spine. What's his name?
Jamie.
Jamie. Hey, Jamie.
Can you hear me?
Okay, okay. Take it easy.
You're okay. Take it easy.
What happened?
It was an accident.
I choked him out.
I had to.
It all happened so fast.
I didn't realize,
I just wanted it to stop.
Jamie was screaming,
Dylan was crying and...
Gordon, I want you
to take a deep breath, okay?
Take a deep breath.
All right.
Have a seat. Sit down.
Okay.
And, um... I...
I just want you
to tell me...
Tell me what happened.
Okay, so I was driving,
talking with Bella, my wife.
Um... The boys were
in the back.
Jamie was playing
with his iPad.
Dylan grabbed it from him,
wouldn't give it back.
Jamie can't control his anger.
He started punching Dylan,
got out of his seatbelt
and got on top of him
and kept pounding.
Bella couldn't pull him off.
I could hear Jamie's fists
cracking against Dylan's face.
He was screaming for help,
so I pulled over.
I just threw myself
on top of Jamie.
I wrapped my arms
around him and held him
as tight as I could.
When he gets like this,
the bear hugs are the only
thing that bring him back.
Bring him back?
From his dark place.
Huh.
Okay.
Will you... Will you excuse me
for a moment, Gordon?
Yeah.
We're gonna take care
of you, little man, okay?
All right.
Ordered a CT, but
I'm almost positive
there's a bilateral
mandible fracture.
Gonna need surgery
to wire it shut.
Man, Ethan, kid's only
six years old.
Jamie?
He's stable, but tormented.
Dad choked him out.
Probably so he couldn't defend
his little brother.
Sometimes I hate the ED.
Jamie, how you doing?
I'm Dr. Charles.
Um, would you mind
if I looked at your hands?
Fifth metacarpal
is broken on each hand.
That's really gotta hurt.
Um, look, we're gonna get you
completely fixed up, okay?
It's nice
to meet you.
This is not child abuse.
Thanks, man.
You know,
one of the volunteers
works at a rehab center.
If you'd like,
she can tell you
about their program.
Yeah, sure.
Maybe another time.
If you change your mind,
we're here.
Will.
Yeah?
You have been here for hours.
Go home, get some rest.
Yeah. I could use some sleep
before I start my shift.
Ah, damn it!
Starts in a half-hour.
Uh, okay. All right,
that woman over there,
her name's Susan.
When she comes down,
she's gonna be hungry.
I stashed some
protein bars...
I know.
I saw.
The electrolyte drinks,
too. Get to work.
I'll be back later.
You call me
if you need anything.
That's the cry, that one.
It's not "I'm hungry"
or "I'm tired." It's new.
Okay. I know,
I know, Axel.
You're in pain,
and my touching
is only making it worse.
Any changes in
his sleep pattern?
No. Every baby book I read
said put your child on
a schedule and stick to it.
Been there.
My son's almost four.
I know, I know.
Almost finished.
Okay. What about diet?
I had to start using formula.
Just not enough
hours in the day
to pump, work, nurse,
do laundry, pump again.
Single mom?
Yeah, me, too.
Dad still in the picture?
No. But I'm okay with it.
Well, I'm not seeing anything
out of the ordinary.
I mean, the switch from
breast milk to formula
could be upsetting
Axel's stomach.
Have you noticed any diarrhea
since the change?
Here and there, but this cry
has been consistent
for the last month.
I'll test for allergies,
but infants and crying...
Don't say colic. I've been to
three pediatricians.
They all diagnosed colic
and sent me home.
No, something else
is going on.
Run tests, X-rays, scans.
Just please, figure it out.
Okay, well,
why don't we start
with some basic labs
and go from there?
Is that okay?
Sure. Thank you.
I'll send a nurse in
to get started.
Thank you.
Hey, Jamie,
you hungry? Thirsty?
I know your casts are bulky.
I can help you.
I'll leave the tray
right here, just in case.
They're talking about me.
About what I did
to my little brother.
I didn't mean to hurt him.
Okay.
I'm so sorry.
It's okay, okay. Okay.
After two miscarriages
and five failed IVF attempts,
we'd had enough heartbreak.
We adopted Jamie
when he was a few days old.
Best day of our lives.
Do you know anything
about his birth parents?
Nothing really.
Um, Mom was young,
in foster care.
We don't know
anything about Dad.
Well, Jamie's 11 now,
so how old was he when
he first started acting out?
As an infant,
he didn't like being held,
was always fidgety.
Hmm. How about
as a toddler?
Sitting still, taking turns,
following directions,
they were all a challenge.
When did Jamie's behavior
start becoming aggressive?
Elementary school. Fights with
classmates and teachers.
We're homeschooling now.
And your other son, Dylan,
is he adopted as well?
Yeah.
It was initially Jamie's idea.
He wanted to be a big brother.
And in the beginning, Dylan's
presence seemed to calm Jamie.
He would push his stroller,
feed him his bottle,
let him climb all over him.
They are so... Were so close.
I'm assuming that Jamie's been
evaluated by a psychiatrist.
Several.
They all just add
to the diagnosis.
Intermittent
Explosive Disorder.
Co-morbid ADHD.
Disruptive Mood
Dysregulation Disorder.
Tell me, what meds
is he on right now?
Risperidone, Valproic Acid,
Lithium, Adderall, Tenex.
They all work for a bit,
but then...
He always ends up
in his "dark place."
Mr. and Mrs. Shaw,
Dylan's out of surgery.
I'll take you to Recovery.
Look, what I'd like to do
is admit Jamie
for a five-day hold.
That'll give us a chance
to assess the situation
and come up with some
treatment options for you.
Anything. Please,
just help him.
Shh. He's out.
Cried himself to sleep.
What'd the tests say?
The labs were normal, um,
but the babygram revealed
a mild bowel distention.
There are no obstructions,
however, the stool
in Axel's diaper was watery.
That suggests a GI issue.
Okay, what do you do for that?
Endoscopy.
So, under general anesthesia,
a surgeon will guide
a camera down Axel's throat
into his GI tract
to search for abnormalities.
And if necessary,
we'll do a colonoscopy
as well.
Can I be there?
I wouldn't recommend that.
I mean, seeing
the scope inside Axel,
it might be upsetting.
No, I really wanna be there.
Are you sure? Because I can't
overstate how distressing
this procedure can be
for a parent to watch.
I mean, seeing your child
on the table unconscious...
I'll be okay.
All right. Techs will be by
shortly to bring up Axel.
I'll be there as well.
Signed.
Thank you.
Hey, Doris.
Julia, the mom
in Treatment Three,
did you get a read?
I like her.
I wish all parents
would handle
the ED that smoothly.
You don't think
she's too composed?
I mean, her son
is clearly in distress
and she hasn't even
broken a sweat.
There's that
Manning ESP again.
Okay. She asked me to run
more tests on her baby
than necessary,
and now she wants to be front
row when he gets scoped.
You don't think
that's a little odd?
Uh... If you say so.
Call Dr. Frisch. I wanna put
Axel on today's schedule
for an endoscopy.
She's busy.
Omphalocele repair.
Gonna be
locked away all day.
But I'm free. I can
take care of it right now,
if you'd like.
Okay, thanks.
Meet you upstairs.
Nurse Doris.
Thank you.
Sure.
Nurse April.
Dr. Marcel.
Okay, stomach and esophagus
appear normal. Let's reset
for a colonoscopy.
Julia, are you okay?
You don't have to
keep watching, you know.
No, I'm okay. It's just...
I have a scrape on my stomach.
I forgot to change
the bandage, and it's
beginning to slide around.
Why don't I have a nurse
change that out for you
when we're back in the ED?
Oh. Okay.
Yeah. Thanks.
Yeah.
Somehow I keep
scraping myself
right there.
I don't know how.
Mom brain, I guess.
Right there.
Okay. Sharp
or dull pain, Chloe?
I think both.
Is that even possible?
Unfortunately.
How long have you
been feeling off?
I don't know, couple weeks.
Three months.
She downplays everything.
We just got married.
I figured the pain
was just nervous energy.
But the wedding's
behind us now
and I still feel blah.
Any constipation, bloating?
She hasn't pooped
in a week.
So, Chloe, I'm gonna need
to take a closer look
to see what's going on.
We'll get some X-rays,
a pelvic and a rectal.
Just keeping the sexy
flowing, aren't I?
Till death do us part.
Well, a nurse
will come in and
get things going.
Congratulations,
Mr. and Mrs. James.
Crockett.
Yeah?
Perfect timing.
Single vehicle accident
landing now. Massive trauma.
I'll have Baghdad ready.
Got it.
What do you got?
Lucy Seaver, 20, GCS three,
intubated in the field.
Bilateral femur fractures
and traction splints.
SATS 100% on oxygen.
Okay, Lucy, don't be afraid.
You're in the ED.
We're gonna take
good care of you.
Parents should be here
any second.
They were on the scene.
They were in the car
behind Lucy.
They saw the crash?
And the aftermath.
Lucy's car was so mangled,
it took us 20 minutes
to extricate her and
get her in the ambo.
Okay, all right. Here we go.
On my count, one, two, three.
Good breath sounds
bilaterally.
Belly's hard as a rock.
BP is 70s.
Two of plasma,
two of blood
on the transfuser.
Trigger the MTP.
Let's FAST her.
Ton of soft tissue damage.
Glass everywhere.
All right, no,
scrap the X-ray.
No time.
Give me that wand.
FAST is positive. Yeah,
I gotta get into her belly.
All right, let's go.
Let's
open up the Hybrid OR.
Oh, my God, Lucy!
Get her
prepped, all right?
Lucy!
Let's get her
on the move.
All right.
Mr. and Mrs. Seaver,
if you will.
Your daughter has been
seriously injured.
She needs immediate surgery
to control internal bleeding.
It's fixable?
She's gonna live?
We will do everything we can.
Huh.
So, uh, what is
your favorite sport?
Football, I guess.
Bears fan?
My dad likes them.
I like the Chiefs.
Oh, really? Well,
how'd that happen?
The quarterback.
Saw a video of him throw
the ball out of the stadium.
That was cool.
I saw that clip, too.
And you're right,
it was cool.
You know, I was wondering
if we could talk
a bit about...
About what happens,
you know, about how it feels
when you start
to get upset?
I don't know... Kind of...
It's fuzzy.
Fuzzy? So kind of like,
um, like a dream?
I guess.
And when that happens,
I mean, what does it...
What does it feel like?
I mean, like, you know,
I mean, in here?
I mean, do you feel anything
in your body?
It feels like
I'm gonna explode.
Wow, I'm sorry.
That must be
really scary.
You wanna take
a little break?
I want this off. It's sticking
to me. I can't stand it.
Okay. Okay.
Don't touch me!
I hate you! I hate you!
Let go! Stop it!
Go away! Stop it!
Go away! Go away!
Two of Haldol!
Stop it! No! No!
I don't want that!
Stop! Stop it! No! Stop! No!
Stop! Stop it!
I wish I could tell you
exactly what happened
in there,
what triggered Jamie,
but honestly, I can't.
I have reviewed
his medical records.
I've spoken with
several of his doctors.
And what is clear to me
is that your son
is struggling
with multiple impulse control
and mood regulation disorders.
So what do we do?
We just wanna help him.
Well, it's the hospital's
recommendation
that Jamie be admitted
to a residential facility
where he can receive
sustained clinical care
as well as supportive therapy.
A residential facility?
Mmm-hmm.
Yeah. Mrs. Shaw,
you know, Jamie's 11.
Puberty is fast approaching.
And that surge of hormones
is just gonna undoubtedly
exacerbate his conditions.
You know, just
make him more difficult
to treat in general,
you know, find the right
balance of meds.
And a specialized
setting like this
will have the behavioral
resources Jamie needs
for the future.
And it'll be a safe place
for him right now.
Anything for our son.
All right. I'll take care
of all the arrangements.
Okay. Looking good.
Four tears in the small bowel
mesentery tied off.
Liver's packed and hemostatic.
Pressure's no good.
We maxed out on pressors?
Yeah, and I've given ten units
of blood and ten of plasma.
She's still
bleeding somewhere.
I don't...
Hematoma on the pelvis.
Bigger than my first look
and growing.
Gotta assume the pelvis
is shattered and bleeding.
Okay, team, new deal.
Preperitoneal packs.
Let's go.
Hey, Chloe,
how you feeling?
Like a stuffed turkey.
X-rays showed
your bowel is FOS.
Full of...
Stool.
The pelvic suggests
your uterus is enlarged.
So I suspect a fibroid
is sitting on the uterus,
putting pressure
on the rectum.
You were right.
The last few weeks
she was scouring the web
with her symptoms,
and a fibroid fit the bill.
We're trying to have a baby.
Internet says fibroids
hinder the ability
to conceive.
Not all fibroids
are created equal.
Okay, I'm gonna order a pelvic
ultrasound and a gyne consult.
I'll check back soon.
And no more googling, okay?
Doctor's orders.
How's it going with
your six-month-old?
Dead end.
Nothing's jumping out on
any of the labs
and the endoscopy
and colonoscopy report.
I'm starting to wonder
if it's really baby Axel
who's the one that's sick.
What do you mean?
Well, Mom, she's just...
She's got this air about her.
This nonchalance that screams,
"Yeah, my baby's in the ED,
but it's just another day."
Well, it wouldn't be
the first time we see
a parent pretend
their child was sick
to get attention.
Yeah, unfortunately.
Have you seen Dr. Charles?
He's upstairs.
I'll page him for you.
Thanks.
Yeah.
Dr. Manning, it's Julia.
There's something
you need to see.
You know, I had my appendix
taken out when I was
in tenth grade.
All right, well,
let's take a look.
Oh, my God.
This is a fistula.
Basically, a tunnel
between your small bowel
and your skin.
The green fluid
is leaking from
your intestines.
Seriously?
Mmm-hmm.
I've been getting
these scrapes for years.
They heal up.
It's been my intestines
oozing out?
The tissue sample taken
during Axel's endoscopy,
I'd like it biopsied.
Biopsy? You're testing
for cancer?
No, something new.
And now I'm thinking
you may have it as well.
The test that I ran on
your son, I'd like
to run on you as well.
Okay.
All right, pelvis is packed.
Bleeding is under control.
Call ICU and tell them
Lucy is coming up to rewarm.
Something's wrong.
Pressure's still
in the toilet.
74 over 38
and falling.
What?
She's peri-arrest.
She's still bleeding?
The abdomen is dry.
Pelvis is contained. I mean,
we are hemostatic, Marty.
She's bradying down.
No pulse.
Come on.
Milligram of epi.
Epi's in.
Pulse check?
Go.
Still nothing.
Come on, Lucy.
Hold compressions.
What do you got?
Asystole.
Come on.
Come on, Lucy. Come on.
Damn it!
Time of death, 16:17.
Okay, if everyone
could clear the room, please.
I'd like a moment alone
with my patient.
What's going on?
There's room for Jamie
at Meyerbrook,
which is the only
residential facility capable
of handling his needs.
Unfortunately,
neither his private insurance
or State Medicaid
is gonna cover the cost.
What about an individual
care grant from the state?
I already looked into it.
It's no help.
Yeah, the grant's
so underfunded, it wouldn't
come close to what's needed.
So what's plan B?
Well, you know, I'm gonna just
try to use the five-day hold
to normalize his meds
as best I can.
And I do know
a brilliant guy
who specializes in
these kind of disorders
that I wanna refer him to.
An outpatient service?
Jamie pummeled Dylan
over an iPad.
The kid's jaw
is wired shut.
He's only six years old.
He's going to invade
his brother's space again.
And when that happens
and Jamie loses his temper,
I'm worried
he could kill Dylan.
I don't like it either, Ethan,
but I mean, you know,
I can't hold him here forever.
I get it, but we have
an obligation
to protect Dylan.
And he needs our help
just as much as Jamie.
Dr. Halstead, the gyne
attending on call came down
a few minutes ago.
She's with Chloe right now.
Great, thanks.
...if you feel
comfortable with that.
Okay.
Dr. Hannah Asher, Gynecology.
Will Halstead.
It's nice to meet you.
Yeah. Likewise.
I was just explaining to
Chloe and David that
I reviewed
her pelvic ultrasound.
Considering the location
and size of the fibroid,
I believe
removing it surgically
is the best course
of treatment.
A myomectomy?
By who? When?
Me. Today.
Chloe, David, you should know
this surgery can be risky.
Yes. I've explained
the pros and cons,
Dr. Halstead.
Was clear that while
this is a big operation,
it's also a common one.
You know, nevertheless,
complications could arise.
So, I would suggest
non-surgical options.
Hormone therapy will
shrink the fibroid.
Well, that's what
Dr. Asher said,
but to ensure that
it doesn't grow back, Chloe
would have to go on the pill.
We're anxious
to start a family.
The pill takes that
off the table.
In the short term, yes,
but not permanently.
Actually,
it kind of does.
I'm 41, Dr. Halstead.
My window for getting pregnant
is already closing.
If I choose hormones,
I might as well slam it shut.
We appreciate your passion,
Dr. Halstead.
But surgery is
the best for us.
I'll get that started.
It was so nice
meeting both of you.
Doctor.
Excuse me just a moment.
Dr. Asher? Doctor!
Hmm?
You can't perform
this surgery.
Hmm?
I mean, you shouldn't
even be working.
Look, thank you for your help
last week, but I'm better now.
I'm over that hump.
So, heroin addiction
is like a cold?
What, you just
get over it?
What I saw
at that injection site...
Was me having a bad day.
A bad day?
Mmm-hmm.
You...
You OD'd.
For all I know,
you're high right now.
Right. And how many
all-nighters
you pull over there
since I saw you last, huh?
Three? Four?
Maybe I should be the one
worried about your judgment.
Don't twist this. I'm not
an addict about to operate.
You step into that OR, you put
Chloe's life in jeopardy.
I would never risk
the well-being of a patient.
And not that it is
any of your business,
I'm sober now.
I'd expect an addict
to say that.
Chloe is in good hands
with me.
Axel has Crohn's disease?
But he's only six months old.
Well, it's rare
in children,
let alone infants,
but not unheard of.
Isn't Crohn's a diet thing?
Axel's barely
started on solids.
Well, diet aggravates
Crohn's, but it's not
the cause. Genetics is.
Crohn's tends to
cluster in families.
Whoa. My test results...
Show that you have
Crohn's as well.
The fistula is just evidence
of the severity.
This doesn't make sense.
If I've got Crohn's
badly enough
to burn a hole in my skin,
shouldn't it bother me?
Well, fistulas themselves
are painless,
but, yes, a Crohn's flare-up
is excruciating.
You should be in pain. Agony.
Yeah, well,
I don't feel a thing.
This is weirding you out,
isn't it?
It's definitely unusual.
Or actually, maybe it's...
Maybe it's rare.
Let me ask you a question.
What emotion are you
feeling right now?
Uh, I'm not sure
what you mean.
Well, I just told you
that you and your son
have an inflammatory
bowel disease.
I mean, what are you feeling?
Stress? Anxiety? Fear?
Confusion, that's for sure.
You know what? I'd like to
run one more test. Okay?
Okay.
B, it's taking too long.
Check with Dr. Asher?
Again? I've already gone
in there twice for you,
Dr. Halstead.
Please, I'm treating Chloe
in the ED.
I just wanna make sure
Dr. Asher's got
everything under control.
Fine.
Thank you.
Dr. Asher said, "Go away."
Nope. Staying right here.
Hey.
Got your page.
You have a new plan
to help Jamie?
Yeah.
Yep, I do.
So, Mr. and Mrs. Shaw,
I have given this a
tremendous amount of thought.
I've consulted with
numerous colleagues,
with social workers,
with our Executive Director
of Patient Services.
Jamie needs to be
at the Meyerbrook
Residential Facility.
So the insurance companies,
they agreed to pay?
No. Both your
private insurance
and Medicaid won't budge.
Then, uh... I'm confused.
There is a way to force
Medicaid to cover
Meyerbrook's cost in full.
It's called
a psychiatric lockout.
But it will require you
to surrender Jamie
to this hospital.
Surrender? I don't understand.
If you were to leave Jamie
here and refuse to come back,
Child Protective Services
would have to take
custody of him.
Then, as a ward of the state,
legally, Illinois
would have to provide him
with the mental health
services that he needs.
Meyerbrook.
This is insane.
We're not doing this.
So there's no other way?
I'm so sorry,
but there just isn't.
We would absolutely
find a way
for you to maintain
contact with Jamie,
but you also
need to know that,
legally, you won't have
any say in his care.
We're still his parents.
This doesn't change that.
Nothing changes that.
No. No, no, no.
We're not abandoning our son.
Mrs. Shaw, you will
not be abandoning him.
This...
This won't be forever.
Jamie needs us to do this.
When?
I cannot imagine how agonizing
this decision must be,
but the sooner Jamie
starts to heal,
the sooner you all can
look forward to
becoming a family again.
Bella,
it's to save him.
Hi.
There's something
that we need
to tell you. Okay?
Listen, buddy, it's gonna be
okay. But right now,
the best thing...
We think it's better
if... For you to stay
with the doctors.
They'll help you.
No, Mom!
Please, I'll be better!
It's okay. Just stay.
I wanna go home!
Please, no!
Dr. Marcel, Lucy's parents
are still in the waiting room.
You haven't told them...
She should be alive.
Well, it's been over an hour.
They need to know that
their daughter has passed.
I won't speak to them until
I can explain how she died,
why I couldn't save her.
Can you give me some light?
Right here.
Every other injury was either
a tear or a rip in the skin.
This one's a hole.
Something embedded inside.
More shrapnel
from the windshield?
Doesn't really
feel like glass.
Can you swing that
X-ray machine around?
Go ahead.
That's a bullet.
Lucy was shot?
Lucy was shot? How?
She was driving
down the highway,
alone in the car.
The steep angle of entry
shows that the bullet
struck from above
and lodged
into Lucy's pelvis.
It severed
her external iliac artery.
Shot from above?
Yes.
Now, the police
will run ballistics.
But they believe,
and the science backs it up,
that someone, somewhere
in the city, fired
a gun into the air.
And when that bullet
came down,
it struck Lucy.
Someone? Somewhere?
And now our daughter is dead?
I'm so sorry.
A nurse will come to
take you to see Lucy.
Excuse me.
Hey. The additional blood work
you ordered on Axel's mom.
Oh, wow.
This whole time,
my take on Julia has been off.
Way off.
We love fun
We're going out
and having some
We love fun
You know we're gonna
have a ton
I've never heard
that song before.
We Love Fun by
The Bouncing Souls.
I don't know
any real lullabies.
Julia, all day I've been
troubled by your demeanor
because you didn't seem
worried about Axel.
But now I know
you really aren't
worried.
And I suspect you've never
felt anxious, depressed
or even afraid
your entire life,
have you?
No, not really.
Same goes for
physical pain,
doesn't it?
Kind of feels like this is
a trick question or something.
No. Okay. So,
when I had my son,
labor was a beast.
Intense pressure, cramps,
spasms. But you didn't feel
any of that, did you?
Nope, whole thing
just kind of tingled.
But I've always had
an extremely
high pain tolerance.
I know. There's something
wrong with me, right?
My friends have been
saying it forever.
Wait, is there something
wrong with me?
No. No. But there
is something
missing from you.
So, we all have what's called
a FAAHP1 pseudogene.
Your preliminary blood work
shows that you have
a rare microdeletion
which affects
your insensitivity
to pain.
When I was a kid, my dad would
say everyone else were wimps,
that we were a hardy breed,
that pain was just a word.
Well, microdeletion is
a genetic thing.
So, it's likely that
your father and other family
members have it as well.
Julia?
What's wrong?
I passed Axel
the gene for Crohn's,
but not the one
so he won't be tortured by it.
And if I didn't know
when I hurt myself,
I wouldn't have known
when I hurt my son.
I probably made the bath
too hot, didn't dress him
warm enough...
Hey, you knew
it wasn't colic.
You knew to bring your son
into the ED.
You may not feel
everything he feels,
but you're his mother, you'll
always know what he needs.
Uh, keep going.
Grab her husband,
I'll meet you in Recovery.
Wonderful.
You're still here.
Is Chloe okay?
Yeah. She's fine.
Operation was flawless.
This time.
How about you and I keep
our distance from one another?
Yeah, fine. Just as soon as
you stop treating patients,
and seek treatment
for your addiction.
Screw you, Halstead.
In that case,
I'm going to submit a letter
to the hospital's
Chief Medical Officer,
and that decision
will be made for you.
That's a stupid idea.
You out me,
I out your own involvement
in a not-quite-legal
injection site.
So if I go down,
so do you.
So if you wanna report me,
have at it, cowboy.
Hey.
Heard you had
a rough one today.
You all right?
Yeah. Little boy and his mom,
your ESP pan out?
Not even close.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Night.
Hey.
Today sucked.
Yes, it did.
We just don't have
enough psychiatric
resources for kids.
And unfortunately, the Shaws
won't be the last family
to face a lockout.
But Jamie will get
the help he needs.
And that's a good thing.
Hey, buddy.
Come on, let's go.