So, I've got this friend and
great guy, a little stubborn,
but, as life would
have it, he's got cancer.
Is that so? Don't worry.
He's keeping his head
up, staying positive.
And here's the thing...
Oh, there's a thing.
I assumed cancer
was the big twist.
No, see, my friend
recently got this new doctor
who, as it turns out,
is making it really hard
for my friend to stay positive.
Hang on, this sounds
like somebody I know.
Really? Weird.
Not only did she put my friend on
an impossible to maintain schedule,
but now she's insisting that
my friend get a feeding tube.
So he was really hoping that
he could get a second opinion.
And your friend wouldn't also
happen to be the medical director
of a major public hospital
in New York, would they?
Well, he asked me to
keep his name out of it.
Max, I... No, no names.
That would be a huge betrayal
to my incredibly private friend.
But my friend was wondering
if maybe you could talk to
Dr. Stauton and change her mind?
I will do no such
thing. I'm this way.
Which is why I'm going this way.
Okay. But she's
totally gone rogue.
Okay? She peppers all her
diagnoses with basketball analogies.
Sometimes you've just
got to shoot from mid-court.
No. Not you, too.
Max, you're on the fourth foul
and there are no timeouts left.
Okay, this basketball thing
is spinning out of control.
Just a second opinion
on the feeding tube.
That's all I'm asking for. Okay.
You want my second opinion? Yes.
You need to listen
to your actual doctor.
I see what you did there.
If it makes you feel
better... I'm sure it won't.
Think of the feeding
tube like the sixth man
coming off the bench when
the starters need a break.
Really? 'Cause I
see it more like a pipe
protruding from my stomach,
spilling my morning coffee.
The chemo has left you
with frequent nausea.
The radiation has burned your throat.
As a result, you have been eating less.
You've lost five
pounds in one week.
Malnutrition negatively
affects your treatment.
It can also impair muscle
function, decrease immunoresponse,
and amass dangerous
toxicity levels within your body.
Max, inserting a feeding
tube would mitigate that.
Okay, yeah.
Put me in, Coach.
These site visits are really more
of a formality at this point, so...
I've been looking
forward to it. Oh?
What's in the bag?
Oh, here we go.
These are Jemma's favorites.
They're from a little
Trinidadian restaurant
near the hospital the
kids order from sometimes.
Once, no joke, Jemma
ate four of these.
I mean, I might have
helped a little bit, but...
Hope you brought
enough to share.
No, no. There
will be no sharing.
Once I put these down in
front of her, watch your fingers.
Hey, Jemma. Hey, kiddo.
How you doing, Jemma?
I'm fine.
Well, I hope you're
ready to be awesome
because I brought doubles and
kurma from Leelee's Roti Shop.
Boom.
I'm good.
Okay, well, I'll leave
them here on the counter
if you want them later, okay?
Everything's okay?
Oh, she's just
cramming for a test.
Things have been great.
So everything's
okay with school?
Yeah, her teachers at
Jefferson say she's catching up.
And her friends? I
met most of them.
Good kids. Creative,
misfits, like Jemma.
But they really seem
to get each other.
Seems to me she's
settling in just fine.
So Dr. Christiansen
will finish up with
the low pitches now.
As before, raise your right
hand if you hear a sound.
If you don't, it's okay.
This is to help us diagnose
what's wrong with
the cochlear implant.
Margot?
Do you need a break?
Is everything all right?
She doesn't like tests.
It's the device we
are testing, not you.
And if it makes you feel
better, I will give you an A+.
Tori and I will be
just outside the door.
Okay.
Okay, let's start.
So, it's been nine months.
We're still having problems.
It's almost
impossible to predict
the rehabilitation period
after a cochlear implant.
I mean, we weren't expecting
her to talk on the phone
but she can't even take the
subway without getting dizzy.
She seems confused and sad.
I know how it feels to see
your loved ones in pain,
but once we diagnose the
issue with the device, we can fix it.
Is everything okay? The
implant seems to be functional.
Basal electrode
responses? All normal.
So it's not the device,
then what's the matter?
Dr. Reynolds. Max.
Dr. Reynolds.
Why do I feel like the two
of you are getting ready
to throw me into
an unmarked van?
Your quarterly budget
is three weeks late.
Oh... Yeah. See, what
had happened was...
Yeah, and if it's
not done today,
then cardiothoracic is going to
have no budget for next quarter.
Which means no surgical supplies,
no surgeons, and no surgeries.
Luckily for you, we have a Dora
and Dora is going to help you.
And by help you, I mean
torture you until it's finished.
Every line in perfect order,
back-to-back. She's really kind of tough.
So you are here by
sequestered to this office
until it's done or, um, you're
dead, whichever comes first.
Wait, you mean now? Mmm-hmm.
No, but... but they need me on the
floor. Can't somebody else do this?
It's your department.
Your budget.
You get everything you want.
You just have to ask for it.
In a properly formatted
Excel-generated spreadsheet.
And Dora really excels at this.
No, it's not funny? Okay.
Well, smile and nod
or pay the price later.
Max, come on! I'm a doctor!
Yeah, not without a budget.
Shall we, Dr. Reynolds?
Can I at least go to the
bathroom first? Mmm...
I think you know
the answer to that.
Everybody out of the
way. Yo! Clear the way!
Jeez, Marie. I turn my
back for two seconds...
It should've been you. Nice.
All right, what do you
got? Marie McNeil.
40-year-old female police
officer on foot when struck...
By a drunk driver. Hit and
run. All right. We got it. Thanks.
Motor vehicle struck right
leg fracturing the femur.
She bounced off the
hood followed by the road,
resulting in thoracic
abrasions and contusions.
She's going to
be all right, right?
Why don't you alert her family?
Let them know where she is.
I'm her partner. I'm her family.
All right, let's get her to bay
29 and get Max down here now.
Hang in there, okay?
Be okay. Please.
Give us some room. She's okay.
Yeah, I... I hear you, Commissioner.
Of course. No, you have my word.
Officer McNeil will receive
the very best care possible.
We've got everything
under control.
Yes. No, thank you, sir.
Police Commissioner?
The one and only.
You ever experienced
a blue wave?
Uh... Sure. In Chinatown.
Then you haven't
experienced a blue wave
at New Amsterdam,
when a cop is brought in,
it's like his whole
family comes with him,
only that family is
three-quarters of the NYPD.
As advertised. I
see what you mean.
Everyone? I'm Max
Goodwin, the medical director.
Hi, I appreciate that you
want to support your colleague,
but this is still a
functioning ED. Go ahead.
So we need to keep this area
clear and calm, if at all possible.
I'd like to ask everyone
to move this vigil
outside these doors.
We really appreciate it.
Leon Hargrow. 68. Probable
DUI. Lacerations to left forearm.
Chemical burns on his face
and hands from the airbag.
I didn't see. Where...
Where... Where am I?
Any sign of head injury?
Witnesses saw him swerving all
over the road before the accident.
That's him!
That's the DUI who hit Marie!
Someone call security. I
think security is covered.
You're going down for a
long time, you hear me?
Easy, easy. ANGELO: I
know you can hear me!
I'm gonna make sure you're locked
up for the rest of your sorry-ass life!
Easy! Get him
back! Get him back!
Back up! Back up, now!
You're not getting away!
Get him back! Get him back!
Angelo's been Marie's
partner going on eight years.
Those two are like
sister and brother.
He's messed up, but he was
never going to do anything
to that driver. You
sure about that?
What can I say? We
take care of our own.
Yeah, well, as long as
you take care of Angelo,
I got no problem with
you guys being here.
I'm sorry for the disruption.
It won't happen again.
Our full focus needs to be on Marie.
Her recovery is what's important.
Not to worry. He'll
get it together.
Thanks. I'll, uh, keep you updated
as I learn more about her progress.
Thank you. You got it.
Hey, how's she doing?
Stable-ish. She's
pretty banged up.
I'm waiting on a cardio consult.
What about the
driver? How's he doing?
Waiting on lab results
from his tox screen.
We need to put some distance
between him and Marie's partner.
Driver's stable. He can move.
Do it.
Where should we put him?
I cleared a bed in the ICU.
He's still out.
It is going to be one
hell of a rude awakening.
There he is! Just the
boss I was looking for!
Can I get an autograph on this?
You bet. Thank you.
Not everyone would sign
their kidneys away like that,
but I really need the
money, so thank you.
Give me that. Another
site visit for Jemma?
I thought you just
had one of these.
Yeah, I thought you had cancer.
Only on the inside.
Okay, well, yeah, so I'm a little
worried Jemma might be isolating.
She literally said
three words to me,
went back in her room, and
didn't come back out again.
Can I give you my completely
unqualified psychological diagnosis?
Sure, why not? She's a teenager.
Well, yeah...
Yo, can I get a
consult? Oh, thank God.
How can I help? You can
tell me who on your team
is available for a consult. Me.
Lab supplies and
consumables. $14,400.87.
Max, please.
What do you got for me?
This isn't fair.
Look, if I had known it was
going to be this much paperwork,
I would've never
signed up to be Chair.
You didn't. I kind of
forced you to be Chair.
Sorry about that.
Pull Hastings off
her VATS procedure.
Thank you.
Nice try. Next line item?
Is everything okay?
Are you all right?
I'm sorry.
I'm usually not like
this. Neither of us are.
No, it's, it's...
It's all right.
I don't know what happened.
We literally never fight.
We met at a meditation workshop.
Margo being able to hear,
this was supposed to
bring us closer together,
but it's just driving us apart.
Tori, I...
I know someone who could help.
Okay.
Margot.
I believe there may be
issues that aren't related
to your cochlear implant.
This is my colleague, Dr. Frome.
Let's talk.
Max.
Okay, before you speak, you
should know that my friend,
the one with the cancer,
is getting a PEG feeding
tube installed today.
So this donut represents his last meal.
Assuming he can, you know, swallow it.
Leon Hargrow wasn't drunk.
The driver? I just
got his blood work.
There were no drugs or
alcohol in his system. None.
But people saw him swerving?
He had a stroke
behind the wheel.
- And that's not all...
- Dr. Goodwin.
I can't find Angelo. No
one knows where he went.
You don't think he went after...
Yeah, I do.
Angelo?
Officer, back away
from that bed right now.
Hey, let's talk about this.
Somebody's got to pay.
Angelo, I understand that you're
upset, but this wasn't his fault.
Don't give me that.
He was wasted. I
saw him swerving.
He had an embolic
stroke while he was driving.
He wasn't drunk. He's very sick.
He's a vet, have
some compassion.
Angelo, please.
Go back downstairs
to the waiting area.
Your partner? She
needs you right now.
Make sure that you
get him downstairs.
What... Wait, what is it?
It's Marie. She's coding.
O-2 sat down to 86.
Respirations up to 30.
Decreased breath
sounds bilaterally!
Heart rate's down to
48. Hang in there, Marie!
O-2 sat might drop again.
Respiratory rate climb.
I've got to get the pulmonary kit.
Dropping an intubation tray now.
Neck vein
distention. Both sides.
It's hard to see because of
the cervical collar but it's there.
Pneumomediastinum. Yeah.
Good call. There must be a
hole in Marie's esophagus.
We need to get her to the OR,
open up her chest and close
that hole before this happens again.
Is she going to be okay?
Mr. Hargrow... I
need to see her.
Look, sir... I need
to tell her I'm sorry.
Sir, you... You
need to remain calm.
But... I promise you,
she is receiving the
best care possible.
But right now, we
need to focus on you.
The stroke that you had was
caused by a malignant tumor
in your bladder.
I know that this is
distressing news.
We need to remove your tumor
immediately and start you on a regimen.
All I want to know is if
that woman is going to live.
Mr. Hargrow, your
condition is very serious.
I already know
what's wrong with me.
How long have you known?
If you knew, then why on Earth
haven't you gotten treatment?
I don't want treatment. I just
want to apologize for what I did.
I understand.
But right now, that is not a
good idea for either of you.
Then I guess there's
nothing else to talk about.
Dr. Kapoor thought
that it would be beneficial
if we sit down and talk
about what's happening
during the rehab process.
And that's sort of my job around
here is to create an environment
or space to explore what's
happening to you emotionally.
Both of you. The interpreter
will be here very soon.
I assure you.
I'm very sorry about the delay.
Should be any moment now.
Okay. We're just
diving right in. Um...
Angry? I... Uh...
Okay, can we just... Guys,
can we slow down just a touch?
Just... I'm getting some
of it. It's a little too fast.
I have never said
you were a burden.
Okay, time out. Time. Time out.
Um... Take a breath. Okay?
I need to catch up
here, but I'm assuming...
Tori, Margo said that
she feels like a burden.
Yeah. Is that right?
Okay, is that... Is that
how you feel about her?
No. I have never
thought of her that way.
All right, so why don't you tell
her how you do feel about her?
Margot has just always
had this spirit in her
that had to experience
the world, on her own terms.
Margot bungee jumped off the
Manhattan Bridge at 3:00 a.m.
when we were in college.
Are you kidding?
Wow!
Right.
I think that she's fearless.
So tell her.
"I feel so far away from
that person right now.
"I know I pushed us here
because I wanted the implant
"and you supported
me through all of it,
"with the money and the
surgeries, because I wanted it.
"And now I'm
afraid that I've risked
"the most important relationship
of my life because of them."
Why do you want the implant?
"So I can hear."
Well, okay. That's
what the implant does.
Why do you want the implant?
"I want it..."
Appreciate it. Thank you.
Throw it in there. Thanks, bud.
How you doing?
Hey, good to see you.
Thanks. Thank you.
Yo, Russetti.
You already taking
up for Marie's funeral?
Relax. It's for her recovery.
She's gonna be ordering
takeout for a while after this.
Thanks.
What's going on? How is she?
We stabilized her and we're
prepping her for surgery.
Now she's not out
of the woods yet,
but she does seem to be
responding to treatment.
Is that for Marie? Yeah,
it's something the PD does.
We have a fallen heroes fund
for officers hurt in the line of duty.
Then count me in.
I'll let you know
when she's out.
Hey.
Thanks, Dr. Goodwin.
Sure.
Guess who's back?
Is it legit or did you
"Shawshank" your way out of it?
Hey, you know what? After spending
the whole afternoon with Dora,
I finally know how the
lights stay on in this place.
What do we got? Boerhaave's
esophagus, surgical repair.
All right. Looks good.
Let's get to work.
Officer McNeil, I'm
Dr. Reynolds. This is Dr. Hastings.
We're going to be
performing your surgery today.
Two doctors? Must be pretty bad.
Vitals are good.
We'll see you in there.
You've had a morning.
Yeah, cops are supposed to
go down chasing the bad guy.
I get clipped writing a traffic
ticket to a grown man on a scooter.
I'm never gonna
hear the end of it.
Hey, well, at least you
were out there, all right?
I spent my morning sitting
in front of a spreadsheet.
I hate desk work.
Tell me about it.
Put me on the street.
That's where I want to be.
In the action, right? Yeah.
My partner, he calls me "one direction"
'cause I always head straight in.
I don't even think about
it. I don't get scared.
Put me in the line of fire
when somebody needs help.
That's my happy place.
Well, if it makes you feel any
better, helping you right now?
That's my happy place.
I'll see you in there.
VA just sent over his records.
Oh, thank you.
You've got to be kidding me.
Kapoor. How did it go?
Well, it was good. Very optimistic.
You know a lot... A lot came out.
There was a definite
unearthing going on.
But ultimately, I do
believe that Tori and Margot
are going to be
stronger than ever.
That's wonderful news. Yeah.
I've discussed with
Dr. Christiansen,
and she's confident that we
can move forward with the MRI.
Well, actually Margot touched
on something really profound.
Powerful. What?
She would like to have her
cochlear implant removed.
Vijay, she wants
to be deaf again.
"It matters not how strait the gate,
how charged with punishments the scroll,
"I am the master of my fate,
I am the captain of my soul."
Cap refill less
than two seconds.
Patient induced.
Twenty micrograms of fentanyl.
T-probe and defib...
Standing by.
I'm so tired of being alone
I'm so tired of on my own
Won't you help me, girl
Just as soon as you can
You've tried to get treatment
two years ago, didn't you, Leon?
Tried.
I went and saw my doc at the VA.
They took me in right
away like they usually do.
Once they found out what I had,
they said they didn't have
the right doctor for me there.
Said that I had to
go somewhere else.
So they gave you a voucher
and sent you on your way.
Yeah.
But you didn't use it.
I wanted to. But the voucher
didn't cover everything.
I'm on my own.
Couldn't afford the difference.
I served my country with pride.
You have nothing
to be ashamed of.
I did four tours.
Army Rangers.
You deserve better than this.
I never meant to put
anyone in harm's way.
Max, I am scheduling
Leon Hargrow
for emergency bladder
surgery and radiation.
Well, let's hope he needs
it. Turns out the VA closed
their urology department,
so instead of treating him,
they gave him a voucher to
use at a hospital of his "choice."
We'll take a voucher. The
voucher only covers 75% of the cost.
He's stuck with the
rest. We'll cover the rest.
What's the problem again?
Do they think that Leon only
gave 75% while he was in Vietnam?
Not to mention there's
compelling evidence
that urothelial carcinoma
is a directly related
to exposure to Agent Orange.
Helen, this is a public
hospital. This is why we're here.
If the VA won't
treat Leon, we will.
No, you won't.
HCC was notified of a payment
being submitted via a VA voucher.
That's right. We
can't accept it.
Why not? Then we'd have
to accept all VA vouchers.
As long as veterans are
getting the care they need,
I'm not seeing the problem.
The problem's the public health system
then has to potentially foot the bill
for thousands of veterans and
the 25% the VA doesn't reimburse.
We have a veteran in the ICU who
needs surgery or he's going to die.
I don't care who I have to call, but
Leon is getting that surgery today.
I understand your
intentions, Max,
but this is privatization
and we're playing right into it.
If we approve of Leon's
surgery and we foot the bill,
it sets a dangerous precedent
for the rest of the country.
Either we save Leon and hurt
the care for every other veteran
or we stand up for better
care for all veterans...
And let Leon die.
I respect your
wishes, of course.
And I'm aware that this is a
debate in the deaf community,
but removing an implant
is a very risky surgery.
"I just want the pain to stop."
I... I want that, too.
And... And... There are
different types of implants
we can use before we...
"Not that kind of pain.
"The migraines, the dizziness,
the strange tones, I expected that.
"My friends told
me that would come.
"That they all love their
implants, but I don't.
"I miss who I was.
"How I experienced the world.
"I don't expect you to understand,
but before the implant, music...
"Was something I felt and
now it's just weird words
"with weird textures.
"And my thoughts
used to be my own,
"and now they're just
cluttered with distractions.
"I thought I was
missing something.
"But really... I'm
missing what I had.
"I loved hearing Tori's voice.
"But I heard you better...
"When I couldn't
hear your voice at all."
Hey, kiddo.
So, I really messed up.
Big time.
I forgot to bring the Solo when
I brought the doubles earlier.
I'm a bonehead.
Yeah. Well, that's for you.
Thank you. You're welcome.
So listen, I, uh... I was
thinking a lot about before
when I came by with Sophia.
You know you can
tell me anything, right?
Yeah, that's kind
of the problem.
Why is that a problem?
'Cause I've told you everything.
Yeah. You know
everything about me.
You know every detail
of all of the homes.
Yeah. All of the
bad... The bad stuff.
You know, and now...
When I see you, I just... I feel
like... Like I'm still the same.
Like I'm still broken.
I don't want to be that anymore.
You know, Jemma,
I... I'm so proud of you.
So proud. You've come so far.
Look at you.
You don't need me anymore.
That's a good
thing. That is a...
That's a very good thing.
It's time for me to go. I've got
to go. Um... And that's all right.
Just, uh, just...
Just try to remember
one thing for me.
You were never broken.
Richardson.
Blood pressure 100/72.
Clamp. NURSE: Clamp.
Suction. Suction.
Lap pad. NURSE: Lap pad.
Dance to the music
Blood pressure is dropping.
Lap pad.
Femoral pulse diminished.
Where's all the
blood coming from?
- Uh, can't see anything.
- Gas exchange tanking.
Got it. Free wall rupture.
Right ventricle. Suture, hurry.
So the blood's just
pouring out of her heart?
Yes.
The surgery was going
well. I know. Keep sewing.
But why is the wall blown?
I have no idea, but we have about a minute
to suture it back up, okay? Just focus.
- We've lost carotid pulse.
- Gas exchange tanking.
The brain's not
getting any blood.
She's bleeding out. Keep sewing.
I'm trying but the
sutures keeps pulling out.
The heart muscle's too weak.
- Did you get it?
- She's cyanotic.
Well, her heart's
still in pieces.
There's no more blood to pump.
It's all gone.
Hear my organ
I said ride Sally ride
You gonna call it?
Cynthia on the throne, yeah!
Listen to me
Time of death, 4:16 p.m.
4:16 p.m.
Listen to the voices
Hi. Condolences. Thank you.
It shouldn't have
gone down like that.
She shouldn't have died.
I know. No. You don't.
Marie never should've
been out there.
But I had a migraine today.
A stupid migraine.
So she steps up to
point and I stay in the car.
Being a cop was
Marie's whole life.
She didn't have
a husband or kids.
We were her family and
that's all that mattered.
Living for this job.
She wanted to be a hero.
And she gets killed
at a traffic stop?
She was a hero the moment
she put that shield on.
We found our place
On the branch of an old gum tree
Our feet would sway
To a voice in the breeze
And birds would sing
On the banks of a narrow stream
These memories will stay with me
It's time.
Ooh
We're not going
to stop fighting this.
I promise you, we'll
figure it out, Leon.
Leon, this is Angelo
Russetti. Marie's partner.
Ooh
The guys and I
have been talking.
Marie didn't have any
family and we figured...
She'd want the money they would've
gotten from the fallen heroes' fund...
To go to you.
Get you fixed
up. This is a start.
I can't accept that.
Marie's not here anymore.
But you are.
We want to pay for the surgery.
Why would you do that for me?
We take care of our own.
These memories will stay with me
It'll take a few minutes
for the anesthetic to kick in.
When it does, I'll bring
in the endoscopist.
Okay. Um...
Thank you.
Now I'm far away
It's like nothing
ever gets better.
I'm just like this broken
thing that nobody wants.
Nobody cares about.
I don't even know why I'm here.
Ooh
Hey...
Um...
Sorry, you know you're not
my doctor anymore, right?
Yes.
But I'm still your friend.
These memories still remain
Now I'm far away
Ooh