Previously on
"The Resident"...
Nicolette Marie Nevin,
will you do me the honor...
He's one of a kind, isn't he?
Yeah.
Our relationship...
It is perfect just like this.
My father owns his own cab.
He put me
through medical school
working very long hours,
and I'm very proud of him.
So, y-you think this place
in Savannah...
You really think
they can help me?
It's one of the best inpatient
centers in the country.
I really want to be there
for all those moments
- that you talked about.
- Me too.
Cain and Bell had their chance
to be the star of this company,
but they couldn't deliver.
Our future is brighter
with Conrad Hawkins
front and center.
I don't know.
I'm still jonesing
for that powder blue tux
with the ruffled shirt.
No, no, no, no, no,
you are not allowed to look
like a lounge singer
on your wedding day.
Seriously... thoughts?
You fishing for compliments?
Come on.
Okay.
Baller.
Slightly different guy
than that jerk you met
your first day of residency.
You were just doing your job
the wrong way.
I must've done something right.
You turned
into a damn fine doctor.
Yeah, well, it...
hasn't always felt that way.
When all hell breaks
loose,
you find out what people
are made of.
You excelled.
That's very kind of you,
but let's stick to you.
How you feeling?
Any last-minute jitters?
None.
I'm as happy as I've ever been.
I'm about to marry my soul mate.
Okay, last stitch.
Something borrowed
and something blue.
It's a twofer.
Those earrings are beautiful.
Whose are they?
They were Jessie's.
My dad bought them
for her 16th birthday.
I wish she were here.
Me, too.
But she's always with me.
- So is my mom.
- Hmm.
And now you get to wear
her circa-1980
wedding dress.
When my dad begged me
to wear it, my heart sank.
Luckily you have Mina.
Something old is now new.
I mean,
you're a miracle worker.
- Thank you.
- Of course.
Is it bad to be this happy after
everything that's happened?
No,
but... I wish
things had been different,
that we could all be here
together today.
Yeah.
2020, man,
what a year.
I mean, we had no idea
what was about to hit us.
Okay, since the service
is outside,
I was thinking,
instead of throwing rice,
people could throw birdseeds?
Environmentally conscious...
I like it.
Okay, how do you feel
about a buffet
instead of a seated dinner?
I feel nothing.
Defer.
Band or DJ?
Up to you.
Oh, my God,
we're bad at this.
Okay, I'm going DJ.
All right.
And I think I want
burgundy flowers.
Dahlias, peonies.
Really? I was hoping
for blue wildflowers.
You don't care
what music we play
and yet you have an opinion
on the color of my bouquet?
Remember that first date we had,
hiking at Sweetwater?
The flowers I picked
for you that day?
Blue wildflowers it is.
And whatever DJ
you decide on,
they have to play
"Mr. Brightside."
You asked.
I thought you had
better taste than that.
Oh, you're about to be
Mrs. Conrad Hawkins.
- We both should have better taste.
- I'm pretty sure
you're
about to be Mr. Nic Nevin.
♪ No more, no work. ♪
Okafor.
Quadruple bypass in an hour.
Get your game on.
My game is always on.
That's what I love about you.
Andrea.
Mon chéri.
Yeah, I will be
picking you up at 8:00
for Chateaubriand
at Chez Pierre.
Do not dis my French accent.
I loathe the in-love Raptor.
Maybe you should
ask yourself why.
Transition team to OR Four.
Transition team
to OR Four.
Look who it is.
The new face of the hospital.
Not.
Why is Barrett Cain's mug
still up there?
Randolph Bell, Barrett Cain,
then Conrad Hawkins?
Hard pass,
thank you very much.
Hey, do you have time
for a quick consult?
Sure.
Bay One, Carter Wiggins, 34.
Headache, febrile and fatigue.
Take a look at his hands
over here.
Hello, Mr. Wiggins.
I'm Dr. Hawkins.
Sounds like
you're feeling lousy.
So these, um, red lesions
are new.
And my nose is all stopped up.
Can't smell my pies,
even the pineapple
and pepperoni.
Can't believe
you went to work today.
Your mama would be angry.
Temp is up to 102.5.
Have you traveled
anywhere recently?
Uh, Seattle.
To see my grandmother.
Okay, we'll be right back.
How many cases of COVID-19
in Seattle?
14 known so far, five deaths.
The symptoms fit.
I think we have our first case
of coronavirus.
We need a crash cart!
I've lost his pulse.
Hundley, stop!
You need PPE.
♪ ♪
*THE RESIDENT*
Season 04  Episode 01
Episode Title: "A Wedding, A Funeral"
Aired on: January 12, 2021
Just got a text.
They can't refund the deposit
for the wedding venue.
Someday this will be over
and we will have
a beautiful wedding.
It seems petty
to even be talking about that.
No, it's not petty.
Just want everyone
to get to that day safely.
You guys,
I've got Hundley on speaker.
Hey, Hundley, it's Devon.
What's your O2 sat?
90. But don't worry.
I just had... a coughing fit,
so it'll come back up.
Mom, are you okay?
Mom, I'm coming in.
No, you're not, honey!
Mom!
Is there anything we can do?
Don't,
don't worry about me.
Not possible.
You should come in.
I'll know if the time comes
when I need you.
Mom, I'm getting scared.
Please come unlock the door.
Don't come in.
Okay, I'm-I'm
officially worried.
Seriously.
This is day five
of the same mask.
Can you check my seal?
Yep.
Seal's holding.
♪ ♪
You ready?
Let's go.
I don't think I ever realized
how many of our surgeries
are actually elective.
I have patients
who need operations
who won't come in.
They're worried it's not safe.
You know, I've never felt
quite so useless.
So what do we do?
Well, I'd say
we join the front lines.
Mina's been in the ER all week.
- Same as Kit, in the ICU.
- Well, that's all well and good,
except I got this
preexisting condition...
Cowardice?
Time to put on
the big boy pants, Nolan.
We got work to do, baby.
C-Can he hear us?
I believe so.
Say whatever
you have to say now;
It won't be much longer.
We will be here
long as it takes.
He can't die alone.
I'll give you some privacy.
♪ ♪
Dr. Bell!
Dr. Bell.
His sat is stuck in the 70s.
What do you need?
Hey.
What's going on?
Everything.
I feel so helpless.
We're surgeons.
We cut, we fix.
With this disease,
there's so little we can do.
Just hold their hands
and support them.
And too many are dying
in these rooms, alone.
You should go
home. You're exhausted.
You should.
It's too dangerous for you here.
People over 65 are most at risk.
I'm 60.
Roughly.
I'm fit. I run marathons.
That's Pete.
He's a tennis pro,
now with myocarditis
as a result of this virus.
He's 33 and he might die.
Fit won't save you.
Well, I'm staying.
Hundley just pulled in.
She's not doing well.
She drove herself.
Hundley!
Hundley, hang on!
- We've got Hundley!
- Put her in Bay Three.
Sat 78, pulse 150 and climbing.
I'll start an IV.
Mina, she needs oxygen.
Get her started
on a non-rebreather.
And 500cc's of saline.
You got this.
We got this.
Here you go.
All right?
Temp is 102.6.
Okay, her sats are rising. 92.
- 94.
- Oxygen's helping.
Don't intubate
if you can avoid it.
I need to stay awake
for Raylee. Promise.
We're gonna do everything
we can to take care of you.
Mom!
Oh, oh, my baby.
Send her home
where she's safe.
- Get her out of here.
- I will. I promise.
Hundley, we need to admit you,
get you to the ICU, okay?
I'm putting in the orders now.
Checking for available beds.
Hang in there.
Nic, please. She
wouldn't even let me drive her here.
I have to see her.
Raylee, we can't have visitors
- in the hospital right now.
- Please.
You know my mom.
She's there for me
when I'm sick.
- I can't just leave.
- Listen, first off all,
are you feeling okay?
Good. So, your mom wants you
to go home and isolate.
Take care of yourself,
and I will call you
as soon as she's settled, okay?
I'm so sorry.
We're bleeding money.
Down $400 million
in a single month.
Uh, you hold the fate
of the hospital in your hands.
Red Rock needs you
to start cutting again.
Can't cut. Everyone's afraid.
Especially the sickest people
who need the operations
the most.
They're afraid COVID
is gonna kill them.
Then-then focus
on elective surgeries.
Stents, uh, knee replacements,
disc repair, uh, plastics.
It's against CMS guidelines.
Elective surgeries
use precious PPE,
hospital beds and resources.
We don't have a
multibillion-dollar endowment
like the Mayo Clinic.
I have to make payroll.
D-Do you understand
that this hospital will close?
- Thousands of jobs are at stake.
- Yeah, but the only job
you're worried about
is your own, Kim.
- That's not true.
- Really?
I-I know we haven't
always been on the same side,
but we need to work together
this time.
There's a
government bailout coming.
- Where will that money go?
- Red Rock's bank account.
Yeah. We're done here.
B-Barrett.
You're the chief of surgery.
My rainmaker.
I... Help me to save Chastain.
Take the lowest-risk
elective surgeries
and-and schedule them
as urgent.
Okay, on one condition.
Don't ever threaten my job again
or replace my face
on the side of this building
with a shiny new object.
Deal.
Dr. Cain?
Is there something wrong?
I'm afraid so.
Listen, I know that I told you
your back surgery
could wait, Ben,
but... I took another look
at your last scan this morning.
Is there a problem?
Yes. I see some progression
in your disc herniation
at your L5-S1 vertebrae
with some potential involvement
of your spinal cord.
- My spinal cord?
- Yes, yes, - and it's getting worse.
I need to get you
into the OR immediately.
But it's not safe
at the hospital.
- The coronavirus is...
- Oh, no, our surgical - facilities are pristine.
Yeah, never been cleaner
or safer.
And you won't be anywhere near
a COVID patient.
We'll take every precaution.
I don't know.
Um, I have to think about this.
See, here's the thing, Ben,
if you put this off,
you take one bad step,
you slip and fall
in the bathroom...
you'll end up paralyzed.
Oh, my God, Dr. Cain.
Okay.
I'll do whatever you say.
Devon?
How are you?
Are you driving your cab again?
That's one of the riskiest
things you could do.
You promised me you'd stay home.
- And who is going to pay my rent, Devon?
- I will.
Listen, Dad, our ER is packed.
Our ICU, too.
Think about Mom.
You could get infected,
you could take it home to her,
she could die.
You both could.
I need you to turn that cab
around and go home now.
Dad, you need to leave
the facility and quarantine now.
It's really not a good time,
Nicky. I'm only...
I'm halfway through treatment.
- If I leave...
- I know, but I wouldn't be asking
if it wasn't serious.
Please. I'll get you
a hotel room.
Just tell me you'll do this.
Yeah, okay.
Okay, okay. Uh...
Anything for you, Nicky.
Okay.
Dad, where are you?
I finally got a guy
who's willing to manufacture
the new mask prototypes,
but now he is telling me that
there are no more materials.
You have Crohn's disease
and a compromised immune system.
We agreed that you were
gonna work from home.
Hear my voice.
This is me not happy with you.
You need to solve
this issue from home.
As soon as I'm finished here.
Hello?
This is Marshall Winthrop.
Unfort...
Hey, you, nurse. I've
been waiting for two hours.
I got gold-plated insurance.
- The taxes I pay, I should be first in line.
- Hey, hey, hey.
There's no special treatment
in this ER.
Put your mask up, six feet apart
or you're out of here.
I am six feet apart.
What are you trying to do,
set a world record for people
in an ER in the middle
of a pandemic?
I understand the male temptation
to exaggerate length...
but you need to back up.
What... Don't touch me!
He's not six feet apart!
We've got five
minutes before our next crisis.
- It is crazy out there.
- And unsafe.
I really wish
you were back in the OR
working as a scrub nurse.
I'm right where I want to be.
I'm laying my head
on your shoulder right now.
I'm holding you and
rocking you back and forth.
Aw. Thank you.
"Lower extremity weakness
and acute onset
of bowel incontinence requiring
urgent operative management."
Come on, he's a 58-year-old
with a simple bulging disc.
We are in the midst
of the single most devastating
public health crisis
of our lifetimes.
Barrett, you can't be
doing surgeries
that don't need to be done.
You put a patient at risk
of getting COVID.
20% of surgeries
are unnecessary.
I made a judgment call.
And he won't get COVID
because my OR is spotless.
You know, you had a chance
to do the right thing.
Pitch in with the rest of us
and help, but no.
You just followed
Red Rock's marching orders.
I'm a neurosurgeon.
I cut.
When that pandemic
can be cured by brain surgery,
shoot me a page.
It's okay, Raylee.
If you get a fever or cough,
don't panic.
Most people don't get this sick.
You're gonna be okay.
My doctors are here.
I'll call you back soon.
- I love you.
- I love you, Mom.
Hey, there.
Proning isn't working, is it?
Well, your O2 sats
are still dipping too low,
so we're gonna try
a high-flow nasal cannula now.
It is a little outside the box,
but otherwise
we have to intubate.
If you put me to sleep
and put that tube in,
there's a good chance
I won't wake up again.
Which is why high-flow
is worth the risk.
Okay.
On three. One, two, three.
Uh-oh, we disconnected something.
- Where do these go?
- Haven't a clue.
White electrode...
under right clavicle.
Black under left.
Red above and left of umbilicus.
What about the beeping?
Just press "silence."
Surgeons, huh?
Nurses aren't paid enough.
Tell me about it.
You're gonna be okay.
Snapped when I was in the room.
I thought I felt something.
Europe, South Korea, China,
they all have state-of-the-art
protection; Look at this.
Dr. Voss is a surgeon.
Could have gone home
'cause she doesn't have
any patients, but she's working
in the ICU, and this is all
that protected her
from exposure to COVID-19.
She's been exposed.
You are sending our soldiers to
face the enemy without any armor.
We have a top ER nurse
in the ICU
fighting for her life.
Two transpo workers are dead.
Med students, residents,
they're isolating
from their families,
they're sick and alone,
and some of them may die.
Everybody is chasing
the same shipments.
I keep getting outbid
by other hospitals.
You need to protect our staff.
That's your job.
I feel your frustration.
I-I do.
- My frustration?
- Why-why don't you come down to my ER
and share my frustration
instead of sitting
in your ivory tower
doing nothing?!
All of you think I don't care.
I care.
I can't escape this either.
This morning, a woman,
a total stranger,
called me a bat eater.
I'm sorry. That's terrible.
The "China Virus,"
the "Kung Flu."
I was born in Savannah.
This is being used to turn us
all against each other.
And yes, I am trying
to save this hospital.
I'll-I'll bend the rules
to do it,
but do not think
for one moment
that this hasn't hit me hard.
I am human.
Prove it.
Yo. How you holding up?
I don't know.
It's pretty rough in there.
I'm proud of you for
working the ER;
However, I need you
in the OR.
We have our first COVID trach.
Sounds delightful.
Well, seriously,
you could use the break.
I'm worried about you.
I'm worried about you, too.
Okay.
You know where to find me
if you need me.
I certainly do.
The high-flow
bought us time, but...
your sat is 82% on 100% oxygen,
and it is dropping.
We need to intubate.
- Can you get Chu?
- He's on his way.
Can you please tell Raylee
I love her again?
You will tell her yourself
because you will wake up.
Now let us fight for you.
I'm here, Hundley. I'm here.
You're gonna be okay.
We're here.
We're gonna put you to sleep
now, my friend.
Just relax.
- You haven't eaten all day.
- I can't eat.
Hundley's a single mom.
I don't want to have to
tell Raylee that
she's never gonna see
her mom again.
She's around the same age you
were when you lost your mom,
isn't she?
If you get COVID,
I get COVID.
The good news is
I can smell that coffee.
And I could taste that bread.
If it's my last meal,
I'm going out with carbs.
Don't even say that.
How's Kit?
Her mask broke.
She's been exposed.
I told her to go home.
She's scared.
You'd rather wear a PAPR
than shave your beard.
You know how long
it takes to grow this beard out?
You know we have
a limited number of these?
They're for people who can't
wear N95s because of the way
their ...faces are shaped,
or because they have
a religious objection
to shaving their beards.
Yeah, well, let's just say
I do have a religious objection.
I worship this beard,
all right?
Well, you certainly are
conceited as you are vain.
Isn't it itchy?
Not at all.
- All right, let me help you.
- Aw, thanks.
Without the beard,
I look too young.
It adds wisdom and gravitas,
- and it's reassuring to my patients.
- Mm.
Well, you don't
look reassuring to me.
You look like you're
about to go into space.
Ha-ha-ha-ha.
It's working.
Yeah, it is.
Where did you get it?
South Korea.
My family still has
relatives there.
I put in an emergency order,
and it turns out this shipment
was on its way.
It wasn't cheap getting
it diverted to Chastain.
Wait, wait, wait.
- You said Red Rock wouldn't pay.
- They won't.
But they did.
What happens when they find out?
Could cost me my job.
But for now, at least our staff
will be protected.
And I could sleep
a little better tonight.
♪ ♪
You never looked better.
You, too.
Ready for the next shift?
Yeah. I'm
ready. And we are not
leaving Hundley.
♪ Whisper in my ear
it's time to go ♪
♪ Head between your hands
but I feel cold... ♪
♪ It's too hard to hold you up
and breathe ♪
♪ My heart is breaking up
the things it wants, yeah ♪
♪ My love, it ain't big enough ♪
♪ What if I can't reach ♪
♪ And pick you up next time? ♪
♪ And make you feel all right? ♪
♪ What if I can't reach ♪
♪ And pick you up next time? ♪
♪ And make you
feel all right... ♪
Hey, Dad, it's me.
Just calling to check in
and make sure you're not driving
your cab anymore.
One second, son.
Dad, what's going on?
Nothing.
I think I have a little flu,
that's all.
♪ What if I can't reach ♪
♪ And pick you up next time? ♪
♪ And make you feel all right? ♪
♪ What if I can't reach, oh ♪
♪ Reach ♪
♪ What if I can't reach? ♪
♪ What if I can't ♪
♪ Reach? ♪
♪ What if I can't reach ♪
♪ And make you feel all right? ♪
♪ And pick you up next time? ♪
♪ What if I can't reach ♪
♪ And make you feel all right? ♪
♪ What if I can't reach? ♪
Randolph...
I'm gonna need you to cover
my patients tomorrow.
I have a fever.
Please give Nic
all my love, and...
tell her I'm sorry
I couldn't stay.
How is your mom doing?
They were married 41 years.
An arranged marriage
that worked, you know?
This is the only thing
that could've separated them.
Yeah.
I have to go.
Got to catch my plane.
Fly safe.
♪ I can hear her heart beat ♪
♪ From a thousand miles ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ And the heavens open ♪
♪ Every time she smiles ♪
♪ And when I come to her ♪
♪ That's where I belong ♪
♪ Yeah, I'm running to her ♪
♪ Like a river's song ♪
♪ She gives me love, love,
love, love ♪
♪ Crazy love ♪
♪ She give me love, love,
love, love ♪
♪ Crazy love... ♪
- I love you.
- I love you, too.
♪ When I'm feeling low down ♪
♪ Yeah, when I come to her ♪
♪ When the sun goes down ♪
♪ Takes away my trouble ♪
♪ Takes away my grief ♪
♪ Take away my heartache ♪
♪ In the night like a thief ♪
♪ She gives me love, love,
love, love ♪
♪ Crazy love ♪
♪ She gives me love, love,
love, ooh ♪
♪ Crazy love. ♪
Welcome to the long-awaited
Nic and Conrad wedding.
We are all gathered here today
to celebrate the union
of these two people we love.
So, without further ado,
I'll let Nic and Conrad
speak for themselves.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Conrad and I wanted
to take a moment
to remember some friends
that are missing here today.
People we worked with
for a very long time...
who sadly lost
their battle with COVID.
George in transpo.
Dr. Peterson.
Peter who cleaned the ICU rooms.
Lois from accounting.
They ate lunch together
every day.
I think she had a crush on him.
We lost them both.
We also want to
send love to our dear friend Devon,
who was to be my best man.
Devon...
lost his father
to COVID-19...
and he almost lost
his mother.
He's on his way
to his dad's memorial right now.
Dad?
Thank you for stepping in
as my best man.
I love you.
Let us honor the
lives of those we've lost,
by holding their memories
in our hearts
as we celebrate
one of life's greatest joys.
Tough times come.
They always will.
But when they do, Conrad,
I want you by my side.
No matter what,
in sickness and in health.
I promise to
always have your back,
no matter what.
I promise to love you,
but to never obey you.
I didn't have my hopes up
for that "obey" part.
Mostly...
I promise you'll never lose me.
This is forever.
For as long as we both
shall live.
Conrad Theodore Hawkins
and Nicolette Marie Nevin,
sounds to me like
you take each other
as lawfully wedded
husband and wife.
We do.
Then by the power vested in me
by the city of Atlanta
and MakeMeAMinisterToday.com,
I hereby declare it official.
You may now enjoy your first
kiss as husband and wife.
♪ ♪
"My Own Soul's Warning"
by The Killers playing...
Oh, yeah.
♪ ♪
- Oh, Randolph?
- No. No, don't ask.
- Don't ask.
- Oh, come on, come on, come on.
I know you've got moves.
You know what? They could
be good for each other.
You know he was there for her
the whole time she was sick?
He'd buy her food, he'd
schedule her nurses' visits.
- I-Is there a chance?
- I mean, could be.
Bell should be so lucky.
Oh, man.
♪ My own soul's warning... ♪
"Meet me under
the covered bridge"?
What's up with the cryptic text?
Andrea was supposed
to be your guest.
But you're alone. Why?
We're not together anymore.
We broke up.
What happened?
What did you do?
You see the way
Conrad looks at Nic?
Andrea deserves someone
who looks at her like that.
And quite frankly,
I'm not that guy.
You know, if I were
to be honest, to me,
she was just filling the space
that I wanted you to fill.
- But I told you...
- I know.
You don't want to lose
what we have in the OR.
I get it. I don't want
to lose that, either, Mina.
Look, you asked me, right?
So I'm telling you the truth.
That's what we do, right?
Don't worry,
I'm not expecting anything.
This changes nothing.
How about that?
Dr. Pravesh,
your father's respiratory failure
is getting worse.
We need to intubate him.
What's the prognosis?
We are doing everything we can,
but he's very sick.
Uh, I need to speak to
him before you intubate, please.
Yes, of course.
Dad, can you hear me?
Dad, hang on.
They're gonna intubate,
but don't give up.
Keep fighting.
People recover from this.
People just like you. You...
You can make it, you just...
you just got to fight.
So proud of you, Devon.
Take care of your mom.
I will take care of
Mom, no matter what. I promise.
Dad, listen to me.
I would be nothing without you.
You helped put me
through medical school,
driving nights and weekends,
working overtime.
I believed in myself
because you believed in me.
And I always knew, no matter
what, that you loved me.
You are... everything.
Dad?
Can you hear me?
Can you hear me? Dad?
Dad, can you hear me?
I love you, Dad.
Sync corrections by srjanapala