Who are you?
What are you doing?
Get out of here!
Mom!
Lue? Lue?
Are you okay?
Okay, honey, calm down.
It's all right. You were just
having another bad dream.
I can't breathe. Yes, you can.
You're fine. Just relax.
Just take slow, deep
breaths. Nice and easy.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
I'm trying, but I can't.
Relax.
Slow, deep breaths.
I can't.
Lue?
Oh, my God. Lue?
Lue, wake up!
Wake up, Lue! Come on!
Lue!
Been paging you
for over two hours.
Must've been in the shower.
And then I had to moisturize.
Eight-year-old boy
was brought into the ER
last night with acute
respiratory distress.
No history of...
No history of asthma or allergies
and his chest x-ray is clear.
Actually, I had to
moisturize twice.
Dominika made Oysters
Rockefeller last night.
Kid's been having night terrors.
Woke up in the middle of
one in full respiratory arrest.
Stress-induced panic attack.
Tell the parents to
lay off the grades.
The world needs fry cooks, too.
He does great in school.
The parents are divorced,
but it was amicable and
Dad's moved out of state.
You seen Wilson around?
The dreams are about an ugly
old hag trying to strangle him.
The family's Hmong.
SUNDS.
Sudden unexpected
nocturnal death syndrome.
AKA BS name for, "No one's
figured out why they died."
Over 100 in the early '80s,
only male, only Hmong.
Healthy right up until the
moment they died in their sleep.
What was he dreaming
about? It doesn't matter.
It's a dream. It
doesn't mean anything.
If the nightmare's scary
enough, meaningful or not,
it could cause a catecholamine
surge and ventricular fibrillation.
An ancient demon, called a dab,
was sitting on
him, strangling him.
Think that qualifies.
Except in the
rational part of the file
where it says his EKG's within
normal limits. It's not his heart.
What about obstructive
sleep apnea?
Sleep apnea wouldn't have caused
breathing problems
after he woke up.
What did you dream of?
I never remember my dreams.
But you're certain that
they're insignificant.
Defensively so.
I was defending science.
You were defensively
defending science.
Lung damage from inhaled toxins
could keep causing
problems after he woke up.
Or an upper
respiratory infection.
Okay. Chase and Park, start
IV antibiotics for pneumonia.
Taub and Adams, go
check the home for toxins.
Can I go with Taub?
It was my idea.
Right.
'Cause for a moment
there I thought
you were uncomfortable
around Chase
because you had a
nocturnal Australian.
You can go with
whoever you want.
But all of you, read
all of these files.
Do you believe a spirit
could be hurting your son?
No, of course not.
Because if he's been
taught to believe that,
it is possible for the fear
alone to affect heart function.
I'm an engineer. I know illnesses
aren't caused by evil spirits.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean
to, I just had to check.
Anything else you need to check?
No.
I had a dream.
House, we can talk later.
Relax, I'm a doctor.
Your spectacular breasts
mean nothing to me.
House. House.
Later.
I had sex with Dominika.
In a dream?
It wasn't literally sex.
Technically, it was flossing,
but you know, teeth, testicles.
I think the symbolism
is pretty clear.
"Later" just changed to "never".
I'll tell you what
would be weirder.
If you didn't dream about
having sex with Chase.
Have you? No.
But I've dreamed
about having sex
with a lot of people I work with
and it didn't freak me out.
That's different.
How?
'Cause you've actually had
sex with a lot of people at work
and that hasn't freaked you out.
Good point.
So you're worried
about what it means?
I'm not worried.
It means nothing.
It means something, doesn't it?
I work with him. I can't
want to sleep with him.
Maybe Chase just
represents work.
You're just falling
in love with your job.
It has been very
satisfying lately.
You smell that?
Yeah. It smells like a wet dog.
It's mold. It's not mold.
It's definitely mold.
I don't see any sign
of water damage.
Holy crap.
It looked like a slaughterhouse.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
It was clean when we left.
You're telling us some random
person broke into your house
to dismember a pig
in your son's bedroom?
A pig?
My father-in-law.
What did you do?
What you should have done
weeks ago, when the dreams started.
I'm saving Lue.
He's coding! Need
a doctor in here!
V-tach. No pulse.
Oh, my God. Push
one milligram epi.
- Paddles. Charge to 50.
- Charging.
Clear.
Still V-tach.
Charge to 100.
100.
Clear.
Charging... Wait.
Normal sinus rhythm.
He's stable, but we've
obviously got a second symptom.
Yeah, yeah, kid's in V-tach. Tell
me about the luau in his bedroom.
It's a traditional
Hmong ceremony.
It's supposed to call
back the kid's soul.
Hasn't he heard of star 69?
There's more.
The reason grandpa thinks
the kid's soul was stolen
is because he's
convinced his son,
the kid's father, had
his stolen as well.
He beat his boss to death.
The dad didn't move
away, he's in prison.
PTSD could definitely cause
breathing problems and...
It's not PTSD.
Even if the kid wasn't there,
just hearing what the dad did...
But he hasn't.
It happened when he was
two, and all he's ever been told
is that his parents divorced
and his dad moved away.
The heart thing indicates
a malignant arrhythmia.
He needs an EP study.
How many of the other files
showed malignant arrhythmias?
None. Then forget the EP.
What about acute pericarditis?
Explains the dyspnea.
How many of the other files...
It's exacerbated
by lying supine,
so the symptoms would get
worse when he goes to sleep.
Just like all 100 of the others.
Do an echo to check
the pericardium.
See if you can find any cardio-active
toxins in the home samples.
Can I just say that I
very much enjoy my job?
No, no, please.
No need to apologize
for your earlier behavior.
The floss was mint, probably
because of this green G-string
she hangs up to
dry in the bathroom.
My watch must have stopped.
Apparently it's already "never".
You might want to
forward your calls.
You do not want the
Reader's Digest version on this.
There was a very
tight hygienist's uniform,
suggestive use of
a water sprayer...
The floss isn't sex. It's guilt.
It's tying you up for throwing
away the INS notification
granting Dominika
her citizenship.
She can move out but
she still doesn't know it,
which means you're
basically holding her prisoner.
Tell her the truth
and leave me alone.
Really? What?
You startled me.
We work together every day,
usually under a fair amount of stress.
It's only natural I pop into a
subconscious thought every once in a while.
Have you ever dreamt
about having sex with me?
No.
You paused.
No, I didn't. You
think I'm lying?
No. I think you were fighting
the urge to snap the word "no"
because your subconscious
finds the idea abhorrent.
So if I snap it's offensive,
and if I don't snap it's offensive
for the exact same reason?
Talk to your subconscious.
This is becoming weird
because you're making it weird.
So you don't find
the idea abhorrent?
I work with you. I don't
have to answer that question.
You just did.
What happened?
Echo was negative but he
has severe abdominal pain.
Ultrasound didn't suggest
any intestinal blockages,
but he's severely constipated.
No spores, clostridium, or organic
toxins in the kitchen samples.
Nothing in the bedroom either.
We need to scope him and we're
gonna need to clear his bowel first.
We should biopsy his thyroid.
For an impacted bowel?
Hashimoto's
thyroiditis would explain
his lung, heart and
intestinal involvement.
And if you think we still
need House's approval,
it also explains
dying in his sleep.
Nice call.
When you invite me for dinner, I
thought maybe you take me to a restaurant.
Or have plates.
Yeah. Sorry.
Idiot delivery guy
forgot them. Hmm.
The idiot delivery
guy, or the idiot guy
whose food you stole from
lounge refrigerator, huh?
You've gotten to
know me pretty well.
My citizenship
depends on it, right?
Yeah.
That's actually why I
wanted to talk to you.
You heard news?
Yeah.
So, what news?
They want us to come
in for another interview?
No.
Since we hadn't
heard anything, I called.
And they said it's gonna
be a couple weeks.
Maybe a month till they
finalize their decision.
A month?
Yeah, I know. It sucks.
No, it does not
suck to live with you.
It's been fun, but, you
know, I just want to be legal.
And you will be. Absolutely.
In the meantime...
You ever shot anyone?
No. Get away.
Look, this needle isn't nearly
as big as the one in your arm,
and that didn't hurt, did it?
I don't want it. They
need to do it, Lue.
You'll only feel a little pinch
as we give you the
numbing medicine.
After that you
won't feel a thing.
No!
Lue, calm down,
it's gonna be okay.
What's he saying?
What's the problem?
I don't know.
He's saying it's too late.
There's nothing we can do.
It's Hmong.
He doesn't speak Hmong.
He's never even heard it.
It isn't him speaking.
It's the dab.
He's seizing.
Oh, my God!
Need some lorazepam in here!
Seizure rules out Hashimoto's.
Yeah, that's the issue.
Not that we have no
rational explanation
for how the patient spoke a
language he's never even heard.
I've got one.
It means "you're a bunch
of pathetic idiots" in Hmong.
Or it doesn't.
But you wouldn't know because
none of you speak Hmong.
Kid, on the other hand, is
presumably fluent in gibberish.
The grandfather speaks
Hmong. He translated.
He heard what he wanted to hear
because if his grandson
really is possessed,
that means his son
which is a giant step up from being
a sledge-hammering psychopath.
Whatever it was
preceded a seizure.
It's obviously a
neurological symptom.
Scleroderma, advanced to the
point that it's affecting his brain?
Interesting.
So we should
start treating with...
Interesting that you keep falling
for it when I say, "Interesting."
The scleroderma
part was idiotic.
We'd have seen skin involvement.
The interesting part is
that you and Park agree
but you're not able
to look at each other.
Um... I'm looking at her.
I'm looking at him.
Good. Now lick your lips.
Rasmussen's encephalitis.
Diffuse spotty inflammation could
hit the autonomic centers of the brain.
That's Hmong for
"get an MRI to confirm."
Rasmussen's encephalitis?
But he'll be okay?
With treatment, it's manageable.
And it explains all the things
that have happened to him?
We think so... You're wrong.
And you're wasting
my grandson's time.
Neurological issues can cause
a person to speak in tongues,
speak with an accent...
He wasn't speaking in tongues.
In times of stress, our senses
can fool us into believing...
I know the difference
between science and faith.
And when my son started having the
same dreams my grandson is having,
science couldn't help him.
I'm sorry if your son suffered
from mental illness, but...
Kao was not crazy.
He was bright, caring, happy.
Until the bad dreams came.
I don't want to watch
it happen again.
Please don't scare the boy.
It won't help him get better.
Axial view of the mid-brain level
looks good. Moving onto thalamic.
I had another dream last night.
This time it was about you.
Really? See.
That's how you're
supposed to react.
When a woman tells you
she's dreamt about you,
you should be thrilled,
even if not interested
in her whatsoever.
You're an idiot, you know that?
Well, I definitely won't be
dreaming about you tonight.
I'm jealous of you two.
You couldn't be
more different and yet,
you have this good
thing happening.
You support each
other, you like each other.
Don't let House screw it up.
We're not that different.
Yeah, you are.
Well, apparently there are some
things about you I don't know.
I served one
year in police unit.
And you're just telling
your husband now?
Immigration doesn't know,
no need for husband to know.
What is happening
to boy with demons?
An absence of
evidence on an MRI,
which my team has mistaken
for evidence of absence.
This is what I am
not understanding.
How can you believe in dark
matters but not in dark spirits?
Is the idea of demons so
different than the Higgs boson?
We can't see it, but we can
see the impact of its presence.
I borrowed your physics book.
I read while in bathroom.
So you're a deadeye shot,
and enjoy reading quantum
physics on the crapper.
I read in bathtub.
Better image. Thank you.
The doctors say
my brain is sick.
Your doctors are
trying their best
but they aren't looking
in the right place.
Yeah, I know this is a lot
to put on an eight-year-old,
but you've angered our ancestors
by ignoring them.
Now, do you remember
how to talk to them?
Yeah, that's right.
Good. Now, close your eyes
and we will ask for
forgiveness together.
You're doing good.
But we have to do more.
The evil spirits are in the air.
And the only way to stop them
is by stopping the air.
You have to be brave.
I'm not trying to hurt you.
This will help you.
I know it will.
Lue, are you okay?
I can't wake him up.
Lue? Lue?
You're safe, you're
in the hospital.
Get Grandpa away!
He's not here, honey.
It was just a dream.
He was choking me!
No, Lue, it wasn't real.
It was. He grabbed my neck!
Those bruises
weren't there before.
He had the dream,
then he had the bruising.
More likely,
and by "likely", I mean rationally,
it was the other way around.
His brain felt the
pain in his neck,
created the dream to explain it.
Coagulopathy.
Lung problems cause
a clotting disturbance.
He would have
bruises everywhere.
Is it really preposterous
that dreams can have
physical manifestations?
The short answer is...
Thoughts during sleep can
and do cause physical changes.
Is that right, Dr. Park?
Did you wake up this morning
experiencing physical changes?
It's medically relevant. Her
dream doesn't mean anything.
Can we start acting like
it doesn't mean anything?
Sure. We could also start acting
like walls don't mean anything.
But then we'd hurt our noses.
You've been
taking the high road.
You haven't been teasing in
an obviously teasable situation
because you know it
does mean something.
She hates the dream because
it makes her feel vulnerable.
You love the dream because
it makes you feel superior.
The poor lass who can't help
but fall sway to your charms,
and you're bestowing upon
her the gift of illusory irrelevance.
Can you please hint to House
that you had a sex dream?
I'd really prefer
not to get distracted
with trying to cure
the patient today.
I refuse to divulge my dreams
about girl-on-girl loofa action.
The bruising could
indicate anemia,
a vitamin C deficiency,
or even leukemia.
That is so weird that you
and I had the same dream.
I assume yours also ends
with me achieving ecstasy
while simultaneously placing
third in the New York City Marathon.
Third?
I'm a realist.
Liver failure can
cause gibberish
from encephalopathy,
constipation,
bruising, and
breathing problems.
Hepatic fibrosis could
hit someone his age.
So let's hit his
liver. Get a biopsy.
Angle a bit more superiorly.
He keeps having these
nightmares that become real.
They really hurt him.
I don't want to believe that a
nightmare can do that, but...
I'm struggling with it, too. But these
things can be explained medically.
But you haven't.
Every doctor, every
idea they've had,
it's been wrong.
Liver biopsy's back.
Team's about to meet.
You're back to avoiding
eye contact with me?
House got to you again?
Want me to gaze
longingly into your eyes
as I tell you the test results?
I want you to treat
me like a friend.
Which means
getting over the fact
that you like me
more than I like you.
Yeah, egotism and
preening really turn me on.
Too bad I'm not
attracted to androgyny
and self-pity or
you'd have it made.
Because anyone who hasn't gotten
wet from your petri dish of STDs
clearly has low self-esteem.
Bitch.
Dick.
Are you coming?
Why didn't your lips
move when you said that?
Chase, are you coming?
The liver biopsy's back.
I'll be right there.
Biopsy was
negative for fibrosis.
So once again you
don't know what's wrong.
It's always good to
rule out the bad things.
Doctors.
God.
Was he...
Yes.
He was levitating.
Cool.
So the one thing we know for
sure is, he was not levitating.
He was floating six
inches off the bed.
He could've just been
arching his back off the bed.
Yes. But then I would have
come into the room and reported
that the patient was weirdly
arching his back off the bed.
It was his whole
body. He was levitating.
So many questions.
Starting with,
why did Chase
address his comment
to someone who
wasn't even in the room?
Hocus pocus, on my
feet you idiots must focus.
I feel so drained.
The kid's not a magician.
Of course not, he's
the lovely assistant.
His Grandpa Pig
Sticker's waving the wand.
Middling with,
is Chase trying to avoid Taub
or is he trying to prove
that he's not avoiding Park?
We checked the bed.
There were no platforms
or wires. This wasn't a trick.
Tetanus can cause
muscle rigidity.
Maybe he was propped
up by his heel and elbow.
Except he wasn't.
Tetanus wouldn't cause
that kind of breathing difficulty.
And ending with,
if Chase is trying
not to avoid Park,
why is he doing this
today and not yesterday?
But hypocalcaemia could,
and the enema we administered
to cure his constipation
had a high phosphorus load,
which could make him
transiently hypocalcaemic.
It's a long shot.
But at least it has the
benefit of being rational.
Go pump up his electrolytes
and start beta-blockers.
And good news for Park.
I think Chase had a
sex dream about you.
Dreams don't mean anything.
I don't know. Nothing
you've done has helped.
If we don't start and
he has another seizure,
the neurological damage
could be permanent.
My father-in-law...
He thinks the calling ceremony
didn't work because Lue wasn't there.
And you think he's right?
I don't know.
I'm sorry, but there's no way we
can allow him to perform an exorcism
in your son's hospital room.
Then I will have
to take him home.
A day ago you were insulted I'd
even think you might believe that stuff.
And now you're willing to stop
all treatment so you can try it?
Maybe Xang was right about Kao.
The man I loved wasn't evil
and would never do what he did.
He was possessed.
And my son needs his soul back.
Why not?
As long as he doesn't feed the kid
anything or put anything on his skin
that we haven't verified as
harmless, what's the problem?
I agree.
And since we're
establishing a new policy of,
"What the hell,
we'll try anything,"
I'd like to hire Shakira to
belly-dance while singing Waka Waka.
As long as you get the
mom and Shakira to consent.
It's no different than having a
priest or rabbi lead a prayer vigil.
The mom is scared and confused
and desperate for anything
that'll give her hope.
True.
But in the long run, I
think you'll be happier
having our lawyer
declare her unfit.
That way, you won't
be ratifying superstition
over science and I'll
still be working here.
And why would that
make me happier?
You're not going anywhere,
and we're not ratifying their beliefs.
We're respecting them.
You do realize it may
involve animal sacrifice?
People who live in glass
hospitals shouldn't throw exorcisms.
I'll talk to the mother.
I don't want to deny
him the medicine.
I just
want to make sure I
try everything I can.
I understand that.
But you have to understand
that we're a hospital, not a temple.
Then I'll take him elsewhere.
No, you won't.
He's sick. We can't
let him leave here.
I'm sorry. You really
have no choice.
I spoke to a lawyer.
He told me as long as I wasn't
saying no to your treatment,
you couldn't say
no to my religion.
Give me 24 hours.
This came in the mail today.
I'm sorry.
I should have told you but...
Tell me what?
I don't understand.
What's the letter?
It's from my uncle in
Poland. My Aunt Luba,
they put in the nursing
home two months ago.
That's too bad.
My mother, I talk
to her twice a week
and she never even mentioned it.
What does she think, that I
can't handle? I'm 29 years old!
I am not a child!
Were you going out tonight?
I could stay.
He's still barely breathing.
Lue,
how you feeling?
Any stronger?
Lue? Can you hear me?
What's wrong? I'm not sure.
Lue, I need you to
squeeze my hand.
He's not responding.
Get me an amp of D50.
You're wrong again?
I'm calling his grandfather.
Genetic tests for Brugada and
Long QT variants came back negative.
What about a carotid aneurysm?
We should do an angiogram.
He's got normal carotid pulses.
Who cares?
Mom's given up, why shouldn't I?
I'm sorry. Do we not treat
idiots because I thought...
And her kid levitated.
That happens to my girl, I'm
expanding my diagnostic horizons.
All the more reason
why we should shut down.
We cure this kid
now, crazy grandpa
and his magic beads
get all the credit.
And since when do
you care about credit?
Since when do I
care about this kid?
All I care about is sending
mommy out into the world
having faith in faith.
Kid's better off dead.
Soon as she's done
appeasing the gods, let's talk.
What about Kawasaki?
Explains the
irregular heartbeat,
respiratory distress
and seizures.
It fits.
Which means he needs
a coronary bypass.
It can't be Kawasaki.
The echo would've shown it.
But a patent
ductus arteriosis...
It can't be a PDA.
He's not an infant nor has he
had any symptoms for eight years.
Maybe he has.
Maybe he had an infected ductus
which we inadvertently
treated with antibiotics.
So no evidence is
evidence of evidence?
Just saying it's consistent.
It's a billion to one.
Which means there
are seven people
in the world who
fit the diagnosis.
I thought we were
looking for 100.
Maybe PDA is more
common than we thought.
But idiot doctors like you...
You're wrong.
But the treatment's
just ibuprofen.
Closes the malformed duct.
Worst-case scenario,
he just doesn't get better.
Worst-case scenario
is, you piss me off...
You're not gonna let
us save an eight-year-old
because one more person
might embrace religion?
Does anyone here think
my diagnosis is right?
Well, then, I've decided, for
today only, to respect your opinions.
We'll proceed according
to your diagnosis.
And nothing else.
That's an order.
Good luck.
We need to put him
on the OR schedule.
His BP is dropping.
He's crashing. Call a code.
You need to stop this.
I'm giving him the ibuprofen.
Dinner's almost ready.
I think I'll stick with the
fluids tonight, thanks.
Why are you sulking?
I'm not sulking.
Oh!
My mistake.
Either religion is
killing a kid or I am.
What are you doing?
Comforting my
husband after a bad day.
If this is not what you want,
I go back to making dinner.
I'm not gonna answer that.
Oh, smart man.
This is killing mood.
U.S. Citizenship.
I'll get it.
This is Mrs. House.
Please give good news so my
husband and I can go back to sex.
It's fantastic!
How many notices you sent me?
Okay. I come pick up
naturalization certificate.
Thank you for calling.
I'm sorry.
Dr. Adams, Dr. Taub.
His vitals are improving.
He's stabilizing.
He's gonna be okay.
It worked.
Um... No, it didn't.
Mrs. Cheng, the
medicine I administered
was a long-shot
treatment for Lue's heart.
But that's what's helping him.
Ibuprofen? That's for headaches.
I know it seems hard
to believe but it's true.
And I know this seems
hard for you to believe.
Honey.
Grandpa was right.
He saved you.
There were two things we
thought were impossible.
One of them wasn't.
That's all we know.
You're such a brave boy.
Was I good?
Doesn't mean anything.
Idea got planted, it
was probably inevitable.
It means something.
What?
Well, it could mean the obvious,
that you want some of this.
When will you learn
that that look is insulting?
Or it could just mean
that we like each other.
I'm weird, and you're pretty,
but we connect, we feel safe.
We trust each other.
Maybe.
Just testing my theory.
Adams defied me. There's
one more zealot in the world.
And Dominika moved out.
She was fun. She was hot.
She fixed my blender.
That is not a metaphor.
You know any good
fake divorce lawyers?
I'm surprisingly
depressed by this.
I have cancer.
You were a little short
with me the other day.
You do need an excuse.
Cancer may be overplaying it.
Stage II thymoma.
I didn't want to tell you
until I had it confirmed.
I got the tests
back this morning.
I have cancer, House.