- Previously on The Resident...
- You're fired.
You're afraid of me.
And you should be.
Security will escort you out.
If my sister has a child,
then that child
becomes my family, too.
Are you saying you'll
be my baby's godmother?
You said yes?
All right, so what's your plan
if Adaku's baby becomes
your responsibility?
I don't have one.
There was a learning
curve, but I mastered it.
Why don't you come
over to our place later?
Uh, not tonight.
I'm tired.
A little time alone
with my thoughts.
This incredible woman
had the ability to save a life
right in front of me. And
I knew, in that moment,
that I wanted to be a person
who could jump out of
the car to help people.
So that's what I do.
Methodist Memorial
went with someone else.
Apparently they checked
in with my last employer.
Red Rock has
gotten you blacklisted
from every hospital in Atlanta.
I want to practice medicine,
I'll have to find
work out of town.
Have a long-distance
relationship
or give up being a doctor.
This is what it's come to?
No, it hasn't.
We're gonna figure this out.
You should go,
you're gonna be late.
Eh...
You have any idea why
Reggie wanted to see you?
No, he just said to meet him
at the Georgia
FC practice field.
Is it bad that I had no idea
Atlanta has a soccer team?
Yes.
But I forgive you.
Well, hel-hello, good sir.
Some tea and crumpets, perhaps?
Ha. Very funny.
I need to make a good
impression on my new attending.
Ah, right, first day in the
dual residency program.
Internal medicine
this week. ER next.
And then I go back and forth.
A foot in two departments
fundamentally at odds.
Well, as a dual resident, I
can reach across the aisle,
- help each department
see how the other lives.
- If you say so.
But lose the bow tie.
You look like a
chemistry professor
who refuses to hand out As
even when they're
totally deserved.
- That was oddly specific.
- I was really good at chemistry.
Fine. You know what?
Okay, baby girl.
Your bottle is coming right up.
♪ The wheels on the
bus go round and round ♪
♪ Round and round,
round and round ♪
♪ The horn on the bus
goes beep, beep, beep ♪
Shh...
♪ The horn on the bus
goes beep, beep, beep ♪
♪ All through the town ♪
♪ The baby on the bus
goes wah, wah, wah ♪
♪ Wah, wah, wah, wah, wah, wah ♪
- Mm-hmm.
- ♪ The babies on the bus go
wah, wah, wah ♪
All through the town. ♪
- Reggie.
- Dax.
- What's good, Conrad?
- Yeah, good to see you.
- Good to see you.
I want you to meet my
mentee, Dax Ramsey.
Yeah, rookie out of Memphis.
- You're supposed to be
the next face of the franchise.
- Yeah. That's the plan.
If I can get my
injuries under control.
Today is Dax's
first practice back.
- He's recovering from
a calf injury.
- Which feels fine, but...
what worries me is I get
these cramps and injuries
from the smallest things.
The more conditioning I
do, the weaker I seem to get.
The team doc, he
ran a bunch of tests.
Everything came back normal,
so he cleared Dax to play.
But I keep telling him
there's something up with me.
But he won't listen,
so I asked Reggie
if he knew a doctor who
could give me a second opinion.
And I thought,
why not the guy who
saved my life in zero G?
Yeah, well, I'm happy to take
a look at your medical records.
That's me. Good looking out.
I'll let you know
if I find anything.
Buckle up.
This may just be
a practice game,
but these boys are
about to put on a show.
Ball. Box.
♪ La, la, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ Nah-nah-nah-nah-nah-nah-nah,
hey! ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ La, la, la,
la, la, la, la... ♪
His footwork's insane.
That's why Dax is the best
rookie this team's ever had.
I need help.
All right, I got you, I got you.
- Oh! Aah!
- All right.
Your ribs are fractured
in several places.
Your chest wall is unstable.
- We need to get Dax
to a hospital. I'll call 911.
♪ ♪
Hang in there.
Trauma Bay 10.
When the paramedics
called this in,
I wouldn't have guessed
you were with them.
Yeah, trust me, I didn't
expect to be here either.
- Who's the trauma surgeon
on today?
- Bell.
- He's already on his way.
- Correction. He's already here.
Hawkins, you care to explain
how you ended up here,
yet again, with a patient?
I was at the practice
center when Dax got injured.
- All right, what do we have?
- 19-year-old male,
blunt trauma to the
chest and abdomen.
Hypotensive and
tachycardic en route.
I'm Dr. Feldman,
this is Dr. Bell.
Do you have any allergies
to any medications
we should know about?
Not that I know of.
Nice as it is to
see you, Conrad,
- Logan Kim isn't going to like
that you're here.
- I know.
- I can't just leave him
while he's still in pain.
- Hey, Conrad?
Yeah, I'm here. We're
gonna take care of you.
I'm a friend of the patient,
that's not against
hospital policy.
Okay, his O2 stats are
dropping. We need to intubate him.
- Chest cavity is full of blood.
- Get me a chest tube kit.
Now, as the friend
of the patient,
I'm gonna have to ask you to
step outside the trauma bay.
- That is hospital policy.
- I understand.
I'm playing by the
rules on this one.
Dr. Lee to Infectious Disease.
Hey, Dad. I was
just on my way out.
Where are you? I'll pick you up.
You're where?
It's fine. I'm fine.
You're not fine.
You got arrested.
You see any handcuffs? I'm okay.
Can we just please go?
What the hell happened?
You got into a fight?
- It was schoolyard stuff.
- Between two grown men?
Well, he threw the first punch.
The police agree that I'm
innocent, so they released me.
- Who were you fighting?
- This guy, he bought my car.
He had buyer's remorse,
he thought I'd take it back.
- And then he made fun of my hat.
- Wait, you-you sold your car?
You've had that
car for 20 years.
Nic, nothing lasts forever.
Dad.
I'm worried about you.
Yes, look... Okay, I've
been a-a little down lately.
But who doesn't hit a rough
patch every now and then?
I'm fine.
I promise.
Well, the repeat
cultures are negative.
Plus no fever in two days.
Which means your
infection is clearing.
So I finally get
to hold my baby?
Yes, indeed.
However, the results
happen to be so good that...
We can discharge you and send
you home with oral antibiotics.
Yes!
Ah...
Thank you both so
much for everything.
- You got it.
- I can't wait to have
Michelle in my arms
- and finally to be able
to get out of here.
- Mm-hmm.
Do you think she'll
know who I am?
I'm sure she'll know
by the love you give her.
- Look at how cute she is.
- Yeah.
As my admitting resident,
you are gatekeeper
to the medicine floor.
And when I say "gatekeeper,"
I mean you are to be
a blocking machine.
Mrs. Allen, 68-year-old female
with alcoholic pancreatitis.
Know what went wrong here?
She binged on alcohol and
gave herself pancreatitis?
Wrong. The ER were too
slow giving her a benzo,
so now we're stuck chasing
her withdrawal symptoms.
That's not entirely
fair. The ER is always...
Mr. Hopper, 80-year-old man.
Fell in his home,
sprained his hip.
Care to guess the mistake?
He's an elderly
man who lives alone
- and he needs
discharge planning.
- Which could have been done
while he was waiting in the
ER. Instead, he's taking up
one of our beds,
waiting for a placement.
I could go on, but
the trend is clear.
We're accepting patients from
the ER that don't belong here.
Look, I agree
that these patients
in particular could have
been managed better,
but most of the patients on
this floor do need to be here.
I know you're not a
pure medicine resident,
that you've been tainted by
habits you learned in the ER.
- I wouldn't say that...
- But you're on this team now.
So, what are you going to be?
A blocking machine.
A blocking... machine.
Dr. Hawkins...
this is Bill Landry,
owner of Georgia FC.
Son, I have a team of
top doctors from St. John's
who take care of my players.
I don't know who you are
or why you were on my field.
Why exactly did you poach
a patient from St. John's
- and bring him here?
- That's not what happened.
- I don't care.
- I want Dax transferred
to St. John's immediately.
- Well, that would be a bad idea.
Dax has sustained
significant injuries to his chest
and his abdomen, leading
to multiple broken ribs,
lung contusions,
lacerations to his spleen.
I trust that, when
he stabilizes,
- you'll make that transfer
happen as soon as possible.
- Y-You have my word.
And I apologize for the
inconvenience. I-I hope...
Bill Landry is the
richest man in Georgia,
and in one morning you have
him pissed off at Chastain.
You shouldn't have been anywhere
near Dax Ramsey to begin with.
He asked for a second
opinion, so I helped.
He's at Chastain now, so your
services are no longer required.
Treating a patient
without hospital privileges
is against the law.
I'm not treating him.
I'm here as a friend.
Which gives Dr. Hawkins
every right to stay.
If you so much as lay a
finger on Dax Ramsey,
I'll have you thrown
out and sued.
Wow. You guys already
boarding patients in the hallway?
One of those days.
- You here for my admit?
- First one of the day.
Riley, this is Dr. Pravesh.
He's gonna do an assessment.
Okay. Hey, can I do the thing?
The floor is yours.
Riley Jackson,
28-year-old female.
Five hours of sudden
onset nausea and vomiting.
- Did I get it right?
- Nailed it.
And that's vomiting
with a capital "V."
I can't even keep crackers down.
It's good to meet you, Riley.
Uh, can you tell me
when all this started?
Uh, this morning.
I woke up fine, dropped
my daughter off at school.
And then on the
drive back home...
- Capital "V"?
- Yeah.
- Hmm.
- All over my steering wheel.
It was not pretty.
Okay. I'm gonna talk to
Dr. Feldman and figure out
- the best way
to take care of you, okay?
- Thank you so much.
All right.
- We'll be right back.
- Thanks.
Hey, this looks
like gastroenteritis.
- This is a soft admit.
- Yeah...
Got you there, Feldman.
Give it a few more hours of
continuous fluids and meds.
Are you seriously
blocking this admission?
Wow, you've, uh, already
become one of them.
Stashing a patient in
the ER for a couple hours,
hoping they somehow
cure themselves?
- Internal medicine's
signature move. Look,
I can't give Riley a
bed that doesn't exist.
Between surgical patients
and medical patients,
- a bed isn't available.
- That's true.
They got a lot of
surgical patients today.
- You know, how about
you just pick a side, man?
- Pick a side.
Sorry. I like watching
you two argue.
My therapist says it's because
I envy your guys' relationship.
Which I do not.
Just because you're
busy upstairs doesn't mean
you get to saddle
us with your work.
We don't exactly, uh, have
spare time down here either.
Fine. I'll put in
holding orders.
But she will have
to board in the ER
until a bed is available.
As long as she's not on my list,
you can do whatever you want.
Look who's here.
Hi.
I'm your mom.
And you're the most beautiful
thing in the whole world.
♪ I had a dream ♪
♪ I got everything I wanted... ♪
Put your finger in her palm.
Can you grab this? Grab this.
Here.
Thank you, Mina.
For everything.
♪ To anyone who might care... ♪
Hi. Hi.
You like my finger?
Here.
♪ I got everything I wanted ♪
Hi.
♪ But when I wake... ♪
Oh. Hey, hey.
Hey, hey. You don't
got to walk me in.
Oh, well, I want to
take a look at that cut.
- It could get infected.
- I-I got bandages
and all sorts of
antiseptic stuff.
I'll be fine.
Okay, well, I thought we were
gonna spend the day together.
You... still want
to do that, or...?
Well, yeah. Sure,
sure. Yeah, of course.
I just, I'd like to
clean up and...
My place is a mess and, uh...
Tell you what, why don't
we grab lunch a little later?
Sure, yeah. I'll
call you in a bit.
Were you at least gonna tell
me that you were leaving again?
No.
I thought you were in trouble.
I told you I was fine.
Things have been
so good between us,
and you want to
throw it all away? Why?
S-Settling down, volunteering
at Chastain, being an angel,
trying to be a good dad
to you, it's exhausting.
- I can't do it anymore.
- So you're just gonna
take off again?
Nicky, I burn down
every good thing
that's ever happened to me.
That's who I am.
I'm sorry I led you to believe
that, even for a second,
that I had changed.
I... Here.
Here, I want you to have this.
It's money from the car.
I wanted to leave you
something f-for the... sh...
I-I don't know, for
all the, for all the time
that you-you wasted on me.
Come on, please. Here.
But his history is unremarkable.
Nothing is jumping out at me.
Whoa. If I knew it was you
on the other end of the page,
I would've rallied the troops,
signaled the alarm,
called the band...
Can you just say it's good to
see him and be done with it?
- Thanks for coming down, Austin.
- No problem.
I see we're hiding out
in the conference room.
Avoiding Logan Kim, I take it?
And the appearance that I'm
treating a patient in Chastain.
A loophole. I dig it. What's up?
Dax Ramsey. He has a
chest tube, a lacerated spleen,
and multiple pulmonary
contusions with hemorrhage.
Do you think he'll need surgery?
His chest tube is only draining
a hundred mils per hour.
So we have to wait
and watch and hope
that his lungs heal itself.
If not, I will come in
and save the day, but...
Taking off my thoracic hat and
putting on my trauma fedora...
- Bell, are you seeing
what I'm seeing? Yeah.
The injuries are severe
for the trauma he took.
Uh, we were just
getting to that.
Is... Any idea why he
wanted a second opinion?
Yeah, over the years,
Dax has suffered
more injuries than normal.
He thought maybe his team
doctor missed something.
Yeah, well, I think Dax
was onto something.
Mm-hmm.
Dax is crashing.
You might want
to hang back, bro.
Our patient is critical. I
can't worry about the rules.
Get a crash cart. He's in V fib.
His sats are down to the 80s.
Hawkins, I need you
to do compressions.
Do it. Abdomen's soft.
There's no blood in his
drainage system either.
We need to decompress his chest.
He's back in sinus tach,
but he's still hypotensive.
You ready? Get it.
Massive hemothorax.
We need to get
Dax to surgery now.
Give me the bag.
Let's go.
I told you what would happen
if I caught you treating a patient.
It was compressions.
For a patient who would
have died otherwise.
It's okay.
- Take care of Dax.
- Yeah.
Well, the lobectomy should
keep Dax's bleeding under control.
We solved one issue, and
another keeps sprouting up.
- You notice his legs
were swollen?
- Yeah.
I also saw what looked
like blood in his urine bag.
- He's in rhabdo.
- But why exactly
is his muscle tissue
breaking down?
His pH is normal. At
least he's not acidotic.
You know, maybe
it's a mixed picture.
Metabolic acidosis
plus respiratory alkalosis.
What is going on with this kid?
You know, the only
thing I know for certain
is we'll figure it out.
No doubt. No, a theory
will come to us in a minute.
We got this.
So it's not coming to
us at-at this m-moment.
Well, w-we... you know,
Bell, we have nothing to prove.
You know, you have a
bomb-ass supplement line
- taking off right now.
- You're a triple-board-
certified surgeon.
- Right?
- The reality is,
we are out of our wheelhouse.
- Well, that's fair.
- This is much less
of a surgical case
- and more of a medical...
- It, uh, is a mystery.
There you go.
I never thought I'd
say these words.
Oh, go ahead, say it.
One of us has to, Bell.
- We might need Conrad Hawkins.
- Now, did that hurt much?
- Yeah, a little.
- Okay.
Look, he can't come here, so
we got to make a house call.
So far, we've only been treating
the trauma-related injuries.
Injuries exacerbated
by an underlying,
- undiagnosed condition.
- Right.
We've seen his records.
What do we know?
He typically
experiences vomiting
after strenuous workouts.
And most recently, he's
been suffering a string
of musculoskeletal injuries
and now has rhabdo.
I know that look.
You know, I dig that look.
It's been an
acquired taste for me.
He's not septic. And
while the rhabdo alone
can cause some
elevation in the lactate,
it's more than I'd expect.
I think we're seeing...
Type B lactic acidosis.
In plain English, there's
something that's preventing Dax
from breaking down
glucose in the normal way.
How do you treat that?
Type B lactic acidosis is a
symptom of something else.
And it's that something
that might explain
what's been causing
all of Dax's injuries
in the first place.
Well, you guys seem to
know what you're doing.
Guess it's good
that Dax landed here.
We only employ
the best at Chastain.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm. You bet.
Surgeons usually don't possess
such an in-depth knowledge
of medical management.
Um, well, I'm sorry,
last time I checked,
you weren't a doctor.
Yeah, so why don't you run along
and worry about whatever
it is you worry about?
And you let us focus
on saving our patient.
Nurse Ingrid, have you
checked on Riley Jackson?
I don't see her on the floor.
I don't know who that is.
Is she a medicine patient?
I admitted her two hours ago,
and we have open beds now.
Do you know why she
hasn't been brought up?
I can tell you, Pravesh.
Canceled her admission.
I told you to be a blocking
machine, but instead
you let your friend
from ER run over you.
No, that's not what happened.
I made a compromise
to ease the tension
between our departments.
Who are you, Oprah?
Since we haven't checked
on her, hopefully the ER has.
Riley?
Open your eyes.
Pupils dilated,
minimally reactive.
She's having a stroke.
Let's go.
- Hey, I have a code stroke here.
- Three.
Code stroke, ER Bay Three.
I need an intubation kit.
Draw up 20 of
etomidate and 70 of roc.
Okay, once we get better access,
let's get the portable monitor
and get her to CT. She came
in with nausea and vomiting.
How did this happen?
Hey, how is it going with Kyle?
Not good.
He's leaving Atlanta.
Wasn't even gonna tell me.
Nic, I'm so sorry.
I let my guard down.
- I let him back into my life.
- Well...
you thought he
changed, so did I.
I should have known better.
I mean, he always bails.
He usually tells me
some lie as to why it's best.
This time, he didn't even
bother to lie. He's just...
he's just leaving.
Bell and Austin know
how to reach me.
Why don't I pack up,
come home, and we
turn this horrible day
into something else?
It's okay.
I think I just need some time.
Okay.
But you call me the
second you need anything.
- I love you.
- I love you, too.
I can't do it anymore.
I'm sorry that I
led you to believe
that-that-that it was
different, even for a second.
First day on the
job as a volunteer.
You're all I got, kid.
He did lie.
♪ ♪
I don't think I'm
doing it right.
Oh, here, let me
- show you what she likes.
- Okay.
Hey, hey.
You know her better than I do.
I've been taking
care of Michelle.
Of course I learned a few tricks
along the way.
Rhythmically, tap
on her back like this.
Yeah.
Oh, come to Mommy. Yes.
Come to Mommy.
Oh.
- You okay?
- Fine.
Yeah?
Mina, is this hard for you?
Will you miss her?
Are you kidding? She's
cute and everything,
but, um, I'll have my life back.
Are Dax's next set
of labs in? Thank you.
They're cooking.
Oh, damn it. Just
stay on the line.
I'm being paged to Dax's room.
- What's going on?
- I'm not sure. Just listen in.
Okay, he is rapidly alternating
between fast and
slow heart rates.
Tachy-brady syndrome, but why?
No, he's too young for
primary cardiac disease.
And his echo from a few
months ago was normal.
His muscle cells are
bursting into his bloodstream.
Yeah, making it likely
an electrolyte issue.
We need a point-of-care chem-8.
Sodium 134, bicarb 22,
glucose 110, potassium 6.9.
He needs calcium and bicarb.
Need an amp of calcium
gluconate and bicarb now,
then an amp of D50
and ten of regular insulin.
I'm not sure how this fits
into his underlying condition.
This is odd.
- What now?
- His abdomen is distended.
Reggie? Patrick?
- What are you thinking?
- I'm just, I'm worried
his splenic lac has
opened up and he's starting
to rebleed. Take him down to CT
- and find out what's going on.
- I want to help.
I need to know.
So keep me posted.
Okay. I will.
Thank you.
That call about your patient?
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
Getting worse.
Listen, you're doing
everything you can do.
Don't beat yourself up.
You're gonna be back
in the trenches soon.
How's the job hunt going?
Rough.
Found some hospitals in
Tennessee that look promising.
Tennessee?
Yeah, I got fired. I'm
poisoned goods in Atlanta.
And after my run-in with
my dear friend Logan Kim,
the poison's gonna
spread statewide.
Okay, so you're
just gonna give up?
I'm persona non
grata. I'm out of options.
I'm sorry, I'm looking for the
table with Conrad Hawkins.
Come on, man.
Look, you're always telling us
to fight, think outside the box.
That's what I've been doing.
I can't keep fighting the
same battle and losing.
I have to move on.
Listen,
you are the guy that pulls
Hail Marys out of nowhere.
And guys like
you, they don't just
think outside the
box, they create
their own box if necessary,
and then you think
out of that one, too.
What's going on
with your patient?
She had a cerebellar stroke,
and then she
started to herniate,
so they did a
posterior craniectomy.
Red Rock prioritizes surgical
patients over ER patients.
It's more lucrative.
So ER patients that
should be upstairs
in a room are being
boarded in the hallway.
And that's what happened
to my patient today.
It delayed us realizing
she was having a stroke.
- So do something about it.
- There's nothing I can do.
Oh, yeah, I'm-I'm sorry, I
was looking for the table
with Devon Pravesh.
No, it-it's... That's
not the same thing.
Patient boarding...
That's a national crisis.
Okay.
So you find the local solution
to the national problem.
If I have to think outside
of the box for my unwinnable
situation, so do you.
I miss this.
Yeah, me, too.
Dad, open the door.
Dad.
I think I know what
you're planning,
and I'm not gonna let you do it.
I'm...
I'm worried you might
be a danger to yourself.
That's a pretty big
leap, but I get it.
You're upset about
what I said earlier.
We are rebuilding
our lives, together,
and things are really good.
And I think it caught
you by surprise.
When you came
back to help Jessie,
you didn't expect that the man
who burns everything down
would start building things
he was scared to lose.
You're-you're just
making this a lot harder
than it has to be. I really
think you need to leave.
You and I both know
if I walk out that door,
- I'll never see you again.
- Nic, if you love me,
you will go.
No.
Because every day
for the rest of my life,
I will live with the guilt that
I walked out on my father
when he needed me, so, no.
It won't be your fault.
I'm the broken
wheel in this family,
and this, today, I
can free you of that.
And I don't want you to
shed a single tear for me.
I don't deserve
it. I never have.
Do you remember
when they took me in
for Jessie's transplant surgery?
I wanted to tell you something.
Yeah.
What was it?
If I died saving Jessie,
it'd be the only good thing
that I've ever done with my life.
I know that I'm worthless.
That's why I-I run,
it's why I, I-I, I fail
at everything I touch.
God... he just keeps
choosing the wrong one of us.
First your mother.
Jessie.
I'm at the end of my life.
And that is all I
got to show for it.
The sum total of my life...
stuffed into an envelope.
That is not true.
Things haven't always been
easy with us, but... you have me.
I'm sorry I didn't tell
you this sooner, but...
when I think about my
future... I see you in it.
At my wedding, walking
me down the aisle.
Birthdays, holidays,
and every moment in
between, you are there.
It would break my
heart if you were gone.
So, no.
I'm not leaving.
Will you be honest with me?
Can you tell me what
you are planning?
Dad.
Okay.
- Sorry.
- Okay. Okay.
Will you give it to me, please?
It's okay.
Okay.
- I'm scared.
- It's okay. It's okay.
Bell, what happened?
Well, I noticed his
abdomen was distended,
and then his
hemoglobin took a dive.
What, you're thinking
it's his splenic lac?
Well, yeah, that's what
I was worried about.
That's what's
happened. That spleen's
got to come out immediately.
Whatever is going on with Dax
is causing him to
become coagulopathic.
Well, clotting issues aside...
we got to get him
to the OR stat.
- I hope there's time
to save his life.
- All right, let's go.
Hey. Hey. What is this?
Patients who have been
sitting in the ER hallways
for hours, waiting for a
bed on the medicine floor.
A hallway in the ER
versus a hallway here.
- What's the difference?
- Proximity.
Doctors tend to forget about
these patients even though,
technically,
they're on their lists.
Out of sight, out of mind.
A patient almost died today
because she fell
through the cracks.
Administration won't allow this.
It'll go back to the
way it was tomorrow.
Maybe.
But at least today,
these patients,
they won't be forgotten.
We're slightly off the
midline to the fascia,
- 'cause I see rectus muscle.
- Agreed.
Wait. Hold up.
Lac.
Peep the color.
That doesn't even
look like muscle.
It's more pale than usual.
And look at that.
It barely twitched.
Well, that's odd, given
Dax's athletic background.
I think we've hit the part of the
story where we find answers.
Conrad? You there?
I am with you every
step of the way.
I know what's wrong with Dax.
You'll need a muscle
biopsy to confirm.
Mr. Landry. Hey.
So, it turns out that Dax has a
genetic mitochondrial disorder.
And that occurs
when mitochondria
fails to produce enough energy
for the body to
function properly.
When Dax went pro, he
started doing intermittent fasting.
It triggered his disorder and it
exacerbated his trauma symptoms.
Is it treatable?
With a specialized
diet and supplements,
it's likely he'll be able
to continue to play.
- I can't thank you both enough.
- Uh,
we aren't the only
ones you should thank.
We didn't make
the diagnosis alone.
Conrad Hawkins
was an integral part.
Really?
Mr. Landry?
I heard what you did for Dax.
I owe you a debt of thanks.
Oh. Glad I could help.
I also heard that
Dax brought you in
because our team doctor
didn't address his concerns.
That's unacceptable.
My players are
like family to me.
And this has shown me
that my family needs a doctor.
I'd like that doctor to be you.
Is, is this is a real offer?
It is. I don't think
I'll have a problem
getting you a
position at St. John's.
So, Dr. Hawkins,
what do you say?
Hawkins, what
are you doing here?
I thought you'd like to
know I've just been hired
as the new team
doctor for Georgia FC.
Physical therapy, medical tests,
referrals, orthopedic surgery.
It's the prestige and money
of a partnership with
a major sports team.
Now, all of this will
remain at St. John's,
unless there's another
hospital I decide to call home.
Do you want Chastain
to be that hospital?
Or should I just
let Red Rock know
you let this golden goose
slip through your fingers?
You're bluffing.
Bill Landry has a
contract with St. John's.
A contract his lawyers
say he can get out of
with a few quick phone calls,
given what happened
to Dax Ramsey.
If I were to agree to this,
what would be the terms,
moving forward?
Well, you and I hug it out...
and then I decide
which physicians treat
and consult Georgia FC
and I monitor every
aspect of team care.
I'm chief resident.
And I'm gonna do
whatever I think is best
for my patients
here at Chastain.
I love it. Yes, yes.
I can't believe
you pulled this off.
I wish I could've seen the
look on Logan Kim's face.
Oh, if you were truly our
friend, you would have
recorded it so we
can play it on a loop.
I have to admit,
it was pretty great,
but this is just the beginning.
He's right. We still
have a lot of work to do.
Like ousting our
corporate overlords.
- Which won't be an easy task.
- True,
but we will get
it done, together.
Agreed.
But first, we need to do
something about your wardrobe.
Welcome home, Conrad.
Yeah! All right.
Yeah!
- Mwah.
- Thank you.
Still looks good.
A toast.
Here's to another
day in the trenches.
I'll drink to that.
- Cheers. Cheers.
- It's good to have you back.
- Cheers.
I'm sorry I wasn't there
to celebrate with you.
After the day you've had,
I'm the last person
you should think about.
Kyle has a long road ahead,
but you don't have
to do this alone, Nic.
Whatever happens, I'm here.
Hey. What did I say?
Exactly what I needed to hear.
Oh. Oh, hey, sorry.
Sorry, I just...
Do you...? I-Is it
okay if I borrow this?
- I kind of already stuck my...
- Oh, yeah, yeah.
You can keep it. You
got everything you need?
Uh, yeah, yeah. You got snacks,
you got tunes, you got road map.
I think we are good to go.
Well, if you need anything...
Yeah.
Hey, so... you-you think
this place in Savannah,
you really, you really
think they can help me?
It's one of the best
inpatient centers
in the country.
It's a psych joint.
I get it, but good.
Whatever it takes.
I really want to be there
for all those moments
that you talked about.
Me, too.
Come on.
Call me on the way?
We can all help prevent suicide.
The National Suicide
Prevention Lifeline
is a national network
of local crisis centers
that provides free and
confidential emotional support
to those in suicidal crisis
and emotional distress
24 hours a day,
seven days a week.
If you're struggling
with thoughts of suicide,
or worried about a
loved one or a friend,
help is available to you.
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH