Hello, my old heart
How have you been?
Are you still there
inside my chest?
I've been so worried
You've been so still
Barely beating at all
Oh
Don't leave me here alone
Don't tell me that we've
grown for having loved
A little while
Oh
I don't wanna be alone
I wanna find a home
And I wanna share it with you
Good morning...
A cruel person wrote these.
A cruel person is gonna
put you back in bed.
Do you remember how much I
loved this bed when we got it?
I do. Hmm.
Now I want to set it on
fire and laugh while it burns.
That sounds dangerous,
and bed rest is important.
It prevents the cervix
from... From having a life.
Max, my cervix is so bored.
Thank you for doing this.
All of it.
How's the couch?
Really good. Hmm?
Yeah, it's a little bit better
than the bed, to be honest.
I want to be ready, Max.
I want to want you back.
I'm just... I'm not...
I got all the time in the world.
I'm all right today
You gonna find a way to cross
And you gonna get there
And I'm on fire today
Ain't no water here to
calm or even put me out
I'll find a better way
Am I crazy, or the wind
is gonna blow me down?
Do you mind if I ask how
long your foot's been hurting?
It's nothing. I'm fine.
I'm a doctor at New Amsterdam
right across the street.
Maybe you could take a walk
with me. I could have a look at that.
Maybe you could leave me alone.
Your foot is badly infected.
If you don't do something
about it, it's gonna get a lot worse.
Can you get away from me?
I love soil. Do you
want to know why?
I am at the edge of
my metaphorical seat.
Because it contains
Mycobacterium vaccae,
which has been proven to
promote serotonin production,
which acts as a
natural antidepressant.
So does that hat.
Can't bring me down,
my friend. Not today.
The HCC has funded my proposal.
After two years, they funded it!
For the community
garden? Yes, exactly.
You know, horticultural therapy
dates back to ancient
Mesopotamia, and, uh...
Oh, my gosh, are those your
little homemade Indian donuts?
They are not donuts.
They are laddus.
Well, I don't mind if I "laddu."
They are not for you.
They are for someone else.
Not the girl from the
coffee shop, though?
Her name is Ella.
It's my gesture of gratitude for
someone who showed me kindness.
Mmm-hmm. Okay, let
me see if I got this straight.
You're gonna give pastries to
someone who works in a pastry shop.
Laddus are not pastries.
They are sweets. Oh.
Well, that doesn't
make it any less weird.
Gladys?
Gladys, what is this?
Volt Cola swag. A gift
from the new sponsor.
What new sponsor? For
your community garden.
Bloom? What's the urgent page?
Uh, got an EMS notification
asking to have thoracic standing by.
You okay? Headache.
45-year-old man, acute
onset tearing chest pain.
Heart rate 110, 140 over 56, right
arm, 100 over palp, left. Respiration's 18.
Gave him nitro...
Dissecting aortic aneurysm.
Mateo?
Hope you're on your
game today, Floyd.
Who's... Mateo Fernandez.
The cardiothoracic from Baptist?
Yeah. Isn't this week...
Yeah. Hey, get
Max down here now.
Oh.
Okay, as I fit you for
the radiation mask,
remember you have
to keep absolutely still.
I always found stillness to be a
highly overrated human ability.
Consider it practice
for when we aim high
energy external beam radiation
at the cancer in your throat.
If you move then, you die.
Has anyone ever told you you would
make a great James Bond villain?
Uh, Max, you cannot move.
Right.
So, uh, come here often?
That includes your
mouth. All of it? Because...
Do I have to remind you that
you need a throat to make jokes?
Relax.
You can close
your eyes if you like.
Stay still, Max.
Done.
I think it's fair to say
that was torture for both of us.
If my cancer gets anyone
else killed besides me,
then I'm really gonna be upset.
I got the 911.
This week's the annual conference of
cardiothoracic surgeons in San Diego.
Everyone goes. All of
my attendings are there.
One unlucky surgeon stays
behind at each hospital to cover.
It's me here, it's
Fernandez at Baptist,
but only one of us has a
dissecting aortic aneurysm.
And since he's here, I'm
guessing no one's covering Baptist.
They still have general
surgeons, transplant surgeons.
Yeah, they can't
cover for Fernandez.
You want a gynecologist
tagging in on your heart surgery?
How can Baptist run their hospital
without a cardiothoracic surgeon?
They can't. Which means they're
no longer a level-one trauma center.
Without cardiothoracic backup,
they can't treat myocardial infarctions,
car accidents, GSWs...
They can't accept ambulances.
Guys, we're gonna have to pick
up Baptist's full ambulance load.
I knew you were gonna say that.
They'd do it for us. Would they?
We're short-staffed too. What
about their network hospitals?
They'll pick up the elective admits,
but emergency patients will die waiting
in cross-town traffic.
We're the closest. It's on us.
You really think we can
shoulder their full ED plus all
the cardiothoracic surgeries?
Just the ones that
need to be done today.
Yeah, just those.
Guys, this is what we do.
We help everyone.
Floyd, I trust you and I believe
in you, so I am only gonna do this
if you tell me
you can handle it.
I can handle it. Okay, good,
because if something goes
wrong, we are both on the hook.
Nothing will go wrong,
all right? I'll make sure of it.
Okay.
Bloom, we're gonna live or
die today based on our ED load.
So, any doc or nurse standing
still in any part of this hospital
needs to go down and pitch in.
I'll take it. I
already hear sirens,
so unfortunately, you're gonna have
to miss the rest of my big pep talk.
Aw, so sad.
Iggy, psych wait
times are the longest,
so make sure you get your patients
up to your ward early and often.
All right. Good thing psych
patients are so compliant.
Kapoor, neurology wait times are second,
so I need you to move double time today.
This is my double time. Noted.
Sharpe. This is a bad idea.
So is sending every
cardiothoracic surgeon in America
to San Diego at the same time,
but they do it every year.
Last year was Barcelona.
I do love sangria.
This is a bad idea.
So, are you telling me
that you wouldn't have
taken the extra patients?
No, I wouldn't have.
I try to make
things simple, easy.
You know, like a
normal person. Ah.
Why do you keep choosing the
hardest road at every opportunity?
Better views?
Tall person, how long have
you been with Reynolds?
Three years. And
it's Nottingham.
I'm a PGY-6, so...
Okay, today is not the day
where I'm gonna be polite
and remember your names.
When patients come in,
I'm gonna point and yell.
Don't take it personally.
You move on my orders only.
What'd you bring
us? Adaline Simon.
53-year-old female, had a
pleurodesis on the books at Baptist.
Tall person, take Mrs. Simon to any
empty bed and get her prepped for surgery.
This is Mr. Gold, 47-year-old
male in need of a VATS procedure.
Casey and brown-haired
woman. Any open bay.
Name is Sherry Fletcher.
68-year-old female.
She requires a mediastinoscopy.
Stay with me. Okay,
let's get her inside.
Okay, put Mrs.
Fletcher in bay 23.
Has anybody seen my ibuprofen?
Tell a nurse to grab
you a bottle from the...
What I need is for people
to stop taking my stuff.
Incoming!
Rib spreader. Rib spreader.
Fair warning. This
is being recorded
so that Dr. Fernandez can see
my technique when he's awake.
Um...
Dr. Reynolds? Uh...
Dr. Bloom asked me to, um...
Start with the
subject, then the verb,
and see where the
sentence goes from there.
The cases from Baptist
are crowding the ED.
There's a pleurodesis.
With your permission, I
was thinking I could grab
a general attending to
supervise and handle it myself.
Appreciate the enthusiasm, but
prep the patient and wait for me.
It's just the ED's awfully full,
and I really think
I can help out.
You have a very
promising future.
I don't want you in over your head
when I'm too busy to bail you out.
A mistake like that can
derail your entire career,
so go ahead and prep the patient,
and I'll get there when I'm done.
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
Baptist's surgeons are on a
flight back from San Diego.
It lands in five hours.
You got this, right?
Do I have a choice?
I could warp the
space-time continuum.
Hey, what patient is that for?
Homeless woman outside.
You couldn't find a
patient inside to help?
If I don't help her, she's
gonna lose her foot.
Send an intern.
She's skeptical of doctors and so
am I, so we have an understanding.
I'll be back in five
minutes. What?
Sorry, Doc!
You and Ella have an
asymmetric power structure.
Giving her a gift
can be misinterpreted
as a deliberate extraction of
reciprocal favors, sexual or otherwise.
I see you talked to Dr. Frome.
Mrs. Monaghan, I am
Dr. Vijay Kapoor and this is Dr...
Kao. Dr. Kao.
I'm dizzy. I'm so
sorry to hear that.
Dizzy can be awful.
Can you explain to me
what do you mean by "dizzy"?
You don't know "dizzy"?
I do, I do, but I also know that it
means different things to different people.
Well, at Baptist, they
understand dizzy.
That may be true, but
here in New Amsterdam,
I want you to think about what
exactly "dizzy" means to you.
It means "dizzy."
The good news is that
your CT scans are negative
and preliminary
lab tests all look fine.
She's a good
doctor. Yes, she is.
So, while I examine
my other patients,
I want you to think
about your kind of dizzy.
Tell me you're
admitting "dizzy chick."
I cannot admit anyone
without a proper diagnosis,
and I don't have any yet.
Maybe we should make it
a multiple-choice question.
We cannot give her choices.
It will influence her answers.
We just need to know
what "dizzy" means to her,
and we will get our diagnosis.
So then I call HCC,
and they say I take the
money from Volt Cola
or I can kiss my garden goodbye.
More than half of the sugar kids
consume comes directly from soda.
I know.
Volt Cola spend millions
each year to defeat
public health legislation
that could actually help.
I know.
So, unless you want to hurry along
the epidemic of childhood obesity,
then there's no way
you can take their money.
I know. Great.
Now you can focus on the
epidemic of overcrowding in my ED.
Your psych patients are in bays
two, eight, rooms 12, 22 and 28.
Get them out of
here. Okey-doke, Doc.
Okay, I'm just gonna check
if the numbing medication
has worked, Tianna.
Can you feel this?
No. How about this?
Mmm-mmm.
She was in pain,
so we called 911.
We didn't want to
take any chances.
Should we have just
driven her to Baptist?
No, no. You did the right thing.
I've read Tianna's
file. I'm all caught up.
Mommy, you're not
watching. I am, sweetheart.
Oh, don't move, Tianna.
I'm just gathering the cells
I need for the biopsy right now.
Those are gonna tell
you if my cancer's back?
That's right.
What's it like when you die?
Baby, you don't
need to know that.
That's not gonna happen
for a long, long time.
All right, baby girl?
Right, Dr. Sharpe?
Do you want the elephant
or the tiger Band-Aid?
Nobody tells me anything.
Miss me? Nope, nope, nope, nope.
I can't afford your
help! My help is free.
Not taking it is gonna
cost you your foot,
so either way, you're
gonna have to deal with me.
You're relentless.
I'm Max.
I'm Faye. It's nice
to meet you, Faye.
Okay, take one of these a
day until the bottle is gone.
I have to go, but, uh, I'll
come back to check on you.
I have a brother
who's very sick.
He won't go to the hospital.
Can you help him too?
I have a hospital full of
patients who need me.
How can I help?
Faye, I really can't go
far. We're close. I promise.
You have to see him.
This way.
Hey, how much longer?
I'm backing up downstairs.
I'm holding this
man's aorta together
with string and Scotch tape.
I'm doing everything I can.
Well, your seven surgeries
waiting in my ED would disagree.
Take it up with Max.
I would if I could find him.
I'm going as fast as I can.
I'm the only
cardiothoracic here.
Well, what about
one of your residents?
I mean, the tall one
looked semi-competent.
Nottingham and, look,
for all these patients,
this is the scariest
day of their lives.
They woke up needing major surgery,
then they were thrown into an ambulance
and dragged across town so
that a doctor they don't know
can cut open their hearts.
They're trusting me, just
like Max is trusting me.
And I'm not putting
that kind of pressure on
a first-year resident
straight out of med school.
Oh, we got a bleeder.
Are the patients
downstairs stable?
Yeah. Then they can wait.
I am giving you one hour and then I
am sending them somewhere else.
All right, here we go.
Suction.
Mrs. Monaghan, can you
describe your symptoms now?
Dizzy!
Are you even a real doctor?
Yes, and I'm trying to help you.
Good, then give me something
for dizzy so I can go home.
I would love to do that, but I want
to give you the right something.
I'll give you more time. You...
She's gonna be here all day.
Maybe, but fast and wrong is not
a service to her or to anyone else.
Dr. Bloom? What
are you looking for?
Are you, uh, getting
her out of my ED?
Not as yet.
Can you get some other patients
out of here? Something's gotta give.
Oh, and you should
totally give Ella your pastry.
So, you do understand it
was a harmless gesture.
Oh, I think it's a huge mistake,
but I want to see you suffer.
Oh!
Laddus are not pastries!
It's like my
college sit-in days.
Every chair occupied, so
people just lie on the floor.
Almost on tilt and
four hours to go.
Go steal the chemo
chairs from onc.
Oh.
Grab and go. Also like
my college days. On it.
Jemma. Jemma, wait. Hey.
Whoa, whoa. Are you okay?
No, I'm not okay.
None of this is okay.
Jemma, hang on. We're
trying our best here.
Okay? It's an uphill battle.
What?
What's this? What's
happening here?
Transfers from the ED.
No, no. Uh-uh. No. No vacancies.
We're all full up. So is the ED.
I'm not their safety valve.
All right, let's go. I just...
Yeah, come in.
This is exactly why we
needed the community garden.
What happened to the
garden? I have to kill it.
You have been wanting
that garden for years.
Yeah, just not with
Volt Cola attached.
In India, Volt Cola builds
playgrounds, football fields,
cricket pitches
for kids to play on.
Which means land,
which takes money.
Would a garden make a
difference to these kids too?
Yeah.
Yeah, it would.
Tianna's cancer's back.
Ewing's sarcoma.
It's extremely aggressive.
I'm very sorry.
What about something
experimental?
Unfortunately, there are no
clinical trials for kids her age.
There has to be
more out there. Uh...
Other countries.
Um...
There has to be something else.
I think
that we should discuss
palliative care options.
How do we tell her? We don't.
We can't.
Tianna is smart.
She is asking questions.
She is looking for answers.
The best course
of... I can't tell her.
Can you?
Who are you? What'd
you bring this guy here for?
He's a doctor and
his name is Max.
You brought a
doctor to our house?
Hey, hey, hey. He can help.
We don't need his kind of help.
Give him a chance, Paul.
Just...
It's okay.
Where are you from?
Are you from the Midwest?
Hamilton, Ohio. Born and raised.
Why?
Vance, you may
have a fungal infection,
and if it's the kind
that I think it is,
we need to get you into
New Amsterdam right now.
No, man. No hospital.
All right, what you got to do
now is just get the hell out of here.
I don't know what you
have against hospitals,
but if we don't take your brother
to New Amsterdam right now,
he is going to die.
That's exactly what the other
doctors said when Mom was sick.
Except rather than help,
they just kept bringing bills.
We lost our apartment.
The debt collectors
took the rest.
I promise you will never see a
single bill from New Amsterdam.
What do you say, Vance?
I took a gamble on you coming
here, leaving my own hospital.
You want to take a gamble on me?
Go away, man.
You heard him.
Get out of here.
The graft's pulling
taut. It's too damn small.
What?
Everyone is prepped,
so I thought I'd scrub in.
No.
I've watched you do
this surgery four times.
I know to ligate the internal mammary
before transecting the intercostal.
I know...
I don't need you in here.
I need you out there.
Go!
Suture.
Excuse me.
Excuse me! That is my chair!
I said I ain't moving.
You're not the only
dumbass that needs space!
Fight, fight, fight!
Thanks. Over there. Not now.
Goodwin! Where the
hell have you been?
It's like a damn
MASH unit in here.
Dean, I had to take...
What were you thinking?
Bloom, get all the department
heads down here. Now.
Here you go, Doctor.
Okay, I'll make
this quick and clear.
I screwed up. All
this chaos, it's on me.
I overcommitted us and
then went out looking for more.
I thought I could help everyone
and ended up helping no one.
I'm not asking for
understanding or forgiveness,
but I am asking you
to help me fix this.
So, here's the plan.
Reynolds, I am sorry that I
put so much pressure on you.
How can I take some of it off?
Are any of the surgeries
waiting in the ED stable enough
to go to Mount Zion? Two.
I'll send them. Bloom,
anywhere there's an open bed,
admit a patient to it.
Admit everyone you can.
And what if we don't get
reimbursed for the beds?
I'll send Baptist
the bill. Iggy.
Captain? Take your
patients to the cafeteria,
to the roof, for a walk. Anywhere to
keep them busy and out of the ward.
Aye-aye. Sharpe.
I know what I have to
do. Great. Any questions?
Any questions not about
Kapoor's laddu situation?
No. Go.
Max, I don't know how
you're gonna pull this off.
We are all gonna work together.
Including you.
I could really use
your help, Dr. Fulton.
The flat metal part goes
on the patient's chest.
How are you holding up?
I thought getting the news
would be the hard part,
but telling Tianna's a
million times harder.
You shouldn't have to.
You be her mum.
I'll be her doctor.
I'll tell her.
In for a little treat here.
Come on. Come on out.
Okay.
So, it's not a garden, but, uh, you
know, it's outside. It's fresh-air therapy.
We got a wonderful view
of the city, so, you know,
spread out, feel the space.
Find your own spot, all right?
Jemma, hi. What's
going on? Talk to me.
There's nothing to say.
Well, I heard that Blanca's
background check came through clean.
That's good news, right?
Yeah. Yeah.
But, like, the site visit
keeps getting pushed back.
It isn't for months. And
there's, like, 100 other things
that could go wrong
before I get out of here.
Hey. Are those facts
or those feelings?
It's feelings.
Right, they're feelings, so why
don't we try sticking to the facts?
Okay, I'll make
some phone calls.
We're gonna get you
the home you deserve.
I promise.
All right.
Dr. Frome?
Don't we have
wheelchairs for that?
They're all taken, but don't need one.
This is how we did it in Afghanistan.
My man right here's
on his way to X-ray.
Got a lateral malleolus
fracture playing indoor soccer,
but he's gonna be
fine. Right, Camden?
Did you take my
ibuprofen? Yeah. Thanks.
Ah, Dr. Kapoor. Oh, Dean.
Mrs. Monaghan has been
telling me a very interesting story.
How you don't seem to
understand the word "dizzy."
I do understand. Do you?
Do you see what I mean?
I should have walked
out of here an hour ago.
Why didn't you?
Because when I try to stand up,
I feel like I'm
going to fall over.
Like my feet aren't even there.
Mrs. Monaghan, you have
Guillain-Barre syndrome.
Excuse me?
The anti-bodies your
system made to fight your cold
are attacking the
nerves in your feet.
That's why you can't feel them.
I can now officially admit
you and get you taken care of.
Help! We... We need help!
Max... Max... Max
said he would help him.
Max? Max?
We've got an arterial bleed.
Ready an intubation tray
and page Max to Trauma One, now!
Max! Come on, stay
with us. Come on.
Class-one airway. Get
20 milligrams Etomidate
and 100 milligrams succinylcholine
and let's start a propofol drip.
Give me a 7.5 on
the hockey stick.
Seven point five
on the hockey stick.
I'm in.
Now we find the bleeder.
There it is.
The bleeding's coming
from that bronchiole.
Don't say it.
We need Reynolds.
Ah. Elbow deep
in a tricky closure.
A man's bleeding out in the ED.
Is this your idea of
relieving pressure?
I know, Floyd. I'm sorry. I
don't know what else to do.
I don't know who else to ask.
Well, I can't be in
two places at once.
Well, I hope you can figure out
how, or someone is going to die.
Thank you. - Clamp.
Blood pressure's dropping.
Push more fluid.
Got two liters open
wide. It's not enough.
Grab a bag of O-negative
out of the trauma fridge.
There's too much blood.
I can't see anything.
There's a pumper in there
somewhere. I just can't find it. Suction.
Will you get the Richardson
and lift up the middle lobe, please?
There it is. I got that bad boy.
Hey, Max, can you give
me a little light over here?
There we go. NURSE: It's ready.
Bleeding's stopped.
Heart rate's steady.
Oxygenation stabilizing.
Nice work, boys.
So, what, you just let Dr. Fernandez
just bleed out in the OR?
I left him in the hands
of a top-notch surgeon.
One more running suture.
Respiration is spontaneous.
- That should hold.
- All right!
Surgeons landed
at JFK an hour ago.
Baptist is up and running.
You did it, Max.
It was fun, being
back in the trenches.
And, Max...
Don't ever do that again.
Good news. Vance will
be in the ICU a few days,
then a course of pills, then
he should make a full recovery.
What was wrong with him?
Histoplasmosis. It's a fungal
infection we see in the soil around Ohio.
Must have been dormant
in Vance his whole life,
and I'm sure living on the streets
weakened his immune system.
The fungus reemerged, and
attacked his lungs and his liver.
I would like to test
you both as well.
We can't possibly
pay for all this.
You don't have to. This is
why public hospitals exist.
This is why I work here. This is
why all these doctors work here.
We don't say no to anyone.
We don't know how.
Thank you.
Casey, hydrate. Why?
Because water plays a vital
role in nearly every bodily function.
Mmm.
Ah, I needed that.
My ibuprofen wasn't ibuprofen.
It was Adderall.
That explains why I
thought I was covered in lice.
And my headache never went away.
I have ADHD. Listen,
you don't have to...
I've had it my whole life.
Adderall got me through med
school, through my residency.
I mean, I couldn't
do this job without it.
So, why do you keep it
in an ibuprofen bottle?
You're killing
yourself for this job.
Everyone here is.
Everyone looks sad.
Sweetheart, your cancer is back.
Tianna,
you asked what it's
like when you die.
I think that it's like this.
Come.
So, when it happens,
you won't be able to
see your mum and dad,
and they won't
be able to see you.
But they will always be there.
And I'll always be here?
Yes.
You'll never stop
thinking of each other.
talking to each other.
You'll just be on a
different side of the room.
Mommy, can you hear me?
Yes, baby doll. We
can hear you, little one.
I can hear you too.
Hello, my old heart
How have you been?
Are you still there
inside my chest?
I've been so worried
You've been so still,
barely beating at all
You okay?
Don't leave me here alone
Don't tell me how we grow
I took the hard road.
And?
Better views.
I wanna find a home
And I wanna share it with you
Hello, my old heart
You know, my attending
wouldn't even let me look
in the OR the first three
months of my residency?
I can still hear him in my head.
"Reynolds, you're more likely
to cut yourself than the patient."
I don't know. Old
habits die hard, I guess.
Well, the difference is
you trained these residents.
Yeah, well, but, you know, if
something had gone wrong...
Okay, do you know what feels
even better than being in control?
Letting go of it.
Don't start what
you can't finish.
Cold
Well, on the bright side, I
can finally take up fencing.
She glides away
In a few weeks, we'll
start chemo in the mornings
and radiation at night.
By "a few weeks,"
you mean... Two.
'Cause sometimes
"a few" can mean...
Two. Right.
Does she know that
we bleed the same?
There's so much to do.
Don't wanna cry,
but I break that way
You're gonna have to prioritize.
You mean start saying no?
I mean start saying yes.
To you.
What do you need, Max?
I
Have got a fear
Oh, in my blood
Cold
Sheets
Oh, where's my love
I am
Searching high
I'm searching low
In the night
Ooh, does she know
that we bleed the same?
Ooh, don't want to
cry, but I break that way
Did she run away,
did she run away?
I don't know
If she ran away, if she ran away
Come back home
Max.
Hey.
It's 9:30. You're gonna be late.
No, I'm not.
Oh, my God. Did you get fired?
That was fast, even for you.
I'm taking the day off.
Thought I'd spend the day here,
with you.