Oh.
We were here first.
Shut up, Beanie.
You shut up.
Move it, Butthead.
It's my turn, Brian.
Okay, okay.
I'll knock.
Al?
Al, you there?
I got you.
Trick or treat!
Okay. All right.
Here's some for you and for you
and for you. Thank you.
Happy Halloween.
Thank you. Happy Halloween!
Treat?
Chocolate bars, chocolate
mints, chocolate kisses.
We'll be seeing half these kids
in the ER by tomorrow morning.
Well, it beats all the
apples and boxed raisins
we got when we were kids.
You can take that off now.
Take what off?
Did you find last year's 1040s?
Yeah, they're around
here somewhere
but here are the loan papers.
You know, I thought taking
out a second mortgage
would be easier than this.
Only if you've
already got the money.
I couldn't finish some of it.
I think you need
an accounting degree
to figure out our net worth.
I'll go over it.
I, uh, I've got to get it
to the bank tomorrow by 10:00.
I'll work on them tonight.
I've got a break at 10:30.
Meet me at Doc McGoo's.
You can pick them up then.
Okay.
Benton hates my guts.
No, I think he likes you.
He just has
difficulty showing it.
Yeah, right.
He bagged me on my evaluation.
"Technical skills... fair.
"Diagnostic skills... fair.
Attitude... needs improvement"?
"Intern shows
lack of discipline.
"Judgment is often suspect.
Fails to complete work
in a timely fashion."
Shall I continue?
Wait, wait, wait. You saw this?
He wrote the same
exact thing on mine.
Does he Xerox them?
I think it's a rubber stamp.
Jerry! What are you, a rat?
It's a kangaroo suit.
The head's too hot and itchy.
Kangaroo?
You're kidding right?
Abdominal pain in three.
Gangrenous toe in two.
Hey, Jerry, can you send
these back to medical records?
I'm running late.
Carol, I've got the
schedule changes.
Okay I'll check it
when I get back.
I'm late for an appointment.
Don't forget you're riding
on the healthmobile tonight.
Yeah, I know. I'll
be back in time.
What is going on?
Maintenance is doing repairs.
It's probably that
ghost from the fifth floor.
Oh, please. Don't
even talk about him.
Talk about who?
The ghost up on five.
Yeah, took a bite out
of that lab technician.
Ghosts don't bite. He just
knocked the wind out of him.
No, he sent a rush of cold air
straight through him, that's all.
Help! My friend's been
shot. He's outside in the car.
Jerry, alert the OR
and clear Trauma One.
Lydia, let's go!
Susan get back
from Hawaii today?
Yeah. Tonight around 6:00.
Orange carnations?
Yeah. You know... Halloween.
Orange carnations.
Yeah.
Doug, got a pumpkin
carver in five.
He ate too many seeds.
Chuny, what are
you supposed to be?
Myself, getting ready for work.
Jerry's trying to get
a count for tonight.
Are you going to the
party at the Jazz Note?
Haleh's singing.
I'm a definite "I don't know."
Yeah, I'm going if I can.
Chuny, is there anything
wrong with orange carnations?
No. I gave them to one
of my teachers once...
Second grade.
Lydia, get that 12
lead out of here.
Take this clown with you, okay?
On my count...
One, two, three
Cyanotic. Intubate. BP's 40.
Pulse thready at 180.
Pulse ox is 80.
Someone call maintenance
about these lights, please?
What do you think?
Increased breath
sounds on the left.
Possible hemopneumo.
What do you do?
Chest tube.
Right again.
Chest tube tray
36 French.
I'm in. Bag him.
I got the O-neg. Pump in two.
He's flatline.
Give me an amp of
epi, two of atropine,
start the external compressions.
Two more of O-neg. Come on,
let's hurry up. We're losing him.
All right, who's got the bullet?
GSW, Left chest.
Carter Intubated
Put in a chest
tube. He flatlined.
Gave him an amp of
epi and two of atropine.
Okay. So what now?
Uh... we should crack him?
Yes, we should crack
him before he ends up
more dead than he
already is, Dr. Gant.
Okay, thoracotomy tray.
Scalpel.
Fifth intercostal space, right?
That's right.
And the left anterolateral
incision, right?
Do you know what
you're doing or not?
Yeah, I'm just confirming...
If you have to
keep confirming, you don't
know what you're doing.
Carter, get in here.
Carter, move. Now!
Rib spreader.
Suction.
Looks like the upper lobe.
All right, cross
clamp the Hilum.
Paralyze him!
Pavulon now!
All right, hold him down!
Come on!
Get him down!
Get it in.
Right there.
Whoa!
Happy Halloween, everybody.
The first thing you do
is calibrate your apparatus.
Collect your data properly
and use the root
mean square to...
Excuse me.
Is this pre-med Physics 101?
For the past 15 minutes.
Sorry.
Do you have a lab assignment?
Uh-uh.
Okay, who's working solo?
There's your lab partner.
The relationship
we're looking at here
is conservation of momentum
in an elastic collision.
The first thing you do is
calibrate your apparatus.
Hi. I'm William.
Carol Hathaway.
I was kind of worried
I'd be the only one
without a lab partner.
Did you bring your
graphing calculator?
Graphing calculator...
That's okay, we
can both use mine.
Neat costume.
That illustrate the
principles of momentum.
Pacemaker's acting up.
Okay, a nurse will
be right with you.
I thought maintenance was done.
Well, some people are saying
it's that g-h-o-s-t
up on the fifth floor.
Jerry, I hate to break it to you
but there's no such
thing as ghosts.
Jerry, who put me in
that damn healthmobile?
Our very own Anspaugh.
It's Halloween.
Every freak in the city
is going to be out there.
Not true, half of
them are here already.
Healthmobile is not so bad.
I was on it last Monday.
Although, we did get shot at.
Oh, man.
It was no big deal.
They missed.
Carol's on, she's not
going to want to go with me.
Doug, it's Anspaugh's baby.
Community access.
It's out of my hands.
We got a little old lady
coming in unconscious, a DNR.
I'll take it.
Actually, you were
due in Anspaugh's office
about ten minutes ago.
Okay, fine.
Uh, get Jeanie ask
her to take the LOL,
and get Doyle to assist.
Oh, uh, Jer...
Any word from Susan?
She's not due in
till 6:00, remember?
Thank you, Jer.
You are getting to
be a big boy, Reggie.
Okay, developmental milestones.
Dr. Benton...
When do we first
see a social smile?
Oh, uh, three weeks.
Dr. Carter?
Mm, it's more like three months.
Right. Using a spoon and fork?
Seven months.
Is that correct, Dr. Carter?
Average is more like 13.
Don't worry, Dr. Benton.
Dr. Carter's just a lot closer
to his pedes
rotation than you are.
You'll just need
to study up a bit,
won't you?
Here.
Why don't you hold Reggie?
Okay, Dr. Carter,
what's the problem here?
Stranger anxiety?
And what would you do?
Reggie was clearly
responding to you
so...
Hi.
Oh.
Being able to keep a
baby calm for examination
is half the battle.
Some doctors have
an instinct for it...
a natural affinity for children.
Uh, you, Dr. Benton, might
want to get some props.
She the "Do not resuscitate"?
Yeah.
Husband's name is Mitchell.
Sweet old guy,
seems really upset.
Is he on his way in?
Yeah. Okay.
Found her in bed, comatose,
end stage of Lou Gehrig's.
Ready... go.
See ya.
PA's run these cases? Yeah.
Not at Southside.
Dr. Greene asked me to.
Pressure's falling, 50 palp.
Her lungs are wet.
She's in respiratory distress.
I don't want to intubate.
She's a no-coder.
Could be pneumonia.
We can treat her
with antibiotics.
Treat her? She's a veggie.
Pressure's crashing...
What do you want to do?
Ten mikes of dopamine
Titrate to a BP of 100
Put her on bi-pap ten over five
and a gram of Ceftriaxone.
Why are you doing this?
Do not resuscitate
doesn't mean do not treat.
You're the PA.
Shouldn't it have
epaulets on the shoulders?
No, those are the
dress uniforms.
Oh, of course.
Mark, come on in.
Cup of tea?
No, thank you.
Kerry and I were
just celebrating
the final stamp of approval
on her research study.
It's quite simple, really.
Free-radical scavengers
prevent celluloid damage,
so why not study
their effect on asthma?
It just occurred to me
while treating a
patient in the ER.
Nothing like research
from the trenches.
NIH Grant shouldn't
take long at all.
I'm keeping my fingers crossed.
Oh, that's me. Gotta go.
I'll see you all at
the party tonight?
Wouldn't miss it.
Good decision bringing Kerry in
as an attending.
Her research ideas are inspired.
I don't need to tell you
that this free-radical study
is going to give
her quite a leg up
on that tenure track.
Not that you
necessarily want to teach
or even stay here at County.
No, I do.
Of course, I'm
interested in tenure.
As for research, I was thinking
fluid resuscitation in
penetrating trauma.
Yes, well, a lot of attendings
are pursuing that one.
There's one that Kerry discarded
that's quite interesting.
Have you thought about
the microbiology
of abscess flora?
Pus?
Well, you don't have
to commit to it right now.
Just explore it. Get back to me.
End of the week should be fine.
Check your data.
It's not working.
Your variable air
source is not on.
My air source.
You've never taken
physics before, have you?
You have?
Just introductory.
We don't have AP
Physics at Jefferson.
Jefferson High School?
Yeah. I want to be a doctor
or mechanical engineer.
What about you?
Um...
I'm not sure what I want to
be when I grow up, William.
My mom got her real
estate license at 40.
I helped her with her homework.
I can help you with
yours, if you want.
Sure. Thanks.
Tina Hargrove, eight
years old. Hit and run.
Out trick-or-treating with Dad.
Loss of consciousness
for ten minutes.
GSC 13, B.P. 130/80.
Multiple facial lacs
blunt trauma to the abdomen.
My stomach hurts.
Dad's on his way.
He got hit too.
Double trauma coming
in! We need the room, clear!
Suture room.
Gant, call radiology.
Get a head CT. And a C-spine.
All right everybody,
on my count.
Nice and gentle, here we go...
One, two, three.
CBC type and cross-match
five units.
Radiology's coming down.
All right, her abdomen is rigid.
Gant, what's the best
incision for an ex-lap?
Midline.
Ow! Please, it hurts.
BP's holding steady. 130/80.
Toes downgoing.
Which organs are injured most
in blunt abdominal trauma, Gant?
Spleen and liver.
My stomach still hurts. Please!
Where's my daddy?
Clear breath sounds.
Carter, get up here
and hold her hand.
What?
Hold her hand.
Stranger anxiety. Remember?
Calm her down.
Gant, check her reflexes.
Hi, Tina, I'm Dr. Carter.
Don't be scared, okay?
Don't be scared, cause we're
going to take such good care of you.
Tendon reflexes
two plus and equal.
Thank you, Dr. Gant.
Now, where the
hell is radiology?
High dose epi.
No pulse, no resps.
How long has he been down?
Paramedics said
almost a half hour.
That his daughter next door?
Yeah. Tina, eight years old.
Abdomen's distended,
probably bled out.
Let's give him a
few more minutes.
All right, I'm going
to check on the girl.
What causes left shoulder pain
in blunt abdominal trauma?
Blood irritating the diaphragm.
How's she doing?
She's stabilizing.
We need to hang
500 of Ancef and
get her up to CT.
Such enthusiasm, Gant, why don't you
run upstairs and tell them what she needs?
Now?
Well, if you're confident
you know what she needs.
Labs are back on Mrs.
Jennings. Not good.
What do you mean?
She tested positive
for Tricyclics.
What's her level?
800.
She's a suicide.
She must have
taken the whole bottle.
Is her husband here?
Not yet.
Give me an NG and 50
grams of activated charcoal.
Why? She's a no-code.
She tried to kill herself.
She has a fatal disease.
We resuscitate suicides.
She wanted to die.
All suicides.
Add an amp of Bicarb to her IV.
So you dressed
up like a cat, huh?
My dad made the costume.
Is he okay?
I'll check for you. Okay?
So, did you get a lot of good
trick-or-treating stuff?
My dad's got it
so I won't eat it all at once.
Uh-huh.
Ruptured spleen.
Could've injured her
kidney and bladder, too.
We'll get a CT and
explore her up in the ER.
Mark.
Carter, got a minute?
Uh, yeah.
Can't you stay with me?
Oh, they're going
to take some pictures
of your head and your tummy
and then I'll be
right there, okay?
Tell my dad where I am, okay?
Okay.
Is this the father?
You ever pronounce anyone?
No. I've called time of death.
The monitor shows
no electrical activity.
Check the pupils.
Fixed and dilated.
Feel for a pulse.
No palpable pulse.
Listen for a heartbeat.
Give it a minute.
That's it?
That's it.
Can I help you?
Oh, yeah. I'm Carol Hathaway.
I'm on tonight.
Gus Jackson, your pilot.
Did you bring the cookies?
Was I supposed to?
The patients kind
of expect them.
You got any valuables?
No.
Good. Make yourself at home.
Hey, hey, hey!
You're late.
Yeah, I know. Uh...
You bring the cookies?
What? The cookies?
Get in.
Yup. Yup.
Hey, Doug.
Hey, Carol.
I didn't know you
were on tonight.
Yeah, well, God
knows I tried not to be.
Okay, listen up.
A few things you should know.
If we come under fire
that back window pops out.
And if anyone tries to steal
anything, let them take it.
Remember to stay clear of...
Wait, wait. Bulletproof vest...
I'm supposed to wear this?
Remember to stay clear of
the cabinets while we're moving
and sit down.
Ah, this is great.
Mr. Jennings.
Yes?
I'm Jeanie Boulet.
This is Dr. Doyle.
Hello.
How is Sophie?
Is she all right?
She's in extremely
serious condition.
Has your wife been
depressed lately?
The past few months
Sophie's gotten so weak,
she can barely sit up now.
She won't talk to her friends.
I, uh, have to beg her to eat.
Does she take antidepressants?
They don't help anymore.
We found a significant
level in her blood and urine.
We think she attempted suicide.
I've been praying...
What to do, how
to help her... but...
She's been praying to die.
Oh!
Hey, Susan, welcome back.
Whoa. Dr. Lewis, how you doing?
Good.
Hi, Dr. Lewis.
Welcome back.
Thank you.
How are you?
What are you?
A kangaroo without
the head part.
Nice.
Susan, hi.
Oh, Mark.
Welcome back.
You look, uh...
Oh... I look wet,
but I feel great.
Susan, it's good
to have you back.
Thank you.
Mark, you signed up for
that asthma patient in four?
Do you mind if I...?
Your research study?
I'd really appreciate it.
Uh-huh.
Good week?
Ha-ha-ha.
Fractured her spleen.
Yeah, and ruptured
her left kidney.
Did you find my dad?
Is he coming to see me?
Shh-shh. Try not to
talk right now, okay?
Where am I going?
We're going to take
you in for an operation
to make you all better.
Please. I want my dad.
Is he okay?
Yeah, he's okay.
We'll talk about it
later though, all right?
Will you come see me?
Yeah, I will, but right now
try and relax and
get some sleep.
You're going to be fine.
I didn't know what to say.
I didn't want to upset
her before the surgery.
Patient should have
been told the truth.
Which could have
upset her to the extent
that we may have
had to delay surgery.
Good instincts, Carter.
Why don't you go on in
and look after her
till we're ready?
Okay.
Dr. Benton, I've got
a diaphragmatic hernia
scheduled in two hours.
Are you free?
Yeah.
Good, 'cause I have a conflict.
I promised some of
the children on the ward
I'd take them trick-or-treating.
Could you handle that for me?
Yeah. Yeah.
Great.
I can't believe
you never made it to Hawaii.
Turns out the fear of
flying cannot be conquered.
Man, when we landed in Phoenix
the attendants had to
carry me off the plane.
The thought of getting
on another plane
was unbearable.
Thanks. Anyway,
Phoenix was great.
Chloe's still sober
still working as a
claims adjuster...
Six months now... And
little Susie was fabulous.
You know, she just...
She made me laugh.
Anyway, how are you?
Ah, I don't want
to talk about it.
Pretty bad, actually.
Kerry's got Anspaugh
wrapped around her finger.
He went gaga over
her research project.
He wants me to do one on pus.
Pus?
Not to mention
the fact that he's
practically given her
the one and only tenure slot
so I have no career, no future.
You know...
Really, I... I don't want
to talk about it, okay?
Sure, Mark. Whatever.
So, you hungry?
You want to get
something to eat?
We can go over to Doc's.
Oh, gosh, I ate the
whole way home
on the train.
So, there's a Halloween
party tonight at the Jazz Note.
Thinking maybe
if you're not too tired...?
Oh.
Well...
Hey, the whole staff's going.
That sounds great.
Great.
Yikes.
Where did these come from?
Some drug rep was
giving them away.
Whoa.
Here you go.
This is helpful, right here.
Look at this.
You got your gauze,
you got your penicillin.
When was this stuff stocked?
Look at this.
1989?
Yeah, well, this healthmobile's
from Southside, remember?
Their budget's even
tighter than ours.
Whoa!
Do you get the feeling
he doesn't care about us?
Hey, Carol...
What are you doing
with a physics book
in your backpack?
It's not mine.
It's a friend's.
Yeah, you just borrowed it
for a little late night reading?
Very funny. Give it back.
Oh, man, look at this.
Doug! This is truly hateful.
I'm getting flashbacks.
You two ready?
Yes, thank you, we're ready.
Yeah.
Welcome to Gonorrhea land.
Ah, this is... truly depressing.
Yup. It's like county
on a slow night.
Here's your first customer.
Uh...
Come on in.
All right.
What seems to be the problem?
Where are the cookies?
Sir, if you could
just tell us...?
Where are the cookies?!
Is she in pain?
I don't think so.
First time in two years.
I love you, Sophie.
I love you.
This morning, she was different.
Smiling like she used to.
She wanted me
to comb her hair, help
her with some lipstick.
Then she looked
at me and said...
"I'm ready."
She begged me.
I counted them out,
crushed them up
put them in some milk.
I held the glass to her mouth.
She said, "I love you"
and the next thing you know...
She was asleep
and I got scared
called the ambulance.
Her whole life, she helped me.
I wasn't strong
enough to help her.
I can't lose her.
I can't.
Can I help you?
Uh, yeah, do you have
those, uh, animal things
that pediatricians use?
Oh. Pocket peek-a-boos.
Oh. Uh...
Well, maybe the beanbag bunnies.
Uh, we also have
dinosaur pencils.
Those are my favorites.
Brontosaurus,
Stegosaurus, Dimetrodon.
Just the paper.
So, Dr. Keaton got you
down here buying props, eh?
No, no, no. I'm just
down here looking around.
She sends down
all the residents who
don't much like kids.
I like kids.
Sure, you do.
We all like kids.
Bears are playing
Tampa Bay this weekend.
Hardly need to watch that one.
Tyrannosaurus Rex?
Debby, your lungs are clear.
Thank heavens.
I'm always so
worried about germs.
Don't I know you?
No, you don't.
You sure we haven't met?
Yep, I'm sure.
I know.
It was at the club 99, right?
Debby, you're done.
Got it?
I was just kidding around.
Anybody else out there?
Only about 20 or 30 more.
Ah! Oh, my god!
Oh, my God!
Please, help me!
Hang on! Hang on!
We're not equipped
for a stabbing.
Gus, call an ambulance!
Help me!
Oh, it hurts!
Give me some gauze.
Larger. Give me larger.
Trick or treat.
That's not funny.
Where's my treat?
You know, we're all out.
Can I get a couple condoms?
How old are you?
Eighteen.
18. Why don't you come
back when you're 15?
Screw it, my dates
don't like them anyway.
Hey, wait a minute.
What's your name?
Charlie.
Charlie, you
working the streets?
What do you think?
I think that you're
at risk for AIDS.
Charlie, where are you living?
In a penthouse on
Lake Shore Drive.
Hey.
Hey! Hey.
Here. You be careful
out there, all right?
Thanks, old man.
Little Susie was so cute.
She thinks the word
for cactus is "ouch"
so we'd go on a walk,
and she'd point everywhere
going, "Ouch, ouch, ouch!"
Jerry.
I've called
maintenance four times.
They're working on it.
Oh, maybe it's the
ghost up on the fifth floor.
Not you too.
It's a true story, Mark.
He's up there.
Poor guy... still pining away
for the woman he loved.
I thought he broke her heart.
Broke his own
heart is more like it.
And how do you know this?
Because that's the story.
It was Halloween night,
the 1930s, or something
up on the fifth floor.
There was rain and thunder
and lightning.
He was a doctor
she was an intern.
She loved him, didn't she?
But a really wealthy,
handsome patient
had fallen in love with her,
and asked her to marry him.
What did she say?
She didn't know what
to say, so she told the doctor.
What did he say?
He said nothing.
I thought he loved her.
He did love her but
he just stood there.
He couldn't get the words out.
And then, after she
walked across the room
she turned back
and looked at him.
She put her hand to her lips
and blew him what
would be their first
and only kiss.
They say it blew through him
like a rush of cold wind.
That is so sad.
Well, what happened?
Unfortunately, the doc
fell out the fifth floor window
so that's kind of it.
I'm sure they worked on
him in the OR for a while.
Hey, John, you seen Benton?
No, not for a couple of hours.
He's got me pulling
journal articles
on Dieulafuoy's lesions.
Dieula... what?
Never heard of it.
Here's your chance.
No, thanks.
Dr. Keaton?
Hi.
How's she doing?
Pretty well.
Pressure's 100/75.
Kidney is still working.
I'll stay with her until
she comes out of it.
I thought you had
a lot of discharges.
Oh, they're done.
Mostly.
Call me when she wakes up.
I need to tell her
about her father.
Dr. Keaton...
I think I need to tell
her about her father.
I'm saying it's none
of your business.
I'm just curious
you know, if you're thinking
about medical school.
You're done. It's just
a physics class, Doug,
which I doubt I'll
even make it through
much less go to medical school
which I'm not even
thinking about yet.
Hey Doc! We got a guy
staggering out here.
Help!
Help me!
Move, move, move!
Look out.
Hey, what is it?
Call 911. He's been stabbed.
Set up an IV.
Anybody see what happened here?
Did anybody see what happened?
Look out, Look out!
I couldn't find an angiocath,
but I got an 18-gauge needle.
Jab it into his antecubital vein
and tape his arm down.
Come on, buddy.
Okay, I'm in.
Tape this down.
What's going on?
We got company.
Okay, we're losing him.
I'll do a cutdown. Out here?
We got to get
more fluids in him.
You got a scalpel...
Anything sharp in there?
Uh, no.
Here. Use these.
All right.
Hey, doc.
Ambulance'll be
here in 15 minutes.
He's not going to
make it that long.
How fast will that thing go?
Faster than waiting
for the ambulance.
Let's do it. Come on.
Let's go.
Pick him up.
Mr. Jennings.
Mr. Jennings, I need to
turn off the monitor now.
Time of Death: 8:53.
Would you like to stay
with her for a while?
Thank you.
What I did...
I don't know if it
was right or wrong.
She was in a lot of pain.
Our whole marriage,
it-it was never
about giving up on life.
This is not who we were.
You stayed with her.
You helped her
when she needed you.
I think that's who you were.
I've got an ET tube, but I
can't find a laryngoscope.
All right, I'm going
to have to go in blind.
All right, Gus, you
made your point.
You want to get there
don't you?
All right. He's tubed.
Give me the ambu bag.
It's right here.
Hit it.
All right, we're in.
What are you doing?
I'm going to put
him in trendelenburg.
I'm having trouble.
What?
My ambu bag's got a leak.
I need some tape.
Thanks. Yeah.
Dr. Keaton asked me to tell you
the trick-or-treaters
are waiting.
All right. Thanks.
And I have the journal articles
when you want them.
Mm-hmm. You write
the post-op notes?
Yes.
Good. If you can, uh...
pull the drains on
the pyloroplasty.
Why are you riding me?
You're an intern.
I bust my ass
and you give me a
mediocre evaluation.
Well, most interns
do mediocre work.
I don't.
Well, you could do better.
So can Carter.
So can everyone.
Yeah, well, you
have to do better.
I have to do better.
Is that because I'm black?
Is that your message here?
Let me ask you something.
When you applied
to medical school,
did you check the box?
Did you check
"African-American"?
I worked as hard as
everyone else to get in here.
Well, that's not what
most people think.
They assume you checked the
box to get preferential treatment.
They assume you
exist to fill a quota.
Now, if you want
to prove them wrong
you have to work twice
as hard, stay twice as late
to be twice as good.
You think I need
you to tell me that?
Ah, well, so we understand
each other, so we don't
have a problem, now, do we?
Did you check the box?
No.
Maybe you should
just tell people.
That way, you won't
have to go around
and keep proving
it all the time.
Hi, there.
You stayed.
You did really well.
You're going to be fine.
I wanted to talk to you.
I have something
I need to tell you.
About my dad?
Yes.
He died, didn't he?
Is that it?
Yes.
What do we got?
Knife wound to the abdomen.
He's stabilized. Needs a lap.
Okay, let's get
him up to the OR.
Hey, how is it out there?
I'm going next week.
Oh, no big deal.
Real smooth, Malik.
Bring cookies.
Well, that's it.
All right. Have a
good night, Gus.
But, I'm not going
to say anything
about that physics book.
Oh, God, it was
probably a stupid idea.
Hey, if it's what
you want to do.
Look, if I can make
it, anybody can.
Thanks.
You going to the
Halloween party?
No. Can't make it.
I hear Haleh's really good.
Yeah, she is.
I heard her sing last Christmas.
That case with
Mr. Jennings today?
When I saw him watching her...
and holding her hand...
Kind of saw what their
whole life had been...
made me wish that
we could save her
just so that we could save him.
What do you mean?
He's alone, left
with all the pain.
She fell asleep in
her husband's arms.
I'll see you.
Dr. Greene, I'm going to
remind you one more time.
I'm on my way.
I'm going to take Susan
with me for protection.
Protection from what?
The ghost on the fifth floor.
Why do we have to go up there?
A guy corked off.
I have to pronounce him.
You're not scared, are you?
Of course not.
Mark?
Susan.
Oh, good. You're still there.
Where would I go?
Hey, hey, hey! Slow
down, Slow down.
All right. That's it.
That's it. Come on.
Come on. We're going back.
It's past your bedtimes,
anyway. Let's go.
Please can we go
to one more floor?
Yeah, one more floor.
Be a sport, Peter.
Yeah. Be a sport, Peter.
Nurse B'jerk would let us.
Bjerke. And yes, I would.
All right, all right.
Look. Let's...
We'll go to the ER,
but that's it, all right?
Mister, Mister!
What, what?
I have to pee bad.
Oh, man. All right.
The rest of you just hold hands
until I get back and
don't move okay?
What do you think
we are, babies?
Just-just don't move.
Come on.
Nyah, nyah, nyah, nyah!
We really have to do this now?
I guess we could
wait till daylight.
He'll only have been dead
about ten hours.
Oh, my!
Next bed, doctor.
Sorry.
You're not scared, huh?
Oh! Did you just feel that?
What?
You're going to think I'm crazy.
Feel what?
I swear to you, it was just like
a rush of wind went through me.
You are crazy.
Oh, boy!
Did you feel it?
No, I didn't feel anything.
Oh, boy!
You felt it, didn't you?
Dr. Carter...
Did you tell her?
She knew. She
said that her father
had been with her
during the surgery
and had kissed her good-bye.
Kids know.
It's as though their
parents' spirit joins them
and they just seem to know.
Yeah. I knew.
My brother died
of leukemia, and...
I was riding my bike
home from school one day
and I just knew
that he had died.
It was like he was with me.
I could feel him.
Maybe that's why
you're good with kids.
See you in the morning.
Hey! Where are those kids at?
What?
The kids!
I-I don't know where they went.
Hey! Come here! Come on!
How could you just let
them walk away like that?
I was doing some paper work.
I looked up and they
were gone, okay?
Check the ER.
I'll call upstairs.
I took my troubles
down to Madam Ruth
Ya know that gypsy
with the gold-capped tooth
She's got a storefront
at 34th and Vine
She sells little bottles of
Love potion number nine
I told her that I
was a flop with men
I've been this way...
Riyadh was like a bake oven.
Really sounds bad.
But, Norm, he'd mix
these desert cocktails...
Equal parts potassium,
sodium with a lemon chaser.
There she is, just sucking
up to him a little bit more.
Mark...
Disparaging me, belittling me
tightening her grip
on that tenure slot.
What's the problem?
She's making
everything so competitive.
You're a doctor;
you love competition.
You're just getting
a little obsessed.
I am not.
All right, a little
myopic, then.
What?
Your wife divorced you.
You hardly see Rachel.
This job is all you care about.
I just spent a week where no one
was stabbing anyone in the back.
I could just drop everything,
take a nice little
walk with Susie.
Big decision of the day was,
like, what to have for lunch.
There's other stuff
out there, Mark.
I know you don't have it now.
I just hate to see you
get so caught up in that.
Love potion number nine
He broke my little bottle...
What are you all
doing down here!
You said you
weren't going to move.
You found us, didn't you?
We could have really
lost you if we wanted to.
Yeah, well, come on.
Let's go back up to the ward.
Didn't you ever
go trick-or-treating?
Yes, I've gone
trick-or-treating.
What did you go as?
I don't know.
One time, I went as a scientist.
Bet no one gave you any candy.
Let me tell you something.
See, when I was your age
we used to have to
do tricks to get treats.
Bet you can't do one now.
Yeah! Do a trick! Do a trick!
Do a trick! Do a trick!
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Shut up, Shut up, all right?
Just one.
How was that?
That was it?
Hey. Sorry I'm late.
They say those trains
run every ten minutes
but I don't believe it.
You never change, do you, Al?
What?
One unbelievable
excuse after another.
Look, I said I'm sorry.
Of course, I never
changed, either.
"Just hang in there, Jeanie.
"Carry this
marriage by yourself.
"Don't think about
where he is tonight
who he's with tonight."
Jeanie, what's wrong?
Hmm...
A man came in today
and sat there and
watched his wife die...
and he helped her to die
because she was in so
much pain, and he loved her.
But we didn't have
that kind of marriage,
did we, Al?
We didn't love,
we didn't cherish
we didn't respect
and now, you've killed me.
This drink is strong.
I think I should've
eaten something, maybe.
Yeah, we should've grabbed
something before this.
Yeah.
You want to...?
Go ahead.
You're probably too tired
after your trip to dance.
Well, kind of, but...
So maybe later.
I guess I'm up for it.
I'll sing to him
Each spring to him
And long for the day
When I cling to him
Bewitched
Bothered and bewildered
Am I
Oh, bewitched,
bothered and bewildered...