♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
Hello.
Oh.
What I'm saying is,
open adoptions are negotiable.
It's just a matter of deciding
what makes
each of you comfortable.
Well, whatever judi needs...
I'm gonna be really busy
with school, so...
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. Go ahead.
No, I was
just going to say,
I am so grateful to you,
judi,
so whatever you need
to feel comfortable...
I feel comfortable.
I-I mean, it's...
Um...
I don't know. I'm sorry.
Mildred, is there
some sort of model for this?
I mean, what do people
usually do?
I-I want judi to be
a part of Henry's life
if she wants to be.
Um, I'd like him to know
where he comes from.
But, uh, maybe some guidelines
would be helpful.
Sure.
A common setup is
weekly photos, monthly visits.
Judi?
Sure.
Yeah, okay.
This is an open adoption.
I have to be open,
and I don't feel open.
I feel like I wanna...
Take Henry and run.
I mean,
what if she hates me?
What if she thinks
I'm doing a terrible job?
That's not gonna happen.
Yeah? Well, then
why did she come now?
I mean, no visits
in eight months.
No replies
to any of my e-mails.
Why now?
Well, maybe it's taken her
this long
to wrap her head
around all this.
I mean, she did have a baby
and give him away.
Oh, so you're saying
not everything's about me?
A little bit,
that's what I'm saying.
But only if it makes you
feel better.
It does.
Thank you.
Okay, Henry.
Let's go meet
the lady who made you.
Hmm?
Judi.
Hi. Um, I-I brought a...
Wow.
He is advanced in all milestones
except peekaboo,
but we'll get there.
And he loves, uh, tigger
and mashed carrots.
I mean, well,
all things orange.
He's so big.
Yeah, not too big,
though.
I mean, he's a fat baby,
but in a healthy
fat baby way,
not in a bad fat baby way.
You know, he's good.
I'm doing a good job.
I'm...
Talking too much.
Um...
Would you mind
if I held him?
Of course.
Um...
Hi. Hi.
Hi, Henry.
Hey, remember me?
I'm...
I'm judi.
Yeah. Hi.
Yeah.
Okay, Henry.
Look over here.
Look at tigger.
Wave to tigger, honey.
That's a good boy.
Oh, honey, I gotta get
a new memory card.
It'll just take a minute.
Okay.
Oh. Did you, um,
want to give him the bunny?
What?
I noticed you brought
the stuffed animal.
Did you want to give it
to him?
Oh, yeah. Um... no.
It kinda seems like
he's got everything he needs.
Thank you for saying that.
I was, um...
I was really nervous
before you got here.
Why? Um, you're the most
together person I've ever met.
I... I just think
you wanting to see him,
it just, um...
It surprised me, you know?
I mean, you haven't shown
much interest until now.
I mean, I sent you photos,
you didn't reply.
And you haven't scheduled
any visits until now.
I'm just...
I don't know.
I'm just wondering what...
What changed.
I don't open
most of your e-mails.
It's not that
I'm not interested, but, um,
I don't know. It--
it's been hard.
Oh. Oh.
You know that thing
where you're afraid
you forgot something?
I-I mean,
you do other stuff,
but all you can think about
is that you forgot something.
Yeah. I hate that feeling.
Since I gave Henry
to you,
I-I feel like that...
All the time.
I mean, e-except now.
Just seeing him
and how well he's doing...
I don't know.
The feeling's gone right now.
Well, I can
send you photos every day,
and you really can schedule
monthly visits.
I'm still open to that.
Yeah.
That would be cool.
But, um, I was hoping,
if it's not too much
or whatever,
maybe I could see Henry
again sooner?
Like tomorrow?
Sure.
Wait.
So she hasn't visited
in eight months,
and now she wants to visit
two days in a row?
It's too much,
and she knows it.
Is judi regretting
her decision to put Henry
up for adoption?
I didn't get that impression.
Well, maybe seeing
that her child's well cared for
will actually help her
move on.
The point of open adoption
is not for the birth mother
to move on.
The point is
to have the birth mother
involved in the child's life,
which... can be
a powerful thing.
It's a douchey thing.
Cooper.
You don't give a kid up
and then hang around
confusing everybody.
I mean, I can't imagine
what that would've been like.
Just because
you can't imagine it
doesn't mean
that it's an invalid choice.
Is anybody else here
adopted that they know of?
No? Okay. Then I get more say
than any of you people.
And I say it's douchey.
Addison, move to Burbank.
Sell the house, disappear.
Henry doesn't need
this kind of confusion.
Judi's presence
could be beneficial to Henry.
If he knows her,
he won't have fantasies
that his birth mother is a spy
or a queen or a supermodel.
Those sound like
your fantasies.
The point is, if we remove
the element of mystery,
Henry won't have any illusions
that judi would've made him
a better life
than the one he has now.
What if the birth mother
is a bad influence?
Well,
that's relatively rare.
These women tend to be
selfless,
envisioning a future
for their baby
that they are
unable to provide.
They also tend to have goals
that are incompatible
with premature parenthood.
Premature parenthood?
Is that a thing?
It is now.
Oh.
The arrangement can be
good for everyone involved,
provided adequate boundaries
are set.
Oh,
that can be tough, though.
If judi's around all the time,
she might start weighing in
on parenting decisions.
It's not about weighing
in on parenting decisions.
It's about making sure
that everyone
in the adoption triad is...
Addison.
Sweetheart.
I'm his mom.
I just want to be his mom.
Dr. Carlsmith,
I'm Dr. Peterson.
I understand you're having
some abdominal discomfort.
In the right upper quadrant.
Start an I.V.
It could be a few things.
It could be,
but it's not.
I have gastric cancer.
Okay.
Let me see what's going on.
Where'd you go to school?
U.s.c. Residency
and fellowship.
Med school at Stanford.
Thank goodness.
I was afraid you'd say
one of those quack schools.
My first day,
my first E.R. rotation,
a woman in labor
presented in frank breech.
I had just read your paper
on the external cephalic
version technique.
Mm.
The description was so clear,
I performed it flawlessly.
Hmm.
I saved her life
and then the baby's.
Sounds like you got lucky.
With your help.
Ohh!
Fentanyl, 50 I.V.
And let's get
an abdominal C.T.
Vivian, is there someone
we can call for you,
someone who can be here
with you?
No, no.
No need to call anyone.
I don't want to be
a bother.
Okay, just give me a call
when she's at 7 centimeters.
Now we take it all
for granted,
but at the time,
there was no treatment.
She's the one who actually
came up with the idea
to put the temporary plug
in the fetal trachea.
Are you talking about
Dr. Vivian carlsmith?
Yeah.
She's in the E.R.
I'm going to admit you.
Oh, I've already spent too much
of my life in hospitals.
Yeah, but we have
really good pudding.
Vivian.
Addison.
Sorry, Addison.
The chart didn't indicate
you're her doctor.
Oh! No, I'm not.
She's my friend,
my mentor.
Oh, that word
makes me feel old.
Oh, no. She taught me
everything I know.
Why are you in the E.R.?
What are you doing in L.A.?
I'm fine.
U.c.l.a. Hired me as a part
of their guest lecture series.
And I thought you were still
in Seattle
with Derek and Richard.
Yeah, well, I took a page
out of your book
and decided to move
to a warmer climate.
Mm.
I just, you know,
didn't wait until I retired,
that's all.
The pupil surpasses
the teacher.
Oh.
Can you give her something?
Already did.
Another 50 fentanyl I.V.
Okay, Vivian,
what's going on?
You tell me.
Acute abdominal pain,
nausea, bloating--
you want me to play
find the diagnosis now?
Mm.
All right, fine. Uh...
Choleocystitis?
Pancreatitis?
Wrong,
but in fairness,
I left something out.
Family history
of c-h-1 mutation.
Gastrocarcinoma.
You always were
my smartest student.
This can't be right.
When's the last time
you saw her?
Too... long ago.
What's your treatment plan?
I ordered an abdominal C.T.
And I'll admit her
for pain management.
Good. That's good.
But my fear
is that her symptoms mean
the cancer has metastasized
to the liver.
It's an easy diagnosis to miss,
and it's almost never caught
in time.
She said she didn't want
to be a bother,
but she really should have
family here.
All she had was a sister,
and she died years ago.
There's no one left.
Dr. Peterson!
What happened?
She was upstairs in p.T.
She tried to walk
and she fell, hit her head.
Mommy, it hurts.
I know, baby. I know.
It's gonna be okay.
What's your name, sweetie?
Gwen.
I'm Dr. James,
and we're gonna fix that
right up, okay? I promise.
You did this.
This is your fault.
I-I'm sorry?
You don't even recognize me,
do you?
Sean patruchi.
Eight years ago...
Right.
In utero surgery--
spina bifida. I'm sorry.
It just took me a minute.
You said my baby
would be okay,
promised me
she'd have a good life.
You lied.
Listen to me.
I can see you're upset--
don't patronize me.
I have been through hell
since Gwen was born.
You were my doctor.
You should've...
You should've told me
to have an abortion.
I should've had
an abortion.
Well, what about
family names?
If there's a girl,
I like Marjorie.
Yeah, but--
but Marjorie's
not a family name.
That's the name
of your horse.
Whom I loved more than
either of my brothers.
Any good grandparent names?
Walter, Miriam, Irving,
and Rivka?
It's too waspy, though,
right?
Mm.
I feel bad for Addison.
It cannot be easy
with Henry's birth mom
coming around all the time.
It's hard enough for us
to make parenting decisions,
and we chose each other.
Right?
I mean, if you make
the honorable decision
to give up your child
so they can have a better life,
then you need to back off
and let them have that life.
That's a little harsh.
Everybody's needs
are different.
Okay, you're right,
but, like, I've imagined what it
would be like if, you know,
one day my birth mother
just knocked on the door...
You are curious about her.
Well, yeah,
of course I am,
but nobody gives up a child
unless they're in crisis.
So who am I to go
and... try and find her?
I mean, what if that made
her life worse?
I've had an amazing life,
and she's responsible,
so I want my birth mother
to have a good life, too.
You were adopted?
Yeah.
Yeah, I w--i was.
The woman
who gave birth to me
couldn't take care of me--
well, I-I know
what adopted is.
What's her name?
I don't know. I don't know
anything about her.
Nothing?
Nope.
I don't want to be late
for school. Are you ready?
Yeah.
Let's go.
He's beautiful.
He's perfect, right?
I know you went
back and forth about it,
but I always suspected
you'd decide to have children.
You didn't go for that
natural birth malarkey, did you?
Actually,
I didn't deliver.
I mean, technically, I did,
I guess.
I was the o.B. On the case.
But the birth mother--judi--
is the one who actually
pushed him out.
I... I adopted Henry.
You did?
Yes, I did. Actually, judi
came to visit us yesterday.
Wait. The birth mother
visited you?
Why?
I don't know.
I mean, I hadn't heard
from her in months.
I thought I would,
but I didn't.
And then yesterday,
she wanted to visit.
It w--i--it was...
It was actually okay.
I don't understand.
She wanted to see Henry,
and you let her?
Yeah, it's part of
our adoption agreement.
To hold a child
you gave up...
Are you okay?
To know
your baby is safe...
Vivian, are you all right?
I can't. I...
I've never told anyone.
Well, you can tell me.
What is it?
In 1954, I had a baby.
I was 15.
I never got to hold her.
The nuns gave her
to a catholic family.
I had a baby,
and they took her away
from me.
Sam, when is your TV show
gonna be on the air?
Oh, it's just a pilot, so...
They have to decide on...
Things.
Damn. I was excited to start
calling you the situation.
Excuse me.
I'm looking for
a Dr. Addison Forbes Montgomery.
Oh, that's me.
You've been served.
What is it?
I'm being sued
by my former patient--
Sean patruchi--
for wrongful birth
of her daughter.
What does that mean?
It means the patient believes
her baby shouldn't exist.
Yeah, but she's not a baby.
Gwen is 7 years old.
What's wrong with her?
When Sean was pregnant,
I diagnosed Gwen, her baby,
with spina bifida.
I gave her options
and I recommended fetal surgery.
Well, it was a cutting-edge
procedure at the time.
It's not a surprise
if that wasn't a success.
No, it worked.
She just hit her head in p.T.
She's starting to walk.
That's a miracle.
Apparently
not miracle enough.
No, I ran into Sean
yesterday in the E.R.
She flipped out on me
and she said she wanted
a normal life for her daughter
and because she didn't get it,
she thinks I should've
advised her to abort.
Well, some parents
are not equipped
to care for
a less-than-perfect child.
I've read lots of blogs
by moms whose babies
are less than perfect.
The majority believe that
parenting a special needs child
is--is a blessing.
All of us are less than perfect.
People just want guarantees.
That's why they have
the genetic screening
and the prenatal testing.
Those tests are done
before birth,
and sometimes
even before conception.
This child is 7 years old?
You know,
none of this is new.
I mean, the ancient romans
left their disabled kids out
for the wolves to eat.
Oh.
What?
I said the blessing thing.
Who cares
if a kid can't walk?
Neither can Stephen Hawking
or Itzhak perlman.
Never stopped them
from being an overachiever.
How does a mother say
her own child's life
is not worth living?
I mean, how do you say that
about any life?
It would be one thing
if I had done something wrong
or made a mistake,
but I didn't.
I helped her.
You did.
You gave her a child.
It's not your fault she
can't handle being a mother.
Wee! Yeah.
You're having a swing,
aren't you?
Wee.
Oh, Henry.
Look at him smiling.
Addison.
My god.
Hi.
Um, I hope you don't mind,
but I-I brought someone.
Addison, Jake, this is Donna.
She's my, um--
I'm Henry's grandmother.
God, judi. He looks
exactly like you.
Just exactly like you.
It's like going back
in time.
I hope this is okay.
Maybe I should've mentioned--
You definitely
should've mentioned--
no, no, it's okay.
I mean... I'm fine.
I'm just a little surprised,
that's all.
Sweetie,
that makes two of us.
Believe me, I never thought
I'd be the mother
who didn't know
her kid was pregnant.
We didn't talk
for almost a year
because she didn't like
my boyfriend.
That wasn't why.
Mom.
Please.
You two, you're adults.
You think a kid should
disappear from her mom's life
and fail to mention
she'd had a baby
because of a disagreement?
It was more
than a disagreement.
Would you mind?
Could I hold my grandson?
Hi.
Judi, is this why
you wanted to see Henry
after such a long time,
because you wanted
your mother to meet him?
No, no.
Or yes.
I don't know.
Look, I wanted to see him.
Every day,
I wanted to see him.
But after mom and I made up
and I told her,
I guess how bad she wanted
to see him
gave me the courage
to call.
I wish
you could've come to me.
If you had just told me...
Gin.
Are you cheating?
In my day, E.R. docs
were better losers.
Your deal.
You said best of three,
then we could talk about
your test results.
Another hand.
The cancer has spread...
To your liver.
We need to talk about--
we don't, actually.
You're going to tell me
the cancer is stage iv,
which means
I should die soon, right?
Yes.
But I've been a doctor
longer than you've been alive.
And I know sometimes,
greater forces are at work.
Are you talking about faith?
I'm saying,
I'm a crotchety old broad
and I don't accept
your diagnosis.
I'm not even
your patient anymore.
Don't you have traumas
to deal with?
It's my day off, and i'm
partial to crotchety old broads.
Then deal, and let's
make it interesting.
A buck a point.
Don't do it.
Do what?
You're going to stare
at Henry
so that he can
make you feel better.
He's a baby. Babies need
to be checked on.
He's a sleeping baby,
and sleeping babies
need to be left alone.
All right.
Okay, so which thing is it?
Because no person
in your situation
would be able to sleep
right now.
Did you see how Donna
went after judi
right in front of us?
And then she--she referred to
herself as Henry's grandmother.
It doesn't matter
what she calls herself.
You're his mother.
You're damn right I am.
And I would do anything
for my boy.
I'd walk through fire.
I would give up all my limbs--
every limb.
And why,
why the hell didn't...
I stay in better touch
with Vivian?
It wouldn't change
her diagnosis.
You don't know that.
Wait. You can cure cancer?
That--that's awesome.
Oh, shut up.
Everyone just wants me to be--
why...
Is this happening to me?
I mean, why is all of this
happening to me?
My--my lawyer says that
we can't win in court
so I should go into mediation
and act contrite
so we can settle.
She can't even speak
in mediation.
Not that she would get
a word in edgewise.
Okay, but no, I just--
it's too much, Jake. Okay?
I can't lose my son
and I can't have Vivian die
and I cannot settle
for millions
when I haven't done
anything wrong.
You will not lose your son,
Vivian will die someday--
we all will--
and you didn't
do anything wrong.
But as doctors, we have
a tendency to go in fighting,
and if we just opened ourselves
up to hearing the other side,
then the--the amount of money
in lawsuits,
the level of hostility,
it--it might all change.
I didn't do anything wrong.
No, you didn't,
but regardless,
if there were a way
to make Gwen's life easier,
wouldn't you do it?
Because you're not just
a doctor, Addison.
You're a mother, a mother
who would walk through fire
and give up her limbs.
But maybe, just maybe,
so is Sean.
You lost?
E.R.'s on the first floor.
Actually,
I was looking for you.
I have
a 74-year-old patient,
stage iv gastric cancer.
She's been on fentanyl,
but it's not enough.
What do you think about
spinal cord stimulation
or intrathecal pain pumps?
I think they're both terrific
options for pain management.
Great. Well--
but not for
a 74-year-old woman
with stage iv gastric cancer.
Surgically implanting
a device at this point,
it's too invasive.
She might not survive
the procedure.
Yeah, I figured
it was a long shot.
This a relative of yours?
Never met her
before yesterday,
but she's just
one of those patients.
I don't know.
I just wanted to help.
Anyway, thanks.
How long does she have?
Could be hours.
Could be weeks.
Maybe a month.
Not more.
But she doesn't have
an advanced directive,
won't consider hospice.
You know her, so I figured
maybe you could get her
to stop being so stubborn.
Sorry.
Um... I need
to talk to you
if that's all right.
I'll catch up with you later.
James.
Thanks.
It is not all right.
You can't do this.
What?
You can't show up
at my work.
You cannot ambush me
with your mother.
You are not a child.
You made a choice.
And I will always be grateful,
but you have to stop now.
Stop ambushing me
or I will disappear.
I will pack up Henry,
and I will move,
and I swear to god,
you will never even see
a picture of my son.
I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry. I d--
I didn't realize...
I was just
coming here to say
that I can't
see Henry anymore.
It's too hard
and it hurts too much.
So...
I just--
I wanted to say thank you.
You're a great mom.
You're a great person.
And...
And I'm sorry.
I won't bother you again.
My job as mediator is
to facilitate a conversation
between the two of you.
I'll start with questions,
okay?
Addison, how many in utero
spina bifida surgeries
do you do in a year?
A handful.
Five, sometimes more.
Please explain to Sean why you
believed, with your treatment,
Gwen would be able to walk.
By repairing the spinal column
while the fetus is gestating,
you increase the likelihood
of muscle tone developing
in the lower extremities.
And judging by Gwen's chart,
it looks like
she's starting to walk.
She hoists herself up
out of her wheelchair
with her arms,
hovers for five minutes,
and falls back
into her chair exhausted.
I don't know what that is,
but it's not walking.
Sean, by suing Addison
for the wrongful birth of
your child,
you're saying that
if you had understood
Gwen would never be
completely ambulatory,
you would have terminated
your pregnancy.
Is that correct?
It's not just the walking.
Gwen will never have
a normal life
because you lied to me.
I did my job.
You're not happy with the way
your life turned out,
and you're looking
for someone to blame.
You are to blame.
You didn't prepare us
for this reality.
I know you didn't prepare us
because my husband left
before Gwen was 2.
He wasn't prepared.
I wasn't prepared.
And now I have spent
every day of my life
since Gwen was born
caring for her,
feeding her, clothing her,
wiping her.
And I will spend every day
of my life doing that
until I die or she dies.
You begged me to save
your daughter, and I did.
Taking care of your child,
dealing with pain
and disappointment,
being afraid every second,
every day--
that is motherhood.
I didn't think it was my job
to explain that to you,
but clearly,
you don't have a clue,
because no mother
could come here and do this.
No mother could ever say that
her child shouldn't exist.
You will not
call me a bad mother.
make me into a villain
because you are the one
who is heartless.
And when I take your ass
to court,
the jury will agree.
You're a dear.
How's your pain level
today?
How was mediation?
You're deflecting.
In fact, I am.
Well, I attempted to
play nice and hold my tongue,
but the truth is,
I didn't make a mistake,
and the woman who's suing me
is a bitch,
and I don't feel like
listening to her
complain about
her life anymore.
Why is it nowadays
everyone thinks
people need to understand
their emotions?
Everyone has so many feelings.
It's absurd.
Aw.
I've worked my whole life
to become a great doctor,
and now my reputation's
being threatened.
And what's even worse,
there's only a few people
who do what I do.
So if I can't
practice medicine,
there will
literally be babies...
That won't get saved.
I know
that sounds egotistical--
oh, don't you ever backpedal
your ego with me, missy.
You're my student.
You deserve every bit
of that pride.
Vivian...
It's time to put
your affairs in order.
You know that, right?
Did judi end up
coming back?
You're deflecting again.
Yes, she did, and she brought
a surprise guest--
her mother.
That must have been
uncomfortable.
I think
it was harder for judi.
I don't think her mother
approves of her giving Henry up.
Mothers try to protect
their children.
But sometimes in the process,
they do a lot of damage.
What did your mother do?
Before you leave
the maternity home,
they let you hold your baby
for 30 minutes to say good-bye.
Everything I'd know
about my daughter,
everything she'd know
about me...
Would come
in that 30 minutes.
I practiced
what I'd say to her
while I crocheted
a pair of baby booties.
But... before
they brought her in,
my mother showed up
to take me home.
And when sister Jo
brought my baby...
My mother
sent them both away.
I wanted to hold my baby.
I wanted to be her mother.
But what kind of life
would I have been able
to give her anyway?
Medicine...
That became my life's work,
and looking after
a few special students,
like you.
Did you ever forgive
your mother?
She did what she thought
was best for me.
The truth is,
I had to thank her.
I was the only female surgeon
in my class.
The male residents
just tortured me.
But it rolled off
my back.
After your mother
calls you a whore,
nothing else hurts.
Oh, where did you find...
The strength?
We're women, honey.
The strength finds us.
What are you doing here?
I just want to talk.
I am done talking to you.
She's a fighter.
She's been working on
taking her first step
for over a year.
Sean, there's no way
you would've terminated.
I went back
and looked at your chart.
You'd been trying for years.
Three rounds of I.V.F.
With no luck
until you and your husband
quit trying,
and then
the miracle happened.
You got pregnant.
There's no way
you would've had an abortion.
Do you have kids?
Yes.
Do they have special needs?
No, but--
you're a wealthy doctor
with a perfect child.
You don't get to judge me.
But you are judging me.
You're putting my life
on trial.
You're trying to
take me down for money
when you know
I didn't make a mistake.
What do you want from me?
I have to take care of her.
I got laid off.
The hospital where I work
cut the social worker staff,
and I got laid off.
Something has gotta give for me
to be able to make ends meet,
and it cannot be
her medical care
or rent or food.
Look at her.
She's amazing.
And of course I don't
regret having her.
What else can I do?
Someday Gwen's gonna find out
where that money came from,
and it will destroy her.
Look, mommy. Look!
I'm walking, mommy.
You are, baby!
You are.
I am so proud of you.
Oh, my god.
That is better than sex.
Okay, I'm gonna pretend
you didn't say that.
Okay.
I figured it out.
Remember that time
we went sailing
and you didn't get seasick?
Mm-hmm.
And on the beach,
found this Rose quartz?
Mm-hmm.
It's basically treasure.
Your parents are pirates.
Jewish pirates?
Maybe not even Jewish.
I was adopted through
a Jewish agency.
I'm Jewish.
But if we found
your real parents,
we could vacationing
on their--
okay, I gr--i grew up
with my real parents.
I think what you meant
is they're my biological--
you have more.
I mean, how could you
not want to meet them?
Okay, Mason.
Some questions, even when they
come from just being curious,
they can be hurtful.
You need to think about
the person you're asking
and how it might
affect 'em.
I'm sorry, dad.
I wasn't trying to be mean.
I know, sweetie.
It's just, all those years
I spent with mom
and nobody else.
I wondered about you.
I get that. I do.
And it's not like I haven't
wondered about my birth mother.
Of course I have.
I even made up
a life for her, too.
She's happily married,
she's got three kids,
she teaches third grade
in a suburb of Dayton.
Look, there's a lot of people
who were adopted
who want to find
their biological parents.
It just...
It was never me.
To me, my parents are the ones
who checked my homework
and stayed up with me
when I was sick
and made me feel like
I was the most important thing
in the world to them.
They're my family,
like Charlotte
is family to you.
Blood doesn't make a family.
Love does.
That makes sense.
But can we still
get the triplets
their own pirate hats?
Vitals aren't so good,
are they?
They're fine.
You need to become
a better liar.
Do you have a wife?
I haven't found
the lucky girl yet.
If only I were
40 years younger.
I was a real beauty
back then.
You still are.
No flirting
with the patients.
Don't listen to her.
I'm not easily discouraged.
I'll check on you later,
okay?
Did you find the stationery?
Mission accomplished.
I need you
to write me a letter.
Okay.
Use your best penmanship.
Make it legible.
All right.
No messy doctor scribble.
To my beloved daughter...
♪ in my bed,
I hear... ♪
In my mind,
I call you Maxine.
But the truth is,
even though
I gave birth to you...
Push. Good.
I do not know
the name you answered to
all of your life.
Good.
I've spent hours listening...
For the sound of your voice.
♪ To warm nights ♪
But I would not be able
to pick you out of a crowd.
Birth mother went through
the book
of prospective mothers,
chose you,
wants to see you.
Uh...
Okay.
You want to comb your hair
or do you want a baby?
♪ You picture me ♪
♪ I'm walking ♪
♪ too far ahead ♪
♪ you're calling... ♪
Do you want to hold him?
I do not wish to burden you
with the details
of my pregnancy
or the sadness I felt
in losing my right
to parent you.
♪ Go slow ♪
♪ I fall behind ♪
You are gonna have
an amazing life.
♪ The second hand... ♪
Okay.
I'm ready now.
♪ If you're lost,
you can look ♪
♪ and you will find me ♪
♪ time after time ♪
♪ if you fall,
I will catch you ♪
♪ I'll be waiting ♪
♪ time after time ♪
I hope and pray
you never felt abandoned by me.
♪ I will be waiting ♪
But I want you to know,
there was not one moment
of one day or night
that I did not think of you
and feel love for you.
Though I did not raise you,
in my heart,
I was always there with you.
You didn't have one mother.
You had two.
♪ Watching through... ♪
All of my love,
your other mother...
Vivian carlsmith.
I have no idea
where she is.
And I won't live long enough
to find her.
Will you do it for me?
Yes.
And give her the letter.
I will.
♪ And you will find me ♪
I promise.
♪ Time after time ♪
♪ time after ♪
♪ time ♪
Thank you.
Hey.
Um...
What are you doing here?
I'm not really sure,
exactly.
I read, uh,
when you adopt a baby,
you're supposed to give
the birth mother something.
Not... that I could ever
give you anything that compares
to what you gave me.
But I, um...
I got you this.
I mean, I don't even...
Do you even like gold?
Uh, should I have
gotten you silver?
No. I like it.
I-I do.
Please don't stop
seeing Henry.
Henry shouldn't be
around me.
When he's old enough
to understand what I did,
he'll hate me.
No, he won't.
He couldn't.
What you did was put
his welfare above your own,
because that's
what a mother does.
I'm not his mother.
You are.
No, that's what
I'm trying to say.
We both are.
You, Henry, and I,
we're connected now.
We're family.
And I get that it's hard,
and if you need a break,
that's okay.
Or if it's just too much,
But you need to know,
you have to know,
that you will always
be welcome in his home,
in our home.
Um...
My break
is in ten minutes...
And the blueberry pie here
is really good.
Maybe if you ordered
two pieces, we could--
I'd love that.
I'm glad you both
reconsidered mediation.
I think if you try to truly
listen to one another--
I want to settle.
What?
Let's stop all this.
Pick a number,
and I'll pay it.
But why would you--
Gwen needs to be
taken care of.
What you've been through--
I can't change what happened,
but I can help.
Let me help.
I can't.
No, it's okay.
Talk to your lawyer,
and I'll make it work.
No, you don't understand.
You were right.
Gwen can never think
I didn't want her.
And if go th--
You didn't do anything wrong.
I can't take your money.
When?
About an hour ago.
I texted you.
I was in mediation.
I'm sorry, Addison.
Thank you.
She had that light
inside of her that...
Made you want to catch
every word she said.
My grandmother had that.
She used to wake up
every morning
and wave up at the sky
and say good morning to the sun,
fed the rabbits table scraps.
Drove my grandfather nuts
'cause they tore up the garden.
She died of cancer, too.
I wish I'd gotten to spend
more time with my grandmother
when she was dying.
But I was in med school.
You know how it is,
always putting medicine first.
You save lives.
You allow family
more time with their loved ones.
You made a sacrifice
for the greater good.
♪ But I never thought... ♪
Anyway...
That's what Vivian
would have said.
♪ Sail ♪
♪ to me ♪
♪ oh, mama ♪
♪ sail ♪
Hey.
I got the resume you left.
Good.
Interesting candidate--
Sean patruchi.
She's extremely qualified.
You know what else
is interesting?
We haven't had an opening
for a social worker
since the last set
of budget cuts.
And then I get Sean's resume.
And what do you know?
An hour later,
the board informed me
we've been given
a substantial endowment
earmarked
for just that purpose.
Well, then I guess
my timing was good.
Uncanny.
I'll make sure her resume
is at the top of the list.
♪ No more time for coffees ♪
Ladies and gentlemen,
we are now beginning
our initial descent
into the Portland area.
Please make sure that
your seatbacks and tray tables
are in the fully upright
and locked position.
♪ And his lit cigarette ♪
Get it! Get it!
♪ No more time for teas
or regrets ♪
Oh, well, thank you for coming.
I'm very interested.
♪ All your memories just set ♪
♪ my whole damn world on fire ♪
♪ oh, mama, sail ♪
♪ to me ♪
♪ oh, mama ♪
♪ sail ♪
♪ to me ♪
♪ across this great wide sea ♪
But the thing
that never made sense to me
is calling golf a sport.
Sure, it's a skill,
but golfers aren't athletes.
Now basketball players,
that's a different story, right?
Because you run up and down
the court for 48 minutes...
You're an athlete.
Hmm?
Hey, sweetheart.
I didn't hear you come in.
Hi.
Hey.
Mmm.
Hi. Hi, Henry.
Mama's home.
So how did it go, huh,
with, uh, Vivian's daughter?
Good. Uh...
You know,
she invited me inside,
and we talked about Vivian.
She's led a full...
Rich life
with a big family.
I just wish that Vivian
would've known that.
Mm. Hey, you hungry
for dinner?
I got pizza.
Oh, do I have spit-up
on my face or something?
What?
I love you.
And you're the last man
I want to say that to.
Let's get married.