Who picked this dump?
You suggested it.
I suggested you look into it.
The online reviews...
were obviously written by some geek
in their own marketing department.
Next time, call someone you know.
Stop relying on a computer
to do your job for you.
Brightsize apparel, eight sexual
harassment suits in two years.
- Who asked for the meeting?
- They did.
Patty Michener,
president of Women's Majority, and...
Do you guys need me!
Nine men.
No one thought it might be
a good idea to put a suit on
one of the gals from the steno pool
to make it look like you give a damn?
We've made it a priority
to promote more women, but...
Well, from now
on you have me standing beside you,
which is good.
Because your problem
is a national problem.
With all due respect, miss Michener,
I'd hardly call a few isolated incidents
a national problem.
Six out of ten victims
never even report harassment.
This is bigger than just eight women.
- That still only means 20.
- Not enough for you?
How many asses does your corporate
policy allow you to grab?
Tell you what you're gonna do.
You're gonna settle with anyone
you haven't settled with.
You're gonna fire any man
who's even been accused.
Somebody help me!
Please help me. I can't get 'em off!
Please help me!
Help me, please!
Somebody help me!
Get 'em off.
You gonna call an ambulance, or
are you just gonna sit there and stare?
Help me, please!
House - Season 05 Episode 01
"Dying Change Everything"
Synchro: ShalimarFox, mpm, Icefreak
www.house-fr.com
Wilson's back.
- You gonna...
- He's been gone two months.
He can wait till I finish slaying a guy
in a skullcap and a pair of tights.
On a video game you stole
from the pediatric ward?
On advice of counsel, I assert
my privilege pursuant to the fifth.
When was the last time
you talked to him?
I think it was after...
When did his girlfriend die?
He wanted time alone.
I considered being a horrendous
pain in the ass,
but I didn't want to tread on your turf.
We got a case.
I've gotta remember to close the blinds.
Just got a call from Patty Michener
From Women's Majority, the women's...
- We know who she is.
- I dated her.
Well, not really dated her, more
metaphorically raped her
by having a penis.
You did too.
Her assistant flipped out.
Ripped off her clothes
in front of a room full of businessmen.
Well, either she cracked under the whip,
or she started to realize that her
evolutionary purpose is to arouse men,
not to castrate them.
Send her to psychiatric.
Anemia, bradycardia, and abdominal pain
aren't psychiatric symptoms.
Then it's the latter.
Send her to my apartment.
I'll give it to Segal.
House actually wants a case,
and you're saying no?
House has more important things to do.
Sorry, can't help you.
You need a specialist
to remove those kind of warts.
Preferably one
with experience spelunking.
Hallucinations, possible memory loss.
Tests show anemia, slow heart rate,
and a stubborn refusal
to shave her pits.
- Have you seen Wilson?
- Nope.
But I have seen the patient's
frequent flyer balance.
Eastern Europe,
Asia, Third-world countries.
- Sometimes more than one a day.
- No fever means
it's not a tropical disease.
If it's not where she went,
maybe it's the work hours.
Could be amphetamine abuse.
She's probably
- popping them like breath mints.
- You haven't been by his office?
Is Wilson hallucinating ants
crawling all over him too?
Tox screen's cleaner than
the windows she won't do.
Her job keeps her constantly
on the road, probably living off
of airline peanuts and diet soda.
Severe B12 deficiency
could cause all her symptoms.
Why is everyone leaping to conclude
a strong career woman's been made sick
by her strong career?
It's not B12,
she has an insulanoma in her pancreas.
It's making her hypoglycemic.
Great.
Now everyone knows.
You knew the patient had cancer?
Is that what she said?
I thought she said,
"I am suddenly
and irrationally defending
"the patient's strong career,
"even though in reality
"she's just a glorified grunt?
"I'm trying to convince my that it's OK
"not to have a life`cause
i don't have a life. `Cause
" I was tested for Huntington's,
and my life span's been cut in half."
Been waiting two months
for her to say that.
Hallucinations, anemia, bradycardia,
Hyper segmented polys
says that Taub's right.
Pump her full of B12.
See how a strong career woman's
been made sick by her strong career.
Are you okay?
Could be years before
you see any symptoms.
- Why wouldn't you tell us?
- I don't have Huntington's.
Are you lying to us...
Because it's none of our business?
Yes, then I shouldn't have
to answer these questions.
I wouldn't have to, except House doesn't
want to answer questions about Wilson.
He's deflecting
his own problems onto me.
Are you deflecting now?
Time for a B12 cocktail
and my life lesson.
No, Patty will do the hearing. She just
needs to be the leadoff witness so...
Okay, I'll lock it down today.
- I need you back in bed.
- My boss has a big Beijing trip.
I've been planning it for months.
I was just tired and dehydrated and
Yeah, whenever I lose
some shut-eye, I pound my legs,
clawing at imaginary ant colonies.
You have a severe B12 deficiency.
Get back in bed.
I'm sure your boss
can do without you for a few days.
It's not about her.
It's about me.
I want to be there.
- I want to matter.
- Yeah, without you,
who knows how much starch
they'd put in her shirts?
I'm sorry, I'm sure
your boss depends on you...
- I need to get up.
- No, you need to stay in bed.
Please, where's a bed pan?
Oh, my god, I'm sorry. I just,
I just had a bowel movement.
It's okay,
B12 deficiency can cause sudden...
That's not a bowel movement.
My patient...
Is still fighting in the feminist
trenches, but the war is over.
Yesterday's sluts
are today's empowered women.
Today's sluts are celebrities.
If that isn't progress...
I'm leaving.
What, are you gonna take
another two months?
Boy, you're really milking
this bereavement thing, aren't you?
I mean, good for you.
Take all the time you need.
I'm resigning.
Maybe moving out of New Jersey.
I don't know yet.
Okay.
That's an understandable reaction.
It's not a reaction.
It's a decision.
I'm writing Cuddy
my resignation right now.
I'm just back for the week to wrap up
my clinical and administrative duties.
You of all people should know,
this is bereavement 101.
You think that a change of venue...
Well, that spares me
decades of psychoanalysis.
- I'm not saying you're not in pain.
- You're saying my pain's a cliche.
- I'm saying that pain fades.
- Did yours?
Physical pain is different.
I'd rather have my leg chopped off.
- You don't know that, you haven't felt
- Neither have you.
Sorry, patient's got a rectal bleed.
- Busy.
- We need you to...
Actually, as you can see, I'm not busy.
It's just a euphemism for
"get the hell out of here."
This is your grief talking.
And, yeah, it is a bit textbook.
So before you give away all your
possessions to the Salvation Army...
My girlfriend's dead.
I'm glad you've read that book before.
I haven't.
I'm late to meet Dr. Olan to brief him
on the cases I'm handing over.
Bye.
It doesn't bother you that House
wouldn't take just two seconds
- to talk about the patient?
- Wilson's dealing with a lot.
Our patient may be dying.
She was bleeding out her rear.
We're looking up her rear.
We needed House's
expertise to set us on this course?
Her heart rate's slow
bleed should have made it faster.
It can wait till after
we know where it came from,
and after he's done dealing
with personal issues.
Yeah? That the way it works around here?
We get cut slack while we deal
with personal issues?
You're not the boss.
Boss gets to make the rules.
Boss gets to ignore...
She's bleeding from...
Nowhere.
- You did an endoscopy?
- And a colonoscopy.
- CT scan?
- Ordered.
It shouldn't show anything
the endoscopy didn't.
- We can't do a CT scan.
- Why not?
We don't need a CT scan.
We don't need House.
Stop grinning and talk.
One of the routine
pre-procedure tests was positive.
Which one?
The one that, if it's positive,
would explain a hormone imbalance
that could screw with
heart rate and blood flow.
Guess she does have a life
beyond her career.
I'm pregnant?
You want me to call the father
and let him know?
Soon as you do some DNA testing,
let me know.
Must be hard
to have a real relationship...
Are you making excuses for me?
- I'm just saying it's understandable.
- You only have to understand something
if it needs an explanation.
I have needs.
I met my needs. End of explanation.
How recently were you...
Needy?
It's been two or three months, at least.
What?
What is it?
Nothing.
- Tell me.
- It's actually nothing.
The ultrasound shows
no trace of a baby at all.
Positive pregnancy test, no pregnancy.
B12 deficit rectified,
but her heart's slowing even more.
And a bleed should speed her heart rate.
House,
this is the kind of case you love.
Contradictions piling up left and right.
Two false positive pregnancy tests,
bradycardia, lower G.I. Bleed. Go.
Choriocarcinoma,
would've triggered pregnancy hormones.
Also would have shown on a sonogram.
Immunoglobulin "A" deficiency.
No urinary bleed.
If she's had Beta HCG injections,
they can cross-react with...
Keep going.
You're being an idiot.
You're gonna blow up your career.
And six months from now,
when you've moved on from Amber to
Burnt Sienna, you're gonna be stuck
in a mobile oncology truck
in Pewaukee, Wisconsin.
I'd need a flow chart
to explain all the ways
in which that was ridiculously
insensitive.
- You can't hide from misery.
- This isn't your business.
My skull was cracked open
trying to save her!
Then we all need
a little tea and sympathy.
I'm through discussing it.
Uh, we have a patient.
Who's obviously not going anywhere
with a bloody rectum.
Great to have you back.
- Actually, I'm...
- Actually,
he's about to thrust a tanto
into the belly of his career.
I'm leaving the hospital.
I'm sorry,
this is obviously a terrible time
Why are you leaving?
I just need a change of scenery.
Buy a plant.
Rectal bleeding,
two positive pregnancy tests.
There's nothing we can do?
You could ask House to be a grown-up
and respect my decision.
I respect things that deserve respect.
This decision, on the other hand,
is a dog wearing a cape!
Hallucinations. Heart won't respond
The patient tested
positive for pregnancy
because the patient is pregnant.
Hey, who are you?
This is Dr. House.
He's too brilliant for introductions.
False positive.
You're too busy to be running
a day care center in your abdomen.
False positive.
Not to mention you should wait
till at least 30 to punish that
pleasure portal
with a 7-pound tissue expander.
I'm 37.
And I thought I wasn't pregnant.
37?
Impressive.
Too bad
you're not passing on those genes.
Does that look false to you?
You were looking in the wrong room.
It's more common
when the egg lands in the oven.
Sometimes
it winds up in the fallopian tubes.
In rare cases, it plummets
through the plumbing entirely.
It's using her intestine
as a blood supply.
It caused the rectal bleed, and now
junior Miss Steinem's junior
must be pressing on her vagus nerve,
slowing her heart to a crawl.
Yank the fetus. If she survives
the surgery, she'll be fine.
What if she wants to keep the baby?
She doesn't.
We can't take
two seconds to discuss this?
Fetuses have been transplanted before.
Whole uteruses too.
Just terminating the fetus
when it's glued to her intestines
is high-risk surgery.
Saving it is a fantasy.
That was at least three seconds.
She's a 37-year-old woman
who deserves...
People get what they get.
It has nothing to do
with what they deserve.
And this has nothing to do
with her genitalia,
and everything to do
with your genetics.
- You told me to get tested.
- I didn't know it was gonna color
your every medical opinion,
every personal opinion.
- You didn't think a death sentence...
- People die!
You, Amber, everyone.
Don't act like you just figured
that out. I gave you a diagnosis.
If you don't like it, there are exits
on every floor.
I'm sorry to be
so definitive about this.
I know you're still absorbing
the news,
but we have no choice.
Remove the fetus.
Absolutely.
I have no boyfriend, no husband.
I'm on the road with Patty
all the time.
Where do I sign?
- You feel any tenderness back here?
- No, not at all.
Treating professional
sports injuries now?
No, I'm not...
Familiar with the concept
of sarcasm.
Don't sweat it, it's new.
- Have you spoken to Wilson?
- We'll get you an EKG, I come back.
You want me to sleep with him
to get him to stay?
I put the bisexual chick on that.
If you'd like to sit in,
so to speak...
- I spoke to him.
- What'd you tell him?
I didn't tell him anything.
I listened.
So you could feel good
about doing nothing.
Tell him...
I am not your errand girl.
Best thing about leaving you...
The two of you used to be together?
She dumped me when I lost
the last 85 pounds.
Said there was less of me to love.
Grief means different things
to different people.
Case in point,
means very little to you.
Grief is Newark.
Okay, it's there.
You can't avoid it.
The idea is to hold your nose,
hope the traffic's not too bad,
and get on to Manhattan as quickly
as possible, not to buy property.
- You think that's facing up to things?
- I'm not the one who's quitting.
- 'cause you haven't lost anything.
- But you have.
He'll listen to you.
What did you do
when your husband died?
I got a new job and I moved.
See how crappy
that worked out?
Separating
the placenta from the wall
of the large intestine.
Sponge.
Suction.
We've got some bleeding.
BP's dropping. 90 systolic.
- She's bleeding like hell. Clamp.
- BP's still dropping.
Amp of calcium chloride, fast!
- still dropping.
- Shut up! Squeeze her spleen.
We need to force platelets out
so her blood clots.
She's in weak shape.
Spleen's friable. It could rupture.
She's stabilizing.
Oozing's drying up.
I hate visitors day.
Removing the fetus.
You have to stop Wilson
from committing career malpractice.
- Talk to him.
- I already talked to him twice.
He threw me out.
Mocking him and insulting him...
Let's see, yes, technically
those are categories of conversation.
Block his references
to other hospitals.
Tell him he can't
hand off his cases until...
Talk to him.
Deal with his grief. Talk to him
about what he's going through.
That's a brilliant idea.
I'll take him out for a beer.
That'll make up for the fact
that Amber's in a pine box.
That there's randomness
and chaos in the universe.
Tell him you're sorry.
I didn't kill her.
You were drunk and...
Yeah, if her daddy hadn't been drunk,
she might never have been born. So...
You called her up
in the middle of the night.
She was on the bus because of you.
I didn't ask her to come out.
I wasn't driving the bus.
I wasn't driving the garbage truck
that hit the bus.
And I did not prescribe her
the flu meds that killed her.
Yes, I know, that's all true.
But.
You really don't feel
any sense of guilt?
You want to keep him,
he needs to know he's not alone.
Just tell him you feel like crap.
It'd be meaningless.
Well, then,
find some meaning.
And do something.
- She's got a neurological problem.
- Surgical complication?
Don't think so.
She keeps on blinking.
- Her heart's not recovering either.
- So the pregnancy was a coincidence.
Pulse is down to 39.
She's maxed out on atropine.
We're installing a pacing wire to...
avoid that. We need some help!
- Page House.
- Already done.
Page him again.
- It's for you.
- If I told you that I was sorry,
- would it change anything?
- I wouldn't believe you.
If you believe me.
It's hard to imagine
such a world.
I'm going home...
Until you agree to stay
at this hospital.
You can't be... That's blackmail.
And to do your job?
Why not hold a gun to your own head?
Your conscience bleeds
more freely than my head.
Text.
Patient's in cardiac arrest.
Ouchy.
You'd jeopardize
a patient
- because of my...
- If it keeps you here.
Your friendship matters
more to me than this patient.
I've gotta do what's right
for me.
You've gotta do what's right
for you.
But it comes easier for me.
Where is he?
- Status.
- Her heart's stabilized.
We have a pacing wire in her, but
the bradycardia isn't getting better.
House is bluffing.
I called him. He's not picking up.
- What do we do?
- What you'd do if he was here.
If he was here, we'd be
asking him what to do.
- What are the usual suspects?
- There aren't any.
She had a vitamin deficiency,
and we corrected it,
- an ectopic pregnancy, we removed it.
- But her heart problem won't go away,
and now something's wrong
with her brain.
I have complete confidence
in you guys.
Who wants to go service House
so this patient can live?
We can do this without him. Maybe
something happened during the surgery.
It was on her bowel, not her brain.
Anxiety, stroke, Tourette's
could all cause eye blinking.
Cause her heart to beat faster,
It's slowing down.
M.S.
If a lesion took out the sympathetic
innervation of her heart,
It'd explain bradycardia and blinking.
But not the vitamin deficiency
or the ectopic pregnancy.
- House would want a unifying theory.
- He's gone, and so are those symptoms.
M.S. explains everything
that's wrong with her right now.
Start her on interferon for M.S.
Mind if I come in?
- Not at all.
- You mind if I leave?
I told you not to take that case
specifically to deal with Wilson.
And the two ended up dovetailing
rather nicely, don't you think?
Is this how you show your friendship...
By bludgeoning him with guilt?
Because he's my friend,
I know what works on him.
- You can't walk away from a patient.
- Then fire me.
You're willing to risk your career,
but youcan't say you're sorry.
I told him I'm sorry.
He didn't believe it.
- Make him believe it.
- I don't.
You don't want to believe it.
Because if you tell Wilson
how you actually feel about him,
about what happened to Amber,
about your part in what happened,
and he walks out the door anyway...
If you make yourself
vulnerable for once
in your nerve-deadening,
emotionally obliterating...
You're doing the same thing he is.
You're running away.
Only he's not killing anyone
in the process.
Where's Dr. House?
He's not feeling well.
Was M.S. his idea?
We work as a team.
You know how it is. Collaborative.
Sometimes it's hard to tell
where an idea mes from.
But you're not really a team.
You work for him.
And you work for Patty.
I'm sure a lot of her ideas
are actually...
She would be fine without me.
I'd be nothing
without her.
Maybe if you just had the chance.
I'm sure you've learned a lot.
Not everybody's created equal.
Does Dr. House think I have M.S.?
Did you just shiver?
You're running a slight fever.
Is that bad?
It means we were
wrong about the M.S.
- You had my cable disconnected!
- That's quite a leap.
Just because I happen to have
a 31-person maintenance department...
each of whom you've personally abused
- at some point...
- Why?
You thought I could let someone die,
but I'm gonna fold
if I can't watch Celebrity Bowling?
That is not an unreasonable theory.
Especially with only ten minutes
till your favorite soap.
Gee, is this the remote
from the doctors' lounge?
This is your 911?
- Good-bye.
- Stop!
I'm withholding your salary history
from every hospital in this region.
You go, girl.
And I'm permanently setting
every TV in this building
to the pottery channel
unless you both sit down.
Welcome to couples counseling.
- It's not the surgery.
- The timing fits.
The location doesn't,
unless brains are in bowels
If bacteria entered her bloodstream,
it could have infected her brain.
The surgery went fine.
You were there.
Peptostreptococcus
could explain the blinking and...
You want to watch a grainy video
and have an epiphany.
Shut up. You're making me miss
House's mocking.
You told us
it was none of our business,
but if your Huntington's
is affecting you,
- maybe it...
- It's not, I don't have...
You're desperate to do it
without him.
You're not trying to cure her,
but to prove...
Stop the tape.
Zoom in.
- On the anastomosis, that little bump.
- It's a hematoma.
A harmless pocket of blood, which is
why Chase ignored it during the surgery.
Could be a ganglioma, which is why Chase
shouldn't have ignored it.
It's an abnormal growth of nerves,
it could be causing
all the patient's symptoms.
We have to open her up again.
Get a piece of it.
- So what do you want to tell us?
- Nothing.
Nothing I say is gonna change anything.
You guys need to talk.
Actually, you should read
the psych literature.
Repression's gaining a lot of fans.
- What you don't face can't crush you.
- Talk to each other.
- How you doing? Good?
- Fine, thanks.
Sit!
See, the two of you are friends.
- Look how you both...
- Think you're an idiot.
We both also eat with forks.
- That doesn't really prove...
- Talk to him!
Tell him how you feel
about what he's doing.
He's an idiot.
Tell him what you think
about him leaving.
- I think he's an idiot.
- You're an idiot. He's in pain.
And your response is just
to emotionally blackmail him.
You told me your position.
- You're against it, right?
- She hasn't told you in front of me.
- She needs to prove she's on my side.
- Go to hell.
- So much for that theory.
- I'm sorry you lost Amber.
I cannot imagine what it is
you're going through.
But it will not get better
by you walking away
from everyone that cares about you.
Do you think Amber
would want you to walk away?
Nobody at this hospital
even liked Amber.
Same time next week?
You want me to do
a second major surgery
on a patient we almost lost
during a first major surgery
to see if she needs
a third major surgery?
We need a piece of the ganglioma.
Then you're talking
about another patient.
Yours doesn't have a ganglioma.
And if there is one
and you missed it?
So you're talking about another surgeon.
I didn't miss anything.
But we're not talking about another
videotape. It showed a bump.
- We need to biopsy.
- A bump?
My grandfather died of a bump.
She can't survive a second round
of general anesthesia,
- let alone a third.
- You'd do this for House.
What do you suggest?
Because the patient's got
a high fever, a low heart rate,
and a dim chance of survival
if we stand here like idiots.
Then I suggest
you don't stand there like idiots.
How do you get coal out of a mountain
when it's someone else's mountain?
If we don't have House,
we can think like him.
But it does mean we don't have
to talk like him.
You don't dig down.
You go in from the side.
We insert a lighted scope
through the rectum,
move the intestine till we find
the ganglioma,
then push it to the surface.
Where we see the light, we cut.
We'll make as small
an incision as we can.
But unfortunately,
it'll be very painful.
After your surgery experience,
we can't give you anesthesia.
Can I talk to Dr. House?
No.
We can do this.
We know what we're doing.
I don't mean to be insulting,
but my former boss
didn't insist on me coming here
because of you or...
Your former boss?
I've been replaced.
- I'm sorry. You must be...
- I'm fine.
She has a big Beijing trip.
Ton of work to do.
She can't just wait for me
to get better.
We've been well-trained.
We'll take good care of you.
How can you let her treat you
like a footstool?
- The world needs flunkies.
- Don't say that.
You're better than that.
I have no problem with it.
Why do you?
Because...
Life is short.
Yours could've ended in that surgery.
You'd have never lived for yourself.
What kind of feminist...
We can have anything.
No, we can't.
We can aspire to anything.
But we don't get it just
because we want it.
I would rather spend my life
close to the birds
than waste it wishing I had wings.
You're through the sigmoid,
into the descending colon.
Switching on the light.
Advance toward the anastomosis.
That's it.
Push the wall of the intestine
toward the skin.
There, I see it.
Don't look down.
Scalpel.
So your last day is Friday.
I'm gonna miss you.
You shouldn't go.
Did house ask you to talk to me,
or are you trying to save the patient?
- Because there'll always be...
- House asked me.
- And you're doing it.
- I told him to go to hell.
Thanks.
But I think he's right.
You think you're making
a rational choice.
You think the worst is over.
And then...
Six months later you look back
and you realize...
You didn't know what you were doing.
Are you saying the pain doesn't go away?
It gets easier.
Not in two months.
Not in two years.
But no...
It never really goes away.
Being here...
This building...
I was just in the lounge.
I kept staring at Amber's locker.
I saw a guy wearing
a scarf this morning.
The color reminded me of his eyes.
We lived 500 miles from here.
- I have to do something.
- Then do it.
But don't think it's the right choice,
because...
There isn't one.
It's not a ganglioma.
- The problem wasn't the surgery.
- Abnormally deposited proteins.
It's amyloidosis. That would explain
the blinking and the low heart rate.
Only way to treat amyloidosis is
to treat whatever's causing it.
It's not as if a lot of things
cause amyloid.
Rheumatoid arthritis.
Familial mediterranean fever.
Lymphoma.
We can't all be right.
But you can all be wrong.
The patient's joints don't hurt,
abdominal pain went away when the fetus
did, and no palpable lymph nodes.
- Got anything constructive to say?
- Sorry. Sorry.
Um, she has lots and lots of palpable
lymph nodes, joint and abdominal pain.
She'll be better by dinnertime.
If we don't find the cause
of the amyloidosis,
we never get her off that wire,
she never walks out of this hospital.
But hey, who needs House, hmm?
So glad we lost those training wheels.
You want me to make the call?
There seems to be some disagreement.
And this isn't just a pretext
to pressure me into staying?
Does it look like a pretext?
No.
She really is dying, isn't she?
Inflammation, enlarged nuclei,
some mitotic activity.
It could be lymphoma.
There are no palpable lymph nodes.
It makes it less likely,
but it doesn't rule it out.
I'm an oncologist.
I see cancer.
Show it to an immunologist,
they'll see autoimmune.
I already showed it to an immunologist.
We'll start her on chemo.
You should leave.
House doesn't want to lose his sidekick.
Cuddy doesn't want to lose
her check on house.
No one's talking about what you want.
It's not that I want to.
Want to, need to.
If there's any chance that being
away from here will make your life
even a little bit easier, do it.
That's what everyone else
here would do.
Don't expect anything
to change too fast.
Lymphoma was your idea?
- Why?
- I feel better.
Sometimes just knowing
you're being treated helps.
You've given me 18 different treatments.
This is the first one
that made me feel better.
I don't think it's psychological.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have gotten angry at you.
Your choices are your choices.
You're not like me.
Maybe you have wings.
I have huntington's chorea.
Dozen years or so, my...
nervous system, my cognitive skills,
even my emotional balance...
They'll all start to fray.
I won't be able to fly.
I won't be able to walk.
I won't be able to breathe.
And you want to make sure
your life matters.
I don't want to just...
Be tightening bolts
and following instructions.
I want something...
To be different because of me.
I am.
Not just 'cause you saved my life.
I'm applying for a job at a foundation.
Running the finance division.
I mean, I don't know
if I'm gonna get it, but...
If I don't...
There are other foundations.
It's almost 4:00.
Soap time.
Nurses' remote.
Works in the doctors' lounge.
Why do you think Wilson's leaving?
How many times do I have
to use the word "idiot"?
That's a good enough answer for you?
Whenever anyone does
anything out of the norm,
you have to tell them what screwed-up
process is really at work in their head.
That is why I locked
the two of you in a room.
So you would say something
stupid and insensitive,
and maybe with a little bit of truth.
But you didn't.
So I can only assume
that you don't want to know the reason.
You're afraid to know.
You're not listening to me, are you?
Try it sometime.
You'll see why.
You look 37.
I am 37.
You looked 27 last week.
Unless I blacked out for ten years.
Your skin...
She's got lymphoma.
The chemo's probably...
- Stop the chemo.
- She's getting better.
- Bradycardia's improving, we...
- She have bruising?
She was pounding her legs
during the hallucinations.
It's not lymphoma.
Hey, don't...
No, no, no.
My bad.
Thought no meant yes.
Those aren't bruises.
They're mycobacterial lesions.
She has diffuse lepromatous leprosy.
Must have caught it on one
of her overseas estrogen tours.
Chemo wipes out some of the bacteria,
she feels a little better.
Wipes out most of her immune system,
she gets a whole lot worse.
Leprosy?!
Like where my limbs fall off?
Actually, this is the flattering one.
It's also known as "pretty leprosy".
It doesn't disfigure, it makes
your skin look younger, smoother.
Don't let the girls hear.
They'll all want to lick your face.
Unless you're that kind of feminist.
Blast her with antibiotics
and Prednisone.
She'll be fine.
Damn, it's after 4:00.
I'm late.
- Damn.
- What?
She's happy you're gonna be fine.
But she'd be happier if you were gonna
be fine five minutes ago.
Tests confirmed Dr. House's diagnosis.
Thank God.
When you got pregnant,
he physical stress triggered
e. Nodosum Lleprosum.
A common complication of leprosy.
Inflamed the nerves to your heart.
Made it hard to absorb vitamins,
scarred your fallopian tubes.
It explains everything.
Better prescribe me some
skin cream too?
You might want it
for those job interviews.
I'm going back on the road with Patty.
My replacement flamed out.
She says I can manage some projects
on my own, carve out more of a role.
Do you really think she can change?
I don't know.
The truth is, I'm not sure I...
You can change.
No...
I'm not sure I want her to change.
She's reasonable.
She's just another employer,
and I'm just...
another employee.
In a weird way, I matter.
I like you better now that you're dying.
I was wrong.
You took a shot.
She's going back to work for that idiot.
It's pathetic.
You thought something would change?
She almost died...
Because of that job.
Yeah, I... I thought...
Almost dying changes nothing.
Dying changes everything.
I'm sorry.
I know I didn't try to kill her.
I know I didn't want her hurt.
I know it was a freak accident.
But I feel like crap, and
she's dead because of me.
I don't blame you.
I wanted to. I tried to.
I must have reviewed Amber's case file
100 times to find a way.
But it wasn't your fault.
Then we're okay?
I mean, I know you're not, but...
- Maybe I can help.
- We're not okay.
Amber was never the reason
I was leaving.
I didn't want to tell you because--
Because I was trying...
Like I always do, to protect you.
Which is the problem.
You spread misery because
you can't feel anything else.
You manipulate people
because you can't handle
any kind of real relationship.
And I've enabled it.
For years.
The games, the binges,
the middle-of-the-night phone calls.
I should have been
the one on the bus, not...
You should have been alone on the bus.
If I've learned anything from Amber,
it's that I have to take care of myself.
We're not friends anymore, House.
I'm not sure we ever were.
www.house-fr.com
www.tvsubtitles.net