Surgeons fight.
- I didn't bring it up. He did.
- Well, what? It's the truth.
I said we're not
talking about it.
We fight against
death. It's our thing.
Well, on the plus side, it's
your last day in the clinic.
- Clinic wasn't so bad.
- What did I just say?
- We're drinking tonight, right?
- Not about this.
Mer, the trial's tomorrow.
It could be our last chance
for, like, eight, ten years.
But eventually, if
history is any indicator...
death is gonna win.
Or you could win, and we
could drink tomorrow night.
Yeah. Right.
- There's a chance.
- Yeah. Slim to none.
We may win the battle,
but we're never
gonna win the war.
What about a plea?
Didn't they offer you a
plea for, like, two years?
I turned it down. Maybe I
shouldn't have turned it down.
Two years is still a long
time. Zero years is the goal.
So the trick is to
go down fighting...
to fight for the right
cause, for the right person.
We're drinking tonight.
It's my last day on Earth.
Stop! Stop talking
about drinking.
Stop talking about
last days on Earth.
The world is not
coming to an end.
And if you go down,
you all go down together.
Oh, we're drinking tonight.
We are the eye of the
storm on this, people.
Everything and everyone
is coming our way.
Code Yellow has been declared.
Disaster protocol is in effect
until you hear otherwise.
I'm recalling
all surgical staff.
Already recalled my nurses.
I've got the ER covered.
Klein's manning the OR floor.
Who do you have up there on...
Doctors Grey, Shepherd,
Baker, and Lowes
are on nonstop cut-and-paste
in ORs one through four.
Okay. I got one
from the supply room.
Also, why do we
keep these, anyways?
Who needs an
instant photo anymore?
Because an apartment
building collapsed
in the middle of Seattle.
Look, right now, we're getting
the victims, the survivors.
Then, in about 20 minutes,
we're gonna start getting
the people who love the victims,
their moms, and
husbands, and girlfriends,
and grandmas, and
friends, and children,
and wives with
babies in their arms.
This waiting room is going
to fill up with hopeful people
wanting to know where
their loved ones are.
Now, some of their
loved ones are here,
but most of their
loved ones are buried
under the rubble of
that collapsed building.
The only way to know for sure,
the only way they can identify
who made it to this
hospital and who didn't...
This photo... is
a golden ticket.
I want a photo of
every single patient...
on this board in the next hour.
- Got it?
- Got it.
Dr. Minnick. I have
surgical privileges.
Dr. Minnick! Well, I didn't
expect you until Monday.
I was unpacking and
I saw it on the news.
They said the injured
were coming here
and I thought, "Hey. I
work here. I should help."
- Yeah. Appreciate that.
- I better get into some scrubs.
Hey, jump in, and then
when this calms down,
- we can grab a cup of coffee.
- I'd love to.
Be a chance to get you
up to speed before I start.
I will find you.
Get me up to speed?
We have two incoming!
Dr. Webber, you're up!
Hey! You gotta
clear the driveway!
My kid's hurt! My kid's hurt!
Someone help, please!
- Someone help, please!
- Sir.
Sir. You need to
move your car now.
My kid's hurt real bad! Please!
Please help my baby!
Okay. Don't move
her. Don't move her.
Get me a gurney out here now!
- Whose patient is this?
- I've got O-neg!
- Another round of epi!
- Excuse me.
Ma'am, squeeze my fingers.
Need you to squeeze my fingers.
O-neg!
- Yeah?
- I gotta go home.
- I need to go home.
- No, you need to...
- My wife. My wife.
- You need to lie down, sir.
I need a priest. I'm dying.
- Sir, no, we...
- A priest, a pastor, anybody.
I need to talk to God.
- Andrew.
- Great. I could use
an extra hand.
Can you put these chart numbers
on the photos as I take them?
- Did you know about this?
- Know about what? The photos?
No. Bailey gave
me this huge lecture.
No, no. The trial.
They want me to testify.
They're calling me
to the stand tomorrow.
What? But they said
you didn't have to.
They said you were
drinking. You're not reliable.
Well, someone's
calling me to the stand.
Did you tell them? Did
you tell them about...
Jo, hey, hey. I
wouldn't do that, okay?
- Here.
- Well, they must know.
Somehow, they...
They started Googling,
and they figured out
that I changed my name,
and that there's a point where
Jo Wilson just isn't a person.
They might not know anything.
What if they ask?
If they ask, then
I have to answer.
Well, you don't have to.
It's court. Excuse me.
If I lie under oath and
get caught, it's a felony.
I would lose my medical license.
I have to tell the truth if they ask.
If I tell them, it's public record.
My husband could find me,
and everything that I
built is... is gone, done.
I'm sorry, Jo.
One minute, you're
fine, and the next minute,
everything just
collapses around you.
Jo...
Yeah, I've got a
depressed skull fracture.
- Is Shepherd here yet?
- I don't know.
Didn't you come in together?
Kepner, your guess is as
good as mine where she is.
- Is everything okay?
- Hey. I gotta get home.
- Sir, you need to lie down.
- My wife is...
I understand that,
sir. What's your name?
- Charlie.
- Okay, Charlie.
What I need you to do...
- All right.
- Thank you, Charlie.
- We got you. We got you.
- Okay.
I need an intubation
tray and a central line kit.
Draw a CBC and a cross-match.
Guys, open up a trauma room.
Riggs, we're gonna need a hand here.
No. I called. The
chaplain's MIA.
There may be a rabbi
up in geriatrics though.
- Could you do it?
- What? No.
All you have to do is listen to
him, nod your head a few times.
No. It's got to be
illegal or something.
- You're not gonna go to jail.
- Go to hell.
Please. You don't
believe in that.
But he does, and
that's good enough.
- Sir.
- Oh!
You're the priest?
I was gonna...
- No, sir.
- I was gonna... fix it.
Fix it?
They said it was the
earthquake last year.
The foundation was crumbling.
Is he talking
about the collapse?
I was getting the money.
And now...
all these people...
Please, please, forgive me.
Okay, okay, okay. Sir, sir...
I killed all these people.
Sir? Sir? Sir?
- I'll get
a crash cart.
- Okay. Notify CT.
Give five lorazepam
and start a benzo drip.
And somebody get a damn priest!
I'm here.
Right-sided hemothorax.
Put in a chest tube. It's already
drained 300 cc's of blood.
Winnie... sweetie, we're
right here. We're right here.
- How old is she?
- She's 12.
We just went to get coffee.
We were about a block away.
This is fresh blood.
She's actively bleeding.
Mr. Adkins, maybe you and
your wife should wait outside.
No, no, I'm not leaving my
daughter here. Please, no.
Cross her for eight and
set up a rapid infuser.
- I need a central line kit.
- Get the family
out of this room now!
It's gonna be... No.
Baby, we're gonna
be right outside, okay?
- I understand.
- We'll be right out here, okay?
We have to do our job.
Dr. Carlyle to Peds.
- So, where is the landlord now?
- CT. Then he's going
in with Grey.
She's holed up in the OR doing
back-to-back surgeries all day.
Hmm, nice work, Father
Warren. Do you do weddings?
Okay, stop it. It was not cool.
He said, "Please forgive me."
What am I supposed to do with that?
Maybe, don't
pretend to be Jesus.
I think we got pictures of all
the patients in the back hallway.
He confessed to me. What
do I do? Do I go to the cops?
I think there's some sort of
confidence with priests, right?
He told you in confidence
as a man of God.
- I am not a priest!
- Amen.
Okay, what about
doctor-patient confidentiality?
- That doesn't apply.
- Fine. I'm out.
Does that apply?
How does that apply?
I'll tell you what applies.
Maybe you don't let
somebody confess to you
in the first place.
Because once you
know, you can't un-know.
The landlord knew that
there was earthquake damage,
and he didn't do
anything to fix it.
- Shady as hell.
- You at least tell the tenants.
You don't sit around hoping
the building doesn't fall down.
- 'Cause, guess what? Yeah.
- It's gonna fall down.
- That's my niece! That's Marissa.
- Okay. Just give me a second.
Okay, Marissa's
got a broken femur.
She's in post-op. I can show
you where she is, all right?
Yes, that's my husband.
He threw up blood?
Charlie threw up blood?
Yes, your husband has a gastric
injury and a tear in his diaphragm.
Oh, my God!
Dr. Riggs and I will be
taking him up to the OR now.
How did this happen?
What happened to him?
Your husband was in your
apartment when the building collapsed.
We don't live in an apartment.
Well, I'm sorry. I'll
update you, okay?
There he is.
Yeah, that's the guy. We're
gonna take him right up.
We were just in bed one minute.
Then the whole world caved in.
I don't know why... I was
okay and he was hurt so badly.
Look, I'll update you
as soon as we know.
Thank you.
I updated Charlie's wife.
- Charlie's wife?
- Yup.
Charlie's married?
Our patient, Charlie?
- What's the matter with you?
- I just updated
Charlie's girlfriend.
Oh.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
It's okay. It's okay.
Hey, I need some
oxygen over here.
It's okay. It's okay.
Take some deep breaths,
deep breaths. Deep.
O2 is right here.
Okay.
It's okay. Lungs are clear.
Okay, make fists with your toes.
Tight, tight, tight
fists. Good job.
Wow. I haven't
seen that one before.
Slow, deep breaths.
It just distracts them.
- It's your first day?
- Sort of.
Just... jumping in where I can.
- Well, welcome.
- Thanks, Dr. Robbins.
Told you I wouldn't forget.
- Forget?
- Your name.
- Huh?
- You don't remember.
Wow. Okay, uh... Forget it.
I just... Last time I saw
you, I said you had a name
I couldn't forget,
and so I thought...
- Oh. I'm sorry. I don't...
- No.
It's fine.
- I'm sorry.
- It's nothing. It's nothing.
Did you see that? Did
you see me winning?
Surgical residents to pre-op.
You're saying he knew? Micah?
That's what we heard.
That for almost a year,
he knew there was
earthquake damage,
and he didn't do
anything about it!
What he did is criminal!
- It's negligence!
- Murder's what it is.
I heard Rhonda Coley didn't
even make it out of surgery.
- He can't get away with this!
- Harry.
He won't! If I have
a say, he won't!
Harry, Harry, the
doctors are here.
- Hi.
- How is she?
Winnie's injuries
are very severe.
Most urgently, she's
bleeding into her chest.
The tube we placed
is still draining blood.
So we'll need to
operate on her right away.
And then she's
gonna be okay, right?
Hey, hey. What'd they say?
- How's Winnie?
- She's in surgery.
Look, he's not gonna
get away with this!
That's exactly
what I'm trying to...
- Are you kidding me?
- I do not like the vibe here.
- Did you hear
that I was subpoenaed?
- Yeah, I...
My attorney's really
good. She says that...
Probably... I don't think
that we should talk about it.
Yeah, I don't
want to. It's just...
after tomorrow, we might
not get a chance to talk.
I might not see you after.
I just wanted to say I'm sorry.
Alex, you've said that. I know.
I mean for the things I said.
You're not trash. Don't
ever let anyone say that.
I'm sorry, and I...
You're not trash, Jo.
Dr. Zaumann, extension 2501.
- Dr. Minnick! You're here!
- Not yet. I start Monday.
I'm just volunteering today,
helping out where I can.
That's so cool.
Doesn't look like we'll
get our cup of coffee.
I can send you some
papers if you want.
And, you know,
you'll just be observing
the first few days anyway,
getting a sense of how it works.
That'll actually help
with the transition.
Transition? I thought you
two were working together.
Yes, we are.
- Has Dr. Bailey spoken with you?
- You know what?
- I think you and I should
sit down...
- You should talk to Dr. Bailey.
They're closing in
OR four. We're next.
Right on. So, what
do we do here?
I don't think we need
mesh for the diaphragm,
- just a running nylon suture...
- No, no.
Are we supposed to update
this guy's wife and girlfriend
separately, hope they never
meet? Do we sell them out?
Or are we enabling some
guy to cheat on his wife?
We don't have to do anything.
You cheat on your wife, it's
gonna come back to bite you.
We had our own problems.
Megan and I. That's...
that you're saying, right?
But we had problems, and
we were working on them.
And I'm not just making excuses,
but you weren't in our thing, so...
- You don't know...
- Riggs.
And you hold me
responsible. I know that.
But I promise you can't judge me
harsher than I judge myself everyday.
It's a life sentence, mate.
And you...
Well, maybe you can't
understand that 'cause you're...
Well, you'd never do it.
You're better than that.
You're better than me.
You always have been.
I'm not better.
I've made my mistakes.
Not...
Yeah.
You cheated?
On Shepherd?
On my first wife.
She made it sound like
you're stepping down.
You're not stepping down.
Have you talked to Dr. Bailey?
I tried paging her.
She's in surgeries all day.
Eliza Minnick
needs to stop talking
like she is running this
program if she's not.
Okay, Maggie. I
will talk to Dr. Bailey.
How's she doing?
The hilum's clamped,
but the PA is still bleeding.
Edwards, suction.
I saw Dr. Minnick earlier.
She's here already.
Lap pads.
- That's awesome.
- Edwards, more lap pads.
So, I was thinking
in honor of that...
do you think maybe I could
have a shot at repairing...
- You're not doing a repair.
- I've assisted Dr. Pierce
and you.
Dr. Minnick would say
I'm more than ready.
But Dr. Minnick would not
say that you could do this one,
because I've done over a
thousand, and this one's not holding.
And if I can't, you
sure as hell can't.
Father?
- Sir...
- I thought I was gonna be dead.
- Now, sir...
- I knew all those people.
The Goldmans, the
Richters, the Flemings.
I heard their stories.
I heard their problems,
their little victories.
I saw their children come
home from the hospital...
Elliot, David... Winnie.
They were my
family, these people.
That place, how
was I gonna fix it?
Couldn't raise their rent. Some
of them couldn't pay me already.
- Sir, I'm not a priest.
- I know. I don't care.
I just need someone
to forgive me.
I need them to know...
how sorry I am...
and to forgive me.
Will you, please?
Will you?
Will you forgive me?
Please?
Sir?
I need an intubation kit!
Pierce, try to gain
control more proximally.
DeBakey.
Pressure's dropping.
Come on! Come on!
Pierce, I can't see.
Damn it!
She's bleeding out. Damn it.
Damn it. Damn it! She's
in v-fib. Get a crash cart.
Charge to 200.
Charge again!
Hey.
I'm married.
What?
What the hell are
you talking about?
Since before I met you,
and... I should have told you,
but I'm married to a guy
who almost beat me to death.
And... I can't divorce him...
because I ran away from him.
And I'm not...
Jo Wilson isn't my real name.
That's why I couldn't marry you.
That's how this whole
thing started, and...
I should have told you.
You're married?
Yes.
And you didn't tell me.
- I was scared. I...
- Scared of what?
Did you think I'd get mad?
You thought I'd get
mad at you for trying...
No, not at me, at him! I
thought you'd want to kill him!
And that you'd try
something stupid
and you'd get hurt, or
killed, or you'd get in trouble,
- and you... you'd...
- Wind up in jail.
It might all come
out in court tomorrow.
I wanted you to hear it from me.
After the trial, if I just take off, if
I leave, it's not because of you.
It's because my testimony will be a
matter of record, or whatever, but...
I don't want you to
think that it's you... ever.
Hey.
Don't go anywhere, no
matter what happens, okay?
I don't want him to find me.
- He can't find me.
- This is your life.
You're Jo Wilson.
You belong here.
Vascular specialist to the E.R.
Is she okay?
Sit down.
Sponge stick.
How did I not know you
were married before?
- And she moved to Finland?
- Switzerland. Suction.
We wanted different things.
I wanted a kid. She
did not want a kid.
No middle ground, no
compromise. Either or.
And here I am again.
Different person, same place.
- I'm right there again.
- Yeah, no, you're not.
You've been there once.
Now you know better.
Hey! How's the kid?
- The hyperventilating kid.
- Fine.
Oh.
- I like girls.
- What? Oh. Okay.
I mean, I feel like you
can't tell or something,
that I like women,
that I'm flirting with you.
You're not getting it,
and I'm really good at this.
I have game. Which means
either you're not into women
and the world is upside-down
bonkers, because I know,
or... you're not into me and
I'm totally deluding myself.
No.
- You are not deluding yourself.
- I'm not?
No. I am a human rainbow.
And you do. You've got a lot of
game. You have a very sexy...
somethin'-somethin'
going on, believe me.
But there's a thing about
you that bugged me.
You walk around like you
own the place. It's annoying.
Hmm... It's charming.
Do you want to grab
a drink some time?
See? That. That is what I mean.
No. I don't want to
grab a drink with you.
Yes. Yes, you do.
Shut up. Fine. I'll
have a drink with you.
And I promise,
you will not regret it.
Go away.
Who's next?
Splenic lac with
blood in the abdomen.
- We had to resuscitate her
in trauma.
- Show me.
Okay.
Finish up prepping her for
an ex-lap and I'll be right in.
Mer, you got a sec?
No. Not really. Unless
you want to scrub in.
- I won't tell Bailey.
- No.
Well, you're not gonna start with the
end of the world crap again, are you?
Jo's married.
Wait. What?
She's married, and
she's freaking out
that she has to take the
stand tomorrow and testify
and put herself on the line.
Herself on the line?
This is your trial.
- Your life is on the line.
- Look, she's scared, Mer.
What're you even
saying right now?
I just need to figure
out what to do.
Figure what out? You're not
even making any sense right now.
- You don't know the whole story.
- Okay. So tell it to me.
Dr. Grey, her BP is 90 over 40.
Okay, so hang two
units. I'll be right there.
You should go.
- I...
- Dr. Grey.
Yes. I'm coming. We're not done.
When this surgery is
over, I'm going to page you.
You're gonna come and tell me
- the rest of the story. Okay?
- Go.
Come back!
Ma'am, can I help you?
I'm looking for my husband.
Good. Yeah, he could...
He could use some company.
You haven't spoken to
the chief yet, have you?
- It's fine.
- No, it's not fine!
What Dr. Minnick said
is not fine. It sounds like
- she's taking your job.
- No. Pierce...
And what's worse is it sounds
like nobody has told you.
Maggie.
Let me in!
- What?
- It's Micah's fault!
Oh, no.
Just let us in.
I need you all to calm down.
- I have a right
to know where he is!
- I'm so sorry.
You don't, and I can't
give you that information.
- He killed my little girl!
- Please step back! Step back!
- Now, what is the problem?
They're looking for the landlord.
He's intubated right now,
but he was talking earlier.
He had a tough time. He
was... he was asking for a priest.
Thank you, Doctor.
Uh, I'll leave you two alone.
- Get out of our way!
- Move. Move now!
No one is hunting down
a patient in my hospital.
You want to get out
of my way right now!
- Harry. She's gone.
- No!
Winnie is gone! This is
not going to bring her back.
You'll go to jail.
And then your wife will lose
you both. This will not help.
Oh, my God!
She's gone.
Security! Security!
We need security!
- No, please!
- Damn it.
Up the O-2, 100 percent.
- What happened?
- She tried
to disconnect his vents.
She tried to suffocate
him. She tried to kill him!
Someone has to be
responsible. He knew it!
He has to be held
responsible for this. Please.
I have been in OR all day.
Well, you missed some things.
Ben feels terrible, says he
led the woman right to him.
She would have found him on her
own. Ben saved his life, is what he did.
I heard you were looking for me.
Bailey, who's running this
program? Me or Eliza Minnick?
I planned to tell you today.
Then she showed up
early, and all of this...
Today? Planned to tell me today?
And you'd have
tomorrow and the weekend
to adjust to the situation,
have your... feelings...
Start fresh on Monday.
That was me.
That's how I taught
you how to fire people.
No. No one's getting fired.
Yeah, right. But she'll
be running the program.
She's the Curriculum Director.
You are the Chairman of
the Residency Program.
- You're overseeing
the whole thing.
- I'm ornamental, you know it.
You didn't want to
discuss it with me.
You don't want to
hear my opinions
about a program that I
built, that I trained you in!
- That's not respect.
- I made a decision
about what is best for the
hospital moving forward,
and I didn't want
my personal feelings,
my Very strong
personal feelings,
to get in the way
of that decision.
If I do that, I won't
be able to do this job.
Bailey...
we reach into people's bodies
and hold their lives and
their futures in our hands.
There's nothing more
personal than this job,
in how we treat a patient,
in how we raise our doctors and
teach them how to do this work.
Every decision you make
should be a personal one.
If it isn't, then you have
no business being chief.
- Hey, do you have a second?
- Not really.
Look, I don't wanna
put you on the spot,
but you're on the
board of this hospital.
Almost done here.
You're doing great.
You're an Avery.
It's an Avery hospital.
Land the plane, Pierce.
- Eliza Minnick works here now.
- I'm aware.
She thinks she's the
new Residency Director,
like she's Richard
Webber's boss.
Minnick said that?
What is it, Karev?
I need to adjust
my pension account.
I need it signed over so
the money goes to my mom.
- Can you set that up for me?
- What are you talking about?
Can you send it to my
mom every month, please?
You don't think it's
gonna go well tomorrow.
Karev, what are you about to do?
You were right about the clinic.
It got my head back in the game.
You are not leaving this office
until you tell me
what is going on.
Okay, you have five
minutes. Let's go.
I'm going to the district
attorney's tonight,
and I'm gonna take
the plea he offered.
Okay, that's not funny.
What're you talking about?
I'm gonna plead out.
I'll be gone two years.
- I just... I just wanted to say...
- You're not doing this!
I am. It's my choice.
Why? Because of Jo?
No. Because I did it. And
I'm gonna go say I did it.
No, you're not.
It'd save everyone a
lot of time and trouble.
Alex, you're gonna go home
and get a good night's sleep.
- And then, tomorrow...
- There's not gonna be
a tomorrow.
Yeah. Tomorrow you're
gonna go into the court,
and you're gonna
tell them who you are,
that you're a surgeon
who saves children,
that you make
waffles for children,
that you did one stupid thing.
And you will face whatever
it is you have to face,
but you are not
going to throw yourself
on the mercy of whatever,
and walk into prison, okay?
You'll be okay.
Me? This is about you!
You think this is noble,
what you're doing?
It isn't. It's giving up.
It's buying into everything
you've ever said about yourself,
and I won't let you do it!
- Look, you'll be fine.
- You are not going to jail!
You'll be just fine.
Stop making this about me!
Stop using me as an excuse
to make yourself feel better.
Of course, I will be fine! I'm
always fine. Don't you know that?
This is about you!
You will be destroyed. Your
life, your career, everything...
will be finished.
Who you are will be gone.
I'd hug you goodbye,
but I'm not scrubbed.
Well, because this
isn't goodbye, Alex.
You don't walk in here when
I'm in the middle of a surgery.
Dr. Grey? We're
ready for you in the...
- I need a minute.
- Kiss the kids for me.
No, Alex. Alex, you're
not gonna walk out of here.
- Dr. Grey.
- I heard you!
Goodbye, Mer.
Alex!
- He did very well.
- Your husband
came through great.
- Everything went just fine.
- He's awake and responsive.
- Can I see him?
- When can I see him?
Don't see why not.
As soon as you'd like.
I'll get a nurse, okay?
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
- Not our business, right?
- Not our business.
Look, you want to grab a beer?
Actually... I want to go
home and see my wife.
I get it.
Another time? Rain check.
Right on.
- Hey, let me know
how it goes, huh?
- Yeah.
They don't get to
make this decision.
There is nothing
wrong with this program,
and it is totally
disrespectful to you.
- Maggie...
- If they want a fight,
they can have it.
- I am not scared.
- Maggie! Look, I appreciate it.
But, um...
I'm not sure this
is a fight I can win.
I'll fight with you.
I'm touched... that you want to.
I really am.
Come here.
Look, I know a lot of you guys
didn't come up in this program.
But I did. April did.
And the difference
between the education
that we got at Mercy West
and what we got under Webber?
- No. There's no comparison.
- This is ridiculous.
He is the program.
So, if you guys are
as pissed as we are...
- Yes!
- and you really,
really should be...
See? It's not just me.
Hey.
You okay?
You want to talk about it?
I know. I know.
Church and state.
No.
No. To hell with
church and state.
It's not working.
It's not worth it. It's
not how to do this job.
I need to talk to you
about something.
Okay, okay, look, I didn't
impersonate a priest exactly.
What? No. I'm
not talking about...
- Wait. What?
- What are you talking about?
Alex Karev.
- Hey.
- Oh. Sorry.
- Where are you going?
- I have to leave.
I got pulled on a case. But you
want to see something gross?
Look, about tomorrow...
Oh. I told Alex.
I told him everything.
And you were right.
I should have told him right
away because... it was okay.
And we are... we're...
I just feel like whatever
happens tomorrow
is gonna happen,
and... I'm not worried.
Not gonna worry. I feel okay.
Well, uh...
I'm sorry. I have to go.
- Right.
- Okay.
You're here to see
the district attorney.
- Is he expecting you?
- Tell him it's Alex Karev.
I'm the defendant
in the trial tomorrow.
I'll let him know.
Alex, listen to me.
Grab my phone, call Alex Karev,
and put it on speaker for me, please.
You've just reached
Dr. Alex Karev.
I'm not here right now,
so leave a message.
Alex, listen to me.
You're better than
this. You're stronger.
Don't make this all your fault.
I know you.
That's what you do.
But, please...
Please don't do that.
We can't just give up,
not after all this time.
We have to stand
together. We have to fight.
Because it's just us now.
There were five of us,
and now it's just you and I.
And it can't be
just me. It can't be.
I will go down
swinging for you, Alex.
You know I will.
But that means
you can't give up.
You don't throw the fight.
So, whatever
you're doing this for...
Mr. Karev?
Please...
He'll see you now.
Don't.
Mr. Karev?