Doug... Doug!
Come on. Up and at
'em. We're busy here.
No way. I'm on double shift.
Yep. So am I. And you
wanted a long weekend. Get up.
I was having a terrific dream...
Beating my high school
football coach to a pulp.
Carter, med students don't
sleep at 4:00 in the afternoon.
Get up, Carter.
There's woman in
three with a headache.
She thinks
it's a brain tumor.
A little kid in five with
chewing gum in his eye.
And there's an
old lady in four...
She just wants her hand held.
I'm really hungry.
Cookies at the desk.
Oh. Repeat H & H order
for abdominal pain in two.
Morning, Susan.
It's afternoon, Doug.
I knew that.
Your brain's rotted.
At your age, Ryne
Sandberg retired.
At my age, Mozart was dead.
Jen, Jen, Jen, I can't get out.
I have got two residents
on double shifts.
I'll be home before
Rachel goes to bed.
Tell Mark to go see his wife.
Go see your wife.
Why can't you tell
me over the phone?
Hey, Jen. Hang on.
Jen? Hey, it's Doug. Can
you hold on a second?
We can survive without you.
I'll meet you there,
all right? Bye.
Thank you.
I know you can
survive without me.
Rescue 51's bringing
in two victims...
Motor vehicle collision...
One major, one minor.
How soon? Now.
Where's Benton?
Do I look like his travel agent?
Ask his student.
Read books of diseases,
you start thinking
you have them.
Find Benton. Head-on
vehicle, two victims on the way.'
TC, seven months
OB. Vitals stable.
Second victim right behind her.
What's your name, ma'am?
Sally. Sally Neimeyer.
How far along are
you, Mrs. Neimeyer?
Almost seven months.
Second one coming in!
Chest trauma, vitals stable.
Air bag didn't open.
Name's Suarez... gangbanger.
Stole the car, hit
the pregnant lady.
Ms. Suarez, is there any pain?
I wouldn't have crashed
if you didn't chase me.
Oh, my chest!
Let's move!
CBC, type, cross
and hold four units.
Hook her up to a fetal
monitor. Now, please.
Your baby has a
nice, steady heartbeat.
I'm going to have a boy.
Get a K-&-B. Call
OB for an ultrasound.
Does this hurt?
No.
Any pain in your head?
No. That girl, she
just ran right into me
and didn't even stop.
What about me, man!
Push down with your hand.
Push against it.
Okay, that's good.
Good. Now push
down on your foot,
like on a gas pedal.
Okay. You're doing great.
All right, gently...
Oh! Oh!
What?
You're in labor.
Two centimeters
dilated, 40% effaced.
Can I get somebody
to call my husband?
28 Weeks... that's too early.
You want to stop labor now?
I want to buy some
time for the kid's lungs.
What if it's 34 weeks,
and the baby's fine?
Well, it doesn't feel
like 34 weeks to me.
We need ultrasound.
Can, um...?
It's too early.
We got to try.
Is my baby going to be okay?
Okay, let's try and stop labor.
Bolus her six grams
magnesium sulfate.
Get a fetal lung profile.
Where the hell is OB?
What about me, man?!
Is my baby okay?
It's okay.
Okay.
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.
That's incredible.
It's terrific.
I still can't believe it.
Why didn't you tell
me on the phone?
It's in Milwaukee.
It's only two hours away.
And a federal clerkship, Mark...
I never dreamed I had a chance.
I thought you wanted
to be a state's attorney.
They haven't made an offer.
The judge had a clerk.
Guy backed out
at the last minute.
That's why I'm getting this.
It's a great break for you.
You deserve it.
Thank you.
There's lots of
hospitals in Milwaukee.
Yeah. I don't know
about chief residents
but, um... we could live here.
You could take the train.
Four hours a day on a train?
When am I going to
have time to sleep?
I'd never get to see Rachel.
I'll make some phone calls.
See what they got up there.
I made a lot of
compromises, Mark.
Pistola!
IFue en el pecho!
Doug, they're not stopping.
Contractions two minutes apart.
Doug?
I don't like this.
We're looking at
major lung trouble.
Fetal heart rate?
135 and dropping.
We've got 128.
Late decelerations.
Fetal distress, maybe acidotic.
What's wrong? What's
wrong? Is my baby okay?
Breathe deeply.
We're taking care of your baby.
Her water's broken.
All right. We can't stop this.
Let's go for delivery.
Okay, your baby's coming.
Call OB. Tell them
we're on the way.
Call Neonatal. Tell them to
expect a preemie, 28 weeks.
Call third floor.
Tell them to send
a team to five.
Mrs. Neimeyer,
we're taking you up.
You're going to deliver
your baby right now.
Let's clear that, please.
There you go.
Hey, how's Jennifer?
She got a great
job in Milwaukee.
Oh. Can she do it by phone?
I don't think that's what
the federal judge has in mind.
Milwaukee?
Don't ask. I don't know.
Miss Suarez, you
hit a pregnant woman.
We're not too happy about that,
but we have to take care of you.
Now, you have
to tell us the truth.
Did you take any drugs today?
No.
170/100.
Pulse 120.
Do any cocaine?
Maybe a little crack?
Nah.
Yeah, right.
CBC, tox screen, and
let's get a chest film now.
Will you look at this board?
Don't worry.
It'll get quieter later.
Don't say the "Q" word.
You'll start a stampede.
I'll take the kid in one.
Hey, how's the preemie?
She deliver?
Yeah, right on the elevator.
Baby's in neonatal.
Lungs are bad...
Hyaline membrane.
Mom's okay, though.
Night, Billy.
Dr. Ross?
Can I talk to you for a sec?
Yeah, sure, if you
can keep me awake.
If a patient has, like,
a burning sensation,
does he necessarily have a...?
A sexually-transmitted
disease? Yeah. He probably does.
You have to do a
culture. You ever do that?
No. No? Okay.
First, you got to do
a chlamydia prep.
Then you have to do a gram stain
for gonorrhea.
Stick this bad boy in
about a quarter of an inch,
and then you spin it
around about ten times.
Ten times.
Who's the lucky girl?
Uh... uh, Liz.
The girl with the rash.
Mm-hmm. Old
hospital saying, Carter:
"Don't dip your pen
in company ink."
Oh, hey, I hope
you used a condom.
Carol, we got a code
3 from Rescue 63.
Full arrest.
They're on their way in now.
Can I take her?
Not till her tests are back.
She's breathing, ain't she?
She stole the car,
and hit a pregnant lady.
Yeah, but, for all I know,
she could have
an aortic rupture.
You want her to die in jail?
Frankly, Doc, I
wouldn't lose sleep.
Okay, neither would I.
But I'm liable... you're not.
Mom... Mom, listen.
I can barely hear you.
Got a heart.
Where to?
Trauma two... Last
door on your right.
Susan, we need you.
I got to go. Bye.
Hi.
I'm really okay.
Are you doctors?
I'm Dr. Lewis.
Dr. Greene.
I thought this guy
was in full arrest.
I was, till they
fried my chest hairs.
Let's get a CBC, Chem seven,
blood gas and coag panel.
On my count...
one, two, three.
He was in fib.
Shocked him once.
Converted really fast.
Had 100 milligrams of Lidocaine.
How'd it feel?
Any pain?
I don't remember.
I just sort of passed out.
Can we get a monitor?
Do you have a history of
heart problems, Mr. Gasner?
Nothing that a transplant
wouldn't cure.
I was up for a good one.
A kid in a motorcycle
accident. It went to Minneapolis.
Who's your cardiologist?
Mike Dickey.
Great guy.
He's at Saint
Luke's in Cleveland.
I'm in town for the
Builders' Convention.
My wife said
I shouldn't travel.
But how could I miss 2,000
construction guys in one...
I don't get a pulse.
Mr. Gasner?
Mr. Gasner!
What? He's not in fib.
Give him an amp of EPI.
Come on.
Come on back.
I'll call Cleveland
for his history.
Whoa.
I just pass out.
Start a dopamine drip,
400 in 250 D5W.
Ten drops a minute.
My chest feels like
someone sat on it.
Uh-huh. That happens sometimes.
Yeah, I know.
You got to give her something.
She can't breathe.
Sandy, just keep
taking deep breaths.
Blood gases are back.
Not good.
PO-2's 70.
You taking any medication?
No. It's never been this bad.
Handheld nebs,
Albuterol 2.5 milligrams.
Peak flow, pre and post.
Give her solu-Medrol,
50 milligrams IV.
Can I talk to you
outside just for a second?
Sandy? This is Lydia.
She's going to take care of you.
You're going to be fine, okay?
Just keep breathing, honey.
Keep breathing.
Your daughter's having a
very serious asthma attack.
Is she allergic to anything?
I don't know.
I don't think so.
Do you have any pets?
This cat... a stray.
Sandy found her in the street.
She just loves her.
You'll have to
get rid of the cat.
We need to do some tests.
It's going to take
about two hours. Okay?
Okay.
All right, Sandy...
Gasner, G-A-S-N-E-R.
First name Samuel.
Can you fax us his chart
and have his physician...?
Are you a doctor?
They said my wife was
here. Is she all right?
What's your name, sir?
Neimeyer. She's pregnant.
She was in a car accident.
Is she all right?
Jerry, Mr. Neimeyer.
Hi. Your wife is fine.
I'll take you up to Neonatal.
Neo-what?
You had a baby.
Thanks, Jerry.
It's Dr. Mark Greene,
with an "e" at the end.
He's chief resident.
This convention?
I got a little tired.
Built 15 houses this year.
I wanted to design them
but, uh, I just build them.
Can you stop
talking just a second?
Old inferior wall M.I.
Low voltage.
Consistent with severe myopathy.
I've been through this.
I know what it says.
It's nothing new.
Am I going to make it tonight?
I ask every time.
He's in fib!
Charging.
Ready.
Two hundred. Do it.
Another 50 of Lidocaine.
Start a drip.
Two grams in 500.
Wow. I don't usually do that.
Could somebody
please call my wife?
That's a big, boggy heart.
Suppose we get a transplant.
Is it too late?
He's been defibrillated twice.
He's in cardiogenic shock.
Keeps going in and out.
Can't be much muscle there.
Jerry, call cardiology
for an echo,
and wake up Dr. Flint,
get him down here
from Lake Forest.
Oh, hey, call the
transplant coordinator
and see if they've
got any hearts around.
Your wife called.
Great. I missed calling Rachel.
Lydia, did you get ahold
of the Gasner family?
I'm trying Cleveland
every ten minutes.
Gasner doesn't think he's
going to make it through the night.
Dr. Ross, peak flow's
gone from 190 to 300.
How's her gases?
Much better.
Sandy, you are doing great.
She's going to need an
appointment with your doctor.
She's also going to need an
inhaler at home, and a medication
called Prednisone.
So you fill this
thing out tonight.
Hospital pharmacy
is open 24 hours,
and it's on the first floor.
Okay? There you go.
Thought you were off at 10:00.
I'm on all night.
What are you still doing here?
I'm on a double.
Oh, thank you.
Why is Mark getting messages
from the university hospital
in Milwaukee?
His wife wants to move.
She got a job up there.
Is he going to do it?
I hope not.
Can't imagine he'd
be happy there.
Doesn't he ever go home?
He's waiting for that
gang girl to come
out of recovery.
What's he doing?
Practicing one-handed knots.
He'd do it
with his teeth if he could.
No, I wouldn't. You can't
wear a glove on your teeth.
What are you listening to?
Snoop Doggy Dogg.
Trends in Cardiac
Surgery, Volume 2.
Blood pressure's
falling... 80/60.
Add a Dobutamine
drip, 250 in 250.
4cc's a minute.
I feel crummy...
waiting around for a kid
to smash up his car
so you can get his heart.
We're getting great pictures.
Frame one for me, will you?
How's your heart?
It's in pretty good shape.
Want to lend it to
me for the weekend?
Nah.
You got better
things to do with it.
Do them all.
You never know when
you'll get the chance.
Left ventricle, please.
You got kids, Doc?
A daughter. She's five.
My girl's nine.
At her age, I... I
shouldn't really travel.
I miss too much of her life.
But what can I say?
I love the job.
How you doing, Mr. Gasner?
To tell you the truth,
I felt a hell of a lot
better yesterday.
What's your wife do, Doc?
She's a lawyer.
You guys must
have your hands full.
Did I get any tests back?
On who?
A patient.
Figured that. Does the
patient have a name?
Yeah. It's Carter.
I'll watch out for them.
Thanks. And, Jerry, don't
tell anybody the results.
"Secret's" my middle name.
Gasner, Samuel. We called it in.
Look, it doesn't
have to be perfect.
We'll take any heart.
Anything?
Type "A" blood.
Negative T-cells
crossmatch, okay?
All right. Keep us posted.
We need a heart. Thank you.
He's getting weaker.
I can't pull a heart
out of thin air.
Peter, gunshot
wound to the foot.
The liquor store guy again.
He's asking for you.
Ivan? What does he do,
wear a sign that
says, "Shoot me"?
That hurts.
Ivan, Ivan, Ivan,
who did it this time?
Thought you didn't
have a gun. Me. I did it
I could not take no more.
Bought a little Glock.
Oh, God, it hurts.
Let's get a gram of Ancef
and 150 Gentamicin I.V.
Book an O.R.
Last BP'S a little
high... 180/110.
All right. Ten
Procardia sublingual.
In Russia, it's crazy.
You need case of
vodka to get good doctor.
God bless America.
Yeah, well, God didn't
bless your neighborhood.
I was showing the gun to Nicky,
the dry cleaner, and bang!
Off went half your toe.
I'm going to lose it?
You already did.
Let's go.
Still can't find a donor.
There's one in Cincinnati,
but the blood type is "AB."
How hard is it to
find a type "A" heart?
The patient has advanced
dilated cardiomyopathy
with severe mitral regurgitation
and an ejection fraction
of less than ten percent.
This is not the best
news I've heard all day.
So, Steve, do you
have an opinion?
Dr. Kayson and I
agree on very little,
but we're both happy
not to be Mr. Gasner.
What if we take him upstairs,
put him on a heart-lung bypass
while we look for another donor?
With no muscle left,
I'd say the stress alone
would kill him in
a couple of hours.
I put the transplant
team on call.
You get a heart, we'll put him
on the table in 20 minutes.
Mr. Gasner's wife's on a plane.
She'll be here around 3:00.
Somebody's going to have
to tell them.
Have the desk beep
me when she gets here.
Oh!
Hey, Carter.
Bend over.
There we go.
Oh, I'm cooking now!
All right. Hold still.
Oh! Good one.
Carter, what is he doing?
I lost a bet.
He's my backboard.
Mark,
I'm on a roll here.
Here we go. And the shot!
Oh!
You ruined my concentration.
Oh! Two.
Dr. Ross?
Yeah.
Baby in four.
Seven inches taller,
I would have been a contender.
The Bulls, the Knicks.
Any luck with that heart?
No.
I, uh... I heard your wife
got a job in Milwaukee.
Yeah.
She's clerking
for a federal judge.
That sounds exciting.
It is.
Are you going to
leave the hospital?
I... I don't know.
I thought you were
off at midnight.
Uh... yeah.
Um... yeah, I am.
I just, uh... I just
thought I'd stick around.
You ever have one
like Mr. Gasner before...
One that took so long?
No.
You look like hell, Carter.
Yeah. I'm just waiting
for Dr. Benton to leave.
Mm-hmm. You need some sleep.
Oh, that hurt.
Hmm... well, you've taken
a bad fall, Mrs. Fadem.
I'm going to have
to get some X rays.
No... no X rays.
They'll hurt my baby.
And how long have
you been pregnant?
Six months now.
Well, suppose I promise
that your baby
will be protected.
We'll shield you with lead,
and we'll use a real low dose.
Just as long as you
promise not to hurt my baby.
I promise.
Lydia, would you mind taking
Mrs. Fadem to Radiology?
Oh, and be careful
of her pregnancy.
Right away.
Her what?
Pregnancy.
You worry too much.
Kayson hates me.
He's a cardiologist.
He's on my review board.
I'll need his recommendation.
Why would you want it?
The man loses so many patients,
he gets endorsements
from funeral homes.
Div!
When I was your age,
I worried about what every
attending thought of me, too.
Forget it. You're a good doctor.
You're better than my ex,
and I actually married her.
Div, there are a lot of
subjects that interest me
and, believe me, your
ex-wife tops my list.
Ah! That's me.
My knife-wielding psychotic
must be up from his nap.
Later.
Your wife's on her way.
She'll be a wreck.
He's not putting out fluids.
160 of Lasix.
Hey, Doc...
do I look stupid?
Why don't you tell me?
You versus God...
We know who wins.
I don't think of it that way.
Yeah? You don't have to.
I'm the one on the table.
We looked at your echo
and, if we don't
find a donor heart,
you probably won't make it
through the night, Mr. Gasner.
It's 2:00 in the morning.
I'm dying.
So, please...
call me Sam.
This is no time to be formal.
Don't forget to check
on Ivan before you go.
Can I take the Suarez girl now?
The gangbanger?
Aortic rupture.
I forgot to tell you.
She died in recovery.
Ah. Well...
I'll see you at 7:00.
A.M.? That's five hours.
Why bother driving home?
Three hours sleep,
I get to come back.
Quinn, Daniel. Hypotensive...
80/70, comatose.
Fraternity kid.
Drinking all night.
Ever see anybody intubated?
Uh... no.
Get Respiratory in here.
Carter, set a second line.
D-50, one amp, 2
milligrams Narcan.
Pam, get an EKG.
Mr. Quinn,
do you hear me? Daniel?
Respiratory's on the way.
He's cyanotic.
Speed up the drip.
Add dopamine.
Hyperventilate him.
Line's in, Susan.
BP is 70/40 and falling.
Get a CBC, blood alcohol,
Chem seven and tox screen.
Let's tube him.
Blood SAT's 80.
Do a dextrose stick.
Okay, Carter,
pay attention.
This is where it counts.
Visualize the cords.
You don't want
to miss the trachea
and end up in his esophagus.
Okay.
It's in.
Bag him.
Listen to the lungs
and the abdomen
to make sure the
tube's in place.
Glucose is normal.
BP is steady, 80/65.
That's nice.
Draw a blood gas now.
Doug, they called from Neonatal
if you want to take a look
at the Neimeyer preemie.
He's going to be okay.
God smiled on him.
Since when do
you believe in God?
I've been contemplating my
insignificance in the universe.
I thought you were the
center of the universe.
Not always.
Are you a doctor? I'm
looking for Dr. Ross.
He's in the emergency room.
Yeah. I'm Dr. Ross.
Thank you very much!
I can't thank you enough.
You're welcome.
Who are you?
Oh, I'm Randy Neimeyer...
My wife, my baby.
They said you took her up.
My little boy's
going to be okay.
In fact, I'm just on my way up
to see your baby right now.
You want to...?
Yeah, yeah.
Okay.
Yeah.
We're hydrating like crazy,
and his blood
pressure's not moving.
Order LFTs, B.U.N.
and creatinine.
His friend's here.
He says the guy didn't
have that much to drink.
Yeah, and the Cubs are
a shoo-in for the pennant.
This is Elliot.
This is Dr. Lewis.
Can you tell me how much
Mr. Quinn drank tonight?
We were playing this
game... Whale's Tales.
You say numbers
around the table.
If you can't remember
them, you have to drink.
How much did Mr. Quinn drink?
Listen, his father's
an assistant dean.
If he finds out about...
What was he drinking,
and how much?
Beer.
Beer and shots of tequila.
He must have had 15, 20 shots.
Did he do any drugs? No.
Will he be all right?
I hope so.
Blood alcohol's back... 832.
Call dialysis.
Let them know we're on the way.
Let's move him.
Mrs. Gasner.
I'm Elaine Gasner.
This is Sarah.
Hi, Sarah.
I'm Dr. Greene.
Sit down, honey.
Where's my husband?
Can I see him?
He's sleeping.
I need to tell you
about his condition.
His heart muscle is
badly deteriorated.
They said he could
get a transplant.
If there was one available.
There isn't one tonight.
He can wait
till they find one.
Your husband's heart is failing.
Unless we find a heart donor
in the next couple of hours,
I don't believe he'll make it
through the night.
I'm sorry.
Sam?
Mark.
Your wife
and daughter are here.
I was thinking.
Did you hear the one...
about the guy on
the country road?
Flat tire...
doesn't have a jack.
Never mind.
You think you can avoid it.
It all counts.
Decisions you don't make.
The real joke is...
I'm still going to die.
I guess I'm
getting ready for it.
I'm not ready.
Damn it, I'm not!
I don't want to leave them.
Sarah needs me.
Could you please have
my wife bring Sarah in?
Sure.
Don't say it.
What?
That I should be
grateful to be alive.
That's not what I was thinking.
What were you thinking?
I don't know.
Is there any chance?
Type "A", negative
crossmatch, 43 years old.
He can handle the surgery.
It just seems that
marriage should be easier.
I never heard it called easy.
Sometimes I think we did it
just to make our parents happy.
You're good at
making people happy.
Not this week.
What?
Well, how soon will you know?
19-Year-old, flatline EEG.
They can't find the
parents to sign a release.
So, what are you going
to do about Milwaukee?
I can be a junior resident
at a suburban hospital.
That would do
wonders for your career.
It all counts.
What?
Nothing.
Oh, Susan, your dialysis
kid's coming around.
Good.
Well, can you keep trying?
Yeah, I need that heart.
Thanks.
Jerry, can you do me a favor
and get a hotel for Mrs.
Gasner and her daughter?
Sure.
You okay, Dr. Greene?
I'm fine, Jerry. Thanks.
Dr. Ross?
Lydia, what is a
seven-letter word for "dumb"
beginning with an "M"?
Moronic.
Your asthma patient's back.
She tried to sleep.
Where's the inhaler?
I'll check the dose.
I didn't get it.
Your daughter's
having another attack.
I told you to fill out
that prescription tonight.
She could have died.
You understand that?
The medicine cost $30.
I don't have the money,
and Medicaid don't come
through for another week.
I'll be back.
Carol, do we have
a spare inhaler?
Just the one.
If he's that bad,
he should come in.
What about Proventil samples?
Nope.
We can't diagnose
over the phone.
If that's what you want to do.
Thank you.
Prednisone... any of that?
Plenty. It's on the top shelf.
It's going to take
more than this
to get her through the week.
You seem awfully interested.
She must be very pretty.
She's 12.
I'll see what
else I can turn up.
Jerry, I don't get it.
I sent that gram stain ages ago,
and it's not back yet?
Who was that for again?
Mine. For me.
Ah, yes.
Came in about 3:00.
Where is it, Jerry?
Bulletin board.
Excuse me.
You got to do something.
I feel like I'm going
to throw up.
Well, we wouldn't want that.
Not here in the hall.
Come with me.
Hi, John.
Hi, puppy.
You're up pretty late.
I fell asleep on the plane.
Did you have fun
with Grandma?
She gave me a present.
Blood SAT's 80%.
15 liters O-2.
What did you get?
A diary.
Grandma made the cover herself.
Grandma likes to
make things for you.
My mom says my
dad's going to die.
Yes, he is.
Why can't you fix him?
We can't fix everything.
I can breathe now.
We don't have a spare inhaler.
Take the Prednisone every day,
and you visit the clinic
first thing in the morning.
Tomorrow? I can't go tomorrow.
Well, you have
to. It's important.
I got to go to work.
It's only my second week.
Dr. Ross?
There's a kid
throwing up in three.
Okay. You're going to
have to take off work.
I can't.
Your daughter has to have
the medication. It
has to be done. Okay?
So do it.
I know...
I know.
I forgot a long time ago.
I was always sure of you.
You never let me down.
Sam? Sam!
Sam?
Please! Please, I have
to tell him one more thing.
You have to make him hear me!
Sam?
Elaine...
Forever, honey.
Forever.
Sarah will be fine.
Remind her I love her.
Sam! Sam. Sam...
Mr. Quinn?
Daniel?
I'm Dr. Lewis.
You're on dialysis because
you drank too much.
Would you blink if
you understand me?
We'll be taking that tube
out of your windpipe soon.
Your kidneys are functioning,
your liver's fine,
and you lost a few
million brain cells,
but you can spare them.
Blink if you will
never do this again.
Playing one-on-one
against yourself
is the easy way.
Here you go.
Come on.
Come on, you wussy!
Get by me.
I'm the short guy.
But you said you could
have been a contender.
You distracted me.
It's the game.
What do you want?
Can I borrow 40 bucks?
For what?
I got to run an errand.
Thank you, sir.
Go home, Mark.
This will get your daughter
through the next three weeks.
Make sure that she uses
the inhaler every day,
and bring her back if
she's not feeling better.
You bought this yourself.
I'll get her to the
clinic, I promise.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Honey...
Hi.
What time is it?
It's 7:30.
I was thinking about Milwaukee.
And... I know it will be hard.
It's okay. Don't worry about it.
But, if you want me to go...
I'll go.
No. You'd hate it.
It's not a big deal.
It's only two hours away.
I love you.
Love you, too.
Daddy, you're home!
Hi, sweetheart.
Come on in.
Come here.
Hi.
I am so glad to see you.
Daddy, what's wrong?
Nothing's wrong.
Nothing's wrong, okay?