Previously, on "ER."
You wanna catch
a movie tomorrow?
Okay.
You actually applied
to the space program?
My second year
of residency.
Tonight's dinner
is semi‐formal
so, uh, any slinky
black number will do.
So, you want me to conduct
a study at County General.
And the drug is for the
treatment of fracture pain?
Mm‐hmm, comparing it against
acetaminophen with codeine.
Joi, what's your son's
medical condition?
ALD, adrenoleukodystrophy.
‐ How old is he?
‐ Eight, why?
They usually don't make
it past the age of ten.
‐ This must be Ricky, I'm Carol.
‐ Hi.
You know, I could've just taken
Lucy out for a pizza.
That's what all
my residents did for me
when I finished a rotation.
No, in my day,
residents always had
their students
over for a meal.
Makes for better mentoring.
That's why I invited
Peter Benton to join us.
‐ Dr. Benton's coming?
‐ 'Sure.'
He was your resident.
Now Lucy's working with him.
It's much more civilized to..
John, no!
No, no, no, no.
I thought the peppers
went in the blender.
No, we want separate colors
for the sauce.
‐ Good save.
‐ Yeah.
You cool
and peel them first.
Why don't you seed
the Persian cukes?
You know, it's funny.
I'm actually gonna miss
havin' Lucy around.
That's how it works.
The instant, students know
enough to be of use
they move to
another rotation.
Okay, lengthwise,
lengthwise.
‐ Oops.
‐ Yeah.
Lengthwise.
And then you
seed them, okay?
You know, emergency
medicine may not be
a bad choice for Lucy.
Well, she might
feel differently
after she has her
surgical rotation.
You know what,
why don't you..
...why don't you chill
the Pinot Grigio?
In the, uh,
in the freezer?
Keep your day job, Carter.
Let's see how
you handle these.
Got it?
Alright, let's do it.
Do you have inside
information on this new drug?
This stuff really
works well for him?
Oh, it's amazing,
Aaron broke his arm
a couple of years ago,
the pain was excruciating.
But, this, I'd like
to buy stock in it.
"This" may just be
acetaminophen with codeine.
No way, I‐I know
that some patients
in the study aren't
getting the wonder drug
but Aaron is
and it's remarkable stuff.
They really keep
you docs in the dark?
Yeah, it's a double‐blind study
so, you're gonna have
to get your insider trading
from somebody else.
‐ See you in three weeks.
Hey, Doug, Jeanie called.
She's gonna be late.
‐ Probably stuck in the snow.
‐ Actually, she overslept.
‐ Had a late night.
‐ I wish we'd overslept.
We are going to kick‐start
the A. M. with a wake‐up call
from my main men,
Hetfield and Hammett.
Lynette, I didn't
expect to see you today.
‐ The clinic's closed.
‐ Oh.
I, uh, organized a seminar
on STD's and cervical cancer.
Kind of like a gab session
for the women in the community.
Oh, that's a great idea.
Is that Metallica?
Lynette, you're a metalhead?
‐ You know this tune?
‐ Yeah.
'Cause it's banned
in my house.
Well, I thought that,
you know, women should
know more about screening
and prevention.
Oh, absolutely. I just, I wish
I could pay you overtime.
Oh, don't worry about it.
I scored some grant money
to pay for it.
‐ Really?
‐ Uh‐huh.
It's going to run
through the clinic?
Yeah, I got lucky.
Caught some dribbles
off the gravy train.
Mark.
‐ I thought that was you.
‐ Hi, Donald.
Listen, I got your, uh,
memo about the NASA offer.
Yeah, opportunity
just came out of the blue.
It's a full year
of training in Houston?
Yeah, it could be 18 months
if they delay the launch.
‐ Don't do it.
‐ What?
Well, I mean, obviously,
do what you must
but I wish you wouldn't.
You kept me awake
last night.
I kept you awake?
I do not want to run
the emergency department
without you.
What'll it take
to get you to stay?
Uh, full tenure,
effective today.
Well, I probably
can't swing that
but I, uh, I could
push up your eligibility
consider you in 0‐2.
2002?
Or two? Is somebody
going to tell us
what to call the future
or is it every man for himself?
You'd consider me
for tenure
in three years?
We need you.
Think about it.
'I think you have
a flair for this.'
Yes, I think I've found
my niche, pulling drains.
Just make sure you
get the penrose
and not the t‐tube.
Pull that,
it's not a pretty sight.
Ah, Ms. Knight, I see you
found your way to Dr. Corday.
Absolutely,
all the pre‐op labs
were in the charts
when I arrived.
‐ I nearly kissed her.
‐ Oh.
No, None of that,
not unless I get to watch.
I, uh, insisted
that you get a decent student.
I knew that you could use
some backup with the scut.
And I live for scut.
If Ms. Knight actually helps
you get finished early
I'd like you to assist
this afternoon
on a choledochojejunostomy.
Choledochojejunostomy?
Well, you can say it.
Would you like to do it?
I'm waiting for the
other shoe to drop.
No, no catch.
You've suffered enough.
'I started the groundwork
today to see'
if we can't get
your fellowship reinstated.
You deserve it.
Well, I'll be damned.
So, should I feel special
or does he stare
at everyone's breasts?
No, only the females.
As far as I know.
'Well, if it's good
for the clinic.'
It's your clinic,
You have the right to know
what grants are applied
for in its name.
Yeah, but Lynette does
have some good ideas.
And you are the boss.
You get to say yes or no.
Jerry, what the
hell is that?
That is part of our
new music program.
Really, you call
that music?
I told you to start
with Erykah Badu.
It's for the patients in chairs.
Music helps people handle
the stress of waiting.
I thought you were getting
ready to DJ a party.
That's just a coincidence.
Somebody signed off on this.
‐ Who signed off on this?
‐ Dr. Lee.
Jerry, there is no Dr. Lee.
There never was a Dr. Lee.
Is that siren in the music or is
there an ambulance pulling up?
It's in the music.
We could use some help here.
Jerry, turn the music down
and give Connie and me a hand.
Oh, boy.
Gird your loins.
36‐year‐old woman found down
at the scene of a kitchen fire.
‐ This is one big woman.
‐ Probable anaphylaxis.
Her med‐alert bracelet
said peanut allergy.
Gave her ten of valium
and tubed her.
Alright, don't pull
until we get a good grip.
Should I get
another gurney?
Yeah, a double‐wide
and a winch.
I hope the wheels
don't snap.
Trauma one,
I'll be right there.
Talk me to Doris,
what is this?
The second victim
is Fred Danziger.
‐ I'm fine, doc.
‐ Short of breath.
He singed his moustache
putting out the flames.
These paramedics overreact.
It's the first call this week
where something was on fire
and she drags me away
at the drop of a hat.
She could be right, okay?
Singed facial hair
could mean a burned airway.
Chuny, let's put
Fred on a pulse ox.
‐ And get a chest x‐ray.
‐ You bet.
I really had to force
him to come in here.
This new policy sucks.
Adding paramedics
to fire trucks?
Yeah and the
guys resent it.
You know, they're firefighters,
so, they blame me
for having to answer
so many medical calls.
Nobody likes change.
You did the right thing.
So, you passed out
and took a fall?
Angie...found me.
Is Angie your
home health aide?
She was.
They burn out
fast with me.
Did you see my chart?
Yes, sir,
pancreatic cancer
and mets to the liver.
I keep hoping that
end stage means it..
..can't get any worse.
The nausea pretty bad?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Okay.
We're going to hydrate you,
see if that helps.
Would you like me to put
your own robe back on?
It can get pretty
chilly in here.
Did...did Angie
call my son?
I can find out.
Is that yours?
Ten years ago..
...I kicked my son out
of the house over this stuff.
Now, I depend on him
to get it for me.
Helps with the nausea?
Do you have
to take it?
Take what?
Ms. Meredith,
can you open your eyes?
She's been unresponsive
since the valium.
Pulse ox is 99 percent.
Can you imagine lugging
around all this fat?
Didn't stop her from hitting
the udon noodles at 9 A. M.
Does radiology
stock a extra
extra large?
Better call
the vet school.
Okay, everybody,
settle down.
Ms. Meredith, you've had
a bad allergic reaction.
So, you have a tube in your
mouth helping you to breathe.
‐ BP's 90/60.
‐ Yeah.
Let's start dopamine
at five mics per kilo.
‐ How many kilos?
‐ You want a calculator?
‐ What do you think, 275 pounds?
‐ Oh, I'll take the over.
‐ Hey, were you looking for me?
‐ Yeah, Carter.
Uh, Connie,
start her at 750 mics.
Let me know how she does.
You're gonna be fine.
We've got it under control.
I wanted to let you know
that as part of your workload
you're gonna teach
patient‐doctor class
to second‐year students.
‐ Patient‐doctor class?
‐ Yeah.
Students practice H and P's
on simulated patients.
No, I remember, you used
bad actors to come in
and pretend like
they're sick, I hated it.
Yeah, well,
why is that?
I don't know,
'cause it's fake.
Everybody knows
it's fake.
The students know
‐ It's a waste of time.
‐ Yeah.
Well, starting tomorrow
you're gonna learn to
hate it all over again.
It'll sharpen your
teaching skills.
Hey, did, uh..
...Lucy give me
a bad evaluation?
Lucy gave you a
fair evaluation.
I'll put the teaching
guide in your box.
Patient collapsed
push‐starting a car.
Slurred speech
and right‐side weakness
Resolved in 30 minutes.
‐ Suggesting?
‐ A TIA.
Dr. Corday ordered
a Doppler ultrasound
of his carotid arteries.
Which demonstrates what?
A 50 percent lesion
on the left side.
Is this
a surgical candidate?
Uh, he's pretty old.
How old? You said
he was push‐starting a car.
He claims not to know
his exact age.
Yeah, well, wasn't your
civil war in the 1860's?
According to Mr. Barnes,
he's roughly a 140.
Hey, Elizabeth,
did you get my message?
‐ Is now a good time?
‐ I'm not sure.
Yeah, go ahead, Ms. Knight
and I can handle this.
Peter, 8 o'clock
tonight, right?
I don't know
if I can make it.
Yeah, we need
to compile
our sternal saw data
by tomorrow.
Mr. Barnes, what are you
doing out of bed?
I asked you
to call me Charley.
Sir, you have to stay
in your gown
so Dr. Benton
can examine you.
‐ Is that you?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
I don't mean
no disrespect
but when you get
to be my age
and you loll around in bed,
them rheumatoids kick in
and pretty soon
you can't move at all.
Unfortunately, you
have blockage
in your neck artery.
It puts you at risk
for a stroke.
No, no, no,
I can't have that.
Too many people
counting on me.
Charley helps the older people
in his neighborhood.
'And the children.'
I mean 'cause they
need sitters.
Those people
working all day.
Are you, uh,
her teacher?
At the moment.
Then you know,
you and I
we have the responsibility
to pass on what life
has taught us.
Can you, uh,
fix me up?
Well, there is
a surgical option
but I'd hesitate
to use it on someone..
Well, someone your age.
Oh, you ain't ever seen
a patient my age.
You don't have to worry.
I can't be killed
'cause I got
a conjure on me.
I don't know
what that means.
Of course, you don't.
'Cause you are
a man of science.
How else are you
going to explain
my being alive at all
when every other body
all the ones
from slavery times
done died..
...50 and 60
years ago?
Ms. Knight,
what would you suggest?
I'd call a
psych consult.
Is that the doc
for loonies?
Uh...yes, sir.
Yeah, yes, it is.
Uh‐huh.
He's outrageous.
He can be tasteless.
He certainly likes
to throw his weight around
but, uh..
So you can't corroborate
any instances
of‐of sexual harassment?
It's a very, um..
It's a very American thing,
if I may say.
This‐this penchant for turning
personal issues into lawsuits.
The hospital's hope,
of course, is for me
as omsbudsperson
to address problems
and avoid lawsuits.
No, one has to be thick‐skinned
working around Dr. Romano
but, uh, you roll
with the punches, don't you?
Whoever is complaining
may be too fragile
to practice
medicine at all.
Her identity
is confidential
until I can assess
if any action is warranted.
It's a delicate business.
Rarely, do I hear
the kind of slam dunk
where Dr. So‐and‐so made
overt sexual advances.
'She declined and then
he either fired her'
'or cut her funds.'
Right.
‐ Uh, Kerry.
‐ 'Hmm?'
Is Robert aware
of this complaint?
He doesn't know who came to me
although, he could
figure it out
since my first response
is to prevent
the parties
from working together.
I see.
It's my fault,
I let it go on too long.
It's not your fault.
I'm going to start a line.
‐ Joi, what's going on?
‐ Remember Ricky?
He hasn't had a bowel movement
in three days.
Joi got worried
when his temp
spiked to 101.
Oh, my god,
I let him get septic.
I've always been able
to disimpact him before.
‐ You disimpact him at home?
‐ Yeah.
I just usually use
a glove and Vaseline
but I couldn't do
it this time.
The morphine's
made him constipated.
Why is he on morphine?
He's having pain
from contractures.
That's what I think.
Ricky stopped speaking
about a week ago.
I'm sorry.
He still opens
his eyes sometimes.
And is the morphine
working for the pain?
I don't know.
Oh, God!
‐ It's alright, I got it.
‐ Oh, my..
I'm sorry.
It's just..
I..
I know, I know.
After everything
he's been through
I fall apart over this.
It's okay, it's okay.
I know.
When we got
to Michigan Avenue
he just passed out.
How long ago did
he hit his head?
Four hours,
He was fixing
a flood light
over our garage
and the ladder slipped,
but he seemed okay.
He just had a headache.
Whenever you have
a head injury
it's best to call
the paramedics.
I did call.
Paramedics
didn't show up?
'No, they came.'
but Jim seemed okay.
And then there
was a fire somewhere
and they got called away.
Jerry's gonna show you
where you can
park your car.
Jerry, I want you
to call dispatch.
Find out which unit responded
to the Haggertys' call.
Done.
Ricky's resting.
His fever is due
to an ear infection.
They're treating it
with antibiotics.
Oh, thank you, Carol,
for everything.
Oh, sure,
Dr. Ross will be
out here in a minute
to talk to you about it.
You always see me
when I'm such a wreck.
I usually cope
much better.
Well, sometimes coping
too much
can drive you crazy.
I meant to send you
a thank‐you note.
The respite care
has been wonderful.
Oh, good. Did you get
to your daughter's recital?
Hmm, and I had the worker
come back another time
just so I could
take a bath.
‐ Good for you.
‐ Yeah.
We had some
great news last week.
My daughter's
blood test came back.
‐ She's not a carrier.
‐ Oh, that's a relief.
Oh, thank God, she'll never
do this to her kids.
Joi?
Uh, we're going
to keep him here
until his fever
comes down.
I'll see you
before you go, okay?
‐ Okay.
‐ Hm‐hmm.
Does this mean
we have to reduce
Ricky's morphine
to prevent
this happening
again or..
Well, that's one thing
we could do.
This was the hardest
part with Michael.
I lost Ricky's older brother
to ALD three years ago.
Right.
And now, he can't
tell me it hurts.
Somehow, it's worse
to see him suffering.
Let me check,
There may be something else
we can do for the pain.
‐ Okay.
I'm in.
Hyperventilate him.
BP 160/90, pulse 60,
Mannitol's in.
Mrs. Haggerty, your husband
has a blown pupil.
I'm worried the bleeding
in his skull
could be putting
pressure on his brain.
‐ Oh, no.
‐ 'CT's ready.'
We're gonna get a head CT
to find out what's going on.
Malik, take Mrs. Haggerty
to the chairs.
Chuny, call neurosurgery
down here right away.
Okay.
Elizabeth, I was afraid you
wouldn't be joining us.
I'm looking
forward to it.
You don't see a
choledochojejunostomy every day.
When they shuffled
the surgical schedule yesterday
I was afraid,
I was going to miss out.
Yeah, I'm sorry about that.
The resident
let the patient eat
and we had to postpone.
It's a problem sometimes
with residents rotating
in from other departments.
They're either not up to it
or they simply don't care.
‐ Who was this resident?
‐ Uh.
Third year from
the emergency department.
Uh, Doyle.
‐ Maggie Doyle?
‐ Hmm.
'They think very highly
of her down there.'
I believe she's being
considered for chief resident.
Pickings must be
pretty slim this year.
I've always found her
to be extremely capable.
Huh! I understand she makes
a lot of women uncomfortable.
Anyway, this is
going to be nifty.
Uh, the ultrasound
showed stones
in the common
bile duct distal
to the
sphincter of oddi.
No kidding.
I'm telling you, my whole team
is tied up in the OR.
I'm telling you that someone
needs to scrub out and join us.
Well, that's why
you have to wait.
Look at the size
of that blood clot.
It's compressing
his brain.
Every second counts.
Chuny,
shave the scalp.
Malik, open
the burr hole tray.
You can't do
burr holes in the ER.
Well, you're not giving
me any choice, are you?
Hey, what size gloves
do you take?
I am not comfortable with this.
We can't wait without risking
permanent brain damage.
Well, I'll try again
to get someone down.
Number 12 blade.
Pulse is down to 55.
Self‐retaining retractor.
This is a big mistake.
Pressure's up to 180/95.
That's the cushing response.
He's gonna herniate
unless, we relieve
the pressure.
Periosteal elevator.
My chief can be down
in 20 minutes.
Too long.
Hudson brace
and perforator.
I can see
the skull fracture line.
ABG is back.
PH 7.51, PC02 is 25,
P02 is 350.
That's what we want.
Okay. I'm ready
for the burr hole.
Can't you wait a few minutes?
Keep the irrigation coming.
I need to see
what I'm doing.
Please?
Not too deep.
It's okay.
I'm through
the inner table.
Okay, there's
the clot.
I need a dural
suction catheter.
Pulse up to 170.
BP's 140/70.
'Pupils are equal.'
'That's more like it.'
Wet sterile gauze.
Let's get him
up to the OR.
I'll alert the team.
Tell them to
take their time.
Hey, Dr. Greene.
‐ Nice job.
‐ Alright.
Hey, Mark.
‐ Got time for a quick question?
‐ Yeah, sure.
How do I account
for a broken container
in the fracture study?
‐ One of the vials busted?
‐ Yeah.
The powder...spilled
in the envelope.
Ah, I'd just make
a note of it.
It shouldn't
be a problem.
We haven't enlisted
as many patients
as anticipated.
We probably won't use
all the samples they sent.
That's what
I wanted to know.
You going to make
your lecture?
Isn't the guy from NASA
going at the med school today?
Oh, right.
I almost forgot.
Mrs. Haggerty, your husband
has been stabilized
and sent up to the OR.
What?
Jerry.
Uh, your husband
has been sent up
to the surgical floor,
so I'm going to find
somebody to take
you up there.
I'll take her up.
Dr. Greene stabilized
your husband.
He's doing fine.
Jerry, did you find out
which paramedic unit
left Mr. Haggerty
with a brain bleed?
Yeah, dispatch said it
was an engine company
that went out
and Doris Pickman
was the paramedic
on board.
‐ Oh, boy.
‐ Yeah.
They said that the deputy chief
will take care of it from here.
Ah, I‐I don't want him
to handle it.
Listen, call dispatch back
and tell them
that I'm gonna follow up.
‐ Okay.
‐ Oh and Jerry.
If you put
that music back on
you're fired.
I'm sorry it's
taking so long.
But since we put
my fingertip on ice
it'll be okay, right?
Like I told your dad
there's a possibility
we won't be able
to re‐attach.
‐ We'll let the surgeon decide.
‐ Hey.
Don't tell me you're still
waiting on plastics.
Yup, I called again.
They swore he's on his way.
Hey, did you find
another candidate
for that fracture study?
No, just recording
a broken container.
‐ Is he a plastic surgeon?
‐ No, I'm sorry.
You thirsty?
You want something to drink?
My dad's
getting me a coke.
Okay.
It shouldn't be
that much longer now.
Did you find my son?
His office said he was
out on a sales call
and he's not picking
up his cell phone.
We'll keep trying.
Thank you.
Is the Zofran
helping the nausea?
No.
Okay, I'm gonna ask
the docs to add Reglan.
Don't bother.
They...they
don't work.
Any chance you could..
...wheel me outside
for some fresh air?
Mr. Ackerman..
...I can't take you outside
to smoke marijuana.
And maybe when your son arrives,
he can help you out.
‐ I'm really sorry.
‐ Don't..
Don't be.
I'm probably not able
to inhale anyway.
'The neuromuscular response
can be studied'
since there's no gravitational
force in the usual Z‐axis
from head to toe.
Gentleman in the back.
What are the applications
of this study?
The loss of muscle tone
in microgravity
is an issue that sci‐fi movies
have largely ignored.
Cosmonauts who spent months
on the Mir mission
had to be carried from
their spacecraft upon return.
'Now I'd like
to kick off the Q and A'
'with a question to you.'
What is it that interested you
in the astronaut program?
And I ask...because a lot of
candidates will admit
to childhood dreams
of adventure
the adrenaline of takeoff,
the vastness of space.
Sir, the doctor
who just walked in.
'Would you care to respond?'
Well, uh, for me, it was
pretty much, uh..
...adventure.
You know,
the adrenaline of takeoff
vastness of outer space.
Thank you
for your candor, doctor..
Mark Greene.
Ah, Dr. Greene.
Doug Lowrey wanted me
to look you up.
'Dr. Greene may be joining us
as a payload specialist.'
'But the real picture
of your schedule'
'should you make it
on a mission'
'is one of routine.'
'In training, you'll
spend an entire year'
'repeating the same
daily tasks'
'following checklists,
adapting to a regimen.'
'Everything you do is dictated
by the ground crew.'
'You follow a precise,
minute‐to‐minute itinerary.'
'There aren't even windows
in the mid‐deck..'
I'm sorry to disturb you,
Dr. Greene.
I didn't know
what else to do.
I‐I know I screwed up
really bad but the guy
seemed fine at the scene
and when the engine
got the fire call,
the guys were all so jazzed.
I told the wife
to bring the guy in‐‐
Doris, slow down.
Um, how's Mr. Haggerty?
He had an epidural hematoma,
but he should be okay.
The deputy chief
pulled me off active duty
and they're gonna start
a formal investigation.
‐ What?
‐ He's worried about bad press.
You know, "Fire engine leaves
an accident scene?"
Wait, that's a medical error.
I should make that call.
You know, maybe I was influenced
by the firefighters.
I knew that they really
wanted to get to that fire
and I know that that
shouldn't cloud my judgment.
But an investigation
is going to ruin my record.
Doris, take a breath.
I'll see what I can do.
‐ Will you?
‐ I'll call the deputy chief.
‐ Come on, doc.
‐ I'm not gonna do that.
No, you heard me.
Roll up your sleeves.
Come on.
I'm not gonna
arm wrestle with you
over whether you can
have surgery.
‐ Oh, you scared to?
‐ Yeah. Yeah, yeah, I am.
Well, I want the surgery.
That's all there is to it.
And that one doctor
calculated that
I was fit
in the head.
Yeah, well, that's because you
didn't bother to mention
to him you thought
you were at Appomattox.
But there was another
doctor who also said
my FEV 1
was over
120 percent.
Now, I think
that's darn good.
They cleared you
physically for surgery.
No, see now you're giving me
that second‐rate pill idea.
I know you think the medical
treatment isn't that convincing
but I've got to use
my better judgment.
No, your judgment needs
to put your arm next to mine
clasping my hand
and we will a‐arm wrestle
because you'll
find out that old Charley
is not as weak
and puny as you think.
I never said..
I don't think you're puny.
But you don't believe
I can't die.
Mm‐hmm.
Don't believe that one, either.
Thank you.
I'll give you something
you can believe.
Just...put your elbow
right here.
‐ Come on.
‐ Mr. Barnes, come on.
Listen, if you don't give
a man his measure of respect
and you don't
believe his history
then you're talking
about a fight.
Oh, come on.
Don't make your elder beg.
Come on, huh?
Huh?
Yeah.
Go.
‐ Come on!
‐ Dr. Benton.
There is an OR available.
Hey, hey, hey.
Don't humor me now.
Oh, boy!
You win.
Nah.
Alright, go ahead.
‐ 'Book the OR.'
‐ 'Yeah.'
It's a brand‐new policy, putting
paramedics on fire trucks.
It's gonna take a little
while to work the kinks out.
But I know Doris Pickman,
I work with her day to day
and she deserves to be
counseled, not put on a desk.
No, no, no,
this is my job, and..
‐ Is Doug Ross around?
‐ Uh, try admit.
Deputy Chief Mead, please.
It's Mark Greene again.
Doug.
Hey, Heather, they let you
out of the lab, huh?
Oh, I make special deliveries
for some customers.
We got the toxicology results
on that powder you brought us.
‐ Yeah, great.
‐ It's negative for codeine.
Mm‐hmm.
‐ Is that all you needed?
‐ That'll do it.
When I heard you
hand‐carried it, I thought
well...maybe you were...
back in the market.
Me?
Uh, no, I‐‐
Doug, uh, I called
the handi‐van for the Abbotts
and Joi said you were
getting her a prescription.
Okay.
I'm on my way.
‐ Nice to see you.
‐ See you later.
Ricky's temp is 98.8...
which is good.
Now, you know, back there,
that was nothing, right?
Huh?
Yeah.
Hey, Kerry, uh..
...I'm afraid Lynette has
appropriated the lounge.
Yeah, I guess the staff
will have to gossip
someplace else for
an hour, huh?
‐ You knew about it?
‐ Yeah.
She showed me
her proposal last week.
I think it's a good area
for the clinic to get into.
'I know you can tell
if he's cheating, but‐‐'
'Alright, hold on,
your man don't take'
'a shower before he leaves
the house'
but he does take one
when he gets home?
‐ He's cheating.
‐ Cheating on her.
Tara's right.
The number of partners
you have and he has
can definitely put you at risk
for cervical cancer.
Put you at risk
for being a damn fool, too.
'The other risk factor
is how young you were'
when you started having sex
and if you smoke.
That's right.
Uh, this is Carol Hathaway.
She runs the clinic here.
Nice to meet you all.
'Oh, carry on.'
I think it's a really important
topic to be informed about
and, um...please feel free
to come and see us
at the clinic anytime.
Thanks, Carol.
My apologies for the delay.
I'm Dr. Baker.
Hi. Jeanie Boulet.
This is Donna.
Her father should
be back soon.
‐ This is the x‐ray, Ms. Boulet?
‐ Yes.
I did a digital nerve block
with Marcaine.
Mm‐hmm, amputation is midway
through the distal phalanx.
We'll need to rongeur
and do a V‐Y flap.
You can put
it back on, right?
No. Not with a cut
at this level.
The blood vessels
are too small.
Did you explain to her?
I told her
it may be a possibility.
Mm‐hmm.
But you guys put
arms and stuff back on.
'That's true.'
If you'd cut your
finger at the base
we'd have bigger arteries
to work with.
'For this, we'll...
trim down the bone'
and create a flap
over the defect.
You mean, I'll have a stump?
Maybe we should talk
to Donna's father.
Yes, if we can get
a trauma room
I'll do the procedure
right away.
Don't worry, Donna. We'll make
you a small prosthetic tip.
I'm just saying, man,
oldies are played out.
People like the classics
mixed in.
Not ones you
can't dance to.
Yeah, I think you're
gonna lose 'em.
Jerry, what is this?
What, you said you wanted
the rap turned off, right?
No, actually, I said
we need a desk clerk here.
‐ Not a DJ.
‐ Fine. It's gone.
It's no more.
Forever gone.
You know, what possessed you
to pick that particular song?
I don't know.
Just instinct, you know?
‐ I'm just going with the flow.
‐ Uh‐huh.
My mom used to play this album
all the time when I was a kid.
'It was always, like..'
'...the ultimate freedom.'
You know, leave ground
control behind
and just float away.
‐ Escape?
‐ Yeah.
Hey, the folks
in the waiting area
wanna know if you could
put Bowie back on?
Jerry, do whatever
you want, okay?
Just use your
best judgment.
Alright, now,
you give this to him
every six hours, if needed.
You don't exceed
four doses in 24 hours.
And you call me if it
isn't working for him.
Watch your head.
Why didn't the genetics clinic
suggest this medication?
Well, it's brand‐new. It's still
part of a clinical trial.
We've had a lot of luck
with kids with fractures.
Perfectly safe for Ricky.
It might give
him some relief.
Do I need to fill on
any of this out?
Um, I wouldn't bother.
He's not a candidate
for the study.
Here you go. Okay?
‐ Thank you.
‐ Yup!
Trauma two is open.
Are you free to assist me?
I insist on it.
You blew by that
twelve‐year‐old girl
like she was a minor annoyance
in your busy day.
You said...there's a parent
here to give consent.
‐ Yes.
‐ Find him, please.
I'll explain
the procedure.
I'll do that.
I can't believe I get
to scrub in on my first day.
‐ That's the best way to learn.
‐ Ready for masks?
Charley attracted quite
a crowd in the waiting room.
Does anyone know
where he's from?
They say that he's lived
in the neighborhood for years.
That car
he was push‐starting?
Registration expired
in 1956.
He had all these
terrible stories‐‐
What are the first two branches
of the internal carotid?
The ophthalmic artery and
the posterior communicating.
Yeah. Okay. That's it.
You're ready.
Let's go.
Gown and glove, Ms. Knight.
She doesn't know the ropes.
How are we doing,
Dr. Riggs?
‐ Just about to put him under.
‐ 'Alright.'
'Around the table.'
Keep your hands in front
of you above your waist.
Don't reach for anything
unless you're told.
What if I have an itch?
Tell a nurse
where to scratch.
What is that?
‐ Dr. Riggs?
‐ He's bradying down.
‐ Alright. Atropine!
‐ One milligram onboard.
His blood pressure's dropping.
Damn!
He's in v‐fib.
Lucy, grab the crash cart, now.
Move!
‐ I'm sterile.
‐ It doesn't make a difference.
Charge to 200.
Amp of epi.
Let's move.
Come on.
Clear!
‐ Asystole.
‐ Start compressions.
Epi and atropine onboard.
Right.
What's the rhythm?
Got an idioventricular rhythm.
Alright.
He's gotta faint pulse.
Lucy, try to get a BP.
Can he still have surgery?
No. Let's get him a room
in the ICU.
Hey.
How long till spring?
I think this is the shortest
day of the year, isn't it?
Uh, no, that's December.
We're way past that.
Made up my mind.
Not going to Houston.
Really?
‐ It's an old dream.
‐ You could've fooled me.
I thought you were
ready to blast off.
I realized...
I didn't want to go.
I don't want
to go anywhere.
This is what I do.
This is where I belong.
Yeah.
Lost that old
restlessness, huh?
‐ I guess, yeah.
‐ Mm‐hmm.
‐ Coming in?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Come on in.
‐ It's cold.
What upsets me is that you
went out of your way
not to involve me.
Why would I do that?
Maybe you knew
I would object.
Object to what?
Well, I noticed
that all the women
who attended
were African American.
Yeah, that's right.
The clinic's for
everyone, Lynette.
Well, I didn't
exclude anyone.
Where did you advertise?
But I do have
a special interest
in an underserved
population
that is, uh,
particularly at risk.
Uh, Latinas are even more at
risk than African Americans.
Our death rate is higher.
Vietnamese women
have even more statistics.
Carol, to get women
to consider
changing their
sexual habits
they need
to feel open.
Women talk more freely
among their own.
Well, then, we're gonna have
to hold more seminars
that target
other populations.
Look, I did this on my own time
out of my own interest.
I understand that.
But I can't have you
pulling against me.
If you want to continue
working in the clinic
you need to adjust
your project
to include other people.
Well..
I guess you've given me
something to think about.
Couple more stitches
and the Y is closed, see?
Mm‐hmm.
What kind of music
do you play, Donna?
Um...
folk and classical.
Some rock.
Well, Ms. Boulet
is right.
More 5‐0 nylon,
please.
The prosthetic will take
some getting used to
but with time, you'll be
able to play just fine.
What about computer games?
No, those you'll never
be able to touch again.
Your dad paid me
to say that.
Oh!
Cut, please, Jenny.
It's Jeanie.
Sorry, Ms. Boulet.
Honest, I owe you
my firstborn.
You do that and
you're on a desk.
No, really.
You saved my career.
I gave you a chance
to turn it around.
We'll work out a counseling
schedule next week, okay?
‐ Get back out there.
‐ Alright. Thanks.
‐ Where's Jerry?
‐ In between sets.
Actually, I was
taking requests.
‐ Hey, you off?
‐ Yeah. Why?
Oh, that poor guy in exam two,
he wanted to say bye to you.
Oh, Mr. Ackerman?
Pancreatic cancer?
Yeah, he's gonna have
to stay the night.
Nobody picks him up
until tomorrow.
Thanks.
Ms. Abbott,
well, are you still
waiting for
the health bus?
No, he's here.
We're all loaded up.
I just had another
question for Dr. Ross.
Dr. Ross is...
in a meeting.
Is there something
I can help you with?
Oh, he gave some
new medication to us.
And...I forgot to ask
if it's alright
to take it with Robaxin.
‐ My son has ALD.
‐ And he has a fracture?
No, but he was in pain
and Dr. Ross thought
this might help.
Well, where's
your study envelope?
He said we didn't need
to bother with that.
Dr. Ross did.
Since my son isn't actually
a candidate for the trial.
I see.
I heard your son
couldn't make it.
Okay.
You need this?
Please.
Never mind.
Oh, God!
Again?
Okay. Okay.
Hey, is Doug
still upstairs?
I don't know.
Well, I'm headed home.
Mark, what are you doing?
Do you know anything
about a boy with ALD?
Ricky Abbott?
Why was he given meds
for the clinical trial?
He wasn't.
Doug wouldn't do that.
Looks like he did.
Mark.
Talk to Doug.
I'm sure there's
an explanation.
Yeah.
Ms. Boulet...
I wanted to thank you
for assisting
on the finger flap.
Not at all.
And for reminding me
to take time
with our young patient.
I don't do well
when I get behind schedule.
But that's no excuse.
You were right
and I thank you.
You're welcome.
Yeah, I was wondering
if by any chance
you'd be free
to join me for an opening
at the Art Institute
this evening.
This evening?
I realize
it's short notice.
But it may
be interesting.
Raghubir Singh,
an Indian photographer.
I'm afraid I don't know
that much about art.
I'm afraid I don't
care much about art
but I promised my wife,
who had died a few years ago
that I'd keep up
our membership
and...not become a total
Philistine without her.
I'm sorry to hear
that you lost your wife.
Mm‐hmm.
And my partner.
Jenny and I had a practice
together for 15 years.
‐ Her name was Jenny?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
You're a sweet angel.
‐ Called for a consult?
‐ Yeah!
‐ Self‐inflicted knife wounds.
‐ Quite a few of them.
Mr. Michaels gave me
a little suturing refresher.
She's my angel.
That is not what
he was calling me
before the Haldol.
Belly seems benign,
no blood in urine.
But these two need a
two‐layer closures.
Good bowel sounds.
Belly's soft.
I‐I wanted to mention to you
I've been having
a problem with...Dr. Romano.
Uh...yeah, Kerry spoke
with me this morning..
...without actually
saying it was you.
I'm sorry I didn't ask before
dragging your name into it.
Well...I don't think
I can be of any help.
Well, there's no sign
of any intra‐abdominal bleed.
He's got another
one on his back.
We'll have to lift him.
You know...I was hoping
that Romano would cool it
if I confronted him,
but instead, he threatened
to blast me
on my evaluation‐‐
‐ You got him?
‐ Yeah.
Dr. Romano
can be volatile.
Yeah, you mean he's a‐a..
...mean‐spirited,
little power monger?
That, too.
Well, the kidneys
look fine, as well.
Whores! Whores! Whores!
I want to die!
Oh, oh, there's
the Mr. Michaels
I know and love.
Look, um...Romano.
He likes to push
things to the limit.
Guess he thought anything
goes with the gay chick.
Well, I just hope you're not,
um...going out on a limb.
He's a star.
Self‐respect's a bitch.
Uh, Kerry! Kerry,
do you have a moment?
Yeah, Mark needed
to talk to me.
You're on your way out?
How about I buy you
breakfast tomorrow?
I think that sounds
like more that a minute.
Well, I've been thinking
about your inquiry
and I may have
some things to add.
Okay, I'll call you.
‐ We'll set something up.
‐ Great!
There she is,
Minnesota Fats.
I was afraid I missed you.
‐ Hey, Reggie.
‐ Hey.
So you're gonna
give me a chance
to win my money
back tonight, right?
Well, I can't play pool two
nights in a row. It's bad luck.
It's bad luck to play
one night against you.
Where did you learn
to clear a table like that?
Signs of a misspent youth.
So what do you say
we get a bite to eat today?
Actually, I already
have plans for tonight.
Something a new friend
can barge in on?
Opening at
the Art Institute.
Uh, say no more.
I'll catch you
on the weekend.
Okay.
I am so pissed.
I almost went
straight to Anspaugh.
What the hell
was Doug thinking?
Well, it certainly
wasn't about county.
If we were exposed
for breaking protocol
on a federally
funded trial‐‐
They'd cut off research money
and medicare payments for years.
Not to mention
that it's against the law.
They brought me the study.
I got him on board.
Mark, given the implications
I‐I don't think
we have any choice
but to handle
this internally.
‐ Cover it up?
‐ 'Mm‐hmm.'
Anspaugh finds out,
he has to react.
Nice position
he put us in, huh?
Mark, do you have the key
to the pain study cabinet?
Doug, why don't you
come in and take a seat?
Mm‐hmm.
Any changes?
Will he wake up?
What do you think?
His brain was deprived
of a lot of oxygen
during the cardiac arrest.
Mm‐hmm...and old folks
don't usually come back
with full function
after hypoxic insult.
It's a wait‐and‐see.
He could live like this
for a while.
Forever.
Well, according to him.
What's his Glasgow score?
An eight.
No spontaneous
eye‐opening.
No speaking.
Responds only
to painful stimulus.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry, I just
didn't expect this.
Yeah, well.
Neither did I.
Should I go tell
his neighbors?
No.
I'll do it.
'And then to top it off,
he goes to..'
...Kerry Weaver instead of
coming, uh, to me.
But you gave Joi the meds?
Well, yeah,
Mark said himself
that he wasn't gonna
use all the samples.
That's not the point,
though, is it?
Well, what is the point?
That breaking
research protocol
could damage
the hospital's funding.
Mm‐hmm.
So you, uh,
you agree with him?
No.
I‐I see their point.
You know how sick
that kid is?
Yeah.
But that decision could
have a much larger impact.
Alright, the hospital
is only at risk
if someone goes
out of their way
to report me and believe me
it kills Kerry Weaver
not to be able to do that.
I don't know
what to say, Doug.
Yeah.
Doug, don't walk away.
Doug!