Fifty.
Okay.
That should not
have been so hard.
You're getting old, Pops.
Thirty-one is not old.
It is in parent years.
They're like dog years.
Damn you!
Why won't you let us sleep?
We shouldn't curse
in front of him.
We didn't.
And he's obviously
gonna be a rock star.
So might as well get used
to hanging out with lowlifes.
He screams like Axl Rose.
And he's definitely a night owl.
Crying uses
the vocal-fold muscles
very differently than singing.
And lots of jobs work at night.
Janitors, truck drivers,
polysomnographic technologists.
All I know,
with those eyes and that smile,
no way he ends up in any job
that doesn't involve
being swarmed by supermodels.
Of whatever the hell
gender he prefers.
I think we may need
to get a swear jar.
Wouldn't work.
Ask my dad.
I'm sorry.
I just don't get what the big deal is.
I've never even met your niece.
Yeah, because you've turned down
every invite
to a family gathering.
Okay. I've just been
really busy lately.
Last time my brother
had a barbecue,
you went to a karaoke bar
with Jordan instead.
That is not true.
- It was an ax-throwing bar.
- Ash.
I've gone out of my way to be
sensitive to your family history.
Mine is different.
We're all super close.
And... And this is a big deal.
It's her confirmation.
I'm not asking you to go to the
church service. Just the after party.
I can't tomorrow night.
I have a ton of work
to catch up on. I gotta go.
Good morning.
I'm Dr. Shaun Murphy.
This is Dr. Kalu and Doctor...
It smells like
a brewery in here.
Sorry. We had a party
at our fraternity last night.
Um, I was gonna shower,
but my roommates,
they insisted I go
to the ER immediately.
I-I can't hear
out of my left ear.
When did you lose...
Miss Lukaitis is
one of our med students.
She is here to observe.
Med students
do not take patient histories
unless directed to.
I wasn't taking a history.
I see you got into
a fight last night?
No. It was...
It was a drinking game.
You take turns slapping
each other in the face
and whoever flinches,
they have to drink.
- Sounds fun.
- Yeah.
I woke up
with an insane headache.
I think I ruptured my eardrum.
I slapped my friend the other
day to treat his hemophobia.
It seemed safe, but I'm
probably not as strong...
There's bilateral otitis externa
and significant
cerumen blockage.
Cerumen?
Yeah, you have an ear infection
and a lot of earwax.
Oh.
Whoa. What happened here?
Ooh.
Oh, it's nothing.
It's just a bruise.
Take more than a slap
to cause that.
One of the guys in my fraternity
has one of those
foam-round shotguns
that the police use
for riot control.
Um, so we were testing it out
on each other.
- Mm.
Flush the ears with warm saline
and administer
polymyxin B drops.
Then get X-rays
to rule out a broken rib.
You can go with them.
I'd rather continue
to shadow you.
I already know how
to clear out earwax and...
Go with them.
43-year-old male,
hand and arm caught
in a meat grinder.
- Bay 6.
- Okay. Got it?
We got it from here. Thanks.
Can you move your fingers?
I-I'm not sure.
Get a BP cuff on his other arm.
How'd it happen?
- I manage a food processing factory.
- You got it upside down.
I was demonstrating
how to clean the meat grinder
when an apprentice butcher
decided to turn
the breaker back on.
I hate new employees.
Worse than worthless.
Oh, my God.
Get me an ortho-powered
driver with a 4 millimeter hex head.
Get the double-action rongeur
so you can use it
to pull off the grill.
Just skin and flesh.
I don't see any bone.
Oh, thank God.
He's just... new.
Thanks for the walk invite.
I keep planning to exercise,
but then I wake up feeling
like a broken-down old boxer.
Ugh, I know the feeling,
and I didn't even
go through childbirth.
Babies are damn hard work.
Yeah. Damn hard. Thank you.
I've been wanting
to talk to you.
I'm creating a living trust
to make sure
Eden's taken care of.
And I'd like to name you
and Shaun as Eden's guardians
if Park and I die.
Wow. I'm...
I'm flattered.
You and Shaun
are great together.
And given Eden's special needs,
you guys are a perfect choice.
Thank you.
That...
That means a lot to me.
And I'll talk to Shaun
about it tonight.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
I got a few minutes till the
patient's sedatives take effect.
I've tried every antiemetic
I could find.
Even started wearing
this here wristband,
but nothing works.
I was a cop for 15 years
before med school.
Saw a lot of rookies lose
their lunch at a crime scene,
but never met one
who didn't get used to it.
It'll become
just part of the routine.
I just got to get
through this rotation.
Hey, if you want to sit
this one out, I'm fine.
You can hit the skills lab,
practice suturing.
Before I went to med school,
I was a D-1 tackle.
Two most important things
I learned is,
it's better
to give than to receive,
and quitters never win.
Good.
Then let's go save a hand.
What are you doing?
I mean, besides forgetting about
this morning's board meeting.
I didn't forget about
So we're still doing this?
No, I didn't skip
the meeting to prank you.
I did it to be here
for the delivery.
A gift for both of us.
Ta-da!
You prefer
to stay in your office, right?
And I'm certainly
not going to leave the clinic.
So I thought, why not convert
the president's office
into the president's lounge?
Sorry.
Co-Presidents' Lounge.
Oh, might as well
add a putting green
and a wine cellar
while you're at it.
I work better with a pool table.
Great.
The board had a list of issues
they want addressed ASAP,
and since I actually
attended the meeting,
I get to divvy them up.
Your half.
He's a cutie.
He's a moron.
When I'm fantasizing
about him tonight,
I'm not gonna be picturing him
helping me study for bio-chem.
Uh, that is not something
we needed to know.
He's kind of got
a Peter Parker vibe,
which is exactly my type.
How about you guys?
What's your type?
Uh, we should
probably just focus.
I bet you like tall women.
- Uh-huh.
- Uh...
I like sweet, handsome,
caring, and, yes, tall men.
You're gay?
Right on.
Top or bottom?
Oh, wow. Charlie...
you're not in your med-school
study group, okay?
That is an inappropriate
question for a co-worker.
You could be fired.
Employers have to consider
my neurodiverse
communication style.
No one should be forced
to change who they are
to be considered
more professional.
Well, I'd suggest
checking in with HR.
They may have a different idea
of reasonable accommodations.
People at work talk about
their relationships all the time.
Asking about someone's
relationship's
a little different
than asking about
their preferred sexual position.
The expression doesn't
refer solely to sexual positions.
No rib fractures.
But...
what is that?
The bleeding's stopped.
The blades are acting
like a tourniquet.
We need to get this hand out
before his fingers get necrotic.
What if we pull his arm while
manually turning the blades in reverse?
Could grind up
whatever's stuck even more.
We have to cut the machine open.
How? The Jaws of Life
are way too big,
and a saw could cut his arm
or overheat the metal.
Not if you irrigate
with cold saline as I work.
I'll go just deep enough
to weaken the metal,
and then we'll break it apart
with a rib spreader.
Brilliant.
Get me an ortho oscillating saw
with a metal cutting blade.
It's a very irregular shape.
Could be an intramural abscess
in his esophagus.
The contrast enhancement
wouldn't be so uniform.
Yes, that is true.
What about an esophageal cancer?
That would be unusual.
- He is very young and...
- A nonsmoker.
I'm confident
we can excise the mass,
but we need to do
an esophagogastroduodenoscopy
and biopsy first.
I have no idea what that is,
but it sounds awesome.
Please do it now.
Uh, Charlie?
Hmm?
Uh, it might be better trying
to be your authentic self
without repeatedly
interrupting your boss.
Thank you, Dr. Kalu.
I appreciate the advice.
I think you may need
to go deeper.
I can't risk popping through
and cutting the radial.
Park, he's bleeding again.
Should you do a vascular cut
down and temporary ligation?
No, it's been too long already.
We need to get this thing open.
- Come on. Give me a hand.
- I-I can't.
Yes, you can. Just close your
eyes. Pretend you're at the gym.
- Come on.
All right.
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
Keep going. It's working.
- Pull, pull, pull!
- It's loose!
Lap sponges!
Severe contamination
of hand and forearm,
arteries are trashed.
Major vascular gaps,
radius and ulna are crushed.
Get the OR prepped.
We're gonna have to amputate it.
Advancing down
the esophageal lumen.
Do you have a boyfriend?
Yes.
Approaching
the gastroesophageal junction.
Is he tall?
Can we talk about this later?
Or not at all.
Doesn't make sense.
Dr. Kalu thinks
I'm being too intrusive,
but I'm actually trying
to establish a rapport.
I wasn't talking
about him or you.
I meant the mass.
It's gone.
This doesn't make sense.
That's exactly
what Dr. Wolke said.
The esophageal mass
was definitely on the X-ray.
And on the neck CT.
But nowhere on the endoscopy.
- Maybe we should repeat all the tests?
- No.
- We could...
- I can't concentrate
if you keep interrupting me.
I didn't interrupt you.
I asked you a question.
You said no,
so I attempted
to make a suggestion,
then you interrupted me.
Could you please just be quiet?
Okay.
He's disoriented
and slurring his speech.
Phipps, do you know
where you are right now?
Um, I go
to San Jose State University.
He is disoriented,
but no longer slurring.
- It was worse before.
- Okay.
Squeeze my fingers.
- Right-side weakness.
- We should prep a bolus dose of TPA.
No, we should not do that.
Can you wiggle your toes?
But if he's having a stroke...
His speech is improving,
which makes a transient
ischemic attack more likely.
And you ordered a nurse
to prep an unindicated
and very risky medication.
- I didn't order her, just making a suggestion.
- Get out.
- What?
- You refuse to acknowledge you've made a mistake,
which wastes my time
and endangers our patient.
Please leave
the patient's room now.
We need a head CT-CTA
to confirm it's a TIA
and not a brain bleed or tumor.
Checking pupils.
Ligation and sectioning
of the viable arteries,
veins, and nerves complete.
Charriere.
I'll make the bone cuts
as distal as possible
- on the forearm.
- Dr. Park.
I gotta leave.
Maybe he should
sit this one out.
Bit of a worst-case scenario
for him.
I gave him the opportunity.
He turned me down.
Have you gotten Morgan's
fecal-sample fridge installed?
I thought the idea
was to divide and conquer.
You do your half
of the honey-do list,
and I do mine.
Yes, but just FYI,
Morgan needs
the fridge installed
before she starts screening
for the IBS trial.
Yes, I'm aware.
Then I assume you're also aware
that it needs
a new electric panel,
and that Gail has put a freeze
on all facility upgrades.
- Not my first rodeo.
- Okay.
And the other stuff on the list?
I plan to ignore.
You should do the same.
- You're advising I ignore the board?
- Yes.
Much of their complaints
are trivial in nature.
They'll either work themselves
out or disappear completely,
which is good for us, because
then we can do our actual jobs.
The current board
isn't as passive
as the one
you're used to dealing with.
The current board
has some newbies, yes,
and they're very anxious
to engage
and nitpick
over every little silly thing.
But you know what?
They'll learn. They always do.
I have
an actual patient waiting.
Are we going in for a head CT?
Doctors Wolke and Kalu are.
You shouldn't have raised
your voice to me like you did.
I spoke with an urgency
that was appropriate
to the situation.
It may be appropriate to some,
but as a person on the spectrum,
I don't do well when shouted at.
I did not shout.
I'm letting you know
the parameters
for communicating
with me effectively.
I'd appreciate your cooperation.
I'll go join
Doctors Wolke and Kalu.
No.
You will go to the skills lab
and study stroke protocols
and procedures
for handling a TIA.
I didn't do anything wrong.
We didn't have to
debride as much as I thought.
And there's more than enough
palmar and dorsal flaps
to close the stump.
- Checking my work?
- No.
Just rubbernecking.
It's not every day
you get to see
a meat-grinder
partial radial amputation.
Thankfully.
But if I was checking,
now that I have a better view
of the injured area,
the distal forearm
vessels and nerves
are actually better
than I expected.
If you could bridge those gaps,
I'm wondering if you might
be able to reattach it.
Ischemic time
is less than eight hours,
and that's best case,
which this isn't.
Mm, not if there's
a blood supply.
You could graft it to his ankle,
keep it perfused
while you prep the forearm
stump for replantation.
You could really do that?
We've built new ears
on forearms.
Wrist anatomy
is a lot more complex.
And if we spread
an infection to his leg,
he could end up losing
two limbs instead of just one.
We could reduce the risk by
planting antibiotic beads in the wounds.
Yeah, but not eliminate it.
Your call.
Prep and drape his left ankle.
Want a second set of hands?
Absolutely.
But don't you
have a hospital to run?
That's what
co-presidents are for.
CT-CTA doesn't show
any blockages
or atherosclerosis.
I'm starting to think this
might not be a stroke or a TIA.
The neuro symptoms didn't start
until after the esophageal mass
disappeared.
Uh, not true.
No, he came to the ER
with neurological symptoms,
a headache, and hearing loss.
Which isn't surprising,
given he let his idiot friends
slap him upside the head.
Mm.
Speaking of idiots,
you should go
to the confirmation party.
Jerome mentioned it.
It's one party.
You might actually have fun.
Look, you love Jerome, right?
Right. So what makes you think
you wouldn't like his brothers?
They play hockey.
Didn't Jerome play hockey?
Yes, as a kid,
and not in something
called the Beer League.
This isn't about hockey or
beer, is it? You're just afraid.
I am not afraid.
I'm actually... I'm very busy.
Or you're scared
they won't like you.
Or that it's the next big step
towards something
you're still not sure you want.
Thank you, Esther Perel,
but I know exactly what I want.
- Okay.
And I have it.
Well, maybe you should consider
making some sacrifices
to hold on to it.
Had a nice walk
with Morgan today.
She's preparing a living trust
and would like us to be Eden's
guardians if she and Park die.
Okay.
"Okay" you're fine
with that plan,
or "okay,"
you didn't hear a word I said
because you're still
obsessing about Charlie?
I'm fine with Morgan's plan.
I was thinking about Charlie,
not obsessing.
I can't work with her
constantly interrupting me.
She's a student, Shaun.
She's excited.
She's enthusiastic.
Why does it matter
if she is enthusiastic?
She makes a lot of mistakes.
Well, now's the time to make
mistakes. She's a med student.
Charlie refuses to admit
she's made them,
which means
she cannot learn from them.
Are you sure about that?
Maybe she's embarrassed.
Maybe you're being
a little bit too rigid.
You know, give her a chance
to work things out.
I have not been rigid.
You're being rigid right now.
Why don't you try being
a little more patient? Right?
I will...
try to be more patient.
Great. Let's eat.
Ulnar to posterior tibial
artery anastomosis complete.
Sutured the main dorsal
to the saphenous vein
and created
a fasciocutaneous flap
to provide temporary coverage.
Great.
Then I think we're ready.
Releasing the clamps.
Awesome.
Totally awesome.
I understand you have a bit of a
medical mystery on your hands.
Yes, it is very interesting.
How's your new med student?
She talks too much,
refuses to acknowledge mistakes,
and doesn't like
to read textbooks.
That does sound
like a challenge.
Dr. Glassman said
I should just be patient
and give her time to adjust.
Wrong.
Glassman's favorite way
to deal with a problem
is to avoid it and then hope
someone else solves it.
You need to tell her precisely
what you want her to do.
I have done that.
Well, do it again.
She's young and faces
communication challenges
that you need
to be sensitive to.
All her recommendations say
she's smart but stubborn,
which, if managed properly,
could be a great combination.
You of all people
should know that.
Uh, why should I know that?
Because you also arrived here
smart but stubborn.
You've become a great surgeon,
and she will be, too.
But for now, she's like a puppy
that needs to be trained
before all the bad habits
take hold.
So don't be patient,
be proactive.
Hmm.
There's no cyanosis,
severe edema, or venous stasis.
Looks great.
- It looks gross.
- Don't worry.
As soon as we clean up
all the damage to your arm,
it'll go back
to where it belongs.
Good, because
I'm gonna need both hands
to wring that butcher's neck.
Dr. Park?
What's wrong?
There's some cellulitis
at the forearm.
But don't worry.
You're on antibiotics,
and we'll watch it closely
until your next surgery.
Sorry. I'm running late.
It's like packing for
the Lewis and Clark expedition
every time
I leave the house now.
No worries.
I got you an Americano.
Thanks.
Shaun agreed. We're good to go.
One thing...
I named you and Shaun
as guardians
if both Park and I die,
but also if just I die.
Why wouldn't Park
be her guardian?
Don't tell me you guys
are on the rocks again.
No, things are great.
Actually, better than great.
They're fantastic.
So what's the problem?
The last thing I want
is for Eden to end up
with an ex-boyfriend if I die.
We've only been back together
a couple months,
so I'll revisit
the plan in a year.
Okay.
I'll let Shaun know tonight.
No, Shaun can't keep a secret.
I haven't told Park,
and I'm not going to.
Are you insane?
You can't lie to Park,
and I can't lie to Shaun.
It's not a lie. It's a secret.
And every marriage has them.
Uh, sure.
Like how much I spend
on hair color
and how often I use
his toothbrush,
but this is too big.
No, it's a tiny,
temporary detail
that's meaningless unless I die
in the next 12 months,
which isn't gonna happen.
Please, just take a few days,
think about it.
That's all I'm asking.
I'm not gonna
change my mind, but okay.
Head CT looks normal,
but the abdominal images
showed acalculous cholecystitis.
Hmm. That wouldn't explain
his neurological symptoms.
But it does explain the fever
and the abdominal pain
he has now.
We got another abdominal CT.
Gallbladder's dilated
with extreme wall thickening.
Looks like
it's about to rupture.
Doesn't make sense.
His most severe symptoms
have been neurological,
and neither the bruise
on his chest
nor the mass in the esophagus
was near the gallbladder.
Whatever the cause,
his gallbladder
needs to be removed.
Get him prepped.
Charlie?
We need to have a talk.
Please have a seat.
I'd rather stand.
When I'm nervous,
sitting makes me feel
uncomfortably constrained.
Okay.
You are still a student,
so it is normal for you
to be making mistakes.
I haven't made any mistakes.
You ordered a nurse
to prep an incorrect
and potentially
dangerous medication.
I didn't order her.
I made a suggestion.
And you talk too much,
often about things you shouldn't
and other times
when you shouldn't be talking...
I learn more
by discussing things
rather than reading a textbook
or attending a lecture.
I do not lecture,
and I can't do my job
if you are
always interrupting...
- At times, my speech pattern can be..
- You just did it again.
So did you.
Compulsive speech is a
characteristic of our neurodiversity.
Please s-stop talking.
I am being proactive.
I have precisely explained
my expectations.
You can't order me to do
something I'm incapable of.
I have a disability,
and the law...
I am trying to help you. Okay?
I... understand
that ASD is considered
a disability.
But I also know that you are
capable of being silent.
If you want to remain
on this case,
that is what I expect you to do.
You are to observe
and nothing else.
Do you understand?
Yes.
Good.
Now you can go join Dr. Wolke
and Dr. Kalu in the OR.
We've got adequate debridement
of the distal forearm stump.
This is gonna work.
Good call.
Hubank, any thoughts
on what suture to use
for our arterial anastomosis?
I'm not sure.
Take your time.
Look closely at the angle
we cut the vessels at.
I guess you could
suture the ends
with a 4-0 Prolene
using an end-to-side formation.
Nice idea.
End-to-end anastomosis
with parachute technique
would work even better.
I'm Dr. Reznick.
I assume you know that Park
and I are in a relationship.
- Actually, no. I didn't...
- Don't lie.
I know how fast the gossip
gets out around here.
How's Park as a professor?
He's awesome.
Intuitive and supportive
without being patronizing.
Stop.
The whole gentle-giant thing
is lost on me.
What I respect is totally
brutal, blunt honesty.
Think of me like Bill Belichick
but meaner and with better hair.
You're right. I lied.
I was actually told by a
bunch of people on my first day
about the relationship
that you and Park had.
I was also told how you broke up
then moved back in
with one another
before breaking up again,
then got back together recently
because Park wanted to help you
take care of the baby
that you wanted to adopt
but were too overwhelmed
to do it yourself
while also running
the clinical trials.
But I wasn't lying about Park
being an awesome professor.
He's been pretty patient
and supportive,
despite the fact that
I don't want to be a surgeon,
and I faint or hurl
at the sight
of any amount of blood.
But he's a great guy.
And I'm sure he'll be
a great dad or stepdad
or whatever the label is
that you need him to be for you.
Is that blunt enough?
Yes. Thank you.
But careful.
Nobody likes a smart-ass.
Freeing up the last
attachments to the liver.
Using ultrasonic coagulator
for hemostasis
on the cystic plate.
What about an atypical
presentation of lupus?
ANA and ESR are all normal.
That's why I said atypical.
I mean,
what else could cause symptoms
in the esophagus,
brain, and gallbladder?
Dr. Kalu,
please irrigate
and lead the wound closure.
- 0 Vicryl sutures on a long needle driver.
- -Can I feel it?
Sorry. I know
I'm not supposed to be talking,
but I've never felt
a live organ before.
It needs to go to pathology.
And please
don't distract Dr. Kalu.
Oh, she's not distracting me.
It's just gonna sit in the pathology
fridge for a few hours anyway.
Do it quietly.
Thank you,
Dr. Murphy!
Sponge here so I can see better.
Need another 0 Vicryl suture.
And I'll take
the Metzenbaum scissors.
That's enough.
Put it back now.
Wait. Just give me a... Ow!
I think a needle
got left in the organ.
That's not possible.
We never suture
inside the gallbladder.
I know I felt... felt it.
Ow! Okay. There is
something sharp in here.
Uh, maybe it's an edge
of a gallstone?
I'm coming.
Okay.
There is something protruding.
Small forceps.
Is it a hair?
No.
It's a metal wire.
Inside the gallbladder?
How is that even possible?
It was definitely
not part of a surgical tool.
Well, I read a case
a few years ago.
A patient got a metal wire
from a barbecue grill brush
lodged in his intestines.
When we were doing
surgical prep,
Phipps said the last thing
he'd eaten
was a cheeseburger
at his frat's barbecue.
The disappearing mass
in his esophagus
could've been caused
by that wire lodged there
before it traversed
the stomach wall
and ended up in the gallbladder.
That would be amazing.
It wouldn't explain
his neurological issues.
Well, that could still
be from the slaps.
But either way,
we never would've noticed it
without Charlie's
curiosity, so...
Yeah. Nice catch.
It was more of an accident
than a catch, but thank you.
We need the strongest
magnet we have. Stat!
What are you doing?
I'm teaching Steve
how to run the table
while, simultaneously,
Barry and I
are trying to figure out
how to lower
the overhead cost of the clinic.
Try those.
"The poop fridge
equals presidential priority"?
You see, Steve? I told you,
alliteration comes off
as pompous.
He prefers "poop"
to "fecal samples."
I'm so glad
you're enjoying yourself.
Meanwhile, Gail is coming down
on me for things I didn't do.
Hey, it's my signature
on the thing.
If Gail doesn't like it,
she can come to me.
She knows you don't
listen to her.
So, now, every time she has
a problem, she comes to me.
Well, I can think of
one way to solve that problem.
Aaron, I don't have time
for these games.
You don't have time
because you're constantly
trying to placate
the damn board.
All they want is to feel
recognized and respected.
All they want,
they don't know it,
but what they really want
is a well-run,
top-flight hospital.
Well, all Gail really wants now
is a full audit of all expenses
for the past year.
Well, that's a colossal
waste of time.
Well, I agree.
And after
a 30-minute discussion,
I got Gail to agree as well.
This division of labor
isn't working,
so from now on,
you can deal with Gail.
Fine. Send her on over.
Just tell her to bring cash.
We don't take markers here.
He's an ass.
Not an ass.
What are you gonna do with that?
It may be slightly painful,
but it's much safer
than another surgery.
Open wide and say, "Ahh."
Ahh.
That was in my tonsil?
Yes, it caused an infection
and fluid build-up in your ear
and irritated
your carotid artery,
which caused
the neurological symptoms.
You shouldn't ever clean a
cooking surface with a wire brush,
or let someone slap you,
or shoot you
with a foam shotgun slug.
That is so cool.
Yes. It is.
I can't wait
to get back to work.
I wouldn't rush it.
It's gonna take time
and plenty of physical therapy
to get your function back.
I don't mean so I can work.
I mean so I can
fire that damn butcher.
The new CTs are all clear.
No more wires floating around.
And you might
want to take it easy
with the frat parties
for a while.
I'm actually
not that big a partier.
I grew up an only child,
so I always wanted brothers,
and now I have like 50 of them.
They've helped me through
all sorts of stuff.
A lot of the crazier stuff
they do isn't my thing.
Um...
But I feel like I owe it
to them to participate.
To be there for them
like they were for me.
That's very generous of you.
You're doing great.
No, I'm not.
Can't even watch a surgery
from another room
without dry-heaving.
That patient would've
bled out in the ER
if you hadn't helped
break open the grinder.
Yeah. I make a great crowbar.
Surgery is always a team effort.
I'm happy to have you
on my team.
Dr. Park...
Dr. Murphy, can I talk to you?
I am trying to get home
to put Steve down.
This won't take long.
I just wanted to tell you
how impressed I was with you,
how you were able to move
that wire fragment
from the tonsil without surgery.
It was very ingenious.
And I also wanted to thank you
for letting me
observe you in surgery.
I learned a whole lot.
Oh. That's good.
And you're welcome.
When I found the first wire
in the gallbladder,
it saved both the patient
and us a lot of time.
That is true.
That's a big contribution from a medical student,
don't you think?
I believe your intense curiosity
and attention to organization
will one day make you
an excellent pathologist.
I don't want to be
a pathologist.
I understand,
but given your aversion
to textbooks,
your extreme impatience...
I'm not impatient.
I'm an assertive,
dedicated, hard worker.
And your refusal to acknowledge
and learn from your mistakes...
I just want to be a surgeon.
Like you.
Oh. You're nothing like me.
And I don't think
you should ever be a surgeon.
Hey, about to head out
to Elizabeth's party.
I just wanted to say goodbye.
Should be home by 11:00.
Wait!
I'm coming with you.
Sure this elevator's
big enough for the both of us?
- I'm not sure the hospital is.
- Well, that's fine.
I'll resign my share
of the co-presidency.
Not if I beat you to it.
Hey, Charlie.
Are you getting out
or just taking a ride?
Charlie, are you okay?
No.
Charlie should not be upset.
I told her she would make
an excellent pathologist.
Well, you've only worked
with her for two weeks.
And isn't she hoping
to be a surgeon?
You said that
I should be proactive.
Proactive?
That's not proactive.
That's hurtful.
Maybe it's not
what you meant, but...
I was telling the truth.
I tried to be patient,
like you said,
but that also did not work.
We gave you
some conflicting advice,
which clearly
didn't help matters.
So maybe now, together,
we can find a better strategy.
Charlie has a unique
learning style...
Why do I need a strategy?
I am a good surgeon
and a good teacher.
Good teachers adjust
to their students, Shaun.
Maybe there's something
you could do.
you should do.
I have already made adjustments.
Okay. Make some more.
- Why?
- Because it's the...
- 'Cause she needs...
Because she needs them,
like you did.
No one ever made things
easier for me.
Or went out of their way
to make accommodations for me.
Shaun.
I'm sure you believe that,
but that is simply not true.
Dr. Melendez
put me on scut work
and threatened to fire me.
Dr. Han transferred me
to pathology,
but I never gave up,
and I learned
how to accept criticism
and improve
my communication skills
in order
to become a good surgeon.
Han and Melendez,
and I'm sure many other people,
were wrong about you.
But that doesn't mean
you should treat Charlie...
I am not wrong about Charlie.
She should not be a surgeon.
You know what, Shaun?
You sound like Han now.
You're being unfair.
No.
I am an attending.
It is my decision
how to manage the medical
students on my cases.
I am going home now.
That went well.
Yeah.
Straight pool or 8 ball?
You can break.
Okay.
This is gonna be hilarious.
And from my favorite uncle,
Jerome,
and his adorable boyfriend,
Asher...
Is this what I think it is?
It is!
I love it!
- Thank you, thank you, thank you!
- I'm so glad you like it.
You bastard.
She's not wearing that
in this house.
Yes, I am.
Go, Kings, baby!
Yes! Whoo!
You like them. We got it.
Boom, boom, boom, boom, boom!
That was good! Yeah!
I told the attorney
that if I die,
I want you
to be Eden's guardian.
I know.
You already told me that.
I was lying.
But this time, I'm not.