When a patient receives
a terminal diagnosis,
a clock starts.
In an instant,
the future becomes finite.
Doctors do their best
to predict life expectancy
based on median survival,
the period of time
after diagnosis
when half of patients
with the disease
are still alive.
But statistics
can't tell you if you'll host
Thanksgiving dinner...
...or attend
your grandkids' recital.
Evynn has just lost
her damn mind.
Who the hell does
she think she is?
Your protégé.
This is not the time for you
to throw that up in my face.
Read the room.
I need to inform
the transplant committee.
Alzheimer's is not
a contraindication
to transplant.
I understand that,
but they approved her
under false pretenses.
They thought the dementia
was encephalopathy.
Okay. Uh, Tasha's being
moved back to her room,
and we've connected the liver
to a normothermic
perfusion machine.
Buys us some time
to figure this out,
but not much.
I mean, you must be able
to explain the situation
to the transplant committee,
yes?
I vouched for Tasha once.
I can't do it again.
Well, they factor in
life expectancy as well.
Yes, of course I know that.
Someone without Alzheimer's
would live much longer
with that liver.
I'm sorry,
we can't assume that.
I mean, people are getting it
earlier and earlier,
especially women.
You think they should all be
denied life-saving transplants?
I don't.
Meredith's right.
We'll tell the committee.
They deserve to know.
I'll tell them myself.
You're left to wonder,
how is it possible to
feel alive when science
tells you you're dying?
Sunny-side up, right?
Uh, yes, please.
Wow. Someone is really trying
to get ahold of you.
It's Dave. He's having
a hard time with the breakup.
I honestly
feel bad for him.
I know what it's like
to lose you.
Morning.
Oh, something smells good.
Pancakes and eggs.
Oh, man, you can stay
as long as you like.
You don't live here.
- Molly? Molly!
- She's seizing.
We got you, Molly.
Catherine told me to make
my board presentation engaging.
It's about
the hospital's endowment.
My eyes glaze over
just thinking about it.
Who's that?
Nora Young.
Said she's been doing
the cardio exercises
you gave her,
and she was able
to jog a full mile today.
Hmm. Good for her.
I wish all of my patients
were that diligent
about their recovery.
-Go, Union!
-Hurry, let's go this way!
-Oh, here we go.
-Washington Union
scavenger hunts.
Every year, lacerations,
broken bones--
Memories that last a lifetime,
bonds that can't be broken.
Third place finishes
that still sting?
We were robbed.
There must be a few items
on the list in the hospital
this year.
Mmm. So college students
are here to steal stuff.
Hey, they're here to win.
Or cause me
a security nightmare.
- Wha--
- Help! Help!
- Come on, let's go.
- Yeah.
-She needs help.
-Yeah, she just collapsed.
-Does she have
any medical conditions?
-I don't think so.
- Okay,
let's get her...
Oh! Security!
- We're gonna need a gurney.
-  -Yeah.
-Feeling better. Gotta go.
-Hey...
I guess my presentation's
gonna have to wait.
Y'all got this!
Bailey, you wanted to see me?
- What's the look?
Am I in trouble?
I am reading
resident evaluations.
-Was I supposed to
turn something in?
-No.
Uh, these are specific
to the resident
who is still in a trial period.
-The one I am married to.
-Oh.
From the look on your face,
I take it they're not
what you'd hoped.
I've been trying to
stay out of his way,
so I haven't
supervised him directly,
and therefore, don't know how
to evaluate his evaluations.
Are you asking for my advice?
So Ben is
supposed to be on your service.
I wanted to ask
if we can swap residents today.
-Oh. Oh, yes.
Of course. Yes. Yes.
-Okay.
Did you not want him
on your service?
I do not have good advice
about working with family.
No. No.
"Critical incision
along the pericardium
to release the tamponade"--
Rob's hosting intern trivia
tonight at Joe's.
-You wanna go?
-Uh, will we have to be
on the same team?
I am really good at trivia.
I will mop the floor
with the other teams.
Yeah. Some of the guys
still don't talk to me
after last time.
Oh. Millin?
Um, I'm on cardio all day,
and then I am going home.
Warren, you're on
Shepherd's service, right?
I was... Uh...
I have a friend
who needs a neuro consult.
Well, page neurology.
I was hoping you could have
Shepherd take a look at her.
- She had a grand mal seizure
this morning.
Griffith, um, Dr. Marsh needs
an intern upstairs to monitor
a transplant patient.
Warren, you're on
my service now.
And, Adams,
you are with Shepherd.
That's a nice surprise.
Maybe we can grab lunch
or something?
I am not your wife today.
I am your attending.
All right then.
Tell me where you need me.
I can't ask my aunt
to squeeze Molly in today.
Her schedule's insane.
-Can't you just go to the ER?
-But you're on
neurosurgery. I...
You can do a workup yourself.
I can help.
If we get caught,
I'm throwing you under the bus.
Hi, Lisa, I'm Dr. Bailey.
This is Dr. Warren.
Go ahead.
Oh, uh, Lisa Saito, 63,
admitted for jaundice
and abdominal pain
from acetaminophen
hepatotoxicity.
Mm-hmm.
-Do you mind if we examine you?
-Oh, please.
Doc...
...I've been taking
acetaminophen for years.
I'm-I'm a high school
librarian,
so shelving books does a number
on my back.
Sure it's not
the high school students
hurting your back?
I've got one that hurts mine.
No, they're keeping me young.
Yesterday, I helped a sophomore
with her biography on Jackie O.
And then I led
a student podcasting club.
Yeah, we're, uh, cracking
a cold case this season.
Well, sounds like
rewarding work.
Take a deep breath for me.
Oh...
I wish my back loved it
as much as I do.
We were just moving
some encyclopedias
back into storage.
No one uses them anymore.
I went and bought some
extra-strength caplets
for the extra pain.
Uh, I didn't realize
that the doses were different.
Uh, it's an easy mistake.
So we are giving you medicine
to prevent more damage
to the liver,
and we'll monitor you
and see if it recovers.
-What if it doesn't?
-Let's not worry
about that yet.
-Okay, you can lay back now.
-Okay.
-All right.
-All right, Dr. Warren.
-Mm-hmm.
-Uh, let's get a repeat
acetaminophen level, ALT,
-AST, potassium--
-You can just say CMP.
And INR.
Order exactly what I asked for
and get a rush on the labs.
Tasha Lawson, 41,
diagnosed with
primary sclerosing cholangitis
and Alzheimer's disease.
Status post-stent
for biliary stricture.
On lactulose for liver failure
while waiting for a transplant.
I can't stay.
I have to go to class.
Have you seen my bag?
-Where are my things?
-Yo, yo, yo. T. T. T.
-What's going--
-It's okay.
We rescheduled it. We can stay.
-Are you sure?
-Yes, I promise.
Just breathe.
-I'll be right back, okay?
-Okay.
Does Dr. Fox know there's
a liver in a box somewhere
that could save my wife's life?
She knows.
She hasn't responded
to my texts. Where is she?
Where is she?
She's pretty upset
on how you handled all of this.
I didn't have a choice.
We're talking about
my wife's life here.
Withholding medical history
is unfair to other people
on the transplant list.
What about Alzheimer's is fair?
Well, look,
as Tasha's transplant surgeon,
I'm gonna strongly recommend
to the committee
that we proceed.
Thank you.
At least one of you is fighting
for your patient.
Meredith.
Hey, Meredith. Wait.
Who are you?
Visitors.
Uh, we're just, uh, looking
for this.
Okay.
I know what you're doing.
I just followed you
into a closet.
I have no idea what I'm doing.
When you look at Tasha,
you see a possible future me.
I don't need saving.
Okay. First of all,
not everything is about you.
And have you considered,
even for a second,
that someone may have
gotten this wrong?
-She is 41 years old.
-That doesn't mean
it isn't Alzheimer's.
Okay, that's fine.
All I'm saying is, let's do
our own neuro workup
before she's denied
life-saving treatment based on
another hospital's diagnosis.
I wanna talk to Shepherd.
You don't trust that
I know what this looks like?
This is my life's work.
Yeah, and transplants are mine.
Okay. Well, see,
the infection is spreading
to the mediastinum.
-Mm-hmm.
-What's the plan?
Broad-spectrum antibiotics
and blood cultures.
Yes, good. Place the order.
"Do not allow unauthorized
persons into secure areas."
Must be the scavenger hunt.
What an epic waste of time.
Okay, you didn't
do stupid stuff like that
in college?
Organized forced fun,
not my thing.
"Work hard, play harder."
That was my motto.
My motto was "Work hard
so you don't have to live
with your hippie parents
until you're 30."
Crap, security!
Cameron, hide in here.
Oh, hey, hey. This thing's on.
Cameron! Oh, my God!
-Oh, my God.
-We need help in here!
Wait, don't turn it off
until we can brace him.
Page trauma right now.
Stay calm. I got you.
Push the magnet stop.
Please, help him!
Oh. Oh.
Let's lay him down.
Nice and easy.
We need
a C-collar, now.
- What just happened?
-  -Let's take care of your friend,
and then we'll go over
physics 101. What's your name?
Not Teddy Altman.
-It's Cameron.
-Andrea, are you hurt?
-I'm fine.
I'm worried about you.
-Any neck pain, Cameron?
Oh, no, my left side hurts
and my chest.
This is what you call fun?
What do we got?
He brought a metal IV pole
into the MRI room.
The magnet pulled in the pole
and pinned him at the midline.
Abdominal bruising.
Let's get him to
a trauma room for an exam.
- On my count, ready?
- One. Two. Three.
Is he gonna be okay?
Don't worry about me.
You have to go on.
Finish the hunt.
Is there some kind of
big cash prize or something?
-Just pride and glory.
-Wait. You went to
Washington Union?
- Yeah. Third place
in my senior year.
The last clue. "Find
and retrieve the identifier
for something that looks
like itself but no longer is."
-Go.
-Okay.
Let's go.
- Okay.
-  -Dev, let's go this way.
Okay. I'm gonna go give
security a heads up on that.
But first, can you inform CT
that we'll likely head there
right after trauma?
Sure, Dr. Hunt.
Doesn't hurt to give them
a little head start, right?
You're sure
we won't get in trouble?
Oh, we might,
but you'll be fine.
Don't worry about it.
-Let me help you here.
-Oh.
There you go.
Hi, I'm Dr. Kwan.
Molly.
Yeah. I'm gonna jump ahead.
Uh, Molly, can you tell me
about your seizures?
Um, I've had them
since the accident,
a little over four years.
You've had grand mal seizures
for four years?
On and off.
Some meds work for a while, but eventually they stop.
Right now I'm on phenytoin,
but I guess that's not working
anymore either.
I'm so sorry. I had no idea.
Okay, we'll run an EEG
and see if we can classify
your seizure activity
and go from there, all right?
Between her multiple scans,
mental status exam,
and previous clinical findings
and tests,
I have no reason to say
it's anything other than
Alzheimer's.
Mmm. Tasha is the youngest
person I've seen with it.
-It happens.
-Yeah, it shouldn't.
No, but younger patients do
hold clues to the disease that
we didn't even know existed.
Maybe we will find some.
If Meredith and I
ever retain funding again.
Yes. Okay, thank you
for the consult.
I appreciate it.
A scavenger hunt kid stole
my badge and I haven't had time
to get a new one.
Thank you.
Cass? What are you doing here,
and how did you get in here?
I kept this
from when I filled in here.
Don't tell the Chief.
I think she'd give you a pass.
I had the day off and thought,
"Where can I go
for harsh lighting
and free coffee?"
David's getting a colonoscopy,
which is its own kind of
scavenger hunt.
Well, I hope his is
less eventful than the one
I'm dealing with.
Between kids stealing stuff
and crashing into MRI machines,
somehow I have to find the time
to make a slideshow
about the hospital's endowment.
I did one last week
for my sixth grader's
biology class on metamorphosis.
-Got an A-plus.
-Congrats. You wanna make mine?
-Sure, I love slideshows.
-I was joking.
I'm not. Catch me up to speed.
I'll make you the best one
you've ever seen.
Really? Thank you so much.
You-You can work
from my office.
The coffee's so much better.
Can we use your badge?
Keep it.
You need it more than I do.
- Uh, Lisa's labs are up.
- Oh.
-No, no, no.
-I ordered exactly
what you asked.
-Look,
her transaminases quadrupled.
-Yeah.
Oh, and her INR doubled from
her last lab draw. Damn it.
- I don't want this!
- Calm down, Ms. Saito,
I'm just trying to help you.
I was just trying
to give her mucomyst.
I don't want that.
Get it away from me.
-What are you doing here?
-Well, we're trying
to help you, Lisa.
-No. Why are you
keeping me right now?
-No, no.
I have to go.
I need to go! I...
-She's encephalopathic.
-That happened fast.
Okay, so we need
to get her to the ICU.
Start her on IV mucomyst.
Uh, consult nephrology
for possible dialysis. Oh.
And get UNOS on my phone.
Okay. Okay.
You're okay.
Uh-huh. Yes, status 1A.
Y-Y-Yes.
Oh. Okay...
Yes, we're interested.
Yes, thank you.
UNOS says there's
a possible match for Lisa.
-Now?
-No, in this hospital.
- She should go to Vegas
with those odds.
- Yeah.
Well, I mean,
the liver isn't hers yet.
There's still
some deliberating...
-Get her chart and tell Marsh.
-Will do.
-Meredith.
-Hi.
Hey, I heard
that you and Marsh were here.
I was hoping
to speak to him
about a liver transplant.
We're still waiting
for the committee to decide
whether to allocate the liver
to another patient.
Excuse me?
You're talking
about Catherine's friend
who needs the liver transplant?
No.
-Oh, you... You know...
-Yeah, cancel Vegas.
She may not get it.
There was a big mix-up
with her medical history.
The committee should
make their decision soon.
They're meeting now.
Lisa needs that liver.
Should we talk
to the committee?
About Grey's patient
who's Catherine Fox's friend?
No, that is not our business.
It's the committee's decision.
You get Lisa
settled in the ICU.
Well, am I broken
beyond repair?
Uh, there's definitely
increased delta wave activity,
and it looks like sharp wave
complexes in the region.
-Even when I'm not seizing?
-Well, it's like an earthquake.
There's seismic activity
all the time, but...
...you only feel
the big ones.
So what do we do about it?
Uh, we could try
adjusting your medication.
Hmm. We should talk
to her neurologist first.
You're supposed to be updating
my post-op notes.
And I don't know where
you're supposed to be,
but it is definitely not here.
Are you running an EEG?
This is Molly.
She had a grand mal seizure
this morning.
-Hi.
-Is she a patient?
Who is her doctor?
-Uh...
-We are.
Both of you, follow me.
Now.
It's okay.
This is my department.
You are interns.
Do you know
what this looks like?
-I'm sorry. We just thought--
-When you sneak patients in,
put them in the farthest room
from the nurses' station,
otherwise you are begging
to be caught.
Yeah. We'll be more careful
next time.
- Uh, he means
there won't be a next time.
I thought you were
slammed today.
Do you want my help or not?
-Yeah.
-Okay.
Uh, still no decision
about the liver?
No, not yet.
No. If they don't decide soon,
the liver won't be
viable anymore,
- and then no one's
gonna get it.
- What...
- Oh.
I told you
to leave that alone.
I just volunteered
to answer any questions
the committee might have
-about Lisa's case.
-You just volunteered.
Yeah.
- Anything?
-  -No, we're still waiting.
Warren might know something.
Apparently he was just speaking
with them.
I'm sorry, how did you know
the committee was meeting?
-Well, I...
-I told them.
It's not exactly a secret.
The liver...
...will go to Lisa Saito.
What? Okay...
Sorry.
You know what?
I just don't get it.
You've made a career
out of finding your ways
around protocols.
-I don't get it.
-It was the ethical thing
to do.
Okay, well then you can
go tell Evynn her wife's
not getting the liver.
Hey. How's he doing?
Uh, still waiting on the scans,
and I'm trying to
crack this clue.
"The identifier is something
that looks like itself
but no longer is."
A portable X-ray machine?
You think the people that
made these clues know there's
a portable X-ray machine?
My sophomore year there
was a pleur-evac on the list.
Millin, what do you think?
Has anyone seen Andrea?
She really wants to win this thing.
Glad she has goals,
and I don't play.
-The scans are up.
-Hmm.
Yeah, he has
a grade three splenic lac
with active extrava.
Hemodynamically stable.
All right, Millin,
let's get him to the IR suite
to embolize.
-All right.
-Looks like itself
but no longer is.
An ID badge.
No, that's too easy. Right?
That liver was hers.
She was on the OR table.
Because you didn't tell us
all the information.
I also didn't tell you
she loves animal crackers,
the old-school kind
in the box with the handle.
Or that she's seen
every episode of Gossip Girl
at least twice.
Or that she talked to her dad
every night on the way home
until she had to stop working
because of the Alzheimer's.
-I understand why you're upset.
-I don't think you do.
You're so focused
on your research,
you've forgotten about
the people living with it.
That's not true.
You helped hand her
a death sentence.
Evynn, these lights
are hurting my eyes.
- When are we going home?
- Soon, babe. Soon.
You said we were
gonna go home soon already.
-I don't wanna be here anymore.
-Me either.
You do know
it wasn't my decision?
Whatever helps
you sleep at night.
Any news from the team?
I didn't feel
the need to check.
So, Cameron, the risks
of the embolization
include bleeding,
-infection and kidney damage.
-Signed.
And we can also call
your girlfriend and give her
an update if you'd like.
Andrea? She's just my roommate.
Is there a reason you thought
she was my girlfriend?
I didn't seem, like, in love
with her or something, did I?
I-I was really focusing
on your injuries.
Oh, it's obvious, isn't it?
Crap. This is bad.
Do you think she knows?
The only way to know for sure
is to tell her.
Is it?
She's the roommate, friend.
You know, it's kind of risky.
You and Altman were friends
before you got together, right?
Yeah, we were friends
for 20 years
before we got together.
That's my entire life.
I don't wanna wait that long.
You could always join
the rest of us
who think that love sucks.
Take your shot, man.
Just be prepared for it to,
you know, not go your way.
I'm gonna do it.
-Can I borrow your phone?
-No.
- Oh, hey. Don't move.
- All right.
-Hey.
-I'll tell you what,
we'll find Andrea.
We'll bring her to you
before the procedure, okay?
Okay.
Be right back.
Oh, don't mind me.
Just saving your ass.
Oh, I owe you, seriously.
- Feel free to
gift me a spa day.
-You still swamped?
-Yeah.
The... The kid who crashed into
the MRI needs surgery.
I can't decide
if I'm more upset about that
or the fact that
I am currently out
an MRI machine
until we pay $50,000
in repairs.
They had to push
the red button.
I have always wanted
to push that button.
How is it that you are
always here when this hospital
is falling apart?
I've seen hospitals
that are falling apart.
I work in one of them.
This place is great.
-Flattery will get you
two spa days.
-I only need the one.
You should give yourself
the other one. You deserve it.
It's, um, been a little quiet.
I am gonna go
check on security.
Thank you again.
It's my pleasure.
How do you know Molly?
I'll let Kwan take this one.
We were engaged.
Now... I don't know.
Molly, you did great.
-Why don't you go ahead
and get her out?
-Yeah.
All right, you see how it is
lighting up in the hippocampus?
- That is temporal lobe epilepsy.
-  -Can you help her?
Oh, I can try.
It doesn't always work.
Let's go.
Molly, the focus of
your seizure activity is coming
from the hippocampus.
That coupled with
your developed tolerance
to drugs
makes me think
that surgery is your best bet.
Deep brain stimulation?
I've had quite a bit of success
with DBS in epilepsy patients.
I'm-I'm sorry. Um...
I'm not interested.
I don't want
any more surgeries.
You'd rather live
with debilitating seizures?
Well, I have been
living with them for years.
And yes,
they can be terrifying,
but you don't know
what it's like
to have entire years
of your life just disappear.
And I can't start over.
I can't.
-That's not going to happen.
-Dr. Kwan.
Molly, You can't let your fears
get in the way of your future.
Dr. Kwan,
why don't you wait outside?
We will finish with Molly.
I'm not asking.
Bailey, just making sure
you saw the graft on the...
on the donor's CT.
Uh, the distance between
the portal vein and IVC.
Yeah, I saw it.
Okay, good.
I'm sorry that your patient
isn't getting a liver.
No, no, no.
You did nothing wrong.
-Good luck
with Lisa's transplant.
-Mkay.
Griffith, did you finish
Tasha's discharge papers?
I need to go over them
with Evynn, but I think
she went to the cafeteria.
So, uh, Tasha doesn't know?
Tasha kept saying
she went to lunch with Reggie.
Extrapolated the rest.
-And who's Reggie?
-No idea. It could be you.
Yes.
Dr. Marsh, how is
Dr. Grey's research going?
They're looking
for more funding.
-Really hope they find it.
-Yeah.
My grandmother has Alzheimer's.
I'm sorry. How advanced is she?
Just moved her into
a memory care facility.
-Does she like it?
-She has a friend
named Isaac.
She loves the coffee cake.
Yeah, she's happy.
That could change any day,
but we'll cross that bridge
when we get to it. Thank you.
-I'll print Tasha's paperwork.
-Okay.
Hey, did Millin respond
to your page?
-Not yet.
-I feel nauseous.
- Cam, are you okay?
- He is in a lot of pain.
Do I have to be here for this?
I wanna die.
Dev, can you leave?
Uh, where am I supposed to go?
Fine.
Just turn around.
You want me to...
Yeah.
I'm in love with you.
I have been in love with you
from the moment we met,
carrying your stupid
Harry Styles posters
into the dorms.
I wanna be with you.
And I don't care
that you're smashing Dev--
-Dude.
-Cameron.
He doesn't wanna
be your boyfriend, Andrea.
And I want everything with you.
I want...
Cam.
Cam, are you okay?
-He's getting hypotensive.
-Change of plan.
- Cameron!
- Is he gonna be okay?
- Take him straight to the OR.
- What's happening?
- Okay, let's move.
- Cameron!
Oh, right.
Ah. Slideshow is done,
and it is pretty kick-ass
if I do say so myself.
I can't thank you enough.
I may finally get
some sleep tonight.
It was fun. The hospital
endowment is a surprisingly
interesting topic.
Said no one ever.
You check out the slideshow
and then decide.
I need to go find my husband.
They've pushed his colonoscopy
till the end of the day.
He is probably
bribing nurses for food,
and I would rather not
lose my house
over a banana nut muffin.
Hey, um, how about, uh,
Saturday for the spa day?
Together? I don't think
that's a good idea.
No?
I'm trying to respect
your boundaries.
It's okay.
When you figure it out,
you let me know.
Pressures are still soft.
Let's hang two units of blood.
Looks like the bleeding
is isolated to the spleen.
Let's prepare to remove it.
Right angle and tie, please.
Okay, blood pressure's
picking up.
Okay.
- Millin, more suction.
- Mm-hmm.
Has anyone ever died
on this scavenger hunt?
Uh, not that I know of.
I think if people were dying,
they'd cancel it. Let's not
give 'em a reason to. Okay?
At least they won't
cancel it over a broken heart.
- We really
steered him wrong.
- Had I known she was sleeping with the other guy...
-  -They're doomed.
It would have been a lot easier
if he just kept his mouth shut.
Removing the spleen.
Rest in peace, spleen.
Time of death: 16:31.
Cause of death:
sheer stupidity.
See? You can have fun.
What?
Oh. I think I just figured out
the scavenger hunt clue.
Millin, welcome to the party.
Glad to have you.
But I'm gonna need
to know what it is.
Hey, how'd it go with Shepherd?
Where did you leave things?
Shepherd doesn't want me
discussing the case with you.
Bro.
Molly's gonna talk
to her neurologist
about switching medication.
I thought we established
her epilepsy is refractory
to meds.
Yeah, but she doesn't
wanna do surgery,
so the only other option
is to hope that another drug
will work.
And you told her
how irresponsible that is?
No, I don't coerce patients
into getting surgery.
- She's not a patient.
- She's the love of my life.
-Have you told her that?
-It's none of your business.
Brain surgery is terrifying.
I wouldn't wanna do it
if I didn't know who was
waiting on the other side.
You're welcome, by the way.
Okay, I'm here.
Okay,
I-I-I know the committee's
already made its decision,
but I think I have a plan.
-My patient's on the table.
-Yes, okay.
And she will get a transplant,
but so can Tasha.
We do a split liver transplant.
Tasha would
get two-thirds of the liver,
and Lisa would
get the remaining third.
A third of the liver
can't nearly be enough
to regenerate and function.
It doesn't need to regenerate.
It will act as a bridge.
Lisa's liver failure
is reversible.
It just needs time
to heal on its own.
The graft will allow that
to happen.
It could save Lisa from having
to take immunosuppressants
-for the rest of her life.
-Yes, it would.
And you did say that the liver
was too big for Tasha.
- So, the split is a great fix.
- Yes.
We do that preemptively,
we save two lives.
It's a win-win.
Well, what the hell
are we waiting for?
Let's go give everybody livers.
-You wanna tell Evynn
the good news?
-Let's go do it together.
Her post-op ultrasound
looks great.
We should be able
to extubate her soon.
-Oh, that's good.
-Evynn's waiting for an update,
- so I'm gonna let her know.
- Um...
You know I... I didn't agree
with what she did,
but I understand it.
She was in a tough spot.
She did
what she thought was best,
given the circumstances.
And I know you did too.
Thanks.
-Are we supposed
to be down here?
-Now you care about the rules?
Well, it's dead bodies,
so, yeah.
Dead bodies or...
something that looks
like itself but no longer is.
-We're supposed to
bring back a body?
-What? No.
No. You're... You're supposed
to bring back the identifier.
Toe tag.
Yes!
-Wow. You're really smart.
-Yeah, I know.
You know
what this means, right?
No one else is gonna be able
to get in the morgue.
We did it!
Hey, hey, hey,
you're surrounded
by the deceased.
Show a little respect.
-I'm so sorry.
-Sorry.
Get out of here
before we get caught.
Go, go, go.
Her vitals look good.
Post-op labs are reassuring.
- Yeah, things...
worked out today.
- Mm-hmm.
-But I need to tell you--
-You really don't.
Altman's evaluation came in.
Yeah.
Ben, you are still
in a trial period,
so can you just
stay in your lane?
Are you asking as my boss
or as my wife?
-What does it matter?
-Well, if it's my boss,
then, okay.
But if it's my wife,
then I'm gonna be honest.
If I can help someone,
I'm gonna do it.
Now, I am not
a 20-something-year-old
intern with no experience.
I am going to do what is best
and hope my boss can see that.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I gotta finish rounds.
Oh, my...
Welcome back.
Surgery went great.
We're gonna have you on
your feet in a couple of days.
Just do me a favor.
Avoid giant magnets, okay?
I don't think
that'll be a problem.
-Can I come in?
-He just woke up.
He's not ready for--
-Can we talk?
-Okay.
I said everything
I have to say.
You know how
you don't have just one jacket?
You have a raincoat,
a heavy coat
for when it's really cold,
a light trench for spring.
I only have one jacket.
Okay.
Well, I have a lot.
He just had major surgery.
If this isn't urgent--
I'll get to the point.
You make me laugh harder
than anybody else.
I need that in my life.
But I also need Dev,
who makes me feel smart,
and Dean,
who makes me feel worldly.
There's a Dean?
I'm 21.
I'm not ready to settle down.
But you are my best friend.
And I hope I didn't ruin that.
I make you laugh the hardest?
Don't get cocky.
Hey, get a little cocky.
We won the scavenger hunt.
-Holy crap.
-We won?
I mean, you won?
That's... Congratulations.
I mean, that...
You're gonna have that forever.
Don't get up. I'm just gonna
check her JP drain.
It'll just take me a minute.
She has good days and bad days,
but every second
I get to spend with her
is a gift, so thank you.
My mother had Alzheimer's,
so I know the hell
you're living in.
I'm sorry
if I implied otherwise.
Everything looks good.
You know, my research is
always about the people.
I never forget that.
Understood.
Is she still
not speaking to you?
-She might not ever again.
-Oh, she will.
-But it just may
take her a while.
-What makes you so sure?
She told me
the two of you are like family.
Reconciling family is
very important to her.
She just needs a minute, maybe.
She'll come around. Take care.
Hey, you want a ride?
No, I am going out tonight.
There's a lot of people
out there having fun,
and I wanna be one of them.
- I'll be at Joe's
if you wanna join.
-Hard day?
-You could say that.
You wanna go to Joe's
and talk about it?
I have a bid whist date.
Your... Your grandma?
Yeah, haven't seen her
in a while.
You should go get a drink.
But what if I'd rather
play bid whist?
-Seriously?
-You had a hard day.
I wanna be there for you.
Both of you.
Thank you.
Plus, when you're tired,
you're easier to beat at cards.
- That is the only way
you can beat me.
Oh.
Before you drove away
that night,
I asked if you wanted
to cancel the wedding,
and you said
you needed to think.
"Wait for me," you said.
I am still waiting
for you, Molly.
As long as it takes,
whatever it takes, I'll wait.
And I'm sorry I tried
to pressure you into surgery,
but I just...
I just don't wanna
see you suffer anymore.
I've been doing some research.
And did you know
that there are experimental
surgeries for amnesiacs
to regain their memories?
What does that have to do
with your seizures?
Well, do you think Dr. Shepherd
would try it?
If I get the seizure surgery,
my brain will be open anyway.
You don't want
a standard procedure,
but you'll let Shepherd
experiment on your brain?
I know, I know.
It sounds like science fiction,
but more than stopping
my seizures,
more than anything,
I want to remember you.
So, if Dr. Shepherd will try
to get my memories back...
I'll do the surgery.
After a terminal diagnosis,
it's hard to trust
the good days,
when every second,
the clock is counting down.
We just got new labs in
for Tasha.
Okay, her lactate
is coming down.
That's promising.
Well, she still
has Alzheimer's.
That won't get easier.
No.
Listen,
I didn't see you in Tasha.
-You don't have to explain.
-No, no, no, I want to.
I, um...
I... I saw myself in Evynn.
Yeah.
Look, you just gotta know
that if I were in her position,
I wouldn't stop
fighting for you.
I wouldn't.
I wouldn't either.
I can't imagine my life
without you.
Same.
-I think we just
agreed on something.
-Yeah.
But what if you stopped
fixating on what you will lose,
rather than
what you already have?
-Hey.
Listen, I...
I need to tell you something.
That's ominous.
The last time
she was at the hospital,
Nora tried to kiss me.
I didn't wanna tell you
because nothing happened.
I pulled away.
And I didn't want you
to get upset for no reason.
And she has texted me
a couple times
other than this morning,
and it started
to feel dishonest.
And I never wanna lie to you.
Thank you.
I also wanna be
honest with you.
I bumped into Cass today.
So, I... I think...
I think I might be
attracted to her.
Well...
What does that mean?
- I don't... I don't know.
I mean...
I love you.
And I love you.
What's gonna happen with us?
I don't know.
Can you take this moment,
just this moment,
and breathe it in?