- Previously on The Resident...
- Old guy I was
playing golf with has
developed a bit of a tremor.
Cracking open his head for a
missed putt is a bit much, huh?
I hear you're applying
for an O-1 visa.
If I help you,
you'll get your visa.
If I don't, you won't.
Tell me about your
Mom. Or Dad. You pick.
- Dad? Well, I hate him.
- Why?
Because he's the last guy
anyone would want as a father.
Alabama Shakes
playing Terminal West next week.
I got an extra
ticket. It's not a date.
It's just a concert.
Have a little fun.
You look good, son.
♪ ♪
♪ Hol' up, wait a minute ♪
♪ Baby, baby, are
you listening? ♪
♪ I go, U go ♪
♪ 'Cause I don't ever wanna
see your face no more, no... ♪
Give me the bag, Doc.
Great.
♪ Now we at a crossroad,
now we at the break ♪
♪ All this back and forth ...,
we gonna lose our way... ♪
I need some help.
I take his head,
you take his legs?
18-year-old male,
unconscious, broken nose,
blunt force trauma to the
head, possible concussion.
Three's open. Dr. Okafor.
- You're bleeding.
- I'm fine. He's not.
His name's Atiba
Johnson, maybe Jackson,
- something like that.
- What happened to him?
I did.
♪ ♪
You know, the key to success
in a business like this
is making the
customers feel like family.
But this place goes
a little overboard.
Sam, how are those
eggs coming along?
You look well.
Atlanta suits you.
Why are you here, Dad?
I'm looking for worthwhile
investment opportunities.
It's been over a decade
since we last spoke,
and you suddenly show
up... What's the real reason?
You were always suspicious.
And you were
always a narcissist.
I was hoping that time
and maturity would open
the doors for us starting over.
Dada! Dada!
Clearly, you don't
know me very well.
Then again, you never did.
I was just... another thing
you could use to hurt Mom.
So fighting for the
custody of my son
- makes me the bad guy?
- You didn't want me.
- You just didn't want to lose.
- Here we go again.
♪ ♪
And so that's it?
- My time's up?
- I meant what I said
when I left for the Corps.
I don't want you or
your money in my life.
You know, I've
done a lot of research
on the health care industry.
You know what's fascinating?
You worked so hard to
distance yourself from me
and... what is it
you used to call it?
- Greed and...
- Questionable ethics.
Look at the
industry you work in.
I help sick people.
And while I'm at
it, I fight corruption
and train doctors
to do the same.
I don't capitalize off
of people's misfortune.
That's the difference
between us.
♪ ♪
Are you sure you don't want
even a little local to numb it up?
- Some ibuprofen? Something?
- What for?
Atiba's scans?
Look clear. He's a lucky guy.
No fractures, no contusions.
He's still under observation
for a possible concussion,
but as soon as that time's up,
- we can turn him over to the cops.
- Mm-mmm, no cops.
The guy tried to mug you.
He wasn't even
holding a real gun.
Turns out it was a toy.
Doesn't negate the mugging part.
- Who got mugged?
- No one. -Mina.
It's not a big deal.
Just some kid
from my neighborhood
made a stupid choice
- while high this morning.
- And for that,
he got knocked the hell out!
I give that a "C" for effort.
Look, I vaguely
know his parents.
They live in my neighborhood.
This is a boy who
needs help, not jail.
- And you're gonna help him?
- I did. I brought him here.
Cheese and grits
from the Silver Skillet.
Down, boy.
This deliciousness
is for someone else.
Well, I'm happy
with the lab work
that came back, which means
you are finally cleared for
your bone marrow transplant.
We can start your
conditioning today.
Dr. Pravesh?
Yeah, so first you'll
receive a series
of Bu-Flu chemo blasts to ensure
that all the bone
marrow is cleared out.
And then we can
perform an allogeneic
hematopoietic
stem cell transplant.
Wow. You know, when
you break it down like that,
it seems so simple.
Why don't you try that again,
but this time not in Latin.
Okay. Sorry.
So, basically, we're going
to take donor stem cells
and have them set up
shop in your bone marrow
and populate your immune system.
Right. Once that's done,
your new and improved
immune system
will recognize any
remaining leukemia cells
as foreign, and attack them.
Go ahead and take that.
I can finish up in here.
Hey. Why'd you page me?
Hey. I need you to keep
an eye on Lily for me.
I was taken off her team.
Yeah, I heard about that,
Nic. Wait-wait-wait-wait.
What's going on?
All right, come on.
Close the door.
Is all this really necessary?
I think Lane's committing
insurance fraud
by over-treating her
patients... Including Lily.
Look, Nic,
Lane is the most respected
oncologist in Georgia,
not to mention someone
whose work I have admired
and studied since med school.
Look, I have pulled every ounce
of research that I
can possibly find
on high-dose
intensification programs
both here and
abroad... Look at this.
These are from Lane's clinic.
Her chemo protocols
are significantly higher
than even the most
aggressive programs.
Did you tell Conrad?
I tried.
But if I'm gonna accuse his
mentor of something so awful,
I need more proof.
Nic...
do you think, maybe,
you are letting your
personal feelings for Lane
cloud your judgment?
It's no secret that you
two don't get along.
No.
I'm doing my job...
A job that Lane threatened,
by the way... so you
just keep an eye on Lily.
You're her doctor...
That's your job.
Do you know how much longer
Doc Davenport is gonna be?
I really need to get
back to rehearsal.
Nigel, I'm Dr. Hawkins.
Dr. Davenport
asked me to stop by.
Look, let me save you
a long trip down an
unnecessary road.
Yes, I'm showing signs
of severe malnourishment,
and no, I don't have
an eating disorder.
I suffer from chronic
digestive pain,
and it makes it almost
impossible to eat.
It's been over a decade,
and no, none of my doctors
back in New York
seem to know what it is.
So before you ask,
the answer is no.
No more tests. Zero.
I've been poked and prodded
by every doctor imaginable.
The only doctor I haven't
seen is a gynecologist.
Eh, they're overrated.
I've accepted I'm just
gonna live with this pain
for the rest of my life.
I'm a ballet dancer...
I'm used to intense pain.
- That's no way to live, man.
- I've made my peace.
Only thing that matters
now is my career.
So can I just get some
steroids for my ankle,
- so I can get back to my show?
- Look...
I get it.
I get how important your
career is to you, okay?
If you leave, you'll be right
back with another injury.
Maybe a day, a
week, or even a month,
but it will happen.
Your twisted ankle's
just the beginning.
You're malnourished,
and your body can't handle
the stress of being a
professional dancer anymore.
- So I should just give up?
- Give me 24 hours, and let me
see if I can figure out
what's wrong with you.
It's worth it if I can
save your career.
Right?
You found me.
- Wasn't lookin' for you.
- Ouch.
Didn't you get the
cheese and grits?
They say the way to a woman's
heart is through her stomach.
Actually, I think that's the way
to a man's heart, but thanks,
- Irving loved them.
- You gave away my gift?
Mm, "gift" is a strong
word. This is more like
you passed a bush, saw a flower
sticking out, plucked it for me,
and then said, "Hey,
look... I bought you flowers."
- Wow. Tough crowd. Okay.
- Have you seen Mina?
I heard she took on a
gang of muggers last night.
It's all anyone's
talking about upstairs.
- I - need some
help in here! Now!
- Damn it, Atiba, calm down!
- Easy, buddy, easy!
He's going through withdrawal.
He tried to take
a chunk out of me!
Give me two of lorazepam.
Code Gray! Bed three!
Okay.
How's Atiba?
Calmer. Drowsy. Restrained.
- You need to call his parents.
- Me? Why me?
Because someone needs to tell
them to come pick up their son.
I don't do people.
I thought you were
still on vacation.
My sister-in-law's in town.
Not a fan?
- Want to grab a coffee?
- Sure.
- Be happy you don't have in-laws anymore.
- Oh, I am.
By the way, that
golf buddy of mine,
- the one with the tremor...
- Right. How's he doing?
Well, he's had to
lay off the benzos.
The side effects were
too aggressive for him.
And now he's all wound up
about the tremor returning, and...
Well, he's right
to be concerned.
If the tremor is
really interfering
with his quality of life,
your friend may ultimately
have to consider brain surgery.
And we both know
when the air hits your brain...
You're never the same.
No, this is...
this is a hospital, Mr. Jackson,
not a hotel. No.
No, we don't have
courtesy shuttles.
Well, you'll just have
to come get Atiba.
Hello?
Are you kidding me?
You okay?
Nothing a little caffeine
- can't fix.
- Oh.
Mmm. It's been a long shift
that is thankfully almost over.
Well, maybe this
will help your mood, too.
Oh, my God. I
didn't even realize
- it had fallen off.
- Lara found it on the floor
of the nurses' lounge.
I'm simply doing the
honor of returning it.
There you go.
I see you wear it all the time.
Figured it's one
of your favorites.
Well, thank you. I owe you one.
Really?
Get over yourself.
I'll see you later.
Hey, Conrad!
Whatever it is, figure it out.
No can do.
I need reinforcements.
The priority is to get to
the source of your pain,
be it psychological,
neurological...
- This is not in my head.
- This is a GI problem.
We'll need to do
a battery of tests,
starting with a colonoscopy
and upper endoscopy...
That's fine, but after I get
nerve condition studies.
- This is neuropathic.
- Has anyone ruled out H. pylori?
- This is a GI problem.
- This is neuropathic.
- It's psychological.
- Nerve conditions.
- Battery of tests.
- After I get nerve conditions.
What's going on? I didn't ask
for any consults
on this patient.
Our attending did.
We can't rule out
biliary dyskinesia, either,
until we do a CCK-HIDA scan.
- Gen surg isn't even here.
- Look who finally showed up.
Nigel, I'm sorry.
Give me one second.
Can I talk to you, Dr. Wilmot?
You're not usually on
the floor post rounds.
I don't have to account
for my whereabouts.
I'm your attending.
You report to me,
not the other way around.
- You requested consults on my patient.
- Yeah.
- Why?
- Yeah, I think the question is why didn't you?
He's already had every test
you're coming up with in there.
Not at Chastain.
We run our own tests.
Nigel is sick of doctors.
He's been poked
and prodded for years.
I'm just giving him a breather
while all his medical records
are sent from New York.
And meanwhile, he sits
around in constant pain?
Pain that can be exacerbated
by unnecessary procedures.
Oh, see, this has always
been your problem, Hawkins.
You think your
way is the only way.
Look, I... I just want to go
over his previous test results
before subjecting
him to new ones.
Yeah, well, look, it's
not your call anymore
because he's no
longer your patient.
He's mine now.
Thank you.
How you feeling?
I'm just gonna check
your pupils, okay?
Doc, are these
restraints necessary?
I'm cool now. For real.
I'm actually a nurse
practitioner, not a doctor.
And yes, they are. They're
for your own protection.
So, I guess the cops
are coming, huh?
Well, looks like
it's your lucky day.
Dr. Okafor decided
not to press charges.
I haven't exactly had
a lot of lucky days lately.
I called your parents.
Why?
They don't want
nothing to do with me.
Because someone has
to come and get you.
If y'all for real not
calling the cops,
- then just release me.
- On your own?
So you can go back
out onto the street
and score again?
I don't think so.
Plus, you have
lorazepam in your system.
- You could OD.
- No. Seriously...
after everything
that happened today,
I'm done with that mess.
I'm-a get clean.
I've heard that before.
Why you care so much
about me anyway?
Is there anyone else who
can come pick you up?
Nah.
I got no one.
So what happens to me now?
What are you doing?
Taking Atiba home.
I asked you to call his parents,
not turn into his personal taxi.
Well, his parents
aren't coming to get him,
so I'm going to
take him to them.
Have you lost your mind?
Y'all know I'm standing
right here, right?
Be quiet. You tried to mug me.
You don't get to say anything.
I'm sorry. This-this morning
I wasn't thinking st...
I'm-a stop talking now.
- Mm-hmm.
- Look, my shift is over.
I'm giving him a ride.
It's not a big deal.
Damn oyibo savior complex.
Someone has to protect
you from yourself...
and him.
Plus, he's my patient.
So, you're stuck
with both of us now.
That's fine by me.
Get your ass
in the back seat.
It's quite a view, isn't it?
Never fails to
impress. You rang?
Yeah, about an hour ago.
I was in surgery.
Ah, Mr. Levine's
parathyroidectomy. How was that?
A success. I
think you'll find him
very indebted to Chastain.
I had the scheduling
nurse clear your afternoon.
I ran into Dr. Edmund
Carver from St. Grace
last night at the opera.
He's in town briefly,
and I invited him
here for coffee today.
And you'd like me
to attend that coffee.
Every reputable
hospital in the country
is trying to recruit Carver
after his surgery on the
former attorney general.
I want Carver at Chastain.
I hear he's overrated.
Maybe.
But with your guidance,
he would be an incredible
asset to your team.
You just talk to him.
Show him around,
give him the full Bell.
Close that deal for me.
Consider it closed.
Thank you.
So, who are we mad at today?
Other than that pen.
How much time do you have?
Anything I can help with?
I convinced a patient
with unknown chronic pain
to stay and let me try
and help him, but then...
Word gets out, and
the vultures descend.
Yep. I'll give you two guesses.
Who was the leader of the pack?
Sampson in Neuro. He
can never resist a call
for a mystery diagnosis.
Allows him to bill
- a ton for testing.
- Oh, he was there.
But today's prize
goes to Wilmot.
Took over the case.
Wants to ensure if we
figure out the diagnosis,
he gets the win.
You sure it's just Wilmot
that's bothering you?
Hey. You're a hard man to find.
- Well, you found me.
- Wilmot asked me to consult
on a possible lap
chole for Nigel Meahan.
You and Wilmot want
to unnecessarily remove
a man's gallbladder
without even knowing
if that's the
source of his pain?
Well, for the record,
I told him it was premature
to consider surgery.
So, has he been biting
everyone's head off today,
- or just mine?
- Depends.
What'd you do?
You know, you really didn't
have to escort me to my
conditioning personally.
Well, don't tell me
you're sick of me already.
You know, once my
immune system is stripped,
just how isolated am
I gonna have to be?
Are we talking no contact? Or...
- It's for your safety, Lily.
- No, I know.
That's stupid, right?
You'd think I'd be used
to being alone by now.
I thought we were
headed to conditioning.
We have time.
Talk to me, Lily.
What's really going on?
Well, this is the right
thing for me, right?
The bone marrow transplant?
I've been doing some reading,
and once we start,
there's no turning back.
You're scared. I get it.
But that's-that's
totally normal.
I know.
I have a 62% survival
rate in my first year.
That's a 38% chance of dying.
But no doctor has ever
just come out and said that.
Besides, there's...
there's other
complications. I mean...
it could damage
my organs. Infertility.
I want to have
kids one day, and...
God.
Listen to me.
Self-pity is so attractive.
You know what? Ignore me.
Bone marrow
transplants save lives.
I need a transplant, so
I'm going to get a transplant.
End of story.
I understand, but...
I don't care what my
husband told y'all on the phone.
Atiba is not welcome
back in our lives.
It's not safe for him to
be out on the streets.
He could OD at any time.
Monique, if he's
trying to get clean...
Do I look like a fool?
I'm done helping him.
That is not the boy I raised.
I know how difficult it is
to watch someone you
love suffer through a disease
- like this...
- Really, missy?
Do you have kids?
Do you know what
it's like to come to work
and find your store robbed
and then realize
that your boy did it
for drug money?
Or to come home and find
your baby alone
in a soiled diaper,
crying for hours
because his brother's
passed out in the bathroom?
You're trying to protect
what's left of your family.
I do understand that.
But I also know you
still love your son.
What if he really is
willing to get help?
He can beat this.
Monique.
Come on. Just hear him out.
Come on.
I'm for real this time, Mom.
Please.
I'll go in a program.
I swear.
I'll do whatever you say.
Ma!
That boy won't be
able to stay clean.
He hasn't hit rock bottom yet.
Yeah, well, you
can't give up hope,
'cause while you're
waiting for rock bottom,
you could end up dead.
So, who is it?
The way you're talking
only comes from experience.
So who is it?
My sister.
Hey. I need a full
panel on Lily Kendall.
Her most recent
labs are in her file.
Thank you, but I'd still like
to have a full panel done.
You've worked here long
enough that I shouldn't have
to explain this to you.
Dr. Hunter handles all
of her patient labs through
her clinic, and they've
already done a full panel on Lily.
Isabel, you've worked
here long enough to know
that I am the doctor,
you are the nurse.
So you can run a
new damn panel on Lily
or I can take it up
with your supervisor.
Green and purple
top coming up...
Doctor.
He's seizing.
What's the first thing
you do, Pravesh?
Let's get some access.
All right. Lorazepam.
Four milligrams.
Go. Soon as possible,
- get him on the monitor.
- What happened here? -Last I saw him,
he was drinking his
colonoscopy prep solution.
Where's Dr. Wilmot?
Let me guess, you
paged him... No response.
Dr. Carver.
Dr. Bell.
It is an honor.
Randy, please. The
pleasure's all mine.
Welcome to my hospital.
This is one hell of a hospital.
Well, you haven't
seen anything yet.
How 'bout a personal
tour before coffee?
Does that tour include a
sneak peak at the Titian?
'Cause I am dying to get
my hands on one of them.
Well, as long as you promise
to share how you were able to do
a Kasai procedure
in under four hours.
Dr. Carver. Wow, such an honor.
- If I may, one question...
- Now-now is not the time.
No, no. It's okay. What's
your question, son?
Uh, your retrospective
study on risk factors for...
How do you keep your
retransplantation rate
- under 20%? -It's actually been 22%...
- This is not the time
or place for any
kind of confrontation.
I need to talk to
Dr. Wilmot. Whether or not
there's a confrontation
or not is up to him.
Just... let me handle it.
Dr. Wilmot.
I don't know what kind of drama
you got going on with Conrad,
but get it the hell away from
Carver and me right now.
Yes, sir.
That's the first thing,
and the most important.
Keep that in mind.
Hey.
I don't appreciate
you embarrassing me
in front of Dr. Bell.
You took anatomy class
in med school, right?
Vestigial organs...
- What are you rambling about?
- You know, like the appendix.
The one in 20 people who have
it removed don't even miss it.
Serves absolutely no purpose
in the human body anymore.
Like certain doctors
here at Chastain.
You really think you're
untouchable, don't you?
What I think is you gave an
already malnourished patient
a prep solution that exacerbated
his existing hyponatremia.
And when he started seizing,
you were nowhere to be found.
He's stable now, isn't he?
Thanks to my intern.
Good. Get an NG tube in there.
We should be able to
get the solution straight
into the digestive
system that way.
You want to put Nigel through
a nasogastric tube
insertion just for a test?
If it means getting to the root
of his pain sooner than later,
then, yes, I do.
Look, I'm trying
to help the patient.
Then why don't you try
actually listening to him?
You did a good thing
getting Atiba to his family.
At least he's
safe for one night.
I'm sorry I judged you.
I didn't realize you judged me.
It was all in my
inner monologue.
Good to know.
I would've wanted someone
to do the same for my sister.
There were many nights
she didn't make it home.
But she's been
sober for a year now.
So, you're sleeping
with Jude now?
What? Why would you say that?
I'm really good at
reading body language.
I mean, look, the guy's
attractive and he's nice...
And safe,
compared to
someone else we know.
Look, Jude and I are just
becoming better friends.
All right. So I guess that means
I can become "better friends"
with Conrad now, right?
I was joking.
I-I'm sorry. I'm
still running late.
What? Where are
you? I'll be there
in less than ten minutes.
I need you to drop me
at my place, right away.
Yeah, sure.
What are you doing?
Wilmot ordered me to
put an NG tube in Nigel.
What a surprise.
He could have us both
cut from the program.
Oh, man up. Where's
all that bravado
you had on independence day?
What happened to
"When someone's wrong,
I'll be the first
one to tell 'em"?
Well...
I'm not so sure Wilmot's wrong.
Get out of my way.
Let me have it. I deserve it.
When you asked for
24 hours, I didn't realize
it would put me closer to
planning my own funeral.
You said you could help
me. Now I'm worse off
than when I came in.
What are you doing?
You're right. I should
have done a better job
protecting you.
Do you trust me?
Yes.
God knows why.
Put your clothes on.
Do I want to know
what you're doing?
Wilmot can't test a
patient he can't find.
Mina, what's going on?
Thanks for the ride.
I'm so sorry. We tried
to wait for you at home.
No, it's my fault.
I was delayed.
She won't stop throwing
up. It's never been this bad.
These episodes can
recur multiple times a year.
- Any abdominal pain?
- Yes. A lot.
Here you go. Here you go, baby.
- Tell me the pain, one to ten.
- Ten.
You followed me?
That call sounded urgent.
I thought I could help.
Mina, what is going on in here?
Do you have any
pain in your head?
Just my stomach.
Mm. I need one
tablet of ondansetron.
Bottom drawer to the right.
And one liter bag of IV
fluid from my backpack.
Are you just going to stand
there or are you going to help?
Mina, are these from Chastain?
Okay, so this is one
test I haven't had.
But, seriously, what
are we doing here?
I'm hiding you where no doctor
will voluntarily
show their face.
A hospital waiting room?
That is brilliant.
And a damn sad
commentary on my profession.
So, what's the
plan beyond hiding?
I'm gonna listen.
I've reviewed all your
old medical records.
Now I want your patient
history directly from you.
Doesn't matter how small
the detail... bore me with it.
You went to all this trouble
and all we're gonna do is talk?
Patient's words over tests.
90% of the time, they give
you the answers you need.
Hmm.
Maybe.
I have to say, you're
not what I expected.
Yeah? What'd you expect?
Frankly, less warmth, more ego.
Well...
Your surgeons are
lucky to have you as chief.
- I hope they appreciate you.
- Well, y-you're very kind.
But I can tell you what they
do appreciate is the autonomy
and the extensive OR time.
And, you know, for
the best of the best,
just a membership
to the Blackburn Club.
Wow.
A lot of benefits to
working here at Chastain.
- It's a great place to be.
- Well...
I'm curious. Uh...
how are your surgical
error and complication rates?
Excuse me?
Well, I'm leaving St. Grace
for a bunch of reasons,
and, to be honest,
accountability's a big one.
They refused to even
consider my recommendations
for tracking surgical error
rates, among other things.
Well, so-so what
you're looking for
is a place that's
willing to embrace that.
Transparency and accountability
force us to weed out the bad
and grow the good.
This one doctor at St.
Grace had patients die
from complications every
time he did a bypass.
No one even noticed.
Except me. I noticed.
That's incredible.
I'm telling you, it's
like they say, you know,
the truth never
gets out of the OR.
Well, you are just
full of surprises.
How's Shalisha?
Cyclical vomiting syndrome.
She'll be fine once she
finishes her IV treatment.
Mina...
Save me the lecture.
I can't.
You're treating
patients from your home.
You're taking
supplies from Chastain.
Those drugs are all
free samples from reps.
Free samples given to Chastain.
Regardless, you could lose
your medical license for
treating people in your home.
Hell, Mina, you
could lose your visa.
I'm not a fool. I know that.
But am I supposed
to look the other way
while people in my community
are dying from treatable illnesses?
So send them to a clinic.
What clinic?
All the big hospitals are
closing their local clinics
left and right for
profit reasons.
And it's not fair. But if
you lose your license,
you're not gonna
help anybody. Ever.
My uncle, Onoche,
he was a brilliant man.
Like a second father to me.
He was a surgeon
here in the U.S., and...
when he'd visit
Nigeria on holiday,
he'd bring my cousins
clothes and candy.
For me, he'd bring
medical books and gadgets.
On his last visit home,
he had a heart attack.
A heart attack he
would have survived
if he had access to
proper health care
and not been in a
hospital in Arondizuogu
without a working defibrillator.
I think that's the most
words you've said, ever,
in the past three
years I've known you.
Don't get used to it.
I don't know how I
was still standing.
It hurt, but I still
finished the show.
My rendition of Albrecht's
Act II variation was
"just perfection."
At least, according
to The Times.
I would've paid to see that.
Colleague issues?
Father issues.
You're talking to a male
dancer about daddy issues?
Bet my old man was way worse.
Oh, you think so, huh?
My dad couldn't wrap his head
around me wanting
to dance ballet.
So he forced me to go
out for football instead.
He'd train me by making
me run stadium stairs
carrying buckets of sand.
My legs would burn,
my lungs exploding.
I was, like, 15
years old at the time,
and I thought I
was going to die.
Never thought just inhaling air
could be so excruciating.
But my father didn't care.
He just kept pushing.
My dad was so
bad, I went to fight
in Afghanistan for
peace and quiet.
You said you were 15
when this happened?
Yeah.
Funny thing is, my dad
still thinks I'm a wuss.
Joke's on him. He doesn't
get how much strength
it takes to do ballet.
Was that the first time
you felt pain like that?
Sure, yeah.
But it would always go
away after the workout.
Huh.
Was your initial pain
centered in your diaphragm,
right about where
your ribs meet?
How'd you know?
I think I know what's
wrong with you.
Don't mess with me, Doc.
Has anyone ever mentioned
median arcuate ligament
syndrome to you?
Hey. Have Lily's
labs come back yet?
She's about to
start conditioning.
Wait. This can't be right.
Isabel, am I reading
this correctly?
Lily's in acute renal failure?
I thought you were the doctor.
Oh, my God. How
did we miss that?
If we proceed with the
transplant, she'll die.
Call downstairs right
now and make sure
that they don't start
her conditioning.
And page Dr. Hunter.
Lily, you're gonna be okay.
How did her initial
labs not show
that her kidneys were failing?
Yeah, I'm asking myself
the same question.
Somebody clearly messed up.
Well, I'm gonna get
down to the bottom of it
as soon as I get
back to my clinic.
Whoever made this
mistake will be fired.
I can promise you that.
Dr. Hunter.
If we would have
proceeded with this treatment,
Lily would have likely died.
Yes. You saved Lily's
life today, Dr. Pravesh.
Excellent work. It's good to
know I was right about you.
You're gonna make an
exceptional oncologist.
Thank you. That means a lot.
Okay.
If Dr. Hawkins is right,
and this is MALS,
the minute this numbing
agent hits that celiac ganglion,
you're gonna
feel instant relief.
How you feeling?
Pain-free.
The first time in over a decade.
Hey.
Where the hell have you been?
Patient's fine, by the
way. Thanks for asking.
Turns out he has MALS.
Surgery's scheduled
for next week
after his final show.
Hey.
You think you're so damn smart.
You know, one of these
days your need to play God
with the rules is gonna
cost a patient their life.
And when that happens,
there'll be a long line of us ready
to make sure your medical
career goes up in flames.
Mmm. One man against an army.
Now you're talking my language.
That gets me excited.
You know what
else gets me excited?
Knowing that if your
hand is still on my arm
in three seconds, you'll
be waking up in the ER
with no memory of
how you got there.
Carver is
even more impressive in person.
Oh. That's exactly
what I want to hear.
He'll be a great addition
to the surgical team.
And I think his
plans for tracking
and publicizing all error
rates are really admirable.
Wait. Publicizing outside
the walls of the hospital?
Yeah, but I think once we
get through those lawsuits
that that transparency
causes, we'll be...
- Lawsuits?
- Yeah, lawsuits.
But Chastain can weather
those, and maybe, you know,
- even get ahead of the bad publicity.
- Right, of course.
You know, we can spin it into
something we can make use of.
You know, here's the thing,
Dr. Carver's very expensive.
And I think I'm gonna
have to take a look
at the budget. I'm
not sure that Chastain
can afford to make a
competitive offer at this time.
That's a pity.
Marshall. I didn't
expect to see you here.
I had some unfinished
business with Dr. Hunter.
Well, good news, I hope.
Actually, I won't be investing
in Chastain after all.
It's just not the
right fit for me.
Well, that's a shame,
that you couldn't have
come to that conclusion
before wasting everybody's time.
I appreciate your time
and hospitality, Claire.
You wouldn't by chance
know where Dr. Hawkins is?
Conrad Hawkins?
I'm sure he's
on the fifth floor.
I can have one of
the nurses page him.
I wasn't aware you
were acquainted.
He's my son. Excuse me.
Did you know?
No idea.
Eh, regardless,
makes no difference.
Of course it does.
A no now could very well
be a yes later.
- You haven't seen me work my magic.
- Yeah, dream on.
Hey. I rushed back as
soon as I got your message.
What's going on?
You were right.
I ju-I just... I-I
can't believe this.
It's crazy.
That transplant... with
Lily's comorbidities.
All right, Devon. I need
you to keep your voice down.
Just tell me exactly
what happened.
Okay, I reran a full blood
panel on Lily without telling Lane.
And the lab showed that
her kidneys are failing.
Which means she's not eligible
for a bone marrow
transplant right now.
Lane just played it off
like somebody at her clinic
made a mistake,
but I don't know...
She had to have known, right?
Why would Lane proceed
with the transplant?
Money. Bone marrow
transplants are the Super Bowl
of cancer treatments
when it comes to billing.
Lily would have died.
You were right.
We have to do
something about Lane.
♪ Blood of my blood ♪
♪ Flesh of flesh ♪
♪ You only want
over them cash... ♪
Let's just try to stay
out of each other's way
while you're doing whatever
business with the hospital.
I'm not investing
in the hospital.
Truth is, I never was.
I was just doing
some recon, that's all.
Recon for what?
I'm opening a small
private hospital.
What I hope will
be the first of many.
And I don't just want
you to work there.
I want you to run it...
after you finish this final
year of residency, of course.
- What?
- Just hear me out.
You can do what you love to do.
Interact with the patients while
training your doctors your way,
without all of this bureaucratic
mess over your head.
You trying to buy your
way back into my life again?
Maybe I am. The point is,
this is something
that's important to you,
and it's important to
me to help you get it.
Conrad, I am trying.
I-I don't need an
answer right now.
Just think about it.
You know how to reach
me when you're ready.
♪ Blood of my
blood, flesh of flesh ♪
♪ You only want over them cash ♪
- ♪ Only want what I can't feel ♪
- Who's that?
My father.
♪ I'm still I'm proud, proud ♪
Your father?
♪ Flesh of flesh ♪
♪ You only want over... ♪
Are we really not
gonna talk about this?
No, we're not.
I'll see you later.
Hey. Talk to me.
Don't do this.
Don't shut me out.
Look, if this is about Jude...
Nic, no explanation
necessary. It's your life.
Conrad...
You told me repeatedly that
this thing was over between us.
I just didn't want to hear it.
That's on me.
♪ Blood of my
blood, flesh of flesh ♪
♪ You only want over them cash ♪
♪ Only want what I can't feel ♪
♪ I'm still proud, proud. ♪
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH