(SAXOPHONE MUSIC PLAYING)
(TRAIN ENGINE CHUGGING)
(APPLAUSE)
SHARON: Thank you.
We owe a great
debt of gratitude
to one man in particular.
He championed us,
supported us and,
happily, along the way,
befriended us.
Without his help,
this incredible
new Emergency Department
would never have
become a reality.
Our Mayor, Rahm Emanuel.
(CROWD CHEERING
AND APPLAUDING)
On behalf of all the people
of the city of Chicago,
all the families,
all the parents
who'll be bringing their kids
and their family members here
in dire need of care,
I wanna thank you
ahead of schedule
for what you do every day
to making sure
that everybody counts
in the city of Chicago.
Thank you.
(CHEERING AND APPLAUDING)
(RUMBLIING)
(GASPING, YELLING)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
Sir, you okay?
Are you all right?
Everybody okay?
Sir, can I see that for
a second? Can I see
that for a second?
All right, It doesn't
Look too bad, all right?
You're gonna be all right.
Call out if you
need some help,
Miss, are you calling 911?
Yeah,
You all right?
Can I take a Look
at that for a second?
Miss, are you
doing all right?
Oh, my God,
Need some help
over here,
(CHEERING)
(PAGER BEEPING)
(GROANS)
(PAGERS BEEPING
SIMULTANEOUSLY)
Mr, Mayor,
this way, please,
(SIRENS WAILING)
CFD PIan 2, mass cas,
Multiple trauma
patients minutes away,
Let's go,
(SIRENS WAILING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
What do we have?
Forty-five-year-old male,
Ieft Ieg amputation,
Treatment Two,
Train motorman,
GCS 3, BP of 90 by palp,
Maggie, where're we going?
Go to Trauma Four,
Maggie, they need X-ray here,
I got you,
Crossing,
Whoa, whoa,
hold it, hold it,
Watch out!
Katrina, how are all these
walk-ins making it through?
Let's set a perimeter,
Let's get her
into Treatment Two,
(SIREN WAILING)
CONNOR: Come on,
(GRUNTING IN FRUSTRATION)
Well, he keeps biting down,
I can't get the blade in,
Look, you bag him,
I'II do CPR,
Okay,
(GRUNTING IN EFFORT)
Come on, We're almost there,
It's not time yet,
(GRUNTING IN EFFORT)
Trigger the all-hazard
disaster plan,
Yes, ma'am,
Page the phone tree,
Right away,
Twenty-eight-year-old male,
crush injuries,
severed artery,
massive blood Ioss,
Trauma Three just opened,
Got a tourniquet
on his right Ieg,
Tried to intubate,
but couldn't get his jaw open,
He Iost his pulse on the ride,
Put him on our monitor
and rapid transfuser,
Grab four units of O-neg
and start with a round of epi,
AIready hit him
with the epi times two,
Still no pulse, He's in fib,
Let's get him in the bay,
I got it from here, man,
Nope, he's mine,
Okay, who the hell
is this guy?
MAN: Says he's a doc,
All right, get off
the gurney, Doc,
I'm senior resident
in this ER,
Yeah, well, I'm your
new trauma fellow,
MAGGIE: Dr, Halstead!
MAN: Female, early 20s,
Head trauma,
GCS 3, unresponsive
in the field,
Trauma Two just opened,
Still GCS 3,
We gotta change that King
Airway to a formal ET tube,
I'II get a Iine in the groin,
(CRYING) Where's my daddy?
Where's my daddy?
Where's your Iine?
Left AC,
Obvious femur fracture,
Good distal pulse,
It's blown,
Where's my daddy?
Sweetheart, we're gonna
take good care of you,
You have to go
back for my daddy,
I Iove my daddy,
You know anything
about that?
Pretty sure her
father was Ioaded,
Must've been sent
to Sinai or County,
I know, honey, Sweetie, Look,
you see this Iady right here?
Her name is Maggie,
She can find
anybody anywhere, okay?
I promise she'II find
your daddy for you,
Better believe
I will, hon,
CONNOR: Hold compressions,
You are?
Sarah Reese,
Fourth year med student,
Can you do a cordis
in the groin?
Mmm-hmm,
Get a Ieft femoral
in there,
Yes, sir,
There, you're sterilized,
Now stick it,
(WHISPERS) Okay,
He's a patient,
not a pin cushion,
I can't find the vein,
All right,
Shock to 120, CIear,
(BEEPING)
No pulse,
Again, 200,
CIear,
(SYSTEMATIC BEEPING)
I have a pulse,
Sinus tach at 112,
And he's back,
Get a BP and keep
giving him blood,
Send a rainbow oftubes
and a type and cross,
Get his blood gas
and get him to the OR,
Yes, sir,
Did you find my dad yet?
We will, sweetheart,
don't you worry,
All right, now
we're gonna put
something in your arm
to give you medicine,
Just gonna be
a Iittle pinch, okay?
No, No, No,
Make a fist for me, honey,
Squeeze my hand,
Make a fist,
Look at me,
Squeeze my hand,
I'm gonna count to three,
Look at me, One, two, three,,,
(GROANS)
All done, good job,
There you go,
APRIL: Excellent, Excellent,
Let's get X-ray in here,
Yeah,
(MACHINE BEEPING)
No gag reflex, didn't
even need sedation,
Not good,
We got another problem,
(HEARTBEAT WHOOSING)
This woman's pregnant,
Yeah, Mmm-hmm,
Dr, Rhodes, welcome,
Oh, are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine,
Uh, Sharon Goodwin,
PIeasure to meet you,
Is every day Iike this?
Some days we're busy,
MAN: Twenty-year-old male,
cystic fibrosis,
Complaining of chills,
Iabored breathing,
Temp's 98,
Jamie, is that you?
Hi, Maggie,
Back so soon?
I missed you guys,
Respiratory rate is 26,
Let's take him
to Treatment Six,
All our ER docs are
busy, Can you take
care of our friend?
No problem,
Maggie?
Yes?
Let Dr, Charles know
that Jamie's down here,
Sure thing,
Deep breath,
(INHALING RASPILY)
(COUGHS)
Hey, Jamie,
(GRUNTS)
Maybe today wasn't
such a good day
to drop in,
Oh, we always got
time for you,
Let's get a CBC,
a CMP, coags,
a chest X-ray and an ABG,
Yes, Doctor,
Now, Mr, Delson,
I see that you're using
inhaled antibiotics,
tobramycin, albuterol,
You wear a vibration
jacket at night and
use a humidifier?
Yeah,
That's all good,
I caught a cold,
A whopper,
Well, we gotta make
sure that it doesn't
turn into pneumonia,
You've had
a few episodes,
JAMIE: A few means three,
I've had more,
Well, we're gonna
take good care of
you here, okay?
You're at Northwestern?
Yeah,
Well, we better get
you out of here quick
so you don't miss
those midterms,
Make a fist,
Hey, who's
my next patient?
The red tags have
all been handled,
Why don't you sit
down for a minute?
You know, exercise is good
for pregnant women,
Come on, next patient,
All right, Treatment One,
Thank you,
Crib party Sunday,
Crib party?
Maggie and I
are gonna come by,
help you put the baby's
crib together,
I'II bring the Allen
wrenches and a deep
dish from Kitchen 17,
You guys don't
have to do that,
Not ifyou think
that you're gonna do
the single-mom
thing all by yourself,
Not with us around,
Takes a village,
Thanks, guys,
I don't know what
I'd do without you,
Why am I putting in
this bolt? Where's my
good-for-nothing resident?
Put in her 12 hours,
Had to knock off,
(SIGHS)
These new rules,
Ridiculous, And
bad for medicine,
(MOCKING)
"Oh, I'm so tired,
I can't work,"
Everybody's so damn spoiled,
The whole generation,
Gina,
Ms, Donahue,
Gina! Oh, my God!
Ms, Donahue,,,
What happened to her?
Dr, Abrams, Dr, Halstead,
this is Ms, Donahue,
the baby's mother,
Thanks, Maggie,
You're the baby's
mother?
(STUTTERS)
Biological mother,
My husband, Joel, and I,,,
He's at work,
he's on his way here,
We're the parents,
Gina's our surrogate,
Opening pressure's 18,
I'm done,
Look at her,
(SNIFFLES)
Is, is she gonna be
okay? And the baby?
The baby checks
out fine,
Oh!
Healthy heartbeat,
Amniotic sac and
placenta are intact,
Gina, though,
I'm afraid, suffered
a traumatic head injury
and, so far,
she's unresponsive,
We need to contact her family,
If you have any information,,,
My husband and I are
pretty much her family,
She's been Iiving
with us since before
the embryo was implanted,
Okay,
She's gonna get
better, isn't she?
She's gonna be okay?
I can't promise anything,
Oh!
Oh, I can't believe this,
What about the baby?
It's too soon to
deliver, isn't it?
She's only 24 weeks,
Yes, the baby
needs more time,
What does that mean?
Are we gonna Iose
our child, too? Oh, my God!
No, Ms, Donahue,
I'm not saying that,
And I'm not
giving up on Gina,
But if the worst
did happen,
it might be possible
to keep her on
Iife support
Iong enough
for the fetus to
become viable,
So,,,
So what,
Gina just becomes
a human incubator?
We're not there yet,
(CRYING)
Dr, Rhodes, I thought
you could use these,
Thank you,
How'd that happen?
Must've snagged
it on the wreckage,
You know, we do
have a couple of
doctors around here,
I could hook you up,
I don't need one,
But I could use
a nurse, though,
Come be my other hand,
Oh, nice, You closed that
Iike a plastic surgeon,
Where'd you pick that up?
Riyadh,
I spent a year there
after my residency,
Saudis paid me well
not to Ieave unsightly scars,
Could you pinch
those two sides together?
There you go,
What about a tetanus shot?
No, I am current,
April,,,
April Sexton,
English? Irish?
My family's from Brazil,
Our real Iast
name is Sanguessuga,
But my parents thought
"Sexton" sounded
more American,
and people could
actually pronounce it,
Where are you from?
Chicago,
Born and bred,
Been away for a while,
Welcome home,
Two and four,
three is headed
to the OR,
Okay,
Who's the young
Rambo over there?
Hmm?
Oh, that's Connor Rhodes,
The new trauma fellow,
(CHUCKLES)
Well, he's gonna Iight
up some estrogen
receptors around here,
I'II say,
He Iit mine,
Oh, that's all I need,
Where's Jamie again?
Treatment Five,
Look,
A doll in a dream,
Your daughter's stable,
She has a pretty
serious Ieg fracture,
but she's okay,
just a Iittle shaken up,
The orthopedic resident
is on his way to
put a cast on her,
And what about my husband?
I can't get any information,,,
We made some calls,
your husband's down
the road at Sinai,
They were able
to stabilize him, but
his injuries are serious,
The Iast word I had,
he was headed
into surgery,
How's this happening?
They were just going on
a father-daughter day trip,
She wanted to go to
the zoo, What am I,,,
Ms, Lewis, the best
thing you can do
right now is just be
there for your daughter,
We'II keep checking
on your husband, okay?
All right,
There, You can see
her feet and a hand,
Everything Looks good,
Mr, and Mrs, Donahue,
Oh, thank you for doing
this, We just needed
to see her again,
She just squeezed my hand,
I swear, I felt it,
Her reflexes
are still intact,
Movement can occur,
but it's not purposeful,
Look, she just did it again,
right when you
wiped her stomach,
She responded,
Tell me that
wasn't purposeful,
Dr, Choi, Iet's get
a repeat CAT scan,
You haven't seen
even one?
Hand to God, J,,
I swear I keep meaning to,
I just,,,
(COUGHS)
You need another
blanket here, buddy,
How many Fast & Furious
movies are there, anyway?
I mean, seriously,
Seven,
Yeah?
Yeah,
I got a Iot of
catching up to do,
Yeah, well, the Iast
one's the best,
How about this? Gonna
start with the Iast one
and move back,
Deal?
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Okay,
Dr, Rhodes, Dressed?
I'm Dr, Charles,
Head of Psychiatry,
Welcome to Chicago Med,
PIeasure, thank you,
Uh, you two know
each other?
Yeah, old pals, Known
Jamie since he was eight,
He taught me
how to play chess,
Big mistake, Beats me
every time, I'm not kidding,
(CHUCKLES)
Uh, Jamie, I've got
your test results back,
I wish they were
a Iittle more encouraging,
You're pancytopenic,
which means that
your cell counts are Iow,
You've got a blood pH of
7,14, which means you,,,
I know,
I'd Iike to intubate you,
Put you to sleep,
Get you on a ventilator,
You're getting fatigued,
This would just
allow you to rest,
so that the antibiotics
can do their job,
I've been intubated
eight times,
I think I'II skip it,
All right,
I'II check back in Iater?
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
Hey,
Well, there's something
I don't often see,
Will Halstead
Looking stumped,
Why is it brain
injuries are never Iike
you read in the textbooks?
My pregnant TBI patient,
Bilateral contusions,
she was a GCS 3,
And now, all of a sudden,
she's exhibiting
movement and
she's improved to a 6,
Well, that's good news,
Yeah, The baby's
parents will be happy,
Oh! She's a surrogate,
Oh, Wow! I don't know
how they do that,
Carry a baby and
then give it up?
(EXHALES)
I mean, I know it brings
a Iot of joy to other
people, but still,,,
Hmm,
Thanks, (GRUNTS)
Yeah,
You meet the new
guy yet? Rhodes,
You could say that,
Likes to throw
his weight around,
It all strikes me
as a Iittle arrogant,
Hey, I am not arrogant,
No, No, not at all,
You just happen to know
more than anybody else,
Dr, Rhodes,
this is Ms, Acosta,
She's the girlfriend
of your patient
Jorge Melendez,
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Ms, Acosta, your
boyfriend has suffered
severe injuries,
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Coma?
Does he have any family
that we could contact?
Familia?
No, I am all he has,
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(WHISPERS)
He speaks Spanish?
(SINGING) But to me, you're as
fair as you were, Maggie
When you and I were young
Hey, Herrmann,
(CHUCKLES)
You boys hanging
in there?
Well, you know,
it's a train wreck,
You?
Hmm, Same,
Is that from
the crash site?
Yeah, Yeah, it's a first
Ioad, Uh, cell phones,
shoes, wallets, purses,,,
(SIGHS) Thank you,
You're welcome,
(MACHINE BEEPING)
(CRYING) Jorge,
We're keeping him
cool to prevent fever,
Come on,
Jorge!
(CRYING)
Jorge,
(READING) "Still, he was
determined to make it,
"With an extra shovel of coal,
"he started up the hill,
"The Iittle train
had never faced
"such a Iong uphill
climb before,
"He was glad that he was red,
"and that none of
the other trains could see,,,"
Mr, and Mrs, Donahue,
this is my colleague,
Dr, Manning,
Hi,
Hey,
We, uh, read to
the baby every night
so she'II recognize
our voices,
I do that, too,
(BEEPING)
Sherry?
Dr, Halstead?
Need to Iower down
her CO2, Take her off
the vent and bag her,
Give her a dose of
mannitol and increase
her dopamine drip to 12,
Right away,
Doctor?
Gina's intracranial
pressure is rising,
What does that mean?
You said that she
was getting better,
Well, she is, in that her
function was improving,
But the swelling
of her brain is
getting worse,
We're gonna try to
control it with medication,
And what if
the medication
doesn't work?
Then she'II
require surgery,
The procedure's called
a "decompressive
craniectomy,"
Would that be
dangerous to the baby?
There's always
a risk for the fetus,
And for the mother
as well, So, yes,
That's why we hope
the medication does the trick,
Thanks, Sherry,
Call me in five,
Dr, Charles,
Jamie has pneumonia,
And if there's any
hope of beating it,
I need to get him
on a ventilator now,
Well, you heard what he said,
he doesn't want that,
No, we're past
what Jamie wants,
You know what, Doctor,
we're actually not
past what Jamie wants,
The kid has been so
brutalized his entire Iife,
He has a right to say no,
Intubating Jamie
is the only hope
we have of
keeping him alive,
What's that gonna give
him? A week? 10 days?
It could be six months,
A year, More,
And in that time
anything could happen,
new treatments are
coming along every day,
Now, is he on the Iist?
He's right at the top,
But a match is
highly unlikely,
He has HLA antibodies from
an islet cell transplant,
Well, have you spoken
to his next of kin?
Have they
weighed in on this?
There isn't anybody,
Dad took off years ago,
His mom's an alcoholic,
Bounces in and out,
Look, Dr, Charles, you know
what's gonna happen,
Jamie'II Iose
consciousness,
and as his doctor,
I'm gonna put him
on a ventilator,
But by then it
may be too Iate,
And there won't be
any more choices,
No matter what
anybody wants,
I'm Sarah Reese,
I'm a fourth year
medical student,
Uh, Dr, Manning sent me
in to check on Rachel
before we sign her out,
This is for you,
Thanks,
What's his name?
Oh, Why don't, why don't
you give him a name?
Okay,
I need to talk
to your mom,
Hi,
So, uh, about
your husband,,,
What?
No, no, He's okay,
Um, he's still in surgery,
The OR nurse says
it's going well,
As soon as we hear something,
I'II Iet you know,
Rachel?
Rachel, can you hear me?
What is wrong?
What's happening?
I can't find a pulse,
Oh, my God!
VOICE OVER PA:
Code Blue, Treatment Three.
(LOUD BEEPING)
Code,,, Little help here?
VOICE OVER PA:
Code Blue, Treatment Three.
Code Blue...
You're not compressing
the heart, Sarah, You
gotta go harder,
But she's so small,
I don't wanna,,,
Harder,
Do it! Let's go!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BONES CRACKING)
Come on, Sarah, harder,
Hold, There we go,
back in sinus, Get her BP,
What happened?
She arrested,
We got her back,
I can't get an IV,
Hand me the drill,
get an IO Iine,
(DRILLING)
I got a Iine,
All right, Iet's get
her a CT-PE study,
then up to PICU,
Mom, you can
come with us,
Good job,
I just broke that
Iittle girl's ribs,
Reese, you saved
the girl's Iife,
Jamie,
You know more about
CF than most doctors,
I'm an expert,
Hmm, So, you know what
will happen if we don't
put you on a ventilator,
(COUGHS)
Dr, Charles,
It's okay,
I've had a good Iife,
Whoa, whoa, Whoa!
(CHUCKLES)
What movie is that from?
(CHUCKLES, COUGHS)
No, no, no,
Jamie, Look at me,
(SIGHS)
It's me, your cornerman,
Yeah?
You got a Iot of
fight Ieft in you,
I'm not ready to
throw in the towel,
One more round,
For you?
Yeah, For me,
Yeah, Okay, Okay,
Mariana,
Hi, I'm Maggie,
This,,, This is Jorge's,
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Yes,
Inside,
I found this,
"From J,M, to M,A,"
You're not his girlfriend,
you're his fiancée,
(BOTH SPEAKING SPANISH)
Jorge,
Natalie, what happened
with the Iittle girl?
Hey,
She had a cardiac contusion,
Bruising caused her to arrest,
She's good now,
but it was a real scare,
Thank you,
Yeah,
Hey, your
comatose guy,
Seems Iike you'd
want to put him
on the hypothermic protocol
and protect his brain,
Well, I just gave him
twenty units of blood,
His pH is only 7,2
and he's too cold
to make a clot,
So, I didn't see
how the hypothermic
protocol would help him,
Hey, you're the fellow,
I'm just a resident,
Heard you're Iocal, Me, too,
Where'd you grow up?
Lake Shore Drive,
(WHISTLES) Nice,
Doubt we have any
friends in common,
Hmm?
Canaryville,
Where'd you go to med school?
Johns Hopkins? Stanford?
No, I went to UAG,
Where's that?
Guadalajara,
Didn't see that coming,
Gotta go,
Her ICP is
unresponsive?
Her CPP is 40,
Sherry, get me
Dr, Abrams,
You're planning
to do the surgery?
What about our baby?
The meds we've
been giving Gina
haven't been effective,
Her intracranial pressure,
the brain swelling,
is getting to
a dangerous Ievel,
And we shouldn't
wait any Ionger,
I'm not sure we
can consent to that,
It's not really
a matter of consent,
Well, actually,
Doctor, it is,
We have a surrogacy
contract with Gina,
A rider to that is
a medical power
of attorney,
giving us the right
to make decisions
on Gina's behalf,
I don't see how
we can sign off
on a procedure
knowing it will
endanger our child,
Mr, and Mrs, Donahue,
Gina needs this surgery,
It's her only hope,
But it's not a guarantee
she's gonna recover,
No, But without
the surgery, I can
guarantee she won't,
You would just allow
her condition to worsen?
This is our child!
What would you do
to save your child?
VOICE OVER PA: Code Blue,
ICU. Code Blue, ICU.
Code Blue, ICU.
MARIANA: Jorge!
I'II take over,
Ma'am, I'm sorry,
we need some more room,
Jorge!
Hold compressions,
No pulse,
Sinus tach,
He's profoundly
hypotensive,
Amp of epi,
Max of dopamine,
max of vaso,
You're gonna max
him on pressors,
Don't have a choice,
Pads,
(SOBBING)
PIease,
That contract's obscene,
I mean, the Donahues
control everything,
What Gina can eat, drink,
how much she sleeps,
Even what she wears,
We have to perform
this operation,
Well, I'd advise
against that,
Because this is
really comprehensive,
And nicely drawn up,
I might add,
The Iady probably
didn't even know
what she was signing,
We can't prove that,
We can't just stand
by and Iet her die,
I guarantee if we
perform this operation,
regardless of the outcome,
we'II be sued,
And they'II Iikely win,
And I'm,,, Millions,
And that's how we
make our decisions?
By how much
it's gonna cost us?
All right!
Get off the high horse,
Dr, Halstead,
How about we call
the Ethics Committee?
Be faster to call a judge,
But I'm not gonna
burn a favor on this,
This is ridiculous!
Why aren't you
trying to help us?
He is, and you
need to back off,
So much easier
to run a hospital
without doctors,
PIease,
Jorge's brain was
without oxygen
for too Iong,
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Dead?
I'm so sorry,
Jorge! (SOBBING)
(WEEPS)
Mariana,
Mariana, this is Ms, Goodwin,
our hospital administrator,
and Yolanda Cruz
from Gift of Hope,
They'd Iike to
speak to you,
Thank you, Dr, Rhodes,
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Let's get Mr, Melendez
typed for organ donation,
just in case,
Keep him on
the ventilator,
Okay,
Your first day,
You already found my
hiding spot, I'm Nat,
Connor,
I don't suppose you
keep a bottle stashed
up here, do you?
(CHUCKLES)
Not in my condition,
I heard about
your patient,
Tough one,
Yeah,
I just keep wondering,
If there was anything
else you could've
done? I know,
Is your husband
a doc, too?
No,
(CELLPHONE VIBRATING)
Excuse me,
Hi, I have some
good news,
Somebody would Iike
to say hello to you,
Oh, God, David,
Judy.
I'm fine. How's Rachel?
She's good,
She's sleeping,
The doctor said
her tests are good,
They just wanna keep
her here a day or two,
David, I didn't know
where you were!
I don't know what
I would do if I Iost you,
Ms, Donahue,
I'm Sharon Goodwin,
Chief of Services,
I know about
your situation,
And you think
we're monsters,
No, No,
I think that you and
your husband are faced
with a, a very
difficult decision,
We just wanted to
have a baby, that's all,
It's supposed to be
so simple, so natural,
And instead,,,
I understand,
We Iove Gina,
But this is our Iast
chance to have a child,
There's no more
embryos, no more eggs,
What are
we supposed to do?
You have to ask yourself
what you can Iive with,
How are you gonna
feel a week from now,
a month, or a few years?
Gina handed over her Iife
to you in that contract,
She trusted you to
make the right decision,
What would you
do if you were me?
I'd want to Iive up
to that trust,
(EXHALES)
I'm removing
cranial flap now,
The swelling's
pretty pronounced,
We'd waited any Ionger
she would've herniated,
Fetal heartbeat's
steady,
I don't recall inviting
you into my OR,
Give me suction here,
NURSE: Yes, Doctor,
All right, As soon
as I cauterize this,
we can get
into the dura,
OBSTETRICIAN: Fetal heart
rate is dropping,
I haven't opened
the dura yet,
NURSE: Patient's
BP is falling,
WOMAN: One hundred ten,
ABRAMS: Oh, I'm almost there,
OBSTETRICIAN: One hundred,
Tracings Look Iike crap,
That strip doesn't
correct in thirty seconds,
we're crash sectioning her,
Give me suction here,
Yes, sir,
Give me suction
right now, More,
Yeah,
Dr, Charles,
A crash victim I'd
been treating has died,
He's a match for Jamie,
Well, Iet's get him
some Iungs,
Only thing, his fiancée
won't give consent,
Where is she?
Joel,
(CLEARS THROAT)
It was a difficult surgery,
But it went well,
Dr, Abrams was able
to relieve the pressure
on Gina's brain,
Both Gina and the baby
came through just fine,
So far,
Dr, Abrams will be out
to speak to you shortly,
Thank you,
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
DANIEL: He's 20 years old,
Without new Iungs,
he'II die,
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Your fiancé,,,
(CONNOR SPEAKING SPANISH)
,,,the man you Ioved,,,
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
,,,the man who
Ioved you,,,
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
,,,can save his Iife,
Wait,
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Yes,
Thank you,
I'II alert
the transplant team,
Central Iine,
I can't tell
you how many times
I missed before
I finally got it,
I know how to do it,
I just couldn't
do it in there,
It takes practice,
that's all,
I'm fine with him,
I never miss,
Yeah, He's the ideal
patient,
You can't hurt him,
and his Iife's not
hanging in the balance,
If this rotation
weren't a requirement,
I wouldn't be here,
Where would you be?
I'm a Iab person,
Pathology?
Maybe,
Yeah,
Every med student,
once they start
dealing with patients,
thinks they'd do
better in pathology,
I did,
Nat?
You okay?
The first few
months after Jeff died,,,
(SNIFFS)
I still kept waiting for him
to walk through the door,
I don't anymore,
(CRYING)
Come here,
"Death, vicious death
Leave a green
branch for Iove"
You do speak Spanish,
Nope,
But you know Lorca,
Third wife was from
Spain, Loved Lorca,
Came in handy when
we were courting,
(CHUCKLES)
They got
the first Iung in,
Halfway there,
Jamie made that for me,
When he was eight,
You know, I was brought
in to help him cope
with his condition,
All the things he
wouldn't be able to do,
Did not need my help,
I mean, this kid
did more things
than most kids
his age ever do,
He went up for the swim team
in high school,
Kid was CF,
Taught me how to cope,
Going back to the hospital?
Yeah,
Wouldn't mind being there
when he wakes up,
Can I come?
Sure,
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)