You can't be serious.
GREENE: Why not?
Barbecuing in January?
Yeah, you just
freeze your butt off
for, like, 10, 15 minutes.
No, you freeze your butt
off for 10 or 15 minutes.
Is this a San Diego ritual?
Dad and I did barbecue a
couple of times last week.
Well, I'm game if you are.
Let's stop by after work.
Pick up some steaks.
Sounds good.
- Good morning.
You're, uh...? Uh, Andrew.
And you'd be Doctors
Greene and Corday?
Yeah. Messages for both of you.
The first of which is
that I'm looking for you.
Actually, the first
one for Dr. Greene...
What's your name again?
Andrew. Andy, yeah.
I think you might wanna
answer those phones.
Thank you. Yeah, good kid.
Few more years of
training, and he might cut it.
What do you need, Robert?
We have a new ER
resident starting today
named Jing-Mei
Chen or Sling-My...
Uh, anyway, uh, I need
you to say howdy-doody.
Starting in January?
Apparently, her program
in New York fell apart,
and, uh, she's got a
daddy with deep pockets.
Sounds like deep
donation to County General.
Let's keep that
amongst ourselves.
You got a minute? Sure.
Uh, that message I
wanted to give you earlier.
Your father's disappeared
from his retirement home.
What?
I'm sensing it's more
of a runaway thing.
I don't believe they're
suspecting foul play.
I feel better already.
What's open? Oh,
uh, uh, Curtain 2.
And now another
case has come up.
A girl, Jenny Cordova,
missing about six weeks ago.
We found her car abandoned.
Dean Rollins' prints were on it.
You haven't found
the body yet? No.
And you want me to
ask him where it is?
Yes.
For better or worse,
you've developed a
relationship with him.
You talked him into telling
you where the other body was.
You talked him
into having surgery.
This family needs your help.
He's a cold-blooded
son of a bitch.
I don't think he'll tell me.
I'll ask.
But I can tell you
now, it's hopeless.
The Cordovas don't
have any option,
so hopeless is
better than nothing.
Five of Haldol?
I just itch, okay.
Cassandra, ma'am.
Can you do something?
Are you taking any medications?
Have you seen a dermatologist?
Whoa. Security!
Stop, stop, stop.
We need security!
Oh, come on, now.
Get her off!
All right, that's enough.
John?
Oh, my God.
Deb.
Yeah, it's me.
I'm surprised to
see you down here.
Thought you'd get a
surgical residency for sure.
I did. I gave it up.
Deb Chen? You're
the new resident?
Oh, that's right, Dr. Greene.
Oh, but it's Jing-Mei now.
Actually, it always
was. Right. Sorry.
Carter, listen, I might have to
fly to San Diego this morning,
so if you could show, uh, Deb...
Jing-Mei. Jing-Mei
the, uh, ropes, okay? Sure.
Hey, is everything okay?
My father's barricaded
himself in our old house.
No heat, no electricity.
He's running around
in his underwear,
so actually,
everything isn't okay,
but thanks for askin'. Yeah.
Yeah, I'm actually
pretty surprised
to see you around here.
I, uh, thought you
dropped out of after...
I almost killed that patient
by leaving a guide
wire in his chest?
I'm sorry, I didn't
mean to bring that up.
Oh, yes, you did,
John, but that's okay.
And let's face it. It
was kind of a low point,
but it did force me
to face the truth.
I was being way too aggressive,
way too competitive, too
much of an overachiever,
always trying to
show people up. Well...
And way too successful at it.
I'd left the patient
out of the picture.
Oh, it looks like your wrestling
partner tired herself out.
Hi, I'm Yosh Takata.
Hi, Jing-Mei Chen.
Much better with the Haldol.
This is Cassandra
Harper. Gloves?
She came in extremely agitated
With intense pruritus.
Called for a psych consult.
Dr. Myers'll be down shortly.
Do you think it's a
psychiatric disorder?
I do, yes.
Either severe OCD,
or a body dysmorphic disorder.
Yes, but, um, did you see these?
What?
Burrows, papules.
I think there's a good
chance it's lindane toxicity.
She's got body lice.
Classic symptoms.
Applied lindane for the
lice, scratched herself,
and the lindane
entered her bloodstream,
thereby causing her
altered mental status.
But I guess we should
wait for doctor, uh...
Myers. I'll give him a call.
Right.
Uh, taxi'll be here
in five minutes, Dr. Greene.
Sorry about no barbecue.
Don't be ridiculous. I'm
worried about your father.
Should be worried. I may
have to kill him for pullin' this.
You know how hard it
was to get him in there?
Yes, I believe you have
shared that with me.
Wish you were coming.
Yeah, so do I.
I'm off to see
Dean Rollins next.
I'll be glad when
you're rid of him.
Makes two of us.
Hey, call me when you get there.
I will. Okay.
Oh, Andrew!
Yeah.
Uh, can you give
that to Yosh Takata?
Dr. Weaver'll be
here any minute,
and, uh, in the meantime,
you're in charge.
What if there's an emergency?
Call a doctor.
There's one!
We need a doctor. Wh...? Wait...
Wh...? What's the problem?
Smile. GIRL: We're
on a scavenger hunt.
We have to find a
doctor a policeman,
a bridegroom and a polar bear.
Thanks. Bye.
Mr. And Mrs. Sumpter,
this is Dr. Chen. Hi.
Mr. Sumpter slipped on
his roof a couple weeks ago.
No big deal at the
time, but the pain
kept getting worse?
That right.
It's the last day or so.
Well, it could be a torn
meniscus or an ACL.
I actually already
told them that, Deb,
but thank you.
An 18-gauge needle
and a 50 cc syringe, please.
You sure? Won't that hurt?
Oh, it should be fine.
Dr. Carter's gonna
insert the needle
into the joint and
aspirate the blood,
which should relieve the
pain almost immediately.
Here we go.
That is gross.
Definitely bacterial. Hm.
Looks like you picked up
a bit of a staph
infection after your fall.
As soon as we get the results,
we'll start you on
some antibiotics,
and you'll be better in no time.
Thank you. Thank you.
You're very welcome.
Yeah, we'll be back.
Dr. Carter, Dr. Chen?
Yosh mentioned lindane toxicity?
Oh, just a crazy guess.
Hi, I'm Jing-Mei Chen.
Pretty good crazy
guess. Good pickup.
Paul Myers, Psychiatry.
Thanks for thinki"
of us, Carter.
Feels good to be back.
Need a trauma surgeon?
Uh, no, just a fender
bender. I can handle it.
The patient doesn't
meet trauma criteria.
Well, I'm here. Might
as well have a look.
And lift.
What's your name? Tamara Davis.
All right, let's
take a look here.
Pupils are equal and reactive.
Do you know where
you are? The hospital.
I have a basketball
game tonight. Can I play?
Let's finish the exam first.
Now, how did the
accident happen?
I was driving and the
next thing I remember
is being put into the ambulance.
Ouch! Point tenderness
at the snuff box.
My shooting hand.
We'll need to get
some x-rays of your wrist.
Make sure you do a
cone-down of the navicular.
Thanks, Peter.
What would I do without you?
Oh, hey, John, Gram stain's back
on that knee
patient, Mr. Sumpter.
Is it staph?
In his dreams. Try gonorrhea.
Ouch. More like his nightmare.
You gonna tell them?
I'll tell him.
Legally, we can't tell her
without his permission.
Hopefully he'll
tell her himself.
Yeah, but we still
have to report it
to Public Health, right?
They can follow
up, tell the wife.
Kind of doubt it.
Between syphilis and HIV,
they kind of have
their hands full.
Yeah, what if Sumpter
doesn't tell his wife?
Then he doesn't tell his wife.
Good morning.
You lied to me.
You turned my life into pain.
I didn't lie to you, and I'm
sorry for how you're feeling,
but you fractured your pelvis
you tore up the nerves
and arteries in your leg,
and it's going to be
a long recuperation.
Give me something.
Give him 10 of morphine. Ten?
Dean, I want to talk to you.
Ten is a joke for what I got.
What are you trying to do to me?
Believe it or not,
I'm trying to help you.
Well, I don't believe it,
and I want you outta here.
Get her outta here!
You're fired.
I want a new doctor.
Get out.
Excuse me, is there a pay phone?
Andrew.
Pay phone? Uh, yeah.
Uh, pay phone.
Pay phone is, uh...
Over by Chairs.
Okay, I know he's
Andrew, but who are you?
Oh, Jing-Mei Chen, new
resident starting today.
Hey. Dr. Dave Malucci.
Did you say today?
I'm Kerry Weaver,
chief of the ER.
And why are you
starting in January?
Um, could I speak to you alone?
Of course.
Now, as chief, I
think you should know
my father bought my
way into the program
by giving County a
huge amount of money.
I'm not proud of
it, but I am grateful.
I'm not a bad doctor,
but, uh, as a med student,
I did almost kill a
patient in this very ER.
I'm more competent now,
so hopefully, this
will all work out.
Hopefully it will.
Andrew, could you, uh,
dig out the yellow pages?
My car broke down
across the street.
Say no more, Dr. Weaver.
Automotive repair
is my middle name.
I'm sure you have patients.
No, I'm not even on yet.
I'm just in doin' paperwork.
Okay, I hope I
don't regret this.
Give it a shot.
Stopped, I couldn't
get it started again.
And remember, it's
broke. It's not dead.
Andrew, since you're
not looking up car repair,
could you find me the number
for the Public
Health Department?
Sure.
My wife went to use the phone.
That's okay, actually.
We don't need her for this.
Uh, Mr. Sumpter, the Gram stain
shows that you have gonorrhea.
What?
You tapped my knee.
I... I don't get this.
The bacteria's carried
through the blood.
It happened to
settle in your knee.
Have you had any
discharge during urination?
Couple weeks back. It went away.
Had sex with anyone
other than your wife?
What the hell's going on?
Mr. Sumpter, you have
a sexually transmitted disease.
Have you had sex with
anyone other than your wife?
Stop. Stop.
One time, okay?
Me and the guys, we were
out celebrating a new contract...
I don't need to
know the details,
but I think that you
should tell your wife.
Oh, man!
Mr. Sumpter, I would
encourage you to...
You son of a bitch!
You lying, conniving...
Come on, come
on... Mrs. Sumpter!
Mrs. Sumpter! Carter! Chen!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
You know, I can walk.
I'm sure you can.
I can walk.
It's okay, Jake.
But I can walk.
Did you drive here by yourself?
Yeah.
I can drive. I want to learn.
Not right now, Jake, all right?
Okay, let's take a look.
I want you to sit here.
Hey, no, Jake.
Let him do it, all right?
She was not supposed
to tell the wife.
I did not tell the wife.
I held out the phone
so that Public Health
could tell his wife.
Okay! Okay, hey, nobody's
done anything wrong. All right?
Next time let's just keep it
from becoming a slugfest.
Carter, Sumpter's your
patient. Clean it up. Chen?
Yes. I've got a
Jane Doe in Chairs
with Officer Grabarsky.
Check it out.
Hi, I'm Jing-Mei Chen.
Jing what?
This Jane Doe?
Yeah, she's a probable runaway.
She won't give us her real name.
She was panhandli" under the el.
She got some frostbite
and a bad lac on her forearm.
I'm fine.
Hey, look, it's warm in here.
They feed you.
They let you sleep.
My advice: take the day off.
She's all yours.
Thanks. Yeah.
Hi, come on.
So you were cooking
breakfast, huh?
Yeah, it's no big deal.
I like French toast.
Oh, so do I, Jake,
with maple syrup.
I like French toast.
That what you were cooking?
I'm sorry, Dillon.
I'm sorry.
Jake, shut up and sit down.
Don't be mad. I'm sorry.
Jake, I'm not mad. Just shut up.
It's okay. He can talk.
Was it grease that burned you?
What the hell
difference does it make?
I mean, just put
some stuff on it,
and we'll be outta here.
And you were having a
kind of late breakfast, huh?
Yeah.
Did you miss school?
I'm 18. I'm out of school.
I'm sorry, Dillon.
What about Jake?
I wanted French
toast. I'm sorry!
I'm sorry! Shut up, Jake!
I'm sorry, Dillon! I'm sorry!
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm...
Jake! No, I'll get him!
I'll get him. Take it easy.
Hey, it's okay. It's
okay. He'll be fine.
Hey, Dave, what are you
doing, stealing Weaver's car?
Just takin' a look.
Couldn't get it started.
So, uh, Carter,
did you know this new resident,
Jing-something-or-other?
That's good, screw up her
name. That'll impress her.
I heard she was a
medical student here.
Is that right?
Yes, she was. Yes, I knew her.
And? And... nothin'.
Ah, it didn't work out, huh?
Dave, I did not
try and go through
every medical student.
Oh, yeah? Why not?
I'm just kiddin', my friend.
You want me to back
off, you just say so.
No, I think you guys
would be great together.
Go for it.
Consider it done.
So Jake was the
one cooking, huh?
I had some business to handle,
so I didn't get
home till like 2.
So I slept in.
Jake wanted some French toast,
so he started fixin' it himself.
Damn. Half that
kitchen caught on fire.
And he knows better than that.
Don't you, Jake?
You can talk now.
I'm not mad no more.
He hates it when he think
he's done something wrong.
Just goes all quiet.
Where are your parents?
They don't ask about us,
we don't ask about them.
Can't even remember
when Pops left.
Mom is on the streets.
We see her every now and then,
but we move around a lot.
Must make it hard for Social
Services to keep up with you.
They got enough to do
without worryi" about us.
Yeah, maybe they could help you.
Or maybe we just
keep helpin' ourselves.
Can you? Yeah, I
do okay, all right?
Jake works around the complex,
sweepin' up and stuff.
People pay him.
We do fine.
I do my job.
You do, man.
You do a good job.
We do just fine.
You can't force me to do this.
We're not forcing you.
We are helping you.
That's the deal. You get to
lie about your name and age.
But you do not get to sit around
in these stinky clothes.
Maybe I can find you
something in lost and found.
Thanks, Haleh.
So... Jane Doe, huh?
My parents weren't very clever.
Maybe not, but I
bet they miss you.
I wouldn't know.
So, Jane,
how did you get these
other marks on your arms?
I don't recall.
You are just a fountain
of information, aren't you?
Yep.
Dr. Chen, you have a call on 5
out here at the desk.
Uh, could you take
a message, please?
Uh, no, it's the
lab calling about
the little boy with meningitis?
Little boy with meningitis?
They said it was urgent.
Okay, um... I'll be
back. Don't run away.
Very funny.
Haleh, I don't know about any...
Wallet. Found it
in her coat pocket.
Name's Alyssa Adams.
Address and phone number.
We're still waiting
on your x-rays,
but in the meantime, we're
going to put you next door.
I can't just walk?
I'm sure you can, if it
weren't for the damn rules.
So where were you
drivin' this morning
when you met up with that pole?
Late to school.
I guess I fell
asleep at the wheel.
At 9 in the morning?
Pulled an all-nighter.
Chemistry mid-term today.
School pretty tough?
Sometimes.
Have you been feeling
depressed about it?
Wouldn't you, if you were
getting a C-in chemistry?
Depressed enough to
do somethin' about it?
You're thinking I meant to
drive into that telephone pole
like suicide or somethin'?
Did you? God, no.
My parents would
kill me if I ever did that.
Not to mention my coach.
Especially today.
That's right.
Basketball game tonight.
Against Union,
who we haven't beaten
in like three years.
Except this year they suck.
I used to shoot a few myself.
You played?
High school and college.
Although, track was my thing.
I do track in the spring.
I run the 100 and the 4-by-1.
I was more distance.
The 800, the two mile.
Oh, Tammy, there you are.
We were worried sick about you.
Sweetheart, are you okay?
Mom, Dad, I'm fine.
Mr. And Mrs.
Davis, I'm Dr. Finch.
Is she going to be all right?
Will she be able
to play tonight?
We're still waiting
on her wrist x-rays.
I'll check back.
I called Coach Avery,
and he's agreed to
keep you on the roster
until he hears from us.
I can talk to him, Dad.
And I'm gonna call Mr. Williams.
See about you taking
chemistry in summer school.
You paged me. Yeah, yeah, um...
Detective Cruson was unable
to persuade Rollins to talk.
I didn't think he'd
have much luck.
Perhaps you could try
again. I already tried.
Besides, he wants
another doctor.
Well, I think you should try
and talk him out of that too.
I don't want to ever
talk to him again.
The Cordovas. Yeah.
Mrs. Cordova's
other daughter, Jenny,
was only 19 years old.
This is not fair of you, Robert.
You and I both know I
am capable of a low blow.
However, I rarely use it
to such purity of purpose.
What's up? Jason Bender, 11.
Shortness of breath
during Phys. Ed.
Also complaining of mild
pain to the upper left chest.
I got hit yesterday
with a hockey stick.
I get hit all the time,
usually in the head.
Squeeze my hand.
That why you're trying
to take a car apart in the snow?
We'll get you fixed up
good. You call his parents?
Mom's on her way. All right.
How's that boy who
broke the light box?
He's okay now.
He lives with his
older brother, right?
There's no parents?
Right.
Hm, have you called DCFS?
I think the older
boy needs a job
more than he needs
Social Services.
Well, are either one
of them in school?
They've been
moving around a lot.
Yeah.
Look, I mean, we see
a lot of kids like this.
It's rough, but if they
get an education,
they have some kind
of chance at a future.
Call DCFS, see if you
can get 'em some help?
Sure.
Mrs. Adams?
Yes, hi, this is Dr. Chen
from County General.
I'm calling about
your daughter, Alyssa.
Uh, Dr. Weaver,
there's a phone call
for a Carol Hathaway?
Yeah, she's on maternity
leave for another week.
Take a message.
Are you a doctor?
We need a doctor.
Yes.
E-excellent. Can
we take your picture?
Yes.
Thanks. Thanks, man.
Your fingerprints were
found all over her car.
They want to know
where the body is.
You know, sometimes I feel
everyone just wants
a little piece of me.
Will you tell them?
No, I don't recall this girl.
What is the point, Dean?
You've already been
charged with murder.
Why cause more needless grief?
Needless grief
is what I do best.
Oh, fine, then.
W-wait! Wait! Wait! I...
Look, I don't know...
If I talk, will you
still be my doctor?
Yes. Then I will, but...
only to the sister.
Well, I don't think
they'll allow that.
Why don't you just tell me?
Mm-mmm. I wanna do it.
But I don't wanna have
to look at the mother.
Take a deep breath.
Okay, let it out.
How long you been
short of breath?
Couple of days. Yeah.
Any fever?
Well, he had a mild
temperature a few days ago.
I thought it was just a cold.
Mm, and have you
been tired lately?
Yeah, I get up at 5 every
morning for hockey practice.
Okay, lie back down.
Jason has a consolidation
in his left lung.
And what does that mean?
Ah, he probably has pneumonia,
which would account
for the chest pain
Is that bad?
We call it "walkin' pneumonia."
Because you're such a tough guy,
it doesn't stop you
from playin' hockey.
Low voltage,
otherwise normal EKG.
This machine's total bull.
You know, why don't we,
uh, find another one, uh,
and run it again? Sure.
In the meantime, I'm
gonna get a chest x-ray
and start Jason on antibiotics.
Who's your favorite
hockey team? The Bruins.
The Bruins? Oh,
man, you're in Chicago.
You're killin' me.
B-hawks, baby, B-hawks.
Adele.
Hey, Kerry. Hey.
Were you able to help that boy
with the burned arms and
hi...? His younger brother?
It's not ringing a bell.
Two brothers,
Dr. Kovac's patient.
No, he didn't mention anything.
Oh, well, uh, you'll
need to see them.
I'll check on it. All
right. Well, I'll be around.
Peter, we've got a
rule-out appy in Four.
I know it's not
trauma, but Mark's off.
Could you take it? Yeah, sure.
All right, she
looks clear to me.
Yeah, except scaphoid fractures
can be pretty difficult to see.
Well, that's why we
have multiple views.
I wasn't impressed
with her exam.
She can come back, and
we'll take a look at her again.
Well, you fill in the parents.
I'll go talk to her. Sure.
Good news. You can
get out of this joint.
No fracture.
Oh, really?
So does that mean
I can play tonight?
Well, if you're feelin' up
to it, I don't see why not.
Hey.
What's goin' on? You okay?
I have a chemistry
exam I'm about to flunk,
and all I do is practice.
Three mornings a week,
every day after school.
I live it, you know.
I really do.
I'm just tired right now.
Let's do this, okay?
Why don't you hang
out here for a while,
and I'll get the radiologist to
take a look at these x-rays?
You said there was no fracture.
I'll get an expert's
opinion. You get some rest.
What do you say?
The doctor was Chinese,
or the nurse, she was black.
I need to speak to them.
I'll try and find them...
Could you tell me where
the lost and found is?
I need clothes. Hey,
what's going on here?
Alyssa, what are you doing
here? What did you call me?
I need to get out of here.
No, no, Alyssa, wait, wait...
Look, you stole my clothes,
and you stole my coat.
You're trying to trick me.
We didn't steal anything, okay?
And we'll give
it all back to you.
You know, you're
not going anywhere
until I sew up that laceration
and you tell me what's going on.
Please, let me help.
You can't, okay? Yes, I can.
No, you can't! No... No...
Sit down. Sit down. Fine, fine.
Just listen for a
minute, will you?
Okay, you are
safe here. Now, ju...
Who tricked you?
Y...? Your parents?
Yes, they...
To get me into this
treatment center.
That's where I ran away from.
Okay, treatment center.
Like for drugs or alcohol?
No.
For gender identity.
What?
My parents sent me away
because they think
I'm sick and confused.
I keep telling them,
"Mom, Dad, get over it.
All I am is gay."
Ultimately, it's
your own decision.
Mom, I can do it.
I don't want you near him.
I'll be just outside,
and Rollins is
still in restraints.
Since the accident,
he's no longer able
to get out of bed.
He can't hurt anyone.
He killed my daughter.
Mrs. Cordova...
I don't understand this
man, and I don't care to.
But right now, you
have nothing to lose.
If Lindsey asks
him, I think he might
just tell her where
your daughter is.
And if he doesn't?
We may never find her.
Please?
Mom, I have to know.
I'll be in there with her.
Dave, do you have a sec?
What a mess. What?
Weaver's car. I got it started,
but these spark
plugs are ridiculous.
I never should have
opened my big mouth.
You oughta to look at this.
Hold on, I'm almost done.
It's your 11-year-old
with pneumonia.
Since when do you
pull x-rays for me?
Radiology flagged it.
Whoa, what the hell is that?
Mediastinal mass.
Around the heart?
Flint suspects lymphoma.
No wonder the EKG
showed low voltage.
Looks like infiltrates
through both lung fields.
It's inoperable.
This boy is dead.
They call this place a
treatment center, John,
like they're gonna cure her.
Her parents sent her
away for deprogramming?
Yeah. They granted
them guardianship.
Get her outta here
before they show up.
I didn't tell her I called them.
She needs help, and
I don't want her to bolt.
Call Social Services.
What are they gonna do?
I'm assuming
this place is legal.
It shouldn't be. Right.
Dr. Chen, we have
a situation here.
Huh? ALYSSA: Get off me!
I'm not going back!
Calm down, Alyssa.
Don't touch me!
Call Security! Hey, hey, hey.
You got it.
No need for that.
I'm her legal guardian.
You called my
parents? You bitch!
Dr. Ramsey, principal
of the Second Turn
Treatment Center.
Second Turn? Her
parents call me,
asked me to pick her up.
Leave me alone. CHEN:
We can't allow that.
I have temporary
custody. She's not ready.
Why not? 'Cause we
need to do further tests.
For what? She's pregnant.
Pregnant? Yes,
lab work confirms it.
I bet. Unfortunately, for you,
this means Alyssa is now
an emancipated minor.
She can decide
where she wants to go.
Look, I don't know
what this girl has told you
about the center, but
this is a load of bunk.
And frankly, an obstruction
of parental rights.
Well, Alyssa, do
you wanna stay here
or go with Mr. Ramsey?
I wanna stay here.
We all know she
can't be pregnant.
She's a healthy young
woman of childbearing age.
You might talk to some of
the male members of your staff.
I wanna see this lab report.
Oh, records are confidential.
Confidential? You just told me.
You're right. I shouldn't have.
Fine. I'll be back
with a court order.
I'll be praying for you, Alyssa.
Don't bother.
Dr. Corday.
Mr. Rollins.
This is Lindsey Cordova.
Hi, Lindsey.
I'd, uh... I'd shake
hands, but...
So how can I help you?
I wanna bury my sister.
Please, just tell
me where she is.
Were you close to her, Lindsey?
Yes, I was.
I didn't have
brothers or sisters.
I mean, all my life, I've never
known what that was like.
You know, to be
part of a family.
I have done terrible
things, Lindsey.
I've done evil things.
I know.
But I am paying for them now.
We don't want you to suffer.
We just wanna
know where Jenny is.
You're a good person.
More forgiving than most people.
Do you know that
maybe if I had met you,
Jenny would still be alive.
What do you mean?
If only I'd met you, Lindsey.
I know it now.
You're warm...
and loving.
If only I'd met you.
I could have had you instead.
What? Jenny
screamed all the time.
I was glad to get
rid of her, Lindsey.
Oh, God. You bastard!
Hey, what's her problem?!
I pulled his medical records.
He had lymphoma two years ago.
Chemo put it in remission.
The mother didn't
mention cancer?
Well, she said she must
have blocked it out of her mind.
It never affected
his breathing before.
Are you doing a thoracentesis?
As soon as the mom
figures out a way to tell him.
Well, she says she can't so...
Yeah, then you should.
I paged Oncology.
No, you... You tell
him. You tell him.
Well, wait a minute.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Wait, wait. Don't
you think Oncology
would be better at that?
No, no, you're his doctor.
Dillon! Just keep walking.
Dillon, wait.
He's calling you. I know.
Where are you going?
Not your problem.
Your brother needs
a tetanus shot.
Yeah, sure, he does.
I don't understand.
Wha... What's wrong?
Yeah, Dillon, what's wrong?
He gave us up. Gave you up?
Gave us up? Shut up, Jake.
You called a social worker.
I didn't call the social worker.
Right, I'm sure
she always come by
and visits all the
retards. I'm not a retard!
I know. I know. I'm sorry.
That's not what I meant, okay?
I swear... I swear I
didn't call anyone!
That was a mistake.
But you guys need help.
I've been taking care
of him for two years.
We do just fine. Yeah?
He doesn't go to school.
You have no job, no money.
God knows where you live.
Yes, you've got everything
under control. We get by.
Yeah, but sometimes
not very well.
You... You're
burned. Jake is cut.
Just, please, hey, let me...
Let me figure
something out, huh?
Then he said he was
gonna get a court order.
Have you heard from the parents?
No, and she's
really not pregnant.
Yeah, I assumed that part.
And I assume you didn't
write it on her chart?
No. Did you? No.
Okay, there's a gay and
lesbian center on Wabash.
Andrew can get you the number.
Get her in a cab.
Get her over there.
Then call her parents. Let
them know that she's okay.
Okay. Right. Thank
you. Hey, Dr. Chen.
As a rule, we don't lie
about our patients'
medical conditions.
Yeah. Ah, it's her first day.
I better get back to work.
Good idea.
Excuse me? Are
you a doctor? Uh, yes.
Can I take your
picture? Wh-what?
I'm on this scavenger hunt...
Who's cleaning auto
parts in Trauma 1?
I know it's not
sterile, but come on.
Oh, Malucci.
Can I take your picture?
I'm on this scavenger hunt.
What? Go away.
Dr. Benton, I thought you
said her wrist was all right.
Yeah, just a little sore.
Yeah, but can she play? Yeah.
Then why is the other
doctor putting a cast on?
What?
Dr. Finch?
Dr. Benton.
She says it's some
kind of cult fracture.
It's hard to see.
Occult. And yes, it
can be hard to see.
Radiology couldn't rule it out.
I thought you
looked at the x-ray.
Uh, yeah, I did.
Um, Dr. Finch, do
you have a minute?
Sure.
I'll be right back, Tamara.
I mean, it feels okay, right?
You think you can play?
Yeah. It's important
that she plays.
It's important that
she stays healthy.
What are you doing?
Casting her wrist.
I told her parents she was fine.
I ran it by Radiology.
They couldn't say for
sure that it wasn't fractured.
The chances of her having
a fracture are negligible.
I'd rather be safe.
She's an athlete.
She can push too
far, really hurt herself.
Well, then tell her not to.
The girl's under way too
much pressure to perform.
She needs a break.
Did she ask you
to put a cast on?
She's emotionally and
physically exhausted.
She can always decide
not to play, you know.
That girl hasn't made a decision
for herself since she was 11.
Everything she does revolves
around pleasing her coach,
her parents, her
teammates, her teachers.
I'm trying to give her
a bit of time to rest.
Did she ask you?
You don't understand. She can't.
You're controlling
her? I'm protecting her.
I'm sure that's what her parents
thought they were doing too.
That's why my chest
has been hurting?
It's spread
throughout your lungs.
So more chemo?
Well, that's an option.
We can try to shrink
it, but... But what?
The cancer is
surrounding your heart.
Am I going to be okay?
I don't think so.
Dr. Malucci. Not right now.
Did you leave something
of...? Dr. Weaver, I'm busy.
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
Dad?
Dad, you there?
Dad... Oh, it's you.
So you, uh, changed the locks?
What are you doing here?
Worried about you.
No one could find you.
You weren't answerin'.
The damn realtor keeps calling.
I don't know how many
times I have to tell her
the house is off the market.
Can I come in? Oh, sure.
You don't wanna search me first?
Kerry, what did you hire me for?
What? I'm not here to simply
perform procedures.
I'm an experienced
emergency physician.
You have to trust my judgment.
Is this about that disabled boy?
Yes, you called DCFS.
Yes, I thought we
agreed you would.
If you didn't intend to,
you should have said
so. But they walked out.
Your social worker
scared them away.
They're gone?
Yeah, I convinced the
older brother to come back
so I could try to help him.
Please, just let me...
Let me handle it.
All right. See that you do.
Okay. Who is...? Who
is the social worker?
Neuman. Adele Neuman.
Your parents left?
They went to get the car.
We gotta go. My coach
makes you sit if you can't play.
You can play, Tamara,
if you really want to.
It's not broken?
We can't be absolutely sure.
But probably not.
So I don't need this?
I was hoping it would
slow you down a bit.
But it's your choice.
I can't slow down right now.
Things'll get better once
we get through this season.
You don't want to start
resenting your talent.
Don't let it get to that.
Play for you.
It's not that simple.
I know.
Promise you'll try?
600 South Stone.
Okay, 8:30.
Yeah, he'll be there.
Oh, did you wanna
talk to Dr. Kovac?
Okay.
Thanks. Bye.
My landlord said yes.
Yes? Good. Yeah.
He owns a bunch of buildings.
He's always looking for a super,
and he'll interview Dillon.
Lucy, thank you.
Sure, no problem.
And what exactly is a "super"?
Collects rent, keeps
the building clean.
Good. Good.
It gives them somewhere
to live, some cash.
If DCFS sees that Dillon...
- Dillon!
He can apply for guardianship.
Dillon! Dillon!
It's all right. Excuse me.
Hold still.
Don't touch him!
Where are you taking him?
Stop!
Hey, don't do that!
Let him go! You are scaring him!
Adele Neuman, DCFS.
We need to take Jake
to an emergency intake center.
You're not takin' him nowhere!
I'm not...! I'm
not releasing him!
The boy has been neglected,
and it's my
obligation to protect
his safety and his health.
I never neglected
him! He's my brother!
I'm getting him a
job. They'll be fine.
Hey, I said let him
go! Hey, stand back.
I don't wanna
have to arrest you.
I have to put him
in protective care.
All right! All right!
Just let me go with him.
I'm sorry. Don't leave me.
Don't be scared, Jake.
Don't be scared.
Watch your head.
I'll be right behind you, okay?
Okay? You can't do this.
Those two only have each other.
I'll find you! I know that,
but I have to. Don't
be afraid, Jake!
I'll be right behind
you, all right?
I'm gonna find you, okay?
Okay?
I'll be right behind you!
I'm gonna find you. I promise!
Don't let me go!
Don't be afraid, Jake!
Don't be afraid!
Don't be scared!
Don't be scared, Jake!
Don't worry.
We'll get him back.
You wanted to see me?
I'm sick.
No more games, Dean.
What is it that you want?
The games... they're
no fun anymore.
Not even that last one.
Dr. Corday...
that day on the road,
you should have let me die.
That's what I want.
Shannon Murphy, 26.
Slipped down a 15-foot incline
into a polar-bear pit.
Polar bear? Yeah, at the zoo.
He was really gentle, actually.
He licked my face.
Everybody else got a picture
of the polar bear.
I got one with the polar bear.
This that stupid scavenger hunt?
Don't call it stupid.
I just won $1000.
Yeah, you also just
broke both your ankles.
And a forearm fracture.
Started an IV. And
gave her 10 of morphine.
Hey, Cleo, you want this one?
No, I've done enough
casting for one day.
Yup.
Could someone take this lady
who burned her
butt in the bathtub?
She will not stop. SHANNON:
You're not a doctor?
I won't tell anybody
if you won't.
Oh, my God! Where's my camera?
Did you bring my camera?
Somebody, I need
a picture of a doctor.
Somebody get me a
camera! It's worth $1000!
Make her split it with us.
Luka, I heard about
what happened.
I'm sorry.
Don... Don't apologize.
It might not always
make sense to us,
but when there's a
difficult family situation,
we call DCFS,
because they have
expertise in this area.
We have to defer
to their judgment.
You don't break up families.
Sometimes we
do. It's complicated.
No.
My wife and kids were taken.
In the war?
Yeah.
And then killed.
You don't break up families.
So much for the
retirement community, huh?
I gave it a try, Mark.
You were only there a week.
Yeah, the longest
week of my life.
What are you gonna do now?
I'll get by.
Don't trouble yourself.
It's no trouble.
Yeah, like hell.
You move in with that girl yet?
Elizabeth?
No, not yet.
Actually, I've been
thinking about it,
and, you know, we
never really talked about it.
Maybe you should come
live with me in Chicago.
For a while.
Why would I do that?
I don't know.
The weather could be better,
but it's a great city.
You'd be closer to Rachel.
You'd be closer to me.
For a while?
As long as you like.
I'm not selling
this house, Mark.
How could you?
Answering the door
in your underwear
tends to scare off the buyers.
I suppose so.
Chicago, huh?
You are not one
to get your tune-ups
done on a timely basis, are you?
Did you get it
started? Sorry, yeah.
It's not gonna break
down on the way home?
Nope, I can at least fix cars.
What? Nothin'
You're good to go, boss.
Thanks, Dr. Malucci.
My pleasure.
Hey, so how was your first day?
Everyone treat you
all right? Uh, yeah,
feels like I never left.
You guys wanna go
get something to eat?
Oh. Nah.
I don't think so. Okay.
Hey, you workin' tomorrow?
Me? Yeah.
Uh-huh.
Oh, what a coincidence! So am I.
See you, Carter.
Do I have to warn you about him?
Oh, please!
So how was your first day?
Uh, well, I wish I could
have done more for Alyssa.
At least you did somethin'.
Yeah, I guess so.
Why did you come back?
I told you.
Uh, my program
in New York closed.
No, no, I mean, uh...
I mean to medicine.
Oh, oh. Um, well...
four months after I quit,
I was on the subway,
and this guy, pretty
young, in his forties,
went into cardiac arrest.
He was dying, and everyone
was just standing
there staring at him.
So I suddenly realized,
"Hey, I know what to do!"
Jumped in, saved his life.
It's a great feeling.
Yeah, it can be.
Then I figured, I'm
pretty good at this.
Why waste it?
Deb, you haven't changed a bit.
It's Jing-Mei.
Well, good night, Jing-Mei.
Good night, John.
Oh, and, Deb, welcome back.
Morphine.
A hundred milligrams
injected into your bloodstream.
You'll simply drift away.
Won't even hurt.
Is that an offer?
You'd have to tell
me where the body is.
Why do you care so much?
Were you serious or not?
Won't you get into trouble?
The Hippocratic Oath and all?
You're worried about
me now, are you, Dean?
No.
But I know you.
As soon as you
get what you want,
you'll just... You'll stop.
I won't.
But how do I know?
What, are you
going to promise me,
Dr. Corday?
Believe me, you'll know.
You'll feel yourself going.
I just hope you have
breath enough to tell me.
Well, what if I don't?
Then I'll crack open your chest
and bring you back to life.
Okay.
Let's do it.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Are you?
I'm glad it's you, Elizabeth.
Where is she, Dean?