It's way too fast.
It felt good.
If we can clear the
stage, quickly please.
Maury, it's too fast.
It's exactly the same.
Then slow it down.
Everything all right, Jeremy?
Sure. Ready whenever you are.
From the allegro please.
What's his problem?
His back's not 100%.
He can't talk to the
conductor like that.
No, he can't.
She could.
You okay with the lift?
I'll be fine unless you
mess up the timing.
My timing is perfect.
Was last night.
Moment of truth.
Damn it.
Penelope, are you all right?
She can't breathe.
Call the doctor!
Are you gonna ignore
me all day again?
I help you.
You tried to kill Chase.
Doing what you
wanted, that's all, boss.
I exist.
No, you don't.
I acknowledge my subconscious
exists. Now go away.
Saying it is one thing.
Living it is another.
You're not rational.
Not completely.
Put the phone on the receiver,
send the hookers
home and get dressed.
We've got a case. I'm
taking a personal day.
21-year-old star of the New
York Ballet collapsed on stage.
I love ballet. But as
someone may have mentioned,
I'm taking a personal day.
Cuddy said get your
ass in or you're fired.
She's not going to fire me.
She's not going to fire
you? If you don't go to work?
Okay. How long, do you figure,
till I just disappear?
Hold on.
No tumors or
punctures in the lungs,
no bruising, no sign
of trauma, no STDs.
And supplemental oxygen's only
gotten her saturation level to 60.
Lungs keep collapsing
despite a chest tube.
ER ruled out the obvious,
white count and temp are
normal, so no pneumonia.
The coffee's burnt, Thirteen's
wearing cherry-flavored lip gloss.
Foreman's staring at
you. Any of that helpful?
House.
STD? We just said
the tests were negative.
You think we should... No.
She's a dancer. What
about dehydration?
What about a
pulmonary contusion?
CT showed no
inflammation on the lungs.
What about dehydration?
BUN and creatinine are
elevated but within range.
Hey. I'm just the
irrational part of your brain,
but elevated means high, right?
Dehydration could
hide an infection.
Go treat her for the obvious.
IV fluids and antibiotics
for pneumonia.
We're like Magic and Kareem.
Mr. Pietramala, you
have kidney cancer.
Wow. Is that a bad one? I
mean, they're all bad, but...
The door was
closed for a reason.
Well, now it's open for a
reason. We need to talk.
He just told me I
have kidney cancer.
Then you'll obviously
need a moment to process.
House.
I'm hallucinating.
I'm... I'll be right back.
I need you to sit in on my differentials,
double-check everything I do.
You can't treat patients...
It's gotta be sleep apnea.
I get a good night's sleep,
and I still feel exhausted.
Lack of delta sleep can
lead to hallucinations.
Do you have any other
neurological symptoms?
Don't think so.
Aphasia? No.
Memory loss? No.
Irritability? Yeah, that one.
Don't deflect. He
cares about you.
You shouldn't be practicing.
You care about him. Tell him...
At least until... Enough.
Don't give me the look. I
told you I was hallucinating.
Who were you talking to?
Someone who's not actually
here, beyond that seems irrelevant.
Your mind made a
choice. It means something.
You know he's just
gonna keep asking.
Kutner.
Good choice. He feels bad.
You gonna help me or not?
Yeah.
I could eat from this
place seven days a week.
We practically do.
You can order tomorrow night.
Do you want some
wine? No, thanks.
I have my husband's sperm.
Your dead husband's?
We froze it when
he got diagnosed.
And you kept it? All this time?
I used to think, if I
didn't find anyone...
You found someone.
I know.
But...
What if it goes wrong?
What if I turn out to
be a radical anarchist
with a secret family,
and that I age backwards?
Nobody plans on
getting divorced.
I didn't plan on my
husband dying. But he did.
So, you're saying
you want a pre-nup?
In liquid form?
What if it's not sleep apnea?
Trauma from your
motorcycle accident?
Vicodin abuse? You
need to be admitted.
I know you're wrong
about sleep apnea,
which means you know
you're wrong about sleep apnea.
You're scared. Tell
him you're scared.
I can't sleep with you here.
Did it work?
Do you see someone
standing beside me?
No.
Then no.
So what's next on your
list of things it's not?
Patient's not responding to
the antibiotics. Still can't breathe.
So run a test to
confirm it's pneumonia.
We can't do a bronc because
her lungs are still collapsed.
Transtracheal aspiration.
That's basically waterboarding.
It is pretty radical.
It's a great idea.
Regular radical, me radical
or me-out-of-my-mind radical?
Somewhere between
regular and you.
So what's the problem?
Everything okay?
No. Our patient can't breathe.
Either do the test or
come up with a better one.
So we're down to
infection, trauma,
MS, schizophrenia, or pills.
Schizophrenia usually
manifests younger.
That's why it's
further down the list.
I can confirm an infection
with a simple blood test.
An infection can
be treated, cured.
Means you've still got a job,
means you've still got a life.
Doesn't make it a better
idea, just a nicer one.
This the rational you talking?
Can't do this on my own.
When we inject the water it's
gonna feel like you're drowning.
But it'll be over
in a few seconds.
And then it'll be better?
A little.
Hold her shoulders
down a little.
Ready?
You're doing great.
Here comes the liquid.
Taub. I slipped.
Oh, no. What?
Her skin came off.
Her skin's sloughing
off faster than
we can replace it
with the artificial skin.
Could be autoimmune.
ANA was negative.
Focus on the lungs.
You want us to ignore the fact
that she's lost 80% of her skin?
We know it's not lung
cancer. Could be a liver tumor.
Eats through to the lungs.
Get an ultrasound of her liver.
If you find masses,
get a biopsy.
We can't just ignore the skin.
It's obviously the
most significant
and dangerous symptom right now.
I don't think it is a symptom.
I think we caused it.
By doing what?
I prescribed antibiotics.
Toxic epidermal necrolysis?
That's a one-in-a-million reaction.
Yeah, well, maybe
this is the one.
Get swabs of her
old skin to confirm.
Where the hell were you?
I do have a practice.
Ballerina has toxic
epidermal necrolysis.
Are you sure?
About to be.
I'm sorry.
I feel guilty.
You didn't do anything wrong.
You prescribed antibiotics.
Any other doctor would have
done the exact same thing.
"Any other doctor"?
Words can hurt, you know.
I have no reason to feel guilty.
It doesn't make any sense.
Unless there's something wrong
in the limbic area of my brain.
Guilt as a symptom?
It's consistent with MS.
And since the blood tests were
negative, I have to apologize.
If I feel better, then you're
right. I'm just feeling an emotion.
If I feel nothing, means
my limbic brain is shot.
I'm Dr. House.
Anyone explain
to you your status?
They found a mass
in my liver, cancer.
They said they
think they can treat it.
And that the skin
is starting to take.
I'll be able to dance again.
She's half-dead and she's
wondering if she'll ever plié again.
Healthy priorities.
Let the mocking begin.
I'm sorry.
I treated you for infection before
confirming that you had one.
That's why you lost your skin.
I know you're in pain. I know
that I caused it. I'm sorry.
Very nice.
Thank you.
Nothing.
Maybe you didn't mean it.
I meant it.
Did you do a liver biopsy to confirm...
- Couldn't.
The artificial skin was
too thin, she'd bleed out.
Why were you
talking to the patient?
I think skinless women are hot.
Do a transjugular liver biopsy.
If she bleeds, at least
it stays in her veins.
Did you just check
with Wilson again?
No.
I felt nothing. It's MS.
Apologies aren't supposed
to make you feel better,
they're supposed to make
the other person feel better.
In order to make
you feel better.
Fine. You want to
do an LP to confirm
or is guilt enough to
start filling prescriptions?
Last mass, about a
centimeter to your right.
Problem?
Short burst of flutter.
We're almost done.
Entering the right hepatic vein.
Cameron kept her
dead husband's sperm.
She doesn't like yours?
She likes his better.
Or at least she
wants to hang on to it
in case mine is
unfaithful or something.
Wow.
Advancing two centimeters.
You gotta let her do it.
If you don't, you'll be
stuck with her forever.
I want to be stuck
with her forever.
She married a dying
guy. She has issues.
You cannot leave her.
Ever. For any reason.
Because then you're not
just the guy who left her,
you're the guy
who killed her kids.
That's not a good
rhythm. Get out.
Narrow complex tachycardia.
She's gonna crash.
Liver biopsy was
negative for cancer.
But the procedure
sent her heart into A-Fib.
We don't know it was the biopsy
that caused the heart problem.
Maybe the heart caused
the lungs to collapse.
Why is Wilson here?
You were looking for cancer.
I thought it'd be helpful if...
We didn't find cancer. Yes,
which you reported to
me five seconds ago.
I thought I'd let him
finish his hors d'oeuvre
before getting the
bouncer to take care of him.
Until we can regulate the heart,
we can't get any
meaningful pictures,
so we can't tell...
Metoprolol can
correct irregular heart.
Tried it. Didn't work.
Is Cuddy making him oversee...
No.
Heart's too irregular for
MRI, other scans wouldn't...
Then you're making
him oversee your choices.
You don't trust yourself. Why?
Wilson, get out.
Are you sure?
Do I need your approval
to throw you out?
You happy now?
There's only one time her heart's going
to be perfectly still for our pictures
and that's when she's dead.
If it's not MS,
severe mental illness
and Vicodin are all that's left.
Mental illness means you
can no longer practice medicine.
Vicodin means detox, which
means pain. For the rest of your life.
Which means you can no
longer practice medicine.
Are you saying
we should kill her?
No.
If we stopped her heart, we could
get our pictures and then restart it.
What if we can't restart it?
Then she stays dead.
We restart hearts all the time.
It'll take four minutes for
us to MRI her entire heart.
And we only have three minutes
until there's brain damage.
You sure about this?
Yeah.
Gonna stop her
heart so I can MRI it.
I think it was her idea. The pneumonia
was her idea, almost killed the patient.
"Her"?
Oops.
Kutner was secretly a woman,
that's why he killed himself.
It's Amber.
Your subconscious
picked my dead girlfriend?
Yeah, the irrational
part of my brain
works like the
rational part of yours.
How about that?
It raises questions.
It answers questions.
Who cares?
I've got competing ideas.
They can't both be right.
Everybody gets competing
ideas. Everybody has doubts.
So is it regular radical, me radical
or me-out-of-my-mind radical?
It's on the upper
end of you radical.
Do you have any alternative?
Nothing that anyone in
my head has come up with.
Then you're as
safe as you can be.
Great.
You get the LP results back?
Yeah.
It's a big shock.
You don't have MS.
But while I had your blood
sample, I checked Vicodin levels.
Way too high.
I need the pills.
Not an argument. He
knows that's not an argument.
It could still be schizophrenia.
House, if you're
on anti-psych meds,
you're not going to
be able to practice...
I know.
You'd prefer electroshock
therapy to rehab?
I'd prefer something
that could actually work.
You're rationalizing.
No kidding.
I know that you're afraid of
the pain, but electroshock...
Don't give me the cancer
voice, that overly earnest tone.
Heart attack, stroke,
seizure, death or worse.
Worse? Double death?
You live but you damage
the only thing you care about:
your rational mind.
I'll make some calls.
I'll actually be dead?
Just your heart. And
just for a little while.
Hopefully.
I had an idea.
Stop having ideas.
Insulin shock.
Yes, that's marginally
less dangerous than ECT,
puts you in a coma,
could cause... It could work.
If you had psychosis,
which you don't.
I have no diarrhea, no
sweating, no vomiting,
none of the symptoms
of Vicodin overdose.
Yeah, except the "I
see dead people" thing.
I've been popping
pills for years.
I've only been seeing things
for days. Something changed.
Vicodin addiction
is still more likely.
So we're no longer
dealing in absolutes.
House, I'll be up
in five minutes,
then we can talk about how you'd
rather be in a coma than in rehab.
Actually, if you could be up
here in two, that'd be really helpful.
Why?
Because I'm about to put
myself into insulin shock.
Left atrium is fine.
Left coronary artery also fine.
We're almost at three
minutes. Keep going.
Chordae tendineae
clear. Right atrium is fine.
I gotta start her back
up. We have some time.
We're over. Right
coronary artery is fine.
The three-minute
threshold is a guideline.
She might have
less. We have to stop.
What's that by the aorta?
I don't see anything.
I'm restarting her heart.
That's a shadow!
Two centimeters...
You're only scared because
you know this is going to work.
We're over three minutes.
I need glucose in here!
You could have died.
It worked. Where are my pants?
Are you sure?
She's been everywhere
I've been for days.
She's not here. Ergo...
This was not the
next rational step.
Now who's being biased?
You wanted me to detox
as much as I wanted...
I forgot how to do my zipper.
Any other neurological deficits?
You don't seem to annoy me as
much as usual. Not sure that's a deficit.
And I'm all better.
Is she really gone? Absolutely.
I can feel myself repressing
all kinds of icky things.
I check out, don't I?
Damn.
He didn't see anything. He
saw an artifact on the monitor.
It was a shadow on her heart.
She'd already been technically
dead for three minutes.
I thought keeping her alive took
precedence over prolonging the photo op.
Any brain damage?
No, all tests indicate that...
Obviously you had more time.
Best of luck.
I assume we can't kill her
again, take more pictures.
You don't want to
check with Wilson?
Good one.
It's something, a lesion.
Tumor, scar tissue.
Could be an abscess. Infection.
Explains why it's
invisible in the blood.
It's doing its damage behind
closed doors. Sealed off.
See, the problem
with speculation is
you make a "spec" out of you
and some guy named "Lation,"
which really doesn't
affect me at all.
We have to guess.
It's all we've got.
We can't do a biopsy. Last
time we went into her heart
she had a major cardiac event.
Which just leaves...
What are you looking for?
I don't know yet.
Picture doesn't change. She lies
there in pain, he sits there worried.
Nothing changes.
I just had an
epiphany. All by myself.
Popped into my
head out of nothing.
Care to share?
He's too devoted.
Too devoted? You
think he feels guilty?
Right, I'm being cynical.
People can care because they
care, and not because they cheated.
Theoretically true, but
gonorrhea fits better.
No. No STDs. We tested her.
You tested her blood.
That is the test.
That's not where her problem is.
Gonorrhea
disseminated to her heart.
If it got walled off in an
abscess, it'd be invisible.
And would look like a shadow.
No need to test her again. But
we can check Prince Charming.
Once you confirm, cut the
abscess out of her heart.
Here are your onion
rings, extra well done.
Thank you, Molly.
And another beer when you
get a chance. I'm celebrating.
Alone?
Thank goodness.
Don't tell me, I was right.
Yep. Boyfriend has gonorrhea.
And everyone's a winner.
He's not too happy about it.
He insists he's never cheated,
must have gotten it from her.
Don't think so.
Timing would fit.
He's got no symptoms
and she's dying.
Lying would fit, too.
He's not hanging out
in her room anymore.
What does it matter?
You were right.
We're prepping her for surgery.
I saw guilt in him.
If he's not actually guilty,
I wasn't right, I was lucky.
House, you made a brilliant
deduction about her heart.
And if I was just lucky...
Enjoy yourself
It's later than you think
While you're still in the pink.
The years go by
As quickly as a wink
Enjoy yourself
Wilson, come get me.
It's later than you think
I know a nice
facility outside Philly.
I went to undergrad
with one of the directors.
Thanks.
How many shirts do I need?
They said three.
They have laundry.
Like living with Mom
again. Delightful.
It's probably Foreman.
He's unavailable.
Tell him the infection's
made her septic.
We can't remove the
abscess until we get her BP up,
and it's not responding
to fluids, it's not...
He's off the case.
Patient okay?
Yeah.
He's lying.
Why don't I feel scared?
I'd say you're unaware of what
you're feeling at this moment.
I feel like crap, my life is falling
apart, but I don't feel scared.
Not of the rehab, anyway.
We've always been able
to find a way to cheat.
It won't work.
You want it to work this time.
Do we?
House, it's your only option.
And what do I do if my
only option won't work?
You don't give up.
It's either that or
electroshock every six hours.
Good night, Wilson.
What if we put her on
a heart-lung machine?
She's septic.
We don't need a
heart-lung machine.
We need a blood vessel
holder-together machine.
We could try a
high-dose dopamine.
It's a vasoconstrictor.
It'll close the blood vessels
so she won't bleed out.
Her heart can't take that
much dopamine. It'll explode.
And if we don't use the
dopamine, it'll implode.
Is House really done?
Sounded that way.
Dopamine it is.
It's late and I'm tired.
Can we get to the talking
part of this conversation?
I quit.
Great.
My nanny is off
the clock at 7:30.
So your week off, bigger desk,
tighter nurses'
uniforms, or whatever
other stupid thing
you're about to demand
is gonna have to wait until...
You can go suckle
the little bastard child
who makes you feel
good about yourself.
Screw you.
Don't do this.
I'm hallucinating.
From the Vicodin?
Ruled out everything else.
We can admit you through the ER
under a pseudonym.
No one has to...
I'll cheat, scam, find
some way to keep using.
These people know
what they're doing.
These people don't know me.
You do.
She's not your keeper. She
has no responsibility for you.
I need you.
Let me call my babysitter.
Blood pressure is 90 over 60.
We know.
I'm just saying, it's still
90 over 60. It's holding.
Abscess is intact.
Doesn't look like any of the
surrounding tissue is affected.
She's gonna be fine.
Doctor.
We've got a problem.
Lie down. I'll get you some tea.
Yeah, then I'll be better.
You really think she hasn't searched
this place for your secret stash?
I already did this room, and
the bathroom and your bedroom.
Where should I
look in the kitchen?
Coffee cup. In the top shelf.
That was a test. I
already did the kitchen.
Nicely played. She'll think you've
come clean, given her everything.
There's more.
Don't. You're hurting
already. It'll only get worse.
House, you should
tell me where it is now,
because you won't have
the will to tell me in two hours.
In my shoes. In the closet.
It's like I don't even know
who you are anymore.
It's okay. Hold my hand.
Am I okay?
We were able to successfully
remove the abscess from your heart.
But the dopamine caused the blood vessels
in your hands and feet to clamp shut.
We need to amputate or the
gangrene will spread, and you'll die.
My feet?
And your hands. I'm sorry.
No. I'm a dancer.
The tissue can't be saved.
No.
We know what House would do.
House would have never
woken her up to ask for consent.
If you can't live with the
answer, don't ask the question.
You're saying we should
accept her decision?
Bold idea, I know.
Maybe we can get the
boyfriend to convince her to do it.
Yeah, boyfriends get
everything they want.
Forget it. The boyfriend
doesn't want to talk to her at all.
Where are you going?
Home. The case is over.
No, it's not. Not
until we come up
with something that might work.
It's a shame that she might die
because House has some
personal crap to work through.
Technically, if she dies,
it's because House has some
personal crap to work through
and we weren't smart enough
to get the answer without him.
False alarm.
Drink this.
That's your advice? Drink this?
It's ginger. It'll
ease the nausea.
You know what would
calm the nausea?
Vicodin. Marijuana. A coma.
Don't pretend you didn't see it.
I saw it, which
means you saw it.
Send her away.
Too bitter. I already
have enough bitter.
I'll add some honey.
You're pathetic.
If you want the pill,
just send her home.
But you can't, because that
would be admitting defeat to her.
Now this is interesting.
If you take the pill,
you don't deserve her.
If you secretly take the pill,
you don't deserve anyone.
No!
No. No!
This isn't going to work.
It might work. That's
all we're going for.
Vasodilators can...
Big jump from
reopening to reanimating.
I'm out of the ulnar.
Not seeing any
clearing. This won't work.
This probably won't work.
Radial artery's really tight.
Don't go too fast. If it
clots, she loses the hand.
If it clots, she's dead.
I can't believe it.
What?
It might be working.
Can you stop?
The breathing.
Air goes in, air goes out.
Use your nose.
You're supposed to feel
like crap. You're doing great.
And after?
You come back to work.
What if I can't?
Opioid dependency
can make you think
you have more pain
than you really have.
You're going to be okay.
You're telling me what I
want to hear, with no evidence.
I'm telling you what I
believe to be the truth.
With no evidence.
You're hardly the most
unbiased observer.
Neither are you.
I'm your hospital's
biggest asset.
Is that why you think I'm here?
That's why you're here, that's
why you're lying to me about...
I haven't lied to
you in 20 years.
Sure you have.
Which means that
you just said that
because you want to tell me what
you lied to me about 20 years ago.
You're an ass.
Am I wrong?
I wasn't in your
endocrinology class.
You sat next to me. I
cheated off you in the mid-term.
I audited your
endocrinology class.
Why would you...
Because I thought you were
an interesting lunatic even then.
I'm not here protecting
hospital property.
We're alone.
We've been alone all night.
No, I mean Amber.
She's gone.
Where's Jeremy?
He left.
You okay?
The surgery worked.
Congratulations.
I can't do it.
You have doubts.
You don't?
No.
That's
naive.
I want to spend the rest of
my life with you. I love you.
That's how I feel right now,
but I don't know.
I'll wait until you do.
I can't know. No one knows.
I do.
I'll see you in later? I have
some papers to push for you.
Thank you.
You want to kiss me, don't you?
I always want to kiss you.