Okay, if you don't have
your child's card
with you, let me know.
Si no tienes su tarjeta
de imunizacion hoy
por favor, digame ahora.
Chuny, can I get a
hand in here, please?
A tengan pacience, por favor...
Okay, listen, I'll be with
all of you in just a second.
Everybody get a cookie?
Get a cookie? Excuse me, pal.
Listen, I need you to
explain to her about the lead.
O tenemos un examen de...
ieu nu-sint spaniola.
Intelet mai bine
engiezeste de cit spaniola.
Sorry. That ain't Spanish.
Uh, we need to take some blood
to see if the baby's
been exposed to lead.
Lead is very bad for children.
Okay.
And then if there's a
problem, we'll call you.
Okay.
You know what, if
you just... you sign this,
and then the nurse
will take some blood.
Okay.
Next, please.
Think that was an
informed consent?
Close enough.
Hey, old man. Hey.
You again?
Yeah. I know you.
Uh... Halloween.
Uh, Charlie, right?
Yeah, you gave me some condoms.
Guess you were
a couple years late.
Uh-huh. You're
telling me that's yours?
Why not?
His dad's a Pakistani dude.
And his name is
"Lopez" because...?
Okay. His mom
Gloria's a friend of mine.
She's got a job today,
so I'm baby-sitting.
She heard they were
giving out free shots.
And Ahmed hasn't been seen
since he was four months old?
Yeah, I guess.
Let me see. Ahmed, come here.
What's he now...
About a year and a half?
All right, well, we're
going to need to have
his mother's address
for a follow-up.
They live at Sisters
over on Grand.
The shelter?
Dr. Ross, don't we
need parental consent?
That's why I told
you I'm the mom.
All right, Ms. Lopez
Why don't you sign right there?
I don't know about this.
Want me to send him home?
Okay, next.
Hey, Charlie.
Shouldn't you be in school?
We're off.
It's Career day.
BP's 200/140.
Try to relax,
Mr. Reynolds. Okay?
Ultrasound's ready.
All right, take a look,
tell me what you see.
You want me to get him
started on beta blockers?
You read my mind.
Osmolal, five grams in 500 mil.
And four of morphine.
It's a triple-A, I'd say
about four centimeters.
Dr. Lewis, great.
I was afraid I was going
to miss you. I'm on till 2:00.
You know it's not going to be
the same around here without you.
Oh, stop it. It's hard enough.
Okay, Dr. Doyle, give
Dr. Carter the bullet.
72-year-old male,
history of hypertension
and hypercholesterolemia,
one previous MI.
Pain began in left lower
quadrant a week ago.
The ultrasound shows
abdominal aneurysm...
Four centimeters.
Yeah, we'll take him
off your hands for you.
Ah, not so fast, Dr. Carter.
Check his femoral pulses.
The ultrasound
indicates surgery.
What do you think, Dr. Doyle?
I agree with Carter.
There's a chance for rupture.
Ten percent.
How are his femoral pulses?
Two plus, bilaterally.
So he has good blood
flow to his lower extremities.
But the ultrasound
indicates a risk.
Shows no leakage.
Let's get a CT to confirm it.
So, you want to
manage it medically?
Yes, I'd like to try.
The machines can
give us test results,
but they like to keep us around
here for diagnostic judgment.
You see, this is her last shift
maybe our last patient together.
She's just trying to bust me.
Someone has to hold
you surgeons back.
Page me if you need me.
Okay, let's get him to CT.
I guess I got a lot to learn.
Yeah, it takes practice.
Don't be afraid to step up.
You should have
seen me my first year.
Don't believe her.
She was always this good.
Are you with the moving company?
No, I'm Mark Greene,
a friend of Susan's.
Then you're the one who's
interested in taking over the lease?
Yes.
Ah, Phyllis Dodds.
I'm the landlady.
Hi, Phyllis.
Are you okay?
It's just a muscle spasm.
Probably stress. Yeah.
It's a great one-bedroom.
Lots of closet space,
nice cross-breeze
on a quiet street.
Yeah, I've spent some time here.
You worked with Susan?
About three years.
Actually, more than three years.
Are you single?
Divorced, and I've
got my daughter
every other Saturday.
No live-ins, no
parties, no pets.
None of the above.
There it is. A landlady's dream.
Well, at least, it
works for someone.
Oh, good.
All the boxes go,
the luggage stays.
Place looks a lot bigger
without Susan's
stuff, doesn't it?
Yeah, it's a whole lot emptier.
Start here.
I got it.
So basically, we're screwed.
We can pull the
interns off their electives,
but unless the senior residents
lose their vacation time,
we won't be able to
cover the schedule.
Are you okay?
Yeah. Just didn't get
much sleep last night.
I'm sorry, what'd you
say after "We're screwed"?
It's gonna be a pain
to lose Susan Lewis.
A big mistake for
her... Phoenix?
I mean, what was David
Morgenstern thinking
letting her go?
You know, I want to be
supportive of lifestyle choices
but we're getting
the short end here.
Good morning, all.
Hang tough, coach Pino.
We've got a 35-year-old
roller hockey coach
got slammed into the boards.
Possible hip dislocation.
Dr. Weaver, can I take this one?
Be my guest.
One of you guys nail him?
He told us to play the body.
Never apologize
for a good hip check,
right, Coach?
Are you sure
you're feeling okay?
Yes. Stiff muscles.
I might be coming
down with something.
You know, go home. This
might be your only chance.
Yeah, I think I'm
going to stick around.
Hey. Hey.
So, T-minus five
hours and counting?
Yeah. I'm starting
to get nervous.
You'll do great in Arizona.
The winters there
are like heaven.
I just don't want to leave
anyone in the lurch, you know?
We'll muddle through.
Oh, hey, I signed the lease.
Oh, great. That's great!
That would be a shame
to let that place go...
and I'll never
forget your address.
You want to help me
with a teaching demo?
Yeah.
Did you give him
five of morphine?
And Valium and 100 Methohexital.
First, the nurse... Or
in this case, Susan...
Applies counter-traction.
Good job, Susan.
Then, you grab behind the knee
and you lift.
And you lift... until...
you feel the...
hip slip back into place.
That's it.
Okay.
Thanks, Susan.
Anytime.
Anytime in the next four hours.
Dislocations aren't that tough.
You get the feel for it.
I know.
I've done a bunch of them.
Why'd you ask for help?
I didn't.
That was perfect.
Will you take one for me?
We will do anything
for you, Dr. Keaton.
Say "discharged."
Discharged. Great.
Oh, good. There's Dr. Benton.
The Herlihys are taking
Megan home today finally.
Oh, yeah. I heard.
Congratulations.
David, get one with
Dr. Benton in it, please.
Oh, yeah, please.
Oh, no, no, no, I...
Oh, it's okay. It's okay.
Smile.
We owe both of you so much.
Well, we're not usually
shy about taking credit,
but in this case, Megan deserves
all the congratulations.
Thank you, Dr. Keaton.
We'll be in touch.
Bye.
God bless.
Bye!
Well, that was awkward.
Why?
Because I almost
killed their baby.
Never begrudge a good outcome.
Well, it's nothing
to be proud of.
But sometimes, the gods smile.
There you are. Hi.
Carter? What are you doing here?
Uh... actually, I was,
um... I was coming to...
Were you ready to go
over the literature review?
Yes, I was. I am...
if you are.
The literature review?
Um, I kidnapped your intern.
I hope you don't mind, but
I'm up against a deadline,
so I asked Dr. Carter
to contribute to an
article I'm writing.
Yes. She did.
Well, as long as
it doesn't interfere
with your other work.
No. This thing
with Dr. Keaton...
This article won't
get in the way at all.
I can go over your
first draft at 3:00.
Okay. Okay?
Yeah.
Okay, see you at 3:00.
Hey, cleaning out your locker?
Oh, this is too weird.
What time's your train?
4:20. I have to go by my house
and pick up my stuff.
I'm not cutting it
too close, am I?
You're on until 2:00?
There's not any farewell
thing going on, is there?
No, not that I've heard of.
Okay, good. Mark
is acting so odd.
Well, he's going to miss you.
He's the one who
thinks I should go.
If I hear how great
Phoenix is one more time...
I think he's just trying to
be a good sport, you know,
judging from how
miserable he looks.
You having second thoughts?
I never made a decision
that seemed so right.
You know, once I
made it, I just felt great.
Of course, I'm having
second thoughts.
Well, I wish you
weren't going...
but you do look happy.
Do I?
I'm just afraid that I'm
not really happy at all.
I'm just barging in on
Chloe and Joe's happiness.
Yeah, well, she owes
you a couple of barge-ins.
Susan.
There you are.
What's wrong?
Uh, I need a second opinion.
Sure.
See? Odd.
I want to get your
opinion on a patient.
You coming down with something?
I hope not. Exam Room One.
28-year-old smoker, on the pill
complains of
shortness of breath.
Diffuse low voltage on her EKG.
I'm thinking
pericarditis... Get an echo.
Yeah. That's what I'd do.
You don't think it could
be a pulmonary embolism?
She's at risk, abnormal EKG,
It could be lead placement.
No. I'd go with the echo.
You sure?
Yeah. It's a no-brainer.
You can always get a VQ scan
if the echo's negative.
You know, that's
what I was thinking,
so I'll order an echo.
There they are...
The Mutt and Jeff of
emergency medicine
pooling their expertise
before she leaves
us in the dust.
Doug, stop.
All right, Randi, call the lab.
Pick up these tests.
Where have you been?
The hell mobile.
Still no reason to
make us miserable.
Diaper rash, curtain three.
Saved it just for you.
Wait, Anspaugh made
you ride the mobile again?
Anspaugh didn't make us do it.
The immunization
program was Dr. Ross' idea.
Is this true?
Keeps me off the streets.
Check this out.
I got sunscreen.
I got a turquoise belt buckle.
I got a snake bite kit.
What for?
Susan's farewell.
Yeah, and we got a
cactus-shaped cake.
Oh, guys, I don't know.
I think she's gonna hate this.
Of course she's gonna hate it.
That's why we're doing it.
Let me know when
those labs get back.
You look lousy.
Oh, God. I woke up with this
neck thing, you know, fever.
Right.
There's a flu going
around, but I had a flu shot...
So you didn't do it, right?
You didn't tell
her how you feel?
She's leaving. Right.
She's made her decision. Mm-hmm.
I didn't see any point
in saying anything.
Mm-hmm.
In two hours, we'll have
a one-week-old male baby
on this table,
and what do we know
about this poor soul?
He has a distended abdomen
visible peristalsis.
The upper G.I.
series showed a partial
small bowel obstruction.
So, when we open him
up, we're expecting...
A malrotation of the gut.
Mm-hmm. Meaning?
In the tenth week
of fetal development,
the cephalic limb
of the intestinal loop
elongated and
twisted 270 degrees.
Okay, but begin
with the duodenum.
What would you expect to
see in a normal one-week-old?
What, you mean like
the duodenum leads to...
Mm-hmm.
Close your eyes.
Try to see it.
The, uh...
duodenum leads to the jejunum
which connects to the ileum.
Okay, but slow down,
and tell me what you see.
What do you mean?
Um, start with the
image of a healthy gut.
I'm seeing the head
of the pancreas.
It's like a tiny fist
holding two straws.
You mean the mesenteric
artery and vein?
Uh-huh.
It's nestled
in the open-C of the duodenum
and its surface is
like fine pebbles...
a beautiful shade of...
tannish yellow.
Go on. You try.
Okay, the, um...
the pancreas is...
shaped like... a
tadpole with a big head.
Uh-huh.
Um... it narrows
into a tail that curls
into the hilum of the spleen.
Go on, now, see the spleen.
Susan.
Yes.
I know you and I
had a rocky start,
but I thought we'd
worked on our relationship
and developed a
professional rapport.
What are you talking about?
The smoker in
one... I diagnosed him
with a pulmonary embolism
and consented her for a VQ.
Well, I thought it
was Mark's patient.
He asked me for my opinion.
Oh, well, I guess my
beef is with him, then.
You know what, I'll talk to him.
I think I know
what the problem is.
Thank you. Okay.
No. Absolutely not. No way.
It just ticks me off.
I mean I probably
could go up there...
No. You can't.
Well, it wouldn't kill me to finish
up just one shift up in neuro.
It's the principle.
Last week I let
Lydia go up there,
and it just encouraged
them to do it more.
What's up?
I got called up to Neuro
to fill in for the day.
Yes, may I speak to the
nursing administrator please?
Carol Hathaway in the ER.
Hey, Haleh when do you
max out on your pension?
Two more years.
See? They are hassling
the senior nurses.
No. I'll hold.
Hey, what's in the box?
Bridal shoppe?
Did you and Al
finally set the date?
No. The opposite.
She broke off with Al.
I'm returning this
ridiculous fake virgin outfit
and they better not
offer me store credit.
Still holding. Sorry, Lydia.
What did Al do?
Nothing. That's the problem.
He kept putting it off. He
didn't want to get married.
I don't know why
he ever proposed.
What's the matter with you guys?
They're wimps.
They're all petrified
to make a move.
It's lack of spine, isn't it?
Whatever you're talking about,
I'm sure you're right.
Hey, Mark, I
need to talk to you.
Ah, Mary. Yes, hello,
Carol Hathaway in the ER.
Well, I'm not doing
too good at the moment.
One of my nurses just
got floated up to Neuro.
Look, I'm trying to
run a department here,
and it doesn't benefit my nurses
to be shipped all
over the hospital.
No. You know what?
She is not going up. She
is not going up to Neuro.
Right. Right.
Hot stuff.
Yeah. Unfortunately,
you still have to go
but this is the last time.
I've made an appointment
with her this afternoon.
I'm going to stop this.
Uh-huh.
Hang in there, Lydia.
Don't worry about me.
But you can't put
me in the middle
of your conflicts
with Kerry Weaver.
I mean literally, you can't,
because I'm not
going to be here.
I just trust your judgment.
Look, I know what this is about,
and I'm having a hard time, too.
I think we've both been
spoiled by what we have...
The shorthand.
Uh-huh.
It just makes our
job so much easier.
Dr. Greene? Jobs. Right.
When I go to Phoenix, I'm
afraid that there won't be
a single person in the
ER that I can talk to.
They got great doctors there.
They have great doctors here...
The best I've ever worked with.
You can rely on them.
Thanks for the pep talk.
Mark.
Is it something else?
No. No, nothing else.
I mean, I could ask you to
consult on the hives in Four,
but you know, time for us
to stand on our own two feet.
Jeanie.
Jeanie, I'm glad I caught you.
Did you get the
mortgage papers back?
No, actually that's
what I wanted to tell you.
Al, you promised.
I talked to this lawyer
we were doing a remodel for.
He gave me some advice, and...
here.
You were right.
Everything you said
about our marriage,
about how you
carried all the weight.
Well, that's going to stop.
What is this?
Divorce papers.
I'm giving you the
house, the car, everything.
And don't say no.
It's not just because
you deserve it.
See, this guy
helped me figure out
that if I get my assets down
and show that my job
doesn't have insurance
then I'll be able to
get this state program
for the working poor.
They offer the drugs I
need. It's a good deal.
But your income has to
be less than $15,000 a year.
You don't have to
worry about me anymore
Okay?
You just take care of yourself.
I got to go.
Hands off.
I don't want to be here.
Settle down. Hold her.
Thank God, she was
passed out at Cubby's.
The bartender started to worry
after she downed that
sixth double bourbon.
She looks full term.
Let go of me. I am out of here.
No, you're not.
Security! We need security!
Oh, damn!
Damn this damn thing!
Doyle, Ativan... two migs.
Ma'am, are you
having contractions?
I need a drink
and I need to
get... out of here!
Restraints!
You're not going anywhere.
I'll do whatever I want.
Hold still so we
won't hurt your baby.
Go ahead and kill it!
I never wanted
the little bastard.
It's a little late to
think about that now.
Just sedate her.
I'll kill myself and
I'll take it with me.
Damn thing. Ow! Ruined my life.
You're pissing me off, lady.
Hold on, Doyle.
I want to die.
Uh-oh. Look out. What happened?
Her water broke. We'd
better get her up to OB.
I'll alert Pedes.
Another kid with Fetal
Alcohol Syndrome on the way.
Need some help?
Yeah, we could use
some muscle here.
Doyle, take her up to OB.
She was trying to kill her baby.
She admitted it.
Yeah, she's bombed.
Alert Social Services.
Will they do anything?
They'll try.
Oh, man.
Keep your legs together, honey.
Yeah.
That was ugly.
It was criminal.
Excuse me, Chaplain.
Do you have a minute?
Did you call for last rites?
No. I wanted to see
if you were free
to see this woman.
She's in labor.
Does she want a prayer?
No, but I think her baby will.
Mark, I've got a
brittle diabetic in two.
Came in with a
blood glucose of 406.
Are you ill? You look flushed.
Uh, no, I'm fine.
Anyway, he hadn't
taken his insulin
and his BP was
210/115. Off his dilt.
I gave him both, but
he wants to see Susan.
He says he always
sees Dr. Lewis.
Yeah, well, I can take it.
Okay.
Where's Dr. Lewis?
Well, she's busy right
now. I'm Dr. Greene.
We've debrided
Mr. Ceebar's ulcerated ankle.
Uh-huh. Do you have
an endocrinologist?
Uh, sort of.
Well, the emergency room
is really not the best place
for you to manage your diabetes.
My ex stole 500 bucks from me.
Well, I'm sure
that was quite upsetting,
but that's still no reason
for you not to monitor
your glucose level.
I-I wanted to tell Dr. Lewis.
Well, you can't
see her right now.
Diabetes is a serious disease.
You can manage it if
you follow the regimen.
But if you neglect it
you're at risk
for kidney failure
blindness, and vascular disease.
Why?!
Why...
Can't I see Dr. Lewis?
Should I try to find her?
Look, Dr. Lewis is leaving
us, Mr. Ceebar, okay?
She's not going to work
here anymore. Malik?
I-I-I didn't tell
her about my car.
Someone ran into it
and didn't even stop.
Malik, will you get
psych for Mr. Ceebar?
I can find Dr. Lewis...
Get psych.
Dr. Ross, labs came
back from the healthmobile.
Can you take a look at this CBC?
Crit's 28.
Iron deficiency anemia?
Nope. Normal MCV, No blasts.
We've got to get this
kid back in for follow-up.
It's Ahmed Lopez, the
baby that kid brought in.
Charlie? Sisters of
Mercy Shelter? Yeah.
All right, I'll get the number.
I need a hand here.
What's the problem?
I never felt better.
The guy is sick, he's
coughing his head off.
I thought I better
bring him in here.
Now it's a crime to cough.
Shut up and be grateful.
I'll get a history.
Lydia.
Cops get stranger all the time.
Don't worry. This
isn't about you.
Lydia...
Oh, she hates me, doesn't she?
Well, she's pretty fed up.
I don't know how
she got the idea
I didn't want to get married.
Al, you kept putting it off.
Yeah, but that didn't mean
I didn't want to, you know?
I know.
I don't.
If you want to be
with her, be with her.
Yeah, you're right.
I woke up this morning
and it was like I was dying.
I couldn't breathe.
You ever get that?
Yeah.
I got so crazed...
I tried to get the license,
I drove to the church...
I tried to drag the
priest over here
to marry us right now, today,
you know, if she'd have me.
What happened?
They were all at a CPR class.
Well, you know, we do have
a chaplain here in the hospital,
if you're serious.
Oh, yeah?
Mm-hmm.
He's in Trauma
One, giving last rites.
Oh, boy, oh, boy,
oh, boy. Look at that.
Where's the cecum?
Can't see for all
the small bowel.
It's pretty blue in here.
Let's eviscerate.
Peter, want to take
care of that obstruction?
Sure. Metz. Retractor.
Look different
from a healthy gut?
I'll say.
Visualize the transduodenal
peritoneal bands
attached to the cecum
and the ascending colon.
I am.
I'm putting some
traction on this mass,
twisting it counterclockwise.
It's pretty tangled.
Like a drawer full of socks.
I'll have to remember that one.
Okay, it's pinking up.
I don't think we
have dead bowel.
Do you have it?
Uh, yeah, it's...
everything's turned
around in here.
Tell me if you need me.
I...
uh...
You better take it.
Okay, retract the intestine.
Metz.
Pick up.
The baby's name is Ahmed
the mother's name is Gloria
and I don't know
what she looks like.
He doesn't remember the mother.
He took the blood
without consent.
I didn't hear that.
That's great, Doug.
I know that all
of your residents
are single moms. If...
Okay, sister, maybe I will.
Thank you. Thank you.
Don't ask.
Don't worry, I won't.
Has anybody seen Mr. Ceebar?
Mr. Ceebar, uh...
a brittle diabetic?
Yeah, psych is here
but he's flown the coop.
All he just needs is five minutes
of TLC and a cup of hot tea.
Well, he's gone now.
Hey.
Look at that.
Think he'll talk her into it?
Shouldn't be too hard.
It's what she wants.
Talk her into what?
Living happily ever after.
Sorry I couldn't
step up in there.
Well, at least you
knew you weren't ready.
The malrotation was more
disorienting than I expected.
90% of correcting a
congenital anomaly
is knowing your embryology.
Yeah, and I reviewed that.
Well, then you had
90% of the job aced.
What was the other ten percent?
Being able to stand there
and let the confused anatomy
start to make its own sense.
How?
By letting it happen.
Abnormalities in neonates
can be overwhelming
if you try to break
it down into parts.
Aristotle would have made
a lousy pediatric surgeon.
Sorry to interupt. Dr. Benton,
they're calling for us from the ER.
They need us. What is it?
A wedding.
Oh, my God, it wasn't a joke.
Is this crazy?
Yeah, this is crazy.
Good thing you had
this old rag lying around.
Well, make it snappy, girl.
They only gave me a
20-minute break in Neuro.
Oh, this veil's
a little crushed.
Let me see if
the coast is clear.
Wait, hold still. I don't
want to stick you. Hold still.
How do we look?
No traumas coming in.
Let's go while
the radio's quiet.
Am I too late?
No, right this way.
Bride's side or groom's?
Okay, they're a little drippy.
Yeah?
All right, everybody.
They're ready, okay?
Right over there...
That'd be good.
Okay, ready?
Well, uh, dearly beloved,
friends and colleagues,
we have come here today
as part of God's eternal plan
and on the spur of the moment
to this holy place
of life and death and healing
to join Lydia Wright
and Alfred...
Grabarsky.
Anybody get a stool
culture on curtain...
Oh, my God.
I'm sorry.
It's okay. I'll go.
I did the rectal swab.
His chart's in exam one.
Best wishes, man.
Like all of us here, they have
chosen as their life's work
to care for and protect
their community.
It's taxing and draining
and at times, it's
dangerous work.
And now, Lydia and Alfred
are choosing to take on
the care and
protection for each other
and the love they share.
Dr. Benton sends his apologies.
He was called into an emergency.
Oh. We join them today
to witness and declare this
sacred union between two people...
Testicular torsion.
Whose souls feed
each other with that love.
It's a love that sustains
all their outer efforts.
A love that is rare, and
that should be treasured.
Code Six.
A... a love
that, at times,
will burn brightly...
I need a hand.
And yet, at other times
it will flicker.
And now the vows.
Do you, Lydia,
take Alfred to love and cherish
from this day forward
till death do you part?
I do.
And do you, Alfred, take Lydia
to love and cherish
from this day forward
till death do you part?
I do.
I now pronounce
you husband and wife.
You may kiss your bride.
So then he just handed
you the divorce papers?
Yep. It wasn't like him.
What do you mean?
It was the most unselfish
thing he's ever done.
She's throwing the bouquet.
Come on, come on.
Come on. No pushing.
Come on. Hey, Carol.
Yeah?
It's bouquet time.
No. Thank you.
Come on! No, no.
Hey, you think we should do
the good-bye for Susan now
while we've got everyone here?
No. We'll do it
in an hour or so.
Hey, did you see those two?
Yeah. Did you see them
during the ceremony?
Yeah, it was pathetic.
I always felt those two
would make a go of it.
Hey, they're best friends.
What more do you want?
No, it's not what I want.
It's what Mark wants.
I don't know. Things
happen for a reason,
things don't
happen for a reason.
Then why is she leaving?
She doesn't have a life here.
And one
two, three!
Oh, my God!
You're next!
Oh, yeah, Susan!
Congratulations.
You're next.
Yeah, right.
That was kind of great, huh?
Yeah. They seem happy.
Hey, Mark?
I guess I proved I'm
no good at good-byes.
Me, neither.
I-I'm sorry that I
snapped at you earlier.
I just don't want to go...
unless I know we'll
always be friends.
We will.
You ready for me?
Come on in. Almost there.
Why don't you shut the door?
So, um, about your
literature review...
It's very complete.
I have a few quibbles
about emphasis.
I mean, I'm not sure
that Ladd warrants
an entire paragraph.
Probably not.
But you have a very nice style.
Easy to read,
not a lot of jargon.
Thank you.
Um, I would ask you to co-author
if you weren't first
year, but I think
that we need to be careful
and not draw a lot of
attention considering...
considering us? Yes.
What happened last
Thursday? Mm-hmm.
And Saturday
afternoon and evening?
Yes. And Tuesday before rounds.
Yeah, we could talk about that.
I mean, the only thing
we need to keep straight
is that this is separate.
Completely separate.
Yes, from our work.
I mean it shouldn't
matter. I am not your boss.
No. You're my boss' boss.
Did you lock the door?
Mm-hmm.
Okay, so that we both understand
this is strictly personal.
It has nothing to do with work.
Oh, I love that.
There are so many things
I'm not going to
miss about this place.
Aftercare documentation
is one of them.
I can't tell you how many hours
I've spent doing this.
You're the only one
who ever bothers.
You kidding me?
No.
She said she's going
to leave at 2:00 sharp.
Are they setting up?
In the lounge.
Hey, Mark.
I got a call from the DA today
about a drunk woman
who came in in labor.
Uh-huh.
They're bringing charges
against her... attempted murder.
Social Services really
jumped on that one.
No, actually, they're
acting on a call from us.
So you've seen that
crayon-in-the-nose trick before?
Millions of times.
Doctor, I got that address
for you... Sisters of Mercy.
Yeah, we can handle it together.
Doctor Doyle, did you make the
call to the 32nd precinct today?
Yeah, I got a cousin there.
She said she wanted
to kill her baby.
I was a witness.
We get a lot of women
with alcohol and drug problems.
If we let Social
Services handle it.
It can fall through the cracks.
That's not what happens.
More to the point, initiating a
criminal investigation wasn't your job.
What about protecting the
health of the baby... is that my job?
We not going to improve
prenatal care for high-risk infants
if we scare off the mothers.
How about this? If I get
to testify against the bitch
I'll do it on my own time.
I think we're going to like her.
Randi, could you try
and find me some aspirin?
It doesn't work for us.
We never had floats in
and out of the department.
Budgets are tight, Carol.
Yeah, well, we're
all aware of that.
Look, the hospital
values its RNs.
Registered nurses
are the best trained
and most versatile part
of the entire nursing staff.
Thank you.
We are also the most
expensive part of that staff.
County has got
to figure out ways
to utilize RNs more effectively.
Well, at least, have
the floats make sense.
Go on.
ER and ICU have
more skills in common
than ward nurses,
Recovery or Neuro.
That's a very good point, Carol.
That is precisely why
I keep trying to
get you managers
who are in the trenches
more active on the committees.
We need your perspective.
Oh, Mary. I'm swamped.
Okay. How about a deal?
I confine ER floats to
ICU per your suggestion.
In exchange, you come sit
on the hospital-wide
re-engineering committee...
We only meet once a month.
Okay. I stalled her
with one last patient.
Better be a good one.
She was out the door.
I think Mr. Frick
will keep her busy for a while.
Hey, you got any tape?
Yeah, yeah. Is Mark coming?
I beeped him twice.
Sorry, folks. We've
got an MVA coming in.
Kindergarten car pool
versus joyriding teens.
All right, let's go.
Could be as many
as eight victims.
I'll clear the trauma rooms.
There goes the party.
What's the ETA?
Oh, they are pulling up now.
Let's go. Come on.
That's me. Runner-up
for Mr. Universe.
Call me a fool, Doc
but I'm betting on a comeback.
I haven't changed
a lick since 1947.
Well, I'm afraid
you may have lost
a little too much
weight recently.
Hey! I'm in training.
Midwestern finals.
American bodybuilders.
70 and older.
Ah! I got to take care
of this damn sciatica.
Oh, man, that smarts.
Yeah. Why don't
you take a seat again.
Do you know how
this injury happened?
My B-12 shot. Must
have hit a nerve.
You're injecting vitamins?
Hey, don't worry. I steer
clear of the steroids.
Oh, that's good.
Scoot back.
Press against my hands.
Yeah. Good.
Any other complaints?
Nope.
Best I've looked in ten years.
When's the competition?
Mid-March.
I'll be 74 by then.
And ready for a comeback.
You think?
Yep.
Plenty of bed rest,
anti-inflammatories
and start back slowly.
Thanks, Doc.
Okay.
This one had a seat belt on
but there was passenger
space intrusion.
Fractured tib-fib.
Hey, honey. You're
going to be fine.
Order a portable
c-spine and left tib-fib.
All right, come
with me this way.
I'll find you a place to sit.
My mom and dad
are going to kill me.
I'll tell them it was my fault.
Ah...
Signing out, Randi.
Thanks, Dr. Lewis.
Good luck in Phoenix. Thanks.
No, this is the ER again.
We need a neurosurgeon now.
I need Dr. Benton's x rays.
Get him to the suture room.
Set me up with some 4-0 nylon.
Wait! Wait! Wait!
Ma'am, you have
a ruptured spleen.
You're going to need
immediate surgery.
But it's my car pool.
All the parents
need to be called!
Randi, come take
these numbers down.
I'm coming. I'm coming.
I told you not to let him drive.
He told me he knew how.
We were just goofing around.
Hush! Hold still.
Complains of chest
pains, shortness of breath.
Diminished breath
sounds on the left.
Let's get a chest tube tray.
We need an abdominal CT
for the kid in Trauma One.
BP's coming down. 190/130.
Poor cap refill. Pulse ox 90.
Type and cross two units.
X ray's coming for the c-spine.
Lower that IV bag.
Anybody need any help?
Susan, what are
you still doing here?
You're going to miss your train.
Lavage is negative.
Get an x-ray.
Call us.
Get some O-negative, too.
I'm calling CT.
Left pupil's sluggish.
Dusky. You want to intubate?
Yes.
All right. You do it.
7.0 ET tube.
Possible subdural hematoma.
Mannitol.
90 grams IV
Let's, uh, hyperventilate him.
All right?
Here you go.
Okay.
Use suction if you need it.
Visualize the cords.
Good, good.
All right, take your time.
He's breathing on his own.
She didn't even leave a note.
Well, you know, she was saying
good-bye to everyone all day.
Dr. Greene, one of those car
pool kids crashed in Radiology.
Which one?
The fractured tib-fib.
How'd it happen?
So, if it's okay with you, I'd
love to get out of here by 7:00.
What, are you working on
that literature review for Keaton?
No, actually, I've got a date.
Yeah? Well, just
don't procrastinate
and keep Keaton waiting...
It reflects poorly on me.
You know something? She's
a hard one to get, isn't she?
How do you figure?
Well, obviously,
she's a great surgeon
but she's not much of a teacher.
You don't think so?
Oh, come on... all
that psychobabble?
Her explanations can
be a little bit eccentric.
She doesn't say what she wants.
Sometimes, she does.
Then again, you know, I
haven't been working with her
the same way that you have.
Carter, she's soft.
She can be.
She doesn't act like a surgeon.
Well, you know, it is difficult
to learn from somebody
who teaches by intuition,
which is one of the things I've always
appreciated about your teaching.
Excuse me, Carter.
Carla?
There you are. You know,
I've been sitting in
that lot for half an hour.
Why?
Kingston Mines.
Dinner before the early set.
That's tomorrow night.
No, that is tonight.
Anything you need?
No, Carter.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Carla, this is Dr. Carter.
Carter, this is Carla Reece.
Pleased to meet you. Same here.
I'm sorry. I'm on
till midnight tonight.
So this is where you
work until midnight?
Yeah. Why don't I
walk you to your car?
Oh, you haven't
been here before?
No, no, I haven't,
knock on wood.
We should give you a tour.
No, no, no, she's got plans.
Not anymore. I've been stood up.
Well, if Trauma One is open,
we could start there.
Mmm. Really. Just don't
show me anything bloody.
No, no, no, no.
What do you do, Carla?
I have this Caribbean
restaurant on Western.
No kidding? My
family used to sail
to the islands every spring.
Half day, Dr. Ross?
I was immunizing
when you were hitting
the snooze button.
I'm upset because
I don't understand
how you could send
a surgical abdomen...
I asked if I should
send him for a CT.
You said go ahead.
Yeah, I assumed he was stable.
No, Mark, I asked for your call.
You weren't listening.
Well, you didn't ask me...
you were distracted.
You were looking for Susan Lewis
worried that she
had left, which is fine.
I understand that, but
don't yell at me now.
Hey, Mark, grab your coat.
Let's go talk.
Hmm, Admin actually listened?
So, no more floating?
You laid down the law?
Well, they won't be
sending any of you to Neuro
or the wards anymore.
They're going to
limit our floats to ICU.
How is that any better?
Well, at least the
nursing skills are similar.
We're going to have
to get it in our contract.
Only way they'll respect us.
Honey, they'll never respect us.
Dr. Weaver is wondering
where all the nurses are.
Look, I don't think it's so bad
floating to ICU.
I'm not going.
They won't send you.
You're not close
enough to your 20 years.
Look, I know it's a compromise
but it's better than
what was happening.
Careful, Carol.
You're sounding an
awful lot like management.
Wow.
I didn't even say good-bye.
Good-bye is not what
you need to tell her.
Well, it's too late now.
What time's her train leave?
4:20.
It's less than an hour.
They're usually
running a little bit late.
She probably had to go
home to get her luggage.
Yeah, well, I'm on till 11:00.
I should just go?
You could.
No, no, no. It's impossible.
She's getting on a train.
She's made up her mind.
It may be, but
that's not the point.
So, what would I say now?
You would say to her
what you've been
wanting to say for years.
You tell her how you feel
or you can let her go
without saying a word
and you'll regret it
for the rest of your life
and make yourself
and everybody else
around you miserable
like you have today.
You're right.
Mm-hmm.
W-w-wait. C-can
you tell Kerry...?
Yeah, go, go, go, go, go.
This is great!
Oh, my goodness.
Is this where you
operate on them?
No, no, no, no.
We just stabilize
them down here.
Then we send them
upstairs to the OR. Oh.
Speaking of upstairs...
Yep. Nice meeting you, Carla.
Yes. Thank you, thank
you for showing me around.
What's in here?
Uh, it's just a suture room.
Oh, really?
What goes on in here?
Uh, we just take
patients down here...
Mmm.
Oh.
You're going to mess up
my reputation around here.
I've been wanting to do that
since I came into this place.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
Um... I'm sorry I
got to work late.
Well, there's late,
and... there's later.
Taxi?
Whoa, whoa.
Hold on.
Susan?
Susan, are you here?
Oh, Dr. Greene,
you just missed her.
She left you a note.
W-where?
On the mantel.
Thank you.
Uh... i-is the
clock right, Sister?
Oh, yes.
It must be slow.
I got a friend trying
to catch a train.
Sister Ann, try to
get them to share.
Sorry. We haven't had
a Lopez all month.
It's a mother and an infant.
Yes, I know, doctor.
I'm sorry.
You could leave a
note on the board.
Southwest gate.
Track ten.
Looking for the Chief, sir?
She got moved.
Track six.
Susan!
Susan, Susan!
All aboard!
Susan!
Mark?!
Are you okay?
You came to say good-bye?
No. Stay.
I want you to stay.
But, Mark...
I love you
And I'm stupid for
not saying it before.
No, it's okay. I knew.
In a way, I knew.
Stay.
We belong together.
Tell me you don't feel the same.
I'm sorry.
Train's leaving, ma'am.
We're right together.
Mark... you are my best friend.
I don't know how I'm
going to make it without you.
Don't go.
I have to.
I don't belong here anymore.
I have a new life.
It's going in a
different direction.
Susan, I don't want to lose you.
Oh...
Ma'am... ma'am,
we're leaving. Come on.
I'll never forget you.
I do love you.
What?
I love you!
Bye.