NARRATOR:
Previously on Private Practice:
- We're all gonna vote.
- You choose which one runs the practice.
- Congratulations, boss.
- Hello, Peter.
- Meg?
VIOLET: How do you know Pete?
MEG:
We were residents together.
Again with the talking?
I'm serious.
We're gonna get to know each other.
I got it.
[LAUGHS]
Oh, sorry.
KEVIN:
Are you still working?
ADDISON:
Okay, I figured it out.
The magic number: $487,000.
If I can find $487,000, it's enough
to get the practice rolling again.
I don't know how,
but I'm gonna find that money.
I will find that money
because I am a good leader.
I wanna be interested and excited
but it's been two weeks
of me sleeping under paperwork.
So pretend this is me interested
because I'm very tired.
- Sleep with me.
- Uh-huh.
Ha-ha. No.
Sleep with me.
Don't tell me that's daylight.
You are a horrible, corrupting influence.
- Oh, what a shame.
- All the sex?
No.
What all those cigarettes
are doing to that gorgeous body.
May I remind you,
my French inhale turned you on.
Yeah, we're not 22 anymore.
We're doctors.
We know what smoking does
to gorgeous bodies.
Cancer. Heart attacks.
Well, I know what I enjoy.
Like you, for instance,
when you're not talking about this.
Well, make me stop talking.
Goodbye, rubber rompers.
Goodbye, my little latex safety nets.
Sex without condoms.
How grown-up are we,
getting HIV tests?
Using just the pill.
COOPER:
It's the next big step in our relationship.
We're two teenagers,
busting at the seams with hormones,
stuck for the summer in our Footloose,
no-dancing, conservative town
where my daddy preaches
with his loaded shotgun under the pulpit.
And then one night, in the cornfield...
What? What happens in the cornfield?
After we take our HIV tests,
I'm gonna show you.
COOPER: Oh, show me now.
- I can't. I have a job interview.
Which, if it goes well, we can celebrate.
In the cornfield.
COOPER:
Job interview?
SAM:
I forgot how much fun irresponsibility is.
NAOMl:
Oh, really? I love irresponsibility.
Mom?
Dad?
Are you getting back together?
- Yeah.
- Absolutely. Yes.
Yeah.
You should have seen
Maya's face, man.
It was like Christmas, new puppy,
first car, all rolled into one.
What was I supposed to say?
Are you and Naomi ready
to get back together?
I mean, I just got single.
I haven't sown any oats.
I can't get over the feeling
that I'm missing something.
- Like?
- Like an ex-lover jetting in
and making me look like this one.
No. Love, companionship. That is not
a step backwards. That's a step forwards.
It's like taking off the condom.
And taking off the condom is good.
Metaphorically.
So you can do that? Let go of the betrayal,
everything he put you through?
Yeah, well, you know,
we both played our part.
But I don't know.
Now it just feels right.
We're Sam and Naomi.
- Sam and Naomi, together again.
NAOMl: Yeah.
You and Sam?
You're getting back together? Nai, that's...
That's great. That's amazing.
Thank you.
So I hear the mean, new boss lady
is calling a morning meeting.
Oh, now, she's not that bad.
Once you get to know her.
Four hundred
and eighty-seven thousand dollars.
- What does that mean?
- How much we need
- to keep the doors open.
- And you have a plan?
A plan that doesn't change
what the practice is supposed to be.
I do, actually. Starting Monday,
our doors will open one hour earlier,
and we will close one hour later.
We will also be working weekends.
Saturdays from 9 to 1.
I have a...
- Sure.
ADDISON: And in addition,
I will be asking each of you
to take on extra responsibilities
- to help generate income.
- What about me?
You will be working with me
to find the extra money.
Pete, we have to go.
It's Jenna's day.
- Jenna's day.
- That's today?
Oh, my God. It's Jenna's day.
COOPER: Jenna.
- Jenna?
Tell her I said hi.
Who's Jenna?
Saved the practice. You're welcome.
Hey, can you set up two blood-draw kits
for me for this afternoon?
- Sure.
- That's a whole lot of condoms.
Planned Parenthood.
Addison's helping them with community
outreach. And they're free.
VIOLET:
Go ahead, Cooper. Line your pockets.
- No, I'm good.
- Oh, you're good with condoms?
Yeah.
So it's over?
- Between you and Charlotte? I'm sorry.
- What? No.
What? Oh. Oh!
You're being monogamous?
You're being serious?
With Charlotte? Really?
- Charlotte?
- Yeah.
Here's the part where you say:
"Congratulations, Cooper.
I'm happy for you."
Uh, I have to go.
An old friend is in from out of town.
A really... A really good friend.
NAOMl: Okay, Jenna.
I am aspirating the follicular fluid.
So tell us about the wedding.
You have a white dress and a big cake?
Yeah. Strawberry.
Look at my wedding ring.
It's a karat. A whole karat.
It was her grandmother's.
Oh, please tell me
you brought pictures.
Now, we need to see the pictures.
I have the album in the car.
I will bring it up.
It was the most amazing day of my life.
- Until now.
- And I am done.
You're done? You got my eggs?
PETE: Hey, Nick.
NICK: Hey, guys.
NAOMl: Hey, Nick.
LYNN: Hey, sweetie.
- I'm sorry, practice ran late.
- She got my eggs, Nick.
Wow, it's really happening.
- How'd she do?
PETE: She's a trouper.
SAM:
Oh, great.
- What's going on?
- Egg retrieval.
Is there an office pool
on how many eggs we'll get?
- No. It's Jenna.
- That's Jenna?
COOPER: Yeah. We've known her
and her family a long time.
- How old is she?
- All right. Seventeen.
Uh... Why are we doing egg retrieval
on a 17-year-old?
- Because she's dying.
PETE: And we're giving her last wish.
A baby.
Thank you.
Vi, oh, look at you.
Look at you. Assistant DA
wasn't impressive enough,
you had to run for Congress?
You big show-off.
- Oh, it's so good to see you.
- Is everything okay?
Yeah, the campaign's going well.
I'm up in the polls, so the other side
wants to bring me down. You know?
They're calling my law professors
and ex-boyfriends.
- No one's called you, have they?
- No.
And even if they did,
you're safe with me.
We've always had each other's backs,
right? Through good and bad.
I need help, Vi.
Okay. Well, if things are tough again,
then I can recommend someone.
A therapist. Discreet.
- Not that.
- Well, tell me. Anything.
I need you
to destroy my medical records.
- You remember freshman year?
- Are you kidding?
- You know, my mother just died and you...
- Yeah.
Well, I never told you,
but Christmas break
I admitted myself to St. Ambrose.
I had shock therapy.
Why didn't you tell me?
We poured our souls out to each other.
Well, I was too embarrassed.
And I just couldn't. But now...
You see my problem.
Shock therapy is not a big deal.
Oh, well, maybe not to you,
but voters won't see it that way.
Everyone's seen Cuckoo's Nest.
- Shock therapy equals lobotomy.
- No.
It's different now. Even the American
Psychiatric Association says...
The voters won't be reading
the annals of the APA.
They're not gonna be reading
your records.
All it takes is one reporter
flirting with a nurse at St. Ambrose.
That's how politicians are ruined.
But, oh, if those files could disappear...
That's how doctors are ruined.
I could lose my license.
Violet, you know I wouldn't ask if...
Please, I would do anything for you.
I just...
I need you to do this one thing for me.
- You're implanting a baby in a baby?
- Jenna is a married woman.
She's a teenager and she's dying.
How long does she have?
- A year or two.
- And what then?
Addison, you don't know this girl
or this family. We do.
Jenna was one of my first patients.
The cutest kid.
Every appointment, she'd bring a doll.
Whatever boo-boo she had,
she'd put it on this doll.
- She wanted to mother it.
- She doesn't need a living doll.
She needs to be living what life
she has left. Making the most of it.
Well, for her and her family,
"the most of it" is having a child.
NAOMl: Violet has seen Jenna's parents
through this entire process.
And they went from watching
their only child die to hope.
Aren't we, in effect, creating an orphan?
Jenna has parents and a husband
who loves her.
Maybe it's young love, but it's real.
Is she even strong enough
to carry a baby?
Do you think that we'd be doing this
if she wasn't?
I think that you all love this girl.
I'm just not sure
that you're doing the right thing.
This what it's like with you in charge?
Questioning decisions
we've already made?
Because we all talked about this case
last year
and we decided that if she could get
through chemo,
and if she were strong enough...
Wait, there's a healthy egg.
I'm gonna grab some more.
I'm gonna get Nick in the donation room.
All right, in 24 hours,
she could be pregnant.
Addison. Hey, Addison.
Naomi was making a dig at me.
What, just because I haven't been here
as long as the rest of you...?
Naomi is just being protective of Jenna.
We all are.
Look, maybe
from the outside it seems crazy.
But what we have been through
with this girl, non-Hodgkins lymphoma,
Sam and Cooper got her
the best oncologist.
She did radiation,
chemo, bone marrow.
I threw the kitchen sink
of alternative treatments at her.
She's dying.
But she is holding on for this.
- Naomi was not making a dig.
- Felt like it.
She's trying.
Just leave the Jenna thing alone.
Do you have any idea how much money
we're owed in overdue accounts?
- How much?
- Hundred and forty-two thousand dollars.
That is great.
That is real money.
You want me to get
a collection agency on it?
What, and give them a huge cut?
No. You have the ledger. You call them.
I need an enforcer, Dell.
Someone to call the patients,
motivate them to pay up.
An enforcer?
Enforcer.
- Are you busy?
- Actually, I'm waiting for somebody but...
So my friend asked me
to do something terrible.
And I don't know if I should do it.
Well, in fact, I know I shouldn't do it.
- But it's a friend.
- Wait, by "friend," do you mean "guy'?
And by "something terrible,"
do you mean "something anal"?
Cooper. It's Kara Wei. She asked me
to destroy her medical records.
Kara Wei? The Kara Wei?
That's your friend
you went to see this morning?
Yeah. It's from college.
- She's my best friend.
- I'm your best friend.
She's not your friend
if she wants you to destroy records.
Was a time when we would've
done anything.
You know, I went through
some very bad times
and she was there for me.
- So you should put your career at risk?
- I owe her.
- She's not your best friend. I am.
- You were.
My having Charlotte
doesn't mean that you don't have me.
And you cannot do this.
You have to tell her
what you've told me.
"Stop sleeping with skanks"?
CHARLOTTE: I'll let that pass.
- Oh, I didn't mean...
- I've got a half an hour. Let's do this.
- We'll talk later.
Yeah.
Right.
- Look at your calendar.
- Okay.
- Hi.
- Hey.
You know, about this morning,
we should probably talk.
We should. Absolutely.
- Later.
- Right.
- Hey.
- I could have a July baby.
- That's a good month.
- You have a daughter, right?
- Maya.
She's a few years younger than you.
- It's the best thing, huh? Being a parent?
- Yeah, it is.
It feels like the only thing I've ever wanted.
To be a mom.
You are so ahead of the game.
To know what you want, so clearly,
and then go for it.
Most people, they put it off
or make excuses.
Maybe you don't get the perspective
of how good,
how precious life is until it's too late.
But this is the only life you have. Right?
Yeah.
- Whoa. Oh, my gosh. I'm so sorry.
- No, no. It's fine.
The basket's over there on the cart.
For your cup.
Oh, thanks.
- Are you Jenna's husband?
- Yeah. Nick.
- I'm Dr. Montgomery. Addison.
- Nice to meet you.
[WOMAN GROANING ON TV]
Oh, the... I couldn't figure out
how to turn it off.
Don't worry. I've got it.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm sorry. It's all just a little weird.
Most of the team
went out for pizza after practice.
I came to get Jenna pregnant.
Yeah, you should be dealing
with college applications
and making your parents freak out
over wild parties.
Well, I mean,
parents aren't really in the picture.
Lynn and Garry, Jenna's parents.
They took me in.
We'd been dating so long I was already
part of the family, so it works.
Can I ask you?
- What happens after?
- After?
When I was 17,
I couldn't have done what you're doing.
Have you thought this through?
Are you going to college?
I wanna go to U. Penn and my guidance
counselor thinks I can get a scholarship.
That's great.
So will you bring the baby with you
or will Jenna's parents raise the baby?
I mean, how will you be involved?
Will you fly home weekends or holidays?
What happens when she's 10 or 15
and she asks
why her father didn't raise her?
Well, Garry and Lynn wanna be parents
again, and Jenna wants a baby, so...
You are gonna be the father, Nick.
What do you want?
No, I won't call back again.
We've sent you this bill three times
and we need you to pay it.
It wouldn't have hurt so much
if you didn't tense up.
I didn't know
you were so afraid of needles.
Shut your mouth.
If you tell anyone, no cornfield for you.
Oh, there will be cornfield.
- How did the job interview go?
- Okay.
It's not out of state?
You're not going anywhere?
I just took an HIV test for you.
Why would I go anywhere?
[ELEVATOR DINGS]
- So...
- It's business, Coop.
Let's focus on pleasure.
Cornfield.
NAOMl: I am injecting a single sperm
into your egg.
She's making your baby, sweetie.
Look at that.
Our grandchild.
Over the next 48 hours,
the cells will divide and multiply
to form an embryo.
That's my baby! Oh, take a picture.
Take a picture of us for the album.
Sure. Okay, Nick. Get in there.
You're gonna be a dad.
Nick?
I'm sorry.
- You've been good to me. You all have...
- Nicky?
I don't wanna do this.
I don't want a baby.
Wait, what would be on your list
of things to do before you die, Coop?
Am I dying?
Did you get my test results from Dell?
- No, l...
JENNA: Nick. Please come out.
I really want this baby.
NICK:
We've barely had sex.
- Babies are supposed to come from sex.
JENNA: My parents can hear you.
GARRY: It's okay, sweetie.
- Nick, I mean it. You promised.
This is perfectly normal.
It's fertility stress.
- I didn't say anything.
PETE: I got the key.
Nick, I'm coming in.
Okay.
What are you doing? You wanted this.
You wanted this.
And they wanted this.
But like she said,
what about what I want?
Fine. Go.
- It's okay, honey.
- No. I'll do it without him.
I'm sorry, but we can't use his sperm
without his consent.
That fertilized egg can't be implanted.
That's not fair.
I need this baby.
Come on. Let's go sit down.
He was scared. We were talking.
He had reservations.
No, you didn't approve of what
we were doing, so you sabotaged it.
He needed someone to talk to.
I was being a good doctor.
Do you wanna pick up the pieces
of that girl now?
I told you to back off.
I could use you on my campaign.
Consultant for my health-care policy.
Affordable coverage for everyone,
including mental health.
I have heard your stump speech,
that is not why I asked to see you.
Well, it may be a stump speech,
but I believe in it.
I can make things better, Vi.
Which is why I don't think
you should hide from your past.
- I'm not hiding.
- You have an opportunity here to do good.
To embrace what happened to you,
to go public.
- Is that what you did?
- Well, that's different.
Is it? This is something from my past
I want kept personal.
Mental illness
is nothing to be ashamed of.
Neither is rape.
But you chose to bury it.
And I held your hand
every step of the way.
I know.
I know you were there for me.
But burying this is not good for you.
Hiding a secret,
walking around, worried about when
the other shoe is gonna drop,
it's gonna eat you up.
And I am not talking about Kara Wei,
the Congressional candidate.
I'm talking about Kara, my friend.
You can stop it now, Violet.
When I first met you,
and your mother had just died,
and you didn't talk about it,
and you buried it,
it almost did you in.
Until you opened up to me,
and then you got help.
And then I opened up to you,
and I learned the same lesson.
- This is different.
- No, no, it's not.
You are about to be
in a position of power.
Think how many people you could help
if they knew that it was okay to talk about...
I have plenty of people I help.
Now I'm surrounded by people
who want my help.
I came to you
because I thought you would help me.
I thought we did that for each other.
- Did you get my patients' blood work?
- Not until tomorrow.
These are rapid blood tests.
You know what I'd like
before I die, Sam?
I would like a lab
that delivers test results on time.
Wait, that wasn't the point
of my question.
It's about life. It's about living.
I sat there today with a girl who's dying,
who's not afraid to live. And me...
- This is about Naomi?
- Yes.
Shook up my whole world
because I felt I hadn't been living, all right?
And what do I do? Nothing.
Now I'm talking about
getting back together with Naomi
without ever stepping off a cliff.
You wanna step off a cliff?
I wanna do something big.
What did you have in mind?
Get ready to step off the cliff, my friend.
Okay.
Ah!
- Yeah, that's badass, isn't it?
- Yeah, congratulations.
You've crossed the same threshold
as every 10-year-old girl in America.
What's happening?
Oh, wow.
That's awful.
[WOMAN CRYING OVER PHONE]
When did he leave you?
That's fine. You just take your time.
Okay.
I'm done. You know the economy's
really bad, right? People are hurting.
I came back to be a midwife,
to do less administration.
And when we dig out of the hole,
you will.
Right now,
everyone's taking on extra duty.
They're doing more medicine.
I'm a bill collector.
We need a bill collector.
Or the rest of the money.
What?
You know something.
- Dell.
- No, I don't. I don't know anything.
William "Dell" Parker.
What do you know?
We have been killing ourselves
trying to save this practice
and you have 10,000 square feet
of prime office space
on the fourth floor?
It is not as simple as it sounds.
Then make me understand, Nai.
The practice is at stake here.
This is the practice.
This was our first space.
Mine and Sam's.
Maya learned how to walk here.
And we had an opportunity to create
a medical sanctuary. Addison, look.
Cardiologist.
Surgical suites. MRI suites.
A dedicated lab.
This was the practice
we always dreamed of.
SAM:
The practice it still can be.
Look, now, the only way to lease this place
is with a five- or ten-year commitment.
And that would mean giving up
on our future.
If we lease it, we can pay off our debt,
our cash flow will be way up,
it will allow us to stay afloat.
No. This is an issue
on which we see eye to eye.
We're not leasing it out, Addison.
You are holding on to something
that we cannot afford.
And once again,
you are trying to control everything.
It's not enough that you've ruined
the wish of a dying girl?
You know what? Keep it up.
I'm gonna stop caring
whether or not you forgive me.
And, Sam, you knew about this place
and you kept it from me. Nice.
Great.
Thank you. Thanks for backing me up.
Well, this is our future, so...
What the hell is in your ear?
Oh. It's a stud.
You know, like Harrison Ford.
Michael Jordan.
You like it?
Well, maybe Maya will think it's hip.
Yeah. Hip.
Speaking of, maybe we could come over
to dinner tonight, you know?
And then afterwards
you and I could talk.
- About us.
- Okay, yeah.
- Yeah?
- Sure.
The kid's 17 and they wanna use him
as a baby factory.
If it was me, I'd run away too.
Why should that boy
wanna be tied down?
Great. I'm already dealing with one girl
who's dying.
- That's subtle.
- I just want you to be healthy.
I'm a smoker, Pete. Take it or leave it.
COOPER:
The lab is fast.
Usually.
No preacher. No cornfield.
- I needed sex today.
- Me too.
Violet's being all passive-aggressive.
Addison's at war with Sam and Naomi
over leasing a floor of the building.
We're doctors fighting over leases.
- That's how broke we are.
- Yeah?
You wanna tell me
why you're looking for jobs?
I'm not a doctor anymore.
I'm an administrator.
I need more. I need...
The interview today was really interesting,
it was...
What?
Never mind.
- We can still be in the cornfield.
- Come on, finish what you were saying.
I'm your friend.
Possibly your best friend.
And we still don't have any condoms.
No need.
I'm pure as the driven snow.
I'm the "everything but" girl
who's waiting for marriage.
And you
are the horny field hand.
And we can only use our tongues.
So if I lease the fourth floor,
then Sam and Naomi hate me.
But if I don't, the practice may go under.
- So you lease it, right?
- You make it sound easy.
I lead guys every day.
A leader makes tough decisions.
Sometimes that means pissing off a friend
for the good of the group.
I want people to stop being pissed off.
You need to decide who you wanna be:
A good friend or a good leader.
You're smart. I don't like that.
Yes, you do.
You want me to eat noodles
off your back?
Yes. Please.
MAYA: Are you gonna move back in,
or will we move to the beach house?
I love the beach.
SAM:
Uh... I don't know. I don't know, honey.
Are you gonna have another wedding?
That would be so cool.
Well... Um...
You know, it's... Your dad and I
have a lot to discuss.
Oh, I know. I'm just really excited.
Come on, eat.
- Where are you going?
- You don't wanna know.
No, Violet.
Don't do this.
If she was your friend, she...
Last night, I stayed up alone
and watched starving teenage girls
vying to be supermodels.
What did you do, Coop?
Best friend, my ass.
- Hey. What's happening?
- Hey, Sam.
NAOMl: Hello.
- Hey.
You wanna know
how I spent the rest of my night
after you rushed us out your door?
Answering questions
that you ducked all night.
- We talked.
- Yeah.
About algebra tests and piano lessons.
We were supposed to talk about us.
Oh, I'm sorry, Nai.
I've been trying to figure some things out.
- And I wrote a list.
- What is this?
It's the things that...
Things I'm going to do.
- Climb Mount Kilimanjaro?
- Yeah.
With or without your inhaler?
- Don't mock my list.
- Learn to sail?
Drive through the Badlands?
What, is this a midlife crisis?
Or is the prospect
of us getting back together
making you wanna hop in a car
and drive as far away as possible?
This isn't about you. This is about me.
And what about the timing?
Is that coincidence?
- Because we've been apart a year, Sam.
- Dr. Bennett?
SAM: Yes.
NAOMl: Yeah.
JENNA:
We have a few hours left on the eggs.
I still want this baby.
- What about Nick?
- He never came home last night.
LYNN: We're really worried about him.
- He's probably at the stupid arcade.
I want this baby.
If I can't use Nick's sperm,
I'll use a sperm donor.
A sperm donor
is not what we talked about.
Yeah, but we agreed
to get her pregnant.
PETE:
We agreed to get them pregnant.
- Well...
- A sperm donor?
You know, Addison, she is still dying.
This doesn't change anything.
I'd say it does for Nick.
Or do we usually allow wives
to pick out sperm donors
when their husbands
don't even want kids?
Look, all Naomi is trying to say
is the family wants this.
Her husband is her family too.
Doesn't he at least deserve to be here,
to be part of this decision?
- Can you just mind your own business?
- No, no, this is my business.
God, I hate this.
What, she's in charge and so she thinks
she gets to be right about everything?
I think the real problem
is she is right about this.
I need a file for a patient of mine:
Kara Wei.
W-E-I.
- You're really doing this? Stealing files?
- You followed me.
- Friends don't let friends steal.
- Don't even go there.
Okay, don't take it off hospital grounds,
don't leave it laying around,
put it in my hands when you're done.
Hospital ID?
Look at me
and tell me you wanna do this.
I don't have one.
But I do have privileges here.
Well, you can't have the file without ID.
- And you can't do this, you can't...
- And do you have ID?
I can vouch for her.
Dr. King, this good clerk has rules.
Dr. Freedman, I assume you have
the results of our patient's blood work?
- No, I don't.
- Why don't we go to my office
so we can call and find out
what's taking so long?
My patient is anxious.
I'm consulting with Dr. Turner
on a matter...
- No. No, I don't need your help.
- Violet.
- Go.
- Come on, Dr. Freedman.
I want answers.
I'm not talking about this anymore.
Jenna still wants to have a baby.
She's looking at sperm donors right now.
If that's what she wants.
- It isn't what you want?
- None of this is what I want.
I said I'd do this.
I want her to be happy.
She's dying.
My girlfriend... My wife is dying.
I mean, I'm just a kid. I don't know.
She's all I have.
I just want us to be happy.
Not with a baby.
Just with each other.
- With the time she has left.
- Then you gotta tell her that.
Let go of what you think she wants
to hear, and just tell her the truth.
I told you everything.
I poured my heart out to you.
About everything that he
did to me. You...
You told me nothing.
She's dying, Nai.
- I know that.
- You can't control it, you can't stop it.
And even if the idea of this baby
makes you forget about it,
it's not going away.
This is not about control.
Because if we were gonna talk
about control, we might talk about you.
You know what, Nai? It's a two-way street.
And I wanna get past it.
I've tried to get past this.
You need to decide.
Are we gonna get past this or not?
You're holding on to your anger
as you're holding on to that dying girl.
I am not holding on to her.
This is her dream.
Her husband doesn't wanna take
her dream away from her.
And her parents don't wanna take away
that dream, but you are her doctor.
You have to stop holding on.
All of you do. To her, to the idea
of the baby, to the fourth floor.
This is not wrapped up together with that.
That is different.
- That is our future.
- That's one future.
Just like Nick and Jenna and the baby
is one future.
And now they need to find a new path.
Some dreams
you have to let go.
She always used a belt.
Buckle hit my teeth once,
knocked four out.
I was 16. I could defend myself.
But my brother Robbie was 9.
She put his hand on the stove
because she said he mouthed off.
I couldn't watch her do that to him.
The judge said it was self-defense
and he sealed the record.
- I'm sorry this happened to you.
- That's why I was depressed.
And that's why I needed shock therapy.
And that's why I need you
to destroy those medical records.
Destroying this file
won't change that it happened.
It doesn't matter how I defend it, Violet.
The headline will read:
"Congressional Candidate
Murdered Mom."
- And I'll be done.
- You can't make this disappear.
Even if the medical records go away,
there are still legal records.
I'm a District Attorney.
- Those were easy.
- Kara...
Why should I expect
the voters to understand
when my oldest friend is judging me?
Okay. You wanna be a politician?
Why not be the right kind?
The kind who makes the right choices?
Because that's the person that I knew.
I'm giving you a choice.
Between the person that you wanna be,
and the person that you are.
Between our friendship and...
JENNA: Dr. Bennett?
- Yes?
- I think we found a sperm donor we like.
LYNN: Do you know where Naomi is?
We're ready. I found someone.
- Can we do it now?
- Jenna.
I can't.
- What?
- I know this is what you want.
You can't say no.
That's the problem. I couldn't.
No one could.
Because everyone in this room loves you
and wants to give you everything.
I don't want everything.
I just want this baby.
And you know what I want?
What everyone in this room wants.
We want you not to be dying.
But you are.
When we talk about the baby,
we get to forget.
And we get to take back control
of this big ugly thing.
Having a baby isn't gonna change
what's happening.
And the more you hold on to that,
the less you're gonna be able
to really live the life you have left
with the people who love you.
I don't want a baby.
But I do want you.
I don't wanna die.
SAM:
Ow!
What? You should have swabbed it
with alcohol.
I don't know what I was thinking.
I guess you just get to a point
where you start to wonder.
Wonder about all the things
you haven't done.
But the truth is
I like what I've done.
You know, the practice, Maya,
you.
I wanna spend my life
with the people I love the most.
Let's do this, Nai.
Let's move back in.
What?
If you had asked me that yesterday,
or the day before,
that would have been exactly
what I wanted.
We don't know anything else, Sam.
I'm afraid that we keep falling back
together not because it's right,
but because
we wanna hold on to what we know.
And if we move back in,
it won't change the fact
that it wasn't working.
We never really let go, Sam.
We have to let go.
Goodbye, Sam.
Goodbye, Naomi.
How's the future congresswoman
from California?
She's gonna be good at her job.
- You let her have those files?
- I messed up.
I messed up so bad.
I don't even think I did it
for the right reasons. I just...
I just wanted a friend.
Everyone's living and I'm just here
alone.
And it doesn't bother me
that you have Charlotte, I'm happy for you.
I am. It's just...
Well, you have Charlotte.
This came for you. Blood-test results.
From the lab.
Open it up.
Make sure you have the "all clear."
Later.
Right now,
I think my best friend needs me.
- Look, about the fourth floor...
- You know what?
You were right. I need to let it go.
So go ahead and lease it.
I already did.
Broker found a tenant.
You're gonna be a good leader.
Thank you.
Welcome.
- You're leaving.
- Yeah.
They need me in Ghana.
Only one direct flight a week.
Maybe I was too hard on you
about the smoking.
No. It's not about the smoking.
This is who I am.
I drop in, have a great time, then I go.
Along the way, I smoke.
Stop trying to domesticate me.
- I'm not trying to domesticate...
- You are. I'm not your wife.
Who died
before she could quit smoking.
Oh.
Maybe I should've told you that.
Go. Go to Ghana.
But come back.
I'm happier when you're here.
I'll think about the smoking.
And thank you.
For being happier when I'm here.
COOPER [OVER PHONE]: The bathtub
is running. The candles are lit.
I've done my best to re-create the world
of two condom-less teenagers
in a Footloose, conservative town.
- All I'm missing is you.
- I'll be right there.
I've got to admit. In our first interview,
I wasn't sure about you.
But when you called me
about this office space,
I knew you were the right person
for the job.
Thank you.
We got your hopes up, I know.
I'm sorry.
I'm so, so sorry.
It's gonna be okay.
All right?
We're gonna be okay.