Previously on ER.
I've been having
a problem with Dr. Romano.
Why didn't the genetics clinic
suggest this medication?
Well, it's brand‐new. It's still
part of a clinical trial.
'Do I need to fill
any of this out?'
Hmm, I wouldn't bother. He's not
a candidate for the study.
Breaking research protocol could
damage the hospital's funding.
So you, uh, you agree with them?
Yeah, I‐I see their point.
Doug, don't walk away.
Doug!
Hey, Jerry,
have you seen Doug?
Yeah, he dropped off
some charts.
Said he was going
up top for coffee.
‐ Up top?
‐ As in keep your coat on.
I missed you this morning.
I tried not to wake you.
Figured at least
one of us should get
more than four hours of sleep.
I love you.
You know that?
Yes, I do.
Doug, what's going on?
You alright?
Well, I'm not thinking
about jumping
if that's what you're afraid of.
Well, that's good, 'cause
I'm attached to you
so you'd have to
take me with you.
It's just...all this,
just about helping a kid.
All what?
You and me getting into it.
Hey, that's over and done.
It's not over and done
for Mark and Kerry.
Now, you don't know that.
They both already said
they don't want to make
a big deal out of this.
They have to do something.
Why?
To prove that
they never wanted
a pediatric attending
in the first place.
Doug.
‐ Alright. But that's not fair.
‐ No.
Hey..
...you put the patient first.
And that's what we're
supposed to do, isn't it?
Huh?
You're good to me,
you know that?
Yeah, I know that.
Largely, it's been innuendo.
The slightly
inappropriate phrase
at the slightly
inappropriate moment.
'I'm not sure you'd even
consider it sexual harassment.'
Well, if you could
give me some specifics.
Oh, one of the more ridiculous
ones was when he spoke of
'sniffing my tailpipe.'
Excuse me?
Oh, I had just parked
and, uh, he said words
to the effect that
had he known it was my car he
would have sniffed my tailpipe.
And I asked him what
he was talking about.
He said something like, uh,
"Oh, I thought we were"
"talking about sex."
‐ But you weren't.
‐ No, of course not.
I was coming in to do
a gastroplasty.
Did Dr. Romano
ever give you any reason
'for terminating
your fellowship?'
Um, I was led to believe that
he didn't have
to give me a reason.
But he didn't
sponsor anyone else
and the funding didn't go away.
Nope.
So why do you think he did it?
Well, I suppose he could
have been punishing me.
Um...we went out
to lunch once.
Uh...he laid his
heart on his sleeve.
He told me he found me
very attractive
and, uh, asked if we might
go out together on a date.
Mm‐hmm, and how long after that
did the fellowship end?
A matter of weeks. Um..
But we don't know for certain
if the two are related, do we?
Well, that will be
for others to decide.
What others?
If a full investigation
goes forward.
And how will that be determined?
Dr. Weaver, Dr. Corday.
'I just ordered up the
high‐cholesterol breakfast.'
Three eggs, pigs in a blanket
and biscuits and gravy.
May I join you?
Unfortunately,
we just finished.
Yep. Drains to pull,
that sort of thing.
Well, then I guess I'll have
to administer CPR to myself.
‐ Doctors..
‐ Yep.
I've been sitting
for three days.
I would rather walk
if you don't mind.
Well, I'd rather you sit, ma'am.
We're going right in here.
Carol, I got us a customer.
SOB, with a cough.
Who are you calling,
"a son of a bitch?"
No, ma'am I just mean,
"shortness of breath."
Okay, let's get you
seated on the gurney
and take off this coat.
No, no. It's cold in here.
Oh, we'll promise to give you
the coat back when you leave.
‐ Just give me some medicine.
‐ You need to help us out.
Oh, Sparky.
Get back up here.
You're not allowed
animals in here.
Give me cough medicine
and I'll get out of your way.
Uh, tell you what.
Um, why don't you let Malik
take care of Sparky
while I quickly
examine you, okay?
‐ Are you a dog person?
‐ Yeah. Sure.
'Okay. Any fever?'
‐ Hey, Sparky.
‐ No.
Coughing up any yellow
or green sputum?
No.
Alright, this might
be a little cold.
Okay.
I hear a few crackles.
'I'd like to get a chest X‐ray.'
'Make sure you don't
have pneumonia.'
'Alice, you're a smoker?'
Yeah. Breaks up the boredom
out there on the road.
I just drove straight
from Albuquerque.
Why?
I don't know.
If I'd known it was
this cold in Chicago
I would have gone
straight to Miami.
'How much is this
x‐ray going to cost?'
I don't have the insurance.
I don't have the money.
Alice, we're a county hospital.
If you can't pay,
it's subsidized.
You have any family in Chicago
you'd like us to call for you?
I don't know a soul in Chicago.
Okay, uh, you stay right here,
keep an eye on Sparky
and Malik and I'll
be right back.
‐ I'll order a portable X‐ray.
‐ Good idea.
I don't think radiology's gonna
want to deal with Sparky.
Carol, medical records just sent
these charts up for review.
Yeah, we sent them last week.
Then why'd they come back?
It's like they said,
for review by the interim chief.
‐ Uh.
‐ That's you again, right?
Thank you for straightening
that out, Malik.
Ugh!
Richard Tuggle, 35.
Complains of 20 minutes of
heavy, substernal chest pain
'with nausea and diaphoresis.'
‐ I felt okay this morning.
‐ Coming through!
I'm sorry. I'll come back later.
It's no problem.
Okay, let's go.
'Here we go.'
BP's 140 over 88, pulse 90.
Chest pain was relieved
by two sprays of nitro.
That's all she wrote.
CBC, chem 20, cardiac enzymes.
Here, help him out of that.
And...12 lead.
Have you had pain
like this before?
Never.
‐ Any history of heart disease?
‐ No.
Okay, high blood pressure?
Diabetes?
No. I'm really healthy.
Kerry, when you're free,
Doug's waiting in the lounge.
Okay, I'll be there in a minute.
Pulse ox is 99 on two liters.
You weren't out
shoveling snow, were you?
No, I work at home.
I'm a telemarketer.
So what is it?
I have a heart attack?
Well, you're a little
young for that.
We'll do some blood work and
monitor your heart for a while.
Don't worry,
we'll figure it out.
‐ I hear an ejection murmur.
‐ Hmm. I hope not.
Carter?
What are you doing?
Ah, Dr. Anspaugh. Meet, uh,
Dudzik, Hiltzik and Strauss.
Second years.
Patient‐doctor class.
Need something?
Well, I was hoping you could
give me some time, but, uh..
...never mind.
Where's your student,
Ms. Knight?
Surgery rotation.
Right. Never mind.
Sure you don't want
a cup of coffee?
No, I'm not having
any trouble staying awake.
Okay.
So what's the verdict?
No big verdict.
We agreed that we're
going to keep this quiet
so that we don't jeopardize
hospital funding.
But Mark and I
want some assurance
that this won't happen again.
So anytime you want to prescribe
schedule two narcotics,
morphine, Demerol, Dilaudid
Fentanyl, Methadone, we want
to co‐sign the order.
‐ That's it?
‐ That's it.
Well, if it'll settle things
down, I'll agree to do it.
You know, whether you
believe me or not
I don't have some compulsion
for breaking the rules.
Sometimes they get in the way
of helping a patient, but..
...if you'd seen how much pain
this kid was in, I think
you would've done
the same thing.
Doug, we have seen
that kind of pain.
Dr. Ross, Carol needs
you in curtain three.
Thanks, Jerry.
His contractions
have been so severe.
Worse than anything
I saw with Michael.
And his seizures
have increased.
‐ Joi, come sit.
‐ Dr. Julian wants to admit him.
But I just can't do that.
‐ Roger Julian?
‐ He's a doctor up in genetics.
Yeah, I know him.
Joi spoke to him this morning.
Michael, my oldest, was in
the ICU his whole last week
hooked up to all those tubes.
I know Ricky doesn't
have much time
but I just can't
do that to him.
Can we keep Ricky here?
No, please. I just want
to take him home.
Okay. I'm going
to talk to Roger
but I think we should arrange
for something called a PCA.
Which is
"Patient Controlled Analgesia."
We would hook
Ricky up to an IV
that would deliver pain
medication to him at home.
Now, obviously, you're gonna
have to control it.
W‐will it be stronger medicine
than what you gave him before?
Dilaudid or Fentanyl.
Okay, I'll do whatever
it takes, Dr. Ross
just so I can keep him at home.
I know he..
...probably won't know the
difference, but you know..
'It's okay.'
We'll let you know as soon
as we can set it up, okay?
Okay?
Alright. I'll go find Roger.
You set up an IV.
‐ Alright?
‐ Yep.
Getting near the end.
If the survival rate is the same
then why not do the lumpectomy
and save the breast?
Well, because with a modified
radical mastectomy
you can save the patient.
Although a lumpectomy can
get around the tumor.
And then you'd do
radiation therapy, right?
Yeah. And there can
be severe side effects.
Yeah, well that can't be with,
uh, with removing a breast.
Hey, look, I'm not discounting
the psychological impact here.
Actually, I think
you are, just a bit.
You'll discover
most male surgeons
find it relatively easy
to just lop off a breast.
Elizabeth, come on,
that's cliche. Don't you think?
Yeah, because it's true.
It's a really personal decision
this woman has to make.
She's going to worry about her
sexuality, her self‐image.
Listen, a patient
comes in here with cancer
I say, we cut it out.
See, even there, you
think of her in terms
of being a patient, not
in terms of her being a woman.
You know what? Uh, it's‐it's,
it's not that complicated.
But you don't want it
to be that complicated.
Just cut to the chase,
so to speak.
Well, isn't this a scrub fest?
Hey, Peter, you mind if
I borrow your intern?
'I got stuck doing an appy.'
No. Not at all,
I've only got a biopsy.
‐ Lucy, you're with me.
‐ Thanks. Appreciate it.
You really need my assistance
on an appendectomy?
Course not, but I'd
love the company.
‐ So, how was breakfast?
‐ It was coffee, actually.
Women never seem to eat
breakfast anymore, do they?
Now it's just coffee or
sometimes maybe a muffin.
Why is that? They're
worried about their weight?
Or they're worried that
they'll get a reputation
for eating like a horse or..?
I really couldn't say.
Can you say what
people are talking about
with Kerry Weaver
over their coffee?
You can stop
playing games, Robert.
I know what's going on.
I know someone's accused you.
Hmm, falsely.
But if someone like Kerry Weaver
starts rooting around
and decides she's determined
to dig up something, you know..
‐ That's how people get hurt.
‐ Yep. That's true.
I mean, for instance, uh...
what if, uh, it came out
that, uh... you were sleeping
with Peter Benton
while you were his intern
and he was your supervisor
in a position to evaluate you.
Which, I'm sure you're aware,
is a very big "no‐no."
Come on.
Peter and I were together
before I was his intern.
Yeah. And you made Anspaugh
aware of that, right?
'Because that's
grounds for dismissal.'
I mean not for you, of course,
but for Peter, Dr. Benton.
Which would be a real shame
considering how much work
he's put into, uh,
getting where he is.
You wouldn't dare.
I wouldn't like myself very much
if I did that, would I?
Anyway, it's not really
in my hands, is it?
Yeah, films are back on Alice
Presley and she's antsy to go.
I told her I'd round up
some meat loaf for Sparky.
Thanks, Malik.
Hey, Steve.
Nurse Hathaway,
always a pleasure.
I've kept these up
so you can see for yourself.
And as you can see
for yourself
there is no evidence
of pneumonia.
There is perhaps
a slight increase
in bronchovascular markings.
Which could be smoking‐induced.
Although it's more likely
she simply has the flu.
Not unlike half the techs
in our department.
In other words,
what we have here
is essentially
normal chest film.
I'd like a VQ scan.
What makes
you think she has a PE?
Well, she's a smoker,
she's hypoxic.
She's been
driving for 18 hours
putting her at risk for
blood clots in her legs.
‐ What's her heart rate?
‐ Eighty five.
‐ Respiratory rate?
‐ Twenty.
‐ Any calf tenderness?
‐ Not really.
Well, nothing you've said so far
suggests pulmonary embolus.
She has pleuritic chest pain.
So does everyone
with bronchitis.
Look, I know there
isn't hard evidence.
It's just a feeling I have.
Well, unfortunately,
I cannot authorize an $800 test
based on your intuition.
Your patient has a cough.
And no insurance, I might add.
So that's what this
is about. Payment?
No, although the hospital
does like to cover its expenses.
I'll pay for it.
Your checkbook is my command.
Thanks, Steve.
One VQ scan...coming up.
Carol, we got a couple
more hackers for you.
I'm going to go ahead and stick
them into exam two.
Oh, no, no, no.
I‐it's not ready yet.
Yes, it is.
Your patient just left.
‐ Alice Presley?
‐ Is she a little nuts?
She was saying about about
going to walk her Sparky.
Oh, God.
So I promised Anspaugh
I'd review charts for him.
Am I a sucker or what?
Hey you know, you don't have
to agree with me.
‐ I do.
‐ You okay?
Yes. It's slippery.
But I'm fine.
Good luck, Mark.
How's he doing?
Oh, pain free,
normal sinus, no ectopy.
Which is all good, right?
Yes, but I got some
of your blood work back
and I'm concerned because
your cholesterol is 465.
‐ That doesn't sound good.
‐ It's not.
Do you have a family history
of high cholesterol?
Did your father or
any male relative
have, uh, heart
trouble in their thirties?
I don't know.
Because there are inherited
conditions which run in families
and can cause high lipid levels.
So you might want to check
because they can put you
at risk for a heart attack
at an early age.
No, I can't check.
I was adopted.
'I don't have a clue
about any medical history.'
I'd like to admit you then
so we can start you on
a cholesterol‐lowering agent
then do a complete workup.
Alice, wait. Wait!
You need to stay
for one more test.
I really can't. Miami calls.
You don't want to get stuck on
the road and be sick, Alice.
You don't understand. I can't
leave the pups out in the cold.
It's okay. You can bring Sparky
back in. I won't tell anyone.
No, you really
don't understand.
It's not just Sparky.
I didn't start out
to collect them or anything.
It just kind of...happened.
Come on, Jules. We did
our residencies together.
Doug, the old school tie
is not going to work.
‐ I hated my residency.
‐ There you go. So did I.
Listen, I know Ricky can't
control his analgesic
but the mother
says she's willing to do it.
Look, up in genetics, we prefer
to admit these end‐stage kids.
We don't have a lot of
experience with home care.
You do it with
cancer kids all the time.
They send them home.
They send them to hospices.
Well, maybe oncology
can help you out.
I don't have time to wade
through that department.
This kid's in bad shape.
He needs it.
‐ Doug, look‐‐
‐ Jules, come on.
Look, I'll talk to the rest
of the team about it, okay?
We meet...day after tomorrow.
I can let you know then.
Ricky doesn't have till
the day after tomorrow.
I'm sorry.
Ouch. You're poking too hard.
Strauss, stop
your whining.
These are
the anterior chains
and these are
the...posterior.
As you examine,
ask yourself
"Do the nodes feel
like BB's
like peas
or sour balls?"
‐ I got two BB's.
‐ I got one BB, one sour ball.
Dudzik, quit goofing.
I don't know, it still
doesn't feel like a BB.
It's not a pea.
Ah, it can be tough
to estimate the size at first.
BB and a pea, right?
Hmm.
Do you have any,
uh...any night sweats?
Any weight loss?
Geez, what is this?
Have you?
No. I feel fine.
Noticed any enlarged
nodes anywhere else?
Oh, wait a minute.
You're kidding, right?
No. Nothing.
I'm sure it's nothing
to worry about.
We might get another doctor
to take a look, though.
Maybe do a biopsy.
A biopsy?
Hi. Listen, I'm Mark Greene.
I'm sorry, I‐I don't
know your name.
Mobalage.
Mobalage Ekabo.
Listen, you've obviously
done something to your back.
Why don't you
let me take a look?
No. Uh..
It's been like this
for a long time.
I'm alright.
No, it might be a slipped disk.
Let me take a look.
Come on.
‐ This won't take long.
‐ Yeah?
Sit down right here.
So, did you just
start here recently?
It's been several months.
Really?
Haven't seen you around much.
I worked on other floors.
Well, we're glad
to have you down here.
Thank you.
Just closing the curtain
for a little privacy.
Okay.
You can go ahead
and take your shirt off now.
No, please.
'Stop, please.'
No.
Stop it, please. No.
'Stop!'
I'm not doing anything.
Stop it now!
Stop it! Stop it!
‐ It's okay.
‐ Stop it!
Stop it! Alright?
Malik, you need
some help?
No, I'm cool.
I'm just going in here.
Hey, how'd you do?
It's all good, as long as
they like cheese sliders.
Sure we ain't
breaking the rules?
'No, Malik, sneaking
dogs in through windows'
and feeding them cheeseburgers
isn't breaking the rules‐‐
Did you say
cheeseburgers?
That's their favorite.
Hey, shut the door.
Shut the door. Please don't ask.
Alright. I need to talk to you
just for a second outside.
Uh...yeah.
Malik, you okay in here?
Oh, he's doing great.
The pups love him.
Alright. I'll be right back.
Shh!
Oh, oh, and after they eat
that's usually when
they need to go outside.
Make a little poop.
So, Genetics
bailed on us.
I'm not gonna be able to get
a PCA for a couple of days.
Well, maybe I can arrange
it through the clinic, you know.
I'll call one of the home health
care agencies I've worked with.
Ah, it's worth a try.
Jerry, did you find out
about that guy Mobalage?
No. Ah, Housekeeping
hasn't called back yet.
Yeah, I heard about that.
What happened?
He just flipped out.
I hadn't even started
the exam.
Oh, you know, ah, Rachel called
and said she's going
with the purple frames,
whatever that means.
Ah, poor Rachel.
She just found out
that she needs glasses.
She couldn't see
the blackboard at school.
Oh, yeah, I hated
when that happened.
I felt like such
an eight‐year‐old geek.
Mmm, happened to me at nine.
Same age as Rachel.
Fiercely
bad eyesight
on my side
of the family.
Well, you must have
had fiercely red hair
on your side
of the family.
Yeah.
And I hope that's
the worst thing
that I pass on
from my gene pool.
Whatever, yeah, I mean
it's not like
she's gonna go bald.
Jerry, weren't you gonna check
those labs for Mrs. Volpe?
Yes, I was. I am.
You owe her, Jerry.
Where'd you say Carter is?
Suture.
ER.
Malik, where are you?
Yeah. Okay. I'll be there
to help you in a few minutes.
I got it...on my second call.
One of the agencies
I used with PCA
on a cancer patient
a few months ago.
And Joi's health
insurance will cover it.
Did you tell her about it?
No. I think you'd better
explain it to her.
Joi, it looks like
we're going to be able
to provide that pain medication
we talked about.
Now? Today?
Well, a home
health care agency
will deliver the machine
to your house.
M‐machine will be set
to deliver
a specific amount
of, ah, Dilaudid every hour.
When do I push
the button?
Whenever you feel
like he's in pain.
How do I know
how much to give?
You don't have
to worry about that.
There's only one booster dose
within a two‐hour period
and then, ah, the machine will
automatically lock out
any additional dose.
Dr. Ross is gonna write
you a prescription
and then I'm gonna arrange
for the Medi‐Van
to take you and Ricky home.
Thank you.
Thank you both so much.
Just wish we could do more.
Oh, it started
snowing again.
Yeah, about
an hour ago.
Listen, Kerry, uh,
I've been thinking
and, um, I don't feel
comfortable with what I told
you this morning.
Well, none of us are really
at ease with the situation.
No, no, what I mean to say
is, ah, I don't feel
there was any
harassment involved.
Well, that's not our
decision to make.
When the full committee
hears the testimony‐‐
I don't believe
I'll be testifying.
I mean, if I'm not
convinced myself
and then I don't feel
I should put it forth
into an official record.
Elizabeth, did
something happen today?
No. No, I just don't think
there's any relevance
to the incidents
I mentioned.
And, that being the case,
I think it's only
right and proper that
I should withdraw my statement.
Look, I'm really sorry.
Sorry that I wasted your time.
Um, I hope you understand.
Ready to go in here?
Yep. Labs are all okay.
Upon physical exam,
no significant findings
in the head or neck,
other than the enlarged
jugulodigastric node
in the right submaxillary area.
Okay. You wanna do
the honors, Carter?
You know, I've actually
never done a neck biopsy.
Okay. Well, here's your chance.
You ready there, Mr. Strauss?
Yeah. Okay.
So, this VQ thing
was positive?
Yes, which means
that small blood clots
have traveled
from your legs.
And if this condition
isn't treated
a larger blood clot
could lodge in your lung.
Yeah, well, that does sound bad.
I'm gonna have to get
myself back here real soon‐‐
No, no. Alice, you need
to be admitted today.
And you need to stay
for four or five days
so that your blood can
be properly anticoagulated‐‐
No. My dogs. I can't leave
them on the cold‐‐
I know and I don't know
what we're gonna do
but I promise you,
we're gonna think of something.
Okay?
Oh, Jerry!
Damn it, Jerry!
Go! Go!
'Go get them, Jerry! Get them!'
Uh, Oh, God.
Hey, Mark, Ricky Abbott,
the kid with‐with ALD.
He's back.
He's in pretty bad shape.
I arranged for his mother
to have a home PCA Machine.
I need you to sign off
on the Dilaudid.
He's a genetics
patient, right?
That's right,
but he's down here right now.
Yeah, I can't sign off on that.
'He's not on our service.'
I just thought
it would be easier.
Yeah, maybe, but, uh,
that's their deal.
You've to go up to genetics
and have them sign off on it.
Yeah, you're right.
Probably should have thought
of that in the first place, huh?
‐ Hey.
You have
a break out?
Yeah, something like that.
Okay, you're on, all set.
Okay, thanks.
I'll give it to her as soon as
I get rid of this little guy.
Alright.
‐ Jerry‐‐
‐ Sorry, Dr. Greene.
Hi.
I was looking
for you.
Hi.
I am very sorry, um..
I can pay for the curtain.
I don't care
about the curtain.
I was wondering
if you were okay.
Yeah, I won't cause
any trouble
and, uh, I'd like
to keep my job.
You didn't cause
any trouble
and no one is going
to take your job.
Thank you very much.
I do think that you probably
have a pain in your back
and I'd like to help
you, if I can.
I think my back is fine. Um..
But there is something.
I'm hoping
you can give it to me.
What's that?
I believe it's called Viagra.
It's a medication
used for impotence.
I am impotent.
‐ Kerry.
‐ Robert, may I sit down?
Ah, certainly.
I'd offer you
something to drink
but we, ah, don't have anything
in the coffee machine‐‐
Did you speak with
Elizabeth Corday today?
She assisted me on an appy.
Is that when you spoke to her
about Maggie Doyle's sexual
harassment inquiry?
Why would I do that?
Maybe to stop it
from going forward.
I am eager
for it to go ahead.
I'm looking forward
to being vindicated.
Oh, well, then you're gonna
be disappointed.
Because the investigation's
been closed.
Really? Hmm.
Well, I guess we'll
all have to go back
to our humdrum lives
then, won't we?
Of course, all the testimony
has been typed up.
I've got it in a file.
Mm‐hmm.
And‐and the thing
that really sticks out
is that bad evaluation
you gave Dr. Doyle.
She's received
such positive remarks
on her other rotations.
Hmm, so, you're thinking that
perhaps I was a little bit hasty
and that if I, um, spend
a little more time on it..
Yes, I'm thinking
that if you took
that time right now
you might write
something very different.
Uh‐huh. Which you'd certainly
be interested in reading.
Oh, absolutely.
I imagine I'd want
to put it in that file.
So, Mobalage,
where are you from?
Nigeria.
Ah.
That's a ways
away from here.
How do you
like Chicago?
Okay.
My wife does not like the cold.
She works here
in your cafeteria.
Oh, that must be nice.
Both of you..
Watch my finger..
Return to the same place
for work.
Mm‐hmm.
Okay.
I need to, uh..
pull the gown
down now.
Alright?
Yeah, the, uh, burns seem
to be well‐healed.
Yes. They're not a problem.
Had 'em for a while?
Want to tell me
how it happened?
No.
I need to examine
below the waist now.
I understand.
‐ You're in early.
‐ I have no life.
Dr. Weaver,
Sam Broder called back.
Said he would meet you
at Doc Magoo's at 8:00.
‐ Thanks, Jerry.
‐ That sounds like a life.
Hot date?
At Doc Magoo's?
Even Dr. Weaver
has her standards.
Thank you, Jerry,
I think.
Dr. Greene,
path report's back
on that med
student, Strauss.
Well, let him know.
Sent that kid
up to the OR.
‐ Hey, you have a minute?
‐ Yeah.
I wanted to fill you
in on something.
Let's go in the lounge.
Sure.
I need to talk to you
about the pathology report.
You guys mind
hanging outside?
No, they could stay.
I already know it's crappy news.
The biopsy shows
Hodgkin's disease.
Which is a form of lymphoma.
Oh, man.
You need
to understand, though
that it's very treatable
with radiation therapy.
Your chances of surviving
are extremely high.
Look, can I just, um..
...can I just have
a few minutes here, please?
Yeah. I'll check back.
Now, I've contacted
a pet rescue group
that can take all
of the dogs tomorrow
but I need each of you
to take two of them home
with you tonight.
Uh, I can't do that, Carol.
I‐I have cats.
You have cats?
Yeah, what's wrong with cats?
‐ Sorry, Carol.
‐ Alright.
Well, I'm a dog person.
I'll take two
and one of Jerry's.
I want the little one.
No, no, no, no, no.
Sparky is my man.
Hey, Sparky.
I'll take, uh,
two of the big ones.
Al's sick of the little dogs.
‐ What's up with that?
‐ I'll take this Airedale.
‐ If no one wants him.
‐ Okay, great.
Carol, Joi Abbott's
on the phone for you.
Okay. Uh, listen, work it out
amongst yourselves.
And, uh, just give me two.
Any two, I don't care.
Just tie their leashes
to my locker.
‐ There you go.
‐ Hey, hey, Spark.
Oh, he's so cute.
Hi, Joi. It's Carol Hathaway.
Wait, wait. Joi, what's wrong?
Well, well, did they
hook it up?
Can you, can you tell
if it's working properly?
Oh, Joi, Joi.
You‐you need
to calm down
and just take
your time, alright?
Just take your time.
Initial lab tests
don't reveal
anything like diabetes
which may be related
to erectile dysfunction.
I understand.
You're not on
any medications
that have that
side effect.
No.
And if it was
psychological
you could still have
a spontaneous
early morning
or mid‐sleep erection.
No, I do not.
I think it's caused
by trauma.
If you were
in an accident
or maybe even, uh, beaten..
If your pelvis
had been broken
internal bleeding
could have
compressed the arteries
and veins
affecting the
blood supply
to and from
the penis.
And, uh..
...if that is the case?
A urologist would
probably wanna do
a vascular
bypass operation
to try to restore
normal function.
I think you should
see a urologist.
Okay.
Where's Dr. Romano?
Last seen
in the lounge.
‐ Was it you?
‐ Sorry?
There are only
a couple of names
I gave Dr. Weaver.
One didn't have
anything concrete
and the other seems
to have backed out.
'Was that you,
Elizabeth?'
'Did you decide to‐to
protect your own place'
'in the food chain?'
Stay in the club?
Yes, I did.
'I'm sorry, Maggie.'
You're sorry, my ass.
PCA Machine
isn't working
then they hooked
it up wrong.
No, it's hooked up right.
She just, she doesn't know
whether to give him
a booster shot or not.
If she thinks
Ricky needs it..
But she can't tell.
Well, if she is in doubt
she should just go ahead
and give it to him.
I mean, I'm afraid it's not
gonna matter that much.
I don't think he's gonna make
it through the night.
I told her we'd
go over there.
Like, why? I..
She knows how
to work the machine.
What‐what are we
gonna do?
She's all alone, Doug.
She's really scared.
I understand, it's just,
I don't know what good
it'll do for us to be there
watching her son die.
I know.
I mean, I‐I don't know.
Probably won't do
any good. I just..
I really wanna be there.
Okay.
I'll probably be
home pretty late.
Mobalage, they told me
you were here.
I didn't know
what was wrong.
Kubby, this is Dr. Greene.
Dr. Greene,
this is my wife, Kubby.
‐ Nice to meet you.
‐ How do you do?
I strained my back
and, uh, Dr. Greene
was kind enough
to take a look at it
and, uh give me some
pain medication.
Yeah, it's gonna
probably be better
in a couple of days.
Thank you.
Sometimes he tries to do
too much at his job.
He works too hard.
Yes, I know.
I'll be fine.
Thank you again, Dr. Greene.
You're welcome.
Uh, you're the only man
sitting alone
so I'm hoping you're
Sam Broder, right?
Dr. Weaver,
nice to meet you.
Call me Kerry.
My office tells me
that you've made
three or four
appointments before
and always canceled them
at the last minute.
You'd think
I was the dentist.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
It's alright,
it's pretty common.
Making the decision to track
down your birth parents
is not something
you should do lightly.
I've done that whole
internet thing.
Yeah, most people
start there
but I do this
for a living.
My company handled
several hundred
adoption cases last year.
Sounds like a good living.
'I'm gonna need
your full name'
'date of birth,
place of birth'
'and the names of your
adoptive parents.'
I'm glad you
could step in
on such short
notice, Robert.
I'm always happy to get
a 16‐year‐old up and running.
Get him back out there, kissing
the girls making 'em cry.
So, uh, how's this interim
chief thing working out?
‐ Oh, miserably.
‐ Hmm.
Between my surgical duties
and all the administrative
crap down there..
Yeah, it's a shame
Kerry Weaver
wasn't able to continue.
And on top of surgery,
you're chief of staff..
Oh, I tackle that part
of my job around midnight.
Alright, hey, didn't it
work out fairly well
when David Morgenstern
was handling surgery and ER?
Yeah, he did seem
to have it down.
Well, then, Donald,
I feel I'd be remiss
if I didn't offer
up my services.
To be interim chief
of the ER?
No, I think "acting chief"
has a bit more
je ne sais quoi, don't you?
I don't care if you call
yourself almighty God
if you're willing
to take that on.
Although, we'd still be
conducting a search.
Yeah, well, hey,
long as you need me.
Huh, I needed you today.
Uh, how's tomorrow sound?
Like a stroke of luck.
Sorry, it's only instant.
There was a day
I used to grind the beans.
Don't worry about it.
Anything is fine.
Stay here. I'll get it.
Hi.