Dr. Marcel,
you saved Nathaniel's life
in spectacular fashion.
Got 30 million social media
followers waiting to hear how
this story ends.
Get ready for what comes next.
What's that?
Fame.
What the hell is going on?
Will and Vanessa bought
meds off a drug dealer.
It's a little more
complicated than that.
You want to risk your own
career, that's fine.
Don't risk Vanessa's.
April?
Are you back in Chicago?
Yeah.
You didn't get married
or anything, did you?
No.
Well,
I'll see you around.
Did you really ask Jack
to dislocate your shoulder?
Didn't have much
of a choice, really.
I couldn't believe it.
Didn't even hesitate.
Well, my arm was trapped
at the time.
I felt it was the best way
to continue treating
Mr. Perry.
Well, no wonder people
are calling you a hero.
But is that how you would
characterize yourself?
Did you know that
he jerry-rigged
a lung transplant
just days after
the incident? Yes.
Confident, creative,
future of medicine, this guy.
It was a team effort.
Look, I'm sure you'd rather
talk to Mr. Dayton here.
And my shift is
starting soon, so...
Dr. Marcel exemplifies
the kind of
selfless dedication
we here at Gaffney
pride ourselves on,
and it's what has attracted
a new crop of generous
donations to this institution.
Dr. Marcel's heroics
that day saved way more
than just one life.
That's very generous.
Thank you.
And we're cut.
Hey.
Yeah?
So I got you lined up
for a few phoners
later in the day.
Uh-huh.
And then we got Today Show
end of the week, okay?
Friday, we're gonna
try to do that.
Morning, Mags.
How's it going?
It's going.
I have a twisted ankle
for you in 5.
Be there in a minute.
You're still mad at him?
CPD and the hospital
cleared us both. They're
letting it go. Why can't you?
Because you brought drugs
into the hospital, Vanessa.
It was irresponsible.
It was dangerous.
We were out of options,
and it saved our patient.
I expect that kind of
foolishness from Will,
but he should have
known better than
to drag you down with him.
No, no.
Will didn't drag me
into anything.
It was my call.
You don't have to defend him.
I get it,
the Halstead School
of Medicine has its appeal,
but it's not who you are.
What is that
supposed to mean?
It means you're not reckless.
You're smarter than that.
And you don't have to be
a cowboy to be a good doctor.
Hey, Dean.
How you doing?
Well, I thought
a patient's bowel
was nicked
during surgery, but it was
just a flatulent intern,
so I'm excellent.
Great, but I meant
how are your injuries?
You're looking a little stiff.
I've had worse.
Than being brutally
attacked by a patient on
PCP-laced cocaine?
I need to hear
your life story.
Another time.
I seem to remember
being in considerable pain
when you patched me up.
So if I do need anything,
I'll be looking elsewhere.
Well, lucky me,
seeing as doctors,
especially surgeons
with God complexes,
make the worst patients.
Help! Someone, please!
Please, I need help!
Okay, what happened?
Please, take him!
Tell me what's wrong.
It's me. I'm what's wrong.
I'm gonna hurt him.
I'll be right back.
Her son, Edison, is in
Treatment 2. He shows no
signs of abuse or neglect.
He's an entirely
healthy newborn.
That's a relief.
Penelope, however,
is not in great shape.
She's dehydrated, anemic,
and is low in vitamin D.
It certainly doesn't look
like she's been taking
very good care of herself.
Well, that's not
unusual for a new mother,
but it could mean she doesn't
have much of a support system.
Yeah.
Listen,
I don't want to call DCFS,
but she did say that
she was gonna hurt her baby.
Are you guys comfortable
holding off for now?
Absolutely,
that's a drastic step
for something
that just might be postpartum
depression and treatable.
Yeah, we're not there yet,
but I should have
a little chat
with her, though.
Yeah.
Halstead! Incoming.
Going to Baghdad.
Says she doesn't want
any doc but you.
Okay.
Seventy-six-year-old female.
Tell the whole world,
madonna.
Maria. What happened?
Crush injury
to the right upper arm.
Lacerations above the elbow.
Denied pain meds on the ride.
I was just moving the stove.
What, Anthony
couldn't move it?
He's useless.
Okay, in we go.
On my count.
I can do it myself!
Please lie still, okay?
Okay. One, two, three.
I need an X-ray!
All this fussing,
Guglielmo. Basta.
All right, I'm sorry.
So you two know
each other?
Maria owns Marguerite's.
Taylor Street institution.
When my folks were alive,
we'd go there every Sunday
for dinner.
Not so much recently, huh?
You look skinny.
Diminished right radial pulse.
Any numbness, tingling?
Mmm-mmm.
Good. Let's get a CT angio.
X-ray up.
Hey, no fractures,
but those lacerations
still need to be repaired.
Let me get you
some pain meds.
So I go to sleep?
No, I have
a dinner service tonight.
Maria, I'm sorry,
but I doubt that's
gonna be possible.
We'll know more once
we get better imaging,
but I'm gonna call
a surgical consult.
Surgery? No, no, no.
If you think Antonio
can run Marguerite's...
Let's worry about that later.
You just relax.
Hey, I'm gonna
take care of you.
Hi, Caitlin. I'm Dr. Asher.
Hi.
Hey.
This is my husband, Steve.
How are you?
Hi, Steve. Okay. So Caitlin,
I saw that you're
nine weeks pregnant
and experiencing spotting?
Yes.
It just started a day ago,
but it hasn't
been super heavy.
Okay. Any pain or cramping?
Nope.
I read it could be normal
this early, right?
It doesn't necessarily
mean that something's
wrong?
That's true,
but it is wise to
get checked out.
So let's get
a type and screen,
a CBC, and a quantitative HCG.
It's taken us some time
for us to get pregnant,
so we're probably
a little more neurotic
than most first-time parents.
Okay, so Caitlin,
I'd like to do an ultrasound.
It'll have to be
transvaginal this early.
Yes. The joys
of being a woman.
Yes.
Okay, let's
get you set up.
Here we go.
A little bit of pressure.
Mmm-hmm.
Let's see.
What? What is it?
I'm very sorry,
but it's an ectopic pregnancy.
The embryo has implanted
in your fallopian tube.
What does that mean?
Won't it move
to the uterus?
No.
No, it's not even viable.
Unfortunately,
that's correct.
We need to remove the ectopic
before it can rupture the
fallopian tube,
which would be fatal
for Caitlin.
Okay, so, what...
What do I have to do?
Well, we have
two different options.
The first is a chemo drug
called methotrexate.
It stops the cells
from rapidly dividing
and ends the pregnancy.
The embryo ultimately
reabsorbs back in the body,
and it successfully
treats about 90%
of ectopic pregnancies.
And how do you get that?
It's an intramuscular shot,
typically in the buttock
or the thigh.
What are your other options?
We would operate to remove
the embryo and,
if necessary,
the entire fallopian tube.
The shot.
Please, no surgery.
We're hourly workers
at a bookstore.
We don't get sick days.
I understand.
We'll just have to do
some additional labs,
and then we'll go
from there, okay?
Try and get some rest.
Thank you.
Hey. Hey, hey,
hey, hey, hey, hey.
I'm sorry.
It'll be okay,
all right?
Look at me.
Penelope?
How's Edison?
Is he okay?
Oh, he's fine.
He's just next door.
Does he need breast milk?
I express him.
He's not always great
about waking up to eat,
even if it's been two hours.
You know what?
I'll tell the nurses.
I'm Dr. Charles.
Psychiatry.
Maybe I have
postpartum depression?
You know, I don't know.
Tell me what's been going on.
How you been feeling?
Um...
I'm not like myself.
Okay.
I cry so easily.
My moods are all over
the place, and...
And I have this ringing
in my ears,
but my OB says it's all part
of the recovery process.
Hmm.
But Edison was crying
so loudly, and I was...
I was so tired.
And it's not an excuse,
I know, but...
I thought about...
Uh...
God... I thought about
throwing him against the wall.
Okay. Well, it was just
a thought, though.
Right?
Mmm-hmm.
Has Edison's dad
been around to help out?
Turns out he wasn't
ready for a kid.
Well, gosh, I mean,
that's got to be so hard,
facing a life-changing
situation like this
all by yourself.
My mom came out
for the first week, but she
had to get back to Ohio.
How's it been
since she left?
Um...
Hard. My job doesn't have
paid maternity leave,
so I've been working
from home, you know,
juggling phone calls while
I breastfeed every two hours.
And there are no breaks
and there's no time to,
like, turn off.
And his cry,
like a screech, it...
It's just...
It's too much. I can't.
I know it's his only way
to communicate,
but it sets my teeth on edge,
and I feel like I'm losing it.
So I just...
I'm sorry.
Can you please
just tell me what...
You know what?
We're gonna get
to the bottom
of this, okay?
I promise you, we will.
Thank you.
No, no, I will make
that flight, and I'm fine.
My doctor just
walked in, okay?
It's good to
see you, Samir.
You too.
Mr. Baqri,
I'm Dr. Taylor.
Yeah. So sorry about that.
My work never stops.
And please,
call me Samir.
What seems to be
the problem?
Lethargy, myalgia.
It's hard to pin down.
You're a physician.
Oh, no.
I work with them.
Samir runs
the Hazma Community
Health Foundation,
sets up clinics
all around the world.
I get your fundraising emails.
Wow. Hopefully, not too many.
I haven't unsubscribed yet.
Okay, let's check
this out.
Open up.
You know, your polio
vaccination program
in Pakistan, incredible.
I was obsessed with
infectious disease
in med school, but they would
always talk about polio
in the past tense,
and I wanted to shout
at my professors that...
We were still
fighting it, right.
You know,
we almost had it beat,
but then the world
took its foot off the gas,
started reallocating funding,
and now it's back,
and well, you know,
we are struggling to get
buy-in from our partners.
It's just... I'm sorry. I will
step off of my soapbox now.
No, do not apologize.
You're doing something.
I wish I knew how to help.
It's the entire reason
that I got into medicine.
But instead, I just turn
off the news, and I eat
a sleeve of Oreos.
But you know what?
At least now
I can help the helper.
Right.
So how long have
you felt this way?
A couple of weeks.
I've been traveling
for work a lot recently...
Indonesia, Pakistan,
Sierra Leone.
I leave for the Philippines
on Friday. I'm opening
up a new clinic.
Well, the most exotic place
I've ever been is San Antonio,
and that was for a conference.
So no interest in travel?
No, I'd love to.
But between school
and residency, it's just...
Well, let me tell you,
it's not always
so glamorous.
I'm glued to my phone,
and I survive
off of peanut butter
protein bars and coffee.
Temp's normal.
Well, you know,
I'm not seeing any
obvious signs of infection,
but given
your travel history,
I just want to cast
a bit of a wide net
with your bloodwork,
if that's okay.
Yeah.
Anything that gets me
on a flight, I'm good.
CBC, CMP, bacterial
and viral cultures,
O&P, and a sputum.
On it.
I don't understand.
You said that most people
can do the drug option.
Unfortunately, your liver
function tests were
a little too elevated,
so you are not a candidate
for methotrexate.
Is there something you can do
so that I can get the shot?
I can't do a big surgery.
It'll put me out of work
for weeks.
If we were to fully open up
your abdomen, yes,
the healing time would
take a lot longer.
Fortunately,
this procedure
is laparoscopic,
minimally invasive,
meaning we could likely
send you home tonight
and have you back at work
in a day or two.
Okay. I guess I can do
a day or two.
Okay. I'll see you soon.
Thanks.
Thank you.
Hey. How'd it go?
A couple of red flags
for postpartum,
but I'm not convinced yet.
You know, she was talking
about this ringing
she had in her ears.
Well, tinnitus
could be caused
by multiple things.
It could be idiopathic,
medications,
hypo or hyperthyroidism.
You know, I can work
all of those up,
but what do you want
to do in the meantime?
Honestly, I want
to see her with her kid.
Wait, Dr. Charles.
You didn't see her
when she came in.
She was frantic.
And we can't be sure
how she'll react to him,
especially without
a definitive diagnosis.
Absolutely gonna make sure
the kid is safe, okay?
It's just that I can learn
so much from watching
them interact, right?
How are they bonding?
Any warning signs
of a lack of connection?
And if it is postpartum,
it sort of helps me
gauge the severity, you know?
While I understand
your concerns, Dr. Choi,
since Dr. Charles
will be there and Penelope
had the wherewithal
to ask for help before
anything happened,
I think we should proceed.
Also, I'd like
to be present.
All right.
Hey, thank you.
Hey, Archer!
Yeah?
Nursing said there's
no fiber optic cables
for the laparoscopic tower.
Where'd they all go
I've got to do
an urgent ectopic.
I know we're down two.
Supply chain issue
strike again.
Can't you just open?
No, it's explicitly
against my patient's
wishes.
She needs it to be
laparoscopic.
So both options are bad.
Either wait it out,
running the risk
it ruptures and kills her,
or turf it to
another hospital.
Or you can go old school
without video
and just look
straight down
into the scope.
No one's learned how to do it
that way since the Stone Age.
That's like performing
surgery with one hand tied
behind your back.
Yeah. I'm ancient
enough, all right?
It's how I was trained.
Well, this doesn't
do me any good.
Hi. Hey. So,
what's the good news?
We're not seeing any signs
of infection, though
you are slightly anemic.
Which would explain
your lethargy.
Excellent, so I guess
I can just take a couple
of iron supplements,
be on my way?
I'm actually not comfortable
discharging you quite yet.
You just said
I'm not infectious.
That's true,
as far as I can tell.
But without an explanation
for why you're deficient,
I'd just like to run
a couple more tests.
No, look, if I'm not sick,
I really got to get going.
I've got, like,
1,000 planning calls to make.
And not to mention,
I think there's people
who need this bed
more than I do, so I think...
Samir...
You all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I'm not...
Let's get back
on the bed.
I'm fine.
Both legs, please.
Dr. Taylor?
It's both legs.
Do you know how long
you've had this?
I don't know.
I thought it was a heat rash.
This is not from
the anemia, is it?
I don't know.
Look, don't BS me.
I know what bad news
looks like.
What is it?
These are petechiae,
a breakdown
of red blood cells.
It's usually associated
with a bleeding disorder.
But it could be any
number of things.
So what are we looking at?
I mean, is it an autoimmune
disease or leukemia? What?
We don't know until we do
further workup.
Um, Maggie, let's get
a lupus panel, an ANA,
and an X-ray.
On it.
Thank you.
Maria.
This is Dr. Marcel.
Apologies for the wait,
Ms. Piscotta.
You didn't tell me the
handsome doctor from
the news was coming.
I look a mess.
No, please.
Apparently,
I'm addressing royalty.
The doctor also tells me
you're the queen of pasta.
Only woman in America
who can make the threads
of God.
Oh!
It's all done by feel.
You have to have the touch.
Well, I look forward
to stopping by once
we get you patched up.
So your angiogram revealed an
injury to the brachial artery,
a pseudoaneurysm like
a balloon pushing out
from the vessel.
What does that mean?
Well, unfortunately,
you'll need
a surgical repair.
But it'll remove
the risk of rupture
while preserving healthy
blood flow to your arm.
Now, Maria, there are
non-surgical options
like stenting.
It's less invasive.
Let Dr. Handsome finish.
My opinion,
surgery would offer
the best long-term results.
I know it seems like a lot,
but it's standard procedure.
And if we did
the repair today,
we can send you home tomorrow.
And you will do the surgery?
I would.
If that's what you think
is best, andiamo.
Okay. I'll make the call.
You have a visitor.
There's my boy.
Sit.
Hi.
Oh, no, Eddie,
it's okay.
It's okay. Come on.
Don't cry.
It's okay.
Please, Eddie, please.
Okay.
You see what I mean
about this cry?
It's like a...
It's like a drill
in my head.
Okay.
Stop, baby.
Stop, baby. Please, stop.
Quiet, please.
Penelope, take a deep breath.
You got this.
You got this. You got this.
I'm sorry. Can you
please take him out?
I can't stand it.
I've got it. I've got it.
It's okay. It's okay.
Penelope?
What's happening?
Penelope? Penelope?
What's happening to me?
Okay.
Help me.
Okay, all right.
Look at me. Look at me.
We got you.
Look at me.
Look at me. Look at me.
Okay, can you smile?
Try to smile. Okay.
Trigger the stroke alert!
Little help in here!
We got you. We got you.
We got you.
What the...
Hey, where's Maria?
They just took her
to pre-op.
Look, I've been
thinking about it.
We should hold off
on surgery.
I want to pitch her
the stent one more time.
Come on, Will.
We both know that's not
a long-term solution.
No, but given her age and her
livelihood, we shouldn't be
so eager to flay her arm,
risk nerve injury,
put her through
extensive rehab.
No, no. Her hands
are her life. We cannot
take that from her.
All the more reason
to stick with
a vascular repair.
Deal with the pseudoaneurysm
with a stitch and keep
her off anti-platelets.
And besides,
she's already consented.
That's because
she saw you on TV.
She's star struck
being treated by the hotshot
doctor from the news.
Hey, you called me,
remember?
You don't think all that
influenced her decision?
I don't know, but maybe your
connection with the patient
is influencing yours.
Hey, Will?
I'm gonna take good
care of her, okay?
Thank you.
You got it.
Hey, Dr. Asher?
I think something
might be wrong.
Okay.
Hey, Caitlin.
Are you in pain?
It's... It's not super bad,
but, yeah, it hurts.
Yeah, heart rate's
in the low hundreds.
All right, I want to do
a quick ultrasound.
Do you mind?
Can you lift up, please?
Sure.
Here we go.
It's gonna be
a little cold.
All right.
There we go.
Okay, Caitlin,
your fallopian tube
is ruptured,
and there's blood
in your belly.
Oh, my God.
Is she gonna be okay?
Yes, but we need
to operate now.
And I need to open
your abdomen.
No, no, you said that
you could do it the other way.
I can't be out of work.
I understand, but we don't
have fiber optic cables.
But we do have a camera scope,
so we're still able to
operate laparoscopically,
just in a different way,
if you're good with that?
Um...
Yeah, okay.
Yes.
Can you open
the hybrid OR, please?
What do you think
you're doing?
You jump in like that
without consulting me?
I'm sorry, but we don't
have time for niceties.
You said yourself
it was emergent,
and this way,
we don't have to
open her up.
So now it's we?
This is my patient.
This is her wish.
Your way, she'd be in
for a lot more pain and
a much longer recovery.
Come on, you'll see.
We'll make a good team.
Come on.
Okay. Clamps are off.
Check the flow.
Triphasic flow is good.
Nice work.
You almost finished in there?
Yeah. Just about
to close.
Good, because
the lieutenant governor
is here with cholecystitis,
and she's requested
you perform the surgery.
Big time.
Oh, ush.
Okay, give me 30 minutes.
I'll be right there.
Come on.
It's the lieutenant
governor.
Dr. Tanaka-Reed can close.
You good?
Yes, sir. I got it.
Minimum two layers
plus skin, all right?
Mmm-hmm.
All right,
I'll be right there.
Penelope's MRI
and CT are clean.
Thank goodness,
that wasn't a stroke.
Yeah. No tumors,
either.
Taken all together,
her symptoms add up
to one thing.
Bell's palsy.
Tinnitus. Of course.
Edison's cries
must have been
excruciating.
Yeah, it's why
she's having
such a hard time
when Eddie was acting up.
And it's no wonder
she was at the end
of her rope.
On top of everything,
she was in pain
and told it was
completely normal.
How'd her OB miss this
when she complained
about her symptoms?
Well, unfortunately,
many women are failed
by postpartum care.
And in American medicine,
the mother is the wrapper,
the baby, the candy.
At least this case
has a happy ending.
We can treat
Penelope's symptoms
and reunite her
with her baby.
You know, I'd say this
is an important first step
in her mental recovery,
but I don't know.
We're not out
of the woods yet.
Samir's labs are in.
No signs of
autoimmune disease
or cancer.
Small victories.
But severe osteopenia?
He has the bones
of a man twice his age.
None of this
makes any sense.
What happened?
I don't know.
Where'd that laceration
come from?
Micro stitch?
No.
Grab me a heat cautery
and lidocaine 1%.
You got it.
It's okay.
Just slow breaths, okay?
In through your nose.
Out through your mouth.
Yes. Good job. Good job.
So what,
did you cut yourself?
No.
Any injuries that
you forgot to
tell me about?
No, no, nothing.
What is happening to me?
I don't know yet,
but we're gonna figure
this out, okay?
Just... Just focus on me.
Maggie, what does this
look like to you?
An appendectomy scar.
Yeah.
We're gonna
figure this out.
A bulge on
the left fallopian.
Let me see?
That's the
ectopic pregnancy.
Yeah, that was clear to me.
Okay, so grasp
the fallopian tubes.
Put them on tension,
and then take your
needlepoint cautery.
Thank you.
Will you help me, please?
You all right?
I'm fine.
Okay. Now, make a longitudinal
incision over the bulge.
What?
Step in.
Step in?
What are you talking about?
You're the only person here
who knows how to perform
surgery this way.
Well, you're about
to learn it now.
If you knew you were
in pain, you never
should have started this.
I'm just respecting
your patient's needs.
Now, stop it. Come on now.
Just take it. Go.
It's not gonna magically
appear on the monitor.
All right,
just put your eye
back on the scope.
Come on.
This would go faster
if I could just open.
You can do this, all right?
Use your assistant, me.
I will guide you.
I will help you.
Come on.
I can't get the angle.
All right, so come in
through the other side.
Just tell me where
the tube needs to be,
and I will hold it.
Okay, hold this.
I got it.
I'm going after the tube.
Give me the ligature.
All right. Got it?
There you go.
Okay.
Yeah.
Got it.
All right. Wrap this up.
How's Samir?
His wound looks good,
but he's understandably eager
to find out why
his scar opened up.
I have a hunch,
but I feel crazy
even saying it.
I want to run
one more test.
Okay.
So fortunately, with time and
steroids, your Bell's palsy
should fully resolve.
But what about
my terrible thoughts?
Well, you know,
there's actually
a name for those?
They're called
intrusive thoughts.
They're involuntary, violent,
often self-destructive.
You ever been standing,
say, on a balcony,
on a tall building,
and you look over the edge,
and you go "What would
happen if I jumped off?"
I mean,
you don't do it, but it's...
It's disturbing, right?
I have friends with kids,
and none of them
ever mentioned having
a thought like I did.
Well, I mean,
it's not exactly
the easiest thing to bring up.
And it's a problem because
that means that people just
don't talk about it.
Don't you understand that
a good mother, regardless
of Bell's palsy or anything,
would never think of
harming her own baby?
No, you sought help.
There's proof
you're a good mom.
No!
God, you have to understand.
I could see myself
throwing him.
This wasn't some fleeting,
vague idea.
I actually thought about
him hitting the wall.
It felt so horrifically real.
This is not gonna be
my last stressful week,
so I can never trust
myself with him.
Look, we get it, okay? We do.
We understand, and we're gonna
keep on working on this.
As a matter of fact,
Dr. Choi and I
are just gonna step outside
for a second, all right?
Hey, we'll be right back.
I get it. She's scared.
But separating her
from her baby?
They should be together.
I completely agree.
I mean, look, we can try
and normalize her fears
until we're blue
in the face,
but I think she needs
to hear about it from
a different kind of expert.
There aren't many reasons
a surgical scar can reopen,
especially an older one
like an appendectomy.
So on a hunch,
I ran one more
blood test.
So have you figured out
what's happening to me?
Hypovitaminosis C.
Better known as scurvy.
You've got to be joking.
Like old timey,
sailor scurvy?
People still get that?
It's rare,
but you mentioned
having a limited diet.
Peanut butter, protein bars,
coffee, they all
lack vitamin C.
And without that, your body
can't maintain the collagen,
the connective tissue,
it needs in order
to function.
Which would explain
your low bone density
and your petechiae.
But this is
all treatable, right?
I mean, what,
eat a couple slices
of oranges,
and I'll be fine?
Pretty much.
We're gonna set you up
on an infusion.
And then after that,
we'll get you on an oral,
high-dose multivitamin.
You should start feeling
better in about 48 hours.
You know, I have been
in some hairy situations
in my career,
but this scared
the crap out of me.
And you were so calm.
Like I said,
got to help the helpers.
Dr. Taylor?
Could I trouble you
for another moment?
Yeah, sure.
I'll get the pharmacy to start
working on your infusion.
Lieutenant governor
did great.
Surgery went perfectly.
Fantastic.
Yeah.
I'll let her chief
of staff know
he can release the statement.
Okay.
Hey, nice having Gaffney
and you name-dropped
by the people
in Springfield.
Well, that's cool.
Uh... Excuse me.
Yeah.
Where've you been?
What happened?
Arm's cold and dusky.
Doppler.
No blood flow
below the repair.
Must have thrombosed.
How?
This soon after surgery?
It's got to be
a technical error.
No way the repair went down.
It was in good shape
when you scrubbed out.
You left the OR before
the surgery was finished?
No. Repair was complete.
Clearly, it wasn't.
You should have been there.
She should have been
your priority.
We got to get her
back into the OR.
Kai, let's go. Come on.
Excuse me.
Let's go.
Easy, easy!
Penelope?
May I come in?
How's Edison?
Is he okay?
He's wonderful.
Has the nurses all wrapped
around his little fingers.
I could bring him in,
if you'd like.
You're worried
about your thoughts.
How could I not be?
No one seems to understand
how real it felt.
May I?
Look at that.
He's so cute.
And he's perfect.
You know that, right?
Do you have kids?
I do.
Two boys
and a girl, all grown.
Tara was about Edison's age.
She had the worst colic,
I mean,
screaming for hours.
Sleeping longer than an hour
felt like a vacation.
One morning about 3:00 a.m.,
I had been pacing the hallway,
trying to soothe her.
My baby was suffering,
and I couldn't fix it.
And I was bone tired.
I felt alone.
I felt like I was the only
person awake in the world.
And I just
was desperate for quiet.
And out of nowhere,
I had this thought
to just toss her out
of the second-floor window.
It really frightened me,
and I questioned whether
I could be a good parent.
And when I finally worked
up the courage
to mention it to a friend
who I thought was like
super mother...
I was stunned when she told me
she had had similar thoughts
with her babies.
And when I went to see
the pediatrician,
he reassured me
that it was normal.
All anyone ever
talks about is the joy
and the love and
the happiness, and...
I felt all that too.
But listen, have you ever
really listened to the
lyrics of a lullaby?
Singing about dropping cradles
from treetops
and feeding crying babies
to crabs and monsters?
But it's proof that parenthood
throughout time
and the world over is hard.
And it is also true
that it takes a village
to raise a child.
And there are mother groups
that have great resources
for making friends,
finding support,
asking questions.
I can connect you with one,
if you'd like.
I'd love that.
And here.
You listen to me, Penelope.
You did not have
an easy start...
But I have
no concerns about you.
You hear me?
Edison is a lucky, lucky boy.
Thanks.
Maybe you'd like to
see him after all?
Yes, please.
Okay.
Bring him in.
Hi, sweet boy.
Thank you.
Hi. Mama is here.
Mama's here.
It was something
we call a vasospasm,
random constriction
of the blood vessel,
totally unrelated
to the surgery.
That said, your repair
was in good shape.
This old bird still
got her wing.
She sure does.
But, uh, maybe
just take it easy
on the pasta roller
while you heal up, okay?
We need to get your picture
on our famosi wall.
Getting to eat your pasta's
reward enough.
Ah, Guglielmo.
Thank you for getting
Dr. Handsome to help me.
You bring him with you,
I'll make you two
squid ink pasta.
Wow. She swore
she'd only ever
make that for the Pope.
Oh!
You got it.
I'm gonna let you
get some rest.
Okay.
Thanks.
Hey, Will, look,
about the surgery, I...
It wasn't your fault.
I was out of line.
No, you had a point.
I got wrapped up
in all the attention.
Okay, that's true.
You're a good
surgeon, Crockett.
Just not sure you deserve
her squid ink pasta.
Touch.
So while the bleeding
necessitated our removal
of your fallopian tube,
this will not prevent you
from becoming pregnant
again and carrying
a healthy baby to term.
Thank you, Dr. Asher.
Thank you both.
Hannah and Dean,
good baby names.
We'll have to remember that.
Actually, I never liked Dean.
I think you can do better.
Oh, yeah?
Okay, we'll get you
a diet ordered,
and if you do okay,
we'll send you home tonight.
Thank you.
Sure.
Hey, I wanted
to say thank you.
I'm relieved we could
respect Caitlin's wishes,
and I'm lucky
I had your help.
Well, you did good
for a mere mortal.
Hey, Dean?
In the OR,
you were in pain.
Please. It's a... It's a...
It's a hard angle to hold
with ribs that are
still healing.
Yeah.
Don't kid a kidder.
Look, you don't want
my help, that's fine,
but you have to let
somebody check you out.
Hey, I'm fine, Dr. Asher.
Yeah.
Okay.
All right.
What's this?
Recommended
travel vaccinations.
I thought you could give me
a hand scheduling them.
I didn't know you
were going on vacation.
Samir offered me
a spot on his team.
He thought
I'd be a great fit.
In the Philippines?
I said yes.
Wait, wait. You can't
just up and leave.
What about your residency?
I'll talk to my
program director
and Ms. Goodwin.
I'll defer finishing for now,
but they'll understand.
But I don't.
Where's this coming from?
From me, Maggie.
Listen, you were upset,
and rightly so, when I bought
those drugs off the street.
But what I didn't say
to you earlier that I should
have is that I was...
I was actually inspired.
I mean, despite the risk,
I helped my patient.
I was resourceful.
I mean, I was a good doctor.
That's the kind of person
that I want to be.
And you can't be
that person here?
Maybe.
But I know that this
opportunity will allow me
to be the kind of doctor
that I want to be,
doing the work
that I love. I...
This is my calling.
Why don't you just take
some time and think about it?
I don't want to.
But...
I just want to close my eyes
and take the leap.
Okay.