Previously on ER:
- The medical board called me.
- I bet they did.
They're issuing a letter for
us to cease our drug program.
Dr. Pratt is under arrest. Violation
of the Controlled Substance Act.
You could sleep here.
I don't know where we are, Tony,
but you have to do something.
I think she's dying.
GATES Sarah.
Sarah.
Call your husband.
Call him.
I just called him.
He didn't pick up.
Shh.
Just try again.
I have no idea where he is.
I don't even know what
he's doing right now.
Try again.
Mr. Ames, why don't you just go?
Okay? Just please go.
And I'm sure Luka will
be happy to talk to you...
about whatever it is you
want some other time, okay?
What I want?
Whatever the reason it is
you're here, just go, okay?
Please go and there won't
be any trouble. I promise.
Trouble?
- You don't know what trouble is.
- Oh, God.
Abby? Abby, you call Luka now.
Sammy.
Sammy, you smell that?
- Something's on fire, Sammy.
- What?
Mom.
Alex?
Mom, help.
Son of a bitch. Sammy.
- Oh, my God.
- Mom, wake up. You have to wake up.
Someone, please.
- You have to wake up.
- What happened?
- I love you.
Hey, Meg.
- She got dizzy and pulled over.
- What happened? Meg.
- Stridorous resps. Let's lie her down.
- What did you take, Meg?
- Bunch of stuff. NEELA:
It's definitely ETOH.
- What else did you take?
- Nothing.
- What are you talking about?
- Sarah, quiet.
- What, Meg? What did you take?
- This Alpro.
Alprazolam?
- Oh, works fast.
- What is this?
- Amitriptyline.
- That's her pick-me-up medicine.
She needs a cardiac monitor.
How long you been
on the antidepressants?
There should be a
lot more pills in here.
Whoa. Roll her, roll her.
- Go ahead.
Hold on, Meg. Hold on.
No need for this. He
hasn't broken any law.
You'll be able to post
bail for him in a few hours.
This is not a criminal matter.
It's just a misunderstanding.
Yeah, I never heard that one.
Hey. Uh, sorry I
couldn't pick up before.
I'm at the police station.
- Luka.
- Are you okay?
Can you come home now?
No, it's gonna be a couple of
hours. Pratt's been arrested.
You need to come home now.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing, I just...
It's just something happened
and we need to discuss it.
- Is Joe okay?
- He's fine.
- Just come home.
- Tell me what's the matter.
I need to see you.
Okay. I'll... I'll
be right there.
Thank you.
I appreciate that.
Come on through. Go, go.
- Go.
- Go!
Move the cars. Let's go.
Keep moving.
Hurry up.
Move away from the building
so our people can work.
People are... Sammy.
Where's Alex? We
should all stay together.
She went back in to get him.
They must be around here.
- They're still inside?
- No, they must be around here.
- If you can walk...
- Where are they?
If you can walk, head to an
ambulance to be assessed.
Command, give me EMS plus
one at 1215 Granger Avenue.
- Sammy, Alex.
- It's my granddaughter, Sam Taggart.
How's he doing?
Who?
Joe.
He's fine.
Please?
My daughter was easy...
but my little boy, I told
you, he was always colicky.
Didn't sleep through the
night for the first three months.
How about Joe?
He sleeps fine.
Grew big since the park.
- They grow up fast...
- Look, what do you want?
I wanna talk to Luka.
Like this?
This happened to the both of us.
Him and me.
So I see no reason why we
should go through it alone.
It's over.
Is that what you think?
You're this successful
doctor, right?
You're smart.
You're beautiful.
You got the man, you got
the baby, you got everything.
So don't take it personal
when I say to you...
you have no idea
where I am right now.
You're wrong.
- You think so?
- Yeah.
I think I know exactly
where you are right now.
You know, nine years ago, I...
My marriage was over, my
mother was in a mental institution...
for the seventh or 10th time.
I don't know, and I drank a lot.
A lot.
And I had reached
this... You know what, I...
One morning, I woke up in this apartment,
and I had no idea how I got there.
Next to some guy I didn't
even remember meeting.
And he was going through
my stuff, looking for money...
so he and his
buddy can get a fix.
So I ran out of there,
and I went downstairs...
I tried to get a cab, but I
had no idea where I was...
and it was 5:00 in the morning,
and there were no cars, so I just...
I just sat down on the stoop, and I
just waited for something to happen.
And at that moment, I'm telling
you, I knew, I mean, I was positive...
that happiness was something
I was never gonna find.
- You getting deep on me now?
- No.
I am just trying to tell you
that things can change.
They can get better. Even
if you don't see it, they can.
Do you have any bourbon?
Dr. Gates, long time no see.
- We need suction and an intubation kit.
- I got it. I got it.
Jenny didn't tell you it was me.
Why you think we took our
time? This lady's messed up.
- It's Meg.
- Hey, I'm sorry, man, I didn't know.
- You gonna give her medicine?
- Take Sarah to the rig.
- I wanna stay here.
- I need room to work on your mom.
- Go to the rig.
- I wanna stay here.
Pulse is thready. Dumar,
let's get a move on.
We doing this here?
- Lower this to transfer her.
- I need to tell you...
Don't talk, okay?
Now, we're gonna place
a tube in your throat.
It's gonna help
you breathe, okay?
Closer.
Sarah.
She's yours, Tony.
She's yours.
Gates, come on.
Let's get her on
the gurney, man.
What? You too
good to talk to me?
No.
Hm.
You don't belong here, huh?
No.
Do you?
What they got you for?
- It's complicated, man.
- So now you calling me stupid.
I helped some people get
some medications they needed.
Medications? Like drugs?
Pharmaceutical, yeah.
See, coz? He belong.
We both the same.
Getting drugs to
people who need them.
Greg?
Oh, great.
Just in the nick of time.
My spiritual advisor.
It's been too long, Ben.
Where are they?
Maybe she went out the back way,
Gracie, or went up through the roof.
Would you ask them
again? Ask them.
Chief.
- Chief, please.
- Hold on, sir.
My friend and her son are in
2B, they haven't come down.
We're doing every...
Hey, hey, up here.
I got a little boy and a
man with extensive burns.
He's got smoke inhalation, no
thermal burns, sat 94 percent.
Pulse ox, chest x-ray,
carboxyhemoglobin level.
I'll put him in Exam 2. Let
me take care of your cut.
No, I'll do it, Dawn.
That'll need suturing.
I'll get to you next.
- I'm gonna go check on Grandma.
- Fine.
- Is Gracie okay?
- Yeah, she's on her way in with Ben.
Ben who? Ben the murse?
- He was over for dinner.
- I'll fix up Alex.
You come back when
you clean up that arm.
Burns on face, chest and arms.
- Pulse ox?
- Low 90's, stridorous.
He needs a line, chem
panel, CBC, lactate, CO.
My neighbor, slept
through everything.
- Mr. Owens, you're gonna be okay.
- How did this thing start?
I'm not sure. Alex said
he knocked over a candle.
Have somebody look at that.
All right, let's get him
exposed, and check the airway.
Hey.
Sorry it took me so
long. The traffic was...
Hey, hey.
I got fired.
What are you doing here?
You said if ever I need
anything, I should give you a call.
So this is my call.
Okay.
What do you need?
To talk.
To be listened to.
Abby, take the baby upstairs.
- No need for that.
- Hey, Curtis.
- Luka.
- Take the baby upstairs.
They can stay right here,
because we're going for a ride.
- All right.
- No, don't.
No, it's okay.
- My car's right around the corner.
- No, please.
- Luka, don't go. You can't go, Luka...
- Hey, Abby, hey.
Abby.
Thanks for the talk.
911 operator.
There was a man in my
apartment with a gun...
and he's taken my husband.
His name is Curtis Ames.
I can't find a pulse. - V-fib.
- Starting compressions.
- Charge to 360, amp of epi and bicarb.
Charged. Let them
know we have arrest.
Back off. Back off.
Clear.
Still in fib.
We're gonna take your
mom in the ambulance.
- You go with Neela.
- I wanna stay with you.
- I need you to do this.
- I wanna stay.
- We're gonna follow them.
- No.
Sarah, go with Neela now!
- Stop!
Just go straight.
I can help you find another
job, if that's the problem.
Look, do you need
money? I have money.
Turn right, right over here.
Come on. Talk to me, Ames.
I thought that's
what you wanted.
Just pull up here.
Park it.
Turn off the lights.
- You have no idea how he got in?
- No.
Look, why aren't you looking
for him? I told them I saw the car.
- '96 station wagon, light tan?
- Yeah, I think so, yeah.
- Ran a check, got one registered to him.
- So you know him?
His history? Ames.
You know, I told the cops this.
He had a stroke.
He lost the use of his left arm.
There was a lawsuit.
Okay. I'll get somebody
on that right away.
Okay. Louise, could you take
him to your place for a little while?
- Sure, Abby, we'll be fine.
- Thanks.
Now, listen, you
need to catch up.
There's a medical record
with information on it.
Numbers, addresses,
probably a psych assessment.
- Where?
- County General. I can get it.
Mr. Owens, you doing okay?
- Throw me a Cordis.
We don't wanna do a
subclavian through this eschar.
The fire.
It started downstairs.
Femoral? MORRIS:
Too much infection risk.
- In my apartment.
- How?
- I'm not sure. MORRIS:
Proximal arm is spared.
I think it was a candle.
I am so sorry.
Give me the ultrasound.
I'll cannulate the basilic vein.
Can we give him something for the pain?
- Oh, there it is.
All right.
Morphine, 5 milligrams, IV.
His nasal hairs are singed.
Should we go fiberoptic?
No, not enough time. His
airway is already swollen.
We gotta get in
before it closes.
She's gonna be okay, isn't she?
Tony's gonna fix her?
Your mom took too much of a
medicine that can be bad for the heart.
They're trying to
get it started again.
Tony can fix her.
I can't see the cords.
Too much edema.
- Pulse ox, 78.
- Help me, Ray. We don't wanna crike.
- I'm working on it. MORRIS:
Need more pressure?
No, no. Anatomy's too distorted.
Okay, damn it.
Let's go, crike tray.
- Wait, hold on.
- Sat's down to 70.
Watch carefully,
okay? Look for bubbles.
This'll force the air back to the trachea.
Bubbles show where to place the tube.
- That works?
- Once in a while.
Whoa, that's really
good. I can see it.
Well, push that baby home.
- All right.
Bag him.
You got it. We're in.
- Color change.
- Oh, Sam is the man.
Mr. Owens, take it easy, okay?
We're taking real good care of you.
- Ben went to find us some clothes.
- Oh, good.
Mr. Owens all right?
Yeah. I think he's gonna be.
He's a nice man. He helped
me with the groceries...
but he drinks too much.
What happened tonight, Sammy?
Uh...
- What did Alex say?
- Nothing.
He won't talk to me.
Well, I don't know
what happened.
But if it is what I think, it
scares the hell out of me.
Heard the cops took
Pratt on a walk of shame.
If they did, they got it wrong.
Pratt's as good as they come.
Get away from my desk.
Sorry, man, I'm just asking.
- Frank?
- Keep it to yourself.
- Frank.
- You're either late or early.
I need you to call up to Records.
Tell them to pull Curtis Ames' chart.
- Curtis Ames?
- Just do it.
- You know, this late...
- Frank, just do it.
- Who lives here, Curtis?
- Quiet. Shh, shh. Quiet.
I've had a gun
pointed at me before.
I know you're not the
type of man to use that.
You see?
I used it.
There's Cheryl. There she is.
Remember Cheryl?
Mm.
She remarried in October.
Banker.
Investments or something. I
don't know about that kind of stuff.
But my daughter's
recital was tonight.
They asked me not
to come this time.
Said we would try rotating.
You know, at the
movies last week...
they wanted to know if it
would be okay with me...
if they call this new guy...
dad.
I mean, they would still call me
that, but they just wanted to know...
if it was okay if they
call this new guy that too.
I know she put them up to it.
I know she...
But...
the fact is...
I think they like the idea.
They're just confused. You
can help them understand.
Pretty soon, they'll
be going to bed.
He's gonna be screwing my wife with
my children sleeping in the next room.
She gets to...
To move on, huh?
She gets to be happy.
Guys like you and me...
we gotta live with it.
She's gone, man.
There's nothing else we can do.
Please give me
a little more time.
Can you spare the room?
Of course.
You take what you need.
Another round of epi and bicarb.
Coming up.
Sarah, you wanna
talk to your mom?
Is her heart beating now?
Well, we're giving her
more medicine, so...
Is she getting better?
I don't know.
Can she hear me?
I'm sure she'd like
to hear your voice.
Know that you're here with her.
Is she gonna die?
Mom.
Mom, I'm here.
I'm sorry you're sick and I'm
sorry that you've been so sad.
And I'm sorry if
I've been a pain...
but, Mom, you gotta
fight right now, okay?
You always said
we were survivors.
Didn't you say that?
So please, Mommy.
Please.
You gotta survive this.
I know you can do it.
Thanks for bailing me out. I'll
make sure you get your money soon.
Greg.
I told you to shut it down.
Why didn't you do that?
- Because the day hadn't come yet.
- What is that supposed to mean?
- I'll tell you about my favorite prophet.
- This about your bookie?
Isaiah knew when the Spirit of God
would unburden the brokenhearted.
Give strength to the meek, open the
prisons so the captives could go free.
You sound like the love child of
David Koresh and Al Sharpton.
- You realize that, right?
- Greg, you're looking for something.
I could see that the first time
you walked into my church.
You need to feel like
you belong to a family.
Well, we are your family.
You know, Isaiah's all fine, but I
prefer the one about the prodigal son.
Even he came back eventually.
Don't hold your breath.
Sarah, we've been working on your mom
and giving her medicine for over an hour.
- It's not working.
- Fix her.
That's why you wanted to be a
doctor, so you could fix people.
Sometimes you can't fix
people if they've taken too...
Shut up!
Go away. Why are you even here?
We don't want you here.
She doesn't want you here.
- Sarah.
- We don't want you!
It's okay.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Now I'm gonna stop CPR.
If her heartbeat comes
back, that's good.
But if it doesn't, that
means your mom has died.
Are you ready?
No, Tony.
No. You can't let
this happen, Tony.
No. Come on, Mom. You gotta
wake up. You gotta wake up.
No.
Mom.
You gotta wake up.
Tony, you have to do something.
Mom!
Mom.
Tony.
Okay.
Okay, let's go.
Curtis, please. Just tell
me, what are we doing?
You're gonna like this.
I'm gonna show you something
that's really beautiful, all right?
Let's go.
Let's go. Come on, come on.
Ha.
I should have said...
that this... This, uh... This
could have been beautiful, right?
Is this yours?
Was.
I bought it four years ago.
We figured...
we'd live on the bottom two
floors, and then we'd rent out the top.
Started working on it.
Fixing it up.
My own two hands.
Those spindles on the staircase.
Yeah, that's... That's me.
The paneling...
took me two months
before I had to stop.
You still own it?
I held on to it even after
everything that happened.
I tried to keep working on
it, but it just took me so long.
You know, I couldn't be
as detailed as I used to be.
I gave Cheryl half
the market value...
in the divorce.
You know, I was stupid,
because I don't know...
why I didn't just sell it.
Now the bank owns it.
There was a time where I...
I thought that we
understood each other.
That we were...
We were hearing each other.
You know, like that
time up by the river.
You were just
talking, weren't you?
Because you
never really felt me.
I don't know what else you
expected, what you want.
Tell me what you want.
Are you a righty
or are you a lefty?
Why?
I'm right-handed.
I want you to put your
hand in that vise there.
I want you to feel that.
No.
Do it.
Look, Curtis. Look,
you're confused.
I know you're upset.
Do it.
Tighten it.
Curtis, look...
Sighting of suspect's
vehicle outside a residence...
formerly owned by suspect,
located at 321 Parkdale.
Get over there, help secure the
scene. I'm gonna pick up Mrs. Ames.
- Did they find them?
- Not yet, just the car.
- All right, I'm going with you.
- That's 321 Parkdale.
Possible shots fired.
Best thing for you is to stay put
until we have more information.
- Did she say shots fired?
- I know this can't be easy.
- No.
- I'll send an officer back, stay with...
Are you kidding me?
I'm not just gonna wait.
I'm sorry. You
need to trust us now.
It hurts, doesn't it?
Don't be so easy on yourself.
Tell me how it feels.
Tell me what it's doing to you.
I can, uh...
I can feel, uh...
crushing of the
metacarpal heads.
Uh...
The digital nerves
being compressed.
I'm losing sensation.
Uh, motor control.
You know what I mean.
- You know what I mean?
- I don't.
- You know...?
- I don't. I don't.
Wait, wait, wait. Hey.
- Stop, please. Hey.
- You tell me how it feels.
Just stop it.
Come on, Luka.
Come on.
You see people
in pain every day.
You tell me how it feels.
Oh, son of a bitch.
See, do you feel me now?
What do you want from me, huh?
What do you want from me, huh? Ah!
I can't...
do it without my hands.
I'm a doctor.
I have a wife, a child.
Ha. Hey... It's hard, right?
Is that what you want, huh?
Is that what you want?
I won't be able to
take care of my family.
I won't be able to do anything.
I'm nothing, okay? I'm nothing.
You wanna kill me? Huh?
Is that what you want? You
wanna kill me, kill me now.
Now you get it. Now
you're saying something.
Now you finally
understand a little.
Get the hell out of here now!
This is my house!
You get the hell out of here!
Hey, hey, hey.
Lady, hey. Get back.
I gotta talk to somebody,
tell somebody I knew him.
I work in... Hey.
Hey. Hey.
I work in County. I
know Curtis Ames.
- Just let her go.
- Okay.
I brought his medical record.
It's the reason why he's doing this.
- There's a lot of info...
- Who are you again?
- That's my husband in there with him.
- Your husband?
Yes. We both work at County and I
thought that maybe your negotiator...
Yeah, move in.
No, I'm good.
Thanks. I don't think
this is gonna help.
Four-six, four-five, clear.
Somebody was here.
Signs of a struggle.
This is Chopper 1. We
got two men on the roof.
One of them's armed.
All right. I want that
chopper to back off.
Tell that pilot to get
some altitude now.
Does Kovac have a
cell phone with him?
I tried to call him before,
but he didn't answer.
What does he want?
If he wanted to kill Luka, he
could have shot him an hour ago.
Well, maybe he wanted
a bigger audience.
Forty-six, twenty-five
Charlie, what's your status?
Securing second floor.
Curtis, it's time to let this go.
- My...
The hospital said it.
Court said it.
My damn lawyers said it.
Even my own wife.
"Curtis, let it go. Let it go."
You know what it's
like to lose everything?
It's not just about the arm.
It's about feeling
like everything...
that ever made you a
man has been taken away.
How you supposed to fix that?
How am I supposed
to just let this go?
Hey.
This is probably
them again, Curtis.
Yeah, this is Kovac.
We're both here.
Yeah, hold on.
It's the police. They
wanna talk to you.
Just put it on speaker.
Mr. Ames, this is Deputy
Superintendent John Valentine.
We'd like to resolve this quickly
and peacefully, so first off...
is there anything
we can get you?
Yeah.
Could you just go away?
Can you just leave me alone?
Just go. Could
you go over there?
Just go over there.
Curtis, we both have families.
Children we love,
a lot to live for.
- This won't solve anything.
- Mr. Ames?
The numbness happened twice.
So it was TIA, right?
- Right?
- Yes.
But you didn't consider that.
Should have considered that.
I thought it was from
sleeping on the gurney.
We've been through all this.
Intermittent numbness
is associated with TIA.
You should have considered
that, thought about my heart.
It was noisy. I explained that.
That's because you
listened with a steth.
But the standard of care
would have been a cardiac echo.
- It doesn't matter.
- It does!
It does!
Because...
you would have seen
the patent foramen ovale...
and you would have
pulled the central line!
Yes, okay? Yes,
yes, yes. You're right.
You were right all along. I blew
it. I missed it. I missed the murmur.
And I'm sorry for that.
Why didn't you ever
just say that, man?
I'm saying it now, okay?
Maybe I needed
all this to... I...
I'm not innocent. I'm just...
Look, if I can take it all
back, if I can fix it, but I can't.
Okay? I can't. I just can't.
I can't.
Luka.
Mr. Ames?
Curtis.
Who fired? There was
no command to fire.
It came from the roof.
Grab her.
- Get up on the roof now.
- No, no.
Go, go, go. ABBY: Let me go.
All units, I want
status reports now.
Forty-five Charlie, we have a
man down. We have a man down.
Oh, God. No, no.
You have to let me go.
Listen, I'm an ER doc.
Just let me go.