Dad, are they gonna
separate you from me?
Why do you ask that?
Because you haven't been
a very good dad.
I promise,
I'm gonna do better.
It was so easy
for me to see Crockett
as the problem.
Whatever
happened between
me and him in the past...
I get it now.
Because the real problem
was always right here.
Whatever it is you want,
it isn't me.
It's been a really
good couple of weeks.
Yeah, it has.
And not just us. Rehab.
You've been knocking it
out of the park.
I'm really proud of you.
Hey
Hey. Sorry, I was
trying not to wake you.
Where you headed so early?
To a meeting.
Feel like
I could use one.
Wait a second,
I'll get dressed
and drive you.
No. No, no, no.
Stay in bed.
I'll see you at work.
Bye.
Hannah, you forgot
your phone.
Dr. Moody said you
were the one to see.
That you'd take
good care of us.
Yeah, Moody and I
go way back.
Medical school.
We used to ride
motorcycles together.
Doctor Moody
rode a motorcycle?
Yeah, but he had
to give it up
when he became
a pediatrician.
The stethoscope
kept flying off his neck
on the way to work.
Please don't give
Billy any ideas.
I have enough worries
with him on his bike.
Uh-oh.
You like riding
your bike, Billy?
Yeah.
But my mom won't let me
ride at night.
That's probably
a good thing, bud.
X-ray's ready.
Step back, please.
Mmm-hmm.
Can you hold your
breath for me, Billy?
Ready?
Got a couple of
non-displaced cracked ribs.
The issue is this hemothorax
here, in Billy's chest.
Hemothorax?
That sounds bad.
No, it's just
a buildup of blood
between the lung
and chest wall.
It explains why he's been
having difficulty breathing.
But we can fix that.
We just have
to drain the blood.
Does that mean surgery?
Oh, hopefully not.
We're gonna try
a chest tube first.
Set me up for
a 28 French Tube.
Yes, doctor.
Okay, Billy,
I'm gonna bring you back.
Now, can you lift
that left arm for me?
Maybe.
Oh, yeah,
I know it's sore.
All right. This next part's
gonna hurt a little bit.
Think you can handle it?
I'll be okay.
That's what
I like to hear.
Billy was born with
a diaphragmatic hernia,
so, unfortunately,
he's no stranger to hospitals.
Well, you are very brave,
Billy. And you're doing great.
Speaking of, Billy,
how come
I ain't never seen
you and Spider-Man
in the same place
at the same time?
Almost done.
Must be torture to watch
your kid suffer like that.
Yeah, I'm sure it is.
You ever think
about having kids?
Oh, no. Kids are
not my speed.
And why is that?
Dr. Marcel.
Detective Poulson,
Chicago PD.
Doc.
And Detectives
Bridges and Hayes
from the New Orleans
Police department.
Oh. My old
stomping grounds.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah. What can I do
for you gentlemen?
I'm just an escort today.
Okay.
Uh, Detective Hayes and I,
we're following up a detail
from this cold case
that popped
back up recently.
Uh-huh.
You mind if we talk
in private?
Uh, the consultation room
is free.
Yeah. Yeah, of course.
Follow me.
All right.
Gentlemen?
Cold case?
Yeah, from a homicide
from their town.
And they came all the way
up here to talk to Crockett?
What's going on?
I don't know.
They weren't
willing to share.
Hey.
I haven't seen you around
the last few days.
I've been doing ride-alongs
with the medics.
Nice of you
to help them out.
Um...
I got the last of my stuff
out of your apartment,
so, here.
I know you'll be happy
to move back in.
Thanks.
I should go.
Sexton,
I need a nurse.
Trent Sutton,
25 year old male,
GCS 12, vitals stable.
Semi-rousable
on four liters O2.
Found collapsed
in the DePaul library.
Looks like he suffered
a penetrating injury
to the chest.
Okay. On my count.
One, two, three.
Is that a needle?
Let's get an X-ray.
AP and lateral.
Hey, Trent, I'm Dr. Lanik.
You're okay.
I'm gonna remove
this needle, Trent,
but I gotta take
a picture first
to make sure
we're not flying blind.
No, no! Don't take it out!
Restraints.
Get off of me!
Get that X-ray already!
He pushed it deeper.
I can't take it
if he won't stay still.
Get off of me!
Push two Versed.
In.
Look who it is.
Anna Charles.
Hi, Maggie.
Hmm. Dad dragged you
into work today?
I did no such thing.
Oh, no. I... I like
spending time with my dad.
I wanted to come.
Uh, wants to volunteer,
actually.
Oh, really?
No school today?
Not really.
My class went on a field trip
to a science museum.
But I figured
I'd learn more
about science here.
I don't know
about all that.
But maybe
Deandra over in Pediatrics
can use some help.
Just so you know,
this one right here?
Her middle name?
Pop quiz.
Mmm-hmm.
Maggie "Pop Quiz" Lockwood.
I'm just saying.
That's me.
Okay.
Come on.
Let's get you a vest.
Hey, Dan?
You got a sec?
What you got?
Our friend
here's insides.
Those are sewing needles.
Four in all, which he seems
to have put there himself.
I was able
to remove this one,
which was only
partially submerged.
But that one there,
it managed to get all
the way into his heart.
I'm gonna do
a cardio workup,
but after that,
he's all yours.
Does it hurt
when I touch it?
Ah, more than
I'd like to admit.
Sorry, man.
When did you first
notice the rash?
Uh, about a week ago.
I was hoping
it would go away.
It's good
you're here now.
You have cellulitis,
bacterial infection.
I want to get you started
on an antibiotic.
Roger, are you
allergic to penicillin?
Uh, not that I know of.
Looks like
Mr. Larusso was here
about three years back.
And you were
his attending.
I, uh...
I thought
he looked familiar.
I apologize for
not recognizing you.
It's all right.
I'm sure you see
a lot of patients.
Yeah.
Okay, so, I see here,
you had a prior infection?
Uh-huh.
And we treated it
with cefazolin last time?
Uh, I don't remember.
My mind's a sieve.
That's all right.
I'm worried this rash
is the same bacteria.
I wanna make sure
we stay ahead of it.
Doris, start him
on an IV?
Mmm-hmm.
And at least we know
we had success with
that drug already.
Uh, What...
What's that for?
It's just to
monitor the rash.
I want to make sure
it shrinks down some
before I discharge you.
Okay, now, your
emergency contact
has your wife listed.
You want us to call her
and tell her
we'll be keeping you here
for a few more hours?
Uh, no.
Don't worry about that.
I'll... I'll give her a call.
All right, then.
Is something wrong?
What's going on?
The chest tube
should've drained
more blood.
Yeah, it's been a few days
since he's been hurt,
there's a chance
the hemothorax
is mostly clot.
Let's get him up
for a non-contrast
chest CT.
I should've taken him in
to see Dr. Moody earlier.
No, you didn't do
anything wrong.
Billy, you mind
if we speak with
your mom outside?
Okay, thanks, bud.
I'll be back.
So, if the CT shows me
what I think it is,
I'm recommending
surgery.
Oh, God.
No, I know
that sounds scary,
but the procedure,
a video-assisted
thoracoscopy
is minimally invasive.
We use a scope
to clean out
his chest.
When Billy was a baby,
he had to go on ECMO.
After all
the transfusions,
he developed
antibodies in his blood.
I guess to help
his immune system.
Yeah, Moody told me.
But I think we should be able
to find compatible blood.
Yeah, I'll have the blood
bank start sourcing
antibody-matched blood.
Billy's gonna get
the best care possible.
And nothing
to eat or drink.
Okay.
All right.
Thank you.
Schedule him in,
in a bit.
Sure.
Hey, Crockett.
Yeah.
What's all that
with the detectives?
They're investigating
a murder from
seven years back.
Well, what'd they
want with you?
I get the impression
they think I'm a suspect.
Why would
they think that?
'Cause they claim
to have gotten
my DNA at the scene.
So, um, let's talk about
these needles.
Can you tell me
about the first time
this happened?
I'm really embarrassed.
Trent, don't be.
If you knew
how many instances
of self-harm
I saw in this hospital...
Self-harm?
No, I wasn't trying
to hurt myself.
I was trying to
make myself feel better.
Okay.
Yeah, I'm under
a ton of pressure
right now.
I have to defend
my dissertation next month,
and it's been
messing me up.
My heart races,
I get nervous.
There's this press...
There's this pressure
in my chest that
I can't get rid of.
And the needles,
they alleviate that pressure?
Yeah, I know
it sounds insane,
but it's the only thing
that helps.
I'm telling you,
there's something
wrong with my heart.
Look, I absolutely believe
that it feels that way to you,
but the EKG
says otherwise.
Trent is a PhD candidate
at DePaul.
And recently, his anxiety
is kicking up this pretty
bizarre compulsion.
Like OCD?
Well, I mean,
kind of,
but instead of washing
his hands incessantly,
he's sticking needles
in his chest.
You get a look
at his scans?
Yes.
This needle appears
to be floating free
in his right ventricle.
At the moment,
it's not doing
any damage.
But if it were to move...
It's gonna get
spit out into his lungs.
Could become
a huge mess.
Most likely
a pulmonary embolism.
So, gonna
schedule him today?
I have reservations.
Is the patient suicidal?
Hmm. I mean,
not consciously.
But I can't argue
that the behavior
isn't life-threatening.
So then
he may be inclined
to reinsert the needles
even if we do pull them out.
How long will it take
for you to assess
his compulsion?
Getting to the root
of his anxiety,
remapping
his coping skills,
I mean,
that's gonna take
some time.
But we'll get
right into it post-op.
Hmm, fair enough.
I will proceed with
removing the needles.
But you'll have to
get his consent.
I'll work on that.
Hey, sweetie.
I got kicked off
the peds floor.
What?
Deandra said that
she wouldn't
get off her phone.
I thought you wanted
to be here.
I do.
I just didn't think
everyone would be
so uptight.
Do I need to
confiscate that thing?
What? No.
Put it in your pocket
and keep it there.
You know what,
Leah in the waiting room
needs some help.
Ideally, something
that requires
two thumbs?
Mmm-hmm.
She'll keep her busy.
Okay.
Hi, I'm Dr. Halstead.
Can you tell me
your name?
Yes, I can.
Oh. This is a test.
Right then,
my name is Christian.
Pleased to make
your acquaintance.
Pretty nasty infection
there, Christian.
Is that why
you came in today?
Christian, hey?
You with me?
Mmm-hmm.
All the way.
Your vein's rock-hard.
When did you last shoot up?
Ah... Oh...
What day is today?
Okay. Let's consent him
for an I&D.
Sorry
that took so long.
They made me park out
in the satellite lot.
That's all right.
I'll just be
a few minutes.
There you are, love.
I was afraid
you'd abandoned me.
You two know each other?
Uh, Christian's
an old friend.
Old friends,
two of us.
Okay, not here.
Okay.
Will, can we talk?
I'll get those
off you later.
I know that
this looks strange.
Well...
We used to date
about a year ago.
Another part of my past
I'm trying to put behind me.
I thought you were
going to the meeting.
Yeah, I was. I did.
And things were
just winding up
when I got this call
from Christian.
When I saw how
bad his arm was,
I brought him in
straight away.
You... You went
to his house?
You see the state he's in?
He's in no condition
to drive.
Hmm.
I guess I might feel
a little guilty
for getting clean.
I understand.
Are we good?
Absolutely.
Okay.
Hmm.
Oh, hey, you forgot this
this morning.
Oh. Thank you.
I'll see you later.
Yeah.
Do you have any updates
for Ms. Harris?
Yeah.
Tell her that
Billy did great
with the anesthesia,
and that
we're progressing.
Great.
The timing may be poor,
Ms. Goodwin, but this is
a police matter.
Dr. Marcel will
not be disturbed
while he's in
the operating room.
Judge just gave us
a warrant for his arrest.
Detective,
I am not interrupting
a surgery on
an 11-year-old child
for any reason.
You can take up
your concerns
with Dr. Marcel
when the operation is over.
Well, we got
no place to be.
Make yourself at home.
Stay here and
notify me immediately
if anything comes up.
Yes, Ms. Goodwin.
You don't think
Crockett's actually
guilty, do you?
Yes. Come on.
Ethan? Ethan?
Hey. You there?
Yeah, what's up?
Do you think Courtney
should dye her hair?
If you want to.
Ambulance 95,
we have a shooting
with injuries
at 2112 North Damen.
95 to main.
Message received.
We're on our way.
Stay low.
Keep your heads down.
What happened?
I got shot.
I was just about
to put on
a tourniquet.
All right.
Doesn't seem
like too much blood.
I'm gonna put a pressure
dressing on it.
Right.
Where's the shooter?
Inside.
Our guys on-viewed
a carjacking.
Gave chase, and the bad guy
came to a crash stop here.
Went inside with a gun.
Store owner
here thought
he was being robbed.
Exchanged gunfire.
Son of a bitch is lucky
I ran out of bullets.
He's holed up
inside now.
Let's go.
Hold your fire!
Wait, hold your fire!
All right,
come on, I got you.
Are you hurt?
No.
But a boy, inside,
my... my neighbor,
he got shot.
All right.
Where was he shot?
I think
in the stomach.
Please, he's only nine.
2112 Squad, notify CFD,
we need a couple
ambulances standing by.
There's an injured
kid inside, we have
to get in there.
SWAT's en route.
The girl said
the boy's been shot.
I hear you, but I got
orders to stand down
and hold the perimeter.
Don't shoot,
medic, don't shoot!
Hold your fire.
Medic! Don't shoot.
Don't shoot!
Hey, I'm unarmed!
I'm a doctor!
I'm coming in!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
I'm a doctor.
Okay, I'm here to help.
Is anyone injured?
Hey, don't move!
Take it easy.
I just wanna
help the boy.
Hey, turn around, man.
Turn around.
Slowly, or I will
shoot you.
Get on your knees.
Come on.
Just take it easy.
Get down.
Let's go.
Damn it!
Units on the citywide,
we have a hostage situation.
Hey, give me that!
Give me that! Come on!
Your phone, too,
I know you got it.
Get up!
Come on! Come on!
And move the fridge.
Move! In front
of the door.
Okay, that's good.
Get back down
on the ground.
Can I take a look at him?
I said, get down!
Come on, man,
he's a kid.
Okay. This helps you, too,
because if he dies...
Fine. But if you
try anything...
I won't.
Look, all I did
was steal a car.
What about this kid?
Hey, I didn't shoot him, man.
It was that idiot
behind the counter.
Look, hey.
He needs to go
to the hospital.
I'm begging you
to release him.
You can still
keep me as a hostage.
I'll let him go
when I'm ready.
Ed Green, 50,
GSW to the thigh,
GCS 15, BP 133/87.
Heart rate, 97
and sats 100%.
Hey, I thought Ethan was
on your ambo. Where is he?
Hey. Where is he?
What happened?
Come on, Kevin,
what've you heard?
I really shouldn't be
telling you this.
But...
The detectives
in New Orleans
had been sitting
on DNA evidence
for a long time.
Why'd they wait until now
to come get Crockett?
Forensics pulled samples
from you and Crockett,
when you two got kidnapped.
Right, to cross-match it
with the fugitives' DNA.
Those samples got put
into a national database.
Crockett is a positive match
for a cold case murder
in Louisiana.
There's no way.
Listen, I'm just
telling you what I heard.
And DNA
is hard to refute.
I'll let you know
if I hear anything else.
Thank you.
So, here's
where we're at.
We gotta get
these needles
out of your chest,
especially the one
that's hanging around
in your right ventricle,
and we're gonna
do that tonight.
Surgery, tonight?
Yeah.
And then when
you're recovering,
I think it'd be a really
good idea if we would
start to address...
How long
will I be here?
In the hospital?
I'd say probably
at least three days,
and then...
That doesn't work.
I only have
a couple of weeks
until I defend
my dissertation.
And if I fail,
the last five years
will have been
a complete waste of my life.
I need to get out of here!
Okay, but you understand
we can't let you
just walk out of here
with a needle in your heart.
Whoa, wait.
Okay, buddy. Here.
Trent, look at me.
Look at me. Look at me.
Trent, Trent, Trent.
Look at me.
Take a deep breath.
In through the nose...
No. You don't understand.
You're ruining my life!
Slow down.
Slow your breathing down.
It's racing. It feels
like it's beating
out of my chest!
I'm holding your hand.
Can you feel my hand?
Code Blue!
A respiratory arrest.
Drop his head and bag him.
Yes, Doctor.
What happened?
Oh, Dr. Manning,
there you are.
I'm Dr. Julian Moody,
Billy Harris' pediatrician.
Of course. Billy's
in surgery right now.
I know.
His mother called me.
She's concerned
about his operation.
She said Dr. Marcel
is in some sort of trouble?
Please.
It can't be true.
Crockett would
never hurt anyone.
I know.
If the murder took place
seven years ago,
then that means
that you and Crockett
would've been
at medical school
at that time.
Did you know him well?
Yeah.
And Crockett was going
through a lot back then,
but no way
was he killing people.
What do you mean?
I shouldn't
have said anything.
It's not my story to tell.
Please.
I just wanna help him.
His baby,
Harper,
she died from leukemia,
not long after
her first birthday.
Dr. Halstead.
He has rashes all over
and parts are sloughing.
What the hell
is going on?
Stop the cefazolin now.
A 125 mg Solu-Medrol
and bolus a liter of saline.
Doris, call his wife.
Why is this happening?
Seems like you're having
an allergic reaction
to the medication.
My skin's burning.
Okay. Two milligrams
of Morphine.
Tell the burn center
we're coming up.
Okay.
I have Roger's wife
on the phone.
Okay. Is she coming in?
She says she's with
her husband, Roger,
right now. At home.
So, who's this?
Excuse me.
Excuse me, please.
This is the nurse
who knows Dr. Choi.
April Sexton.
Is Ethan okay?
No idea. We can't
get eyes on him.
And the offender won't answer
the phone inside the store.
You have Choi's cell?
Yeah.
Okay, good.
You know, for a guy
who's supposedly taken
his TEMS training,
Choi violated about
100 different protocols
when he ran in there.
I heard there was
a kid in there
with a gunshot wound.
We're trying to hack
into the security camera now.
And once we get eyes
in there, we're going.
Hey.
That's probably SWAT outside.
You should talk to them.
It's the only way
you're getting out...
Just shut up. Uh...
I need... I need a plan.
Hey, how long does it take
to drive to the border?
Canada?
Four or five hours.
But listen, man,
I need to help this kid
and it can't wait...
Look, just shut up!
Hello?
Yeah, who is this?
Shut up and listen
to me, okay?
It's my turn to talk.
I'm gonna make
the demands. Okay?
Okay, look. I've got...
You're trying to kill me!
Wait, wait, wait.
It's for the kid!
Drop it!
I can't.
He can barely breathe.
He's got a collapsed lung.
I need to make
a hole in his chest
to release the air
that's trapped inside.
Keep the gun
pointed at me.
I'm gonna take this knife
over to the boy now,
all right?
I'm gonna make a small
incision in his chest.
I'm gonna throw
the knife away,
where I can't reach it.
Wow.
Why is Trent Sutton
still down here?
I thought you were
sending him up to the OR.
I want to, but he won't
consent to surgery.
You know
what's bizarre?
He claims to get this pain
in his chest, right there.
I was pretty
much convinced
it was psychosomatic.
But then, after this
last episode, he fainted.
Leads me
to believe that,
I don't know, maybe
there is some kind of
underlying physical
condition there.
Well, let me know
how it progresses.
Because I got
a waiting room
full of patients and...
And now, I got
ambos coming in.
I'd like to
free up the room.
Give that to me, now.
What? Why?
Why? Because clearly
it's interfering with your
ability to do your work.
I'm just texting my friends.
Well, if that's
so important to you,
let's get you over
to the science museum
so you can do it in person.
No, I... I can't.
Why not?
Because.
Because, why?
Dad, if you make me go
on that field trip, I'll die.
Honey. What's going on?
He laughed at me.
Who? Who laughed at you?
Pete Slater.
When I asked him
if he'd like to meet me
at the mall sometime.
And everyone saw.
And they laughed, too.
And now, Jen says
that Lisa Carruthers
is holding hands
with him on the bus.
And now, they're, like,
officially going out.
And my life
is ruined!
Is she all right?
Looks like some guy
she's sweet on,
decided he was sweet
on somebody else.
Oh.
Ouch.
Yeah.
But, damn, Mags,
all the texting?
Mmm-hmm.
I mean, doesn't it just
amplify everything?
Thirteen-year-old girls,
their hearts are just
wired differently.
Wired differently, indeed.
Hey, do me a favor.
Page Dr. Latham for me.
On it.
Dr. Halstead?
Dr. Halstead,
this is Roger Larusso
and his wife, Yvette.
Your nurse called me
on the phone.
Yeah, I apologize,
there's been
a misunderstanding.
We had a case
of mistaken identity,
but you didn't need
to come in.
We came to see Brian.
He's a friend of mine.
I'm sorry, but, um,
Brian must've stolen
your insurance card.
He presented it
when he came in.
No, I gave it
to him.
Roger?
His insurance lapsed
and he needed
to see a doctor.
Because I was going off
of your chart,
I treated his skin infection
with a cephalosporin,
which you're
not allergic to.
Brian is?
Extremely.
Is he gonna be okay?
The burn surgeons are hopeful
we caught it in time
but there's gonna
be permanent scarring.
Oh, my God.
Do you know
how reckless this was?
I'm sorry.
I didn't know
what else to do.
He needed my help.
Well, your help
could've killed him today.
You can't just
keep me here.
I don't understand
why we are
doing this again.
Versed wouldn't have had
an effect on his EKG.
No. But it would
affect his anxiety.
I mean, look at his
U wave without it.
He's tachycardic.
What is that?
It means your
heart rate's elevated,
because you're anxious.
And it also appears
there's an extra
electrical pathway.
Most likely
Wolff-Parkinson-White
syndrome.
Wait. What is that?
It's actually
a congenital defect,
that usually becomes
symptomatic around your age.
And it can be
intermittent.
Sometimes
only appearing
during exercise.
Or periods of stress
and anxiety.
I can correct this
when I remove
the needles.
You... You can make
this all go away?
Yeah. What are we
waiting for?
I'll assemble
my team.
So, I'm out
of here when?
We will have plenty
of time to talk about that.
Yeah, but you just
said that everything
was gonna be fixed.
Look,
what we've done
is we've figured out
where that terrible
pressure is coming from.
Now, we have to address
why you were
responding to it
the way you were.
I was just relieving
the pressure
in my chest. I mean...
Trent, sticking
needles in your chest,
physiologically,
had absolutely
nothing to do
with relieving
that pain.
You're a human being, okay?
You're gonna have
stressors in your life.
We just gotta
figure out a way
for you to deal
with that anxiety
in a way that's
less self-destructive.
Gonna take
a little time.
"DNA evidence can lead
to wrongful convictions"?
Is this about Crockett?
What do you need, Doris?
Blood bank rep
just delivered
a new batch
for your patient,
Billy Harris.
He's in surgery now.
I'll run it upstairs.
Thank you.
It's a good thing you
got the right blood.
Will had a patient today
who got the wrong medicine.
Oof, was that a mess.
Doris, wait!
It's hard to match
bone marrow, too.
You know what?
I'll take the blood up myself.
Get this to Dr. Marcel.
Right away.
Thank you.
Dr. Marcel?
Yeah.
I know this is gonna
sound crazy,
but did you donate
bone marrow in the past?
Uh, can we talk
when I'm done?
No, we can't.
Yeah, I did.
A long time ago.
I suppose it's
in my medical records
somewhere.
Okay, thanks.
No. No, no, no, no.
I... I need a car now!
And forget it.
I'm done talking.
I knew, I knew
they were gonna
mess with me.
You need
to call them back.
Keep negotiating.
Three hours to get a car?
They're playing games.
Hey.
I know how these guys think.
You say you're
done talking?
That's when they
force their way in.
Man, I've screwed up
so many times in my life.
It's like...
It's like I never do
the right thing.
I know how that feels.
What do you mean?
I blew it with someone
I care about.
Made some big mistakes.
Wish I could do it over.
Yeah.
Me, too.
You give yourself up now,
we both get a chance
to do the right thing.
How is he?
He needs more
medical attention
than I can give him.
So, call them back.
Okay.
I'll turn myself in.
SWAT OFFICER 1:
Fire in the hole!
Go! Get down!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
He's not resisting!
SWAT OFFICER 2:
Come on, come on.
I need paramedics
in here now!
Ethan.
April.
When I saw SWAT
go into that building, I...
I've never been
more scared.
I, um...
Dr. Choi,
we're gonna need
a formal statement
about what took place
inside the store.
Come with me,
please.
You done?
What's going on,
fellas?
Crockett Marcel,
you are under arrest
for the murder
of Georgine Burrows.
What, are you serious?
Poulson.
Wait. You're making
a mistake.
You've got
the wrong guy.
Ma'am, it's
police business.
Just a minute
of your time.
You said you found
Dr. Marcel's DNA
at a murder scene
seven years ago.
His medical records
show that he donated
bone marrow,
and he donated it
before the murder occurred.
So?
Sometimes, recipients
of bone marrow transplants
inherit their donor's DNA.
Their blood cells become
genetically identical
to their donor's.
It's rare,
but it's real.
And we're not disputing
your evidence, Detectives.
We're only
asking you to consider
looking at the recipient
of Dr. Marcel's bone marrow.
And if his recipient
does have his DNA,
then your murderer
is still out there.
Excuse me.
How you doing, hon?
Do you care?
Actually, I think I might be
coming down with something.
Think maybe you should,
uh, stay home from school.
Mmm-hmm. Yeah.
You know, when I was
in eighth grade,
I faked a note
to get out of gym class.
And said
I had drop foot.
I was just embarrassed
'cause I was just slow.
I wasn't athletic.
Ended up having to fake a limp
for the entire year.
Yeah?
Yeah.
I mean, look at me.
A guy like me probably
should've gone
to gym class, right?
Yeah, we all have
our ways of dealing
with things.
And some work,
others, like running away,
I mean, they just...
they just don't.
You're saying I need
to go back to school.
It just hurts.
You know, like,
when does it stop?
You mean,
when does life stop hurting?
Yeah, I guess.
Life's always gonna have
its ups and downs, you know?
But in my experience,
we do get better
at dealing with 'em.
You will, too, honey.
Oh, Will.
Your insurance fraud patient
used a fake ID when
he checked in today.
I looked at the copy
that Leah made,
and she should've
caught that.
I had a feeling
something was up.
You know when
you get the sense
you're being lied to?
I should've said something
right then and there.
It's okay to give someone
the benefit of the doubt.
Even if I'm wrong?
You believe in people.
That's a good thing.
And you know
you need to quit.
Yeah, yeah.
Mmm-hmm.
Ah.
Seems I've been
released back
into the wild.
Thank you, doctor.
Again, if you want
some help,
we can set you up
with addiction
specialists.
This one's already been
in my ear about that.
Ash, I really appreciate
you coming over today.
Cheers, mate.
Yeah.
Well...
This all must have seemed
pretty suspicious.
Especially with
the whole phone thing.
Hannah.
Look, I did go to
that meeting today.
And when I said
that Christian called me,
I meant that he called
our mutual friend, Laura,
who was there with me.
And so when you gave me
back the phone,
it felt like may...
Hey.
I believe you.
Really?
Because if I heard
you ended up at your
ex-girlfriend's place...
If you're telling me
that's what happened,
then that's what happened.
Let's get
out of here.
Mmm-hmm.
The good news is,
you'll be back
on your bike soon.
Don't go
too fast now.
Told you, Dr. Marcel
was the guy for this.
Thank you,
Dr. Marcel.
Thank you, both.
Of course.
Hey, Nat.
Mmm-hmm?
Appreciate
all your help.
Yeah.
The thing I can't
figure out...
What gave you the idea
I donated bone marrow?
I always knew
you were a good guy.
Dr. Moody told me
about what happened.
With your baby.
I see.
Do me a favor,
keep that to yourself?
People hear
that sort of thing,
they tend to look
at you different.
Of course.
Yeah.
Good night,
Dr. Manning.
Night.