I'll be targeting your cancer directly
with stereotactic body radiotherapy...
With simultaneous intravenous
Cis-Platinum. Two-cycle regiment.
And I may throw in an
EGFR inhibitor like cetuximab,
depending on how
your tumor responds.
Works for me.
In English, please.
It sounds very important,
but, um, all I care about is...
Could he...
What are his odds?
Georgia. No, Max.
I need an answer
from your doctor.
Georgia, with cancer,
the odds are
difficult to quantify.
But I believe that this
is our very best option.
So, why haven't
we started already?
Yes, Max,
why haven't we started already?
Because there's a lot of pre-treatment
procedures I still need to get done.
Like, um, radiation tattoo,
oral surgery... Oral surgery?
Max's back molars will
fall into the field of radiation
and they'll need
to be extracted.
Um, so, why haven't
we done that yet?
Because I have been kicking
this thing down the road,
a little bit.
To try to buy myself
a little more time,
you know, as medical director.
Which, now that I say out loud,
in front of my wife, does not sound
like the excuse it
sounded like in my head.
Mmm, ya think? Yep.
Could he have his
molars out today?
That's up to him.
We have the big
Domino Transplant today.
The run-through's in
30. I can't, uh, if I'm...
But I think I could
because once they start,
they don't really need me.
And I could probably be
free as early as tomorrow.
Today...
Early afternoon.
You're on board. I'm on board.
Just like that? Just like that.
Domino day. Yeah.
You excited? Oh.
Um, transplant surgeons
get to have all the fun.
I don't even get
to sing back-up.
You know, I had a
really good time last night.
And the night before.
I hope you did too.
Mmm.
What?
I did.
I really like where
this is going.
You know, you and me.
You sound so surprised.
No, no, um, I
just didn't think...
I don't know.
I don't know what I thought.
Well, when Lauren
introduced us I had a feeling.
Yeah.
So, uh, what do you say?
We probably shouldn't
walk in together, right?
Oh, yeah. It's way too soon.
I don't know about you, but
on our side of the building
we're real gossipy.
I'll see you later.
What have I told you
about drinking those things?
You end up bouncing off the
walls and annoying the other nurses.
Yeah, that's part of my charm.
Besides, I need it.
Pull another double?
Bronx General.
"Knife and Gun Club?"
A guy's gotta eat.
Man, their ED never stops.
They need docs?
Since when are you
hard up for cash?
I'm not. It sounds like fun.
Don't you just ever wanna
go home and do nothing?
Now, where's the fun in that?
Hi, I'm Dr. Bloom.
Diego. My daughter, Gianna.
Hi, Gianna.
So, you're having
some trouble breathing?
It's getting worse.
I waited too long.
We can't... Papa is...
Worried...
You can't help us. You
don't have insurance?
Undocumented.
Well, we treat everyone
here. You're safe from ICE.
If that's what you're
worried about.
They won't even
know you were here.
Come on. Pop up,
Gianna. Let's have a listen.
"Sandstorm," huh?
You, know it?
Obsessed. Been collecting
single issues since the '90s.
Deep breath.
Again.
You, uh... Have you
seen the platinum issue?
Gemini, she steals the Halter Cross
from the fourth dimension. It's wicked.
Gemini's my favorite.
I'll be right back.
Casey, I need a chest x-ray,
and I need you to page Reynolds.
I need him now.
You got anything that
will anchor the roll?
Ooh. Science project?
Yeah, living that
extra credit dream.
Yeah, I can see that.
Domino run-through.
No time for
chitchat. Yes, I know.
Do you always have
to be such a buzzkill?
How is she being a buzzkill?
Oh, um... Well, do
you remember how
I said I was gonna try to
pull some strings for Blanca?
You couldn't do it. Figured.
Mmm, you figured, did you?
Yeah, well, figure this,
my friend at Family Services got Blanca
named an Emergency Foster Provider.
Boom.
She had a site
visit this morning.
Boom.
Guess what else.
Something that ends in "boom?"
Uh, yeah. She passed
with flying colors.
You got a home.
Really? Yes.
They can't take it back?
No, there are no
backsies on this boom.
Okay, by this time tomorrow,
you're gonna be moving
into your brand-new digs.
Trust me, it's good. All right?
Okay, I better go
before I have to relocate.
I'll see you later.
Dr. Albert? ALBERT: Here.
Dr. Franz? FRANZ: We're here.
We've got Pittsburgh and Newark.
Morning. Uh, Max Goodwin here.
I'm the new Medical
Director at New Amsterdam,
and just to confirm, you are both in
charge of your respective harvest teams?
Yes. FRANZ: Correct.
Great. Dr. Sharpe here has been
working on this project
for the last seven months,
so it is our job to not
screw it up for her.
To that end, I would like
to take everyone through
the Domino Transplant
Chain one last time
set to the illustrious
tunes of Mr. Van Morrison.
Max.
I'm just getting everyone
pumped for the dry run.
Am I right, Newark?
Not a Van Morrison fan.
What about Pittsburgh?
Yeah, all right, moving
on. We have six patients
receiving partial liver
transplants today,
and, uh, six living
donors from three states.
Our first donor surgery
will be Tanya Mayer.
She just arrived at JFK.
Dr. Kapoor, you are
running point on her.
Except Tanya isn't a match
for her brother, Matthew.
So, a lobe of her liver
will be going to Aminah Ali.
My patient. Aminah
is the anchor patient.
Her HLA factors
were difficult to match.
That's why it took so
long to find her a donor.
Each of our recipients
couldn't find a donor match
within their own families,
so their families agreed
to donate to someone else
who would be a match for them.
Aminah's husband, Tariq,
will donate to Francis Potter.
His mother, Lily Potter, will
then donate to Beck Newman.
Omar Kahn in Newark
will donate to Lisa Verdad
here at New Amsterdam.
Mina Verdad
donating to Gil Hess.
And last but not
least, to close the loop,
Peter Stern in Pittsburgh will
donate to our very own Matthew Levy.
It's like Hands Across
America, but with livers.
Yeah. I'll be here all week,
Newark. Thank you. Wow.
Um, all these surgeries
are time sensitive.
All right, let's, uh,
give this our best shot.
And, Dr. Sharpe, bravo.
Knock, knock.
How's the superstar doing today?
So happy the
waiting's finally over.
Dr. Sharpe, back when Aminah
was going through chemo,
I used to hate seeing you.
But now...
Tariq, she's a doctor.
Have some respect.
Sorry.
She's like family, umi.
Is the young lady who's donating
here yet? We would like to meet her.
Tanya should be
arriving any moment.
Hey, T.
You're looking good.
How are the kids?
You know, they each have
their own bedroom now.
So, they kinda love that.
Until they told
me you'd landed...
I wasn't sure you'd
get on that plane.
Me either.
But I got over it.
It's for a good cause, right?
Family.
So, this part of my liver, why
can't it go straight to Matty?
You're not a donor
match for your brother.
The same is true for
everyone in the chain.
Not a match for their own family
but a match for someone else's.
Sounds complicated.
It is.
But also very simple in the end.
Everyone lives.
Where's Reynolds this time?
We're not doing this again, are we?
He's busy.
He's been busy for the past three
days, whenever I need a consult.
Gianna, this is Dr. Flores.
She specializes in
cheekiness and lungs.
Cool.
Do you know what's
wrong with my daughter?
I do.
Scattered interstitial
infiltrates on the chest X-ray.
Mmm-hmm.
Dr. Bloom.
Hey.
We miss you, Mommy.
Hope you have a good surgery.
Hello, Ms. Mayer. I'm Dr. Frome.
We spoke on the phone.
You have to do some
kind of psych evaluation?
I do, yes. Just to make sure that
you understand what you're getting into
before you give your liver away.
Part of my liver.
Right, yes.
One step ahead of me. Good.
Okay, just a, um, few questions
that aren't on the forms you sent me.
Uh, first, I need to confirm that you
are doing this of your own free will.
Under no pressure
from anyone else.
I'm doing this because
my brother asked me to.
Siblings, am I right?
Do you have a
brother, Dr. Frome?
I did, yes. He passed away.
Would you have given him
part of yourself to save
him if you could've?
Yeah.
But you don't get
do-overs, right?
Okay, why don't we
talk about post-op care?
Tanya?
Are you all right?
What do you mean she's out?
I mean she's out, Max. I
can't clear her for surgery.
I don't believe this.
This house of cards is
built entirely on her consent.
Listen, Tanya Mayer is
nowhere near emotionally
or psychologically
capable of being a donor.
What... What
exactly did she say?
Well, she's got two small kids.
She's worried she won't be able to
take care of them while she's in recovery.
What's the real reason?
On a deeper level, on a more
emotional, personal level...
She's not convinced that Matty
would make the same sacrifice for her.
She can't be serious.
There are deep wounds
in this relationship,
Kapoor, old ones.
They're family.
Can't you talk to her? No.
Anything I say to her at this point
could be construed as coercion.
No one is suggesting coercion.
Stop. Look at this board.
Look at these people.
How do we fix this chain?
Are you saying the
chain's in jeopardy
and we might need to pull the
plug on Omar Kahn's surgery?
Well, let's just
call it a pause.
We can't hold the OR forever.
I know, just give us
some time to regroup.
If we can put this thing back together,
then we are gonna need your donor.
Keep us in the loop.
Thanks. Any luck?
We have been on the phone with
the Organ Transplant Foundation
for the last couple hours.
No match for Aminah.
The same with the
Living Donor Network.
Okay.
So, what now?
We keep looking. The
chain depends on it.
What if it didn't?
We might need a few more
words from you there, boss.
We can still move forward
with most of the surgeries today.
Don't even say it.
Tanya is gone, all right?
Aminah doesn't have a donor,
but the rest of
these recipients do.
Because of Aminah.
She's the anchor patient. We
started this chain to find her an organ.
Without her and Tariq,
there would be no chain.
I know, and we will
find Aminah a donor.
Just not today.
Will Tariq agree to donate
without Aminah having a donor?
It's the right thing to do.
The right thing to do?
That he should give up a piece of
himself while we take away his wife's hope?
This is the best option we have.
I'm sorry to cause so much
trouble. It wasn't you. It was Tanya.
No, I knew it was risky.
We haven't been
close in a long time.
She has her own family now...
She promised you, Matty.
She broke her promise.
And now because of her, a
woman across the hall is...
Would you give me a second?
Hey. Hey.
What kind of a person makes a
promise, gets on to a plane and then throws
that promise in your face?
Um, a mother who's scared
to die? A sister who feels used?
Where I come from, that's
not how we treat our family.
We don't turn our back on them.
Ooh. Okay, Vijay. This is
not about you and your son.
You can't make this about
him turning his back on you.
Iggy, you are most
welcome to play psychiatrist
with everyone else in
this hospital, not me.
So, no transplant today.
I am so sorry, Aminah.
Did the donor say why?
We can't ask those
kinds of questions,
but we are searching
for a new donor right now.
It took seven
months to get here.
Aminah doesn't have
another seven months.
Neither do the
others in the chain.
What happens to them?
Many of the other
recipients are very sick.
They're much sicker than you.
That's why we...
That's why we need to proceed
with the other surgeries today.
You're what?
We need to, um...
I need to ask you...
You can't be serious.
You would be
saving so many lives.
By sacrificing my wife's.
Tariq. No.
No, no, no. Hey, I love you.
I am not gonna let
them do this to you.
The Quran teaches
us that... Not now, umi.
I know that it seems
unfair... I won't do it.
Not unless Aminah has a donor.
This should relieve the pressure
building up in Gianna's lungs.
I'm through the right atrium.
So, is there a reason
you keep sending me
to do ED consults when
Dr. Bloom's on duty?
Do I need a reason?
I get the sense Dr. Bloom
thinks you're avoiding her.
That or she has no
confidence in my abilities.
She thinks you're
an excellent surgeon.
It's just that, uh,
she and I have a
bit of a situation.
Oh. No, no, no.
Not like that. Well,
whatever it is, may I suggest you
start answering your own pages?
Right Ventricular pressure's 35.
Draining the fluid didn't work.
I got your page.
What's happening?
Jemma had an impulsive
aggression episode.
How bad?
The other students said
it came out of nowhere.
She was screaming,
throwing things.
We put her in a quiet
room to calm down, but...
It's not my fault! Not so quiet.
Do you think we need to pump the
brakes on Jemma's home placement?
It's not my fault.
It's not my fault!
So, your daughter has a condition
called idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis,
and we couldn't tell how
advanced it was in the X-ray...
But she's going to
need a new lung.
You can do that?
You can give her a new lung?
Normally, yes.
But because you're
undocumented...
Dr. Bloom says you
treat everyone here.
We do. We do. But the Organ
Transplant Foundation, they won't put
an undocumented person
on their recipient list,
because post-operative
care requires...
Well, stability.
And they don't
think we have that.
Yeah.
What about me?
Give her my lung.
Well, we can check
to see if you're a match,
but there won't
be any guarantee.
Any chance is better than none.
Please.
That leaves only
four recipients.
And we still have
more donors to talk to.
Let's hope they stay in.
Why do you think any of them will
have a different reaction than Tariq?
They're good
people, but they're not
giving out of the
goodness of their hearts.
Quid pro quo.
Hey, how's the chain going?
Don't ask. So, uh, I have a
patient presenting with IPF.
She needs a lung, but
she's undocumented.
No family matches?
She only has her father,
but he's not a match.
I was hoping that maybe
you could call the Mayor,
get her a visa, so we
can get her on the OTF list.
Sharpe?
I don't see how this
helps. The HLA factors.
Uh, let's get the
whole team in here.
We might have a
way to save everyone.
The chain fell apart
when we lost Tanya Mayer,
but it looks like we have
a new match for Aminah.
And that is Diego Morales.
So, the chain is complete?
It will be if Diego agrees
to donate part of his liver.
Wait, how does
Diego donating his liver
help his daughter?
She needs half a lung.
That's where the chain comes in.
We need the families of the donors and
the recipients to reach out to their people
to find anyone who might be
willing to donate their lung to Gianna.
Why would anyone do this when
they weren't willing to before?
Because they weren't getting
anything in return before.
But now they would
be saving the lives
of everyone in the chain,
including their loved one.
It's a win-win. Win, win...
We don't have a lot of time. Some of
the recipients won't make it past tomorrow.
Then we better do it quickly.
You becoming part of this chain
is our best bet at saving Gianna.
We realize you may
need some time. I'll do it.
You understand
what we're asking?
Give me the knife
and I'll do it myself.
Well, let's hold off on that, but we
do appreciate the enthusiasm. Um...
Now the hard part.
Are you seriously asking
me to donate a lung, too?
No, you would just
be the liver donor.
What I'm asking for is
help finding someone
willing to donate a
portion of their lung.
A second donor.
So, we start this
all over again.
This girl, she is just a child?
Twelve years old.
The only person
she has is her father.
And he is not a match?
Gianna can only qualify for
a "directed organ" transplant.
Without it... No.
We've done everything you've
told us to do. We've done enough.
Is there anyone else?
Another family member?
We need a lung donor
to make this work.
My sister was all
the family I had.
And you know how that ended.
Peter Stern is getting antsy about
donating, and frankly, so are we.
At some point we're
gonna have to move on.
Just not yet. Please.
I'll do what I can on my end, but at
this point, I can't promise anything.
Okay, thanks.
Dora, get me Iggy. Oh.
Hey.
Hi. Hey.
Guess what.
Helen pulled some strings,
got us in with Dr. Britland.
Best oral surgeon in the city.
But something came up.
I'm not trying to
get out of this, okay?
I am just trying to rebuild
this transplant chain,
uh, one piece at a time.
Until each piece falls into place,
but it just keeps falling apart.
You know I'm on Team Max, right?
Of course, I do.
No, I mean I have banners
and hats and... You have a hat?
But sometimes it feels
like I'm the only one.
You're not. I promise. Look,
I want this cancer out of
my body more than anything.
I just have to push this
appointment a few hours.
Just until I can fix this chain.
Hey. Team Max.
Team Max.
I'm here to make it 100%
clear to you what happens
emotionally and physically
after organ donation.
Dr. Frome, Gianna and I
came here from Guatemala.
I was police there.
The gangs, they don't like
it if they cannot corrupt you.
They threatened our lives.
That's why you left? You fled.
When Gianna could not walk
and breathe at the same time,
I carried her.
And when we finally
got to New York...
I made sure we were hidden,
so they could not send us back.
And she got worse.
This is my fault.
And I'm going to fix it.
It doesn't matter
what happens to me.
Okay.
That's all I needed to hear.
Hey, I was just about to head out. I
wanted to see if you needed anything.
Oh.
Are you okay?
I'm scared.
I don't like being alone.
You wanna know a secret?
I don't like being alone either.
What do you say, you and I, we
keep each other company
until your dad gets back?
Yeah? Yeah.
Okay. Come on, scoot over.
Okay.
Hey, you know, Gemini's
boyfriend was my very first crush.
But he's a one-eyed
meteor beast.
Yeah.
Yeah, I was a weird kid.
We shared Gianna's case with all the
families in the Domino Transplant Chain.
And it was a tough
ask of a perfect stranger
to donate a part of their lung.
I, uh...
I understand.
The thing is, Diego, um,
we don't have a
donor for Gianna.
We have 12.
Now with so many volunteers,
we are almost sure to find
a match for Gianna today.
What is it?
- She just stopped breathing.
- BP's dropping.
Got any room on
her dopamine drip?
Maxed out. So is the dobutamine.
Start levophed. Start levophed.
We've got this. NURSE:
Heart rate's up to 120.
Are you sure her heart
can tolerate the levo?
No, but do it anyway. Reynolds?
We've got this.
Come on, Gianna.
Come on.
Come on, come on.
Gianna's heart
is failing, Diego.
Her lungs are so scarred that her
heart can't pump blood through them.
We have to take her to the OR
to put her on an
aortic balloon pump.
That will stabilize her condition and
hopefully it will help her heart recover.
But until it does,
she's not strong enough to
withstand transplant surgery.
I'm sorry.
Take care of my little girl.
We'll give you
some time with her.
I really thought we were
gonna make this chain work.
You're giving up? There's
nothing else to do today,
except hope everyone hangs on.
Is Gianna okay?
We're getting her to the OR now.
Uh, can we talk?
I don't know, can we?
It seems like you've been doing
everything you can not to talk to me.
I deserve that. I got
more, you wanna hear 'em?
Okay, look, uh, Evie and I have
been spending a lot of time together.
And our history makes
that, you know, complicated.
And awkward.
Not for me. Really?
I introduced the two of you.
I mean, shouldn't that
prove that I'm fine with this?
Or do you think I just
like torturing myself?
I mean... Shut up.
Come on, stop being weird.
We're friends and we're fine.
Now, can you just
please go and fix Gianna?
All right.
You can't lock me in here!
Okay, we can talk about that,
but not while you're yelling.
It's not even my fault!
Janine was messing
with my machine.
And I told her to stop
it and she wouldn't!
Wow, you really... You really
cared about that project, huh?
Yeah. Okay.
So, then why did you break it?
All right, um...
Do me a favor and, uh, just
close your eyes for a second.
Jemma, close them.
Close them, please. Thank you.
All right, now I want you
to picture that machine.
I want you to see it broken
in pieces all over the ground.
How does that make you feel?
Sad, I guess. Okay.
Why sad? Because it's a waste.
All right, what else?
It's...
sad because...
it's useless now
and nobody wants it.
Jemma. I know what
you're gonna say.
You do?
Okay, all right,
smarty-pants. Then tell me.
What am I gonna say?
No one wants me.
Why would I say that?
It's not true. Yes, it is.
No, it's not. Blanca wants you.
Yeah, today she does.
Someday she won't.
Look, I'm gonna
mess it up. I always do.
No, I don't believe
that. Not for a second.
I know that trusting
people is scary.
That's the scariest thing.
But when it comes to family,
that's just the
price of admission.
That's the way it goes.
And nobody deserves a
family more than you do.
Nobody.
Trust me.
You don't have to go.
But...
If you do decide to
take that leap of faith,
I'll be there with you.
I hate feeling like I'm
giving up on these people.
Max, when have you
ever given up on anyone?
Right now, if you don't
take care of yourself,
how are you gonna
take care of them?
- Max.
- What's going on?
Is everyone okay?
Everyone's fine.
Diego?
May I still give to the chain?
What did he say?
The Domino Chain's a go.
Okay. I hereby bequeath unto you
the "Holy Sticky
Notes." Such an honor.
We're gonna be
late. Text me, okay?
I wanna know everything that's
going on, every step of the way.
Absolutely. That sounds
like a great use of my time.
I want a full play-by-play, right?
Leave no patient's condition un-texted.
Leave no surgeon's
incision un-communicated.
Max, you're headed into
quadruple molar extraction.
You'll be under anesthesia
for hours. I can multitask.
Just please say "okay," so I
can push him into a passing cab.
Okay. I'll text so frequently,
you'll need a new data plan.
That's what I'm talking about.
Donor Diego Morales' right liver
lobe has been isolated and extracted.
The donor liver has arrived for
transplant recipient Aminah Ali.
And meet me there
Bundles of flowers We
wait through the hours of cold
Good news? KAPOOR:
Your organ just landed.
I'll be here with you
every step of the way.
Shelter as we go
Go ahead.
And promise me this
You'll wait for me only
Scared of the lonely arms
Surface, far below these burn
Welcome home, kiddo.
And maybe
Just maybe I'll come home
Matty's in recovery.
Congratulations.
Your chain is complete.
Our chain.
Do you know, in Oncology,
you get so few wins.
It becomes harder and harder to
believe that things will ever work out.
Oh, I thought for sure
this would not work out.
But it did.
Welcome back.
Gianna.
How is she?
Ask her yourself.
Cómo estás, Papi?
We were able to shore up her
heart enough to do her transplant.
She got her lung?
Your daughter is a fighter.
Just like Gemini.
She gets it from her mother.
I get it from you, Papi.
Thank you.
Thank you, Doctor. Ah.
I only saved one life today.
You saved six.
Now that was awesome.
Yes, it was.
Hey, you wanna have
lunch with me and Evie?
Her favorite spot's
this place on 23rd
where they literally put
everything on a donut.
As tempting as, uh, that sounds,
I think I'm just gonna
head home and chill.
Chill?
Later.
Don't keep her waiting.
Hey, what are you doing
here? So, the thing is...
I do wanna walk
into work with you.
Haven't seen you
in a while, Dr. Bloom.
Welcome home.
Bronx General
Emergency Department.
Hey, uh, it's Dr. Lauren Bloom.
Can I still pick up
that shift tonight?
Morning, sleepyhead.
Ready for breakfast?
Well, lunch.
Bone broth.
Yummy.
Oh, Helen texted you all right.
So many texts.
Lot of, uh,
complicated doctor talk.
But there's only one thing
you need to know right now.
"Our Domino Chain
was a complete success.
"Thank you for never
letting us lose hope."
You can read the rest after
you've had your bone broth.
You can try and try
Even if it lasts an hour
With all our might We'll
try and make it ours
Because we're on our way
We're on our way to fall in love
Yeah, we're on our
way to fall in love
We'll do it together.
One piece at a time.
Until each piece
falls into place.
We're on our way to fall in love