Move it or lose it! Whoa.
Sorry, boss, I, uh,
didn't realize it was you.
Malucci, as an ER resident,
you should know
enough to wear a helmet.
Don't worry, I got a
melon like a wrecking ball.
Been hit three times,
nothing worse than road rash.
Let me ask you something,
you always been at County?
Gosh. Going on 10 years.
Damn. Guys kill their entire
families don't get 10 years.
It's not a prison, Dave.
I don't know about that.
Dr. Weaver acts like a warden.
Hey, what's with the leg?
She lay her Harley
down in traffic?
I don't know. I never asked.
So you wanna lift?
On your bike? Yeah, why not?
Never ride double before?
Not since I was 8 years old,
had a sissy bar
and a banana seat.
A what?
Forget it. Before your
time. Thanks anyway.
All right, suit yourself.
See you in the trenches.
Watch out!
You're such a good boy.
Jeanie.
Daddy's home.
There you go.
Hey. Hi.
Sorry I'm late. I got held up.
It's okay. No problem.
Better get going,
you'll be late.
How's my buddy?
Say goodbye to Mommy, Carlos.
"Bye, Mommy. Bye, baby.
Daddy and I are gonna
watch some ESPN."
Oh, hey, the med schedule is...
On the fridge.
Don't forget to wear gloves...
Jeanie, don't
worry. We'll be fine.
Okay. Love you.
Love you too. Have
a good day. Okay.
We don't have this department.
You have to go to the V.A.
No, no, no.
I've gotta get to work,
and I can't cross
the kids safely
if I can't hold up my sign.
Why can't you
hold it in that hand?
That's my whistle hand.
Here. Problem solved.
Randi, can you help
this gentleman, please?
You better not have parked
your bike in the lounge again.
It's not. There's a rack
in the ambulance bay.
I know. My bike's
not in the lounge.
Take Jesse Keenan, Curtain
1. Severe abdominal pain.
Hey, how you doing,
Jesse. I'm Dr. Dave.
I'm not feeling too well.
Well, what's the problem?
Oh, that's colorful.
All right.
Lucy, meet Jesse.
Not my patient.
Come on, he is now.
I gotta get my bike
out of the lounge
before Weaver shoots
me. Hey, isn't that your bike?
Hey!
Ooh, that's gonna leave a mark.
He is so cute. How's
Reggie like being a dad?
He's loving it. Who took
Mr. Opotoski's chart?
Every time I turn
around one of the nurses
is taking my chart.
You left this in
the suture room.
I wasn't in there.
- You're welcome.
- Dr. Lawrence.
Dr. Carter.
A grateful patient gave
me two Blackhawks tickets.
Right behind the penalty
box, you interested?
Trauma on ice. Who could say no?
What do we got here?
Guy slashed with a knife.
Looks pretty clean
and superficial.
Uh-huh. Check this
out. This is Dermabond.
Been using it since
January. It's pretty nifty stuff.
Like medical Super Glue.
Army had that in the '60s.
Come on. Yeah, really.
Took the FDA 30 years to
approve it for civilian use.
Probably better
update his tetanus.
Gabe, did you work up the
woman with the dog bite?
Is there a problem?
I can't read the chart.
It's illegible.
You're not supposed to
read a physician's writing.
Didn't I teach you
that in med school?
Ha! You were a
student? All right. Look.
Admit it. Hey, you
can't even read that.
That's for security purposes.
Why not put your
orders into the computer?
Because the computer
crashes. My notes don't.
I'll help with the computer.
Great idea, Carter.
Haven't you heard the saying:
"You can't teach an
old dog new tricks."
You're not old. Just stubborn.
Hi. Hello.
Elaine. John.
Dr. Gabe Lawrence,
this is Elaine Nichols.
Nice to meet you.
Have you got a minute,
John? Would you excuse us?
Yeah, certainly.
Hey, Dr. Lawrence. Dr. David.
It's just Dave. Listen.
You're an old friend
of Weaver's, right?
She ever tell you about her leg?
Not that I can recall, why?
Just curious.
Don't look at me. Ask
Carter. He lived with her.
Really? Mm-hm.
I'm doing everything
by the book.
I even gave up caffeine.
Are you getting plenty
of rest? I'm trying.
I'm really sorry about
the cafeteria thing,
but I got a new job at
the Big-T Pharmacy.
And I, um...
I gave them your name as
a reference, if that's okay.
Uh, sure.
I told them I've known
you for a couple of years.
Just in case they call.
But I doubt they will.
Something wrong with my eyes?
Are you taking any medications?
Just, um, prenatal vitamins.
Good.
Okay, I'll be back.
Why don't you take
a break? I'll cover.
Aw. Thanks.
Could you send this up to
the lab? UA and a tox screen?
Sure thing. Thank you.
Taking a breather?
My breathing's fine,
but my ankles are
about to explode.
I wonder if I could
wrap them in duct tape.
Don't think that's recommended.
Is this our MVA?
Yeah, Benjamin
Hearn, 16, with CF.
Auto versus pedestrian,
blunt trauma to the right side.
How you feeling, Ben?
Hurts to breathe.
Tachy at 130, BP's 110/72.
Did you take his temperature?
Okay. Call me if
you need me. Bye.
Okay, there's no
sign of a fracture.
Did his blood work come back?
Jeanie? Yeah?
Blood work? Oh.
No, it isn't back yet.
Is everything okay? You
seem a little distracted.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
Carlos was a bit
off this morning,
and Reggie's still getting
used to the dad routine.
Well, why don't you call and
make sure everything's okay?
I did. Everything's fine.
I just hate being away from him.
What do we got?
Rib fractures,
possible liver laceration.
When were you last
hospitalized for cystic fibrosis?
About a year ago. Ow!
Rebound and guarding,
right upper quadrant.
Let's get a CBC, type and cross
for four, chest, and a C-spine.
Okay, let's get ultrasound.
Carol, call up for an
O.R., tell 'em hold on.
And let's get Genetics down
here for a pre-op consult.
Oh!
Carol? Carol, you okay?
I think I'm having
a contraction.
Okay, why don't you step out.
No.
It's gone. I'm fine. Must
have been a Braxton Hicks.
Carol, go sit down. If
you have another one,
you're going on a monitor.
Soft, mild tenderness.
No rebound.
Let's get a tox
screen, CBC, Chem-7,
liver panel, and a lead test.
Coming right up.
So, Jesse, how much
paint did you eat?
I don't know. Like,
half a tube, maybe.
And do you do this very often?
Just this once.
I had a pretty bad day.
You depressed?
Creatively challenged.
So you're an artist? No.
Francis Bacon, William
Blake. Those guys were artists.
You know, I'm actually
feeling pretty good now...
I don't know. No.
You gotta stay.
We need to run some tests,
and I wanna check
the toxicity of the paint.
You must think I'm
pretty stupid, huh?
Eh. Creatively challenged.
Dr. Benton, Roger
Julian, Genetics.
This your CF patient?
Yeah, 16-year-old needs
a laparotomy for a liver lac.
I'd like you to sign off
on general anesthesia.
What are his room-air
sats? 97 percent.
How's his x-ray? No infiltrates.
Okay. Uh, give me five minutes.
Let's set up for
bedside spirometry.
His father's here.
I'll be right there.
Peter, you got this? Yeah, go.
Hey. Any more contractions? No.
Perhaps you should go home
and get off your feet for a while.
I'm fine, Mark.
As long as these guys stop
using my bladder for soccer.
Still, maybe you should
back off the big traumas.
You know? Slow
things down a little.
I don't need you
worrying about me.
Somebody's got
to worry about you.
I've gotta pee.
Ultrasound showed a
tear in Benjamin's liver.
Is he gonna be okay?
He has an excellent
chance of survival,
but he's gonna need
surgery to repair the damage.
Should we donate blood?
We have to operate immediately.
We'll use a cell saver to
give him back his own blood.
If he requires a transfusion,
I can assure you our blood
supply has been screened.
No, I don't want
Benjamin getting blood
from some stranger.
Okay. Chuny, would you type
and screen Mr. Hearn and his son?
They want to be designated
donors to Benjamin Hearn.
Sure. You wanna follow me?
I'm sorry I didn't
return your calls.
And I apologize
for standing you up.
It's okay.
I guess I just needed
time to sort things out.
And have you?
I think so.
You don't have to worry
about me anymore, John.
I'm... I'm gonna be okay.
And your follow-up?
I'm seeing a plastic
surgeon on Wednesday.
And after that, um...
I'm thinking about
going to Europe.
For how long?
I don't know. Couple months.
Just do a little soul searching.
So this is goodbye.
This is thank you.
For everything.
Will you give me a
call when you get back?
I'll send you a postcard.
Hey, Carter. Uh...
Is true you lived with
Weaver? In her basement.
She kept you in the basement?
She was my landlady. Okay. Sure.
So when your landlady
was collecting rent,
you must have
seen her leg, right?
Go away, Dave.
Come on... Hey, Lucy.
I'm not talking to you.
Why's everybody so
grumpy around here?
Unit contacting County
General, meet me on one-alpha.
County from Rescue 43
at a multi-victim incident.
How many can you take?
Two and eight. Two
major, eight minor.
Page Benton and Corday.
Let's prep Trauma 1 and 2.
Kidney failure, liver damage,
your red blood cells
could literally explode.
Okay, okay, you made your point.
I won't eat any more paint.
And what about the cocaine?
Your urine tested positive.
Okay, so on occasion I...
I have used some
mind-expanding chemicals
to facilitate my
creative process.
I'm not the first
artist to do so.
But you've been using
them the last few days.
I wanna put you
in a rehab program.
I appreciate your
concern, but I'm really cool.
I've been under a lot of
stress lately, my work sucks.
Maybe your work suffers
because you're using cocaine.
Jesse, you came here
for help, so let me help you.
Do they let you paint
in these programs?
I'm sure arrangements
could be made.
What do you think?
I don't know. I can't
promise anything.
I'll check it out though. Great.
Explosion in a
high-school science class.
I told them we could take
two major and eight minor.
Feeling generous, were you?
Victor Sutherland,
52-year-old teacher.
Altered LOC,
respiratory distress,
BP is 90/60, pulse,
120. What's he saying?
HAZMAT said it was chlorine gas.
It's okay, don't try to
speak. Lungs are wet.
Tube him. Any other criticals?
He's the worst.
Gabe, triage the others
and watch the
residents. No problem.
What is this? What
do we got here?
Ken Kranics, 17. Blunt
head trauma with LOC.
Tubed him for a
respiratory rate of four.
BP, 124/86. Pulse, 74.
Get a head CT,
call Neurosurgery. I'm on it.
Call me if you need
me. Need a hand?
No, there's more
on the way. Malucci?
What's going on?
Science room explosion.
There's a dozen more
coming in. This is Quinn.
Looks like partial
thickness burns
to the head, face and hands.
Nothing circumferential.
She's wheezy.
16-year-old Leanne Lawler,
penetrating abdominal injury.
Not sure how deep.
BP, 95/65. Pulse, 110.
We gave her a
liter in the field.
Pull this thing out of me.
We will. Hang in there.
Right over the spleen.
We need an ultrasound
before we go to O.R.
What's open? Trauma 1.
Looks like a Colles' fracture
with an overlying laceration.
That's a Grade 1 open fracture.
The bone punctured the skin.
Should I set up for
an open reduction?
Only if there's more than 20
degrees of dorsal angulation.
You want something for
the pain? No, I'm okay.
Gram of Ancef.
Stop it! You're not helping
any! You have to let me irrigate.
How we doing here? He's
already had 10 of morphine.
Glass injuries to
the eyes and face...
Dr. Lawrence?
Should I give this guy mannitol?
It's tricky. I see papilledema...
What do you mean? Slower.
My head trauma patient.
He hasn't blown a
pupil, but his GCS is nine
and disc margins are blurred.
Do you think he needs mannitol?
Has he blown a pupil? No, no.
They're 4 mm,
equal and reactive.
No, hold off. Wait
for the head CT.
What were you saying? Huh? What?
Thin cuts...? Yeah, yeah.
Thin cuts through the
orbits. Ophthal consult.
Titrate some Ativan.
I-I can't see anything.
You're in good hands, son.
In good hands.
Dr. Lawrence,
Janet Gunderson, 17,
chest hit the edge of a desk.
Complains of pleuritic
pain. Pulse, 100, BP, 132/74.
What's open?
Try Curtain 3. Chest
x-ray and an EKG.
Dr. Lawrence, we got a
finger amputation here.
Is the finger on ice?
He gave it to a friend,
who seems to have lost it.
All right, give him
a gram of Ancef,
an aspirin suppository and
call the reimplantation service.
Don't worry...
Something for pain?
Ten of lidocaine.
I'll do a wrist block.
Dr. Lawrence, we could use
you. What...? What patient?
The girl with the hand
burns and the facial burns.
Malucci's worried
about her lungs.
What are you putting on
me? It's just antibiotic ointment.
Did you call the burn team?
Yep, 8 percent body area.
Second degree
burns. Dr. Lawrence.
Vancomycin okay for my patient?
What patient? Hand injury.
The amputation?
No, the wrist kid.
You said Ancef, but
he's allergic to penicillin.
Fine. What room
is he in? Exam 4.
All right, all right, I'll
be there in a minute.
Should I give steroids?
Steroids? Yeah.
For the wheezing.
No, I wouldn't.
Why not?
It... It's not good. Just
don't do it. Trust me.
How you doing?
All I did was puke.
You weren't in the explosion?
No. Is that what happened?
Sounds pretty crazy out there.
Yeah.
Take slow deep breaths, okay?
Haleh, you got the drug
key? I need 10 of morphine.
Thanks.
Coming through! Coming through!
HAZMAT... MAN
2: Let's run the tests.
Dr. Lawrence, we
need you in here.
I'm in. Bag him.
Kerry, what's up?
Ah, I could use an
extra pair of hands.
His lungs are full of fluid.
It's the pulmonary
edema from the chlorine.
Still hypotensive
after decompressing
a tension pneumo.
32 French right here.
Better check the belly.
10 blade. Let's get
ultrasound in here.
It's tied up in the other
room. I'll do a DPL.
Uh, Dr. Lawrence? Yeah.
My EKG. Um, my patient
may have a sternal fracture,
with the QRS voltage.
I'm afraid of tamponade.
So do a cardiac
echo. Okay, but...
Do it... Just do the damn echo.
What the hell is this?
Peritoneal lavage kit.
It's a percutaneous kit.
Use the Seldinger technique.
No, I want to do an open lavage.
No, it's a new kit.
They work well.
Where's the drug box?
Just get me a scalpel,
couple of towel clips, a
pair of rakes, and a... And a...
A cur...
- You know, a cur... What?
- A hemostat?
Hemostat? Yeah, yeah!
Come on! Hurry up.
Come on, come on.
It's fairly easy to use, Gabe.
You just spread the guide-wire
through the thin-wall
needle, and then...
These are unreliable!
Half the time you wind up
in the preperitoneal space.
I think if you tried...
I said no, damn it!
I always do an open
technique. It's the gold standard.
That's what I'm gonna
do. These are crap!
Dr. Lawrence. Yeah.
The finger amputation is
ready for his wrist block.
Right.
You seem to have everything
under control here, Kerry.
Another patient needs me.
I'm sorry, Kerry.
That was unprofessional
and totally uncalled-for.
Do you wanna talk about it?
There's nothing to talk about.
I... I screwed
up. I lost my cool.
It's been a while since I've
had multiple casualties like that.
If you were in trouble, you
should have asked for help.
You had your hands full.
I... No, I was... I was
overloaded, that's all.
It happens to the best of us.
You remember that time,
you were third year, I think.
A double-decker
tour bus hit a bridge
and sheared off the
top, you remember that?
That was an insane trauma.
That was a little hectic.
A little hectic?
There were three
gurneys in every space.
Everybody lost it.
But you kept your cool.
I don't know if I should
be telling you this...
What is it, Gabe?
There were times
when you drove me nuts.
You were like having
10 other students.
I swear to God, you...
You asked more questions than
I thought was humanly possible.
But it paid off. I'm
proud of you, Kerry.
Chief of Emergency Medicine.
You were great in there.
Damn, I was a good teacher.
You were and you still
are, according to Carter.
Yeah, well...
I think you're making a big
mistake with these lavage kits,
but I'll use 'em.
It's your ER now.
For the record, my
way may be older,
but it's still
faster and better.
Kind of like me.
Are you taking any
pain medication?
No. Why?
Your urine tested
positive for opiates.
What do you mean?
You know what I mean.
You're taking drugs,
which means your
baby is taking drugs.
What is it? Codeine?
Heroin? I'm not using drugs.
If you're sharing needles,
you're putting both
you and your baby
at risk for hepatitis,
HIV, endocarditis...
I'm not sharing needles.
But you are using.
Meg, I know you
care about your baby.
I do. I do care.
You don't want
to hurt it, do you?
No.
Then you have to
stop. I'm hardly using...
Just...
Just a little. Just
so I don't get sick.
You can't use at all.
Let me put you
into a detox program
and help you get clean.
Okay.
I'll see what I can do.
You're putting him
on a psych hold?
No, it's voluntary admission.
He's willing to come in.
I'll call down when
the bed's open. Thanks.
So did I pass the audition?
Yep. You should
go up within the hour.
They won't let me paint.
I'm sorry. It's okay.
They said I could sketch.
Thanks.
For helping me.
I really needed it.
Dr. Myers. Carol.
Hi.
I have, uh, an expectant mother
in need of a rehab bed.
Any way you could see her?
I just gave our last
spot to a guy in Exam 1.
She's pregnant.
I'm sorry. We only
have so many spots.
I can sign her up for an
outpatient program now.
Any chance to sign the guy
up for an outpatient program?
We're talking about the
welfare of an unborn child here.
Let's see what we
got. Where is she?
Thanks. In here.
Hey.
Hey, uh, how's it going?
Have you spoken to Ben yet?
No. Is he doing okay?
Uh, you know what?
Uh, let's talk in here.
Is something wrong with
Ben? No, no, he's gonna be fine.
It's just that when I
screened your blood, uh...
you tested, um... HIV positive.
You should have told me.
I didn't know for sure.
Until now.
Well, I-I... I'm sorry.
I figured this would
happen sooner or later.
You didn't practice safe sex?
Apparently not.
You know, I could
send you to a clinic.
You could start treatment.
The sooner the better.
You're not gonna tell
my parents, are you?
No, that's your
choice. But... Listen.
You know, family
support is very important
when you're dealing with HIV.
Support? Are you kidding?
My old man would disown me.
You know, I-I tried
telling him once.
I did the whole:
"I've got this
friend who's gay."
He freaked.
He said that if I ever
brought a fag to his house,
he'd kick my ass.
It would be easier
for your treatment
if your family knew the truth.
No.
No, forget it. I...
Every family has their
secrets anyway. Right?
Could you see a
possible CVA in Exam 2?
No, ask Carter. I gotta
finish these charts.
You took my spot. What?
My patient's detox spot.
Oh, Dr. Meyers said he
could be an outpatient.
After you convinced him.
Yeah, well, we needed the
spot for a pregnant woman.
If she doesn't get off heroin...
You can't do that.
You're a nurse, and I...
You're a what?
You're a med student!
I didn't know he was yours.
I'm sure he'll be admitted soon.
That's easy for you to
say. You got the bed.
Did you find Lawrence?
Yep. And?
And... what?
Practically had a meltdown
in the trauma room.
That's a little melodramatic,
don't you think?
I don't know. I,
uh... Come on, Mark.
Gabe is not the first
doctor to lose his temper
in the heat of the moment.
Over a lavage kit?
You know what?
He's been doing
this for 30 years.
He's set in his ways.
Doesn't like newer equipment.
I know you two are close.
What are you
trying to say, Mark?
He's acting a bit strange.
Not setting a good example.
Yeah, he's eccentric.
He's also one of the best
doctors I've ever worked with.
Don't get defensive. I'm not.
You don't like
that I hired Gabe.
But I did, so deal with it.
I repaired Ben's
liver. He's doing well.
Any complications?
He lost blood in the operation,
so we gave him a transfusion,
but, uh, I expect him
to make a full recovery.
You gave him our blood, right?
Well, just yours. I... I
couldn't use Aaron's.
Why not? Well, it
wasn't a good match.
Nurse said that we all
had the same blood type.
Yeah, yeah, I know,
but Aaron's blood
has different antigens
that could have caused
a transfusion reaction.
I'm sorry.
It's not your fault.
The important thing is
that Ben's gonna be all right.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. Mm-hm.
Thanks.
Most of your friends were
brought in an hour ago.
Where were you hiding?
I wasn't hiding.
I just didn't think
it was so bad.
How's my teacher,
Mr. Sutherland?
I haven't heard.
What kind of experiment
were you guys doing?
The wrong one.
What does that mean?
Nothing.
Do you know what
happened today, Howie?
If you have any information
about the explosion,
I think you should let me know.
It might help us
treat Mr. Sutherland.
Do you promise to
keep this between us?
Like, doctor/patient
confidentiality and all that?
All I can promise you
is that you're gonna feel a lot
better if you tell me the truth.
The right eye is
going to be fine,
but the glass sliced
through the left eyeball
and displaced the lens.
Well, uh...
How long before
they can fix that?
It'll be a difficult repair job.
Can I see? I... I
don't think that...
Jeez...
Dad? What...? What
is it? What's wrong?
Everything's okay, Nathan,
we just have to wait
for the specialist.
Is everything okay, Dad?
Mr. Perez, would
you come with me?
- Dad? Where's he going?
- He needs to sign some...
They can't fix that.
I'm not a specialist, sir.
The ophthalmologist...
His eye is gone.
He's gonna be blind.
We don't know that. His other...
He has an athletic scholarship.
I understand. He's
the first to go to college.
Mr. Perez... He worked hard.
Mr. Perez. Now
he's lost everything.
Please.
What's important right now is
that you're here for your son.
He needs you.
Okay?
Is everything okay?
Everything's fine, mijo.
Jeanie. Reggie's on
Line 1. Says it's urgent.
Thanks.
Reggie?
For how long?
Okay. Okay, I will. Bye.
Is everything
okay? Carlos is sick.
I think his pneumonia might be
coming back. I need to get home.
You do. Go on. Thanks.
Did they bring in a patient
named Howie McMurtry?
I don't know. Why?
Tell her.
Howie's the one that
caused the explosion.
The jocks talked
me into doing it.
I switched the chemicals.
It was only supposed to be
a small exothermic reaction.
A little smoke and a
few bubbles, that's all.
But Mr. Sutherland
changed the experiment,
and I didn't have a
chance to warn him.
This wasn't supposed to
happen. It was just a joke.
You little son of a bitch.
I'm sorry, sir?
My son is blind because of you.
It wasn't my idea, Mr. Perez.
Nathan and his
friends told me to do it.
You have to leave.
You're a liar! Hey. Hey.
Get out of the
way. Hey... Security!
It was an accident!
Hey! HOWIE: Stop it!
Get off of him! Get
off of him. Get away!
Get off of him!
You okay?
Yeah.
Sir. Sir!
He's not breathing.
We have to intubate?
No. Let's get him
to the bed. Okay?
Let's get him in here.
Go. All right.
Go, go, go, go, go!
Let's get him out.
All right, give me
an 8-0 ET tube.
I need suction.
Thanks for pulling
him off of me.
Just get the tube in, Carter.
Is he okay?
Let's get him on a pulse ox.
All right.
I'm in. Let's bag him.
No breath sounds.
He's not pinking up.
It was good intubation,
I saw the cords.
Aw, man, he's blowing
up like a balloon.
Subcutaneous emphysema.
You broke his larynx?
Let's prep his
neck, I'll do a crike.
No, uh, the injury could
be below the cricoid.
We're gonna have to trach him.
What about the tube?
Pull it out. It's useless.
Pulse ox is falling to 81.
Heart rate's down to 50.
Amp of atropine.
Carter, blow some
oxygen down there.
I'm not seeing his chest rise.
Pulse ox, 76.
Run of five.
I see it. Need a crash cart.
Okay.
I'm in. Bag him.
I'm getting breath sounds.
Pulse ox up to 85.
That was a nice save.
Yeah.
Good news, Quinn, I spoke
with the plastic surgeon,
and he said that your burns
shouldn't leave much scarring.
Right. Well, um...
I'll check on you later.
If you need anything,
just hit the buzzer.
I'm gonna have scars?
The new skin may have
irregular pigmentation.
But it's only temporary.
How temporary?
Six months to a year.
The plastic surgeon
will give you the details.
I might look like
this for a year?
No, no.
Um, it will take up to
a year for you to heal,
but you... You may, in
fact, heal much faster.
Okay?
How much faster?
I don't know.
It will get a little
bit better each day.
You know...
You were lucky, Quinn. It
could have been much worse.
You think this is lucky?
I look like a hideous freak.
No. No. You... No.
You look like, um...
Like a girl who was
fortunate enough
to survive a dangerous accident.
I'd rather be dead
than look like this.
You okay?
Peachy.
You were trying to
protect the patient.
You did the right thing.
Something tells me Mr. Perez
is gonna feel differently.
I was a witness.
Mark. We need to talk.
Howie, you all right?
Yeah.
How's Mr. Perez?
He's gonna be okay.
But not Mr. Sutherland, huh?
I don't know.
A lot of kids thought
he was a geek.
Sometimes he'd mess
up the experiments,
but I think he
did it on purpose,
just to make class
a little more fun.
He was a really good teacher.
There's still a chance
he might recover, right?
Like, a long shot or something?
Like, one in a million?
Yeah.
I told him.
I told my father I
was HIV positive.
Good for you.
He kicked me out.
Well, you know,
he might just need
a little time to deal with it.
He no longer
considers me his son.
Mm.
I'm sorry.
At least he knows the truth now.
Screw him if he can't handle it.
And it might be a few days
before I can get you
into the detox program.
Should have called ahead.
I'm sorry. But in the
meantime, I can get you
into an outpatient program.
Don't sweat it.
Jesse, you need help.
I need a real job.
I watched you here
today, running around.
You, the doctors,
the cops, paramedics.
Everybody's doing
something important,
helping people, saving lives.
And I'm in here for
eating paint. Pathetic.
Why don't I get someone
for you to talk to?
I don't need a shrink to tell me
I need to get my act together.
I'll see you around, Lucy.
Hey, could you, uh, speak
with one of my patients?
No, go away, Dave. I don't
want any more patients.
Why not? By the looks of things,
you fixed that last guy up good.
Yeah, real good.
But this one's
different, all right?
I got a teenage girl who
burned her face in the explosion.
She's really depressed,
and nothing I say seems
to be the right thing.
Really?
About the hockey game tonight,
I'm afraid I'm gonna
have to cancel.
But you go, you go without me.
Everything all right?
Oh, yeah. Everything...
Ah, just something came up.
So I can see.
What?
Well, mood swings, haggard brow.
Inability to concentrate.
Classic signs of woman problems.
Is it that obvious?
Only if you've been married
as many times as I have.
Plus, I met her today, remember?
I never forget a pretty face.
You got any professional advice?
What? From me?
I can diagnose a
million diseases,
but I still can't
figure out women.
I guess that's what
makes them so irresistible.
Yeah.
But I do know...
life's too short to... To...
You know, to waste on regret.
Hm.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Dr. Lawrence. Yeah.
I've got your ankle films.
Has anyone seen Meg Corwin,
the pregnant woman in Curtain 3?
No, sorry.
I think she left.
She was supposed to go to detox.
How's he doing?
Oh, chest is clear.
Satting at 98 on two liters.
I'd, uh... I'd give him
albuterol treatment Q4.
And, uh, I'll stop by tomorrow.
Thanks.
Hey, Dr. Julian, I
wanted to ask you
a question about DNA testing.
What about it?
Sometimes pregnant
teenagers, single mothers,
they have questions
about paternity testing.
I was wondering
if there's anything
that we could, you
know, use down in the ER.
Yeah, we've, uh... We
got a test kit you can use.
Just, um, call my office,
they'll give you the
name of the supplier.
Okay, great. Thanks.
He said my skin
would be discolored.
The new skin will be
sensitive to UV rays.
So you have to be very
diligent about using sunscreen.
So much for my tan next summer.
Ah, your skin will
be healthier for it.
And you'll look younger.
There will come a day, Quinn,
when younger is better.
Trust me.
What about my hair?
It'll be thinner, maybe
a little patchier at first.
But it'll grow back.
How long does that take?
Does your hair grow fast?
No. Heh.
Well, then, uh, you might
have to wear a wig for a while.
A wig?
You could try being a blond.
It's true what
they say about us.
But just be patient, okay?
And if you have any questions,
call me or Dr. Dave. Okay?
Thank you.
Wow, you're good.
Thanks.
No, I mean really good.
You're welcome, Dave.
Dr. Malucci.
Chief.
Heard you, uh,
wanted to see me. No.
No? Hm, I heard you had
a question about my leg.
Me? Uh, no. Not... Not me.
I mean, I... I had a...
A patient with a bad ankle.
But someone must have
misunderstood what I was asking.
Oh. I see.
Well, you know, if you
do ever wanna know,
you should just ask.
No problem.
Yeah, but it's really none
of my business, right?
No. No, it's not.
Well, well, well, if it isn't
the lean, Greene,
fighting machine.
It was an accident, Robert.
Supposed to treat
accidents, not cause them.
It was self-defense.
Oh, he attacked you?
No, he attacked Carter.
But Carter didn't
crush the guy's throat.
Okay, what do you want from me?
A formal apology to
Mr. Perez and his family
would be a good place to start.
Fine. Something else?
Well, hey, hey. Look, I
didn't bring this on, Markie.
I'm gonna do as much
damage control as I can,
but I can't make promises.
This guy's family's
gonna be coming at us
with both barrels blazing.
They're gonna look
for a sacrificial lamb,
and I have to tell you, you
are looking pretty woolly.
ER. Hey, Jeanie. How's Carlos?
Good.
No, no, Kerry left
already. Mark?
Yeah. He's right here, honey.
Hi, Jeanie, it's Mark.
Sorry that I had to rush
out in the middle of my shift.
Yeah, he's better, he
was just a little wheezy.
Would you tell Kerry that I
might be a little late tomorrow?
Thanks, Mark.
Okay. Gotta go. Bye.
Hey, you.
Hey, big boy.
Hey, big boy. Oh!
How's my favorite
little man? Hm?
How's my favorite little man?
John. Hi.
What are you doing here?
Can I come in?
If you want me to
leave, just say so.
I don't want your sympathy.
I know.
Gabe?
Hey, Kerry.
Everything all right?
I think somebody stole my car.
What?
I never leave it unlocked.
I thought maybe
I did. I don't know.
I left the house in such
a hurry this morning.
And are you sure
you're on this level?
What?
Did you park on this level?
Oh, yeah, yeah, I...
Every day I park on four so...
You know, so I wanted
to fight for a space.
This is three.
What an idiot.
You know, after a while
they all look the same.
I swear, I... I'd forget my
head if it wasn't attached.
Do you want me
to help you find it?
No, no, no, no, no. Thanks.
Please. I'll see you tomorrow.
Okay, good night, Gabe.
Yeah, good night.