The dictionary defines grief as:
"Keen mental suffering or
distress over affliction or loss;
sharp sorrow; painful regret."
As surgeons, as scientists,
we're taught to learn
from and rely on books,
on definitions, on definitives.
But in life, strict
definitions rarely apply.
In life, grief can look
like a lot of things
that bear little resemblance
to "sharp sorrow".
"You're not missing much.
New York smells like pee."
God, I hate them.
More pain? Your CT
results should be back soon.
I'm fine.
You should go home tonight.
You can call off the 24-hour
suicide watch, you know. Honestly.
I'm better now. I am.
Do you know what I think?
I think you're using me to avoid
moving in with your boyfriend.
- Am not.
- I'll make you a deal.
You move in with your boyfriend,
and I'll let you call my mum.
- Oh, mean.
- Chicken.
OK, Clara, the CT shows
you have an infection
in your small bowel,
your colon's inflamed.
It's likely something you
picked up in the water,
but it seems to have
formed an abscess,
which means you
need surgery right away.
No.
- Uh, if we don't...
- No. No more surgery.
- I'm not being cut open again.
- OK, uh...
- No.
- You just take a minute.
Take a few minutes and I'll
come back and we'll discuss it.
Um... Start her on pre-op
antibiotics and book an OR.
What are the options? Can
you give me drugs, can you...?
No. You need surgery.
But it's a simple procedure,
- and if it goes as planned...
- My boat ride didn't
go as planned.
So... tell me. Worst case.
Well, worst case is...
we'd have to take
out part of your colon
- and give you a colostomy bag.
- Colostomy bag?
A poo bag, outside your body?
My granddad had
one of those, it was...
- No, it's a small possibility.
- No. No poo bag.
- No surgery.
- The infection will kill you.
No! No more surgery.
No.
We tried pain meds,
treated him for pyelonephritis,
but it could be something
more serious, so we did a CMG.
You did a CMG for a UTI?
Why would you even look for...?
Because we were out of
ideas! The CMG was negative
so we went back to a
possible neurological cause.
If we could get a better look,
if you could give us permission
to get a 3D MRI, we
could maybe, just possibly...
This kid's been in the ER four
times in the last three weeks.
The pain meds aren't
working. Why can't we...?
- Five thousand dollars, Karev.
- Sir?
That's how much you or Dr. Robbins
has to put up to cover that scan.
Otherwise, you can come
with me to my board meeting
this afternoon and explain
why you're running this hospital
like it's a charity.
- Dude, are you crying?
- I have authority issues.
Walk away, Karev.
Where do you get off
killing my patients, Yang?
- Killing?
- You take it upon yourself
to talk that girl out
of life-saving surgery,
- you're killing her.
- I didn't talk her...
She had questions about
the surgery. You left the room.
I left the room to give a very
fragile, very distraught patient
time and space to accept
what's being asked of her.
Then, and only then
would I have discussed
the possible risks with,
I'm certain, more tact
and sensitivity than
you have ever displayed
- in the time I've known you.
- She asked...
I don't care what she asked
you, if she asks you anything else,
your only answer will be,
"Let me ask my attending."
These are good. Do they
sell these in the cafeteria?
- No.
Those are the cancer pops.
Why do cancer
people get all the fun?
How do you feel, Iz?
Not looking forward to the
hurling, but I feel OK, I feel good.
Bailey's on some
sort of rampage.
I think it's Post-O'Malley
Stress Disorder.
- She's not dealing with grief.
- Sounds like Owen's shrink.
Owen's shrink is withholding
sex. So she is grumpy
- and inappropriate.
- Derek doing that, too?
- Withholding sex?
- Why would Derek withhold sex?
Alex is withholding
everything. It's like he's afraid,
- but I don't know
what he's afraid of.
- Afraid of cancer sex.
- Cristina!
- He doesn't want a cancer pop.
- Just shut the hell up.
- I'm not contagious, Cristina.
- I know that.
I would totally
have sex with you.
- Really? Nothing?
- No.
- You don't even want a drawer?
- A toothbrush? Change of panties?
- No.
- Damn. I like your panties.
- I am trying to focus.
I'm becoming a resident
today. I need to focus.
I'm across the street from the
hospital. Crash here sometimes,
- you'll get
a jump on surgeries.
- OK, OK. Which one?
My first day at Mercy West.
I wanna look nice, you know,
serious, talented, hardcore,
not someone you push around.
Nice, but hot. Like me.
- That one.
- Really? I thought this one.
Too hot. Better for
a date. That one.
OK. Here. Eh, thanks.
OK. OK.
- Less hot?
- Less hot.
OK. Good.
Thanks. Wish me luck.
Or not luck, 'cause I'm
all talented and hardcore.
You're an attending.
Go kick some ass.
So, um...
Did you forget to mention
that your hot, hardcore ex
sex friend lives
right across the hall?
- Did I?
- Yeah. Yeah, you did.
And it is only under
my tenure as chief
that Seattle Grace has grown
into one of the most renowned,
lauded and sought after
surgical centers in the country.
Replacing me... no.
Disrupting that process
would be an epic mistake.
It is for that reason that
I stand before you today
and say with the
utmost confidence
that there is no one who
understands and cares more
about Seattle Grace than...
Than me.
Look, this is
ridiculous. I'm fine.
It's a sprained ankle. And I
have a meeting I have to get to.
- Look, I said I'm fine.
- Chief?
- Torres, thank God.
- - You were in a car accident?
Yeah. It was minor. I ran
a red light. I was distracted.
I'm fine. Can we make this quick?
I have a meeting with the board.
Hmm? OK. Let's see.
Ooh!
Ooh, I don't know, sir.
This lac looks pretty deep.
You'll definitely need stitches.
And the ankle... Oh, yikes.
- Yeah. You could need surgery.
- It's a sprain, Torres.
- You two know each other?
- Yeah.
Dr. Webber and I go way
back. We worked together for...
What was it? Five,
six years? Yeah.
I hate to say it, but you
have to have that lac repaired.
Being a teaching hospital,
not to mention Dr. McKee's
first day, I have to
let him work you up,
so... You know how
to do sutures, right?
- Damn straight.
- Great.
Good seeing you, chief.
She's... She's just kidding
about this being my first day.
It's... It's my eighth.
What kind of sutures
are you using?
- Uh... 3-0 nylon.
- No, no, no.
Use DERMABOND. Takes
less time and heals quicker.
Yeah, I know, but, like,
budget cuts, you know?
You like working in
this place, Dr... McKee?
- You think
it's a strong program?
- It rocks.
Like, day eight and I'm doing
unsupervised procedures.
- Not too shabby.
- Hmm... Not too shabby.
He trained at Northwestern
and then at Harvard.
He grew up five miles away
from here. Not rich, not poor.
Comfortable and well
loved by his parents, but...
itching to do something
more with his life.
Which is when he
enlisted at the age of...
Cristina, this is
not a book report.
I'm trying to explain to Dr. Wyatt
that I know things about you.
- Cristina...
- Wait! He knows things about
me, too, if that's what you were
gonna say. We talk all the time.
Honey?
- "Honey?
- " - Cristina, let me be clear.
It's not that I want the two of
you to get to know each other.
It's that I want Owen to
feel comfortable with you.
Oh, he is comfortable with me.
It's fine. You can
talk to her. It's fine.
OK, Cristina, um...
He talks to you. He's
comfortable with you.
Does he talk to you
about his trauma?
Does Owen talk to
you about the war?
Does he talk to you about
the incident between you two?
The choking?
Owen's post-traumatic
stress is fed
by his avoidance of talking
about anything in the war.
In order to improve, to heal,
he's going to have
to start talking about it.
To you, and to me.
And my concern is if you
get lost in the lust of it all,
he won't have to make a start.
He won't have any reason to.
He'll feel that he has everything
he needs, until he doesn't.
So I'm asking you... to wait.
- Finished.
- Read it back to me.
"Hi, Mom. Please prepare yourself.
This is gonna be difficult to read.
- I've been in an accident."
- That's not what I said.
"I've suffered
terrible injuries..."
You can't send that.
"I'm suffering from an infection
which I've refused to treat,
so I'm gonna die soon.
Please come quickly, Mom,
and if I'm gone
before you get here,
I wanted to tell you
how much I love you."
- Stop it.
- "Thank you for making me
- from scratch."
- You bitch! You're a bitch!
I can hit the call button and have
the nurses take you into surgery.
- Or I can hit send. That's the deal.
- I will sue you.
I will sue you
and this hospital.
No, you won't. You'll be dead.
Please.
Hello, the nurses
said you called for me?
This is Andy.
Andy Michaelson.
I'm sorry, have I
treated you before?
Dr. Arizona Robbins referred us.
Oh, Andy!
- You're the kid with the...
- With the thing no one
can diagnose?
- Yeah, that's us.
- Dr. Robbins sent you here
- to Mercy West because...?
- These are copies of Andy's
paperwork
from Seattle Grace.
We don't sleep anymore.
We basically go to the hospital.
I don't know what else to do.
- I feel like a terrible mother.
- Mom.
I feel like a terrible mother
because I'm supposed to...
I'm supposed to do something.
And I can't, you know?
I didn't go to medical school.
I majored in freaking history.
You're the doctors, you
know? You're the doctors.
And, basically, all we've
been doing up to this point,
any of us, is getting my
kid strung out on pain meds.
- Mom, stop.
- I can't, Andy!
I can't stop.
We don't sleep.
He can't sleep.
We can't sleep.
And I'm scared.
And Dr. Robbins said that what she needs
you to give us is a 3D MRI of his spine.
She said you wouldn't want to
'cause there's no
indication or whatever,
but she says that's
what he needs.
Please.
I can't be this useless. And
you know what? Neither can you.
Please.
That's a lot of
necrotic small bowel.
- Can you save any of it?
- - Yesterday, I could have.
Yesterday, this would've
been a simple drainage.
But that was before
Dr. Yang threatened my patient
with a colostomy
that, thankfully, will not
be necessary because it did
not actually involve the colon.
- How can I help?
- Oh, you've done enough.
She asked me a question.
I was right to
answer it. I did my job!
A patient asked me to disclose
the risks of a surgical procedure,
and I am required by
law and my oath to do so.
If you know a way to sugar-coat
a colostomy bag, I'd like to hear it.
If you know a more respectful way
to speak to an attending surgeon,
I'd like to hear that! Until
you do, you don't talk to me.
You're off my service.
OK, seriously? What
is your problem?
More suits? It's
freaking people out.
Talk of downsizing, corporate takeover,
rumors that Webber's jumping ship.
You've got the chief's
ear. What's he got planned?
- Here's the test.
- Thank you.
He's retiring. They're
making me chief.
- No!
- Yeah.
- Really?
- Really? Wow.
- Yep. Mm-hmm.
I mean, the chief never
said anything to me.
I would've fought
you hard for that.
But hell, I guess if
that's what he wants,
congratulations are in order.
Wait. That was...
- You're messing with me?
- It's just too easy.
You got a mean
streak, you know that?
- Yeah.
- Mean!
- Seriously, what's going on?
- I have no idea.
Oh... I have wine.
White and red.
And I have cigarettes.
Which is awful, I know.
I only smoke them very occasionally
when I know I'm gonna be in trouble.
- Like now.
- It was inappropriate.
Not to mention
manipulative and stupid.
- You smoke?
- I know. Listen, I know.
You have every right to
be mad, I ran out of options.
It's expensive! There
was no indication!
There's a reason
Webber turned you down!
- So you didn't do it.
- Of course I did it, Arizona.
- Thank you.
- No. Don't thank me yet.
- The scan didn't show anything.
- What? Come on. Nothing?
No.
That looks a little funny to me.
I thought so too, but the
radiologist said it's normal.
OK, all right. Here.
Was there anything
peculiar about his H&P?
Oh!
Sorry! Sorry!
- Sorry! Sorry, we're sorry.
- Sorry!
We'll be sure to
clean the countertop.
You didn't used
to do this before.
And now it's kind
of all the time.
- Everywhere. And...
- You know, it's...
We're married now.
Things have changed a little.
But sorry about the countertop.
So you guys are... That's it?
The Post-it? That's for real?
Yeah. That's for real.
- What are you reading?
- This patient I'm trying
to diagnose.
- It's driving me nuts.
- So take a break. I miss you.
- Well... I'm right here.
- No, you're not.
You're here, but you're
not here, and I miss you.
Iz, come on, I'm trying to work.
I'm wishing for a brain tumor.
I'm wishing, all the time,
for a giant tumor that
would press on my brain and
make me hallucinate George.
So that I could
talk to him again.
So I could laugh
with him again. I...
I miss him.
So much. I miss
him all the time.
And I just want to feel
better, even for a minute.
I just want to be a person who
isn't wishing for a brain tumor.
Just for one minute.
And I can't drink because
of the cancer meds,
I don't do drugs, I can't even
work. I don't have any distractions.
I'm sad.
And I miss George. So please...
Please, come inside
and help me feel better.
"I miss George."
Nice. Real seductive.
Oh. Hey. Is Mark around?
- He's in the shower.
- Oh, thanks.
Have you heard anything about
what's happening with the chief?
There's all these rumors
floating around Mercy West,
like he might be coming to work
for us. That'd not go well for me.
I haven't heard. I'll
check with Derek.
- Thanks.
- Can you hand me the shampoo?
- Thank you.
- Mmm-hmm.
Are you really gay?
Like, how gay are you
on a scale of one to...
gay? 'Cause that's my boyfriend.
In the shower. My hot,
hot, naked boyfriend.
And I... How gay are you?
I'm sorry. It's...
I've known Mark a while and...
But I'll... try not
to do that again.
The naked in the shower thing.
Or the you half-naked
in the hallway thing.
'Cause even if you
really are gay, he's not.
And... and you're hot.
He doesn't look at
my boobs anymore.
The first thing he used to look
at when I walked in anywhere
was my boobs.
He doesn't look anymore.
Not since he met you.
- OK?
- OK.
- Shepherd?
- You're a hard man to track down.
- I'm busy, as you know.
- Scoping out Mercy West?
You planning on jumping ship?
Because I assume, as a friend,
you'd tell me anything
I need to know.
- Those are rumors, Derek.
- There are a lot of rumors.
And Jennings isn't
answering my calls.
Why are you calling Jennings?
I told you I'd fill you in when
there was something to tell.
You feel the need to
go behind my back...
Behind your back?
I'm the one who's got your back.
Don't you forget that.
- Dr. Shepherd, have a minute?
- Yes. For what?
A kid with a tethered spinal
cord. I thought tethered spinal cord.
You're not gonna see it on there.
I need another test to confirm.
A tethered cord's rare.
He have spina bifida?
- No.
- Lower back lesions? Hyperreflexia?
No and no. But the pain
is aggravated when he
extends or flexes his spine. I
know what you're gonna say.
A tethered cord shows up on
the MRI. But what if it didn't?
What if what this kid
needs is not an MRI,
- but a specific CT myelogram.
- Maybe.
- Order one.
- I can't.
Because if I did, I'd get
fired and I really like my job.
- Did the chief deny
that request?
- Several times.
You should've led with
the part about the chief.
Come on.
- You're doing great.
- You're up, girl.
Who'd think standing could be
so hard? You're doing awesome.
- Awesome.
- Put me down.
- Let's go a couple seconds...
- That was great.
- Take a sec and
go again for me, OK?
- No.
- I know, Clara.
This is where the
hard part begins.
McDreamy.
- I'm sorry?
- I get it now.
The whole McDreamy
thing. I didn't get it before,
but now... I get it.
You know they
call you that, right?
Yes.
I'm involved, by the way,
in case you thought I was
coming onto you,
because I was not.
Plus, I heard that
you got married.
- So congratulations.
- Yes, thank you.
You wrote some hokey
crap on a Post-it note
in the resident's lounge.
Sorry, but until you're
sweating it out in a morning coat
with a ball of white
taffeta coming at you,
you're not really married.
OK. Well, I've consummated mine.
I consummate mine all the time.
How's that going for
you, Karev? Girls talk.
You might wanna consider that
next time you judge my Post-it.
I haven't cried yet.
I'm using work and
sex as a distraction.
And I think it's working for me.
Have you seen the girl, Amanda,
sitting outside the hospital
on that bench all day long?
I miss sex. I miss it so much.
What?
Mer!
I'm worried about
Clara. She's depressed.
Like, a whole new
level of depressed.
- I don't know what to do.
- You talking about Ceviche?
That...
Oh, my God! That's...
That is so rude!
Ceviche? That is
so... That's rude.
That... That is so rude!
- Anyone else I can offend?
- A tethered spinal cord?
One of the threads in his
cord is attached to his tailbone.
Normally, the spinal
cord is free at the end,
but with it attached, when
you grew, it started pulling.
- Thus, the excruciating pain.
- Can we fix it? Is it fixable?
- Microsurgery.
- I'll snip the tethered cord,
and he'll be free of pain.
She's not normally like this.
Before all this, she
was like a normal mom.
- Oh!
- Andy, this is a normal mom.
Are we waiting for Dr. Swender?
No. Dr. Swender has
handed you off to me.
What are you, like, second year?
- Third.
- That's, um...
Can we page
Dr. Swender or something?
Stevens, this is a good thing.
It is. You still have cancer.
But not enough to interest
Dr. Swender anymore.
- It is a good thing.
- You're saying I have
JV cancer.
I'm saying your mets
have shrunk way down,
and there are no new ones.
Your protocol is
working very effectively.
Stevens, this is about
as good as the news gets.
- Um... So, what now?
- We're gonna use
the port in your chest
to continue with your
IL-2 regimen for now.
And we'll continue monitoring
the progression of your disease
with PET scans every
three to six months.
Is there some kind of
timeline on this, or...?
Your wife is living
with cancer, Dr. Karev.
Right now, the cancer
has stopped growing.
With a cancer this aggressive,
that's pretty stunning success.
There's no timeline.
There's just... We watch it.
We wait. We hope it
doesn't start to grow again.
- That's it?
- That's it.
I see contractions
in the anterior tibialis.
OK. That's the nerve
root, not the filum.
Bipolars and the
micro scissors, please.
- Wanna make the cut?
- No. I don't need to.
Without you, this kid would've
been a chronic pain patient,
possibly addicted to pain meds.
He owes his
entire future to you.
You should make the cut.
OK?
OK.
Put the scissor in...
There. Nicely done.
Dr. Grey says you're still
refusing your physical therapy.
Now, I understand it's hard.
But you have to work
these muscles now
or they will atrophy
and heal incorrectly.
Clara, you gotta do the work.
You got to do the work now.
I know what it is to not want
to live, to wish you'd died,
to lose everything, to not
want to call your mother.
Believe it or not, I know
exactly what that is.
I have been there.
I am back now.
As impossible as
it felt, eventually,
I came back.
And so can you. You
have got to do the work.
- You have to get her
admitted to Psych.
- Committed?
You want me to
have her committed?
Nothing more we can do.
You have to make that call.
People are calling
you "Ceviche".
- Dr. Grey.
- That's... You know,
you can't go out like that,
with people calling you Ceviche.
- Ceviche?
- Yeah. It's a meal.
It's Peruvian, I think.
It's chopped up fish.
That's really
horrible, isn't it?
It is. It's...
It's horrible.
It's horrible!
I didn't expect this.
They say cancer, they say
stage four, you expect to die.
And then you start
thinking, "Maybe I can kick it.
- I'll be the miracle."
- Well, you are the miracle.
I'm still living with cancer.
You know, I just...
You don't expect that.
Isn't that the girl
that George saved?
Oh, Amanda.
- Yeah.
- What is she doing here?
Oh, she sits there.
Every day, all day.
- For God's sakes.
- Where... What...?
Get up. I mean it, get up.
Get up!
Now, go get a life.
I can't.
George was a surgeon,
he had a purpose.
He wanted to save lives and
now he doesn't get the chance.
Now, he doesn't get the
chance to do anything anymore,
but you do. You could go to
medical school, you know?
You could hang out
with your freaking friends.
I don't care what.
Just go do something
with your life.
Because you have one, you lived!
You lived and George didn't!
And I know...
I know that that feels horrible
and shocking and terrifying.
But you lived.
So go live your freaking life.
I... I don't know how.
Nobody does.
Nobody knows how.
But, God, have enough
respect for George to figure it out.
'Cause if I see you sitting
on this bench ever again,
I will kick your ass
from here to Sunday.
I can't get back
on Bailey's service.
She's still not
even looking at me.
Give her time. She was
close with O'Malley...
It's not about O'Malley. She's
mad at me about Ceviche.
- You got to stop that.
- Ceviche?
- It's a patient.
- A boating accident victim.
She thinks it's OK to call her
a seafood dish. Is that OK?
- Well, it's... pretty dark.
- Come on. I'm dark?
I'm not the one going around
choking people in their sleep.
Too soon?
I'm not the guy going around
choking people in their sleep.
- I know.
- It was a dream. I...
I can't remember what I
was dreaming about, but...
I was trying to
save my own life.
I wasn't trying to hurt you.
I was...
I was fighting for my life.
OK.
You made a start.
- You have it, you have it.
- - You've got this.
- Yeah, girl!
- I did it.
- You did it.
Lexie?
Will you call my mum?
Yeah. Yeah.
OK, come on. Come on.
You got it!
Grief may be a thing
we all have in common...
but it looks different
on everyone.
Hey.
It isn't just death
we have to grieve.
It's life. It's loss.
It's change.
And when we wonder why
it has to suck so
much sometimes,
has to hurt so bad, the
thing we gotta try to remember
is that it can turn on a dime.
- What is this?
- Take off your pants.
Iz, Iz...
Be my husband.
Get undressed, get
into bed and hold me.
I don't know what you're
so mad about and scared of
because you won't talk
to me, but I'm scared, too.
I can't... If you won't...
If we're gonna have any chance
at a life together, I need you.
Please.
You died in my arms.
You died in my arms!
You freaking died,
and you left instructions that I
wasn't allowed to save your life!
You want to know what I'm
scared of? I'm scared of everything!
I'm scared to move!
I'm scared to breathe!
I'm scared to touch you!
I can't lose you.
I won't survive.
And that's your fault.
You made me love
you, made me let you in,
and then you freakin'
die in my arms!
That's how you stay alive.
When it hurts so
much you can't breathe,
that's how you survive.
Miranda.
By remembering that one day,
somehow, impossibly,
you won't feel this way.
It won't hurt this much.
I... I am an attending
and I am a single mother
and I lost O'Malley and, um...
I just can't.
I can't care anymore.
Stevens is not my child.
O'Malley was not my child.
I have to stop treating...
I just have to stop
caring so much.
I can't keep...
feeling like this, not at work.
I have to save the feeling
for my son, who needs it!
I just can't keep
giving it away here.
I can't.
I won't.
Grief comes in its
own time for everyone.
In its own way.
So the best we can do,
the best anyone can do...
is try for honesty.
I don't want to hurt you again.
My problems, they're real.
And this... this makes us real.
It makes my problems
your problems.
I'm afraid.
I don't want to hurt you again.
You can sleep in the bathtub.
Wha...
The really crappy thing,
the very worst part of grief,
is that you can't control it.
- What are you doing?
- We need the space.
The best we can do
is try to let ourselves
feel it when it comes.
Hey. Ugh... Thank you.
I got stuck with
this intern today,
took him four tries to
throw in a central line.
Reminded me a little
bit of George, actually,
when he was an intern.
And let it go when we can.
Meredith.
The very worst part
is that the minute
you think you're past it,
it starts all over again.
And always, every time...
George O'Malley died.
It takes your breath away.
There are five stages of grief.
They look different
on all of us.
But there are always five.
I know you all have
heard a lot of rumors,
- and I'm sorry for that.
- Denial.
And what I'm about to
say will be hard to hear,
and I'm sorry for that as well.
Anger.
The economic climate
is... You all know what it is.
In the coming weeks,
Seattle Grace Hospital
will be merging with Mercy West.
Bargaining.
I wish I could tell you
you'll all survive the merger,
but there are only so many
jobs. And the board and I
have some tough choices to make.
- Depression.
- I'm on your side, people.
I'm rooting for
every one of you.
All I can say is please,
be at your very best.
Acceptance.