- All right, that'll be $3.40.
- Oh, okay. Let me just...
- I'm so sorry.
- It's okay.
And here you go.
And there you go.
- Thank you.
- No worries.
Thank you very much.
- Have you seen my ID badge?
- No.
I had it last night.
But maybe it fell out of my
bag when I paid for the pizza.
This wouldn't happen
if you stayed over.
If you'll remember back
to when I lived here,
my ability to lose things
has always been top-notch.
If you stayed over, you wouldn't
have had to come all the way back here
- when you realized...
- It's too soon, Shaun.
Why?
If I stayed over, we both
would've gotten a lot less sleep.
Why is it too soon?
We've only been
together a few weeks.
How many weeks of being together
are required before you can stay over?
Yes!
Saturday. I will spend
the night Saturday.
I'm glad we come here.
I don't want to stop coming.
- Why would we?
- I don't know, that's the way it works.
You mourn, you cry,
and then you forget.
You don't forget. You...
start to move on.
I don't want to stop coming.
Your temperature is almost
101. Your other symptoms?
First, it was a sore throat,
then my body started aching.
And then there's this
cough. I even had my flu shot.
Unfortunately, influenza
is constantly mutating,
the shot always lags behind.
Hopefully, you'll recover
faster because of it.
My daughter's very worried that I
might have this virus from China?
What's it called?
Have you been to China or been around
anyone who's been to China recently?
Taken any cruises?
The coronavirus doesn't
cause sore throats.
This is a bad case of the flu.
Go home, rest, drink plenty of
fluids. You'll be fine in a week or two.
The virus damaged
your mother's lungs.
Her body is working
harder to breathe,
but her blood oxygen
levels continue to drop.
She definitely has Corona?
We're doing everything
we can to help her.
You have COVID-19.
But you haven't tested me.
Your chest X-ray suggests
ground-glass opacities.
That's COVID. I don't need a test.
Which is good because we don't have any.
But I can't smell.
I've read about it.
That's not a symptom.
I guess it is now.
You have COVID.
Okay. Now what?
Now, you go home.
- That's it?
- That's it.
There's no treatment,
stay away from people.
Come back if you have
trouble breathing. Goodbye.
Twenty-five tests? Per day?
No, just give me
one of tomorrow's.
Hello? County Health Department.
I don't have time for them,
and they don't have time for me.
Patient.
- Needs a lumpectomy?
- Yes. Needs. And yet.
- Surgery canceled?
- They ruled it elective.
- It is.
- You just said "needs."
I didn't say when. This can
wait till after the pandemic.
Yeah, I'm twice the size of SJ General.
I should have twice the amount of tests.
Well, who do I speak to?
Do you feel shortness of breath?
A little.
If I'm sick, is my baby sick?
This disease doesn't really
seem to affect children or babies
like it does adults.
Should we admit her?
She's probably safer at home.
What's at home? Do you
have a support system?
Can anyone come help
you, in case you get worse?
It's just me and the little one.
Get her a room. Start her
on oxygen via nasal cannula,
and let's try some
vancomycin and cefepime.
Hey, Mia. No, I'm not headed
back there today. Or this week.
I found a temporary place here.
There are hospitals
in Phoenix too.
If I come home, do you
want me living with you?
That's the point.
Every night after 12
hours of COVID patients,
to hang out with you. And
Kellan. And his asthma.
He's gonna be really
bummed. His graduation...
Isn't till June, this'll be
over long before then.
Someone must have connections.
At county? Van Kleek does, Woo
does, Nguyen's husband works at...
Get one of them to call.
The board of every
hospital has connections.
They're calling Public
Health and getting nowhere.
- So we do nothing?
- No. We do everything we can.
We hammer at official channels
and every manufacturer's
rep that we deal with
and see what companies,
if any, have undisturbed...
Nuts or no nuts?
Uh...
I'm sorry, I'm in the middle
of a meeting with the board.
Hey, everyone. I'm just
making banana bread.
Let's just take a...
I'll take a quick break.
If someone can get me a list of
PPE suppliers in the area, thanks.
I'll be back.
I don't want banana bread. I
want to be back at the hospital.
I'm the president and
I'm at home, watching.
You're doing your job.
And whatever you gotta do,
whatever decisions you need to make,
you just do it right here.
I can take the necessary precautions,
that whole meeting was about PPEs,
- mitigation...
- Aaron, you are 65 years old
with a history of cancer.
You get that virus, then what?
I don't know what I'm doing.
You're being smart, you're being
safe. What is wrong with that?
And what is wrong with being
home together for a while?
Nothing, I guess.
We have no
choice. Let's enjoy it.
Nuts or no nuts?
- Nuts.
- Okay.
What's going on?
Your mother's oxygen
got critically low,
- we need to get her on a ventilator.
- That'll help her get better?
It'll keep her alive, hopefully long
enough for her to fight off the virus.
- Is it dangerous?
- More for us.
She's out.
Lots of swelling.
Slow. You want this over
with as soon as possible.
But you also don't
want her to cough.
Hello.
Sorry. I woke you. Thought
you had to be up now.
- I do. I pushed snooze twice.
- I read the numbers.
You guys had seven deaths in
Santa Clara County yesterday.
Any at St. Bonaventure?
We have deaths at St.
Bonaventure every day, Kellan.
- I miss you.
- I know. You already said that.
I wanted to reinforce the point.
You said you missed me a
lot. And we're together right now.
It's different not
being actually together.
You mean not being
able to have sex?
Haven't been tested
because there's no need.
I'm fine. No symptoms.
You can be asymptomatic
and still have it.
I know. You still working out?
Don't want to lose arm
strength while you're off.
I'm making a salad.
Figured I'd bring it by and we'll
have a masked, distanced dinner.
You can't eat with a mask on.
We'll take them off when
we're eating, and turn our heads.
- Regular masks don't work.
- Bring me one from work.
No.
Do you have enough PPE?
- PPE?
- Personal protective equipment, Dad.
Someone's been doing their research.
We have enough. I'm being careful.
- I heard your mother joined a book club.
- Is Shaun being careful?
Oh, yes, I am. Very.
So am I. It should be
safe for me to come over.
You can't come over
because we are being safe.
What about apples? Do you have
enough apples? I could go shop...
He does.
- Everything is under control.
I told you not to come back
unless your breathing got worse.
Between the fever and the
cough, he's barely sleeping.
Who said that?
My wife wanted to come
with me, but she has to work.
She's essential personnel.
He's lost ten pounds.
Breathe.
He should have
come in a week ago.
Please don't talk
when I'm listening.
Breathe.
He's also coughing. A lot.
He hasn't told you, but he is.
- I'm sorry.
- Did you just apologize for me?
Because I'm worried?
So sorry. I'm a wife who is
worried about her husband.
- Forgive me, I'm evil.
- It's lucky that you're so irritating.
What?
Your husband's blood
oxygen level is dangerously low.
That can't be.
I mean, I don't feel that bad.
Not great, but my breathing...
That's interesting. You don't
feel bad, but you are. Hm.
Admit him to the COVID floor,
start heated humidified
high-flow nasal cannula at 8 LPM.
Her CRP, ESR, ferritin, D-dimer,
transaminases, and
IL-6 are all way up.
Try her on dexamethasone.
I read in my online
physicians' group
that the UK's had
some success with that.
Thank you.
Sorry. What did you say?
Couldn't hear with the mask.
Thank you. I heard you
stepped in for a therapist
that didn't come in today.
My son has asthma. I've been
doing this kind of stuff for years.
I got a dresser and a crib,
bolted them both to the wall.
All that matters is her. I'm
going to do everything right.
You're going to be a parent. No
way you're doing everything right.
Even trade, 200 surplus
vials for your COVID test kits.
What do you need?
I've got hydroxychloroquine,
ribavirin... EKG leads?
No, no, I'm not saying no.
We'll pick them up in two hours.
We have a surplus of EKG leads?
No. We've got a shortage. But
that's a problem that can wait.
Mildred's P-to-F is below 50, she's
showing signs of cardiogenic shock.
- Start her on steroids.
- Already have.
If she goes downhill,
I'd like to add ECMO,
- take the strain off her heart and lungs.
- Good idea.
I need EKG leads,
what do you need?
- Should we intubate him?
- Not yet. Not a minute before we need to.
His oxygen saturation has
been dropping steadily...
- It's 74 now.
- At this rate...
We're gonna prone him. Buddy in
New York says it helps. Sometimes.
How is Claire feeling?
I assume she's exhausted.
That isn't a feeling.
How is she feeling?
It's a little tough to tell,
Shaun. She's wearing a mask.
Exactly. You can't tell if
she's happy or if she's sad,
you can't tell if I'm
sad or if I'm happy.
You seem distressingly happy.
It's exciting. I can't read people,
now no one can read people.
We're all forced to rely
on more reliable markers,
like what people are saying.
Since you can't tell from
my face, I'll use my words.
I feel terrible, we
all feel terrible.
Because we spent the last 18
hours watching people get sicker,
we didn't help anyone, we just
fended off death for a little while.
We're all pretty disgusted at the
joy you're taking from this situation.
- Give him a break.
- You're enjoying this too.
All elective surgeries have been
canceled so no one is a surgeon anymore,
- not just you.
- Claire...
We're all exhausted. And
tomorrow won't be any different.
But it'd help if we didn't hate
each other when that time comes.
You work in a hospital?
Yes.
Could you wait for
the next elevator?
I appreciate you.
No.
- What's wrong?
- No, no!
But they had toilet
paper. 12 rolls. Double ply.
No! No! This is Lea's cabinet.
But she's not using it now...
It needs to stay free. For
when she comes back.
This is my apartment.
You had no right to put anything
anywhere without my permission.
I miss Kellan and Mia too.
What do they have to
do with Lea's cabinet?
You miss her, Shaun.
No, I don't. If I saw Lea, she
might be exposed to COVID
and she might get sick.
I don't want that.
And yet, you miss her.
Why would I want something
that isn't what I want?
Why do people on
diets want ice cream?
I thought the ECMO was
supposed to help her heart.
It's taken some of
the strain off of it,
but her own immune system
is still attacking her organs.
The steroids were
supposed to stop that.
We switched to a stronger
medication. So hopefully, that'll help.
This is from her
bedside table at home.
I gave it to her for
Mother's Day when I was 13.
- Would you like me to...
- Please, can I bring it to her?
I'm sorry, Lashelle, I
can't. It's just too risky...
I don't care what happens to
me. My mother is in there, all alone,
hooked up to a machine.
I just need to see her,
and tell her that I love her.
I can't.
Your lungs are filling with fluid and
secretions. Suction catheter, please.
Is that from COVID?
I guess so. I don't
know. It keeps changing.
Probably in combination with the
bacterial pneumonia he's developed.
First, I probably
brought this home to him,
then I sent him to the
hospital where he's...
- Don't blame yourself, I'll be fine.
- I need to suction out your lungs.
I'm going to feed this tube up your
nose and down into your airway.
It will be quite uncomfortable.
Please try not to grab my arm.
Take deep breaths...
We need to prone her.
We can't, she's pregnant.
That's why I bought this off Michelle
in PT. She does pregnancy massage.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, I'm on
another call. Can you hold it down?
- You can close your door.
- Okay.
I'm making cioppino for
Merchant Marine Night.
- Where did you get the clams?
- I ran out to Bruno's.
You ran out to buy clams?
I wore a mask and they were
really good about social distancing.
I'm sorry, I'm not supposed
to go to the hospital,
where I possibly
could save lives,
but you can go to Bruno's to buy
clams for Merchant Marine Night?
I'm younger than you, I have
no history of health issues,
and unlike a hospital, Bruno's
is not a petri dish of COVID.
Now, this whole menu planned, I
thought I could wear my uniform.
And you could...
We're on quarantine,
we're not on a cruise.
I know, but I thought since we're
stuck at home, we can have some fun.
It's not a party,
it's a pandemic.
I don't have time
for theme dinners,
elaborate menus
and sourdough starter.
Okay. We could at
least dress up for dinner.
Yeah.
Were you able
to drain his lungs?
Yes. Why are you here?
It helps Martin relax.
Knowing that I'm around.
Do you think it helps
Martin miss you less?
Yeah. Yes.
Martin has a heart murmur.
- What?
- Martin! Martin!
Hello, I'm glad you're awake.
You may have a bacterial
abscess on your heart valve.
- That sounds really bad.
- It is.
COVID's complications
are not consistent.
It's becoming annoying. I'll tell you
more on the way to the procedure.
ECMO isn't working for her?
She's pulseless V-Tach.
Epi in the crash cart.
Pushing epi.
One hundred and
twenty joules. Clear.
V-fib now.
Pushing amiodarone, 300 in.
Two hundred joules. Clear.
I'm sorry.
Seventeen deaths in
the county yesterday,
up by two from the day before.
Too small to draw
any conclusions.
What were the new
case numbers again?
They're also up by 112.
Does Shaun look okay to you?
- I'm fine.
- He looks fine.
I wasn't asking you. You'll lie.
Kellan, how does Shaun look?
- I'm fine.
- He looks tired, right?
I am tired, but I'm also fine.
Lea, Shaun's fine,
he just misses you.
No, no, I don't. I miss
having sex with you.
Hey, not alone,
teenager present.
Does Kellan not
know what sex is?
He's graduating high
school in two weeks.
- Congratulations, Kellan.
- Thanks.
He knows. He doesn't want to
hear about you having it. Neither do I.
Does he think Lea and I don't have
sex? Because we do, a lot. Or we did.
We're all sure you do. We
don't need to talk about it...
Sexual intimacy is beautiful.
I'm gonna skip breakfast.
You miss me.
No, we talk twice a day.
The only difference is
the lack of physical contact.
Which reduces
your risk of infection.
But I do miss sex. Don't you?
I do.
We can't do that over the phone.
That's not really true.
Go on.
Call me after work.
When you're alone.
Oh.
Are you muted?
- Yeah.
- I'm sorry to bother you.
- When can you take a break?
- Can you come back in an hour?
You really should take a break.
Just get out of
the house for a bit.
It'll help you work better.
You need to stretch your
legs, and stretch your mind.
Can you come back in... Oh, man!
Are you working?
Who is GoodPlaceFan 793?
I don't know, but whoever he is, he's
richer than he was five minutes ago.
I wanna go on a walk,
can I just finish this?
No! No need. You just play as
long as you want with your friends.
Vegetations from the abscess
had implanted on your mitral valve.
A narrow-margin sharp dissection
left enough leaflet to
allow a primary repair...
We expect a full
recovery of the heart.
Of the heart? What
about the rest of me?
Unfortunately, your lungs
are still compromised...
What was that?
Someone's going home.
♪ Celebrate good times Come on ♪
Your lungs have a lot of
inflammation and swelling.
We need to put you on
a non-rebreather mask
and hope it gets
your O2 level up.
That doesn't sound promising.
Isn't there anything else you can do?
No.
You need to go on a ventilator.
So I'm gonna sedate you.
For how long?
Hopefully just a few
days. But it could be longer.
My baby is due in two weeks.
This is better for both of you.
- If I don't make it...
- You will.
Your baby is safe. You're
young, you're strong.
Sex is not just about touch.
It's about imagery,
emotion, connection...
Oh, but touch is
very, very important.
I mean, there will be touch.
But I won't be touching you
and you won't be touching me.
Are your ears okay?
They hurt. Because of COVID,
I have to wear two masks
and the elastics cut into
the skin behind my ears.
You're going to masturbate
while I masturbate?
Yeah, and we'll
talk to each other.
That sounds very distracting.
We're going to talk about sex.
Tell me what you're doing to me.
Looking at you on my computer.
What do you wish you
were doing with me?
Kissing you.
Mm-hm...
But what if I have
COVID? Then you'd...
I'm unfastening your belt.
No, no, you're not. I
don't have my belt on.
Okay, no belt. Shaun, just close
your eyes and imagine we are...
If I close my eyes,
then I can't see you, Lea.
And I can't see
most of you anyway.
- You can remember.
- No, this is stupid.
I don't want to pretend to have
sex with you, I want to be with you.
I miss you too, Shaun.
Any cough?
- Any fever?
- No.
Any shortness of breath?
Sore throat? Loss of smell?
No, no, none of that. Just
searing abdominal pain...
and the runs. I'm pretty sure
it's my diverticulitis acting up.
My roommate is deeply
into pandemic baking.
I've avoided coming in. I
don't wanna catch COVID.
Have a seat. Non-COVID floor.
NPO, IV acetaminophen for pain
while he waits on his abdominal CT.
No food?
Usually, my first stop with
an abdominal pain patient
is the cafeteria.
It's Ambar. Repetitive late
decels. I got a baby coming.
Go.
Thank you. I know you're busy.
What can I help you
with? Are you doing okay?
My mother had a necklace, a
cross, she wore it every day.
I'm hoping to get it back.
Uh... The patients' things
are all being held in one place.
We're not supposed to
release them until after the crisis.
I'm so sorry.
Thank you.
Okay, um...
Let me see if I can find it. I'll
clean it and get it back to you.
Wanted to let you know
that it'll be quiet around here
for a little while. I'm taking a
walk on the beach with Susie.
We will stay six feet apart.
Six feet is the absolute minimum.
It's still considered quite a risk.
So not only do you not
wanna do things with me,
now you don't want me to
do things with other people?
I want you to be careful like
you want me to be careful...
You don't want
me to do anything.
I can't go shopping,
I can't take a walk,
- you won't spend any time with me.
- I'm a little bit busy.
You're playing poker!
I played poker for one
hour while I was working.
I spend every minute
of every day with you.
Oh, well, you should be so
happy that I'm taking a hike.
It'll be a long one.
- Could you please...
- Wear your damn mask.
Rodriguez or Jeter?
Easy, Jeter. I hate A-Rod
with a white-hot hate,
but it's Jeter who beat us.
Who's your most hated Yankee?
I never cared for Paul Revere.
Your CBC doesn't
show a high white count,
which is atypical for
acute diverticulitis.
We'll see what
the imaging shows.
- Will you bring Walter down to CT?
- Sure.
Remember when they lost
game 7 to the Diamondbacks?
Oh, I cried tears of joy.
- I feel the rump.
- Apply pressure there.
Don't be shy, we
need this baby out now.
Baby's out.
How's she looking, Dr. Park?
Good.
She's pink, active,
and breathing great.
The third fuse on the left.
It looks like it hasn't
been flipped, but it has.
You just... you turn it...
turn it off, and then back on.
This is for the dryer?
I don't want you
calling a repairman...
just because of a tripped fuse.
The dryer is fine.
You're gonna be fine.
I love you.
- You don't need to say that.
- But I want to.
You don't need to. Okay?
This isn't a big moment.
You'll be fine.
Don't come off.
Put the doctor on.
Tell him he's going to be fine.
I can't.
He's right.
The majority of COVID patients
who go on a ventilator never come off.
Put the other doctor on.
Martin's relative
youth is a positive.
I'm sorry, I wish I
could give you more.
Your daughter is beautiful.
Six-and-a-half pounds, 19
inches, completely COVID-free.
She's got your nose.
Eats like a champ.
Everyone on the floor
knows when she's hungry.
She just needs you to get
better so you can hold her.
So far, good news:
no signs of diverticulitis.
- Just need to scan your...
- What?
Scan my what?
- Hello.
- Put on a mask.
- But I'm in the...
- Put on a mask now.
Walter's abdominal CT caught
the lower portion of his lungs.
It's not diverticulitis,
it's COVID.
We've both been exposed.
And so has everyone who passed
through that hallway Walter
was sitting in for an hour.
Ambar's acidosis is getting worse.
She's not getting enough oxygen.
- What's her ventilator's setting?
- She's maxed out.
We can't increase pressure
without blowing out her lungs.
She have any family? Might
be time to notify next of kin...
I read about a clinical rescue
therapy trial, the chill study.
She's a good candidate,
no cytokine storm,
her troponin's low, so
are LFTs and creatinine.
Her organs are in good shape.
So why not freeze them and paralyze
virtually every muscle in her body?
Lowering the temperature
reduces her inflammatory response
and her need for oxygen. And it's
better than calling her next of kin.
She'll require constant monitoring,
we're already overstretched.
I'll do it. I'll take full
responsibility for her.
- Who's there?
- It's Lea.
- You can't come in.
- I got you something.
That's too bad. You can't
come in to give it to me.
I saw online, doctors are using
these to help with their masks.
You attach an elastic to each
arm, so they don't rub your ears.
It is better. Thank you.
I know I can't come in, but...
I don't wanna leave.
You can stay there.
♪ Where can I go
when you don't hide? ♪
♪ Who am I If not seen
through your eyes? ♪
What's for breakfast tomorrow?
Park's making pancakes.
Mm. That's great.
He's done it before.
They weren't very good.
Why?
They were not very good. I
don't know, but I told him, I said:
"Dr. Park, these pancakes are not
very good. You need to do better."
♪ You're falling from the sky ♪
♪ You're rolling in my mind ♪
♪ Whispering my breath ♪
♪ How can I be ♪
♪ Without you? ♪
♪ Try to grab hold,
got nothing left ♪
♪ Oh, but love, my
dear Is stern as death ♪
♪ Wherever I go ♪
Is that my nightstand?
What?
Oh, since you feel
that our time together
is something to be
endured instead of enjoyed,
I decided to make
that easier for you.
This is as far away
as I can get right now.
So could you just please shut
the door and go back to your room?
Things will be okay.
♪ Where can I go
where you don't hide? ♪
♪ Who am I If not seen
through your eyes? ♪