Before they're even
scheduled for surgery,
every patient asks
how long it will take to recover.
The implication being
the quicker the better.
The fancy car, the private jet.
It's a nice way to distract
from the ick factor
of being flown in for an F.O.C.
That's a "friend of Catherine."
Her friends deserve
liver transplants too.
Right. Okay. So we're doing it
out of fairness?
I miss the OR.
Hmm. And this has nothing to do
with Ellis's school fundraiser tonight?
I spend all my time fundraising
for Alzheimer's research.
It gets a hundred-percent of my focus.
And I can donate to the school online.
Okay. I get it.
You're scared of
the other moms, aren't you?
They're scared of me.
Oh. That's true.
That is true.
Plus, this gives me a chance
to check on Catherine's shunt.
And, uh, Richard?
Maybe you check on him?
Well, I didn't operate on him.
So...
Search online
and you'll find advice
from all kinds of people
without medical degrees
about how to heal faster...
Morning.
Mmm. Intern retreat morning.
Yeah, a whole day out of the OR.
Why do you sound happy?
No morning rounds.
Why do you sound miserable?
- Just interns all day.
- You still avoiding Millin, huh?
She threw me under the bus with Altman.
Has barely acknowledged me since.
It's kinda hard to do that
when you're avoiding her.
Whose side are you on?
What are we supposed to wear
to this thing?
Uh, clothes?
- Oh. - But do you have to
put them on right now?
...because most people
don't wanna hear what we say,
which is to rest,
and let your body heal
on its own time.
Oh, th-this is great.
Well, it's not Cottonwood
Resort, but you know,
you gotta do what you gotta do.
I loved when Richard would invite
my residency class to his home.
For a party or a meal.
But you know,
retreat is supposed to be a change of pace.
This is change.
You rearranged
the whole living room.
I hope this is fun.
They need it.
I gotta go. Altman's been watching me
like a hawk ever since the heat dome.
You should be happy
that's all she's doing.
What happened to
staying out of it?
I'll see you tonight.
Good luck with your retreat.
Oh. No luck needed.
- Danny Ford, retreat facilitator.
- Uh.
I've got a curriculum that's worked
for its clients from Fortune 100 CEOs
to at-risk teens.
So you're in good hands. Mine.
Well, then I'll keep
my luck to myself.
- Okay.
- Danny, come on.
- Thank you.
- I appreciate it. All right.
- Okay.
- Oh, I'll take it.
- Thank you, Dr. Bailey.
Good morning, sleepyhead.
I am beat.
Scout woke me up twice
last night asking for "wawa,"
and I brought him water,
and he spiraled his cup across the room.
I thought you were
supposed to be resting.
Yeah, well, most of my patients
will be back at work by now,
but Bailey's strong-armed me
into taking more time.
It's been less than a week
since your procedure.
I am fine. I just...
I feel a little pressure
when I go up and down the stairs.
Want me to carry you?
Mmm. Like when
I sprained my ankle,
and you carried me to the campus
health center. No, thank you.
- I only dropped you once.
- Yeah, I wouldn't brag about that.
Okay. Yeah.
Hmm.
- I don't hate it, but what is it?
- Mm-hmm?
Bacon, egg, cheese, a pancake between
two doughnuts.
It's a sandwich
of my favorite breakfast foods.
Yeah!
Mmm.
- Okay, you just...
- Okay.
Yeah, so you just kind of
just squish it down.
Go fix bones. Okay.
My Aunt Jeannie brings potato salad
to family picnics in a cooler like this.
Well, this one's
for precious cargo.
Katie Ramsey's waited
six months for this heart.
Well, I won't tell
my Aunt Jeannie
that you don't think
her potato salad is precious.
And I won't tell our patient that you
compared her heart to potato salad.
- Fair enough.
- Mmm.
Morning.
- Dr. Ndugu.
- Hey.
I thought I missed you.
Jackie said that you had
already checked on her.
Oh, yeah, I got an early start
on rounds today.
- Jackie's doing well, so...
- Yeah.
...and now I'm picking up a heart
for a transplant patient.
That's impressive.
I'm actually glad I ran into you.
We've been here so long.
It feels kinda weird
not to start my day with you.
She seems nice.
- Yeah, I helped save her daughter.
- Mm-hmm.
Doesn't seem like that's why.
- Hey, Amelia.
- Hey, how's Jo?
Not answering my texts about lowering my rent
now that Levi's moved out.
That wasn't for me.
Marley Frank, 37,
jumped off the 15-foot high bridge
into shallow water. No LOC.
Complains of neck
and back pain. Vitals stable.
I'm also freaking freezing.
Hello, Marley, I'm Dr. Lincoln.
This is Dr. Shepherd and Dr. Helm.
We're here to help.
I do need to ask, did you
hurt yourself on purpose?
We can find somebody
for you to talk to.
No, it wasn't that kind
of jump, I swear.
Marley, we're here.
Are you a runaway bride?
Divorcée. Just finalized it.
I'm having a divorce party to
ring in my good riddance era.
Yeah, you are!
I was tossing my ring into Lake Union
when I remembered how expensive it was.
We tried to stop her,
but we didn't make it in time.
We had a few
celebratory mimosas.
- Oh, I can make more.
- Yeah!
- They were my bridal party.
- Now we're her divorce party.
Yeah! Yeah!
Okay, let's go to Trauma 3.
- Okay. Not you.
- Let's go!
You take them to the waiting room.
No alcohol in the hospital.
This way.
So what happened to the case
you mentioned last week?
The patient's thigh skin graft worked
'cause it was thicker and stronger.
Are you talking about the thigh skin
or his new penis?
You know it's both.
Are we interrupting?
Oh, no, Dr. Marsh, please.
- Meet my former student, Dr. Evynn Moore...
- Hi. Pleased to meet you.
- ...and her lovely wife...
- Nice to meet you.
- ...Professor Tasha Lawson.
- Hi.
Nice to meet you. Urologist?
Oh, leader in
penile reconstruction.
She thinks she taught me
everything I know.
Child, please. You couldn't have cared less
about a penis before you met me,
- and you know it.
- She's not wrong.
Tasha, Evynn.
Good to see you again,
Dr. Webber.
- Good to see ya.
- Good to see you too.
I see you already have
a general surgeon on the case.
Tasha's case is complicated.
She needs a real team.
On top of her bile ducts
being scarred
because of the primary
sclerosing cholangitis,
she has situs inversus.
I thought my sinuses were okay.
They are, babe. We're talking about
your abdominal organs being reversed.
Don't let her confusion
fool you.
She's a poli-sci professor
and the smartest person I know.
We might be looking
at hepatic encephalopathy.
That's why she needs
a new liver.
I need a new liver?
Yeah, baby.
That's why we're here.
Your liver's failing because
it's not draining properly.
Yeah.
But what about my sinuses?
They're okay, T.
We're grateful Dr. Fox got us listed here
and the liver's finally become available.
The Portland hospitals were
giving us the run-around.
You're with the best now, Tasha.
Okay, well then, I'd like Tasha's consent
to have her records sent over.
I already got 'em.
We've had issues
with hospitals losing things.
Dr. Fox always said we have to
take care of ourselves
- 'cause no one else cares as much.
- Mm-hmm.
- Okay, let's get started then.
- Okay, I'll see you soon.
Thank you.
Richard, where are you going?
- Marsh and Grey, they can handle this.
- Evynn is expecting you.
I can go. He clearly
doesn't wanna work with me.
I know Meredith prefers to keep
her cases close to the vest.
- I'll work with whoever.
- Stop. Everybody, just stop.
Do you know what happened to Evynn and Tasha
before they came here with us?
They were rejected by, not one,
but two hospitals that were
thrown by the situs inversus.
And when Evynn pushed on them,
they questioned her medical credentials.
They said whatever they could
to make her feel lesser, make her feel small,
to make her go away.
I promised them
top-notch doctors.
I promised them A-plus care.
Make me rescind those promises,
and you know what will happen.
Put it aside.
Okay.
Shall we go look at the scans?
It's good to be back
in the field, huh?
Yeah, I barely get out,
even near the hospital.
Well, that woman in the elevator could
probably show you around.
All right, she's...
Her daughter's my patient.
Not forever.
Yeah, well, we already
went out once. So...
And? What, you didn't vibe?
I think once is kind of
my max right now.
- You ever been divorced?
- Uh, no.
Okay, well, when a date finds out I'm divorced,
the conversation shifts.
Like she's trying to figure out
why my ex left, you know,
so she can decide
whether to cut and run.
Sounds like you just
haven't met the right woman.
Or maybe this is my life now.
If you want it to be.
But years ago I dated a woman
who was divorced.
And, you know, I had to wait a minute
for her to be ready for me.
But it was worth it.
You ever wonder
what happened to her?
She is at our house
running an intern retreat.
Hey, can you not stab me?
Molly sent me a picture of her toothbrush.
I'm trying to send something back.
Wow, you two
are terrible at sexting.
Yeah, don't care. I'll get the real thing
after she comes back
after breaking up
with her boyfriend.
She walked right by me.
Didn't even say hi.
- Bailey?
- Millin.
She owes Simone an apology.
- Do I even wanna know why?
- Mm-mmm.
Is this where the caffeine is?
Hey, good morning to you too.
Oh, crap, I'm sorry.
That's okay.
I accept your apology.
Let's forget about it
and move forward.
Does she know what she did?
Sorry I asked.
See, even you can say it.
- Who do you have odds on?
- Not us.
Okay, let's go, everyone.
All right, come on in.
Take a seat. Any seat. Let's go.
But don't get comfortable.
Today isn't about being stuck behind a desk
writing progress notes.
Is it about working
with patients?
- Or improving technical skills?
- Yes, and yes.
Today has been designed
by Danny and myself...
to help you become
better surgeons.
Why don't we start with an icebreaker
to get to know each other?
Well, we know each other pretty well.
Can we skip that part?
No, you cannot.
We're gonna break into pairs.
So, turn to the person
sitting next to you, and let's...
Or we could count off ones
and twos so we can mingle more?
Yes, that's an excellent idea.
- Let's start.
- Great.
These scans are
from three months ago.
She has some beading
in the common bile duct,
but the common hepatic vein should be
long enough to do a proper anastomosis.
Mm-hmm. Sure.
Previous stent is in place.
We can transplant the liver
at 90 degrees
with the right lobe up
to accommodate the situs inversus.
Mm-hmm.
We're going to operate together.
You're going to have to
speak to me eventually.
Hey, sorry, excuse me.
So, Valley Green Hospital sent
images of the donor liver.
Well, any strictures
or anomalies
that would prevent us from grafting the liver
at 180 degrees horizontally?
Uh, I just said we should transplant
it 90 degrees, so we need to discuss it.
I didn't think you liked discussing
medical procedures with me.
What do you think
that I've been doing...
I just... I just came to tell you
I'm passing on the liver.
Yeah, it's too big. I wanna hold out
for a better fit for Tasha.
They'll be disappointed,
but at least it gives us extra time to get
some updated imaging.
Yes.
Marley, I'm sorry that we had
to cut your wedding dress.
Don't be. I can't believe
I paid to have it cleaned and boxed.
When did I think
I was gonna wear it again?
Let me know
if you feel any pain.
All I wanted was a clean break.
It's such an ugly divorce.
Brad and I argued over every soup spoon.
And I don't even like soup.
It doesn't mean
you don't like spoons.
Okay,
you're feeling pain
at the thoracolumbar junction.
I think I feel a step off.
It could be a chance fracture.
Did she say a "France fracture"?
No. "Chance." Like you took a chance on love,
and it didn't work out.
It's a specific kind
of vertebral fracture.
It's hard to say. We'll know more
once we get some scans.
You said you wanted
a clean break.
- Hey.
- Hi, Dr. Grey.
That's Dr. Marsh, T.
That's... That's what I said.
Be right back.
- Sorry about that.
- That's okay. I'm terrible with names,
and I don't have encephalopathy.
Are you gonna get the liver?
So I took a look
at the donor scans,
and I think we should
hold out for a better one.
But it's a good match.
Dr. Fox let me see the scans too.
Okay. Well, in terms of blood work
and viral serology, yeah, it could work.
- But the graft is too big.
- We're talking about three millimeters.
I've read several case reports
of successful transplants with bigger grafts.
There's also plenty of cases
where it's caused complications.
Portal hypertension,
delayed graft function,
not being able to close up
the abdomen.
There are always risks.
Yeah. And I'm a transplant surgeon.
It's my job to minimize those risks.
Tasha is stable.
We should wait. We have time.
Every day that goes by is another chance
for her liver to fail.
We could wait weeks
for another match.
You may know transplants,
I know my wife.
She needs this now.
Evynn. Something's wrong with the phone.
It keeps buzzing.
Okay. I'll be right there.
You're supposed to be the best.
Make it happen.
Let me see.
Baby, it's just Minya.
Her and Bahr say "Get well soon."
See? They sent pictures.
- That's them?
- That's their kids.
It's your niece and your nephew.
Untying the human knot takes teamwork
and direct communication.
Ooh. Ooh. Adams. Adams, your elbow
is uncomfortably close to my testicles.
Okay, believe me,
it doesn't wanna be.
- Kwan.
- I'm communicating directly.
Uh, uh, step over my arm.
Exciting.
See, this is some untangling.
Honestly, this is a great
exercise that you can do
whenever you need a little
brush up on cooperation skills.
Well, we should be practicing
square knots, not human knots.
Can you turn right? Your...
No. Your other right.
- Oh, my right or your right?
- I can't tell.
Well, I don't know
which way to move.
- Can you turn under my arm?
- All right.
Yeah, yeah. No, no, no, no!
Hey!
- Okay.
Okay. Good try.
Learning how to laugh
at our mistakes is also a part of this.
Next, we're going to work
on problem solving.
So pick a number
and find your partner.
- Oh. That's good. Here, I'll help.
- Oh. Thank you.
Spinal fractures just require
a brace or a cast, right? We googled.
Sometimes. Um, unfortunately,
yours is unstable.
We need to surgically place screws
and rods in your spine for support.
That... That sounds like a lot.
Are there other options?
Risking paralysis, unfortunately.
I was 23 when I married Brad.
I went straight from living
with college friends
to moving into his condo.
This is the first time
I haven't ever had to share a bathroom.
I finally have white towels
because I don't care
that they're not practical.
I'm supposed to be
living my best life,
not worried I'm never
gonna walk again.
You've got this, Marls.
You'll get anesthesia, much better
than cheap champagne.
It wasn't cheap.
Plus, this guy will be
taking care of you.
You're single, right?
- No ring.
- Okay.
I just got divorced.
We weren't thinking for you.
Um... We need to prep her
for the OR, so...
I will let you know
when she's done.
Okay. Oh, we'll be here
the whole time.
Don't be scared. Oh, think about how
you got the dog and Brad didn't.
- The scans aren't done?
- Almost.
Then why'd you page me?
Because we're working together.
I apologized to you.
I told you I hated lying to you.
Catherine was my patient.
What did you expect me to do?
- I expected you to tell me.
- And break every oath I've ever taken?
It hasn't stopped you before.
Hey.
Ndugu's picking up the liver
since he's already on his way
for the heart.
- I'm booking us an OR.
- I thought it was too big.
I can make it work. Her encephalopathy
is only gonna get worse if we wait,
so we gotta do it.
Scans are in. New labs too.
Let's take a look.
Okay, her biliary tree
is draining. That's good.
The stents still seems to be working well.
LFTs are elevated, but...
Not high enough
to cause altered mentation.
What if it isn't encephalopathy?
What if it's a stroke?
If it's acute,
we shouldn't do the transplant.
- We should scan her brain.
- We should consult Evynn first.
We don't need her consent.
She's in the scanner already.
Tasha isn't in a position
to understand.
We should talk to her caregiver.
Will you stop walking out on me?
You stop giving me reasons
to walk out.
Remember, the goal is
to build the tallest tower
that can support
a marshmallow on top.
Wait, is this one spaghetti
or two?
Two. I spilled water
on the blueprint.
Or should I say "Bluecas" print.
God.
Yeah, we don't think your jokes
are funny like Molly does.
We should've drawn a plan.
Well, ours is almost
as tall as theirs.
Yeah, and they're building faster
because they have a plan.
Okay, well, here's a plan.
Why don't you stop complaining
and stick more of these things together?
Okay, this is too wobbly. I'm...
It's made of spaghetti.
Okay, time's almost up.
You might wanna stop debating and...
Resolving conflict
is also part of this.
...figure it out yourselves.
Fifteen seconds.
We need to figure out where
to put the last marshmallow...
Why don't we just
put this here, like...
- I have it...
- Ah!
Should've seen that coming.
What's that supposed to mean?
It wasn't secure. So, it fell.
We built this together.
- It's not just my fault.
- Right, it's never your fault.
- Are you done?
- Okay, time.
Okay, uh...
We have a winner.
Good job, gents,
and, uh, good teamwork too.
I texted Marsh to let him know
that we're on our way back.
You ever consider using
a professional matchmaker?
I will be quiet.
- Stop! I need help...
- Whoa, whoa, whoa. Pull over. Pull over.
Thank you. Thank you.
My dad, he's...
Just take a breath,
take a breath. Try again.
My dad, his bike skidded off
the road and it crushed him.
And I called the paramedics,
they're on the way but he looks so bad.
- He looks so bad.
- We're doctors. We can help.
We gotta be quick.
We got organs on ice.
Yes, they're doctors.
Thank you.
Okay.
We're doing
a father-daughter ride.
We do one state every year,
five so far.
- No problems until now.
- Carrie? Carrie?
I'm here. I'm here. These men are doctors.
His name is Arash.
I'm Dr. Ndugu. This is Dr. Warren.
His chest looks crushed.
Multiple contusions,
crepitus on palpation.
He must have an injury
to his lung or his airway.
How long until
the paramedics get here?
They just said that they're on their way.
You're not leaving, are you?
We got patients waiting
for lifesaving organs.
The heart's good for a few hours,
the liver even longer.
Okay, all right,
let's stabilize this neck,
- check the leg and go from there, okay?
- Okay. Okay.
Here we go. We got you.
We got you, Arash.
All right.
There we go.
Nice and tight.
We got you.
Tourniquet is on.
Bleeding's stopped.
When's that ambulance getting here?
Can you call 911 again?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
His pulse is getting thready.
Do you see any more sources of bleeding?
- Is that JVD?
- Could be cardiac tamponade.
Dad! Dad!
Why aren't you guys
still helping him?
We have no supplies.
We've done all we can do.
Now we have to just wait for the paramedics.
But they're still
five to ten minutes out.
We've lost pulses.
Starting CPR.
Dad.
Dad, don't die. Please.
Breathing.
- Hey.
I reviewed your most recent labs.
Everything looks normal.
- Oh.
- Any pain or nausea?
I feel exactly the same way
I did when you asked two weeks ago.
Lord. Okay. No pain, no nausea.
- Happy now?
- Mm-hmm.
Where's the rest of your team?
We're dividing and conquering.
Nick is studying the donor liver.
And Richard?
You can't be mad at me.
He's upset because
I was keeping your secret.
You know, Evynn's first ever surgery
was on my service.
We were doing a hernia repair,
and I cut the vas.
It took me a moment to notice.
We repaired it, but later on, I found out
she saw it all happen.
She didn't say anything.
She was worried that I would be mad.
That's when I taught her to speak up,
to call people out, even me.
She seems pretty comfortable
with you now.
Maybe too comfortable.
She's like family.
When you nurture family,
when you train family,
the lines become blurred,
especially when they use the skills
you taught them against you.
It hits harder. That means
it takes longer to get over.
All right,
get your team together.
Hydrocelectomy consult.
Don't judge me.
I know I should be taking time off,
but that's how I cope.
You really are
Catherine's protégé.
When I was a resident, they called me Kit.
Like we were KitKat.
Not that we'd ever call her Cat
to her face.
Tasha's scans
still aren't done yet?
Mmm, Dr. Grey didn't find you?
No. Is there a problem?
Uh, Tasha's tests
aren't adding up.
We're concerned that she's had a stroke.
Dr. Grey wants another MRI.
No. Tasha's already been through
hundreds of tests. We're not doing that.
Absolutely not.
I'm sorry.
She'd been managing her PSC
just fine for 12 years,
but lately, I'm scared for her.
I don't blame you.
Two years ago, she was accepting
the Margeaux Prize for Distinguished Faculty,
publishing her third book,
doing political commentary
for the local NPR station.
She's deteriorating
before my very eyes.
I'd do anything to save her.
Anything.
All right, no displaced
bone fragments or swelling.
No need for decompression.
Let's move on to fixation.
We'll place the first screw.
Now her vertebrae
will be bonded forever.
Better than being paralyzed.
Yeah, well, she'll have scar tissue
and less flexibility.
Some unions are just not meant
to be permanent.
That's why I'm never getting married.
I mean, look at what you...
um, uh, a lot of people
have avoided.
I think it's best to say no,
no matter how many proposals
or rings are involved.
You spilled your guts to Wilson back then.
She had to talk to someone.
- You?
- Schmitt.
Okay, I recommend more work,
less chatter.
Oh, they're here, finally.
Swap out with me. Thank God.
- What's going on?
- He's got blunt trauma to the left chest.
No palpable pulse.
Let's try decompressing him.
- Here's a needle.
- All right.
- Dad! You have to help him.
- I'll grab the Lifepak.
- Can you get me an LMA?
- On it.
No rush of air. No pulse.
Still has JVD. I need a stethoscope.
Give me that.
Is he gonna be okay?
Tell me he's gonna be okay.
It's definitely
cardiac tamponade.
I think we should
open him right here.
- What do you mean "open him"?
- His chest injuries
have caused blood to fill up
the sac around his heart.
That pressure is keeping his
heart from pumping properly.
In the ER, we would cut open the sac
to relieve the pressure.
You want to do that here?
He won't make it
to the hospital.
Carrie, your dad is
moments away from death,
but we can do this procedure
right here, right now.
- We just need to move fast.
- You really think that this will work?
It'll give him a chance.
If they take him, his chances are zero.
- Okay, okay. Do it.
- Get a scalpel, OB pack and gloves.
Hang on, Dad.
- Silver Linings might be
my favorite exercise. - Mm-hmm.
When we're facing a challenge, this can be
a helpful tool to remind ourselves
how well equipped we are
to handle tough situations.
So, who wants to start?
- Mm-hmm.
- Mmm?
All right, someone volunteer
before they're volun-told.
Um...
I-I was struggling to connect
to a gunshot wound patient.
But now that
I've experienced it myself,
I think maybe
I'll be able to help more.
- You were shot?
- Grazed.
- Kwan and I talked
a med student off the ledge. - Yeah.
It was a good reminder that we can save lives
both in and out of the OR.
- Uh, this ledge is metaphorical or...
- Hospital roof.
Oh.
Well, this is some heavy stuff.
Um, next? Uh...
Uh, yeah, I'm actually
feeling pretty great.
Oh.
But it's nice to have
a moment to reflect.
Right.
Uh, I-I don't wanna do this.
Listen, this is a safe space if you have
an aversion to public speaking.
I, um, just don't want
to put a positive spin
on terrible things.
I mean, we lost a classmate.
- Oh, my God.
- She's still alive.
She-She's still alive.
She dropped out of the program
and everybody's acting
like nothing has changed
and everything has changed.
- No, Millin, that's not true.
- We're playing games.
I mean, these two are
making out all over the place.
Blue is texting his ex or his girlfriend
or whatever she is.
And you're only doing this
to protect yourself
in case another one of us
flames out or kills someone in the OR.
What's the point in team bonding
if we don't have a team?
Our team is broken. I'm sorry.
All right, almost there.
Help me retract the chest.
All right. When we get through,
I'll release the pressure
around the heart.
Wait, what is that?
What are you doing?
We're opening the sac around his heart
to get it pumping again.
Oh, my God.
You might want to look away.
Making the incision
on the pericardium.
All right, done. I see a small hole
in the heart. Give me a suture.
Wait, a suture? Are you sure you know
what you're doing?
I'm the chief of cardiothoracic surgery
at Grey-Sloan.
That means yes.
Just a quick
figure-of-eight stitch.
All right.
Warren, cut for me.
Bleeding's stopped.
Start cardiac massage.
Yeah, BP's coming up.
Does that mean you did it?
Please say you did it.
We got a rhythm. We did it.
Where is T's liver?
It got delayed.
What's taking so damn long?
The doctors transporting it stopped to save a life
on the side of the road.
You know I don't care
about anyone else right now.
Getting mad is not gonna
make it get here any faster.
Uh, Ndugu says that the liver should be here
within 30 minutes.
I stand corrected.
- Oh, my God. It's actually happening?
- It is. Mm-hmm.
- Thank you.
- I told you it would.
- You gotta learn to trust.
- I know, I know.
Okay, I'm gonna go get ready.
Would you mind
if I watched from the gallery?
I just wanna see the first incision
so I know it's actually gonna happen.
Uh, um, I mean, it's not typically
how we, uh, um...
Fine with me. Absolutely.
- Thank you.
- Sure.
How is she doing?
Um, she's fine.
Okay, you want to
yell at somebody.
Yell at me. Come on.
Come on.
I know you're still angry
with me.
I never said that.
You don't think
I can see the anger?
The hurt?
The frustration?
Th-That's why I scheduled
this retreat.
I-I thought we could have a day
away from the hospital.
Polish up on some skills.
Have some fun.
Cook a meal.
It may be too soon,
but I had to do something.
Because...
I'm feeling all of that too.
You were right.
Your team is broken.
And I wanna...
I wanna help fix that.
Do you?
This is the patient
we called in for Beckman.
I'll get this liver to Marsh's OR
and then prep Ms. Ramsey.
Hey, great work today. I'll be sure
to tell Altman when I see her.
Thank you. You ever do
anything like that before?
Nope.
Are you sure you can't stay?
We planned a few more activities.
Listen, your interns have been
through way more than I'm equipped to handle.
What about all those
CEOs you helped?
There are psychologists who specialize
in workplace stress or trauma.
I'd go to one of them.
Good luck.
Silver lining,
the traffic should be light.
Thank you for hosting the retreat.
Your home is lovely.
Uh, the bagels were good.
Uh, yeah, no, I've never done
the human knot before.
Also, uh, honestly,
what Kwan said.
The bagels were fine. Go home.
Um, I thought we were going
to make a meal together.
Yes.
Yes, we are.
Okay.
It's not optional.
I scanned Tasha's brain.
- Meredith...
- Hear me out.
Her brain is atrophied.
The confusion, the memory loss,
the disorientation.
I think it's dementia.
I don't need to see it,
because I have these.
After speaking with Evynn,
I had some questions.
So I had Tasha's full medical records
faxed to me from Portland.
She was diagnosed
with Alzheimer's two years ago.
It's probably why the hospital's transplant
committee rejected her.
Evynn was mentioning
Tasha's recent accomplishments.
The awards, the books,
the public recognition.
It made me think of your mother.
Do you think Catherine
knows about this?
You think she doesn't?
- Are you okay?
- No, I'm pissed at Kwan's pile of onions.
We don't need that many.
The recipe said two,
so I cut two.
I'll take those.
Use them for the chili.
Oh, uh, I'll wash it.
I'll dry.
If you wanna visit her,
I have airline miles.
It might not be enough,
but you can have 'em.
Um...
I was trying to plan a visit,
but she said she needs space.
I'm sorry.
- Here.
- Yeah.
The surgery worked.
We were able to fuse your spine
and stabilize your fracture.
How long until I can walk?
PT starts tomorrow.
It might be painful,
but it's good for you.
You sound like my friends telling me
to get back in the dating pool.
Sometimes you just
gotta dive in, you know.
Right, sorry.
Guess what the Seattle
Fire Department found?
Oh, my God, is that...
We got the box
at the hospital gift shop.
It's ready to sell, then Cabo.
Mm-hmm.
I'm sorry for your divorce.
Mmm. It's for the best.
No, I don't doubt that.
You were married, I'm sure at some point
you loved him and he loved you.
It's okay to mourn that loss.
He was an ass
from the start though, right?
Like really horrible.
He made you split the check on your first date
at that sandwich place.
He never remembered
your birthday.
He texted me the day of,
asking for gift ideas under 50 bucks.
He wore sandals at my wedding.
You don't need him.
We're your besties and your soulmates.
We'll trade off
taking care of you.
I'm this week. Get ready
to watch a lot of Housewives.
All right, um, check her labs
and write her post-op notes.
And, um, when you're ready,
Jeremiah's Jewelry downtown.
Pays good prices.
Thanks.
I always wondered
what happened to those rings.
Yeah, two of the jewelers
let me return it.
The other guy was a jerk.
- Well, thank goodness for Jeremiah.
- Yeah.
Hey, for what it's worth,
I thought what you said was nice.
A friend of mine promised me
that if I took time to grieve
a broken relationship,
it'd eventually be okay,
and it'd eventually be better.
Yeah, sounds like a good friend.
Um, would you watch
Marley's post-op?
- Yeah. Everything okay? All right.
- Okay. Yeah.
- Hey.
- Oh. Hey.
Jackie just fell asleep.
Does she need a procedure?
No, I was actually
looking for you.
Do I need a procedure?
No. I'm about to, uh,
transplant that heart I mentioned.
- Oh. - I wanted to ask if maybe you'd
like to have dinner sometime.
You know, um...
if this were a few months ago,
I would've loved that.
But Jackie knows you now and...
That just creates a set of expectations
I'm not sure you're ready for.
Okay, yeah. I...
I respect that.
Well, if you change your mind,
you know where to find me.
Catherine.
Aren't you two
supposed to be in an OR?
We had a few issues
to work out first.
Like why you lied.
I told you
I didn't want you to worry.
This is not about the cancer.
It's bad enough.
Now you're implicating
Grey and me in God knows what.
Fraud?
Falsifying medical records?
What are you talking about?
Tasha's Alzheimer's.
Her what?
Tasha has Alzheimer's.
- What?
- Evynn left it off the electronic records
she gave us.
No. She had me vouch for Tasha
to the transplant committee.
If they had known, they might've made
a very different decision.
Evynn played all of us.
Well, she learned from the best.
Where is she now?
Page Grey and Webber again.
- Hey, where you been?
- We need to talk.
- Uh, I'm just about to...
- I know. Stop. We need to talk.
Okay.
They say patience is a virtue.
But it often feels overrated...
...especially
when we're in pain.
When we're recovering
from a fractured leg,
a bruised ego, a broken heart,
all we want
is to feel better now.
How are you still eating?
It's cereal.
It goes in a different stomach.
Now I know
where all our cereal goes.
- Hi.
Uh, do you...
do you want a drink?
Maxine's hosting canasta at our place
and it's kind of a lot.
Sure. Come in.
We can look for
shortcuts to speed things up.
- Is he still eating?
- That's what I said.
Different stomach.
But more often than not,
it's best to let things
play out in their own time.
Hey.
So, uh, dinner is
on the counter,
but you might have to reheat it.
This bedtime took forever.
Luna started crying and then Scout started
sympathy crying and it was...
What?
You are my best friend.
- Are you making fun of my hair?
- Will you just let me talk?
Okay, but can you make it quick?
'Cause I have to shower.
Marry me.
What's happening?
You said make it quick, so...
I love you. You love me.
And I know that it takes more than
that to make a marriage work,
but what do couples who have been together
for a long time say?
"I've married my best friend."
That's us.
It's been us.
Since you sprained your ankle
and I dropped you on Cannon Green.
You know? Since we stayed up all night studying,
eating Jimmy's cheesy bread.
It's been us since that summer
of epic phone calls
- when you nannied in West Windsor.
- Yeah.
It's still us.
You're my soulmate.
And years from now,
we'll tell our kids,
our grandkids,
that the secret
to our marriage...
is that we were best friends.
So...
- Josephine...
- Yeah.
Yes.
Sorry.
- Oh.
- Um...
Based on my experience,
it's probably better
if you picked your own ring.
Mm-hmm.
It's usually worth the wait.
- -
-