So, I get
this specimen labeled
"Synovial fluid, left hip."
And I'm looking at it,
and it's not very viscous.
Obviously, I'm thinking
maybe it's gout,
but there aren't any crystals
under the microscope,
just cells.
So I call the intern
who drew it,
and he tells me he's trying
to rule out cirrhosis,
which doesn't make any sense,
until I suddenly realize
that those weren't
monocytes I was seeing,
they were PMLs.
The guy had drawn it
from the left hip,
but it was
peritoneal fluid.
What is the matter
with you?
Did you see
someone following us
when we got off the bus?
No.
I'm pretty sure I did.
Who?
I don't know.
I just can't
shake this feeling
I'm being followed.
Followed?
Mmm-hmm.
Oh, I get it.
But don't worry,
it's not real.
What?
You're a first-year
psych resident.
What does that mean?
You spend all day treating
very disturbed people.
It's only natural that
you'd start mirroring
some of their disorders.
For example, paranoia.
I don't know.
That sounds kind of
condescending.
Stacking up here,
Maggie.
We need to get these patients
to the medical force.
Oh, really? Sorry,
Dr. Choi, I didn't notice.
Dr. Manning,
Hayley Kline, incoming.
Adolescent female, on chemo
for non-Hodgkin's lymphoma...
No, no, no, Baghdad.
Okay.
Dr. Manning,
thank God you're here.
Stop the shoes. No shoes.
Honey,
I don't understand.
She's been
talking nonsense.
GCS 10,
altered mental status,
mostly incoherent.
New onset of jaundice.
April?
Got it.
Her eyes, they're yellow.
Hayley, honey,
it's Dr. Manning.
Do you remember me?
I can't find my...
What is wrong with her?
We're gonna find out.
No rain. No. No.
Let's hang a liter
of NS and draw a CBC,
BMP, LFT, and lytes.
On it.
When was her
last dose of chemo?
A few days ago.
A week, actually.
Sweetie, honey.
She could be
in liver failure,
which could be causing
her brain to swell.
No.
GCS is worsening.
We need to intubate,
protect her airway.
I got it.
Do what you gotta do.
Ten of etomidate
and 75 of sux.
Yup.
One fluid line.
Keep an eye on her sats.
I'm in.
Let's get a head CT
and belly, hyperventilate,
and get labs now
with an acetaminophen level.
Got it.
Call 'em and tell 'em
we're on our way up,
we don't have time.
You can come with us.
Let's go.
Hang in there, Hayley.
Can't you rush
those discharges?
I need those beds.
You paged?
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
We're jammed,
and there's no
beds upstairs.
I hate to say it, but maybe
we should consider...
We're not diverting patients
to other hospitals.
I'm just saying...
Maggie, we're not going
on bypass.
If the medical floors
are filled, call the ICUs.
Put patients there
until beds are available.
I'll try.
Sorry for
the lack of privacy.
No problem. I just
want to get out of here.
When did
the pain start?
About a half hour ago.
I was just gonna
ignore it, but my neighbor,
he's a nurse.
And so he said I should
get it checked out.
I don't like hospitals.
I hear you.
Where exactly is the pain?
Here. The belly button.
Dr. Halstead.
Mr. Logan, do you have
a history of A-fib?
What's that?
An irregular heartbeat.
No. Is it serious?
Oh, very common,
but something
we should look into.
How about this? This hurt?
No.
This?
Yeah, there.
Well, good news,
your belly's soft,
and you're not guarding,
meaning you're not tensing
when I touch you.
Oh, so it's probably
nothing, right?
I mean, it's probably
something I ate.
I hope so,
but let's just be safe.
Excuse me.
Uh, let's order
a chest X-ray,
KUB and lactate, CBC,
amylase lipase.
Mmm-hmm.
Just the basic chemistry.
Right.
How long is that
all gonna take?
Uh, do you know what?
Not long.
We'll get you out of here
as soon as possible.
Tolerated the surgery
well, Mr. Collins.
Your chest sounds good.
That's great.
Let me.
Mr. Collins, we're gonna
have to redo your aortic
root valve replacement.
What?
Dr. Latham?
Apical systolic murmur.
I didn't hear it.
It's subtle.
I'm sorry,
I still don't hear it.
Call the OR,
have them set up for
an emergent
aortic valve take back.
Right away.
You're gonna have to
operate again? Really?
Dr. Latham, if I may.
Excuse us.
We're gonna put him
through it again?
Shouldn't we at least
get an echo to confirm?
The valve will fail.
If you need to
assuage your doubts,
we can do an echo
on the table.
Meanwhile, I'm changing
into my scrubs.
Here is the reason for your
tummy ache, Shannon.
You have an obstruction
in your stomach.
Oh, dear.
It's not a growth.
It's clearly
a foreign object.
What did you eat?
Nothing.
You must have
swallowed something.
It's the only way
it could've gotten there.
I don't know.
Honey, think.
What could it be?
I had some of
those little carrots.
No, a carrot
wouldn't reflect X-rays.
This is dense.
It's metal or ceramic,
maybe some kind of toy.
Honey?
I don't know.
Won't it just
come out eventually?
You know, peristalsis.
Well, whatever this is,
I don't want it
moving through you.
It could cut the bowel,
and that would be serious.
With your permission,
I'd like Shannon
to have an endoscopy.
We'll sedate her,
put a scope down
her esophagus,
and get the thing out.
Shouldn't be a problem.
Oh, God.
Don't worry.
It'll be over
before you know it.
All right.
Well, you were right.
Diffuse cerebral edema
with effacement of
the sulci and ventricles.
Yeah.
Get her up to PICU.
I'm sorry,
but the CT shows that
there is significant
swelling in Hayley's brain.
The cause is
acute liver failure.
"Acute"?
There are things
we can do for her.
We have her
on medication that will
help reduce the swelling.
This is Dr. Abrams,
he's a neurosurgeon.
I've called him to consult.
I'm gonna put in
a drain to relieve
the pressure
on your daughter's brain.
With your permission,
of course.
Are you talking
about brain surgery?
I do it bedside.
It's not
a difficult procedure.
My baby.
My poor baby.
It's okay, honey.
We are gonna do everything
that we can for her.
I...
Chicken salad,
chicken wings,
chicken tenders.
Don't you have
anything without chicken?
Dude, can you read
the sign?
We only do chicken,
and we do it "clucking" well.
Next!
You don't eat
chicken anymore?
Since I got my parrot,
you know,
eating birds
doesn't feel right.
I'd like to order
chicken tenders.
Dr. Reese?
Danny.
You've been
following me.
I had to talk to you.
Alone. Uh...
Mmm-hmm.
You were nice to me.
We know
what's going on.
That woman with you
was not your mother,
and you're being
sex-trafficked.
They make me do things
that I don't wanna do.
We can help you, Danny.
No.
No, nobody can.
But you came to me. Why?
I can't take it anymore.
I want to kill myself.
I twisted arms,
got a few beds,
but we're still shy,
but I'm sure
there's more up there.
You know how
those ICU nurses are,
they always keep
spares for emergency.
Yeah, right.
We both played that game.
Go up there,
light a fire.
If you get
any push-back,
call me.
Will do.
Danny said he'd
get back in touch.
When he does,
you should refer him
to the psych clinic.
Well, he won't go.
He's afraid to come
into the hospital
or any clinic.
He's afraid the traffickers
will find out,
and he only wants
to see me outside.
Bad idea.
Dr. Charles, he's suicidal.
So, let me get
this straight.
You are gonna
give him psychotherapy
in the parking lot
once a week?
Dr. Reese,
this patient, any patient
has gotta be treated
in the proper
clinical setting.
He feels a connection
to me.
Let me ask you something.
You feel like
you're the only one
who can help him?
Only one
who understands him?
No. No, it's just...
Just what?
I care about him.
Cut it off.
You're too involved.
But I...
I...
I don't understand.
What happens if you don't
get the rosy outcome
you're looking for?
I think I can deal
with that.
No.
Crucial part of my job
is protecting my staff.
You are headed down
a dangerous path. Step away.
We clear?
Good.
Mr. Logan's
lab work.
Albumin's a little low,
creatinine's a little high.
Yeah, so is his lactate.
Yeah. Thanks, April.
Yeah.
Mr. Logan.
How are you feeling?
I'm pretty good.
And the pain
in your belly?
Uh, it's about the same.
No worse.
I'd sure like to
get out of here.
This is the last X-ray
of your abdomen.
It shows
some vague dilation,
not enough to be
a real concern,
but your labs, too,
they're just
slightly off the norm.
So?
So I'm not comfortable
discharging you just yet,
till I know for sure
what's going on.
I'd like to do a CT scan
of your abdomen.
Really?
Humor me.
Fine. Whatever you say.
All right.
Sternum closing
looks good.
Dr. Bardovi, any help
with closing skin?
No, sir.
Amazing how effortlessly
you throw oh-eight stitches.
You too, Dr. Rhodes.
Hey.
Oh, hey.
Your friend, Izzy Latham,
that guy hears
heart sounds that are
practically undetectable.
It's the same
when we play music.
He has
an unbelievable ear.
I mean, my hearing is good,
but this patient today,
Latham caught a murmur.
I didn't.
It just sounded fine to me.
Yeah,
he's not Superman,
you know?
I mean, knowing Izzy,
he's worked
very hard at it,
probably listened
to a lot of hearts.
But you're
a first-year fellow.
You'll get it.
Hey, Nat.
Yeah?
I pulled this out of the gut
of a 14-year-old girl.
Any idea what it is?
I have never seen
anything like it.
Me neither.
Care to find out?
Yeah.
You're gonna be
all right.
Shannon, Mrs. Fisher,
this is Dr. Manning.
Hi.
We removed
this foreign body
from your stomach.
That was inside her?
What is it?
Shannon.
It's mine. I need it back.
Is that something you made
in the basement?
You made that?
Tell them
what it is.
It's a prototype.
For what?
A robot.
A robot?
The idea is
you swallow it.
You swallowed that?
And it can clear blockages
or repair intestinal wall
without surgery.
Excuse me, "clear blockages"?
It caused a blockage.
Okay, so it needs work.
What exactly goes on
in your basement?
Shannon and her friends,
they call themselves
"bio-hackers."
I'm a body-hacker.
Kyle and Jen
are bio-hackers.
Bio-hackers,
genetic engineering,
a bunch of kids?
They make things,
the DIY generation,
turned our basement
into a lab.
I can hardly get to
the washing machine.
I do not want you
experimenting on yourself.
I'll second that.
Yeah, seriously.
This was very dangerous.
You could have cost
yourself an operation.
You listen to the doctors.
Can I have it back?
Please?
That's up to your mom.
Body-hacking?
They could really
hurt themselves.
Shouldn't we report this
to someone?
Who? It's not illegal,
just crazy.
Excuse me.
Kids, where do
they get these ideas?
Listen to me,
I sound like my dad.
Your dad would be right.
Still, makes you wonder
what goes on there.
Mmm. See you.
Thanks.
I just came
from 3 West.
They said they have
a Mr. Isaac Johnson
who was just transferred
from your ICU.
How can he still be
listed there?
You should have a free bed.
We just didn't get
around to clearing
the computer,
but we already gave
that bed to
an ortho patient.
What about that room?
Oh, that's the Red Room.
"The Red Room"?
That's what
the docs call it.
They won't let us put
their patients there.
Why?
They think
it's bad luck.
Say what?
Three patients
have died in there
in the last two weeks.
They think
it's bad luck.
Doctors.
Nguyen won't operate
without orange socks,
and Bernstein's
gotta play Mandy
in every single surgery,
drives the OR nurses nuts,
and now this.
Dr. Rhodes.
I see you got
a patient in the SICU.
Emergent redo aortic valve.
How do you feel
about transferring him
into that room?
Given the choice,
I'd rather not.
Really, Dr. Rhodes, you?
Why take a chance?
All right,
let's fight fire with fire.
You know that Hawaiian guy
that you talked to me about?
Yeah, Keoni?
Yeah, the one
who owns the bar.
Yeah.
Can you put me
in touch with him?
Yeah, sure.
Thank you.
Okay, so since you
couldn't tolerate
the oral contrast,
the images are nonspecific.
We can't tell much.
Luckily, there's no evidence
of perforation or free fluid.
And you know what?
That pain I was feeling,
it's gone.
Really?
Yeah.
That doesn't hurt at all.
So, uh, I can go home, right?
I'm sorry, no.
I think you need
an operation.
Surgery?
Immediately.
No, no, I told you,
it doesn't hurt anymore.
Well, in this case,
that's not a good sign.
When a section
of the bowel dies,
at first, you can't feel it.
We need to remove
that section
while there's still time,
otherwise it could be fatal.
Page Dr. Rhodes
right now.
Mmm-hmm.
How long has
she been on chemo?
Multiple courses
over the last year.
To get to this.
We're still
in the Dark Ages.
Done.
Peds cases.
You can go in now.
How is she?
Um...
It's too soon to tell.
We have her on dialysis,
that'll take over
the function of her liver.
Is our daughter dying?
Uh... No.
No, she's not.
With dialysis,
she will stabilize
and her labs should improve.
Unfortunately...
The damage to her liver
could be permanent.
She may need
a transplant.
Oh, my God,
a liver transplant?
Another operation?
She's been through
so much.
I know.
I know, but...
Hayley's a fighter.
I've seen these things
turn around.
We're not giving up.
She could pull out
of this.
Thank you.
Little more.
Toward me.
We're on
borrowed time right now.
We need to get him
up there now.
No, look,
I am looking at the scan
myself and I am telling you
I am not taking
him up for surgery.
Connor, he's got
an ischemic bowel.
So show me on the scan.
It's inconclusive.
Exactly.
So you are asking me
to take him up
for a laparoscopy,
possibly an open laparotomy,
on what, your hunch?
Okay, look, he was
in A-fib when he came in.
Uh-huh.
Made me think right off,
a clot had immobilized
to the gut.
Now, his bowel sounds
are gone
and he's distended.
The differential for
what you're describing
is a mile-long,
gastroenteritis
to inflammatory
bowel disease.
This man's bowel
is dying.
I felt it
with my hands.
Your hands?
Yes.
If it wasn't for
what I just went through
with Latham today,
I would say no.
Fine, but for both our sakes,
I hope you're right.
Hey, Dr. Charles.
Do you have a second?
Of course.
I did something today
that I shouldn't have.
I have a patient,
an 11-year-old girl,
non-Hodgkin's lymphoma.
I've been treating her
for some time now.
Her name's Hayley.
She came back in today
in acute liver failure
with acute cerebral edema.
Sorry to hear that.
Yeah. Um...
Dr. Abrams put in
a ventricular drain.
We've got her on
liver dialysis,
waiting for a transplant.
Sounds about right.
This, on top of
her lymphoma,
I mean, she is
in very bad shape,
Dr. Charles.
Like...
And I told her parents
that she could
pull out of it,
that I've seen it
happen before.
Haven't you?
I gave them hope,
and I don't think
there is any.
Do you really
know that, though?
I didn't give them
an honest assessment, though.
I let my feelings
get in the way
because I so much want
Hayley to pull through.
I didn't
act professionally.
prepare them for...
Nat.
You can't
torture yourself.
It's really hard
drawing these lines,
you know?
When do we know
we've become
too involved?
At the very least,
you can't fault yourself
for caring.
Hmm? I don't think
Hayley's parents would
want anything less.
Right?
Yeah.
Thank you.
Dr. Reese,
got a second?
Years ago,
I had a private practice.
I saw patients
on a regular basis.
One of them
was a musician.
Young lady in her 20s.
Talented, funny.
Suffered from bouts of
depression and anxiety,
but we were
working through it.
You know,
she was a brave lady.
Really liked her.
Looked forward to
our sessions together.
One night,
I got a phone call.
3:00 a.m.
She had, uh,
jumped off the roof
of her building.
Left a note.
"Sorry, I'm done."
I couldn't understand
why she killed herself.
Went over my notes,
looking for cues...
You know, things I could've
done differently.
Replayed our conversations
over and over in my head,
wondering what I could've
said or done.
Never got over it.
Sold my practice,
you know, went into
emergency psychiatry.
Swore I would
never get that involved
in anyone's life again.
Look, Sarah,
it was wrong of me to dismiss
your feelings for Danny.
You know,
my issues are my issues,
not yours.
Look, I really
need you to trust me.
Seeing him outside
a clinical setting
is a terrible idea,
especially given the people
he's involved with.
But...
But if you insist on...
I do.
Well, then grab your coat,
'cause I want to
introduce you
to someone who can help,
the right way.
Inject
the Indocyanine Green,
please.
Going in.
Let's get the lights.
That area that's not lit up
is about a foot and a half
of dead bowel.
Lights, please.
You were right.
Gotta open him up.
So, this
hypothetical patient,
female?
Male, hypothetically.
Okay.
And you say he was implanted
with a tracking device?
Yes.
Innovative.
We... We usually see
human trafficking victims
who've been branded
or tattooed, but not this.
How old is he?
We don't have consent
to get any more specific.
Sure.
You want to help this boy
get out of the life.
It's complicated.
Traffickers control
their victims in a number
of ways.
Psychologically, through fear
and emotional abuse,
and physically.
Drugs, torture.
He's up against a lot.
I think it'll help him
open up if he feels like
he can trust you.
Pretty sure
he already does.
Great.
Once he tells you
that he's ready
to involve us,
just call me,
and we'll start looking
at ways to extricate him,
but, in the meantime,
you have to be
really careful.
His fears are legitimate.
If these traffickers
find out that he's trying
to get out,
that he could
potentially become
a witness against them,
They'll kill him.
Dr. Abrams?
Tell me if you concur.
Her pupils are large,
sluggish.
What does that mean?
No. Wait.
Wait.
What aren't you
telling us?
Unfortunately, the swelling
in your daughter's brain
is so severe
that it's affecting
the brain stem.
BP's spiking, 200 over 100,
heart rate's falling.
She's crashing.
Call a code.
She's in v-fib,
1 milligram of epi,
charge to 200!
Now!
Hold compressions. Clear.
Still in v-fib.
Charge to 200,
another milligram of epi.
Hold compressions.
Clear.
V-fib's...
Fine v-fib.
Please, please, please.
Asystole.
I'm so sorry. She's gone.
Gone?
Are you...
Are you sure?
Yes. Yes. May we stop?
Stop?
I need
your permission.
Yes, please,
for God's sake,
let her be.
No, no, no.
No, no, no, come on.
Come on, baby, come on.
Baby, come on.
No! No! No!
I hope this
isn't inconvenient.
I'm just concerned
about what Shannon
and her friends are up to.
Believe me,
they won't mind.
They love to
show off their lab.
Little mad scientists.
But you're very supportive.
They get so excited.
They think they can
do anything.
Listen, I had to give
Shannon back that gizmo.
She said she'd never
speak to me if I didn't.
Shannon, look who's here.
What you're describing,
the suicidal thoughts,
the sense of hopelessness,
lack of energy,
these are all
signs of depression.
And I can prescribe you
medications that could help,
but I think we need
to address something
more fundamental.
What do you mean?
Um...
Hey, Danny, when we...
When we examine
a patient who's in prison,
we have to ask ourselves,
"Is this person
really depressed,
"or are they just living
in a situation
that is so awful,
"so inherently depressing,
"that any person would
have these feelings?"
So what I'm saying...
Sorry, um...
If you were living
in a better situation,
you might not be depressed.
You mean leave them?
Yes.
No.
No, no, I can't.
These people,
they'll hurt me.
We can protect you.
What about the heroin?
I need it, you know that.
They give it to me.
We can get you off of heroin.
You won't need it anymore.
They'll find me.
They will, they always do.
Well, of course they do.
They put a tracking device,
a chip, in you,
but we can take it out,
and then they won't
be able to find you.
You don't know these people.
They're too smart.
Okay, Danny,
you don't have to make
any decisions right now.
I just want you to know
things can be different.
This was a bad idea.
I shouldn't have come.
No! No!
No, Danny. Danny!
I heard. I'm sorry.
Yeah.
We ran the code, all the time
knowing it was hopeless.
Yeah.
I failed her.
You did everything
you could.
No, I did everything I could,
and it wasn't enough.
I felt helpless, Ethan,
watching that
little girl slip away.
How many more kids
like Hayley are we gonna
have to lose?
Nat,
you know
that patient of mine
you saw today, Shannon?
Yeah.
I was worried about her,
so I went to see her lab.
Nat, you can't believe it,
they're doing
gene sequencing.
One kid's trying to make
an affordable Hep C drug,
another's trying
to bio-engineer
chicken meat
so we never have to
kill another chicken.
Okay.
These kids
are doing stuff
in a basement
that 10 years ago
you could only do
at a major university
or hospital lab.
You should go.
Make you feel better.
Make me feel better?
Nat, when we find
the cure for cancer,
it might just come out
of a lab like that one.
Keoni.
How's it, brah?
Good, good.
That's the room?
That's it.
Not a healing atmosphere.
Can you do anything?
Oh, yeah.
What?
You said he told you
that certain abilities
ran in his family.
The shaman thing?
Seriously?
Show some respect,
Dr. Rhodes,
the term is "kahuna."
And for a man who thinks
a room can be unlucky,
you're one to judge.
Just calm down.
It's okay, just calm down.
Dr. Choi, incoming.
Trauma Two's open.
Nineteen-year-old male,
found on the street
with a self-inflicted
wound to the right flank.
Sarah!
April, page Dr. Reese.
Yeah.
GCS 15 but lethargic.
BP 110 over 60.
About 200 of blood loss
at the scene.
I need Dr. Reese!
Looks superficial,
but there's still
a lot of bleeding.
Type and cross
and hang a unit.
Right.
And a liter of
normal saline.
Yup.
Danny.
He cut himself.
Were you trying
to kill yourself?
No,
I tried to cut it out,
the chip.
The chip?
I want... I want to live.
I want to get away
from them. Help me.
Okay.
We're culturing
gut bacteria over here.
Maybe we can reprogram
some E. coli Nissle
to boost the immune system.
But Nissle's
not dangerous.
Still, what level of safety
are you operating at?
BSL-1.
Maybe one and a half.
What we're doing here
doesn't need more than that.
And who's supervising
all of this?
Ms. Herbert,
our biology teacher.
But I don't think
she really gets
what we're doing.
She just tries to make sure
we don't kill ourselves.
Oh! This is cool.
Kyle, show her the ear.
He took a slice of apple
and implanted it
with HeLa cells.
The cellulose in the apple
is kind of like scaffolding
for the cells to grow on.
Wow.
That really looks
like an ear.
Well, it's not.
I carved it to
make it look like one.
But it's not
apple anymore, either.
Well, when I was your age,
I was working with
hippocampal cultures,
studying the transduction
pathways with
short interfering DNA.
I know, big deal, so 1995.
You were
a science geek, too?
Mmm-hmm.
And I would've killed
to have a place like this.
Let me ask you a question.
What do you know about
non-Hodgkin's lymphoma?
Blood cancer.
Body produces a lot of
abnormal lymphocytes.
How'd you like
to give it a shot?
The room is clear.
"Clear"?
For lack of a better word.
All right, now. Everybody,
you heard the man.
The room is good now.
I'm sending patients up.
No argument.
Okay.
Mahalo.
Mahalo nui.
Come on,
you don't actually think
that there was
anything wrong
with the room, right?
Oh, yeah.
It's just physics.
Physics?
Vibrations from sound waves.
They create
micro-movements in things.
They imprint themselves.
So, stuff in a room,
tables, chairs, walls,
they get changed
very slightly,
but they get changed.
A lot of grief
and anger in there,
left its mark.
Not helpful to the ill.
So, how do you fix that?
You can't erase things,
but you can write over them.
Big first step.
Remember, it's just
the beginning.
What do you want
to do with this?
I'll take it.
Hey, I just checked in
on Mr. Logan.
He's doing fine.
He said to say thank you,
and he would like to know
when he's going home.
That was a tough
diagnosis you made.
How could you be so sure?
When I was a fourth-year,
I did a rotation with
this amazing surgeon,
real old-school.
Unbelievable diagnostician.
Didn't need a scan.
She had such great hands.
Just by touch,
she could tell
if a patient had
cystic fibrosis,
renal cysts.
They don't make 'em
like that anymore.
I think I know one.
You know, it's a good thing
I didn't know
what I didn't know
before I became a doctor.
I don't think
that I would've.
Oh, who would?
Good night.
Good night, Will.
Hey, looking good.
Hello, Dr. Rowan.
Hello.
Here you go.
Oh.
How are you today?
Oh, fit as a fiddle.
Mom said we're
going to take a train.
Perfect.
I love trains.
You know, Dr. Rowan,
you were my teacher.
Was I?
That's right.
You were a surgeon.
The best.
How about that?
Yeah.
And I wanted to tell you,
today, what you taught
me saved a man's life.
Oh.
Thank you.
Oh, you're welcome.