Previously on "ER.."
How does a week
in St. Bart's sound?
St. Bart's?
In the Caribbean?
I defend you in
a civil rights suit against you.
In exchange,
I play doctor for a day.
You know and I know this
was not about your HIV status.
Do I?
Anna, this is my cousin, Chase.
‐ Hi.
‐ This is Anna Del Amico.
We're interns together.
‐ Where's my mom?
‐ 'She's a young woman.'
She deserves
a chance to keep her leg.
Got a hot one eh, Lizzie?
Couldn't ask
for a better candidate
for a free fib
transfer candidate.
‐ She's crumping!
‐ Get on it, Corday!
Sternal saw!
'Doug. Hey.'
It's time
to get up.
A few more minutes.
Uh‐huh.
You have to
get up now.
Your shift's over.
You got all day.
What time is it?
It's 6:10.
How was your night?
Ah, I hate night shifts.
Did you get tomorrow off?
Not yet. Did you
get tonight off?
No. I owe too many shifts.
Christmas Eve
is gonna cost me double.
This is so unfair.
Yeah, well, flex your muscle.
You make the nurses' schedule.
Yeah, which is why
I get stuck with it.
Carol can work Christmas,
she doesn't have a life.
they don't even
feel guilty about it.
Yeah, make 'em
Now that's the
Christmas spirit.
Tell them about us.
This is stupid.
I'm not going anywhere.
You know that.
I know.
200! Clear!
‐ One more. Clear!
‐ Herb, Herb, you finished?
‐ Yeah.
‐ You said couple of minutes.
Finito, all
done, okay guys
break it down
that's a wrap.
Yeah, very good, George
you're very
good very believable.
Listen, is there there
any papers I need to sign?
Nah, a couple
of formalities
I'll send them over this
afternoon, you're done.
That's it? I'm clear?
Yeah, yeah.
The law family
wanted an apology.
‐ An apology? From me?
‐ Ah‐h‐h.
No possibility, I said.
You're all done, you're clear.
I want a picture with you.
‐ No, no, no.
‐ Chris.
‐ No, no, no, that's okay.
‐ Hey.
I made the lawsuit
disappear, come on.
Smile, this
is going up on my wall.
Good morning.
‐ 'Need some help?'
‐ No, I'm fine.
I...uh, damn it!
On second thought, yeah.
Waited till the
last minute, huh?
‐ Yeah.
‐ What Did you clean them out?
Well, I'm bringing the baby
to my sister's house.
You know I can't be outdone.
Yeah. Just don't
get discouraged
if he ends up playing
with all the boxes.
Hey, what are those
for the Christmas party?
Yeah, they're pizzelles.
Like, uh, Italian
Christmas cookies.
My mom bakes
them every year.
I thought I'd give it a try
since I won't get home.
It's not quite
the same, you know?
Yeah.
'Hey can you give us a hand?'
'What's with the dog?'
Put this in the doctors lounge.
A blind pedestrian
versus auto, hit and run.
A head trauma, brief LOC.
GCS 15, moves
extremities times four.
'Name's Bart. Lives
under the bridge.'
Homeless guy with
a guide dog?
Not his fault I told him to go.
I heard the traffic stop.
Okay, hold up, hold up, hold up.
‐ How's your neck? Any pain?
‐ What's going on?
‐ Can you feel this?
‐ Oh, uh, it's snowing.
Alright, let's
get him inside.
No! You don't understand.
My eyes! I can see!
Sir! Sir!
Try not to move, okay?
You're‐you're a black
man in‐in a brown coat.
She's blonde
in a red jacket.
I can see.
Oh, Santos.
Santos, is that you?
It's a miracle
that's what it is.
You're a miracle worker, doc.
That's what we all say
about him.
'The room's green.'
'There's a big light above me.'
Pupils are equal, round
and reactive to light.
Your shirt's brown
under a yellow
apron thing.
‐ How many fingers?
‐ Three.
‐ Yep. He can see okay.
‐ I told you.
Guess you have
the magic touch.
If the X‐rays
come back normal
send for a non‐contrast CT
'Wait. Wait!
What's your name?'
What do you
think his scam is?
I don't know
but that guy
was never blind.
Wait.
‐ Hey, what's his name?
‐ Dr. Benton.
Lydia, don't suppose you could
cover for me tomorrow night.
Oh, I wish.
I'm cooking Christmas dinner
for Al's family
all 25 of them.
You're lucky
you're working.
You're doing it wrong.
You gotta plug in a string
and then separate
it one at a time.
‐ Oh, really?
‐ Yeah.
Why don't you show me?
Hey, Carter, do you
know if your grandparents
would like any
food or anything?
For what?
They're coming to
check out the clinic
this afternoon 3 o'clock.
Their annual pilgrimage
to their worthy causes.
It's that bad?
No, but the clinic
won't be the only thing
being checked out.
Henry!
Something wrong?
No, I‐I feel
much better.
Why?
You're on time.
Oh. I suppose I de..
I suppose
I deserve, I deserve that.
Uh, listen, I still have
to pass this clerkship.
No one's pulling for you
more than I am, Henry.
Chuny, can we get a gram of
Ancef for our friend in two.
Sure thing.
Oh that's, that's good, see
because the way I figure it
the only thing that
I really haven't done
is a major
emergency procedure.
That's a matter of opinion.
So, why don't
you just give me, uh
an LP or an
intubation or something
and then, you
can ship me off
with a clear
conscience.
I, I brought
my own gloves.
Look, please, I..
Uh, Merry Christmas
to you, too.
Who was that?
I hit my
limit on my credit
so they froze my card.
I mean can you believe it?
It's Christmas Eve and
I had your
present all picked out.
How much do you owe?
$600. And you know I was
making a dent in it
but with the holidays
and everything it's just..
Listen, I haven't gotten you
a present yet, either, so..
Why don't I pay your balance?
As a Christmas present.
No, I cannot
let you do that.
Sure, you can.
But you have to promise
not to go and spend it on me.
‐ Really?
‐ Anybody home?
‐ Carol?
‐ Oh, what happened to you?
I went chimney sweeping
for this little guy.
Jonathan, 7‐years‐old.
‐ His brother found him stuck.
‐ Playing Santa?
No, trying to prove
Santa could make it.
Complains of
shortness of breath‐‐
Carter, give me a hand.
Still having
difficulty breathing.
BP 140/92, resps
at 32, tachy at 150.
On O2 ten liters.
'What is this?'
Respiratory distress.
On my count.
One, two, three.
Is there place
I can get cleaned up?
Oh, yeah there's
a shower down the hall.
Alright, pulse Ox is 88.
Stridorous
breathing and hypoxia.
Two of versed
followed by 50 of sux
and five of Pavulon IV.
What do we do, Henry?
‐ Uh, increase the O2?
‐ No.
Six ET Tube.
The soot that he inhaled
could cause tracheal edema.
'The swelling might make it
harder to intubate him.'
‐ So, we intubate now?
‐ That's right.
Jonathan, Jonathan,
we're gonna put you to sleep.
And then, we're gonna put
a tube in your windpipe
to help you breathe okay?
Can I try it?
Kids are kind of tough.
This isn't really
a teaching case.
Next time, Henry.
‐ Jeanie, you're working today?
‐ Yeah.
I didn't see you
on the schedule.
I'm volunteering
at the clinic.
What are
the needles for?
Man with hepatitis B,
he's been sharing
with his friends
in the park.
You're giving
them to him?
I'm gonna replace
them from clinic stock.
That's not my concern. I just,
uh, it's against the law.
Well, do you want
him to pass it on
or get infected
with something worse?
Just be careful.
Know who you're dealing with.
The patient
won't report me, Kerry.
Will you?
Hey, St. Peter.
I heard about
your miracle.
Yeah, well some
of us have the touch.
Where's the blind guy
who needs the CT?
‐ He's not blind.
‐ He's not here either.
He took his dog and left
AMA about ten minutes ago.
Said he wasn't hanging
around a crummy hospital
when there's a whole
world out there to see.
Yeah, he just wanted
some attention.
Don't sell
yourself short.
So you're gonna work a shift?
I have been known to practice
medicine on occasion.
No. I meant, I thought you had
backup covered scheduled.
Oh, the truth is
I gave him the day off.
Figured I should
keep an eye on you
make sure you made
that plane tonight.
Hey, Kerry could we we
get a taxi voucher for Pablo?
He doesn't have any shoes.
Where are your
shoes, Pablo?
My shoes are gone,
have no shoes.
Yeah, we've been over this
before. You know what, Pablo?
I'm gonna try and get you
something to wear home, alright?
‐ Alright.
‐ I'll call you a cab.
I'll wait outside.
No, no, you know what
wait in chairs.
It's cold outside.
Oh, okay. I'll
wait in chairs.
♪ Feliz navidad ♪
‐ Feliz navidad, Pablo.
‐ Thank you, Kerry.
You know just curious
who pays for those?
The vouchers? Us, why?
Why? You probably got
a cab company to comp them.
‐ Yeah.
‐ Good PR.
And you promise to call
them for paying customers.
Oh, I wonder why no one
thought of that before?
We do it at
other ERs.
‐ 'We'll try it.'
‐ Excuse me.
Do you have a scrub top,
I could borrow? Greg Powell.
I'm the paramedic
who brought in the boy
who got stuck in the chimney.
Oh, right, God,
I didn't recognize you.
‐ You clean up well.
‐ Well, thank you.
A scrub top isn't
gonna keep you very warm.
I'll get you a coat,
from the Goodwill POW.
Are they clean?
Oh, and very fashionable.
‐ Oh.
‐ Follow me.
Careful watch
your step, it's icy.
Vinnie Capoziello,
48‐year‐old man
experienced acute onset
crushing substernal chest pain
shortness of breath.
BP's 50, palp, resps 28.
O2's at ten liters.
Saline's wide open.
Whoa, ho, he's sweating.
Diaphoretic. Are you feeling any
pain now, Mr. Capiozelli?
‐ Maria.
‐ How bad, Carter?
He's in cardiogenic shock.
Trauma two.
I'll be right in.
I'll get it.
Uh, sure. Great.
Ellis West, visiting attending.
Carter, is it?
‐ Uh‐huh.
‐ What do we have?
MI, hypotensive and cyanotic.
Alright, let's
start a dopamine drip.
Titrate to
a systolic of 100.
Give him aspirin
and 5,000 units of heparin.
‐ He's bradying down.
‐ 0.5 atropine.
Pansystolic murmur.
Hold that heparin.
I‐is that bad?
Could be a ruptured
left papillary muscle
or interventricular septum.
Does that mean that
we're going to intubate him?
‐ 'Yeah, maybe.'
‐ Okay, can I, can I try it?
‐ Med student?
‐ Yes. George Henry.
I can't get a pressure.
‐ Whoa, he's‐he's crashing.
‐ Need a hand?
Nah, it's alright,
Kerry. Thanks.
Amp of epi and
a mig of atropine.
You, bag him.
‐ Heparin?
‐ I held it cause of a murmur.
Maria.
I love you, Maria.
‐ What?
‐ I love you, Maria.
‐ Come on, Henry, bag him now!
‐ 'Let's intubate him.'
Alright I got it.
out of the way. 8.0, please.
Hey, wait a minute I thought
I was gonna get to do this.
Not now, Henry.
What you got in here, Bricks?
Gifts, mostly.
No time
to ship them all.
‐ What time is your flight?
‐ Half past 4:00.
I just need to catch up
on some post‐op notes.
Before I leave.
They'll wait
till you get back.
You can assist me
with the vascularized
free fibular
transfer on the Beaumont girl.
‐ Today?
‐ Yeah.
I wanna be out
of town next week.
What's her neuro status?
Anesthesiologist signed off.
She's stable enough to undergo
the next phase of her surgery.
The first phase
put her in a coma.
Lizzie, we started
this reconstruction
let's finish it.
If she comes out,
she'll have her leg.
That's 45 minutes.
I'm calling it.
Time of death 13:38.
You can stop now.
Good effort, gentlemen.
Part of the job, Henry.
Sometimes, you lose them.
I‐I didn't get
to intubate him.
Sorry, it had
to be done fast.
He was coding.
Do you, uh...want
to try it now?
He's...he's‐he's dead.
So? You're not going
to hurt him, right?
I'll get a death kit.
Wait are you
sure we can do this?
You want
to pass, don't you?
Try a 7.5.
Okay.
‐ Insert it laterally.
‐ Okay.
Sweeping the tongue
out of the way
and placing the tip
of the blade on the vallecula.
'You see it?'
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Hey, gen‐gently, man.
Come on. Easy.
You don't wanna
break his teeth.
'Advance until
you see the cords'
and then, lift
the scope 45 degrees.
‐ Oh, my God. Vinnie.
‐ Who are you?
Joey, his brother.
What happened?
Uh, he had a heart attack.
Is he gonna be okay?
Yeah, yeah.
Uh...keep going.
It might be better
if you waited outside.
I wanna to be with him.
Nah, I really think it'll be
better if you wait outside.
Come on, push the epi
and another round of atropine.
‐ Sexual assault victim come in?
‐ Trauma one.
I'll get the rape kit.
‐ How bad?
‐ 'Bad.'
67‐year‐old woman
found bound gagged
and unconscious
by a neighbor.
‐ GCS 15.
‐ Oh, my God.
Multiple lacs
contusions and abrasions
'possible nasal fracture.'
Let's get
a cross table C‐spine
cath her and dip
the urine for blood.
Nasal fracture, alright.
Are these burns on
her mouth and eyes?
No, we had to pull
off the duct tap
so she could breathe.
BP 135/70, pulse 120.
Looks like a possible
ankle fracture here.
You're gonna be alright, ma'am.
We're going
to take care of you.
‐ Where are the cops?
‐ 'On their way.'
‐ Oh, God.
‐ What?
Hey, Jeanie,
I have a follow‐up otitis.
Could you see him
in the clinic?
Yeah, sure.
Send him in.
‐ I'll be right there.
‐ Okay, thanks
'10‐0 prolene.'
Avoid any
axial twisting.
This lumen
is quite narrow.
Hey, bovie that bleeder.
‐ Got it.
‐ Retract distally.
It's always nice to take
care of any unfinished business
before the holidays
don't you think?
Pardon?
So we can have
a vacation with no worries.
Allison has a
few left, I'd say.
'You know...worries.'
Kerry, can I
talk to you privately?
‐ Not now, Jeanie.
‐ 'It's important.'
‐ It'll have to wait.
‐ It can't wait.
I'll be right back.
I left my meds at home.
It'll take me over
an hour to get back there
and I need to keep
on a strict regimen.
What do you need?
I know you handle
the ER needle sticks.
I thought you could dispense
a dose of my triple cocktail.
Of course.
I meant, what's your
crixivan dose?
800 milligrams.
It's, uh,
150 3TC, 200 AZT?
That's right.
Thank you.
Um, w‐what do
we tell them?
What we would had
to tell them anyway.
Just follow my lead.
Well?
How is he?
Your brother had
a massive heart attack..
...that produced a rhythm
that was
incompatible with life.
We applied every lifesaving
measure at our disposal
but were unsuccessful.
Oh, no. No.
'I'm afraid he
didn't make it.'
'No!'
I'm sorry.
Y‐y‐you should know
that his last
thoughts were of you.
What? What did he say?
"I love you, Maria."
Maria?
I‐I'm Angela.
Maria is Joey's wife.
'Maria?'
'That bastard!'
Mrs. Larkin, I'm going
to need to use a solvent now
to get the rest of the tape off
it may sting a little.
Nurse Hathaway is going
to ask some questions.
They may be difficult to answer
but they're very important
in catching and prosecuting
whoever did this.
And in helping us treat you
medically,
Mrs. Larkin. Okay?
My name's Carol.
To your knowledge
did penetration
occur vaginally?
Yes.
By a penis?
By anything else?
Any foreign object?
Mrs. Larkin?
I don't know.
Maybe.
Did ejaculation occur?
I don't think so.
It happened so fast.
He, he grabbed me
from behind and..
'a‐and threw me
on the floor'
'and he hit me.'
'He‐he hit me and..'
'...and kicked me
again and again.'
'He broke my glasses.'
Did you see his face?
'I don't remember it.'
Just the tape and...and then..
Can you finish this, Carol?
Nurse Hathaway is going
to collect some samples.
Uh, she needs a sedative
valium, five milligrams, PO.
‐ Hey, Peter.
‐ 'Uh‐huh?'
Guess what.
I was curious about your
miracle so I looked him up.
Bart Periard.
He was in last year.
The chart says he's Blind.
‐ Are you sure?
‐ Mm, take a look for yourself.
And there's nothing to
indicate that he was faking it?
No, he came in
with a minor leg lac
that he got falling
out of a dumpster.
Doesn't look like they
did a visual acuity test.
Huh. I wonder
what's his angle.
Who knows?
The lord works
in mysterious ways.
‐ Are you Dr. Benton?
‐ Yeah.
Tommy Gruger.
I'm a friend of Bart's.
I just saw him on Michigan
Avenue playing with his dog.
He could see,
says you did it.
I'm sorry.
Your friend is mistaken.
Please, help me.
I wanna walk again.
You cured him.
Why won't you cure me?
I'll believe
whatever you say.
I'm sorry, there's
nothing to believe, okay?
'I'm gonna take your picture
now, okay, Mrs. Larkin?'
Broken nose,
fractured ankle
multiple lacerations
and contusions.
Duct tape used
on her mouth.
Vaginal penetration,
possible foreign object.
Anything else?
Yeah. Yeah, they wrote on her.
The word whore
in black magic marker.
That suggest something?
'Maybe.'
Do the, uh, injuries seem
consistent with her story?
Story? You think
she might have made this up?
A victim's account
isn't always accurate.
Yeah, it's hard to take notes
when you're being bludgeoned.
Give her a break,
she's been through a lot.
Okay. We'll take
care of it. Thanks.
No problem.
‐ Your taxi's downstairs.
‐ Great.
Has Allison Beaumont
been moved from recovery?
She's just coming
out of anesthesia now.
Uh, no, not this one.
She's in a coma.
I don't think so.
Tell the cab
to wait a minute.
Allison?
Can you hear me?
Don't try to speak.
Just squeeze my
hand if you hear me.
'I'm Dr. Elizabeth Corday.'
'Do you know
where you are?'
You're in hospital.
You were involved in a very
serious automobile accident
ten days ago.
Do you understand?
Are you in any pain?
What is it?
Uh..
I'm afraid she didn't survive.
'Your mom died.'
I'm sorry.
Hey, hey, what's that?
Hey, oh, nothing.
Uh, Mark, here this guy
dropped this stuff off for you.
I think it's more lawyer stuff.
Ah, don't worry.
‐ It's good news.
‐ Oh, good.
So, come on,
what is this, is that for me?
‐ What'd you get me?
‐ No. Mark, don't. No.
Come on.
What'd you get?
Oh!
Who's the heavy
artillery for?
A friend of
mine...her son.
God I wished they had
this stuff when I was a kid.
Mark, I've finished
Mrs. Larkin's rape form.
I wanted to know if
you want to review it with her
before I give it to the cops?
‐ I'll give her a minute.
‐ Alright.
Mark, that was a lie.
This is for my son.
He's five.
You have a son?
Yeah.
I‐I haven't seen
him since he was two
but I talked to him
on the phone a few times.
You never said anything.
I know, I'm..
I know, I'm sorry.
'It's really complicated.'
'His father and I broke
up when he was born.'
You know I wasn't
really together back then
so I decided to let
Joe's parents take care of him.
He lives in a, um..
He lives in a trailer park
right outside Kankakee.
I'm going to seal
the rape kit now.
‐ Is that alright?
‐ Uh, yeah. Sure.
I know that this is
the best thing for Jason
although I, uh..
Miss him, you know?
Sure. I can only imagine.
But at least,
this year, for Christmas
I can send him
some nice things.
‐ Sure.
‐ Yeah.
What kind of sicko
would rape an old lady?
I know, I can't begin to count
the amount of times
I've done this.
It never gets any easier.
I'd get worried if it did.
Hey, Chuny, I don't suppose
you'd wanna work
for me tomorrow.
You'd get
time and a half.
Sorry. I'm going skiing
in Michigan with Alex.
Just the slopes, the snow
and a hot tub built for two.
Sounds great.
Hey, Carol, some
blue‐blood old lady is here
with Santa Claus
looking for you.
Already? She's early.
I'm sorry. As policy,
I don't give to panhandlers.
I recommend the Lakeshore
Shelter at 10th and Wacker.
Two bucks.
‐ Buddy, just give it a rest.
‐ Up yours, Santa.
Hey, go wait over there.
someone will
be with you in a minute.
I don't want someone.
I want the miracle man.
I'm so sorry about this.
Thank you so much for coming.
My pleasure.
This is another of my grandsons
Chase, John's cousin.
Hi. I'm Carol Hathaway.
Do you smell smoke?
Oh, my God! Cynthia,
get the fire extinguisher!
‐ 'Hey, look out!'
‐ 'Quick!'
‐ Do you know how to use it?
‐ Yes.
Nice job.
It's been, um..
...a little crazy
around here today.
Oh, man!
'All these lights need to
come down. They're way too old.'
Oh, even Rudolph?
I just bought him.
Uh, Rudolph can stay.
Carol, we need to talk.
In a minute.
So, this is where the
clinic patients wait
before they're seen.
Tell me about it.
I've been here over an hour.
Um, we're still
working out a few kinks.
Sharing space with the ER
Is, well, it's confusing.
Hey, Merry Christmas, gamma.
Oh, Merry Christmas.
I was just
giving her the tour.
Great. Where's‐where's gramps?
He overdid it playing
squash at the club.
Thought it best
to stay home.
Oh, must have been
pretty serious to keep him
out of the Santa suit.
We have an excellent substitute.
‐ Ha ha, yes.
‐ Hi, Scooter.
Very sharp.
Is the new improved?
Changing of the guard?
‐ Uh.
‐ I sure hope not.
Chase is
executive heir apparent.
We can't all be doctors.
Would you like
to see an exam room?
Hmm.
Hey, Nat, how's
it going, man?
Ah, just fine, Dr. Benton.
‐ How are you?
‐ Ah, can't complain.
‐ Having a little trouble?
‐ Yeah. She's 15 years old.
Bound to die on me sometime.
How's that baby of yours?
Ah, loud.
Actually, I'm looking
forward to his first Christmas.
Pretty soon,
you'll be begging him
to come home for Christmas.
Enjoy him while he still
wants to hang with his old man.
I'll do that.
‐ Hey, Merry Christmas, Nat.
‐ Merry Christmas.
Hey, hey, look at that!
She's working.
‐ Hey, Mark.
‐ Hi.
You know if we have any decaf?
Decaf? What's the point?
Well, Carter's
grandmother's asking for it.
Listen, did you catch that?
‐ What Cynthia said?
‐ What?
She has a kid.
A 5‐year‐old boy.
Yeah, living with her
ex‐boyfriend's parents.
Is this the first
you've heard of it?
Bad sign?
You're asking me?
Doug warned me
not to get involved.
Well, I mean if she's
expecting something of you
you're not willing to give
you're not doing her
any favors by dragging it out.
I'm not dragging
anything out.
Cynthia's great.
'Hey.'
I thought
you were flying home.
I postponed
to the red‐eye.
Allison Beaumont
came out of her coma.
Well, what's the prognosis?
Neurologically,
she looks good.
Romano and I did the
fibula transfer on her leg
this morning.
Congratulations.
Good work.
Part of me wants
to run in their and confess
tell her that it was my
enthusiasm for the procedure
that put her in
a coma in the first place.
Look, you saved her leg.
She's out of danger.
She's better off.
That's it, isn't it?
Purging my guilt will
help me to feel better.
It certainly
won't help her.
Bad things happen to people.
But you...you did your job.
Merry Christmas.
So, you have
any idea what happened?
Early morning, guy jumped
through her apartment door.
‐ It wasn't a secure building.
‐ Do you have any leads?
No, she wasn't much help.
It's all still a blur.
What about the writing?
Does that make it personal?
Look, doctor, uh?
Greene.
We can't discuss
an ongoing investigation.
We appreciate
your concern.
We'll handle it
from here, okay?
Sure, you will.
Well, what did she do,
liquidate a toy store?
You know Gamma Mill
never comes empty‐handed.
Who you supposed
to hand this out to?
Who cares? As long
as it makes her feel good.
I suppose we can pass them
out on the pediatric floor.
Hey, so did, uh,
gramps really overdo it
or does he just have
an aversion to hospitals?
All men over 70 have
an aversion to hospitals.
‐ Don't take it personally.
‐ No, it's a relief actually.
I don't have to defend
my wasted life in medicine.
You don't think
gamma will report back?
Well, it's a stay
of execution then.
He probably just
wants to wait
and get me on
his home turf.
He still thinks
you're a surgeon.
Yeah, I'm a coward.
Ah, you're braver
than I, my friend.
John, this
Mel Sauderback
headache, fever, malaise.
I think, he needs a spinal
tap to rule out meningitis.
I thought I might do it.
‐ He has diarrhea?
‐ Oh, yeah.
It's the stomach flu, Henry.
Oh. Oh.
Honestly? Continuity
of care is hard to measure.
Ah, sometimes you're part
care giver, part social worker
even part parent sometimes.
‐ And, um, Jeanie? Hi.
‐ Yeah.
I'd like you to meet
Millicent Carter.
‐ Oh hi, I'm Jeanie Boulet.
‐ How do you do?
Jeanie's
a physician assistant
who is helping us out
in the clinic today.
Cops are done
with Mrs. Larkin.
Can we scrub
the writing off?
I'll be right there.
Don't let me keep you.
Umm, actually
Jeanie, would you mind if
Mrs. Carter followed you around
while you saw some patients?
Sure.
Only if they're
comfortable with me there.
‐ That's no problem.
‐ Great, thank you.
pCO230, pH 7.4.
All good news.
How would you like to take
that tube out of your throat?
Hmm? I thought you might.
Alright.
When I tell you I want you
to take a deep breath in..
...and blow out hard
as I pull out the tube.
Can you do that for me?
Okay.
Now. Breathe in..
...and blow.
Well, great.
Great. That's better.
No. Don't try to speak.
The tube's been
in for over a week.
Your throat
needs time to adjust.
Okay?
Let me get you
some ice chips.
Can you ring the head‐and‐neck
surgeon on call, please?
Is it an emergency?
It's Christmas Eve.
Just do it, okay?
Gina, have you
been tested for HIV?
‐ No.
‐ You should.
Look, the boys
are all in high school.
They don't have AIDS.
That's not true.
And with
your history of chlamydia
you're at greater risk.
I got to get home.
I can draw
some blood right now.
No. I'm cool.
Gina, look,
if you are HIV‐positive
and you decide
to have this child
you'll want to protect
it against infection.
There are drugs
that you could take now
that'll help reduce
the chances
of passing the virus
along to your baby.
Look, I don't
have AIDS, okay?
I don't sleep with
gay guys or druggies.
Neither did I.
You have AIDS?
I'm HIV‐positive.
How long will
the test take?
Chuny, someone
paged me for a consult?
Not that I know of.
God, no.
Hey.
He wouldn't calm down
until I promised to call you.
What is it?
You're not going
to believe this.
He's blind again.
No nystagmus
with the opticokinetic drum.
Is that him, is that Dr. Benton?
‐ What's his name again?
‐ Bart.
'I can't see no more, doc.'
'You have
to touch me again.'
Okay, look
straight ahead, Bart.
Have to touch me, doc.
Please...do like
you done before.
Touch me.
Okay, um..
...try again.
Okay, let's get
him up for a CT.
One more time.
Just one more time, doc.
Try it again, please.
'One more time.'
I'll dress this an orthopedist
will look at your ankle
and we'll admit
you for observation.
They'll be
so disappointed.
I'm sorry?
I play the organ at church.
They always have
an organ for Christmas mass.
I'm sure
they'll understand.
It's probably too late
to find a substitute.
Mrs. Larkin, you have
to stop worrying about mass.
You've been through
something horrible.
I don't want
to talk about that.
You don't have to.
It's so hard.
I'm so angry.
'I hate him.'
'Whoever he is.'
There's nothing wrong with that.
I can't be like that.
I have to forgive.
You don't have
to forgive anybody.
He did this, not you.
Hating him won't
make this go away.
I'm afraid nothing
will make it go away.
Kerry, can you
cover my last half hour?
There's something
gotta take care of.
What is it?
I covered for you
this morning
and you do have that bionic
attending from Synergix to help.
‐ Sure, I'd be happy to.
‐ Okay.
Merry Christmas.
Yeah, Merry Christmas.
'Hey, you leaving?'
Listen.. I gotta do this thing.
Um, can you take the El home?
‐ To your home, right?
‐ I don't know.
I'm gonna have
to call you later, okay?
Okay.
I'm sorry
I've been so busy.
Did you get to see
anything interesting?
It's been a very
enlightening experience.
Is there anything else
you'd like to see?
No, I've seen
everything I needed to.
Uh, may I use your phone?
Yes, of course.
Uh, we're having
a potluck dinner
if you'd like to stay.
No, thank you.
‐ Is she upset?
‐ I'm not sure.
Oh, John, I'm
ready to leave.
‐ Where's your cousin?
‐ I thought he was with you.
Maybe he's handing out gifts.
‐ Are you talking about Santa?
‐ Yeah.
He went out
for some fresh air.
Santa, you in there?
What is this?
‐ It's nothing.
‐ Nothing?
Sh‐shut the door.
Are you crazy?
What the hell
do you think you're doing?
Just a little...stocking
stuffer.
This isn't funny.
How long you been doing this?
Oh, John, just chill out.
It's.. I'm not an addict.
I just.. I do it
when I'm bored, okay?
I cannot believe
how stupid I was.
A spider bite.
That was from
skin popping wasn't it?
‐ You lied to me?
‐ Can you blame me?
Oh, come on
you're smarter than this.
I got it under control.
Yeah, so does
every street junkie
that I see come
through this place.
I am not a street junkie
and I, buy pure stuff.
Yeah, I don't care,
I don't care how pure it is.
You know, I thank you for
the medical advice, doctor
but I'd prefer it
if you were just my cousin.
Taking to hiding out
in cars, have we?
Filling in for
your grandfather
doesn't entitle you
to his bad habits.
I had some...work I had to do.
Or his excuses.
Something that matter?
No. I better get back.
Come a little
early tonight, John.
Your grandfather
would like to talk to you.
I'll try.
That is one
nasty‐looking craniopharyngioma.
Right here, compressing
against the optic chasm.
So that explains
the blindness.
Boy from the size of it,
it's been growing for years.
How do you account
for the temporary sight?
Ah, sometimes,
the mind plays tricks on you.
So the head trauma
could have caused it?
Or maybe it triggered
some visual memory.
No, no, no, this guy could see.
Trust me,
I was there. I saw it.
I don't know what to tell
you, from the medical evidence
'in front of me,
I mean there's no way'
this man has seen anything
for five or six years.
Lizzie, I thought you'd
be somewhere
over the Atlantic,
by now.
Oh, slight change of plans.
Oh, I didn't make you
miss your flight did I?
No. No, I just decided
on spending Christmas
in Chicago after all.
Awesome.
I'm on my way to a party.
A friend of mine is, uh
renting out the entire top floor
of the prudential building.
You want to come along?
Oh, thank you,
but, uh, no.
I'm waiting on
a head‐and‐neck consult.
Oh, for the Beaumont girl.
Yes, I'm afraid her vocal
cords might be paralyzed.
Hmm.
Well, don't hold your breath
on the consult, that is.
He's probably on his way
to a party somewhere himself.
Just the same.
Well, maybe New Year's Eve.
Hmm. Lovely.
Carol, I got three
things to say to you
Gladys Knight,
Atlantic City, fourth row.
What do you want, Connie?
My girlfriend has
tickets for New Year's.
I'm so there you gotta get
someone to cover for me.
What are you doing
tomorrow night?
Is Carol Hathaway here?
Yeah, I'm her.
Holiday design.
I have a delivery for you.
‐ Oh where is it?
‐ Outside.
‐ Why don't you bring it in?
‐ It won't fit.
'Wow!'
‐ Now, that's a tree.
‐ It's gorgeous.
I can't believe
they got it in here.
‐ Sign here.
‐ Thank you so much.
Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas to you, too.
Who is this from?
"Happy holidays from
the Carter family foundation."
‐ 'Oh, my God.'
‐ 'What?'
‐ It's a check.
‐ A 150 grand.
Oh, my God.
I guess she
liked it here.
Hi. I'm Mark Greene.
‐ I'm the doctor..
‐ I know who you are.
Yes. Uh..
I'm very sorry
for your loss.
It's Christmas Eve,
Dr. Greene.
I know.
What the hell
you doing here?
Uh, I came to apologize.
I thought you was
above all that.
And your uptown
lawyer he blew us off.
He‐he was wrong.
Uh, I was wrong.
Look, I can't tell you if my
assumption about your brother
was racism or experience.
Probably both.
I can tell you
that I used you.
It wasn't you.
No.
Feel better now?
Maybe.
Can't front, though.
Hell, I was glad when I
heard you got beat down.
'I wanted you to hurt..'
And whether you get messed up
or we get a million dollars
my brother's still dead.
Some punk dealer shot him.
And there's no meaning in that.
I'm sorry.
‐ Dr. Benton?
‐ Yeah.
How'd you know?
Your shoes squeak.
Come to give me
the bad news?
You've a very large
brain tumor.
It's what caused
the blindness.
It's operable, but, uh,
because of the place and size
it's going to be
difficult to completely remove.
However,
with a little radiation
there is, uh..
...a good chance of survival.
So, I'll be able to see again.
Well, once the
tumor is extracted
it's possible,
but...highly unlikely.
It was highly
unlikely I'd see today.
Medically, that was impossible.
I spent all afternoon
in the park, you know
just...watching.
Santos playing
in the snow and..
'...steam coming
up off the water'
'and‐and the way'
snow falls lightly on the trees.
It's beautiful, innit?
Yeah. I guess so.
Trust me.
It's beautiful.
‐ Hello.
‐ Hey, good day?
It ended good.
Guess who got tomorrow off?
So you flexed a little
muscle, did you?
Well, I had to give up
New Year's
but I figured it's worth it.
‐ Oh, no.
‐ What?
Uh, I volunteered to work
for Anna tomorrow.
She's an intern.
I just thought maybe we'd
spend more
time together then.
Oh, you didn't.
No, I didn't.
That's a lie.
Oh, God!
Would have been
romantic, though.
Well, yeah.
You're looking at me.
What?
Come here.
Can I have
your attention, everybody?
Hello? Can I have
your attention, please?
I have an announcement to make.
Can you turn down that music?
Okay, I have kept
this a secret far too long.
Doug Ross and I
are seeing each other again..
And we're very happy.
Okay, pay up, pay up.
I was a week to late
I thought New Year's for sure.
Yeah, I'm surprised
they kept it a secret this long.
You knew?
Please, honey, it was obvious.
‐ Well, I didn't know.
‐ Me, either.
Maybe, uh, something
that you guys
didn't know is
uh, that, uh, we've
been seeing each other
for, uh, a little
while now, again
and, uh, I think
it would be great
if she were to marry me.
I mean everyone
talk her into it.
Help me talk
her into it.
To Carol and Doug,
get it right this time.
‐ 'Guys! Congratulations!'
‐ Hear! Hear! Hear! Hear!
You always have
to outdo me, don't you?
I had the opportunity,
and I took it.
Congratulations. I'm so
happy for the both of you.
‐ Thank you, Dr. Carter.
‐ Thank you.
'Hey everybody let's move
this party outside.'
So you gonna stick around
till I get off work?
Hell, no.
'Careful.'
Whoa.
Promise to meet
me at the airport
or I'll take
you there myself.
I didn't pack
my bathing suit.
Don't worry. I know
a private beach.
‐ Merry Christmas, Kerry.
‐ Yeah. You, too.
'So, you got plans tonight?'
Yeah, I plan
to be alone.
You want some company?
Don't you have some family
obligation or something?
I've had enough
family for one day.
John?
Whoa. You okay?
Listen, I got
the blood gas
on the asthmatic in three.
Only took me
two sticks.
Great. Put it on ice
and run it up to the lab.
Okay.
Hey, Henry, Henry, Henry.
Merry Christmas.
Oh, John,
I‐I didn't get you anything.
It's your evaluation.
Congratulations.
You just passed
emergency medicine.
‐ I don't know what to say.
‐ Do me a favor?
Stick to brain research?
‐ I promise.
‐ Alright, then.
I will, thank you, John.
‐ Thank you.
‐ Okay.
Okay.
Thank you.
‐ Thank you.
‐ Henry.
Okay.
‐ Okay.
‐ Goodnight.
♪ Pray for peace
people everywhere ♪
♪ Listen to what I say ♪
♪ Oh the child the child ♪
♪ Sleeping in the night ♪
♪ He will bring us ♪
♪ Goodness and light ♪
♪ Goodness and light.. ♪