Keep it in, Dad.
I have to cough, Mark.
Yeah, well, you
don't have to talk.
Put it back in.
You want me to bite down on it?
Dad.
End up with a
mouthful of mercury.
Dad.
All right, say "E."
E.
Once again.
Last time.
E. Cripes!
Sounds like pneumonia.
We gotta get you to the hospital
and get a chest film.
Oh, hell, Mark, do we have to?
You have something
better to do today?
It's Sunday. I figured
we could go to church.
Yeah, right.
Temperature's 101.
Big deal.
Morning, Randi.
Dr. Weaver, welcome back.
Kerry, nice to see you.
Robert.
I hope a few weeks
off was enough time
for you to rethink some of
your professional choices.
Few weeks long enough for
you to get buried down here
with Mark taking extra time off?
Not at all. I loved being
up-close and personal
with my troops,
and you didn't
answer my question.
I don't intend to.
Well, I'll take the fact
that you came back to work
as a yes.
After all, I didn't
appoint you chief
so that you could turn
all soft and mushy on me.
No. I know you didn't. Mm.
And I'm sure you do realize
that I can un-appoint you
should you find it too difficult
to uphold the standards
of this department.
Yes, I do.
Well, then, top of
the mornin' to you.
John.
Oh, man.
What time is it?
Quarter past 7.
How about some breakfast?
Um... yeah, maybe
just some toast.
Did you get any sleep?
Well, I gave up trying around 2.
I came downstairs and
watched a couple infomercials.
Hey, I ordered you
one of those machines
so you can make
your own beef jerky.
You didn't?
I didn't.
Then I came in here.
This seems to be the
only room in the house
where you can sleep.
Maybe we should
put a bed in here?
S-somebody!
John?
Hm? What?
I wish you'd talk to somebody
about your not sleeping.
I'll be fine.
You want a slice?
Absolutely.
You wanna shoot some hoops?
Wait till she's done bulkin' up.
Hey! I'm sorry, Cleo.
I can take it.
As soon as I'm done bulking up.
Hey, why don't you guys
go ahead? Go, go, go, go.
'Cause she's so
bad, it's no fun.
I could kick your butt.
Hey, hey. Go, go,
both of you now.
I'd like to say
excuse my children,
but there's just no
excuse for my children.
It's okay. I grew up with three
brothers. I'm used to the abuse.
Peter tells me you're
from Indianapolis.
That right? Yup.
Hm, does your family
all still live there?
Yeah, they do. JESSE: Mom!
Peter, could you go
shut them up, please?
Yeah, yeah, listen,
just don't grill her
with a million questions,
all right? Go, go.
So... any of your brothers
become doctors too?
No, a couple of
them work for my dad.
And that would be in?
Insurance. Hm.
He's in insurance.
It's a good line of work.
You didn't wanna do that? Mm.
Working together,
living so close,
family can be a little stifling.
I mean, not all
families, of course.
Of course.
Have another waffle.
Mm. Thanks.
Let's transfer. One, two, three.
Get a CBC, chem
panel and dip a urine.
Delia, do you remember
what happened?
Daddy was taking
me to Shelly's house,
and this car hit us really fast.
Mr. Chadsey, does she have
any previous medical problems?
She had leukemia. Do
you know what kind?
AML. She's been in
remission for eight months.
How's your arm? Uh...
Oh, looks like you're
gonna need sutures.
Uh, I... I wanna
stay with Delia.
Haleh.
We could do it right here.
I'll go get a chair.
Are you okay, Daddy?
Yeah, it's just a little cut.
They're gonna fix me up.
I had stitches
once. It's not bad.
Well, I'm gonna try to
be as brave as you are.
Okay?
Okay.
All I'm sayin' is
you can't go wrong with a Chevy.
I've gone wrong
many times in a Chevy.
I always admired the Subaru.
Yeah, I say go with
something classic,
like an old Mustang convertible.
Two babies, Randi, remember?
Maybe Al could get you something
from the police auction.
What do you drive, Luka?
An old Saab.
No, don't go Swedish.
They've got the
highest suicide rate.
Well, what's this all about?
I'm gonna go buy a new
car. I mean, a new, used car.
When? Today?
Yeah. My mom's
got the twins, so...
What time are you off?
About an hour? Why?
You should go to
the place I got mine.
I know the guy there.
He'll give you a good deal.
If you can wait a bit,
I can come with you.
You should definitely
take a guy with you.
They don't listen to
me, but they listen to Al.
They listen to me,
but I'm on all day.
Me too. You sure you don't mind?
No, of course not.
I just have a few
cases to finish up.
Okay, thanks. Good.
Dr. Corday?
CBC's back on Delia Chadsey.
White blood count of 60,000.
Fifty percent blasts.
Her leukemia's back.
I wonder why she never
got a bone-marrow transplant.
Do you want me
to talk to the father?
Uh, no, I could do it.
Thanks.
Oh, Mark, I heard
your father's here.
Malik's gettin' him settled in.
What is it?
Rhonchi, consolidation
in his right lung.
Wanna go check on him now?
I didn't wanna be here, either,
but my son has the last
word in most things medical.
Tell me about it.
My son's a first-year
med student.
Only thing worse is a
first-year law student.
That would be my daughter.
Hey, Mark, this is
Sarah MacKenzie.
We're, uh, kindred spirits
in being hospital hostages.
How do you do?
Nothing serious, I hope?
No, knocked up my
shin. Got infected.
Hello, David, how are you?
Well, I'm still here,
Elizabeth. Couldn't be too bad.
Wanna do a portable chest?
No, get him to
Radiology right away.
Get a good P.A. and a lateral.
And make sure he
goes over on O-2.
This is Dr. Elizabeth Corday.
She and my son are...
I don't know what
you call it nowadays.
"Friends."
Hello. Hello.
Looks like you've
got your hands full.
Yes. I can do that.
No, I got it. Five of albuterol.
Want me to start a saline lock?
I can do that too. Sure.
Not bad. Two doctors, huh?
No waiting.
Reece went out like a light.
Not only can she
eat, she can play.
Yeah, the kids like her.
Mm-hm.
What about you?
Since when do you
care what I think?
The question is,
do you like her?
I wouldn't have brought
her here if I didn't.
Are you serious about her?
Jackie, it's a little
early to be serious.
I hope so.
Because she's not
serious about you.
All right.
What's that supposed to mean?
I'm just sayin'.
She's havin' fun,
but that girl's not
ready to settle down.
Who says I am?
Oh, right.
You're not so settled
with a 3-year-old.
Come on, Jackie, that doesn't
mean I wanna get married.
She's nice, we have fun.
But it's not serious, you know?
Good. Glad to hear it.
Then I like her too.
So, what is this, your
female intuition thing again?
Certainly not.
Did she say something?
She had to.
I asked a million questions.
Come on.
Edgar's mother is
an ICU nurse upstairs.
She's trying to find
someone to fill in for her.
What are you
thinking, meningitis?
Fever, vomiting, headache.
I need you to help
me with the LP.
Is he lethargic?
A little sleepy.
Gave him Versed.
Can you roll him up in a ball?
Yeah.
All right, Edgar, don't worry.
Everything's gonna be just fine.
Okay, good position.
Okay, here we go.
Steady.
Okay, I'm ready.
Good, I'm in.
Okay, I feel the pop.
Did you feel the pop?
No. Keep going.
I... I can't. Yes, you can.
Stop, please! You're
hurting me. Please.
Calm down! It's all right.
What are you
sticking in my back?
Malik, give him another two
of Ativan. Lucy, keep going.
It'll be a traumatic tap,
blood in his spinal fluid.
Don't think it's
gonna get any easier.
To the lab OLIGARIO: Right away.
There you go, Edgar.
This isn't so bad, is it?
Your medication
will wear off shortly,
and you won't feel
so sleepy, okay?
Thanks, Carter.
Carter? Hm?
Thanks.
Sure... Yeah, sure. No problem.
Did anyone ever discuss
a bone-marrow
transplant with you?
Yeah, there was no
HLA-matched relative.
I only matched three
out of her six antigens.
You've been through
this before, I guess.
Oh, yeah, bigtime.
Well, with the recurrence,
she's gonna need
reinduction chemotherapy.
Chemo again?
Oh, man.
God, we were so hopeful.
In about two months,
when she goes into
her second remission,
they can try a BMT.
Yeah, if they can find a donor.
There are no other
possibilities in the family?
Nah. Not exactly.
Not exactly?
Delia has a half sister,
but she's not been tested.
Why not? Daughter
from my first marriage.
The divorce was pretty ugly.
My ex-wife's not
really inclined to help.
Not even to save
another child's life?
I think that we should just
go ahead with the chemo,
and then just go from there.
Sure. And I'll check with the
National Registry in Milwaukee,
'cause a match with
an unrelated donor's
better than nothing.
Thank you.
Are you ready yet?
Uh, just about.
CVA is being
admitted to medicine,
seizure patient can go home,
and little Edgar Braley's LP
was negative for meningitis,
but we're still
waiting for his lytes.
And his mother had to
go back to work upstairs.
Okay, I'll check up
on him. Good luck.
Thanks. Thank you.
Hey, Edgar, how you doin'?
What's she got?
Why does she have that stick?
No, no, it's okay. It's okay.
What's she going to do?
Nobody's gonna do anything.
I don't want her to touch
me. Don't let her touch me!
It's o... OLIGARIO:
Wait a minute.
Get her away from me!
Whoa, whoa!
It's all right. No,
get her away!
Hey, hey.
It's okay. Get her away!
Whoa! Get her away from me!
Okay. Hey... Hey.
Oh, I'm sorry, Dr. Weaver.
Well, I guess he's,
uh, feeling better.
Go. Go ahead and get him, Conni.
Get Malucci if you need help.
Mark.
Hey. Hey.
How is he?
Making new friends as usual.
Got the films back.
It is post-obstruction
pneumonia.
Gave him a gram of
cefotaxime, IV piggyback.
So are you going
to keep him here?
For a while.
Make sure he doesn't
have a bad reaction
to the antibiotics.
I'll stop in and say hello.
So, um, can I do
anything to help?
I'm just gonna
steal some supplies.
Don't tell anybody.
Well, I love
stealing. Let me help.
Uh, saline flushes.
Need alcohol wipes.
Okay, check.
Ah. Uh, two-by-twos,
extension tubing.
Extension tubing. Check.
Needles and syringes.
Syringes.
Mark.
Uh, needles and syringes.
I'm gonna, uh...
I guess I'm gonna need
to borrow some more, uh,
infusion bottles of cefotaxime.
My dad'll be on antibiotics
for 10 to 14 days,
depending on how he responds.
Yeah, of course.
I'm sorry. It
would've been faster
if I'd had my car today.
Oh, that's okay.
Unfortunately, it's
in the shop. What?
No, just a routine checkup.
Nothing wrong, really.
This is a good
place. You'll like Herb.
Herb? Yeah.
He and I are like
this, you know.
He's my second cousin's
wife's brother-in-law.
That would definitely
make you like this.
Excited?
About buying a used car?
No. My mom thinks I
should get a minivan.
Oh, yeah, they're very
good. You know, practical.
Very "my life is over"?
Ah, don't say that. Come on.
We'll have him put a
Porsche engine in it.
Really?
No.
I'm... I'm sorry. I was kidding.
I don't think bringing you
along was such a good idea.
No, you'll see. We'll get
you something really good.
Mrs. Pooler, do you
have any allergies?
Wh...? What is it?
Wh-what's wrong?
Tachy at 120.
Pulse ox is 91 on two liters.
Are you on any medications?
Uh, just a pill for
high blood pressure.
Uh, proprana... Propranolol?
Yeah, propranolol, yeah.
You shouldn't take
that with asthma.
That can kill you.
Who's your doctor?
Mr. Pooler?
I-it's my medication
for high blood pressure.
You see, Ruth has Medicare,
and they won't pay
for her prescriptions.
Her, uh, uh, enala... Enalapril?
Y-yeah, yeah. It costs $50.
We... We just have
our social security,
so we thought she
could take mine.
See, I'm in an HMO.
I-I get 'em for free.
Well, I don't understand.
Why are you in an
HMO, and your wife isn't?
I-I have heart trouble.
I take a lot of pills.
But she just has the...
The asthma and wanted
to keep her own doctor.
So, uh, the HMO won't...
Won't let her do that.
Hey, found your runaway.
Where was he?
Cafeteria, eatin'
tapioca pudding.
Says he hangs out
there with his mom.
Is he okay? Yeah, he
seems to be all right.
Good. His labs came back.
Elevated BUN and creatinine.
Also his potassium's
a little low.
Give him a saline
bolus, 10 per kilo,
and put him on maintenance.
Ooh, you want me to take him?
I want you to spiff
him up, Malucci.
Sure thing, chief.
I don't think this is right.
Uh, no.
I think you would've remembered
if it had been across the street
from a major-league
baseball field.
It doesn't seem
like a natural place
for a used-car lot, does it?
Gee, no, it doesn't.
I'm hungry. Yeah, me too.
What do you think? A hot dog?
It's here.
Sorry about this.
Mr. Chadsey.
Oh, I was just getting
Delia some water.
Uh, I spoke to the
Legal department,
and there's nothing we can
do to make your ex-wife...
I didn't ask you
to check on that.
What are you doing?
Well, I-I think you
should talk to her.
No, I-I already told you,
she's not gonna help.
Well, then, let me try. No.
Mr. Chadsey... I said, no!
I just wanna be
with my daughter.
Please don't make this
harder than it already is.
Do ya think this is
really necessary?
The propranolol that you
gave her lasts for 24 hours,
so she needs to be
on a continuous
breathing treatment.
Oh, such a fuss. I'm sorry.
Don't worry, Mrs. Pooler.
The ICU will take
good care of you.
I know.
They did last time
after my operation.
You were here for an operation?
Mm-hm. CARTER: For what?
Oh. Oh, dear, let me think.
Uh, uh, wh...? What...?
What was it called, Ralph?
Oh, gee, I-I'm not sure.
It was something to do
with her, uh, stomach.
Oh, yes, that's it.
They took something
out of my stomach.
Do you think that'd
make a difference now?
Oh, I doubt it, but I'll check
her old chart just to be sure.
Come on, here we go.
Oh, thank you, doctor.
You're very welcome.
Randi, I'll be in
Medical Records.
Okey-dokey.
The infield fly rule
is when the
batter hits the ball,
and it goes way high up, and,
you know, up, like,
over the pitcher's mound.
Then, the runner on
2nd has to run to 3rd
before the runner
on 1st can run to 2nd.
Hm, I thought they weren't
supposed to run at all
on a fly ball.
It's complicated.
You... You don't have any idea
what the infield
fly rule is, do you?
Can we go now?
I mean, you may
have a new used car,
but I don't.
My first transportation
was a tractor.
A tractor?
Yeah, my grandpa's farm.
He let me drive when
I was about 11, 12,
till I took out a couple of
fences and one of his cows.
Was your dad a farmer too?
No, he was a train conductor.
He let me ride on his
lap when I was little.
Sometimes, my... My
brother and I would go
all the way to Zagreb with him,
and we'd run
through the other cars,
looking at the passengers,
thinking, you know:
"My father drives the train."
You spent a lot of
time with your dad?
Yeah.
Did you come here
a lot with your father?
Learn about baseball?
Why? 'Cause I know so much?
Yeah.
No, actually.
My dad died when
I was really little.
I'm sorry. I never
really knew him.
Yeah, so am I.
It must make you think
about Kate and Tess,
about their
knowing their father.
Yeah, I guess.
But you would know what
they're missing more than I do.
Yeah.
Are we gonna buy a car,
or are we gonna buy a car?
We are going to buy a car.
I couldn't find the
file on Ruth Pooler.
If it's been more than two
years, it's in remote storage.
I can get it in about
an hour. Okay.
Oh, but I found that other
one you wanted. Uh...
Paul Sobriki.
Psych file?
Well, that's the one.
Sign right here.
Thanks.
Hey, Dr. Carter.
Dr. DeRaad, hi.
How you doin'?
Good. Fine.
Yeah, just goin' over an
old chart. Asthma patient.
Gettin' back into work okay?
Yeah, pretty well.
I have good days and bad days.
Actually, today
hasn't been, uh... I...
Well... come on
up and we'll talk.
No. No, no.
I'm okay.
I know.
But I have time.
Say 3:00?
Sure.
Thanks.
That was a hell of a
time. That's for sure.
Sam did two tours.
Wanted to do a third
but I told him I'd kill him.
He heard me.
Dad, what are you doin'?
Mrs. MacKenzie
and I are talking.
Please, call me Sarah.
Pulse ox, Dad.
You gotta leave
it on your finger.
I didn't even know it was off.
Her husband's an
old naval man too,
even served in Vietnam.
Although later than I did.
Is that so?
He still thinks he's a Navy man.
Out on the lake right
now runnin' around
in his old powerboat,
says it keeps him sane.
Isn't this thing
supposed to be dripping?
I understand what he means.
Try and keep
your elbow straight.
I love being out on the water.
Sometimes, in the
middle of the night,
you'd get a storm.
Thirty-foot waves coming
in different directions and...
rocking and rolling like
you wouldn't believe.
Still,
it puts you to sleep
like a little baby.
I'd wake up at dawn,
go out to the tip
of the bow, and...
the water would
be clear and calm.
The ship slicing
through it like cool air.
Calmest place on
earth, I used to think.
Like the storm...
never even happened.
Hi, Jessamyn?
Yes?
Jessamyn Chadsey?
Yes. Jessamyn, who is it?
Hi, uh, Mrs. Lomax?
Yes? Uh, my name
is Abby Lockhart.
I work at County General.
Is something wrong?
Did something happen
to Terry? Please, come in.
No, no.
Um...
I've... I've been treating
your former husband's daughter.
Did he send you here?
No, he didn't.
You know about her leukemia?
Get out of here right now.
Jessamyn, upstairs.
No. Mom, I wanna stay.
Mrs. Lomax, she's a child.
And the closest match we
have is an unrelated donor.
I said, get out!
If Jessamyn matched,
she would have
a much better chance of
survival. At least let us try.
I don't care about him
or anything to do with him!
Can you understand
that? Mom, calm down.
Don't tell me to calm
down, Jess. Now, please...
leave.
Mrs. Lomax, if you could just...
I asked you to leave.
Do I need to call somebody?
'97 Camry, power
steering, power brakes,
power windows, power locks,
power seats, and all for only...
$18,000? That's outrageous!
You're really enjoying
this, aren't you?
Now, here we go.
Special deal. Very
low price, $3300.
What is it?
It's a Dodge Dynasty. 1989.
Excellent year and
only 90,000 miles, huh?
Who gets a Dodge Dynasty?
Okay, okay, it's not your thing.
How about the '91
Mercury Sable for... 2900?
What more could you want?
Hey, four doors,
windshield wipers, antenna...
Hey, Malucci.
Yeah, chief?
Come here.
Don't look now, but your, uh,
little runaway, Edgar Braley,
- is hiding down the hall.
- What's he doing?
I don't know. My guess
is he's spying on me.
Get him back to Exam 2.
We're treating
her with antibiotics,
but the oxygen level is low.
Pneumonia can be a peaceful
way for an elderly person to die.
We don't want her to die.
As the oxygen level drops,
she'll simply fall asleep,
and eventually stop breathing.
There's no pain or suffering.
Well, can't you put her
on a breathing machine?
Sometimes it's best to just
let nature take its course.
When I saw her last month,
she was sitting up
in a chair, eating.
Well, she stopped
eating a while ago
according to the nursing home.
She's being fed
through a tube now,
directly into her stomach.
We can't just let Grandma die.
We're not going to, honey.
If you'd like some time to...
No, we don't need time.
We need somebody
who's willing to help us,
and obviously, that's not you!
Um... if you'll excuse
me for a moment.
Oh, have you seen Dr. Weaver?
No.
I keep having these thoughts.
It's like I, uh, see
moments of the accident.
Or something reminds me.
The accident?
I'd say it was
more of an attack.
A brutal attack for which
you had no warning.
Right.
Well, that's the thing.
See, I assisted on the
spinal tap on Paul Sobriki.
And he was aggressive.
And he was overreacting.
And he'd had Ativan. And I
numbed him with lidocaine.
But his... His response was...
as if...
we were stabbing him.
In his mental state,
he thought you were.
I... I should've realized that
something was very wrong.
So should've Lucy,
but she didn't pick up
on it either, did she?
There's always
gonna be "what ifs."
What if I had gotten down there
sooner for the psych consult?
It'd be easier for all of us
if we could think
of it as an accident,
but none of us have that luxury.
I know.
I just want to get these
thoughts out of my head.
It's gonna take some time.
Have you seen him?
Paul Sobriki?
You know, I was just wondering
if you'd seen him or his wife?
No, I haven't.
You're curious about
what's happening with them?
No. No. I just...
It's a 911. I gotta go.
Um, thank you.
Anytime. Come back.
It has been a pleasure.
A real pleasure.
Come back soon.
Although I know
you won't need to,
'cause this car's
gonna last you 10 years.
My name is Manny. Uh,
did you get a number?
Oh, God, I hope I'm not
driving this car in 10 years.
Hey, it's a beauty. Come on.
Luka, it's a small
station wagon.
But I thank you for your help.
Shall we celebrate?
Are you stealing?
No, Dad, I'm borrowing.
I think he's stealing.
Dr. Greene, I need
your help with this family.
Uh, I'm not on today.
I know, but I can't
find Dr. Weaver.
All right, Dad, I'll be
right back. Let's hear it.
What happened?
Syncope with blunt
head trauma. Altered.
He took a fall while
settling his wife into the ICU.
Mr. Pooler, are you all right?
Lateral C-spine and chest?
CBC, lytes, cardiac
enzymes, repeat EKG.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Look out, look out, look out.
Let's get a head CT
after we clear the neck.
Where's all the
blood coming from?
Occipital scalp lac.
No hemotympanum.
Systolic's 95, pulse ox, 98.
All right, bolus
another 250 of saline.
Give me a gram of Ancef
and update his tetanus.
Here's the 12-lead
from upstairs.
No ST changes.
At least he's not
having a heart attack.
She can't eat.
She has no quality of life.
If we intubate her,
they'll take her up to the ICU.
And hook her up to tubes
and wires and machines.
And she'll die in
perhaps two, three weeks.
If we leave her as she is now,
she'll die today,
maybe tomorrow,
but peacefully.
You need to think carefully
about what she would want.
Mr. Hemmings, your
mother is letting go.
And you think that's
what we should do?
I think you should spend
some more time with her.
Thank you, Dr. Greene.
Sure.
Thanks Elizabeth. I'll let you
know what the head CT shows.
Mm-hm.
How's it going?
All right. How are you?
Uh, I think I'm gonna
pack up the old man
and take him for a spin.
His labs haven't come back
yet and neither have his films.
Okay. I'll call the lab.
You call Radiology? Okay.
Oh, boy. What?
Um, do you remember that
leukemia case I mentioned?
Hi, Jessamyn.
Are they still here?
Um, this is Dr. Weaver.
Hi, Jessamyn.
Yes, they're waiting
for a bed upstairs.
I wanna do this. I
want to help out if I can.
So, what do I have to do?
Uh, okay. Well,
um, I don't know...
Did your mother drive you here?
No, I drove in myself.
Does she know you're here?
I'm old enough to
decide on my own.
My mom is a good person,
but when it comes to this subject,
there is no talking to her.
So she hasn't given consent?
My dad wants this. I want this.
That has to count for something.
It does. I mean, it...
I-it counts for a lot.
But I'm afraid the rules
are very clear on this.
This is your mother's decision.
She said she couldn't understand
how something like this could
happen with a life at stake.
I don't either.
I'm so sorry.
Abby, let me know
when those labs are back.
Um, why don't I take
you to see your father.
I don't want to see him.
Well, I'm sure it
would mean a lot
knowing that you
wanted to do this.
I don't care what he thinks.
I'm only trying to help Delia.
Good eating today.
Hot dog, hamburger.
French fries?
Mm.
Thank you.
I haven't been
through a drive-through
in I don't know how long.
Hey, it would've
been a pity to have left
the car all alone
on its first day.
Yes, I agree.
When I first came to Chicago,
I used to come out here a lot.
You know, to look at the city.
It's so beautiful.
Did you grow up in a city?
No, near the coast.
Is that where you
were during the war?
No.
Then we were in, uh, Vukovar.
A small apartment. I
didn't have much money.
We kept the children
in all the time for safety.
They would get crazy.
Wh-what do you call it?
Cabin fever. Yeah.
I was going to the market.
Not for much. Some
cheese and bread.
And they were
climbing all over me.
"Please let me
come. Let me come."
And the answer was the same
as always, "No, it's not safe."
My wife stayed with them.
Luka.
No, it's okay.
I was only maybe,
uh, 50 meters away
when I heard the
whistle in the air.
An artillery shell
hit the building.
It's all redone now.
People rebuilt
all during the war.
One day, you are
sitting at a caf,
the next day, it's bombed.
And the day after that,
they... They begin to build.
That's what you do.
Something happens,
you rebuild, you go on.
We should probably go.
Your mother will think
you've gone joy-riding.
Hey, Randi, where
is, uh, Dr. Malucci?
Uh, he was with a patient
in Exam 1 a little while ago.
Thanks.
Hey, Malu...
Dr. Weaver.
Abby, uh, can I speak
to you for a moment?
I don't want to
hear your reasons,
I don't want to hear
your justifications.
Did you know that I
could fail you for that?
Yes.
What were you thinking?
I was just trying to help.
What that girl did
coming here was brave.
What you've done is stupid.
I mean, her sister's gonna be
in chemotherapy for two months
before the transplant.
You don't think the
mother's gonna find out?
She just wanted to help.
Yeah, and it's our
sometimes lousy job to say no.
There are rules this
emergency department
must follow and will
follow. Is...? Is that clear?
Yes.
Make sure she's
okay to drive home.
Dr. Weaver.
I don't think trying
to help is ever stupid.
I'm really sorry.
I hope I didn't get you
into too much trouble.
No, I'll live.
Jessamyn, while you're here,
why don't you just
go see your dad?
No, I'm... I'm gonna leave.
Well, I... I really
wish you wouldn't.
Dr. Weaver, Hm?
I'm having a little
trouble with an HMO.
A 76-year-old guy with syncope.
They want to transfer him, I
think we should keep him here.
Any EKG changes or
ectopy on the monitor? No.
What's the health
insurance? Blue Beacon.
They contract with New Western,
we transfer their
stable patients.
Well, it's more
complicated than that.
I admitted his wife to the ICU.
They won't authorize that.
I think it would be best
if we kept 'em together.
They won't authorize it, John.
I don't think he's gonna be
stable enough for transfer.
He's dehydrated.
So rehydrate him.
Well, he's hypokalemic.
Replete his potassium.
He's anemic.
Actively bleeding? No.
Then it's a chronic
problem. He's ready to go.
He should stay with his
wife, it's what he wants.
Does he also want to
pay a $2000 hospital bill?
All right, well, I'm
leaving pretty soon.
I don't know if I'll be able
to oversee the transfer.
Then I'll do it.
They were filming this movie...
Swedish, I think.
Near my grandpa's farm,
and they needed animals.
So you just rented out a whole
bunch of cows and chickens?
Sheep and horses
too. My brother and I.
You know, made a lot
of money for teenagers.
But it was a huge mess.
Luka? What's happening?
I don't believe this.
I'm gonna kill Herb.
We didn't even meet Herb.
Same thing happened
when I bought my car,
and Herb said it was a fluke
You're telling me this now?
Not to worry, I can fix it.
So you brought me to the water.
Good boy. Good boy.
It's funny, Mark.
You know how some years
seem to pass faster than others?
Yeah.
Well, this year has
been the fastest.
I was thinking how
strange things can be.
Do you know... that in
all the wars I served in,
I never watched a man die?
On some ships, you get lucky.
But I must have told
you about that time
we had an explosion
at the base motor pool.
When you were stationed in Guam?
Yes.
I was little.
Mom and I were at San Diego.
And I remember you
called and told her about it
over the phone.
We lost seven men.
I was in the Exchange
when it happened.
I was looking for some
shaving cream or something.
Everybody scrambled out.
I started to,
me and this lieutenant
in the aisle next to me.
The shampoo
section, as I recall.
Next thing I know,
I hear this crash.
I turn and all these bottles
had come flying off the shelf.
And this poor son of a bitch
is collapsing on the floor.
He'd had a heart attack.
What'd you do?
Well, I screamed for help,
but no one came 'cause they
were all over at the motor pool.
I got down.
I loosened his tie and
unbuttoned his collar.
He grabbed on to my hand,
begged me not to leave him.
So I stayed.
And I pulled him into
my arms, and I held him.
Just the two of us.
For the next four
minutes, I watched him die.
The longest four
minutes of my life.
But in a crazy way
four of the best
minutes of my life.
There was some kind of value
in just being there.
Thank you, Mark,
for bringing me
out to the water.
You're welcome, Dad.
Sam?
Dr. Greene.
Sam, uh, I'd like you
to meet my father,
this is David Greene.
Dad, this is Sam MacKenzie.
Sarah MacKenzie's husband.
How do you do, sir?
What the hell?
I-I know how hard Dr. Carter
tried to keep me here.
Yeah, it's pretty
tough with the HMOs.
But they'll take good care of
you at New Western, Mr. Pooler.
Yeah, could you get a message
to my wife? She's in the ICU.
I'll call as soon
as I get settled.
They don't have phones
for the ICU patients,
but if you call the main
number, they'll put you through
to the desk and you can
ask how's she's doing, okay?
Good, good. And thanks...
Thanks again for everything.
My wife and I, we
certainly appreciate it.
You're welcome, sir.
How's Paul doing?
He's at Chester.
I guess that's the
main place for Illinois.
They put him on medication.
What did you wanna
talk about, Dr. Carter?
I don't know.
I just keep thinking about
what happened and...
You're not the only one.
Sometimes the
thoughts in my head
seem to be as loud as the
voices Paul seems to hear.
I lived with him,
I slept with him.
I'm about to bear his child.
How could I not see it?
I don't know.
Keep trying.
I am trying. It's not starting.
Keep trying. It'll
start. It'll start.
"Keep trying. It'll
start. It'll start."
It'll start.
It's not starting.
It has been an otherwise
really nice day, huh?
Time it was and what
a time It was, it was
A time of innocence
A time of confidences
Long ago it must be
I have a photograph
Preserve your memories
They're all that's left you
Thank you for calling.
I'm sorry about all
this, Mrs. Lomax.
Where are they?
I think your ex-husband
went up to the cafeteria,
but I can take you to Jessamyn.
Everybody wants
this, Mrs. Lomax.
A lemonade stand?
Yeah. Me and my friends,
we would set up a card table,
put it on the curb,
with a sign that said:
"Lemonade, 10 cents a glass."
'Course it wasn't as lucrative
as the chicken-and-cow trade.
If we made $1.50
we were riding high.
But less cleanup than
the cow-and-chicken trade.
True.
I look forward to that
for Kate and Tess.
You know, when that's the
most important thing in their world.
When all they think about is:
did they put in enough sugar
and when the next
car is driving by.
Yeah.
I expected the tow
truck to be here by now.
But then nothing has
gone as expected today.