- Here, let me help you.
- No, I got it.
- No, really, I got it.
- I got it.
- I'm not sure
about that bag on you.
- Well, perhaps
with a different shoe?
- Nah.
- You jealous?
- Jealous?
Of how bad it looks on you?
I don't think so.
- Dr. Halstead,
got a possible MI coming in.
- And good morning to you,
Maggie.
- Good morning.
- Dr. Manning, it was a pleasure
being your caddy today.
- Don't expect a tip.
- [chuckles]
- Hey, we still on
for tonight?
- Tonight?
- Ladies' night at Molly's,
Me, you, and April.
April hasn't had a date
in a while.
She can use
some wingwomen.
- Me, a wing woman?
- Your hormones--they will
lure the dudes in.
- Right.
Hey.
- Thank you.
- You're going the wrong way.
- Left my badge in the car.
- I'll think about it.
- Help!
Help, anyone!
I need help here.
- [grunts]
I got her, I got her,
I got her, I got her.
Come on!
She's bleeding from somewhere.
- Trauma two.
Get your asses over here!
Who is she?
What happened?
- I don't know.
I found her
a couple blocks away
collapsed on the sidewalk.
- Let's get her
on the monitors.
- April, you got this?
- Got it.
- Where's she bleeding from?
- Working on it.
- HR 130.
BP's at least 90.
I've got a radial pulse.
- All right, get two lines.
- On it.
- Get an i-STAT ABG
and send labs.
Make sure we type and cross.
- Can you hear me?
Can you tell me what happened?
The blood--
did you get shot?
- Let's get these wet clothes
off her now.
- Don't worry.
We're gonna put you in a gown
and see what's going on,
okay?
- Get blood, O negative,
make sure it's warm.
Put it on level one.
Give her two.
- Hey, stay with me.
- You find the source?
- No head, neck,
or torso trauma.
Belly distended but soft.
- That's not an intestine.
- It's an umbilical cord.
This kid just delivered
a baby.
- What do you mean "just"?
- Maybe five minutes ago.
- She's still bleeding.
Clamp.
- Where did you deliver
this baby?
- Hey,
what happened to your baby?
Hey, sir?
Sir, you're the one
who brought the girl, yeah?
- She gonna be okay?
- Yeah, she's fine.
Where'd you find her?
- About two blocks that way.
- Okay, can you show me?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Hey, grab an OB kit
and follow us.
- You got it.
- She was right there.
What are we looking for?
- Sexton!
- Did she just abandon
the thing?
- April!
Bulb syringe.
Come on.
Come on, come on,
come on, come on.
Come on--
[baby gags, cries]
Oh, okay.
Blanket, blanket.
[baby crying]
Oxygen.
[murmuring]
- Okay...okay.
- There you go.
All right.
- I'll take him to the NICU.
- I'll take him.
- She hasn't delivered
the placenta yet.
It has to come out.
Where the hell is OB?
- Stuck in a delivery.
I can do it.
I've done it before.
- I'm on the baby.
You sure?
- Yes.
April,
where'd you find the baby?
- In a backpack
behind that building on Huron.
We got there just in time.
- Hey, hotshot.
Yeah, you.
An old lady had a fall,
sprained her wrists.
last name Francis.
- Miss Francis?
Ms. Connie Francis?
- That's me.
You look awfully young
to be a doctor.
- Oh, I'm a medical student.
Sarah Reese.
- Why don't you
come with us?
- Come with you?
- To the beach.
Hey, did you bring
the Coppertone?
- The...
- He says he's having
a heart attack.
He's always having
- I'm not always
having a heart attack.
- Nope, just when the lawn
needs mowing
or the gutters need
clearing
or the garbage
needs taking out.
- Can you describe
the pain you're feeling?
- It feels like someone
sitting on my chest,
slowly squeezing the life
out of me.
- How about we take a look?
- Keep your hands off of me.
I want to go to the beach.
- Oh, Dr. Charles, good.
Could I get a consult?
I need to get this splint
on her, but she won't sit still.
- I'm late, and we're still
30 minutes away
from Fort Lauderdale.
- Ms. Francis,
I am so sorry to hold you up,
but do you mind if I ask you
a couple of questions?
I'm Dr. Charles.
- Well, I hope you're not
one of those
stuck-up Princeton boys.
- Oh, heaven forbid.
University of Pennsylvania,
thank you very much.
Please forgive Ms. Reese.
Smart and caring as she is,
she's still learning.
Do you mind terribly
if we were to borrow this
so that we could contact
your loved ones?
- Well, if it won't
take you too long.
- We will make it snappy.
Be right back.
Thank you.
So it didn't occur to you
she might have dementia?
That name didn't mean anything
to you, "Connie Francis"?
- Should it have?
- Oh, I'm so damn old.
Just call her contact.
- Uh--
- If you could just fill
each of these with nuts,
and I brought the nuts.
I'll take care
of everything else.
- Helen,
I thought this was gonna be
a little bit more casual.
- But I just--I want it to be
just right, you know?
I want--I want it to be
something
she'll remember always.
- Helen?
Hey, what were you doing
with my mother-in-law?
- Who, Helen?
Was she just here?
Wish I would've known.
I would've said hi.
- She handed you
that pink box.
- Huh?
- What's in the box,
Maggie?
Maggie!
- Napkin diaper nut cups.
- What?
You fold the colored napkin up,
you see,
and then you hold it together
with safety pins,
and then you stuff it--
- You're throwing me a shower?
- Surprise!
Tonight at Molly's.
- So the whole
ladies' night ruse--
- Just roll with it, okay?
- Fine.
- Oh, how's baby Doe?
Poor thing.
- He's stable for now.
And the mother?
- Just came to.
- Do we have any information
on her yet?
- All we know is that
her name...is Erika.
- Okay. Thank you.
- Yeah.
Hello, Erika.
I'm Dr. Manning.
- When can I leave?
- Based on how much blood
you lost
and what your body's
gone through,
I'd say you're
at least here overnight.
Is there anyone I can call,
your mother or father?
- No.
- Maybe a friend?
- Did they find
the backpack?
- Yes.
How did you end up
in that alley, Erika?
Why did you leave your baby
there?
- I don't know.
I mean, I knew something
was going on inside me,
but I figured if I could just
not think about it, then maybe--
I'm so stupid.
[sobs]
I'm just so happy
that somebody found him.
- Erika, honey,
how old are you?
- 14.
There is someone
you can call.
- She's 14 years old, a kid.
She's scared, alone.
- What about the family?
- Her mother's in prison.
Father's long gone.
She does have an older sister
living in Champaign, though.
I left a message.
Here's the thing--
she was two blocks away.
Two blocks--maybe she was trying
the make it here.
- Is that what she said?
- She clamped
the umbilical cord.
She did not mean
to harm that baby.
- Right. Put him in a backpack.
Leave him in an alley.
That'll keep him safe.
- It's not that cut and dried.
She was delirious.
- She left her baby to die.
It's exactly that cut and dried.
- She's a child.
She wasn't ready for any of
this, right?
- People come here for help.
I try to leave my feelings
out of it.
- Well, that's convenient.
Look, you don't understand
because you're not a woman.
- Don't give me that.
People need to be held
accountable, regardless of sex.
- This is a safe haven.
She could've dropped the baby
off, no questions asked.
- So now you do have feelings?
She's got to live with this
for the rest of her life.
Do we really want
to punish her as well?
- You're talking
as if there's a happy ending
where that baby survives.
- That baby is
going to survive.
- And if he doesn't, then what
that girl did is murder.
How you gonna feel then?
- Who's the pediatric surgery
attending today?
- Dr. Grant.
- I've got to get
back down to the ED.
Page me if anything changes
with this one's condition, okay?
- Dr. Rhodes.
- Yeah?
- Your father called.
Wants you to call him back.
- Thanks.
- Mm-hmm.
- Excuse me, Dr. Czerny.
You said yesterday that you may
have some time today
to discuss our new
tranexamic acid drug?
- Talk to me tomorrow.
And are you
even supposed to be in here?
- Have a great...day.
Good morning.
- Good morning.
- Dr...Halstead.
I'm Zoe Roth with Stewart
and Breck Pharmaceutical.
- Will.
- Okay, so how big of a problem
is blood loss
during surgery, Will?
- I'm an ER doc, Zoe.
Don't do a lot of surgery.
But keep going.
I might learn something.
- Well, you should know
that S&B is conducting
a major multi-institutional
trial
to establish
our product's efficacy
in so many different uses
and procedures.
- I'm sorry, I have a patient.
Can we do this tomorrow?
- W-what about later?
Maybe over dinner?
- Dinner?
Sure, I'm free for dinner.
- Good.
Say about 8:00?
- Yeah, I'll meet you
out front.
- Call me if there are
any conflicts.
- All right, will do.
- Yeah, okay.
- She's very friendly.
- Just doing her job.
- You got a high fever
in treatment 5, dog bite in 4.
These just came back
from cardiology.
- Uh, thank you, April.
- Doug, Jenna,
good news.
Second set of enzymes
came back fine.
Both EKGs are normal,
CK and troponin as well.
These chest X-rays
look solid.
- So you're telling me
I'm fine?
- That's what the tests say.
Looks like you are good to go,
my friend.
- I knew it, huh?
We wasted six hours here,
and it's all on your head.
- Well, it's not
that simple.
There are plenty
of other factors
that can contribute
to chest pain.
It could be reflux
or stress, anxiety--
- [laughs]
Yeah, like I said,
all in his head.
Speaking of which,
just in time to pick up Liam
from daycare.
Bye.
- I'm gonna refer you
to a cardiologist.
She'll get you
on a treadmill
and put you through
a stress test, okay?
- Like Jenna's not
enough of a test.
I started calling her
"Jenna-cide," as a dig,
but it turns out
she likes the nickname.
- All right.
I'll see if they can get you in
this week, okay?
In the meantime,
you tell Jenna
the doctor recommends
no lawn mowing.
- [chuckles]
Just in time
to start shoveling snow.
- All right, you take care.
- Thank you so much.
- Absolutely.
Heard you had
a bit of a morning.
- Yeah.
So listen, my mother-in-law's
throwing me
a surprise baby shower tonight
that I totally
don't want to go to,
so you have to come
with me.
- Can't. I'm having dinner
with Zoe.
- Zoe?
- The new S&B pharma rep.
Blonde hair.
- Yeah, I think
I know the one.
So you're deserting me
in my hour of need
to go get laid?
- What are you talking about?
It's strictly business.
She wants to pitch me
on their new TXA product.
- Whatever.
- I was frantic
trying to figure out
where she'd gotten off to.
- Mr. Donovan, how long have we
been in the Connie Francis era?
- We met in Fort Lauderdale,
Spring Break, 1960--
same year
"Where the Boys Are" came out.
Carol loved that movie.
She mixes it up in our life.
This past year, it's been
getting worse and worse.
- Mr. Donovan, caring
for someone with dementia
is one of the most demanding
tasks in the world.
Remind yourself
from time to time
it's okay not to be
perfect.
- Thank you, dear.
I'll give that a try.
- Mr. Donovan,
I just need your signature
for these discharge papers.
- What did I do?
- You get that
from a greeting card
or a fortune cookie?
- So where's my wife?
[tapping on glass]
Thank God.
Carol?
- Who is this?
- Your husband.
- My husband?
- Yes.
He loves you,
and he's gonna take you home.
- I'd rather go with you.
- I wouldn't know
where to go.
Tom does.
Tom knows the way home.
- She'll need to keep the splint
on for about six weeks.
- I feel so stupid.
Get up to go to the bathroom
and trip over the rug.
- Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Are you hearing
what I'm hearing?
Are you okay to walk?
Would you mind just getting up
and taking a few steps for me?
- Sure.
- Here we go.
What do you think?
- Magnetic gait and complete
recall of her injuries
not consistent with a diagnosis
for Alzheimer's.
- Very good.
- What's going on?
- I'd like to run a few tests
on your wife.
I promise it won't take long,
and it could very well
be worth our while.
- Sure.
[alarm blaring]
- Juvie's hemorrhaging!
Trauma 2!
- How many pads
did she soak?
- Dozen or more.
- She must still have
retained products.
Which attending did this?
- They were busy.
I did it.
- You?
You did it?
[sighs]
All right, page OB.
Let's get her
up to the OR now.
- Got it.
Yep, your newbie.
[dramatic music]
[beeps]
- How many units
has she gotten?
- 6.
- Her most recent hemoglobin?
- 5.9.
- She still looks like a ghost.
She needs more blood.
Restart the MTP.
- Give me methergine
and 1,000 mics of Cytotec.
Little room--
- Erika Dougherty's been
in the system for years.
In and out of foster care since
her mom was sent to Logan.
Runs away when the families
don't kick her out.
Suspected substance abuse,
at least alcohol, maybe worse.
- Would you ask Dr. Manning
to step in here, please?
- Yes, ma'am.
What about the baby's father?
- [laughs]
Who knows?
Erika's been arrested
more than once for solicitation.
- Ms. Goodwin?
- Yes, Dr. Manning,
this Madeline Gastern
from the Department
of Child and Family Services.
What's the baby's
condition?
- He's stable.
- And Ms. Dougherty?
- Dr. Pachefsky's
treating her.
She may need
a hysterectomy.
I reached her older sister,
Kara Dougherty.
She's on her way
up from Champaign.
Kara's an adult.
Could she potentially take
custody of Erika and the baby?
- Potentially.
- I know you always try
to keep families intact.
- Thank you,
Dr. Manning.
- This girl is in big trouble.
She could be going to prison.
- Come on.
She's 14 years old.
Solicitation or not,
that's rape.
- Doesn't absolve her.
She's facing
several potential felonies.
Abandonment,
attempted murder.
It's up to the State's Attorney
and the judge, but Cook County?
Anything could happen.
- I thought I got it all.
- Forcing the delivery
of the placenta
is an OB procedure, so
what the hell were you thinking?
- It was an emergency situation.
I made a decision.
- A bad one.
You overstepped your bounds,
and you botched it.
That girl almost needed
a hysterectomy.
A 14-year-old!
Now, let me ask you
something, Dr. Choi.
You didn't like this patient.
You disapproved of her.
- You think that affected
my judgment and my performance?
- You tell me.
- Dr. Halstead to the E.D.
Dr. Halstead to the E.D.
Code blue.
- Dr. Halstead,
cardiac arrest, treatment 5.
Your patient.
- Code blue.
- I thought you said
he was gonna be okay.
- Get the pads on him.
- He was in earlier.
Is there anything
we need to know
from his charts?
- No. We did a full workup,
and everything checked out.
- I was driving home,
and he--I looked over
and he was just
white as a sheet.
And then I turned around and
drove back as fast as I could.
I don't think
he was breathing.
- Ma'am, I'm sorry.
You need to wait outside.
- Okay.
- Hold compressions.
V-fib,
charge to 200 joules.
Everyone clear.
all: Clear.
[electric pulse]
- I got a pulse.
He's in sinus rhythm,
brady at 50.
- BP?
- 90 over 45.
[beeps]
Wait, wait, wait. 72 over 35.
- Start dopamine at 10
and titrate to a systolic of 90.
- Yes, sir.
- Get a 12 lead EKG.
- Right away,
Dr. Halstead.
- We gotta get his BP up.
- You paged me?
- Dr. Grant.
- Pneumothorax.
Right lung collapsed.
Tubing him now.
- O2 sats at 78.
We get below 75 and--
- We're not getting below 75.
Campbell.
- What do you need?
Inhaled nitric oxide.
We need to improve oxygenation.
- I'll get a tank.
- He's really bradycardic.
- Turn up the dopamine.
It should help the pressure
and heart rate.
- Dr. Halstead, it's been
15 minutes--make a decision.
- I'm not giving up yet.
RV's not moving.
- You have a blown-out RV
and severe akinesis.
I think you might want to
consider giving more fluids
instead of escalating
the pressers.
- Call RT for a tank
of nitric oxide.
- Nitric oxide?
- It'll reduce the afterload
so that the heart works less
and buy some time
till the cath lab is ready.
- I've never seen
it used for this.
- It's unorthodox, I know,
but I don't have a balloon pump,
and we're out of options.
- RT says Dr. Manning is
signing out the last tank.
They'll have another ready
in ten minutes.
- He'll be dead by then.
Nat, where are you going?
- NICU. Baby Doe's sats
are in the 70s.
- Put him on ECMO.
- That's a last resort.
- I'm sorry,
but I need this tank.
- What the hell
are you doing?
- I have no other option.
You do.
- Give me that tank!
- Nat,
my patient will die
without it.
- You're putting the baby
at risk.
- I'm not gonna lose this guy.
- Will--
- He's got three kids.
Try thinking like a doctor
and not a pregnant woman.
- He's in v-fib.
Lost his pulse again.
- Charge to 200.
Everyone clear.
[beeps]
all: Clear.
[electric pulse]
One more round of epi.
Let's go.
Restart compressions.
- Nothing.
- Come on!
- Doug?
Doug, please?
Please listen to me, okay?
We need you, all right?
I need you, okay?
- Nurse.
- Please?
[sobbing] Please--stop.
- Hold compressions.
I got a pulse.
Sinus brady again.
- Start amnio drip.
Let's get him to the cath lab.
- Let's unclamp.
Turn on the circuit.
- ECMO acts
as a heart-lung bypass,
oxygenating the infant's blood
outside its body.
- Sats are rising.
- Thank God.
- Dr. Manning?
There's a Kara Dougherty
downstairs to see you.
- Okay.
- The usual, Dino.
- Dr. Charles.
- Dr. Choi.
You were in the--
what, the Navy, right?
- Still am.
Naval Reserves.
- Doc I did my residency with
was on away leave from the Navy.
[chuckles]
It was tough as hell practicing
psychiatry with you guys.
Couldn't get anybody
to open up.
- Could be
a sign of weakness.
- Pork rind?
- No, thanks.
- No?
I shouldn't eat this stuff
so much.
Guess that military culture's
tough, right?
Loose lips and all?
[loud crunching]
[clears throat]
Last chance, man.
Pretty sure
they're organic.
- I'm good.
- No?
- Kara, I'm Natalie.
We spoke on the phone.
- I brought Erika
some clothes.
- Thank you.
- Where's my sister?
- Follow me.
There were some complications
with the birth,
but we think the baby's
gonna be fine.
- You think?
- It's still very early,
but we have the best
neonatal ICU in the Midwest.
I could take you up to see him
if you want.
- Maybe later.
- I spoke to a social worker.
It might be possible
for Erika and the baby
to come live with you.
- Let me talk to her.
- Hey.
- You really stabilized him
using nitric?
Interesting.
- What about the patient?
- The RCA was completely
occluded,
and there was a 60% occlusion
of the circumflex.
I stented both and placed
an impella for a couple days
to rest the heart.
What was his code time?
- Maybe 20 minutes total.
- 20 minutes?
I would've let him go.
What's the difference
between God and a doctor?
God knows he's not
a doctor.
- I just got a page.
- Dr. Rhodes?
- Yeah?
- Please, my boss wants
to talk to you.
- Okay.
- You wear the scrubs well.
- I'm glad you approve.
- Long time.
Got a couple of minutes?
We can go grab a coffee,
maybe catch up.
- I'm working.
- Ah.
You know, I took it as a good
sign that you'd come home,
that maybe you'd worked
through your issues?
- My issues?
- Come on.
Let it go.
Let's move on.
- You're still the same,
aren't you?
Just untouchable.
- Let me tell you something.
When you left this town, Connor,
I was deeply hurt.
Yeah.
You ask Claire.
But right now, I'm willing
to put all that behind me,
for the two of us
to start over.
- It's a good pitch, Dad.
Really.
You hit all the right notes.
I'm not buying it.
- We can go.
- You ready to see
your nephew?
- I wish I could
help them.
- Kara.
- I just got a promotion--
customer service rep--
and my boyfriend and I
are talking about us
moving in together.
I've come too far to get sucked
back into this crap again.
- They're your family.
- You make that sound
like a good thing.
- Hold that position.
- What did you say
this might be again, hydro what?
- Hydrocephalus.
Literally means
"water on the brain."
The lumbar puncture should
relieve some pressure.
- So her dementia might--
- Well, hopefully, we'll see
some cognitive improvement,
and if that's the case,
we'll implant a surgical shunt
for long-term treatment.
- I, uh...[chuckles]
the summer we met,
dancing to "Where the Boys Are."
- Wow.
- I'd give anything
to see that look in her eyes
even one more time.
How did they miss this?
How did I miss it?
- How would you know?
I mean, give yourself a break.
It goes undiagnosed
80% of the time.
- I feel like
I betrayed her.
- Sometimes, when somebody
that we love gets sick,
very easy to lose sight
of the person
and see only the disease.
Remembering that our loved one
is still there--not always easy.
Why don't you go get yourself
a cup of coffee, okay?
This can take a while.
I'm here.
I know where to find you.
- Nat.
- Dr. Manning,
the police are on their way
to talk to Erika Dougherty.
- Police?
- That's the way it works.
- What are they gonna do
to her?
- I don't know.
It's not my call.
- Can't you change this?
- No, and neither can you.
- Well,
this should make you happy.
[TV voices]
[TV stops]
- Listen...
the hospital's
only two blocks away.
- What?
- The police
will be here soon.
Tell them you knew the hospital
was only two blocks away.
- The cops are coming?
- And tell them
you clamped the umbilical cord.
You wanted your baby to live.
- The neurologist
will talk more about this,
but there are going to be
deficits--
increased irritability,
forgetfulness,
impaired mobility.
He won't be getting out of bed
anytime soon.
- I'm sorry.
I don't understand, um...
deficits?
- We'll see
how he does in rehab.
I'm sorry, but your husband's
going to need a lot of care.
- Oh, my God.
What have you done?
Have you turned my husband
into a vegetable?
- We don't know the extent
of the damage.
- This is not what Doug
would've wanted.
He would never want this.
Why didn't you tell me something
like this would happen?
We...
We have three kids.
We live--we live paycheck
to paycheck.
What am I supposed to do now?
You son of a bitch!
[sobbing]
[continues sobbing]
- She's still weak
from the delivery.
- We just need to ask her
a couple questions.
She's not facing
any charges yet.
- Would you mind just
giving me a moment with her?
- Yeah, sure.
- She's gone.
- Shocker. Leave a 14-year-old
runaway unattended...
- [deep sigh]
That poor baby.
I had this fantasy
I could give him a family.
Where was my head at?
- You weren't thinking
with your head.
And good for you.
You want out of the shower,
everyone'll understand.
Ugh, maybe not Helen.
Oh, Helen.
[both chuckling]
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Time to rally.
- All right.
- Dr. Charles...do you know?
Did they find that girl?
- Oh, not yet.
- I think it's my fault
she took off.
I told her
the police were coming.
- Huh.
So, um...
how's that
sitting with you?
- Thought I'd feel worse.
- Huh. Interesting.
- What are you doing?
- Trying to figure out
where I went wrong.
Guy showed up this morning.
I ran these, discharged him.
Two hours later, he's wheeled
in with a massive MI.
How did I miss it?
- Where was the lesion?
- Right coronary.
- I know what
I'm looking for,
and I don't see
any abnormalities.
- I got the guy back,
but it's not good.
It's not good.
- Sorry, man.
It's late.
[pats]
- Yeah.
- Hello there.
Do you know where you are?
- In a hospital.
- And can you
tell me your name, please?
- Carol.
Carol Donovan.
- Good.
- Why am I here?
- You had some buildup
in the frontal subcortical
region of your brain.
We drained about 50 ccs
of spinal fluid.
- What my colleague
is trying to say
is that
you weren't quite yourself.
The pressure on your brain
was causing you
to see things
in a different way,
and now that pressure
has been relieved.
Can I ask you, do you
feel strong enough to stand,
take a few steps?
- Oh, yeah, sure.
Tom, honey.
- Carol. You're back.
- I was here...
and I was not here
at the same time.
Like I was fading away.
It all seemed so real.
- Your memories
are gonna feel very real.
That's perfectly normal
and to be expected,
but this was
just a temporary fix.
We're gonna
have to do another procedure.
- Ms. Donovan, I have something
for you and Mr. Donovan.
I went online
and did a little research.
["Where the Boys Are" plays]
-  Where
The boys are
Someone waits for me
- Not bad.
- Hello?
- Zoe, it's Will.
- Dr. Halstead, how are you?
- I am so sorry.
I got bogged down with a case,
and I totally lost track
of time.
My bad, completely.
Can I--can I get a rain check?
- No problem.
I just got pulled into a sales
meeting that's going long,
so this works out for me
as well.
[speaking under music]
[somber music]
[somber music continues]
- Thank you.