Billy?
Is anyone here?
Hey. Hey.
I just noticed the
front door was open.
Maybe you left it that way?
I don't know, I thought
I heard something.
I mean, I know the whole
house creaks, but I was just...
You have any doubts,
go to the Cassanos'.
I'm in the car, I'm
a few blocks away.
No, I'm sure it's
nothing. Love you.
Oh, God.
The door banged shut, I'm
sure it was just the wind. God.
It's okay.
It's okay, it's just me.
Huh.
You all right?
Margaret.
Hey!
Margaret! You okay?
My stomach!
I get it!
You're jealous of my new cane,
so you hired a new doctor
that you could lean on.
Exactly. Nothing to do with the fact
that you instructed me to hire one.
Dr. House, this is Dr. Kelly
Benedict, your new fellow.
Nice to meet you.
Um...
I just finished my psychiatry
residency at St. Jude's.
And I loved studying the mind,
but I thought I could make
more of a difference, or at least...
Man, you're hot.
I mean, seriously.
Thirty-year-old female... I
know what you're thinking.
"She looks like Cameron, and he's
hired her solely to sleep with her."
No. None of us
were thinking that.
Well, you should have.
But you'd be foolishly wrong.
Yes, he's been dating at a
near-Clooney pace recently,
but at this point, the only hole
he's trying to fill is the one in his soul.
Which means it's the emotional
connection with Cameron he misses.
Did you ever marry a dying man,
and if so, did you freeze his sperm?
Okay, so Cameron's
his ex, but the sperm...
She's not like Cameron.
Then why did you make
her wear Cameron's clothes?
No. I'm wearing my own clothes.
Thirty-year-old female.
Severe vomiting
and abdominal pain,
preceded by three days of
moderate pain, slightly elevated LFTs.
Could be lead...
Ah-ah-ah. If I know
Dr. Shameron, and I think I do,
she'll want this chance
for a little stuff-strutting.
Okay. Hepatitis A...
Serologies are negative.
Right. Uh...
Appendicitis... That
hasn't ruptured by now?
It's hepatic fibrosis.
At the risk of having
Foreman snark at me, too,
lead poisoning could also work.
Liver angiogram
to check for fibrosis,
search the home
for heavy metals.
What's your position on the
legality of illegal break-ins?
That's more of a second-week
type activity. We'll do the angiogram.
I'll meet you in
radiology, third floor.
She was nervous.
Give her a break.
Oh.
And she's not like Cameron.
True. Cameron had
much smaller breasts.
By which I mean,
she was smarter.
How are things going with Cuddy?
Great.
We've gotten to fifth base.
That's two home runs, and
then she gives me back a triple.
I could see you on this one.
Am I wearing a dashiki?
Easy Rider auditions
ended four decades ago.
Are you sleeping over there yet?
Nope. She comes over,
we hook up, she leaves.
Whose idea was that?
Mine.
But I let her think it's hers.
It's the fun of a relationship.
You get the sex, the dinners,
videogame partnership.
I also get a full night's sleep.
Okay. Taking it
slow. That could work.
You are spending
time with the kid.
As little as possible.
That is one boring child.
House, she's a toddler. I know.
Grading on a
curve. It's that bad.
You think you were a
scintillating wit at two and a half?
I wasn't trying to eat shoes.
Cuddy could have
adopted a golden retriever.
Yeah, things are
definitely going great.
We'll get to it
when we get to it.
You really like these, or are you
just avoiding a touchy conversation?
Nah. This one's too metrosexual,
this one is too heterosexual.
They're identical.
Do you even want my input?
No.
Then why did you invite me?
Who would drive my
car home if I buy a bike?
You did fine. House is
just trying to get at me.
And he's wrong, by the way.
I hired you because you were
the most qualified applicant.
Injecting dye.
Dr. Foreman didn't
seem to like me, either.
Oh, well, he takes a
little while to warm up.
In my case, I'm hoping
year seven does the trick.
Tapering cutoff in the left
branch of the hepatic artery.
Tumor?
Looks more like scar tissue.
From what? Surgery?
Probably.
Look at her rib cage.
She broke five or six
bones at some point.
She didn't tell us about this?
No, she didn't.
I checked the
pipes and the paint.
It's not lead poisoning.
You got anything?
Yeah. I was looking around,
and in the corner over there,
I found a question about why you
have a problem with our new doctor.
Sorry. We should all be super polite
in the DDxs, fail to correct each other,
and then treat patients for
diseases they don't have.
Dude, is this about Thirteen?
No. Why are you
calling me "dude"?
Maybe it's hard seeing House
replace her when you still got feelings?
One, I don't have feelings
for Thirteen beyond friendship,
two, it's a temporary
replacement,
and three, "Dude"?
It felt right.
The day the patient collapsed,
she say where she was working?
A cleaning job in Summit,
then she went straight home.
Then why's she got a credit card
receipt for lunch from a café in Trenton?
I'm not hiding anything.
I just got the days wrong.
I worked in Trenton on Tuesday,
I worked in Summit on Monday.
I guess it slipped my mind.
And breaking eight ribs,
that slip your mind, too?
You know how I was on the
cycling team when I was at UMass?
Well, during training, I fell off my
bike, right onto a sprinkler head.
Why didn't you tell us?
That was 10 years ago.
I didn't think it could be
related to my stomach problems.
We're gonna need to see
the records from the operation.
You think it is related?
The strange stuff
we found in your liver,
it's probably hepatic fibrosis,
but it could also just be a
screw-up from your old surgery.
The operation was done
at the university hospital.
Hopefully, they still
have the records.
Come back. Just one
more time. You'll love it.
My wrists are tired.
I can't defeat NoobDecimator98
all alone. Come on, we're a team.
You understand, right?
Babysitter's leaving
in half an hour.
Oops! You're right.
Scram, I got a massage
coming by in five.
It was at that moment she realized
the romance was already gone.
Headshot!
Oh! Hi.
Hi.
I called UMass. There's no
record of any surgery for Margaret.
You use her maiden name?
No, Kelly knows nothing about
the concept of married names.
It wasn't covered in
her psychiatry residency.
Margaret was never even
registered at the university.
Call the other
hospitals in the area.
Done. Nothing.
So I ran her social security number
through one of those websites.
Her number matches her name.
But she's got no credit
history until three years ago.
And based on her number,
she was born around 1945.
She stole someone's identity.
Supraventricular
tachycardia, 150 bpm.
Carotid massage? Not responding.
- I'll get the adenosine.
- Tried already.
Get the pacemaker,
we can overdrive her.
Dorothy. Dorothy. Dorothy,
dear. It's Aunt Em, darling.
What's wrong with me?
Well, on the one hand, you've got some
mysterious heart and tummy problems.
On the other, you look
great for a 65-year-old.
So who are you?
And no, that's not some weird
Canadian pronunciation of "how."
They're saying you
changed your identity.
What are they talking
about, Margaret?
I don't know.
Well, that falls in the
"obviously stupid lie" category.
Which you're familiar with from the
one you told us about your bike accident.
You thought we'd never check?
Five years ago, I was married.
Who was he?
Just a guy. I met
him in high school.
He was older.
He used to get
jealous, do drugs.
Those broken bones?
He would tell me to
take off all my clothes,
so he could inspect
me, then he would hit me.
I got a restraining order, ran
away. And he found me anyway.
That's when he broke my ribs.
I moved away again, to Arizona.
Came back from work one day,
he'd broken in, fed
pesticides to my dog, killed her.
I bought a dead
woman's identity,
changed my name, moved here.
Is this related to why you
were in Trenton yesterday?
There's a support group for
abused women at Trenton General.
I go a lot.
What's his name?
Please don't do this. I don't...
Just tell me.
Carl.
Carl what?
This is why I didn't tell you.
'Cause you go confront
him, he'll kill you.
Well, I got another name you
could tell us instead. Yours.
It's Jenny.
Now, some person seemed to think that I
was not being fair to you in our last DDx,
because I made you nervous.
So this time, I'm
gonna put you at ease.
It's just you and old Doc House.
Couple of pals
chittin' the chat.
Why not just place her chair above a
trap door with a shark tank underneath?
Because Wednesday's when
I get my shark tank cleaned.
Also, because I'm
giving her a chance.
You're giving her a test.
This whole job is a test.
I'm giving her the chance to
fail it sooner rather than later.
Or pass.
Arrhythmia and elevated LFTs rule out
hepatic fibrosis. So heart and stomach.
Gastritis. Explains the
stomach, not the heart.
Atrial fibrillation? Explains
the heart, not the stomach.
Sorry, sorry. Cystitis.
Explains the... Nothing.
I meant cholecystitis.
Would have showed
up on the physical exam.
Do we have to sit here all day?
You got a better answer than
she does, then let's hear it.
I'm sure she's already
starting to think how,
if we add the symptoms
to an abusive ex,
the fact that she'd just
eaten, the opened door...
Rhymes with "moison"?
You think her ex-husband
tried to poison her?
Even if he found her somehow,
these abusers have a pattern.
He beat her with his hands.
Poison's too impersonal, it doesn't fit.
Exactly, but the
counterargument is...
Her ex poisoned her dog.
Oh.
Right.
She said he used pesticides. He
could have stuck some in her dinner.
Treat with pralidoxime.
A for effort?
House was wrong trying to come up
with a complicated reason you hired Kelly.
Thank you.
It's actually quite simple.
You think she's hot and
you want to sleep with her.
Well, it's nice to see you finally
taking an interest in my life.
We should go bowling sometime.
I'm just saying if you spend all your
off-work time and energy getting laid,
it's gonna spill into
your work as well.
She's smart. You
didn't interview her.
I did glance at her résumé.
Middling grades, middling med school.
She was editor for Rutgers'
daily undergrad newspaper.
That shows a lot more guts and
determination than med school grades.
Uh-huh?
How long did you interview her?
Forty-five minutes, at least.
How much of that was
after you decided to hire her?
You saw what you wanted to see.
This guy broke into our house?
That's the theory.
I don't know. It could be true.
And you didn't tell me about
him because you didn't trust me?
I just didn't want
you to get involved.
I'm already involved.
We're married.
It was the worst time in my
life. I wanted to block it out.
I'm sorry.
I gotta get out of here.
Where are you going?
I don't know.
Hey.
So I'm seeing you tonight.
Yes.
And you would have even
if you hadn't told me that.
I was just wondering...
Your masseuse?
Brandi.
I'm sure I'm imagining this, although
not as sure now that I know her name,
but she seems a little... How
do I say this? I don't know.
A bit slutty. Well,
she is a hooker.
If she's not slutty, she's
doing something wrong.
What?
Did you have sex with her?
Yesterday?
Ah! You're getting
confused by the hooker thing.
No, of course
not. I'm dating you.
But you used to
have sex with her?
Well, it was a
massage-plus-happy-ending sort of thing.
Now it's more of a sad ending.
Because of you.
I've tried 15 different massage
therapists in the last few years.
I don't know why, but
she's the best I've found.
She makes my leg feel better.
So you really think that
I would be okay with you
getting a massage from a
hooker you used to have sex with?
You don't mind the massage part.
You mind the sex part,
which doesn't exist anymore.
I know a great
physical therapist.
I will give you her number.
Why would I give up one who
definitely works for one who might work?
Because I asked you to.
Well, that's not really
an argument now, is it?
I won't see you until
you stop seeing her.
Well, that's an argument.
How's our patient doing?
Well, she's stable but it's too early
to tell if the pralidoxime is working.
Come on, go home. You can't
re-cram all of med school right now.
I'm feeling a lot
of pressure here.
You were the editor
of your school paper,
I think you know how
to deal with pressure.
No, I wasn't.
On your résumé, it said, "Rutgers
Daily Herald, Editor." Didn't it?
I wasn't head of the paper.
That's called "Editor-in-Chief."
I was just a writer.
We're all called editors.
Ah.
Did you hire me because of that?
Not entirely.
Look, if you're having
buyers' remorse...
I'm not. I'm not.
You might wanna check out
volume two on infectious diseases.
Patient's husband just
got admitted to the ER.
Let's say you had a
really fantastic handyman.
I was hoping you'd interrupt my
cooking to ask about handymen.
Do go on.
Would Sam ask
you to stop using him,
because you might have had a
sexual relationship with him in the past?
Yes, the age-old
hooker-massage conundrum.
Cuddy might have
mentioned something about it.
Let's say you're right, completely
right about everything. Give in anyway.
This isn't a point of pride,
this is a point of principle.
Right, you're the Rosa
Parks of hooker massages.
The principle is
she's being irrational.
I give in on this, it sets the
stage for the whole relationship.
Putting up with irrationality is the
foundation for every relationship.
I agree with Sam when she's
calling her father a monster.
I agree with her when
she's calling him a saint.
And in exchange, I
get to have sex with her.
And I'm sure she has
similar tradeoffs with me.
Relationships are hard.
You have to make sacrifices.
So, sacrifice being crazy.
Go get her a gift, apologize.
You've finally
made a good point.
Which clearly you've
misunderstood,
based on how quickly you agreed.
Kitchen's burning.
Oh!
We gotta get you
thinking like House.
The husband's in the ER,
if he's got similar symptoms,
it could mean environmental.
Which helps our
organophosphate theory.
Or maybe it's an infection,
which would mean we were wrong.
Exactly.
Or maybe he just got
sick with something else.
A coincidence? Yeah.
Here's one big piece of advice,
House doesn't buy coincidences.
Okay. It's not environmental.
What happened to you?
What does it look like?
It looks like someone kicked
your arse. What happened?
I looked in her address book.
There's a guy named
Carl in Brooklyn.
She told you to
stay away from him.
I'm not so good at following
directions sometimes.
I found him, I got angry,
which I also do sometimes.
He said he didn't know
what I was talking about,
he wouldn't let me
in, I got more pissed.
Next thing I know, I'm on the
floor, and he's called the cops.
You get arrested?
No, he didn't press charges.
Well, you should press
charges. If he tried to poison her...
No. He really didn't know
what I was talking about.
He was just some
guy that Margaret...
Damn it, that's not even
her name, Jenny just...
Some guy that Jenny
used to work with.
I was stupid. I just assumed
the name Carl was...
I just wanted to find the
guy that poisoned my wife.
What's up?
Pyrexia, 103 and rising.
I'll be right up.
Your wife just
spiked a fever. What?
What's that mean?
She wasn't poisoned.
What are you doing?
Just letting you all share in the joys
of my last trip to Carlsbad Caverns.
Which the husband probably
would have beaten up
if he'd found it in
the address book.
Would you mind standing
next to the screen?
Yeah, she'd love to become
a target for your ridicule.
She's not already?
Endocarditis?
Normal EKG. No Osler nodes.
Right, Dr. Kelly.
Kelly's her first name.
What's your point,
Dr. Robert? Run an echo.
I already did. No
vegetations, valves are clear.
Snapilicious! But as
I always like to say,
it's better to be a Helpful
Helen than a Negative Nelly.
So while you're cooking
up some ideas of your own,
allow me to present theory
2.0 of why Chase hired you.
Dr. Kelly, meet
your doppelgänger.
Oh, no. Hold on a second.
Come on. House.
Is that... That's Baby
Chase and his mum.
That's adorable.
Never mind the
baby. Peep the babe.
Note the cheekbones
and eye shape.
They do actually look alike.
I know what you're thinking,
"Chase wants to sleep with his mom."
But who wouldn't hit that,
if that looked like that?
It's a classic case of what Freud called...
- Stop.
This isn't about Chase's mother.
You're wrong. What do
you mean, he's wrong?
It is about your mom? No.
So it's about...
I'm assuming he thought I'd
be a good member of the team.
And on that subject,
what about Legionnaires'?
Taub said he saw a rattle-y, old
air conditioner in the patient's house.
I don't care if he saw her
licking a petri dish of bacilli.
There's no lung involvement.
All we know is we don't see it.
Dehydration from the fever
could hide the pneumonia.
Okay. Forget the mom theory.
Now water the patient,
treat for Legionnaires'.
Hey, Taub. You didn't
write up the AC system.
Did you mention it to Kelly?
No.
You mentioned it to Chase?
Yeah.
Whose idea was Legionnaires'?
Dr. Chase's.
Well, you get major
points for trying to trick me.
Unfortunately, you
lose them all for failing.
Hold that, hold that.
See, now you're frowning, you
can really see the resemblance.
Who gives a crap
if I prepped her?
House. And that's just
off the top of my head.
Why are you doing this?
You're trying to make me
look bad so you look better?
Or you don't like her? Or
you're angry at me? What?
We hire someone unqualified, it's
just dead weight we'll all be pulling.
Me especially. You
especially, why?
What do you mean,
why? Because I'm...
You're what? You're
my boss or something?
Something like.
So that's what it is.
You're angry that House gave
me the chance to hire someone,
'cause you still think you're at a
different level to everyone else.
That's just pathetic. I
am at a different level.
Which is reflected in what,
exactly? Your title? No.
Your salary? Not really.
Your responsibilities? Hardly.
Your attitude?
Ah.
I think we've finally found it.
Doesn't change the fact that you made a
bad decision because you wanna get laid.
Or the fact that you're
courageously picking on Kelly,
'cause you're scared
to take on House.
Congratulations.
You're a real leader.
I am Felipe.
Oh, you've got to be kidding.
Dr. House was worried how you
left things. He is giving you massage.
As an admission
he was wrong? Yes.
Well, tell him thanks, but I have a
meeting with Dr. Schatz in 20 minutes.
He says you would say that,
and to say, "No, you don't."
Well, tell him he needs to
stop canceling my appointments,
because I will just
reschedule them.
He says you would
say that, and to say,
uh,
"That Dr. Schatz is
a fat, lonely moron
"who, in an effort to have
contact with a human female,
"makes the same exact complaint
about parking spaces every month,
"and you know you have
to stop enabling him."
I have great fingers.
That's so nice.
Thank you.
How long have you
been a masseur?
What is that, "masseur"?
A massage therapist?
Oh.
No, not long.
How did my boyfriend find you?
Boyfriend?
Dr. House.
He is your boyfriend?
Why is that surprising?
I just mean, if he found me,
I do not think he's
got no girlfriend.
Are you a prostitute?
Are you a cop?
Then no.
Get your hands off me.
I didn't know you smoked.
I don't.
I don't mind screwing up.
I've screwed up in my
life, and I've gotten over it.
But I'm not a cheater and I'm
not a liar, and now I feel like both.
You're right. I'm sorry.
You work with House, you kind
of get a messed-up perspective
of what's permissible
in the workplace.
Maybe I should just quit.
No. You're smart,
you're hardworking.
Yeah, but I'm not like you guys.
Use what makes you different.
A lot of this job is reading
people, dealing with them.
You're a psychiatrist.
Use your skills.
You okay?
I checked with Trenton General.
There's no support
group for abused women.
Maybe it was just...
If she was lying about that,
what else is she lying about?
I mean, maybe she wasn't even
abused. Maybe she's a criminal.
Who the hell knows? You
don't know, that's the point.
The way she's acting, that's
the way abuse victims act.
Their personalities are affected
by what they went through.
They find coping mechanisms.
I gotta talk to her
about this Trenton thing.
If you wake her up, make
her feel defensive, it'll go bad.
She doesn't need any more
hostility or aggression in her life.
Okay.
Seriously? A massage
from a male hooker?
He was?
Huh!
Well, it doesn't
bother me at all.
I guess we both learned
a valuable lesson.
Except that I didn't use to
have sex with him, you idiot.
Plus, he was a gay hooker.
Have you any idea how hard it
is to find a straight male hooker?
Come on. It's a massage!
I don't care who
gives it to you.
Why not treat me the same way?
I'm sure that some part
of you believes this idiocy,
but you can't possibly be
stupid enough to think that
you can convince any part of me.
And that can only mean you're
trying to sabotage this relationship.
Why would I do
that? We're doing fine.
Because the next step from fine is
serious. And you can't handle that.
So you're trying to keep me at
arm's length with all this crap.
How about you?
I have been completely
open with you.
You won't let me sleep over.
You basically haven't
introduced me to your daughter.
But do you want to
spend time with her?
Honestly, before this,
I would have said no.
But, yeah, how are we ever gonna be a
couple if you keep hiding her from me?
House.
I need to protect her.
If I let you into her
life and you go away...
I can call it what it is.
I'm not the only one
who's holding back.
Hey, baby.
I am not getting mad. I'm just
trying to understand you here.
But there's no meeting like you
talked about at Trenton General.
You see, it turns
out that... Turns out.
The turnout. The turnout.
It's been turned. Turning.
What?
Turning. Hey.
The turnout. The turnout.
It's turning. BILLY: Hey.
You're going to burn.
What's happening to her?
It's hit her brain.
Whatever "it" is.
Opacity in the
left temporal lobe.
It could be nothing.
Which would get us nowhere,
so let's assume it's something.
What kind of something?
Abscess.
Or lymphoma, or Wegener's.
We'd have to biopsy it to be sure. Any
of them could explain all of the symptoms.
You know, we're assuming
everything is connected.
Because it probably is.
But her delusions are
consistent with mental illness.
Bipolar disease, for example.
She's 30, it could be hitting
her right now for the first time.
So her mind just happens to
fall apart right after her body?
I thought I was
having a bad week.
I know it sounds
coincidental, but...
You know what, I'm back
to the Cameron theory.
But you hired the dumb
version of Cameron,
so you can fire her
and get revenge...
Give her a break.
What, you switched sides?
Let me guess, Chase represents
the dumb version of Thirteen...
I realized if we all
just keep pressuring
Kelly, of course she's
gonna get stuff wrong.
It's irresponsible of
me to let that happen.
You are a true leader of men.
Get someone to cut into
her head and get me a biopsy.
Whoa!
Just say "hold on" next time.
Her temperature's normal.
So what? She was
on the cooling blanket.
We took her off an hour ago.
She should be febrile again.
Tell House one of the patient's
symptoms just disappeared.
Could it be Legionnaires',
and our treatment worked?
I wish, but no, we've been hydrating
her, and there's still no lung involvement.
So relapsing, remitting fever.
Malaria, dengue...
Why wasn't she frozen?
This morning.
If you put a healthy
person on a cooling blanket,
they'd be chilled like
a fine chardonnay.
She's a nice warm
merlot, 98.6 all day.
I didn't want her to freeze.
So you titrated the blanket. As her
fever dropped, you lower the power.
Exactly.
So it's been on the
lowest setting since when?
Yesterday afternoon.
Which means we could have known that
her fever was gone yesterday afternoon.
The fever was brief. Sounds
like a reaction to medication.
The antibiotics?
Without vomiting?
When did she last puke?
Not since she was admitted.
Two down.
Shooting for three.
You're gonna turn
her pacemaker off?
You sure that's a good idea?
No. But it might be.
No tachycardia.
So only the delusions are
left, if they're even still there.
Maybe it is a bipolar disorder.
She's female, she's 30...
It's not a coincidence.
You gotta stop doing this.
But it could've been prompted
by the physical symptoms.
You couldn't be more wrong.
You got the cause
and effect backwards.
Start her on haloperidol
and lorazepam.
Give it a few hours to take
effect. Call me when she awakes.
Still hallucinating.
Can you hear me?
What are you looking at?
The table, it's on fire.
If it was, you think
I'd be able to do this,
without screaming for my mommy?
Thank you.
Don't be too impressed. It's
mostly the happy pills you put her on.
But she can talk to us now.
The obviously stupid lie you
told us about your hospital records,
it turns out to have been
un-obviously un-stupid.
You thought you
wouldn't get caught,
'cause you thought that
you'd be cured and back home
by the time we spoke
to the other hospital.
Because you knew
what was wrong with you.
Your doctor was treating
you with risperidone, right?
That's why you were in Trenton.
You had the stomach pain, you went
to see him, he wanted you to taper off...
Her doctor's not in Trenton.
Not the one you know about.
If you haven't figured it out
by now, your wife has a secret.
What the hell is
he talking about?
This about your ex?
The ex was not so much
a secret, more of a lie.
You weren't married
before, were you?
I'm sorry, I didn't want
you to know about it.
Know about what?
She's sick. She's
been sick for years.
Maybe it put you on the streets,
maybe that's where
you got the broken bones.
She's only suffering
from one condition.
Everything else is side effects
of the drug that was treating it.
When she stopped taking
the drug, the side effects faded,
but the underlying
disease is still there.
Why don't you tell your husband?
Billy, I'm schizophrenic.
That's the kind of
thing that a recent
psychiatric resident
might have figured out.
What the hell am I
supposed to do now?
Nothing. Her physical
symptoms are gone.
We'll put her on a different
anti-psychotic for the mental ones.
You can take a nap.
This is not who I married.
Of course she is.
You just didn't know it.
I don't know if I
can stay with her.
Sorry, as your
marriage counselor,
I'm not allowed to talk to
you without your wife present.
Just tell me how hard it would
be for us to handle this, medically.
Look, if you want me to give
you a reason to leave her, fine.
Apparently you haven't noticed,
but she's got a
serious mental illness.
It's too hard.
It's always hard.
Okay, so I made a mistake.
Kelly will make a fine doctor,
but she's not
ready for the team.
Up to you.
What? You like her now?
Nope. But she got
me to the right answer,
which none of
the rest of you did.
If you want to give her
another shot, go for it.
Okay. I will.
Great.
It'll make it easier for
you to sleep with her.
Come on. Why else
would you have hired her?
That's not why I hired her.
What are you doing?
Got bored with the
porn on my computer.
You got any girl-on-girl-
on-girl-on-vibrating-object-on-girl stuff?
I wouldn't have to do this
if you'd gave me the name of
that physical therapist you like.
You done with Brandi?
Eh...
Knobby hands.
I will get you the name.
Let's stay at my
place tonight, okay?
Will you get cable? No.
Then we'll have
to have more sex.
Okay.
What are you doing?
Quitting before House fires me.
Hold on.
We both know he is.
But maybe there's a bright side.
What?
You really looked out for me.
And you seem like
a really good guy.
And I never date anybody
who I work with, but...
Yeah. Sorry it didn't work out.
You want to get
dinner tomorrow night?
You want some more meat?
This is meat?
Yes, please.
Hey, hey, hey. Come on. Kid,
come on, come on, come on.
Come on.
Hey, hey.
Aren't you adorable.