Get up, House.
Must be some mistake.
I specifically requested my
wake-up startle three hours from now.
Some VIP visitor. Dean of
Medicine from your old hospital.
I've had dreams about this.
I'm gonna assume
this is another one.
Get up.
I can refuse to see
any visitor I want.
Tell the Dean that I
don't want to see her.
He said you'd say that.
"He"?
What's the hiring policy
over there? All ass-based?
I can get you out of here.
Not unless that
file has a file in it.
Judge's order for your
immediate release.
I had eight months added to
my sentence two months ago.
The math is pretty basic.
We have a crisis.
Which is good news for you.
You're out tonight
on conditional parole,
the condition being that you're
employed by me at PPTH.
No, thanks.
You think it's a
good idea for me
to go right back to my old life?
For either of us?
Your patient is
two lungs in a box.
It only has 12 hours left.
No pulse, no body, no
ability to answer questions.
It's your perfect patient.
I did pay for the room
for the whole week, but...
Donor's an 18-year-old
college kid back from Hofstra.
Goes to a homecoming
party with his buddies,
hops on his motorcycle,
ends up an organ donor.
Asystole in the ER.
No pulse. No blood circulating.
His heart, liver,
kidneys were all toast.
Surgeons had the
recipient on the table
when they realized the lungs
had increased airway resistance.
The team closed her up, put
the lungs in suspended animation.
Buys 24 hours to fix it,
12 of which have passed.
And we still have
no clue what's wrong.
Nice painting.
Blues and greens. Calming
with a hint of nurturing.
Totally offsets the stench
of suffering and death.
Where's my patient?
We need to not talk.
ICU isolation room.
The transplant team
will meet you there
with updates from
the past two hours.
Great. Take this.
How about you
drop it in your office?
I completely understand
and almost respect your desire
to appear to be Dean of Medicine
given that your title
is Dean of Medicine.
On the other hand, seriously?
Get this straight.
You break the law,
you go back to jail.
Scam extra
Vicodin, back to jail.
Flout my authority, make the
hospital look bad, back to jail.
I own you.
Yes, master.
See, that would be an example.
When did Cuddy leave?
She gave her notice the
day after your incident.
Took a job...
Don't need the details.
Ortho needed more space.
You're this way.
Where's my stuff?
No idea.
What about my team?
Pathetic.
The first thing you said to me
was you don't want
your old environment,
the fourth thing you said was,
"Where's my old environment?"
It's been a year. Taub,
Chase, Thirteen all moved on.
The world does that sometimes.
No, it doesn't.
Here's your new office.
And there's your new team.
Hi.
I'm not interested in another
department's sloppy seconds.
I'm not sloppy seconds...
It's 3:00 a.m.
If Foreman had called
you in from home,
you wouldn't have pressed
clothes, coiffed hair and make-up.
Which means you were
already here in the hospital.
Yes, I was on-call
for Neurology.
If that were true, you'd be working
right now and unavailable to help.
Which means that
you're hanging out
in the hospital
pretending to work.
Which means you're
not just a reject,
you're a cowardly reject who's trying
to hide her rejectedness from someone.
I am not a reject.
Then go back to Neurology.
I can't.
I punched my attending.
ARDS secondary to trauma
is our leading hypothesis.
FI02 is 93%...
Prison!
Sorry, I thought I heard
everyone else think that.
I was in prison, see?
It was a long time ago,
but still, you're curious.
Never was raped.
Not raped-raped.
Well, raped-raped but
not raped-raped-raped.
Well, now that we've got
that completely behind us...
I'm sorry. Dr. House,
welcome back...
Is there cake?
Any alveolar exudate?
No. Lungs are dry.
Well, it's not ARDS.
It's the autumn.
It's tick-borne disease season.
Ehrlichiosis
causing bronchiolitis.
You'll appreciate that I
left the "idiots" subtextual.
Blood smear was
clear, and we idiots
treated with
broad-spectrum antibiotics.
Cocaine. Tox screen was clean.
Dead men don't pee.
Tox screen tests for
metabolites in the urine.
Coke never got past the lungs.
Also explains the
motorcycle crash.
Idiots.
Let's get the
lungs on treatment.
Great idea, unless you're wrong.
And by you, I mean me.
Then this treatment will
burn holes in the lungs.
I'd call you idiots,
but at this point,
I'm starting to doubt whether you
understand what I mean by the word.
Kato, get Black Beauty
and meet me out front.
We're gonna find
the dead kid's stash.
Since an 18-year-old
with organ donor
on his license is
not a cancer patient,
I'm figuring the recipient
is a lifetime member
of the Wilson Cares
Too Much Club.
Excellent deduction.
You're the reason I'm
out of the big house.
Doesn't quite make up
for never visiting, but...
Springing you was
Foreman's idea.
I wasn't convinced until
Simpson failed three times.
Amounts to the same
thing, you wanted me back.
See, I knew you'd
over-interpret it.
Strong, emotional reaction.
I guess that's what lifetime
membership gets you.
How's your wrist?
Healed, thank you.
I was wrong.
I went to prison,
I paid the price.
You're a changed man.
I said I was wrong, I didn't
say I changed. I haven't.
Neither have you.
Which is why...
Analyze it however you like.
We're not friends anymore.
What can I do?
My chest...
Angina's back.
Upping the nitro. Should
knock it back down.
Sis and I were talking,
trying to figure out
how many hospital
sleepovers we've had.
Definitely started with the
Great Mastectomy of 2001.
God, I miss my boobs.
They were spectacular.
Is there a chance of
locating another donor?
It's unlikely,
especially since with the extent
of the emphysema,
she needs a double lung.
How you doing?
Better already.
It's a good thing that worked
or I was gonna make
you bring me a bottle.
Lighten up, Sis.
Least you could do is
laugh at a dying lady's jokes.
Your drinking wasn't funny
then, okay? And it's not funny now.
Because you're not dying.
The hospital brought in a
consultant to work on the lungs.
Do you know him? Is he good?
He is an excellent doctor.
We probably shouldn't be
turning up unannounced like this.
Their son just died.
Bright side, they're
probably up weeping.
Hey, we both assaulted our
bosses. It's like we're twins.
I'd really rather not discuss...
Okay, I'll go first.
My boss dumped me.
And yours, what,
called you his china doll?
Joked about what a crappy
deal you got for Manhattan?
Assumed that you
have a huge penis?
I have no idea
what flavor you are,
so I thought I'd just
cover the spread.
My mom's Filipino, Dad's Korean.
And my boss grabbed my behind.
Behind what?
Oh, yeah, your...
Grabbed your tushy.
So now you're
pretending to be on-call
so that your overly
protective boyfriend
won't find out you got groped.
I don't have a boyfriend.
It's my parents.
If they found out what I've
done, they'd be mortified.
Your parents know
your call schedule?
I live with them.
Right.
No issues there.
I told you, my son
didn't do cocaine.
Druggies are not
known for their honesty.
Trust me on this one.
Mr. Weathers, I'm sure you're
right, but we need to be thorough.
Did your son ever
smoke marijuana?
He was an athlete, took real
good care of himself... Hey.
Take it easy. Steve
loved all that...
Sorry, but we're on a clock.
I think he's about
to throw us out.
Nope.
His son is dead.
The only way that
has any meaning
is if we fix the lungs
and transplant them.
It doesn't matter how
much we piss him off
as long as we find something.
So go back there, piss
him off and find something.
Do you know any of the kids
at the party with your son?
A bunch of his
high school buddies,
they'd gotten really into poker,
decided to have an all-night game
in Brandon Broome's basement.
Hey...
I understand we're in a hurry,
and that he's probably
not gonna throw us out,
but maybe he should.
Your son isn't wearing
glasses in any of these pictures.
He just got them a
couple weeks ago.
Because he was having headaches?
Answer the question
before answering the door.
Yeah, he was.
You're right, he was
not doing cocaine.
He had a brain tumor.
Don't bother, it's for me.
Turns out they
monitor these monitors.
Thank you, Officer.
I thought the bracelet
was decorative.
My aunt had one just like it.
Wait a minute.
You're allowed to be at the
hospital, you're allowed to go home.
That was made clear.
The dead kid's house was
on the way to my apartment,
assuming I got lost twice.
Those consultants in my office
are only costing the
hospital 100 bucks
every minute I
keep them waiting.
Why didn't you just tell
me what you were doing?
I knew you were very busy
being vaguely important.
I might have cleared
it with the cops.
Yeah, it's the word
"might" that bumps me.
I'll run it by you next time.
House.
Getting you out of jail was not a
popular decision with the board.
I need you to solve this,
and I need you to do it without
making me look like I can't control you.
For both our sakes.
Disciplinary hearing
should be fun,
and the subsequent lingering
black mark on your record.
I'm not worried.
We have to wheel
this out to the MRI.
We should probably
leave the body in the bag.
There's a mass in the arm.
Analyzing part of this tumor is
gonna be quicker than a scan.
So, where's the next job?
You worry about what
people think of you,
thus the carefully maintained
hair, clothes and parental secrets.
The only way that you're
not worried about this hearing
is if you don't think
there's gonna be one.
The only way that happens is
you leave Princeton-Plainsboro.
I had a video interview with
Chicago yesterday. It went well.
My money's on rhabdomyosarcoma.
Chicago has a great program.
And you're a dumbass.
Running away from home
is a time-honored tradition.
But you're not doing
it to flee your parents,
you're doing it to protect them.
That's an insult to everything
teen prostitutes have worked for.
Time to grow up and come clean.
You're right. I should
just drive my car
into their living
room and tell them.
Didn't it turn out that he'd
stolen the hot dog cart?
No, borrowed. Bobby was
very insistent on that point.
Seems like someone's
feeling better.
No more chest pain.
I haven't heard the name
Bobby in a long time.
How's he doing these days?
I don't know,
we're not in touch.
And don't even pretend like you're
not relieved, you never liked him.
Bobby is an incredibly fun, great
guy, just not a great influence.
I would have gone
with colossal drunk.
I was gonna leave that
implied, but yes, colossal drunk.
What? It's good for a
couple to share a hobby.
Your catheter bag is empty,
despite taking in 200 cc's of fluids.
I'm gonna have to
dial back on the nitro.
Won't her chest pain come back?
We don't have any choice.
The nitro is dropping the
blood flow to your kidneys.
They're shutting down.
This is so our song.
My patient is
running out of time.
Not worried.
My team is confirming
the diagnosis as we speak.
I want to be understanding.
It's your first day back...
See?
I smell empathy.
Just remember
all the good times.
Like when I gave
you that necklace
that you just
dumped in the ocean.
What were you thinking?
House, I haven't
forgotten our friendship.
For every good memory,
there's a slew of bad ones.
Come in. Come in.
Paraneoplastic syndrome is out.
The lung donor
didn't have cancer.
You tell that to the tumor
that I found in his arm?
That mass wasn't a tumour.
It was coagulated plasma.
ER pumped him full of
it, IV leaked into his arm.
I even did a complete
MRI. No cancer anywhere.
We've got nothing.
Just 'cause it wasn't a tumor
doesn't mean it didn't
mess with the lungs.
They're reacting to
something in the plasma.
But every unit of plasma can
have up to 25 contributing donors.
We'd need to track
down all of them.
Still. Not as bad
as 1,000 people
going down in a
gigantic boat, right?
My heart will go on.
No. You can't
leave the hospital.
Twenty-five donors contributed to
the plasma that the lung donor got.
My "team" cannot track down
and interview them all in six hours.
I vouch for you to the cops,
you take some parole-violating
detour celebrating your freedom,
justified, of course, by some absurd
theory connecting it to the case.
You asked me to ask you. Was
that just so you'd enjoy saying no?
I don't trust you,
House. I can't.
Actually, you have to.
Not absolutely. Not outside
the walls of this hospital.
Fine, then give me a team I don't
have to put in quotation marks.
Use the people
already on the case.
Get me Chase, Taub, Thirteen.
We don't have the
money to pay them.
Oh. Yeah, it went to interior
designers, I understand.
You only have Park because
she's on Neurology's tab.
You are making minimum wage.
I am?
Get out of my office, please.
What you got?
Number three went to a baseball
game the day before he donated.
Boredom is not transmissible.
He ate a bag of peanuts.
And peanut proteins would be.
If our donor had an allergy,
could explain the lungs.
Nice.
What? HOUSE: Nothing.
Don't start that.
Start what? I'm enjoying
our conversation.
The repartee.
There was no repartee.
That was repartee.
I'm not doing this for you.
I'm doing it to help my patient.
It's just good to
hear your voice.
Goodbye.
That's my whiteboard.
I need it.
And he really doesn't care
how the cast comes off.
Dr. Foreman warned us
that you'd try something.
Told me to call him if you did.
I'd like to do that.
I'll take this outside.
Yeah.
Donor six traveled to
Thailand, around Korat.
Region was endemic
with dengue fever.
Good.
Yeah. CHI: Alcohol.
You'd have to be pretty drunk
for it to affect a pool of plasma.
These guys have
got that covered.
Acute ETOH ingestion
could have... Hey!
Paint around them.
They're not hurting anyone.
Who's painting?
The crew is just starting. The paint
fumes didn't cause contamination.
But maybe the old paint did.
They scraped off the underpass,
probably because it contains...
Lead. Lead.
Chest pain back?
It's worse this time.
Is there any way
to take the edge off?
We're still working on the
lungs. We should know soon.
Soon is good.
How's the chelation going?
Reverend Moon started
it about 20 minutes ago.
You missed lunch tracking
down the plasma donors.
Got you a Reuben
from the cafeteria.
Thanks.
Lead exposure's
a nice diagnosis.
I hope it pays off.
It will.
I appreciate your confidence,
but she's not really...
Oh, no, she could die.
But technically, it
would still pay off.
Even if your patient dies,
someone will get the lungs.
You really haven't changed.
But I've given up red meat.
What round of chelation is this?
Fourth.
Are you checking up
on me? Or on House?
On this case.
Unique situation.
Oxygenating?
98%. Airway resistance down.
Great.
Is House okay?
I have no idea.
Dad, what are you doing here?
Got your text. I brought you
some of your mother's gomguk.
What text?
The one asking me to
bring you some dinner.
I went by Neurology. The
secretary said you were on leave.
I'm consulting on this case.
Unique situation.
Looks very complicated.
You can help with that?
Lungs are crashing.
I have to go.
Bye.
Increasing to 100% FIO2.
Saline flow is down to 10 cc.
Blockage? Clot in the line?
Chelation is making it worse, which
means we were wrong about lead.
Hold the analysis and
help me save this thing.
Saline's flushing forward,
but getting no return.
One-way valve. Vasospasm.
If you're right, calcium channel
blocker should relax the artery.
The lungs have no nervous
system, will that still work?
We'll know soon.
Saline flow's rising.
Vasospasm's relaxing.
Left lung is pinking
up. Good job.
Right middle lobe isn't.
Nothing.
We killed part of the lung.
Page Dr. Pinto
stat to the cath lab.
We're going to the cath
lab? Are you thinking that...
What? Who?
One dead lobe
means four live ones,
means enough to transplant,
with a side order of dead
tissue that we can test.
Makes sense, unlike
you stealing my phone.
You have unlimited texting.
Until your parents
know, you'll never see
that punch for
what it really was,
your February 4th.
Sri Lankan Independence Day.
I told you I'm
Korean and Filipino.
And I told you I wasn't
listening. By my actions.
Violence isn't an appropriate
way to handle conflict.
It was a moment of weakness.
You've barked at me, picked
a fight with a painting crew.
Maybe it's time to recognize
it's not a character flaw.
Maybe it's your character.
Pinto.
House.
Embrace your inner bitch.
So, why did chelation
make the lungs worse?
We got about five
minutes till Pinto gets back.
Give me a hand with this. No.
I tracked down
another bag of plasma
from the batch they
used on the donor,
negative for all our
other exposures.
Sarcoidosis could be
inflamed by the treatment.
I'm a cripple, in
need of assistance.
Transplant team
ran an ACE, negative.
It's mine. And it's your job.
My job is to assist
you in curing the lungs.
This chair will help me do that.
What if the scrapings from the
bridge contained other heavy metals,
like beryllium, or asbestos?
Chelation for lead wouldn't
have made them worse.
But
maybe the problem isn't a
heavy metal from outside.
It's inside.
But it's not leaving the body
like it's supposed to, it's stuck.
Iron. Donor had hemosiderosis.
His body wasn't
disposing of iron,
massive amounts
choke up the lungs.
Then our chelation
would wreak havoc
because it picks
up too much stuff.
Go stain the dead
lung tissue for iron.
I'm sorry, young lady, I simply
will not help you steal this chair.
Pinto. House.
Hi.
She can barely catch her breath.
Lungs ready yet?
We had a small setback.
We're testing for iron overload.
I thought it was lead.
This is not an exact process.
Your small airways
are collapsing.
You're not getting
enough oxygen.
I'd like to try forcing an
oxygen-rich slurry into your lungs.
It should open up the airways
and buy you some time
until the lungs are ready.
Fluid in my lungs?
Sounds like drowning.
It is.
Gonna hurt, isn't it?
Yes. A fair amount.
No.
I'm done.
House, the nurses
saw you come in.
Enter.
It's a bathroom.
Ah!
Explains the hole in this chair.
God, I've missed doors.
And air freshener.
Now go away. I'm waiting
for some test results.
My patient signed a
DNR, she's giving up.
Looks like someone else
will be getting the lungs.
Making this yet another interaction
with you in which I get nothing.
It's not my fault you
can't handle your patient.
She said she's done.
I spent half an hour trying to change
her mind, but she'd made her decision.
I accepted that.
It's called respect.
What's after respect?
You find another angle,
you hold her hands,
get the sister to beg, stick
your fingers in your ears
and pretend you can't hear her.
Do whatever it takes.
Oh. Whatever it takes? Thanks,
House, I hadn't thought of that.
What are you testing
for? Hemosiderosis.
I'm staining for excess iron.
Promising.
When your dad showed up
unexpectedly, House have a hand in that?
I'm guessing he does
things like that a lot.
His version of a compliment.
I spoke to the head of
Neurology in Chicago.
I gave you a good
recommendation.
Did you mention what happened?
Lawyers say I'm not allowed to.
Works out well for everyone.
Why exactly is
that good for you?
Excuse me?
I'm a talented physician,
top 2% of my class.
I'm an asset to this hospital,
an asset you're about
to lose to Chicago.
You applied for the job, you asked
me to call and recommend you...
Andrews is the one that
should leave, he's the supervisor.
He touched me first.
I can't discuss any of
that, not before the hearing.
But if you're having doubts about
Chicago, I can call them back.
No. Thank you.
Dr. Foreman, would
you look at this?
Iron? No.
White blood cells.
Classic presentation
of an infection.
How the hell did we miss that?
Biopsy revealed white
blood cell infiltrates.
Infection was right after all.
Fresh fruit in prison
is usually chicken.
Why aren't you more alarmed?
We're running out of time.
She's dying!
Were you able to figure out what
was wrong while I was screaming?
Infection was the first thing that
the transplant team treated for.
Which would've worked if the
bacteria had been out in the open.
If they're hiding
inside the lung's cells...
I'm thinking Brucella.
To wipe that out,
you need special ops.
An intact immune system.
But that's what
white blood cells are.
They're part of the immune
defense force, like the infantry.
Those lungs need the
Air Force, the Marines,
antibodies raining
down from above.
Antibiotics and IVIG.
Did you use metaphors
for your old team?
Or do you just think
I'm particularly stupid?
No. They were stupid, too.
What are you doing here?
I'm here for Vanessa.
Now is not the time, Bobby.
She asked me to
come. Right, Doc?
Actually, it was my idea.
What? What are you thinking?
She doesn't want to see him.
When Vanessa was
ready to quit chemo,
Bobby's the one who got
her to do one more round.
Yeah. And then he got her drunk.
At least tell me you
haven't been drinking today.
I should go. Yeah.
Hail, hail, the gang's all here.
Hey, beautiful.
Hi.
Case is under
control. It's me time.
Vanessa's gonna
do the lung slurry.
You were right to push me.
I needed that. Thank you.
So we're good?
It was good advice. I just
came here to say thank you.
I like you.
I have fun with you.
And if you can honestly say that you
don't like me, you don't have fun with me,
I can accept that.
But just do whatever you
have to do to get over this.
Punch me in the face,
kick me in the nuts.
Either/or. Both seems excessive.
The thing is, House,
I don't like you.
When did the
discoloration start?
A few minutes after
I started the IVIG.
Means we're wrong
about infection.
And by we, you mean you.
You screwed up the lungs.
Wrong about
auto-immune, about cancer,
heavy metals, genetic issues...
Increase PEEP.
Already maxed out.
We're close to the
point of no return.
The lungs will never
be viable for transplant.
I need...
I need ideas.
LgA nephropathy?
It's already ruled out.
Lupus? No.
Maybe we're just out of time.
We're out of time when we're out
of time. When they die or she dies.
Keep them stable
as long as you can.
I need to think.
One, two, three!
Make a wish, make a wish!
The lungs are smoker.
You of all people
should know better.
But the kid never smoked.
He played poker. Who
plays poker without cigars?
Even if he didn't
light up himself.
It was a rainy night. The
windows were closed.
All parents think
their kids are special.
These ones were right.
At least his white
blood cells were special.
They had an on switch for
reacting to smoke, but no off.
If he inhaled small amounts of
smoke, he had small problems.
No one even noticed.
Big amounts of smoke
is enough to trash a lung.
As soon as he breathed in all that
cigar smoke, he was a dead man.
The motorcycle accident was
an unnecessary dramatic flourish.
Eosinophilic Pneumonitis.
But the steroids would
have treated for that.
I was right.
Not about anything medical,
but my metaphors were perfect.
We need to hit it harder.
We need to carpet
bomb, blitzkrieg.
We need the nuclear option...
At some point, you're gonna
say we need to radiate, right?
See? The metaphors work.
But that'll destroy
the good lung, too.
Better to go with a strong
cocktail of immunosuppressants.
Won't be fast enough.
Wilson needs these lungs.
It's working.
He did it.
I'm not going to Chicago.
If you stay, we'll have
to have a hearing.
I know.
Dad. Do you have a minute?
Thoracic cavity clear.
Ready for the donor lungs.
Thank God you called him.
Wonder what happens now.
She can handle it.
House.
Got something for you.
Found your stuff in storage.
This is all you get. Ortho
still has the outer office.
Well, that sucks.
Where are Chase, Taub
and Thirteen gonna sit?
You're welcome, House.
Dinner later? I'll
pick something up.
I heard about a good
new vegetarian place.
Screw that. I want a steak.
I'll meet you at
your place at 8:00.