In some residency programs,
graduating surgeons
get a wooden chair,
emblazoned with the emblem
of their program.
♪ Thug life, baby
♪ It chose me,
I didn't chose this city ♪
♪ Uh-huh, uh-huh, uh-huh
♪ Walk right over
♪ You're a ten
♪ I'm a four-leaf clover
♪ Well, tell me,
do you hate me? ♪
When those residents
become attendings,
the chair usually goes
in their office,
where it collects dust
for the rest of their careers.
Relax.
And come off the mouthpiece.
♪ Lookin' like
it's time tonight ♪
♪ For fight or flight
in Van Horn ♪
Well, don't just stare at me.
Did I pass?
Not only did you pass,
but your lung capacity
is 50% greater than we'd expect.
And your sats are consistently
in the high 90s.
Mer, you killed it.Yeah.
So, as long as your labs check
out, we're kicking you out.
Are you happy?
I am happy.
I'm just not sure I believe you.
We are going to have
this framed.
Well, I am.
I'm having it framed.
You give your program years
of your life,
your sweat, your tears,
and in my case, at least,
your blood,
and your program
gives you a chair.
Oh.
Please.
Give me some good news.
Is it happening?
Is it finally happening?
Yeah, looks like
it's finally happening.
Perez, let's get
a clap-out ready.
And you know what?
Keep it quiet.
I want it to be a surprise.
Understood.
I know how to handle a queen.
Ah.
Mm.
DeLuca took
such good care of her.
We need to tell her
about DeLuca.
I wish he could see this.
Maybe he can.
I suppose
it's a nice tradition,
if you're into
that sort of thing.
And if you want
a constant reminder
of the hell you went through
to get here.
Hey, you okay?
Yeah. Sorry. I just, uh...
I needed a minute to...
Meredith's going home.
She's going home.
I mean, I haven't had
good news since forever,
and I-I know that we are still
in the thick of things,
but we're finally getting
a handle on how to treat this.
I actually feel hope.
It's about time.
Okay.
I'm ready. Let's go. Okay. Okay.
Oh! Sorry. Sorry.Sorry. Sorry.
Sorry. After you. Okay. No, ser... Okay.
Oh, my God.
Scout is dressed
and chewing on his plastic cat.
It is a giraffe.
I used to get dressed.
Clothes are overrated.
Says the man
leaving for work.
You sure you don't want
to help Ellis
with some finger painting?
No, I'm good with work.
If Nico ever sends me
those post-op scans.
I used to get texts
about post-op scans.
Oh, my God.
What?
Oh, my God!
Mer's
pulmonary function tests
show a total lung capacity
of almost 4 liters.
That's amazing.
And aren't her other numbers
good enough
to send her home
instead of rehab?
What if she comes home?
What if
she finally comes home?
Oh, my God.
Oh... my... God.
What if she finally comes home?
This place is a dump.
She is gonna report us
for child abuse.
What... What?
Hang on. Hang...
Look, if you start now,
it's gonna take Ellis
all of five minutes to undo
the whole thing.
How about I go to the hospital,
confirm the good news,
and I'll call you
with an update?
That's a good idea.
Good.
Yes.
I will see you later.
Oh, God! Oh!
Why aren't you going?
Because you're crying. No, no.
This... This is
gonna happen all day.
Just go, go.
Alright.
Oh, God.
You didn't get my text. Which one?
The one about Dr. Grey.
Oh. Yeah.
One less person to wheel
to the freezer truck.
Gotta go.
Incoming.
Dr. MeredithGrey!
Chief of general surgery?!
Mentor to all?!
Okay, so, you need to teach me
everything you possibly can
before you move
back to Italy,
which I'm
a little devastated about
because everyone says
that you are the best OB.
I did quit,
but then I begged Bailey
for my job back
this morning.
I am getting married
instead.
What? Ha! Yeah.
Congratulations! Grazie mille.
I'm still going back to Italy,
though.
Oh. Yeah. I'm only
going for a month.
I'll help where I can,
and...
I'll scatter
my brother's ashes
and, um, yeah,
there will be plenty of rounds
when I get back,
but now I need you
to update my patient roster
while I find coffee.
Oh, wait.
I can get you coffee.
No.
Cappuccino?
Uh, double espresso,
but no, Dr. Wilson, y...
Just call me Jo.
Jo, you are an attending.
You don't...
Not anymore.
Dr. Koracick.
Thanks for meeting us.
Do I know you?
Your forehead
and your irises look familiar.
What...
I'm an intern here.
James Chee.
He almost quit
after his first day
when you took over
the class.
Oh. Right.
Not my finest moment.
What do we have here, Chee?
William Lawrence,
a 68-year-old Suquamish
and Duwamish man,
presents with aphasia
and right-sided paralysis.
Hello, sir.
What does a duck say?
Yeah.
Just making sure.
Helm, call a stroke alert.
I'll meet you in CT.
Go, go, go, go, go.
I treated him for COVID
a couple months back
at the urban Indian
health clinic I work at
on my time off. We're
not paying you enough?
He made a full recovery,
but about a half an hour ago,
his granddaughter
brought him in like this.
How's he doing?
I-I'm his granddaughter.
You have to save him.
That's the plan. He's
an elder in the tribe.
A language keeper.
Well, that doesn't change
the plan.
Dr. Chee, show
Mr. Lawrence's granddaughter
to the waiting tent.
We'll update you
when we know more.
Come on. Let's go.
So, you're
going to fulfill
this new leadership position
from Boston?
I am.
Not here, in Seattle,
where you work?
For me.
My official resignation.
I have to take off
first thing in the morning.
What?! Bailey, I know it's sudden,
and I apologize.
It's just...
It's a really good thing.
The work I'm gonna be able
to do,
the changes we'll be able to
enact from the foundation...
It's gonna be really great
for all of us.
It would have been...
Been better
if you'd have left me
a surgeon
who's double board certified
in plastics and ENT.
Pretty good list of
recommendations there
on the second page. What? Wait.
Why am I the only one
who's surprised?
Did you know about this? I did.
It wasn't my news
to share.
I went to see my dad,
who I realized my entire life
has shown me
exactly the kind of man
I never want to be.
Checked out and unwilling to
really fight for anything.
The two of you
showed me the opposite.
Example after example
of not giving in
to hopelessness
and despair
and consistently resist
complacency.
You get up over and over
and over again and fight.
I learned the kind of surgeon,
the kind of father,
the kind of person I wanted
to become from you.
I'm always gonna be grateful
for that.
We're proud of you, Avery.
I'm proud of you, son.
Thank you.
Talk to you soon.
To clarify what just happened,
Jackson Avery is now...
Our boss.
I see that Ms. Mora was
discharged this morning.
And Evan Pearson. Wow.
He was only here for three days.
I'm not sure if our meds
are getting more effective
or the trends are changing,
but we're seeing more patients
breeze in and out. I need more doctors
in order to keep up
with the turnover.
Already took care of it.
Y-You called these guys?
Ouch.
No. Sorry.
I just... I-I just thought
that we would grab
a few residents,
not heads of departments.
They said it was slow
downstairs.
Well, if you don't need us two,
then...
you know, I could just go back
and check on the ICU or...
No, no.
I mean, it's just...
You know,
um, it's up to you.
Do...
Do you want to be up here?
I just want to help.
Well, it's probably just
gonna be proning patients
and checking vent settings
and inspecting chest tubes,
but, I mean, if you
don't... if you don't mind.
I'm happy to.
So am I.
If I'm still being asked.
Oh, um...
Yeah.
Okay, great.
Mm-hmm. Thanks.
Was that normal?
Are they, uh...
My advice... Don't ask.
You still have laps to do.
I want to talk about
something else.
You're all making me feel
as if I'm going to drop dead.
Not that I blame you.
So, Maggie,
uh, when's the big day?
Oh, you know, we're still
considering our options.
'Cause there's just
a lot to plan.
We don't want to do anything
without his grandma and my dad.
Oh, right, right.
Of... Of course. Mm-hmm.
Wait,
have you even met Winston?
Well, apparently, we've been
in the same room together.
- Yes.
- Mm-hmm.
But only on the phone,
so...
Pierce locked that down.
Well, so did we.
He signed
a five-year contract.
Well, Zola cannot stop talking
about his dance moves,
so I think he's in.
So, what else?
Um...
Jackson's moving
to Boston to...
run the Fox Foundation.
What about Catherine?
It should be interesting.
It's sad, is what it is.
Okay.
Any other tragedies
I should know about?
Um... well,
it'll be tragic
if you have to spend
one more night here.
Yes. Come on.
On your feet.
Come on.
Let's go. Chop, chop. Come on.
Ooh.
Have I ever told you
that my days
of wearing ugly bridesmaid
dresses are over?
Who said you were
going to be a bridesmaid?
Uh, looks like he had
an ischemic stroke
on the left side of his brain
due to...
Probably that.
And by that,
you mean the large clot
in his
internal carotid artery?
Okay, book an IR suite,
please.
Unless you have
someplace else to be.
Dr. Sellers...
Dr. Marty Sellers, 4619.
Hey, Luna.
Meet your new roomie.
Hey.
Vanilla?
Vanelle.
That's your handwriting?
Yeah. I just...
Oh. I, uh...
Sorry.
I was in a rush.
Great. That's what
we'll tell the parents
when it's wrong
on the birth certificate.
Crap. Give me a pen.
Go. I got it.
Wow.
That's, um...
Yeah.
Well, you're lucky
I'm in pink scrubs today,
so I can take
a little extra sad.
Well, you look good
in them.
Happy.
Turns out
you canchange careers
in the middle
of a pandemic, I guess.
Yeah.
We're totally normal.
These last couple months,
um...
Thank you.
You're thanking me
for all the sex?
I'm thanking you
for being a good friend,
especially when
I really needed one.
Okay.
Also, the sex is worth...
worth a thank you. Yeah.
Well, thank you for saying
goodbye in person
and not in a letter,
and for being...
A bridge. You're more than a bridge.
You're a friend.
When I feel like I have
fewer and fewer of those.
It's Carina. A patient's
fully dilated and effaced.
Now that you're
a resident again,
I do have some dry cleaning
I need picked up
before I leave town.
Can't hear you.
But good luck saving the world.
Bye.
Whatever happened
to putting in your two weeks?
One day's notice.
You know, Avery should have
to hire his own replacement,
as far as I'm concerned.Yeah.
Any word
on Meredith's morning labs?
Uh, I keep refreshing
my e-mail, and nothing.
Mm-hmm. But I have every reason
to believe that...
Oh. Hello.
Yeah? Oh, the physical
therapy gave clearance.
Just as I suspected.
There's no longer any
medical reason to keep her here.
You can't keep
not telling her, Bailey.
I know.
I-I just don't want to.
Meredith's
gonna be clapped out tonight,
and if Andrew DeLuca
were alive,
you can bet he'd be the first
in line to cheer her on.
She needs to know
he won't be here.
Mm-hmm.
I'll remove the clot
with a catheter endovascularly
and then place a stent.
Once the blood flow's
been restored,
we're hopeful that his symptoms
will improve, uh,
fairly quickly.
He has teachings, stories
that have been passed down
for hundreds of years
in Lushootseed,
the ancestral language
of our people and this land.
I tried to learn them
as much as I can,
but it's a full-time job,
and I already have one of those.
We can't lose him.
Indigenous communities
have already lost
so many elders to COVID.
We've been hit hard.
The clinic's been packed,
and still doesn't have
enough PPE.
The government was supposed to
send in a shipment, but...
Let me guess...
All booties.
Body bags.
I'm...
Oh, I'm so sorry.
That's awful.
Tribes in other parts
of the country
with less access to healthcare
and running water
have it worse,
but we believe
we're all connected,
like my Diné friend here.
Mary Ann, I'm gonna look out
for your grandfather.
I'm gonna do
everything I can
to make sure
he can pass down his knowledge
to little junior
in there.
Thank you so much...
Oh! Mary Ann, are you okay?
Helm, Chee,
get a wheelchair.
She's not due yet.
Okay, okay.
Breathe. Breathe.
Breathe.
It's alright. I need my husband!
Okay, Mary Ann,
when's your due date?
In five days.
Any past medical issues
or surgeries?
Okay, Mary Ann, you're
8 centimeters dilated.
You're having
this baby today.
T-This can't be
happening right now.
Um, my OB at the clinic.
Dr. Mills.
I-I'm supposed to have
this baby there with her.
It's okay.
Dr. Wilson here will call... Yeah.
And see if she's available
to join us.
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
And my parents,
and... and my husband.Everyone.
I will call everybody.
Oh, my grandfather!
His surgery.
I'm on my way.
That's one impressive thrombus
right there.
Helm, pop quiz...
What's the normal etiology
of an ischemic stroke?
Hello?!
Did that sound rhetorical?
I, um...
I don't remember.Hmm.
You don't remember, or you
weren't paying attention?
Where do you need me?
Schmitt, step right up.
What's he doing here?
He's taking over for you.
Call me old fashioned,
but I think our patients
deserve surgeons
who can at least muster
the strength
to pretend
to want to be here.
Fine.
- Hey.
- Oh, uh, any updates on Mer?
I've been too busy to check,
but I'll ask Teddy.
I miss something?
Nope. No.
Um... no.
Where do you keep
your... incentive spirometers?
Okay, what's going on?
Sorry.
It's just the new guy
trying to get
the lay of the land.Mm-hmm.
Alright, I couldn't help but
notice earlier,
you and Altman
seemed... friendlier today.Mm.
So I...
But it's not my business.
It's not my business.
You know, I couldn't explain it,
even if I tried.
Which is fine, you know?
Privacy is in short supply
these days.
I can't wait
to get mine back.
As soon as Mer's got
her house under control,
Amelia and I
are out of there.
Mm.
What?
Good luck with that.
Incoming. Okay.Yep. Let's go.
That was a big one.
Uh, contractions
are three minutes apart.
They're getting
closer together.
It's almost time.
Okay.
The good news is,
is that your husband
and parents are on the way.
The bad news
is that Dr. Mills
had an emergent
premature delivery
and won't be able
to make it. Twins.
I was supposed to be with
the same OB that delivered me.
I'm so sorry.
But I promise, we'll take
great care of you and your baby.
Oh.
How's my grandfather?
Oh, that's me, too.
Got it.
Before I'm in too much pain
to remember my own name...
do you think you could save
the placenta for me?
Of course.
We're taught to bury it
on Suquamish land,
so she always knows
where her home is.
Mm.
That's beautiful.
Deploying the stent.
Is Dr. Helm coming back?
She is not.
So, you... you met
our friend William
at the Indian Health Clinic?
Yes, sir.
I volunteer on my time off.
Mostly
primary care visits,
but there's also
an apothecary,
so sometimes I'll make salves
for burns and scars
using local plant
medicine.
Other times, we use
traditional practices
like prayer and song.
And I do
a lot of smudging.
What's that?
Burning sage, right?
Or, uh... tobacco?
Here they use cedar.Mm.
But I'm Navajo,
and we use tobacco.
It's one tradition a lot
of tribes have in common.
Hey.
Any update for Mary Ann?
Oh, just have to shoot
one more angiogram...
to make sure the blood flow
has been restored
and he should be
good to go.
Great. Okay.
Did we run out
of blue scrubs?
Oh, she changed
specialties.
Yeah, but really.
That's really
what happened.
She was sick of general.
Dr. Koracick?
Fluoro.
So, you're ditching us?
Well, I mean, in fairness,
I saved you.
So anything after this
is really gonna feel like
a letdown anyway.
Right,
because that was all you.
I mean, Altman
kind of helped out.
I think I recall
Bailey and Richard
being there now and then.
But, yeah, I did... I did
the heavy lifting, mostly.
Do you know
how cold it gets in Boston?
Yes, Meredith.
I did spend the first 18 years
of my life there.
Well, good luck
finding any racism.
So, what's first
on the agenda?
Making sure the girls
are settled in, happy.
And then change the world?
And then change the world.
So... I win.
How's that?
I'm the last man standing.
It was you and me,
from our residency class.
Everyone else has either
abandoned me or died.
We were
the only two left.
You think they're giving out
a medal for that?
I could...
I could stick around.
They probably should,
because it sucks.
Yeah.
Did I ever tell you
what I thought
the first time I met you?
Oh, God.
Um..."legacy hire," probably.
Or, "Is he single?" maybe?
No.
No. No, no, no, "legacy hire"
is what I...
Is what I meant, yeah.
I thought, "That's
a big name to live up to."
I mean, you would know.
Mm.
I honestly can't imagine a time
when the name wasn't ruined.
It isn't ruined.
It took
some well-deserved hits,
and you are making it
your own.
You're reinventing it.
I'm impressed.
Well, don't give up hope.
There's still plenty of time
for you to make something
of your life, kid.
Okay, now you can go.
I guess this is, uh...
the real thing, huh?
This is it.
You're not gonna come
to my clap-out?
How do you know
about the clap-out?
Are you new here?
No one can keep a secret.
Oh, God. I mean, I know
it's become a tradition,
but it really feels...
It's a little too much.
I know.
Yeah.
I mean, I survived,
and so many people haven't
and won't.
And not because I did
anything special.
Just because I'm lucky
and I have the privilege
of great health care.
Ishould be applauding
the people who took care of me.
This place almost broke
with you sick,
so maybe let them
celebrate a win, huh?
Yeah.
It just feels...
I feel you, but none of them
are gonna stop.
They're all gonna be there.
I'll be there.
I just didn't want that
to be our, uh...
I-I didn't want it to be
our goodbye.
I don't want this
to be our big goodbye.
You go give 'em hell,
Avery.
Well, thanks
for showing me how.
Oh, I can't...
I can't do this.
You can.
And you will.
Yeah, you're almost there.
♪ Bite my tongue
♪ Count to ten
Okay, Mary Ann,
at the count of three.
♪ Close our eyes You ready?
Good.
♪ And just pretend
♪ That this could have
One, two...
♪ A happy end
Good.
♪ Close your eyes Okay, good, good, good.
♪ And just pretend
There she is.
♪ Ah-ah
♪ Let's pretend
♪ Take me home
Hello, Rosie.
Okay, Wilson,
begin fundal massage.
Once we cut the cord,
we'll deliver the placenta.
♪ Back where I belong
♪ Let me rest my weary bones
♪ Take me home
They teach you that
at the clinic?
No.
Grew up with it.
I was born into a family
of healers.
Same here.
Only change "healer"
to failed Broadway singer
and substitute math teacher.
Mr. Lawrence,
how are you feeling?
I've been better.
Well, given the day you had,
that's to be expected.
Can you tell Mary Ann
I'm okay?
Yeah,
as soon as she's settled.
Squeeze my fingers.
Your great-granddaughter
was jealous
of all the fun
that you were having.
She decided to make
an appearance.
She had the baby?
She did.
So, get some rest,
and we'll be back soon
and set you up
with the, uh,
time-honored COVID tradition
of meeting new family members
over video chat.
Okay?
You know, Amelia wants out
more than I do.
It's one of the only things
she talks about.
Well, talking about it
and doing it
are
two very different things.
Historically speaking
at least.
Didn't you and her
share a house?
Yeah, we did, but Meredith's
house... it just has this power.
It's like a magnetic pull.
Karev used to call it
the Sister House,
because no matter who else
lives there,
you're just kind of
in their orbit.
They do have a special bond. Mm.
Okay, you're making it
sound like a coven.
It's just a house.
Sure.
It's nice there, man.
It always smells like
toasted waffles in the kitchen,
and the kids are excited when
you walk through the door.
I never had that
growing up.
Well, me either. But
I think I've filled my quota.
I miss my house.
And my bed.
And my guitar picks.
And quiet.
God, I miss quiet.
Well,
quiet is overrated.
Hard disagree.
When Meredith comes back,
there will literally be
too many people in the house.
It'll probably break
fire codes, so we gotta go.
Totally. On your side. Me, too.
And there's a reason
that I got my own place
before I moved here.Hmm.
So that's it?
I'm trapped?
Pretty much.
Oh, I hate this.
I do, too.
But nobody would be happier
for her to go home than DeLuca.
Okay.
What is it?
What?
Pleural effusion?
The physical therapist
changed his mind about rehab?
No, no, no.
Nothing like that.
Then what is it?
M-Meredith, there is
something we need to tell you.
It's about Andrew.
He's okay.
Meredith... he's not.
He... is with his mother.
Your grandfather is fine.
He is awake and asking to see
his great-granddaughter.
One new life and one saved.Mm.
I told you
nothing could kill that man.
I want to thank
both of you.
We... haven't had
the best of experiences
in big hospitals.
Oh, it's our pleasure.
When could he meet
our baby girl?
It should be
any time now.
Oh. There you go.
Right.
Someone wants to say hello.
What'd I tell you?
Pretty cute, huh?
She's perfect.
She has your eyes.
And your... feet.
Thank you for that.
- Oh!
- Hi. Hi, Rosie.
I'll be right back.
Dr. DeLuca.
Carina.
Carina. Um...
before you go, I just...
I just wanted to say that,
um...
your brother
was incredibly kind to me.
He was good.
He was noble.
He was sweet.
And he was brave.
And I-I just...
I just want to say that.
I know that you're going
to scatter his ashes.
And I'm so incredibly grateful
to have known him.
♪ Oh, that the song
I'm singing ♪
Thank you.
And beautiful work today.
♪ Was an ocean wide
♪ And that the word
I'm bringing ♪
What's her name?
Rosie.
After Mom.
Rosie, I'm your scapa.
Your great-grandfather.
This is your mother
and your father.
We are your family.
And you are ours.
You come
from the Coast Salish people.
You are Suquamish.
You come from this land.
Rosie, one day,
you will be able
to tell the story
of when you were born.
Of how the world
was experiencing
a time of great difficulty
and devastation.
Grandparents
could not even hold
their newborn grandchildren
when they came Earth side.
But it was also a time
of great resilience and change.
And you will be able to tell
them about an abundance of joy
you brought to your syaye,
your family,
upon your arrival, just
at the time we needed it most.
♪ Be halfway around the world
♪ 'Fore truth can get
its trousers on ♪
Make sure he has a neuro check
every two hours and...
With all due respect,
Helm is having a tough time.
Mm.It might make her feel better
to help.
Uh... I don't know.
I don't think I know
anything anymore.
♪ Up to that high rock plateau
Do what you want.
♪ Make my home
inside the winds ♪
Ooh.
Okay, okay. Okay.
Folks, I know we're excited,
but you're gonna spoil
the surprise.
So let's keep it down
until Perez wheels her out.
Okay?
Okay. Yeah.
Okay, here she is.
Get ready, get ready!
Whoo!
- Yeah! Finally!
- Whoa!
- Whoo!
- Yeah! Yeah!
- Yeah!
Fair. Fair.
What happened?
Uh, Dr. Grey
is not in her room,
and all of her things
are gone.
Nice one, Grey.
Brilliant.
Evening, everybody.
Where the hell is she?
You know, you're
really milking this.
We're supposed to leave
the chairs at the entrance.
This is so much more fun.
Your chariot.
Oh.
You good?
Take me home.
Thank you.
So Meredith just left?
I guess
fanfare's not her thing.
I guess not.
Um...
you two have a minute?
Yeah.
Of course.
When, uh,
I asked you earlier
if you'd chosen a date
for the wedding,
I hope you didn't take that
as me inviting myself,
or trying to take anything
away from your father.
Um, I know the lines
of our relationship
have been blurry,
but I would never
presume anything.
We didn't really want
to do this right now.
Yeah, maybe over coffee.
Or dinner.
Richard, my father is going to
walk me down the aisle.
Of course.
Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
But he had
a really great idea.
We'd like you to officiate
the wedding.
Oh...
Really?
Obviously
only if you want to.
We couldn't think of a better
gift for you to give us.
♪ The stories
they wrote for us ♪
♪ Are a thousand years old
It would be
the honor of my life.
♪ Pick it up
♪ The pen
other lovers dropped ♪
♪ And color a page for us
♪ Sincere as stone
♪ Blur the edges
of the world you know ♪
Taryn?
Hey.
I was looking for you.
Are you okay?
♪ Whole
You okay?
♪ Pick it up
I used to pretend my, uh,
stuffed animals were sick
and bandage them up.
I never wanted to be a singer
or a super hero.
It was always this.
And now all I think about is
leaving and never coming back.
♪ Cut by another's words
I don't know
what happened to me.
It was more death
than you thought it would be.
♪ Fill your cup
♪ Don't give away too much
For so long,
all I wanted from Nico
was... more.
And then he asked me
to move in with him,
and I froze.
I might have even run.
♪ Now the vacancy
inside my heart is whole ♪
Great story about
how you have a boyfriend.
What I'm saying is,
this pandemic
isn't just affecting people
who get sick and die.
This isolation...
It's making all of us...
less ourselves.
Move in with me.
What?
We can be alone together.
You know what I mean.
Sorry.
Why?
And Wilson's gonna be okay
with this?
She is an OB resident.
She'll be home
less than we will.
♪ You were moving like a poet
♪ I was falling,
I was falling for you ♪
♪ We were falling into chorus
♪ You were wading in the water
Bailey! Bailey!
Bailey!
You have been wearing
that shirt since Saturday.
For the love of your family
who has to smell you,
please change it!
♪ We were falling into chorus
Come on. Okay.
Ready?
♪ I was taking in the motions
Okay, let's
get this over with.
Mommy!
♪ You were moving
like a poet ♪
♪ I was falling,
I was falling for you ♪
♪ We were falling
into chorus ♪
♪ Falling in,
we're falling into chorus ♪
♪ Falling in, we're falling in,
we're falling in ♪
♪ Falling in, we're falling in
I didn't think
you'd show up.
Yeah, well, I was
in the neighborhood.
I had to drive
the getaway car.
What's, uh... What's up?
You know, I heard you were
taking over the foundation,
and I-I called Catherine
to get the details.
I'm impressed.
Okay.
You needed me to be
in a parking lot
for you to say that?
You know, I lost, uh,
six roommates
when I was being treated
for COVID.
Three were
husbands and fathers,
one was, uh...
One's single,
one was very happily divorced,
and
um... one came and went
so fast, you know,
I didn't...
I didn't even get a name.
And, uh...
I was the only white guy.
I know I'm not
exactly out of the woods,
but I just felt like
I owed it to them
to be better, you know?
Because...
chaos and i-injustice
and pain and...
The world is only that way
because we let it be.
Or because people who look
like me made it that way.
And... so what I'm saying,
I, uh...
Let me become worthy
of being spared.
I want to be an ally.
I want to spend whatever time
I've got left
making this lousy,
stinking place better.
You know, you can use me
however you want.
I can operate, uh,
administrate...
Hell, I'll even help you
understand
how ignorant white people
think.
I'll do anything.
I don't need money.
I don't need a big title.
You don't even have
to stop hating me.
Uh...
Just... I just...
Just let me help.
Monday. 6:00 a.m.
Boston.
I'll e-mail you
an address.
And, yeah, technically,
I do have space on my jet,
but I really don't want
to be tempted
to fire you
before we land, so...
I'll figure something out.
Good night, Avery.
Thank you.
Well, that happened.
Yeah. Again.
Mm.
What're you thinking
right now?
Remember after a rough day
in Iraq,
we would stare at the sky
and we would talk about
how much we missed hamburgers?
Mm-hmm. Vividly.
That's what I want.
I mean,
not the talking about it.
But the actual eating.
Maybe two.
Mm-hmm.
Mmm. And French fries and... Mm-hmm.
And onion rings
and... and maybe...
Maybe a vanilla milkshake.Yeah. Okay.
Listen,
I'm buying, okay? Mm.
Okay.
But, uh...
♪ I've been waiting
for the tides to change ♪
♪ For the waves to send you
my way ♪
Your mom was Val.
And we loved Val.
And you are Luna.
And you have
a family here.
Every time I step
into an OR,
I think about your mom.
And you.
♪ 'Cause I'll be there when
you can finally make it home ♪
♪ And I don't mind
'cause we both know ♪
Ah, God,
Link was supposed to call
when you were
on your way home.
We had signs and hats,
and I swear we were not living
like this most of the time.
Amelia, come sit down.
It's just the way
I like it.
You did a great job.
I can never
thank you enough.
♪ You know, when you're
by my side, darling ♪
Okay, I think
she's on her way home!
Uh, hurry and get the signs
and the donuts and...
Is there really donuts?
In the kitchen.
Uh... don't move!
It's not done yet,
but...
we made this for you.
I love it!
It is so beautiful.
Okay, everybody,
come sit up here.
Let's eat donuts.
You all can tell me
every single thing
that happened
while I was gone.
♪ You said hold the line
Whoo!
♪ I won't let go
♪ 'Cause I'll be there when
you can finally make it home ♪
Traditions have
never really been my thing.
But at their best, they help us
remember who we are,
where we're from,
and those who came before us.
They give us something to pass
on to future generations.
♪ Because
when I'm in a room with you ♪
♪ That missing piece is found
♪ Ooh, ah-ooh
♪ You know, when you're
by my side, darling ♪
♪ Nothing can bring us down
♪ Ooh, ah-ooh
♪ It's like when you're
far away from me ♪
♪ I get lost in the crowd
♪ Ooh, ah-ooh
♪ Because
when I'm in a room with you ♪
'Cause if you don't know
where you're from,
it's kind of hard to know
where you're going.
Unless, of course,
where you're going...
is home.