[Max] Previously on New Amsterdam...
[Helen] Have you met the group?
That's Willow.
-And Millie.
-Don't be scared. We don't bite.
You're calling yourself this and you're
going to keep suffering until you stop.
If I can stop.
It's been a family tradition
since before I was born.
Sunday means church, family
and a meal with two meats!
It's so good. I can't live without it,
-like I can't live without you.
-Aw. [chuckles]
-[Helen] How's Luna?
-Frolicking in suburban splendor
with Georgia's parents.
I miss her. It's just not safe enough
to bring her home.
Nothing's safe anymore, though, is it?
[distant cheering]
[Floyd] Every tile in her house
needed re-grouting.
Every pipe needed to be winterized.
That was between the grocery store runs
and delivering chicken dinners
to the usher board.
I knew your mama
would have you rippin' and runnin'.
You know she's still mad
we moved to San Francisco.
Every time I tried to talk about it,
she just snuck off to bed. [chuckles]
But just getting to see her and my sisters
for two weeks made it all worthwhile.
Well, when you get off that plane,
you'll putting those eyes on me.
-Well, hopefully more than eyes.
-What did you have in mind?
-[chuckles]
-[phone beeps]
Oh, surprise. That's her.
-[chuckles]
-Hang on.
Oh.
Three goodbyes at the door wasn't enough?
Mama?
Whoa... whoa, Mama, hang on.
I can't... I can't understand you.
Mama.
No, no, no.
Do not move. I'm coming.
Hey, we need to turn around.
[tires squeal]
Am I supposed to feel
like I'm being choked?
-I want this off now.
-You need to stay immobilized.
-I told you not to call an ambulance.
-Mama.
[scoffs] You know how expensive
those things are?
-It's fine. I'll handle it.
-Oh, sure, Mr. Moneybags,
while you're dragging me
all through COVID-land here.
If I could've given you
a CT scan at home, I would have.
-I don't need a scan.
-You don't need a scan?
I found you laid out on the ground,
bleeding from your head.
We're going to run every test we can
to make sure you don't have trauma.
-Do I sound like I have trauma?
-Floyd! I just heard.
-How you feeling, Ms. Reynolds?
-Lousy. You?
-It's crazy. I was going to the airport...
-I got you.
We're going to run tests.
I'm going to run point.
-You don't have to do...
-No. You were here for Vijay.
-Now we're here for you.
-[elevator dings]
-It's just down there.
-[Helen] Oh! Max!
I hear Floyd's mother's in the ED.
Oh, yeah, she took a fall,
but we're getting some tests.
I think she's going to be okay.
Speaking of falling...
[Luna babbling]
Oh, Luna!
[giggling]
She'll be walking in no time.
-I'd say she's walking now.
-No, no. That's... that's a stumble.
Well, it's less than a saunter.
I'll give you that.
Yeah, but it couldn't be
because there's no way
that my baby girl would take
her first steps without me.
All video evidence to the contrary.
When you bringing her home?
Not till it's safe. If Luna doesn't
need to be here, she shouldn't be.
Her grandparents are great. They're
crazy careful. They got a big yard.
-They take lots of videos.
-They do.
-Of Luna not walking.
-She's not.
-Max?
-Yeah?
-Hey. Can I talk to you for a sec?
-Yeah, perfect timing.
-What does this look like to you?
-Um... Oh, my gosh!
-Luna! She's walking!
-No. No. Wrong answer.
Oh. Sorry, yeah. Hard to tell what's
happening on that tiny little screen.
-It is!
-Which is what I want to talk about.
I was trying to get
some screen time in with Ella and Vijay,
who I think is recuperating well,
but I wouldn't know,
because the hospital's system sucks.
-Yeah, agreed.
-It glitches all the time.
-It does.
-The telemedicine thing is getting brutal.
I need to be with my patients in person.
-I need to see them.
-It's not safe, Iggy.
Unless we're talking life or death,
the longer people stay away
from the hospital, the better.
-They'll wear masks.
-How are you going to read facial cues?
-All right. We'll sit outside.
-Not until they're vaccinated like us.
Iggy, it's too soon. I'm sorry.
[indistinct chattering]
Can someone help?
-I'll take her, but you just can't...
-It's okay.
-I got it.
-It's her wrist.
Can you move it?
Ah, it hurts so bad.
Okay, we're going to do a COVID test.
Casey's going to get your patient history.
We'll order a scan...
I'm thinking Colles fracture
of the distal radius.
And you are?
-Her DriveTime driver.
-I can take it from here, but thank you.
-Five stars.
-[door thuds]
38-year-old woman.
Stage-II esophageal cancer.
Millie?
[sighs] I'm so sorry, Dr. Sharpe.
Large-volume hematemesis.
Now tachy, but otherwise
hemodynamically stable.
-Can we get her in the back?
-Yeah.
[Helen] We've been worried about you.
My office reached out.
I know. I know.
-You've missed a number of treatments.
-[sighs]
We were doing
the whole stay-at-home order thing
and I was feeling so much better.
I thought it was crazy to take the risk.
I mean,
after three years of fighting cancer,
to die of some stupid virus? [chuckles]
We'll need to do some new tests.
I'm going to be all right, aren't I?
[indistinct announcement of PA system]
[Iggy] June, remember our agreement?
I love a carousel as much as the next guy,
probably even more, truth be told,
but, uh,
let's try to keep the focus on you.
Thank you.
How's your day?
You do any journaling this week?
Okay, June, I, uh...
I get that this is not ideal,
the video thing, but I would love it
if both of us could give it our best shot.
What do you think?
So tell me about your journaling.
What've you got?
-I guess it was...
-[static interference]
No. Oh, no. Ah!
June, hang... hang on one second.
What is... Hold on.
Can you hear me?
June, can you hear me?
Oh, my God.
This sucks. [frustrated chuckle]
Welcome to my world.
[chuckles] Yeah.
Yeah.
How often do you get to see anybody that's
not trapped inside of this little box?
Folks not included, obviously.
Never, like never.
And most of your friends,
they're all congregating outside again?
They all are.
I'm just the immunocompromised freak
still stuck at home.
Whoa, whoa. You are not a freak.
You have an illness that you are managing.
Maybe we can talk to your parents
and see if we can set up
some safe visitations or...
I don't know, something.
Good luck.
They won't even let me out on our stoop.
[sighs] Right.
When COVID hit and everybody was, like,
stuck in their house, hating it,
that must've been really weird for you
because suddenly, everybody kind of knew
what it was like to be you.
I mean...
I guess I felt normal for a couple months.
I could hang out with my friends online
without missing out on anything,
but now, everything's back to normal...
for them.
June?
Will you show me your hands?
You have to show them to me, June.
Now, please.
[sighs]
[elevator dings]
-Max.
-Hey. Still waiting on those labs.
-How's she doing?
-Well, she's more concerned
-about getting COVID than the fall.
-She should be.
I'm sure that'll make her feel better.
I don't suppose
there's a safer place for her.
How do you feel about New Zealand?
-Now I don't even want to be here.
-Maybe you shouldn't be.
-Wait outside. I'll give you an update.
-Think I'm going to do the six-feet thing.
-Max.
-Dora!
The conquering traitor returns.
It was a promotion.
Yeah. I still can't believe
those evil pencil pushers
lured you away with a fancy title
and more money.
Shocking, I know.
Yet here you are
finding your way back to me.
It wasn't hard.
There's hardly anyone here.
Yeah, which most would call good news.
Speaking of which, can I show you this
adorable video of my daughter not walking?
No and it's not good news
if you're trying to dig yourself out
of a massive financial hole
left by this pandemic.
The public is wary
of coming back here, Max.
Without the money from elective surgeries,
you can't pay for the emergent ones.
So we need a powerful and effective PSA
to save this place.
A what now?
HCC's funding a campaign to encourage
patients to return to New Amsterdam.
But I don't want patients returning
to New Amsterdam,
not if they don't have to, not until
there's enough vaccine for everyone.
We can't wait for that.
We need revenue now.
You need to step
in front of a camera, smile
and tell the good people of New York
to get their butts back here.
Or you'll go down in history
as the medical director
who closed
America's first public hospital.
[easy listening music]
Can I be straight with you?
Here at New Amsterdam, we all honestly
feel that, despite our great challenge...
[scoffs]
Max?
Sorry, I'm not a writer or anything.
It feels like calling
our recent experience a challenge
feels like calling the Holocaust a bummer.
You know what I mean? Maybe this thing
is just a little beyond words.
Oh, no. We have the words.
Your job is to say them.
Oh, okay. Great.
And action.
Can I be straight with you?
I don't know. Can I?
Am I allowed to be? Because if I was
honestly being straight with you,
-then I would probably tell you never...
-Max!
Okay, I'll just do it again.
[murmuring]
Okay. [clears throat]
Of course, no one likes
coming to the hospital,
although that's not even true.
What about having a baby?
That's a great moment!
That's exciting. Right?
Can I be straight with you?
Sorry. My brain just kind of... [whistles]
We should probably cut.
Is that okay if I say that?
Can I be straight with you? Uh, sorry.
I don't know why I did the point thing.
Can I... no, cut. Let's cut that.
[clears throat] Sorry, cut.
Sorry for shouting. That was bad.
I got it this time.
Nope, I lied. What's the line?
[exhales] Uh, what's the next one? Uh...
As an administration, we've implemented
dozens of new safety measures.
So, as a patient, nothing should deter you
from walking through those doors.
Except, I don't know, death maybe.
Which, of course, no safety measure
can completely rule out
and is a pretty strong deterrent,
wouldn't you say, Brad?
Can I be straight with you?
Here at New Amsterdam, we honestly feel...
[sighs]
I can... [sighs]
I can honestly tell you...
What's wrong now, Max?
When people
are genuinely being honest with you,
they don't keep telling you
how honest they are.
They don't say things like,
"Can I be straight with you?"
It implies that they haven't been
straight with anything else,
which, to tell you the truth,
makes me sound like a liar.
How could you be a liar
when you haven't said anything?
Including the tagline,
"Come back to New Amsterdam."
Because that would be
the biggest lie of all.
What happened to the guy who used to say,
"Our doors are always open"?
What happened to bringing
in patients off the streets?
What happened was a global pandemic
with no fully-vetted vaccine
and even when we get enough doses,
30% of Americans won't take it,
because
of all the insane conspiracy theories.
So can I be straight with you, Dora?
This hospital is not safe.
Not completely.
And if you want a tagline, how's this?
Uh...
"Come back to New Amsterdam,
'cause if you're not dead yet,
we can finish the job."
I wanted to bring you both into this,
because if June's anxiety
-has escalated into self-harm...
-Ripping off her fingernails?
How long has this been going on?
I don't know. I just saw it this morning.
But how could we have missed this?
Because she hides it.
But it's not your fault.
You should know I have been pushing to get
my patients back in here with me.
If I we'd been working with in person,
I would've caught it sooner...
-She can't come back to the hospital.
-Are you even allowed?
Um... not at the moment,
but I could convince our medical director
in this particular case.
No. It's too dangerous.
She would be wearing an N95 mask
just like our frontline workers.
Have any of your frontline workers
died from the virus?
Yes. But with
all of our safety protocols in place,
New Amsterdam is safer
than going to the market.
We don't let her go there either.
We want her here with us. Our home
is the only place where she's 100% safe.
But she's not safe.
COVID has caused
an epidemic of loneliness in this country.
The studies coming out show that
living like June with no peer contact,
it's like smoking 15 cigarettes a day.
Your daughter is on the brink
of serious clinical depression.
But she's not dead.
And that's what lets us sleep at night.
[sighs]
Thank you for your concern.
As you can see from the charts,
there's no evidence of fracture, bleed,
-or subdural hematoma.
-So zero damage from the fall.
-Everything looks normal.
-Uh, not quite.
Right, okay, thank you.
Um, sorry, I told Floyd
I'd help out on this one.
There does seem to be a type
of central hippocampal atrophy.
-So?
-Max, we found no indication of trauma.
-Right, because his mother has diabetes.
-Diabetes?
I've been living with her
for the past two weeks...
Did she seem overly tired?
Was she going to bed early?
Did she forget things? Repeat stuff?
Well, sometimes, yeah, but...
Neuropathy from diabetes.
I think it's why she fell, Floyd.
And it's good news,
because now we know how to treat her.
[Helen] It's going to get a little loud.
Louder than a house
full of forced homeschool kids?
-Probably not.
-[chuckles] Quarantine wasn't all bad.
The whole family stuck together.
Found our rhythm.
Movie nights. Cooking together. Puzzles.
[clack of keyboard]
So many puzzles.
You remember Brandon?
-The quiet one?
-Yeah, the moody one. [chuckles]
Without all the chemo, my hair grew back
and he became a different person.
Because of your hair?
Because he stopped seeing me as a ghost.
I became Mom again.
[machine pumping, clanking]
And without chemo brain,
I could actually listen.
I could really hear him, you know?
I could hear my son
for the first time in years.
Dr. Sharpe?
It's back, isn't it?
-The cancer's metastasized.
[exhale softly]
[voice breaking]
Is there anything we can do?
I'm so sorry, Millie.
[sobs softly]
Well, you do, in fact, have
a broken bone in your wrist.
Crack diagnosis from your DriveTime gal.
It's crazy. It was days ago.
I was riding so slow.
The bike started to tip.
I stuck my hand out to brace myself
against the wall.
That's what did it.
There was hardly any force.
How could I have broken anything?
Hey. How are you feeling?
You're back.
-Did you...
-I got tested outside.
-[door thuds]
-Her wallet. Found it in the car.
Pedestrian on the wrong end of a taxi.
Severe head and neck trauma.
Intubated in field.
Okay, let's get him to Trauma One.
-Stat, page respiratory and get me ortho.
-You've really gone above and beyond.
-Can I give you something?
-No, please.
[gags]
-Riley?
-[monitor beeping]
-Can you breathe?
-[gasping for breath]
This woman needs help!
[grunts]
Nurse! Anyone!
[monitor beeping]
[gasping for breath]
[gasps, coughs]
[coughing]
What the hell are you doing?
Someone call security!
Adult-onset diabetes is nothing to fear.
You should be thrilled
we caught it when we did.
This is me thrilled.
[chuckles]
Um, so seeing as your pancreas can no
longer produce enough insulin on its own,
we're going to need to start you
on basal-bolus therapy.
And, uh, Dr. Goodwin is going
to take you through the routine
so you can do it by yourself, Mama.
I've been doing for myself my whole life.
Diabetes won't slow me down.
Good. So let's say you're in your kitchen
and, uh, you've just finished this meal.
You need to figure out
how much insulin to take.
So you're going to divide your carb intake
by your personal IC ratio.
You didn't tell me there'd be math.
Well, we'll take it slow, I promise.
So your ratio is 1:20.
That is one unit of insulin
to 20 grams of carbs.
So you're going to take the total number
of grams in that meal and divide it by 20.
[murmuring] Okay, dividing that...
I would...
stop hovering.
If it's on me, let it be on me, you hear?
Max is here to help, Mama.
3.25 units.
[Max] That's very good. That's excellent.
Great. Okay, so, step two.
Administering the insulin.
So what you're going to do after
you've washed your hands
is simply remove this,
insert the needle into
the rubber stopper here,
turn the bottle upside down
and why don't we try just that much.
Come on.
Come on, now.
Oh.
That's okay. Maybe...
I've got it.
[sighs]
Oh. [sighs]
I can do this.
Mm-hmm.
[Max] It's okay. Let's just try again.
My mother's raised three kids,
owns her own home,
prays harder than anyone I know
for everyone else's troubles,
and now she needs full-time care.
She can't live by herself.
[Evie] Wish I was there with you.
Well, maybe
if I click my heels three times.
[Evie] Or maybe if you just turn around.
[chuckles]
-Why'd you...
-'Cause we're family too, baby.
-Come here.
-[siren blares in background]
Two centimeters to the left
and you would've killed her.
One centimeter, actually.
Oh, they teach you that
in DriveTime school?
I saved your patient.
You knew nothing about my patient.
You swooped in here with no knowledge
of preexisting conditions,
or current treatment plan,
and you stabbed her with a syringe.
You're not curious
why her wrist broke with no fall?
You need to check her bone density.
Maybe test for Wilson's disease.
Okay, WebMD,
I think it's time for you to leave.
If it's Wilson's and you don't push
magnesium, her heart could stop.
Or if it's a calcium deficiency,
maybe you could pick us up a quart of milk
-on your next run.
-[frustrated sigh]
Get her out of here
before I file assault charges.
[sighs]
[exhales] Okay.
[phone buzzing]
Dr. Frome.
What? Gabriella?
No. No, June is not here with me.
Then where is she?
Okay, did...
Okay, did she take her phone with her?
Then you need to check all of her texts
and call all of her friends.
Yes.
I'll be in touch.
[sighs]
You're still here?
Yeah, don't worry.
I'm not making you do the PSA.
Sorry, I... [mutters]
Yeah, I appreciate that.
Mm, I forgot that no
one can make you do anything.
Well, except for you. You could always
get me to do what was right,
even if I couldn't see it at the time.
-You know, if you ever want to come back...
-No.
-Okay, maybe you want to think about it...
Oh.
Okay.
So if you're not doing the PSA
and you're not coming back,
then why are you still here?
Oh.
I said you weren't doing the PSA.
I never said I wasn't. Oh.
But, uh, how are you going to do it
without me?
Uh, you've been recast.
Tell me it isn't true.
-If you're referring to the PSA...
-No, it's not a PSA.
Saying, "Don't text and drive,"
that would be a PSA.
This is propaganda!
You are putting your name,
this hospital's name, on a dangerous lie.
Millie came in today.
She might have a week to live.
While you were out
seizing the moral high ground,
I got to tell her that her kids
would soon be without a mum.
Her chemo was working,
but she missed six vital treatments
because she was worried about coming here.
So, yes,
of course I'm going to do the PSA.
Oh. Millie.
If we'd have got word out a month ago,
it might have saved her life.
Yeah, maybe, but it won't just affect
people like Millie.
Elderly people deciding to get a physical,
or, uh, diabetics wondering
if now's the right time to get LASIK.
Things that can wait should wait.
No hospital's 100% safe,
but we've made ours a lot safer.
-Consider the alternative...
-Jumping off the third floor is safer
than the roof, but it's not going
to make a difference in the outcome.
I won't even bring my own daughter here.
How can I ask anyone else to come here?
If something happened...
to her...
or anyone
because I put my thumb on a scale...
After what I've seen today,
I am more than happy to tip the scale.
[pager beeping]
It's Millie.
[machine beeping steadily]
Millie's cancer metastasized to her brain.
It caused a massive bleed.
But she was feeling so much better.
[Max] I'm so sorry, but...
it doesn't look like
she's going to regain consciousness.
[Helen] Millie's being kept alive
by the life-support machine.
Her brain has stopped functioning.
There's nothing more that we can do.
[exhales shakily]
We just got her back.
Hey, I'm just curious.
Why is this your virtual background?
Before COVID,
my parents used to let me come here.
You know, see some friends.
They wouldn't let me ride, though.
Too many germs.
Well, better than nothing, I guess, right?
-You going to tell my folks I'm here?
-Yeah, bad news.
I, uh... I narc'd on you already.
The second I saw you.
But you got some time.
You want to tell me why you're down here?
You know, sometimes when people
hurt themselves, it's a distraction.
The physical pain, just for a second,
it stops the emotional pain.
Maybe you came down here
to make it really stop.
You need to put your mask on now.
Why?
We can talk about that
after you put your mask on.
Please.
If I knew when this virus would be over,
I could maybe do it.
Just... just deal with it
until it was done.
And what if the virus
never goes away for kids?
There's no vaccine for us.
I'm just stuck in my room forever.
It's basically like being dead anyway.
I can't keep being alone.
[exhales]
So, after much discussion,
we decided to take Mama
back to San Francisco.
-Oh, hell, no.
-Wa... wait.
-Mm-mm, absolutely not.
...Can I lay it out first...
What makes you think taking her away
from everything and everyone she knows
is going to be good for her?
Court, we got the space
and with both of our incomes...
-So it's about your money?
-No.
Is Mama good with this?
I thought we should be
on the same page first.
Oh, your page.
Mama's golden child.
-Whatever her baby Floyd says is law.
-Oh, come on, Court.
I'm just trying to step up. You and Brandi
have your own families to deal with.
Our lives are a little more flexible,
so we can do more now.
Not more than us. Where were you
when we were checking in on her every day,
bringing her food,
making sure she was safe?
We did all that with no problems
while you were chillin',
-bunned up in San Francisco.
-He wanted to be here.
Every second of every day, he was worried
sick about Mama and you and your family.
-Pump the brakes. This is family business.
-Whoa. Don't talk to her like that.
Stop this!
I am not dead!
So stop talking about me like I am.
[background chattering]
I know she was out of line,
but pulling off a successful needle
decompression is pretty cool.
In fact, she kind of reminds me of...
Are you sure
you want to finish that sentence?
It's Riley. She's having runs of V-tach.
-You push esmolol?
-Yes, no change.
-Procainamide?
-Didn't work either.
[machine beeping rapidly]
Yeah, it's V-tach, all right.
Push amiodarone.
[machine beeping]
-BP's dropping. It's not working.
-[machine beeping]
Magnesium. Push magnesium.
You sure?
One gram now.
[machine beeping frantically]
[beeping slows down]
[sighs]
Nice save, boss.
[machine beeping steadily]
[man] Settle.
Okay, Helen, and action.
I'm Dr. Helen
and this office adjoins one of our new
Airborne Infection Isolation Rooms.
It's built with negative airflow pressure.
The HVAC filters are cleared daily,
and it's fitted with outdoor air intake
COVID-19-safe exhaust handling.
Here at New Amsterdam, we're confident...
[chuckles awkwardly]
Here at New Amsterdam,
we're confident that you'll be...
-Actually, I'm sorry.
-You're doing great.
No, I'm not.
Helen, everything you're saying is true.
-The HVAC, the exhaust.
-Yes, the facts are accurate,
but "Here at New Amsterdam,
we're confident..."
I'm not confident...
of anything right now. Are you?
'Cause to tell you the truth,
I'm terrified...
most of the time,
because we've been living
in a dystopian nightmare.
We are losing good people with children
and with families
and I'm standing here
talking about exhaust handling?
People need reassurance.
Do they?
'Cause the people I know want to stop
feeling scared
and they want to stay alive.
And I can't reassure them of that.
No one can, because the world is not safe!
You can't expect me to stand here and say
there's nothing to be afraid of,
when everyone should be afraid!
[breathes heavily]
So what do we do?
We can tell... [exhales]
We can tell people the truth...
that we may never get rid of this virus,
so we have to find a way to live with it.
'Cause even if we vaccinate
every single American,
there's another virus around the corner
and another one after that
and we can't stop living.
We can't barricade ourselves in,
because that is when you give up things
that you can never get back. [sighs]
[exhales deeply]
So, Brandi and Courtney will take turns
helping you during the day
and we'll get
someone to stay with you at night.
That don't sound too bad, does it?
So...
I'll be living with a stranger?
A trained healthcare professional.
Would you do that to your mama?
I hope I never have to make that decision.
Because it sucks.
All of it.
-I like her.
-[chuckles]
Oh, Mama.
[sighs heavily]
I wish there was another way,
but there isn't.
I'll visit as often as I can.
You know that.
New York will always be my home.
Mm.
Hm?
Come here.
It's okay.
-[background chatter]
-[elevator dings]
[elevator doors clunk]
[elevator dings]
[chattering]
Hi.
Thank you...
for saying what we've all been feeling.
What? What?
[applause continues]
What did I...
I'm on the news?
Meltdown is a strong word,
don't you think?
-Max?
-I wouldn't worry about it.
You only have, like, 3.2 million views.
-...because the world is not safe.
So you can't expect me
to stand here and say,
"I'm confident
there's nothing to be afraid of,"
when everyone should be afraid!
-Oh, my God.
-Yeah.
Why would you release that?
-Who, me?
-Just stop.
Are you... I would never! Yeah, okay.
Yes, I would, but I didn't.
And you were brilliant!
Okay. Big swing, Max.
Of course you think I did it.
You think I did everything, but I didn't.
Stop it.
...virus after that and another one
after that and we can't stop living.
We can't barricade ourselves in,
because that is when you give up things
that you can never get back.
Actually, do you... Do you know what?
-I'm relieved that my words are out there.
-I'm glad to hear you say that.
3.2 million views and a huge spike
in our scheduling.
It worked.
-Sorry, what worked?
-You were both right.
People don't need reassurance.
They need honesty.
You didn't release it?
No.
But I think I know who did.
I learned from the best.
[sighs]
[birds chirping]
[Iggy] Hi. Hi, guys. Thank you.
Thank you so much for coming. I know
that's a really big deal, so thank you.
You're sure this is safe?
As safe as it can be, yeah.
You ready?
-Are they all your patients?
-Um, no, no.
They're just a group
of really cool young women just like June.
Each one is immunocompromised
in one way or another,
each still living at home on lockdown
without much family or friends,
and each one knowing
exactly what you're going through.
You brought them all here for me?
I also brought you here for them,
so don't make me look bad.
[chuckles]
All right? Get in there.
[] Thank you, Dr. Frome.
I mean, we're all just parents
trying to figure this out, right?
Which is why there's a group of them
right over here
that I'm sure would love it
if you went over there and said hey.
I'm sure they'd love for you to join them,
if you're up to it.
Sure. Okay.
Good.
[indistinct chattering]
-[woman 1] Oh, yeah.
-[woman 2] You guys are lucky.
I don't even have any siblings.
[woman 1] Yeah, well no. Trust me,
I wish I didn't either sometimes.
[woman 3] Same, same.
[Lauren] Wait!
Wait!
Would you open up?
What?
One gram of magnesium.
Riley's alive thanks to you.
[window whirs]
I'm trying to say I'm sorry!
Then you should know,
you're not very good at it.
Yeah. I know.
So where'd you practice medicine?
[sighs]
Pakistan. Pediatric attending.
Are you living in here?
[window whirs]
-I can get you a spot in a shelter.
Good night, Dr. Bloom.
-What about a hotel room?
-No hotels.
No shelter. No, thank you.
Okay, there's got to be something
that I can help you with.
You saved my patient's life.
Well, there's got to be
something you need.
[door beeps]
[shushing]
[sighs]
So, here are our showers.
They're either freezing or scalding hot,
but if you toggle the handle to the left,
then you're going
to land somewhere in the middle.
Thank you.
Five stars.
[elevator dings]
Floyd! You guys taking off?
Yeah, we're hitting the road.
Hey, uh,
thanks for all your help with Mama.
Oh, we'll take good care of her.
Anything you need, just let us know.
-I love you, brother.
-Love you too, pal.
You know, your family here...
will miss you.
Ready to go home?
I think you already are.
Saw your meltdown on YouTube.
Pretty boss.
Willow, you came back.
You heard about Millie?
Home again, home again
I thought maybe...
One day, I know, I feel born again...
...it was time to do some more tests.
Born again, born again
One day, I know I'll feel strong again
I lift my head
Many times, I've been told
All this talk will make you old
So I'll close my eyes
Look behind
[whispering] "Hi. My name is Iggy...
and I have an eating disorder."
I close my eyes, look behind
Moving on
Lost again, lost again
[sighs] Evie.
I shouldn't have made you leave New York.
You did not make me leave.
I wanted to.
If only wanting was enough.
Many times, I've been told
Speak your mind, just be bold
So I'll close my eyes
Look behind
Moving on
So I'll close my eyes
And the tears will clear
Then I'll feel no fear
[Max] Yeah, well, I've been thinking.
Uh...
Maybe, uh, instead of me coming up
to Connecticut this weekend,
Luna should come home...
for good.
Yeah, I know,
but I missed her first birthday.
And then I missed her first steps.
[sniffles]
I just don't want to miss anything else.
It's safe enough.
[exhales]