Okay, home stretch, Luna.
We just need to find
Dada's other shoe.
Did you steal Dada's shoe?
No? Well, that's nice of you.
Where is it?
Where's my shoe?
Shoe, shoe, shoe. Shoe!
Luna, shoe!
And...
Oh, yogurt.
Uh, hey, hey, hey, hey.
Hey! Thank you guys so much.
- I know it's last minute.
- Oh, no worries.
My Tuesday nanny
just canceled on me.
- I didn't have anyone.
- What is that smell?
Oh, uh, fun fact,
when Luna's waffle gets stuck
in the toaster too long
it becomes a charcoal
briquette.
I'll get that for you.
I think I smell
something else.
Yeah, that's her,
uh, lo mein.
- She really likes it spicy.
- Takeout for breakfast.
Uh, well,
it's usually milk and eggs
but we are out of milk.
Also eggs.
So I tried to do
the waffle thing
but that turned
into a briquette.
So, I, uh, yeah.
It was either lo mein or soup.
Could you guys do a quick favor
and go to the grocery store?
We just need milk and eggs
and, uh, waffles.
Come on, sweetheart.
Grandma's gonna
get you changed.
Hey.
You got a double kiss!
- Oh, and wipes?
- Wipes, yes. We need wipes.
Thank you so much.
Best grandparents ever.
The stuff of legends.
Yes!
Luna, I love you.
Okay, thank you, guys.
Seriously. Bye.
Wow.
*NEW AMSTERDAM (2018)*
Season 03  Episode 12
Episode Title: "Things Fall Apart"
Aired on: May 18, 2021
♪ Nobody gonna
bring me down ♪
♪ Been running
since I hit the ground ♪
♪ Try to catch me if you can
♪ Most people
don't understand ♪
- We need to talk about this.
- ♪ I'm a rebel
- Harper, turn it down!
- ♪ I'm on another level
I put that in the closet.
And I took it back out.
We need to talk about him,
Ig.
Yeah, we will.
What? You've been
saying that for a week.
- Have you thought about a 21/20?
- No.
I mean, yes, I've thought
about a 21/20, obviously.
But that's a psychiatric hold,
it's not...
It would keep Chance
off the street
- and away from our kids.
- For 72 hours.
And then he'd be back on
the streets, feeling betrayed.
Okay, fine.
Then go for something
more permanent.
No, Martin,
I am not discussing
a restraining order with you.
Hey.
Hi, babe. Hi.
Everything's fine, okay?
We're just discussing some
boring old grown up stuff.
Why don't you go back up
and log in to school, okay?
I'll meet you there.
It's okay. Go for it.
And music off, sweetie.
That is exactly why I didn't
want to discuss this, okay?
A restraining order
is a formal connection
between Chance and I.
It's what he wants.
All that matters
is they reduce risk.
- Sometimes.
- Most times.
And they got
a way better track record
than wishful thinking.
If we provoke Chance,
he could hurt himself.
This is not about Chance.
This is about us.
Our safety, our kids.
Look, we...
No, you know what, Iggy?
You have to do something.
Today.
- What? I don't want that.
- It's just oat milk.
What you mean,
"just oat milk"?
You ever seen
an udder on an oat?
- That's not natural.
- Natural?
A few minutes ago
you were just raving
about some beer
made out of oysters?
Oyster stout is normal beer
made from the shells
of oysters. It's...
And I've yet
to meet a mollusk
made out of grain,
hops, or yeast.
- All right, look, that's it.
- I'm... I'm gonna take you out
to have that beer tonight.
Oh, no. I... I'm...
I'm sorry. Not like that.
I wasn't trying to make a move.
Uh-huh.
I can't be home tonight.
You know, I'm trying to think
of a reason to stay out.
- Why's that?
- You know, my...
My roommate is having
a gentleman over for a "visit."
You have a roommate?
Yeah, my mom.
My roommate is my mother.
You live with your mom?
And your mom is the one
hanging the sock on the door.
So now we're clowning?
Is that it?
Yeah, you definitely
were not making a move.
See, now, that...
That's the way...
Now you owe me a drink.
Fine, I know
the perfect place.
- I will text you the address.
- Okay.
Helen. Hey, uh,
hey.
- What do you need?
- Uh, nothing.
I just saw you
walking down the hallway
and it looked like more fun
than my hallway so...
Okay.
You okay? Um, work, life?
- It's good. All good.
- All good.
What's with the rosary?
It's not a rosary.
Yeah? Uh, well, you know,
if it looks like a rosary
and smells like a rosary...
It's personal.
I don't think
that's how it goes.
You're actually
considering it?
- Leaving New Amsterdam?
- Hey, it's a good gig.
More money, less drama.
Plus, I could walk to work.
Plus, it is Mt. Zion.
Oh, I'm Casey,
and I want to work at a big,
posh, private hospital
where nothing exciting
ever happens.
- Whatever.
- Your accent's wack.
Incoming!
Bertha James, 64 years old.
Accidental impalement
on pruning shears.
BP 138 over 74
and slightly tachy at 114.
Already vaccinated for COVID.
Okay, let's get her
to Bay 24.
Just get these things
out of me!
We will, but first
you need a CAT scan and work-up
so we can figure out the safest
way to remove them, okay?
How bad is the pain?
- Bad!
- Okay, uh, Turan,
can I get, um... what the...
Is everybody okay?
You okay? Everybody okay?
We need help over here!
What the hell is going on
in here?
Let's pull them out.
Let's get them out of here.
Okay, get maintenance
down here now.
Are you kidding me!?
- Feel the excitement.
- Excitement?
Okay, let's get them
out of here.
So great to see you all
in the flesh again.
Mask-less, here we are.
You know, virtual visits
were great.
What a great tool
we got to use but, man,
have I missed in-person
inpatient visiting days.
These are the best.
I mean, families coming
together, reconnecting.
This is why we do
what we do, right?
Are gifts okay?
Yeah.
'Cause I, uh,
brought my son a journal.
Great, yeah, journal.
Good call.
Anything that encourages
expression, I'm all for it.
Yeah, but the orderly
confiscated it.
Ahh, yeah...
spiral-bound, I'm guessing?
Yeah, okay, good segue.
Couple ground rules
we should talk about.
No sharp objects
are allowed inside.
Anything spiral-bound,
jewelry, earrings.
Um, anything that
a child inclined to self-harm
would or could self-harm with.
Um, also,
no outside medication
is allowed in, okay?
So any pills
that you came with,
you can leave them with me.
You get them when you leave.
Uh...
but, guys, that's not... that's...
Hey, that's not what
today is about, all right?
Today is about progress.
Your kids are getting better.
They're getting better
every day and in a few moments,
you are going to see that
with your very own eyes, so.
You can bring your son
my cookies, if you want.
I made way too many.
Yes, that is
the spirit right there.
Okay, guys, what do you think?
Want to go see your kiddos?
Let's go! Follow me.
DeMarcus Lott, 27.
Taxi-to-bike head-on collision.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
What the hell happened here?
Emergency bowel disimpaction
of the building's
old drainage pipes.
- Crap.
- Well, let's hope not.
Uh, Mr. Lott,
how are you feeling?
Like I'm about
to be Internet famous.
Check this out.
Tossed off the hood of the car,
rebounded off the mailbox,
landed smack on the pavement.
That's why you wear a GoPro.
And a helmet.
Brunstetter, let's order
a CT scan for Mr. Lott.
Any more openings
at Mt. Zion?
Heard that.
Dr. Bloom.
Damn it, she's tachypneic.
Okay, let's get her
on nasal cannula O2.
It was the shears?
Nowhere near her heart
or her lungs.
Hello?
Somebody?
What's this on my leg?
You see this?
I got that on my arm.
We need to evacuate the ED.
Evacuate? Why?
That's not dirty water.
That's a chemical spill.
Okay, the sickest patients
and those with the most
chemical exposure
go to the front of the line
for DECON showers, chest CTs,
and arterial blood gases.
Less acute
are gonna have to wait.
Uh, Mrs. Westbrook,
how you feeling?
- Better.
- Blood sugar's down to 187.
Okay, that's what
I like to hear.
Low exposure, back of the line.
Dr. Bloom, I ran
the symptoms by Poison Control
and they suspect
herbicide called
4-methyl-2-chlorophenoxyacetic
acid.
Apparently,
MFCA is odorless, colorless,
and highly corrosive.
Huh, what a great trio.
- Coming through.
- I put the ED on diversion
- and activated HazMat protocol.
- HazMat!?
Busted pipe doused
Bertha pretty bad.
- Into the open wound?
- Direct hit.
Since then,
she's been tachy with runs
of wide complex V-tach.
Not to mention
the gardening shears
- still sticking out of me.
- We're gonna get to those.
But first we gotta take care
of your heart and lungs.
Which means a DECON shower
to get the chemicals
off your skin.
And then some wound irrigation
to get the rest of it
out of your insides, all right?
Just try to breathe.
Bertha's in,
but we only have two showers.
It's gonna take hours
to get everyone through.
Okay, HazMat's bringing
more tents with more showers.
Until then, we just
need to hold on.
I'm gonna go find where
an herbicide banned in the '70s
is hiding in our hospital.
Oh, just who
I was looking for.
Dora, the HCC heard about
our chemical spill, I take it?
And I need an important file
the medical director
should have on hand.
Well, then you need to talk
to the medical director.
Because Max would know
where any important files are?
I'm betting
I'll have better odds
with his former number two.
All right,
what are we looking for?
Hazardous material
inspection reports.
If we were briefed
on any MFCA storage issues,
then we're liable.
The ED ceiling caved in
and poured poison
all over our patients.
I'm pretty sure we're liable.
Just find the report.
I'm just doing my job.
The MFCA has branched
into all these pipes.
Corrosion's not as bad
as the ED.
You get a flood
of that stuff,
- all these pipes will go.
- And then instead
of one chemical spill,
we'll have 50.
It's gotta be
coming from somewhere.
We'll split up
and we find the source.
The protection order will
legally compel Chance Becker
to stay away from you,
your workplace, and your home.
He'll be prohibited
from any direct contact
with you or your family.
The court may add exceptions,
but I've been in-house counsel
here a long time,
there won't be any issues.
Do we need
to inform anyone internally?
No, only if you want us to.
I think I'd like
to keep it quiet.
You know, for Chance's sake.
For Chance?
- Yeah, um...
- Anne.
Uh, Neil,
if you'll excuse me.
Thank you, thank you very much.
Hey, Anne, Julie.
Hey, guys, wait up.
Whoa, what's the matter?
What happened?
Something happen with your son?
Alex just got upset.
Upset? He was screaming.
He was completely
out of control.
Okay, well, why don't we all
go have a chat in my office
- and we'll figure it out.
- What's there to say?
He doesn't want us here,
so we're leaving.
Well, that's a bit
of a hasty reaction.
Sorry folks,
we're shutting the exits.
There's been a chemical spill
downstairs.
No one in or out
until it's safe.
- But the kids...
- Everybody's fine up here.
I just need you to hold tight
until the downstairs exit's
decontaminated.
Okay.
Okay, thank you. Um...
Well, since we're
all stuck here...
come on, let's have a chat.
Come on, let's go.
Couple more should do it.
Take your time.
Certainly, don't worry
about the shears.
We haven't forgotten,
I promise.
No rush.
Once we stabilize
your vitals,
they are coming out.
Would you like
more pain meds?
What I'd like is a hospital
that's not falling apart.
I mean, how can you even
see what you're doing
when the lights keep dimming?
It's like a cavern in here.
The lights aren't dimming.
But why is everything
getting darker?
♪
You ever heard of MFCA
exposure causing blindness?
I'd barely even heard of MFCA
before it gushed
all over my ED.
Well, Bertha's
now experiencing
complete and total vision loss.
She did take the biggest hit.
Had the most extreme exposure.
Well, I put her on dialysis
to try to clean the toxins
out of her blood but, look,
if this is blinding people,
then we need to get
everybody decontaminated
as soon as possible.
Oh, yeah,
'cause up until now,
we've been dragging our feet.
Hey, look, I'm just saying
there could be more surprises.
Got it. Thank you.
Let's get this line moving,
people.
Come on.
Come on!
Help!
I need some help in here!
Anybody! Help!
Max, Sandra Fall and I
have been looking everywhere
for the hazardous materials
inspection report
that you should've filed.
But of course,
it's nowhere to be found.
Much like yourself.
Where are you?
Call me, please.
Miguel, do you know where
Dr. Goodwin went after this?
They just called me
for clean-up.
Right.
Ah, bike man, good news.
Your CT came back clear.
I'd prescribe Advil
and a brake on that Fixie.
- So I'm good to go?
- Ah, no.
Not until you go through DECON.
But I was barely in there.
Which is why I'm sending you
to the back of the line.
Um, is the insulin
back in the ED?
Check over there.
I put them in the crash cart
but we're still moving stuff
out of the ED.
Ah, somebody is thinkin'.
Hey, you had
way more exposure
- than anyone else.
- And your point is?
You need to be the next one
into the DECON showers.
Okay, I don't know
how it works at Mt. Zion,
but in my ED,
patients come first.
Oppositional defiant disorder
is tough.
Kids with ODD like Alex
are rude.
They're aggressive, vindictive.
- Our son hates us, Dr. Frome.
- He doesn't...
You were there. You saw him.
- No, no, listen to me.
- It can feel a lot like hate.
It can look exactly like hate.
But it's not hate.
It is brain function,
that's it.
It's an inflated response
to perceived threats.
And exactly how
did I threaten him?
You didn't.
She didn't. I...
I honestly think
this morning was just
a low blood sugar moment.
You know how he gets.
I bet now that he's had
a minute, he'll be different.
We should go back in
and try again.
No, actually, I don't think
that's a good idea.
Julie...
- Why not?
- Because I don't think that
the problem today was Alex.
I think that the real problem
is here, in this room.
You think Alex's ODD
is our fault?
No, ODD is no one's fault.
I'm... I'm talking
specifically about
what triggered Alex today.
And you think it was his moms
bringing him cookies.
I'm sorry.
I don't understand that at all.
Your wife does.
Anne?
Anne, look at where you are.
Hiding the truth
is not working.
The two weeks that Alex
was out of the house...
Have been the best two weeks
I've had in years.
No screaming.
No hitting.
No one...
attacking my beautiful wife...
when she's just
trying to be nice.
I didn't want to see him today.
And on some level,
I think that he knows it.
Dialysis went great, Bertha.
We're gonna give your sight
a little more time
to reset, okay?
In the meantime,
I'll just lay here impaled.
Not at all.
Look, next stop,
those shears are coming out.
I'm so sorry.
None of this is your fault.
Don't worry about me.
Just focus on you.
Focusing on me
is why I started gardening.
My shrink said
it's a way to tune everybody
else out and hear the universe.
I know, it's hippy.
But doesn't that sound nice?
Hearing the universe.
- It does.
- I'm trying to hear it now
but these shears...
makes it kinda har...
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Grab me two milligrams
of Ativan IV.
Do we need to get
her back on dialysis?
It's too late, her body's
absorbed too much MFCA.
So where does that leave us?
Dr. Reynolds?
I... I don't know.
Max?
Anybody?
Help!
Max?
Max, you need
to get out of there.
I... I can't, I... I...
If I let go of this,
the whole tank's gonna give.
And it'd go
all over the hospital.
Hundreds of people
are gonna be exposed.
You need to go get help.
No, you're gonna leave.
I'm gonna hold the pipe
and you're gonna
go and get help.
- I can't.
- Why not!?
I can't see.
Anne, what you just described
is a perfectly normal feeling.
But Alex didn't erupt
this morning
because you asked him
a question.
Alex erupted
because Julie stopped you
from disciplining him.
And you just said that at home,
Alex is triggered
by Julie just being nice.
The threat that
Alex is perceiving
is your positivity.
How can positivity
be a threat?
Well, Alex knows
that his troubles
are deeper than blood sugar.
And when you pretend
that they aren't,
it scares him.
It denies his reality.
And Anne's, too.
You agree with him.
Yes, I try to be positive.
Alex can't. You won't.
- Somebody has to be.
- Why does somebody have to?
Why can't we just acknowledge
what's actually happening?
You of all people
asking me that?
The person who stood up
in front of all of us today
like some camp counselor,
acting like we weren't
all here to visit our kids
in a mental hospital.
Telling us, "Oh, it'll be
a great day today.
"Just remember
to remove your jewelry
so the kids don't try
and kill themselves."
I'm denying reality?
You're actually
removing the shears?
Floyd, it's too late for her.
She's dying.
Because of us.
We did this to her.
This hospital,
this... this building.
You know, Bertha said that
the shears were making it hard
for her to hear the universe.
Well, if there's ever a time
that we deserve
to hear the universe,
it's when we're leaving it.
Staff's all through.
After Ms. Westbrook,
it's just you
and DeMarcus Lott.
- Where is he?
- He's around the corner,
editing video
of his head-on collision.
Mr. Lott?
It's okay,
I've got you, DeMarcus.
I got you, I got you,
I got you.
I need help over here!
Casey!
A blood vessel
damaged in your accident
must've just given way.
It's caused
an expanding hematoma
and it is closing off
your windpipe.
I can fix it. I... I can fix it.
I just gotta... just need to
drain the blood.
Casey!
Help, Casey!
I need help!
Come on, come on.
Come on, breathe. Come on.
Come on.
Her end-tidal CO2 levels
just went off a cliff.
It's severe acidosis.
Push two amps of bicarb.
Removing the shears
caused a pancreatic storm.
This is not
how she's going out.
Suture.
Helen?
Hang on, Max.
You need... you need to go.
- Not without you.
- And if you're not willing
to let go of that pipe,
then I've got
to seal the drain.
Helen, just go! Please!
I won't, so stop yelling at me.
What are you doing?
Weighing down the trash lid
over the drain.
- It's working.
- Wait, it's working?
- Give me your hand.
- Are you sure?
Give me your hand.
Come on.
Come on, watch your step.
Lean on there.
We're almost at the tent.
Just hang on, okay?
He... help!
Can someone help, please!
Help! Oh, Floyd!
Floyd, he's drenched in MFCA.
How are we treating
acute exposure?
- We tried everything.
- And?
There's no treatment.
Nothing's worked.
The bolus bicarbonate
and IV saline that you ordered.
I need CHEM panels drawn
Q15 minutes
until his toxicity is halved.
Q 1 hour after.
His BP was only 80/50.
- The bicarb will work.
- How can you be so sure?
I'm barely getting a pulse.
When we removed
the shears from my patient,
it caused a pancreatic storm.
She was going to die,
but then we pushed bicarbonate
to neutralize the acid
in her pancreas.
Which raised the pH
in her blood,
enhancing excretion.
Dr. Bloom's
responding to treatment.
How did you know
to remove the shears?
Listened to the universe.
Welcome back.
Hey, so, uh, your numbers,
they look great.
You're gonna be fine
by tomorrow.
And don't worry about the ED.
I got it taken care of.
And I'll...
You can't go to Mt. Zion.
I can't do this without you.
You know that, right?
Yeah.
I ain't goin' anywhere.
But um, let's just, uh...
Let's dial it down a little bit
on the excitement, all right?
I can't take this no more, man.
Oh, come on.
This morning, I was, um...
I was pushing the hope
pretty hard.
And, uh, I was asking
you all to ignore...
everything else.
It's just, it's a weird idea
that positivity can be toxic.
But it absolutely can.
Especially when it comes
at the cost of what is true.
And what is true...
is that nobody wants
to be in this room.
None of you want to be here.
And no pep talk
that I can give you
will wish that away.
So I wanna
reframe this meeting.
I want to use this time and
this space to tell the truth.
The real truth,
the brutal truth.
I want you to say the things
that you're
not supposed to say.
I'm giving you permission
to say them in here.
The hope that you and your kids
actually need only comes
with that kind of truth, so...
I keep my gas tank full.
Just in case I, uh,
I can't take it anymore.
And sometimes
I dream about just...
Just driving away.
I sit in the bathroom...
And check prices
on one-way flights.
Just knowing I could leave...
It's okay.
Oh, baby, it's okay.
I love my daughter.
I do.
But when we're out
in public, she...
She screams and she...
says awful things
and I beg her to stop
and she won't.
And sometimes I...
I hate her.
What's wrong with me?
My son.
He's my miracle.
But sometimes I wish...
Sometimes I wish
he hadn't been born.
Please.
- I woke up at 4:00 a.m.
- to bake the cookies.
I wanted them to be fresh
because Alex is here.
And when he threw them
in my face, I...
I swear to God,
I almost hit him.
I would never. I...
of course, I... I...
I just want him to know
how much he hurts me.
How much I hurt.
It's not his fault.
I shouldn't feel like this.
Lyn.
This isn't a bar.
You said drinks.
Okay.
You still married?
It's like this.
My husband and I,
we have this understanding.
When he's out of town,
we're both allowed to...
Wow, um...
you obviously...
got a vibe that I dig.
But you also have a ring.
And "understanding" or not,
I can't get down like that.
It... it's not me, either.
I never actually, um,
acted on it.
I... I just... I thought this
would be easier.
Or at least,
not totally humiliating.
Because I, um,
I dig you, too.
Yeah, so you know what?
I probably should
stop talking right now
so that's what I'm gonna do.
I am going
to stop talking and...
Hey.
Grab a coat.
Why?
You still owe me a drink.
Now it's a double.
Helen?
Can you see?
I see you.
What happened?
I remember getting to the tank
and then...
It just goes blank.
It was just...
Just DECON
and bicarb and stuff.
Stuff?
I'm gonna go.
Just gonna let you rest.
Thanks.
You were there, weren't you?
I'm sorry.
Guess sometimes...
it takes me a minute...
to remember...
what matters.
More than anything.
You.
♪ Well, I tried
to repress it ♪
♪ And I carried its crown
♪ I reached out
to undress it ♪
♪ And love let me down
♪ Love let me down
♪ So I tried to erase it
♪ But the ink bled
right through ♪
♪ Almost drove myself crazy
♪ And these words led to you
♪ And all these
useless dreams ♪
♪ Of living alone
♪ Like a dogless bone
♪ So come let me love you
♪ Come let me love you
♪ And then
I... I didn't know
we still had landlines.
I have to...
give me a sec, sorry.
Hello, hello?
Max, we have Luna.
Oh, thank God, um...
We heard
what happened to you.
- We, uh...
- I have been...
We're taking her
back home with us.
Y-yeah, okay.
Great, um, that would
be great, actually.
And I... no, no.
I will... I will pick her up, um,
first thing tomorrow, okay?
You almost died, Max.
We want her to stay with us.
That's really not necessary,
Gwen.
I appreciate it but
I'll see you tomorrow, okay?
No, Max.
We're filing for custody.
Uh...