Damn it! Oh, Elizabeth!
Six months ago this wedding
seemed like a good idea.
Look at me. What
the hell was I thinking?
You look beautiful.
Oh, please.
What could be more perfect?
You're marrying the man that
you love while carrying his child.
Yes, well, this love child
also comes with an extra
40 pounds and hemorrhoids.
There are some things
I don't need to know.
Where's Mark?
Why don't you sit down
and have some tea?
What? So that I can pee every
two minutes instead of every 10?
Elizabeth, listen to me.
You need to stop, take a moment.
Relax.
Enjoy your day.
You're being awfully nice to me.
It only makes me more nervous.
I'll get it.
It is not raining.
Hello? No. No.
A little mist. I'm
sure it'll blow over.
Have you seen my
wallet? It's not in the car.
No.
Damn it. Must be
in my locker at work.
Everything will be fine, dear...
Well, let... Let
me get your father.
It's Rachel. Hey, Rach.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Slow down.
What's wrong?
She missed her flight.
No.
I'm sure she can
get another one.
But perhaps she shouldn't
have left it until today.
Well, she was starring in
her school play last night.
Well, that's why they
invented understudies.
Mother. All I said was that...
Don't. Everything's okay.
She's, uh, switching airlines,
and she's gonna fly into Midway.
Give me time to grab my wallet.
Then I can swing
by and pick her up.
Hey, it's no big deal.
Why does it always
have to get so complicated
just at the last minute?
Everything is gonna
go like clockwork.
In a few hours we're gonna
be surrounded by friends
and people we love,
and your mother.
And the three of us
are going to be married.
You said you were covered. No.
You told me Malucci
was covering for you.
I said he might cover
my last few hours.
Well, is he or isn't
he? I don't know.
Well, when will you find out?
When he gets here.
Oh, that's great.
Malucci's reliable.
Peter, I have my
dress in the locker.
If I'm ready when
it's time, I'll go.
If not, you can go stag.
Hey, uh, does Malucci
have a cell phone?
I don't know. Why?
Why don't we call him?
I'm not going to call him.
Open radius fracture
on call for the O.R.
Gastroenteritis in Seven
is being rehydrated.
What about the renal colic?
Discharged. If you
need to reach me,
I'll be at my hotel.
Dr. Weaver, Connie on four.
Okay. Tell her she can speak
with Dr. Kovac when she gets in.
Says she has a fever. Too late.
Her co-conspirators have used
the last of the
back-up registries.
Co-conspirators?
The nurses are calling in
sick to go to the wedding.
Says she has a
temperature of 102.
Give it to me. Connie,
I need you here.
Somebody might want to
look at the guy in Curtain Three.
Accidentally used Bengay
instead of Preparation H.
How are you feeling?
Like a Snuffleupagus
on Benadryl.
Go home. Take a nap
before the wedding.
We're already down a few nurses.
We're slow. We'll float someone.
Come on. I saw you yesterday
trying to change your shift.
I'm gonna wait
till she goes home.
She won't see you there.
She has to miss the wedding
for a billing conference.
Luka, she wasn't invited.
Okay, fine. Fine. Go ahead.
But I want a note from a doctor.
And if you show up in
any of the wedding pictures,
you're fired.
Go.
Hey, Mark, shouldn't you be...?
Oh, uh, forgot my wallet.
You going someplace?
Yeah. Reimbursement
Strategies Conference.
The one in Las Vegas.
Yeah, I missed it last year.
I thought it would
be the best way
to put a dent in our deficit.
Well, play a hand
of blackjack for me.
Sure.
Hey, Mark.
I want you to know how happy
I am for you and Elizabeth.
Thanks.
Dr. Greene, you're here?
Wow, that's devotion.
You never saw me.
Ah. Okay. Got it.
Jing-Mei, that pilonidal cyst
in Three isn't going anywhere.
Hm. Uh, new rule:
Anything that involves
pus waits until after lunch.
Can you see that
Mr. Tuttle gets a sandwich?
The unborn twin inside
of his stomach is hungry.
Okay. Uh, can you
wait over there, please?
County base, this is Rescue 43.
County base, go
ahead on Bravo One.
We're at the site
of an accident.
So you taking the cheerleader?
What?
To the wedding.
Or are they carding?
Et tu, Deb?
You have to admit,
She gives new meaning
to the term "girlfriend."
Who are you taking? I'm not.
Someone has to stay
here and hold down the fort.
Not invited? Amira,
find Luka now.
What? Prison van
over an embankment.
They want to know
how many we can take.
Three major, 10 minor.
Tell 'em.
I should ask Luka.
Three major, 10
minor. Are you sure?
This is County base. We can take
a total of three
major, 10 minor. Over.
Got it. Rescue 43 out.
Whoa! Whoa! Hold
on! Hold on! Wait!
That's my van. You can't read?
I'm a doctor here. Then
you should know better.
Look, I'm getting married
today. Give me a break.
Congratulations.
Let me get my tux out!
Dr. Greene, what are you doing?
He towed my van!
Aren't you supposed
to be getting ready?
I just came to grab my
wallet, and he towed my van.
You wanna take my car?
Continue CPR. Keep bagging.
This from the prison van?
Yeah. The driver,
blunt chest trauma.
Ah, damn it! What?
Rachel. She's stuck in
St. Louis. I gotta call her.
No seat belt. Lost the
pulse two minutes out.
First epi's onboard.
Well?
You're getting married.
It's not exactly
what I had in mind
when I used to imagine it.
I still remember you
running around the house
with one of your ballet
tutus on your head,
pretending it was
a wedding veil.
If I'm not mistaken,
weren't you going to marry
that little freckle-faced boy
who lived down the street?
Tommy Bradshaw. Ah.
I wonder whatever
happened to Tommy.
He was indicted
for insurance fraud.
Well, there you are.
Things have already turned
out better than you expected.
I wish your father
could see you.
Yeah.
Well, maybe he
couldn't get another flight.
Oh, I'm sure he has some
excuse. He always does.
Mother.
You're right.
I'm sorry.
I simply can't believe
that he wouldn't at least
have made the effort.
Oh, now,
don't start crying.
I'll be doing plenty of
that for the both of us.
This is your day.
Your hair is perfect.
Your dress is wonderful.
This color looks
fabulous on you.
Well, I didn't have much
choice, did I? Had I worn white,
I'd have looked like I
could sink the Titanic.
Only one thing missing.
What's that?
They belonged to
your grandmother.
She wore them for
her wedding, as did I.
Now, I know you're
not one for tradition,
but if you were thinking of
something old, something new,
something borrowed...
They're beautiful.
Thank you.
It's okay. It's okay, honey.
Don't worry. We're gonna
make a video. You can watch that.
Complains of neck and chest
pain. BP's 124/82. Pulse, 90.
Miss, are you short of breath?
Hurts when I inhale. Ow!
What is it?
My arm!
Do you guys have
the room number?
Pupils are equal and reactive.
Trauma panel, C-spine,
portable chest. Dip a urine.
Any pain back here?
A lot.
We're gonna keep this
on until we clear your x-ray.
What's wrong with my wrist?
Which one?
Left.
Can we take these
cuffs off? Not a chance.
Any O-neg here?
Two in the cooler.
My guy's in arrest.
She may have a wrist injury.
Probably did that herself.
She was in a major
trauma. I need to assess her.
I could only get two units.
All right. Normal saline,
wide open. Hang the blood.
Amp of epi and 100 of lido.
That's weird. Is
he gonna be okay?
The badge must have
impacted on the steering column.
Okay, clear.
He's got blunt chest
trauma. No vitals.
Vasopressin. 40, IV.
What should I tell his family?
Tell them we're doing
everything that we can.
Charging again to 360.
Stand clear.
Got a rhythm. Sinus at 50.
Got a pulse? Nope.
Shot twice on the job, and
now the weather kills him.
Okay. Let's run the O-neg
in. I'm gonna resume CPR.
He's P.E.A., Carter. Yeah?
So try another mg of atropine.
I hope you're joking.
Well, would you check again?
What is it?
Then I suggest you
do that. Yes, I'll hold.
Is it the limo?
Apparently they don't
have your booking.
Like hell they
don't. Give it to me.
Don't concern yourself.
I'll take care of this.
I'll do it.
I don't want you
upsetting yourself.
I won't. Here.
Yes.
No. Well, I booked this
limousine months ago.
I gave you a deposit.
Yes, and when you
cashed my check,
you guaranteed me you'd
be here to pick me up.
No.
No, I don't care if it's
raining fire and brimstone.
You are going to
get me to that church
if I have to ride on your
back like a bloody donkey!
Perhaps you should
eat something.
I do not need to eat. Nor
do I need a spot of tea,
Or a moment's quiet reflection
on this, my special day.
This is America,
and sometimes in this country
you have to kick some ass!
We'll take your car
and get there early.
Fine. Fine, okay.
But unless you
can drive stick shift
on the right-hand
side of the road,
I am doing the driving.
Elizabeth, you can't possibly
drive in your condition.
Get your purse, grab
the flowers, and let's go.
Now, listen here,
you ignorant bastard...
What's wrong?
Oh, Mark. Sorry.
Uh, nothing, nothing.
Um, where are you?
At the hospital.
Both the airports
are closed because of the storm
and the flights from
St. Louis are canceled.
No.
Rachel's pretty upset.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Well, what can you do?
Do you want to postpone?
No. N... Do you?
No, no.
But, uh, if all the
airports are closed,
then other guests won't
be able to make it either.
Well, if, uh... If
you want to wait...
No, no. I don't want to wait.
Neither do I.
Are you sure?
Let's get married.
Okay.
I'll see you walking
down the aisle, then?
I'll be hard to miss.
I love you.
I love you too.
Smart move. What's that?
Not telling her
about the tow truck.
Don't need to stress out brides
anymore than you have to.
Especially pregnant
ones. Need an umbrella?
You have one? Yeah.
You transported them
without backboards?
Medics cleared
the necks on-site.
Was this a work detail?
No. Busy court day.
I'll work for you, honey.
Hey, nice stethoscope.
Let's shut the
pie holes, ladies.
Yosh, can you put
them somewhere?
This way. We gonna
play doctor with you?
Not a chance.
What have you got?
Tammy Gabbard, 19,
alert, oriented times three.
Complaining of belly
pain and a scalp lac.
I need to call Joe.
Vitals? BP, 120/80.
Brief LOC.
Ooh. Nice umbrella.
Hey, Mark. You still here?
Not anymore.
Don't bother.
Why? What happened?
Closed. Tree fell on
the track near Cermak.
Shorted out the Red Line.
How long is it gonna be down?
Hold on.
Let me on.
Wait for the next one, pal.
I gotta get to my wedding.
That's original.
It's true. Why else would
I be carrying this tux?
Look, they towed my
car. The El is down.
Right.
Make room! Make
room! Dead man walking!
Thanks.
Second chest tube in.
- Back in V-fib.
Let's charge again. Clear.
C-spine. Type and
cross times four.
Three-sixty. Charge
it again. Clear!
Where are you, Carter? V-fib.
Correcting volume loss.
Pulse/ox is down to 75.
Did he ever have a rhythm?
P.E.A. for five minutes.
He degenerated into V-fib.
How long has it been
down? Thirty minutes.
No response to
defibrillation times five.
Okay, call it. Take her.
Head injury and abdominal
trauma. BP's dropped.
Charging to 360.
Here we go. Clear.
Carter, now. He may have
a pericardial effusion
or an aortic tear.
You're done. He's a cop.
He's brain-dead.
Time of death, 1458.
I want to see the x-ray
before you clear her C-spine.
Okay.
Excuse me.
Another beer.
Shady.
Five down.
Oh, yes.
Thank you.
Stuck on a layover?
No, my flight's delayed.
Do you mean canceled?
No. It still says "delayed."
Ah, an optimist.
Where are you trying to get to?
Uh, Las Vegas.
Oh, so you're not an
optimist. It's a compulsion.
Mm. Where do you play?
I-I'm going there on business.
And whatever
the lady's drinking.
Oh, no, thank you.
We may be here for a
while. I'm fine. Thanks.
Well, either he's
getting a very big tip,
or you're getting a free drink.
Excuse me.
BP's 90/75.
Has anybody called Joe?
We can't do that, Gabbard.
Who's Joe? My fiancé.
Meth dealer and lowlife. She
got nailed for holding his drugs.
He was set up. Uh-huh.
Ow.
Ooh, we got tenderness
and some guarding
in the left upper quadrant.
Let's call for a surgical
consult and get a CT.
You got a dislocated
shoulder in Curtain Three
in a lot of pain.
I'm off. Grab Chen.
Dr. Kovac asked for you
to take it before you left.
Okay. We'll get an
x-ray of your abdomen,
then another doctor's come
and gonna assess you, okay?
Have Surgery see her,
and I'll sign her out to Deb.
But you're calling Joe! I will.
Carter, IV and oral
contrast?
Yeah. Check her
BUN and creatinine.
I thought you were going home.
We're still short a
few nurses. The storm.
Boyfriend didn't
give you permission?
I haven't asked. You
should. You look worse.
Excuse me while I
complete my penance.
He's not doing that.
Oh, you don't think so? John.
Hi. Hey.
You look great.
Thanks.
Yeah, you do.
Thank you. Are you sick?
Um, it's just a cold.
You're not going to the wedding?
No, I don't think I'm
gonna be able to go.
Can you... Can you tell them
I'm sorry and congratulate them?
Yeah.
Are you ready?
Yeah, in a minute. Uh, wanna
give me a hand for a second?
Oh, sure.
Hi, Veronica. I'm
Dr. Carter. This is Rena.
She's helping out
in the ER today.
A well-dressed candy-striper.
Yeah. Ow.
Let's take a look at
that shoulder, huh?
Ah-ah. Okay, okay.
We're not gonna do that again.
Have you been given
any pain medication yet?
Mm. Nurse said
you could use a local.
I could. But local anesthesia
is not very effective
with this type of injury.
Ah.
I've been clean
for a year. Heroin.
Okay.
Well, maybe we could try
a mild sedative like Valium.
No, man. The taste
will bring me back.
I kept using on the inside.
Ow.
Oh, that was almost fun.
I thought I was past
morning sickness.
Well, I offered to call a cab.
I've never seen
it rain this hard.
Why brides get married in June.
I'll be breast-feeding
a 4-week-old in June.
Hello?
Perhaps we should
have called ahead.
It's not a restaurant, Mother.
They are expecting us.
Then why are the
doors locked? Hello?
I'd recognize that
bickering anywhere.
Daddy!
I didn't think you'd be here.
I wouldn't have missed this
day for anything. You look radiant.
Oh.
Belle, it's been a while.
Yes. Ten years, I believe.
You popped by for Elizabeth's
med school graduation.
I'm so happy you're both here.
I'd prefer if I didn't
have to separate you.
So please be at
least civil to each other
until the reception.
Hopefully, I'll be drunk then.
No doubt. Good behavior.
I'm serious.
Of course.
Do I get to meet the groom
before I hand you over?
Mark's not here?
Your umbrella is poking me.
Sorry.
Oh, for Pete's sake, leave it.
The damn things
give you brain cancer.
Can somebody ask the
driver what the problem is?
Excuse me. Coming through.
Hey, watch it.
Sorry. Excuse me.
Excuse me.
Why isn't the bus moving?
Engine seized.
So we're broken down?
Another bus on the way.
When?
When it gets here.
Let me out.
Raining like hell out there.
I know. Thanks. Let me out.
Lungs are fine. Neck is clear.
We can take off the collar.
I think I broke something
in here. I couldn't walk at all.
Hm. Any pain in your abdomen?
Uh-huh.
Yeah, she hurts everywhere.
All right, tell me
if this is tender.
Wait, lower.
Ah! Right there. Right there.
Send her for an AP pelvis.
I want to rule out
a ramus fracture.
We're gonna get an x-ray, Sara.
Okay.
She's playing you, doc.
You've had a C-section?
Yeah. So?
Any chance you're pregnant now?
No.
I got fixed after Diana.
I got pictures.
But these cuffs.
Save it, Morris.
I'm missing my visit
with her right now.
I don't know when
I'll see her next.
Why?
My sister's moving to L.A.
And there's no one
else to take care of her.
She's 7.
I got four years mandatory
before I see her again.
Should've thought
before you broke parole.
I just wanted to see her today.
That's all.
She's probably
better off. Shut up!
You shut... Ow!
Sara.
Sara, I'm gonna come
back after the x-ray, okay?
You just keep giving resistance
to the pressure I apply, okay?
Veronica, you ready?
Do it.
Here we go.
Whoa! No, no, no, no.
You gotta keep pulling.
Right. Okay, sorry. Okay?
Here we go.
That's it. Hold it
right there, Rena.
She needs more sedation,
Carter. She's a former addict.
She doesn't want any
narcotics. I gave her a local.
She needs more than that.
I offered. She refused.
Stop. I almost got it.
Stop!
Abby?
She asked me not to
administer narcotics.
Give her 10 of morphine.
No! No! Keep going.
We need to relax you to
pop your shoulder back.
She's my patient. I'm just
trying to respect her wishes.
If we don't, you could end up
with permanent nerve damage.
Okay. Okay.
Push the morphine, Abby.
Okay. You know
what? I'm off the clock.
She's all yours. I'm
out of here. Let's go.
I had a dream last night
that I'd be in a car
wreck, but I'd survive.
My grandmother was like that.
She could predict when
her cat would get sick.
In the dream,
I strangled a female
doctor with my bare hands.
Hey, Cleo. Is Malucci here yet?
No. We're done.
Someone'll be back
to fit you for crutches.
Just sit tight.
You should get dressed now.
So when he gets here, we can go.
I'm thinking this
might not happen,
between this storm and
how swamped we are.
You should go ahead without me.
Are you serious?
Yeah, Malucci only said
he'd try. He couldn't promise.
Aw. What?
Cleo, come on.
That would've been nice to know.
Well, it would've been
nice if you'd asked me to go.
What? I did. No.
You RSVP'd and told me to
save the date. Cindy Purcelli?
Right here. All right.
So, what are you saying?
You don't want to go?
I don't have a compelling need
to attend your
ex-girlfriend's wedding.
Cleo, we dated. It's no big
deal. She's getting married.
Peter. All right.
Listen, if you don't want to go,
just say you don't want to go.
All right.
All right what?
I don't want to go.
Fine.
Amira, I need a car.
What are you doing back?
A car. I need to borrow...
Peter! Peter, can
I borrow your car?
I-I need to get to the church.
I'm on my way
now. Right. Perfect.
Can you take me? Come on.
I'll just change in your car.
Where's Cleo?
Are people arriving?
A few.
Any sign of Mark?
He'll be here.
Where's Isabelle?
Oh, she went off looking
for someone to complain to
about the temperature.
So I'm going to
be a grandfather.
This won't affect
my dating, will it?
One can only hope.
Yes. Well,
maybe I'll be better at
it a generation removed.
Parenting.
Listen, I didn't turn
out that badly, did I?
That was luck.
You gonna continue to
practice after the baby's born?
Eventually.
What?
Nothing.
That's good.
I know what you're thinking.
For years I criticized
you and Mommy
for all the time
you spent working,
and now I'm about
to do the same.
I'm sure you'll strike
a better balance.
You don't believe that.
Actually, I do.
No answer?
Just the church
service schedule.
Elizabeth is gonna be on
the verge of a meltdown.
Yeah, I bet.
Between the weather,
and her mother,
and her father, who
I have yet to meet.
Oh, he's okay.
You know him?
Yeah, I met him.
That's right.
Why aren't we moving?
We should've taken
the expressway.
You said not to
take the expressway.
I know. I know.
Is he a nice guy?
Who?
Elizabeth's dad.
Oh. Well, he seemed nice.
That's good.
'Cause her mother can
really be a piece of work.
Yeah.
What is it with women
and their mothers?
I mean, I got along
with my mom. You?
She was the best.
Must be a chick thing.
And weddings
really bring it out.
So have you met Cleo's mom?
No. Really?
Thought you guys
were, uh, pretty serious.
What the hell is the problem?
This isn't gonna
leave a scar, is it?
Not that you'd notice. Huh.
A nurse will be by
to put on a dressing.
Jing-Mei,
we've got a hypothermic
10-year-old coming in.
ETA?
Mm. Ten to 15.
Okay, set up some warm saline.
Close the exit!
No!
Morris! Morris!
Now, Morris!
Get the cuffs on her!
Leave me alone! Let go!
What happened?
She jumped off
the table and ran.
Stop! She bit me!
The bitch bit me!
You're hurting her. Stop
it! I'm missing my daughter!
Please! Where's the cuffs?
Stop. Stop!
I'm missing my daughter! No!
Come on!
Please! I have to
see my daughter!
I have to see her!
How was that wine?
Oh, it was very nice. Thanks.
I'm getting a refill.
You want one?
No, I really shouldn't.
Oh, come on. You're not driving.
You're tenacious.
Is that a yes? Heh-heh. Okay.
Only if I buy this round.
Even better. Excuse
me. Two more, please.
May I?
Sure.
I'm Mike. Hi, Mike. I'm Kerry.
Yeah, you working on your novel?
Uh, no.
No, I was just writing
a letter to a friend.
E-mail or actual letter writing?
An actual letter.
A lost art.
The last letter I wrote
was to Marcia Brady.
Did she write you back?
No. Never really got over it.
Oh. I'm sorry.
So, what do you do when
you're not writing letters?
Uh, I'm a... I'm a doctor.
Really? Yeah.
Emergency medicine.
Brains too.
That's impressive.
Thanks.
Damn it! What?
It's dead. I dropped it,
and it must have... Uh!
All right, calm down.
There's nothing you can do.
I'm missing it. No, you're not.
It... It started, Peter.
Obviously, it hasn't.
I am screwed.
She'll wait, Mark.
Mark, what are you doing?
Mark!
Mark, get off my car!
I'm trying to see
what the hang-up is.
Mark, get down!
I think I see lights.
Maybe a cop. Maybe a rig.
Mark, get down! Now!
Come on, man! Get down!
Approximately
seven-year-old male,
environmental exposure
with secondary hypothermia.
This is ice. Rain's
freezing everything.
Any idea how long
he's been down?
Groundskeeper found him
down on the soccer field. No ID.
Guess he was at the
game that got rained out.
Where's the rest of his
team? Or his parents?
BP is 70 palp. Core temp is 86.
Pupils are slow but reactive.
Set up for re-warming.
Start a second
line of warm saline.
And put in a Foley.
He's about 80
pounds, soaking wet.
I'll be right there.
Yeah. let's get him
out of these wet clothes.
She just wants to see
you. Is that so hard?
Yeah, I know it's
been a long time.
How many years has
she served for you?
Hello?
Jerk.
Who's a jerk?
Nobody.
You feeling any better?
No.
Why don't you go lie
down in the lounge?
I'll take you home
when I'm done.
Okay, I just have
to finish this first.
Are you mad at me?
Me? No.
You were a little
hard on Carter.
He wasn't listening to me.
He's a good doctor.
And, uh, he's been
here for a long time.
And I'm his Attending.
I know. It's just
he's my friend.
So?
I don't know. He's
a nice enough guy.
But he's got to
let me do my job.
Isn't he your supervisor?
Technically.
So this has nothing to do
with him dating
your ex-girlfriend?
No. No.
Actually, Abby and I
never really went out.
You said you did.
Yeah, I made that up.
Why would you make that up?
I'll explain it to you later.
So you'd like to
go out with her?
I... Hey, Dave!
Hey, Carter. Nice weather, huh?
Do you know Rena?
Yeah. How are you doing?
Fine, thanks.
I didn't think you'd
come. Cleo didn't need me
and a few girls from Uncle
Sal's party like weddings.
Did you RSVP for 'em?
With the rain, there's bound
to be a couple of no-shows.
A few extra butts in
the pews couldn't hurt.
You know where can I dump this?
Uh, they'll probably have
a gift table at the reception.
I'm supposed to lug this
around till then? It's heavy.
You didn't buy them a
crock pot, did you? No.
No. We got them
something off the registry.
Yeah, I'm not into that.
"Here's a list of things
to buy me." It's dicky.
Evening, gentlemen.
What? You didn't
think I'd be invited?
So where's the bride?
Uh, she's in waiting.
Dr. Greene hasn't shown yet.
Really? Well, if he's smart,
he's halfway to Mexico by now.
She runs me off the road!
It's my wife!
Ex-wife, you
cheating son of a bitch!
Kept ramming me over and
over, completely out of control.
Do you have control
over your zipper, Kevin?
Look at this!
Take your mid-life crisis
car and shove it up your ass!
You could have
killed me, Brenna.
Everybody settle down.
Shut down around Bedford.
Excuse me. How long
before you clear the street?
Sir, would you step
off to the side, please?
Listen, I'm getting
married in 15 minutes.
Get back to your
car. Nothing's moving.
We're waiting for a tow truck.
Hey, I'm a doctor
at County General.
Any chance of one of
you guys giving me a lift?
You're joking, right?
I heard he's awake.
What are his vitals?
BP's 100/70. Temp's 97.
Good.
Hey.
Hi. I'm Dr. Chen.
You're in a hospital.
You were very cold
so we had to warm you
up through your tummy.
It might hurt for a while,
but you're gonna be okay.
Can you tell me your name?
Bryan Cooley.
Bryan,
do you remember what happened?
I was waiting.
I think I fell
asleep on the field.
What were you waiting for?
They were supposed
to pick me up.
Who? Your teammates?
My parents.
They forgot.
Well, there's a pretty
bad storm outside.
Maybe they were
just running late.
No. They forgot.
Sometimes they forget.
Are you denying it?
- I had to work late!
Doris! What are you doing here?
I'm stuck. Can you, uh,
give me a ride to Northbrook?
That's outside my
catchment area.
I'm trying to get to my wedding.
When? Now.
O-okay. If you help
me clear the scene.
Sure. Let's hurry.
Screwing your dental
hygienist was an accident?
You're crazy.
I'm home having your baby.
Sir, we have to check you over.
I'm fine. Let her
check your vital signs.
Let him bleed. If you're okay,
you can take yourself
to the hospital.
Who are you? I'm a doctor.
Did you hit your head?
What do you think?
Mark, what are you doing?
I'm gonna catch a ride with
Doris when we clear them.
No, I got it. Wait in the
car. No. Check her out.
Did you lose consciousness?
Ma'am, I'm a doctor.
Is there any pain?
Where is the whore? Getting
more ass fat put in her lips?
She didn't slam her car into
anybody, you psychotic bitch!
Hold still. We need
to check your head.
He doesn't think with
that head. Ah! Ooh.
Ma'am. Are you all right?
Okay, come on.
Oh, my God! What is it?
I think my water broke.
When are you due?
Tuesday.
Is this your first baby?
No. I gave this bastard a son.
How long was your first labor?
Oh, boy! What is it?
The baby's doing somersaults.
Sit down.
What's wrong?
Your grandchild
is getting restless.
He's not the only one.
Have we heard
anything from the groom?
I'm sure he'll be
here momentarily.
We'll let you know.
Make yourself useful,
Charles. Get us a glass of water.
I hope Mark
didn't get cold feet.
Oh, no.
Surely he would've called
if there was a problem.
Yes. Well, he's not
answering his cell phone.
He probably left it at
work with his wallet.
Men get just as nervous as
women on their wedding day.
Right, Charles?
Well, to be honest,
I was never more...
More anxious.
Practically forgot it
was our wedding day.
In retrospect, that could've
been wishful thinking.
In hindsight, it would've
saved me several years of grief.
Stop it, please, the two
of you, just for one day!
We were teasing.
Well, don't! It's not funny.
Oh, he'll be here,
Elizabeth. Don't fret.
But I do fret!
Every time he's late I fret.
Every time he
slurs a word, or...
Or... Or gets tired
or bumps his head,
I fret!
I'm about to get married.
And I'm afraid.
Not of being with him.
But of being without him.
I'm afraid he won't be
around to raise this child.
But you told me the last
MRI showed no recurrence.
These new therapies
offer a long survival.
We don't know
that for sure, do we?
Oh, darling,
don't start crying now
or we'll never get
through the ceremony.
Say something, Charles.
You're going to have a
wonderful life together.
Your mother and I love
you very much, Elizabeth.
And we will always
be there for you.
You know that.
Breathe! Just relax.
Blow through the pain.
I'll bring her in. I'll give you
a ride after we drop her off.
I can't. I'm better
off riding with Peter.
I have the lights and siren.
Right. Go, go! Good luck!
Thanks.
Brenna? Don't talk to me.
I wanna come. Yeah, we're full.
Keep him away! She's my wife!
Radio County. Have
them call the church.
Tell Elizabeth where I am.
Brenna... Go away!
Let's go.
Ah.
He was found unconscious
on a soccer field.
I thought his mother
was picking him up.
He was hypothermic.
But we managed to bring his
body temperature back to normal.
So he'll be all right?
We'd like to keep him
overnight for observation.
He thinks you forgot about him.
I guess we did.
It's just, uh...
It's been a real bad few months.
Mr. Cooley, Bryan almost died.
He understands you both
are very busy and work a lot...
His mother and I are
going through a divorce.
We haven't told him yet.
That doesn't mean you
can forget about him.
Dr. Chen.
We got a mother in active
labor following an MVA.
When? Just rolled in.
Excuse me.
Is she full-term?
Mm-hm. Contractions every
eight minutes, says Dr. Greene.
Who?
Thirty-two-year-old, G-2, P-1.
Fetal heart tones 1/40.
BP's 120/80. I have to push.
No, Brenna, not yet. You
gotta wait till we get upstairs.
I can't hold it. Yes, you can.
What happened to you?
Oh, nothing. I'm fine.
Mark. We'll take it from
here. Go to your wedding.
But I need my gurney.
Take it later. Go.
Good luck, Dr. Greene.
You know, I-I need a shirt.
Luka, give him...
Give him yours.
What? Give him your shirt.
Is this a private party?
Uh, Mommy, Daddy, I
think you know Dr. Romano.
Yes. I believe you were
operating on a dog
last time we met.
That's right. You were in town
attending an
astrology conference.
Astronomy.
Well, anyway, I don't wanna
break up this love fest. I...
Your guests are getting
ready to eat each other.
Now, I have $50
Greene'll be a no-show.
Robert. But we just
heard from the ER.
And it seems that your
ex-boyfriend and future hubby
decided to play
paramedic on the way here.
He's with Peter.
Not anymore.
Greene's still out there
saving some pregnant
woman or something.
What? Suffice it to say,
if you give him a
few more minutes,
I'm gonna lose that bet.
Oh, uh...
You look beautiful, Elizabeth.
Thank you, Robert.
Greene's a lucky man.
I know.
I always wanted
to move to Florida,
just get away from
the ice and snow.
Why didn't you?
I don't know. It just
never worked out.
I know what you mean.
By this time I always thought
that I'd be married
with two kids and a dog.
Well, you can always
get the dog. Heh-heh.
That's true enough.
How about you?
You don't live with,
like, 50 cats or anything?
No.
I didn't think so.
Too pretty to be one of
those crazy cat ladies.
Now boarding at Gate 17,
Flight 2247 to Portland...
I guess you were right.
Some of those flights
were just delayed.
That was mine.
Maybe when we're both in town
again, we could have dinner?
Since we've already had drinks.
Uh...
I'm not so sure that
that would work out.
Oh, uh, okay.
Well, thanks for the drink.
And thanks for the
company. Really.
If you ever change your mind,
or you find yourself
stranded in an airport...
Enjoy Las Vegas, Kerry.
Thanks.
My last jailbird had an
ingrown hair in her groin.
How lucky is that? Hey.
What happened to you?
Has anyone seen Dr. Finch?
I think she's in the lounge.
Oh, great.
Whoa.
Peter, what are you doing here?
There was an accident.
Where are you going?
On my way to meet
you at the reception.
Oh, really?
Yeah. Do you
think it's too late?
No, no, no. I don't
think it's too late. Good.
Whoa, whoa. What makes
you think I still want to?
Because you like
to dance with me.
Oh, I do, do I?
Yeah. Let's go.
You know you're
looking good, right.
Thanks. You look wet.
Mind if we stop so I can change?
We'll take my car. All
right. Give me the keys.
You're not driving.
Of course I am.
Why does a guy automatically
think he has to drive?
Hi, Linda? Yeah, hi.
This is Jing-Mei Chen.
No, no. Everything's
fine. Um, it's just, uh,
I thought I'd call and, um...
I got your card.
Oh, yeah. He's beautiful.
Is that him?
He's laughing already?
Oh.
Wow.
Hm.
Really?
Thanks.
Your jacket.
Your jacket! Good luck! Oh.
Are you Mark?
Yes.
Glad you could make it.
Sorry. Ahem.
Good luck.
Nice of you to show up.
It was raining.
Dearly beloved...