Dr. Halstead, the pharmacy
won't release the medication.
I've got an idea.
There's
a region-wide shortage.
I can't have it
turning into the Wild West.
I think we're already there.
I'm a recovering addict.
I need to earn my reputation
back with everyone.
But with you,
it doesn't feel like
that's ever gonna happen.
You suffered a stroke.
If I can't operate again,
what does it matter?
If it had been me
on the table,
I'm pretty sure you would've
done the same thing.
Hey. Sorry I'm late, Dean.
I don't know what was going on
with traffic today.
I got caught up
in it too. You know,
you can blame the HyperTrain
unveiling for that one.
It shut down the Red Line.
A lot more people on the road.
HyperTrain?
Yeah.
You know,
Jack Dayton's
new toy.
Oh, yeah.
Jack Dayton. Right,
Mr. Megabucks.
Yeah.
Yeah, sure, genius.
That HyperTrain is supposed
to revolutionize public
transportation
by moving twice
the speed of the L.
Meanwhile, it takes us
schmucks in cars twice
as long to get to work.
How come Blake's
locker is empty?
You hadn't heard?
Blake tendered
her resignation.
She's taking a job
at Brigham and Women's.
Boston?
Uh-huh.
Guess she's good enough
to perform surgery again.
When did all this happen?
I don't know.
I got an email
about it last night.
When is she leaving?
She can't leave.
I need to talk to her.
You probably
blame yourself, huh?
No answer?
Voicemail.
All right. I got to go talk
to her. I'll be back
in an hour, okay?
All right.
Just don't make it
any more than that.
Hey, Candace.
I'm Dr. Asher.
Hi.
All right.
Well, it says in here
that you are at 28 weeks.
So how's
your pregnancy been?
You know,
it was going great, um,
but my lower back started
hurting about a week ago,
this, uh, this sharp pain.
And it's only gotten worse.
And I called my OB
this morning.
And she told me
to come here right away.
Okay. Have you had
any abdominal pains,
any cramping?
No. No, just my back.
Okay, CBC, CMP,
and urine cultures, please.
You okay?
No, no, no.
It's good. She's, um...
She's kicking.
I'm sorry. I've had
three miscarriages
over the last six years.
And I'm alone right now
with my husband
away on business,
so I'm kind of on edge.
Well, that's totally
understandable.
Let's get your feet up here,
get you comfy.
We'll put you on
a fetal heart rate monitor
just to make sure
that that baby is
happy and healthy.
All right?
I'll be right back.
Thank you.
Maggie, you're back.
Hey.
Yeah.
How was your honeymoon?
It was Paris, right?
Mmm-hmm.
Mmm. Nice.
Oh.
Wait. Paris sounds
so great.
I've never been
anywhere.
I have a passport.
I've just never used it.
It'll happen.
Thank you.
Dr. Asher.
Just a reminder,
you still need to submit
your urine sample
for your weekly
drug test.
Right. Of course.
I've been doing it
the last six months now.
How could I forget?
Okay, then.
Nope. No pedestrian
access here.
Oh, come on, man.
My friend's building
is up on Ontario.
Sorry, the barricade
is here for a reason.
Jack Dayton,
he's showing off his new
HyperTrain down there.
What happened?
The train jumped the tracks!
Hey, come on!
Come on!
Are there more
people down there?
Come on, come on.
Let's go, let's go.
Go. Come on.
Hello?
Is anybody in there?
Help!
Hello?
Over here!
Help us, please!
Help us!
Hold on! I'm coming!
Over here!
Hey!
Oh, thank God.
I tried 911, but there's
no service down here,
of course.
I'm Jack Dayton.
Yeah, I know.
Are you hurt?
I can't tell.
My leg's stuck.
Easy, easy, easy.
All right. Here we go.
One, two, three.
Come here. Your left knee.
Here, sit down. Let me
take a look at that knee.
It can wait.
I'm a doctor.
Over there in the conductor's
compartment. His name is
Nathaniel. He works for me.
He was driving the train.
Come on.
Nathaniel,
can you hear me, bud?
Keep your weight off
that left knee.
Hey, buddy.
Can you hear me?
There you go.
All right. I think
we can pull him out.
I can't...
I can't breathe.
Looks like the lithium ion
battery got dislodged,
hit him in the chest.
Okay. All right.
Here we go.
All right, I want you
to, uh... I want you
to grab him by his ankles.
Nathaniel, I'm gonna bring you
up a little bit, okay?
Okay.
Keep going. Right here.
Yeah.
Right here.
Okay, okay.
It's gonna be all right.
I got you, buddy.
I got you.
There you go.
Okay, look at me.
Nathaniel, you have
a flailed chest
and likely
a hemopneumothorax, okay?
What does that mean?
He broke several ribs
on both sides,
which is now causing
a free-floating segment.
His lung is likely collapsed,
and his chest is filled
with blood and air.
Let's get him
out of here.
No, no, no, no.
Sounds like the tunnel
is still coming down
around us.
Yeah, then we better
move quick.
Come on.
No, no, no.
If we try to move him,
we could make it worse.
All right, then.
I'll go get
some help.
No, it's too dangerous
the way I came in.
All right?
So what do we do?
We wait until CFD
comes to get us out.
It's the safest option,
all right?
I need to get control
of this bleed.
I need to create a pressure
dressing for this wound.
Give me your tie.
Hang in there
for me, Nathaniel.
And you're gonna feel
some pressure, okay?
Okay.
Morning, Dr. Taylor.
Hey.
Rose, Emmanuel,
this is Dr. Halstead.
Hi. Sorry to hear
you're feeling
poorly, Rose.
Dr. Taylor thought
I might be able to help.
The more, the merrier.
I'm well-accustomed
to doctors.
My wife has
type 1 diabetes
and hypertension.
But Rose is here today
because of a chronic UTI.
Her internist prescribed
her several rounds
of antibiotics,
but none of them
have done anything.
So I sent
a urine test
with cultures.
Mmm-hmm.
Multi-resistant
fungal infection.
"Fungal" is such
an unpleasant
word, isn't it?
A lot of
medical words are.
Phlegm, discharge.
Rose taught
11th grade English
composition for 32 years.
Words are her thing.
Some are just
naturally embarrassing,
like having a fungus.
Well, no need to be
embarrassed here, Rose.
It says it's sensitive
to voriconazole
and amphotericin only.
So voriconazole.
200 milligrams. IV.
Um, I had the same thought,
but there's a problem.
It's on the shortage list.
For three weeks now.
What about this
other medication?
Let us talk it over.
We'll be right back.
Amphotericin B
is old-school.
They call it amphoterrible.
I know.
And Rose's kidneys
are already compromised
because of her diabetes.
Her creatinine
is 2.8 to start.
Ampho will knock them out
and put her in dialysis,
or worse, kill her.
It has to be voriconazole.
Let's start calling around
hospitals, pharmacies,
see if they have any.
No, I already did.
Everyone I talked to
in Chicago was out.
I'm not sure what the next
move is, which is why
I dragged you into this.
I mean, what do you do
if you can't get the only drug
that'll treat an infection?
The pain is localized
to her back.
It says here
her UA is dirty.
Yeah, that's not normal
for a urine dip,
but it also doesn't
scream infection either.
Mmm-hmm.
I checked the shortage list,
and I know that the contrast
dye supply is low.
It's currently restricted.
Yes.
But protocol also states that
if a patient needs a CT...
Okay, did you
ultrasound her
for a kidney stone?
No.
Why don't you?
Kidney stones usually present
in pregnant women
with peritonitis
or flank pain.
Right.
Candace only has
low back pain.
Sure. You can still
ultrasound her to check.
I could,
but as we both know,
ultrasound is not
very sensitive
for a stone.
A CT would give me
a much better picture
of what's actually
going on.
Okay.
So if the ultrasound doesn't
show anything conclusive,
you'll order the CT, yeah?
I'll do an ultrasound then.
Right.
And you might want
to start her on empiric
antibiotics too.
In case it's pyelonephritis,
you should get ahead of that.
I mean, like, it's perfectly
natural for a teenager
to want distance from...
from their parents, right?
But I don't know.
Recently, it just seems like
she doesn't want anything
to do with me
at all anymore.
That may only be temporary.
And it's healthy for
your daughter to seek out
this kind of independence.
You think that I,
of all people,
wouldn't know that?
But I don't know, man.
It's been a...
surprisingly difficult pill
to swallow, you know?
And that kind of dovetails
with this other issue
that I'm having
at work, right,
involving being there for
patients in difficult times.
I mean, I'm used to living
in those uncomfortable
moments, right?
I mean, it's what we do.
You know what
I'm talking about.
You've been doing
this a long time.
Mmm-hmm.
But recently, when, say,
I have to give
a patient, like, a really
tough diagnosis, right,
like, tell them
or the people
that they love
that they have
a lifelong mental illness...
Their lives are over.
Yeah.
And I've just been...
I've been haunted
by these moments, right?
They stick with me.
It's like sometimes
they stare back at me.
Sometimes they cry.
Sometimes they don't know
what to do, nor should they.
But you know what?
Maybe I should.
Dr. Greenwell?
Please, go on.
Are you all right?
My chest.
I think...
I think I might be
having a heart attack.
Dr. Greenwell! Otis!
Dr. Greenwell?
What do we got?
Otis Greenwell,
52 years old.
Collapsed into
a glass coffee table.
EKG was normal.
Multiple lacerations
to the forearm.
We applied pressure
dressings en route
and gave him an aspirin.
He was having chest pains.
Make sure he gets
a complete cardiac workup.
Will do, Dr. Charles.
I'll be right out here,
Dr. Greenwell, okay?
He's a doctor?
Yeah. My therapist,
in fact. So take
good care of him, okay?
Pulse is weak.
He's likely in hemorrhagic
shock from all the blood loss.
Please,
am I going to die?
I'm gonna do everything
in my power to make sure
that doesn't happen, okay?
All right.
Anyone there?
Anyone in there?
Yeah, yeah! Hey, help us!
Hey, Severide?
Severide, is that you?
It's Crockett!
Crockett? Hey, what's
going on in there?
What's the situation?
There's three of us in here!
Two of us are okay,
but the train's conductor,
he's badly hurt.
He's pretty shocky.
This passageway is too narrow.
We'll try and widen it
and get a backboard through.
It might take a while.
No.
No, listen to me.
We can't wait.
I need you to get me
some supplies off the ambo,
and I need you to call Med.
I need them to
send some things
you don't have.
Copy that!
Just hold tight, Crockett!
Nathaniel doesn't
have that long.
If we're gonna save him,
we got to do it right here,
right now.
People, I don't have many
details, but Crockett
is down in the tunnel
trying to help those
who are injured.
I do know that he is
in touch with CFD
and appears to be
safe at this time.
And I'll update you as soon
as I hear anything more.
Thank you.
Jeez.
I hope he's okay.
Yeah. Come on.
Ms. Goodwin,
we were just
coming to find you.
Do you have a second?
Sure.
My patient, Rose Fremont,
has a serious
fungal infection
that needs treating.
And the only drug
that can help her,
voriconazole,
is unavailable
all throughout Chicago.
Well, could be just another
region-wide shortage.
I'll reach out
to our suppliers
out of state.
The Army, Navy,
and National Guard
might be resources as well.
Just do what you can
for her in the meantime.
Okay. She's gonna
need pressors to keep
her blood pressure up.
Speaking of the army,
I heard about
your brother.
Yeah, Jay needed a change.
I think it'll be
good for him.
Well, I know
you two are close.
I'll make those calls.
Adia, talk to me.
Trey Bruso, 22. BP 138/80.
Heart rate, 104.
Fell off a ladder
while painting a house.
I hate hospitals.
Okay, we won't take that
personally, but we'll still
try to get you back up
on that ladder soon,
all right?
Okay, everyone.
Let's get ready
for a transfer.
Okay, ready?
One, two, three.
No breath sounds
on the right side.
We need an X-ray!
I want out of here!
The faster we
can get this done,
the faster you can
leave, Trey, all right?
Just relax. Relax.
Stand back.
40% pneumothorax
to the right chest.
Let's get a chest tube.
28 French.
Sorry, Ethan.
There's a problem.
I sent the last Pleur-evac
out to the tunnel collapse.
Crockett requested it.
This is ridiculous.
Relax, Kai.
Dr. Marcel shouldn't be
putting a chest tube
in someone under those
conditions anyway.
It's not
a sterile environment.
Oh, really?
You think I should have
sent him a note
explaining that?
So now our patient
needs a chest tube,
and we can't connect it
to a drainage system.
How is that supposed to work?
The Helmand Province.
Remember?
Yeah. I'll hit up
central supply.
Yeah, you want help?
No, I'm good.
It's like riding a bike.
One of you guys want to tell
me what you're talking about?
Pay attention, Kai.
You might learn something.
Mind if I join you?
Candace,
this is Dr. Archer,
Chief of the ED.
He's been consulting
on your case.
How you doing, Candace?
My back really hurts.
Well, hopefully, that won't be
the case much longer,
so bear with us.
Was I right about
the kidney stones?
I'm not seeing any stone,
but I am seeing
some hydronephrosis
on her left kidney.
Ah.
What does that mean?
Your kidney is not
draining effectively,
so it's a little swollen.
I'm concerned that it might be
infected, so it's a good thing
that Dr. Asher here
has already started you
on antibiotics.
Will it hurt the baby?
The sooner we get
ahead of it, the better.
Give her four of morphine
for the pain and call urology.
Excuse us, Candace.
We don't know for certain
that it's a kidney infection.
If it walks like a kidney
infection and talks like
a kidney infection...
Hydronephrosis is not
uncommon in pregnant women.
When a uterus gets
enlarged, it can cause
urine to back up
and dilate the kidneys.
It doesn't confirm
an infection.
I appreciate your
determination to get
a definitive diagnosis,
but you are
overthinking this one.
You know, I just
have this feeling
that I'm never gonna
pass some test of yours.
Oh, God.
All right.
Look, I'm getting squeezed
by a lot of shortages,
including contrast dye.
And if the antibiotics
don't work and if her
back pain gets worse,
then you can
send her for a CT.
I removed the shards,
redressed his wounds.
Did you get
his labs back yet?
Yeah, he's not having
an MI.
Though his heart rate was
elevated when he came in,
there's no sign
of a cardiac
event at all.
I mean, he's in
good health, but he said
he's not sleeping.
Huh. Um, shoot me
his chart.
Yeah.
Well, this is awkward.
Oh, come on.
We're both doctors, Otis.
Stuff happens, right?
But let's face it, Dan.
I'm supposed to be
taking care of you.
Well, you're gonna
have plenty of opportunity
to do that, all right?
What do, uh...
What do you think happened?
I don't know. I just...
I must have passed out.
Happen before?
No.
Dr. Hudgins said that you were
having a hard time sleeping.
Yeah. I haven't been
sleeping much recently, no.
What would you say
to the idea
that maybe what you had
was a little panic attack?
Well, let's say that
it was a panic attack.
I guess maybe it could
have been the result
of a buildup of stressors.
All right. All right.
I'm wondering what
those might be.
I mean, when it
happened, I was talking
about the difficulty
that I've been having
giving bad news
to patients.
Does that sound right?
I actually don't remember.
Look, I really
just want to go
home, okay?
Okay.
Except your heart rate
is going back up.
I'm...
I'm sure it'll be fine.
Yeah, yeah.
You're all right.
It's not a heart attack,
okay? Just breathe.
Okay.
The pain, it's back!
Five of Valium, please.
Look at me. Look at me.
In through the nose,
out through the mouth.
In through the nose.
Okay, secure!
Okay, first bag coming to ya!
All right!
Okay, got it!
Okay, looks good.
Put that over there
by Nathaniel.
Okay, will do.
Okay,
send the next one!
All right!
Pull!
It's stuck.
It's caught on something.
Pull harder!
Jack, I need you.
Yeah, coming.
Give me a hand
with this Pleur-evac.
Yeah, got it.
Crockett!
You okay?
I'm stuck.
Oh, no.
Okay, yes. Thank you
for letting me know.
That was CFD. There's been
a secondary collapse
in the subway tunnel.
They lost contact
with Dr. Marcel.
Do they know if he's okay?
It's unclear.
They said they're doing
everything they can
to tunnel him out now.
Okay.
Dr. Asher, we need you.
What happened?
She wasn't complaining
of nausea, and then
she just started vomiting.
Okay, let me see.
101.2.
Is this all from
a kidney infection?
Well, let's get her up
to radiology for a CT.
Thank you.
I can move my arm freely
on the other side.
If I could just get the right
angle to pull it out...
Nathaniel?
Nathaniel, can you hear me?
I think he's losing
consciousness.
He's gonna stop
protecting his airway.
Come on. What can I do?
Throw your weight against me.
Square in the back.
Give it everything you got.
What are you talking about?
You hit me just right.
Pop my shoulder
out of its socket.
I think I can
reposition myself
to get the leverage I need
to pull my arm free.
Come on, Nathaniel
doesn't have much longer.
I could break your arm.
Just do it.
Hold on.
Okay.
Ready?
Now.
That did it.
Pull my arm free.
Grab my wrist.
I want you to pull my arm
straight out in front of me.
I need to pop
my shoulder back
in the socket.
Go, go, go, go!
Go, go, go!
I'm good. I'm good.
I'm good.
Crockett,
listen, if we don't
get out of here fast,
this whole wall
and everything above us
could come crashing
down any second.
Nathaniel is the priority.
Come on.
I need your help.
You got
your phone on you?
Yeah.
All right.
I need some light.
All right, Nathaniel.
We're gonna get you
fixed up. Okay, buddy?
I want you to take the blood
out of that red bag.
And there should be
some tape in there.
I want you to
tear me a little piece.
And there's
a needle in that bag.
I want you to pull that out
and get that ready for me.
Got it.
All right, this might
feel a little uncomfortable.
Okay, buddy?
There you go.
I know, I know.
Easy, easy, easy.
He's lost a lot of blood.
We need to get his blood
pressure back up before
we do anything else.
You got that needle prepped?
Yeah.
We got to sedate him,
intubate him.
And then we're gonna
hook him up to that portable
ventilator there, okay?
Okay.
I'm gonna get you
out of here, okay?
We've got to get that
halfway into the chamber.
There we go.
Anything else I can do?
Yeah, why don't you get us
a little bit more light,
if you can?
You get a collapsed lung
to re-expand
by evacuating the
excess air in the chest
with a chest tube.
And you hook it
to a water seal
drainage system
to keep the air
from coming back
through the tube.
That's right,
but what if you don't have
a commercial drainage system?
You have to make one.
Three bottles.
Bottle number one is
the collection bottle.
All the fluid and air
that exits the chest
tube comes here first.
Now the fluid stays,
but the air is still
on the move,
so we have to reroute that air
through this tube here,
into bottle number two,
the water seal.
And that water
keeps the air
from heading back
the other way.
Exactly.
Bottle number three
is for suction.
We connect this bottle
to the regulator in the wall,
and it creates a negative
pressure vacuum
that sucks all the air
through all three bottles
but only to the level of water
in the suction bottle.
Makes sense,
but kind of primitive.
But it works.
Two of Versed,
100 fentanyl?
Yeah.
Fentanyl is in.
Go ahead.
Put it in the tube.
Lidocaine.
Scalpel.
And that's how you
DIY a drainage system.
Okay.
Let's secure the tube.
So there isn't any
voriconazole anywhere because
the FDA cited the manufacturer
for workplace issues.
And until that gets resolved,
there will continue to be
a production delay.
So that's it? Rose might die
because the manufacturer
screwed up?
Look, it infuriates me too.
What can be done
for Rose right now?
We can try
to mitigate her
symptoms.
But unless
we treat the infection,
she's going to get worse.
All right. I'll keep
searching on my end.
And if anything comes up,
I'll let you know.
Look, I wouldn't mention this
if we weren't desperate,
but I had a friend
in medical school
who was able to get
pharmaceutical-grade drugs.
What do you mean?
For students
who wanted
to pull all-nighters.
Usually, it was like
Ritalin or Adderall,
but it seemed like
he had access to everything.
You're talking like
some kind of drug dealer.
It's illegal, yes,
but we're out of options.
How would we even know
the drugs are legit?
He has relationships
with pharmacists.
The quality of the medicine
is not an issue.
Vanessa, we could
lose our licenses,
maybe even go to jail.
I want to help Rose, I do,
but not that way.
No, we can't.
The light helps. Thanks.
Yeah.
Okay, Nathaniel is sedated.
Hand me this tube
when I ask for it, okay?
Yeah.
All right.
Okay, intubating.
Okay, tube.
Okay, tube is in.
Okay, we're in business.
Okay.
I'm still not hearing
enough breath sounds
in the left chest.
We have to drain the blood.
He needs a chest tube.
Can you, uh, fetch me
that jumpbag, the one
with the Pleur-evac, please?
Yeah.
Candace's CT results.
Retrocecal appendicitis.
Really?
Well, that's not something
you see every day.
No, it's not. And the fact
that her appendix
is angled medially
explains why she only
had back pain.
Uh-huh.
Change her antibiotics
to ceftriaxone and Flagyl.
Call the OR and have them
open for a lap appy.
I'll join you, in case
anything goes wrong
with the pregnancy.
Mmm-hmm.
My heat.
She's not making any sense.
Pressure is down. MAP's 45.
Her septic shock
is getting worse.
Add vasopressin and increase
the Levophed to 20 mics.
My feet...
are cold.
Is there nothing else
you can do for her?
Yeah, place a foley
and update me
on her urine output.
That's it?
I'm begging you, please!
I'll be right back.
How are you feeling?
A little sheepish.
I think you might be
on to something
with this panic attack idea.
I mean, what do
you think's going on?
Because at this point,
it's kind of difficult
to ignore the fact
that in both instances,
I was talking
about the difficulty
that I've been having
giving patients bad news
when you were triggered.
Yeah.
I read journals
all the time
to keep up, stay fresh.
Uh-huh. Okay.
I recently read about
sporadic fatal insomnia, SFI.
You heard of it?
You know,
I'm familiar with
familial fatal insomnia.
It's a genetic
brain disorder, right?
Yes. SFI is a variant.
It's nongenetic
and even more rare.
It starts with a mild
inability to sleep
that progressively worsens
until it robs you
of your faculties
and kills you.
Right, and so,
you're concerned
that you might have this
or that you're
developing it?
I know it's irrational,
but I... I can't help it.
I'm really scared.
Well, I mean,
have you thought
about getting tested?
No, I can't do that.
Hey, a simple PET scan
will tell you everything
you need to know.
But that's the problem.
If I test positive,
my life is over.
Every last second I have
will be consumed by that.
I... I won't be
able to function.
But, I mean,
aren't you kind of
consumed by it already?
I'm so tired.
Well, I mean,
of course you are.
Look, have you
thought about,
I don't know,
what clarity might
bring to this scenario?
Look, if you
test negative,
you get a good night's
sleep, right?
That's easy.
But even if you test positive,
which is unlikely,
look, I mean, it'd be
difficult, but wouldn't
it also kind of,
I don't know, inform how you
want to spend the rest of the
time you had left?
People you might want
to hang out with?
The places you might
want to go?
I don't know, it just seems
to me that there's an upside
to clarity both ways.
I'll get the scan.
Voriconazole, the antifungal?
Yeah, thought I'd
check anyway.
Thank you.
Will. Uh...
Voriconazole.
200-milligrams.
Tablets.
I know it's an IV,
but the bioavailability
is the same.
Where'd you get them?
It turns out someone
did have it.
No.
Will.
These are the real deal
from a pharmacy.
The prescription
was filled two months ago.
Check the label. I've already
called and verified it.
And your friend
just happened
to have them?
He said that sometimes
people empty out
their medicine cabinets,
and they turn over
the contents to him.
That's how he got these.
That's called diversion.
It's a crime.
Rose will likely die
from this infection.
You know that.
Even if you were to give her
these pills, how are you gonna
explain it in her chart?
I don't know.
I guess we just...
We wouldn't put them in?
She needs
these pills, Will.
There's only
one way to do this.
No, no. You stay here.
Hey, Nancy. Could you
give us a moment?
Sure.
Thank you.
Emmanuel, I found some
voriconazole.
Oh, thank God.
But I can't
give it to Rose.
I don't understand.
Yeah.
The pills weren't acquired
through the proper channels.
But I assure you,
this is the antifungal
Rose needs.
It will knock out
her infection.
It will save her life.
I just can't legally
give them to her,
but you can.
It's your decision.
Dr. Taylor and I cannot
know about this.
We'll check back
in a little while.
You put your blood,
sweat, and tears into
a project like this train.
You try to anticipate
every potential catastrophe,
only to be undone
by rusty old tracks
and cracked tunnel walls.
So it was the tunnel's fault?
It's not my train's.
Let me guess,
you're one of those
"never explain,
never complain"
guys, yeah?
Yeah, well, this day
wasn't good for me either.
What's that?
Oh, the battery on the vent.
It's dying.
Why are you
down here, Crockett?
What do you mean?
A train crashes,
and a tunnel collapses,
and you run in.
Why?
I... I just did.
You want to know why
I created this train?
To change the world.
Chicago first, but soon,
every other city would
see a faster, more efficient,
cost-effective,
environmentally-friendly
mode of transportation.
Jack Dayton has done it again.
A brilliant innovator. A hero.
That's the portrait
I try to paint for
the media anyway.
The truth is, I developed
this train to make me
another fortune.
Money and ego
have been the motivation
behind almost
every decision
I've ever made.
Every good deed.
Every good deed has
really been self-serving,
unlike you.
No.
What?
Believe me, Jack, I...
I am far from selfless.
Crockett?
Doc. Hey.
Okay, so what do you guys say?
Want to get out of here?
My results.
Negative.
Oh, good God.
Thank God.
Hopefully, you can get
a little sleep now.
I can't thank you
enough, Dan.
Hey, I'm just really happy
it turned out the way it did.
But I think we
should stop seeing each other
professionally, I'm afraid.
I'm sorry, but this has
been a massive breach
of therapeutic boundaries.
You know what,
I would actually
really like
to continue,
if it's okay with you.
You want me to stay on
as your therapist after this?
What, are you kidding me?
I mean, all this experience
has done for me today
is humanize you.
We might have hit the fast
forward button a little bit,
but, Otis, do you
have any idea how
difficult it is out there
to find a practitioner
who will just, you know,
listen and talk
and be present?
All I saw today
was the kind of,
I don't know,
humanity, right,
that made me really want
to keep working with you,
if you're good with it.
Sure.
Good.
Everyone,
gather around, please.
Everyone?
Good news.
We've just been informed
that Dr. Marcel is safe,
and he and his patients,
including Jack Dayton,
are en route.
All right, everybody.
Let's get back to work.
So how'd it go?
Good.
You showed Dr. Choi
how to do that thing
with the bottles?
Yeah, I did.
Ah, in Afghanistan, we had
a whole lot of GSWs without
a whole lot of equipment,
but we did have bottles.
Cool.
Yeah, it's cool.
In any case,
he is a good teacher.
Hey, and FYI, Dr. Marcel
is a pretty good teacher too.
Hmm.
Excuse me.
Nice work today,
Dr. Asher.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Your patient got lucky.
She had a good doctor.
And which one of us is that?
Well, we both know.
Listen, your weekly drug test,
we can dispense with that.
Great.
Pressure is stable
and has been
for some time now,
even without the pressors.
We'll have to wait
for your cultures
to come back,
but I'd wager
the infection is
resolving.
I feel...
What's the word I'm
looking for?
Relieved?
Sanguine.
Good word.
People don't
use it enough.
It certainly seems like
she's getting back to normal.
Well, hopefully, if this all
continues, you can
go home tomorrow.
We can't
thank you enough.
It worked.
Yeah, look.
We did what we had
to do, but no one can
ever know about this.
Ever.
They're here!
Nathaniel Perry,
34 years old.
Chest was crushed
in a train crash.
Dr. Marcel intubated him
in the field and placed
a chest tube.
All right,
I got him. All right.
You're going to two.
Mr. Dayton,
sorry to meet you
under these circumstances.
Sharon Goodwin, executive
director of patient services.
And I'm Dr. Choi.
Let's get you checked out.
All right, and Crockett said
I'm gonna needed an MRI.
Will do.
Where is Crockett?
He's okay, right?
Yeah, he said he
had to see someone
and that it couldn't wait.
Pamela?
Pamela, please.
Pamela, please talk...
Crockett, are you okay?
Yeah. Where's your mom?
She left for Boston this
morning. I'm sending
these things on to her.
Oh, I need
to tell her something.
Yeah, she saw
you called. She didn't
want to talk to you.
I get it.
Could you tell her
something for me?
Just tell her I haven't been
entirely honest with her.
Honest with myself, really.
Oh?
Your mom never would
have risked her ability
to perform surgery.
I mean,
you said so yourself
when she was on the table.
But, uh, I made the decision
I wanted anyway.
It was selfish.
I didn't want to lose her.
But I guess
I lost her anyway.
I'm sorry.
You take care, Ava.
You, too, Crockett.