Did I say anything stupid?
I had two drinks.
Three.
Okay. Yeah. There was
that last one also. Mm-hmm.
It's okay. Someday you'll be
pregnant, and you can return the favor.
I feel like such a
idiot sometimes. Oh.
You know, when the baby
comes, I am gonna be...
You know what? You're
gonna be so great.
You are.
Mmm.
Hey!
You all right?
Uh— Uh-huh.
Oh, no.
You know why I pulled you
over? I'm—I'm so sorry, Officer.
I must have, uh, dozed
off. Have you been drinking?
No. Of course she hasn't.
- Somebody has.
- I've been drinking.
You all right? Uh,
I'm—I'm—I'm not, uh...
How far along are
you? Uh, almost...
Ma'am, step out of the vehicle.
Ma'am, walk to
the rear of the car.
Naomi. Are—
Naomi?
- Naomi.
- Sir, remain in the car.
Hey, listen. She's not
drunk. I will arrest you, sir.
- She's sick! Look at her.
- Can you roll me another unit?
Get back in the car.
Naomi! Get off.
Call an ambulance.
The good news is it
doesn't look like a stroke.
No bleeds, no clots.
Thank God. It sounds
like there's bad news.
We got your blood work back.
Some things are a little off.
Your liver and kidneys
aren't working so well.
Why? What would cause
that? It's preeclampsia, isn't it?
I'm gonna miscarry, aren't I?
Preeclampsia is a possibility.
But let's not get ahead of ourselves.
I've miscarried
three times. I'm 39.
We had to use in vitro. You've
gotta make sure the baby's okay.
Let's make sure
that you're okay first.
How about we take care of
both of you at the same time?
The nurse will be in soon to take some
blood. I'd like to run some more tests.
- Thank you, Doctor.
- Thank you.
Where is everybody?
No one's in the office?
No. I haven't heard from
Cameron all day. You seen House?
Look for a shallow grave
with Vogler standing over it.
You have a stage IV cancer.
It's metastasized to your liver.
There's a new drug called 8C12
that's shown promise in Phase II trials.
It's your best shot.
Thank you, Doctor.
You've been so good to me and...
Well, I—I did...
publicly bash your
company's drug.
When I think about
how I treated you...
Oh, hey. Come on.
There, there, there.
So, um, there is some hope.
Always.
But just in case, I special-ordered
an extra-jumbo-sized coffin.
Hey.
Don't thank me.
It's just who I am.
Hey!
Up and at 'em, big guy.
Sorry. Up late. Internet porn.
How come you're
not in your office?
Because there is a computer in my office,
and if I log on, romance will ensue.
- My wrist might fall off.
- Hiding 'cause Vogler's
looking for you, huh?
That's just pathetic.
I don't like loud, angry giants threatening
me with violence. How is that pathetic?
You think you can avoid firing
one of us by hiding out here?
He'll find you sooner or later.
I'm okay with later.
39-year-old female,
28 weeks pregnant.
- G, four. P, zero.
- Three miscarriages?
Gimme. Altered mental status
and complete loss of coordination.
Tox screen? Negative
for alcohol and drugs.
She was on oxybutynin.
For incontinence.
Yeah. Well, we took her
off. No change. B.U.N.
and creatinine are up.
L.F.T.'s slightly elevated.
Preeclampsia. Call the OB-GYN
service and rub some prayer beads.
B.P.'s normal. No preeclampsia
in other pregnancies.
Because she didn't
carry for long enough.
The three miscarriages make me
think it's an underlying physiology.
Pregnancy-related autoimmunity.
Too bad that Cameron quit.
We could use an
immunologist right now.
We'll see if you're
right. Check the blood.
Cameron quit?
Last night.
And do an M.R.A.
for vasculitis too.
There's no way she quit.
She got fired because you
couldn't swallow your pride.
An ultrasound?
Excellent thought.
And put her on magnesium
too, in case it is preeclampsia.
Sure.
Here, pussy, pussy, pussy.
I didn't do anything.
Exactly my point.
You wanted me to yell at him?
What would that have
achieved? Was he gonna
jump into his time
machine and fix everything?
When a dog dumps on the
floor, do you pat its head?
No. You smack it in the
nose with a newspaper.
Dogs can learn
things. House can't.
Coward. Child.
Hey, there.
I, uh, brought my colleague
along to help out. Hi. I'm Dr. Chase.
Hi.
Well, ultrasound looks
good. No sign of fetal distress.
So it's not preeclampsia?
Well, it still could be, but it
hasn't progressed at least.
We're gonna put you on
bed rest and monitor the baby.
Okay. We'll give you some
potassium and magnesium as well.
We should keep
the fluids running...
and check her again in an hour unless
there are signs of fetal distress. Honey?
She's choking!
Lean forward.
- Is she all right?
- Probably just some muscle weakness.
- What do you mean "probably"?
- Naomi, open up.
People choke. It
could be nothing.
You all right?
I can't—I can't— I
can't even swallow.
She gets sick a lot.
Like this—this cold got
really bad all of a sudden.
And the fever...
Shh. It's okay.
It's not a cold. It's pneumonia.
- Pneumonia?
- Relax. Pneumonia's her
second biggest problem.
She has gone from the 25th weight
percentile to the third in one month.
I'm not a baby expert, but I'm pretty
sure they're not supposed to shrink.
Well, there's this diet we put her
on when she stopped breast-feeding.
But it's healthy. Um,
raw food. We're vegans.
Almond milk, tofu,
uh, vegetables.
Raw food.
If only her ancestors had
mastered the secret of fire.
Babies need fat, proteins, calories.
Less important, sprouts and hemp.
Starving babies is bad—
And illegal in many cultures.
- I'm having her admitted.
- Is she gonna be all right?
Antibiotics for the pneumonia,
I.V. feeding to get the weight up.
Don't worry. It's a vegan I.V.
Don't see any
signs of vasculitis.
Odd.
Since you're always
right about everything.
Could be a different
autoimmunity.
Or you could bite me.
Oh, no.
- Naomi, you okay?
- No. I can't—I'm getting cramps.
Strong? Oh. Yeah.
Feels like my miscarriage.
Stop. Preterm labor.
He's too little.
He won't survive.
She's on magnesium already.
Fluids and terbutaline then.
We're gonna give you some
medicine, okay? Try to stop your labor.
Okay.
Oh! Ah.
There you are. Been
looking everywhere for you.
Uh, listen, you said that I
had to cut one of my people...
if I didn't give that
speech about your drug.
And, uh, in fairness
to your point of view,
my speech really wasn't the one
you had in mind, so I've cut Cameron.
Now we're all
squared away, right?
In the morning, I expect you...
in my office with your
letter of resignation...
and plans for a public apology,
otherwise I'll destroy you.
So, that's a no on us
being squared away?
She might make it to full term.
Contractions are less
frequent and not well organized.
Great to see you back in the
office. I guess Vogler found you?
Yeah. We had a nice little chat.
I really should
have kept Cameron.
- She knew where to find the sugar.
- It's what I said: preeclampsia.
- A little stress from the M.R.A.,
she pops right into labor.
- Aha.
- What about the myasthenia?
- Come on. She didn't seem that weak.
She choked. She
couldn't even swallow.
- What did she choke on?
- Her food.
But muscle weakness isn't
a symptom of preeclampsia.
What kind of food?
A little bit of cooked pear.
Doesn't matter. Shows weakness.
She choked on soft, wet pear?
Did she forget to
take the bones out?
That's way past muscle weakness.
- Did you do an upper endoscopy?
- You think there's something
obstructing her esophagus?
- We gotta talk.
- Ooh. We gotta talk.
And check her eyelids.
Check her eyelids?
Special board meeting today.
Only one item on the agenda: you.
Enjoy the bagels.
I'm untouchable.
Right.
Any vote to revoke
my tenure has to be
unanimous. I've got you
and maybe even Cuddy.
Well, that settles it.
Mr. Ruthless Corporate Raider...
will be totally stymied, go home, curl
up on the floor of his shower and weep.
What can he do?
I got a contract.
Does it say how
much your team is paid,
where you parking space is, if your
car should be filled with horse manure?
Vogler's smart. He's
got some plan to get you.
Does it involve candy? 'Cause
I'm a sucker for chocolates.
- She's doing better.
- Oh, thank God.
Technically, Alexander
Fleming. He developed antibiotics.
Pneumonia's under control.
From now on, what say you
go with human food, okay?
- Absolutely. Swear to God.
- This time, that's your guy.
Rachel and Joel Kaplan?
Yes? You're under arrest.
You have the right to
remain silent. What did we do?
You're being charged
with child endangerment.
What? How?
Starving your kid. I'm
from Social Services.
We're taking
responsibility for your baby.
This is how Vogler's
gonna destroy me?
- What did he do? Grease your cane?
- He had my patients arrested.
Uh, no. He didn't. I did.
The nurses were concerned,
and they called me.
There was evidence
of abuse. You took a big
legal risk by not
calling Social Services.
Those parents are not
abusive. They're idiots.
Oh, well, that's
certainly a relief.
It was my call. You
made the wrong one.
You know, there's a new biography
of Quisling. I think you might like it.
Sure. No idea who that is.
Uh, Norwegian guy,
World War II, traitor.
- The fact that I have to explain this
takes the edge off my flow.
- I was protecting you.
From what? Cops
aren't gonna bust me.
Disciplinary Committee maybe
gives me a slap on the wrist.
And Vogler has an
excuse to get rid of you.
If I don't give him one, he makes
one up. Vogler's just one vote.
He's gotta convince
the other 11 of us.
I'm just trying to stop you
from making that extra easy.
Dr. Charles, dial 454 1.
Sean, do your wife's eyelids
look any different than usual?
Uh, maybe one is
drooping a little bit,
but, you know, she's tired, so—
Naomi, can you open your mouth
for me and, um, tilt your head back?
This is gonna be a
little uncomfortable.
Yeah. There's swelling,
indenting the esophagus.
Is that why she choked?
- We'll need to do an X-ray.
- What? No. The baby. You said no X-rays.
It's important.
She has a
three-centimeter mass...
in her right upper lobe.
Maybe it's a granuloma.
No. There's no calcification.
It's small-cell lung cancer.
The tumor's starting to
press against your esophagus.
It hasn't metastasized,
but it has spread to
other parts of your
lung, so we can't operate.
Wait. That doesn't make sense.
She had, uh, kidney
failure and brain problems.
Some cancer patients get what
are called paraneoplastic syndromes.
You were making
antibodies to fight the tumor.
They got sidetracked
and attacked other cells.
Your brain first. Then
your liver, kidneys.
Even the nerves that
control your eyelids.
That's called Lambert-Eaton syndrome.
It told us the tumor was in the lungs.
How bad is it?
Small-cell is the most
aggressive kind of lung cancer.
The five-year survival rate
is only about 10% to 15%.
Which is why we have to start you
on chemo and radiation right away.
- Radiation? What about the baby?
- You'll need a C-section
before you can start the treatment.
I can get you in first
thing tomorrow morning.
What are the chances
my baby will survive?
Pretty good. Twenty-eight
weeks, so about 80%.
No, wait. That's
one-in-five chance he'll die?
I really wouldn't
advise waiting.
- Naomi, you gotta
start this treatment right away.
- What happens if I wait?
Well, 29 weeks, the
survival rate is closer to 90%.
I'm not doing the
radiation. But you'll die if...
Listen. You know the
chances. They're nothing.
But a few more weeks
will save the baby.
Listen. You're depressed right
now, and you’re not thinking right, so—
Could you j— Tell her, please.
This cancer moves quick. The
median survival's two to four months.
If you postpone—even
for a week...
I'm sorry, honey.
As most of you know, Gregory House
recently gave a speech about me.
I'd like to return the favor.
- Sorry.
- Dr. Wilson.
I was hoping you were
gonna miss this one.
A man is the sum of his actions.
Here are a few of Dr. House's.
He violated a D.N.R. and
was charged with assault.
He brought a termite into the
O.R. and spat on a surgeon.
He accepted a Corvette from a patient who
was a known member of the New Jersey Mafia.
- Ed, look— - Edward.
Edward. You look at anyone's
career, you can find things that are...
These are the last three months.
He's personally had
more complaints filed
against him than any
department in this hospital.
Okay. He's screwed-up.
He's miserable.
And he should probably
reread the ethics code, but
it works for him. He's
saved hundreds of lives.
He is a drug addict who flaunts his
addiction and refuses to get treatment.
He is a disgrace and an
embarrassment to this hospital.
I'd go on, but it gets
kind of mean, so...
I'm gonna keep this simple.
House goes or I go.
- You shouldn't personalize this.
- And by “I," I mean
my hundred million dollars.
How's that for personalizing?
You gave us that
money for a reason.
Are you really willing to throw it
all away because of one doctor?
Gregory House is a symbol of everything
wrong with the health care industry.
Waste. Insubordination.
Doctors preening like they're kings, and
the hospital is their own private fiefdom.
Health care is a business.
I'm gonna run it like one.
I hereby move to revoke the
tenure of Dr. Gregory House...
and terminate his employment at
this hospital, effective immediately.
- Don't you think we should discuss this?
- We just did.
- We need time— - The vote
is on the table. All in favor?
Dr. Wilson. Opposed.
The motion is defeated.
Dr. Wilson, would you mind
leaving the room, please?
- Excuse me?
- We're going to take another vote.
Well, first of all, you can't void my
vote by making me stand in the hallway.
And second, you
should check the bylaws.
You need notice and at least one business
day before you can reconsider any matter.
We're voting on a different matter,
which you are conflicted out of.
How can I be conflicted?
This vote is whether to
dismiss Dr. James Wilson.
Naomi is refusing
to have the C-section.
Her odds aren't good enough.
They do suck. Where's Wilson?
Paged him twice. She does
this, she knows she's gonna die.
She's saving her child. Cameron would point
out that people are capable of sacrifice.
Cameron isn't here.
- Perhaps proving her point.
- You think this woman
is making a rational decision?
I think people can
overcome their baser drives.
Pretty damn rarely.
And not this time.
This is purely biological.
In evolutionary terms, the needs of
the next generation are more important.
You're saying she's
making the right call?
Darwin is. I'm not.
The next generation
is not my patient.
We have to raise
the odds for Mommy.
Where the hell is Wilson?
He's the oncologist.
Good plan. Cure cancer.
I'm surprised no one
ever thought of that before.
There he is.
Dr. House.
You guys bust out? We made bail.
They won't let us in our baby's room.
Weird. You think they'd
let you take her home
while they figured out
if you tried to kill her.
We're good parents. We fed
her whenever she was hungry.
Big meals. We had no
idea that diet was so bad.
The nutritionist said it had
everything she needed. Listen.
The kid who stacks the
free-range grapefruit in
your health food store
is not a nutritionist.
But my uncle is.
He went to college
and everything.
- Foreman, I need a C.T.
scan on— - Olive Kaplan.
Seriously?
Olive Kaplan.
Look for abscesses or
occult infections. Yeah.
Bye-bye.
Listen. Vogler's all
about clinical trials.
The hospital's
chock full of them.
There's gotta be something
for small-cell lung cancer.
What are you doing?
I got sacked.
Did you make a pass at Cuddy?
I told you. She only
has thighs for me.
I voted to keep you.
So he's getting rid of every board
member who votes to keep me around.
Yeah. Every one of us.
Just you? Yep.
But you're only
off the board, right?
They couldn't have gotten
unanimous approval for you.
Brown from oncology
voted no. So did Cuddy,
Taylor and Peavey.
Oh, so you're off
the board. Big deal.
Frees up Wednesday
nights for bowling.
You're still a doctor. Getting
dumped looks great in Who's Who.
Vogler gave me the
option of resigning.
And I took it.
Big of him. I got no kids.
My marriages sucks. I only had
two things that worked for me.
This job and this stupid
screwed-up friendship,
and neither mattered enough
to you to give one lousy speech.
They matter.
If I could do it all again—
You'd do the same thing.
Well, you'll be gone soon too.
Those clinical trials?
I'll make some calls.
Thanks.
It's—It's not cancer.
It's not gonna kill me?
- It's hemorrhoids.
- But all that blood—
I mean, that can't be right.
Looks worse than it is.
- Nice job of protecting me.
- Can this wait?
His ass can wait. You save
my job by sacking Wilson?
What did you think would happen
when you made that speech?
That you would just pout for a
little while and we'd all forgive you?
You don't spit on the man
that signs your paycheck.
First Cameron, then Wilson.
You're next. Pull your pants up.
So it's about the money. Of
course it's about the money.
The money Vogler gave, he could have
bought a few jets, maybe a baseball team.
Or just stuck it in Chase
Manhattan and collected interest.
But he gave it to us to buy
equipment, to do research.
You are a great doctor, House, but you
are not worth a hundred million dollars.
We've sequenced the
D. N.A. of the tumor cells.
P53 gene mutation at codon
55. She's perfect for your trial.
Hmm. She's pretty far advanced.
Well, you want easy cases,
you picked the wrong specialty.
Otherwise in good
health? Excellent.
When can she start?
Middle of next week.
Cancer's already stage III. It'd be a
waste of time. She can start in two days.
She can't start in two
days. She's pregnant.
She won't be in two days.
- I've scheduled a C-section.
- She'd still have to wait a month.
You can't take part in any trial for
at least 30 days after major surgery.
Well, it's definitely
surgery, but major?
It's not your call. Again,
question of interpretation.
You're scamming a doctor? Now?
Come on. Vogler's looking
for any excuse to can you.
Oh, I think he's got a
big bag of those already.
These regulations
aren't just here to annoy
you. Doing this is
dangerous to the patient.
Well, I'll be sure
and let her know that.
Care to join me?
Angiogenesis inhibitors prevent the
tumors from creating blood vessels.
Without blood,
the tumor starves.
That sounds great.
What about the baby?
The treatment would
be fatal to the baby.
I've scheduled a C-section
for this afternoon. No.
It's in the trial phase
right now, but so far...
complete remission in
more than 30% of subjects.
- I told Dr. Foreman I didn't want a C-section.
- When your chances of living were less
than a third of what they are now.
Well, if the baby's
premature, then...
Our Pediatrics department has
the best neonatal I.C.U. in the state.
No. His lungs. His
brain. He's not ready.
And he could be fine. You don't
know what it's like raising a sick child.
His odds are much
better than yours are.
You have to let
them at least try this.
- Talk to her.
- Okay.
Leave the room.
Okay.
How long have you
been taking oxybutynin?
Uh, since I was about 20.
Incontinence is pretty
uncommon in a woman of your age.
It's even more bizarre
in a woman in her 20s.
I guess I haven't had the best
luck when it comes to my health.
Seems that way.
You said to your husband, "You don't
know what it's like raising a sick child."
You didn't say, "You don't
know what it would be like."
This is not your
first child, is it?
And he doesn't know.
I was 18.
I got pregnant, got married.
I had the most
beautiful little girl. Grace.
She had infantile
Alexander's disease.
I'm sorry. Two years
we watched her die.
My husband was a— Uh,
my first husband was a...
A great guy,
but after that I couldn't even
look at him without thinking of her.
I left him.
I left my job. I left
everything. Very moving story.
Explains why you're
being so selfish.
I'm willing to die to
protect my husband.
Because it's what you want.
Your husband wants you to live.
Well, he doesn't understand—
Oh, who the hell does?
Tragedies happen.
If you think that turning yourself into a
disposable incubator for a few weeks...
is gonna protect your baby from
all the crap in this world, go ahead.
Die happy. I got no problem
with people killing themselves.
But don't think it
makes you a hero.
Okay.
You're scheduled for 4:00 p.m.
Yes. This is Dr. Lim.
Count down from 10.
Okay.
Ten,
nine,
eight...
Tray setup. That seemed
kind of fast. Is she all right?
She's fine.
Wake her up. That was
Vogler. Surgery is off.
Hey! You're killing her!
Really? I thought you
were the one trying to ram
her into a drug trial five
minutes after surgery.
She knows the risk.
She was fully informed.
Well, the guy running the study
sure wasn't. Not his life. Not his call.
- His study, his call.
- Right. So she kicks off,
his numbers look bad.
The numbers look
bad, the study looks bad.
Which would cost you money! And
keep a lifesaving protocol off the market.
One person! One
blip in the data!
Ever heard of the F.D.A.?
They eat blips for breakfast.
One person should
never endanger thousands.
Well, thank God you were
here to save all those lives!
The board's meeting
again this evening.
Why don't you settle down,
play some Game Boy?
Why don't you watch your soap?
I hear they're firing the handsome doctor
today. Boy, that should be a good one.
If we had the C-section anyway,
she could still do the
experimental treatment, right?
- We'd just have to wait 30 days.
- Assuming the doctor running the trial
isn't too pissed off to let her in.
And assuming I'm
even healthy enough to...
Honey.
Are you okay?
Sats are dropping— - down to
the 80s. Stay with us, Naomi.
What's going on? We
need you to leave the room.
Respiratory distress.
- Could you tell me
what's going on?
- We're trying to find out.
Here. Still kicking.
Flash pulmonary edema?
Lungs are clear. Here it is.
- Pulmonary embolus.
- Gotta get her to an O.R.
- Now. Right away.
- Uh, what happened?
It's an embolism—a blood clot.
Fairly common with lung cancer.
It's not a full saddle embolism.
So blood's still trickling
through. We've been able
to get Naomi breathing a little,
but we need to remove the clot, and we need
you to approve the treatment. Of course.
Whatever you have to do,
just do it. It's not that simple.
The best course for
the baby would be an
immediate C-section.
The longer we postpone,
the greater chance he'll have brain damage
from lack of oxygen. Fine. Just do it.
Here's the problem.
The C-section would be very, very
dangerous for Naomi. Dangerous like...
In her current condition, there's
a real chance she won't survive.
I'm sorry.
Your wife's unconscious. We
need you to make a decision.
I just want her to live.
No C-section.
Sats are still way down. We
gotta push the streptokinase.
Too risky. Even if it dissolves
the clot, she could still bleed out...
- She's hemodynamically compromised.
- It's not good for the baby.
Dad doesn't care.
Bolusing 250,000 units.
B.P.'s dropping.
Pressors. Don't have
time. We've gotta suck it out.
Systolic B.P.'s 80.
B.P.'s stabilizing.
O₂ sats rising.
- Did you get the clot?
- I think so.
She's stabilized. How long
was her oxygen at that level?
- About 10 minutes.
- Brain function compromised?
Shouldn't be, but we'll...
B.P.'s dropping.
Up the dopamine.
- She's not responding. How much?
- Up to 30 micrograms.
Is she septic?
She's bleeding into her abdomen.
We won't be able to stop it.
I'll go talk to the husband.
No. You stay here. Keep her as
stable as you can for as long as you can.
She had trauma
during the procedure.
She's bleeding into her abdomen.
There's nothing
we can do. I'm sorry.
Oh. No.
I need you to okay the C-section.
That's gonna kill her, right?
Probably will.
I can't do that.
She's dying either way.
I'm—I'm sorry.
Stay with me, Sean. I
need your okay on this.
She makes the
decisions, and I'm...
Right. And that's gonna be tough
from now on, but this decision is easy.
You know what she'd want. Yeah.
I can't do— You make this
call, only two things change.
One, yeah, you feel guilty for
killing your wife. Two, your baby lives.
Naomi's baby lives.
Okay. Okay.
He's out. Umbilical
cord's clamped.
- No respiration.
- His lungs aren't opening up.
They aren't mature.
Come on. Take a breath.
You know you can do it.
What you got?
- Looks like V-fib.
- Pulse?
- No. Paddles.
- Right here.
Come on. Come on.
Clear!
- Nothing.
- Charging.
- Good boy. Open up.
- How's he doin'?
Still not breathing.
We've gotta intubate.
Clear!
Thank you.
I'm late for the board
meeting. We need to talk.
I don't want to hear
it. It's about a patient.
The pregnant woman?
She wasn't qualified for
that trial. And I'm
not gonna apologize...
I'm not talking about
her. At this point, I think it's
best if I concentrate on
patients who are still alive.
Pulmonary embolism. She
bled out. Saved her son.
This is Olive Kaplan's C.T. scan—
The incredible shrinking baby.
Her thymus gland.
DiGeorge syndrome. It's genetic.
Caused the gland to wither to nothing.
This is why she couldn't
gain weight. Yeah.
I'll call the police and Social Services
and have all the charges withdrawn.
I've sent a test down to
confirm. When it comes back,
you should start Olive on
immunoglobulin replacement.
You're not gonna do it?
Well, I assume I won't be here.
Your boy is doing good.
It's the same motion as
yesterday, people. Same reasons.
All those in favor of dismissing
Gregory House, raise a hand.
Dr. Cuddy,
you realize this
is going to happen.
- I can't do it.
- You can't abstain.
I'm not abstaining.
I'm voting no.
You've changed your
mind since yesterday?
What did he do? Buy you dinner and
roses? Threaten to drown your dog?
- He did his job.
- Right.
He saved another life.
Maybe. Good for him.
- It's great. It's not the point.
- It's what we do.
And you could do it a lot better if you
didn't have to worry about some madman...
running around the hospital
accountable to no one.
- But that's not the choice
you're giving us.
- House won't listen to anyone.
And you're not accountable to anybody
either. Because you think you own us.
I move for the immediate
dismissal of Dr. Lisa Cuddy.
She's upset. We all are.
Why would you risk
your career to save him?
If you think House deserves to
go— If you think I deserve to go,
Wilson deserved
to go, then vote yes.
But if you're doing
this because you are
afraid of losing his
money, then he's right.
He does own you.
You have a choice. Maybe
the last real one you'll have here.
Cuddy is a genius.
Convincing four people to give up
a fortune to save our sorry asses.
- Dr. Cuddy, the man of the hour.
- Hey, hey!
Hey. What are you doing?
We're drinking. I would have
thought that was pretty obvious.
To the great
champion. Saved you,
saved Wilson—
Saved the whole team.
Of course none of them
would have needed saving if
you could actually get along
with another human being.
Thank you, Miss Buzz Kill.
Well, you only cost us a
hundred million dollars.
Could have saved some lives,
could have made a few jobs,
helped a few people—yippee.
You voted to get rid of him.
The lesser of two evils.
You should be mourning.
I know I am.
That's some bad hat, Harry.