Who we got coming in?
Fifty-four, he's got
an unconscious kid.
- I should've asked if you wanted coffee.
- No. I had a couple hundred cups.
I feel like I got
ants all over me.
You mean fleas, from that
homeless guy with the dogs.
I saw a rat by the Dumpsters.
I thought it was a cat at first.
Call Jerry, he'll have Maintenance
bring down a couple extra traps.
More like a couple of shotguns.
That thing was the size of a beaver.
- Here we go, girls.
- All right.
- What do we got?
- 15-year-old female.
Found passed out after playing a
drinking game at a slumber party.
Unresponsive,
sats 93 over 2 liters.
BP 72 palp, couldn't get a line.
- Name's Stacey.
- Stacey, can you hear me? Stacey?
- How long has she been down?
- Not sure.
Bunch of kids that were at
the party are in a car behind us.
- Jerry, what's open?
- They're both open.
All right, access, ETOH level,
tox screen, d-stick, and lytes.
Non-rebreather, she's hypoxic.
Ready for a transfer?
One, two, three.
Dr. Morris?
Archie!
Fire's bringing in an altered
old lady, found her out in the rain.
- How's escalator lady?
- Ortho took her up to screw her hip.
- Explosive-diarrhea guy?
- Loperamide's working, he's sleeping.
- Belly pain back from CT?
- Nope.
- Oh, I hate working nights.
- Really? I like it.
- Nights?
- Yeah, lets me babysit my grandkids.
- What do you got?
- Found her out in the rain.
Looks like she slipped and fell. We called
for a paramedic unit, but she passed out.
We were only a couple blocks away,
be quicker to bring her in ourselves.
She's cold. Warm saline,
humidified O2 and the Bair Hugger.
- Right here.
- Jerry?
- Open your eyes.
- Pulse is weak.
- She broke her wrist when she fell.
- Maybe hit her head, she'll need a CT.
Some room.
- Pupils, equal and reactive.
- Fourteen liters by mask.
CBC, chem panel, UA,
EKG and chest x-ray.
Core temp is 90
degrees. Hugger's ready.
What's your name, dear?
Hello?
We got a name? ID?
- Nothing but her nightgown.
- Excuse me.
Blood alcohol
level is back, 420.
All right, no gag, she needs a tube.
- Systolic's only 66.
BA of 420. What is that,
like a gallon of tequila?
Dr. Gates. The girl's friends
wanna come back, see if she's okay.
Does she look like
she's okay, Jerry?
Give me that. Another 250
into the IO. Where's my access?
- Vein blows every time.
- Mac 3 and seven-oh.
- Damn it, lost it with the flush.
- Sterile gloves and a cordis.
- The tube won't pass.
- Try cricoid.
Breaths are shallow.
The rain is gonna continue...
and that cold weather will
move across the lakes...
Still raining?
I was thinking about renting
a boat, and rowing to work.
- How are the inmates?
- Cranky.
What's with the iCarly
crew out in the waiting room?
They came in with a kid
with alcohol poisoning.
- Gates has been flogging her for hours.
- Okay.
Looks like it's just us, we'll
work the board in 15 minutes.
- PV in three, needs an H & P, honey.
- Oh, lucky you.
- What's a PV?
- Projectile vomiting.
Guy's like a champ.
Puke went 8 feet.
- Thought he might have broken a window.
- Isn't this a nurse's job?
Why God created med students.
Did you finish your
lab paperwork...
or leave your usual
mess for me to clean up?
Love you too, Frank.
And so long, sucker.
Ah, ah.
- Ow! What?
- Didn't see you put anything in the jar.
No pay, no eat.
- No, I swear. Five bucks last week.
- Mm-hm.
Morris, your old lady standing
in the rain is back from CT.
- Night, everybody.
- I even put a 10 spot in the week before.
Sure, you did. Next time, write
your name on it just so I know.
- You don't trust me?
- You got it, champ.
Money with your name on it
before you leave today, Morris.
I've got a 3-year-old
with otitis media.
Mom poured hot garlic
oil into the kid's ear.
Looks like he has
second-degree burns.
Man. MORRIS: What was that?
PV patient, thought he'd
be out of ammo by now.
- Otitis kid?
- You know what? Find Brenner.
I'm off. I gotta finish up
with a few patients first.
CT negative for
fracture or bleed.
No anemia, EKG is normal.
And chemistries are okay.
- Okay?
- She's awake?
- Started coming around in CT.
Hello there.
- What's your name?
- Beverly.
- What's your last name?
- My name is Beverly.
Temp's up to 97.
Well, that means you don't
need this big blanket anymore.
Hey, do you remember what
happened to you, Beverly?
- No.
- You were out in the rain, you got cold.
- You slipped and broke your wrist.
- Oh, my wrist hurts.
Tubular stockinette.
Ooh. Oh.
Your hands are so warm.
Soft and strong.
Just like my Bobby's.
What do you see here?
She must've aspirated when she
was unconscious in the bathroom.
- And?
- Her brain is oxygen deprived.
And she still may be
altered when she sobers up.
All right. Two grams of
ceftriaxone with 500 clinda.
- And repeat an ETOH, please.
- So, what do we do now?
Now we wait.
Do you mind if I take off?
- My shift ended 20 minutes ago and...
- Yeah, go ahead, go. Go.
Her friends are still out front
asking if they can come back.
- Send them in. TRACY:
You think that's a good idea?
- Letting them see her like this?
- They should see the consequences.
- So it's okay with you if I go?
- Yeah, go.
Get some rest. Go ahead.
- Tony?
- Hey, did I wake you?
- No, I'm just getting Alex off to school.
- Happy birthday.
- I got the day right, didn't I?
- Yep.
- Do you want me to sing for you?
- No. God, no.
Mom, I don't wanna be late.
- Are you gonna do anything special?
- Like what?
I don't know. Get a tattoo?
Go skydiving? Hang
out with your friends?
- Come on.
- I gotta go.
- Happy birthday.
- Thank you.
Tony?
- Hi, I'm Dr. Gates.
- Dick and Heather White.
Are you Stacey's parents?
No. Stacey stayed at our house. Her
parents were in Springfield for a wedding.
So you've contacted them?
Yes, they're already coming,
they should be here soon.
Is she gonna be okay?
She's in a coma, and she
may have brain damage.
We're not gonna know if
she's okay till she wakes up.
Why does she need the tube?
To give her some oxygen
and protect her lungs.
It keeps her from choking
to death on her own saliva.
What were you guys drinking?
Vodka. Vodka and Kool-Aid.
We were playing I Never.
Stacey won.
Where'd you get the vodka?
Kids drink, we all know that.
We just wanted them to
be doing it somewhere safe.
So you supplied the alcohol?
I'd rather they drink at home,
than out where they could be driving.
Can I give her something?
- Come on, girls.
- Come on.
Let's go now.
Call the cops, get
them down here.
Hey, 9-month-old
with bronchiolitis...
on continuous nebs,
waiting on the PICU.
In 2, we have testicular pain
after a pommel horse incident.
That sport should be outlawed.
28-year-old with leukemia
cutis, Oncology's gonna see him.
We have the DKA. A is gone but
still has K, he needs to come in.
- What is that smell?
- The guy is a geyser.
- Who?
- PV guy.
- It's like dodging artillery.
- I don't think the wipes will do it.
- Grab some scrubs and ditch the clothes.
- Don't ditch, burn.
Guy in 3 torched his
fingers making crème brûlée.
Displaced tib/fib
going to Ortho.
Hallucinating trombone player in sutures
needs a tox screen and a psych consult.
And my job here is done.
Okay, Sanchez, testicular pain,
trombone guy, and displaced tib/fib.
Julia, leukemia cutis,
crème brûlée, and the DKA.
- Chaz. Chaz.
- Yeah?
We have prospective medical students
coming in here today for their interviews.
Dr. Anspaugh asked me to show them
around, but as I don't really want to...
and you're low guy on this
totem pole, you're elected.
- Med students?
- Prospective med students.
They're just a bunch of over-educated,
fiercely ambitious seniors...
trying to claw their way
into a prestigious program.
So show them a good time.
- Morris?
- Shh. I'm gonna put it back.
- Hey!
Money's in the jar, Frank.
- Morris?
- I'm out the door.
- Beverly's daughter showed up.
- Who?
- Old lady with the broken wrist.
Hello, I'm Dr. Morris.
Temp is 99. All
her labs check out.
God, she scared
us half to death.
Mom, you scared
I went in to make sure she was
getting up and her bed was empty.
I looked around the
house, around the yard...
I ran up and down
the street in the rain.
Tom got the car, he drove
all over the neighborhood.
- Her CT...
- I went over to the church, to Emma's.
I called the police and 20 hospitals.
I was out of my mind with worry.
- Out of my mind.
- She's gonna...
Sometimes she
wanders into the yard...
but she never,
ever, leaves the yard.
You can't leave the yard, Mom.
- She broke her wrist...
- You're gonna give me a stroke!
- You can get that from stress?
- A stroke?
- Stress can cause a stroke...
- What am I supposed to do about this?
Am I supposed to sew a LoJack
into your nightgown so I can find you?
Well, we're just
glad she's safe now.
You have to bring her back in
a couple days for a cast check...
come back sooner if there's pain,
redness or swelling. Take care, Beverly.
- Dr. Morris...
- No, no, no.
Get away from me or I'll hit
you. I mean it, right in the face.
Freedom!
- What was that all about?
- Hell if I know.
The police are here on
your alcohol-poisoning girl.
You've got to be kidding
me. Wait a minute.
- You called the cops?
- Damn right, I called the cops.
- This isn't our fault.
- Whose fault is it?
- Look, everybody does it.
- She had a blood alcohol level of 420!
That's not like giving
a kid a sip of wine.
- You're gonna have me arrested?
- Damn right, they're gonna arrest you.
That kid almost died. She could have
permanent brain damage. Four-twenty?
What were you doing when they
were drinking themselves to death?
TV? Mixing up another
batch of vodka and Kool-Aid?
- Get off!
- Come on!
Daddy! COP: Stay down!
Ma'am, please. Stay
down, stay down.
- Wanna call my lawyer.
- Have a good one.
Doc, you know
what? Shut the hell up.
Wow. Should we
be building an ark?
The news said we could get
as much as 5 inches today.
Glad I'm not an EMT anymore.
Day like this, you get wet early,
you stay wet the whole shift.
You'll never get dry.
37-year-old construction worker,
took a 15-foot fall from the scaffolding.
- Diffuse abdominal pain, impaled thigh.
- No pulse in the right foot.
Bagged his femoral artery.
BP 90, palp with 3 liters
of saline over 45 minutes.
Kind of a long transport time.
Had to wait for City Fire
to saw him off the rebar.
- His name's Dickie DeAngelo.
- That looks nasty.
Look at this idiot.
Who drives into that? What, did
he think it was, like, just a puddle?
Dr. Gates, that alcohol-poisoning
girl's parents are here.
- Hi.
- Hello.
Hey, doc. You got time
for a kid with a bellyache?
Grandma only speaks Spanish.
My Spanish is pretty shaky,
I've been taking a course...
It's gotta be better
than mine. All I got is:
Four-year-old boy, only thing I can think
of is something to do with his stomach.
The administrative
social worker...
and counseling offices
are all on the second floor...
along with the wellness
classrooms and the therapy rooms.
Oh, my gosh.
This is... This is beautiful.
- John.
Thirty-six exam
rooms, radiology suite.
Two dental suites, shower
facilities for the homeless.
Ob-gyn, optometry,
pharmacy, diagnostics...
rapid HIV testing and
support, reproductive health.
Wow, I can't believe you
were actually able to pull this off.
You had doubts?
No, I was pretty sure
you were gonna fail.
Tell me, are you gonna be able to
get funding for the county to staff this?
No. I'm gonna be fundraising
for the rest of my life.
We have enough to keep
us going for the first year...
while I try to build
up some endowment.
Carter, I knew you were rich. I
didn't know you were this rich.
It's the ill-begotten gains of my
Carter forefathers, put to good use.
- Redemption?
- Maybe so.
Your grandma would be so proud.
Grandfather's rolling
over in his grave.
He thought the Carter money was
gonna last longer than the pyramids.
- You spent it all?
- No, but most of it.
You've done a great
thing here, John.
A truly great thing.
Paramedics are pulling in with a
47-year-old male with chest pain.
And I've got a 60-year-old
man short of breath.
Okay, Julia, take the short of breath.
Chaz, you're with me for the rule-out MI.
He looked like crap so
I brought him right back.
Sats were 72 percent. So I went ahead
and hooked him up with some oxygen.
Okay.
Hello, I'm Dr. Wise.
And you are Mr. Gandhi.
My mom was a Mahatma fan.
And how long have you been sick?
- About 20 years.
- More recently?
Trouble breathing?
Couple of weeks.
- Do you have lung disease?
- Not that I know of.
- Heart problems?
- No.
- Any fever?
- Just can't breathe.
Okay.
Portable chest, 100 percent
non-rebreather, EKG, first-day labs.
- IV?
- Start a saline lock.
- Wear gloves.
- What?
I have AIDS.
- Should we intubate?
- Not yet.
Tachypneic, still
hypoxic on 100 percent?
What do you see?
Bilateral effusions, that
explains his shortness of breath.
Mm-hm. And that
gives us something to fix.
Two thoracentesis trays, please.
We have to tube him if he
has underlying pneumonia.
One step at a time.
What are you two talking about?
You have a lot of fluid outside your lungs.
It's making it hard for you to breathe.
- What can you do for that?
- Well, we can drain the fluid.
Which is gonna make
you feel a lot better.
So put your mask back on
and let's lean you forward.
Just dangle your
legs. That's the way.
We're gonna clean
the skin with Betadine.
You're gonna feel a sting while
we numb the skin, Mr. Gandhi.
- Gandhi?
- Yeah, his mother was an admirer.
Now, you're going to feel some pressure
while the needle passes through the ribs.
Fluid looks a little bloody.
Let's send it for a cell count, culture
and gram stain, AFB, and Cytology.
Hey, you're gonna have some
coughing as your lungs expand.
But that's a good thing.
That means it's working.
No change?
We have to move her, we need
the trauma room for an MVC.
Come on, guys.
Why don't you go home? We'll
call you if anything changes.
Hey, Frank, I'm going home.
Call me if anything
changes with the Taylor girl.
- Who?
- Alcohol poisoning?
Oh. Another one of those kids
showed up asking about her.
She's the one with
braids out in waiting.
Hi. I'm Dr. Gates. Are you
here to see Stacey Taylor?
- Yeah.
- Okay, well, she's in a coma.
And we don't know when or if
she's going to regain consciousness.
- Were you at the party last night?
- No.
I heard what happened.
Are you here by yourself?
You know, her friends and her
parents are on the second floor.
Maybe you wanna go up there.
You might be more comfortable.
I should have done something.
Well, you weren't there, right?
Stacey was texting me.
My parents wouldn't let me go.
I was really angry
I wasn't there...
so she was texting me all
night to tell me about the party.
She told me she was sick,
really sick, and throwing up.
And I...
I thought it was funny.
I should have called somebody.
I could have...
Maybe I could have...
The ER is the nerve
center where it all begins.
Between the ER and urgent care,
we see over 200,000 patients a year.
As med students, this is
gonna be your first rotation.
Four years to see if
you've got what it takes...
to be on the front line
of urban medicine...
or if you're a little bit more
suited for dermatology or plastics.
Something a little bit more...
A little bit more safe that you
can practice out in the suburbs.
Triage is our first stop.
We rely on our
talented nursing staff...
to determine who's gonna
be first and who is gonna wait.
And wait, and wait.
These trained professionals can
tell the difference between a hot MI...
and common indigestion
just by looking at a guy.
After triage, the patient is
brought back, their chart is racked.
You pick up the next
in line, no matter what.
Swap fecal incontinence for knee
pain, you'll never hear the end of it.
Glad you learned your lesson.
Our curtain areas are
for our subacute patients.
Over there is the break room where
we got bad coffee and stale bagels.
Trust me, you don't wanna be
going over there. Excuse me?
Keep up, okay? So here's the
deal about being a med student.
Some docs like to teach, but most
just see us as being a pain in the ass.
So they're not gonna be issuing
no formal invitation to the cool stuff.
You gotta keep your eye
open and go after the action...
it's not gonna come
to you, come on.
Another epi, let's shock
him... Shock him again.
- Chaz?
- This is Dr. Brenner.
One of our fine ER attendings.
This is the tour of prospective
medical students you asked me...
Chaz, get them
the hell out of here!
Okay.
So who wants to
see the Suture Room?
Clear!
- Anybody seen Brenner?
- Down in Trauma with the chest pain.
- You okay?
- Just got results back on a patient.
Bad news?
- You want company?
- No, I should do it.
No time like the present.
Right.
Post-tap film came back.
Your lungs have re-expanded.
- No pneumonia, are you feeling better?
- I can breathe again.
- You said you've been sick for years?
- Well, I got the AIDS diagnosis in 1987.
Started AZT soon as it was out.
It's great that you've been
able to fight it off this long.
Come on, doctor,
no holding back.
I can take it, believe me.
Your test results came back.
There were atypical lymphocytes.
Large immunoblastic cells.
And what does that mean?
It means that you have cancer.
It's a little nasty
out there today.
Keeps up, we're gonna
start handing out life jackets.
- How are you?
- I'm on the mend.
- Everything working?
- No complaints with the plumbing.
Wish I could say the same. I
was up six, seven times last night.
- Kind of a quiet day today, huh?
- Yeah.
I'm pulling out a crossword
puzzle to fill the time.
I had lunch with Susan
Lewis, Kerry Weaver.
Really? How is
the old dragon lady?
She's good.
- Susan, actually, looks fantastic.
- What are they doing in town?
Tonight's the opening of the
Carter Center. They came in for it.
- Open bar, free food on fancy crackers?
- All that.
Housekeeping needs
to clean up Trauma 2.
- It's still a mess after that shotgun kid.
- They're trying to mop up a roof leak.
- What's up?
- A pregnant woman coming in, MVA.
Here they are.
- Hey, store that for me, would you?
- Sure.
36-year-old female, nine
months pregnant with twins.
Broke her water at home.
- Contraction!
Traffic collision on the
way. T-boned by a CTA bus.
- Is this your first pregnancy?
- Fourth.
Struck on the passenger
side. Tachy to 120, BP's normal.
- Get me off this.
- As soon as we assess you, ma'am.
Let's get her inside. - Ah!
On my count. One, two, three.
My husband should be here.
He was on his way to
meet me at Mount Sinai.
Okay, check the perineum,
I'll do a primary survey.
- I've gotta push.
- It's okay, not yet.
Not yet. LISA: I gotta.
Sterile gloves and an OB
kit. What do we need, Julia?
CBC, coags, type, Rh.
- And?
- Fetal monitor.
- Right, fetal monitor.
- Would you care to pitch in?
Oh, I thought you'd never ask.
- Ah!
Now, don't move your neck until
we make sure that it's not broken.
I'm fine. HALEH: I
guess the C-spine is clear.
She's crowning.
- All right, Mom. You can push now.
- Ah!
Get ready, twins, go quick.
Delivering the shoulders.
It's a girl.
- Umbilical clamp.
- Is she okay?
She's got a great set of lungs.
Oh, baby looks great.
Apgar of 9. One off for color.
Congratulations, Mom.
One down, one to go.
Hi, you're beautiful.
Hi.
We paged OB down for the
twins. Has anybody seen them?
Coburn's in an
emergency C-section.
She'd send a resident soon
as she could free one up.
The husband just showed.
He's the wet, anxious guy.
- Mr. Salamunovich?
- Yeah, Chris, is Lisa okay?
First baby's out and healthy,
we're waiting on the second.
Oh, God.
- Can I help you?
- You don't remember me.
Should I?
God, it's amazing how little
has changed around here.
- My dad used to be on staff.
- Mm-hm.
Mark Greene. I'm
his daughter, Rachel.
We have three boys
under the age of 10 at home.
Three? LISA: Yep.
It's a madhouse.
But I wanted a girl.
So before Chris went in to get
snipped, we decided to try one more time.
We ended up with twins.
- Hey.
- What are the chances of that?
Hey, little Camille. Hey.
- We're still going with Camille?
- Yeah, fine by me.
It was my grandmother's name.
Honey, keep an eye on the clock.
Preschool pick-up is in an hour.
- Oh, I'll just have my mom go get him.
- No, no, no, you should... Oh!
- Another contraction.
- Okay, big push this time.
Okay, big push.
- Fetal heart rate's down.
- What does that mean?
- It could be a sign of distress.
- Okay, Mom, let's get this baby out.
I can see the head.
- Meconium.
- Give me suction now, please.
What's meconium?
It's in the baby's
intestine prior to birth.
It can pass into the amniotic fluid
and get into their lungs during birth.
Ah!
- How bad is that?
- Clamp and cut.
If it gets into the lungs,
then she has to be intubated.
It has to be sucked out.
It's another girl, honey.
- She's not crying.
- That's intentional.
- We don't want her to breathe in the mec.
- Laryngoscope and suction, please.
Mom's heart rate's up to 140.
- Some bleeding.
- Two liters of saline, wide open.
- A lot of bleeding. BRENNER:
Let's get more access.
Put gentle traction on the cord.
Get two units from the blood bank.
Meconium at the epiglottis.
She's cyanotic. - Honey?
- Poor tone.
- Is she okay?
- Systolic's down to 90.
- Prime the rapid infuser, where is OB?
Ah!
Is that the placenta?
That looks like
uterine inversion.
- What?
- Need some steriles.
The uterus has turned itself inside out
and has pushed itself through the cervix.
I need you to push it back in.
Ah!
- It won't go.
- All right, IV nitro, right now!
Ah!
Set up for an intubation
on Mom. Two units of FFP.
Let's have the blood
bank stay ahead four units.
Pressure's only
65/45. Second unit's in.
- Hang two more.
- No, it won't go.
- Four units of mag.
- What's happening?
If we can't get your wife's uterus
in, we have to take her to the OR.
Put her under and see if
we can relax the uterus a bit.
- Heart rate's up to 140.
- Try one more time, push hard.
Really push.
Come on, get in
there, really push.
- It's in.
- It's in?
- Yeah.
- Great. Hold off on the nitro.
20 of Pit in a liter, wide open.
Keep pressure on the cervix. Push
in, all the way up to your forearm.
I want you to massage
the uterus at the umbilicus.
OB's here. Heard you had twins.
We just reduced an inverted
uterus, she's bleeding with accreta.
- I'm bringing her up. CHRIS:
What are you going to do?
- You're the dad?
- Yes.
We need to stop the bleeding or
else we give her a hysterectomy.
- How about the twins? BRENNER:
Second one aspirated mec.
- I paged Pedes.
- Should I let go?
- Don't let go till they tell you to.
- Should I go?
Your wife is gonna
be under anesthesia...
but we'll give you updates
from the operating room.
Your wife mentioned something about
having to pick up your kids at school.
If you need to make a call, you
can use that phone on the wall there.
Sarah, Sarah!
Wait. GATES: Hey!
- I thought you couldn't pick me up.
- I couldn't sleep, get in.
But I was gonna go
to Madison's to study.
I'll give you a ride, I have
to meet Alex to finish the car.
So, what's up, Tony?
You ever play I
Never? A drinking game.
I haven't been drinking, okay?
- I Never?
- I've heard of it.
I mean, some kids from school
have played it at parties and stuff.
How many drinks do you think
it'd take to be drunk enough to die?
- What?
- What do you weigh, 90 pounds?
How many drinks would you have to
down before the alcohol would kill you?
- What do you think?
- I don't know.
- Five, 10, 20, 50?
- I don't know, 20?
- Try six.
- Six?
Yeah, that could do
it. That could kill you.
Hand me your phone.
Give me your... I'll give it back
to you. I just wanna... Give it.
Do me a favor.
Next time you're at a party and you're
drinking, you've had too much to drink.
Or you're throwing
up, or your friends are...
or somebody's texting you
saying they're throwing up...
hit that.
"Help"?
- Who's it call?
- Me.
And I'll come, no
questions asked.
I'll help you, I'll help your
friends, I'll make sure you're okay.
No questions asked?
When did it stop raining?
- How's that second twin doing?
- Intubated, waiting for Pedes.
- Did Mom get to the OR okay?
- Yeah.
I'm going for coffee,
anybody want a latte?
- Sure, non-fat, double shot.
- Non-fat, double shot.
Mocha frap, extra foam.
Excuse me, I'm not
sure I'm in the right place.
My daughter-in-law's here
somewhere, having twins?
Is her name Lisa? Come with me.
Go right in and just
check in with that nurse.
- Julia, there's a call for you, Oncology.
- Thanks.
Hey, you guys know a doctor
used to work here named Greene?
His daughter was on my
tour, applying to med school.
- Rachel?
- Yeah, I think so.
You're kidding me.
Is she still around?
I dropped the tour
off at the dean's office.
They're doing
interviews this afternoon.
Rachel?
- Dr. Carter!
- Hey, look at you.
You're all grown
up. How old are you?
- Twenty-two.
- Oh, my God.
I remember you when you were...
Now you're going to
medical school, huh?
- Took your MCATs?
- Yeah.
- Where you doing your undergraduate?
- Duke.
Elizabeth's on faculty there,
so I get a good deal on tuition.
- Elizabeth Corday?
- Yeah, actually she flew up with me.
Elizabeth is in Chicago? What
are you both doing later tonight?
I don't know. I think
we're seeing some friends.
No, no, no. You have to come
to this thing that we're doing.
Rachel Greene?
This is my number. Give this
to Elizabeth, have her call me.
- It's good to see you, good luck in there.
- Good to see you. Thanks.
Thanks, yeah.
Path says it's primary
effusion lymphoma.
- Who's this?
- My guy who couldn't breathe.
- What's his prognosis?
- Median survival is two months.
And his options?
Chemo and radiation could
give him a couple months.
- You told him he has cancer?
- Yeah, a couple hours ago.
- Brave.
- Or maybe he's just relieved.
- Relieved?
- Dr. Brenner?
To finally know how and
when after all these years.
Back and forth, keep it smooth.
Excellent. Good. That'll do it.
Yeah, man, it looks good.
You were right about the color.
I don't know. Cobalt blue
would've been cool too.
No. Red is more your mother.
- Yeah, all fire.
- Well, better than cold and distant.
- If you say so.
- I know so.
- She's gonna love this.
- Definitely.
- Sorry, I've been gone so long.
- Oh, that's okay, Gerry came by.
Gerry Gugliemotto,
Dr. Wise. She is very nice.
- Great to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
Gerry brought me gardenias.
I just love gardenias.
Don't you? I mean, the smell.
The rest of your labs came
back, everything looks clear.
Except for the cancer.
It means your body could
tolerate chemotherapy.
- No, no, thanks.
- It could buy you a few more months.
I've already had an
extra 20 years, doc.
I should have died with
my friends in the '80s.
You're still here.
Tommy and Bill.
Jeff and David.
- Remember Michael Thomas?
- Of course, I do.
Little Bobby?
So many people I loved.
I've been trying to live
for them, you know?
Keep their memories alive.
But I've had my
time, no regrets.
I went skydiving
last year, in Hawaii.
It was the most remarkable
thing. I was floating, free.
I couldn't feel my body.
I'm afraid of heights,
but I wasn't up there.
I guess that's kind of what
I hope death is like, doc.
Floating, free in the
air, above everything.
Just watching
the world drift by.
- Is there anything I can do for you?
- Yeah, there is.
I don't want it to hurt.
We can help with that.
66-year-old woman
ruling in for MI.
Going to the cath lab any second.
Hula girl needs an x-ray of her wrist.
We've got an SBO who's
NPO and not happy about it.
A sickler with a fever.
Dislodged G-tube on an old
gal that came in from Lakeshore.
And a 3-week-old with lethargy
and cardiomegaly, admitted for echo.
As you can see, the hallucinating
trombone guy's still here.
Tox was negative, but we're trying to
find a psych bed somewhere in Chicago.
- My alcohol-poisoning girl still here?
- Family didn't want her admitted here.
They're transferring her to Mercy,
but Mercy hasn't picked her up.
Hey, Jerry. Look at
this inbox, it's empty.
All of my day-shift
paperwork is completed.
Look, it's a thing of beauty,
it's a clerical Mona Lisa.
I just wanted you to see what
an empty inbox looks like...
so you can try to replicate that
for when I come in tomorrow, okay?
- Tough day?
- About the same as every other.
- Night, y'all.
- Good night.
Watch out for the guy
in 3, he's a grabber.
Thanks.
Hi.
- You look nice.
- Oh, I got a thing to go to.
You saw a med-school
applicant today. Rachel Greene.
She's pretty great.
- She a student of yours?
- She's Mark Greene's daughter.
Mm-hm. So you have no first-hand
knowledge of her academic qualifications?
No, I've known her
since she was a kid.
Mark was a pretty great doctor.
I'm sure the apple didn't
fall too far from the tree.
She did well on the interview.
I can't say if she'll make our
final list, but she made the first cut.
- So he's a bit of a boozer?
- Stinks of bourbon by noon.
- It doesn't affect his work?
- That's the irritating thing.
Drunk as a skunk and he's
still a wonderful surgeon.
- Is that Neela?
- Yeah.
- Hey, how's the teaching going?
- Hey!
Oh, I've got mostly R-3s, very polite,
following me around like ducklings.
I'm sure they're in awe of the
depth of your surgical brilliance.
It's either that or your
exceptional beauty.
- They may just be stupid.
- Is that Neela?
- Yeah.
- Hey.
- Hey! MORRIS:
How's life on the bayou?
The bayou is like 100
miles away, Morris.
Dr. Brenner? Pedes showed
up to extubate the mec twin.
- I've gotta go, I'll speak to you later.
- Oh, okay.
- How's the mom?
- Still in surgery, I think.
- She's still in the OR?
- As far as I know, yeah.
Hey, you mind if I
tag along with you?
- See you, Neela.
- Okay, bye.
Hey, Joe. How we doing?
Suctioned out the trachea and the
stomach. No mec below the cords.
Satting at 100 percent. Vigorous
tone, good respiratory effort.
- I think we can extubate.
- Blow-by oxygen is ready.
Here we go.
Good air movement.
- Can I hold her?
- By all means.
How about you go and
prep the rest of the kids?
Oh, I gotta go.
Good work, doctors.
- Thanks, Joe.
- Yeah.
What's the mom still
doing up in the OR?
She's probably already out.
Sometimes, they forget to call.
Hey, guys. You wanna
meet your sisters?
- Yeah.
- Yes.
- Come on.
- All right.
- Hey.
- Hey. Hey, kiddo. Look at this.
- Look. Hi, love.
- Hey, Ma.
- Look at this.
- Look.
You got sisters.
Where's my mom?
82-year-old woman with history of MS
and pyelonephritis on home IV therapy.
Now with altered mental status
and respiratory distress. BP's 60 palp.
Gave 500 cc's of saline to get her
pressure up but it's going to her lungs.
She's been coughing
and groaning terrible.
- She's burning up.
- Pulmonary edema, probably septic.
This is the second time we've been here.
We've been taken care of by Dr. Gates.
Her parents around?
They've been here all day,
they must be around somewhere.
Hey, Tony? Elderly MS
lady just came in with sepsis.
Husband said you've
been treating her.
- You look tired.
- Thanks.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, this...
This 17-year-old girl came in
last night with alcohol poisoning.
BA 420. Still
hasn't come around.
She was texting her friend all
night, telling her she was throwing up.
Friend thought it was cool.
Mr. Manning.
Marjorie's not
doing too well, huh?
I know a lot of us never actually
thought that this day would come.
In fact, I think I
was one of them.
But here we are in
this beautiful facility.
Finally ready to provide
state-of-the-art outpatient services...
to the HIV/AIDS community,
the homeless, families in need.
Medical care, dental care,
daycare, counseling, services.
Services that have been sorely
lacking at County for many years.
I don't wanna try your
patience by rambling on too long.
But I hope you'll bear
with me for a moment...
while I talk about why we chose to
name this the Joshua Carter Center.
My wife and I had a son
and we named him Joshua.
And he died.
Excuse me.
And it seemed so
senseless that we...
That we... My wife
and I, we struggled...
to find some sort
of meaning in it.
And in the aftermath
of our small tragedy...
we realized that we could make
a difference in other people's lives.
Other people experiencing
their own small tragedies.
And that made, somehow,
the loss of Joshua bearable.
Thank you so much for coming.
Bravo.
- You done good.
- I didn't embarrass myself?
I wouldn't go that far.
You came, I didn't
think you would.
Neither did I.
Sorry I was late,
flight was delayed.
That's...
That was a beautiful speech.
- Hey, John.
I want you to meet Wendy
Spence from the Ford Foundation.
Right over here.
Your wife has low blood
pressure from the sepsis.
But giving her IV fluids will only
cause more damage to the lungs.
We discussed this when you
wanted to take her home, Paul...
that this would
most likely happen.
I didn't realize.
Please, do something.
Well, Marjorie has a DNR,
she doesn't want us to intervene.
Oh. I've got her
power of attorney here.
Yeah, that means I
can decide for her, right?
Your wife has a degenerative
disease that's left her debilitated...
without enough strength
to fight off this infection.
Even with
aggressive treatment...
she would only live a week
or two in the ICU on machines.
A ventilator, dialysis, IV pumps
to keep her blood pressure up.
It's only going to prolong
the pain and suffering.
I'm not ready to lose her.
It's time to talk about how to make
her as comfortable as possible.
Paul?
Excuse me, I'm here
to check on a patient.
- You are?
- Dr. Wise from the ER.
I called but I got put on hold.
We're swamped, couple of
people called in sick, stomach flu.
We brought a woman up, inverted
uterus, bleeding with an accreta.
Her name's Salamunovich.
Dr. Zwerling went
out to find the family.
They're downstairs, they have a
bunch of kids. One of the twins had mec.
Did she have to have
the hysterectomy?
No, she went into DIC, they coded
her for over an hour and she died.
It wasn't me. It wasn't me.
Here. Make a wish and
blow out the candles.
- Very funny, very funny.
- What'd you wish?
I wished that nobody told
you guys it was my birthday.
- Cut the cake.
- What are you doing here?
I wanted to give
you your present.
- How'd you get here?
- I drove.
- Drove? Drove what?
- Well, wanna see it?
- Go ahead. We got it.
- Yeah.
Maybe...
Hey, the twins are doing great.
They're keeping one
overnight in the NICU...
but the other one's already
on the way to the nursery.
What?
- What are you doing?
- Just one second.
- Give me one second.
- I'm working.
Mom, just one
minute. You'll love it.
What are you doing?
You drove that?
Whose car is that?
- Alex, do they know you have it?
- Mom.
Nobody's gonna let a
16-year-old kid drive that car.
- Open this.
- Whose car is that, Alex?
Just open the box.
Mom, it's yours.
It was pretty banged up at
first, but Tony helped me fix it up.
- Alex did all the work.
- No, no.
- Get in, go.
- What?
- Go, Mom.
- Oh, my God, are you kidding?
It's beautiful.
Are you serious? Are you...?
Mom, just turn it over.
Oh, my God.
I don't know if I can do this.
Do what?
This. Every day.
Sure you can.
People need help and
you know how to help them.
And if I can't help them?
You do the best you can, then
you go home, you get some sleep...
and you come back the next
day and you help the next one.
I'll see you tomorrow.
I should have grabbed
a jacket. It's freezing.
Feels good. I like it brisk.
- Brisk? You could hang meat out here.
- So go wait inside.
Not like we need
you to push gurneys.
Global warming? Those scientists
should spend April in Chicago.
49-year-old woman, laceration
to the forehead from a bottle.
- Vitals stable en route.
- What happened?
- Drunken brawl at the Marriott.
- Bitch cut me.
A free-for-all. Chairs
flying, champagne bottles.
We had to wait for the
cops to arrive to break it up.
Take her, I'll get the next one.
28-year-old female,
blunt trauma to the head.
- Lacerations to the left forearm.
- She broke my damn arm.
- Tiffany, you're dead, you hear me?
- You hit me with a chair.
It was like all-star
wrestling in there.
- At a wedding?
- My wedding.
You did this at my wedding, Mom.
That's what you wanted?
To ruin everything?
- That's your mother?
- Worse, my new mother-in-law.
That's not true.
Totally not true.
Yes, it is. You were there, yes.
No. I never pulled a guy's Foley
without deflating the balloon first.
You did. The patient
was so angry...
- he threw an emesis basin at your head.
- A Foley is for collecting urine.
Okay, what about the time where
he got crazy with Dermabond?
- And glued the lady's eye shut?
- That I did do, actually.
What about the time
when he spent three hours...
doing a one-inch head
lac without an x-ray?
He discovers there's still glass
in it, he had to go and do it again.
Really glad you came.
Don't believe them, Reese.
- Should we head out for a nightcap?
- Yeah, I'm in, you coming?
Gotta get this young man home.
- Come on.
No, no, no. It's a school night.
Gotta go to... No, get
you home. Go to sleep.
Drop Reese off with Cleo, then
come back out. The night's young.
I was gonna try Elizabeth,
see if they wanna drop by.
Great.
Elizabeth's an old friend.
No, a friend.
- So?
- So yeah?
- Yeah.
- You know, maybe, maybe. Maybe.
- All right, ready?
- Yeah.
- Meet you there.
- Okay, great.
What were you talking about?
- What?
- With Kerry Weaver.
Africa. She was just
back last summer.
Visit friends.
It's gorgeous, John.
Do you wanna join us for drinks?
I'm a bit tired.
And it's 5 a.m. in Paris.
How long are you staying?
I leave tomorrow night.
It's hard for me
to be here, John.
I know, I'm glad you came.
Me too.
Can I buy you lunch tomorrow?
Go to Shaw's. Eat
too much seafood.
Take a walk by the lake.
It's supposed to be a nice day.
I was thinking about Joshua.
He'd be 5. Nearly 6.
I think about him
almost every day.
Lunch?
Maybe.
Call me in the morning.
Kem?
78-year-old man in
from the nursing home.
Penile pain, deformity and
bruising. Sorry I called you in on this.
I just don't feel very comfortable
with him alone, he's kind of randy.
Welcome back, doc. You
bring yourself a chaperon?
Mr. Thunhurst. You're
having penile pain?
Hurts like a son
of a bitch, doc.
Let's take a look.
- You're sexually active, I take it?
- Oh, yeah.
I don't need Viagra either.
The odds at the
nursing home are great.
I mean, women outlive
men, it's at least 4-to-1.
- You use condoms, I take it?
- Oh, you betcha, the big ones.
All right, you
fractured your penis.
Fractured?
- There's a bone in there?
- No bone.
A tear of the fibrous sheath
called the tunica albuginea.
Swelling, bruising, hematoma,
standard eggplant deformity.
Usually happens when the female is
on top. Was your partner on top, sir?
What? Cowgirl position?
Oh, no, no. That's not for me.
We were going at it
in the nurses' station...
while they were
running the movie night.
I slipped out and Mr. Fred
hit the edge of the desk.
He's gonna need retrograde urethrogram
to make sure there's no damage...
and surgery to evacuate the
hematoma and repair the albuginea.
Tony? THUNHURST: Surgery?
- How long am I out of action?
- Six weeks.
Good Lord.
What am I gonna tell the girls?
Paramedics have a chest pain...
and MS lady's breathing
is scaring the husband.
So do you like the car?
It's incredible and amazingly
cool, but I can't keep it.
Why not?
Alex couldn't afford that. I barely give
him enough to support his iTunes habit.
- He worked his ass off on that car.
- I can't take a car from you, Tony.
It was a piece of junk, he did
all the work, we found the parts.
It still must have cost
you hundreds of dollars.
Thousands of dollars?
Alex learned to rebuild a car. If
you don't take it, you'll break his heart.
Hey, that rule-out
MI is pulling up.
Talk Mr. Manning through what's
going on. I'll be there soon as I can.
If you're thinking about
selling the Mustang...
I will give you
$500 cash for it.
- Go away, Jerry.
- Seven hundred?
Oh, is Dr. Gates coming?
- Yeah, he'll be here soon.
- Because she stopped breathing.
And I thought she was gonna...
And then she started up again.
Yeah. Her irregular
breathing is completely natural.
It's all part of the
dying process.
Seventy-two years.
- I'm sorry?
- Seventy-two years.
I met her in the sixth grade.
That's how long we've known
each other. Seventy-two years.
And her family had
moved in from Nebraska...
because they lost the farm,
you know, during the Depression.
And Mrs. Ross, our teacher...
she said to take the
empty desk next to mine.
That was it.
You know?
I never looked at
another girl for 72 years.
You hear that, Mrs. Manning?
Not once, sweetheart.
Yeah, just, like, move it out.
Well, this is a thoroughly
disreputable looking group.
Oh, my God, Elizabeth.
Oh, it's good to see you.
- How are you?
- I'm good.
- Hi, Susan.
- Hi.
Hello.
- John.
- Thank God you showed.
- You were the bait we used to...
- Oh, come on, that's not true.
You remember Rachel.
- Oh, my goodness.
- Hey.
- Hello, Peter.
- I remember you when you were this big.
- Yes, everyone's been saying that.
- I can imagine, look at you.
- What can I get you?
- I'll have a cranberry juice.
- You look great.
- Thank you.
- And for you?
- I'd like a margarita, no salt.
- See some ID?
Absolutely.
- Oh, my God.
- So how's Ella?
Oh, she's 9, gorgeous.
Now, Peter, you and Cleo
are still together, right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. She's
actually an associate...
No, no, no, I'm dating again.
- A much younger man.
Yeah, it's shameful. - No.
No?
Roger Anderson, 48, with eight
hours of substernal chest pain.
- Why wait so long?
- I thought it would go away.
- Good vitals, no ST changes.
- Am I having a heart attack?
Too soon to tell.
First she traps Donnie
into getting married...
by getting herself pregnant.
Right, innocent Donnie,
perfect little Donnie.
I have news for you, Donnie about
raped me in the back seat of his Camaro.
I warned him that all she was after
was his paycheck and health benefits.
Right, his incredible salary
working for the post office. Ow!
Then she insisted on inviting her
inbred Kentucky relatives to the reception.
It wasn't my Uncle Phil who was
found pissing in the lobby fountain! Ouch!
- Keep still then.
- Am I gonna have a scar?
- A little one.
- You hear that, Tiffany?
- I'm gonna have a scar.
- Yeah?
I'm gonna be on my Caribbean beach
honeymoon with a cast on my arm!
- Tiff, are you okay?
- Oh, honey, baby, she broke my arm.
- Donnie, Donnie, is that you?
- Yeah, Mom, it's me.
Donnie, she cut me.
- I'm getting stitches in my face.
- Hold my hand, please.
- Come here and see what she did to me.
- Donnie, sweetheart? Hold my hand.
- Donnie, Donnie?
- Come here now.
- Come here.
- Donnie.
- You come here right now.
I want to prepare you,
your mom's unconscious...
and the sepsis has made
her breathing more difficult.
We have her on oxygen to help
and morphine to relieve any pain.
- So she's dying?
- Yeah.
- Soon?
- Probably.
Would you look at that?
How much he loves her.
I never could understand
how he put up with that woman.
Tough as nails.
Hard on him, hard on us.
Then she gets sick and he takes
care of her for all these years.
I would've left her by the
side of the road somewhere.
You know what I was doing in the car
the whole way down from Milwaukee?
Crying.
Crying my eyes out.
Beating myself up
trying to remember...
what it was we fought
about last time we talked.
Isn't that something?
As if it mattered anymore.
Hey, you mind if I eat
this last piece of cake?
- No, knock yourself out.
- Thank you.
ER. Yeah.
What's up?
I know. Soldier Field.
No, Tommy's gonna
get us tickets. Yeah.
That's fine.
Mom. Hey, did I wake you?
Uh... Yeah.
Oh, who does Leno have on?
No. No, I'm working tonight.
How was your day?
Yeah, they got me
a cake. Chocolate.
That crazy grandson of yours, Alex,
tell you what he got me for my birthday?
A car.
No, he rebuilt...
Ah. WEAVER: Whoa.
It got so cold.
You wanna come and see what
a real doctor does for a living?
Oh, yes, a doctor in an underfunded,
over-utilized, insane asylum...
that passes for an
urban medical center.
- I'm in.
- Oh, no, it's very late.
- Don't start.
- How are you gonna get to the hotel?
- I'll call a cab.
- Come on, she's not a baby anymore.
- We'll make sure she gets back safe.
- You gonna come, Kerry?
- No, I've got an early flight.
- Peter?
No, 7 a.m. rounds.
That's a cab.
- Come here, bye.
- Bye.
- So good seeing you.
- All right.
Bye, guys! RACHEL: Bye!
Well? Ready?
Hey, our flight leaves at 9.
Car's coming to pick
us up at the hotel at 7.
Kids.
She's not a kid anymore.
Her mother would
absolutely kill me...
if she knew I'd let Carter haul her
off to the ER in the middle of the night.
Hey, want me to get you a cab?
Oh, no. I've got a rental car.
All right, well, you
want me to walk you?
Um...
Sure, thanks, yeah.
So is Cleo good?
Yeah, really good.
- Do you have any more children?
- No, no, no.
- What about you?
- What about me?
- Do you have any more kids?
- Oh, no, no.
- Are you in a relationship?
- No.
- Dating?
- No, not really.
Well, I've got a 9-year-old
at home and a busy career.
Maybe when Ella's a
little older, I might, but...
So...
this is me.
As usual, there was a problem
with the rental reservation.
This is all they had.
Well, it's... It's big.
Well, you know, if you need to
transport an infantry for any reason...
Yeah, or a rap star's entourage.
Anyway.
It was really nice
seeing you again, Peter.
Yeah.
Take care.
- Jerry, you remember Rachel.
- Yeah, I heard you were around.
- Hi, Jerry.
- Hi, you remember me?
- No way.
- Jerry!
Oh, my God.
There's a spirit of camaraderie
here. It's what makes this place work.
Everybody helps
everybody else out.
Oh, God, maggots.
Tracy, this is Rachel.
She's thinking about a
career in emergency medicine.
Run, don't walk, to Radiology.
Trust me. You don't ever,
ever want to have to do this.
I am the chosen one,
come to be known as Uhdia.
Ten of Haldol and restraints.
And he who believeth in
me shall have eternal life.
- Hey, Morris.
- Hey, Carter.
- How did the opening go?
- Good, you missed it.
You know, work. Can't
wait to see it finished.
- Give me a call, I'll give you a tour.
- Rachel, Rachel Greene?
- Hi, Chuny.
- Oh, my God, look at you.
You'll be around for a while? Don't
you dare leave before we get to catch up.
And I will deliver...
Haldol, miracle drug.
Laverne, what have you got?
Mr. Meyer here polished off a few
too many bottles of fine burgundy.
Fell off the curb in front of
Spiaggia, broke his ankle, hit his head.
- Waiting on CT and Ortho.
- Mind if I take over that IV?
Sure, no problem.
- You ever done one of these before?
- No.
Okay, well, we use an angio-cath with
a 16 gauge needle. That's a large bore.
You need that in case there's
bleeding and you have to transfuse them.
What you wanna do
is pull that skin tight...
so that the vein doesn't
roll, go in low, bevel up.
Once you're in the vein, you pull
this little gizmo out and tape it down.
Gates, is it my imagination,
or is Dr. Carter...
who is not on duty by the way,
in Trauma 1 with a patient...
demonstrating IV placement
to a college student?
- What?
- Never mind.
Jerry, why is Dr. Carter performing
medical procedures on our patients?
Because he's a doctor?
Tony?
Excuse me. One sec.
Perfect timing. That
poor bastard, his son...
Marjorie Manning died.
So...
that's it?
Can I stay with
her a little longer?
Of course, stay as
long as you'd like.
Oh, yeah. Pizza.
What is that?
A meat-lovers special,
you want a piece?
You better call a cardiologist
and schedule your first angioplasty.
- It's good.
- How old are you?
Thirty-seven.
Make an appointment
for three years from now.
You keep eating like that,
40 ought to be just about right.
No. Come on. - It's true.
- They don't get it.
Who are you?
Oh, hi, I'm Dr. Susan
Lewis, I used to work here. Hi.
What is it with men
and their penises?
I've been trying to figure
that one out for years.
Amen to that.
My trouble-urinating guy.
It turns out that he has erectile
dysfunction and he can't afford Viagra.
He takes a tube of bathroom caulk,
the kind you use around the tub...
and squeezes it
into his urethra.
It's not a religious talisman.
Get that in a biohazard bag.
Police brought in an altered old
woman, wearing one of our bracelets.
It had your name on it.
Beverly?
- Hello.
- Hello, how's her temperature?
Core is 96.
- My name is Beverly.
- Yes, I know.
She was in here yesterday.
Her daughter's name and
number should be on the chart.
- Martha or Mary...
- Margaret.
Margaret, that's right. You know, she's
gonna be worried about where you are.
Oh, Margaret is a lovely
girl. Just quiet and thoughtful.
How's your wrist, any pain?
- Oh, I broke my wrist.
- I know, I fixed it yesterday.
I fell out of a tree, Margaret was
telling me to go higher and I fell.
Really? Margaret was
telling you to go higher?
Mm-hm. She's...
Margaret's my sister.
Yeah, just a lovely girl.
You know, you really shouldn't
leave your yard. It's not safe.
Oh, you have such strong hands.
Warm and strong.
You can tell a lot about
a man by his hands.
Yes, ma'am.
Where's the daughter?
She went to call
the mortuary, I think.
Thanks.
For what?
For everything you do with Alex.
I really appreciate it.
A little cold out here to
be playing basketball, huh?
- I'm just trying to stay awake.
- Oh, yeah?
Yep. I've got...
an important call to
make in a couple hours.
I'm afraid if I close my
eyes, I'll sleep through it.
Don't you own an alarm clock?
Can't chance it.
Yeah?
- Love or money?
- What?
Well, if it's that important, it
only can be one of two things:
love or money.
- Love.
- Oh!
Hey, put a towel around that
guy. There's women in there.
Thought streakers went out with
disco and the Ford administration.
I'm going across the street.
- Want a burrito? Bean and beef.
- I'm fine.
I'll pass.
Man's a culinary
freak of nature.
Nice.
Where's your little ward?
Who, Rachel?
The women stole her
from me an hour ago.
- Are you coming back, boss?
- What?
You're hanging
around here enough.
Take some shifts,
get paid for it.
I don't know.
Maybe.
Hey, Tony, I need you.
Transport guys from
Mercy finally showed up...
for your alcohol-poisoning girl.
They tried to move her, she
started groaning, thrashing around.
Is she responsive?
I didn't stick around long enough
to find out, went looking for you.
- Stacey?
- What? What's happening?
Stacey? All right,
responds to stimuli.
- What does that mean?
- Stacey, can you hear me?
MRS. Honey. GATES:
Stacey, you're in the hospital.
I'm Dr. Gates. You were at a party,
you had a little too much to drink.
Please, is she all right?
- Stacey?
Stacey.
I need another CT.
It's gonna take a while.
- How long?
- Hour, maybe two.
I'll call Dispatch.
Doctor.
She's responding, but
not in a purposeful way.
It may be a sign of lack
of oxygen to the brain.
I'm gonna order another CT, make
sure there's no swelling in the brain.
But she's going to be okay?
Well, it's too early to tell if
her mental status will improve...
from what you see now.
But it could? - Maybe.
- CT can take her now.
- Okay, good.
- Can we go with her?
- Of course, yeah.
My first ER rotation, they
sent me to a jail ward...
to do a rectal on this
prisoner with a GI bleed.
So this guy is very sketchy,
and he's kind of a leech...
but I don't wanna
seem like a wimp.
So I close the door to
give him some privacy...
I pull on my glove, lube up my
finger and go ahead with the exam.
When I'm done, I go to the
door to leave, and it's locked.
It's a jail ward.
The doors don't
open from the inside.
So here I am, stuck with creepy
convict guy who is now laughing...
pulling up his pants, asking me if it
was as good for me as it was for him.
Oh, my God.
It took me 10 minutes of banging on that
door to finally get a nurse's attention.
Guy in Exam 2 is coughing red
snappers. Be sure and wear a mask.
- What's a red snapper?
- TB.
- Tuberculosis?
- Yup.
My first week in the ER, I forgot
Haleh's name and called her "nurse."
- As in, "Nurse, can you get me 4-by-4s?"
- Oh, bad idea.
- Nurses hate being called "nurse."
- Why?
- Because we have names.
- Or we know more than med students.
- The interns.
- More than most doctors.
So anyway, Haleh
decides to punish me...
by paging me for Tylenol
orders every 20 minutes.
I would have paged you every 10.
- Every five.
My first year in med school, the
dean comes into our very first lecture...
and he says, "I want you to
look to your left and to your right.
A year from now,
one of you'll be gone."
Our dean told us that when
I was in med school too.
- Was it true?
- No, but it scared the hell out of us.
I mean, as if we weren't
worried enough already.
Hey, what are you doing here?
Couldn't sleep. I thought I'd
come in, catch up on some charts.
Maybe check up on a baby in
the NICU I helped deliver yesterday.
- Where's Banfield?
- In Sutures.
- Stitching up drunk-and-disorderly guy.
- Get her down here now.
- What is it?
- Explosion at a power substation.
Burn and blast victims.
Three minutes out.
- How many?
- At least eight.
Chuny, clear the trauma rooms.
Jerry, get the blood
bank to send O-neg.
Dawn, make sure we have
enough morphine and rapid infusers.
Yipee-kie-yay. You wanna be
an ER doc? This is the fun part.
Industrial explosion.
Dr. C.
Morris, Triage.
EMT 1:55-year-old man
thrown against the wall.
- Diffuse abdominal pain, BP 80 palp.
- Rigid abdomen, probably spleen or liver.
Tracy. Two of O-neg. Hold for the OR.
- Yep?
Open femur, good distal pulses.
- I'll take this. Chuny.
- Yeah?
Gram of Ancef, 100 of gent,
titrate Dilaudid and call Ortho.
Julia, you're up. Laverne.
- I got Bardelli's rig.
- Good.
In V-fib on a high power line.
Epi, lidocaine and 10
shocks. Put him into asystole.
- Trauma 2?
- No, Curtain 3.
We have to hold Trauma
for the ones we can save.
A 27-year-old male, short of breath,
pulse ox, 82, decreased breath sounds.
- No facial burns?
- Pneumothorax.
Set up for a chest tube.
- Arm was blown off.
- Intubated after 10 of MS.
- All right. Sam.
- Anything to re-implant?
- Bits and pieces.
- Go.
- Dr. Carter?
- What? I'm sorry.
- You okay?
Yeah, just a little déjà vu.
Carter, are you working?
- Absolutely.
- Come on.
Burns over 90 percent of his
body, soot at the vocal cords.
Three liters of Ringers, let's
call the burn service. Okay, cool.
Dr. Greene.
Are you coming?
Tight wheezing throughout
the ride. Pulse ox, 88.
Check for singed nasal
hairs from smoke inhalation.
Set up for intubation.
Thirty-eight-year-old male...