Ariel's not overdosing.
- And you are?
- Dr. Reese.
I used to work here.
You got too close to
your patient again.
Lost all objectivity again.
Let's face it, been an
issue before, Sarah.
You arrogant son of a bitch.
You could never fathom
that you might be wrong.
That was the reason I left.
Resignation letter, going to
slip it under Goodwin's door.
Lenox is the future of the
ED. Time for me to move on.
I don't have a family
anymore because of you.
Scream, and I cut
your damn throat.
No, no, please
wait. Wait! Please!
Wait!
Hey.
Oh, hey. What's up?
Do you want to go grab a coffee?
You know, I can't. I got
rounds starting in five.
Are you... are you good?
Um...
Carl didn't show up for our
first therapy appointment.
Oh, man.
Do you... do you know why?
He lost track of
time, apparently.
OK, that's lame.
- Yeah.
- But don't worry about it.
Totally typical, much
harder to get men to show up
for therapy appointments.
I gotta dash.
But I will come find you later,
and we'll strategize, OK?
- OK.
- Looking forward to it.
Come on!
Oh.
Hey, hey, call security.
Code Silver. 10th floor.
Oh, no. No. No.
Ugh.
No!
Stop!
Hey, come here. Come on.
Come on. Come on.
I can't... I can't...
- I can't feel it...
- I got you.
I got you. I got you.
I need help! Maggie?
- Get me a gurney.
- Right now, let's go!
- Sharon?
- What the hell happened?
Abdominal stab wound.
We need a trauma room right now.
- She's lost a lot of blood.
- Maggie?
We're going to
Trauma 1. Let's go.
She's been out of
it in the elevator.
- Let's go. Move it.
- Let's rotate.
Line her up, get
her resuscitated
while I get the OR ready.
- Come on.
- Oh, my...
Let's get an IV.
- Bilateral breath sounds.
- Going over you.
Radial pulse is
weak and thready.
- Dr. Archer.
- All right, activate MTP.
2 grams TXA.
- She needs a Cordis. Kai?
- Yeah?
EFAST her. Get a good
look at her heart.
- Already on it.
- Cordis.
We're going to need to intubate.
Heart rate 140. BP 80/55.
Sharon? We got you.
We're going to get you
through this, Sharon.
All right, push a dose of
epi so she doesn't code.
10 of etomidate. 100 of sux.
Epi on board. Etomidate
and sux going in.
- What happened?
- I don't know.
No pericardial effusion.
- OK, I'm in.
- Damn it.
Free fluid in the belly.
Bleeding into her abdomen.
All right, let's
find the source.
- Let's get her to the hybrid.
- All right.
Let's go.
- OK.
- Yeah.
Let's rotate. Here we go.
Let's go. Let's go, let's
go, let's go, let's go.
I just heard. I
can't believe it.
I should have forced Sharon
to let security trail her.
Just tell me one time
anytime anyone's ever been able
to force Sharon to do anything.
Peter, it isn't your
fault, all right?
Everybody, law
enforcement included,
thought that this
stalker thing was over.
Ms. Goodwin's alive.
She's stable.
She's not out of the woods yet.
Bad news is the knife
lacerated her pancreas
and her common bile duct.
Damage is extensive,
but temporized.
Some tough decisions
need to be made.
- Maggie?
- Yeah?
Who's her medical proxy?
Her daughter, Tara.
She's on her way.
All right, let me know
when she gets here.
- Yeah.
- You know...
Just, what...
w-what's really going on here?
She's hour-to-hour, OK?
And we'll see how
well she resuscitates.
And...
you know, it's a
waiting game now.
Thank you.
What's her condition?
Her local wound
exploration was negative.
The knife didn't hit any organs.
That's some kind of luck.
It's not luck.
Ms. Goodwin knows her anatomy.
She was avoiding
the major organs.
Is she dead?
We'll clean her up.
Then she's all yours.
Then I suggest you
get her out of here.
What's going on?
Where's Dr. Reese?
Listen, I completely get
how upsetting this must be.
But the fact of the matter is
that while you're
here at Gaffney,
I'm responsible for your
care, not Dr. Reese.
This is about the pills I took.
Why do I keep having
to repeat myself?
I told you it was an accident.
I just... I just got
confused. That's it.
I believe that you believe that.
Really, I do.
The trouble that I'm
having is that you've been
taking antidepressants
for a long time, right?
And you know that
the appropriate dose
is one pill a day.
So what I'm struggling with
is how could you all of a sudden
just take a dozen,
and it's an accident?
I-I don't know,
OK? I don't know.
But it's not what you think.
Well, what do you
think that I think?
You obviously know I
tried to kill myself.
Well, I mean, since
you bring it up,
Dr. Reese actually
left that part out.
Look, this was not that, OK?
I... I don't want to die.
And you know why?
It's because of
Dr. Reese, because she...
she brought me back
from a very dark place,
so if you don't mind, I'd
like to talk to her now.
There is one more thing
that I think that you have
a fundamental right to know.
OK, which is?
You have not actually
been taking citalopram.
What are you talking about?
You've been taking a placebo.
A placebo?
Yeah.
So Dr. Reese lied to
me the whole time.
Look, I know that
Dr. Reese was acting
with your best
interests at heart, OK?
You know, she was trying
a new course of treatment
where others had failed.
And believe it or not, placebos,
when used appropriately,
can be effective for depression.
I just don't believe that
that was the case here
and that you have a
right to know that.
I thought I was getting better.
I know it's a whole
lot to process.
I'm sorry to
interrupt, Dr. Charles.
Do you have a minute?
I'll be right back.
What?
It's not Sharon.
But I need you to meet me
in the conference room ASAP.
Why?
Look, I know this is the
worst possible timing,
but Dr. Reese filed a
professional misconduct claim
- against you last night.
- What?
I know.
Look, from the
IDPH's perspective,
Ariel Sparkman is a
potential suicide risk
on a 72-hour hold, OK?
If they deem you unfit to
continue as her psychiatrist,
we need to find a
suitable replacement
before the hold ends.
Not to mention, if
this claim is upheld...
I could lose my license. You
have got to be kidding me.
Daniel, I'm sorry, OK?
But, please, we just have
to deal with this now.
Allie, Dr. Abrams
from Neurosurgery.
I've asked him to consult
on your new imaging.
I'm Grace, Allie's foster mom.
So what I'm seeing
is consistent with
progressive Moyamoya disease.
Her carotid arteries are...
Are severely narrowed,
and I'm not getting
enough blood flow to my brain.
Sorry. This is boring you?
You bore me, Dr. Abrams.
You're reading me a
book I've heard before.
Well, forgive the
redundancy, young lady,
- but you need surgery.
- Oh, I don't think so.
Already had three, and
they didn't do jack.
Allie.
The last so-called surgeon
failed to establish
perfusion to my left side
and didn't even
bother with my right.
Which is why it's
still progressing.
Your history is one of
endless mini strokes,
and imaging shows
some concerning
true strokes as well, and
if that's not corrected...
I could die.
You could suffer permanent,
life-threatening damage.
- Yes.
- Please, save me, Dr. Abrams.
Um, I'd like to
restore blood flow
with the direct bypass
bilaterally today.
Yeah, but there is one issue.
Well, Allie knew
you'd suggest surgery,
so she has a request.
Oh, do tell, Dr. Frost.
Well, she doesn't
want her hair cut off.
The kids make fun
of her at school.
They call me a
freak. I hate it.
All right, that's impossible.
I need the area around the
incision to be cleared.
Hair gets in the way, and
that's an infection risk.
Unacceptable. I choose death.
DCFS gave signed consent?
- They did.
- Good.
OR is booked for 2:00
p.m. See you then.
I'm so sorry
about Ms. Goodwin.
Thank you.
It's important to
me that you know
I filed the claim yesterday.
OK, so have either
of you been through
a misconduct claim before?
No.
I've been sued
before, but I've never
been subject to a complaint
from a colleague before.
All right, well, it's
a multi-step process,
the first of which
is to establish
the validity of the claim.
A risk management facilitator
will run the proceedings,
and an expert witness
in your specific field
will analyze the data,
speak to Ms. Sparkman
and decide if it should
advance to the next step.
And they should be
here momentarily.
In the meantime,
Dr. Reese, I'm wondering
if there is a chance that you
and Dr. Charles could resolve
this claim between us,
you know, here and now.
No, I'd like to proceed.
The facilitator is
stuck in traffic.
They send their
apologies. I guess...
Don't worry about it, Peter.
You know, there aren't
any other psych patients
in this hospital that need
my attention right now,
and my best friend
in the world's life
isn't hanging by a
thread a floor below us.
So, yeah, I have all
the time in the world.
No place I'd rather be.
What's going on?
Isn't Allie supposed to
be prepping for surgery?
Allie talked a lawyer
into petitioning
the ward that
greenlit her surgery,
so I've now been
forced to cancel it.
Foster kids have rights too.
Allie, I wish you'd reconsider.
You've known me
three weeks, Grace.
So please be a
peach and butt out.
She won't win, but obviously
protecting her hair seems
to be more important
than protecting her own life.
Allie, you need to
have this surgery.
This is your fault,
too, Dr. Frost.
Me? How do you figure?
You lied to me.
You told me Dr. Abrams
was the number one
neurosurgeon in the country.
- I am.
- He is.
Not according to the
"Northwestern Journal
of Neurological Medicine."
That distinction belongs
to a Dr. Harrison DeSocio.
Is he available today?
Those rankings are
highly political.
Oh, and you're not
very good at politics,
are you, Dr. Abrams.
What a profound shock.
As you kids like
to say, I'm out.
Allie, is this really
about your hair?
I've been told three times
by three different doctors
that they'd fix my brain.
Every time they say I
have to cut my hair.
Every time they fail, I end
up looking like a freak.
The kids at school are
happy to point that out.
All my life, I've
been the sick kid.
I just want one small
piece of it to feel normal.
Well, you know what?
I think that is completely fair.
- You do?
- Sure.
When people keep
letting you down,
why would you keep
believing them, right?
But, hey, I am not going
to let you down, Allie,
and neither is Dr. Abrams.
Look, middle school may
feel like it's forever,
but it is the blink of an eye
compared to the
rest of your life,
which you won't get to see if
you don't have this surgery.
I know it feels right now like
you have no choice, I get that.
But, Allie, choice is what
lies on the other side
when you are free
of this disease.
So come on, please,
just drop the petition.
Let us help you.
I'm sorry,
but until you can promise me
that Dr. Abrams
won't touch my hair,
my answer is no.
Um, what's a Whipple procedure?
I would take the head
off the pancreas,
the first part of
the small intestine,
the gallbladder, and the
damaged common bile duct,
remove them, repair and
reroute her digestive tract
so that it functions normally.
That sounds like a lot.
It is, but it would
allow your mother
to live the life she's used to.
Dennis, what do you think?
Sharon's lost a lot of blood.
And if you factor
in her diabetes,
the risk of complications
is pretty high.
Look, I really would
like to move forward.
I've considered all the risks,
and this is her best plan.
And what if we didn't
do the Whipple?
Without the surgery now,
she would need a
biliary drainage bag.
And due to complications
associated with that,
it's likely she wouldn't be
able to eat by mouth again
for the rest of her life.
Her life is our primary concern.
And mine.
But if drainage fails,
I wouldn't be able
to get back in for
at least a year
or longer because
of the scar tissue
from the injury, so...
I can't risk losing mom.
No Whipple.
Of course. Of
course, I understand.
Look, look, I know that
this is frustrating.
When the hell did everybody stop
listening to me around here?
They're just afraid,
Dean. Everyone is.
Yeah, well, Ms.
Goodwin is going to pay
the price for that fear.
Dissect here with
the right angle.
Wait, stop. What is that?
Biliary drain is dislodged.
The common bile duct is totally
transected at the ampulla.
Bile from her liver,
pancreatic enzymes
are leaking everywhere in the
back wall of the bile duct.
Draining her isn't
going to work.
So we'll have to reattach
the duct over a stent.
No, no.
The damage to the
pancreas and the ampulla,
it'll just happen
all over again.
We have to do the Whipple.
We already need to
reattach the duct.
It would be irresponsible not
to do the entire procedure.
Dr. Archer, we need
Tara's permission
if we're going to
be changing course.
No, actually we don't.
It's part of all the
other indicated procedures
on the current consent.
She and Dr. Washington
were very clear that...
Ms. Goodwin is not going to
spend the rest of her life
attached to a bag and an IV.
It's my call, we're doing it.
Hand me the clip and plier.
Hey. Where's Grace?
Off finding me Jell-O.
She thinks I'm 6.
I take it you're not
her biggest fan, huh?
She's fine, actually.
But she'll be gone
in a few months.
They always go.
Did you talk to Dr. Abrams?
I did, yes.
But he is not willing to
compromise the surgery.
And, Allie, look, I
totally understand.
I mean, he's just
trying to protect you.
I don't like him.
I think you might.
Look, Allie, I know
a lot of surgeons
have made you promises
that they couldn't keep,
but Dr. Abrams is
not one of them.
All right? I have
full confidence
that he will succeed
where others have failed.
Sorry, no dice.
Yeah, I thought
you might say that,
which is why I brought you this.
I'm not going to let
you cut my hair either.
It took forever to grow it
back out after my last surgery.
Yeah, I bet.
But this is me trying to make
your situation 1% fairer.
I can't make middle school
kids nicer, all right?
But I can make sure that you
don't go through this alone.
So here's the deal,
whatever Dr. Abrams
does to your hair,
you can also do to mine.
- If I'm bald, you're bald.
- Oh, even better.
You get to be the one
that makes me bald.
The other doctors
will make fun of you.
Oh, trust me when I say
they already do, so...
So? Deal?
Deal.
Yes.
- All right.
- Yeah.
Dr. Cuevas, did you assess
Ariel Sparkman earlier today?
I did.
She adamantly maintained
that yesterday's
overdose was accidental.
Do you think Ariel
is being truthful?
She certainly appears
to believe it.
But?
Well, her behavior
is undeniable.
She took 12 pills she
believes to be antidepressants
when her prescribed
dose is only one,
and I certainly observed
a great deal of anxiety
in my conversation with her,
and in light of her
two suicide attempts...
Two suicide attempts?
Yes, the first was
about eight months ago,
plus the incident from
yesterday morning.
Hold on, I'm
sorry, Dr. Cuevas,
but not only do you work here,
you report to Dr. Charles?
This is a clear
conflict of interest.
Point taken, Dr. Reese,
but Dr. Cuevas is just
an expert witness.
She doesn't decide the case.
And, quite frankly,
given the urgency
with which you
filed your petition,
it was our only option
given such short notice.
Mm.
Please continue, Dr. Cuevas.
Ariel is upset because
she can't see Dr. Reese
while on her 72-hour
cycle because
Dr. Reese's Gaffney
privileges were revoked
by Dr. Charles last night.
But she is infuriated
she's being denied
her citalopram
dose today when...
Wait. I'm sorry, Dr. Cuevas.
You said she was infuriated
that she was denied her...
her dose today?
I told her this morning that
she had been taking sugar
pills for seven months.
Wait, you broke the placebo?
Yes, because she
deserved to know.
I'm sorry, am I the only
one who's lost here?
Wait, wait, so I interviewed
this morning in an attempt
to get some clarity on why
she took 12 antidepressants.
So what we're saying
is that even though
she knew they were placebo,
she asked for them again?
Maybe she didn't believe you.
Or more likely...
she forgot you told her.
Exactly.
I'm thinking EML,
episodic memory loss.
Which would explain
why she didn't remember
taking so many pills.
Yeah, she was confused
because, well,
she couldn't remember.
Maybe even a little embarrassed.
So that's the name she gave it
to make sense of it
that it was an accident.
Which means she isn't depressed
and something else is
causing her memory loss.
That's right, and the
root causes of EML
can be very serious, so we
need to figure this out.
So are we good?
Are we done here?
Clear the room, please.
- Sure.
- OK.
Tara and Dennis are
asking for an update.
It's all good. Kai's
closing her up,
and then we're taking
her to surgical ICU.
All right, good. They'll
be happy to hear that.
I can't believe we just
did a trauma Whipple.
Make sure you're
closing her right.
Take 1 centimeter
by 1 centimeter
bites of fascia.
We don't want a hernia after
all the work we've done.
This isn't my first
abdominal closure.
- What the hell was that?
- Pulse ox is dropping.
Almost done here.
Dean, she's more difficult
to ventilate now.
Peak pressures are high.
Her X-ray showed broken
ribs on the right side.
Right.
Marty, what do you hear?
No sound on the right side.
Trachea's deviated.
She's got a tension
pneumothorax.
- All right, needle her.
- She's in asystole.
14 gauge Angiocath and
get the crash cart.
Damn it. Push epi!
I'll take over compressions.
- Epi's in.
- All right, pulse check.
No pulse. Still asystole.
Move over.
Another round of epi.
Come on, Ms. Goodwin.
Come on. Come on.
Ms. Goodwin is on
her way to the ICU.
She's going to be OK.
Thank you, Dean.
- I owe you everything.
- Oh, you owe me nothing.
We all wanted the same thing.
Thank you for saving my mom.
Graves' disease? No way.
Physical presentation
doesn't match.
Oh, well, that's
the end of that.
What does that mean?
That you always
have to be right.
I am wrong all the time.
Don't give me that
fake mea culpa BS.
One of your best moves.
Close cousin to the
double-edged compliment...
you build me up and then
tear me right back down.
I might have pushed
you hard on occasion
because I believed in
you, but tear you down?
Give me one example?
You called me
insubordinate and reckless
for using exposure
therapy on a patient.
Could that have been the
time when you let a patient,
who had been having
recurring visions
of stabbing his wife to death,
put a knife to your throat?
Not walking that one back.
My point is you did
not trust me to decide
- how much was too much.
- Trust you to decide.
It was the third or fourth
time you'd crossed that line.
What line?
The line where what was
going on in your own life
compelled you to overpersonalize
your treatment of patients
and put yourself in danger.
- I almost fired you.
- Well, I was a kid, OK?
I was still learning.
And you're one to tell
me about crossing lines.
You? You gave Tic
Tacs to patients
on more than one occasion
and just told them...
Completely different,
and you know it.
How? Because the
only difference
is that it's coming
out of your mouth.
Only you get to decide
how far is too far,
and you just move the line
whenever it suits you.
And this placebo
situation is no different.
Let's just say that we're right
about episodic memory loss.
OK, well, when did it start?
How often did it
happen? Who cares?
You kept prescribing
a fake antidepressant
to somebody who is suicidal.
Ariel tried to commit suicide
while she was on citalopram.
And you and I both know
that one of the most
dangerous proven possible
side effects of SSRIs
is suicidal ideation.
OK?
So I had a hunch that the
pills were responsible,
but Ariel deeply believed
they were helping her,
so I consulted my colleagues
and several
significant new studies
and switched her to a placebo.
Yes, without telling her.
But guess what? It worked.
Why didn't you tell
me all this before?
Your voice
stayed in my head for so
long after I left here,
and I just went on
second guessing myself,
like I couldn't
do anything right
unless you were
there to tell me so.
So when I learned Ariel had
been brought to Gaffney,
I was admittedly a
little anxious and...
and then also excited because
I realized I missed you.
But then you just
went right back in
with your questions
and your judgments
and I just felt like a
little kid again, OK?
And I hated it.
You want to know
the real reason why
I could never bring
myself to fire you,
and why I kept you
around? The real reason?
It's because you
were right so much.
And I don't mean right in
a, oh, that's a sharp kid.
She's going to make a
great shrink one day.
I mean, in a complex,
diagnostic, like, why didn't
I think of that kind of way.
- Yeah, right.
- You don't believe me?
How about the depressed florist
who you figured out
just had Addison's?
The lawyer couple
who were intent on murdering
each other until you...
Wait.
Could Ariel have Addison's?
Sodium levels are a big
red flag for Addison's,
and hers... hers were normal.
Yes, but she's been
craving salty foods.
Maybe because her body
is trying to correct
its low sodium levels?
I mean, Addison's and
depression certainly fits.
Why don't we do a
ACTH stimulation,
and if we're right, put her
on prednisone right away?
Sharon's going to be OK.
- Maggie?
- Yeah.
Wait.
She's going to live.
She's strong.
Stronger than you'll ever be.
Remember that.
How'd you get the best
room in the house?
Peter Kalmick, close
personal friend.
Oh, yeah? I know him too.
Hey.
I really thought we
were going to lose her.
Oh, man. Tell me about it.
You're not going to get rid
of me for a good long time.
Good.
Because I need you
more than you know.
Mm-hmm.
- You know what?
- Mm?
I actually have a
little surprise for you.
Wait a minute.
How much morphine
are they giving me?
Sarah Reese?
It's good to see
you, Ms. Goodwin.
I'm so glad you're here.
So who's next, Will Halstead?
Why are you looking at
me like that, Daniel?
You scared the crap out of me.
Please don't do it again.
I don't intend to.
Anything you need,
anything I can get you?
Yeah, could you
tell Dr. Archer
that I'd like to
see him, please?
I'm, like, fixed?
No more surgeries?
No more surgeries.
That's wonderful news.
And Dr. Abrams knocked
it out of the park.
I'm so glad you
think so, Dr. Frost,
but I do hope the
queen is also pleased?
It depends.
Did you cut my hair off?
Of course I did.
I'm a professional.
Then you better get
your hair buzzer ready.
A promise is a promise, right?
All right, let's
skip the bonding.
I got a surgery, and I need
to check these incisions.
Looks like your freak
days are done, huh?
You look lovely.
So...
I didn't cut your hair at all.
I used the braids to part
it along the incision lines,
so it'll take about
a week to heal,
but when it does, you
can let your hair down
and no one will be the wiser.
It was your idea?
Well, it was Dr. Frost's idea.
A safe, but ridiculous solution.
Nice braiding.
Do you have a daughter?
I do.
And I also have three
older sisters who
forced me to braid their
hair when I was growing up.
Do you think they sometimes
wish they were related
to the number one
neurosurgeon in the country
instead of just you?
But fourth place isn't bad.
Can you tell him
thank you for me?
You just did.
Well, one Sharon Goodwin was
certainly happy to see you.
Look, I didn't mean
everything I said earlier.
Well, you meant some of it.
I mean, at least I hope you did.
I needed to hear it.
Listen,
you're an excellent
psychiatrist,
and if I ever did anything
to make you feel otherwise,
I sincerely apologize.
I'm so glad that you
set me on this path,
and I will be forever grateful.
Want to come work for me again?
Absolutely not.
Want to grab a couple dogs
at Gene and Jude's someday?
- Absolutely.
- Excellent.
Yeah?
Hey.
Oh, hi.
How you doing?
- I'm good.
- Yeah?
I am so sorry that I spaced
out on our appointment.
Oh.
Anyway, I cannot
believe that Carl, what,
he played hooky for
your first session?
Shrinks.
They're unbelievable.
How do you mean?
Well, you had this
incredibly crazy day.
I mean, I know that
you and Ms. Goodwin,
you're really tight.
Oh, yeah.
Well, at least she's
going to be OK.
That's good, but, you
know, you don't have to be.
This... it's a lot.
You know, I really
appreciate you saying that.
And, yeah, man, upsetting.
But look, her physical
injuries are one thing, right?
But it's, like, the
emotional trauma, that's...
that's going to be
the tricky part.
Mm.
Well, and on top
of everything else,
there's that rumor
that's going around.
What rumor?
Well, apparently your
curly-haired protégé
dragged you in front
of a military tribunal.
A military tribunal?
We figured it out.
Yeah, it's fine.
Look, this may be incredibly
presumptuous of me,
but I think that if the person
you normally download to
is currently in intensive care,
maybe I can be the one
to check in on you?
You know, like, how friends do?
You know what?
That is incredibly
thoughtful of you, really.
I just think that what I need
to do right now is I just,
I don't know, I need a little...
quiet time to process
all this crap, you know?
I totally get it.
I appreciate your understanding,
and it's so nice of
you to come down here.
- I'm here if you need me.
- Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Wait, Jackie?
Do you mind just before you go
saying a quick hello to
another friend of mine?
Oh, that guy?
Yeah, we go way back.
You think I'd be
a better patient,
but I just cannot
stand sitting around.
Well, you did almost just die,
so maybe give yourself
a little break.
Where is everybody?
Well, Dr. Asher here
is babysitting me
while Tara and Dennis grab
some dinner downstairs.
Mm.
I'll give you two a minute.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
Whew.
The VIP presidential suite.
Man, Kalmick is... he's
really treating you right.
Yeah, he is.
So, be honest with me...
how close did I come?
Candidly, I'd say you had
one foot firmly in the grave.
Whew.
Thank you for your candor.
I don't know how
much you remember.
Everything.
But, mostly, I
remember your voice
over me as I was drifting away,
so I knew I still had a chance.
I'm just glad I got
there when I did.
You not only saved my life,
but you saved my ability to
live it the way I want to.
You deserve that, Ms. Goodwin.
Oh, we are so beyond that.
Sharon, please.
OK, Sharon.
You know what else I deserve?
You tearing up your resignation.
Yes, Tara found your
letter in my office.
Yeah, that's a conversation
for another day.
No, no, it's a
conversation for now.
Boy.
I want you to promise
me that you'll stay.
This is highly manipulative,
given you just narrowly
escaped death and all.
Highly manipulative.
But Gaffney needs you, Dean.
So do I.