You got patients waiting.
I know.
Are you going to
stand here all night?
I don't know.
Are you okay?
I just can't stop
thinking about them.
Maybe you should
take some time off.
I'm okay.
Take tonight off.
I'll get someone
to cover for you.
If we get in trouble, I'll
have someone page you.
Yeah, okay.
Thanks.
No, no, no, Bob.
Intakes go here.
Discharges go there.
I have my own system.
Well, you're screwing
everything up.
Okay, Diane.
Listen. I got to go.
I'll pick you up at
9:00. Okay. Bye-bye.
What's the problem?
Bob's reorganizing
the department.
Tell her to put
me in for a raise.
Me first. Good night, all.
Good night. All
right, what's my bid
for the Saturday night special?
A jilted boyfriend on PCP...
22 years old, 6'8",
comes strapped
to his own gurney.
I'm going home.
Going once, going twice.
Sold to the doctor in
the pale green scrubs.
Doug, I said I'm going home.
Susan, you take it.
He still upset?
Still.
Hi.
Hey.
Busy night?
Refreshingly slow.
Are you going out?
It's Saturday night.
Oh, yeah.
You need a break, Peter.
Go home, get some sleep.
Yeah, but my mother gets
anxious if nobody's there.
How long can you keep this up...
Working here and
staying with her all night?
I don't know. Till
she goes home.
Home?
Yeah, home.
Why don't I sit
with her for a while?
We can finish up
here, grab some dinner,
give me a chance to get
all the gory details
about your adolescence.
All right. Yeah. Yeah,
that sounds good.
Yeah, it sounds fascinating.
I'd like to come along.
Carter, finish your notes, and
mind your own business, huh?
Carter, will you
stop him? Carter!
Whoa! You're speeding, sir.
Help! She's killing me!
Louie drank a six-pack.
He has an enlarged prostate.
Been trying to put in a
foley catheter for an hour.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, but I'm off now,
so, Carol, he's all yours.
Oh, gee, thanks.
All right, Louie. Don't worry.
I'm going to use
plenty of Lidocaine.
Your shift over yet?
Yeah, if Benton ever leaves.
Ever worked a full
moon Saturday night?
No. Is it that different?
Stick around and find out.
Call security!
Code white to trauma two!
Get me out of here!
Watch it, watch it. Stay back.
Rita! You cheating
bitch, I'll kill you!
Full moon Saturday night.
Cool.
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.
What are you doing?
Just checking out
your procedures.
Well, hey. Next time, ask.
You think you've done
enough to get high honors?
I don't know.
I don't count.
You should. I do.
Hey, Carol, Mark went home.
Could you call
Foster in tonight?
He broke his leg skiing.
Oh. Uh, what about Alonzo?
Doing ICU.
How about Ross?
Previous engagement. Oh.
Do you care?
Nope. Yes, you do.
No, I don't. Diane Leeds.
Really? The one with
the kid? Mm-hmm.
Susan. Yeah.
Auto versus pedestrian, ETA now.
Gangbanger in the suture room,
and that sore
throat is still waiting.
Call someone. Moonlighter?
They're always senile
or dermatologists.
Okay, moonlighter it is. Okay.
It's going to be
one of those nights.
Kerstetter, David,
18, intoxicated.
Played chicken with
a Taurus and lost.
He came out of nowhere.
I slammed on my
brakes, but it was too late.
Okay, don't worry.
We'll take care of him.
B.P.'s 140/90; tachy at 160.
Minimal blood loss,
considering the chest laceration.
Gave him 300cc's of saline.
Mental status at the scene?
Alert. GCS 15.
Notify his family.
Oh, nasty gash.
Malik, get chest
and abdominal films
and throw in a head CT.
Carter, what do you want to do?
Check for pneumothorax,
do a quick neuro exam,
rule out abdominal trauma
and get an EKG to screen
for cardiac contusion.
Good.
Carter?
Oh, yeah. Okay, everybody,
on my count, now...
One, two, three.
Nice and gently.
Good. Go ahead.
Does this hurt?
No. My chest.
Get a tox screen
and a blood alcohol.
Reflexes intact.
Pupils are equal and
responsive to light.
Haleh, get a
cross-table c-spine.
Breath sounds clear bilaterally.
God, it hurts!
Abdomen is soft,
apparently nontender.
Give him 60 of Toradol.
Don't want to mix
alcohol with morphine.
Need any help, Dr. Lewis?
How are you with
sutures? Excellent.
Great. When we're
finished here, you can start.
Looks like he's going to live.
What are you doing here?
I heard you were
staying, so I'm staying.
Susan, that banger's
waiting. Okay.
Uh, Dr. Lewis, I was sort of
hoping I could follow this patient.
Carter, there's plenty
of wounds to go around.
Deb, you start there.
Carter, you start there.
Call me when you
reach the middle.
Okay, looks like we're
going to need two suture kits.
How's it going?
Okay.
You work around here?
Yeah.
What's good on the menu?
Nothing.
Bagel looks safe.
Excuse me.
Friendly place.
Oh, doctor?
Yeah?
Will he be all right?
Well, for a guy hit by a car,
he's in pretty good shape.
Can I see him? Apologize?
Yeah. As soon as they're
done sewing him up.
Wait right here.
This isn't a race, John.
Yeah, well, you
could have fooled me.
You know, if you
go a little slower,
your stitches wouldn't
invert so much.
Is he screwing up?
Relax.
What are the rules for
sharing procedures?
What?
You know, for our books.
Whoever's been here
the longest, I guess.
Hmm...
how about whoever
sews more takes it?
You're on.
Hey, Carol!
I need a gurney!
Mr. Travis, are you in pain?
My chest...
Okay, okay. We're
going to take care of you.
Get this off him.
Okay. On my count...
One, two, three.
Good.
What do you got?
Hank Travis, the driver
who hit the chest lac.
He collapsed with chest pain.
Looks like an MI.
Yeah.
What's going on?
Can't tell.
John, um, finish
up for me, will you?
He's got an early
diastolic murmur.
B.P.'s skyrocketing... 230/160.
Aortic rupture?
I don't think so... pressure's
too high. Do we have a crit?
Yeah. 46. Not bleeding.
Do you have high blood pressure?
Yes.
We need to lower his
pressure before he strokes out
or rips his aorta.
I'll call O.R.
Thanks, Malik.
Susan, want a beta blocker?
Yeah, bolus and
3.5 migs of Esmolol
and let's do a
transesophageal echo
to check out the damage, okay?
I'll get the echo.
Okay.
Who's in charge?
Dr. Lewis.
Sir, you're going to
have to wait outside.
I'm Dr. Swift.
Oh, moonlighter's here.
Spandex. Nice look.
Well, don't just stand there.
Glove up and get
your butt over here.
How's his pressure?
It's falling... 190/130.
I'll bet you've never seen
an transesophageal echo.
One or two.
Mr. Travis, this
isn't going to hurt.
I'm going to look at your heart
heart by putting this
instrument down your throat.
Two Versed?
Okay... Yeah. Let's
see what we've got here.
Look, it's going to get
real hairy here tonight
so pick out what you
think you can handle...
Sutures, weak-and-
dizzy-all-overs
kid with the croup...
All the easy stuff, okay?
I'll try and keep up.
There it is. Call a
thoracic surgeon.
This guy's in trouble.
Okay, get him up
to the O.R. now.
He's got a type-a dissection
of the ascending aorta.
You sure about that?
Acute chest pain, hypertension,
water hammer pulses
nonspecific ST changes.
Could be an aortic rupture.
I don't think so.
You don't think you
should consider that?
Who the hell are you?
I'm William Swift,
your new E.R. chief.
I'm taking over from
David Morgenstern.
Nice to meet you, Dr. Swift.
William.
So where are these
weak-and-dizzy-all-overs?
Okay. Short end takes the lice.
Oh, man.
It's 50-50.
Yeah, in theory,
but I never wi... win.
Cheer up, Carol.
Your bedpan days
will soon be over.
Man, not with my luck.
Once you marry Tag, you
can do whatever you like.
So, you're going to leave
us when you get rich?
What? And leave all this beauty?
Hey!
Here you are.
What do you have here?
"12 Common Errors That
Can Ruin Your Wedding."
Modern Bride?
There's some
great articles in here.
Hey, did somebody page me?
No, not me.
Lookit. Check out number six.
"Make sure you audition the
band before you hire them."
So I guess your
brother's band is out?
They'd actually have
to know how to play.
So, what kind of
band should we get?
I thought maybe we'd do
some polka music or something.
Tag! Taglieri!
You're hysterical.
Yeah, what's up?
Did you get my page?
Yeah. So how come
you didn't tell me
you were kicking
my mother out, huh?
He's been at the computer again.
Yeah, you're damn right.
Hey, we talked about you
staying out of your mom's file.
Why are you discharging her?
The hospital's breathing
down my neck, okay?
I put them off a week.
Medicare won't pay any more.
Look. She needs
more time to recuperate.
I got her three more days...
It's the best I could do.
Get your family together
and talk over your options.
She's not ready to go home yet.
Face reality, Peter... she's had
a stroke and a hip replacement.
She can't go home.
She's going to require
skilled nursing
the rest of her life.
I will take my mother home
and care for her
myself if I have to.
She's not going home.
The hell she isn't.
Dr. Susan, we are
running out of rooms.
Ah, midnight...
The witching hour.
Let's make room for the
punks, skunks and drunks.
Man with hiccups
and 18-year-old female
weak and dizzy after sex.
Her first time? An
orgasm... god, I'm jealous.
Been a while?
I'll take the hiccups.
I've got a woman
with abdominal pain
and a wheezer who
needs a blood gas.
Carter, do a focused
H&P on the abdominal pain.
Hiccups sound more interesting.
You'll see a thousand
acute abdomens
for every case of the
hiccups... You need the practice.
And do a pelvic and a rectal.
Ooh...
Patient fumigation.
Hey, hey.
Hey!
Walking in space?
Lice.
Uh... sounds sexy.
You want to hear some bands?
Might as well.
What do you think?
I think your brother
is starting to sound
better every minute.
Is that Wild Willie?
You know Dr. Swift?
Know him? We played
ball together at Ohio State.
Hey!
Hey, Lewis! Special delivery.
Where do I sign?
On the dotted line.
Four Beta Tau Sigma pledges
dumped on Rush Street.
Possible frostbite
to all extremities.
They left us in Lincoln Park
with just our shoes and socks.
What have we got here?
Popsicle pledges.
Uh, could we get some blankets
over here to warm these guys up?
Somebody... help me.
Ma... Ma...
it's Peter. I'm here, okay?
Why did they do that to me?
It's okay, Ma. It's okay.
I told them not to, but
they wouldn't listen.
I know, I know. It's okay, Ma.
I asked them to stop it,
but they wouldn't listen!
They won't do it again.
They never listen!
Okay, I know, I know.
Ma, listen to me...
I'll be right back, okay?
You okay?
All right, all right.
I love you, all right?
I...
I thought you were
sitting with her.
I went out to get
a cup of coffee.
How could you let
them do that to her?
Do what?
My mother doesn't
need to be restrained.
She was trying to
crawl out of bed.
Still, you shouldn't
have let them do it.
I'm the one who
asked them to do it.
Oh.
Don't bother to come back.
What?
I don't want your help.
Peter, she needs
to be restrained.
Mm-hmm... and
take a deep breath.
And let it out.
Ahh!
Oh... does that hurt?
A lot.
Uh-huh. Have you
had this pain before?
Never. It's the moon.
It's in the fifth house.
Something strange
is going on inside me.
Could you be pregnant?
Well, with this month's aspects
the unlikely is
probably definite.
Uh-huh.
Uh... I'm going to go ahead
and order a pregnancy test,
and then we'll just
take it from there, okay?
Um... are you by
any chance a Gemini?
Yeah.
When's your birthday?
June 4.
Um... year?
You know, I don't...
1970?
Yeah.
Time of birth?
For that, you're going to
have to ask my mother.
What's her number?
Timmy's tried everything...
Breath-holding...
Drinking ice water...
Tickling,
breathing into a bag,
scary movies...
I haven't slept in two nights.
We're getting married
in two weeks.
Will he be all right?
Probably just a case of
the pre-wedding jitters.
Is there anything
you can give me?
Thorazine sometimes
works, Mr. Falco.
We'll try that, and we'll
run some blood tests
and take an abdominal X ray
just to cover all the bases, okay.
You know, I just can't decide
between Hawaii or Paris.
I kind of had my
heart set on the beach.
You burn so easily though.
No, I don't. I tan.
Hawaii it is.
But Paris sounds so romantic.
Have you had a chance to
check out those china patterns yet?
When was I supposed to do that?
People are starting to ask.
Really?
Got a call from the Tiki
Torch down the street.
They got a guy on a Porta-potty
with our name on it.
That would be Louie.
Could you get a cab
to pick him up, please?
Mm-hmm. Thanks.
Where were we?
How are we doing?
Swift's looking for Mark.
Where's Dr. Greene?
Board says he's on tonight.
He went home with
a touch of the flu.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Your unsolved mystery is solved.
Congratulations.
You're pregnant.
Oh!
That's according to the Pisces
astrological forecast
in the Tribune.
Oh, and these lab results.
Thank you, Dr. Gemini.
I had a feeling you'd
bring me good news,
but are you sure there's
not something else?
What do you mean?
Well, I...
I constructed your chart,
and I'm certain
we haven't finished
our journey together.
Saturn is aligned with Mercury.
Is that bad?
It could be.
For who?
Both of us.
You're conflicted,
searching to find your way.
Go with the voice inside you.
Fight the influence of others
who seek to destroy you.
I'll, uh... order
that ultrasound.
Welcome back, Louie.
Did you miss us?
Have you been
drinking, Louie, hmm?
You still have your catheter in?
Louie...
Six pints, Louie.
It's time to change your bag.
Okay.
Stay right there, Louie.
Hey, how are you holding up?
Not bad. It's kind of nice
not having the boys around.
Oh! Oh, my god!
Cherry bomb in the trash can.
Pledges. Pledges.
Hey, Carter.
Are you glad you stayed?
Whew!
There's a call on the radio.
Read you, Dispatch.
Implement disaster protocol.
EMS Plan One at
Wabash and Balboa
for nightclub fire.
How many? Over.
15 to 20, most with
third-degree burns.
I'll set up a triage point.
All right, I'll put
out call-backs.
What is it?
I'm getting beeped.
2:00 in the morning?
Welcome to my life.
Just better not be
another woman.
Oh, quit making so much noise.
I'm never going
to get back to sleep
if I really wake up.
Hey.
Mmm...
So, can I come back?
There's a spare key
on the kitchen table,
but you have to be back
out before Jake wakes up,
that's all.
Damn.
29 minutes, 32 seconds.
I beat you.
You what?
What's going on?
Where's the victims?
You're looking at them.
Everyone, I'd like
to introduce Dr...
William Swift, your new chief.
It's good to see y'all.
Which one of you
is Chief Resident?
We haven't been able
to locate Dr. Greene yet.
Okay.
I find these drills ideal
for meeting my team
and assessing how quickly
the residents can mobilize.
Now, seeing that
I have you here,
I'd like to take a few moments
and go over some of the
basics of E.R. management.
At 2:30 A.M.?
Don't worry. I'll have
you home by 4:00.
John, could you please
help me with a patient?
Why, is it a procedure
you've already done?
No. It's a guy
who's really drunk
smashed his finger in a car door
and he's pawing at me.
He also smells terrible.
And you have a
problem with that?
I can hardly wait
to get out of the E.R.
Mr. Denardo, this is John Carter
and we're here
to take care of that finger.
I want a real doctor,
not a couple of kids.
Great. then we're going to go,
and we're going to let
your finger get infected,
swell up and fall
off, if you prefer.
Thanks. Uh, you numb the finger
and I'll drain the nail
bed with a cautery.
This is going to
feel a little cool.
Wait, wait, wait!
Didn't anybody ever tell you
ethyl chloride is flammable?
Damn!
I'm really sorry.
Please don't tell anyone, okay?
A patient presents to the E.R...
Ptosis, miosis, anhidrosis.
Dr. Ross
what does that bring to mind?
The osis sisters.
I dated the short one.
Um, I believe you're describing
Horner's syndrome.
Correct.
Otherwise, a drooping eye.
What should you worry about?
Hmm?
Pancoast tumor
of the superior
sulcus of the lung.
Correct. And you are...?
Bob. I started in housekeeping
and now I'm a desk clerk.
Yeah.
Dr. Greene for you on two.
Okay.
However, many of you
have a fondness for using
antibiotics prophylactically
when dealing with animal wounds.
Where are you?
An arcade.
I didn't feel like going home.
What's up?
New chief pulled a drill.
Okay.
One hour, 47
minutes... A new record.
Where are they?
Trauma One.
Any questions, my
door is always open.
Dr. Bagel, come right in.
Man, you're in trouble.
Wild Willie's on a tear.
Wild Willie?
Hi. Uh, Mark Greene.
Yeah, I've heard.
William Swift, your new chief.
How's the flu?
The what?
I guess you're
feeling better, huh?
Look. Go home,
read that before
your next shift,
then we'll talk.
The flu?
Sorry.
Guess I should have stayed, huh?
Ma.
Ma?
I'm here. I'm here.
Are you in any pain, Ma?
No.
Okay. Okay, I got you, okay?
I got you. Damn!
How'd it go?
I think I blew it
with the new chief.
Let's just say you didn't
make a strong first impression.
You have to stay?
No. He sent me home.
Good. Let's get out of here
before he changes his mind.
Move the transducer down
to visualize the adnexa.
Is that the ovary?
It sure is.
And that's the ectopic.
You have both an
intrauterine pregnancy
and an ectopic pregnancy.
Twins.
That makes sense.
He's a Gemini.
Will they be all right?
You can carry the
one in your uterus
but we need to operate
and remove the other
before it ruptures.
If that happens, you could die.
I'm sorry, Arlena.
Don't be.
I'm having a baby, and
I'm going to be just fine.
Mm-hmm.
I scraped it climbing a cliff.
And why were you
doing that, Mr. Talbot?
Chasing cats.
Cats?
I'm a werewolf.
Oh, full moon, right?
Please put me in restraints
until sunrise.
It's only a couple of hours.
You think you might harm
yourself or somebody else?
There's no telling
what I might do next.
Okay. Well, I will go
and get you a doctor.
Never turn your
back on a werewolf!
I forgot. Sorry.
Oh!
Carter, I am so sorry.
Any good patients?
Nope. Just a couple of drunks.
Why don't you take a nap?
I'll beep you if
anything good comes in.
I'll be in Four.
What was that?
Werewolf.
Huh?
Maybe you should lock your door.
Oh, you cured his hiccups.
They're gone.
I feel much better.
I have some test results.
I should probably
go over them with you alone.
No. No, go ahead.
We... we don't have any secrets.
You have some serious findings
in your CTs and ultrasound.
How serious?
These are abscesses...
Pockets of bacteria
invading your liver.
It's inflaming your
diaphragm, which is
what caused your hiccups.
We're going to have to
admit you, run some tests,
treat you aggressively
with IV antibiotics.
I see.
Well, that'll cure him, right?
I hope so.
I need to ask you
some difficult questions.
Okay.
In cases like these,
in which an apparently healthy
young individual like yourself
has such an unusual
illness, we need to consider
the causes.
Have you ever used IV drugs?
Never.
Have you had high-risk
sexual contact...
Unprotected sex
with men, prostitutes?
What, are you
suggesting I have AIDS?
It's an unusual condition,
and is sometimes seen
in patients with HIV.
It's probably just a
bacterial infection,
but I needed to
consider the risk factors.
I can't believe
you're telling me this.
You didn't answer
my other question
about other sexual contacts.
No. Never.
So what do you think
about Wild Willie?
I don't know.
Probably going to make us
do pushups before every shift.
Yeah.
You think he'll take
Morgenstern's recommendation
and make you attending?
Yeah.
You know, I hear that
he's promoting Carter
to chief of surgery.
Uh-huh.
You getting any sleep at all?
Mark.
What?
Nothing. Just, you didn't
hear anything I was saying.
Sorry.
You got to let this OB case go.
Could have happened
to any one of us.
If you killed a patient,
you wouldn't be upset?
You didn't kill her.
Mark, you did everything
you could to save her.
Tell that to her husband.
A year from now that little
boy will be taking his first step
and his mother won't be there.
His mother will never be there.
It's not your fault, Mark.
That's my stop.
Listen, Mark, why don't
you come over to my place?
We can talk.
What for?
See you tomorrow, Doug.
All right, let's move him.
Okay. On my count.
Ready. One, two, three.
What happened?
Drunk.
Took a 12-gauge
to the lower chest.
Accidentally broke into
the neighbor's house.
Laryngoscope.
7½ ET tube?
Yeah, perfect. Call
Carter and Deb.
We could use some
help down here.
Deb's doing lacs,
and Carter's asleep.
Okay, get Carter.
Call Respiratory for a vent
and call Radiology
for a chest film.
Hang some O-neg.
Cross and type as
many as you can.
Looks like a flail chest.
He's got four or
five broken ribs.
After a blast like that,
he's lucky to have a chest.
He's bradycardic.
Pressure?
40 palp.
Okay, I'll start a central line.
He's bleeding out.
Tank him up with O-neg.
Hey.
Good morning, Carter.
Morning, Carter.
He's in arrest. Give
him an amp of epi.
Carter, ever done
external compressions?
Uh, yeah.
Okay, Carol, get him started.
A little lower. There you go.
Watch the right
side of his chest.
It's about to fall off.
Susan, baby with hypothermia.
Cops found it in a trash bag.
Okay.
Line's in. Keep the
compressions going.
Give him four units,
and someone call Swift.
Get another body down here now.
Okay. I'll call Tag.
It's darkest before dawn.
Yup.
More epi.
Three-to-four-week-old male.
B.P. 60 palp. Rate, 80.
No arrhythmias. Temp 89 degrees.
Okay, give him
heated humidified O2.
Get a dextrose stick.
Let's start an IV.
Heated saline to 110 degrees.
What kind of parent
would do this to a baby?
How's he doing?
We're rewarming him.
Pleural lavage?
No, we need a neonatal warmer.
Check his lytes for acidosis.
I got a date with a
thoracotomy next door.
Go.
How are we doing?
Not so good.
No pulse. A
pellet hit an artery.
Compressions aren't working.
We're losing him.
Thoracotomy tray.
Hey, hey!
Heard you needed some help.
Bone crusher? We're
doing a thoracotomy.
Cut between the ribs.
I'll clamp the aorta.
I'm a little rusty on
my thoracotomies.
Don't worry, we'll
walk you through it.
I'll support the right chest.
Carry the incision
through the intercostals.
Okay, let me get in here.
Vascular clamp.
Rib spreaders.
Easy does it.
All right. Where is
that little gusher?
Got it. It's clamped.
Heart's beating.
That's teamwork.
It's fibrillating.
Carter, ever felt a live heart?
Make like a crocodile.
Okay, now...
gently compress the
heart between your fingers
about 80 times a minute.
It feels like a bag of worms.
Give him a couple
more units of blood.
It's filling.
No pulse.
Second unit's in.
He's still fibrillating.
We need to shock
him back into sinus.
Internal paddles.
Start with five.
Charging.
Five, clear.
Clear.
Five more.
Charging.
Clear!
Clear.
We've got a rhythm.
Let's keep it.
I've got a pulse.
He's stable.
Good work.
Okay, take him up to the O.R.
How's he doing?
Temperature's 92.
I think he's going to make it.
How's your guy?
Still ticking.
Hey...
You look exhausted.
Why don't you take a breather?
I'll call Family Services.
He'll need a foster placement.
Hey, Deb, how's it going?
Fine, thanks.
Wow, did you shave
that scalp all by yourself?
Uh-huh.
What have you been up to?
Oh, internal cardiac massage.
See you later.
I don't think I like this.
What?
You coming and going
in the middle of the night.
Did you miss me?
You woke me up.
Aww...
All right, you got 15 minutes.
Jake's an early riser.
15 minutes?
That's not really
my style, but...
You can do it.
Come here.
Mark.
Hey.
Lovely place to sit around
feeling sorry for yourself.
It has its charms.
It's freezing out here.
How'd you find me?
Doug.
He said he'd never
seen you so upset.
Things just, uh, aren't
working out the way I planned.
Sure they have.
You leaving me...
I didn't plan for that.
People die, Mark.
You do the best you can.
You're human.
I'm not supposed to be.
Sure you are.
You're the only one
who doesn't know it.
What am I going to do?
You could get breakfast.
I'll even buy.
Come on.
Come on, Mark.
Susan... Susan.
Hmm?
Susan, Mr. Falco's
fiancee is out here.
She needs to see you.
Oh, yeah. Yeah, sure.
Bring her in.
Dr. Lewis.
Sorry to bother you.
No, no problem.
Is there a chance
that I might be sick?
I don't know.
To be safe, you
should be tested for HIV.
We're getting
married in two weeks.
I thought I knew him.
I didn't say he had AIDS.
I know...
but I think he hasn't
been honest with me.
I'm sorry.
Who'd have thought
a case of hiccups
would turn out like this?
Can I help you?
Yeah. I'm, uh, I'm
Dr. Peter Benton.
Your wife, she's been
taking care of my mother.
Oh, yeah, sure.
Al Boulet.
Is everything all right?
Yeah, yeah.
Jeanie!
Peter Benton's here.
What's wrong?
I, um... I left
the restraints off
and she fell out of bed.
Is she okay?
Yeah, yeah. She's
got a couple of bruises
but, um, her hip's okay, so...
I got to get to work.
All right.
See you.
Okay.
Nice meeting you.
I, uh...
I can't do this by myself.
Uh... I mean...
take care of my mother.
I've seen a lot of children try.
And uh...
it's just that I'm
afraid of what's going
to happen to her.
Yeah, um...
can you, uh...
can you help me
to... you know...
find a couple of names
of some good places?
Sure.
I didn't think we
were going to make it.
You were great with
that thoracotomy.
You weren't so bad yourself.
Hey, every full moon
should be ladies' night.
Yeah, we were terrific.
Like Thelma and Louise, man.
More like Lucy and Ethel.
Whose are those?
Tag brought them for me
so I could make some
headway on our wedding.
Bridesmaids still wear peach?
Hey, don't say anything
you might regret.
You may have to wear that.
Me? A bridesmaid?
Yeah. Would you?
Yes, I would be honored.
You may change your
mind when you see the dress.
See you later.
Hello?
Sink's clogged and
somebody stripped
the damn threads.
You need some help?
I called maintenance
four hours ago.
I figured it'd be
quicker if I do it myself.
Maybe you need a plumber's snake
like angioplasty.
Thread it in, break up the clog.
You know, you're right.
Don't mention it.
You thought of applying
for chief resident?
I'm only second year.
Really. That's all?
Huh...
What?
Well, I find that
hard to believe.
Well, I can see we're
going to have to make
some changes
around here. Really?
There's a few kinks in
the chain of command.
Oh.
Don't worry...
You did a good job.
Thank you.
Right now, I need
a plumber's snake.
Ask Bob.
Bob...
Hey...
Hi, Dr. Lewis.
Good morning, Jerry.
Busy night?
Kind of crazy. Mm-hmm.
Not for me. I had a blast.
Ah, we'll have to do
a Friday the 13th then.
Ooh, those are really spooky.
They called twice. From
1962, let's "Twist and Shout"
for Susan.
Carter, did you do that?
♪ Shake it up, baby, now ♪
♪ Shake it up, baby ♪
♪ Twist and shout ♪
♪ Come on, baby, now ♪
♪ Come on, baby ♪
♪ Come on and work it on out ♪
♪ Well, work it on out, honey ♪
Oh, yeah.
♪ Yeah, you look so good ♪
♪ You know you look so fine ♪
♪ Now, you know
you got me going ♪
♪ You know you got me going ♪
♪ Just like I knew you would ♪
♪ Come on, I knew you would ♪
♪ Whoo ♪
♪ Shake it up, baby, now ♪
♪ Shake it up, baby ♪
♪ Twist and shout ♪
♪ Come on, come on,
come on, baby, now ♪
♪ Come on, baby ♪
♪ Come on and work it on out ♪
♪ Come on and
work it on out... ♪
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.