- Previously on The Resident...
Lamar is his biological father.
Your mother is better
than me in every way.
My hope is that
you'll reach out to her.
You crossed lines that
I would never cross.
Talking about the hostage?
I'm talking about the
patient that you tortured
to get the information
that you needed.
- I'm pregnant. But
Adaku's getting great care
and she's done everything right.
Pregnancy hormones
might bring her cancer back.
Jessie died of a pulmonary
embolism. Five other
dialysis patients
died at Chastain.
I think whatever
killed your sister...
It killed them, too.
If you want to make a call,
you got to pick up the
phone and hit the buttons.
I don't know if I should call.
Head injury in one is a pilot.
Just flew in from New York.
Took a tumble down the
escalator, so they brought him
right in.
His blood alcohol was .06.
Which means he was
drunk while flying the plane.
And according to
his liver enzymes,
this is not his first time.
He's a chronic drinker.
- No question.
- So you're thinking
about whether you should
report him to the FAA.
But in order to make that call,
have to reveal his
medical information,
- which violates HIPAA.
- Exactly.
Patients need to know that
they can come to us for help
- without getting in trouble.
- This guy is
a safety risk to others.
HIPAA rules won't matter
to the people he kills
if he's in the cockpit.
Make the call.
Bandage can come off tomorrow.
Okay. So, uh, am I
good to get out of here?
Tell me, how often
do you fly drunk?
So, what... you gonna report me?
I thought about it.
But no.
There's an AA meeting
around the corner.
I'm-I'm not a drunk.
Take it.
Yeah, I-I...
I don't think I have a problem.
I promise. Okay?
I'll-I'll read through it.
And I'll give it
some... real thought.
Radiology transport
needed in the ER.
♪ ♪
Conrad, what's going on?
I couldn't sleep. I can't
stop thinking about Jessie.
And all the dialysis
patients that died
because of these blood clots.
Well, have you found anything?
Oh, my God. You did.
I went over all the
information we have,
and there is a long...
safety record
for every medication
they were on.
Except for one.
Hemopleatin.
These types of drugs can
increase the risk of clots.
Does hemopleatin increase
that risk more than others?
I don't know.
Conrad, could this have
caused the P.E. that killed Jessie?
I don't know enough yet,
but we need to talk
to people who might.
I can't believe this all
started with my dad.
He really believed there
was more to Jessie's death.
I think he could've been right.
I already confirmed
your afternoon pitches
for the health supplement.
Then roll dat ass to Midtown,
'cause I just scored you
the Rain Man suite
at el Cuatro Seasons.
I'm talking upgrades
on upgrades, baby.
The views are gonna be pano-ram.
- Good.
- I got you.
Question is, do you got a
lady in the Big A or what?
Get out of my chair.
Thanks for your patience.
We'll now begin boarding
our first-class passengers
for New York City.
Hi. How you doing?
Good, thank you.
I'm sorry, sir.
We're not boarding
your zone yet.
You just called first class.
Yes, and you are in coach.
I don't fly coach.
Just scan it again.
Yeah, no, see? Right
here, it says "Zone 5."
Uh, you know, um...
my assistant probably...
Sir, we have a
full flight today.
If you could just
step to the side
so that our
first-class passengers
can continue boarding.
Thanks. We'll be
with you in a second.
Hi, sir.
Here you go. Enjoy your flight.
You're welcome.
FLIGHT ATTENDANT:
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome aboard Flight 1980, -
with service from
Atlanta to New York.
We are currently
third in line for takeoff
and are expected to be
in the air in approximately
seven minutes' time.
Flying solo?
- Mm.
- Me, too.
Ellen went up yesterday.
Her brother's got
a cabin upstate.
It's a five-hour drive,
but cheaper than a hotel.
Ellen's my wife.
- 42 years. Flight
attendants, prepare for takeoff.
You married?
No ring. Whoa.
Handsome guy like
you must have some fun.
I know I'm not a lot
to look at right now,
but, let me tell you,
when I was young,
oh...
there were ladies.
Oh, yeah.
Then I met Ellen.
Blind date.
Can you believe it?
Yeah, mini golf. True story.
Our second date
was Argentinian food.
Oh, boy.
Let me tell you, that did
a number on my wallet
and stomach.
Oh, boy, let me tell you...
Somebody help me!
Let me help!
♪ ♪
Come on!
We have to get out.
Come on.
♪ ♪
Yeah, I heard on the radio.
They say most
passengers are okay,
but the seriously injured
are headed here, Atlanta
General and Emory.
- All right, I'll turn around.
- No, you will not.
We have plenty of
trauma surgeons here.
And we both know you
have other plans today.
Look, I know you're nervous, but
you have to do this.
You decided. You're going.
I just have this feeling
in the pit of my stomach
that I'm about to do harm.
And I do not like to do harm.
Chastain will page
you if they need you.
Go.
♪ ♪
Oh, my God!
- Oh, my God!
- 34-year-old female
with blunt head trauma
and a large scalp lac.
- GCS and vitals?
- GCS, 14.
BP, 108/60. Pulse, 92.
Okay, let's get her to CT.
Let's hear it!
76-year-old male with complaints
of diffuse abdominal pain.
Still hypotensive after
two liters normal saline.
Tell me exactly where it hurts.
All right, let's get
him to 11, please.
60-year-old male with
significant trauma...
an unstable pelvis,
open radial fracture.
Randolph, you were on the plane?
Yeah. I'm fine.
Him, not so much.
He's had 12 milligrams
of morphine so far.
Let's hang two grams cephalexin.
Mild diffuse tenderness.
Postponed all my
elective surgeries.
- What do we have here?
- Well, he wasn't wearing
his seat belt when
the plane dropped.
He hit the ceiling hard
and then fell to the floor.
How you doing? I'm Dr. Cain.
Can you wiggle your fingers
and give me the okay sign?
- Perfect.
- I can't feel
- distal pulses. I need the Doppler.
- How about thumbs-up...
Can you do that?
Radial nerve injury.
- I need to get him to the OR.
- He needs
a pan-scan and
angios of his extremities
before he goes to the OR.
Ellen.
That's his wife.
Don't worry.
- We'll get her here.
- Dr. B.
Dr. B, you're
alive. I never pray,
- but when I saw the crash
on the news, I prayed hard.
- Okay.
- Thank you, Grayson.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah. I'm just a little stiff.
- We should get you checked out.
Or we can focus on the people
here who are actually hurt.
Ms. Mitchka.
Dr. Hawkins.
Where's my phone?
Oh, sorry. I know-I know
you don't allow these in here.
I saw the signs. I-I just...
I have to try to
reschedule a meeting
- in New York and get there ASAP.
- You've had a pretty rough day.
- I'll make an exception.
- Thanks.
Any past medical problems?
Oh, just strangers waking
me up in weird places,
like car washes, drive-throughs.
But a hospital's a new one.
I can fall asleep anywhere,
whether I want to or not.
Narcolepsy?
Since I was nine.
Sorry.
Sorry, I... This is
so rude, I know.
I just... I have to
e-mail my boss.
They don't give you the day
off after being in a plane crash?
I just... I can't
risk losing this job.
Most employers aren't so patient
about the whole
falling asleep thing.
What do you do?
I sell accounting software.
Yeah.
I don't love it,
but I get to travel.
And on, uh... on planes,
no one judges you
for falling asleep,
so... oh... that...
so that's a perk.
- Is that all right?
- Yeah.
Oh.
Your blood pressure's high.
Says here you're on
three medications for it.
Sometimes I forget.
Honestly, it never
seems to help anyway.
- Are we done?
- High BP is a tricky one.
It's called the silent
killer for a reason.
You don't feel the damage
it's doing on a daily basis.
Okay.
So, before you go back to work,
I'd like to keep you
here, run some tests,
get your BP under control.
I'll have someone come
back and suture that up.
And I'll write your boss
the best doctor's
note you've ever seen.
How's the eye?
She'll be fine.
No foreign bodies.
Just a pterygium.
Pterygium. P-T-E-R-Y-G-I-U-M.
Nice.
Oh, come on. That was too easy.
They were headed
to a spelling bee.
- Ah.
- And Rufus here
suffered quite the
scare, but his tachycardia
was resolved
with a bit of juice.
Tachycardia. T-A-K...
C-H, not K.
Tachys from the Greek
"tachys," meaning "quick, rapid."
Cardia from the
Latinized "kardia"
- meaning... "heart."
- Mm.
Dr. Hawkins won the
Chatham County Spelling Bee
when he was your
age. Loves to bring it up.
Ah, it's the biggest
bee in the Southeast.
I've never heard of it.
You're early.
I saw the news.
Time of death, 10:13.
You all right?
That pilot I
treated last night...
He'd fly between New York
and Atlanta for the same airline.
I thought I'd convinced
him to get help.
You didn't report him?
You think he was
flying this plane?
I could've stopped him.
It's a great drug.
So much so, we made hemopleatin
the standard of care
for anemic patients
six months ago.
- Any adverse side effects?
- None.
- In fact, quite the opposite.
- Uh, six patients
recently died of a P.E.
Would you say that
hemopleatin patients
are more likely
to get blood clots?
My colleagues and I do
weekly case conferences.
If a drug were
killing our patients,
- we'd notice.
- How many patients
- are on it currently?
- Let's see.
Uh, some are on chemo.
Others have blood
disorders or on dialysis.
I'd say 200.
We'd like to see their records.
For that you need
to submit a request
to the Institutional
Review Board.
The IRB takes weeks.
Months, with Red Rock in charge.
Any way you can
help us get it faster?
Hospitals don't
like to share data.
Not even with their own staff.
Last year, I put in a request
to find out the infection rates
- in my department.
- And how long did it take
- for you to hear back?
- I'm still waiting.
I swear, I'm not
trying to be bossy.
I just want to help
you with your birth plan.
That's why I'm here.
- Let's do this.
- Okay.
Everyone, listen up.
You must be Adaku.
I hear you're quite
the world traveler.
- I prepped them.
- Of course you did.
This is from all of us.
This is incredible.
I'm gonna cry.
Does everyone
get this treatment?
You're not everyone.
- Just remember, I'm in charge.
- Of course.
And you have many
choices to make today.
Thank you.
Thanks, guys.
Okay, so where are we going now?
- Okay, so this is where
you're gonna have the baby.
- Okay.
What did the fish say
when he swam into the wall?
Dam!
Help your old man out, son.
Could have laughed just once.
I could, but it
would be fake, Dad.
But in my heart, I
would receive it as real.
Yee... look at him.
- Something is not right.
- I know.
My kung pao shrimp has
made grown men weep,
and he hasn't touched a bite.
All right, come
clean, son. Did you
get a girl pregnant?
I found my birth parents.
How? The records were closed.
They didn't tell us anything
about who they were.
- If we'd have known,
we would've told you.
- I know.
But they came looking for me.
At least, my
biological father did.
Dude just showed
up at the hospital.
Tell us everything.
What was he like?
No sense of humor, like you?
Well, he's stubborn.
He's melodramatic,
and he's opinionated.
So, no, he's nothing like me.
Hey. Any word on the pilot?
NTSB isn't releasing any names.
We don't know for sure your
patient crashed the plane.
Same airline, same route.
Too much of a coincidence.
Hey, you didn't crash the plane.
If he did cause
this, it's on him.
One man is dead. Maybe more.
Every doctor has a
patient in their past
they want to go back to
and treat in a different way.
Focus on the ones
who need you right now.
So I took him into surgery.
You operated on
your birth father?
I saved the dude's life.
Ah.
That must've really
impressed the man.
He must really want
to get to know you now.
Well, that's not gonna happen.
But what about
your birth mother?
I didn't meet her.
And I don't plan to.
Look, you are the only
parents that I know.
Everything that I am,
everything that I've accomplished,
I owe to both of you.
Ah.
Here we go.
"I cannot help you,
for I am just a cookie"?
Oh, th-this you laugh at.
It's true.
This is not even a fortune.
Well, take it up with the owner.
- Oh, I will.
- Mm.
You okay, Ma?
I'm okay.
Grayson, do you believe in fate?
I do believe I was
born to do this job, sir.
Passengers at the
front of the plane
didn't fare so well
when it crashed.
Had I been seated in first class
instead of coach, I
might've been hurt.
It's because of your mistake
that I was able to
help people to safety.
People are saying
you're the Sully of Atlanta.
Now, we both got lucky.
Because if you ever
seat me in coach again,
you're fired.
This poor guy was seated
next to me. I've called his wife,
but she's not here yet.
Cervical spinal
damage and nerve injury.
Yeah. We got to
stop the bleeding first.
By stabilizing the bones?
Yeah, and removing the
spleen. The nerve repair can wait.
It can, if you want him to
lose all neurological function.
Look at these injuries.
- He's far too unstable to
fix everything. Well, yeah.
So we prioritize.
You good?
Yeah. You should start
on the nerves that
are most at risk,
and then I'll control the
hemorrhage from his spleen.
I'll stabilize the
pelvic fractures
and ex fix arms and legs.
Yeah. We'll just get
him back to the ICU
until he's stable
enough for another go.
Oh!
Randolph!
Are you all right?
No.
♪ ♪
I think filling out
that IRB application
gave me carpal tunnel.
Red Rock hopes people tire out.
Well, it's in, so now we wait.
Patients are on
hemopleatin right now.
One click
is all it takes to cut
through the red tape.
If I break the glass,
we get immediate
access to the records
of any patient on the drug.
Conrad, if you break the glass,
your name is recorded on
those charts permanently.
You could be fired for
accessing medical records
for patients that aren't yours.
If anyone notices.
Well, maybe they
don't now, but someday.
Do you really want
that hanging over you
the rest of your career?
And if we can't get the
answers any other way?
Then I'll break it.
- I won't let you.
- Well, I won't let you.
But we're not
there yet. Come on,
let's explore all of
our other options first.
All right.
Come on.
Yeah. I knew we'd
feel something.
- Here?
- No. No.
- What about here?
- Yeah. Yep. Felt it.
Left paralumbar
tenderness right there.
You're seeing what I'm seeing.
Yeah, I wish I wasn't.
- Care to share?
- You have a herniated disc.
A disc is bulging out from...
Yeah. No. I know
what a herniated disc is.
It may be pressuring
the L5 nerve root,
and causing nerve impingement
and radicular symptoms.
We can give you some
anti-inflammatories
to help get you through the day.
And something
stronger if you need it.
I think our next step is clear.
- You need physical therapy.
- I'll perform a discectomy.
Surgery? You're not serious.
With a discectomy and fusion,
you have a better
chance at a quick recovery.
And you can avoid nerve injury.
Head-to-head trials show
that spinal fusion surgery
has a success
rate of barely 35%.
Even successful
patients often end up
- on pain killers for years.
- Well, those stats
are national averages.
I'm above average. In fact,
my success rate is phenomenal.
That's an easy claim to make
when most hospitals
aren't required
to publish their
surgical outcomes.
Okay, well, talk to my patients.
You can find them
on golf courses,
running marathons,
not popping pills.
Surgery seems aggressive.
After all, the injury
was only today.
I have no perceptible nerve...
- perceptible nerve damage.
- Yeah, well, even without
the nerve damage,
PT takes a long time.
We're talking no
sailing, no golfing...
no sex.
Yeah, and how long?
What do you want
to do, Randolph?
So...
do you want music for the labor?
I want to start off
with some Lizzo.
- Mm-hmm.
- Talking Heads
for the big finish.
I like it.
What about, um...
birthing positions?
We can have an exercise ball,
a sling or a birthing stool.
- Yes.
- Oh, we'll have all three
on the day.
- You're doing great so far.
- You know, there's, um...
there's another decision
I already gave a
lot of thought to.
Mina Okafor,
I want you to be my
baby's godmother.
- Godmother?
- I'm cancer-free now,
but we both know
that that could change.
If anything happens to me, I
want my baby to have a strong,
brilliant Nigerian woman
to show them the way.
Okay, how can I help?
Leave.
Your blood work shows your
kidneys are severely damaged.
And with your abnormal
EKG, we're seeing signs
of cardiac injury.
All from the crash?
Your kidney damage is from years
of untreated high
blood pressure,
but the stress of the crash
raised your blood
pressure even more,
and now...
you are at risk for
further organ damage.
It's a hypertensive
emergency, Susan.
We need to transfer
you to the ICU.
The ICU? For how long?
We'll know more
in a couple days.
But we need to get your
blood pressure under control.
No. I have to get back
to work. I have lived
with high blood pressure
my entire adult life.
- This is...
- This is much more complicated
than just high blood pressure.
We need to prevent
irreversible damage
to your organs.
So what?
I'm sleeping my
life away anyway.
And there is no cure.
You can't change that.
My life is what it is.
So... I might as well
at least make sure
that I don't lose my job.
Excuse me.
Susan.
I don't think you understand.
If you leave, you could die.
Now do we understand each other?
Call security. We
can't let Susan Mitchka
in bay three leave.
What are you doing?
I'm putting Susan
on a medical hold.
I think she has
hypertensive encephalopathy,
and she lacks the
capacity to make decisions.
Hang on a minute.
She can make
decisions just fine.
She's not in the
right state of mind.
This isn't about her.
It's about the pilot.
This is not the same thing.
His drinking put
other people in danger.
- She needs treatment.
- Yes.
But the decision
only affects her.
She wants to leave
against medical advice,
it's her choice, not ours.
- Prepare her paperwork.
- Yes, Doctor.
I'm signing myself out
against medical advice.
This is all very dramatic.
After we get your BP
sorted out, we can try to get
- your narcolepsy under control.
- You don't get it.
I've seen every specialist.
I've tried every medicine.
Nothing works for me.
So save your effort for
someone you can actually help.
You seeing what I'm seeing?
You don't think it could be?
Only one way to find out.
Hey, Susan.
Anyone ever tell you
you walk kind of funny?
Insult patients who leave.
What kind of hospital is this?
Your CT was normal,
but I think all your
doctors missed something.
I'd like to do an MRI of
your brain before you go.
- You're kidding.
- Hey, I get it.
You don't think things
will ever change.
You've spent your whole
life just trying to get by.
I can't.
I can't hope anymore.
I am fresh out.
We're not.
I think we can help you,
but you got to trust us.
- We just need two minutes.
- I don't have two seconds.
We've got a female patient, 30s,
diagnosed with
narcolepsy as a teenager.
Hypertensive emergency
we thought was due
to med-noncompliance
and the crash.
She has a wide, staggering
gait indicative of cerebellar ataxia.
Because she doesn't
actually have narcolepsy.
- She was misdiagnosed.
- What she really has
is central sleep apnea,
caused by a Chiari malformation.
She needs you to operate.
I'm booked five weeks out.
She's got gold-plated insurance.
Okay, I get it.
So you guys think I'm
some Red Rock tool
who only cares about the money.
I could have gone
to any hospital
in the country, gentlemen.
I chose Chastain because
I saw the opportunity
to help as many
people as possible,
with a staff who
would support me,
or at least stay out of my way.
Coming at me like
this is not how it's done.
Your patient needs my help,
I will operate on
her because I care,
not because she can pay.
Maybe we misjudged him.
Check her insurance.
I'm a surgical resident,
which means I work
80 hours a week,
but it's more like 120 with
all the studying and prep.
I arrive by 4:30 a.m.,
leave no earlier than 7:00.
I'm on call every three days.
Work Saturday or Sunday or both.
And I have two more
years left of residency,
followed by at least another
few years of fellowship,
during which my schedule
will only get worse.
- Uh...
- Do you know what the salary
for a surgical resident is?
- Ah, there's more.
- Yes.
$55,000 a year.
Even if I had time, I
can't afford childcare.
Is that all?
And I only like children
that belong to other people.
Okay, so...
what you're saying is, you...
don't want to be my
baby's godmother.
I'm saying I'm the wrong choice.
I will hold your
hand at ultrasounds,
shop for baby clothes, be
with you every step of the way.
- Unless I die.
- I will do everything in
my power to make sure you don't.
Got it.
So I have four
choices for pain relief,
two for fetal monitoring.
I can choose between
membrane stripping
or Pitocin or
artificial rupture.
But who will take care
of my baby if I'm gone?
That choice I do
not get to make.
I'll help you find someone else.
Adaku, I don't understand
why this is so upsetting to you.
Because it's the only thing
that we've talked about today
that actually matters to me.
Pelvic fixation complete.
- Rongeur.
I'll be quick.
I can insert the
pins while I wait.
Drill.
Watch your alignment, Dr. Voss,
or your radial shaft
will be gapped.
Oh, thank goodness you're here.
Bleeding controlled.
Applying the abdominal vacuum
so I can get him
back up to the ICU.
I'm right behind you.
Starting the graft now.
Oh? Already?
- Got someplace to be?
- Speed and performance
can go hand in hand.
What do you drive?
Jerry is a person, not a car.
If I didn't move this fast,
this person would lose
all nerve function in his arm.
Jerry can't move his
arms if he has no arms.
Get height restoration
and page me if
there's any surprises.
Wait, you're not leaving
this man's nerve
function to a third-year.
Of course. Hanna's
extraordinary.
She may be, but that's
not how we do things here.
Now, get back there
and do your job.
Uh... his pelvis is
filling with blood.
I thought we were about
to close. No, the packing
must have stretched the
vessels. I also repaired
- a partial tear up here earlier.
- Corona mortis.
- It's the crown of death.
- Bleeding from the connection
between the obturator
and iliac arteries.
- It's usually
fatal. Bovie. Lap.
- Retractors to me. We need to control this now.
- Lap suction.
Lap. Lap.
- You must be Jerry's wife.
- Yes.
I'm Dr. Bell.
During the surgery, your
husband had significant bleeding.
Our surgeons managed to stop it,
but his blood pressure
dropped for a long time.
- Is he okay?
- Well, he's being moved
to the ICU now.
He's alive.
But, uh...
we just don't know if
he's gonna wake up.
What?
You know, actually, I was...
I was sitting beside your
husband on the flight.
He wouldn't stop
talking about you.
I hit "ignore."
He called me.
I was at the store
and I hit "ignore."
Because once Jerry gets going...
I hit "ignore."
Well, I'll let you know as
soon as you can see him.
Thank you.
- Hey.
- Hi.
How long before
your next surgery?
- About 20 minutes.
- Oh, good.
Come, please sit with me.
What's up?
You know, your dad
always wanted to adopt a kid.
I took a little more convincing.
I was scared.
That's funny, I...
You?
I can't imagine you
being scared of anything.
Yeah. I was worried that
we wouldn't be enough,
that we were being selfish.
Taking a child who might
be better off with people
who would give them
everything they needed.
Okay, something tells me
you didn't drive from Buckhead
- to tell me that.
- I came here to tell you
that I don't think
you're being honest
with us or yourself.
- Come on, Ma.
- No, you come on, AJ.
You are my son, and I know you.
And I also know that one day,
you will want to meet
your biological mother.
That woman is a stranger
who threw me away.
I do not want to meet her.
Because you're scared.
That she won't
be enough for you,
or that you won't
be enough for her.
And you're also scared
that she might hurt you again.
Listen.
You won't know what you'll find
when you walk
through their door,
but you will know
exactly what you'll find
when you walk back through ours.
No matter what, we will
always be here for you.
So when you're ready...
you go see her, my son.
But I got a few ground rules.
Birthdays and holidays are mine.
You got it.
And every other day in between.
How did it go with the parents?
Better than I could
have imagined.
You know, my mother
actually encouraged me
to meet my biological mother.
Will you?
I don't know.
But now I know I can.
They're great people.
Mina, they are amazing people.
Even when they don't know
what they're saying yes to,
they still put me
first, even if it hurts.
That's family.
The ones who sacrifice
for you out of love.
Who make the
difficult decisions.
Even if they have every
reason to run away.
I hope I can be the
kind of parent they are.
How'd it go with Adaku?
It didn't.
And now I think I
understand why.
How's Susan?
Dr. Cain is retrieving
the patch now.
She should be okay.
And what about you?
- Long day.
- Ah.
Every doctor has them.
And we go home,
we learn from our mistakes.
The thing is... I
didn't make one.
I was right not to
report that pilot.
Wrong.
Drunk pilots
should not be flying.
Period.
62 injured.
14 critical.
Do I feel bad about
what happened?
Of course I do.
But patients need to know
that when they come to us,
we will keep their
medical information private,
good or bad.
Once we lose that trust,
we can't help anyone,
and people will die.
People did die
because of your choice.
- How do you not see that?
- I took an oath.
I get that you would have
made a different choice.
- The right one.
- For you.
But I don't want to be
the kind of doctor you are.
Well...
clearly, I've been
wasting your time.
- Hi.
Uh... what happened?
- They fixed you.
- Well, not yet.
In a few days, we'll
complete your reconstruction,
but we will get you there.
I've never seen
a hospital like this.
Where exactly are we?
Welcome to First Class.
Oh.
How long can we stay?
You really need to deal
with that back, Dr. Bell.
I threw my back out
pole dancing last year,
and it was no fun.
- Mm.
- For you.
Hey.
How do you feel?
Awake.
- Oh.
- Well, let's have a look.
Dr. Cain enlarged the covering
over the back of your brain.
This will relieve the pressure
that was causing
your sleep apnea.
- Just like that, huh?
- Just like that.
Just like that.
And the surgery cured
your blood pressure.
This means I don't have
to work in sales anymore.
I've never quit a job before.
But it's up to you now.
You got choices.
Choices.
Oh, I like the sound of that.
Thank you.
So dramatic, Randolph.
This is me taking your advice.
Yeah, it's a good look on you.
Well, if it doesn't
work in a few weeks...
You won't need surgery if you
do your exercises every day.
Don't be one of those
patients who forgets.
Yeah, well, I have a feel...
feeling you'll remind me.
Just doing my job.
Is this a job you've
decided to stay in?
'Cause you set up
meetings with other hospitals.
I did.
But I care about the
people here too much.
And I'm not giving
up on any of you.
Oh.
Work him hard.
So I guess you're
the Bell whisperer.
Hardly.
I don't think anyone's quite
figured out that man yet.
You talked an
educated doctor out
of a proven
medical intervention.
Well, if Bell's mastered one
thing, it's self-preservation.
Yes, and he also
plays well with others,
which is more than
I can say for you.
Don't ever speak to me
that way in the OR again.
I should say the same to you.
I can say whatever I want.
That's the difference
between a surgeon
who bills $80
million a year like me,
and one that bills... two.
It's a good one.
I'm reading the
chapter on episiotomies.
Yikes.
I threw this whole godmother
thing at you fast, huh?
I understand if you're
not comfortable with it.
I thought about it.
And?
It's been... a long time
since someone asked
me to sacrifice for family.
I don't really have any left.
We've both lost so much.
But you became my
family a long time ago.
And if my sister has a child,
then that child
becomes my family, too.
No matter what.
Are you saying you'll
be my baby's godmother?
You said yes?
I didn't have a choice.
Women who've had triple
negative breast cancer
have the highest recurrence
rates in the first three years.
Not to mention the risk of
developing ovarian cancer.
All right, so, what's your plan
if Adaku's baby becomes
your responsibility?
I don't have one.
Good night, guys.
Good night.
Busy day?
Yeah.
Yeah, um...
I thought about going
to AA like you said,
but I ended up
back at the hotel.
There's a bar.
And it was late, so,
when I got to the airport
the next day, I was...
I was still pretty buzzed.
I was about to board
when I heard the noise.
This crash wasn't my fault.
But the next one...
it could be.
I need help.
I lost the pamphlet.
We got hundreds. Come on.
Spoke to Andrews.
No more P.E. deaths today.
Great.
What about tomorrow?
Making sure a drug is
safe shouldn't be this hard.
If it is harming patients,
it's only gonna get harder.
Red Rock, the
pharmaceutical company...
You ready to take these guys on?
I keep thinking, what
would Jessie want me to do?
♪ Overdrive... ♪
She made a lot of
bad choices, but...
she was fearless.
She always wanted the truth.
We don't stop until we get it.
My shift ends in a few hours.
See you at home?
I like the sound of that.
♪ Time is running out ♪
♪ We're down to the ♪
♪ Wire. ♪
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH