- Previously on The Resident...
- Why isn't she returning my calls?
This is your sister
we're talking about.
AJ, I'm really
getting worried, okay?
She really loves her babies.
My goal is to make amends to you
for all the harm
that I have done.
You can get sober or don't.
But I'm not lying
for you anymore.
Nic would've been
proud of you today.
I want you to be proud of me.
♪ ♪
Resync By M_I_S
www.opensubtitles.org
♪ ♪
Paddie!
Where were you?
I need help.
Wh-What's going on,
Padma? Please talk to me.
I can't.
You can't what?
They deserve better than me.
I can't be their mother.
Okay. Okay.
Hey.
We're gonna get you the
help you need, okay?
Okay.
It's gonna be fine.
Hey.
Oh, my God.
What happened to you?
Oh.
Yeah, there was a scuffle
at the hospital last night.
Looks worse than it is.
What do you mean, a scuffle?
Oh. It was actually
pretty crazy.
This woman who should've
never been operated on
to begin with died
after surgery.
Her two sons, who pushed
for it, went ballistic.
What, and they attacked you?
They were after Billie.
I just got in the way.
Ah.
Can we talk?
Yeah. I have something
I want to tell you
and I didn't want
to do it at work.
Okay. Want to sit down?
No, no, no, that's okay.
I wasn't at a vineyard
with friends this weekend.
I was...
visiting my dad
at an addiction
treatment program.
Uh-huh.
It was family day and he asked
me not to tell anyone and...
I stupidly agreed.
Okay.
First reaction:
- this is great news.
- You're not angry?
No. I'm happy for
you. And for your dad.
- That's huge.
- Thank you.
It-it-it was.
But...
lying to you
is something I never
want to do again.
Cade, don't beat yourself
up. I understand.
I just thought I was
protecting him, you know?
The way I always have. And...
that's actually something we
talked about at the program...
All the lying and how...
it doesn't help anything. It
just makes everything worse.
You know? For him, for me
and...
now maybe for us.
I'm glad you told me. Thank you.
There's something
I have to tell you.
I haven't been
honest with myself.
Or you.
About my feelings for Billie.
Did something happen?
I kissed her.
Hmm.
Okay.
Hang on. Let's talk about this.
There's nothing to say.
I just wish you'd
been honest with me
- a long time ago.
- I was.
I wanted things to
work out with us.
I didn't know how I
felt about Billie.
Well, everybody else did.
I mean, literally everyone.
You know, maybe this is why
I could never fully
be open with you.
You've been half
in from the start.
Oh, come on. That's not true.
I tried to make
things work with us.
- You know that.
- You tried?
I know I've hurt
you, and I'm sorry.
You should put some
arnica on those bruises.
♪ ♪
Excuse me.
Sir, have you been registered?
I'm sorry. There's
no time.
Who took this electrocardiogram?
- I did.
- Phil, give me that chair
and let's get him
into Bay Three.
This man's having
a heart attack.
Uh, inferior
myocardial infarction,
to be precise.
Uh, Dr. Feldman.
I need your help here with...
I'm sorry, sir,
what's your name?
Dr. Leonard Perry.
You're the Leonard Perry,
the cardiothoracic surgeon?
Yes, I am.
I learned about
you in med school.
This man's research gave
us the defibrillator.
Which you should
probably hook me up to,
- as a precaution.
- Absolutely.
I'm also gonna
need nitroglycerin
- and a heparin drip.
- Yes.
Anything else we can get
you to make you comfortable?
Yes.
Dr. James Yamada.
- Absolutely.
- That's who I'm here to see.
- Let's page Dr. Yamada.
- Okay.
♪ ♪
I thought you'd at
least take today off.
How are you?
I'm okay.
I'm still processing it all.
It's unacceptable,
what happened.
I want you to know we're
increasing security.
I appreciate that.
Especially since the budget
is so tight right now.
That's an understatement.
I heard we might have to start
shutting down departments?
I was hoping for some
kind of reprieve,
but the governor didn't budge.
So, yes, we will be
closing the ER to trauma
- at midnight tonight.
- That's awful. I mean,
can't we make an emergency
appeal to the state assembly?
Our funding was always from the
governor's discretionary fund.
So we're completely
at his mercy.
Cade.
Just the person I wanted to see.
I'm gonna need
you to take a look
at all our current ICU patients.
Any who are stable
enough to move, find them
- a new location.
- Okay.
If you have any questions,
I'm here to help.
Or Billie.
I'm sure I can manage.
Today is not going
to be a fun day.
It's great to see you, Leonard.
I wish it was under
different circumstances.
Well, once you get a
stent into my heart,
we'll catch up properly.
I didn't know you
were in Atlanta.
Mm. On my way to
Switzerland for a lecture.
- Mm.
- Connecting flight was canceled.
Trouble started at the airport.
Well, we are honored to
have you here, Leonard.
People are very impressed
you asked for me.
I wouldn't have anyone else.
Is there anyone we should call
once we get you on the table?
My wife died last year.
- Sylvia?
- Yeah.
Aw, I'm so sorry.
We'd been married since
we were in college.
Outlived all my
closest friends, so...
no, no, uh, I'm alone.
Well, for now, you got me.
Thank you, James.
Dr. Perry, AJ Austin,
Chastain's CT surgeon.
Dr. Perry here was
my greatest mentor.
He taught me everything I know.
I know Dr. Austin.
From reputation, of course.
It's an honor.
Oh, the honor is
all mine, Dr. Perry.
The surgical techniques
you pioneered,
the work you did with
electrophysiology
- of the heart...
- Not to mention
accepting the Nobel Peace Prize
for the International Physicians
for the Prevention
of Nuclear Weapons...
If we could save this
for another time,
if you don't mind.
Of course, of course.
Uh, likely RCA occlusion.
Radial approach.
Should be in and
out with a stent
and a new lease on
life in no time.
James, cancel the cath lab.
Stop the heparin.
Get me to CT stat.
Your EKG
shows inferior ST elevations.
Your troponin's elevated.
You're having a heart attack...
Apparently I am also having
an aortic dissection.
Dr. Austin, I hope
you're ready for surgery.
Well, if you're right,
I'm more than ready.
How long do they want
to keep her here?
They'll talk to us
once they check her in.
So what happens next?
Medication?
- Therapy?
- All of that.
God, the anxiety,
the sense of inadequacy...
I thought it was the stress
of being a new mother.
How did I not see it was
postpartum depression?
What's important is
now Padma's gonna be able to
get the help that she needs.
We have to tell AJ.
He has an incredibly
important patient today.
Leonard Perry.
The Leonard Perry?
God, I don't want
to distract him
when he can't do anything
for Padma right now.
I'll talk to him later today.
You have to go to work. I know.
- I love you.
I just don't see how he can
have an aortic dissection.
He's too functional.
His pain is manageable.
It doesn't make sense.
Yeah, it was
probably a slow one.
Atypical presentation.
I know I said he's
always right, but...
I want him
to be wrong this one time.
Man, what was he
like as a teacher?
A saint.
Medicine is like a...
spiritual vocation for him.
He believes in the power
of the human touch.
Hmm.
Well, I'll be damned.
Right there. Ascending
aortic dissection.
His right coronary artery
takes off anomalously
from his ascending aorta.
Which means when he
had the dissection,
he also had an inferior MI.
That is... that is a
one-in-a-million diagnosis.
How the hell did
he figure that out?
Observation
and experience.
Sir, you should be
back in your bed.
- You're not well.
- A type 1A dissection.
A Perry-1A, to be exact.
Named after you because you're
the one who categorized it.
Well, are you ready to repair
a Perry-1A dissection on Perry?
Let's... take a moment to figure
out the best course of action.
Yeah?
Sure.
Sure, he's right, Dr. Perry.
Let's get you back
to an ICU bed.
Okay?
You get called to the execution?
- Sorry, what?
- You didn't see the email?
We're all supposed
to meet with Voss.
Chastain's level 1 trauma
center is closing. Tonight.
Whoa. That is a huge loss.
No more helicopters on the roof,
no more trauma team activations.
Fewer doctors, nurses, surgeons.
It makes you think what's next?
Cath lab? Transplant?
We're gonna be a nine-to-five
urgent care clinic
before you know it.
Prepare for a thrilling future
of nonspecific abdominal pain
and tingly arms and legs.
What do we got?
Unidentified woman.
Witnesses say she got
into a violent altercation
with a purse thief.
Closed head injury and
thrown to the ground.
- Femur looks broken.
- All right, let's take her
- to Trauma 12.
- Hello, ma'am,
I'm Dr. Pravesh,
and you are at
Chastain Hospital.
Do you remember what happened?
My purse.
She wandered out of
the dementia unit?
It's possible. I have no clue.
She's pretty banged up,
but protecting her airway,
and her vitals are stable.
Let's get a full set of
labs and get her to CT
as soon as we can.
At her age and degree of trauma,
she could have injured
just about anything.
He needs emergent surgery.
His mortality's
increasing one percent
- every hour we wait.
- But at his age,
and with the extent
of involvement
of his aorta, and the hit
his heart's already taken,
the mortality for that
surgery's over 50%.
- So what's the alternative, conservative management?
- Yes.
But we keep strict tabs
on his heart rate
and blood pressure.
And hope the tear in
his aorta clots off.
It's a long shot
and still risky.
He said it himself. It's
a Type-1A Gray Zone.
Medical management and
surgery have similar outcomes.
All right, so we have
to convince the man
who created the surgery
not to have the surgery,
and hope the world's
most famous heart surgeon
doesn't die in Chastain today.
Right.
Hey.
Heard Leonard Perry's
here. How is he?
Well, he's hanging in
there, but it's not great.
Um, so Kit wants me to move out
all the ICU patients that I can.
What? Why?
Budget issues, I'm assuming.
I found a good
candidate. Amir Sheridan.
The kid with the
fentanyl poisoning?
- I thought he was improving.
- He's not.
But he's alive.
Neuro says wait a year
before they give up on him,
but he can't stay here.
So we have to find
a skilled nursing facility
- that will take him.
- Yes.
Which will not be an easy task,
and it's all yours.
Someone needs to
talk to his family,
and it should probably
be his surgeon.
- Billie.
- Can you give that to her, please?
Hey, you got some time
for a trauma patient?
Go for it. Distract me.
- What was that?
- A mess.
I get it. If you ever
want to talk, I'm here.
I got to say, though, we
all knew it was coming.
Kit and Bell's wedding?
Everybody saw it.
Everybody but me, I guess.
Hi. Can you tell us
your name, ma'am?
You first.
This is Lillian, and
she's a real fighter.
She took on a guy who
tried to snatch her purse.
Lillian... something.
I can't remember the rest of it.
- Bizarre.
- Lillian,
- I'm Dr. Hawkins.
- What time is it?
I need to make sure
that I let the dog out.
No. I need you to
stay right here, okay?
Stay here.
Can you keep an
eye on her for me?
She's been this
disoriented the whole time?
She's clearing up a
bit, but not much.
Any explanation for her
confusion on her workup?
Possible Alzheimer's, but her
urine is clearly infected.
She's dehydrated, sodium at 150.
She's in pain from a
broken femur, but listen.
What's really
concerning me is this.
Mm.
Acute on-chronic subdural.
That's pretty big.
This could be what is causing
her to be so confused.
If you're asking my advice,
fix her sodium, treat her UTI,
- see if she clears.
- I think she needs to get to the OR stat.
Taking a woman at her
age to the OR is risky.
And if it is dementia,
putting her through surgery...
That-that could just
make things far worse.
We have to get her to the OR
anyway for her broken leg.
I say we try and treat the
bleed at the same time.
Okay, so both Billie and Kit.
Yes.
Now, as confidant as I am in
using your surgical techniques,
my recommendation would be
to carefully monitor you
and hope the
dissection stabilizes.
Honesty first, among colleagues?
Well, neither option is good.
We believe odds slightly
favor wait and see.
Slightly favor?
So it's not clear.
No, it's not.
Given the choice
between hope and action,
I've always tended
towards action.
But now that I'm
here, I'm frightened.
Dr. Perry,
if you choose to
have the surgery,
I promise you that these hands
will do everything they can
to save your life.
So you have it?
The healing touch?
Well, I don't know about that,
but I do have
experience, talent,
and a very big ego.
That and the healing touch.
That is where I place my trust.
Okay. No watching and waiting.
- We move forward.
- Yes.
Together.
You sure?
You don't have to make this
decision right this moment.
James, I have never let
fear guide me in the OR.
I won't let it
steer me away now.
No more half measures.
I want bold action.
All right. You heard
the man, James.
Dr. Leonard has decided
to come out the
bunker guns blazing.
That's the idea.
- Okay?
- Okay.
How's it going?
Good.
Good. Me too.
Ah, so, I spoke to Cade.
Been avoiding texts
from James all day.
Could have done this in
a cleaner way, but...
it happened.
And we are gonna do
this right from now on.
I'll talk to James.
I heard you're looking to
relocate Amir Sheridan.
- I'm so sad he hasn't woken up.
- Yeah.
We're still looking
for a facility,
but I thought I'd get
the conversation started
with the family. They're
coming in this afternoon.
Did you want to talk to them?
Well, I should.
- I mean, of course I will.
- No. No, no, no.
- Not after yesterday.
- I'll talk to them.
Would you?
Of course.
I don't love how we got here,
but I am so happy
that we are here.
I know.
Me too.
- AJ.
- Yo.
I brought you this
for good luck.
It's from when I was on
Perry's team in Boston.
Thanks, man.
Yeah.
So, listen. Obviously, Perry
is consenting for himself,
but is there somebody
we should call?
He's a widower, no kids.
He always said his
interns were his children.
Oh, wow. So I guess
you're his family now.
Yeah, I guess so.
Acute on-chronic subdural,
broken femur and
some bruised ribs.
Lillian's 84.
What's she doing, playing rugby?
She tried to fight
off a purse thief
who then battered her
within an inch of her life.
Human beings are
capable of greatness.
Bravery, charity, love, decency.
And yet the very same species
has monsters who do
things like this.
It's gonna be a
scheduling challenge.
I'm trying to ramp down the OR
now that we're closing Trauma.
So there's less
on-call anesthesia.
Maybe if you guys double-team it
you can share anesthesia?
Well, the surgery's
pretty risky already.
Are we sure we want
to do it at all?
I see she has a possible
diagnosis of dementia.
We could table the
subdural for now,
get her another CT
scan in a few hours,
- put her on frequent neuro checks.
- Mm-hmm.
Conrad had a similar impulse,
but we have no proof that
the problem is dementia.
I mean, for all we
know she could finish
the Sunday New York
Times crossword puzzle
when she doesn't
have 200cc's of blood
pushing on her parietal lobe.
Book the OR.
Okay.
I don't want to lose
another patient.
I understand being risk-averse
after what happened yesterday,
but the patient you lost
had metastatic cancer
and an unhinged family.
This woman has no one but us
and at least a
chance of recovery.
You're right. I'm in.
What's his temp?
Cooled temperature is down
to 20 degrees Celsius.
Ah, the tear
could have extended since.
All right, we're gonna
have to stop his heart
to get a good look.
And the bypass machine.
We'll have no
circulation at all. For how long?
Thirty minutes until anoxic
brain injury sets in.
Maybe sooner at his age.
I know this sucks,
but the man said he was all in,
which means we are all in.
Bold action.
He's at 18 degrees.
Cooling goal reached.
He's going into
hypothermia-induced V fib.
Cardioplegic
medication to me.
And here we go.
- Arrest time starting now.
- Good. Let's move.
You got 25 minutes.
I'm almost done. Hopefully.
The dissection took out
his whole aortic arch.
Left carotid, left subclavian
and the innominate.
He certainly did not
make this easy for me.
Not to mention the
single-vessel bypass for his RCA.
The good news is
we're almost there.
Damn it! 4-0 suture to me.
- You are running out of time.
- My OR requires everyone
to be cool, calm and collected.
And that includes
the observation room.
All right, we are good.
I'm unclamping.
Yes.
- Whew.
- Yes.
All right.
Oh...
All right, put him back on pump.
How's Dr. Perry?
He made it through the surgery,
but that's all we know for now.
Cade, if you have a minute,
I think we should talk.
I'm not sure what
there is to say.
Well, we're gonna
be working together,
I hope for a long time.
So I want to give you the
chance to get whatever it is
you're feeling off your chest.
Okay.
I know Conrad talked to you.
I just wanted to say that
- neither of us saw this coming.
- Oh, come on.
You've been in love with Conrad
the entire time I've known you.
I never had any intention
of taking him away from you.
The dance at Kit
and Bell's wedding?
Unplanned.
But you're right.
And I don't want you to think
that I'm the kind of person
- that would swoop in...
- Look, I like you.
Right now I wish I
didn't, but I do.
So for what it's worth,
in these types of situations,
no one does the swooping.
It's kind of a two-handed game.
Well, I'm not sure
Conrad's responsible
for feelings he couldn't
fight or even face.
Okay. I
didn't need that.
I... I'm sorry, I'm not
finding the right words.
It's fine. I will survive.
Because I know what I deserve.
I deserve someone who loves me,
not someone who's
working overtime
to deny they love you.
I really am sorry.
Don't be. It's pointless.
Just so you know,
Hawkins never said "I love you."
Not once.
Neither of us did.
Extubating now.
Subdural
drain complete.
Perfect timing.
Just closing skin.
Well, I think we
actually managed to pull this off
in record time.
If we're good here,
I was due in my next
OR ten minutes ago.
I appreciate you working
with our staff cuts.
Thank you, Paul.
Let OR 7 know
I'm on my way.
I'm pretty
much wrapped up here,
and I should check on some
post-op patients, too.
You good?
Yes. Thank you, Billie.
She's in SVT.
Blood pressure's tanking.
Get Paul back here.
No time. I know what to do.
- I am not losing this patient today.
- Do it.
Pushing adenosine now.
She's back
in sinus rhythm.
Pressure's coming back up.
We've got this. Thanks, Paul.
Love being irrelevant.
Nice job.
Looks like someone's
made a full recovery.
And I'm not talking about
our lovely patient Lillian.
Turns out I survive, too.
Ah. Well, you certainly
put me to the test, Dr. P.
Oh, he was masterful.
Full aortic arch repair.
Truly, Dr. Austin.
And you're already
weaned off the pressors.
Your BP's looking good.
When did you do the
first arch repair...
- 1970?
- '69.
Wow. And they didn't have
all the fancy OR tools
- we have now. Can you...
- Aah!
Oh!
What's going on?
I'm dissecting again.
The aorta's torn through.
And we knew this could happen.
- It's not your fault.
- Okay.
Continue the nicardipine
- and the esmolol.
- We'll do that.
The man is crashing and
he's still in control.
You won't be able to operate
again. This is worse.
We'll control your blood pressure.
And your heart rate
and pain, okay?
- You're gonna make it through.
- It was a long shot.
We got you, all right?
And your job is to stay calm.
Once your blood
pressure spikes...
I die instantly.
I'm aware. And calm.
- So calm. So calm.
- Hi.
- I'm Dr. Devi.
She's Padma's
sister. Is she awake?
Yes.
Hey, um, I think she'd
rather see you alone.
Hey, Paddie.
You okay?
They think I'm crazy.
Tomorrow you'll
see a psychiatrist,
and we'll move you
to a better place.
One that specializes in
postpartum depression.
What would I ever
do without you?
You'll never be without me.
And I can't be without you.
The boys.
They're with Serena.
AJ's gonna go home to them soon.
The worst is over.
This is the beginning
of recovery.
The first day of a new life.
Hello, Ms. Lillian Cortland.
How you feeling, my dear?
I'd like some applesauce.
And a clicker that gets me PBS.
Because cable news
will rot your brain
faster than a moldy grape on
the bottom of a fruit bowl.
- Can you tell me who our president is?
- Can you tell me
who all the presidents
are in order,
including Millard
Fillmore? Because I can.
Yeah, I get your game.
I'm old, so you think I
got mush in my noggin.
Hey, you were
right, I was wrong.
Look at that, a man
who admits he's wrong.
Now that is a rare quality.
My late husband,
may he rot in hell,
he never apologized for
a thing in his life.
Lillian, do you remember
how you were injured?
Yes, I'm fully aware.
I was beaten up by a
mugger because I would not
let him steal my purse.
And where is it, anyway?
You know what, Lillian,
we're gonna find out.
We're gonna see about
that applesauce, too.
And PBS.
Hey.
What's the latest on Dr. Perry?
Well, the godfather of
cardiothoracic surgery
did not die in my OR.
But his outcome is uncertain.
How are you?
There's something we
should probably discuss,
but, you know, we
can also talk later.
No, no, no, no,
don't do that to me.
Sit. Talk.
I could use the company.
It's about Padma.
Did she make it home?
I certainly hope so, because
this absent mom thing
is getting real old.
Padma is struggling with
acute postpartum depression,
and she was suicidal.
Suicidal?
She almost threw
herself off a bridge.
She came to me and Devon
for help, and now she's here
- on a temporary psychiatric hold.
- Can I see her?
No, no. Not yet.
She doesn't want to
face you. She's ashamed.
Wow, I knew it was bad. I-I
didn't know it was that bad.
Devon said no one saw it
because Padma didn't want us to.
What about the boys?
Once she's better,
she'll be there for them.
Uh, no, we don't know that.
Lots of mothers go through this.
Now at least she's getting help.
What if they're
not safe with her?
She loves those
little boys. She does.
She's just feeling inadequate
right now, like she...
she doesn't deserve
to be their mother,
or she's overwhelmed,
I don't know.
Right. Right.
It's, um, it's-it's biochemical.
It's hormonal.
There are a lot of things
that factor into this.
And it can be treated.
Look, she really needs our
support right now. Okay?
So please, please
don't turn on her.
I won't.
I can't.
- Hey.
I hear you're
having a rough day.
I am.
How's Dr. Perry?
We don't know.
He dissected again. He
could still pull through.
His tear could stabilize, but
it's out of our hands now.
I'm so sorry.
Hey, before you say whatever
you're about to say,
I think I already know.
Hawkins?
You're an amazing
guy, James, 100%.
If there was no Conrad...
Hey, hey, hey. Don't, don't.
It's okay.
You knew him long
before you knew me,
there was already a
history. I'm aware.
I don't know what to say.
It was fun while it lasted.
However brief.
My heart's intact, okay?
This is him. I... I should go.
Of course. I hope
he's all right.
What's going on?
He wanted you to be here.
Unfortunately, the patient
has entered the dying process.
You see?
Acute aortic valve
insufficiency.
Widening of pulse pressure,
a harbinger of doom
following a repair.
It means the aorta has torn
again through the valve.
Even as we speak,
the patient's heart is
being surrounded by blood.
Tamponade will ensue.
There's nothing more
we can do for him
but stay with him.
Make sure he is in no pain.
Do not give his
care over to nurses.
Walk with him on
the final journey.
Hold his hand.
You see what James...
is doing?
This... is how it's done.
Can't we place a pericardial
drain, return to the OR?
His blood pressure
is too low to travel.
We can open his
chest at bedside.
No.
I can't... tolerate that.
Goodbye...
my children.
♪ ♪
I am so sorry.
Thanks.
I think you and I joined
the same club today.
Yeah. We were
too good for 'em.
Listen, if you don't
want to be alone tonight,
we could grab stiff margaritas
at Waylon's.
You could tell me
all about Dr. Perry.
Yeah.
I'd like that.
He was a truly great man.
I know it's not the outcome
you needed this week...
One of the most famous living
doctors dies at Chastain.
We were honored to treat him.
If he could have been
saved, you'd have done it.
Is it true we're no longer
a level 1 trauma
hospital after today?
I never thought I'd
say it, but yes.
The money is gone,
the fight is over.
You know what, Kit?
Whatever happens,
even if this whole
place shut down tonight,
we created something
great here together.
And that will live
on in everyone
- who was a part of it.
- Thank you, AJ.
Hey. EMT said I
needed to get this
to you right away.
They went back to where
they picked up your patient.
It was in a dumpster.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
There's someone I want
you to say hello to.
Miss Lillian, I want
you to meet someone.
Hello. I'm Kit Voss,
CEO of Chastain.
It's wonderful to
see you on the mend.
We have something
that belongs to you.
My purse.
Oh, that's wonderful.
Oh, thank heavens.
Yeah. No more wallet, obviously.
But tissues and...
and my bus pass
and-and my lipstick.
And-and Werther's!
Here. Have-have some.
- Okay.
- Oh.
Gosh, I... I'm just so happy,
I can't tell you. I...
To think I almost died
over some worn-out old
- crossbody bag.
- It's the principle of the thing.
That's right.
You can't let some jerk just
take what belongs to you.
I'm old, but I
fought like a tiger.
When I know what's
right, I'm all in.
I'm sorry. You're gonna
have to reroute the patient.
Our trauma center is closing
down in five minutes.
- Stroke of midnight, finished.
- What was that?
- GSW.
- Oh, good luck getting that rerouted.
Nobody else takes
gunshot wounds.
- I know.
- This is so wrong.
May I have everyone's
attention, please.
I have two announcements.
One, I have meat and veggie,
and for anyone who's vegan,
there's salad because I
cannot condone vegan cheese.
Hear, hear.
Two, I have determined
that Chastain Trauma will
not be closing tonight.
What?
I repeat, we will not
be closing our doors.
Hey, just kidding.
We'll take that GSW.
- What changed?
- I did.
I've decided we will not
let a bully destroy us
piece by piece.
He cannot win. We are going to
spend every dime to deliver top
care until the money's gone.
We're not gonna limp along
as a hollowed-out shell.
We are going all in.
Yes! Yes!- -
Come on, before this gets cold.
Grab a slice.