Previously on Grey's Anatomy...
Webber has singled you out?
Yeah, anointed me.
He knows about us.
Oh! I'm so screwed!
Maggie, I told him
you were a wildcat.
What?
Blake should be in our surgery.
Callie, stop. No, I am sorry,
but I can't just stand here
and... You're embarrassing me!
Stay out of it.
If you want to start
over, let's do it.
Just like new? Square one.
What are you doing?
I barely know you. At least
ask me out on a date first.
Did Arizona tell you...
I worked in peds.
I figured it out.
How far along are
you? Nine weeks.
He doesn't know? Not yet.
Behold. Everything the
light touches is yours.
Congratulations, Chief.
Meredith, you got really
good at being alone.
Are you saying I can't
be alone anymore?
No, I think you can.
I just don't think
you want to be.
Back in med school,
I knew a guy who spent
his weekends as a magician
for children's birthday parties.
Okay, this is only a dry
run, and it's the first of many.
Won't be perfect,
but once we start,
I don't want to stop until
we get to the other side.
Agreed? Okay.
Let's go. Yep.
It makes a weird kind of sense.
If you plan on sawing
a person in half,
you're going to
need to practice.
When you take the stage
and all eyes are on you,
you don't want the
audience to see you sweat.
Three days ago,
I received a call
from a colleague
at Bauer Medical,
a military facility just
outside of Seattle.
A consult was requested
for a 35-year-old male patient
with an osteosarcoma
of the left pelvis,
lumbar spine, and sacrum.
You only want them
to see the magic.
Whoa! Seconded.
Traditionally, a tumor like this
would be approached with
aggressive chemoradiation
that would give him a
few years to live, at most.
There's got to be
something better than that.
Torres thought so, too.
She had a better idea.
Torres' plan was to use
the vascularized fibular grafts
from the amputated leg
to attach the right leg and
pelvis to the spine at the midline.
This would provide axial
stability, and potentially...
Okay.
The ability to walk.
That's...
Impressive? Insane.
And I mean that in the best way.
What did we just do?
A miracle.
It's a solid plan, Torres.
You should be proud.
I am.
But we still have
a few days left,
so I'd like to run
through it twice tomorrow,
see if we can get our time down.
Right. But first, sleep.
Yeah, all the sleep I can carry.
Folks, hang on.
We have a problem.
Colonel Miller just called
from Bauer Medical.
Our patient just took a fall
and has fractured his pelvis.
What? OWEN: Our
timeline has changed.
His fractured pelvis has
compromised blood flow
to the leg we need to salvage.
Our window's closing.
If we wait, there
won't be anything left
to use in the reconstruction.
Okay, well, when
do they want to do it?
Tonight.
Would've liked
another run-through.
Okay, when... When...
When can he come? He's not.
After the fall, the patient's
not stable enough to move.
We have to go to
him. It's an away game.
It's an away game.
It's not even fair.
I mean, no one else got a
chance to volunteer to go.
What can I say?
I'm good at ortho,
I'm good at plastics.
I'm a switch-hitter.
I'm an integral
part of the team.
Wilson did the only trial run.
Of course I would
rather take you.
I'm kind of stuck here.
Whatever. I still get to go.
Now, listen, about Bauer.
Bye! Military
hospitals are a mix
of civilian and military doctors
with a very strict
idea about hierarchy.
Okay, Hunt, I get it.
These are your people.
We'll do you proud.
Take me with you.
I thought you didn't want
me messing in your career.
Maybe just this once. This
surgery's gonna be amazing.
Sorry, Blake. No
special treatment.
Same thing I tell my husband.
Hunt! We got incoming.
Be right there. Good luck!
You know Curt Morgan?
The neuro-ophthalmologist?
I do, yeah. He's a nice guy.
He is a nice guy.
And he was asking about you.
Bailey. I'm just
saying he was asking.
Who was asking about what?
Oh, uh, Curt Morgan
was asking about Dr. Grey.
Wilson. Oh. Curt.
Yeah, he's great.
We play ball with him
on Wednesday nights.
Okay, what about we stop
talking about Curt Morgan
and focus on what we have to do?
Or we could talk about the
fact that he's tall and handsome,
divorced, funny, doesn't
have kids... Handsome.
You said handsome twice.
That wasn't an accident.
Hey, remember,
we're guests here.
Hunt wants us on
our best behavior.
I've spent a lot of time
working with the military.
If we're respectful
and do our jobs,
we won't ruffle
any feathers. Okay.
Dr. Bailey. Colonel Miller.
So nice to finally put
a face with the voice.
Likewise.
This is Captain Vaughn. Hi.
She's here to help make sure
you have everything that you...
Colonel, what the hell?
Dr. Bailey, this is
Major Thorpe. He's...
I'm Sergeant Carson's surgeon.
And you are... The "Dream Team"?
You can't just make
decisions for my patient.
Oh, we're not here to
step on toes, Doctor.
You're here to make
my patient a guinea pig.
How about we take a step back?
How about you take 10
steps back, through that door,
because no one's touching my patient!
- Thorpe.
Sir, I understand that you
want what's best for your patient.
Is the surgery new
and risky? Yes, it is.
But if it works...
Oh, It'll work.
Major Thorpe, your
chief asked for our help
because he knows we're the best.
Now, you called
us the Dream Team,
and that's exactly what we
are. We are miracle workers.
Now, the sooner
you recognize that,
the sooner we can get to
the business of saving a life,
which is all any of us are
here to do, yourself included.
If you'll all follow me.
I think you may have
ruffled some feathers.
"Miracle workers"? You
think maybe you overdid that?
We've practiced
once, Torres. Once.
I might've gotten a little
carried away. A little?
We're so screwed.
Karev wants me in the ER.
Look, I'm on call all night,
but if it's slow, I mean,
I could meet you back
here in a couple hours.
Sounds tempting.
Ah, Pierce, there you are.
Yes, Riggs, here I am.
Wanted to see
about getting you in
on an elective
VATS in the morning.
Yeah, absolutely.
That is a two-hander,
so let's do it.
So I'm gonna put you
down for 9:30, yeah?
Mmm-hmm. Cool. Cheers.
That was close.
Are we still doing this?
Yes. Because it's a secret,
and that's what you do with
secrets. You keep them secret.
Yeah, but what's the point?
Look, your sisters
know, Webber knows.
It's getting a little
old, honestly, okay?
And... And I got
to get out of here.
Karev's paged me
three times already.
Coming through.
Clear the way!
DeLuca, where the hell have
you been? Grab me some Kerlix.
Lisa. Have you seen
Lisa? She's our captain.
Let me guess.
Ponytail, hair bow?
God, she's gonna be so mad.
We didn't stick the final pose,
and it wasn't even that hard.
It was just a 13-person
synchronized Liberty Twist.
Thirteen? Wow.
Pulse is over 130.
Run an EKG and a metabolic
panel and add a detox.
Nobody was
listening to each other.
Danielle hit her trick too soon,
so everyone else
had to match, and...
All right, just try to
calm down a little, okay?
Are you kidding? We
were in the final round!
We were about to
qualify for Nationals!
Slight tenderness
to the abdomen,
but I want to do an ultrasound
to make sure everything is okay.
Oh, my God. Dani, are you okay?
Everything hurts.
I can't believe this. I...
I can't... Hey, Maxine,
are you a little dizzy?
Maxine? I am.
My life is over.
Coming through!
Page neuro. No telling how hard
she hit her head when she fell.
Her BP's through the roof.
And you understand the risks
of the surgery that
we're talking about?
I've explained
the risk in detail.
Yeah, he won't shut
up about the risk.
He's explained the
benefits, too, I hope.
And keep in mind, with some
aggressive chemo and radiation,
you've got a chance at
a couple of good years.
And with our approach,
you have a shot at a full life.
Many... THORPE:
Brian, you're sick.
I'm not convinced you can
withstand this kind of surgery.
You roll the dice on this one,
we could lose you
on the table tonight.
Listen, I've spent five tours
of duty, all around the world.
I missed the births
of both my girls.
I have another one on the way.
I want the life
I've been missing.
If you can give me that,
well, I'm all in.
Well? We're a go.
Your work better be
as good as your talk.
Dr. Thorpe, we'll
see you in the OR.
Let's not waste any more
time. We need to get to the OR.
And Dr. Avery needs to be shown
where he can set up for
the bone-graft harvest.
Yep.
We're really doing this?
It's gonna be great.
Okay. Okay, this will work.
I'm glad you think so.
Do you see everything you need?
Uh, you know, I need
a Bovie in here, please.
I'll grab it if you
let me watch.
The bone-graft retrieval.
Sorry, we're a
military hospital.
I see mostly trauma-related
patch-up jobs.
You have a reputation for a
much more refined approach.
My reputation? I
have a reputation?
I Googled you.
I mean, I Googled all of you.
Everyone's really
excited about the surgery.
We don't get a lot of chances
to see someone with
your level of expertise.
Um... You know what? Yeah. Sure.
You can watch.
Thank you.
I'll be right back
with that Bovie.
Could she flirt any harder?
What? Nobody's
flirting with anybody.
Oh, come on. "I Googled you?"
She was totally
flirting. So were you.
I was not! What did I even say?
You didn't have to say anything.
All of this is a flirt.
I'm gonna need you to be still.
I mean, she barely
even looks hurt
when my face is split open.
Maxine screwed us.
Danielle's the one
who threw us off.
She didn't put her
weight in her heel
when she knows she has to... Ow!
What? Are you trying
to break it more?
I am so over them.
We have worked too hard
and sacrificed too much
to let Maxine and Dani
humiliate us like that.
They are out.
Down.
Done. Hashtag that.
That girl is the reason
I hated high school.
What a power trip.
She can't just kick
somebody off the team.
Are you kidding me?
She's the power center here.
She's cheer captain
and squad leader.
What's the difference?
You see the way
they all look at her.
She's the top of the
social food chain.
She calls all the shots,
decides who's in, who's out.
She says jump, they
ask, "Off which bridge?"
How do you know all this?
'Cause I was squad leader.
It was exhausting.
You were the reason
I hated high school.
I actually loved high school.
I bet. Everybody loved
high school in the '50s.
Yep. I will send
someone right up.
That was psych.
One of their patients
needs a surgical consult.
Oh, dibs! Me, please!
Come on. Shoot for it.
Bam! Warren, head up to psych
and bring Spencer with you. Yes!
What the hell? I'm on it.
Maybe we could intubate them.
Mmm.
They would be so, so quiet.
Maxine, can you
touch your nose for me?
Are they talking about
me? Lisa and Chelsea?
I know they are. They're
always talking about someone.
Other hand, please.
I've been trying so hard
just to make the team
a team, you know?
Maxine, you're working
yourself up again.
Take some deep breaths.
You can't advance in cheer
if you don't trust each other.
Balance and trust, that's the
foundation. I keep telling them.
So maybe I'm a little
bitchy about it. So?
It's not like Lisa isn't bitchy
every single day of her life.
Wow, that was all one breath.
Your neuro exam is clear.
I'd like to get a head
CT just to be safe.
I just wanted us to win.
What's so bad about that?
For starters, you're 17
with the BP of a 50-year-old.
Nothing too good about that.
Never been up to psych before.
To be clear, I didn't actually
go to school in the '50s.
It's dark up here.
Smells weird.
I mean, I know I'm
older, but I'm not old.
Patients keep screaming.
Dr. Siegel, right?
You called for an
abdominal consult?
Yeah, right here.
I was doing his intake, and he
just started clutching his stomach.
Sir? Sir? Can you hear me?
He's non-communicative.
Pulse is 130 and
thready. I think he's...
Yep. He's crashing.
Should we take him out of here?
I can't get a pressure.
Yeah, he's bleeding into
his belly from a triple-A.
We need to get him into the OR.
I think I lost his pulse.
He's not gonna
make it to surgery.
I'm just gonna have to
open him up right here.
Oh, that's not going to happen.
I need a thoracotomy
tray, a crash cart, and blood,
and a scalpel, now.
There is nothing
here! There's no...
This is the psych ward.
There's nothing sharp here.
- There's nothing sharp here!
- It's not allowed.
You got to be kidding me.
Look, go find me
something I can cut with!
You don't think maybe we
should wait for an attending?
Wait. You're not an attending?
Spencer, get me a scalpel now!
Okay, yeah.
I'm not feeling good
about this, Torres.
I don't like walking into a
surgery where I'm not feeling good.
You feeling good, Grey?
We practiced it once.
We're about to pull an
all-nighter. Sure. Feeling great.
Everything's gonna
be fine, you guys.
We just have to be
squirrels about this.
Couldn't have heard
you correctly there.
You know, squirrels...
They store nuts
for the winter, right?
But they don't do it all at once.
They do it one nut at a time.
Everyone has their part to play,
so everyone just needs
to handle their own nut.
We do that, we get all the nuts.
- Makes sense.
- Does it, though?
All right, if we're doing this,
let's not waste any more time.
Yeah, Thorpe, can
you give us one minute?
I need to confer with my team.
Okay.
Dr. Bailey, are we conferring?
We're praying. Torres is right.
We'll be fine if we
each just do our part.
Figure it doesn't hurt
to ask God to do His.
Callie, how long do we
stand here doing this?
I don't know. How should I know?
You pray and stuff. I mean,
what's she looking for?
Some kind of sign or something?
If I was, I sure wouldn't
hear it over the two of you.
Sorry. Apologies.
You told Karev?
You told Karev about
your baby situation
and you haven't
even told Jackson?
I didn't tell Karev
anything. He figured it out.
It's like he could smell
it on me or something.
You can do that if you
spend enough time in peds.
Pregnant ladies have a smell.
What?
Oh, calm down. I'm just kidding.
How many more people
have to find out about this
before you tell...
Find out about what?
Nothing.
You two have a secret.
Mmm-mmm. No,
we don't. What is it?
Did you find out about
DeLuca? Come on.
Robbins, you have
hospital gossip.
You're gonna hold out
on me? Mmm-mmm.
Spill. ARIZONA: No,
there's nothing to tell.
Whoa. Sorry. I
need a crash cart,
a thoracotomy tray, and...
Spencer.
Do you need something?
Yeah, I... I need you.
Where the hell is Mitchell?
I think you should call it.
He's been down a long time.
Shut up. Just shut up, please.
I think I got a faint pulse.
I think that's your
pulse you're feeling.
I got to open him up
now. If I don't, he's dead.
Again, I'm not gonna allow you
to open up a man in my ward.
This is not an OR. You
are not an attending.
What in the hell are you...
No. No, no, no.
Are... Are you insane?
Dr. Siegel, this
man is going to die.
You are way out of line
here. And it will be your fault,
so please, don't make
me put my hands on you.
Are you threatening me now?
Whoa, whoa. No,
no, no! No, no, no!
Hey, I found Dr. Webber, and
I go... Okay! Too... Too late.
Warren, what are you doing?
Spencer, get over here.
Help me spread
his ribs. Spread his...
Reach in, push your
fingers through his muscles.
Harder! Come on! Do it! Warren!
I got it. I got his
aorta in my hand.
Yeah, I got a pulse.
Dr. Webber, can... Can
you get an OR for us?
Okay, Callie, you are
good to go up here.
All right. Okay, I just
need to inspect the SI joint,
make sure we're ready
to amputate the left leg
with the hemipelvis.
Okay. Okay.
Margins are adequate,
and the stasis is achieved.
Landmarks are looking...
Good.
Torres?
Looking good? CALLIE:
Yep. Yep, yep, yep.
Just... Want to be sure.
'Cause once it's off, it's off.
Excuse me?
Bailey? This looks good, right?
Right there.
It's gonna have to come
off one way or the other.
Yes, I know that.
It's just, after this, there's
really no turning back.
I mean, none, so...
Torres...
Be a squirrel.
Okay.
Oscillating saw, please.
Owen is completely
serious about starting over.
He wants to take me on a date.
Like, a "date" date.
Like, no sex, just
dinner and a movie.
Kind of into it.
DeLuca wants to take us public.
God, he wants to hold hands
in the hallway or something.
I like holding hands.
What if we hold
hands and make out?
When was the last time
you made out with a guy
without it going any
further than that?
Why do we have
to parade it around?
You don't, but
what is the problem?
If DeLuca wants to... Shh, shh!
Oh. It's just you.
This still with DeLuca?
Yes, "This still."
I don't even know
what "this" is,
and I don't need to figure it
out in front of everyone else.
How's our cheerleader?
Well, there's no sign of a bleed.
It looks like a mild concussion.
What if it ends?
Then I'm the woman
who dated the pretty boy,
and it all fell apart.
We done here?
Who will take me seriously then?
Yeah, I'm... I'm supposed to
take you seriously right now?
I'm a very serious person!
Incredible.
Excuse me?
Just your technique,
the way you
preserve the vessels.
It's really smooth.
Sorry. I...
I have a patient I should
check on. But I'll be back.
What?
Nothing. That wasn't flirting.
I mean, I know what
flirting looks like.
I didn't say anything.
All right. How we
doing with the harvest?
Oh, slow moving,
unlike Dr. Vaughn,
who's super-fast.
Wilson.
What're you talking about?
She was flirting with him.
She was not.
Oh!
Well, I mean, I
don't see why not.
She doesn't know him
the way we do. Mmm.
- What the hell's that mean?
- Oh, you know.
We see you every day.
We're used to all of that.
All right, you two,
I need to focus.
Yes, by all means.
Your head CT is fine.
You probably have a mild
concussion. Not a big deal.
But you need to figure out
a way to control your stress.
I know. I've always
been like this.
My parents say I'm high-strung.
Mmm. Your parents
are on their way?
Yeah, Coach called them.
Lisa, it was an accident!
You never stick the mount.
You trick too early, no matter
how many times we tell you not to.
Edwards, get them to chill.
Guys, it's an emergency room.
Can you please save the
yelling for actual emergencies?
So, what, you think
I did it on purpose?
She thinks you're
a liability. Truth.
What's going on?
Lisa's kicking me off the team.
What? Lisa... No,
you can't do that.
How about we
don't do any of this?
Do you need me to separate you?
Last I checked, I
was team captain.
Last I checked, you
were a megabitch.
Hey! Hey! Enough!
Dani is the best
climber we've got.
Her kicks are incredible.
You're just defending her
because she's your bestie
and you're basically
attached at the hip, so...
Blake, can you quiet her down?
What do you want
me to do, sedate them?
What does that have
to do with anything?
Guys, be quiet. CHELSEA:
You didn't belong up there.
You're clearly not
pyramid material.
Blake, keep her quiet!
Well, you quiet yours down!
Who says I even want to
cheer with any of you anyway?
Good! Because you're
bringing us all down!
Literally! Everybody shut up!
I don't have a pulse.
Is that Maxine? Blake,
charge the paddles to 200.
What happened? What's happening?
Is she okay? Maxine?
Is she dying? Oh, my God.
What happened to her?
Guys, look. Is she dead?
Somebody, curtain!
Clear!
How's that hand, Warren?
I'm losing feeling in it.
Worried I'm gonna
let the aorta go.
Okay, well, we'll
get you out of this.
Rib spreader, Spencer.
Get a clamp ready.
Okay.
Got it. I got it.
Okay. What's his pressure?
Uh, holding steady. 90 systolic.
Of all the stupid,
irresponsible...
I cannot fathom what
possessed you to pull a stunt...
I don't know what else
I should have done.
Hey, you don't want to get me
started on "should" right now.
You should've
called an attending
the second you walked in there.
You should've
known the situation
was nowhere near
under your control.
And right now, you
should be thanking God
that I'm here to
clean up your mess.
Yes, sir. I'll do what...
Yeah, you'll do
whatever I damn well say.
Right now, you better be praying
that this man doesn't
die on the table.
Maxine, you with
me? Stay with me.
I had a heart attack?
How were her electrolytes
before she coded?
Good. Within normal limits.
Her heart rate was
over 200 on the monitor.
Did Lisa see it? Did she see me?
Maxine, you did not
have a heart attack.
You have a heart
condition, WPW syndrome.
It causes dramatic fluctuations
in your heart
rate. Wait, wait...
Normally, I would
treat it with medication,
but your symptoms
are pretty severe,
so I want to take it up to
surgery to correct it right now.
No, but my parents...
I'm sorry, but we
don't have time
to wait for your parents, okay?
Call upstairs. Prep
for a cardiac ablation.
Will I still be able to cheer?
Lisa already hates me.
If she thinks I'm sick,
she's gonna kick
me off the team, too.
I can't get kicked off.
The team is my life.
Can't you downplay it or
something, keep it a secret?
I just... I really don't want
this to go public, you know?
I'll handle them.
Don't worry.
I'll take these DeBakeys.
Dr. Thorpe, are you
ready with the ileal conduit?
Almost there.
Great. Right on time. Good.
Damn it.
Look, this bone's friable.
Well, I must say, your
work is impeccable.
Oh, yeah? You think so?
Beautiful lembert, Dr. Grey.
Watch out. You almost
sound glad we're here.
Dr. Grey, can you
come with me for a sec?
You want me to step
away from the table?
Mmm-hmm.
I need you on this.
Go ahead. I'm good.
Callie, what?
I don't think I can do this.
I can't believe
this is happening.
I can't believe Maxine is dying.
Oh, I didn't say she's dying.
She and I have hung together
forever, since elementary school.
You're such a
good friend to her.
Oh, shut up! This
is all your fault.
You're the reason
she had a heart attack.
It's not a heart attack.
I didn't do anything to her.
How dare you! STEPHANIE: Okay...
You pushed her like you
push all of us. Calm down.
I push because I care!
Calm down. And because you suck!
I suck? Your hair sucks! Yeah.
Your face sucks!
My face doesn't suck.
Gerber baby. Gerber baby.
All of you sucks!
That's the worst
comeback in the world.
Oh, no, it's not.
God, I hated high school.
Yeah, well, you were,
like, 11 in high school.
Diffuse ST elevations.
Her coronaries are spasming.
We'll need to open them up.
I'll need the ultrasound
and a 5-French sheath.
Prep a drug-eluting stent.
Push 75 of lido
and a bolus of nitro.
- Right away, Doctor.
- Look at this girl.
She's stressing herself
into a heart failure
over whether these
little popularity vultures
will allow her into the
in-crowd like it's life and death.
It's all life and death to them.
Yeah.
Thank God we grew out of that.
Yeah. And look at you now.
Yeah.
What do you mean,
"Look at me now"?
You and DeLuca.
Come on.
My point exactly. I work
with teenagers every day.
I know what high
school crap looks like.
Multifocal PVCs
from the ischemia.
She's not responding
to the meds.
Pull in the cart and prep the paddles.
- Yes, Doctor.
You're the big quarterback, and
he's the little freshman nerd girl
you're embarrassed to
be seen with in public.
What?
That's misogynistic and wrong.
I am the nerd girl. I've
always been the nerd girl.
Not around here. Around
here, you're a prom queen.
You're All-State.
Attendings are
the popular crowd,
and he's a nobody,
and that bugs you.
She's in fib.
All right. Charge to 200.
Charging.
Everybody clear.
Nothing. Again.
All right, we have sinus.
No, this is not high school.
This is life. This is work.
Yeah, exactly, and look around.
I live with a resident.
Torres dates one.
Meredith married an attending.
Nobody cares except you.
Let's get that stent in.
Why are you not in the OR?
Tell him what you told me.
What's going on?
I can't do the reconstruction.
Torres, what the hell?
I had to...
I had to resect the wider
margins to get to
healthy bone, okay?
The fibular grafts will be too
small to hold everything in place.
I've got no way to dock the leg.
We don't have a
fallback plan here.
Okay, I need you to hear me.
This is not a matter
of confidence, okay?
It's not me. It is the bone.
I am saying that, with
the pelvis that I have left,
I literally cannot do it.
Well, you better do something.
She's right. Look,
if we stop now,
we're leaving him worse
off than when we got him.
He's not gonna
survive the night.
Okay. Stop. Stop it. Okay?
You guys aren't telling me
anything I don't already know.
Just... I need a minute. I
need some space to think.
Okay? Just... You all go
back in there and irrigate.
I don't know. Just buy
me some time, okay?
Okay, you heard her. Let's
just give her some space.
I will think of something.
Come on.
Damn it!
She's coming back, right?
She's coming back.
Good. Because he's
been under for a long time.
Listen, I know you've
had your reservations,
but when we're done...
I still have my reservations.
I've known Carson ever
since the Medical Corps.
He's a one-night stand for you.
I'm sorry?
Look, you fly in,
do a flashy surgery
that'll make all the journals,
and you're gone in the morning.
And I'm still here to help him
make sense of what you did.
You're leaving him with one
leg in the middle of his body.
You say he'll walk again? How?
How's that even gonna work?
Not to mention how
you're compromising
his gastrointestinal system,
his nervous system.
He thinks you're
giving him his life back,
but what's that life
gonna look like?
We'll follow up.
Of course we will.
Dr. Torres will be available.
Will she? When's that?
You didn't get
through to them at all?
Whatever. I hope
they eat each other.
Look. He's down
there, all right.
DeLuca. Is it true?
Warren cut a guy
open with a clipboard?
It is.
I feel like I'd get in trouble
for something like that. Yeah.
And he gets a surgery out of it.
It must be nice being
married to the chief.
Look at Wilson.
All she has to do is
sleep with Grey's BFF.
Of course she gets
the wonder surgery.
Come on. You're...
I mean, you're
seeing Torres, right?
Callie doesn't give me anything.
Besides, she was dating Torres
before she even
started working here.
She's not nailing an
attending to get ahead.
I don't think that's
what's going on here.
Really? Warren's
married to the chief,
so he's scrubbed in
down there on a surgery
while we're stuck
watching up here.
You don't think
the two are related?
I know they are.
It's unfair. Uncool.
Lame. So lame.
Oh, dear God.
We sound just like...
Yeah, we do.
But we're not like those girls.
Well, I'm not.
Oh.
Excuse me?
I was never like
one of those girls.
I never fit in the usual molds,
I always did my own thing,
I never wore a hair bow,
and I never worried about it.
And you think I did?
You said yourself
you were one of them.
Like "boss lady" one of them.
Hmm.
You're right.
I was.
Where are you going?
Good blood flow to the kidneys.
You know what this
means, Dr. Spencer?
That the patient's
gonna survive, sir?
Well, it means that Dr. Warren
will only be facing suspension
instead of
criminal-assault charges.
Sir, I understand
you're upset...
The time for pulling
boneheaded stunts is long past...
"Boneheaded"?
What about saving a
man's life is boneheaded?
Warren...
Look, sir, I may be a resident,
but I have been a
doctor a lot longer.
The other residents
love to give me crap
about how much
older than them I am,
but at the end of the
day, I'm also wiser, too.
All right, this wasn't a stunt.
This was a judgment call.
I took a risk, it paid off,
and this man is alive.
Now, I understand,
I broke the rules,
and I need to pay
the price for that, but...
I'm not an idiot.
And I don't deserve to be
spoken to as though I am.
No, what you deserve
is a hell of a lot worse.
What you call a calculated
risk is what I call foolish.
Don't confuse the two, Warren.
You did not show skill today.
You showed bravado,
and that is dangerous.
Suction.
Callie.
No, get back in
there. It's fine, it's fine.
I'm... I'm... I'm thinking.
Okay, I just need to think.
You want space? Yes!
I get it.
I keep asking for space.
People keep not giving it to me,
bugging me about hot
doctors asking for my number.
And I keep shutting
them down because...
Why? Why are we
talking about this?
Because it's not always the
worst thing when people push you.
When people push you,
they're trying to help you.
I'm trying to help you.
Let's figure this out, please.
You can't. It's my specialty.
It's on me. And I am trying.
I just... I don't
know how to make...
So if we had
another practice run
and we were in the cadaver lab
and you had all the time in the world,
where would you start?
We don't have time!
That's the problem.
Okay. So what's the
first thing you would do?
I don't know!
Yes, you do. I know you do.
I would
review the biomechanics,
and then I would...
Recalculate the angles.
Okay. And then?
Okay, ladies! Okay, ladies!
Hi!
Here's how this is gonna
go. Your teammate is down.
She needs you. She
needs your support.
You're her spotters. All of you.
'Cause you're her team,
and it's time you
started acting like one.
If you want to
talk medicine, fine.
But, sorry,
you have no clue
about our team, okay?
So...
I mean, who the hell does
she think she is anyway?
Cheer captain.
Promoted as a sophomore
for a triple-year reign
because I was just that good.
Led my team to
victory after victory.
Regionals, Nationals,
Internationals.
Three years in a row. Yeah.
That's amazing.
So let me break
this down for you.
You are jealous of her
because she and
Maxine are close now,
so you got all butthurt,
but they aren't actually
trying to leave you out.
Are you? Danielle.
Uh... No, ma'am.
Good.
You see, Lisa?
It's time for you to lose
that chip on your shoulder.
It's a Double Full Basket Toss.
Throw it up, move on.
You've got cheerleading to do.
She told you she'd be in soon?
Yes.
BP's dropping.
Hang a dopamine drip.
Hey, what, is she on the phone?
Why don't you give her a minute?
We don't have anymore minutes.
His BP is dropping,
and he's fluid overloaded.
I think we have a
couple more minutes.
You know what I think?
You people don't
know what you're doing.
You didn't have the plan.
You weren't ready to move,
and you moved anyway.
And I think you knew that when
you came through that door.
And I think he's gonna
suffer as a result of it.
Listen, here's the thing...
I'm gonna do a back flip!
- What the hell...
- For the sacrum!
I cut off the proximal
end of the femur,
I flip it around backwards,
and I make it into a sacrum.
Can you do that?
Mayo's done it a
few times. We'll see.
Hell, yes, I can do it!
Avery, let's go see
a leg about a femur.
We have a plan.
We're the Dream Team.
Damn.
Told you.
It's a miracle.
Whew. We almost
just killed that guy.
Oh, my God. Right?
Skin of our teeth.
Thank you, Jesus.
Oh, my phone's been blowing up.
I got to go, now.
Oh!
So, the good news is,
the surgery went very well.
Hey, Edwards, what do
you think you're doing?
They can't be up here. You
want to wake up the whole floor?
It's not gonna be a
problem, Dr. Karev.
These ladies aren't
gonna make a sound.
Are we, ladies?
No, ma'am. No.
We'd just like to see Maxine.
Would that be okay?
Uh...
Yeah. Okay.
I'm gonna need you to
show me how you did that.
Just a matter of leadership.
Yeah, but, no, really.
I want updates every hour.
If that man's hemoglobin
drops so much as a point,
I want to be paged.
Well, a single point isn't
exactly cause for you to...
You don't have
autonomy here, Warren.
I make the calls
from here on out.
Understand? Understood, sir.
Uh, someone want to
tell me why I received
not one, but two,
separate phone calls
from two separate attendings
telling me my husband
had lost his mind?
Look, it was a
unique situation...
I got an earful on
how unique it was.
I'm clear on the situation.
Excuse us, please.
Miranda, listen, I...
Okay.
Chief, I know you're angry...
I am angry that
I have a resident
who ignored every single
protocol he's been taught.
I'm disappointed by
the ego and arrogance
that this resident
has displayed.
And I'm embarrassed
that the resident in question
happens to be my husband!
Wow. Okay.
Oh, come on! You know
better than this, Ben Warren.
You are better than this.
Now I got... I got to set up
sit-downs with both attendings,
and I have to discipline you!
You're making an already
difficult night that much harder.
Well, I'm sorry I had to add
to your workload, Miranda,
but I was trying to save a life.
The man was dying.
And how is he now?
Alive. Stable. I
got to him in time.
No, you got lucky.
If you'd been left with a
dead man on that table
after you did what you did...
What?
Well...
I wouldn't be letting you off
with just a 3-day suspension.
You're suspending me?
You're... You're
damn right I am!
Because no... No
special treatment!
Come on!
That said, you opened
up a man's chest
with your bare hands
and a clipboard.
Yeah, you got to walk
me through this one.
I want to hear every detail.
Hey.
Are you still... Yeah,
still here. All night.
We have that VATS this morning.
We can push it to
tonight if you need sleep.
Yes. That would be great.
Yeah, what time
were you thinking?
Actually... Very good.
Dr. DeLuca?
All right.
Can you come here
a minute, please?
Um... Dr. Riggs?
I'm sorry. I cannot join
you on that case tonight
because I have plans
with Dr. DeLuca.
A date. Okay.
Whom I've been seeing.
We've been seeing each other.
As a couple,
romantically... In romance.
So you want to keep the
surgery this morning, then?
Yes, that would be fine.
Okay.
All right. I'll see
you in there.
That was hard to watch.
Shut up.
It was hard to do.
It was really hard
to watch, though.
So, I... I did it.
Right? Yeah.
No, you did it.
There's a reason we like
to keep things to ourselves.
Well, I was wrong.
I can admit that.
It's great what you did in
there. I'm just glad I saw it.
Well, it was nice
working with you.
See? You fly in, you fly out.
Well, we said we'll
follow up, and we will.
When you have an audience,
even the smallest moments
end up feeling huge.
Well, I'd like that...
To follow up with you.
It makes the really big moments
seem positively
earth-shattering.
Okay. So, here is my service,
and the hospital
number's on there, as well,
if you want to
follow up with Torres.
Great. I'll... I'll do that.
Let's go. Take care.
Thank you.
Yep, that guy definitely
just asked for your number.
Like, asked for your number.
Yeah, to follow up
about the patient.
No. I know when
someone's flirting.
Okay? That's what
flirting looks like.
The trick is not
letting the pressure
keep you from
taking big chances.
Meredith, let's go. What,
did you forget something?
You just go out there...
Oh! Come on!
Naked and afraid...
All right.
Ahem.
Shut up. It was
nothing. Mmm-hmm.
And pretend no one's looking.