The skin is the largest
organ in the body.
It protects us,
holds us together,
literally lets us know
what we are feeling.
Reaction, observation,
communication.
Any questions so far?
We're doing this because
Chief Shepherd suggests
we brush up on our patient
sensitivity skills, that's why.
And it just so happens this
morning was a very good time.
Besides, half of you
were raised by wolves.
"Reaction."
"Keep your face impassive.
Whether prompted by a
patient's appearance or lab results,
facial expressions of
surprise, concern, disgust, etc.,
can be counterproductive."
Uh, la la la la la...
"Jokes.
Don't make jokes about patients.
Not in front of them,
not even in private."
- Yang.
- What if the joke
is really funny?
It's not. Neither was
that one. Moving on.
We assess quickly in the
ER, and go to Radiology.
What if he has to be admitted?
Can we get to the surgical elevator?
What about the freight elevator?
Richard, are we set up for this?
I mean, our tables...
Do we have enough?
Is our equipment
gonna be strong enough?
They're five minutes out. We'll
have to figure it out as we go.
The skin can be
soft and vulnerable,
highly sensitive.
Easy to break.
Is that Gary Clark?
He's filed a wrongful
death suit in his wife's case.
- I'm being deposed today.
- Chief Shepherd? Hi.
Whatever you're selling,
leave the samples in my office.
I'm not a drug rep.
I'm your lawyer.
- Lauren Turner.
- Go. Don't worry. I got this.
OK. Thank you. Dr. Shepherd,
Lauren. Follow me, please.
"Observation."
OK. "Use reflective listening.
Repeat the patient's
feelings back to them.
'I hear that you're
concerned about the surgery.
Let me explain the risks.'"
"I can see you like vegetables.
After surgery, you might become one."
"Communication.
Don't use jargon. Use language
that the patient can understand.
Be creative in using metaphors."
I'm terrible with metaphors.
- I can never come up with them.
- Why?
You're dumb as a box of hammers?
See, that's a good one. You're
an ass, but that was a good one.
"Be clear and comprehensive.
Explain all risks and probable outcomes,
leaving nothing out."
Question. Adamson.
- Why are you going so fast?
- It just so happens
that we have an
emergent patient arriving
who will need a
little extra sensitivity.
So remember to employ
your R, O, C, and you will...
"rock" your patient's world.
OK, that's enough of that.
Follow me to the pit.
Hustle!
The skin doesn't
matter to a surgeon.
We'll cut right
through it, go inside,
find out the secrets underneath.
So did you get Izzie's message?
Did you send the divorce papers?
I gotta find them,
then I'll send them.
- Izzie sent you divorce papers?
- Yeah. So?
Nothing. Just...
congratulations.
Or... something. Excuse me.
It takes delicacy
and sensitivity.
- What's her problem?
- She cares. That's her problem.
She cares about you.
She doesn't. It's
not like we're a thing.
Well, you should make it
a thing or put a stop to it.
All right, people, remember
what you've been taught.
Use it throughout the day.
There will be
consequences if you don't.
What the hell is it?
Did the circus come to town?
Nope. Just the elephant.
Avery, you're off the case. Go.
Damn it.
Consequences.
We're gonna need
a bigger hospital.
Coming through!
All right, on three.
One, two, go!
Easy. That's it.
Let's get him a chem
panel, CBC and LFTs.
- Type and cross.
- Got it.
Now does that hurt?
Sweetheart, I
can't even feel that.
- Having trouble
finding a vein here.
- Or anywhere.
I'm using up all
your doctors here.
Probably somebody
dying somewhere, right?
X-ray.
Now I understand
the sensitivity training.
- Yeah, no fat jokes.
- Yang, you're off the case.
- I said no fat j...
- Goodbye.
Clear.
Sir, when did the stomach
pains become more acute?
Last couple days, I guess.
It's hard to keep track.
I'm a real busy guy.
- I'm here!
- Let's roll him.
- Bobby, are you OK?
- I'm sorry, you are?
I'm his wife.
- Facial expressions.
- Hon, I'm fine.
Melissa worries. She likes to
make mountains out of molehills.
And I'm already a mountain.
Man. Tough crowd.
Mr. Corso, we're gonna
need to turn you over again.
Whoa, whoa.
Dr. Webber. Look at that.
You poppin' the hood down there?
Facial expressions.
- Dr. Altman.
- Dibs!
- Do you need any help today?
- I'm free.
Aren't you both on Webber's
big emergent patient?
- He got kicked off
for making a joke.
- She got kicked off, too.
- But for not making
a joke, so dibs.
- Both of you.
I've got a consult in the pit.
- Jamie Anders? Hi.
- Hi.
Dr. Torres.
Oh, wow. What the hell
did you do to your knee?
Some jackass mowed me down
on my bike and then took off.
Hit and run? That sucks.
OK, this is probably
gonna hurt a little,
but I need to get in there
and see what's going on, OK?
Go for it.
- No, no! Don't go for it!
- Sorry. You OK?
- Wow! This really blows.
- That's one messed-up patella.
- Plus, I'm out 20 bucks.
- What do you mean?
My friend said there's
always an upside to an injury,
and I said she was on crack,
and she said, "Watch,
the doctor'll be hot."
I said, "The doctor
will be old and gnarly."
Now you show up, which
means I owe her 20 bucks.
Nancy Temple, 39, complaining of
nausea and dizziness since waking today.
Then she threw up. Twice.
Kelly said I had
to go to the doctor.
At school, you
have to if you vomit.
Good call, Kelly.
Let's have a listen.
- How's her EKG look?
- It's coming up right now.
Having any chest pains or
numbness in your arms or fingers?
No, not at all. Why?
Nancy, heart attack
symptoms show up
completely differently
in women than in men.
They're often missed.
Sometimes, they just
look like stomach problems.
- Are you saying...?
- You're having
a heart attack now.
Let's hang a nitro drip
and call the cath lab.
What about my daughter?
We're here alone.
We're flying back to Miami
tonight. And my husband...
We'll call your husband,
let him know what's going on.
Dr. Yang will take care of
Kelly until your tests are done.
- No! I mean...
- It's patient
sensitivity day,
- right, Dr. Yang?
- It's not a day.
Take care of Kelly and Avery
will page you when we're ready.
- Mommy!
- Sweetheart!
- I want to go with her.
- I know, I know.
So do I.
How long has he
had that infection?
I've never seen it
before. Nothing like that.
- What is it?
- We don't know yet.
It could be superficial,
or it might be something
- worse going on internally.
- I'm gonna be fine, baby.
Don't worry.
- Oh!
- Karev!
Crap. I thought we'd clear
it. Let's take the sides off.
We should put a "wide
load" banner on this thing.
We have a gurney right here.
Couldn't we move him onto this?
- No, I don't
want to have him...
- Yeah, I can do it.
No, no, no. Sir,
let us move you.
Come on, come on.
It's only two steps.
It's either that or you gotta
grease me up like a stuck pig.
- Nobody wants that job.
- He hasn't walked
in a year. Bobby!
OK. Easy, easy.
I didn't think I could do this!
Oh, my God, baby,
you're standing!
You know what
this reminds me of?
Our wedding.
Um... Bimalleolar
ankle fracture.
It was too weak to
support his weight.
- He can go to CT now.
- He's not going in that CT.
I think if we can
position him...
It's rated for half his weight.
If it breaks, he gets hurt
again, it's not available
for the 50 other
patients who need it.
What about the zoo? They gotta
have a CT for, like, rhinos, right?
Percy, off the case. Goodbye.
That wasn't a joke. That
was an actual suggestion.
- Go.
- It's a pretty
good idea, actually.
- It's a terrible idea.
- - We will spare this man
the indignity of treating
him like a zoo animal.
If we can't get an image, we'll
go with clinical labs and tests.
I could do a nuclear
stress test on his heart.
I just wish I could
get him on a treadmill.
That's not gonna happen.
All right. I have a lawyer
waiting for me, I have to go.
I want a meeting with all of
you when his studies come back,
before we go any further
down this road, OK?
Let's work him up.
So just a couple more questions.
His diabetes, did he
have it before he was...
- immobilized?
- No. That's since
he put on the weight.
And that's been,
um...? How long has...?
How long has he been like this?
Five years ago, his company
laid off 300 employees.
He tried to find work for
two years. No one was hiring.
And then he stopped trying.
It was real hard on him. And food,
well, food made him feel better. So...
I think he's been
in pain for a while.
He'd tell me it's indigestion,
but I couldn't ignore it.
- After the news,
I just had to call.
- The news?
Well, we're gonna have
a baby. I'm pregnant.
How?
I mean... Wow! Congratulations!
That is... That's joyous news.
You're off the case.
- Hi.
- Hey.
Your deposition's today?
Yeah. Let me ask you something.
Teddy and Owen,
can they work together?
- What do you mean?
- Nothing. I was just surprised
he didn't go to bat for her getting
the job. It was like he wanted her to go.
- Really?
- I gotta go.
Good luck.
Hey, what are you doing?
- Um... Bobby Corso's labs.
- Still on Fatty Fatty
Two By Four?
- No fair.
- Uh, name calling...
- Who's this?
- My patient's kid.
The social worker
won't return my page.
- That's not very social.
- Where's Callie?
She's been whining for a kid.
Cristina?
What?
Um... Oh, never mind.
They have no case.
Gary Clark is grieving.
You can do me
one favor in there.
Try not to refer to her
as "Mrs. Clark" or "she."
Don't use pronouns,
just stick to "the patient."
- It keeps it less emotional.
- OK.
- So why is he here?
- Sorry?
Gary Clark. He shouldn't be here
for this. He doesn't need to hear this.
He's the plaintiff, it's his
prerogative. Don't let it bother you.
I'm more worried
it's gonna bother him.
Sorry. I have to go.
Hey. Is the meeting with
Shepherd in the conference room?
Mm-hm.
Thank you.
My contract came in, and
Cristina told me you
put in a good word.
So... thanks.
Of course.
- What?
- Nothing.
What are we looking at?
The patient's got a severe deep
tissue infection under his belly.
There's a significant abscess. Hunt
and I need to get in there and debride,
- clear out the infected fat.
- Sudden fat loss is dangerous.
It's preferable to him dying of an
infection. It's a risky surgery, yes.
Have Bailey and
Webber on standby
- in case he goes south.
- What is the surgical
risk calculation
- on a patient like this?
- Almost too high to calculate.
Five times the risk of heart
attack, respiratory failure,
- airway complications.
- He's diabetic,
there's risk of a
ketoacidotic coma.
High risk of pulmonary embolism.
Believe it or not,
he's malnourished,
which leads to slow
healing, renal failure...
Nerve damage, post-op infection.
I'm saying no. The risk
is too high. That's all.
Thank you, but that's it.
You're saying we
send him away to die?
We send him to a bariatric center
prepared for a patient like this,
instead of us spending our time
and resources caring for someone
who obviously
doesn't care for himself.
Derek, he's me.
Just swap out the
booze for the food.
You don't think I
care about myself?
He has an illness that he
cannot control, he needs help.
- I'm sorry. I...
- That wasn't you in there.
And that wasn't about Bobby
Corso. It was about Gary Clark.
You're seeing potential lawsuits
where you used to see patients.
It's the job, Derek. The job
can change your priorities.
- Excuse me, Shepherd?
- Derek, don't let it.
Tell Sloan to go
ahead and open him up.
Yes?
The conversation
we had about Altman,
did you share that with anyone?
- I...
- Did you share that
with your wife?
Did Meredith say something?
When I make a professional
recommendation about a fellow attending,
I expect it to be kept in confidence.
I do not expect to hear about it
from one of my residents. I
thought I could assume that much.
How's your day going?
- Dr. Grey.
- Uh, yeah.
Jamie, we're going to open up
your knee and wire all the pieces
- of your patella back together.
- Are you gonna do
the operation?
- Yep.
- You'll hold my hand
through the whole thing?
I think it's better if
I'm holding the scalpel.
- But I can hold
your hand right now.
- Fine.
OK.
Do you have any other questions?
I can't think of anything, but I don't
want the hand holding part to end,
so can we sit here a minute?
You are so bad. I
will see you in the OR.
Wow. Should we
have left you two alone?
- What?
- Getting a little
steamy in there.
Give me a break. I'm in
a committed relationship.
- That was chit-chat.
- Yeah, there was steam.
- It was steamy chit-chat.
- With hand holding.
Yeah, physical contact is an important
part of establishing a patient's trust.
Bailey did patient
sensitivity this morning.
Did she teach you nothing?
So there was no flirting going
on. I was just imagining that.
She was flirty, and
I was flirty back,
because I'm trying
to put her at ease.
Talking to the patient the
way the patient talks to you,
makes them feel
understood. And safe.
And... you're morons.
Oh, and a little pervy. Jeez.
- Put me down for 715.
- Got it.
- What happens at 7:15?
- 715 is her bet.
I'm making a pool on
Bobby Corso's actual weight.
Twenty bucks. Closest without
going over wins the pot. You want in?
How are you still on that case?
Artificial insemination.
It had to be.
- What are we talking about?
- Bobby Corso.
How did they make a baby?
He hasn't left the house in five
years. It took a truck to get him here.
How's he supposed to go to
a fertility clinic to fill up a cup?
- How does he find it
to fill up a cup?
- They can still do it.
- The regular way. Right?
- Have you seen the guy move?
'Cause he can't, really. At all.
Maybe he doesn't have to.
Maybe she does all the work.
- But how? I mean...
- I'm finished.
Oh, um...
Get yourself some ice cream.
But I'm not allowed to
have that much sugar.
- Get some roast beef then.
- She can sit.
No, she can't. We're
talking about S-E-X.
I'm nine, and you
just spelled "sex."
- That's good.
- OK. Know what?
Let's say this is the wife.
- No! Don't do that.
- And this is... him.
- I won't be eating that now.
- She's gotta be on top.
She might get altitude sickness.
Guys.
- Sorry. Um...
- It's all right. I get it.
You're trying to figure how my husband
and I managed to get a baby in here.
There are some
logistics involved.
You want me to tell you?
But first, how about you tell me how
you like to do it with your husband.
Or your girlfriend?
Any favorite positions?
Or kinks! Let's talk about that!
Because I know you all must have
a freakshow of your own going on.
Who wants to go first?
No? Nobody?
OK.
Well, it's probably none of
my damn business anyway.
The fat under your skin
has become necrotic.
It has died.
And the infection is
eating through your skin.
I suppose it had to come to
that. I've eaten everything else.
The operation is
extremely risky.
You have a higher
than normal chance
that a surgical
complication can kill you.
If I don't have
the surgery, I die?
How long will I
have, do you think?
Mr. Corso, you want the surgery.
- You want to try.
- I've tried.
Everything.
High protein, the low carbs,
drugs, pills, hypnosis.
I've tried everything.
You have a baby on
the way. Think about that.
What do you think
I'm thinking about?
You...
You dream of having a kid.
You picture yourself
playing ball with him.
You picture her
standing on your feet
while you dance around
with her, you know?
You don't picture them bringing
you food and cleaning you up.
I can't walk four steps
to go to the bathroom.
You tell me,
who deserves that
guy as a father?
I just want to be gone
before the kid has a
chance to know who I am.
Don't tell my wife
about this, OK?
Let's just tell
her it's too risky.
Let me go home.
- Hey, peanut.
- What's going on?
- Can we see my mom now?
- I'm trying to find out.
- Is she gonna be OK?
- You want an honest answer?
- Yes.
- I don't know.
Do you know anything?
I hear that you're scared.
It's scary when your
mom or dad gets hurt
- and you feel alone.
- How do you know?
'Cause when I was your age,
my dad and I were
in a car accident
and he was hurt and I was
really scared. So I know.
Was your dad OK?
Yep. He was fine.
Now, let's go see
about your mom.
Get back, get back!
- What happened?
- Echo shows a ventricular
wall rupture.
- OR 2's ready, they're waiting.
- Yang, you coming?
- Yeah. What about the kid?
- I'll take her.
Mommy?!
Mommy!
- Do you need me?
- What?
- You have Avery. Do you need me?
- Yang, in or out. Let's go.
Um...
You wanted me to
sign discharge papers?
Mrs. Corso, I'm sorry about
the thing in the cafeteria.
It's easy to make
jokes about him.
You didn't know him before.
You don't know that inside all that
is the same man I've always known.
Who can make me
laugh till I can't breathe.
He's been trying to make
you guys laugh all day,
but you're too disgusted to
even smile or joke with him.
Make him feel like a person.
I brought him here because
I thought you would help him.
But you're only
making him feel worse.
So unless you want
to tell me the next step
to getting him out
of here and home,
I don't need to hear
anything from you.
Are you bringing
my forklift around?
We thought we'd just open up
the loading dock and roll you out.
That's good.
Right into Puget Sound.
Float me home like a barge.
- I got a good one.
- Yeah?
What did they call
the guy who was so fat,
he couldn't get
out of the house?
- What?
- Dead.
And selfish.
Yeah.
'Cause you left a 700-pound mess
for your wife to clean up.
That's a good one.
Look, I'm sorry that we've
been tiptoeing around you all day,
trying not to make jokes,
but you're the one
who's gotta stop.
Stop calling
yourself the fat guy.
You got a wife who loves you.
You know, who stuck
by you through all this.
You did something
right to deserve that.
I know what it's like to have
life hand you so much crap
you just want to sit
on the couch and die.
But you gotta look at
what's in front of you.
You can't just walk out on
her now. She deserves better.
Look, chances are, you're
gonna die on that table.
Then you get what you want.
But at least your wife
will think you tried.
She'll tell your kid you tried.
Give 'em that at least.
How'd you get
back on the surgery?
They said they needed big guys.
Karev, Percy, retracting the
abdomen. Adamson, stay there.
Kepner, over there.
Where do you want me?
I think we are good.
That's all we need.
Did you irrigate the ears to
induce an ocular response?
- No. That was not necessary.
- Why?
- The patient had
a pupillary response.
- So you saw life in her eyes?
- There was
a pupillary response.
- Yet you declared her dead.
- No, you misunderstood.
- Absence of a pupillary
response
is one of the signs
of brain death,
yet you declared her brain dead.
I never declared her brain dead.
She had minimal brain activity.
I'm sorry, I tried
to explain to you...
So she was alive
until you withdrew care.
- Until you pulled the plug.
- I'm sorry. I'm not being clear.
According to the letter
of her advance directive,
there was a level
of brain activity
- that I judged...
- That you judged. You decided.
It was my opinion to...
Should we stop?
I'm gonna suggest
we take a break.
Get ourselves together,
resume later on.
- Does that sound all right?
- Fine.
You remember when I told
you they don't have a case?
- Yes.
- With respect, Dr. Shepherd,
please stop trying to give
them one. Do not apologize.
OK.
The infection's really deep.
- Underneath all this fat is just...
- - More fat.
- I'm down to the abdominal wall.
- - How's the fascia?
Not too good. Wanna
take a look inside?
It's probably a can
of worms, but here.
Let's have a little peek.
Damn it! We have to go in.
- Bailey, Webber,
you scrub in? Fast?
- OK.
So there's a hole in the wall?
Right, and the blood is supposed
to go from one room to another,
except it's just rushing
outside through the hole.
And it can't get to
her brain? Got it.
Yes. Or to her lungs.
- So they're gonna
sew up the hole?
- They'll try to.
But the heart has to
be strong, like, um...
Like nylon. Like your shoes.
Your mom's heart
is weak. Like paper.
What happens if she dies?
We'll talk about
that if it happens.
Gotcha. Mine.
If your mom dies...
you'll feel a lot of things.
First, you'll feel like, uh...
you could have done
more to help her, but...
that's not true.
You did everything you could.
It won't feel that way, but...
remember me telling you this:
You did everything you could.
And it will hurt, every
time you think of her.
But over time, it will
hurt less and less.
And eventually...
you'll remember her and...
it will only hurt a little.
I'm not gonna be here in the
morning when they let you go,
so if it hurts before your
follow-up, give me a call.
OK? And if it's oozing
green stuff, call me.
Can I call you if it's late at
night and I'm kind of drunk
and I run across an old John
Hughes movie on the tube?
Wow, um...
- I don't, uh...
- Here.
I don't think...
- Just...
- What?
- Use that...
- Um...
if the spirit moves you.
Now, get out of here.
I'm on drugs.
OK.
Pull that back more. I
can't see what I'm doing.
- This? Is this good?
- No! More!
I think I found the
culprit. Diverticulitis.
Perforated colon.
Completely infected.
- How long's he been under?
- Too long.
This abscess will kill him if
we don't get it under control.
- OK, keep it together.
- Let's pick up the pace,
people.
Laps. Come on.
More.
Pack it in.
Hey. How's the deposition going?
- Apparently, I can't tell you.
- Why?
Why did you tell
Hunt what I told you?
- I didn't, I told him nothing.
- He came to me
and said you knew.
No. I told him nothing.
I looked at him...
You looked at him. When you're
pissed, your face says everything.
So now I have a staff
that can't trust me.
So, what am I supposed
to do, control my face?
- Yes. Control your face.
- Maybe you shouldn't
tell me things
you don't want me
to know. Control that!
Then I can't tell you anything.
Then 80 percent of my day is
off limits and I don't want that.
I don't want that
either. I'm sorry.
I know. It's just...
- But I have to tell Cristina.
- Damn it! What are we
talking about?
Owen lied to her.
And he must have done that
because he still wants Teddy.
- Doesn't matter!
- It doesn't matter to you.
Cristina is my best friend. I
get that you're the chief now,
but she's still the person
she's always been.
Am I supposed to stand
around and watch her get hurt?
What am I supposed to do?
Chief Shepherd, they're ready.
Nothing. You do nothing.
Where's the little girl?
Social Services came. We
put her to bed in a patient room.
Her dad should be here
by the time she wakes up.
Good. You were
great with her today.
Thanks.
So when did your mom die?
- She didn't.
- Your dad, then?
I'm sorry if that's
too personal.
It was just clear from the way
you were talking to her today.
It's been a long day. I thought
you might want to talk about it.
That's very insightful of you.
You're a super,
super sensitive man.
Let me tell you
what you saw today.
I reflectively listened
to a patient's concerns.
I spoke to her in a language
she could understand.
I clearly stated possible
complications and probable outcomes.
That's all you saw today.
Me kicking patient
sensitivity ass.
So go be someone
else's dish rag.
Hey, what are you doing tonight?
Do you wanna drink?
We should drink.
Although, maybe I shouldn't,
because then I'll talk.
And I'm not allowed to talk
or make a facial expression.
Can you go away,
please? Just go. Go away!
What is it? Cristina,
what's wrong?
Owen. Can you get
me Owen, please?
And describe what you
saw in Mrs. Clark's scans.
The patient suffered an
acute hemorrhagic stroke
- in the left temporal lobe.
- Based on those scans
and the EEG,
you recommended
that care be withdrawn.
According to the advanced...
- Yes.
- How long did that take?
From the time you looked at the
scans until you decided to end her life,
- how much time elapsed?
- We talked to the patient's
family,
assemble an ethics
review committee.
I'm talking about
your assessment.
How long did it take you to decide
to recommend that she should die?
- Less than a minute.
In my professional opinion,
there was no other option.
Thirty-two years.
I... I think we have
everything we need.
Alison and I were
married for 32 years.
I loved her for more
than half my life.
And you decide to kill
her in less than a minute?
Mr. Clark,
- I'm so sorry...
- I begged you.
And you just kept
saying you're sorry.
You just kept saying
legal this and legal that.
- This is no longer productive.
- Gary...
I begged you!
But you signed her death sentence!
You didn't even show up to do the job!
You're a coward, Dr. Shepherd!
You're a coward and a killer!
Come on.
Come with me.
- Dr. Shepherd,
can I have a word?
- What?
Nothing. I'm just keeping you
here until Mr. Clark has gone.
You're a kind man, Dr. Shepherd.
I respect that, I admire that.
But he's grieving,
and they have no case.
He got to say what
he needed to say.
And the kindest thing you
can say to him is nothing.
You can't help him, and
you won't help your hospital.
It's over.
I know you want to
do more, but it's over.
It was a pleasure
working with you.
- So you told her.
- I didn't say anything to her.
What? What is it?
What happened?
I miss my dad.
Bobby, you survived the surgery,
but you're not nearly
out of the woods.
We'll still have to watch you
very closely for post-op infections,
and you're gonna have to make
some serious lifestyle changes.
I know. I need to
lose the weight.
You have no choice,
if you want to survive.
Well, then I have no choice.
Right?
How did it go?
Derek, you can talk to me.
I don't want to think about
what I can and can't say
and who I can
and can't say it to.
I can't do it anymore today.
I love you. You
know that, right?
I love you, too.
No matter how
thick-skinned we try to be...
- Did you find out
Bobby Corso's weight?
- 678.
So who won your stupid pool?
- Bailey.
- Bailey?
She bet in your pool?
After all of that.
Are you kidding me?
My God, the hypocrisy!
There's millions of electrified
nerve endings in there.
- You going home?
- Yeah.
You want to go together?
Open and exposed...
and feeling way too much.
Hey! We scored! My cousin
said we can use their timeshare.
So Fiji. We can either
go at the end of this month
or we could save up
three weeks of time,
rearrange our surgical schedules
and go at the end of next month.
Try as we might to
keep from feeling pain...
What's that?
This cute girl's number.
And I can't get it off.
And I'm not gonna use
it, I don't want to use it.
But I can't stop wondering if
maybe she wants a baby one day.
I love you.
Everything about you.
But there's this one
thing that I need.
I can't change it, I
can't ask you to change,
- I don't want you to change...
- I can't be the one
that keeps you
from having a baby.
I love you, too.
- And we can keep going.
- But I don't know
where we're going.
Come here.
Sometimes, it's
just unavoidable.
God, what are we gonna do?
Well, I'm gonna get
my stuff together.
Oh...
And what? We'll just...
We'll see each other at work.
I'm so sorry!
I love you.
Me, too. Me, too.
Sometimes, that's
the only thing left.
- Thanks. This was a good idea.
- No talking.
- You shanked it.
Just feeling.