The first surgeons
were vivisectionists.
- ♪ Yeah ♪
- When they opened a body,
they had no intention
of closing it.
♪ One, two, three, yeah ♪
They just wanted to see what was inside.
- Phenomenal job.
- Yeah.
Hats off to you, too.
And what they found was
a world of possibility...
You know, this
no-strings-attached thing...
it is like hidden treasure.
All of the fun,
none of the emotional baggage.
We should write a book.
We would make millions.
Mmm, mmm, mmm. Oh.
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
Oh, shoot.
- I gotta go.
- Um.
♪ Give 'em what they want ♪
It's Intern
Trauma Certification Day today.
Okay.
The possibility to heal...
to reverse the damage...
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
to turn back time.
- ♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
- You sure this is cool?
You know,
me leaving in a hurry?
I just...
I don't want to be a...
Stop. No feelings.
I'm good.
And it'll stay good?
- ♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I just keep waiting
for the other shoe.
What do you mean,
the other shoe?
You know, like you saying
you wanted to have kids
and then
you don't want to have kids.
That was more like a boot
than a shoe.
Actually, it was more like
an ass kicking.
- ♪ Give 'em what they want ♪
- Well, I'll see you tonight.
- ♪ Give 'em what they need ♪
- Or not.
No strings.
No shoes.
We can
start work on that book.
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
Hey, Sofia?
Sofia!
I've got three fluffy pancakes
patiently waiting for you.
What...
Hey, why aren't you dressed?
- I put out your red shoes.
- I don't want my red shoes.
Okay, well, at this point, I'll
settle for any shoes at all,
so let's just put on...
let's put on shoes.
What's wrong? Hey. What?
What, are you sick?
Does your tummy hurt?
- No.
- Okay, great.
Then let's get up
and get dressed, okay?
'Cause I have a huge day
at work, and you have school.
So, what do you want first?
You want the shirt?
You want pants?
You want... Hey.
Whoa.
Hey.
What's the matter?
You can tell me.
I want to go to New York.
With my friends
and my other teacher
who lets us draw
in our notebooks.
- And...
- And you miss your mommy, too.
Sweetheart,
hey,
why don't you come
to work with me today?
Okay? All right,
come on.
All right.
You paged.
I paged.
Do you need help
looking for something?
You know what? I did.
But I think I see it now.
Mmm.
Does this door have a lock?
Mnh-mnh. I don't think so.
Maybe we should find a room
with a door with a lock.
I don't have time for that.
I got a vagina to build.
- My vaginoplasty for the contest.
- Right.
That surgery's today
with my mom and Richard.
Wow.
Some families do puzzles.
It's okay. Tonight.
Tonight I say
we cancel the reservation
and have dinner at my place.
I got a lot of doors
and a lot of locks.
- That sounds perfect.
- Oh, good.
Yes.
Hey!
- Hey.
Hello.
- We should...
- Uh...
Yep.
Um, good luck
with your vagina.
Don't...
I'm just gonna...
Excuse me.
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 14   Episode 16
Episode Title :
"Caught Somewhere in Time"
What are you doing?
All this stuff has
to get cleared out.
That centrifuge that we stole
from oncology...
that should go back.
And do you and Alex want a mouse?
No. No, no, no, no, no.
The mouse stays.
I have news.
I have great news.
Oh. You got engaged, right?
Congratulations.
No. No, no, no, it's...
I mean, yes. Thank you. But...
No, no, no, no.
I was up all night.
I found seven polymers that could replace
the one that hag Marie Cerone
stole from us.
And I know she's your aunt or
whatever, but she's still a hag.
Jo, let it go.
We're outsmarted, outgunned, outfunded.
Even if we won the stupid contest,
she's way ahead of us.
No. Okay, if you could just
look at any of these...
Hey, you,
where are all the interns?
Trauma Certification with Hunt.
Ugh.
I have a massive crush injury being
helicoptered in from Spokane
and no one to teach about
massive crush injuries.
- Take her, please.
- No!
Yeah, you'll do.
With me.
Meh!
Dr. Boraff to the cap lab.
Ah, good for you.
I always said you should
find more friends.
Uh, these are for...
I know. So, speaking of dummies,
you know that thing
you said earlier
about wanting and then not wanting kids?
You realize I had a brain tumor
at the time, right?
Yeah, okay. That's true,
but... you can't blame everything
on the tumor.
No, I sort of can because of
the massive, heaping ball
that was pressed on my cerebrum.
Okay, I thought you said
we were cool.
Oh, I'm cool.
No. I am the coolest.
But, you know, even with the tumor,
I still never cheated
on anyone.
- Whoa. Wait.
- Good luck with your show.
Hey.
Please let me run this thing
with you.
Or... Or I could run it
for you.
Without you. Just...
Just please let me run it.
DeLuca's on board to help.
We're good.
I said please!
Fine. Breezeway in 10 minutes.
Okay.
Wow.
And it turns out this woman
had an ax to grind with Ellis Grey.
So, Dr. Grey's dropping out
of the contest?
She's not giving us her patent,
so Dr. Grey is just quitting.
- It sucks.
- It does.
But it does improve the odds
for my "AnalGlide."
- Hmm?
- I'm trying out names
for my colonoscopy device.
Anal... No?
Mnh. Mnh.
Hello.
I'm Chief Miranda Bailey.
This is Dr. Jo Wilson.
Please, uh, present.
Marjorie Kersey. 66.
Sustained blunt trauma
to the abdomen and chest
four days ago when
a 22-foot test apparatus...
Electromagnet.
Big-ass electromagnet.
Fell onto her.
Hospitalized
at a community center,
where her clinical course was complicated
by rhabdo and
acute kidney injury,
all resolving, but...
- Marge Kersey?
- Mm-hmm.
Has recurrent abdominal pain.
Transferred here
for consultation.
"Bargin' Marge" Kersey?
The astronaut?
- Okay. Here we go.
- Oh, my God.
This woman has clocked
over 1,000 hours in space.
- In space!
- Oh, my Lord, we have a nerd!
Oh, I'm a huge fan.
But y-you won the Fundamental
Physics Prize twice.
I know, hon. I was there.
Oh, oh, is that like
the Nobel Prize?
Ahh! The Nobel Prize wishes.
Oh, Dr. Kersey, well,
it is an honor to meet you
and a privilege to treat you.
Are you rhyming on purpose?
I... What?
No.
I... I've followed you
since I was a little girl.
You are a trailblazer.
Oh, my gosh,
thank you, hon.
I hope you're prepared to blaze
a trail
through my intestine or whatnot.
Of course.
Hey, um, what were you
working on, if I can ask?
- Can you say?
- I can say.
Um, it's a temporal variance
spectrometer.
It'll detect time-space changes
in the Higgs Boson field
and will eventually
control it.
It sounds like...
Are you building a time machine?
Wow. You really are a nerd.
I'm impressed.
A-A time machine?
Are you serious?
You're building a time machine
for... for NASA.
Oh, no, I parted ways with NASA
years ago.
I'm building it for me,
so I can travel to the future.
Yeah!
- So cool.
- Uh-huh.
So, your temporal variance spectrometer,
what, creates a wormhole?
No, no, that's a guy
in South Africa.
He wants to send
little "beep-boop" signals
through time dilation.
I want to send people.
Sending people through time?
That seems, uh...
- Bananas?
- Yeah.
Apparently, NASA thought so, too.
Stop.
Uh, hey, uh, why do you have me
set up for a head CT, anyway?
You looking for a tumor?
Yeah, uh...
Okay. No. Hold still.
Just covering our bases.
It's fine.
You're not the first ones
who've looked at me
like I'm bat-crap crazy.
- You won't be the last.
- See? I told you.
- Shh!
- I'm not the only one.
You're fine.
Big day, Mother.
You ready?
Anything, uh, bothering you?
I haven't said a word.
You don't have to.
Your face did.
My face isn't saying anything.
Richard,
is my face saying something?
It's like reading
Hemingway, dear.
Ahh.
Good morning.
- Mwah!
- Good morning, doctors.
- Ah, good morning.
- Morning.
You opening a flower shop?
Yeah.
They're from my boyfriend.
He thinks he's hilarious.
Sent me a book of
Georgia O'Keefe prints, too.
I never dreamed
this day would come.
And I certainly never dreamed
that a mother and son
would build my vagina.
And father.
Stepfather, about a...
about a year and a half.
- So... no offense.
- Mm.
Uh, none taken.
Well,
family is family is family.
Like the saying goes.
That's not a saying,
but okay.
- Not to you, it's not.
- No one's ever said it.
Is everything okay?
- Yes.
- Mm-hmm. Oh, yeah.
Because part of me feels like a
little kid on Christmas morning.
But the other part is
a world-class physician
who knows you're dealing with
the most sensitive organ
in the body.
I can't afford any distractions.
Michelle, I hear you.
Let me assure you
that my mind is not
anywhere but right here,
in this surgery.
Shall we do this?
Yes.
Let's do this.
Yeah.
Oh, all right, bring it in. Nice.
- Ohh.
- Hey.
Oh, wow,
this is where the party is.
Dr. Robbins.
Who is the new intern?
This is my daughter, Sofia.
And this must be
the infamous Noah.
It sure is. Noah, honey, say hi.
- Hi.
Liz, when did the pain
start and where?
I was on my way to his school.
It's here in my lower back.
Is it stabbing or shooting?
- No. More like pressure.
- All right.
Um, hey, Noah,
can you come over here
and sit on the chairs
while I give your mom an exam?
- Want to see my robot monster?
- 'Kay.
He's a full-blown prodigy,
and I'm definitely not biased.
Well, it has been a while
since I've heard Sofia
laugh like that.
Noah seems to laugh a lot.
Yeah, he's always been
a happy kid.
Good.
All righty.
Let's see...
- Okay.
- What we got going on.
You're gonna feel a little bit
of pressure.
Okay.
You said I could carry to term.
Liz, you have
Ehlers-Danlos Syndrome,
so I said that we would try
to get you to term.
But I'm a... I'm a little worried
that you have
an incompetent cervix.
Well, that sounds... rude.
Well your uterus
is putting pressure
on your cervix, causing it to open.
And then your amniotic sac
is bulging through.
And the monitor shows that you
might be having contractions,
so let's admit you and let's try
and stop them.
Contractions?
But she's only 23 weeks.
Right. That's why I'm gonna do
everything I can
to make sure that she stays
exactly where she is.
Hey, should I start
freaking out now?
No, because that would be
neither helpful nor necessary.
Hey, Noah,
can you come, um,
hang out with your mom for a second?
Hey, honey.
Um, okay, uh,
I will see you soon.
- Okay.
- All right.
Yeah. See you.
Oh, hey. Hey.
There you are.
What are you doing?
Packing it in. You okay?
No. Something happened.
What's wrong?
Are you quitting the contest, too?
Uh, no.
I was making out with Jackson,
and we got caught by his mother
and my... and Richard.
I mean, we're all fine.
We're all adults.
And Richard isn't even really my dad,
but I suddenly feel like
he is my father.
And I... I feel like I felt
when I was 15,
and when I was 15, I was 12.
Jackson?
Oh, crap, I didn't tell you about that.
Wait a second. You're dropping
out of the contest?
Marie Cerone wanted me to
rename the Grey Method
the Grey-Cerone Method and...
That's crazy.
Yeah. I couldn't do it.
That would kill Ellis.
And I've already watched her die
once, so...
Uh, well, you can't let her
take this away from you.
I won't let you.
No, Maggie. Stop. It's fine.
Listen, you've never
had your hopes and dreams
crushed by our mother,
but for me it was an annual
occurrence, so, really.
I'm pissed, but I'll get over it.
Ugh. I got to go.
Consult.
But Jackson... You're...
You're... Jackson?
Oh, yes, I'm seeing Jackson,
and it's wonderful.
We haven't had sex yet,
but I hope we will tonight,
so... Oh, I won't need a ride home.
Okay, bye.
Wow. Okay.
Welcome to Trauma Certification.
Moments ago, a Cessna has
crashed into a Greyhound bus.
The EVAC helicopter is on its way.
Yeah, yeah, maybe somewhere else.
No, not here. What happened here is that
the EVAC helicopter also crashed
and is up in flames right now.
All right, people are dying.
It is your job to their lives.
What are the rules?
This is real life, Bloodbank.
In a harsh and
uncaring world,
the only rule is
there are no rules.
People are bleeding!
People are dying!
Go! Go! Go!
Why aren't you moving?
Let's go. Hustle.
Grab a body.
Work on your patient.
Get to work.
I want to see hustle.
There's air in the biliary system.
Wilson, thoughts?
Probably a fistula from
the liver to the duodenum.
We'll have to ligate.
Good. Uh,
do we need to open the chest?
No. I can treat the abscess
by infusing TPA and DNase
through the chest tube
while you're in there.
Well, her brain scan is clear.
And it's a sexy brain.
She's 66?
Oh, well, if you believe her,
then she's 166
'cause she's a time-traveler.
Time travel?
Like wormholes?
Exactly!
- What are we looking at here?
- Oh, wait. "Wormhole"...
that's a great name for your device!
Bailey is looking for names
for her... colon thingy.
No, I'm not.
"Ass Gasket"... that's a good one.
God, if I could
go back in time.
No, you can't.
Time doesn't go backwards.
Read your Einstein, Einstein.
The men I would not have
slept with.
- And the one woman I would have.
- "Crack Jack"?
I would go back
and undo this morning.
Well, I would... I would
kill Hitler and end slavery,
and then I would go
straight to this morning.
Oh, no, wait. I would go back
and see what happened between
Ellis Grey and Marie Cerone.
"Fanny Spanner."
Karev, stop.
Hey, your patient's hypotensive,
hypoxic, and tachycardic.
- What did you do?
- So, we did bilateral chest tubes first.
There was no improvement,
so we checked for a JVD,
muffled heart sounds,
and pulsus paradoxus.
Good. Your patient's gonna survive
and fight for another five minutes.
Schmitt, your patient just
aspirated in his own blood.
Dead.
Hellmouth, your patient's pregnant.
He's a dude with a beard.
She's a bearded lady
and she's a mom
and her baby's just gone into
fetal distress.
- What do you do?
- Uh, I-I cut the... No, I use that...
Too late. Both dead.
- Kepner, Kepner.
- What?
They're not gonna learn
anything
if you keep killing their patients.
Pow! Piece of shrapnel
from the plane wing
just fell out of the sky
and into your boyfriend's body.
What now, Bello?
T-The plane wing hit me?
Oh, yeah!
Another plane is crashing.
- Who saw that coming?
- C-Can she do that to a doctor?
It feels like cheating.
You're hurt and bleeding,
DeLuca. Get down.
Ahh.
I said hurt and bleeding,
not hot and bothered.
Aaaaaah!
All right,
what are you gonna do, Bello?
Is she cheating?
Uh, Kepner, you got this?
- I need to step out for a few secs.
- Yep.
Whoa, whoa, wait.
Y-You're leaving us?
- Oh, yeah. Yeah, I am.
- Hey, you can't talk.
You're bleeding from your femoral artery.
What's it gonna be...
him or the patient, huh?
Don't let lust cloud
your judgment.
What's it gonna be?
Hey, more pain!
- Aaaaah!
- More!
Aaaaaaaaaaah! Aaaaaaaaaaah!
There you go.
- Aaaaaaaaaaah!
- There you go.
First I have to ask Dr. Shepherd
and Dr. Karev
some important questions, okay?
- How's it going, Rugrat?
- Hey, Dr. Alex.
I have a patient whose son
laughs all the time.
Is that bad? Because then
I've been doing this all wrong.
No,
II had a case back in peds.
It's... It's uncontrollable laughing.
It sounds sort of hollow, peculiar.
- You're thinking H.H.?
- Gelastic seizures?
- What's a seizure?
- Oh, it's when...
It's when something's hurt
inside your brain.
Is Noah sick?
I thought his mommy was sick.
Hey, you got a sec?
Yeah.
- Um, so, can you see him today?
- Now?
Okay.
- I'm not a cheater.
- I never said you were.
You implied it.
I mean, I have cheated,
but that doesn't make me
a "cheater."
Ah, tomato, "tomahto," potato, adulterer.
Listen, you were the one
who told me to go to Teddy.
And you listened.
- What was I supposed to say?
- "Hey, Amelia. That sounds crazy.
Hey, Amelia.
Teddy and I aren't like that.
Hey, Amelia. I'm gonna be a good husband
and not cheat on you with
this woman I have history with."
You had options
because you, unlike me,
did not have a brain tumor.
Okay, that is not fair.
Isn't it?
Okay.
Teddy is my...
She's Teddy. She knows me.
And she's always been there
for me if I've needed her.
And tumor or not, you weren't.
So I didn't feel like
I was cheating on you.
When you told me to go to her,
it felt right.
And I'm sorry if that hurts,
but it is the truth.
Wow.
Our marriage didn't stand
a chance.
- What?
- Teddy.
She's your tumor.
What?
The Party is now
the world's worst hangover.
I, um... I pre-oxygenated the
patient, rapid-sequenced him.
And then I inserted an ET tube,
and then I checked the position
with a CO2 indicator.
I right,
Hellmouth's team is winning.
- The rest of you are losers.
- Hey!
Kepner,
is the hose really necessary?
Oh, you know what?
Whining doesn't save dying people.
Speaking of dying people,
your boyfriend's bleeding out, Bello.
Okay,
I apply a tourniquet
- onto his...
- No, no, no. ABCs, remember?
No. You're bleeding out.
- You can't help me.
- Well, I don't want to die.
You don't think
I understand you?
Spanish is pretty close to
Italian.
Kepner, what are you doing?
What? Oh.
I got rained on when
I did my Trauma Cert.
Yeah, because it was raining.
I don't like this game.
I don't like this game!
You're breaking them, Kepner.
Look, they're losing
- their minds.
- Hey, keep up those compressions,
Bloodbank!
You're losing her!
Damn it.
I got to go the ICU.
This was getting so fun.
Hey, make sure he doesn't
stop compressions.
There's no crying
in Trauma Cert!
Here you go.
It's okay. It's okay.
Just... Just breathe.
Just breathe.
She's gone. She's gone.
It's okay.
Just... Just breathe it out.
Then Dr. Webber
will use a laparoscope
to extract
a piece of the peritoneum.
Minimally invasive,
minimal scarring.
Thanks for
letting me know.
- Thanks for not hiding it from me...
- Mom, come on.
Like you've been hiding
Maggie Pierce.
Yeah, I get it.
Uh, let's talk about this later.
- Over pie.
- You know what? Yes,
I am seeing Maggie Pierce.
- And, no, it's none of your business.
- None of my business?
My love life isn't
any of your concern, no.
- It never was and never will be.
- What about your wife... April?
- You all work together all the time.
- Guys... - Ex-wife.
Of all the places on earth
for you to dip your wick,
- you chose...
- Out of line, all right?
- Come on. Oh, child, please.
- Guys!
- What?
Oh, now look
what you did.
- What I did?
- Yeah. You just did.
Michelle, stop.
Michelle, it's not what
it looks like, all right?
It isn't?
'Cause it looks like
my doctors
don't have their heads
in the game.
My mother's upset about
a personal matter.
- It's nothing, really.
- It's not nothing.
- Mom, come on.
- No.
Whatever happens in there,
I'm gonna leave here,
for better or worse,
with my life and body
permanently altered.
And I would rather it not
be for the worse.
So, whatever
this "nothing" is...
figure it out
because you're not
cutting into me
until I have your full attention.
♪♪
So, as your liver was healing,
a fistula developed,
uh, sort of
an accidental bridge
between the liver
and the small bowel.
- Sounds like a design flaw.
- It is.
We'll have to go in
and dissect it out.
Mm. Almost poetic, right?
I'm searching for ways
to make time bridges in space,
and one forms inside me.
Too bad I hate poetry.
See, I-I respect what you're doing,
but I worry about you
being out there all alone,
working with all that
heavy equipment...
- On a lunatic's errand.
- No...
Yeah. I get it.
I may never crack it.
But I never want to be
a person who says, "No."
Like, you say, "No,"
and you stop the future cold.
All you have is your past,
your mistakes, your regrets.
But you say, "Maybe,"
and the whole world opens up.
The past is gone,
and there are a million futures
you can have.
Okay, Liz, I need you to
take deep breaths, okay?
Deep breaths slowly, slowly.
- She's scared, Mommy.
- I know, honey. I know.
I know you're scared.
I know you're...
It's just his laugh.
It's just a laugh. This is so stupid.
I shouldn't have
let them take him.
It's just an MRI.
There's no radiation.
He's not gonna get hurt,
and it's better to be
safe than sorry, right?
You couldn't wait?
You couldn't wait till I'm not
t-till my baby's not...
to tell me that
my son's laughter might be...
Liz, I really couldn't wait, okay?
I'm... I am so sorry,
but Noah's laughs...
if they are seizures,
every time that they happen,
they are doing damage
to his brain,
and I need those doctors to do
everything that they can
to make them stop them
immediately.
Sweetie, I'm sorry
I'm such a crybaby.
This mus
t be pretty scary for you, huh?
All this grown-up stuff.
I just hope that
Noah's okay.
Okay, hold on. Hold on. Hold on.
I know... I know that it's really hard.
I know that it's really hard,
but if you move,
you could rupture the amniotic sac.
And if it ruptures,
- then I can't help your baby.
- Okay.
- Mommy.
- Stay still. I know, honey.
You know what, Ella,
can you please take her?
Ella, I need you to take Sofia.
Hey, book an O.R.
and get me some orderlies, okay?
Mommy, I want to stay with you.
Sofia, I need you to get out of here now!
- All right, Liz...
- Yeah?
I'm gonna lower your head, and
we're gonna take you to the O.R.
W-Wait. O.R.?
I need to see Noah first.
We don't have time.
It's gonna be okay, okay?
We got to move.
We got to move. Let's go!
Stop it.
If we can't get him to stay
still, we can't get a good scan.
Hey, Noah, what's orange
and sounds like a parrot?
A carrot!
You are zero help.
Noah, how do you get
a tissue to dance?
You put a little boogie in it.
I'm just trying to
hear his real laugh.
Okay, Noah, you and Dr. Karev
are gonna play
a game called Statue.
Whichever one of you moves first
loses.
Okay, Statue game.
Ready? One, two, three.
They're seizures, right?
Yeah.
Yeah, they are.
Did I win?
I don't know what was wrong
with that lawyer woman.
She was accomplished,
and she was attractive.
So is Maggie, Mom.
This is not a contest.
Oh, really? What is it?
Don't look at me.
I can't answer that for you.
Why not?
I don't understand why you're
not more upset over this mess.
Oh, I'm plenty upset.
- Thank you.
- You are?
Not with them, Catherine.
With you.
Excuse me?
Nothing's ever good enough
for your child.
I get it, that you have strong feelings
about who Jackson dates.
Any parent would.
This is not about Maggie.
No, it's not about Maggie...
because she's brilliant.
She's skilled, and she's kind.
And any mother in her right mind
would be elated
that she'd deign
to date their son.
- Damn!
- Don't "damn" me.
You have my blessing, son,
but if I hear that
you've hurt Maggie in any way,
I'm gonna come after you.
Damn.
Now, you two let me know if
we're doing this groundbreaking
surgery today or not.
In the meantime, I got patients.
Michelle.
Michelle, we want to apologize.
Michelle, we were out of line earlier.
We've settled our differences.
We're ready to get back to work
if you'll have us.
That's a load of crap.
What's it about?
No.
It's about a woman
he's seeing.
No, that's not Michelle's concern.
It's not even yours.
Is he dating garbage?
No. She's brilliant.
She's lovely. She's...
- And Mom thinks she's my stepsister.
- Oh.
- But it's not like
- we grew up together, okay?
We're... Didn't even meet
until we were adults. It's...
It's not that.
That's not even the main thing.
It's not about her.
Great. So it's about me.
It's about Richard.
When your father left,
I just closed off a part of my heart,
slammed the door, nailed shut...
until Richard Webber came along
and shook me like
I didn't know I could shake.
And when I saw you and Maggie today, I...
All I could think was,
"Richard is gonna take her side,
like I would take yours,"
like he just did.
Then what if
we can't reconcile that?
Jackson,
I want you to have love.
I just don't want it
to cost me mine.
Richard's not my father, Mom.
I know. He's my husband.
No. I'm saying
you should give him
a little more credit than that.
I've met my father.
Richard ain't him.
He's a lot better than that.
Okay. Good.
Now hug it out. Come on.
It's a shortcut between
two points in space.
You enter the wormhole,
space folds like a taco,
and then you come out
the other side.
And the other side is the past?
No, you can't travel
to the past, but...
"Yester-me" can come
meet "now-me,"
but "future-me" can't go back.
Okay, now-me has a headache.
Now-me wishes I could talk to
future-me about tonight.
Clamp.
What's happening tonight?
Oh, uh, n-n... Uh, nothing.
Funny story.
When I was little, I used to wish
I could go back in time
and meet my birth mother.
- Not me.
- Really? Never?
Well, you were put up
for adoption.
I was left outside a firehouse.
- Fair enough.
- I'd meet your mom, though.
Ellis Grey was
this world-renowned,
award-winning surgeon
and...
Wait. What if
Cerone was an Ellis stalker?
Like... Like... Like a groupie,
like "Single White Female"?
Oh, no, no, no, no.
There's blood in her N.G. tube.
She's actively bleeding.
From where?
A ruptured vessel?
Or an ulcer or varices.
Oh, man.
Okay, I'm gonna need
to scope her.
Bring in the C-arm for an angio
and order 10 units!
Okay, the peritoneum is ready.
This tissue looks perfect.
Need a six-oh
on a driver, please.
That was beautiful work, dear.
Thank you.
You know, I really like her, Mom.
I know.
I like her, too.
And I want it to work between us.
But if it does all go to hell
with me and Maggie,
then you do have my blessing
to take her side.
Deal?
Deal.
So much bleeding.
I-I can't find the source.
Okay, Bokhee, contrast.
Good, good, good.
Oh, where are you? Where are you?
I wish I could go back in time
to before this happened.
- You can't go backwards...
- I know. I know.
There it is. There it is. See it?
Ah, yes, I will advance the catheter
and try to embolize the bleed.
I think Cerone was
telling the truth about Ellis.
We can't know for sure.
There's proof.
I'm the proof.
Ellis didn't leave me
outside a firehouse,
but she did keep me a secret.
She lied to Richard.
She lied to Meredith.
If she's capable of doing that
to the people she loves the most,
you don't think she's capable of
screwing over a friend?
Oh, damn it.
Her B.P.'s bottoming out.
Okay, I can't
isolate this bleeder. Pierce?
No, there is still too much blood.
Okay, Wilson,
you have to help me out here.
Get in there and open up her stomach.
Okay. 10 blade.
Come on, Marge.
You want to see the future.
- Help me understand your logic, please.
- Owen, our marriage is over.
- There's no point in just hashing it...
- Amelia.
Okay. Fine.
You see this tumor?
Officially, it's benign.
No cancer.
But if we leave it in, it's
gonna kill this kid, anyway.
So, really, "benign"
is neither here nor there.
- I don't how this is...
- Mm-hmm. Okay.
So, you were never with Teddy.
You never played it out.
She was your friend.
She was your person.
Benign.
But always there,
quietly growing.
So, when you marry other women
and she's still there...
She's not benign.
She rejected me.
Because you were married, dummy.
And she's not as flawed as we are.
Wait. You are single now.
You're free.
And you can't get it together
to tell her how you feel?
What is stopping you?
Well, I kind of feel like
all we talk about
since our "no feelings" rule
is, uh, feelings.
Maybe it started
when we were breaking up.
Maybe that's why
I didn't notice.
- What?
- The baby's dad.
This baby's dad.
Mike.
We were gonna get married.
Noah was so happy
to have a dad.
He was so excited
to be a big brother.
But, uh, Mike would always
call Noah "your son"
and this one "our baby,"
like Noah was just
some piece of furniture
that I moved into his house.
"Our baby will be raised like this,"
and, "Your son should know
better than that."
I loved him.
But I knew that if I stayed,
I would have a husband,
but Noah would never have a dad.
So I left him.
And I cried every day for months.
And maybe
that's why I didn't notice...
when Noah's laugh changed.
- Liz...
- I just want to go back and notice.
Oh, God.
Checked back for wound,
placed pelvic binder,
transfused two units,
and ruled out
intra-abdominal bleeding.
She should be stable now.
Nice work, guys.
I'm back! I'm here!
Dr. Kepner, our patient with
the facial trauma survived.
How do you know that?
Oh, we tried nasal intubation,
but that was impossible in
the... weather conditions,
so we criked him,
and it worked.
- We established an airway.
- Who says?
Um... I say?
All right, well, I guess
I'll have to give it to you
since I was just paged
on a freaking goose chase.
No fair. He's the one who paged you.
What?
I realized that the thing that
was most endangering
our patients was you.
I figured, if I took you
out of the equation,
I neutralized the threat.
You tried to cheat the system.
No offense, Dr. Kepner,
but you did something similar
in your Cert.
The ambulance story is legendary.
No, I mean, I-I know.
That's why it's funny...
because...
because three months after
I cheated to get my Trauma Cert,
a car-crash victim
came in to this E.R.,
and guess what.
I-I couldn't save him.
Oh, my God.
He died right in front of me.
Dr. Kepner, do we need to
pause the exercise?
No, no, no, no, no,
you can't pause
because in real life,
the trauma doesn't just stop!
God doesn't work that way.
Because you can do
every single thing right,
and still, people die.
Like, look, look.
This guy right here... this guy...
he was just, you know,
living his life, right?
He was applying to colleges,
and then one day...
bam! shot in the neck.
And then he's dead because,
guys, there are no rules.
Okay, Dr. Kepner,
I-I-I think
- that's enough.
- And this? This woman...
This woman was about
to become a mom.
Her husband was so happy.
They both were.
And one second, she was fine,
and then the next, we couldn't...
We couldn't save her.
We couldn't...
Come on. Come on.
Come on! Come on!
Dr. Kepner, Dr. Kepner.
Hey.
Are you okay?
We're do... We're done.
We're done.
♪♪
Sorry.
She was a woman
before her time.
She was bat-crap crazy.
And she was a genius.
It's a thin line
the real trailblazers straddle.
And who knows?
Ol' Bargin' Marge
might've done it one day,
discovered time travel.
An engineer decided to walk
in front of
a radar magnetron one day,
melted the candy bar
in his pocket,
and discovered the microwave.
People thought he was crazy
for suggesting they use it to heat food.
No, at the very least,
she pushed back.
She took the first step,
and she said, "Maybe."
Maybe you should name your
device "the Bargin' Marge."
Now, that would be
disrespectful.
It goes in people's
rectums, Wilson.
Right. Sorry.
"The Trailblazer."
Perfect.
♪ I see our footprints in the sand ♪
♪ I feel hairs raise
on the back of my hand ♪
♪ Take me northbound, back to home ♪
♪ Where I know ♪
♪ You feel like you're alone ♪
- ♪ And you feel like something's wrong ♪
- Hey.
- ♪ I feel like I won't know ♪
- Hey. You all right?
- No, I...
- April, hold on. Hold on.
♪♪
Let me...
Come here for a second.
♪ So keep me in mind ♪
- What?
- What is going on?
- ♪ Keep me in mind ♪
- April.
April, every time I see you,
you look like you're spinning out.
- Ohh...
- Okay? Every time
I try to talk to you,
- you slam the door in my face.
- I'm...
- ♪ Keep me in mind ♪
- When? Huh?
When did you decide that
we're not friends anymore,
that you can't talk to me?
When did you decide that...
I'm not here for you?
I'm sorry.
What can I do?
Oh.
Whoa, April.
April, no, no, no.
You said you wanted to help.
April, look, you can't fix
what you can't face, all right?
- Please.
- Fine!
Just talk to me.
Can you take Harriet tonight?
That would really help.
Thanks.
You're being a wormhole.
What?
You're being a wormhole
for your mother.
What are you talking about?
Ellis did something 30 years ago,
and it's messing with
everything we've built today
- because you're letting it.
- Jo, you didn't know my mother,
but she doesn't need my help
to mess with me.
Yes, she does.
She does because she's gone
and you're still here.
Your mother
was a trailblazer, Meredith.
If she was here, she wouldn't
want you to sit back
and polish her legacy.
She would want you to try
the crazy thing.
She would want you
to try everything.
I'm saying,
don't let something that
your mother did in the past
wipe out your chance
to change the future.
Okay.
"Okay," what?
Let's get to work.
Really?
You called me a wormhole.
I did. I'm sorry.
Should I be sorry?
Let's just get to work.
Okay, this is, uh...
Hey. Oh, sorry.
Oh.
Oh, hey, how did it go today
with your mom and Richard?
Were they awful?
They were great.
I mean, eventually.
Oh. Wow. Okay.
Obstacle number one...
not such an obstacle.
- Mm.
- So, you ready for dinner?
- Um...
- Oh. You have company.
I do, yeah.
Uh, April is, uh... Sorry.
Oh, no, no. No. I get it.
Yeah, no, she's just going
through something big, so...
Well, no. We have plenty of time.
You know,
the longer we wait to eat...
The hungrier you'll be.
I-It's inoperable?
It's too close to his brainstem.
I can't get to it with a scalpel.
But this project
that we're working on...
the ultrasound...
he could be a candidate.
I thought that you hadn't
done human trials.
We don't... We haven't yet.
I barely kept a 23-week-old baby
in her today,
and you want me to go in there
and ask her
if her 8-year-old
can be your guinea pig?
I'm sorry.
That's your plan?!
We don't have any other
course of treatment.
And he's seizing every three minutes.
This is his only shot.
♪♪
Do you want to come in with us
to talk to her?
No!
No.
Damn it.
♪ Maybe I've done enough ♪
♪ And your golden child grew up ♪
- ♪ Maybe this trophy isn't real love ♪
- Yeah, okay.
When the worst
of our fears are realized...
♪ And with or without it ♪
- Hi.
- ♪ I'm good enough ♪
♪ Maybe I've done enough ♪
♪♪
♪ Finally catching up ♪
♪ For the first time I see
an image of my brokenness ♪
♪ Utterly worthy of love ♪
♪ Maybe I've done enough ♪
When everything we've
counted on has disappeared...
♪ And I finally see myself ♪
♪♪
Something still drives us
to try to fix the past...
♪♪
Airport. International terminal, please.
Or to find our future...
Okay. Come on.
- ♪ Now I only want what's real ♪
- All right.
You good?
- Mm-hmm.
- ♪ To let my heart feel what it feels ♪
when the only thing that
really needs our attention
is the present...
♪ Gold, silver, or bronze ♪
- Mommy?
- Hmm?
♪ Hold no value here ♪
Are you crying
because Noah has a tumor?
No. No.
Um...
No, I'm crying
'cause I'm lucky.
I am so lucky
to have a beautiful, smart,
healthy little girl.
♪ I set aside the highlight reel ♪
And sometimes I get so busy
that I forget how lucky I am.
♪ And leave my greatest failures
on display ♪
You know what?
How about tomorrow
I take the day off?
♪ With an asterisk ♪
You and I can go
find an adventure,
just the two of us, okay?
- Yeah?
- ♪ Worthy of love anyway ♪
Yeah? Yeah?
and its infinite possibilities.
Ooh, I love you.
All right, sweet dreams.