Previously on The Resident...
I really am sorry.
Don't be. Just so you know,
Hawkins never said, "I
love you," not once.
The treatment... it didn't work?
Oh, it did, just a
little less than before.
Your only hope for survival is
a heart transplant, Governor.
Move me to the top
of the UNOS list.
Betz agreed
to save Chastain.
- If he gets a heart.
- And survives the transplant.
- You're leaving?
- I couldn't tell Kit the truth.
I can only take so
much at one time.
Sammie. When does she get here?
They're on a plane
right this minute.
Honey, are you okay?
- Maybe up more?
- How's that?
A little more.
- Okay.
- Perfect.
Good.
Who knew six-year-olds
were so bossy?
The woman
knows what she wants.
Hey, since you
only turn six once,
I got you a very special
something for your party.
He looks just like Mr. Giraffe!
But bigger. So big!
Happy birthday, sweetheart.
I love you, Billie.
I love you, too.
And I can't wait to show
Sammie when she gets here.
Yes!
Wait till she sees what they
do to get that candy out
- of Mr. Giraffe's big brother.
- Oh.
Excuse me.
Don't let me stop you.
Kiss him again!
- Again, she says.
- Oh, again, yeah.
Wow. Okay.
It's Bell.
- All right. Oh.
- Hope you're not calling
to bail on Gigi's
birthday party.
I got a pretty pink party
hat with your name on it.
Yeah, uh, about that. I-I
know it's your day off,
but we have an emergency.
- Not Betz.
- No, the governor's fine.
He's, uh... His donor
heart's on the way.
But it's-it's Sammie.
What's wrong?
Well, she got sick
on the flight here,
and Jake and Gregg
thought it was the flu,
but she woke up far worse, and
they had to call an ambulance.
So, given her medical
history, you can imagine.
Yeah, you're terrified.
I'll be right there.
- That looks really good.
- Daddy, what's wrong?
Sammie got sick on the
plane. I have to go see her.
I'm coming.
- Let me get my nursing kit!
- Uh, no, honey.
Why don't we stay here
and wait for news?
Might not be serious.
The donor
was a young male
with an addiction to motorcycles
and a resistance to helmet laws.
But I'm told the organ
survived the accident
in pristine condition,
and it's a perfect match.
Uh, when do we do this?
He's prepped and ready to go.
Then we're headed to the OR now.
- Got your text.
- Hey, it's go time.
Let's scrub in.
I'll meet Sammie's ambulance.
I have to deal with
Betz, but don't panic.
- It could just be a bad flu.
- I know, I know, but Jake's a doctor.
He would know if
it wasn't serious.
Keep me posted.
I'll be there as soon as I can.
You're in great hands. I'll
see you on the other side.
I'm counting on it.
We kept our end of the bargain.
I want to hear, on
your word of honor,
that you will do the same.
Save my life, and I
will save this hospital.
You have my word.
- How's she doing?
- Decompensating by the minute.
- Glad you're here.
- Look. Honey, it's Grandpa.
Hey, sweetie.
Don't worry. We've got
you. We've got you.
- Status?
- Ten-year-old female
presenting with fever over
104 and flu-like symptoms.
- Sats over 80.
- She spiked a high fever
last night, became nauseous
and started vomiting.
Then she had trouble breathing.
Okay, Trauma Bay Ten. Hundley,
we need you and Irving.
We'll update you.
Okay. On my
count. One, two,
three.
Hey, sweetheart, how you doing?
Gigi's birthday party.
No one's having a
party without you.
Cross my heart.
- Let's get labs and an ABG.
- You got it.
- Airway's intact.
- Absent breath sounds on the left.
- Pneumothorax.
- We'll need to decompress it.
- I'll get an ultrasound.
- Okay, I'll order a stat chest X-ray.
- Hundley, will you please?
- I'll prep the chest tube.
Sammie, your lung's collapsed.
But we're going
to do a procedure
that's gonna help you
feel better, okay?
Uh-huh.
I came as quickly as I could.
Oh, Jake.
- Gregg.
- Hi.
Where's Sammie?
She's with Conrad and
Devon in the trauma room.
- Do they know what's wrong?
- Not yet.
What's the update on Betz?
The heart arrived.
He's already in the OR.
I have to brief the press,
but I'll be right back.
Please.
Governor Betz is in surgery.
Our best team is performing a
heart transplant as we speak.
We have every reason to expect
a good outcome. Thank you.
Extending the incision towards
the mitral valve annulus.
Great. Now,
removing the cold...
I mean old heart.
Ready for the donor.
All right.
Here we go.
Oh, looks pristine.
No evidence of valvular disease
or damage from the accident.
This is
pretty terrifying.
We have two lives
in our hands today.
The governor's and Chastain's.
Some people, when
the pressure is on...
They wish anybody would step
in and take their place.
Me? I prefer the
Michael Jordan approach.
You're gonna have to
elaborate on that.
Michael had no fear.
If he was in a game,
and what was needed for
a win was a three-pointer
from mid-court, a
nearly impossible shot,
he would demand that ball and
never wonder if he'd miss.
I'd like to be like that.
Well, then be Jordan.
Hey, sweetie. You
feeling better?
- A little.
- We love you, honey.
You are very brave.
You're admitting her?
Yes, but the good news is,
her BP and sats have come up.
Temp's still a
little high, but we were able
to reinflate her lung.
- How is she?
- I didn't want to mention this
to Jake and Gregg just
yet, but we did a CT scan.
And it's not great.
You better
come have a look.
I have it right over here.
So it wasn't just
a collapsed lung.
She's got an effusion.
We'll need to drain the
fluid and send it to the lab.
And given
Sammie's history,
there's a strong possibility
that her cancer has come back.
Look, obviously,
we want it to be anything else,
and we will keep searching.
But there aren't
many other reasons
to explain a
spontaneous pneumothorax
and pleural effusion in
a child of Sammie's age.
Just give us a minute.
Okay, let's not panic.
Let's think this through.
How am I going to break
this to Jake and Gregg?
Oh, this child,
this precious child...
- We don't know that it's cancer yet.
- Yeah, right.
The first step, the obvious
one... we need pediatric help.
Well, after the cuts
Betz forced us to make,
that entire department's
been on life support.
And we just lost our
best pediatric surgeon.
She's my granddaughter.
We got to get Ian back in here.
Thank you for agreeing
to be my sponsor, Wade.
I'm happy to do it.
I'll take all the
help I can get.
I'd like
you to make a list
and identify your triggers.
Things you see or do that
make you want to use.
Avoiding them is an essential
component of relapse prevention.
Well, my biggest
trigger is stress.
I treat sick kids.
Families come to me for help at
the worst moment of their lives,
and I'm supposed
to be the savior,
make their children better
and never break a sweat,
but not every
child can be fixed.
Do you have a plan for how to
deal with this without drugs?
I've taken a leave of
absence to reassess.
Trying to figure
out if the truth is
that my work will always
threaten my recovery.
Well, are you searching
for coping mechanisms?
Well, the drugs were
my coping mechanism.
The only ones that
worked, but now,
I'm facing the
awful question of,
am I gonna have to
find a different way
to make a living,
which is something
I can't even contemplate,
because I... I love what I do.
Medicine is literally my life,
and I am very good at it.
Even loaded, I was better than
99% of the doctors in my field.
That's a dangerous way to think.
In Nar-Anon, it's known
as "Euphoric Recall,"
the tendency to romanticize
your drug use -
while conveniently forgetting
all the harm it caused.
- I have to take this.
- No problem.
Hello, Kit.
I'm... I'm really sorry to
hear that. That's awful.
I-I would like to help,
Kit, I really would,
but I don't think that I can.
Okay. I'm coming in.
Now remove the
aortic cross clamps.
Give it a couple seconds for
his new heart to kick in.
Moment of truth.
Nothing.
Paddles to me. Ten joules.
Clear.
Increase the charge to 20.
Let's try it again.
Charging. Clear.
Maybe we're missing something.
We've rechecked the electrolyte.
It's not the potassium.
All right, give him
a dose of magnesium
and lidocaine. We'll
give it one last shot.
Charging.
Clear.
Normal sinus!
MJ for the win with
two seconds left.
I think these elephants would
look nice over the windows.
Sammie's my best friend.
I know, sweetie.
I want to go to the
hospital to be with her.
She needs me.
Okay, why don't you keep
coloring these hearts for me?
Conrad, what's going on?
Waiting on Sammie's labs.
Just hoping her cancer
hasn't come back.
Oh, no.
How is Gigi?
Oh, she's fine, but she
keeps saying she wants
to go to Chastain, you
know, to be with Sammie.
I'll try and keep her
busy. Keep me updated.
Will do.
I'm Dr. Ian Sullivan.
Dr. Voss asked me to consult
on your daughter's case.
Of course. We know you
by your reputation.
Thank you so much for
coming in. I'm Jake.
And I'm Gregg. We are
so glad you're here.
If anyone can save her...
Honestly, we just
have so much faith.
An-And trust in you.
And this must be Sammie.
How are you feeling?
Not so great.
But I think, now
that you're here,
I'll start to feel better soon.
Okay, Sammie.
I am going to listen to your
lungs and then your heart.
Okay. That's it. Take
a deep breath for me.
Sorry.
- That-that wasn't really good.
- No, you're doing just fine.
Okay.
Now I am going to press
on your belly, okay?
- My belly doesn't hurt.
- Oh, that's good.
Okay, princess, you sit tight.
If anything gets worse,
or if something new
starts to bother you,
I want you to press
that red button, okay?
And then I'd come running.
Thank you for coming
in so quickly.
Of course. She's a heartbreaker.
Have you seen Sammie's
medical history?
I'm about to take a deep dive
into all that immediately.
- I just did a brief exam.
- Do you think it's cancer?
Fear of a recurrence
is understandable,
but it could be a host
of different things.
The effusion could be
secondary to an infection,
which would fit with
the low-grade fever.
I'll order more cultures.
- Thank you.
- Sit tight.
Strong pressure,
normal heart sound.
Limited mediastinal output. We
can put these to water seal.
At this rate, we can
clamp the tubes tomorrow.
I'll order another chest X-ray.
Translation?
Your new heart is
functioning well, Governor.
Ah. Oh. Is...?
Is-is... is this pain normal?
BP 60/40.
- He's in shock.
- No signs of obstruction
in the chest tube. Unlikely
to be a tension pneumo.
The valves sound good.
He's still in sinus.
- Crank up the norepi.
- Add vaso.
And start vanc and cefepime.
We need an ultrasound
in here now!
- Hey.
- What's going on?
I thought you resigned.
I'm here at Dr. Voss's request
to consult on Bell's
granddaughter's case.
- A consult only?
- Yes, I promise.
If they end up
needing a surgeon,
I'll help them find a good one.
Well, what if
there's an emergency?
Then I'll tell Kit everything.
Everything? Including
how you were using here?
Yes. I would rather
avoid it, but I will.
Would you like to be a witness?
Dad, it's just, you've
come such a long way,
and this commitment
to honesty...
I haven't had to be honest yet.
I wouldn't say there's
anything too admirable.
But unless you object,
I'd like to stay, as
long as there's a chance
I can help that sweet
kid and her family.
Of course.
Let me know if there's
anything I can do to help.
All right.
Oh. Does Sammie have a visitor?
Conrad thought it might not
be a good idea, but she...
I said I had to come.
I couldn't refuse her.
Okay. Well, I think you may be
just the person Sammie needs.
Sammie's been asleep for a bit.
Jake and Gregg just took the
chance to get us some food.
Gigi.
Birthday.
- Sorry.
- It's okay.
We'll have a party
when you're all better.
For now, just sleep.
I'll be right here.
She is just like her mother.
I feel like I just saw Nic.
Cardiac index is marginal,
even on pressors.
Steroids are not
improving contractility.
His heart's only getting worse.
- Let's intubate.
- Yeah.
That'll offload some of the
pressure on his left ventricle
and buy us some more time.
Labs are back.
Antibody testing is
completely negative.
So rejection is
extremely unlikely.
But if he's not rejecting
the transplanted heart,
then what is it?
Rechecking his echo.
It's subtle.
Apical wall akinesis,
- hyperdynamic septum.
- Stress cardiomyopathy.
Something else in his body
is causing his heart to tank,
and we got to figure
out what it is fast.
I got this.
- Hey.
- Labs and pleural fluid are back.
There are no malignant cells.
So it's not cancer.
Did you hear that?
The cancer hasn't returned.
That's great news.
But if it's not cancer,
then what is it?
She's having trouble breathing.
We have to know what's
wrong to treat it.
I'll be back.
Hey, just the guy
I'm looking for.
Same here.
So, we've effectively ruled
out rejection for Betz.
And we've ruled out
cancer for Sammie.
Infectious studies?
Blood cultures
are negative so far.
Same here. Galactomannan
and glucan?
Pending, but Sammie
is not a likely host
for a fungal infection.
Neither is Betz.
Maybe I should just
add micafungin.
All right, so his
pressure's getting worse.
What if it's not vasodilatory?
How about obstructive
shock or pneumothorax?
And tamponade. Ruled out.
I thought about adrenal
insufficiencies.
But you've given him a
slug of steroids anyway.
Which is about the only thing
you haven't given Sammie.
I'm still thinking
infectious is possible
despite the negative
fluid studies.
Considered autoimmune?
ANA, ANCA, rheumatoid
factor are all in lab.
But you don't want
to empirically treat?
Not with the concern
for infection.
We got nothing.
You know what?
You taught me, from my
very first day at Chastain,
that if the answer isn't
on these white boards...
Go back to the patient
and the physical exam.
Have I ever told you, you were
the best intern I ever had?
Well, I had the best teacher.
Nearly maxed on epi drip.
Repeat labs are back.
His lactate is sky-high.
Not a surprise. He's been
hypotensive for hours.
Wait. The lactate isn't the
result of the hypotension.
It's a clue about the cause.
Right. Right.
We've been so
focused on the heart.
What if...?
Distended abdomen.
It's barely noticeable,
but I think you're right.
- He has bowel ischemia?
- Yup.
- That explains the shock.
- And the heart failure.
We'll need to take him to CT
to confirm, but if we're right,
he'll have to go back to the OR.
I'll page Bell.
Just take a few deep
breaths for me, Sammie.
Why is her tongue red?
Lean back for me, Sammie.
Open up and say "aah," okay?
Aah.
Strawberry tongue.
- She has Kawasaki disease.
- That would explain
the fever and the
flu-like symptoms.
Now we can treat it.
Let's start her on IVIG.
That's-that's great news.
I can't believe it.
Um, AJ needs me.
It's Betz. Got to go.
- Sammie, what's wrong?
- Must be some kind
of cardiac complication
related to the Kawasaki.
All right. You guys stay here.
We're gonna get her
to the cath lab.
And page Yamada.
Got your page. What's going on?
- Betz isn't rejecting the heart.
- Okay.
Here's the problem.
Bowel ischemia.
That's your specialty, Bell.
It is, but the last
bowel ischemia we had,
the patient died on the
table, and that guy in there
made sure I got sued.
Well, we need you
to operate on him.
Is that going to be a problem?
No. I'll save the S.O.B.
She has a giant
coronary aneurysm,
a result of the Kawasaki.
It looks clotted off.
And partially ruptured.
Blood is accumulating around
the heart, causing tamponade.
I can do a
pericardiocentesis right now,
but it's only a temporary fix.
Look, the aneurysm could
rupture at any second.
She's gonna need coronary
artery bypass surgery.
A CABG on a ten-year-old?
That's unheard of.
Look, ischemic heart,
MI, sudden cardiac death.
She could have it all.
The surgery's a Hail Mary, but
it gives Sammie her only shot.
Okay. I'll book an
OR, Dr. Sullivan.
When can you be ready?
I'm gonna need a half hour.
Okay.
So, tell me where
we are with Sammie.
Then I have to
scrub in for Betz.
She has a GCA... Giant
coronary aneurysm.
Oh, God.
I'm sorry. As I'm sure
you're both aware,
the surgery to fix this
is incredibly risky, but
at this point, it's the only
path left to save her life.
At least we know what's wrong.
Yeah, yeah.
Obviously, you're the
best person to operate.
You still have privileges here.
Look, I'm ready, and
I-I want to help,
but there's something that
you need to know first.
I was not hiking across
Spain these last few weeks.
I was in rehab.
Rehab for what?
Addiction to pills.
Uppers, downers.
Whatever I needed to...
relieve stress, to focus,
to do my best during surgery.
At least that was my excuse.
Were you operating
here at Chastain
while under the influence?
- Yes.
- So you lied.
You some... somehow
cheated the drug tests
and put sick
children in jeopardy.
Yes, but I never
harmed a patient.
I was a functioning
addict, I was...
Look, there's no excuse,
there's no justification.
I'm not doing that.
This is a disaster.
Sammie needs the OR now.
- I mean, what do we do?
- Look, I am sober.
I intend to stay that way.
If you have lost your trust
in me, I fully understand.
But there is not a pediatric
surgeon at Atlanta General
who can do this, okay?
I have been in contact
with colleagues
in Boston and New York, and
they can be here tomorrow.
- Well, it might be too late.
- This is appalling.
I can't even
drug-test you in time
to make sure you're
sober right now.
I am, you have my word.
What's your
word even worth?
We can't believe
a thing you say.
She's your granddaughter.
What do you want me to do?
Well, Ian has to do the surgery.
We have no choice.
So, you have this chance to at
least partially redeem yourself.
I'll go scrub in.
If he screws this
up, I will kill him.
If anyone
can save her...
Honestly, we just
have so much faith.
And trust in you.
We're ready if you are.
Scalpel.
Sternal saw to me.
I'm fine. Let's do this thing.
Ten-blade to me.
Retractor.
That's a lot of dead bowel.
That's much more
than I expected.
That explains the shock.
- Oh, pressure's dropping fast.
- Yeah, we need to move.
- Bowel resection.
- Stapler to me.
Aneurysm is completely
ruptured. She's exsanguinating.
Please save her!
BP's dropping.
I need to get control here.
Too late. She's coding.
Dr. Sullivan!
Initiating cardiac massage.
I need cardiothoracic. Get
Dr. Austin in here right now!
Hey, it's Sammie.
Her aneurysm
completely ruptured.
Dr. Sullivan needs your
help right away, AJ.
Randolph,
you got this, man?
Dr. Bell?
I heard about Sammie.
Do you need another
set of hands?
Get ready for the big
leagues, Devi. We need you
- to take over for Bell.
- I'm ready.
Pass me the ball.
Let's go.
- What can I do?
- Finish cannulating,
so we can start the bypass
and stop the bleeding.
And cannulating complete.
Hit it.
Cross clamps.
The machine is taking over
the function of her heart.
And it's stopping the bleeding.
- She's stabilizing.
- Yeah, but it's not over yet.
The hardest part of the
surgery is coming up.
I've never performed
a CABG on a patient so young.
Remember, delicate
vessels, delicate fingers.
Divide and conquer.
Dissecting out the vein.
Acquiring target.
There's a
perforation in the duodenum.
It's-it's passing.
The flare, it's... passing.
You have to get control
of the spillage.
- I'll suction and wash him out.
- Well, we have
to patch up the hole. That's
the only way to save him.
It's big. Think we'll
be able to close?
We'll use a piece of omentum.
Okay, harvesting the tissue now.
Pressures are tanking.
Okay, just finishing
the omental patch.
His MAPs are still
falling. We're losing him.
I know. I know. Hang
on. Almost there.
And...
done.
Bravo.
The torch has passed.
Far from it.
- We're in this together.
- No.
Not anymore.
You're the lead surgeon.
The patient couldn't
be in better hands.
So, if you don't mind,
I will... leave you to it.
How's it going?
Well, Ian's been brilliant.
Almost there.
Last stitch.
And the
CABG is complete.
Let's get her heart going.
We just need one
more miracle today.
Removing the clamps.
And...
here we go.
Come on.
Oh.
A week ago, my life was saved
at Chastain Memorial.
I saw firsthand the
care they provide,
and I saw the impact that
taking that care away had
on patients and on
other hospitals.
- He's keeping his word.
- He'd better.
As a result,
Chastain's full funding
has been restored.
Yes! Chastain lives!
Never give up!
Oh! Ho-ho-ho.
Congratulations. You
saved the hospital.
Congratulations to all of us.
Thanks for coming to talk to me.
- Of course.
- Hi, Dad.
Oh. I didn't see you there.
I invited Cade because I
wanted her to hear this, too.
The work you did last
week saving Sammie
was nothing short of miraculous.
Oh, well, Dr. Austin
was an equal partner.
It was teamwork all the way.
Cade told me how hard you've
been working on your sobriety.
She also reminded me
that addiction is a disease,
not a moral failing.
Operating under the
influence is a moral failing.
All I can do is
dedicate my sobriety
to making up for
the risks I took,
and for the damage my
addiction did to Cade.
That's a fine sentiment.
I hope you can hold onto it.
After considerable
thought, I've decided,
if you're willing, I want
you back at Chastain.
That's amazing.
And very brave.
It's a risk I'll take.
You're too valuable to
patients. I can't replace you.
You'll be tested regularly.
And if you use again, even
once, it will be your last day.
- Understood.
- So, will you come back to us?
You couldn't drag
me away.
I'm so happy for you, Dad.
So, um,
I've got some good
news and some bad news.
As you suspected, your
MS has progressed.
But that also means
that you're eligible
for the second
phase of my trial.
Well, that's...
that's a huge relief.
And I wonder, you know, if...
full remission is possible.
Well, with or without
the trial, it is.
And that can be weeks or months,
and in some cases,
it can be years.
Well, let's just hope it's
long enough we can find a cure.
You know, um...
I remember when you first
came to this hospital,
and you were...
green and innocent,
and had so much to learn.
And now...
Devon, I'm just...
I'm just so glad it's you...
that holds my life
in your hands.
Let's beat this.
Together.
All right.
Thank you.
Welcome back.
God, I'm so excited
to see the boys.
- I'm so sorry for everything.
- Hey, don't be.
Postpartum depression
is a medical condition
that can affect anyone.
And we both want you to
know that we support you.
And we believe you are going to
be a great mother to our boys.
And I promise to always be
honest with you and let you know
- if I'm getting overwhelmed.
- Good.
Well, let's go see our
babies, shall we?
Yeah.
♪ All I had was you... ♪
Oh, my heavens, they
are so beautiful.
Of course they are.
They look just like me.
You know, Padma,
when my mom died,
I... I felt lost and alone.
And I know
no one could ever replace her,
but my heart feels full.
I now have a family, and I
will never be alone again,
and that's thanks to you.
♪ Do the melodies convince you ♪
♪ Written by a man
who's lost and afraid? ♪
♪ All I had was you... ♪
Hi.
I'm their mother. I'll
take it from here.
♪ All I had was you ♪
♪ All I had was you. ♪
One of us suits up
while the other stands down.
I heard you were taking
a leave of absence.
Yeah, I'm entering
Devon's MS trial,
and I want to spend a little
more time alone with Kit.
And with luck,
I'll be back soon.
You and I have something
in common, don't we?
We both have an
incurable disease.
Yeah, but I can't cure
mine with will power.
Well, you've done
pretty good so far.
You know, there's
another thing we share.
When I agreed to
do Betz's surgery,
I knew my symptoms were
getting worse, and I believed
that I could control
something I couldn't control.
You're worried I
won't stay sober.
I'm worried that you, like me,
have the worst disease
of this profession...
Arrogance.
Are you capable of
policing yourself?
Arrogance was never my problem.
It was the opposite... fear...
that I'm not good enough,
that I am an imposter.
Drugs took the fear away.
Why didn't you come to Kit
and tell her you had a problem?
Fear again.
I didn't want to lose the thing
that was most precious
to me, beside Cade.
But she has her own life.
At the end of the day...
every night, I go home alone.
The work...
This... is what I have.
Well, that I understand.
'Cause I was that guy.
- Hmm.
- For decades.
But not anymore. Now with Kit,
I mean... I mean, there's a
whole world outside these walls.
I don't think you'll be
outside for too long.
Well, Kit and my family
will be my priority,
and possibly helping to find
a cure for this disease.
But I'm-I'm not gonna disappear.
I'll teach incoming interns.
Well, that is one of
your finest skills.
You've already helped create
the most brilliant
young doctor here.
My mentor gave me
his stethoscope
when I became an
attending, and I...
I kept it all these years.
And now, on the day
you become an attending,
I give it to you.
I will treasure it, Dr. Bell.
Congratulations.
And call him "Randolph."
You're not a resident anymore.
Thank you.
Couldn't be more proud of you.
Will you marry me, Dr. Devi?
Yes.
Happy birthday!
- Oh! Oh, wow!
- Oh, my goodness!
- That's amazing!
- Look at this!
- Rainbow!
- And I've got something special
for you.
- We can match.
- Yes, join the party.
Here we go. Ready?
Make a wish.
Regrets?
Presents! Presents!
- Come on.
- Presents! Presents!
I'm thinking Charleston
for the weekend.
That sounds ideal.
All right.
Okay. We hope you like it.
Oh, look at that, huh?
Thank you.
I love it!
Sammie, I
have a present for you, too.
It's not new, but
it's really special.
Oh, no, you can't
give Mr. Giraffe away.
- It's your birthday.
- I want to
'cause I know
he'll keep you safe
so you'll never
get so sick again.
- Aw.
- Thank you.
If you'd rather have
a brand-new toy...
Never. He's perfect as he is.
- Oh.
- And so are you.
You want to continue?
I love you.
Resync By M_I_S
www.opensubtitles.org
And I love you.