Okay, boys and girls.
Guess what kind of animal
Wacky Benny's making now.
Give you a big hint.
Is it a dead animal?
I say we put him out of his
misery and bring out Emma's cake.
He's so new to this. How's he
gonna learn if we stop his act?
You're a sucky clown.
And you're a
super-duper audience.
Hey, that is not okay.
Hey, keep your hands off my son!
Tell him to keep
his hands off me.
I can't move my arm or leg.
So how does a completely
healthy teenager have a mini-stroke?
Head CT and cerebral
angiogram are normal,
clotting parameters are normal.
You're forgetting the wrinkly
clump in the middle of his shirt.
Thought we'd diagnose
the middle-aged clown first.
It's probably from my seatbelt.
Wrinkle pattern's too varied.
Looks like someone
shoved you. Or grabbed you.
Probably from the diaper
bag. If the patient's using drugs,
cocaine could've caused an
arterial spasm in his brain...
Tox screen's clean.
I'm gonna say it was the
ex-girlfriend you cheated on,
not the ex-wife you cheated with
because if the latter
was prone to violence,
you'd have been scattered in
various dumpsters years ago.
Seriously?
No one else wants to
talk about the patient?
New office
furniture. Meaty topic.
What's the action
on the ex-wife?
It was Rachel's boyfriend Phil.
His company's moving
him back to Portland.
He wants me to change
my visitation order
so he can ask Rachel and my
daughter to move out west with him.
Things got a little heated.
The patient was
punched in the groin,
could've triggered a massive
sympathetic discharge...
Carotid duplex is normal.
And who's better
qualified to be the daddy?
The guy who spilled a
little DNA in her gene pool,
or the guy who's gonna
be there day and night
to pass on important values like not
shtupping Mommy after the divorce?
I am her daddy.
She's staying here.
House has a point.
A couple nights a week with
each kid may make you feel better.
It doesn't replace two
round-the-clock parents.
Round-the-clock or not,
parenting's an impossible job.
No way not to mess it up.
Why shouldn't Taub
be the one to do it?
Thank you. HOUSE: Makes sense.
Park's tiger mom and
dad were so insufferable,
she has to measure
their affection in hours.
Chase's careerist dad and
alcoholic mom were so indifferent,
he has to believe it's a wash.
Your turn.
What did your
screwed-up parents do
to screw up your
view of parenting?
They were good parents.
That's an oxymoron.
Chase is right, all parents
screw up all children.
He's also dreamy, but
it's not relevant now.
So all parents
screw up all children,
but it makes some
huge difference
if I keep my daughter
here or let her move?
Endocarditis, flipped a piece
of vegetation into his brain,
which could've broken
up before the angiogram.
Transesophageal echo to confirm.
And screwed up is her best-case.
Bouncing between a
philandering, workaholic dad
and an embittered,
sexually-betrayed mom,
it's gonna lead to
screwed-up squared.
Is endocarditis treatable?
Very.
The echo will show us any
growths on his heart valve.
Most likely meds'll be enough,
he won't even need surgery.
He's just taken up performing,
and it's very stressful for him.
Could that have caused this?
It's not stressful, I have fun.
Stress wouldn't be relevant.
But anything that increases his
adrenaline could have made it worse.
Maybe we find you a new
hobby. One you're a little better at.
I'm gonna get better at
it, and it's not a hobby.
I think I want to
get a job working
as a circus clown,
making people laugh.
Ben, I don't think
that's a good idea.
It was good enough for my dad.
You were a...
His biological father.
Could his dad's
melanoma be a factor here?
That wouldn't be related.
Ben, you barely knew him.
You're such a smart kid,
you could aim a lot higher than
face paint and seltzer bottles.
I need treatment for
my Type 2 diabetes.
There is absolutely no part
of that sentence that is true.
I've been experiencing weight
gain, fatigue and sluggishness.
Weight loss is a
symptom of diabetes.
Fatigue is a symptom
of thinking you
have a disease you
don't actually have.
And sluggishness is
a synonym of fatigue.
I need insulin. I know it.
Much as I'd like to kill you by
dangerously lowering your blood sugar,
murder violates my parole.
That blood work is
weeks old. Test me again.
I am the test. The
test is negative.
The test also thinks you're
a giant pain in the ass.
That last insult was
your cue to leave.
Test me.
Fine. Wait right here.
Thank you.
Sleep study. Please
make sure he's
not disturbed for
the next eight hours.
We need to talk
about Saturday night.
No, no, no, no, no.
Historians will talk of
Saturday night, not us.
The legendary night on which we
watch Santos shatter Rubio's jaw
and you epically pay me $50.
I have a chance
to really watch it.
A patient of mine has a
pair of tickets he can't use.
And obviously you're under
house and office arrest,
I just wanted to make
sure you were cool
if I go to Atlantic
City without you.
No, thanks.
I'm afraid I'm gonna have
to decline your invitation
to not spend Saturday
night with you.
These are ringside seats.
Cameras are ringside, too.
If you want, I
could sweat and spit
and bleed on you
from time to time.
I'd take you if I could.
Well, I'd take me
if either of us could.
See what a tough spot I'm in?
I'm going to that fight.
All right, I'll take
the other ticket.
Let me worry about logistics.
Patient's heart valves are
normal. It's not endocarditis.
But he has a thickened
pericardium, which makes no sense.
He has a heart problem, but not
one that could've caused his TIA.
Syphilitic vasculitis
would explain the TIA
and the pericardial
inflammation.
Syph test was negative. Plus,
the kid's never been sexually active.
Yeah, I got that from the line on
his chart that says "birthday clown".
His late father
was a circus clown.
Histoplasmosis.
He's not immunocompromised.
And I assume you
added that irrelevant tidbit
because you're moved
by the son's idiotic tribute,
and think it justifies keeping
your daughter in New Jersey.
But what if he has a
heightened immune system.
I mentioned it because...
Take your time. We'll
continue with medicine.
Sjögren's could've
given him chronic
pericarditis and
cerebral arteritis.
Sjögren's it is. IV
immunosuppressants to treat.
Anything?
This'll calm your immune system.
You should be out of
here within the week.
My mom'll be happy to hear that.
I've got an internship
that starts in three weeks.
I take it it's not at a
place with a big top.
It's in my stepdad's law office.
I know I'm not any good
at being a clown yet,
but when I do get a laugh,
see those kids' eyes light up,
that's how my dad made
me feel when I was a kid.
You need to hang onto that.
My mom says he
was a loving father,
but always broke and
always on the road.
It's a stupid way
to make a living.
You're 16. Plenty of
time to make money.
Wanting to build a
connection with your dad,
pass on some of the
joy that he gave you,
that's not stupid at all.
I got it.
Is this because of the
medication? Is it normal?
It's not normal, and
it's not Sjögren's.
TIA, thickened
pericardium, and now
he's bleeding from
his nose and mouth.
What are you doing with her?
"Her"?
Surely this little bundle
of fun has an actual name.
It's Sophie.
Both your kids are named...
She's Sophie. The
other one's Sophia.
It's different enough.
They actually have two
completely different derivations.
No, they don't.
I wasn't in a strong negotiating
position. Why is she here?
Ruby dropped her off.
Seemed pretty upset.
Apparently someone forgot
that it was Daddy's night.
She wasn't even gonna leave her
till I said that I was
letting you off early.
Damn it. I just started back on
the team. My schedule's a mess.
If your own kids are
a scheduling item,
maybe you should
let one of them move.
Patient has low platelets,
makes me think DIC.
She doesn't seem
to like that idea.
You're right. No
schistocytes in his smear.
He also has a low red count.
What if it's a retroperitoneal bleed?
No Grey-Turner's sign.
She wasn't fussy like that
when I was holding her.
Maybe she likes the
sound of my voice.
Which is weird because I have
no genetic connection to her.
Could it be she doesn't
know the difference?
So many children of your own,
no wonder you
have such insight into
my relationship with my babies.
Good point. How could I
comprehend that you're too despised
to keep them from
having the same name,
too overwhelmed to
remember your own calendar,
and too vain to admit
that at this stage,
you don't matter to either baby?
Low white count
suggests infection.
What if you're all right? Low
platelets, plus low red count,
plus low white count equals...
Aplastic anemia.
Kid needs a bone
marrow transplant.
Everyone except Adams transfuse
his platelets till
you find a match.
You started college
a semester late
because you left high
school a semester late
because you had five
incompletes in your junior year.
And you're offering
one bad semester
as proof that my
parents screwed me up?
Did okay before that,
straight A's after that.
I went through a
rebellious phase.
Don't tell me. Mom and Dad
were at each other's throats,
and the academic
crisis was a cry for help.
Sorry to mess with your world
view, but I'm not messed up.
So my parents couldn't
have messed me up.
Mom's HLA is only a 3/6 match.
Maternal grandmother's
worse than that.
Where'd you unload the baby?
Maternity ward. Shut up.
You realize you're making
House's argument for him.
The part where he said any
parent who uses day care
should ship their child
across the country?
No, the part where he said
that baby doesn't need you.
You've only got her
a couple days a week,
and most of that's spent
with a rotating cast of nurses...
That's how Daddy likes
to spend his time, too.
Shut up. First
cousin's also a whiff.
So much for genetics mattering.
I'll try the marrow registry.
Dr. Park is
searching the registry.
Transfusing his platelets will
keep him healthy while we wait.
You sure there's no one on
the father's side of the family?
If one of them's a match,
that'd speed things up a lot.
His parents died young,
he was an only child.
There's no living
relatives that I know of.
Something will turn up soon.
How soon is soon? Will
he miss a lot of school?
I'm actually thinking
of just getting my GED.
How do you expect to
get into a good college?
I'm gonna take classes on magic,
juggling, try to make a go of this.
Ben, you keep your grades up,
you can do anything in the world.
Like what? Work in
some boring office?
Do you think my father would
have done that for 10 minutes?
You don't remember your
father. You don't know...
I want to build a
connection with him.
Pass on some of the
joy that he gave me.
My...
My back hurts.
His BP's dropping.
We think we've dealt
with all the liability issues.
I'm in a meeting.
Sorry. Since you paged me, I
didn't want to keep you waiting.
Yeah. I paged you,
which means you're next.
That's cool. I'll wait.
That's a good start. Let's
go through it point by point.
First up...
I'll call you back.
Just got this.
The American Association
of Rheumatology
wants you to speak, 9:00,
Saturday, in Atlantic City.
Dr. Neusinger canceled
on them at the last minute.
I hate conferences.
Well, this is a big one.
And it's the premium slot.
I'd like you to do it.
I'll clear it with
your parole officer.
What do I need to do for you?
Halve the clinic hours
that you recently doubled,
and double the hooker
budget that you recently halved.
I think you refer
to it as petty cash.
Fine.
Just one thing. I'm gonna ask
them to put you on in the morning.
We're doing them a favor. Why
should you have to spend the night?
But you said that 9:00
was the premium slot.
I want to feel like I've
earned my hookers.
The place'll be a madhouse.
Especially since it's 2 miles from
the Rubio fight, at the exact same time.
Nice try. You called up, pretended
to be Neusinger, canceled,
then suggested yourself
as a replacement.
You go to that fight,
you go to prison.
Well, that'd be redundant
when I have an angry black guy
waiting for me to drop the soap right here.
Better go do some of those
clinic hours I recently doubled.
Test my urine.
Looks like I was wrong
about my diagnosis.
Yeah. I have diabetes.
No. But you're not
a hypochondriac.
Or you'd have imagined
some new disease
after I shot down the first one.
So whose urine is that? Diabetic
girlfriend without health insurance?
It's not a scam, I'm sick.
Now I have swollen ankles.
The medical term is cankles.
Is there some black market in
insulin that I don't know about?
It's in my genes.
My old man got diabetes at 50, my older
brother got it at 50, I just turned 50.
Well, that's a great argument
if diabetes was a gold watch.
I've got sciatica like my dad,
class-four hemorrhoids like him.
I need to get a
jump on this thing.
We had to stop the transfusion.
Patient's having an allergic
reaction to donor platelets.
No one in Mom's
family's a match,
and as far as she knows,
Dad has no living relatives.
It's been years since he died.
If the kid's dad died
young of melanoma,
how come the overprotective mom
never took him to
a dermatologist?
Are you gonna test
my urine, or what?
Not diabetes.
Use crossmatched platelets,
try to find the patient some
blood that's closer to his own.
And get the real story
on clown senior's death.
Mom's hiding something.
There's a good bet that
it's medically relevant.
Apple juice. Easiest way to
fake a spike in blood sugar.
His family history of melanoma
may have affected his cellular outlook.
If we had more detail on the exact
type of melanoma his father had...
Otherwise we might not be
able to find a marrow match.
He never had melanoma.
How did he die?
He didn't.
He lives in Pennsauken, under a
different name. Mitchell Gordon.
How could you keep
this from me? From Ben?
He really needs to know his dad
just breezed in
and out of his life,
drunk and incoherent?
It's better to think the
man's dead but decent.
You realize I have to invite
someone else to the Rubio fight.
Nope. No realization whatsoever.
You have a LoJack on your leg.
I was happy watching
the fight on pay-per-view.
You're the one who
insisted we go to Atlantic City.
Your biological father was a
decent, God-fearing minister,
the guy who raised you
was a cold-hearted jerk.
I'm trying to figure out
why you're so convinced
Adams has
parentally-inflicted damage.
You're trying to deflect.
Now you are.
You have to believe that every
parent screws up every child,
or you were screwed
out of a decent childhood.
My decent
daddy-of-the-cloth was also
being indecent with
my married mom.
He probably would've taken
other kids to the playground.
Not my fault, bad parenting.
Mitchell Gordon?
I've already got a
religion. Go away.
We're doctors.
Your son Ben is in the hospital,
at Princeton-Plainsboro.
He's very sick.
Yeah, well, I don't have
a son. Not anymore.
We know there are
some issues there,
but your bone
marrow could cure him.
There's a hospital 2 miles
from here. It's a simple test...
You said he was at
Princeton-Plainsboro.
His mother feels it's better to
do the tests at a different hospital.
Like I said, I don't
have a son anymore.
House isn't gonna give up.
Just tell him about your parents.
Or make up a lie.
I don't want to lie.
And I don't want to
validate his ridiculous theory.
It's not ridiculous. Even
the best-intentioned
parents end up
damaging their kids.
You're a smart,
successful doctor.
How much damage could you have?
Know how I got
interested in medicine?
When my mother drank,
she couldn't handle me,
so she locked me
in my father's study.
Only so many hours you
can cry and bang on the door
before you give up,
find something to read.
We all have family dysfunction.
That's why we're successful.
To fill that hole.
My parents have a lot of money.
But they didn't make it legally.
White-collar crime?
Started with card
games, high-stakes poker.
Then my dad got into narcotics.
At first just selling,
but then using, too.
Or he never would've
gotten into the slave trade.
Children mostly.
Easier to pack in small crates.
Plus the shipping's
a lot cheaper...
Won't even trust a co-worker.
What did your parents do to you?
You have to go see him yourself.
He wouldn't even come
to the door a second time.
Okay. I'll drive over there.
It's a pleural effusion.
He had a bleeding
problem earlier,
must be bleeding into his lungs.
Except there's no blood.
What does that mean?
Means you don't have
to make that drive.
The problem isn't his
marrow, it's his liver.
Liver failure
explains everything.
Question is, what
explains the liver failure?
It's not an infection. We tried
antibiotics, but he's not responding.
More curiously, what
explains the mom lying
about Dad pushing
up squirting daisies?
This is how you plan to
get to that boxing game?
Why are you looking at her?
Because I'm stunned
and I have to look at something.
Match, bout, fight,
contest, day, Helena.
Almost anything works after
boxing except the word game.
Your bigger
problem is the people
who design those
things aren't idiots.
Can you believe she
used to work in the can?
Nothing is tamper-proof.
It's a synthetic problem.
His liver's not
synthesizing proteins,
so fluid is leaking out
of his blood vessels.
And Mom's a selfish jerk.
She traded up, married a lawyer,
wants to forget the
lowly circus clown.
You're defending the father
because you feel like a jerk for
baking buns in two different ovens.
You want to believe
the mythical biological
connection excuses
being a man-slut... Ow!
I don't know why I'm starting
to doubt your expertise.
You do have a classified
ad and a piece of metal.
It's temperature that
sets it off, not force.
The rivets go pop, I slide in
the heating pad. Easy peasy.
More likely the patient has
a hyperammonemic problem.
His liver's not
cleaning out his blood,
the buildup of toxins
is causing everything.
I'm defending the dad
because he got screwed.
After he lost his
son, he lost his job,
been in and out of
rehab, gave up clowning.
Yes, as a parent, I empathize.
I say we tell the kid.
He's a minor, the
mom's his guardian,
and it's not even
medically relevant.
She robbed them
of 12 years together.
Or she ripped off
the Band-Aid too late.
That memory she let
Son of Bozo establish
is making him chase his
father's moronic profession.
When he could be living
the high life in Portland.
And I mean that
metaphorically, of course.
This is where you dazzle
me with your contingency plan.
I see why employers are
reluctant to hire ex-cons.
Well, what about the patient?
Is the problem
hyperammonemic or synthetic?
Can't treat for both.
One requires hemodialysis,
the other a liver transplant
and we couldn't even get
the kid a marrow match.
Get the mom's consent
to pump him full of protein.
If it's a synthetic
problem, more fluid
will leak into his chest
and his heart will fail.
If it's hyperammonemic,
toxins will
overwhelm his body
and he'll go into a coma.
Do you only like tests that
involve the risk of death?
There are some slower, less
conclusive tests, but why take that risk?
In here.
Oh, my God. The water.
This is completely my fault.
There are very serious risks,
but if we don't figure out what
he has, we can't treat him at all.
I may be a little
out of bounds here,
but in case there
are complications,
might be a good time to
come clean to your son.
Let his father visit.
A little out of bounds?
I don't know the history, but
everyone makes mistakes.
Your son worships him.
The doctor's right about that.
Yeah?
And when did he learn that?
When he encouraged
Ben to drop out of school?
Mitchell is not Ben's father any more
than a sperm donor would've been.
Dr. House?
Unless you're a
locksmith or an electrician
with political
contacts, I'm busy.
My husband saw you in the
clinic. Wants treatment for diabetes.
My condolences on
your forthcoming divorce.
He keeps imagining symptoms,
and now I have to make him
these awful anti-diabetic meals.
Since I have no
intention of testing him,
treating him, or
cooking for him...
Could you write me a
fake prescription for insulin?
The advantage of
fake prescriptions
is you don't have to be
a real doctor to write one.
Just tell me what's
safe to inject in his thigh.
His symptoms will go away and
then I can show him he was never sick.
Water?
Imaginary medicine's
not my specialty.
I do have an imaginary colleague
who's just sent me
an imaginary page.
Imagine how sorry I am.
Still mad about what
happened in the lab?
I'm not mad, I'm
being professional.
You claim you're not screwed
up, you may even believe it,
but House doesn't, and I don't.
So you can wait till he camps
out on your parents' lawn,
or you can admit you don't live
on some higher plane
and thank me later.
My... My eye feels weird.
What's happening to me?
You look tired.
I hate when people say
that. I know, I look bad.
I thought you were gonna
go to bed early last night.
Like an idiot, I went out with my
girlfriends to pretend I have a life.
When all I did
was flirt with guys
who'd have no interest in a mom,
and miss the baby I
couldn't wait to get rid of,
and then get yelled at by my
mom for staying out too late.
You need your own place. Yes.
I moved back home because it
was too drafty at the Four Seasons.
So go back to
work at the hospital.
Day care costs more than
what I earned as a nurse.
Have you considered
sub-standard day care?
Why don't you stay here tonight?
No, I mean in the guest room.
I'll watch the baby again,
you can get a real night's sleep.
You'd do that?
Win-win.
Mommy gets a rest, Daddy
gets more time with his little angel.
There's some sweats
in the closet in the back.
Lucky girl, gets another
sleepover with Dada.
Makes a difference,
doesn't it?
Didn't answer
your page last night.
Sorry, battery died.
We got the patient's eye back
in place with steroid injections.
But a bulging eyeball
means it's not a liver problem.
And Mom's determination
to keep Dad away,
even as her kid gets sicker and
sicker, means she's got more to hide.
It's not diagnostically
relevant, let's let it drop.
You just lost my vote. You
flip-flopped on parental rights.
I've been trying to
persuade the mother,
but it's her son,
so it's her call.
Well, that's very
evolved of you.
You don't usually see
Darwinian changes over breakfast.
You made nice-nice with Phil.
You decided that he'd make a
decent father for Thing Two after all.
I had Sophie again last night,
and Ruby slept in my guest room.
Which has nothing
to do with Phil,
who will never be a
father to my children.
Angioneurotic edema
can cause rapid swelling.
Hey, we're having
a conversation here.
No abdominal pain.
So that must've been nice having
Ruby and the baby
under one roof.
Yes, it was nice having
my daughter in my home.
That's why I would like her
sister to live near my home.
Anasarca?
Swelling would
have followed gravity.
Isn't that getting this whole
parenting thing ass backwards?
Aren't you supposed
to figure out
what you can sacrifice to
maximize their niceness?
And do you think I should
sacrifice myself from their lives?
Just one life. Until the other one's
mommy meets someone nicer than you.
Swelling that fast and localized
has to come from
the lymph nodes.
Burkitt's lymphoma.
Swelling.
Cankles.
That's not a symptom of
Burkitt's. Are you saying...
It's Burkitt's. Prep
him for chemo.
I think you should give House
permission to go to Atlantic City.
We'll stop by the rheumatology
conference. Everyone's covered.
No.
The guy has earned the
right to go to one boxing match.
He's done everything
you've asked.
Funded and staffed
his own department,
hasn't even broken
as much as a traffic law.
You're right.
So you'll let him go?
No.
I get why he wants to go to
that fight. I'd love to go myself.
Which is kind of why
I have to stop him.
My job is to be the jerk.
House has to believe that
I have authority over him.
He can't function
under someone's thumb.
I know. Which means
you can't go either.
Your job is to be his friend.
To stay here and sit with him
and watch the fight on pay-per-view
while bitching about me.
If we both do our jobs, we might
actually get him
through his parole.
You're right.
Sorry to show up like this.
I was expecting a
battery of lawyers.
No lawyers.
Phil had something
that he would like to say.
So I thought that he
should say it in person.
It was wrong of
me to confront you
about taking Rachel to Portland.
You don't want to
move to Portland?
Of course I do.
But this is about
your daughter, too,
and I'm not gonna do something
like this without your support.
So, you guys are trying to manipulate
me by playing good cop/good cop?
Is that how little
you think of me?
It's clear you're back
working for House.
I will see you this weekend
when you pick up Sophie.
Sophia.
We actually started
calling her Sophie.
Yeah.
Great.
It's cute.
Cankles.
Is there some problem with
the prescription you gave me?
I'm faint, I've been gaining more
weight. I think I need a bigger dose.
If you double his
placebo, he might drown.
Also, you forgot to mention
that your heart rate is slow.
My heart rate's not...
52?
The technical term is slow.
Those awful anti-diabetic meals
you eat, do they contain bok choy?
A pound of it. Every day.
Bok choy has glucosinolates,
which inhibit thyroid function
and account for all your symptoms.
So, this isn't diabetes?
You have a bad case of irony.
The food that you're eating to stop
making you sick is making you sick.
Maybe I don't have my
father's crummy genes after all.
On the other hand, maybe you're
fat enough to get
diabetes even without him.
I can't believe I have cancer.
We caught it early.
You should be okay.
I could die. I never went
anywhere, did anything.
If my father had lived, everything
would have been different.
Your mom and stepdad love you,
they've given you a great home.
That counts for a lot.
He's crashing,
everything's shutting down.
Renal failure, lung failure, heart
failure, all before we started chemo.
Burkitt's lymphoma is
fast-moving, but not this fast.
No rush. ICU stands for
"take your time" in Latin.
Multiple aneurysms.
That would mean every symptom
after his TIA was a coincidence.
Cholesterol emboli.
Bingo! Fits perfectly.
Check the file, confirm that we
did major abdominal surgery on him,
and then completely
forgot about it.
House.
Hello.
What the hell are
you doing here?
I was told this might be my
last chance to see my son.
You had no right. This
is none of your business!
I didn't... I called him.
This man is Ben's hero. Let
them spend five minutes together.
No. You get out of here!
Wait.
You sexually molested your son.
Your walk, tabes dorsalis.
You have late-stage syphilis.
Which you gave to our patient,
presumably 12 years ago.
Which also explains why Mom
is not big on family reunions.
I shouldn't be here.
We tested him for
syphilis, he was negative.
After 12 years, the active
infection would have died down
everywhere except
the arteries in his brain,
where it could hide
out from our tests.
When that six-year-old heckler
punched him in his juggling pins,
it kicked up the dormant
bacteria in his pelvis.
The immunosuppressants we
gave him sent it into overdrive.
The antibiotics we gave him
actually started destroying the syphilis.
But like pouring
water on a fire,
led to a trail of
toxic smoke and ash,
which made his immune
system overcompensate.
Severe
Jarisch-Herxheimer reaction.
Is this true? HOUSE: Yes.
Jarisch-Herxheimer is
real. It sounds silly but...
You mean the... Right.
I found stains on his clothes.
He didn't understand and
he didn't seem traumatized.
I kept trying to talk to him,
but before long, he'd forgotten.
And he seemed...
He seemed happy,
and he seemed normal.
So you made Daddy
go away, and you made
sure Junior had no
reason to go looking.
I was just trying
to protect him,
like I should have
done from the start.
I'm sorry.
IV penicillin and anti-TNF
antibodies, he'll be fine.
Apart from the whole
daddy-rape thing.
We're not done.
No, we are not.
Notify the dad's sexual
partners, notify his employer,
his landlord, notify the police.
I meant the kid. We're not
gonna tell him he was molested?
To make him miserable,
or to forfeit your license?
To tell him the truth.
He's a virgin, how
do I explain the STD?
It's a medical diagnosis. Screw
the parents, the kid's our patient.
I guess Taub's got a tough choice
to make when the kid wakes up.
Why is it my choice?
Because you're a dad.
How could the rest of
us possibly understand?
What was wrong with me?
It's called syphilis.
Uh...
You can get that
without having sex?
I didn't tell him.
Your heart said
he needed to know,
your brain knew he's
better off without it.
Following your heart is easy.
Following your brain is tough.
Especially after
years of following
that much smaller, third organ.
That's why all parents
screw up all children.
Evening.
Clever tactic, pretending
you're not interested anymore.
How could that
possibly work as a tactic?
The fact is, once I
saw those incompletes,
I knew your parents
screwed you up.
The details are just gravy.
You're wrong.
The only evidence you have
is proof of something else.
I ran away from home.
Because you had lousy parents.
Because I didn't.
All my friends' parents were
divorced, or having affairs,
or barely knew
their kids' birthdays.
You envied their dysfunction?
I thought it made
them deeper somehow.
It was stupid.
I hitchhiked to Manhattan,
moved in with an older guy.
In two months I
came running home.
Took my parents
years to get over it.
That's when you started to excel.
You were making it up to them.
Your parents screwed you
up by not screwing you up.
How does briefly wishing I was
screwed up make me screwed up?
It's normal to be screwed up. It's
really screwed up to romanticize it.
Guess that's why you
wanted to work with prisoners.
It's why I wanted
to work with you.
It was a tactic.
Chris. Yeah.
I need to talk to you and Phil.
Is everything okay?
Yeah.
I can't let you move.
You drove all the
way out here just
to tell us what you
already told us?
I'm sorry.
House, open up. I don't
want to miss the opening bell.
House?
Telecast, and we expect an
electric atmosphere in the arena
and a sell-out crowd of about
10,000 for Rubio vs. Santos.
Two great fighters
with illustrious careers
might have been expected
to meet a long time ago.
As for Santos,
his handlers tell us
that he's done more roadwork
than at any time in his career,
hoping to prove tonight that
he can box for 12 full rounds.
Significant, because
Santos hasn't heard
the final bell in
more than six years.
He comes in with 11
straight knockout wins.
He saw how a
power-puncher with a left hook
was able to cut Rubio
over the right eye
in the 10th round
of that last fight.