As surgeons, we are
our brother's keepers.
Ride or die. Womb to tomb.
We see each other's fears. We see
the white-knuckled panic of failure.
We see ourselves.
And who the hell
likes looking at that?
Alex, we should... get
going. That's the wrong tie.
Well, it's not gonna matter
what tie I'm wearing when...
Did I tell you I have
a thymectomy today?
Patient has myasthenia
without a thymoma.
So, I'm thinking I can get
away with a partial sternotomy.
So, we're avoiding what's
actually gonna happen today.
We're discussing medicine.
We're doing our rounds.
Surgery and work. That's what's
going to get us through today.
I don't spy on my co-workers.
I'm not asking you
to spy on co-workers!
No, you're asking
me to be your mole.
I'm asking you to
keep this hospital safe.
This Karev-DeLuca
thing is a mess.
I have an attending who
posted bail for another attending,
an intern pressing charges,
people are taking sides.
I'm trying to hold this down, but I
need someone to be my eyes and ears.
Baby, baby, I am just starting
to get my reputation back.
- Just my eyes and ears.
- No!
When Webber was chief,
I was his eyes and ears.
Okay, but Chief, Chief. You
can have my whole body.
- Don't be nasty.
- But not my eyes and ears.
I'm not your mole.
You're right.
I know. What am I
right about this time?
You need eyes and
ears. I can be your mole.
Won't work. People shut
up when you're around.
If they know I'm around, okay.
Have you heard of
Hercules Mulligan?
He was a great Revolutionary
War spy, helped defeat the British.
No one saw him coming or going.
I know who Hercules Mulligan
was, and you're no Hercul...
Well, damn.
Dr. Neil...
he's fine. I just
want to make sure...
Hey! I thought you had
Alex's thing this morning.
Ahh, we do. We are keeping
our heads up. We are working.
- It happened again last night.
- Again?
Riggs walked me to my
car and we said good night,
and then he took
me in the parking lot...
over and over again.
That's the third time this week.
Mer, these dreams
are really hot.
In the parking lot? No.
- I should ask him out.
Here you go, Doctor.
- Thanks.
- I know. I'm his boss.
What if I ask him
and he says no,
or comes off like some
gross sexual harassment?
Which is the only kind
of sexual harassment.
But what if I don't ask him?
Am I just gonna wait
around for my life to happen?
Just wait for my big
love? You've had yours.
Amelia has hers. I want mine.
So I am acting like a grown-ass
woman and I am asking him out?
- Was that a question mark?
- No.
Unless you think that it
should be a question mark.
This is happening. I'm doing
this. This is definitely happening.
Good talk.
And the wedding photographer
wants us to pick our favorites.
From five hundred
proofs? We have jobs.
- We are very, very busy.
- So busy, all the time.
Oh.
Hey. Morning. Morning, Riggs.
Hey, guys. I almost forgot. You
want me to bring anything tonight?
I make a whitebait fritter
that's out of this world.
- You invited Riggs to our house?
- Well, we have a new home!
We're supposed to have friends
and family over to warm it up. Right?
Hey, this is a housewarming?
Who else did you invite?
You two were so happy at the
wedding and you were so close once.
That was a long time ago. You
should have checked with me first.
Sorry. You're right. I meant to.
You were never gonna
check with me, were you?
- Probably not.
- Hmm.
- Dr. Shepherd. How's it going?
- I suck at marriage.
I'm sorry. I need a favor. Can you
take Wilson on your service today?
No, I have Warren. And he's
already familiar with my Wilma case.
You know how
gnarly she's gonna be.
But if you put Wilson on your service,
she doesn't have to work with Karev.
I see you've picked a side.
I'm on the side of we all want
to punch interns, but we resist.
So Wilson gets neuro. What do
you get out of it? A surgery? What?
Nothing. Just trying to be a
good friend. That's all. Please.
- I'll take Wilson.
- Thank you.
Oh, and can you take pictures
of Wilma? I want neuro porn.
Dr. Horowitz...
Dr. Karev, this is
Zach Thompson.
Six months post-renal transplant,
complaining of abdominal pain.
I know the history.
- Dr. Alex.
- Hey, buddy.
Hey, Reena. Didn't want
to see you guys here again.
Yeah.
- When did the pain start?
- This morning.
It came on kind of
gradually. I got scared.
His kidney is so
new, and I worry.
- Ow!
- Sorry, bud.
No, I'm fine.
Don't make me
give my kidney back.
Look, I'm gonna
have to run a few tests,
and I need you to be brave.
But remember what we say?
No matter how bad it
gets, no matter how scary...
- Nothing's as bad as broccoli.
Here's our girl!
Hi, sweetie! Gimme,
gimme, gimme, gimme.
Harriet is gaining
weight right on schedule.
- She's healthy and fat.
- Fat baby.
Fat baby. And healthy
enough to go home today.
Yeah?
Are you sure she's ready?
What about her
respirations? I thought I saw...
Kepner, you can
take your kid home.
Yeah, I know.
- Look, I gotta go.
- Oh, that's today.
- Congrats on the fat baby.
- Okay. Yeah, thanks.
- Why the face? This is a good thing.
- Not for me.
- Babe...
- My incision opened back up.
They want to do wound therapy.
Harriet's going
home. But I'm not.
So... they're just
charging you today. I know.
It'll probably be a
misdemeanor with probation.
I know, Mer.
Is the State ready to charge?
We are, Your Honor. We're seeking
felony assault in the second degree.
- Felony? This must be a mistake.
- It's not, Your Honor.
- What the hell? I thought...
- The State is pulling this
- at the last minute.
- It's prosecutorial discretion.
- It's overreaching.
- It's not, Your Honor.
- This is
a misdemeanor case.
- Tell that to the victim,
seated here in the courtroom.
A first-year surgical intern
who almost lost his
career when the defendant,
his professional superior, his
teacher, was unable to mask his rage.
This act was a felony.
The State and Dr. DeLuca
want appropriate justice here.
You want to argue
this now? Fine.
The defendant is a pediatric
surgeon with no priors. He...
We're not at trial. We're here
to enter a plea to the charge
and the charge is felony
assault in the second degree.
How do you plead, Dr. Karev?
You have to answer.
Not guilty.
- It's just a charge.
- Yeah, a felony charge.
But you haven't been
convicted of anything. Alex...
Every single one.
Every guy I grew up with
Is either where I left them,
dead or in prison.
I thought I was special
'cause I went to med school.
Guess you can't
wash the stink off trash.
You're not trash. You're a surgeon.
And you are not going to prison.
- You don't know that.
- You are not going to prison.
Do you know the charge?
Yes.
The DA subpoenaed DeLuca's
medical records and your personnel file.
- What now?
What now?
People come to this hospital
so that we can help them.
Do you know how many problems
I have to deal with already?
Who gets the expensive,
experimental drug,
whose body deserves
the organ transplant,
which parent is
ready to hear that,
yes, your toddler is
dead, but here is a bill
for a quarter million
dollars anyway.
Problems! Real problems, Karev!
Yet, somehow, you are
now problem number one.
A pediatric surgeon walking around
this hospital with an assault charge.
Do you realize what happens
if you're convicted of a felony?
Yes, Dr. Bailey. I realize.
Do you have a decent
lawyer? Do you need help or...
Are we done?
DeLuca's starting back today.
Is there gonna be a problem?
Not from me.
Then we're done.
When you get home
just put her in the little yellow
onesie with the frogs on it.
That was her... "going home
from the hospital onesie".
I know. I'll take pictures.
- Hey.
- She's going home without me.
Yeah. And what did
we just say about that?
The important thing is that
she's healthy and I'm healthy.
Exactly.
Is crap! She's
supposed to be with me.
Bonding and
attaching or whatever.
Smelling me like birds and dogs.
- Birds and dogs?
- Shut up. It's nature.
How is she gonna attach to me
when she's there and I'm here?
- You're gonna be
discharged soon.
- And then what?
I'm still gonna be in recovery.
You know the ins and
outs of post-op incisions.
I'm not even gonna
be able to pick her up...
Without help. I'm gonna have to hire
someone to come and take care of her.
Some... mama bird
who smells good
and bonds with my baby
while I just lie there and watch.
You know what? You should go.
I'm not going anywhere
when you're this upset.
You have to because
I'm not gonna stop.
I'm just gonna
die of dehydration.
- It's gonna be all right, you know.
- - Get out!
Okay.
Dr. Karev, I've got Zach's labs.
His CRP is a little
elevated, but...
- Dr. Karev?
- What?
Just didn't know
if you heard me.
Just tell me what the CT showed.
Well, his kidney looks good.
But he's showing
signs of appendicitis.
What?
Appendicitis? So he
needs another surgery?
I want to avoid that.
The immunosuppressants he's
on because of the transplant,
put him at greater risk
for post-op infections.
I want to start him on
broad spectrum antibiotics,
- see if it clears up on its own.
- Okay.
I'll be by to check
on him every hour.
- Thank you.
- Which means you and I
are gonna be
here hanging out all day.
I bet I can score a video
game for your room. Deal?
Deal.
So, how's Alex holding up?
He's working. I'm working.
We're focused on medicine.
Right. Yes. Good. We should
all... focus on medicine. Lap pads.
Just... How should I ask
Riggs out? Is there a way to do it
so that the boss
thing isn't a thing?
Oh, you actually meant that.
You're gonna ask Riggs out?
Grey, what are
you doing tonight?
- Nothing.
- Amelia invited Riggs to dinner
at our house. She's trying to
make us, I don't know, friends again.
I need you to come over and
talk to him so I don't have to.
I'm busy.
Come on. You guys
got along at the wedding.
- It was a wedding. I had tequila.
- You need a buffer?
I can. I'm a great buffer.
- You're free?
- Tonight's perfect. What time?
- Eight-ish?
- Awesome, I'll be there.
- We'll see you at eight.
- Yeah.
- Hey, you changed your mind.
- If you're going, I'll go.
Dr. Shepherd. I just want to say
thank you for letting
me work on service.
- I know that you...
- Stop thanking. We got work to do.
- Wilma is waiting.
- Wilma?
- Nasty, annoying Wilma.
- It says
here Patricia.
- Hello. So, how we doing?
- I'm fine.
- It's not Wilma.
- So, you know the drill.
We are going to draw a few
more labs, do a pre-op CT,
- and tomorrow,
it is all about Wilma.
- Patricia. Patricia.
Oh, she's talking
about the tumor, dear.
I'm Patricia. The
tumor is Wilma.
She named her tumor after
her ex-husband's mistress.
Wilma, because they're both
parasitic mounds of unwanted flesh.
And tomorrow, we
are kicking Wilma's ass.
Yeah, that bitch is going down.
Wilson, meet Wilma.
Tomorrow, we beat
the crap out of this bitch.
Come on. Show some enthusiasm.
I'm enthusiastic. It's just that the
tumor is a woman named Wilma.
- So?
- And you're excited to kick
Wilma's ass and beat
the crap out of Wilma.
And it's cute when it's
the name of a tumor.
It's that when it's the
name of a woman, if...
It's what?
It's nothing. It's nothing.
The Karev thing. I'm an idiot.
Here I am, saying
all these violent things
- after what you've been through.
- What I've been through?
Witnessing Karev attack DeLuca.
I'm sorry. I'm bringing
up bad memories.
You must think I
am the worst person.
It's... It's okay. I'm fine.
Are you?
I... don't have
any place to live.
And the entire hospital
won't stop whispering
about the scarlet
letter on my chest.
So it just feels like I'm
trapped in a glass box
and everyone's on the outside
watching while I run out of air.
But, yeah, it's... I'm great.
Okay... I'm having a housewarming
party, and you are coming.
You need a break from your life.
Alex will not be there. I just
picked a side, and I'm on yours.
- It's been quite a day.
- Dr. Webber!
There have been rumblings
about some sort of turf war
over who gets control of Dr. Torres'
ortho lab now that she's gone.
Oh, and, the doctors at the
Duquette Clinic, they feel overworked.
At the clinic? That's not news.
You know what's news?
Karev was charged with a felony.
Hm... I did not hear that.
First day back?
Mm-hmm.
- How is it?
- It's fine.
DeLuca, I know I don't
know you very well,
but you know I was attacked.
I remember.
I didn't want to forgive
the guy who attacked me.
But I did because I needed to.
The guy who attacked
you was in a fugue state.
Dr. Karev knew
what he was doing.
Have you ever made a horrible
mistake because you overreacted
or you just... had the
wrong information?
Dr. Karev is genuinely sorry
and would like to tell you himself.
Yeah, well, I'm...
I'm not ready for that.
Okay.
Just, you are an intern, and...
you shouldn't be spending
your time in a courtroom.
You should be
scrubbing in on surgeries.
This job is hard enough. You just
don't need to make it any harder.
Look, we shouldn't
talk about the case.
Okay, okay. I'm...
Look, I know you can
keep me out of the OR,
you can end my career, you
can ruin my life if you want to.
- I'm not trying
to ruin your life.
- You don't get to.
You think because you're an
attending and Dr. Karev's an attending,
you can threaten me?
I don't care. It's
not gonna work.
Okay, so, this is bad.
Well, save it,
'cause I don't need it.
I think I might have
just threatened DeLuca.
What? What?
- I was trying to help.
- What?
- I didn't mean it.
- What did you... Why would you...
- What exactly did you say?
- He twisted my words.
I just got charged with a
felony today. This is my life, Mer.
Dr. Karev. I was just looking at
Zach's latest absolute neutrophil count...
I saw it. It's fine.
- His heart rate's inching up...
- I've had him for three years.
His heart rate rises every time
he comes here. He's a nervous kid.
- But this looks...
- I looked at it! I saw the labs!
- I did my job, now do yours.
- I'll keep you posted.
Crap. You think DeLuca's
gonna say anything?
- I don't know.
- Yeah, he will.
Or he won't. We
can't control it.
All we can do is just
go on, live our lives,
be there for our patients and our
friends, and go to dinner parties.
- I'm not going to a party.
- You have to go
because I have to go.
If I can go to court for you, you
can go to a dinner party for me.
Eight 'o clock.
Sorry! I had an aortic
valvuloplasty and I...
Wilson! I mean... Hi, Wilson.
I should have warned
you this is casual.
What? I'm casual.
I'm casual. You look hot.
- No. I look hot?
- Your butt looks like an apple.
Hey! Pierce,
when'd you get here?
Okay, I'm tagging you in.
Riggs is right over there.
She's your buffer? No,
Maggie, you are not tagged in.
I am tagging her in.
That defeats the
point of all this.
- I didn't agree to all of this!
- No, tag me in. It's fine.
- You're starting a thing here.
- No, it's okay. All good.
You're not even
giving it a chance!
Guys, I'll tag myself in. You
obviously need to talk about this.
And I am right behind you.
- No, you don't have to...
- I don't mind.
You're still crying?
Of course I'm still crying.
April, come on, okay?
I'm gonna bring her by every
single day at the hospital.
We already talked about it.
Soon as you get home,
we'll fly your mom back out,
get her to stay for
a couple months.
My mom already came for
as long as she could, okay?
I can't ask her to come
back. She's... She's got work.
I'll get a baby nurse who can
stay, who can live with you then.
- I can't afford that.
- I'm loaded. I can.
Well, I'm not. And
we're not married.
Yes, I know.
You can't fix this, okay?
I have to figure this
out. I am a single mom...
April, I'm her
father. I'm right here.
As long as Harriet is fed
and sleeping and happy,
you're doing your job. You don't
need to, like, check in on me, okay?
Or call unless Harriet
needs me, okay?
So I'm just supposed
to let you cry, then?
Yes! Good night, Jackson.
You're here. Good.
For a while, He's been with
Maggie but you're up next.
I have not put my bag down yet.
If you don't get in there, Amelia's
gonna make me talk to him,
and we're gonna fight.
You've been married
for, like, two minutes.
- Right, so just get in there!
- Fine, fine!
Hey, hey!
- Hey.
- Hey!
Have you had the tour
yet? Owen gives a great tour.
Yeah, I helped him move in.
We painted the
bedroom since then, so...
Okay. Nathan, you want to...
I need to talk to Dr. Riggs about
Mrs. Peterkin. She relapsed.
Great. So it's just us, then.
Let's go. Come on, let's go.
- Who's Mrs... Peterkin?
- There is no Mrs. Peterkin.
- You just...
- Maggie is going
to ask you out.
- On a date.
- Oh, so...
- Maggie wants me?
- She wants to date you.
And you are going
to be nice and say no.
Oh, so she doesn't know that
you're madly in love with me.
- I am not madly in love
with you.
- You're close. You will be.
I am close to hating you.
Really? Then we should
just end this, right now.
Let's just make
out on the couch.
Sends a clear message,
then everyone knows.
Oh, hmm, you're considering it.
- You're disgusting.
- And yet you're falling for me.
Shut up. You are
going to say no.
You are going to be very nice...
but you are going to say no.
Got it?
Okay.
- Hey, you're here.
- Yeah. I don't know why I came.
He was charged with a
felony. I don't know if you know.
I know. I was there.
I don't know what's going
on with you guys, but he's...
Alex is in a really bad place.
Maybe you could talk to him.
Why are you telling me this?
I'm telling you this because
you said you showed up in court.
- I thought you care.
- I do care.
Okay, so, then talk to him.
I care about what
Alex did to Andrew.
That's what I care about.
Owen says they get
great morning light.
- Light is good.
- Yeah,
- I was thinking, do you wanna...
- No, we shouldn't.
Double team on that
transplant tomorrow?
- It should be fun.
- Oh, yeah, okay!
- We should do that.
- Okay, definitely.
And then maybe
after that, we could...
finish up my resident
competency reports.
- I'm... I'm way behind.
- Yeah! Okay.
Excellent, definitely.
I can do that, too.
- Great, sounds good.
- No problem.
I'm gonna go help
Amelia. She can't cook.
- Hey.
- Mommy, I'm scared.
- I know, baby.
What's going on?
His pressure's dropped.
Getting central access.
All right, get
me an art line kit.
- Honey...
- Mrs. Thompson,
please step back.
I'm sorry. He doesn't know
you guys. He needs Dr. Karev.
Where's Dr. Karev?
Yes, can we find out
where Dr. Karev is, please?
- Hey.
Uh...
You're... I didn't
know you'd be here.
How are you?
I don't know how to answer that.
I'm leaving, so you can go in.
Jo... I don't want
to go in there.
I want to be home with you. I
messed that up, and I know that,
- and I'm sorry.
- You can't just say that.
I mean it, and I'm
gonna keep saying it.
It doesn't fix anything.
Sorry doesn't fix...
- What do you want me to say?
- You lash out and hurt people,
and then you think you can
just walk it back with "I'm sorry."
I'm not walking anything
back. I might be going to prison.
- But you and me...
- You and me? What you and me?
You walked out. You left.
- And I came back.
- And then you called me trash.
And you just...
You said it so easily.
You were trying to hurt me.
It worked.
Jo!
- I got your page.
- Took you long enough.
- What happened?
- His appendix ruptured. He's septic.
All right, gown and gloves.
No need. Dr. Karev
will not be scrubbing in.
You're not touching
this boy. Babcock.
- Bailey, this is my patient.
- Not anymore.
You're off this case. Stapler.
This is just painful to
watch. Owen, can I see you?
Sure.
- You're off the hook.
- I told you.
I don't know why
you feel you need to...
I'm a fixer! I fix things.
I see something sad and broken,
maybe just a little
pathetic, and I want to fix it!
It's a compulsion!
But we're done here. Party's
over. No more meddling.
- You promise?
- Yeah.
Kind of. Yes.
- Good, thank you.
- Okay.
Yeah, she just won't
go back to sleep.
Well, let, let me try.
Can she... Can she hear
me? Is the sound okay?
Yeah, yeah, she can hear you.
I'm so glad they
reached you. How's Zach?
He's still in surgery.
Why aren't you
in there with him?
- Reena...
- No, I want you in there.
I'm not on Zach's case anymore.
I made a mistake. I missed a
sign that there was an infection.
He's in there because of you?
I checked his
labs before I left.
You promised me
you'd check him hourly.
Not his labs, him!
I know.
And what about his kidney?
If the infection spreads, it
could affect his transplant.
They're doing
everything they can.
So the next few hours
are crucial. I'm sorry.
So, he could lose his kidney.
Yes.
- Reena...
- Would you please go?
- Where's Alex? This is his patient.
- Not anymore.
What is this I hear about
you threatening DeLuca?
I didn't threaten DeLuca.
I was trying to advise him.
You were talking
to him about Karev,
and you know it isn't your
place to discuss that with him.
- Bailey, it's Alex.
- Yeah, I'm well aware.
I've just spent six hours
in the OR because of him.
You are not Karev's
guardian angel.
You are blinded by this thing.
Look, I know you want to help.
But there's no need
to go down with him.
I'm his family. Who
else is going to help him?
Did Karev tell you what
happened with this patient tonight?
You should ask him.
I thought this little
one got to go home.
Yeah, she did. We're
just back visiting mommy.
- May I?
- Sure. There we go.
Yeah, how's April?
Well, she was
up all night crying.
Yeah, I took Harriet
home, so she misses her.
She's sad and angry and doesn't
really want any help from me.
Maybe she doesn't
want to ask for help.
I've been there, needing to prove
I could do something on my own.
Determined not to ask for help.
Yeah, well, I can't make her lean
on me. We're not married anymore.
I thought you were
your mother's son.
You two have a beautiful
baby girl together.
Kepner's family. Be persistent.
It's what you do for family.
Which lights up the borders of
the tumor so that we can get it all.
I know what to
expect. I'm ready.
- I can see that.
- I can't wait. Cut open my head.
I get it. The headaches
must be terrible.
No, I know terrible.
I was married to the same
man for over thirty years.
Wasn't the best choice.
He was a preacher.
Thought he could cheat on me
because he had a hot-line to heaven.
And I just let it happen.
- I was a church mouse.
- Literally.
I thought of leaving,
but I kept thinking
about how the church would
react. That he'd lose them.
So... I made myself small.
And then I met Wilma. The tumor.
I knew I had to start
looking out for myself,
so... I walked right out
that door with a tumor
the size of a
cantaloupe in my head.
Stronger because I had to be.
- Wilma made you brave.
- No, she made me pissed.
Being pissed made me brave.
Hmm.
She shouldn't have
taken that case from you.
I messed up, big time, Mer.
We all mess up. I mean,
why is everyone around here
acting like they never
made a mistake before?
Stop. I torched a kid's
kidney and he could lose it,
because I screwed up.
And I keep screwing up.
Just... open your eyes.
You're backing the
wrong damn horse.
Dr. Grey, the chief wants
you to scrub in on a surgery.
Well, I have a lap
chole scheduled, so...
She asked for you. The patient
has a renal artery thrombosis post...
Who's the patient,
Warren? Zach Thompson?
There's no blood
flowing to his kidney.
It failed. We've to remove
it. Dr. Grey, we should go.
Okay, okay, I got it.
You asked for me, Dr. Grey?
Yes, have you ever scrubbed in
on a kidney transplant removal?
- It's a yes or no, DeLuca.
- No. No, I haven't.
Well, bootie up
fast. We're going in.
Where's Dr. Alex?
I want Dr. Alex.
Zach, I'm Dr. Grey.
Dr. Alex can't be here.
But I know he'd want me to
tell you how brave you've been.
But why isn't he here?
- Karev, you're still off
this case.
- Does he know about his kidney?
His mother wanted
us to wait until after.
Can I see him for a minute?
Just for one minute, please.
Dr. Alex, are you
coming with me?
Dude, I gotta stay out here.
Are you gonna sit with
my mom? She's scared.
- Are you scared?
- Yeah.
It's a piece of cake.
- What do we always say?
- Nothing's as bad as broccoli.
Nothing's as bad as broccoli.
I'll be here when
you get out, okay?
Hey, okay, let's go.
Zach wanted me to check on you.
I guess it's time
for you to get going.
- Hey, buddy.
- Bye.
What?
I think you and Harriet
should come live with me
when you get out of here.
- Just until you've recovered.
- No.
- April, come on, you need help.
- I know that.
Good, so then why won't
you accept it from me?
- Because it's from you.
- Come on.
I need boundaries. And
I can take care of her.
Of course you can, and you will.
I know that we need boundaries.
I know that I'm
not your husband.
I also know that I
am Harriet's father.
She needs her mother
and her mother needs help.
Just think about it. Okay?
- Okay.
- She said okay.
Nathan! Long, long day, huh?
Yeah, it was. The short
ones are boring as hell.
Hey. Do you want to
grab dinner sometime?
Like, after work, like, away
from work? Like a date?
Like an actual date?
You're an amazing woman.
Oh. Okay.
It's just I'm not... I'm
not ready to date...
- No, right. I...
- anyone right now.
I, I totally understand.
- I'm sorry.
- Gosh, no. No, it's...
Don't. It's not a big deal.
Have a great night.
You too.
Zach is stable.
We removed a large
blood clot from the artery
and the kidney pinked up again.
Thank you.
You were the big surprise.
You were "Most improved."
The person that beat
up DeLuca is someone
I thought you left
behind years ago.
Me too.
I can't in good conscience
let you perform surgery
in this hospital right now.
You're a good doctor.
You're compassionate.
And you're good with people.
It's exactly what we
need right now in the clinic.
A little mole told me
they're short-staffed.
The Denny Duquette Clinic?
Unless you want me to fire you.
All right, then.
You start tomorrow.
Thanks.
- Hey.
- This is you and Riggs
at the wedding. You invited him.
Okay, what happened
to no more meddling?
You married a
twelve-stepper, get used to it.
Why is this so important to you?
You guys were, like, best
friends! You're brothers.
You don't get a lot
of those in your life.
So you have to try.
You're required to try.
I am happy. Okay?
You could be happier.
So do you want me to stay or go?
'Cause, you know,
I mean, either way...
No, I'm fine. You can go.
We walk through
these doors as interns.
Chips on our shoulders. Loners.
Lesser rock stars on
the verge of greatness.
I still can't believe
you saved that kidney.
You would have done the
same thing if you were in there.
Bailey was right, my
head's not in the game.
We're thrown into
the deep end together,
told to save lives together, to
save each other. We become family.
So get it in the game.
I'm gonna be working
in the clinic for a while.
- That is just...
- It's fine. It's right.
It's not like I didn't
do it to myself.
- I slept with Riggs.
- Okay.
In the parking lot. In my car.
In the car you drove me home in?
- It's bad.
- It was bad?
No. It's bad because...
Hey! What are we drinking?
Slow down.
My God, that was humiliating. It was
worse than being dumped by DeLuca.
And now he knows how much
I like him. Why am I crying?
Some guy said no?
Who said what?
You live here now, so
you're gonna hear things.
It's Riggs. I asked him out.
He said no. So fast.
You know what? Forget him.
It's really time to move on.
- Okay.
- Look on the bright side.
Yeah. He did say he
wasn't dating... Right now.
And even when
you really screw up...
I'll give it some time.
Family is always
there. Always on call.
Womb to tomb. Ride or die.