Banana blueberry
with a hint of cinnamon.
I think
it's my best yet.
Hm.
I like chocolate chip...
Mmm....with syrup.
I like eating pancakes
in bed.
Do you want to
have sex again?Yes.
Do you want to finish
the pancakes first?
Yes.Me too.
We are very good
at pretending to be married,
but we are very bad
at getting married.
I don't want to
do it anymore.
Not the marriage,
the wedding.
I don't want any more
dress fittings or guest lists.
I just want to be married.
Shaun...
...we have 45 more minutes
of our fake honeymoon.
No work.
There is an opening at
the courthouse tomorrow
at 4:30.
Cheese, no.
Peppers, yes?
Perfect.
Is that him?
Based on the last
three voicemails,
he's calling about
the restraining order I filed.
How are you feeling?Like my future is a dark,
formless void,
which makes it
full of possibility.
Like a one-bed,
one-bath rental.
You've only been here
a few days.
Which is a few days longer
than anyone should crash
on their boss's couch.
Thank you, Audrey.
Thank you.
Why am I watching you
make a smoothie?
You're watching me dance
while I make a smoothie.
It's not a smoothie
if it has tequila in it.
It's a spinach and flax seed
margarita.
Hey!
And it makes you dance.
Mm.
Okay, listen...
No.
Too much butt, though.
Think about the butt.
Asher?
What are you doing here?
Meet my parents.
Steph Lewis, 35.
She had a brainstem stroke
nine years ago
that left her paralyzed
from her face down.
I still have
10% movement in three fingers
so don't sell me short.
W... How'd you type that
so quickly?
I have eight different
pre-programmed phrases
to put people at ease.
She's had four serious bouts
of pneumonia
in the last few months.
Um, she's taken levofloxacin
for the infection
and glycopyrrolate
for the trach secretions,
but she still has high fever,
decreased energy,
night sweats.
He's so sexy
when he talks medical.
The pneumonia
caused scar tissue,
which is compressing
her lung.
She needs surgical
decortication.
That's a pretty aggressive
approach.
Surgery comes
with serious risk,
recurrent air leaks,
respiratory failure, sepsis.
And giving round after round
of antibiotics
is only going to make
the infections harder to...
Hello.
I want the surgery.
I know the risks.
I'm sick of feeling crappy.
I have terminal
lung cancer.
Doctors say I have
less than a year
and no good surgical options.
I'm... So sorry.
We're not here
for sympathy.
God, in his wisdom,
gave us a son
who would grow up to be
a doctor for times like this.
He will work a miracle
through you.
I can't do lunch today.
I have a job interview
with New York Medical Center.
I didn't know you were
considering positions
on the other side
of the country.
I'm not. I just want to
get multiple offers
so I can leverage a better one
from St. Bon's.
Makes you look in demand.
Uh, I'd rather look like
I want the job I have now.
Oh, hello.
Hi.Yes.
Um, thank you so much
for your gift, whatever it is.
We are returning it.
We're getting married
at the courthouse tomorrow.
And since neither of you
are invited,
Weddiquette.org said we're
supposed to return the gift.
Excellent. I can exchange it
for store credit.
That's exciting.
They're getting married where
people pay parking tickets.
What about
a destination wedding?
Hmm. We're good.
I have to go.
We are going to be
husband and wife
in 30 hours and 27 minutes.Mm. Mm.
Stage four lung cancer
which has invaded
the chest wall.
Six rounds of chemo.
The treatment has caused
severe anemia and colitis.
Your hair is flatter.
We need a CT of the chest,
abdomen, and pelvis,
CBC, blood cultures,
and an EKG.
I will review your results
with Dr. Andrews,
and we will try to find
a treatment to help you.
God bless you,
Dr. Murphy.
Okay, thank you.
Can you guys cool it
with the blessing people
in the name of God?
This is
a secular hospital.
It's called
Saint Bonaventure.
Mr. and Mrs. Wolke,
I'm Jerome.
We met briefly
this morning.
I'm gonna draw some blood.
Jerome is...
A nurse.
Jerome is your nurse.
The surgery went well.
We removed
all of the scar tissue,
and the lung expanded
completely.
Thank you.Mm.
Why can't she
move her hand?
Steph, can you blink
when you feel something?
What's going on?
Will it come back?
I don't know.
I read your letter
a few months ago.
I sent it six years ago.
I wasn't sure I wanted to hear
what you had to say.
But it was nice.
I just wanted to tell you
about the family.
I'm not a part
of the family anymore.
You made that very clear
when I left.
You chose to leave.
We wanted you to stay,
wanted to help you.
You're not the only one
who struggles
with finding
the right path.
We all must sometimes choose
to deny our flesh.
You're right.
I did make a choice.
I could follow your rules,
or I could love and accept
who I am.
I chose which one
mattered more...
And so did you.
Are you okay?
Take a deep breath.
I need some help!
CT shows the chest wall tumor
has grown.
He's bleeding into
the thoracic cavity,
and it is collapsing his lung.
He needs surgery
to stop the bleed now.
His blood cell counts
are too low.
Maybe we should do an echo
to see if his heart
is stable enough for... No. There isn't time.
Get consent from your mother,
and I will start
prepping your father
for the embolization.
The anesthesia
must have caused
a drop in
Steph's blood pressure
and completed
her previous injury.
Then her best bet's
eye-tracking technology.
That'll be great,
as long as she only wants
to speak one word a minute.
Well, she'll get
the hang of it.
After months of training.
Well, it's better than
what she has now.
How'd the interview go?
Mm. Great.
The head
of internal medicine
is basically me
10 years from now.
We loved each other.
And her department just got
a SPORE grant.
Sounds like
you're interested.
It sounds like I'm answering
your question.
Oh, with enthusiasm.
Wha... What am I gonna do
with a second blender?
Yeah, I got you a blender.
Open it.
Weddiquette says I can't.
That's dumb.
Just open it.
Oh, I can't.
Mm.
I really love it.
Mm-hmm. The photo's
just a placeholder
until you get the real
wedding pics.Mm.
But that dress
looked amazing on you.
Thank you.Mm-hmm.
This was fun.Mm-hmm.
Your blood pressure
looks good.
No fever
or sign of infection.
We should be able to start you
on eye-tracking tomorrow.
W... We tried that before.
It can take a while
to get used to.
No, no, the camera's
facing the right way
this time.
I promise.
This is the living room.
Also the dining room, kitchen,
guest room, and office.
All conveniently located
in these 400 square feet.
And it's all ours!
Someone's phone's ringing.
I know.
Park.
We can give Steph
her voice back.
Advance the catheter to
the right fourth
intercostal artery.
He got this scar teaching me
how to ride a bike.
I was going too fast.
I didn't know how to
brake yet.
He caught me.
We both ended up
with stitches.
Delivering
the embolic agent.
My dad taught me
how to tie a tie.
He was a minister who wore
his Sunday best
every day of the week.
When he died,
I wore his suit jackets
every day for a year.
My dad was my first
chemistry teacher.
We baked together every
weekend on a quest to find
the perfect oatmeal
chocolate chip cookie recipe.
I'm cold.
Fluid is cloudy.
He has a malignant
pleural effusion.
Can we drain it?
It will keep coming back
and spread the cancer
everywhere in
his chest cavity.
Your father's prognosis
was wrong.
He only has
a few weeks to live.
You have weeks.
Maybe days.
But likely weeks.
We'll continue
to drain the fluid
and try to find a surgery
that will give you more time.
God has privileged us
with great miracles.
And He will again.
Shabbos.
The Jewish holy day of rest
begins tonight.
God and I plan to do
just that...
Rest.
Okay, let's...
We'll implant electrodes
on her sensorimotor cortex,
which will decode
her brainwaves.
All Steph has to do
is try to speak,
and the receiver relays
the signals,
which are translated
into speech.
It's brand-new technology
that's only been done
successfully a couple times.
It's new technology that would
give Steph not just a voice,
but her voice back.
By uploading audio files taken
before the stroke, we can...
But Steph can't handle another
life-threatening surgery.
The eye-tracking device will
allow her to communicate...
Right now,
they've got nothing.
They love each other.
You're pushing false hope
because you see Steph
as nothing but a burden.
I'm trying to give them
some quality of life.
You're risking her life
because you can't imagine
making that kind of sacrifice
for another person.
Park's right.
It's risky.
But it's not false hope.
Let's take it to them,
without any hint of whatever's
going on between you.
No one is coming into
a patient's room
to turn on the TV.
And this way,
I can ensure it.
Okay,
if you want him to breathe
through Shabbos,
I suggest you leave those
plugged in.
Hi, family.
Hello.How's your pain?
It's nothing
I can't handle.
Will you join us for Shabbos,
Dr. Allen?
Uh, I'd love to,
but I should be researching
how to save your life.
Am I dying tomorrow?
Then Shabbos
is more important.
From sundown to sundown,
we devote a day to joy
and God.
How can I say no to God?
♪♪ Blue
♪♪ To green
♪♪ So quickly
♪♪ Whispered words
♪♪ So sweetly
I'm sorry.
I was projecting
and overreacted.
An interview is
just an interview.
They offered me the job.
♪♪ Whispered words ♪♪
Asher, will you say
the mischa beruchfor Abba?
Prayer for the sick,
for his father.
You want me to pray to a God
I don't believe in?
Why can't you honor me
in my last days on Earth?
These aren't
your last days.
You told me...
We're finding
a surgical solution.
I am dying.
I have accepted that.
Yosel.
I'm sorry, Miriam.
What I want is
to go to God at peace.
I want you to come home.
Be with me and your mother
and your brothers
and sisters.
It's sad.
I want to be your son...
Almost more than
I want to be myself.
But I can't.
This is who I am.
And this is my boyfriend.
You have been acting
differently.
Is it because you think
it will make your parents
like you more
if you act more...
More...
Straight?Mm.
I think they'd like me more
if I actually was straight.
My parents would have
liked me better
if I didn't have autism.
But your dad
is not like my dad.
Your dad came to see you.
Mm.
The effusion fluid is
reaccumulating
faster than
we can drain it.
The tumor's like a faucet
we can't turn off.
It's spraying cancer-water
everywhere.
That is
an interesting simile.
We can't turn it off,
but we can give it
nowhere to go.
Hm.
By injecting the pleural
cavity with a slurry of talc,
inflammation and scarring
will fill up the space,
clogging up
the tumor and giving
it nowhere to leak fluid into.
And after you heal
from the surgery,
we'll try an experimental
targeted immunotherapy.
It should give you a year,
maybe more.
Ko vay hashem
Yah-chalifu Koach.
How long is the recovery?
You will have to
stay in the hospital
for at least one week.
What are the chances
I'll survive it,
the surgery, the treatment?
There are risks of both,
but we're confident...
I don't want to die away
from home and my family.
We're giving you
more time.
Please take it.
Okay.
Baruch hashem.
Excuse me.
I have flowers for...
Someone else
can take them.
Exposing the sensorimotor
cortex of the left hemisphere.
Electrode array is prepped
for implantation.
I heard Morgan got a job offer
in New York.
Yeah.Tough call for her.
As long as she's at St. Bon's,
she'll be seen as
the doctor who used to be
a surgeon but
can't be anymore.
5-0 prolene on a castro
to suture the dura.
The AI will take samples from
a variety of cortical regions
that are used
in speech processing,
and the predictive analytics
should...
Would you work faster if you
didn't explain every step?
Mm.
To have and to hold,
to honor, to treasure,
to be at his side
in sorrow and in joy,
in the good times
and in the bad...
...and to love
and cherish always.
I love you.
You're being a jerk.
You think I'm being a jerk
to the people
that want me to be
the godly, straight person
I never was?
For the two years
I've known you,
you have been cute and funny
and clever
and caring and sensitive.
Suddenly, your parents show up
and you're just angry.
I think I have
every right to be.
Why do you think
he came here?
So I could save his life
and send him back
to his real family.
Asher, he would have
found a reason
to get on that plane
if you were a car mechanic.
He came here for peace.
Not a miracle cure.
We have
two minutes in total
at the courthouse
to say our vows.
My vows are 26 seconds
if I'm talking slowly,
which I might because
it is an important moment.
Is one minute and 34 seconds
enough time for you?
Lea?Sorry.
Yeah, it is.
You don't sound happy.
Do you not like
Jordan's wedding gift?
No, it's beautiful.
It's just a reminder
that I'll never
wear a real wedding gown
at my dream wedding.
That's kind of a bummer.
Have you changed your mind
about the courthouse?
No. In those dreams,
you are the only constant,
Shaun.
Just the two of us,
that's enough for me.
Shaun?I'm confused.
Okay.
I think I'm getting
mixed signals.
Well, that's a good thing,
isn't it?
Is it?
It doesn't feel like it is.
Well,
you don't normally pick up
on non-verbal cues, right?
That's quite a leap.
Lea says she's disappointed
that we are having our wedding
at the courthouse,
but she also says
she wants to
have our wedding
at the courthouse.
Not quite as big a leap
as I thought, but...
I want to respect
what she wants,
but I also want to respect
her disappointment.
How, How,
How do I do both?
Oh, boy.
People don't always
know what they want.
But they should.
Especially
if it's a wedding.
Yeah, they should.
Let me think about it.
Excellent.
He wants to die.
He's scared.
I think he's at peace.
He wants to go home,
be with God.
You should let him.
You want me to take
moral advice from you?
You gave that up when...
I lost my morality
when I lost my religion?
Without God, there can be
no objective...
My compassion?
My decency?
You don't really
believe that.
Samuel 1 31:4.
"When Saul saw himself losing
to the Philistines,
"he threw himself on his own
sword to avoid
being captured."
Your father's
not facing torture.
He's with his family.
He's...
He is the one suffering.
He gets to decide.
It's pikuach nefesh!
You do not stand by
while your friend bleeds.
This is not your friend.
This is your father.
This is suicide.
You know there's a difference
between actively taking a life
and passively
letting it go!
And you know that doesn't
let us simply give up.
The principle...
If you cared about
principle,
you wouldn't put a timer
on the lights for Shabbos.
If you can find
a way to justify this,
you can justify this!
But you don't want to.
You don't care about
what the Torah says.
♪♪ This is what you wanted
People are curious
about my life, my old life.
♪♪ At least that's
what I thought
They ask if I learned
Western history in school,
if I ever saw a TV,
talked to girls,
if my parents had
an arranged marriage.
♪♪ Nothing's ever enough
They're curious
and kind of...
♪♪ Everything is happening now
...appalled by it all.
♪♪ But I'm still having
the hardest time
And the truth is...
♪♪ Hardest time
when all you see
...a lot of it
appalls me.
A lot of it
is embarrassing for me.
♪♪ The tide going in and out,
the in-between
But... The one thing
I push back against,
the one thing
I will always defend...
♪♪ You're feeling tired
♪♪ Oh
...is your marriage.
♪♪ It's getting harder
and harder
♪♪ OhYour love.
♪♪ Keeping my head
above water
I dream of finding
someone to love me
the way you two
love each other.
Mom, you don't want him to die
because you love him.
♪♪ I'm strong enough
to hold my own
♪♪ Hold my own, yeah
That's the only reason.
It's a very good reason.
♪♪ When all you see
♪♪ The tide going in and out
You don't want the pain
of losing him,
but do you love him enough
to take away his pain?
♪♪ The push and pull
holding you down
To make that pain yours?
♪♪ You're feeling tired
♪♪ Oh
♪♪ It's getting harder
and harder
♪♪ Oh
♪♪ Keeping my head
above water
above water ♪♪
I'd like to ask you
a favor.
It's gonna cost you.
I don't think it will.
It'll take some time
for the AI
to completely learn
your brain waves,
but you can
give it a try...
When you're ready.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Those from him?
I'm finding them
a good home.
And I found an apartment.
Wow. You only just started
calling me Audrey.
Yes, Dr. Lim, you will have
your place to yourself
within a week.
That's great.
I remember,
my sophomore year of college,
my boyfriend dumped me,
said it was
the honorable thing to do
because he was sleeping
with my roommate.
Wrecked me.
Three weeks later, I thought,
"Wow, I am so over that jerk."
Three months after that,
I thought,
"Wow,
I can't believe I thought
I was okay after three weeks.
"But now I'm doing okay.
"I'm gonna be fine,
back up on my feet."
Took a year.
Your situation is
obviously different.
And you're more mature,
wiser.
So maybe you are ready.
But on the other hand...
I get used to things,
and right now,
I've gotten used to
your world-class breakfasts.
Maybe you could give me
a few more weeks?
I'd be honored
to do you that favor.
I need those.
Well, that won't do.
Will that do?No. Not at all.
We are going to
throw you a wedding.
A proper wedding.
No. We decided
not to wait...
Now. Here.
Surprise.
You need a haircut.
I love you, son.
Goodbye, Dad.
I got you something.
I would assume so.
You are invited
to a wedding.
It would be rude
not to.
Yes.
These were passed down from
my great-great-grandparents.
This was supposed to be
for Maddie.
I'm glad you two will be
wearing them both.
Was your father
a good father?
He did his best.
Was he good?I don't know, Shaun.
I... I loved him, I guess.
Okay, but was he good?
Shaun, I'm clearly trying
to avoid this question.
My father's not around
to defend himself.
You know?I know.
Can we go fishing again
sometime?
I thought
you hated fishing.
I'm cold.
And wet.
And very bored.
It'll be a good memory.
My father is
a very good father.
Is?
I love you,
Dr. Glassman.
I love you, too,
Dr. Murphy.
Maybe we should go with
the clip-on.
Hmm.
Oh.
I've been lucky enough
to be given the training
to save lives.
But I don't think
I've ever felt
luckier than I do right now.
Shaun Robert Murphy,
do you take
Lea Abigail Dilallo...
I do.
Oh.
To have and to hold,
to honor, to treasure,
to be by her side
in sorrow and in joy,
through good times
and the bad,
and to love
and cherish her always?
I do.
Lea Abigail Dilallo,
do you take
Shaun Robert Murphy,
to have and to hold,
to honor, to treasure,
to stand by his side
in sorrow and in joy,
through the good times
and the bad,
and love
and cherish him always?
Oh, yeah, I do.
Uh, the rings.
Okay.
Then by the power vested in me
by the State of California,
I now pronounce you
husband and wife.
You may kiss the bride.
And you may kiss the groom.
♪♪ Even when you're far away
Whoo!Whoo!
♪♪ I won't let go
♪♪ You're deep in my soul
♪♪ Stay
♪♪ Even when you're far away
♪♪ I will survive
♪♪ Our love
will guide me home
♪♪ You feel like home
♪♪ You take me home
About 20 years ago,
a young man walked into
my clinic with his brother,
cradling a dead rabbit.
He was very young
and very sweet
and...
I thought totally lost.
And here we are,
some many years later,
and I realize...
I was wrong.
♪♪ When I'm close to you
He was never lost.
♪♪ The world feels small
He always knew who he was.
He always knew
what he wanted.
He always knew exactly
what mattered.
♪♪ Even when you're far away
And he found it.
♪♪ I will survive
Someone else I may have
underestimated just a tad.
You two deserve each other.
You deserve love...
And you deserve all
the happiness in the world.
♪♪ You feel likehome ♪♪
And then some.
♪♪ You take me home
♪♪ You feel like home ♪♪
To Shaun and Lea.
To Shaun and Lea!
♪♪ I may not always love you
♪♪ But long as
there are stars above you
♪♪ You never...
I want the job.
♪♪ I'll make you
so sure about it
I understand.
♪♪ God only knows
what I'd be without you
♪♪ If you should ever leave me
♪♪ Though life will still go on
believe me
♪♪ The world could show
nothing to me
♪♪ So what good
would living do me?
♪♪ God only knows
what I'd be without you
They look so happy,
don't they?
Yes, they do.
Make me kinda hate 'em
a little.
Okay.
People are drinking.
A lot.
We need more glasses.
We have a bunch
in the break room.
I'll go get them.
♪♪ God only knows
what I'd be without you
♪♪ If you should ever
leave me... ♪♪
Dalisay?
Can you hear me?
I've got you.
Code Blue!
I need a cart!
He's here.Please don't talk.
He's here.
What? Who's here?
My ex.
Aah!
Oh!
♪♪ God only knows
what I'd be without you ♪♪
what I'd be without you
♪♪ God only knows
♪♪ God only ♪♪