[Naomi] Previously on Private Practice :
What do you say
we just see how it goes ? Tonight.
He stood me up.
You and me.
Friends with benefits. Tonight.
What time should I come over ?
You're not some random girl. With you
it doesn't mean nothing. It never will.
All right. Get out.
I am so sick and tired of being the only
person in this practice who thinks !
[ ? Sharon Jones
and The Dap-Kings : Tell Me]
- Violet here ?
- No. Not yet, but, um... OK.
- Morning ! You've got a...
- Morning.
[Elevator dings]
Hi. Good morning.
- Hi. Here you go.
- Naomi ?
Yeah. She just went...
- Is Naomi...
- What's up with everybody ?
Was there a car accident
or something ? What ?
Or something.
- Milk ?
- Oh, thanks.
- They're behind closed doors.
- Who ?
The women.
If they're going to talk about us,
we should talk about them.
Yeah. Let's talk.
Let's talk smack.
- I need ten minutes with Naomi.
- I need Naomi first.
- Naomi ?
- Nai ?
She slept with Cooper. She slept with
Pete. The cats out of bag, all that.
- Didn't sleep with Pete.
- Didn't sleep with Cooper.
[Both] How did you know that ?
- There're no secrets around here.
- I know.
Oh, there are secrets.
I mean, I didn't know.
Wow. Neither one of you ? Really ?
I didn't know.
- That's all I'm saying.
- Pete literally stood me up.
I don't get stood up. I'm Addison.
Which means something...
...in places where things
mean things. It was humiliating.
Were you completely naked ?
Did you stand in front of him
like a peeled banana
while he looked over your best parts ?
Because I have good parts and Cooper
passed on them. I have good parts.
- Damn right, you do. And so do I.
- I like your breasts.
- You have a good ass.
- Thank you. I like it.
Hey ! Hey, hey, hey. The point is, we
should not be having sex in the office.
Who's having sex in the office ?
No one. No one. That's the point.
It gets complicated. You just...
You don't know where you stand.
What do you think
they're saying about us ?
- You know what ? Who cares ?
- Yeah. Who cares ?
The guys are still in the kitchen.
How am I going to get coffee ?
I need it.
- Can we skip the morning meeting ?
- No morning meeting today.
- Thank you.
- Charlotte King is coming by
to walk all of us through
the Safe Surrender program.
- That's today.
- Yeah.
I signed up with Pete.
I am in control.
I work here.
I'm moving on.
But I'm getting my coffee
from downstairs.
- Oh. Small non-fat chai latte.
- Frappuccino. Extra whip.
- Blame the guy in front.
- Sorry ?
The guy at the front
just ordered a coffee with, like,
seven descriptive words in front of it.
Blame him if you're running late.
Oh, I work upstairs.
I just have a meeting to get to.
Not a big deal.
Well, you can go in front of me.
You look important. I'm guessing
this meeting won't go on without you.
Thank you.
- I'm Carl, by the way.
- Addison.
- Hey.
[Elevator dings]
- Hey. I...
- Stop me now if you had amnesia
or you were bleeding to death in an ER.
- Addison, I...
- No ? Good. Here's the deal.
I take full responsibility for last
night. I was warned repeatedly.
By you, and I should know by now that
when someone tells you who they are,
you should believe them.
I can work with you, but personally,
you've been downgraded
to acquaintance, I'm moving on.
Fair enough.
- We have coffee here.
- Shut up.
What is wrong with everybody ?
OK, Safe Surrender rundown.
Montgomery, you and Pete
are the go-to team.
Am I wrong ? That's what I have here.
No, we volunteered last week.
Good times. Happier times.
The cell phone. That's all they need ?
Well, the next 48 hours, all calls
placed to the Safe Surrender hotline
will be rerouted to that phone.
Don't stray far from here
or from each other.
- Fine.
- Calls are from women
- who want to give up their babies ?
- Most have given birth already
and can't or don't want
to keep the babies.
They call from school bathrooms,
friend's places.
Too scared to go to hospitals,
where they have to provide names.
So we arrange for a place to meet,
they surrender the baby, then what ?
Bring them back here.
Dr. Freedman can do the exams.
- If the babies are healthy ?
- Then call social services.
And most important :
Don't forget the bracelets.
One to the mom,
one on the baby's wrist or ankle.
If birth mother changes her mind,
she has two weeks to reclaim the child.
The victory is when that baby
is placed with someone who wants them.
If it's the mom, all the better.
That's all I have time for.
Any questions, call me.
Nothing Charlotte likes better than
bossing people around, huh ? Glowing.
Safe Surrender saves hundreds
of babies a year.
It's an amazing thing that she's doing.
How did you feel about the homework
I gave you last week ?
Well, I didn't think I was an "imagine
yourself on a warm beach" kind of guy.
- But ?
- Every time I started to feel anxious,
I thought about the Mediterranean,
it worked.
Well, maybe you're ready
for some more homework.
- Bring it on.
- Let's identify something
that would have triggered you in the
past. Something you'd like to try again.
Done. I met a woman today.
We exchanged business cards.
I think I'm ready to try dating again.
- Hey.
- Hey. Hey.
- We didn't forget how. [chuckles]
- [Chuckles]
I tell you that.
No, we did not.
I think we...
- Yeah, we didn't forget.
- Nah.
Uh...
So...
...what do you think ?
- What do I think ?
- Yeah. I just...
...you know, you laid it on me.
So that gives you the right
to speak first.
- I laid it on you ?
- No. Well...
Because I jumped you
and you were helpless to stop me or...
I didn't say that.
I just... was this a slip-up ?
Like, a one-time thing ?
Or would you want more here ?
I don't know, Sam. I don't know.
For once, I hadn't thought it through.
- Well...
- You know, the practice,
we barely got through it
after the split.
- I know.
- And Maya.
I mean, it's not...
not fair to Maya.
We got divorced for a reason.
So, um...
...I think it was just a slip-up.
Yeah.
- I, uh, I thought that too.
- OK, good.
- Yeah.
- Good. OK.
OK.
Hey, there was a message
on your voice mail. Your priest called ?
You have a priest ?
Had. We used to.
OK. Yeah, well, he wants to see you.
- Me ?
- Both of you. Together.
As soon as possible.
It sounded serious.
What did you do, commit a mortal sin ?
- [Scoffs]
- [Chuckles]
[Church bells tolling]
- God's trying to tell us something.
- It's a coincidence.
No. We have sex and then the day after,
our priest summons us ?
It's the fires of hell, Sam.
We had sex.
Just don't mention we got a divorce.
I don't need a lecture.
- Play it cool.
- Yeah, yeah. Cool.
- Thank you so much for coming.
- Hey.
- We had sex and we're divorced.
- Oh...
- Naomi.
- I'm sorry. He's our priest.
- I can't lie to him.
- I'm going to let that go for now,
I'm also going to overlook
you two have been
Christmas and Easter-ing it
for the last ten years.
I called about one of the nuns.
It's Sister Helen. She's sick.
Well, we don't know what it is.
She's 86. She hates hospitals.
I thought of you two.
Sam, this is your area. Naomi, having
a woman would make her comfortable.
Has she been ill for a while ?
Sister Amy would know. The sisters have
been sequestered alone together.
- Sequestered ?
- For three weeks.
St. Mary's is our motherhouse. We spend
the year on missions around the world,
so this is the one time of year
we get to see each other.
This is the first I've been outside
these walls in the last three weeks.
- All right. So, please.
- OK.
- Father Mark ?
- I'm not supposed to enter.
No one from outside the sisterhood.
But they need you.
- You're good Catholics, doctors.
- Doctors, at least.
Go on. I'll wait for you here.
[Grunts]
It's all right, Sister Helen.
She's a doctor. It's all right.
When did she start feeling bad ?
A week or so ago she said she felt
like she was getting the flu.
She's the one who doesn't complain
of aches and pains. So we noticed.
Sam.
What's this ?
[Exhales] It's definitely not the flu.
- Still don't want to talk, Cooper.
- But I want to talk.
Well, there's a world wide web
out there waiting for you.
You can find someone who will listen.
I can just grab the peanut butter and...
Men. They're overrated.
Dating is overrated. Sex, is...
Don't.
Don't say something
you're going to regret.
[Phone ringing]
Um...
Hello. Addison Montgomery.
Carl. Hi.
Yes, I would love to have coffee.
But I am on call for work today, so...
Are you sure ? OK.
Then, yes. I will see you later.
Bye.
- I have a date tonight.
- You don't...
You don't want
to move too fast, Addison.
- Not with a guy you barely know.
- Unhand me, woman.
I'm getting my date on.
It would help if we could
precisely identify the rash.
- I don't have my derm atlas on me.
- Wait.
- Sister Virginia ? Could you...
- Oh, yes, of course.
Thank you.
- Sister.
- OK. There we go.
I'm going to send it to Dell. See if
he can't find someone to identify it.
OK.
- How she feeling ?
- We may need to get her to a hospital.
We'll do everything we can
to keep her here,
but we can't treat her until we know
what kind of an infection she has.
We also need to check the other sisters
to see if it's contagious.
You ever seen a rash like this ?
Can't say that I have.
I'm tracking down an infectious disease
specialist to get an answer.
Um, I'm done with patients for the day
but I'll be back later.
Ring me if we get a call.
I'll be down the street.
- I've got a thing.
- A "thing" ?
- Yes.
- Well, don't drink.
Friends don't let friends
drink and save babies.
- I think Addison has a date tonight.
- Good for her.
She's getting back on the horse.
- I'm about to have a date tonight.
- Really ?
Yeah. With CanUHandleMe441.
- Oh.
- What ? I don't believe in dwelling.
I believe in getting back on the horse.
- Well, I'll leave you to it.
- He's a lucky guy.
- Who is ?
- Addison's horse.
[Woman coughing]
- You feel a little clammy.
- I'm fine.
I spend most of the year
ministering to people in Uganda.
You ought to see
what I'm exposed to there.
- I'll weather Sister Helen's cold.
- Sister Virginia, please.
Sister Helen's temperature is a 103.
Her resps 26.
And Sister Virginia's getting sick.
And Dell still hasn't come up
with anything on that rash.
All right. We should just get
Sister Helen to a hospital.
- I'll call the ambulance.
- Already did. They're 20 minutes out.
- We make a good team.
- Yeah, we do.
And then I moved to L.A.
- And lived happily ever after ?
- Yes.
The life of Addison Montgomery
in ten minutes or less.
- Well, you can have 11 minutes.
- Don't need it.
Here it goes :
Never been married, never had kids.
Want to get married, want to have kids.
A man without baggage. That is rare.
Well, I have a little baggage
to confess.
I'm a...
a patient of Dr. Turner's.
I've been seeing her almost a year.
And I can say, without a doubt,
that she's made me a better man.
OK.
OK. It's, um...
It's refreshing
to meet someone who's
interested in being a better man.
- Really ?
- Yes. Really.
- [Phone ringing]
- Oh.
I have to take this. Excuse me. Hello ?
Her name is Darcy.
She said to wait, she'd meet us.
Darcy.
It's a girl.
She's not... She isn't crying.
- I can take a look at her.
- Are you bleeding ?
- Let us take you to the clinic.
- No. Just take it and go.
My mom's upstairs sleeping.
Your mother was here in the house
when you were...
I crawled on the top bunk, played my
stereo to cover the contractions.
- You cut the cord...
- I clipped it.
See ? With a barrette.
You made the right decision by calling.
Give me five minutes.
I'll do an exam quickly.
Make sure there aren't any problems.
Darcy ? It's a little late
to have friends over.
Sorry, Mom. You have to go. Now.
Take my card. And a bracelet.
- Your daughter has a matching one.
- I... Just go !
- In case you change your mind.
- I won't.
[Coughing]
- Hey.
- Sam.
- The ambulance is here.
- Sam. May I show him ? Please.
I felt fine.
Oh.
- Naomi.
- Yeah, I know. I see it.
Not just Sister Helen and
Sister Virginia.
- Sam.
- Hey ! No, no ! Don't come in !
This building is a hot zone.
Lock it down.
Until we figure out what this is,
nobody in or out.
- I am not leaving them.
- Shut the door then. Shut the door.
[Sam] Saint Ambrose spoke to the CDC.
They said we were right to lock down
until the hospitals can prep some
isolation units for them.
Or us.
What do they think this is ?
Probably viral contagion.
Considering where these nuns have been.
Dell forwarded the pictures on to
an infectious disease specialist,
- we'll know as soon as he hears back.
- All right.
How long until the iso unit's prepped ?
- Six hours.
- OK.
Three more sisters have a fever,
so that makes eight of the 12,
and I'm not feeling too good.
Still don't think
God's trying to tell us something ?
You don't think we're being punished
for what we did last night ?
What, just because we may have some
rare tropical, probably deadly disease ?
The morning after we have sex ?
Well, if we are sick...
I'm glad we got some.
- How sentimental.
- That was a joke. I was joking.
Yeah, I got to say, that kid did a
good job of giving birth on a bunk bed.
I did a primary check
and she's fine for now.
Her lungs are good, heartbeat's strong.
Get Cooper to do
a well baby check tomorrow.
- Or you can call him now.
- Cooper's, um...
...out on a date.
Oh, God. He's doing his
get back up on the horse thing.
Addison is too. Right ?
You had your date ? How did it go ?
It's OK, Violet. I know Carl's
your patient. He told me.
Oh, good.
Good.
Baby blankets. We need baby blankets.
- [Phone ringing]
- Oh, hey.
You know, that might be
the guy... the nun rash.
So you're dating one of Violet's
patients ? A psych patient ?
This is L.A. You're weird
if you're not seeing a shrink.
You all done, kiddo ? Huh ?
OK. There you go. Good girl.
You want me to call Social Services
to come pick up her up ?
No, no, no. That's OK.,
I'll stay here tonight.
- Are you serious ?
- Yeah, you know.
She should get to feel wanted.
At least for one night. Huh ?
Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
Little girl. That's a little baby.
[ ? lke & Tina Turner :
Crazy 'Bout You Baby]
Seven and seven. More on the first
seven, less on the second.
Charlotte King, as I live and breathe.
- Oh, no you don't. That's saved.
- Big date ?
Not a date. Far from it.
I'm just meeting someone.
Scoot. I don't want him to see you
and think you're here with me.
What time did he say ?
9 :00 p.m.
Mmm. I'm meeting someone at 9 :00, too.
[Exhales]
A blonde. Petite.
- We met on the internet.
- What ?
- Huh ?
- No.
[Chuckles]
Oh, God.
- Oh, my God.
- No. No, no.
We should laugh about
the unfortunate coincidence.
Let's be clear. This never happened.
Or the opposite of laughing.
Yes sir, I just got it.
OK. I see. Yeah.
I'll call them right now.
Holy crap.
A patient of yours is dating Addison ?
I'm not allowed to discuss it.
You know that.
Yes you are. Our patients know
we share files.
- We don't if we don't have to.
- On a scale of one to ten,
- how bad is his thing ?
- Moving away, not talking.
Are we talking a three ?
Like, "I'm afraid of seagulls
and I'm considering hypnotherapy" ?
- I'm closing the door in your face.
- Oh, it's bad, huh ?
- We're way beyond mommy issues here ?
- Ethics, Pete. Look it up.
Sam.
Tachycardic at 130. I can't get
a blood pressure. She's in septic shock.
We've gotta get her to a hospital.
We got to get everybody
to a hospital. Dell called.
- What is it ?
- It's typhoid.
- How is Sister Virginia ?
- Well, she's still not responding.
And her blood pressure is very unstable.
Typhoid ? I didn't even... I thought
it disappeared in like the early 1900s.
It's a common disease in
exactly the kind of Third World places
where the sisters work, transmitted
through skin to skin contact or food.
- One sister caught it on a mission ?
- No. And that's what's troubling.
The incubation period
is two weeks at the most.
These sisters were sequestered longer.
So how did they get exposed ?
Excuse me. Just one second.
I spoke with Health Services.
No other outbreaks
of typhus in this area.
And all the food in
the convent tested clean.
So, if it's not the food...
Somebody had to have contact
with an outside carrier.
The sisters claim they've been isolated.
Nobody in, nobody out.
Sam, what are we saying here ?
That one of these nuns...
We're saying that somebody's lying.
You're not ready to date. You're
certainly not ready to quit therapy.
I feel fine. I feel good.
This is you going off your program.
Hi.
I'm just leaving some flowers
for Addison.
She's sleeping, so,
make sure she gets these, OK ?
Thanks.
Seizure ?
Addison's date was
with a patient of Violet's.
- Now Violet seems worried.
- No way.
Awesome. What's his deal ?
If it was nothing, she would say.
You know you'd say.
Just a hint.
You don't have to tell us...
He calls himself "Trunk."
OK.
When I think "trunk" in relation to
a guy... not necessarily a bad thing.
Elephants, trunks, very large...
Oh, is he freakishly large ?
- Is he hideously...
- I can't tell you !
"Trunk."
Aww.
- Flowers.
- How you holding up ?
Good. A little hungry.
A lot tired. And I can...
...can only find one shoe.
Every time I try to put her down
she started screeching like a bat.
Eee-eee-eee.
OK, you realize I didn't
actually give birth.
From your psych patient.
He just dropped them off.
That's so sweet.
Here, give me the card.
Uh, the thing is, I think Carl
might have some problems.
- Everybody has problems.
- Violet said his nickname is Trunk.
- I don't know what that means.
- I think it means...
...he's not Addison Montgomery material.
That's all.
No. You don't know what my material is.
You've never even seen my material,
remember ?
So, mind your own business.
- Huh ? Huh ?
- [Baby grunts]
Oh. Eee-eee-eee.
She isn't getting any better, is she ?
No, not yet. Her lungs are congested.
Pressure's borderline.
I'm putting all the sisters on an
aggressive course of antibiotics.
It's a dangerous disease, but the cure
rate is high for those with mild cases.
Thank you, Sam.
Father... there you go...
...Naomi's going to ask
the sisters some questions.
Anything you need.
Is there anyone
you think we should speak to ?
A sister that might have had contact
with a typhoid carrier
in the time they were sequestered ?
From the outside ?
Maybe a sister was meeting
with someone secretly.
No, no. I can't imagine
someone would lie about that.
Well, people keep secrets, Father.
Believe me.
I got a page from the ER.
Dr. Violet Turner.
Oh, hi. Yeah, you have a patient here.
We were able to remove the foreign
body non-surgically.
He's on pain meds now.
Seems to be resting comfortably.
- Is he going to be OK ?
- Yeah. Oh, yeah.
Yeah, he's lucky
he didn't perforate his bowel.
Just one question for you.
You got any idea whose shoe this is ?
The circumstances of the birth,
this is a very, very healthy baby.
- Did you hear that ?
- I heard we had something to celebrate ?
- You rescued a baby ?
- Yeah.
What exactly happens
once Social Services takes her ?
It's out of our hands.
She'll be placed in foster care while
they start the adoption process.
Come here, Batgirl. Yes.
Time for a little stroll.
A little stroll around the office ? Yeah.
Batgirl ?
Here's a question. Cotton balls
at St. Ambrose. Do you...
Triple size. Hospital grade.
Right. More cotton per ball.
Goodbye, Dr. Freedman.
Goodbye, CanUHandleMe.
I didn't mean to take her shoe.
You took her shoe, Carl.
And you did what you always do.
- Yeah.
- You need to come back to therapy.
This is not a good way to live, is it ?
No.
One more thing.
Can you tell Addison I can't see her ?
She's great, she's perfect.
But I don't trust myself
around her shoes.
How do you give up your baby ?
[Naomi] How do you give up
your whole life ?
Falling in love, a family, all of it,
just to go live in a convent ?
That's why somebody's lying.
This girl, Darcy ?
She carried her for nine months,
I've had her for one night,
one night,
and the thought of her being thrown
into some foster home is killing me.
You can't have this baby, Addison.
I know.
I named her. Batgirl.
OK. You just can't have kids.
Nai, I wish you were here today.
It's been such a weird day.
Tell me about it.
I'm interrogating nuns.
I wish I were there, too.
[Pager beeping]
- Damn it. I got to go.
- Bye.
- [Knock on door]
- [Softly] Come in.
I thought I heard you in here.
Batgirl can only sleep
in total darkness.
OK. Um...
Can I talk to you ?
It's Carl.
Carl likes you very much.
But he wanted me to tell you that
he's not going to be calling again.
I don't understand.
He has a medical issue
that worsens under stress.
- What issue ?
- Doesn't matter.
Why do you call him "Trunk ?"
Oh, you know about that,
OK, well that was very
unprofessional of me to say that.
A trunk is a place
where you might put
all sorts of things.
Things you might have taken
or borrowed from another person.
- In an anatomical sense...
- Oh, God.
- Where's my shoe ?
- We can talk about this.
It is nothing to be disturbed by.
It is an issue of control...
I am going to get up
and I'm going to walk out of this room
and you and I are never ever
- going to speak of this again.
- I would like that very much.
- No change ?
- No. I'm sorry.
I'd like to give her
the sacrament of the sick.
Oh, yeah. Of course.
The grace and peace of God our Father,
and the Lord, Jesus Christ, be with you.
Through this holy anointing, may the
Lord, in his love and mercy, help you
with the grace of the Holy Spirit.
May the Lord...
- The way he looks at her...
- I know.
Save you and raise you up.
Amen.
[Knocking]
Don't be mad,
but I called Social Services.
I meant to call, I just...
...forgot. That's good.
- I can help you pack up her stuff.
Thanks. Uh...
How long until they get here ?
- [Baby whines]
- There you go. Oh, Batgirl.
- [Crying]
- OK. Shh, shh, shh.
- [Phone rings]
- Oh...
I'll be back as soon as I can, OK ?
Safe Surrender hotline.
- Did she say where exactly ?
- No.
She just said Marine park,
past the first parking lot.
Addison.
The baby's not breathing.
There's no pulse.
[Flatline tone]
Continue to bring up his temp with warm
oxygen and fluids. More saline bags.
- What's his core temp ?
- Core temp is 95.
Let's do another round of epi.
Come on, little guy.
Come on, baby. Don't do this.
- Asystole.
- You've been at this almost an hour.
OK.
I'm going to call it.
Time of death : 10 :42 p.m.
- We got there as soon as we could.
- It's over.
- We tried.
- It's over, Pete.
- Addison, we did everything we...
- It's over. The baby's dead.
Tough day.
[Exhales]
Yeah.
I used to get off on them.
The tough ones.
When I was a resident,
I used to think,
"I got through this. I survived.
And the next one,
I'll survive even better."
I don't.
It's days like these where I slip
and make mistakes.
Bad mistakes.
These long, crappy days just...
I just need something...
...someone and I end up...
Falling off your wagon.
- Whoever your wagon may be.
- We have to get back to the practice.
This is the last time
I'm offering to talk.
Cooper, it's not that I don't
want to talk to you. I can't.
- Of course you can. It's what we do.
- I know.
But...
Allan obliterates my heart and
you tell me that he doesn't deserve me.
Some girl named Trixie
uses and abuses you and I listen to you
and I tell you you're being stupid.
I will always be able to talk to you
about someone else.
But I can't...
I can't talk to you about you.
I don't know how to talk about us.
Not like that.
Then talk to me about something else.
Whatever's on your mind.
I went to the ER.
Carl shoved one of
Addison's shoes up his...
- Yeah. OK, OK.
- Well, you know, you asked.
That's what was on my mind.
Maybe Carl will find a girl
who enjoys what he does.
So that's the answer ?
My job has no point ?
- Freaks should be with other freaks ?
- You talking about us ?
- About me ?
- No.
No.
Sister Virginia's doing better.
She...
Her pressure is normalized
since last time.
Father, we'd like to test you
for typhoid.
- Me ? I feel fine.
- Carriers are asymptomatic,
wouldn't know you had it
until it spread.
I've done missionary work all over
the world, but years ago.
That doesn't matter. This disease
can stay dormant for years.
You think...
...Sister Virginia got it from me ?
I know you say you don't go
in the convent but...
If you had direct contact with her...
I would sneak in at night
and we would...
- You don't have to say.
- I would sneak in and we would...
...cook.
Cook ?
I couldn't boil water
before she arrived. Never had to.
But then I would see her and
she was just so graceful, smart.
When no one else was around,
I would ask her for pointers.
It's been years now.
We have never touched.
I know it was forbidden.
She'd be away on missions
and I'd just...
Part of me was always waiting.
For the next time you could be together.
I missed my friend.
- All this pain because of me. I...
- Oh, no, no. You couldn't have known.
We'll get you on a course of
antibiotics, you'll be fine.
Thank you.
Sam, Naomi.
We all make choices.
The two of you made a choice.
I know, I was there. So was He.
I just want you to know
that as far as we're concerned,
you will always be married.
[Elevator dings]
Darcy, are you OK ?
You're the doctor who...
you took the baby ?
We offer your daughter a safe option.
Safe Surrender. She's protecting
herself and the baby.
She made the right choice to call.
The brave choice.
You think we'd ever let her
give this baby away ? My God !
This is my grandchild !
I didn't even notice.
Is she OK ?
She's a very healthy baby. Here.
OK ? There.
Yeah. Hi.
Hi.
Her name is Melanie.
My daughter's name is Melanie.
That's a perfect name.
Father Mark said we're still married
in the eyes of God, so technically,
what we did the other night, not a sin.
- Really ?
- Well...
It's what the Father said.
Which means if we were to do it again...
[chuckles]
[ ? Leona Naess : Learning As We Go]
- Charlotte.
- I'm going home, Dr. Freedman.
Come have a drink with me.
What ?
- No.
- Come on.
I am not having sex with you because
I wrote some things on the internet.
- No.
- [Elevator dings]
A drink. Not sex. Absolutely no sex.
[Panting]
- Can I get you that drink now ?
- Not yet.
- Ask me again in two hours.
- Yes, ma'am.
You heading out ?
I don't think I can be
in this day any longer.
- You shouldn't be alone tonight.
- I won't be.
[ ? Leona Naess : Learning As We Go]
- Hey.
- I'm sorry,
- I know it's past neighbor time.
- No, come in. It's cold.
Can I get you anything ?
Some tea or wine ?
Wine.
I called Naomi, but, uh...
...no one answered.
You want to talk about it ?
It was, um... a night.
You know ? Just a night.
And, like, I called Naomi
and she wasn't home.
I just couldn't go home yet.
Hey.
[Sobbing]